Spanish explorers invade the Americas
and bring with them the horse.
First brought to the Caribbean islands,
these animals reproduce and spread in the new world
as fast as the wind.
Horses have not been seen here since the Ice Age.
Now they're back.
It's as though the landscape has been waiting for them.
Once ashore a few horses run wild.
A new breed evolves,
which soon takes over North America: the Mustang.
Within three hundred years they had reached the central plains and the Rocky Mountains.
At the end of the eighteenth century
the Mustang makes it as far as Canada.
One hundred and fifty years later
there may be seven million wild horses in North America.
For the nomadic tribes like the Black Foot Cheyenne,
Sioux and Comanche of the central plains
these wild horses are a blessing.
What they used to do on foot
fighting, hunting, travelling,
they can now do on the backs of wild horses from Europe.
It transforms their lives.
This old world animal becomes the symbol of their native culture.
Although the horse once came from across the Atlantic, it is now an image of nomadic America.
As soon as the conquistadors have conquered South and Central America
one of them heads north:
Fernando de Soto
travels from Florida up the Mississippi river.
Looking for gold.
The Spaniards leave death in their wake.
And something else they bring along to keep them alive.
As they journey through unknown jungles,
the pigs help them survive.
They are a perfect source of food.
They don't take up much space in the boats.
They look after themselves
and they eat everything they can in this new continent.
They're prolific little beasts.
A healthy sow can give birth to ten piglets at a time.
When the conquistadors leave some behind
they will have an ever growing food supply for those who come after them.
The pigs are key to their survival.
But to native Americans
they're a curse.
In North America natives do not fence their fields
and the staple crop of corn is irresistible.
There is no evidence that native Americans know how to fight this plague of pigs.
Soon European swine are eating the seeds and the young shoots.
Only a few generations after running wild
the animal becomes very different from the typical farm pig.
It grows tusks and gets bigger and aggressive.
What began with a few pigs
becomes a daily nightmare for the native Americans.
In addition to horses
Columbus brought eight pigs to America on his second voyage.
Within twenty years
there are thirty thousand pigs on the island of Cuba alone.
They multiply conquering the Andes, the Amazon and North America.
But the Spaniard, his horse and his pig
would never have been so successful in the conquest of the new world
without a hidden passenger.
It is when the old and new worlds touch that the native American meets his worst enemy.
A very black ** for the continent.
A Spanish missionary reports:
"An epidemic broke up, a sickness of pustules
large blobs spread on people.
Some were entirely covered
on the face, the head, the chest
they lay in their dwellings and sleeping places no longer able to move or stir.
The pustules caused great desolation,
very many people died of them and many starved to death.
No one's took care of others any longer.
Deadly diseases contaminate both continents of the Americas.
For the natives
writes a chronicler.
they are near all dead at the smallpox.
so the Lord have cleared our title to what we possess."
To this day
scientists are still working to identify these diseases,
to trace their paths
and count the dead.
Smallpox was accidentally introduced in the Americas in the sixteenth-century.
The smallpox virus is very hearty. In blankets that are used by smallpox victims
the scabs can live
for weeks carrying the virus and smallpox can also pass from host to host
on board a trans-atlantic vessel until it reaches the Americas. And of course
once smallpox reached the Americas it was introduced to millions of new hosts,
human hosts who had no acquired immunities to these diseases.
And so smallpox together with measles and influenza had a devastating impact
on native American populations.
No one knows exactly what the mortality was. Conservative estimates are about 50%.
It was probably closer to ninety percent or even higher.
Through trade between native peoples
diseases spread through the whole continent.
Many natives die from diseases without ever seeing a European.
Microbes move faster than the conquistadors who brought them.
Some fifty years after Columbus first sets foot in the Americas
conquistadors and explorers find neither towns nor people.
No one stands in their way.
Most of the people are dead
and Nature reclaims the land.
Everything that they now find is pure wilderness.
A garden of Eden, without humans.
A thousand different kinds of birds and beasts of the forests
which have never been known
neither in shape or name.
"And ** there is no mention made
neither among the latins or greeks or any other nations of the world".
reports a Spanish missionary.
It may be God has made a new creation of beasts".
Explorers send exotic plants and animals, evidence of God's second creation
on the ships back to Spain.
Corn
Chilean pumpkins,
domesticated in the new world
unknown in Europe.
Tomatoes and potatoes.
But there is an unwelcome passenger on board.
An unintentional gift from the natives.
It will lead to death in Europe.
It was spread in the brothels, in the courts and cities of the old world.
It will be painful.
It drives its victims mad.
And it can take a long long time to kill.
This is the French pox,
or the Spanish sickness,
syphilis.
Europeans have no idea
that this disease came from America,
where more and more are aching to go.
In the seventeenth century a new wave of people heads to the new world: the settlers.
England has defeated Spain to become a new European superpower.
The English crown sets out to claim its share.
In 1607 the British start a colony on the east coast of
North America, in what is now Virginia.
They name it Jamestown after their king.
This will become