Were you skeptical about it at first?
At which point did you decide that you could actually make money from blogging?
For some of you who are new to eatyourkimchi
and you restarted watching our videos
and some of you have been watching us from the beginning
We feel sorry for you
Embarrassing actually...
Our videos suck....really suck
This is really good chance to explain it to people how we are blogging full time now
what we were doing before,
and how the heck we got to this point
YES!
Both of us are certified as high school teachers in Canada
and we came to Korea to be teachers as well
But when we came here first though
we set up a blog to show up our families what life is like in Korea
because after all they had no idea what it was like
and was worried about us
In fact, I'm sure that a lot of you planning coming to Korea
are already experiencing these problems with your friends and families who are like,
"Don't go!! ~~~ No water!! You can't do stuff there!!!"
"What's KPOP?"
So from D-1 we started to blog, just as a hobby, for ourselves and for our families
Then something really weird happened
Very weird...
People started to subscribe our videos
and we both were like
WHY???
WHO...WHY WOULD SOMEONE SUBSCRIBE?
WE ARE SO BORING AND NERDY
WHO IS THAT PERSON??
I DON'T UNDERSTAND...
Coming to think of it, 4 and a half years
WHY ARE YOU WATCHING OUR VIDEOS??
WE ARE SO NERDY AND WEIRD...
DORKY.....I DON'T UNDERSTAND
ME NIETHER
So some of you know that part of our history
but a lot of people don't know is that, during my 2 years of teacher in Korea
I had a really rough time as a teacher
Meemers said it was a rough time also...
So then I thought, since we are getting in more popular
What if I decided to work as full-time for a year while Martina teaches for her 3rd year
which ....
Actually what you meant to say was that I was your sugar mama for you
Buy me this T-shirt!!
Give me some money!!! I'm so hungry!!!
Home in my pjs working on my website while my wife brings home the money
Our website..was not actually making any money after 2years..
It had potential ... but for those few months after I started to do this for full time
REALLY....TOUGH TIMES...
So the big goal for us to be were just able to work together
like if we were both teachers we are in separate schools but we love each other a lot
and we wanna be with each other all the time
so why don't we have a job while we can work with each other all the time
This is really like our rookie groupy year
We only had one salary coming in, which was my salary
We had to pay the half the rent since you weren't a teacher anymore
We were still paying off for our student loans
we would run out money by the end of the month because we had to pay our bills
We would have no food to eat
Yes we were not eating for....last week of the month
EVERYTHING!!!
It was our rookie group year ..so much ramen
SO MUCH RAMEN.....
It was a really hard year for us
By the end of Martina's 3rd year of teaching, that was when we realized
"Yes, she could quit teaching, we both could live off the blog!
Yes it was going to be more difficult because we would be cutting off her salary as a teacher as well
But it's something we can do, we tighten our belts and can get through it!!"
And we wouldn't eat
And a lot of people don't realize is that, it was a really stressful 2 years for us really
cuz it's a risky thing to do,
we are not on a contract, we weren't being paid monthly by someone
It's risky, if our videos flop.. then we are not getting paid or
if people stop liking us and everyone unsubscribes and leaves....
then we'll become lonely and we'll be out on the streets and have a homeless cup and we'll be really sad
So to clarify, we are not actually hired by any company
the Korean government doesn't give us any money,
no music industry is giving us money
we are just working off as Youtube partnership and our own website ads
And also this is just two of us, we don't have a PR team
we don't have a staff of camera men or video editors,
we don't have makeup artists, we don't have stylist , we don't have writers
we are just two of us
"We can make it if we try ~~~
JUST THE TWO OF US~~
YOU AND I
Don't forget about me guise~~
Spudgy works hard also
Just the three of us~~
Meemers...
JUST THE FOUR OF US~~
And when i decided not to return to my school for 4th year.
it was actually really really hard for me
I cried and cried and cried
and for the first 6, 7 months I'll say
"I'm still a teacher....I'm not used to this blogging thing"
She would keep talking about her students
You don't have anymore students....
YOUR STUDENTS ARE ALL DEAD...
I didn't say that they were all dead, I'm not that mean
So the big question that everyone wants to know
"How is it possible to make money from blogging?"
Actually this is quite simple, when you watch our videos in Youtubes
you see like a preroll ad or ad at the bottom or ad on the side,
or if you visit our websites you see the ads on the side as well
we make money for those ads
The more people watch our videos, the more people visit our sites
the more money we make
Except, if you are one of those people who use ad blocks that you don't see any ads
which we make no money whatsoever which means...
Every time you use ad blocks, you visit our site or watch our videos
Spudgy goes hungry
You want Spudgy to be hungry?
Is that what you want?
And especially you China, because we know that sites download our videos and re upload them
so we make no money out of it
China...I've got eye on you....
You are watching these videos for free..
for small exchange, watch an ad at the beginning of the video
Can you say that in more cooperate ways?
No..
Now we really appreciate of the fans support that people buy our T-Shirts
because that T-Shirt money goes to us and you don't had to buy those T-Shirts
like you can keep watching those videos for free
Those direct support of us and sites and we really appreciate that and thank you very much
And if you guys can't afford the shirts we don't wanna put pressure on people
Just thank you for watching our videos in general
Just by watching our video you are giving your support that way as well,
and Spudgy food and Meemersworth pats and kisses
So currently we are trying to get a business visa in Korea that we could set up eatyourkimchi as a business
and we are saving up money to apply for it
because getting business visas is not cheap...
and it takes a long time to apply it and we could not do it outside of Korea
and we've been working on this for awhile
What we are hoping to do is that actually set up a business that we could actually hire editors
that could help us with the workload and we could maybe hire a videographer help us out as well
It's totally awesome guys
We want to get more video segments for you guys
we have so many ideas and things we wanna do,
just don't have enough time and for those of you who edit videos
you know that it is the most time vampire in the world!
Like if we film one video, a WANK, it could take us like 8 hours to film
and then editing, that could be 6 to 10 hours, exporting and uploading it
It could take us a day or an a half for one video
Literally we don't have enough time in the day for one video but we do it
So this is our very long answer to this really complicated question
I hope you have a better understanding what we are doing now
You can check on our blog post on our website for more details about it
we don't wanna just ramble on and on in this video
30 minutes!!
So that's for this week's TL;DR
If you have a question for next TL;DR, leave your question on the comment section below
or you can check out the question that are already asked, and you can thumb them up
and hope we notice that question and choose it
And don't forget to subscribe for more TL;DRs
and not to watch us video with ad block
Cuz it would make us really sad
and Spudgy very sad
and Meemers really sad
HEY AD BLOCK!