place. We're doing on the top of a mountain.
Look at that!
That counts, c'mon, that counts!
That wasn't down! That was not down.
Absolutely beautiful! Got some friends!
Heeeeeeey!
We've put all of this together. Have a little
look at this. We have got some beautiful local
cheeses. This is Bang cheese.
This is amazing.
How did they make that?
I tell you, I do know what they do. They have
a little.. this cheese, this bang cheese,
they have it.. it's about 6/7 inches, like
a little Pecorino, they take the top off and
they've got this little stirry thing and it
shaves it.
Potato salad. A lovely sweet potato, a little
sort of galette with puff pastry, feta, nice
bits and pieces. Some salad, some lovely seafood.
Over here we've got some dressing, we've got some roast chicken. Lovely! And a nice little fig and almond tart for dessert.
There you go.
Thank you to the CK Verbier posse in the background.
Yaaaaay!
Best, best, best chalets and food and everything
on the planet. And to my lovely friends who
I love very much.
Yaaaay!!
It's time for a picnic!
Yeeeeeeah!
C'mon, let's eat!