You know what I like to
do when we're camping?
I also like to make s'mores.
The problem with this is that
in Colorado we have a lot of
forest fires, and so because
of those forest--
Because of those forest fires,
I've got to come up with a new
way to be able to roast
marshmallows.
And I think I've got a great
idea using just the
power of the sun.
I'm Steve Spangler and I'm all
about making science fun.
For the last 20 years, I've
been teaching ways to turn
ordinary science experiments
into unforgettable learning
experiences.
I have an amazing team who will
do whatever it takes to
affect the way people
think about science.
And to do that I live
by one motto.
Make it big, do it right,
give it class.
Well, before we can harness
the power of the sun to be
able to cook our s'mores, we
need to learn something about
the science of this solar
radiation that's
coming to the Earth.
See the sun up there?
It's this giant enormous ball of
gas that goes through this
fusion reaction where there's
four hydrogen atoms that get
fused together to make one
helium atom and this--
That's not really important.
What's important is all this
radiation is coming down and
the Earth's atmosphere, just the
air and the ozone layer,
block 97% to 95% of this
radiation that comes through.
But the stuff that does get
through can still be
dangerous, and that's why you
need something like this UV
checker to tell you whether or
not you need to have sunscreen
and how much you need to have.
So you just push the little
button here on this solar
index meter and it reads the
amount of UVA, which are the
longest waves all the way to
UVC, which are the shortest
waves, to be able to determine
how much sunscreen you need.
Bottom line, you've got to
have sun protection.
So let's just say you don't have
one of these fancy little
UV detectors, is there another
way to be able to see the
radiation that's coming
through the sky?
Come to find out, there is.
They're these fancy little
beads called UV
color changing beads.
You see, these beads start
perfectly white when they're
not in ultraviolet light.
But as soon as they're exposed
to ultraviolet light, you can
see what happens here.
Watch.
See the white goes to this
beautiful color.
And there's actually a pigment
in each one of these that the
ultraviolet light causes the
bond inside to be able to
dance and twist and
you get these
beautiful colors like this.
You can see, just like glass,
this plastic here, on the
outside of this pail, allows
the ultraviolet light to be
able to come through enough
to be able to
make them change color.
But if you dig down inside,
where we haven't seen any at
all, take a look at this.
You can see they actually are
white on the top until the
moment they reach the
ultraviolet light.
Now, the really cool thing about
these color changing
beads is that when they're out
of the sun's light, and they
have no UV radiation, the little
pigment bonds twist
back to their original shape
and they go back to their
colorless state, which
is very, very cool.
Watch this.
While these UV color changing
beads are really fun to play
with, they actually are a very,
very cool tool to be
able to use for a science fair
project to be able to test the
effectiveness of sunscreen.
So, here's how it works.
You take a bag and you put the
beads in the bag like this.
Now, they're going to change
color immediately because this
plastic here isn't blocking any
of the sun's radiation.
Now, you take your sunscreen and
you put your sunscreen on
the bag like this and you just
rub it all around the bag.
And you kind of smooth it in.
It's not going to absorb, but
you just try to cover it.
And then you can see
how the intensity
changes with the beads.
So that's why this makes it
such a cool science fair
project is you're really
comparing the effectiveness of
these sunscreens using a control
and some very visual
ways to be able to see how
they change color.
Watch this.
This bag here has no sunscreen
on it whatsoever.
So it's our control bag.
It's just the ultraviolet
light coming through.
You can see, we get
these beautiful
colors as we had before.
The second bag here has
SPF 30 on there.
So now we have some blocking.
But take a look at this.
It's not nearly as intense
as it used to be.
While the blues are still
coming through and some
purples, those yellows are
almost completely white, which
just goes to show you that
there's a different amount of
energy needed to change all the
beads a different color.
Move over to SPF 50.
That's very, very cool because
now we really see some white
beads in here.
Blues are still coming through
but that's cool.
And as soon as you move to 70,
this is the coolest part,
because you really see how faint
and how well the SPF 70
does to be able to block the
harmful rays of the sun.
The very end, you turn them
all back over again.
So now, there's no sunscreen
showing and they should all
look like the control
that you started
with at the very beginning.
That's cool.
Well, now that we know the
science behind the sun and
kind of what we need to do to
cook our s'mores, we've got to
find a device to be
able to do that.
For that, we've got to head
back to the kitchen.
The microwave oven, what
an amazing invention.
Just a couple seconds,
your dinner is ready.
I remember when we got our first
one in the 1970s, every
time Dad cooked a little
burrito, I'd forget my name
and make animal sounds.
But that's not important, what
is important is this.
It uses microwave energy.
Now this is a wavelength of
energy that can either be as
big as a meter, maybe as small
as a millimeter, that have
different energies and different
frequencies between
300 m zzzzs and--
m zzzs?
HIGGINSWORTH: It's megahertz.
STEVE: I told you to do it
phonetically, Higginsworth.
HIGGINSWORTH: Sorry, Steve.
STEVE: Stand by.
Between 300 megahertz
and 300 gigahertz.
Honestly, who cares?
Even though the microwave is
cool, it's not harnessing the
power of the sun, and to do that
it's time to head over to
arts and crafts,
science style.
In order to make our solar
cooker, you're going to need a
recycled pizza box, preferably
your own.
Just pick off the old remnants
there, it'll
be perfectly fine.
Close it up, we're going
to make a window
inside here as well.
To do that, I'm going to take a
ruler and measure a two inch
border all the way around
so I can cut
out the perfect window.
You're going to leave
the back, so that
you don't cut it.
We're going to cut these
three sides.
And bam, done.
This is our flap.
Perfect.
We need some aluminum foil.
We're covering the bottom here,
so it reflects the sun.
We're also going to put
it on the inside
of the flap as well.
We're going to glue both of
these in place, so we really
have a way to be able
to trap the sun's
energy inside our cooker.
So now it's a matter of using
a little glue stick to just
glue the aluminum
foil to the box.
Next thing you're going to need
is a piece of plastic.
These are just pieces of plastic
bag that we opened up
and taped together.
This is going to go over the
opening like this and now
we're going to take packing
tape and you're
going to seal the edges.
We want to trap as much of that
solar energy in the box
as possible.
Just as we saw with the UV
beads, the solar energy can go
through the plastic with
no problem at all.
We just want to be able to trap
that energy inside the
box and not allow that heat
to come back out.
Let's see if it worked.
It's a perfect window.
And black absorbs heat, so it
only makes sense to take a
black square of paper and put
it right here, on the very
bottom, to be able to
concentrate the heat here is
very, very center.
So all the reflected light goes
right here to the center
and this will be our
cooking surface.
Glue it down and you're
ready to go.
But there is one more problem.
And that is, this lid
won't stay open.
But I've got a solution
for that.
Higginsworth.
In a little bit more.
Perfect.
Fixed.
So let's say you don't have a
Higginsworth, that's where
this skewer comes in.
Watch.
You put the tape in place like
this, and now, you lift it up,
and it rests right there.
Voila.
Let's review.
The object you want to
cook goes inside.
Now, the reflective part gets
folded down here, the handy
dandy adjustable reflector gets
opened up, positioned
perfectly to catch all of the
sun's rays, this gets held
right in place, and you've got
yourself a solar cooker.
So now, let's head back
out to our campgrounds
and see if it works.
In the wilds of pristine,
beautiful Colorado.
Nobody around.
Takes me hours to get there.
Don't even see any wildlife.
It's just me, my cooker,
and my tent.
And my iPhone and a computer
and an iPad.
That's it.
That's all I need.
And a cooler, and
a propane tank.
That's pretty much all I need.
And some Taco Bell,
just in case.
I get hungry.
That's all I need.
Oh, Higginsworth,
my ice melted.
Can you get me some more ice?
On me please, right on me.
Thank you.
Can you hurry?
I'm really hot.
Ding.
Mmm, mmm, it's done, and it
only took 3 and 1/2 hours.
Lucky for me, I was wearing
plenty of sunscreen.
No need for this anymore.
Perfect.
Two more.