Alright Mustang fans, you know what day it
is! It's December 5th, 2013. The big reveal
of the next generation Ford Mustang is finally
here and we're right here in New York City
to bring it to you guys. We're starting things
off right here at Good Morning America. The
reveal is happening worldwide. Keep in mind
that this is the first worldwide Mustang.
Shanghai, Barcelona, Sydney, LA, Dearborn
Michigan and of course right here in New York
City. Now this whole day is full of Mustangs.
We're going to be here for the reveal, first.
Then we're going to go to a press conference
where we're going to learn more about the
2015 and of course we're going to be bringing
you guys with us every step of the way. You
should know the deal by now you have to subscribe
to our YouTube channel if you haven't already
to keep tabs on all of these great videos
including the new 2015 Mustang! I'm excited
to see the car, I know you guys are as well
so let's check it out. Well, here it is guys
for the first time, nationally televised the
2015 Mustang. I have to admit... absolutely
stunning in person. Now, you guys can see
the thing looks pretty sharp. It definitely
looks a little smaller than the 2013 and 2014's
in my opinion, but overall impression, man...
very nice! And of course for Mustang fans
in North America it's very exciting. Alot
of new things to expect, new technology, new
suspension, so it's a very exciting time to
be a Mustang fan. Alright guys, love it or
hate it the next generation Mustang is here
and I think it's a beaut man. It really does
look sharp in person, but this is only the
tip of the iceburg. We're on our way to our
next stop which is an invite-only Ford press
conference. They're actually going to have
a Mustang GT there from what we understand,
so I'm excited to see that! Let's go check
it out. What I want to do now is give you
an idea of how much change we actually made
if we actually pull the images up on the screen.
That's the 2014 Mustang compared to the 2015
and what you're hopefully going to see there
is how much lower and wider that the 2015
really is. We have now a 2.3L Ecoboost that
we're bringing into the Mustang. The Ecoboost
will put out more power and torque than the
V6 and yet it's going to be significantly
more fuel efficient. Our 5.0L is going to
undergo some overhaul and it's going to get
more horsepower and it will also be more fuel
efficient. What are we doing to the paddle
shifters? We're rev-matching in the downshifts
and when you take the car and put it into
drive from Sport-Mode and then you use the
paddle shifters, you're going to get quicker
and more aggressive shifts. We did put an
IRS in the vehicle, I know everybody has been
wondering. It has an IRS. It's a world-class
integral link suspension. So, we ended up
doing an all new front suspension, as well.
So we have the double ball-joint front suspension
with a full subframe, more than 20 new technologies
built into the car. When you get in it, you're
going to push a button to start your driving
experience. After that you have toggles to
mess with. One of those toggles is going to
feature a selectable driving mode. It will
toggle between Normal, Sport, Track and Snow/Wet
mode. So right next to that toggle switch
we have some additional toggle switches that
will allow you to override those settings
so that you can customize your own steering
settings if you don't like the ones that we've
chosen for you or you'll be able to modify
the electronic stability control, the traction
control. So all of this comes together to
provide you a vehicle that is a much more
capable and easier to drive than any Mustang we've
ever produced. Alright guys, we just wrapped
up the press briefing here at the 2015 Mustang
reveal. We got to hear from all of the brilliant
minds that went into making this incredible
machine and let me just tell you there's alot
more going on than I originally thought. I
mean, this car just leaps and bounds above
the 2013 and 2014 Mustangs in just about every
way. Most powerful Mustang lineup of all-time
with the Ecoboost motor, the V6 and the pumped-up
Coyote 5.0L motor. Most capable handling Mustang
of all-time with the new independent rear
suspension set up going on. Let's hop inside
real quick and take a look. Just totally redesigned
interior. Just feels more modern and I think
that's what they're going for overall with
the 2015. It's just pushing the car forward
and getting out of that retro styling which
they've been doing since 2005. Don't get me
wrong, I love it. But, in Ford's opinion,
it was time to move the car forward and they've
done a great job with it. It's jut a much
better Mustang, that's the only way I can
put it. I was a little apprehensive like you
guys all were online. We all saw the renderings,
we all saw the early leaked photos, but seeing
it here in person it's the only way to appreciate
this car and I can't stress that enough guys.
You really have to check this thing out in
person and make your own final judgement.
Alright, here with Dave, Chief Engineer of
the new Mustang. How you doing, sir? Dave:
Good man, how are you? Justin: I am great.
The car is amazing man, well done. Dave: Thank
you! Justin: Now some Boss 302 internals we're
hearing about. Can you be a little bit more
specific about that? Where are you getting
the extra power from? Dave: Yeah, so a couple
things. We learned alot from the Boss 302
in how to make the engine breathe better.
So, we have larger intake and exhaust valves,
we've got a revised camshaft lifting those
valves higher. We have new heads to support
the flow alot better and then we're using
the valve springs out of the Boss. We're using
the forged connecting rods. Justin: Maybe
a little higher revving enginng? Dave: It's
not going to rev any higher as far as the
redline goes, but you are going to get more
horsepower out of it and more torque. Justin:
Any numbers you can give us right now? Dave:
We're not sharing numbers now, but you've
seen us that the 5.0L from 412 horsepower
to 420 horsepower and we're going to take
yet another step forward and we're going to
make everybody happy. Justin: The Ecoboost
is making its introduction into the Mustang
for the first time. Tell us a little more
about your experience with that? Dave: So
the Ecoboost technology has been phenomenal
right? Now for the first time we're adding
a new Ecoboost, a 2.3L to the family, specifically
designed to be in this machine. I've been
out on the track with it, I've flogged it
and I'm telling you it'll put a smile on your
face. It is absolutely worthy of being in
that car. Justin: So, killer gas mileage,
over 300 horsepower... I mean, I'm a V8 guy
through and through, but it's kind of hard
to beat those kind of numbers. Dave: I will
tell you that you will definitely enjoy it.
I'll tell you that! Justin: We're here with
Moray, Executive Design Director. First off
sir, I just want to say congratulations. You
can finally take a breathe right? Moray: Thanks!
I know, right? Justin: Let's talk about probably
one of the most changed areas, the rear end
Morray, what are you thinking about the rear
end? Moray: Well, I think one of the, you
know, one of the things that's very important
is the tri-bar tail lamps. It's very important
to keep that, but we wanted to do them in
a much more exciting and modern way. So, we've
really used new LED technology not even just
to give the cars a beautiful lit appearance,
but the unlit appearance with so much 3-dimensionality
to the actual forms, as well. So, although
it's the formula of Mustang, its done in a
very much more modern way. Justin: Well Moray,
that classic kind of icon happens up front,
too with the gills from the 1964 and 1965
Mustang, so... Moray: Yeah, some people recognize
that. We've paid homage to the first car with
the gills and we turned those into daylight
running lamps. There's nothing subtle about
"Mustang". It needs to be this fist where
you, you know, you want to see it in the mirror
coming behind you and be able to recognize
what it is. Justin: Alright, we're here at
the Ford after-party. Obviously, it's been
a long day. We've been up since 4AM. Now it's
time to blow off a little steam, but not just
a good time. I mean, we're actually checking
out the Good Morning America fastback 2.3L
Ecoboost 2015 Mustang here. Very cool stuff,
you actually get a good feel of the fastback
right here. You can see the angle, see the
very cool rear end and again 2.3L 4-cylinder
motor, great fuel mileage but guess what?
Over 300 horsepower, so... this thing should
be pretty nasty. Well guys, that's going to
wrap us up here for the 2015 Mustang unveiling
live from New York City. It's been one heck
of a day, we saw Good Morning America, the
press briefing and now the after-party where
everybody's blowing off a little steam and
we're getting to check out both cars here
in the flesh. I'll be the first to tell you,
I was skeptical on how this car was going
to look after seeing the renderings, seeing
the spy photos, but again seeing it here in-person,
the car just looks amazing and it's just leaps
and bounds over the S197 in many different
ways. I encourage you guys to give it a chance
before rushing to judgement. We cannot wait
to give this thing a chance and get behind
the wheel, get our hands on it, go crazy,
make it our next Project Car when it does
launch and you know we'll be all over that!
You guys have to stay up-to-date with our
blog so you get to see all of the latest 2015
Mustang news and rumors and of course if you
haven't already, click the button below to
subscribe to our YouTube channel. I think
it's time to enjoy the party, we've had a
great day up here in New York City and for
everything having to do with your Mustang,
you have to keep it right here at AmericanMuscle.com!