And when I went to Israel as a candidate,
I didn't take donors, I didn't attend fundraisers,
I went to Yad Vashem, the — the Holocaust
museum there, to remind myself the — the
nature of evil and why our bond with Israel
will be unbreakable.
And then I went down to the border towns of
Sderot, which had experienced missiles raining
down from Hamas. And I saw families there
who showed me where missiles had come down
near their children's bedrooms, and I was
reminded of — of what that would mean if
those were my kids, which is why, as president,
we funded an Iron Dome program to stop those
missiles.
So that's how I've used my travels when I
travel to Israel and when I travel to the
region.
And the central question at this point is
going to be, who's going to be credible to
all parties involved?
And they can look at my track record — whether
it's Iran sanctions, whether it's dealing
with counterterrorism, whether it's supporting
democracy, whether it's supporting women's
rights, whether it's supporting religious
minorities — and they can say that the president
of the United States and the United States
of America has stood on the right side of
history. And — and that kind of credibility
is precisely why we've been able to show leadership
on a wide range of issues facing the world
right now.