On today's episode, we meet
some of our weird and
wonderful friends
from YouTube.
It's the first installment of My
Life Online, and it's with
the Gregory Brothers.
Then we get some updated
etiquette rules from John
Martin, but first up, we sent
the nicest person we've ever
met, Shan Shan, out into the
streets of New York to talk
about MLK Day.
SHAN HUANG: This is Shan for
Vice Magazine, and I'm on the
street today because today's
Martin Luther King Day.
And I want to know how much
people know about Dr. King.
So do you know what's
today's holiday?
MALE SPEAKER 1: Martin
Luther King Day.
MALE SPEAKER 2: Martin
Luther King.
FEMALE SPEAKER 1: It's Martin
Luther King Day.
MALE SPEAKER 3: Yeah, MLK.
Martin Luther King, yeah.
SHAN HUANG: Oh, MLK.
MALE SPEAKER 3: Yeah.
SHAN HUANG: Ahhh.
Do you know what's
today's holiday?
FEMALE SPEAKER 2: Yeah, Martin
Luther King's Day.
Yeah.
SHAN HUANG: Do you know what
he stands for, for America?
FEMALE SPEAKER 2: I don't know.
He break--
broke, the abolish?
Maybe?
MALE SPEAKER 4: He's just black
guy, and he worked for
black people right?
Yeah.
SHAN HUANG: Are you going to
do anything to celebrate?
MALE SPEAKER 1: Yes.
SHAN HUANG: What are
you going to do?
MALE SPEAKER 1: I'm going to
go south where it's warm.
And I think that's about it.
Get warm.
That's what black people like.
We like to be warm.
So this cold weather shit's
for like white people.
SHAN HUANG: Are you going to
do anything to celebrate?
MALE SPEAKER 5: No,
I have to work.
All day.
SHAN HUANG: What are you
going to do today?
MALE SPEAKER 6: Um, I might do
the same thing I did last
year, was I read a little bit
about him when I got home.
And like, that's mostly it.
Just read about him
and like, yeah.
What he did.
SHAN HUANG: So you
read a little bit
about him every day?
I mean, every year?
MALE SPEAKER 6: Mm-hmm.
SHAN HUANG: So maybe when you're
50, you would know
everything about him.
What do you know
about Dr. King?
FEMALE SPEAKER 1: Um, well, he
was leader of the Black Civil
Rights Movement here.
MALE SPEAKER 7: The whites
didn't like him, and so he
protested, and he had this
speech that he had a dream for
everybody to be the
same equal rights.
SHAN HUANG: Very,
very impressive.
FEMALE SPEAKER 2: I had a dream
my English teacher came
out, and he said, oh, your
English is so poor.
You have to try more.
MALE SPEAKER 5: I had a dream
that I was teaching kids, and
one of them turned
into my boss.
FEMALE SPEAKER 3: We're actually
experimenting with
dreams at the moment.
You have to go this forest in
your dream and then meet this
cat there while a brass
band is playing.
SHAN HUANG: So what about if
you're going to cook one
dinner for Dr. King, what
would you serve him?
FEMALE SPEAKER 1: Crispy kale.
MALE SPEAKER 3: Maybe I'd just
have a burrito, right?
Everybody likes Mexican food.
FEMALE SPEAKER 3: Fish.
SHAN HUANG: What type of fish?
FEMALE SPEAKER 3: Whitefish.
And steamed potatoes.
We call that nursery food.
SHAN HUANG: Nursery food?
FEMALE SPEAKER 3: Yeah.
It heals everything.
And we'd make him miso
soup as well.
SHAN HUANG: What do you think
that Dr. King needs to be
healed for?
FEMALE SPEAKER 3: Needs
to be healed for?
Being assassinated, I suppose.
SHAN HUANG: Oh, OK.
RYAN DUFFY: So you try to
go out and have a nice
conversation with people on a
holiday here in New York, and
you just hear about their
bullshit dreams.
Next up is My Life Online,
where we go and meet the
Gregory Brothers.
And you may think that you don't
know who they are, but
when you see these videos,
you're going to realize you
know them all too well.
[MUSIC - GREGORY BROTHERS,
"DOUBLE RAINBOW SONG"]
EVAN GREGORY: The Gregory
Brothers are mostly known for
online videos that we do.
And those videos are a
realization of a Utopian
vision in which we uncover
hidden songs from within the
speech of ordinary people.
ANTOINE DODSON: Well, obviously
we have a rapist in
Lincoln Park.
[MUSIC - GREGORY BROTHERS,
"BED INTRUDER SONG"]
EVAN GREGORY: Um, we started
in a musical background and
had toured together
with my brothers.
ANDREW GREGORY: I don't know.
We toured a lot as a band, but
in a very small-scale way
where we were playing to crowds
of anywhere between
zero and 200 people.
MICHAEL GREGORY: Nobody
likes a regular band.
SARAH GREGORY: We were
definitely pursuing the arts
in very traditional
ways when we first
started working together.
But then once your imagination
gets a little crazier and
crazier, there's stuff that
you can only produce using
technology.
JIM LEHRER: Senator Obama,
two minutes.
[MUSIC - GREGORY BROTHERS,
"DEBATE HIGHLIGHTS"]
SARAH GREGORY: Back in the 2008
presidential election,
Michael made a video out of the
first debate between Obama
and McCain.
And he wanted to write a song,
basically, about the issues
that he knew that
were going to be
coming up in that debate.
So he successfully made that
video and just thought it
would be way more fun if we
could somehow get the
candidates to sing
along with us.
[MUSIC - GREGORY BROTHERS,
"AUTO-TUNE THE NEWS 5"]
EVAN GREGORY: We took some
technology that we had a grasp
of, pitch correction technology
that includes
Auto-tune, and used it to modify
their voices so it
sounds like they're
singing with us.
And then we could create duets
and melodies that we're
actually participating
in together.
And that became Auto-Tune
the News
MALE SPEAKER: He said,
any world war--
MICHAEL GREGORY: Uh, I'm laying
down a beat for you.
Keep going.
SARAH GREGORY: We spent about
a year auto-tuning the news,
and then realized that we
shouldn't limit our quest for
music to just news
and politics.
[MUSIC - GREGORY BROTHERS,
"REALITY HITS YOU HARD BRO"]
"CAN'T HUG EVERY CAT"]
SARAH GREGORY: So then we just
started calling it Songify,
because that's essentially what
we were doing, was just
finding songs out
in the universe.
EVAN GREGORY: Where
are we, Andrew?
ANDREW GREGORY: Well, as you
might notice, our office is
very spacious.
Why, you might ask?
Because it used to
be a horse barn.
EVAN GREGORY: This is where all
the audio magic happens,
where we try to summon various
types of sonic wizardry to
coax songs out of those places
in the universe that
heretofore have been dark,
songless corners.
[MUSIC - GREGORY BROTHERS,
"TAXI DAVE SONG"]
EVAN GREGORY: We are trained
musically, but not in the art
of video editing.
So we just kind of accrued those
skills by saying, let's
try this in the video.
I don't know how.
OK, let's figure that out and
let's do the next thing.
MICHAEL GREGORY: Nearly
everything that we shoot for
our videos is done on
a green screen.
EVAN GREGORY: Let's say if we
needed a floating head.
MICHAEL GREGORY: Or arms
waving around?
We'll still use the sheet.
EVAN GREGORY: But we upgraded
this year and
just painted the wall.
It's like, why hang the sheet?
Just paint the wall, man.
MICHAEL GREGORY: So let's
take you back to the
area where we edit.
Hey, Sarah.
SARAH GREGORY: Hi guys.
MICHAEL GREGORY: We run After
Effects stuff and Final Cut
stuff in tandem to sort of put
the videos together while the
audio is being made.
EVAN GREGORY: That's
a gold record.
MICHAEL GREGORY: That single
just went gold in January.
I mean, something like "Friday,"
Rebecca Black's
"Friday" has gotten watched
a lot more than "The Bed
Intruder Song," but people
are not as excited about
downloading "Friday"
for $0.99.
EVAN GREGORY: Little
known fact.
You have to buy the plaque for
yourself once you get it
certified gold.
But we got, we got a couple
of them and--
and sent one to Antoine.
So he's got one hanging
in his house, too.
MICHAEL GREGORY: And
unfortunately, solid pure gold
does not come cheap.
INTERVIEWER: Do your moms
understand what you actually
do for a living?
MICHAEL GREGORY: She
understands, but she still
says YouTubes, plural.
[MUSIC - GREGORY BROTHERS,
"WINNING"]
EVAN GREGORY: Once
the number of--
SARAH GREGORY: Really
great feeling.
EVAN GREGORY: Once the number of
views exceeds the number of
moms related to video producers,
then you feel like
you're beginning to hit your
stride as an auteur.
We have found success on
YouTube, if only by the metric
of we all left our day
jobs to just do this.
[MUSIC - GREGORY BROTHERS,
"WINNING"]
SARAH GREGORY: And we're getting
into comedy, and we're
doing more writing.
MICHAEL GREGORY: We're in the
middle of a development deal
with Comedy Central, which
is really cool.
EVAN GREGORY: It's, I mean,
pointless to plug, since no
one could actually watch
it right now.
If it was about to air on TV,
then we would be like plugging
it like silly.
CHARLIE SHEEN: Duh.
Winning.
EVAN GREGORY: But it is true
that a lot of doors have been
opened to us based on our
videos being seen a lot.
ANDREW GREGORY: Basically,
YouTube actually works.
That's a huge first--
MICHAEL GREGORY: YouTube
actually works.
ANDREW GREGORY: It
MICHAEL GREGORY: It's
just so egalitarian.
It doesn't matter if it's very
grainy footage of a bunny
making a weird sound or
whether it's very
high-definition footage of Newt
Gingrich giving a speech
that he later regrets.
[MUSIC - GREGORY BROTHERS,
"SONGIFY THE NEWS 1"]
MICHAEL GREGORY: The desire of
the American workforce to not
be working while on the clock
is just really impressive.
[MUSIC - GREGORY BROTHERS,
"SONGIFY THE NEWS 1"]
MICHAEL GREGORY: They don't
need Solitaire anymore.
They have cats.
[MUSIC - GREGORY BROTHERS,
"SONGIFY THE NEWS 1"]
RYAN DUFFY: It took me about
a year to get that Antoine
Dodson thing out of my head,
and now it's just back
permanently.
And finally, we have John
Martin's Etiquette Update.
Rules for living from the
biggest blowhard we know.
JOHN MARTIN: Some
rules for food.
When you're out to lunch, you do
not touch your food before
everyone else has theirs.
No sneaking French fries.
No Floridian table Jenga.
That means when you get in, if
there's a four-top and a
four-top and there's
eight of you, you
don't push them together.
Using forks in Chinese
restaurants, McDonald's
breakfast, skim milk, granola.
Not classy.
Making lists of etiquette
that have
declining values of humor?
All day long.
RYAN DUFFY: Hope you enjoyed
another episode of Vice Today,
and keep an eye out for new
episodes Monday and Thursday
of next week.
And if you like the channel,
please subscribe.
Thanks for watching.