BEEFY: Mate, I'm starving.
NATHAN: Tell me about it.
What have you got?
BEEFY: Burger.
NATHAN: Oh, man.
Ha.
BEEFY: What?
NATHAN: Hey.
BEEFY: What are you
mean about?
NATHAN: OK.
Right.
You ain't going to believe this,
because I didn't believe
it at first.
But I swear it's true,
'cause Ash said he
heard the same thing.
BEEFY: What are you talking
to Ash for, man?
NATHAN: Look, you know
that kid who got
stabbed last month?
BEEFY: Yeah.
I heard about it.
But I didn't know him.
NATHAN: Yeah, but you heard
about it, right?
BEEFY: Yeah.
NATHAN: Well, anyway, after he
got stabbed, the guys who
stabbed him let him get away.
Too busy arguing like idiots.
So the stabbed kid, you know,
he's trying to get away, but
there's no where
for him to go.
So he's stumbling down
that alleyway.
You know, one arm pushed against
his wound like that.
And as he looks behind him,
they're all there,
coming after him.
So he turns a corner, and
he sees the bright
lights of this place.
He stumbles in.
He's fallen behind
the counter.
But now, he's leaking
like a tap.
Blood everywhere.
BEEFY: No way.
This place?
NATHAN: Yeah.
This place.
I mean, the kebab guy, he didn't
know what was going on.
He didn't know whether to help
him or chuck him out.
[CLINK]
BEEFY: Yeah.
And?
NATHAN: Right.
So now, the gang bursts through
the doors, and they're
looking to finish him off.
-What the fuck are you
looking at, man?
Move.
BEEFY: Wait.
This really happened here?
NATHAN: Yeah.
It gets worse.
Look, I'm telling you.
They started giving it real
big to the kebab guy.
You know, telling him to get out
of the way so they could
get to the kid.
-Move.
-Get out of the fucking
way, man.
Are you mad?
NATHAN: What do you think
the owner's done?
BEEFY: I don't know.
NATHAN: Well, they didn't take
too kindly to it, you see.
Some fuckers running in
there with knives
out looking for trouble.
They've had enough
of that shit.
They're probably from some
war-torn country, you know?
Seeing shit me and you
wouldn't believe.
So he picks up a knife.
I ain't talking about
no pocket knife.
I'm talking about a big,
motherfucking knife.
BEEFY: Shit man.
That's some "Crocodile
Dundee" shit.
NATHAN: Exactly.
And the other two workers,
they got two knives.
And it's three on three.
BEEFY: What the hell happens?
NATHAN: What happens?
Oh, come on.
Use your imagination.
Why do think I'm only
eating the chips?
[LAUGHING]
BEEFY: [INAUDIBLE], man.
Is it true?
NATHAN: Yeah.
BEEFY: What?
NATHAN: No, I'm joking.
You should have seen
your face.
Oh, I should have held
it for longer.
Eat up.
[KNIVES CLANKING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]