HANS: Too bad.
COLIN FARRELL: Every now and
then, you read something and
it slaps you in the face.
It gets you by the back of the
head and slams you off a table
and gives you a kick
in the arse.
It just really takes you
on a wonderful ride.
MARTY: Oh, great.
You know what that it?
Do you know what that is?
HANS: Great.
MARTY: That's just
fucking great.
MARTIN MCDONAGH: I think the
tone is similar to "Bruges."
there's always a degree of
humor running through it.
COLIN FARRELL: "In Bruges"
was funny as fuck.
WOODY HARRELSON: Kind of proved
that he was capable of
not just writing, but really
being a great director.
He makes everybody feel,
you know, part
of something special.
SAM ROCKWELL: He knows exactly
what he wants.
He has a very particular visual
aesthetic, as well as
what he wants going
on emotionally.
CHARLIE: Don't give me that
moany fucking face, OK?
MARTY: Ow!
MARTIN MCDONAGH: This was almost
like a puzzle, like a
gigantic kind of jigsaw.
BILLY: Don't get technical
on me.
MARTIN MCDONAGH: The canvas is
pretty big and cinematic.
ABBIE CORNISH: It had a
comedic edge to it.
BILLY: Who's better than you?
MARTY: Who's better than you?
MARTY: You're better than me.
BILLY: You're gorgeous.
BILLY: You're the best
I ever known.
BILLY: I wanna jump
inside your pants.
SAM ROCKWELL: There's a
lot of hijinks with
me, Woody, and Colin.
And then me, Chris, and
Colin have to do a
lot of stuff together.
That was a lot of fun.
WOODY HARRELSON: There's
a lot of camaraderie.
But Chris Walken, he's
a fucking legend.
To be able to get up there and
do a scene with Chris Walken--
I just was in heaven.
MARTY: You ain't gonna fight.
What are you gonna do, then?
HANS: Guess I'm gonna die.
MARTY: Friends don't make
their friends die, Hans.
HANS: Psychopathic friends do.
CHRISTOPHER WALKEN: You know,
the thing about movies is that
they're always a surprise.
The other night, we were
shooting a scene out there in
the desert, and this enormous
owl flew right over the set.
For hours, this big owl just
kept floating around.
You're not likely to see that
unless you're making a movie.
COLIN FARRELL: I've never met
anyone like him in my life.
He's so just brilliant.
BILLY: Fucking badass, man.
SAM ROCKWELL: Who--
who do you like?
Who do you like better?
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
COLIN FARRELL: The Irish guy's
interesting, isn't he?
The Irish guy's interesting.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
SAM ROCKWELL: Very undervalued
actor, that Irish kid.
CHRISTOPHER WALKEN: I didn't
you were gonna do that.
MARTIN MCDONAGH: This one has
got a lot of tenderness and a
big human story at its heart.
BILLY: It's about seven
fucking psychopaths.
HANS: I want to know what
happens at the end.
SAM ROCKWELL: Well, I don't know
if I should reveal that.
That's kind of a plot point.
HANS: Fuck 'em.