DAN SANTORO: I did a gecko and
I started shading outside of
it because I did
the line work.
And then I jumped
onto the shader.
And I had lime green.
And let's say this
is the gecko.
I wasn't looking and I
just went like this.
And just the way I was
stretching, I thought this was
inside the gecko.
So I just started whip-shading
lime green.
And then I pulled my hand away
and there was this giant green
whip shade marks.
And they guy didn't
see it, though.
So I was like, yo, man.
You know what would
look real cool?
If this thing was sitting
on some leaves.
And he was like, yeah.
I was like, I'm not going
to charge you, man.
He's like, yeah, I'd
love some leaves.
So I just put a big
leaf there.
BERT KRAK: Dan has a very
distinct style that, usually,
when you see it, you can
tell it's his own.
Dan's approach is
just different.
And it's unique.
We're all special.
Dan's just a little extra
special, you know?
He's into, obviously,
tattooing, music--
DAN SANTORO: The new
Inquisition record.
This is the shit, right here.
BERT KRAK: He's into painting.
And that's with brushes
or aerosol.
He's also into collecting
and antiquing.
Oh, he's extremely
well-rounded.
DAN SANTORO: It's confusing.
It's a cultural identity
issue.
I'm almost overly exposed
to things.
I have so many friends
that are into so
much interesting stuff.
And I've manage to find merit
in almost everything.
Luckily, I've really kind of
cultivated what I like the
most about things that I like.
And I've kind of made it work.
The shop I work at now is Smith
Street Tattoo Parlour.
STEVE BOLTZ: There's four
of us working at
Smith Street Tattoo.
It's me, Bert Krak, Eli
Quinters, and Dan Santoro.
Me, Eli, and Bert opened the
place sort of together, and
then Dan joined us about
a year later.
But Dan was always
in the plan.
Dan was like our fourth guy.
DAN SANTORO: I was at Adorned.
And at the time that Smith
Street was even a twinkle in
any of their eyes, I
was around a lot.
I was spending a lot
of time at Steve's.
A lot of nights, get off work,
hop on the train, go over to
Steve's, have a couple cold
boys, some painting.
So around that time, Steve had
mentioned something that he
was walking his dog in the
neighborhood and he saw this
storefront that looked like it
had been vacant for some time.
And how he thought it was a
really cool block, right by
the train, and all this
stuff like that.
And he said he was going
to look into it.
I was scared to say
yes at first.
I didn't know Smith Street
was going to be as
amazing as it is.
I mean, I should have known.
But I didn't.
And I thought about it
for like a week.
And then I was like,
you know what?
I'm just going to do it.
I'm pretty impulsive
and whatever.
So I'm just going to do it.
It's just one of those things
where the planets aligned for
Smith Street.
We were all friends.
Dream situation for me, working
with these guys.
BERT KRAK: This is 100%
our clubhouse.
I never feel, driving here
from Queens, like
I'm going to work.
I always feel like I'm coming
here to hang out with my
friends and have a good time.
DAN SANTORO: I think Eli's
closer to Steve.
And me and Bert, I think, might
be a little similar.
We exchanged birthday tattoos.
We have the same birthday.
So we actually did little Cancer
crabs on each other on
one of our birthdays.
Bert absolutely loves
the fact that we're
born on the same day.
He brings up about
once a week.
BERT KRAK: I was born
July 12, '77.
I believe he's July 12, '83.
I'm very much a Cancer.
So is he.
You know, hard on the outside,
soft on the inside.
We're both really sensitive.
It wouldn't take much to really
ruffle our feathers.
No, there was already
graffiti, dude.
DAN SANTORO: Of course, but yo--
but there's not already
tags all over the fucking
walls in here.
All right, we're not having
a fucking moral
conversation right now.
It's the dumbest shit ever.
STEVE BOLTZ: Before Dan
came on, I was kind
of the loose cannon.
Because I'm a little
bit messy.
I definitely can be
a loud mouth.
And, maybe in a different way,
Dan's now the loose cannon.
He's just a pathological
thinker, you know?
DAN SANTORO: I don't know.
It's like when you go to Walmart
and you see the old
lady with the puffy, pink,
patch sweatshirt.
You know the feeling you get?
That's how I feel sometimes
when people bring certain
tattoos in.
I really want to give
it to them.
And I want to make
it really good.
All right.
So I get a phone call.
And this woman's like,
we have this woman.
She wants to get tattooed.
I think she got--
I think it was Charlie Brown,
if I'm not mistaken.
And she's going like, aargh.
And she's shaking her leg.
Within three lines, the
tattoo is so fucked.
So I was just like--
dude.
It was like being on a ride.
I was just like.
And I did it.
ELI QUINTERS: Nothing's ever
set in stone with Santoro.
Dan seems to be definitely
the least
organized out of everybody.
STEVE BOLTZ: Dan also has the
same mentality, as far as
that's our job and
making tattoos.
But Dan just does everything
by the seat of his pants.
And I think that the whole
seat-of-the-pants or
unpreparedness or whatever, I
think he subconsciously is
that way on purpose.
The way he tattoos, there's
a lot of confidence.
And even very simple, clunky
tattoos just look so good.
ELI QUINTERS: He's one of
my favorites, for sure.
It's traditional, real
stripped-down, real bare bones.
I would say he's a little
looser than maybe I am.
I really try to do a very exact
line and everything.
And he recently moved
me away from that.
He's made me loosen up a lot.
I think he's kind of got a lot
of what Dan Higgs had in that
he knows just how to put down a
line and just do the tattoo.
And it comes out--
I don't know.
It looks great.
He can make something look
pretty and delicate and all
those things, but they
still have that
Santoro look to them.
BERT KRAK: Me and Dan,
we do a lot of really
kind of bold tattooing.
But it doesn't mean
that Eli and Steve
can't do the same thing.
We're a team.
DAN SANTORO: Almost every tattoo
that gets done, good or
bad, we show off
to each other.
I think that's a really
good thing.
I've worked in shops where I
couldn't even tell you the
last tattoo I saw of an
artist for months.
You know what I mean?
You just kind of work in your
little corner of the shop,
finish a tattoo, put a bandage
on it, see you later.
There's no fun in that.
I mean, I want to see it.
I want to see what
you're doing.
I want to see if you did
something that maybe I
should've been thinking about.
We bite the hell out of each
other, but it's cool.
We work together.
That's why we're there.
FERGUS SIMMS: These guys are
just doing the best of the
tattoos around, in my opinion.
It's the best shop in the world
by far, for the style
especially.
We've been planning this
trip for a while
from Melbourne, Australia.
I don't know.
We saved up for six, seven
months or so, and then bought
tickets and came.
We haven't done too much
tourist stuff yet.
We've just kind of been
sitting in the shop.
I think we're up to 11
now, and then got a
couple more on Tuesday.
So this one's from Steve.
And from Dan.
This one's from Dan as well--
cool little cat.
Got the dagger skull from Dan
and little crying hema heart
from Dan as well.
And that one's from Steve.
STEVE BOLTZ: It's just like a
kind of a special thing at
Smith Street because we all do
anything, but we all basically
do the same thing, too.
And people don't necessarily ask
or say, that looks like a
Steve Boltz tattoo or a Bert
Krak tattoo so much anymore as
they might say, that looks like
a Smith Street tattoo.
And I hear that and I love it.
If you come to the shop and
I'm not there, you're not
afraid to sit in Dan's chair
or Eli's chair because you
know that you're going to get
basically the same product.
We very consciously want our
tattoos to look a certain way.
And New York is part of that.
New York's a very
straightforward approach to living.
There's no fucking around.
And I think in tattooing, maybe
there's a similar thing
whereas it's a very
straightforward look to
tattoos as opposed to it being
fancier or more artistic.
Hey, we want our tattoos
to look classic.
We don't want them
to look dated.
And when somebody comes and
wants an owl on their chest,
it's like, why don't you
just get a fucking
eagle on your chest?
Why do you got to get an owl?
The technical application
is what will make a
tattoo slick, to me.
It's a good thing to just be
able to give somebody a nice
solid, clean, predictable
tattoo.
That's a good thing.
And even if it's a tattoo that
50 people have, its new and
it's original because you have
to put your hand to it.
ELI QUINTERS: We're all really
going for the tattoo style.
We want our tattoos to
look like tattoos.
When you're a little kid and you
think about what a tattoo
is, the first thing for myself
and I think a lot of people
that popped into their head are
the anchors like Popeye
had, or even a Mom heart
or something like that.
Just something that would almost
be represented in a
cartoon, so to speak.
What you picture in your head
when somebody says the word
"tattoo" is usually some sort
of tattoo imagery, not some
no-outline, color
portrait thing.
You know what I mean?
So, I mean, I think
that's probably
unifying in that terms.
We use a bold outline and
a lot of black shading.
We have a lot of the same
reference material.
Tattooing is an art and its
form is this traditional,
almost sailor-style tattooing.
DAN SANTORO: I guess maybe I
started tattooing late enough.
There was still enough going on
with people wanting to do
traditional stuff that
I was like, OK.
I know I want my tattoos to
look like that, but how?
And then I was finding the Dan
Higgs tattoos that were in
"Tattoo Time."
"Tattoo Time" was a publication
that Ed Hardy put
of from early '80s probably to
the early '90s that had the
weirdo art section.
And they were just really
strange tattoos, but they
still had that traditional
application that I was looking
for in anything, really.
I'd see tattoos and not really
know why I liked them.
But I knew I just liked them.
And then I'd realize down
the road, oh, it's
because they're bold.
And they're simple.
[JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING]