It's not going to matter what
TV show says I'm a bad
influence on youth.
It's really about continuing to
just follow my dreams and
passions, be myself,
and share my voice.
I was in college.
And I was working six,
seven days a week.
And if I was by myself, not
studying, I was probably
watching porn.
And it was like, yeah, I like
it, and yeah, I can get off.
But I felt like there was a
creative component missing.
And I also had different
ideas of what sex was.
And I felt sick--
you know what I mean?
I felt sick to my stomach.
I'm like, I'm not supposed
to think this way.
I was the oldest out
of all my friends
to lose their virginity.
I was 16 and a half.
I know that's funny.
But I was a senior
in high school.
I kind of had this very
male-driven mentality, like, I
don't want to love a boy
to have sex with him.
And at the same time, I was
so conflicted internally.
Like, I didn't know how do I go
about doing that and just
feel safe and feel like
I'm in control?
So for me, getting in the
business was a way to continue
exploring those things safely.
But then also, I kind of just
had this awakening.
And I started to really
understand the sexual
revolution that I
so idealized.
It doesn't matter what you
say to your parents.
No parent wants their
kid doing porn.
I didn't tell them until I had
been here for two weeks.
Because, like, I want to get
down there, and get started,
and then tell them.
And my mom is Catholic.
So that's where the
guilt comes from.
And my dad was just like,
follow your goals
and don't fuck up.
And it was all in the subtext,
like, I'm going to be really
fucking disappointed if you
fuck up, and do something
stupid, and make the
wrong mistakes.
I showed a series of photos to
my literary agent in 2007.
And I had been taking
photographs onset to just
document my environment
each day.
And they were just, like,
for me to look back
on when I was older.
For me, it was about
self-examination in these
self-portraits.
Some of them look more like
a documentary-style photo.
But they were completely
conceived of.
And it's funny, because you
could say, no, that's totally
candid, right?
No, it's not.
Or this totally looks like
something post-sex.
No, it's not.
I think what, for me, is kind of
important is that it leaves
people guessing.
I think it shows misconceptions
about the adult
industry that don't apply
to everybody.
Right now I'm really focusing on
proving myself as an actor.
So while going out and looking
for roles, the thing that
keeps me really going, and
driven, and motivated is when
I'm not working.
Because that's when you
want it the most.
And that's when you're hungry.
And that's when you want to
stand up and fucking scream
and say, I can do this.
So my friend and our writing
partner, Anthony, is coming
into town today.
And we're going to have a
three-day writing workshop.
So it's really about creating
opportunities for myself.
2006.
Our band, aTelecine, started
making music, and we ended up
putting it on MySpace
without my name.
People liked it.
So we were, like, well, OK.
What happens when we put Sasha
Grey as part of it?
And of course, that helped
us get our deal
with Pendu and Dais.
I can't sing, but I sing.
I can't play a cool
Sabbath song on
guitar, but I play guitar.
You know what I mean?
It's just pure fun.
And it became really
cathartic.
I love Throbbing Gristle,
Current 93, Joy Division,
Parliament-Funkadelic, NWA.
This is what I played this
morning before you guys came.
Oh, yeah.
This one is really good.
It's a live Crosby, Stills,
Nash & Young.
I'm pretty sure somebody did
cocaine off of the back of
this, because there are
literally razor marks on the
back of this.
DAVID CHOE: Hey.
How's it going?
SASHA GREY: Good to see you.
(BRITISH ACCENT) Thank you for
watching Granada Television.
Without further ado--
oh, wait, sorry.
This is Vice, right?
I don't think this guy needs
an introduction.
This is Dave Choe.
INTERVIEWER: How do you
guys know each other?
DAVID CHOE: That actually
involves
our friend over there.
SASHA GREY: James wanted
to paint me,
because he liked my work.
DAVID CHOE: Your work?
That's a very interesting--
SASHA GREY: It's a very
diverse body of work.
DAVID CHOE: I went out
with Sasha once
to the Machete premiere.
And so every single person
was like, hey!
I love your work in Entourage.
And I was like, wait.
So what did they say before
you were in, like,
movies and TV shows?
And they're like, oh,
I love your work.
SASHA GREY: People, they
want to say it.
But they're so polite
about it.
Because I look like I'll
kick someone's ass?
DAVID CHOE: I have a radio
station upstairs.
So we'll do, like,
a real interview.
This is a radio show
that I have that's
broadcast to nowhere.
You'll probably hear this after
the world's exploded.
So is it true, this
whole journey?
You're very determined.
You knew, at a very young
age, porn, this is
what I want to do.
And you said, I wasn't going
to do it forever.
Then you got out.
Now you're doing movies,
TV shows.
The bottom line for
all of this is--
tell me if this is true.
You're working, doing all this
stuff to ultimately own a
blow-dry salon in Las Vegas?
Is that true?
That's the golden--
SASHA GREY: That was
my master plan.
DAVID CHOE: That's the golden
pot at the end of the rainbow?
SASHA GREY: Ah, yes.
Because all I care
about is hair.
DAVID CHOE: Probably one of
the best painters I know,
James Jean.
We were painting her naked
in Highland Park.
And you were rocking a pretty
big bush back then.
SASHA GREY: Still am.
DAVID CHOE: You brought
that back, right?
SASHA GREY: I don't know if I
single-handedly brought it back.
DAVID CHOE: I think a lot of
your appeal is that you look
like such a nice girl that could
be, like, a model for
Victoria's Secret
or something.
And then you always imagine--
SASHA GREY: Without the boobs?
DAVID CHOE: You got
nice boobs.
SASHA GREY: Oh, I
like my boobs.
DAVID CHOE: I mean, you
don't look like
most porn stars, basically.
And you were doing super, like,
violent, crazy shit.
SASHA GREY: See, violence is
the way you like to put it.
DAVID CHOE: I don't know.
How would you put that?
SASHA GREY: No, I mean,
I don't think I
feel the way you feel.
And I think a lot of
people expect me--
DAVID CHOE: Some of your movies
were, like, borderline
snuff films, I think.
This is the mask I wore in
Coachella for Die Antwoord's
American debut.
[COMPUTER VOICE]
SASHA GREY: Ugh!
My head is bigger than Dave's.
[COMPUTER VOICE]
SASHA GREY: Shut up!
DAVID CHOE: Now that you're not
doing porn, do you feel
like there's something
missing?
Like, you're like, damn, I used
to do fucking gangbangs
and all this shit, and now--
SASHA GREY: No, I think it's
more about a new way of
discovering sex, because there's
no camera there.
And I think you get so used to
having a camera watching you.
And that's part of what
makes it exciting.
So now it's about finding out
ways to make it that exciting.
DAVID CHOE: What
are these ways?
Explain.
I want to know these ways.
SASHA GREY: It's less about
exactly what you're doing, and
more about the adrenaline
rush that you get.
DAVID CHOE: Has it had a real
negative effect for what you
want to do now?
Because I mean, people compare,
like, oh, it's Sasha
and Jenna Jameson are the two
that made it out of this.
But yeah, the internet exists.
And that will stay
with you forever.
So you are trying out for,
like, mainstream
movies and TV shows.
Has that caught up to you to
the point where people say
fucked up shit to you?
SASHA GREY: No.
Nobody will ever say anything
to your face.
I think right now it's
about proving that
I'm not just lucky.
Because that's a way a lot
of people perceive
it as, she's lucky.
She got these chances.
And any porn star could
have done it.
So it's about proving
that I can go way,
way, way beyond that.
I mean, sex and money are the
two oldest professions.
And they've always been
part of society.
And they've always been part
of art in a huge away, even
before video, or even
before films.
DAVID CHOE: Anything else you
want to say about whores or
married sex life?
SASHA GREY: Your blanket
looks like it came
out of a crack den.
DAVID CHOE: Yeah.
SASHA GREY: I don't know where
you got this thing.
DAVID CHOE: This is my
spot, right here.
SASHA GREY: You just want to
put the blanket over the--
DAVID CHOE: That's
my glory hole.
That's, like, you know.
I don't like to be touched
during sex.
I need to be under
a lot of fabric.
That's my weird shit
that I'm into.
SASHA GREY: You'd probably
like latex, then.
DAVID CHOE: Yeah.
I like latex.
I like masks.
I like hiding.
SASHA GREY: That's fun.
DAVID CHOE: Hit it as
hard as you can.
[CRASH]
[DRUMMING]