Evan and Cappie got into a fight that
night that ended their friendship.
We were all friends again,
why'd you have to screw it up?
Hey, you screwed it up!
Why are Cappie and Evan
still fighting?
Because of you.
They both fell for the same girl.
Picking something I hate
just to pick.
Welcome, truthseekers.
Why are we here?
There's nothing
happening between us.
So if I did anything to make you think
otherwise, then I'm really, really sorry.
She's not going to declare
our house a historical landmark.
It either has to be fixed up
or it'll have to be torn down.
- Lasker's buying the house.
- We're saved!
The attacks on KT, it
all started rush night, right?
Maybe young Mr. Parkes
is our Villain X.
- What's that?
- It's nothing.
Our house was built
in the Spring of 1916
and originally held 20 members
and cost $36,000 to construct.
It has seen over 15 changes
to its structure,
twelve of which were
intentional.
And now it's about to see
its most extensive one to date.
Yep, thanks to my dad,
Mr. Saving the Day... Man.
I need to work on my insults.
Hey, Cap.
Good luck on your finals!
Gee, thanks, Peter!
I don't trust that kid.
And it's not just because
of his shifty eyes.
Well it's a little bit
his shifty eyes.
I really don't think
Peter is Villain X.
He just has family issues.
And shifty eyes.
Regardless, we have
more pressing matters.
We have to be out of here
by tomorrow night
so Lasker's guys
can start the renovations.
And get our house GPA
up to a 2.0.
Which is something I want
to talk to you about.
I have one more final left.
Well, it's not so much
a final as it is a
philosophical rumination and
oration on life and the history of
the universal perception.
How do we not have a 2.0?
And since you're done
with your finals,
I was thinking maybe while I'm
preparing to orate,
you could be
substitute president.
We have a lot to do around here,
I could really use the help.
- Yes, Yeah, Yes.
- Yeah?
President Russell Alan
Cartwright. Substitute.
Hey, Case.
What's up with your arm?
Nothing.
Look at this, I found
an article on the razing
of a historic pre-World War I
building.
I know Segal's
going to want that.
- Evan.
- Yeah?
I'm sorry he asked me to be his
research assistant and not you.
OK, well, he wants me
to help too.
He's telling the truth, the whole truth, and
nothing but the truth, Miss Cartwright.
I need you both.
What happened to your arm?
Oh, it's nothing.
- Uh-huh.
- What's going on?
Well, the university
has been developing
some expansion plans
for some time now
and they want to break ground as early as
next semester on a new athletic center.
Are they expanding
into a puppy shop?
Sort of. See, your mock trial
case was never that mock.
CRU is acquiring some properties,
a few vacated residences
and a blighted fraternity house, which
they plan to tear down in two days.
- A blighted fraternity house?
- Yeah, Lambda Sigma.
Oh, thank God.
Wait, nope, that's the safe
one. It's Kappa Tau Gamma.
- What?
- Uh...
I think what she means is,
what would you like us to do?
You're both so good forecasting
opposing strategy during the mock trial,
I want you to put yourselves
in this fraternity's shoes.
Think about what they might try
to pull to prevent the university
from tearing their house down.
But, Professor Segal, that is
my boyfriend's fraternity.
And my brother's.
I don't think I can do this.
Don't think you can
do your job?
How do you think your colleagues and
future professors are going to react
to you no longer being my assistant
because of your boyfriend's fraternity?
You'd fire me?
The choice is yours.
This is important to
the university and to me.
If you want to be successful, it needs
to be important to you too. Both of you.
Sync by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
OK, you know what?
This is insane.
I mean, we can't be a part of the research
team that destroys Kappa Tau, right?
Why not? I mean, look, it sounds like it's
going to happen with or without us, right?
And KT's a sinking
ship, it's inevitable.
OK, but KT means
so much to Cappie.
Not to mention Rusty.
OK, well, how much does
your future mean to you?
But they'd never forgive me.
I'm going to tell them.
All right, well do what you
want. Just lea6e me out of it.
Come on, Evan. There isn't there
some small part of you
that still cares about Cappie?
Why can't you just let it go?
Because I'm not interested
in pissing off Segal,
or the university
for some stupid fraternity.
You pledged that
stupid fraternity.
Yeah, and that was in the past.
Since when did Casey Cartwright
stop thinking about her future?
Peter mentioned his dad was investing
in more land around the KT house.
Now why would Lasker Parkes
Incorporated buy up all these lots?
Maybe it's not just renovation,
but expansion.
Maybe you guys
are getting a pool!
Hey, working girl.
Hello, boys.
Sorry I can't dawdle,
but Clarissa and I are
checking out our new offices,
so I better start my commute,
maybe get a latte on the way
in my on-the-go to-go mug.
Well, I'm psyched for you.
Thanks. It feels good. I was
kinda adrift there for a while.
Me, too. But... hey, big news.
I've finally
picked out a major.
- What is it?
- Really?
Yeah. Uh, accounting!
Oh.
No, it's good.
It's practical, you know?
The business sector is robust.
Not recession-proof but...
And you love it. Right?
Yeah, I mean, yeah, you know,
I will. I do.
- Yeah!
- OK. So, yay!
Ashleigh, before you leave,
I got you a little something.
It's for your office,
so everybody knows your name.
You hate it?
No, I love it.
It's just so...
...grown-up serious.
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
- OK, bye.
- Bye.
You still like her.
I like giving her presents.
Big deal.
Oh my gosh, wait,
you gave her that taxicab not-rape whistle
when she went to New York, right?
How long have you had
these feelings for Ashleigh?
Well, it doesn't matter 'cause
nothing's ever gonna happen.
I'm sorry, man.
Whatever. It's just...
you know, it's stupid.
I'm stupid.
To even think...
whoa, wait, oh my God.
- What?
- I don't think KT's getting a pool.
Vince lavaliered Betsy
last night!
He hid it in her chili dog!
I almost choked and died.
It was so worth it!
What a waste of
a perfectly good chili dog.
Hey!
Happy couples make me sick.
True dat.
My second cousin Barry
got married last weekend.
He hadn't left the house
in five years.
So why am I hard up right now?
If he can find
Mrs. Barry Kettlewell...
Well, look at me.
An extremely hot ZBZ president,
and I'm totally dateless.
I couldn't make it last with
Cappie or Evan. Or a girl.
Girls aren't any easier.
I've been dumped
by a landlord and Laura.
You don't think we're
the problem, do you?
Hey. Remember that terrible
Matthew McConaughey film?
Sahara ? Ed TV?
The Wedding Planner?
Failure to Launch?
How to Lose a Guy in Ten Days?
- Fool's Gold?
- No.
Ghosts of Girlfriends Past.
He revisited his exes
and learned what went wrong.
Forget it.
Fine.
Ooh!
Oh Crap! Hey, sorry.
Better tell Lasker we're
gonna need a new TV.
Hey, Cap, I got really bad news.
You broke the flat screen?
Plug that in,
it might still work.
- Oh!
- Sorry.
This is gonna be
the easiest move ever.
OK, um...
Hey, guys, I have
really bad news.
- You broke the bottle tank?
- Well my news is a lot worse.
Trust me it pales in comparison
to what I'm going to say to you.
- You can't just walk in here...
- Do not shoot the messenger...
Kids!
This is why daddy drinks.
OK, I was researching Lasker
Parkes Incorporated
and I found some geological
surveys of our area
and I think he's buying up
land around us
because we're sitting on oil.
Lasker Parkes
is buying up land?
- For oil.
- No, it's not for oil.
He's donating the land to the university,
because they want to build an athletic center.
And... they're going to tear
down your house to do it.
They're going to tear us down?
- Lasker?
- Yeah.
Well, he... He knew about
our secret rush party,
and our fake philanthropy.
Hell, he created Joshua Whopper.
- Lasker is Villain X.
- Are you sure about this?
Segal put Evan and me on the
university's legal research team.
Oh. Well, are you staying on?
Cap, this is my future.
It's just research.
Research that they're using to
help tear down our house.
I'm so sorry. I...
I get it. I'll handle
our side of things.
Hey, what are you going to do,
Spitter?
- Good one, Cap.
- No, I'm serious.
I have my philosophy final to worry about
and you're acting president, so...
So what? First of all, it's
an oration, it's not a final.
Second, since when
do you care about grades?
I'm gonna worry about
the house GPA, I'm the nerd.
But you've been wanting to take the reigns
since the beginning of the semester.
But this isn't saving parties
or stealing goats.
If we lose our house, Nationals
said they'll shut us down.
You're the president.
You are KT.
You're the only one
who can do this.
Cap...
Well, I guess I'm the only one.
We should get,
like a million balloons,
and tie them to the house,
and move it.
I think I saw it on 20/20 once.
Yeah, I saw that episode.
It totally worked.
What did old 90210 do
to save the Peach Pit?
Maybe we should try something
a little more in the box.
The house is a box...
I'm so sorry, guys.
I had no idea. I swear.
We believe you. Right, Cap?
You can't blame Luke Skywalker
for being Darth Vader's son.
- Spoiler alert.
- Hey, maybe you can talk to your dad?
Change his mind?
About business? No way.
I don't get it. All I heard growing
up was how awesome KT was.
Clearly, he doesn't
feel that way anymore.
That's it! What if Lasker Parkes
forgot what it's like to be a KT?
Yeah, like, he has
amnesia or something.
Maybe he hit his head a long time ago, and
we just need to hit him on the head again!
Or... maybe he just forgot
what brotherhood means.
And we need to remind him.
Nostalgia is a powerful thing.
So, did your dad keep
any of his old KT stuff?
Pictures, pledge paddles...
inflatable dolls?
The only fraternity stuff of his
I've ever seen are in his office.
- We're going to need 'em.
- I can't go in without him noticing.
There's serious security.
Corporate spying,
tech theft's a big issue.
Well, it's about to
get even bigger...
Pledge Spidey, bring
me the action figures...
...and the Barbies, too!
We're gonna need 'em all.
After you.
Not bad.
Yeah, it looks like all fun and games...
bought with blood money.
Relax. Nobody's dying.
And how would you feel if it was the Omega
Chi house being torn down, Evan Bacon?
What?
It's like Kevin Bacon, but like
Ev... you know how... Yeah.
My two star pupils.
- A pleasure to meet you both.
- We are ready to get to work.
Have you had lunch?
I thought we'd hit one of our organic cafes.
Ooh. Sorry about your arm.
What happened?
- Ah, nothing.
- This way.
Welcome to Laskerplex.
This enchanting world of productivity
and technological advancement...
Oh, you know who should work
here? Rusty!
Ah, you know who should move out
of his apartment? You.
He really likes you. He has
apparently for some time.
Yeah, well, I like him too.
Then why don't you just go
out with him?
Casey made me promise that I
wouldn't unless I was a 100% sure.
Maybe I'm just gonna hurt him.
Being in his life so much
might be hurting him more.
Happy to be at Laskey.
Woo-woo!
With over 300 beanbags
company-wide.
- I gotta go to the bathroom.
- I have to go, too.
We'll just wait here.
Do not go in there. Somebody's
got IBS and real bad aim.
I'm afraid you'll have to hold
it 'til we reach the lap pools.
- It's lady business.
- I might explode.
Fine, the executive wing is
this way.
You'll find the restroom
on your left.
Don't talk.
Or make eye contact.
Please be a sweetie
and wipe the seatie.
Have I told you about our
house rabbit adoption center?
This coffee is so good, but
how do you know that it's organic?
Well, I picked these beans
myself.
Oh!
It's just, how do
you find the time?
- That was a joke.
- It's a joke.
- Ready to save the day?
- I think Cappie is the hero here.
You could've handled all this,
Rus.
I don't see why you
gave up the presidency.
Hey, If I get caught with this ID, your
dad's going to be pretty pissed at you.
- You sure you're good with that?
- It's my house too.
- Uh, could you take o picture?
- Oh, of course, sir.
- Photos aren't allowed.
- Thanks.
Oh, wow.
Perfect.
Lost a contact. Sorry.
Is that the same girl
that you went in there with?
- Of course she is.
- What?
That's definitely the same girl
whom I've never met before.
Quickly this way people.
Like baby birds.
I'm the momma let's do this.
I'm totally serious. I was told Mr. Parkes
is screaming for you in Conference Room Fauna.
And I'm supposed to
cover your phones.
Not again.
I'll be right back.
- Well done.
- Oh, Thanks. Go, I'll sit guard.
Well, It should be smooth
sailing, Mr. Parkes.
You own the property, you have
all the necessary permits.
The law's completely
on your side.
But I'm more concerned
about unlawful activists.
What are we up against?
Knowing KT, they'll probably try tying a million
balloons to the house and float it away.
What about you, Miss
Cartwright? What do you think?
Well, I'd imagine there will be
some kind of protest rally.
They could contact the school
paper, or local news stations.
However, per Rardin v. O'Toole,
they'd be trespassing.
You know you own that land, you
could have them forcibly removed.
Sorry, my assistant is not
at her desk, which is strange.
And a little unacceptable. I'm gonna
run up to the office. Excuse me, guys.
God, he's going to
be up here any second.
- Bingo.
- Yes!
Hillary?
Oh my God, go!
Yeah, It's Lasker, where is my
assistant? Lasker.
Lasker Parkes,
how many Lasker's are there?
They're like robots,
or Terminators,
sent from the future to destroy
our house without any remorse.
- I'm one of 'they'.
- But you are 'you',
Even though you're part of
'they', they're the 'they'.
I hate helping 'they'.
Well, you're pretty good at it.
Maybe a little too good.
I don't want to be good at
something like this,
that I don't agree with
or believe in.
I know how much
the house means to you.
There's something else
we need to talk about.
What's this?
Over the past five years I took
so many different classes
and had so many different
majors. I kinda lost track.
And, this letter explains
that, um...
...I can graduate.
This semester.
You accidentally graduated?
That's great!
Or is it?
Well, I was waiting to surprise
you, and to see if I passed
but now, I'm not so sure
if I can.
Because of the fraternity.
I thought Rusty could
take over. I don't get it.
- I think he's scared.
- So am I,
but that's not going to save KT.
I mean, that house...
it's kinda where I grew up.
You have grown-up.
Right now I feel like the only
person who can save it.
If I go, so does Kappa Tau.
It's funny. I've spent
most of college
feeling like the KT house
was the 'other woman',
knowing I'd have to share you.
If this doesn't work out
tomorrow...
...tonight's her last night.
I get it.
Go to her.
Thank you.
So, I got an e-mail from Robin.
She claims we didn't work out
because I'm not a lesbian.
Despite your masculine energy.
Which leaves me with Cappie,
who's way busy with Kappa Tau.
And Evan, who I'm
saving for last.
Kind of dreading that one.
Yeah, I'm saving Laura for last.
Or you could rip off the
Band-Aid.
OK. All right here we go.
- A little privacy?
- Right.
Ladies, could you excuse us?
OK.
What?
Why didn't we ever work out?
You don't like to sweat.
No, I mean...
like our relationship.
Did we even have a relationship?
- Never mind.
- Because I wish we did.
You do?
Oh, come on!
Spitter?
What are you doing here?
Probably the same
thing you are.
So I'm guessing you'll confront Lasker
tomorrow morning, at the protest.
You know, I'm not very proud
of the way that I backed out
as interim president.
I thought you wanted
to lead the house.
When I came to CRU, I didn't
know how to have fun.
Having Kappa Tau in my life
changed all that.
But without it, I'm just gonna
go back to being same old
nerdy Crusty Cartwright.
This house is way too important
for me to take over.
It's a good thing we're not
going to lose it then.
Guys?
We just thought it'd be fun to
get trashed here one more time.
One last round.
So, is this it?
We're coming to you live
from Cyprus-Rhodes University's
infamous Greek row, where a student
rally is taking place to save...
I'm disgusted by what they're trying
to do to you guys, Mr. Cappie.
Back up, knucklehead!
- Wade!
- What are you doing here?
KT forever!
And my parents finally kicked me
out of their basement,
so I'm looking for a place
to crash for a few weeks.
- So let's save this house!
- You got it, bud.
- So good to see you, buddy.
- Yeah, you too!
Whoa, check, here we go.
Hi, I'm Cappie.
President of Kappa Tau Gamma.
I just want to thank
every one of you for coming out
to support the preservation
of our beloved home.
Now this house is a time
capsule for many, many...
...many parties and personal
college stories.
Now, does anyone want to share
a KT story with us?
- Great, thank you.
- All right.
Hi, my name is Katherine Parker, I am former
Pan-Hellenic President and Gamma Psi alum.
Thank you. Thank you.
This house is especially important to me
because this is where I lost my virginity.
It was like two months ago!
So, how many of you guys lost
your virginity at this house?
Ok.
Does it matter which virginity
you lost?
Anyone else? Yes?
- Lisa Lawson.
- Hi.
OK. And how many of you
lost it to me?
Oh, my word.
- Ok.
- Thanks. Anyone else?
Oh all right, yes.
Hi. I'm Jennifer Kenney, Editor in Chief of
the Cyprus-Rhodes Courier.
Oh, you'll be happy to know
I took your advice.
Finally. Wow, Rus
is a really lucky guy.
Oh no, not that advice.
The moving out part.
I put down a deposit on an
apartment last night.
Oh, taking the safe road.
Uh, you should know.
Accounting.
When I was a freshman, I wrote
a scathing yet award-winning
indictment on the Greek system
that I have now come to regret.
In my article, I attacked the common practices
of this two- century-old tradition.
Hey, everyone. My name
is Lasker Parkes,
and I guess you could say I'm the
one responsible for all this.
All right, all right.
All children grow up.
Dad, please don't do this.
Son, it is just a house.
But it was your house, too.
Remember this?
Brother Falken?
Falken? Pretty big WarGames fan,
right?
You were in my office?
In WarGames, the nerd
got to be the hero.
Which isn't always the case.
- That's very informative, Rusty.
- The name's Spitter.
I'm a nerd, just like you.
And KT's accepted me,
just like they accepted you.
You can still be the hero here.
Doesn't the spirit of KT
mean anything to you?
Is this how you
want to be remembered?
Rusty, when you leave college,
this stuff doesn't go with you.
None of this matters.
This athletic center though...
...this will be my legacy.
Now, we're all going to miss
the KT house, including me.
But this is in the name of
making a better CRU, with a gym,
racquetball courts, an
Olympic sized swimming pool.
Oh really? Oh sweet!
So, not everyone is
opposed to this idea.
Now, I even have with me
two recent CRU grads,
the former presidents
of ZBZ and Omega Chi,
and they will explain to you why
this is a really good idea.
Miss Cartwright? You're up.
Say something.
No.
Casey, your legal career
hangs in the balance right now.
Look, I'm sorry, Professor.
But I don't want to be
remembered as the girl
who helped tear down
the Kappa Tau house.
It's all on you, Chambers.
Are you going to choose your
future or your friends?
Well, when you put it
like that...
Thanks.
OK.
Tear it down, guys.
♪ I still love you ♪
♪ After all ♪
♪ Please don't
leave me after all ♪
♪ After all ♪
♪ Till death do us part ♪
♪ I still love you ♪
♪ After all ♪
You know, you did
all you could.
Then why can't I help feeling
like I let the whole house down?
And after all we went through to
get that stupid paddle.
You were amazing, Rus.
Seeing you stand up
to Lasker like that?
You're not my geeky little brother who got
beat up by a sixth grader in high school.
She was an eighth grader.
And you heard Parkes.
Without Kappa Tau, I'm
basically back to geeky Rusty.
I don't believe that.
You've changed.
That old Rusty is gone for good.
You know...
You don't need me or anyone
to protect you anymore.
You can handle yourself.
I get that from you.
The way you stood up to your professor,
that was pretty incredible.
What?
So, what are you going to do
about law school now?
I have no idea.
But I did the right thing.
That's from you...
...Jiminy Cricket.
Come here.
That was pretty impressive, what
you did at the Kappa Tau rally.
You came here to tell me that?
No. I came here
to ask you a question.
Dale and I are doing this dumb
thing, so, I just wanted to ask:
Why exactly did you and I
not work out?
We couldn't work out
because I blew it.
You know, I screwed up,
putting law school ahead of you.
That's been something that's been
really hard for me to accept.
What do you think
happened to my hand?
- You got in a fight?
- With a wall.
For what it's worth,
it's a really tough wall.
It's Professor Segal.
You better get that.
Yeah.
Good luck.
Adios, KT.
It was good knowing you.
I see a lot of frowny faces!
Spitter, we're standing in
Greek ruins. Literally.
But you're still the president
of this house.
Not if there's no house
to be president of.
I'm so sorry, again, guys.
I'm sensing a lot more family
therapy after all this.
So Lasker grew into a bitter
nerd. So what?
But it doesn't have
to be that way.
He's a relic of the '80s.
It's his generation who
tells us the real world sucks
because they make it sucky.
But he was right
about one thing.
This was just a house.
Kappa Tau isn't one person.
Kappa tau isn't wood, it isn't
dry-rot, it isn't moldy wallpaper,
it isn't beer-soaked carpets.
It's living for the fun of life.
And that's what bonds us.
As long as we remember that,
Kappa Tau lives on,
past houses, past college.
So, what do we do now, Spitter?
Anybody who still has finals
to take... go study now.
We're gonna have to get our
GPA up going into next semester.
But where are we
gonna live then?
We can't sleep in tents
all winter.
In case you forgot,
this is Ohio.
I'm gonna find a new house over break.
A better one. With working toilets.
- Can I crash there?
- Absolutely!
No more moping around. Get up!
Let's go!
Spit-ter!
Spit-ter! Spit-ter!
Hey, what are you doing?
I haven't been in here
since I left for New York.
You know, this room
is crazy big.
Yeah.
I'm meeting Cappie at Dobler's,
if you want to come.
Nah, I'm good.
But, um, tell him
I'm sorry for his loss.
Oh, and when you see Rusty,
let him know that I thought it was pretty
cool how he stood up to Lasker like that.
It was, huh?
Um, I'll tell him you said so.
You know... I was wrong.
When I told you to be
careful with Rusty.
He's a lot stronger than I gave
him credit for.
You should've seen Rusty today.
You would've been proud.
I already am.
Hey, Crappie.
The name's Cappie.
And thanks for
your support today.
Yeah, well... you know, seeing
Casey make that choice.
And join you on the other side?
It helped me realize
what really matters.
Segal looked pissed, huh?
Oh, he wants to see us both.
I bet he does.
I guess it's time
to start groveling.
I'm not going to.
I don't want to have to
compromise what I believe in.
Law school, or defending Evil Corp
or Lasker Parkes, or whomever.
It's not me.
What am I supposed to do now?
Go to Washington,
no law degree? No plan?
Why the hell not?
Yeah... why the hell not?
I'll go with you.
I got one more final to pass,
then I can graduate.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
You can graduate?
- Accidentally.
- What?
- What about KT? - After today, I'm pretty
sure Rusty can handle it.
We'll figure it out together.
As it should be.
There's just one problem.
I've barely studied
for my last class.
- Then we should get going!
- Go!
- Are you...
- Yeah, yeah, go.
Bye!
♪ Have a drink,
the sky is sinking ♪
♪ Toward a deeper blue ♪
♪ And you're still all right ♪
- Hey.
- Hi.
So, you're moving out.
Couldn't live on the futon
forever, huh?
Yeah.
Well, I have a rule that
I don't date roommates.
It's kind of a new rule, since
I've only ever lived with girls.
Mostly your sister, and this
really big rat in New York.
Neither of whom I
wanted to date. But...
...now.
You want to date me?
♪ We are always living
in twilight ♪
Can you just wait two more minutes?
I know Cappie will be here any second.
'The only true wisdom is in knowing
you know nothing.' Socrates.
OK, well, Socrates didn't text.
I'm here! I'm here!
I'm sorry!
I overslept because
I was up all night preparing,
and then my house was torn down,
and I, I just, I need this
credit to graduate.
Class is over. I'm afraid
you have no more time.
But what is time?
I see you've been
paying attention.
OK... you can present.
For your final,
I just have one question.
Why?
Because you're lazy?
I'm just joking.
Well, the first thing you asked us at
the beginning of the semester was,
'Why are we here?'
Well, I thought about that.
A lot.
We all have a purpose.
And our purpose is to
figure out our purpose.
That's what college is.
So why college? Why CRU?
The truth is, I chose CRU because a
friend of mine from camp was going here.
Then I chose to rush a fraternity,
and I made new friends,
and college has been everything I
could've ever imagined it to be...
so I kept thinking,
why would I ever
want to leave this place?
But then I realized...
...that there's so much left
to learn, and experience,
and look forward to.
And now I'm graduating...
hopefully...
...and heading out into the real
world with the love of my life,
who was my purpose.
So, today, I'm here to graduate.
And tomorrow?
Well, that's har$ to say,
because I have no idea
where I'll be.
Nice hat.
This is your real name?
"Captain John Paul Jones"?
How did we never know that?
Congratulations, Cappie. This is
an emotional day for all of us.
I guess we should drink
to KT's newest alum.
Oh.
And to Calvin!
We're gonna miss you
next semester.
You're going abroad, right?
Going to help people.
Yeah, we leave for India the
first week of the new year.
Not playing it safe.
Hey.
Best way to play.
Dale lavaliered me!
I brought this here as well.
Oh, you didn't.
- And this!
- Oh my God!
They say that that if you sit
in it and it fits,
you're KT president.
Go ahead, try it out.
Do a test drive there.
Test it out.
Oh!
And the transfer of power
is complete!
You are my legacy, Spitter.
Here's to the new KT president.
Shots! Shots! Shots!
And to Cappie! The best...
Long live KT!
- Cheers.
Yeah!
I'm sorry I'm leaving again.
Well, I'm not
following you this time.
I have my own apartment,
my own job.
And a new relationship.
Take care of each other.
I can't believe you're
making me hire a new house mom.
Oh, I will miss the sorority.
And you.
I know.
♪ That I was only lookin out
for me ♪
♪ Instead of gettin you
the help you need ♪
♪ Who do you think you are? ♪
♪ Who do I think I am? ♪
Hey, we'll see you guys
at Christmas.
Love you.
- Bye.
- Hey, keep in touch, man.
- You too.
Thanks.
Case.
It arrived this morning.
And, since you were such an integral
part of us winning the Golden Lily,
I'd like to give it to you.
Oh my God, I couldn't possibly.
I said I'd like to,
not that I was going to.
Have a safe trip.
- Bye.
Well, Dale, this is it.
You could've been the
future Mrs. Dale Kettlewell.
- Never forget that.
- I won't.
Don't forget that either.
- Dale?
- Bye, buddy.
Take care of my sister for me,
OK?
I promise.
I love you, Casey.
I love you, too.
See you later.
You ready?
Yeah.
Bye, guys!
Take care.
So, um... where to?
Wherever you're going.
♪ I want to be forever young ♪
♪ Do you really
want to live forever ♪
Bye!
Sync by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
www.tvsubtitles.net