The 435i is lower, stiffer, and
generally sportier than
the 3 Series.
But the biggest news is probably
the name, which to me
is plain wrong.
It's like renaming Coca Cola,
Vegetable Bum Water.
Actually, it's not quite
that bad, as you know.
But you get the gist.
The 3 Series coupe was
a motoring staple.
It didn't need renaming.
After several aborted attempts
to record a [INAUDIBLE]
camera on the roads around
Lisbon, I'm resorting to
voice-over.
It just wasn't happening.
It's a man thing.
--434--
Please turn left
in 100 metres.
I need to be rid of you.
This is a curious car, because
at first it seems ridiculous
that a 306-horsepower BMW coupe
that will smash up to 62
miles an hour in 5.1 seconds,
could come across as a bit
uninteresting.
This one is at least fitted with
the optional 8-speed auto
which is, as I have to keep
saying, is plain brilliant.
Optional electric dampers ride
well in comfort, a little bit
spiky in spots.
The 435i is so fast and
discreet, you wonder if BMW
could have made it any more
ordinary looking--
except for those weird arrow
bits on the front wings, which
look like seals' ears.
The problem here is
a familiar one--
the 435i is so accomplished,
you wonder if it borders on
the boring.
So I wandered into the faded
glory of Estoril.
And couldn't really hide my
disappointment at the
normalness of it all.
I know the M4--
now that sounds completely
wrong to my ears--
will be the hot shoe, but a
300-horsepower, rear-drive BMW
should make you tingle
just a bit.
Shouldn't it?
The steering is quick, the car
changes direction beautifully,
the motor does that
BMW growly thing.
But it's just not
that enlivening.
Nor was the message from BMW.
The pre-track briefing
stipulated, no drifting.
Talk about red rag to a bull.
So here we are at Estoril.
Four laps.
And, curiously, in the briefing
at the end, no drifting.
I'm a bit like a 14-year-old
being told not to smoke, when
someone says, no drifting.
It's a bit, red rag to a bull.
So I'm going to try and resist
drifting, cause it's not big,
and it's not clever.
But this is a rear-wheel
drive BMW.
And what are rear-wheel drive
BMWs for, if not to kind of
play with the back of the car?
Isn't that the whole point?
Otherwise you just buy
an Audi, don't you?
I don't know.
We'll discuss that later on.
What have we got here then?
We have a strange car, because
this is 10,000 pounds more
than an M135i, and yet,
it has less torque.
So I'm not quite sure what
they're trying to do in
performance terms.
The chassis immediately
feels better balanced.
Longer wheelbase, everything
about it just feels a little
bit more grown up.
And I really like the
rear axle location.
The rear axle is far better
located in this car than it is
in the 1 Series.
It deals with this torque
without thinking about it.
Steering--
really nice and quick,
actually.
Very impressed by that.
Brake pedal-- firm.
Why am I doing this
on the track?
Who's going to come and do
a track in their 435i?
Not many people.
We're just on a normal
street tire.
But even so, the performance
of the car.
A few years ago, this would have
been just about bordering
on supercar performance.
It's incredible.
Transmission--
love this 8-speed ZF.
I know I crap on about it,
but it's just so good.
Matched with this turbo-charged
straight-six, it
works brilliantly, really
brilliantly.
Remember, no drifting
please, no drifting.
and I mean, no drifting.
[CAR ENGINE]
Okay, no drifting.
BMW, I mean, it's a bit like
leaving plates of cake out at
tea-time, and saying,
don't eat it.
Your cars are brilliant
at going sideways, so
I'm going to do it.
Morally wrong not to.
Really nice chassis.
I get the hint of what
an M3 might be like
now, it's pretty exciting.
Because this structure
is stiff.
Everything about it
is high quality.
Can a BMW be called
a 4 Series?
That's a philosophical
question.
That's a deeply philosophical
question, isn't it?
I'm not sure it can, actually.
I struggle with the
group four.
It doesn't sound quite
right to me.
[CAR ENGINE]
This guy has more performance
than most of the people that
buy it will ever need, OK?
It really does.
But--
and there is a "but" here, as
I cruise into the pit lane.
The "but," for me, is that
despite driving so well, and
being so fast, this is quite
an ordinary-feeling car.
You know?
It doesn't feel that special
to me at all.
Well over 40 grand in the UK.
Cabin is quite ordinary
3 Series.
The whole thing is
quite ordinary.
Leaves a lot of space
for the M3.
A lot of space for the M3.
And so, underneath all that
gloss and perfection, there
really is a very good
performance car.
One that keeps BMW well ahead
of its German rivals in this
particular sector.
And, as if to acknowledge the
fact that it might need some
added spice, BMW will be
offering a load M Performance
modifications as aftermarket
parts--
suspension, brakes, a locking
differential, and a power kit
that adds 34 horsepower, and
37 foot pounds of torque,
taking it back up to kind
of M135i levels of poke.
The only problem is, they
didn't let us drive one.
Just remember--
no drifting.
[CAR ENGINE]
[LAUGHTER]
[BEEP]
you.
Of course we're going to do
some drifting, you know?
I mean, it's a BMW, isn't it?