NACHOUM: I'm originally from Israel and about
30 years ago, I came to the United States
with the search of glory and who knows what
else. I really wanted to learn film and television.
I went to New York University and I was accepted
from 350 people that tried to get in, in 1980,
only 31 were accepted. Only later on I discovered
that the three instructor that was actually
checking us out or evaluate our ability, they
were Martin Scorsese, Francis Coppola and
Woody Allen. I did not know any of them. In
the 80, none of us know any of them, right?
Anyway, but that was a long story, that's
a long time ago, so I'll put this in perspective.
I want to drive a taxi. That's what most Israelis
or foreigner, and today it will be Indian
or Pakistanian, will do it. I want to drive
a taxi in New York for six months until eventually
I have enough money and I started a company.
And what I wanted to do really is involve
myself in the water and in underwater photography,
to tell the story about the ocean and what
I knew about the ocean. During the time that
I was driving a taxi, I was driving a taxi
at night and during the daytime, I was working
as a diving guide or divemaster at a dive
shop in New York City. How many diver we have
here? Beautiful. How many of you are photographer
also, holding a camera underwater? No, it
doesn't make any difference what camera. That's
okay. I started from there. That's okay. That's
perfectly all right. So if I speak fast, it's
only because I picked my English in New York
driving a taxi. So please forgive me. If my
accent is difficult, I don't believe you because
the 30% of Silicon Valley is all Israelis
anyway. So you already have been in business
with an Israeli one time or another. So to
make the long story short, what I'm here,
really, is to be able to share with you the
story and the privilege that America gave
me. I was privileged, or I am privileged perhaps,
and visited over 131 nations all around the
world, and believe me, there is no country
in the world like this country. No matter
how difficulty, no matter what the obstacles,
the challenges we have, there is no country
in the world and there is no Constitution
like we have in America. And no surprise,
we reached this level. I was able to master
what you're going to see now only because
either the country, the substance of this
country, the foundation and the people that
believe in my dream and participate and join
me. As a photographer, there are two ways
to go about it; either you go, you create
a portfolio, you send it to so many different
places to get work, or you go out and execute
your own vision, my own dream. I chose the
last one. I've chosen to work after my own
dream and make it available. However, in the
process, what became very clearly that institution,
like magazine, television stations and network,
were concerned that they were not able to
get their money's worth for my vision and
for my dream. So I went and I did it alone,
trusting that people like yourself or other
in America will join me, will participate
in what my dream is, because I'm not any different
than any one of you. We all have dreams. But
some of you and me, may have seen our dreams
and we can joint venture. So, I put my expertise
in the field. You put your expertise among
the pixels and all those nanotechnology. I
put it out in the big animals. So let's go
and see what I have in store for you. What
you're going to see today is anthology of
years and almost 30 years of having found,
pushing the envelope, photographing on the
edge of wilderness, comfort and common sense.
And I'm not saying that lightly. I desired
very much to come back again. And thank you,
Vivian, again for the opportunity to work
with people like yourself and to share because
you are on the edge of technology. Yes, you
have all the comfort in the world, but you're
putting--you're pushing the envelope in what
you do and that is fascinating. How we connect
some of the elements in your life, some of
the elements of my life, and some of the elements
of somebody else and get--make a better life.
And the idea in my view and my presentation
today is to be able to show you or to bring
to your knowledge not a specific trait, not
a specific picture, but just the conglomerate
issue of what the big animal, what the position
they have in our culture, and what we can
do, each one of our self, small world or big
world, to protect them and to make them bet--to
make them available for future generation.
And that will be just a glory for the big
animal. But that's how I--most of the time,
an ugly shot like that is very unusual for
me. I could not even put it in my pants because
I'm too fat by now. I'm not in the water for
long time ago. Not long enough. But only that's--this
weekend, I'm leaving for Mexico, diving with
a great white for about two weeks. And that
is my backyard. And all those places that
you see here are the places where images and
the expedition that I'll conduct or I'm conducting
all around the world. So if you go some time
sooner or later to my Web site, you'll be
able to see all those places one by one as
they are relating. And we'll start with the
polar bear. I will--all of you all probably
heard and knows what the polar bear plight
and all the story about the global warming.
It is indeed taking effect and we don't know
what will be the next generation, the next
step. However, what is important to know,
that the polar bear are ancestors of the grizzly
and they are evolved into being polar bear
only 300,000 years ago. It is not something
that take, like, sharks that live in the ocean
400 million years. Polar bear only evolved
in the past 300,000 years ago. So there are
poses--the planet is on a continuous chase,
continuous evolution, continuous--and we are
part of it right now. But to understand how
the polar bear live and to get close to that,
that's what I do. And that's what we bring
in people in small group, my team usually
about only four people when we go to look
at the polar bear and will give you few opportunity.
So you ask me how close I was to the polar
bear, almost as close as I am to the front
row right now. Understanding that every animal,
like human beings, we have a pattern of behavior.
We have tools of how we protect, how we feed,
how we make babies. Also, animals have the
same pattern, similar pattern. And the polar
bear in this case, its pattern or its protection
is the sense of smell. So if the wind goes
away from the polar bear, he will not smell
when we get close to it. The question is how
often I can do it. It takes a long time. You
not--you'll not challenge the environment
and to guess the environment, you just play
together with the wind until this happen.
So, usually, a trip like that may take two
or three weeks, but we're able to achieve
result as you see right now. Everything is
timely. Everything in the environment is about
time. It's about knowing exactly when the
polar bear, or in this case, the animal, is
on nurturing, when they are mating, when they're
migrating and when they are feeding. If we
know--if I know all of these, that's when
I take the people with me on a trip for a
small window of opportunity throughout the
year. That's why I don't repeat the same trips--the
same trip each year. There are only one trip
of a kind every other month. But we'll be
able to bring this kind of opportunity, this
kind of images. Vivian, can we ask somebody
to turn some of the light down so maybe the
images will be seen better? I want also to
take you underwater, not just top side. And
I want to share with you this. Anybody knows
what is that? Anybody? Yes, that's very good,
Vivian. Thank you. That's the blue whale.
Any--what do you know about the blue whale?
Anybody? Any idea? Big? How big?
>> Biggest in the world.
>> NACHOUM: The biggest animal ever live on
the planet. Bigger than any dinosaurs. How
big is it really? How long? How long?
>> Sixty feet.
>> NACHOUM: Sixty feet. Any other number?
>> Hundred.
>> NACHOUM: Hundred-feet long, yes. And eat
only plankton. There used to be about over
a quarter of a million blue whales on your
planet. Today, how many left? Anybody knows?
Hardly 12,000; 7,000 of them in the southern
hemisphere and about 5,000 on the northern
hemisphere. And from the 5,000 on the northern
hemisphere, about 3,000--2,500 to 3,000 along
the Coast of Mexico, back of California, California
and Washington State. Why? Because we have
the mammal protection law in the United States
that also extend into Mexico and extend further
up to Canada. So, protection. And when we
apply the protection, it's very helpful to
support the existence of the animal and especially
the big one. And that's where you see really
how big is this animal. That's aerial photography,
of course. The blow of the blue whale reach
almost over 30 feet, 10-meter tall. Anybody
knows what is that? It's beluga whales. What
are called the canary of the sea. And what
is that? What is that?
>> A killer whale.
>> NACHOUM: There is no killer whale. There's
no such things. That is how we use the language
and how we are mystify things and how we create
bad reputation to many of the animal because
of lack of knowledge. Fear. The enemy of fear,
number one, is lack of knowledge. Orcas are
actually dolphins. They're not even whales.
There are in truth, dolphins. The name "killer
whale" have been adopted to the orca only
because the Englishmen that came to translate
the manifest of the Spanish galleons of the
14th, 15th century could not give it any other
name because the Spaniard and the Portuguese,
what they wrote in the manifest, they're looking
at an animal that's actually killing other
whales. So they call it "killer whale." They
did not give it a name yet, orca. Only later
on when we start to do research, when we start
to develop university along the coast of Canada,
Washington, Norway and other parts of the
world, then we give them name. Today, we know
there are about five different species of
orca in the wild. Two of them still unidentified
in Antarctica and the other three that we
know of are resident, transient and nomad.
And each one of them is different into where
which how they behave, which how--their social
formation and how they feed. Those images
are from Norway where we see mostly, actually,
transient--not transient--we see resident
orcas. Resident orca feed mostly on fish and
there are a group of about 12 to 15 of them.
But the--all of the citation, the dolphin
and whales, are actually led by females. And
same thing with the orcas. And there is not
even one, not even one, accident ever happened
in the wild between orca and mankind. The
only time there was an accident, anybody knows
where?
>> SeaWorld.
>> NACHOUM: Bravo. So let's close them because
that's bad reputation unnecessarily. And they
play without the need to have trainer and
whistle and all kind of toy. They play freely
in the wild. That was a moment of really unforgettable
moment in the history. In my case, being in
the wild for as long as I've been, and all
of a sudden we had sunset in one hand, moonrise
on the other hand and the orca just passed
in--under the mountain and in front of the
moon in Norway. Anybody knows where Norway
is? Of course. We have Google Earth. And that's
the beauty of the sunset together with the
orcas. And anybody knows what is that? What?
Great whale? What else? Humpback whales, humpback
whales. Only 16,000 of them today are in the
wild [INDISTINCT]. How we know all of them,
I don't know for sure, but I can tell you
quite from research and from all the environmental
organization and the tech place, but especially
after the [INDISTINCT] of the Soviet Union,
we were able to get into the record of the
Soviets, of the Finland, of the Norwegian,
and the Iceland fishermen from the early part
of the previous century and then we'll be
able to put all the number together how many
they have actually hunted. Not just the number
they gave at a time publicly but get into
the record and only then find out really how
many at least they have hunted. In addition
to what we have today, the science and researcher
came to approximate numbers. And that is the
number I'll mentioned. Today, we have more
accurate information about what's left in
the world. Again, not specifically, but much
more accurate in a 10% to 20% margin of error,
but we have about 16,000 to 20,000 compared
to 500,000 and this is a result of hunting.
And today, there is no reason for that whatsoever.
Although, the Norwegian and the Icelandic
and the Russian or the [INDISTINCT]. We can
swim with them just like with the humpback,
just like with the orcas, just like with,
you know, close with the polar bear. Understanding,
we can also actually snorkel. Actually, no
scuba, no BC, no weight, just with our own
air, be able to snorkel with them because
snorkeling is perhaps the best activity to
meet the big animal. Just like for us men,
be gentle is the easiest way to get to any
woman if we want to--nobody's laughing anymore--simply
because big animals are most vulnerable when
they are on the surface. They're on the surface
because they need to breathe. And when they're
there, that's the only time where we can really
match and get close to them. And the moment
they get to the water, they took their breath
and they went underwater, after the first
five feet there is no way for us humans ever
to reach to get them because they are much
faster, stronger than us. But when they are
on the surface, then that's all a question
of timing and coordination. That's why any
of the expedition I lead, the photographic
expedition, for the animals, are with small
group. It was only four to six people only
to get the maximum result and the ability
not to affect the animal and not to really
impose on them. Only two people at a time
as we descend to the water, so the animal
will be interactive with us like in these
images. Or like with this image, this is a
single. Among the whales, the Humpback Whale
is the only one--the male actually sing to
attract the female toward them. And in the
water as I was mentioning before, the water
are three or 800 times denser than air. So,
let me ask you that, where will be the best
acoustic place in the world? Carnegie Hall,
the Opera House in Sydney, or underwater?
Underwater. Three hundred sixty degrees, 800
times denser, any vibration that this single
humpback whale will do your heart will pump
together with the music. It will be actually
echoing in the vacuum or in the air space
that you have in your lung. It's absolutely
stunning. Whale mother and calf. Again, as
I mentioned, it's all a question of timing
to know in all animal--and you see that the
pattern will repeat itself, either among the
orcas, among the polar bear, and among the
humpback whale, it's about feeding, about
migrating and about nurturing, knowing the
right timing to be able to bring this kind
of encounters between you and the animals.
And the animals who come very close and anybody--we
said that we have seven photographers here.
This is a very, very wide angle lens. As a
matter of fact, this is a fisheye lens, that
means that I was less than one feet away from
this juvenile humpback whale that came in.
It was very curios what am I doing in the
water. And that is a breach, 40 ton of animal
lifts itself out of the water and we don't
know why. There is no reason that human can
develop--and we say that communication, removing
parasite--we really don't know why. But they
can do it and they're doing it. And that's
the classic of the tail of the humpback whale,
dripping water in Alaska. Well, moving rather
along for another creature of a lot of excitement
and colors. And those are the dolphins. There
are about three dozen different species of
dolphin in the wild and those are--these one
in particular are--those are the bottlenose
dolphin in Galapagos. This is the common dolphin,
the Atlantic common dolphin in South Africa.
Of course, this is the bait ball where the
dolphins are feeding on. And what is that?
What's that? Go ahead. No, no, go ahead. It's
good. What do you think is that?
>> [INDISTINCT]
>> NACHOUM: [INDISTINCT], what else?
>> Sailfish.
>> NACHOUM: Sailfish, what else? It is indeed
a sailfish. There are about seven--there are
seven species of what they call the billfish
family. There are swordfish, there are blue
marlin, there are marlin, there are stripe
marlin, white marlin, sailfish and maybe one
more that I forgot at the moment. However,
there wasn't any pictures of sailfish until
about four years ago. Anybody knows what happened
four years ago? [INDISTINCT] remember? It
was the first time that both stories of the
Blue Planet and the images of the--of this
sailfish and I was the one that actually took
them out there into Mexico to dive actually
off the [INDISTINCT] 15 minutes off Cancun
into the water of Isla Mujeres. If anybody
been there will know. It's a beautiful little
island, very rustic it was at the time, but
today it's becoming almost like a hub after
Cancun because it become very popular among
the fisherman and among the diver. After [INDISTINCT]
about, everybody plunking out there. Yes?
>> How big is that?
>> NACHOUM: The fish is about nine feet long
and the bill is about one-third of the whole
fish. It is the fastest fish in the ocean.
It clocked at over 75 miles per hour, faster
than a cheetah on the land. It is fantastic.
But the only time to catch those images, and
the one that you see next, is when they're
actually coming by--they're coming into Mexico
to this particular part of the water in a
particular time of the year, in January, February,
to feed on the Brazilian sardine. And here
as you see is the bait ball of the sardine.
Nobody knew. And, you know, a lot of fisherman
going for many, many, many years, [INDISTINCT]
and the rest, have been catching those sailfish
and those marlin in Cuba, in Mexico, in Peru,
everywhere else. But hardly anybody until
four years ago--actually, not hardly, it's
clearly, nobody with a camera went to the
water about four or five years ago--five years
ago when I went, I called the BBC and when
they did Blue Planet, they call [INDISTINCT]
okay, put us together with the story and we
set up the set-up. And that is the evidence.
We told you about bait ball. Bait ball happened
many different parts of the world all the
time, especially in the remote island. In
this case, off Galapagos. Anybody been in
Galapagos before besides Vivian? You, have
you been all the way in Darwin and Wolf?
>> No, no.
>> NACHOUM: No? Then most don't--northern
island.
>> I don't know.
>> NAHCOUM: You don't know. There is two island
up north of the equator of [INDISTINCT] called
Darwin and Wolf. The middle of nowhere, 600
mile from any land and 100 mile north of Galapagos
itself, they are a part of Galapagos. And
they are [INDISTINCT] there's no land. They
need to feed. They need food. And the food
is in the water, so all with sea birds. And
when you watch well enough, you'll be able
to see eventually the birds feeding and then
the tuna feeding underwater on a bait ball.
And those are actually yellowtail tuna [INDISTINCT]
fish actually use its bill, like the baseball
bat used in a baseball game. They actually
hit the fish with the bill. They move it like
that all the time into the school. But only
one sailfish at a time. All the other sailfish
will wait until one finish and then it come
the second round of like it [INDISTINCT] moving
very, very fast. And just like this one. Anybody
heard about the BBC Wildlife Competition of
the Year? The Photographer of the Year? So
about three years ago, this picture took the
first place in the underwater photography.
This was the moment as--again, very fast fish,
very fast action. And to catch it when he
took the bait or to take the bait in its mouth,
it was very--I was, I guess very lucky to
be able to capture it and bring it alive.
And this picture taken actually from the side
of my shoulder. That's no manipulation and
no Photoshop-ing and nothing, any other elements.
It's just the way it is, captured in camera
at one time. And after everybody has seen
the bait and you see the blood that actually
already--the fish already bleeding between
the two parts of the bill. What is that? Great
white. What does it do? Breaching out of the
water. It was very--it was a situation that
was up until seven or eight years ago, nobody
knew of--or if we knew about it, nobody reported
or did anything about it. This actually happened
only in South Africa. The great white breach
also other places but not to such extraordinary
behavior. The reason why exactly we don't
know, but the purpose of the great white breaching
is because they are looking after there actually
seals that moving out from the island in early
part of the morning. So in order to do that,
after a year or two or three observing that,
it become clear that the great white, just
like all other predators, like all other master
of their ability are very conservative animal
despite their power, despite the uniqueness
ability that nature gave to them. They are
not a man eater. They are not eat anything
they see. They are very methodical. There
is an island just off Cape Town called Seal's
Island, about 45,000 to 60,000 seals on it.
Come January and they give birth, the seal
population give birth. The population rise
to about almost 60,000. The adult will have
to go to sea to bring more fish for them for
food. And [INDISTINCT] July, this is where
the most migration of a big and the bigger
seals go out to sea. The shark will arrive
around Seal Island around May, June and wait
for the opportunity. Seal's Island, it is
relatively deep. If you go to the water there
is a steep cliff, it goes to about 40, 60
feet before it reach the bottom and that's
how they rise out of the surface. The great
white patrol around it, especially in the
morning hours. And exactly like all surfer.
When surfer go to sea? Early morning and late
afternoon. When the shark operate? Early morning,
late afternoon. Why? The sun hardly rise over
the horizon, the angle of the sun over the
horizon is the angle of penetration into the
water, the light. So the lesser the angle,
or the more angle, lesser, lesser activity.
But a shark can see there is a light on the
surface, the shark [INDISTINCT] on the surface.
The seal cannot see the shark underwater because
there's not enough light. Beside the shark
on the back of it, it's dark over like the
water, totally stealth. The shark will go
straight up 40 feet to accelerate and to catch
the seal. The seal don't know what hit it.
Come the light, eight, nine o'clock in the
morning, the operation or the nature went
to sleep, until later on four or five o'clock
in the evening again. In order to be able
to do that, we have to emulate the behavior
of the seal and we tow behind [INDISTINCT]
a dummy, a plastic or a rubber dummy, about
20 feet away from the boat and wait for the
moment for the shark to jump out and here
you go. So three years ago in the BBC competition,
the Photographer of the Year, this also had
the first place in animal behavior. And [INDISTINCT]
get close to the animal and to bring really
the behavior be able to put almost--not almost,
I put actually--the camera was in the mouth
of the shark and take it away and be able
to bring the images back. Because understanding
how the shark operate, and that's because
of this understanding, I, next week as Vivian
knows and hopefully she'll join me next year--when
we go to Mexico and there is a great white,
there is one thing that all operator do continuously
including Discovery, we do the very unethical
things. It is challenging the shark, actually
teasing them and irritating them, by putting
blood and chum in the water to take them to
the camera. But if you don't put chum or blood
and not take it away from them, the shark
will care less and they'll swim around me,
just like I'm a piece of nothing in the water.
And you don't believe me, am I right? Let's
see. That's the animal that was captured in
our imagination. That's the animal that the
media wanted to use so badly. That's the image,
Discovery have used this exact image. In '93,
they used this as a poster. They turned it
vertical, they make it a poster and all over
the front of buses and all over New York,
California and Texas and Chicago to promote
the Shark Week. But the truth of the matter
is that we don't use blood because this is
the prey, what you see here, are the seals.
Well, that's what they feed on. If we don't
use chum and blood in the water, we can sit
on the edge of comfort and against common
sense because there is nothing to do with
what we've been feed. We can swim openly,
freely, safely with a great white. However,
if we'll not be too bravado or too macho's
or imposing our superiority, perhaps superiority
over the wilderness. On the contrary, living
with the wilderness like making love to nature,
make love with nature, nature will be able
to show us some most amazing moments just
like this. And this is not again, no touched
and not expended and not been blown, it is
over 50 millimeter lens. Especially I use
this lens in order to bring the image of the
shark and distort it. All photographers know,
and if you don't know, of anytime you go to
a movie and you see anything, lenses have
the ability actually to distort the images.
There is depth of field. There is shallow
depth of field, a [INDISTINCT] depth of field
and distort the images because of what they
call the false perspective. But when we take
a 50 millimeter lens, which is almost like
exactly what we see in our own eyes, we'll
be able to get this particular images. And
that's a picture that one of my client took
of me swimming with a great white last year.
Face to face as I'm closest to the people
on the front row. And that's the image I got
in my camera. And I allow the shark to come
even closer toward me. This is another photographer.
That's even close, half the distance between
us two. And that's the image I got then. So
if the movie created such--how do you call
it, memories in our mind, I have to do--to
try to do the same thing, rather the opposite,
remove this negative and be able to share
with you the knowledge how this happened and
how to avoid it, or what to participate if
you want to participate in something that
has the positive effect on your life, on the
life of the animal, and the life of nature.
But not only to the great white, we come even
closer with this. Anybody know what is that?
>> The whale shark.
>> NACHOUM: The whale shark. How big is the
whale shark?
>> Huge.
>> NACHOUM: How huge is huge? It's not as
huge as Google. But how huge is huge? It's
about 40, 45 feet long. One of the three or
four different species of shark that feed
only on plankton and it's the largest of all
the shark species. So it does not have to
eat meat in order to be large. You can eat
plankton and you are the largest. Which is
bring another problem altogether, it is not
necessarily the place right now, but the over
fishing of plankton in the southern ocean
in and around Antarctica by the country like
the Soviet Union, China and other, and they
use that mostly for fertilization and food
for their animal stocks. That is becoming
a problem because they are competing practically
with the albatross which are in decline and
of course with all the large whale, the blues,
the sei, the fin whale, the humpback, and
all of the other whale that actually go to
the Antarctica to feed during the summertime,
in Antarctica summer time, our winter time.
And here is the example of the size of this
mouth of this animal together with the driver
just beside that. It could swallow it very
easily but it does not really happen. We can
imagine whatever we want to imagine. And,
of course, these stories and this stigma of
this very prehistoric look like of them, of
the hammerhead sharks, out of Galapagos. When
you see them in great numbers, sometime hundreds
together, but very--and then unusual shape
of the head, and the eyes all together by
the side, but they come very, very close to
the reef and they are waiting for their--actually
for the butterflyfish to come and to clean
them and they open mouths like--just like
we see it in a barber shop waiting for the
opportunity to somebody come clean and give
us a good time. There you are. But that's
the drama that you're looking for. That's
the event, the phenomenal event, that you're
looking for. The schooling Hammerhead, sometime
hundred to a thousand. It could be three,
five, sometime up to seven, eight minutes
parade of those school and they are in the
distance between me and the third--the second
or the third row from here. Or this, or this.
Anybody knows what is that?
>> Ray.
>> NACHOUM: Ray, what kind of ray? They are
mobula rays. They are not mantas, they are
mobula rays. They are smaller in size and
they feed also on plankton and they move in
a big crowd. In this case, about 40 or 50
of them at one time off the coast of Galapagos
Island again. And this is the manta ray. This
is the Oceanic manta ray or the giant manta
ray, almost 20 feet from wing tip to wing
tip. And this is, not a sailfish, what is
that? Striped marlin. A striped, yes. It's
a marlin and there's--it's that marlin about
almost 12 feet, about 2 feet larger than the
sailfish. And again, the bill is about one-third
of the fish, the fish length. They are as
fast as a sailfish and they are--you can find
them in exactly opposite side of Mexico. If
the sailfish was found out in the Caribbean,
then the marlin we would find out in the Atlanta--in
the Pacific of Cabo San Lucas. And let's see
how the marlin feed. The marlin feed a lit
bit different than the sailfish. And as you
see, as the marlin here coming in to the school,
actually he use his bill like we use the chopsticks.
Anybody knows how to eat with chopsticks?
You remove one sushi at a time, right? Look
at the fish--the picture is not very clear,
unfortunately, but in--on the edge of the
bill, you'll see one of the sardine and then
it took it. It's the last day of the life
of this sardine. It is fun being in the water.
It's joy. The water actually will carry you.
As long as you just not fight with it, just
let the water do what the water does and get
along with it, the water will just carry you
like being in the womb of the mother. Seventy
percent or more of our planet is ocean. Seventy
percent of the planet is giving us over 50%
of the oxygen that we breathe on. And we polluted
it galore. Anybody--most of you heard about
the plastic island that we have somewhere
in the middle of the Pacific Ocean all the
way throughout Japan. And all the pollution
that we throw into the water, factories from
all over the country, including United States,
and all the other developing country, we have
to do something about it because there is
no place as beautiful as--look at these images.
Look at this coloration. Look at the animal
that's suffering, animal that we can relate
to. They are our size, a turtle, we can relate
to one to one. They are happy to be where
they are. How can we continue contaminate,
or really continue avoid playful with them?
They are part of a playground. This is--I
showed you the world of the--the map of the
world, that's my playground. I don't have
to go to Yosemite only, the ocean, the rest
of the world is our playground. And they are
beautiful things out there to play with. Like
those seals in the kelp of South Africa or
the narwhal out in the high Arctic or the
pink dolphin from the Amazon river. Even the
anaconda. I know the movie create such drama
and such a--it's a piece of cake, fortunately,
understanding that anaconda doesn't feed underwater.
They feed on the land. But they don't feed
underwater. And then would do nothing. We
swim with them, 24-feet long animal. This
is how we find some of the animals in the
ocean. We cannot see into the water but we
can use the same understanding that the old
generation had. We don't need sophistication
and we don't need the Google Ocean to find
out where are the service because Google Ocean
doesn't know unless I tell them. And that's
what happen when you look from the surface
into the water, half over, half under. The
birds on top, the sailfish on the bottom,
and between them are the bait ball or are
the sardines. Going to Antarctica. We're not
necessarily going to be like Titanic. It happened
once in history. We learned the lessons. We
dive under the ice, which is like diving in
a palace. And we see these amazing vistas
of the continent that's totally frozen. It
go through changes like everything else. It
goes through out the changes. But we have
the gear. We have the equipment. We are knowledgeable.
And this exist if you just reach out a little
bit farther away from the normal life and
be able to do those things, they're very unusual
things, and to see these unusual places. Look
how small we are under this planet that's
called ocean. And this is the edge of the
ice and what we see under the ice, those jellyfish.
That's how the old generation were looking
and listening to whales, and before they arrive
into the crack in the ice. Those are the Inuit
guide. And with those guys will be working
in the field, on the edge of wilderness, to
be able to bring different kinds of experiences
rather than drive in the freeways of America
or sitting at Starbuck, we're sitting on the
edge of the ice, in a tent, for three weeks,
looking for polar bear or looking for the
narwhal. And those are the guys who'd be able
to tell us exactly because they don't have
navigation, hardly ever a satellite phone
working there. And the walruses. And the lonely
walrus that went to die and she moved away
just like the Indian, the American Indian,
you will leave the--she would leave the home
and go by herself into farther way in the
ice and look at the size of those tusks, she
was probably about 11 or 12 years old which
is the maximum that walrus could live and
she went to die by herself, away from everybody
else. And mother and calf. On the edge of
comfort, wilderness, and on the edge of noise.
Two hundred fifty thousand of king penguin
of the island of South Georgia. And sorry,
if my English is believable--just staggering
from the smell, from the noise, and from the
vistas altogether. And only one place on the
planet you see something like that. And it's
one of the most beautiful island you will
ever see and that's is the, you call it the--I
call it the Grandiose (ph) as they stand up,
as we lower ourselves down, it's about 30
inch--about 30 inch tall, 32 inches tall,
laid myself down and looked at the mountain
behind, which was over almost 2,000 feet,
and the penguin in front of us, they are the
king. They are just--give you a chance. That's
a reason to live. That's a reason to breathe,
to do something so fascinating. Who'd designed
anything like that with those colors, with
those wings, and able to swim in the water
and to walk on the land, all at the same time.
Looking for predators, waiting to be eaten.
But there is a predator roaming around the
ice and the only one of it's kind. And we
are all ready to catch his--its picture. We're
all ready for the moment. And they want to
know--anybody knows what is that? Leopard
seals, the only predator that is in Antarctica.
And actually, very interestingly, only during
two months it feed on penguins, on meat, on
meals, on meat. The rest of the time of the
year, they feed on plankton. And look at the
size of the teeth, the canine teeth and the
grinding teeth, that this animal got. Mother
Nature is very, very unique. The animal look
like a prehistoric. It's a nine feet, 9 to
12 feet, long. And it is powerful and it's
fast. It's so agile. It's second that we'd
never seen anything like that. And very curious
by--as diver being together in the water with
them. They are a perfect hunter. But this
is also a perfect places for people like all
of us, clear, fresh water and 300 foot visibility
or more that you notice in Mexico. And, of
course, among the big animal we cannot forget
the gorillas out in Rwanda, or the lion and
the buffalos in Ngorongoro Crater in Tanzania.
Anybody knows what is that? And what is this?
What is this? This is the cheetah. And so
what is that? Leopard, right. Well, we're
getting somewhere. And I'm getting away from
you guys. This is on--anybody knows Argentina?
Peninsula Valdes? Anybody heard about Peninsula
Valdes? A world heritage site is in--actually,
a peninsula completely closed to--stopped
to be developed by the World Heritage Foundation
and there are only one--for one particular
reason, there are group of orcas that still,
the only place in the world, which they will
come in and feed by stranding themselves on
the beaches and take the seals out of the
beach. And if you seen the latest movies of
Disney, and they are some section in this
particular place when the orca come on the
beach and take the animals away. Once in every
two or three years I run a special trip out
there and that's the edge of the place in
Peninsula Valdes. And then one of the gauchos
there had arrived in horse and sees I'm an
Israeli, he's the only one that let me ride
on a horse and it was this, I guess, going
just to--I got another native images from
the island of Palau--on the island of Yap
in the Pacific. And to let you know that all
these images are taken actually in the natural
setting and all the animal depicted here are
free and wild. None of them been fed. None
of them been trained. None of them in captivity.
All in the wilderness and all are there somewhere
in the ocean that you can be able to see if
you'll join me. If you are--if you're interested
in any of the trips, either photography or
expeditions or want to know more, one of the
best place to find information is, one of
the best place besides National Geographic
or Noah (ph) is to find from--on my website,
BigAnimals.com. All right. Any questions?
Yes?
>> Do you have an incoming trip that we can
join?
>> NACHOUM: Yes, trip that you can join. This
open--that's open to the public. That's the
reason I ask you. If any of you, please, before
you leave, just fill me up then--there's a
card that I left with you, I'll be able to
continue to be in touch with you. As today,
as you know today, by the media--not the media
but the network or the server are not allow
us to send mass mailing to people unless people
give us the permission to use and to send
you an email. I cannot do that anymore. Otherwise,
they will not let--if they--if you're email
is not certified that I've received it from
you I cannot use it. So if you want to receive
information, I'll be delighted to send you
but only through these cards. Any more questions?
Yes.
>> Have you ever been hurt?
>> NACHOUM: Only in my heart. I was hurt once
and that is the result only of human error.
I was hurt once by, actually, by walrus. When
you operate with the walrus, you need to have,
I need to have always a back-up with me, somebody
watching my back because as you saw on the
images, the walrus is mostly on the iceberg,
but there are other walruses will just coming
back home. And usually mother and calf, that's
the season. So we got off the boat. I got
first with my camera, I'm ready to go, and
the safety divers supposed to come behind
me. He did and I did not pay attention, I
continue moving because when you are with
a camera, you're going to work, your safety
diver is supposed to be behind you. He went
to the water but unfortunately he lost his
tank. The tank was fall off of the carry,
of the BC, so he was delayed getting to me.
I did not know that. I'm looking at the--to
where the iceberg where the walruses were.
And all of the sudden, I felt something strange.
About, you know, you sometimes you a sixth
or seventh sense or ninth sense? The hair
out in your back stand up and you know something
is wrong. And I looked to my side and this
female was very, very close toward me. And
she had a cub with her. So she's clearly going
for me because she was very close with the
tusk. If I will stay where I am, all this
area will be the most sensitive area of humankind
will be affected. I turned my butt and she
nabbed me on my butt. She made a hole in the
dry suit and then I got flooded with water,
got up and put air in my BC, and she came
again. But the second time when she came again,
I turned around and then we had a distance
and I could raise my head with my leg with
my fin and it was a distance between us, she
understood that I'm not after her. She continued
and I took her picture and she went home.
But that's the only time that really we'll
get close to be hurt. It is--that's what I
do. That's what people do when--I have over
30 years of immaculate record, but managing
risk. Well, as you probably--as I mentioned
to you before, I'm from Israel. I was an officer
in the military about almost 12 years in the
Special Forces. Managing risk, it is what
we do, what we learn to do. It doesn't make
any difference. It's not necessary be uniform.
It's not necessary to be guns. It's not necessary--it
is knowing, understanding what the risk you
are facing and how to manage it and to avoid
it. But how to reach the goal that you want
to despite this element is knowledge is the
enemy of all fear. And that's the key. The
more knowledge, the more experience in the
field. Every time pushing the envelope just
one step--don't let the envelope break because
if you blow in it too hard, it will break.
Push it one step at a time and be able to
see the result, measure it and move again,
and retreat. If you need to retreat, it is
a very proud things to do. Retreat, it is
not a defeat. And defeat is when you're not
be able to stand here and share with you the
experiences. Any more question? Yes.
>> [INDISTINCT] you mentioned that [INDISTINCT].
>> NACHOUM: It is about being a long time
in the field. Yes, just being in the field.
I did not learn in any other way. I did not
have, sorry to say or good to say, I did not
have education. But the education was in a
knock--with real knock of life. I paid dearly
for that. But, again, thank for America for
the ability. I borrowed the money. I was able
to return--pay back and that's what gave me
the chance to learn, being in the field. And
if you read the bio that Vivian put together,
in any of the trip I ran as a businessman,
I realized in order for me to gain anything
I had to have the leader of the world in their
businesses; either marine biology, research,
photography, to be co-host with me on the
trip. I learned from them while I went along.
Yes?
>> But what about the [INDISTINCT].
>> NACHOUM: You just said it. You just also
yourself--very, very close to the subject.
You cannot have powerful enough strobe to
match the light from the sun. When you work
with wide angle lens versus working with a
macro, wide angle lens may be capturing a
lot space, you have to count on the ambient
light. The strobe you bring in is only like
a painter bring a brush over, just to highlight
several elements. You touch a very interesting
point and I'll take one more minute. I learned
photography not in photography classes, not
in photography school, not from any photographer.
I learned from the people which their--which
their prints or images sell for millions.
Anybody can give two names of--or three names
of people that their picture of prints sell
for millions? [INDISTINCT] photographer, print,
painter, painter that sell for million. They
are the best teacher in the world. [INDISTINCT]
Van Gogh, Monet, all those--and those picture
are for free. You go to any museum in the
world and you could sit for hours and watch.
Not what they're try to tell you as a photographer
but only how they paint the light. Guys, painter
have the difficult, have a difficult job to
do. They have only white canvas. They have
to create everything to put on the canvas;
the color, the position, the composition,
everything else. As an underwater photographer,
I have exactly opposite challenge. I have
the most creative photo--painter in the world
and creator. He put everything in the water.
The only thing He did not put in the water
is the white light because the water--light
absorbs through the water very fast and the
first 30 feet, you have--you don't see any
more red, no yellows and only green and blue.
So as a photographer, my task is how to bring
the light out and how to understand the light.
And the second job is if I--I don't have a
canvas, so--but what I have is a lens and
to select what part of the animal or the scenery
I see that I want to capture to share with
you. That's the parallel, that's how I look
at it. I was sitting hours, honestly and looking
at the prints or painting of the great painters
to understand what they've done and that's
what I took with me to the water. But not
because of a photographer because I don't
think you can learn photography unless you
do it. And unless you put it out of the market
to sell and you see what people react and
how they buy and how they react to the images
as some of you reacted today.
>> Can you tell us your proudest image? And
can you talk about the image that you missed?
>> NACHOUM: I cannot tell you about images
that I missed because then I'll be very sorry.
That is indeed the dilemma that all photographer
deal with because nobody at home know what
we went through or what I gone through. There
are moments that we miss, but these are not
the moment that we dwell on, it's the moment
where we learn the mistakes or we learn what
we did not know at the time and how it make
it better. But I can tell you the moment which
I'm proud of is like the breach in great white
or like the one with the striped marlin with
the fish in its mouth. It's timely second
to none and that is what make the difference
in still photography versus when you do video.
The anaconda, the anaconda was swimming in
actually in barren river until it eventually
came over the green grass. And I was waiting
for that. You take back all the time with
Mother Nature. So you miss a lot of different
things. I missed several images of the narwhal
as they come in towards--as you saw the narwhal
with the tusk out. There were other images
which I totally missed. Then there are images
that--of a polar bear that actually was--he
had a prey and put his paws over the prey
and rolled it over. But I changed lenses at
that time. You miss. But nobody know those
images except we have to live with it. And
we do. Next time, we do better and better
and better. And that's the challenge. That's
what keep me doing it compared to being in
the military and wearing uniform and commanding
and running after. But that's the challenge,
the excitement and the productivity, and the
beauty you bring to the world rather than
sorrow and pain. Yes?
>> [INDISTINCT]
>> NACHOUM: The million dollar question. I
really don't know. I know I don't take many
pictures while I'm shooting. I don't take
many. No, I don't take many because it is
a mind set. Again, remember the painter I
talked to you about? They knew what they're
going to paint. Da Vinci, Angelo, Rembrandt,
Monet, all of them, Van Gogh, [INDISTINCT]
they knew what they're going to paint. They
elaborate about their painting, about their
colors and what they do, until eventually
they get what they want. I think the same
because I start from the school of film, not
from the school of digital. Digital can shoot
305--800,000 images in one count. I start
with the school of 36 frame so I have to be
very methodical in the way which how--what
is the subject about to choose, what I'm looking
for. And the best photography, in my view,
in photograph--in icon images are images that
you saw before you photograph it or you thought
you're going to see and what happens is Mother
Nature in most time have actually outdid my
own imagination and gave me a present bigger
than any. Like the image of the blue whale
on the back of the card. You said the image
of the blue whale with the fin open is an
image that I've seen earlier in the--about
'87 or '87 or '88 in National Geographic by
Flip Nicholin. And there's an image of a fin
whale across the two pages with a beautiful
sunset in Baha. I really wanted to have this
image or really--but as a good person, we
don't copy, we emulate. We don't copy. So
when I went eventually to Baha in the mid-90
and tried to get my own image, when the blue
whale was just a foot of us, I had to make
a decision, either I'm going to take the picture
of the whole blue whale or half of it because
it's so big the lens could not take it or
find something else. And all of the sudden,
this blue whale actually was resting on the
surface. It allowed me to think for a moment
and to be fast if I could, because that's
the human element, and move toward the tail
which is much more powerful rather than the
whole body, which would be very long and not
distinguished, but over the tail and look
over the horizon and see the island. And that
was a gift. It is not something that I could
dream about. I was impressed by the image
that I've seen in '87, but Mother Nature at
that moment, if I was not open to receive
the information that's given to me, I would
not see it. I'll just do the same thing as
other people did and move on. But at the moment
you look at other opportunities. Always look
at other opportunities. Just like Google does.
Honestly, you guys, or whoever managing and
running and driving you, they are just brilliant.
Never had about bait ball. So you--that means
that you have to join me because that's what
I'm looking for. The bait ball is where the
action is. Most of diving trip, most trip,
period, take people into places which is very
usual and very common and they put down to
walk either to see the Louvre, either to see
the Eiffel, or either to see--jump to the
water, if you go diving, to see the reef,
the coral reef, the clown fish and the eels,
and the so on and so forth. But they are not
focusing, not willing to take the risk, to
see something which not predictable. Bait
ball is not predictable. There is time and
places around the world that could happen.
That is where I put my effort. You will have
to look for an operator that is really looking
for something like that to be able to give
you the opportunity. Oh, why is the ball?
Because the small fish, like people, when
there is an explosion they all run together.
They hug each other for protection. So they
all get together very, very tight. They hope
they will not be taken by the predators because
they will be in the center of the group. But
the group is turning around and everybody
want to be on the center. So is everybody
in and out, in and out and that's the bait
ball. The bait because the bigger fish come
feed on them. Then come the tuna, and then
come the dolphin, and then come the sharks,
and the berets on the top, and a photographer
like us come and take their picture. Any more
question? Yes.
>> [INDISTINCT]
>> NACHOUM: I love film. I grew up on film.
But there's no film yet anymore almost to
be processed, especially slides, to be processed
and to get the result. And digital today really,
coming to an age of excellent in delivering
good--delivering quality. So it's a toast.
It is just because I raise on film and the
black and white and the color and we like
some of the nuances that the cut--that the
film has, but the dynamic range of a digital
reaching to the level of quality of what film
did. So in the next year or two or three,
we'll have digital perhaps even suppress film
and we have to deal with that. If you heard
about HDR, yes? HDR prints have remarkable
details in images that we could not do in
film. So there is a--there is a positive progression
and increasing value and increasing quality.
Any more, guys? I'm sorry?
>> [INDISTINCT]
>> NACHOUM: I used to carry more than one
camera, yes. But in today because of the digital,
I'd--you don't need. You have 800, a thousand
frames you can shoot on those 32 gigabyte
cards, you can do video at the same time,
so it's one lens in my kind of work, specialty
on the big animals, so only one camera. When
you go to work on the reef, it's a different
story. Because when we work with big animal,
we are in an open ocean. It's wild, it's wilderness.
The encounter could be very short, like, maybe
30 seconds or it can be even half an hour.
But over--but you have only one subject, one
big subject to photograph, so only one lens
will work well. But when you work on the reef
it's a different story because in the reef
you have other elements that you can photograph.
It will be a seal. It would be a sea fin.
It will be sponges. It will be the clown fish.
It will be the fish giving birth or the fish
laying eggs. It's different cameras you want
to carry with you. And also when you are working
on a reef, you're going to be on shallow water;
30, 40, 60 feet. You can stay much longer.
Hour, hour and a half, two hours, if you are
on night treks without problem and then give
you--but you want to have more cameras, even
digital, yes. It's all in the line of work.
It's like everything else. You have a computer,
and you have a handheld, and you have the
iPod, and the whatever. The same thing in
a photography, it's only tools to do the job
and know about the job you want to do, or
if you have a fan and you want--you have a
particular vision, how to keep your vision
and bring it to light. Thank you very much.
Or any more question? Who is coming on a trip
to--this weekend? We're going to do a great
white swimming in and out of the cage. All
right. Thank you very much, guys.