HEARD THROUGH THE GRAPEVINE THAT SOME PEOPLE
ARE HAVING
DIFFICULTY LOCATING THE LECTURE NOTES THAT
I'VE BEEN POSTING.
SO BE SURE TO LOOK FOR THOSE ON BSPACE, NOT
ON THE BIO 1B
WEBSITE. YOU SHOULD HAVE RECEIVED E-MAILS
AFTER EACH LECTURE
WITH THE LINK TO THE LECTURE NOTES, BUT IF
YOU DIDN'T, YOU CAN GO
TO THE BSPACE SITE. LOG IN WITH YOUR CAL ID.
GO TO MY ACTIVE
SITES, THE MENU UP, IN THE UPPER LEFT, RIGHT
OF THE MENU. AND
UNDER THERE YOU SHOULD FIND THE LINK WHICH
SAYS BIO 1B LECTURE,
PLANTS, FALL 10. AND THEN CLICK THERE. AND
THAT WILL TAKE YOU
TO A SCREEN WHERE YOU'LL SEE RESOURCES AS
ONE OF THE CHOICES ON
THE LEFT. CLICK RESOURCES AND YOU'LL FIND
THE, THE LECTURE
FOLDER, AND JUST OPEN THAT UP AND ALL THE
LECTURE PRESENTATIONS
ARE IN THERE WITH THE NOTES EMBEDDED IN. SO
PLEASE CHECK THAT
OUT. AND IF YOU HAVE TROUBLE, JUST GIVE ME
AN E-MAIL. OKAY,
ALSO DON'T FORGET ON SUNDAY NIGHT TO CHANGE
THE CLOCK BACK ONE
HOUR OR YOU'LL SHOW UP AN HOUR EARLY FOR LECTURE
WHICH I'M SURE
YOU'D RATHER NOT DO BECAUSE I CERTAINLY WON'T
BE HERE THEN.
OKAY, SO WE'RE GOING TO START OUT TODAY JUST
GOING BACK OVER,
ACTUALLY, CONTINUING THIS SURVEY OF THE ALGAE
AND LOOKING AT THE
LAST MAJOR FORM OF LIFE CYCLE. AND IT'S ACTUALLY
THE ONE WE'LL
BE LOOKING AT FOR THE REST OF THE COURSE,
SO IT'S REALLY
IMPORTANT TO IN PARTICULAR FOCUS ON THIS ONE
WHICH ISN'T COMMON
TO ALL THE ALGAE, JUST SOME OF THEM, BUT IT'S
FOUND IN ALL THE
LAND PLANTS. AND THEN WE'LL GET TO SOME ALGAL
USES. AND THEN
TALK ABOUT THE INVASION OF LAND BY PLANTS
WHICH WILL BE A THEME
INTO THE NEXT LECTURE AS WELL. OKAY, I JUST
WANT TO MAKE ONE
JUMP BACK TO THE FUNGI THOUGH, THIS SLIDE
YOU MIGHT REMEMBER
ABOUT PENICILLIN. I JUST WANT TO CLARIFY WHAT
I WAS TRYING TO
GET ACROSS HERE BECAUSE IT WAS A BIT UNCLEAR
THE WAY I PRESENTED
IT, THAT PENICILLIN REALLY, THE MAJOR POINT
I WAS TRYING TO MAKE
HERE IS THAT THE, THE CELL WALLS OF BACTERIA
ARE DIFFERENT FROM
THE CELL WALLS OF ALL EUKARYOTES, OKAY. THEY'RE
COMPRISED OF
PEPTIDOGLYCANS, WHICH AS THE NAME IMPLIES
ARE MADE UP OF AN
AMINO, OF AMINO ACIDS AND SUGARS. AND PENICILLIN
ACTS TO
INTERFERE WITH THE ENZYMES THE BACTERIA NEED
TO SYNTHESIZE THE
PEPTIDOGLYCANS. AND WITHOUT THEIR CELL WALLS,
THE BACTERIA WILL
BURST. AND SO IT'S VERY EFFECTIVE AS A MEDICINE
BECAUSE OF
COURSE WE LACK CELL WALLS. AND FUNGI CAN GET
AWAY WITH
PRODUCING IT BECAUSE THEIR CELL WALLS OF COURSE
ARE MADE OF
CHITIN WHICH IS, I MENTIONED THAT A FEW TIME
EARLIER, THE SAME
CARBOHYDRATE THAT ARTHROPOD EXOSKELETONS ARE
MADE OF, OR
ORGANISMS LIKE CRUSTACEANS AND INSECTS. SO
I JUST WANT TO ADD
THAT EXTRA CONTEXT HERE AND HOPE THAT IS A
LITTLE CLEARER NOW.
ALL RIGHT, SO AS FAR AS THE ALGAE GO, I JUST
WANT TO RECAP THE
MAIN POINTS SO FAR BEFORE WE LAUNCH BACK IN,
OOPS, OOPS, YEAH,
THAT'S RIGHT. SO REMEMBER THAT THE CYANOBACTERIA,
THE
BLUE/GREEN BACTERIA, THESE SHARE THE ABILITY
TO PHOTOSYNTHESIZE,
TO USE LIGHT TO CAPTURE ATMOSPHERIC CARBON,
FIX IT AS SUGAR.
AND THEY'RE THE ONLY ORGANISMS THAT HAVE ACTUALLY
EVOLVED
PHOTOSYNTHESIS. I SHOULDN'T SAY THE ONLY ONES,
BUT THE ONES THAT
EVOLVE PHOTOSYNTHESIS THAT ALL THE ALGAE HAVE
SUBSEQUENTLY TAKEN
ADVANTAGE OF. SO THE EVOLUTION OF PHOTOSYNTHESIS
BY
CYANOBACTERIA REPRESENTS THE SOLE EVOLUTIONARY
EVENT THAT
RESULTED IN PHOTOSYNTHESIS. AND THEN ALL THE
OTHER ALGAL
LINEAGES BASICALLY JUST CAPTURED CYANOBACTERIA
EITHER DIRECTLY OR
INDIRECTLY AND HAVE UTILIZED THEIR EVOLUTIONARY
INNOVATION THAT
WAY. AND ONLY ONE MAJOR LINEAGE OF THE CYANOBACTERIA
GAVE RISE
TO ALL OF THE PLASTIDS, THE CHLOROPLASTS,
AND OTHER PLASTIDS IN
THE EUKARYOTIC ALGAE. OKAY, SO THAT --
STUDENT: IS THE CYANOBACTERIA THE FIRST [INAUDIBLE]
PROFESSOR: AS FAR AS I KNOW, YEAH. THAT'S,
THAT'S ALL, I'M
ONLY FAMILIAR WITH, WITH CYANOBACTERIA. I
MEAN ONE OF THE
THINGS WE'RE GOING TO SEE, THERE'S QUITE A
FEW SINGLE EVENTS IN,
I MEAN IF WE LOOK BACK TO THE LAND PLANTS,
THEY ALL SEEM TO STEM
FROM ONE ANCESTOR. PHYTOSYNTHESIS SEEMS TO
STEM BACK TO ONE
LINEAGE. BUT IT'S HARD TO SAY, YOU KNOW, IF
THERE WERE
EVOLUTION-, IF THERE WERE OTHER TRIAL BALLOONS
OUT THERE THAT
JUST DIDN'T SUCCEED AND THEY WERE OUT COMPETED.
IT'S DIFFICULT.
I MEAN THERE MAY HAVE BEEN MORE THAN ONE ORIGIN
OF LIFE ON EARTH.
AS FAR AS WE CAN TELL THERE'S JUST ONE LINEAGE
OF LIFE AND ALL
LIVING ORGANISMS DESCEND FROM THAT COMMON
ANCESTOR. BUT THERE
COULD HAVE BEEN A LOT OF DIFFERENT, YOU KNOW,
LIVING OR
SEMI-LIVING, WHATEVER YOU WANT TO CALL THEM,
TYPES OF THINGS OUT
THERE THAT COULDN'T COMPETE WITH THE ORGANISM
THAT GAVE RISE TO
LIFE.
STUDENT: [INAUDIBLE]
PROFESSOR: WELL, THAT ALL THE PHOTOSYNTHETIC
EUKARYOTES HAVE
CAPTURED THE CYANOBACTER-, RESULT FROM AN
EVENT, THIS
ENDOSYMBIOTIC EVENT WHERE CYANOBACTERIA WERE
CAPTURED. AND THIS
BASICALLY, THIS TREE ENCOMPASSES ALL OF THE
MAIN LINEAGES OF
EUKARYOTIC ORGANISMS THAT DESCEND FROM THAT
EVENT. AND THAT
INCLUDES ALL OF THE PHOTOSYNTHETIC ORGANISMS.
THE GREEN ALGAE,
AS I'LL POINT OUT LATER, ULTIMATELY GAVE RISE
TO LAND PLANTS.
SO THIS IS, THIS IS PRETTY MUCH IT. SO IT
REALLY DOES LOOK LIKE
ONE EVENT THAT GAVE RISE TO, TO ALL THE PHOTOSYNTHETIC
ORGANISMS
THAT WE CALL ALGAE OR LAND PLANTS. SO AGAIN,
WE HAVE THIS MAJOR
DIVERGENCE BETWEEN THIS FIRST MAJOR SPLIT
BETWEEN EUKARYOTIC
PHOTOSYNTHETIC ORGANISMS, RED ALGAE ON THE
ONE HAND AND GREEN
ALGAE ON THE OTHER. AND WE'LL TALK ABOUT THOSE
GROUPS IN A
LITTLE MORE DETAIL IN A MOMENT. BUT I WANT
TO, I WAS STARTING
OUT FIRST TALKING ABOUT SOME OF THESE OTHER
LINEAGES THAT
ORIGINATED FROM A SECONDARY ENDOSYMBIOSIS
OR ACQUIRED THEIR
PLASTIDS, THEIR CHLOROPLASTS BY SECONDARY
ENDOSYMBIOSIS WHERE
THEY ENGULFED A EUKARYOTIC PHOTOSYNTHETIC
ORGANISM, EITHER A
GREEN ALGA OR RED ALGA. AND THIS LEAD TO A
NUMBER OF LINEAGES.
I DIDN'T HAVE MUCH TO SAY ABOUT THIS ONE BECAUSE
IT'S PRETTY
MINOR. BUT I DID MENTION THERE'S A MAJOR LINEAGE
HERE. THE
EUGLENIDS WHICH CAPTURED THEIR CHLOROPLAST
BY CAPTURING A
UNICELLULAR GREEN EUKARYOTIC ALGAE. AND THEY
HAVE A FLAGELLUM
WHICH ALLOWS THEM TO MOVE AROUND QUICKLY LIKE
YOU CAN SEE HERE.
IT'S VERY DISTINCTIVE. IT HAS SOME CRYSTALLINE
INCLUSION IN IT
THAT YOU CAN DO A SECTION OF IT. IT'S VERY
DISTINCTIVE. THEIR
PLASTID IS VERY MUCH LIKE A GREEN ALGA, SO
THAT THAT IN ADDITION
TO THE MOLECULAR DATA MAKE IT REALLY CLEAR.
BUT MOST OF THEM
ACTUALLY CAN STILL CAPTURE PREY. THEY CAN
STILL ENGULF PREY.
AND SO IT'S, EVEN THE, YOU CAN SEE THAT THE
POTENTIAL FOR A
SECONDARY ENDOSYMBIOSIS, YOU KNOW, TO ACTUALLY
STILL ENGULF AN
ORGANISM THAT COULD POTENTIALLY BECOME A SYMBIONT
IS EVEN STILL
PRESENT IN THESE ORGANISMS, EVEN THE ONES
THAT ARE PHOTOSYNTHETIC
IN PART IN MANY CASES. OKAY. AND THEN THE
OTHER MAIN LINEAGE,
THE ONES, THE SECONDARY ENDOSYMBIONTS THAT
CAPTURE RED ALGAE
INCLUDE THESE ONES. AND I MENTIONED LAST TIME
THE
DINOFLAGELLATES, WHICH LIKE THE EUGLENIDS
ARE MAJOR COMPONENTS OF
PHYTOPLANKTON. AND REMEMBER PHYTOPLANKTON
JUST MEANS BASICALLY
PLANKTON WHICH ARE FREE-FLOATING ORGANISMS
IN AQUATIC SITUATIONS,
UNICELLULAR ONES TYPICALLY. PHYTO MEANS PLANT,
SO PHOTOSYNTHETIC
BASICALLY. SO DINOFLAGELLATES DESCEND FROM
A COMMON ANCESTOR
WITH THESE OTHER GROUPS THAT HAD A RED ALGA
INCORPORATED INTO
THEIR CELLS. AND A GOOD NUMBER OF THE DINOFLAGELLATES
ARE STILL
PHOTOSYNTHETIC. SOME OF THEM HAVE LOST THE
ABILITY TO
PHOTOSYNTHESIZE AND STRICTLY ARE HETEROTROPHIC
AND ARE ACTUALLY
PRETTY GOOD PREDATORS IN SOME CASES. BUT I
SHOWED YOU SOME
PHOTOS, OOPS, OF THESE LAST TIME. AND THEY
HAVE THIS EXTERNAL
ARMOR, THESE PLATES OF CELLULOSE. AND CELLULOSE
AGAIN IS THE
SAME CARBOHYDRATE THAT -- WE HAVEN'T GOTTEN
TO THIS YET -- BUT IN
PLANTS THE CELL WALLS, THE LAND PLANTS HAVE
CELL WALLS OF
CELLULOSE AS WELL, BUT THIS APPEARS TO BE
AN INDEPENDENT ORIGIN
OF THAT. ANYWAYS, THESE HAVE SOME INTERESTING
ECOLOGY,
ESPECIALLY IN OCEANIC SITUATIONS THAT I MENTIONED
LAST TIME WITH
THE RED TIDES AND TOXINS, BIOLUMINESCENCE.
THE OTHER REALLY
MAJOR GROUP OF PHOTOSYNTHETIC ORGANISMS THAT
DESCENDED FROM THIS
SECONDARY ENDOSYMBIOSIS INVOLVING A RED ALGA
ARE WHAT'S CALLED
THE STRAMENOPILES. AND THAT NAME'S NOT SO
IMPORTANT, BUT IT'S
BASICALLY A GROUP THAT INCLUDES A HUGE DIVERSITY
OF DIFFERENT
GROUPS OF ORGANISMS AND SEVERAL THAT ARE PHOTOSYNTHETIC
THAT
WE'VE LONG RECOGNIZED AS DISTINCT GROUPS.
BUT NOW IT'S CLEAR
THAT THEY'RE ALL VERY CLOSELY RELATED. WOOPS.
AND ONE OF
THESE IS THE DIATOMS, WHICH I JUST GOT, I
WAS JUST GETTING TO AT
THE END OF LAST LECTURE. AND THIS IS ONE OF
THE MOST DIVERSE
GROUPS OF ALGAE. THERE ARE OVER A HUNDRED
THOUSAND SPECIES
DESCRIBED. AND REMEMBER THAT'S ROUGHLY THE
SAME DIVERSITY THAT
WE SEE ACROSS ALL OF THE FUNGAL PHYLA, SO
THAT'S A HUGE NUMBER OF
TAXA. YOU KNOW IT'S, IT'S ROUGHLY A THIRD
OF WHAT WE'VE
RECOGNIZED AMONG THE FLOWERING PLANTS. SO
IT'S A HUGE AMOUNT OF
DIVERSITY. AND YOU CAN SEE, GET SOME SENSE
OF THIS DIVERSITY.
IT'S REALLY CLEAR MORPHOLOGICALLY THAT YOU'RE
DEALING WITH LOTS
OF DIFFERENT GROUPS OF ORGANISMS HERE. AND
ONE OF THE REASONS
THERE ARE SO MANY OF THEM DESCRIBED, WELL,
THERE ARE A COUPLE OF
REASONS. WELL, FOR ONE THING, THEY'RE INCREDIBLY
ABUNDANT. YOU
FIND THEM IN HUGE NUMBERS. IF YOU JUST TAKE
A SCOOP OF SEA WATER
OR LAKE WATER IN DIFFERENT AQUATIC SETTINGS
OR MARINE SETTINGS,
YOU CAN FIND LARGE NUMBERS OF DIATOMS TYPICALLY
AND A LOT OF
DIVERSITY. BUT THEY ALSO ARE MORPHOLOGICALLY
DIFFERENTIATED
OFTENTIMES BY THEIR CELL WALLS, WHICH YOU
CAN SEE ARE REALLY
EXTENSIVELY ORNAMENTED. AND THERE ARE MANY
DIFFERENT SHAPES AND
SIZES OF THESE THINGS IN TERMS OF DIFFERENT
TAXA. AND THESE
CELL WALLS ARE REALLY AMAZING BECAUSE THEY'RE
ACTUALLY LARGELY
MADE UP OF, OF HYDRATED SILICA LIKE GLASS,
AND THEY PRESERVE
REALLY WELL THEN IN THE FOSSIL RECORD. THEY'RE
INERT. AND WE
HAVE AN EXCELLENT FOSSIL RECORD OF DIATOMS
THAT GOES WAY BACK.
AND PALEOBOTANISTS THAT WORK IN THIS GROUP
HAVE LOTS OF STORIES
TO TELL FROM THE FOSSIL RECORD, USUALLY REALLY
RICH AND PRETTY
COMPLETE RECORDS. THERE'S ALSO EXTENSIVE DEPOSITS
OF
DIATOMACEOUS EARTH IT'S CALLED THAT'S REALLY
VALUABLE. IT'S
MINED EXTENSIVELY WHERE YOU FIND THESE DEPOSITS
OF DIATOM
SKELETONS AND USED FOR FILTRATE AND A WIDE
VARIETY OF PURPOSES.
BUT THERE'S ONE REALLY HUGE DEPOSIT DOWN IN
SANTA BARBARA COUNTY
NEAR LOMPOC. IF YOU EVER DOWN IN THAT AREA,
THEY'VE BEEN MINING
THAT FOR MANY DECADES. AND ONE OF THE MOST
IMPORTANT THINGS
ABOUT DIATOMS IS THAT THEY MAY ACCOUNT FOR
UP TO 25 PERCENT OF
THE PHOTOSYNTHESIS, THE PRIMARY PRODUCTIVITY
THAT'S GOING ON ON
EARTH. SO THEY'RE PUMPING OUT A HUGE AMOUNT
OF OXYGEN. THEY'RE
CAPTURING A LOT OF CO2. AND THEY'RE CONSIDERED
TO BE ONE OF THE
CRUCIAL ORGANISMS FOR MAINTAINING ATMOSPHERIC
CO2 AT A REASONABLE
LEVEL. SO THERE HAVE BEEN PROPOSALS TO ACTUALLY
TRY TO INCREASE
THE NUMBER OF DIATOMS IN THE OCEAN BY DUMPING
LARGE AMOUNTS OF
IRON INTO THE OCEAN. BUT SO FAR THAT HASN'T
HAPPENED BECAUSE
THESE MAJOR TYPES OF ECOSYSTEM INTERVENTIONS
LIKE THAT SOMETIMES
HAVE UNFORESEEN CONSEQUENCES, AND IT'S NOT
QUITE CLEAR WHAT THAT
MIGHT END UP RESULTING IN. YOU KNOW, THE NEGATIVE
IMPACTS MIGHT
OUTWEIGH THE POSITIVE ONES. BUT ONE OF THE
THINGS THAT DIATOMS
DO THAT'S IMPORTANT IN ADDITION TO FIXING
CO2 IS THAT WHEN THEY
DIE, THEY TEND TO SINK. AND SO THEY ACTUALLY
END UP ON THE
OCEAN FLOOR. AND BY DOING THAT, THEY TAKE
THAT CARBON OUT OF
THE ECOSYSTEM ESSENTIALLY. AND SO THAT CARBON'S
NOT
RECIRCULATING BACK INTO THE ATMOSPHERE. AND
SO THEY CAN REALLY
STORE A LOT OF, THEY CAN TAKE CARBON OUT OF
THE SYSTEM WHICH
WOULD BE A REALLY VALUABLE THING RIGHT NOW.
OKAY, AND ONE OF
THE STRANGEST THINGS ABOUT THESE GUYS IS THAT
THESE ARE
UNICELLULAR TYPICALLY. SOMETIMES THEY'LL BE
IN FILAMENTS, BUT
THEY'RE SEPARATE CELLS, SEPARATE ORGANISMS.
AND AS YOU CAN MAYBE
MAKE OUT HERE, NOT VERY WELL, THEY ARE, THEIR
CELL WALL IS
BASICALLY LIKE TWO HALVES OF A PETRI DISH
WITH ONE-HALF INSIDE
THE OTHER ONE. AND SO WHEN THEY ACTUALLY GO
TO REPRODUCE, IT'S
PRETTY BIZARRE. BUT, I SHOULD MENTION FIRST
OF ALL THAT THEY
ACTUALLY HAVE AN ANIMAL-LIKE LIFE CYCLE IN
TERMS OF THE, THE TYPE
OF, WELL, THAT THE FACT THAT THERE'S ONLY,
THE ONLY HAPLOID STAGE
IS THE GAMETES, SO THEY'RE JUST LIKE US THAT
WAY. THE MATURE
DIATOM IS DIPLOID. AND THEY HAVE, BASICALLY
FERTILIZATION
HAPPENS RIGHT AFTER MEIOSIS LIKE IT DOES WITH
US. THOUGH THAT'S
AN INTERESTING DIFFERENCE FROM OTHER GROUPS.
THEY ALSO
REPRODUCE BY SEMI-CONSERVATIVE REPLICATION
IN A SENSE. IT'S
ALMOST LIKE DNA REPLICATION IN THE SENSE THAT
THEY'RE, EACH HALF
OF THEIR SHELL, THEY MOSTLY ASEXUALLY REPRODUCE
WITHOUT SEX,
MOSTLY. BUT WHEN THEY ASEXUALLY REPRODUCE,
THE TWO HALVES OF THE
SHELL SEPARATE AND A NEW HALF FOR EACH ONE
OF THOSE HALVES IS
CREATED INSIDE THE OLD ONE. SO IF YOU'RE CREATING
NEW SHELLS
INSIDE THE OLD HALF ALL THE TIME, AT LEAST
SOME OF THE LINEAGES
ARE GOING TO GET TO BE PROGRESSIVELY SMALLER
THROUGH TIME. AND
THAT DECREASE IN SIZE OF COURSE IS GOING TO
REACH A CRITICAL
THRESHOLD AT SOME POINT. AND ROUGHLY AROUND
THAT TIME, THESE
LINEAGES ARE STIMULATED TO START PRODUCING
GAMETES. AND THEY
UNDERGO SEXUAL REPRODUCTION WHEN THEY GET
TOO SMALL. AND THEY
RELEASE THEIR GAMETES. THE TWO HALVES OF THE
SHELL SEPARATE,
RELEASE THE GAMETES WHICH HAVE BEEN PRODUCED
OF COURSE BY MEIOSIS
BECAUSE THEY'RE DIPLOID ADULT ORGANISMS. THE
GAMETES GET
TOGETHER WITH THOSE OF OTHER INDIVIDUALS,
MAKE A ZYGOTE, AND THEN
THAT DEVELOPS INTO A NEW DIPLOID FULLY-SIZED
DIATOM. SO THAT'S
ONE OF THE REALLY INTERESTING THINGS ABOUT
DIATOM REPRODUCTION.
OKAY, SO ARE THERE ANY QUESTIONS ABOUT DIATOMS?
YEAH?
STUDENT: [INAUDIBLE]
PROFESSOR: WELL, DIATOMACEOUS EARTH IS USED
INDUSTRIALLY FOR
LOTS OF DIFFERENT PURPOSES. IT'S AN ABRASIVE.
IT CAN BE USED
AS AN ABRASIVE. I MEAN IT IS, YOU KNOW, SILICA
IS INVOLVED.
AND IT'S ALSO, WELL, THERE'S, YEAH, IT GOES
ON AND ON. BUT IT,
IT'S USED AS A FILTRATE. THE DIATOMS HAVE,
YOU KNOW THEY'RE SO
TINY, AND THERE'S SOME POROSITY TO THEIR SKELETONS,
I MEAN TO
THEIR CELL WALLS. SO IT'S, YEAH, THERE'S A
WIDE RANGE OF USES.
BUT, YEAH, IT'S HARVESTED ON A MASS SCALE.
I MEAN IT'S MINED ON
A LARGE SCALE FOR A NUMBER OF DIFFERENT INDUSTRIAL
USES. OKAY,
SO THE DIATOMS ARE JUST ONE GROUP OF STRAMENOPILES,
THAT ONE
CLADE I MENTIONED THAT HAS QUITE A FEW PHOTOSYNTHETIC
ORGANISMS
IN IT. ANOTHER ONE OF THE GOLDEN ALGAE, AND
THESE ARE ALSO
UNICELLULAR OR COLONIAL, BUT THEY'RE MOSTLY
IN FRESHWATER.
DIATOMS ARE EITHER FRESH OR SEA WATER. BUT
THEY'RE CALLED GOLDEN
I JUST WANT TO MENTION BECAUSE THEY HAVE THIS
GOLDEN APPEARANCE
BECAUSE THEY HAVE THESE, THESE ACCESSORY PIGMENTS
IN THEIR
PLASTIDS IN ADDITION TO CHLOROPHYL THAT ARE
USEFUL FOR CAPTURING
LIGHT AT WAVE LENGTHS THAT PENETRATE WATER
WELL. AND THAT'S
SOMETHING THAT WE ALSO SEE IN THEIR CLOSE
RELATIVES THE BROWN
ALGAE WHICH ARE MOSTLY MARINE. ALMOST ALL
OF THEM ARE FOUND IN
THE OCEAN. AND THEY ALSO HAVE THIS YELLOWISH
OR BROWNISH COLOR
FROM THESE ACCESSORY PIGMENTS. WELL, IT USED
TO BE THOUGHT THAT
THESE ARE PRETTY CLOSELY RELATED TO LAND PLANTS
BECAUSE THEY HAVE
PRETTY SIMILAR MORPHOLOGY AND SOME OF THEM
HAVE SIMILAR LIFE
CYCLES. BUT NOW WE KNOW THAT THESE ARE ACTUALLY
A COMPLETELY
DISTINCT LINEAGE OF EUKARYOTES THAT HAVE CAPTURED
PLASTIDS. YOU
KNOW, THEY DESCEND FROM A COMMON ANCESTOR
WITH THE DIATOMS, THE
GOLDENS. AND EVEN THE DINOFLAGELLATES THAT
CAPTURED A RED ALGA,
HAVE AN ANCESTOR THAT CAPTURED A RED ALGA,
THEY DON'T DESCEND
FROM THE GREEN ALGAL LINEAGE. AND THIS INCLUDES
SOME OF OUR
REALLY SIGNIFICANT AND LARGE KELPS. WE FIND
THESE WORLDWIDE, BUT
OFF OUR COAST WE HAVE SOME OF THE MOST SPECTACULAR
MEMBERS THAT
BOTH IN THE INTERTIDAL REGION UP IN THE WAVES,
THE WAVE-CRASHING
ZONE AS WELL AS OUT IN DEEP WATER. SO UP IN
THE INTERTIDAL ZONE,
IF YOU'VE BEEN OUT ALONG OUR COAST, THIS NORTH
COAST IN SOME OF
THE ROUGHEST AREAS OF THE INTERTIDAL ZONE
WHERE THE WAVES ARE
CONSTANTLY BREAKING AGAINST ROCKS, YOU MIGHT
HAVE SEEN THESE
THINGS. THEY LOOK LIKE LITTLE PALM TREES OUT
THERE. THIS IS THE
SEA PALM IT'S CALLED, POSTELSIA PALMAEFORMIS,
WHICH IS ACTUALLY
EDIBLE. I'VE EATEN THIS. IT'S PRETTY GOOD.
BUT IT'S ONLY
HARVESTED ON A LOW, ON A MINOR SCALE. BUT
IT DEMONSTRATES FIRST
THAT SOME OF THE FEATURES OF KELPS THAT LOOK
VERY MUCH LIKE THAT
ARE LAND PLANTS. FIRST OF ALL LOOK AT THIS
THING. IT LOOKS
VERY TREE-LIKE. IT HAS BLADES UP HERE THAT
ARE HIGHLY PACKED
WITH PLASTIDS WHERE WE GET A LOT THE PHOTOSYNTHESIS
OCCURRING.
THEY LOOK VERY MUCH LIKE LEAVES OF THE FLOWERING
PLANT. THAT'S
CONVERGENT EVOLUTION, AND THERE'S NO CLOSE
RELATIONSHIP. THEY
ALSO HAVE A STEM-LIKE STIPE OR STOCK HERE
THAT LOOKS VERY
STEM-LIKE BUT THAT'S COMPLETELY CONVERGENT
AS WELL. AND THEY
HAVE A HOLDFAST THAT AFFIXES THEM TO THE SUBSTRATE,
AND THAT'S
ALSO, THEY LOOK ROOT-LIKE, BUT THAT'S NOT
WHAT THAT IS. IT'S
AN, IT'S BASICALLY AN ATTACHMENT STRUCTURE
RATHER THAN A
CONDUCTING STRUCTURE. AND THESE THINGS CAN
WITHSTAND WAVES
CRASHING AGAINST THEM THAT WOULD TEAR ANY,
ANY OTHER UPRIGHT
ORGANISM APART. AND VARIOUS BIOMECHANICISTS
THAT HAVE BEEN
INTERESTED IN THE, THE WAY THAT ORGANISMS
CAN SURVIVE IN THIS
ZONE WHERE YOU HAVE THE WAVES CRASHING AGAINST
THEM CONSTANTLY
CAN'T REALLY EASILY ACCOUNT FOR THESE GUYS
BECAUSE THEY BREAK ALL
THE RULES. AND THEY SHOULDN'T BE ABLE TO WITHSTAND
THESE, THESE
IMPACTS. BUT ONE OF THE THINGS THAT'S IMPORTANT
IN THIS REGARD
IS THAT THEIR CELL WALLS ARE BATHED IN THIS
GEL-LIKE
POLYSACCHARIDES, THIS KIND OF MUCILAGINOUS
POLYSACCHARIDE WHICH
IS FOUND ACROSS THE BROWN ALGAE. AND ALSO
WE'LL SHOW LATER IN
THE RED ALGAE AS WELL THOUGH IT'S DIFFERENT
BIOCHEMICALLY THERE.
BUT THESE MUCILAGINOUS POLYSACCHARIDES GIVE
THIS THING A LOT OF
FLEXIBILITY AND STRENGTH. AND IT'S ONE OF
THE MORE INTERESTING
INTERTIDAL ORGANISMS. BUT OUT AT THE OTHER
END OF THE SPECTRUM
WE GET THESE KELPS GROWING IN WATER UP TO
200 FEET DEEP, SO IN
REALLY DEEP WATER. HERE YOU CAN SEE ONE OF
OUR COASTAL FORESTS
OF KELP. AND THESE ARE KEYSTONE ORGANISMS
ECOLOGICALLY. THEY
PROVIDE BASICALLY A FOREST-LIKE ENVIRONMENT
OUT IN THE OCEAN THAT
PROVIDES COVER, YOU KNOW NURSERY GROUND, A
FEEDING AREA FOR A
WIDE VARIETY OF VERTEBRATES AND INVERTEBRATES.
SO THESE KELP
FOREST WE HAVE OFF OUR COAST ARE, YOU KNOW,
BASICALLY ARE
FUNDAMENTAL ELEMENTS OF THIS UNUSUAL ECOSYSTEM
WE HAVE HERE ALONG
OUR PACIFIC COAST. AND A LOT OF THESE BIG
KELPS THAT ARE OUT IN
DEEP WATER, THEY HAVE FLOATS NEAR THEIR BLADES
THAT SERVE TO BUOY
THEIR LEAVES OR THEIR BLADES UP IN THE UPPER
WATER LAYERS WHERE
THEY'RE MORE IN CLOSER PROXIMITY TO OR THEY
HAVE MORE
AVAILABILITY TO LIGHT. SO THEY HAVE A NUMBER
OF INTERESTING
ADAPTATIONS THAT, FOR A NUMBER OF DIFFERENT
KINDS OF
ENVIRONMENTS. AND THEY'RE A REALLY DIVERSE
GROUP BOTH ON OUR
COAST AND ELSEWHERE. OKAY, SO THOSE ARE THE
BROWN ALGAE. FOR
THE RED ALGAE YOU MIGHT, YOU'RE PROBABLY FAMILIAR
WITH THESE TOO.
THEY OFTEN WASH UP ON THE BEACH JUST LIKE
THE BROWNS. AND WE
CAN FIND THEM FROM THE INTERTIDAL ZONE DOWN
INTO MUCH DEEPER
WATER THAN WHERE WE FIND THE BROWN ALGAE.
THESE GUYS CAN GET
INTO WATER THAT'S ALMOST A THOUSAND FEET DEEP,
I MEAN WHERE LIGHT
CAN BARELY PENETRATE. SO THAT'S, THESE ARE
REALLY EXTRAORDINARY
IN TERMS OF THEIR ECOLOGICAL RANGE IN THE
OCEAN. AND WE FIND
THE MOST DIVERSITY OF THESE ONES IN THE, IN
THE TROPICAL OCEANS,
BUT THEY'RE ALSO WELL-REPRESENTED ALONG OUR
COAST, AND WE HAVE A
LOT OF DIVERSITY. THEY HAVE INCREDIBLY COMPLEX
LIFE CYCLES.
AND I WON'T, WE WON'T EVEN ATTEMPT TO TRY
TO TEACH YOU THE LIFE
CYCLES OF RED ALGAE BECAUSE THEY HAVE VARIOUS
STAGES. IT'S,
THEY'RE REAL BRAIN TEASERS AS FAR AS TRYING
TO FIGURE OUT HOW IT
ALL WORKS. BUT THERE'S BIZARRE THINGS THAT
HAPPEN. THERE'S
SOME RED ALGAE THAT ACTUALLY WILL PARASITIZE
OTHER RED ALGAE.
THEY HAVE STRANGE ECOLOGY. BUT AS YOU GET
INTO DEEPER WATER, UP
IN THE SHALLOW WATER, THEY TEND TO BE MORE
GREENISH IN
COLORATION, LIKE THE NORI THAT YOU'RE PROBABLY
FAMILIAR WITH FROM
SUSHI, PORPHYRA WHICH IS HARVESTED FROM SHALLOW
WATER AND IS USED
TO WRAP SUSHI IN JAPANESE CUISINE. AS YOU
GET OUT INTO DEEPER
WATER, THEY TEND TO BE MORE REDDISH. AND THAT'S,
THERE'S A GOOD
REASON FOR THAT REDDISHNESS AND THAT IS THAT
WHEN YOU GET OUT
INTO DEEP WATER, HERE YOU CAN SEE THE DEGREE
TO WHICH LIGHT
PENETRATES IN THE OCEAN AND BREAKING IT OUT
BY THE DIFFERENT
COLORS OF LIGHT. AND WHEN YOU GET DOWN BELOW
ABOUT 125 METERS
IN DEPTH, YOU'RE PRETTY MUCH JUST CAP-, YOU'RE
JUST GETTING THE
PENETRATION OF BLUE AND GREEN LIGHT DOWN HERE.
AND SO THIS IS,
THESE ARE THE WAVE LENGTHS THAT THESE ORGANISMS
CAN UTILIZE WHEN
THEY'RE IN THE DEEPER WATER. AND SO THEY TEND
TO, THEY HAVE
ACCESSORY PIGMENTS THAT APPEAR RED BECAUSE
THEY'RE REFLECTING RED
LIGHT. THEY'RE NOT ABSORBING RED LIGHT, THEY'RE
REFLECTING
IT. THEY'RE ABSORBING BLUES AND GREENS. AND
THESE ARE
PHYCOERYTHRINS. THE NAME'S NOT IMPORTANT,
BUT THERE ARE
ACCESSORY PIGMENTS IN THE PLASTIDS ALONG WITH
THE CHLOROPHYL AND
THEY'RE MASKING THE CHLOROPHYL COLOR. CHLOROPHYL
ALSO HAS A HIGH
ABSORPTION IN THE BLUE END OF THE SPECTRUM
HERE, BUT ALSO IN THE
RED PART OF THE SPECTRUM AS YOU CAN SEE HERE.
THE PHYCOERYTHRINS
ARE, HAVE THEIR ABSORPTION OF LIGHT UP IN
THIS AREA, SO THEY
AUGMENT THAT AND LEAD TO A LOT MORE PHOTOSYNTHESIS
THAN WOULD
OCCUR OTHERWISE AT THOSE DEEPER DEPTHS. SO
THAT'S WHAT'S GOING
ON WITH THE RED ALGAE.
OKAY, SO FINALLY NOW THE GREEN ALGAE.
AND WE'RE GOING TO BASICALLY BE TALKING ABOUT
GREEN ORGANISMS FOR
THE REST OF THE COURSE. ARE THERE ANY QUESTIONS
ABOUT ANY OF
THE OTHER GROUPS WE JUST TALKED ABOUT? OKAY.
SO THE GREEN
ALGAE HAVE A WIDE VARIETY OF DIFFERENT FORMS
AND ULTRA-STRUCTURAL
MORPHOLOGICAL VARIATION. THERE'S A LOT OF
DIFFERENT ECOLOGI-, A
NUMBER OF DIFFERENT LIFE CYCLES AMONG THE
GREEN ALGAE. IT'S A
REALLY DIVERSE GROUP. BUT THESE ALL SEEM TO
STEM FROM THAT
PRIMARY ENDOSYMBIOSIS THAT INVOLVE THE CAPTURING
OF THE
CYANOBACTERIUM. AND THEY DESCEND FROM A COMMON
ANCESTOR WITH
THE RED ALGAE THAT ALSO DIVERGE FROM THAT
COMMON ANCESTOR THAT
HAD ACQUIRED ITS PHOTOSYNTHETIC ABILITY FROM
THAT PRIMARY
ENDOSYMBIOSIS. AND THEY RANGE FROM UNICELLULAR
ORGANISMS LIKE
THE CHLAMYDOMONAS WHICH IS A MODEL ORGANISM
HERE. YOU CAN SEE
THE TWO FLAGELLAE UP AT, AT THE APEX OF ITS
CELLS HERE. THAT'S
AN SEM. IT'S ACTUALLY GREEN. IN THIS IT'S
JUST IN BLACK AND
WHITE. AND HERE YOU CAN SEE COLONIAL GREEN
ALGA, VOLVOX.
THESE VOLVACALEANS ARE REALLY COOL. THEY MOVE
THROUGH THE WATER
AS A BIG SPHERICAL COLONY AND PRODUCE ADDITIONAL
SPHERICAL
DAUGHTER COLONIES INSIDE. THE CELLS CAN LIVE
SEPARATELY, BUT
THEY CAN'T REPRODUCE SEPARATELY, SO THESE
ARE REAL TRUE COLONIAL
ORGANISMS. AND THEN WE HAVE MULTICELLULAR
GREEN ALGAE LIKE THE
SEA LETTUCE HERE, ULVA, ONE OF THE SEAWEEDS.
SO THERE ARE
SEAWEEDS AMONG THE GREEN ALGAE TOO. AND THEY
OCCUR IN BOTH
FRESHWATER, I SHOULD SAY GREEN ALGAE OCCUR
IN BOTH FRESHWATER AND
MARINE SITUATIONS, DIFFERENT TAXA. THEY ALSO
OCCUR IN HIGH
ELEVATION SNOWFIELDS. AND IF YOU'VE BEEN HIKING
UP IN THE HIGH
SIERRA DURING THE SUMMER TIME AND YOU FIND,
YOU SEE SOME
SNOWFIELD THAT LOOKS RED, THAT'S NOT SOME
SORT OF AIR POLLUTION
OR SOMETHING THAT'S CAUSED THAT OR SOME SORT
OF A POLLUTANT, BUT
IT'S ACTUALLY THIS ORGANISM, CHLAMYDOMONAS
NIVALIS, WHICH IS A
CHLAMYDOMONAS LIKE THESE THAT HAS ACCESSORY
RED PIGMENTS AND
WHICH IS WHAT WE CALL CRYOPHILIC. IT LOVES
EXCEEDINGLY COLD
WATER, SO IT LIVES IN THE SNOW MELT FROM THE
SNOW THERE. SO
THERE'S A HUGE ECOLOGICAL RANGE IN THESE THINGS,
ACROSS THE GREEN
ALGAE THAT IS. OKAY, SO BEFORE GOING INTO
THE ORIGIN OF LAND
PLANTS, I JUST WANT TO TALK BRIEFLY ABOUT
THIS MAJOR TYPE OF LIFE
CYCLE THAT HAS A NICE REPRESENTATIVE IN THESE
GUYS, THE ULVAS,
THE SEA LETTUCES. AND IT'S ALSO THE TYPE OF
LIFE CYCLE WE SEE
IN ALL THE LAND PLANTS, EVERY ONE. BUT IT'S
BEEN INDEPENDENTLY
EVOLVED IN THOSE TWO GROUPS AS I'LL POINT
OUT IN A MINUTE. BUT
ULVA SHOWS THIS TYPE OF LIFE CYCLE WELL, SO
WE'LL TALK ABOUT,
TALK ABOUT IT IN THIS CONTEXT FIRST. SO WE'VE
ALREADY TALKED
ABOUT GAMETIC LIFE CYCLE WHERE THE GAMETE
IS THE ONLY HAPLOID
STAGE, LIKE IN THE CASE OF US AND THE DIATOMS.
AND WE TALKED
ABOUT A ZYGOTIC LIFE CYCLE AS IN THE FUNGI
WHERE THE ZYGOTE IS
THE ONLY DIPLOID PHASE, THE ONLY DIPLOID STAGE.
IN THOSE TWO
CASES MITOSIS IS ONLY OCCURRING IN ONE OF
THE TWO STAGES.
WHEREAS IN AN ALTERNATION OF GENERATIONS WE
HAVE MITOSIS
OCCURRING IN BOTH THE HAPLOID STAGE AND THE
DIPLOID STAGE. AND
THAT RESULTS IN SEPARATE MULTICELLULAR ORGANISMS
THAT ARE HAPLOID
AND THAT ARE DIPLOID IN THE SAME SPECIES.
AND THESE DIFFERENT
MULTICELLULAR ORGANISMS, HAPLOID AND DIPLOID,
ARE ALTERNATING
GENERATION AFTER GENERATION. THIS IS KIND
OF A BIZARRE CONCEPT
THAT YOU WOULD ACTUALLY HAVE TWO DIFFERENT
KINDS OF ORGANISMS IN
THE SAME SPECIES THAT DIFFER IN THEIR PLOIDY
AND THEIR CHROMOSOME
NUMBER. AND ONE OF THEM, THE GAMETOPHYTE WHICH
IS THE HAPLOID
ORGANISM -- PHYTE LITERALLY MEANS PLANT --
GAMETOPHYTE REFERS TO
THE GAMETE PRODUCING PLANT, OKAY, AND SINCE
THIS IS A HAPLOID
ORGANISM, GAMETOPHYTES ARE ALWAYS HAPLOID,
THAT MEANS THEY'RE
GOING TO BE PRODUCING THEIR GAMETES BY MITOSIS,
NOT MEIOSIS LIKE
IN US. SO WE PRODUCE OUR GAMETES BY MEIOSIS.
REMEMBER GAMETES
ARE HAPLOID. WE'RE DIPLOID. WE HAVE TO PRODUCE
OUR GAMETES BY
MEIOSIS WHICH RESULTS IN A REDUCTION IN THE
CHROMOSOME CONT-, YOU
KNOW, IN HALVING OF THE GENOME CONTENT. BUT
GAMETOPHYTES ARE
ALREADY HAPLOID. THEY, THEY GERMINATE DIRECTLY
FROM SPORES,
HAPLOID SPORES. AND SO MITOSIS PRODUCE, PRODUCES
GAMETES THAT
ARE GENETICALLY IDENTICAL TO THE PARENT GAMETOPHYTE.
THOSE
GAMETES FUSE OF COURSE LIKE ANY FERTILIZATION
EVENT. AND THEN
WE HAVE A ZYGOTE, NOT SHOWN HERE, BUT THERE'D
BE A ZYGOTE, OF
COURSE. AND THEN THAT WOULD UNDERGO MITOSES
TO GIVE RISE TO
WHAT'S CALLED THE SPOROPHYTE, WHICH MEANS
LITERALLY THE
SPORE-PRODUCING PLANT, AND IT'S DIPLOID. SPOROPHYTES
ARE ALWAYS
DIPLOID. THEY ALWAYS PRODUCE SPORES, NOT GAMETES.
EVEN THOUGH
THEY'RE DIPLOID, THEY DON'T PRODUCE GAMETES.
THEY PRODUCE SPORES
BY MEIOSIS. BUT THE IMPORTANT THING TO NOT
TO GET CONFUSED ABOUT
HERE, YOU KNOW, WE THINK OF OURSELVES AS DIPLOID
ORGANISMS
UNDERGOING MEIOSIS TO PRODUCE GAMETES. THAT'S
NOT WHAT HAPPENS
IN LAND PLANTS OR IN SOME OF THE GREEN ALGAE.
MEIOSIS GIVES RISE
TO SPORES. AND REMEMBER SPORES, UNLIKE GAMETES,
THEY DON'T FUSE
TOGETHER WITH ONE ANOTHER. THEY JUST GERMINATE
TO PRODUCE A NEW
ORGANISM, WHICH OF COURSE WOULD BE HAPLOID
AFTER MEIOSIS. SO
THAT'S THE LIFE CYCLE. WE HAVE THIS MULTICELLULAR
ORGANISM
THAT'S HAPLOID AS WELL AS THE MULTICELLULAR
ORGANISM THAT'S
DIPLOID. ARE THERE ANY QUESTIONS ABOUT THAT?
OKAY, LET'S LOOK
AT AN EXAMPLE NOW WITH ULVA. OH, SORRY.
STUDENT: [INAUDIBLE].
PROFESSOR: EXACTLY. IT'S EXACTLY THE SAME
AS FERTILIZATION. I
DIDN'T ACTUALLY MAKE THIS SLIDE. IT'S FROM
YOUR BOOK, BUT IF I
HAD WRITTEN IT, I WOULD HAVE WRITTEN FERTILIZATION
THERE BECAUSE
EVERYBODY KNOWS THAT TERM. BUT SYNGAMY JUST
MEANS FUSION OF
GAMETES. "SYN" JUST MEANS FUSION OR FUSE.
AND "GAMY" IS,
REFERS TO GAMETES. THEY'RE IDENTICAL, THEY'RE
SYNONYMOUS TERMS.
STUDENT: [INAUDIBLE].
PROFESSOR: WELL, YEAH, GOOD POINT. THIS, THIS
LIFE CYCLE IN
ITS ESSENCE RIGHT HERE, THIS PARTICULAR SLIDE
IS REALLY AN
IMPORTANT ONE BECAUSE THIS REALLY BOILS IT
DOWN TO ITS, TO THE
ESSENCE OF WHAT THE ALTERNATION OF GENERATIONS
IS. THE ONLY
THING THAT'S NOT SHOWN HERE THAT REALLY SHOULD
HAVE BEEN INCLUDED
WAS THE ZYGOTE AFTER SYNGAMY. BUT YOU KNOW
I THINK JUST
REMEMBER THAT AFTER FERTILIZATION, YOU GET
A ZYGOTE HERE. BUT
THIS IS THE LIFE CYCLE WE'RE GOING TO BE SEEING
THE REST OF THE
SEMESTER. AND IT HAS VARIOUS EMBELLISHMENTS
IN DIFFERENT
GROUPS. AND SO IT'S REALLY IMPORTANT TO GET
THIS DOWN ASAP
AFTER THE EXAM TONIGHT, OF COURSE. I'M NOT
GOING TO, YOU KNOW,
YOU PROBABLY DON'T WANT TO CLOUD YOUR MIND
WITH IT RIGHT NOW.
BUT AFTER THE EXAM, YOU KNOW, REALLY GET THIS
DOWN BECAUSE I MEAN
IN TERMS OF THESE MAJOR COMPONENTS, BECAUSE
THIS IS WHAT WE'RE
GOING TO BE LOOKING AT FROM NOW ON, OKAY.
SO I JUST CAN'T
EMPHASIZE ENOUGH HOW IMPORTANT THIS IS. AND
THE REASON I WANT
TO SHOW YOU AN EXAMPLE IN THE SEA LETTUCE,
ULVA, IS BECAUSE THIS
IS ONE OF THE SIMPLEST ALTERNATION OF GENERATIONS
THAT THERE IS.
ESSENTIALLY EXACTLY LIKE THAT OTHER SLIDE
I JUST SHOWED YOU.
AND WHY I SAY IT'S SIMPLE IS BECAUSE IT'S
WHAT WE CALL AN ICE --
THIS TERM ISN'T IMPORTANT, BUT IT'S WHAT WE
CALL AN ISOMORPHIC
ALTERNATION OF GENERATIONS WHERE THE SPOROPHYTE
AND THE
GAMETOPHYTE LOOK IDENTICAL. ISOMORPHIC, ISO
MEANS THE SAME.
MORPHIC, THE SAME MORPHOLOGY FOR BOTH THE
SPOROPHYTE AND THE
GAMETOPHYTE. THOUGH WE HAVE THE SPOROPHYTE
HERE GIVING RISE
THROUGH MEIOSIS TO ZOOSPORES. THESE ARE ACTUALLY
MOTILE SPORES,
BUT THEY DON'T FUSE TOGETHER. THEY'RE NOT
GAMETES. THEY JUST
UNDERGO MITOSES AND END UP DEVELOPING INTO
A HAPLOID GAMETOPHYTE.
HAPLOID GAMETOPHYTE PRODUCES HAPLOID GAMETES
BY MITOSIS. THESE
ARE GENETICALLY IDENTICAL TO THE HAPLOID GAMETOPHYTE.
AND THEN
THEY FUSE TOGETHER TO PRODUCE THE ZYGOTE.
AND THAT ZYGOTE THEN
AFTER MITOSES AND DEVELOPMENT, BECOMES A DIPLOID
SPOROPHYTE. SO
THE ONLY WAY TO REALLY TELL THESE APART IS
IF YOU DID A
CHROMOSOME COUNT. AND YOU CAN SEE THAT THIS
HAS TWICE AS MANY
CHROMOSOMES AS THIS DOES, THESE TWO GENERATIONS.
ALSO IF YOU
LOOKED AT THEIR REPRODUCTIVE STRUCTURES, THIS
IS PRODUCING
SPORANGIA WHICH ARE HOLLOW SACS THAT PRODUCE
SPORES BY
DEFINITION. AND THIS, THE GAMETOPHYTE PRODUCES
GAMETANGIA WHICH
ARE BASICALLY HOLLOW SACS THAT PRODUCE GAMETES.
SO THAT'S THE
REAL DIFFERENCE. BUT THERE'S NOT A WHOLE LOT
TO GO ON THERE.
SO THIS IS A REALLY BEAUTIFUL CASE OF A, OF
AN ALTERNATION OF
GENERATIONS WHERE THE TWO PHASES OF THE LIFE
CYCLE, WE CALL IT
THE SPOROPHYTE OR DIPLOID PHASE AND THE GAMETOPHYTE
OR HAPLOID
PHASE ARE, ARE VERY, VERY SIMILAR. YEAH?
STUDENT: [INAUDIBLE]
PROFESSOR: YEAH, THESE ARE FREE LIVING FROM
ONE ANOTHER. BUT
THAT'S A REALLY GOOD POINT BECAUSE WE'LL SEE
LATER IN THE LAND
PLANTS THAT IT'S OFTEN THE CASE THAT THE GAMETOPHYTE
OR THE
SPOROPHYTE IS DEPENDENT ON, ON ITS IMMEDIATE
PARENT. SO WE'LL
SEE PARASITISM BY ONE GENERATION ON ANOTHER
GENERATION IN A LOT
OF CASES. OKAY, SO AS FAR AS ECONOMIC IMPORTANCE
OF ALGAE, I'VE
ALREADY MENTIONED DIATOMS AND DIATOMACEOUS
EARTH. BUT THERE'S
SOME REALLY IMPORTANT COMPOUNDS THAT ARE HARVESTED
FROM BROWN
ALGAE AND RED ALGAE IN PARTICULAR. AND I THOUGHT
THEY WERE
WORTH MENTIONING. I ALREADY MENTIONED, WELL,
THERE ARE A LARGE
NUMBER OF DIFFERENT RED AND BROWN ALGAE THAT
ARE HARVESTED AS
EDIBLE SEAWEEDS USED EXTENSIVELY IN ASIAN
CUISINE. WE CAN'T
REALLY, WE CAN'T DIGEST THOSE CARBOHYDRATES,
BUT THEY'RE A GOOD
SOURCE OF MINERALS, ROUGHAGE, ET CETERA. AND
ALSO THIS IS A RED
ALGA ACTUALLY, NORI, THE ONE YOU'RE PROBABLY
THE MOST FAMILIAR
WITH. BUT THERE ARE BROWNS AS WELL THAT ARE
USED IN JAPANESE
CUISINE FOR EXAMPLE. ANOTHER COMPOUND HARVESTED
FROM RED ALGA
IS AGAR. AND AGAR OF COURSE IS USED FOR BACTER-,
FOR MICROBIAL
CULTURING IN PETRI DISHES. YOU KNOW THIS IS
OUR TYPICAL
CULTURING MEDIUM IN SCIENTIFIC STUDIES OF
MICROBES AND MOLECULAR
BIOLOGY. AND AGAROSE, A REFINED PRODUCT THERE,
IS USED IN
ELECTROPHORESIS. SO IF YOU'RE TRYING TO SEPARATE
OUT DNA
MOLECULES OF DIFFERENT SIZES, AGAROSE IS GENERALLY
THE MEDIUM
THAT'S USED FOR GEL ELECTROPHORESIS FOR LARGE
FRAGMENTS, NOT IN
DNA SEQUENCING WHERE YOU USE ACRYLAMIDE, BUT
FOR, FOR LARGER
FRAGMENTS AGAROSE IS OFTEN USED. SO THESE,
FOR MICROBIOLOGY AND
MOLECULAR BIOLOGY, RED ALGAE HAVE PROVEN TO
BE REALLY IMPORTANT.
AND THEN THE BROWN ALGAE ARE SOURCES OF THINGS
LIKE
POLYSACCHARIDES, THESE MUCILAGINOUS POLYSACCHARIDES
CARRAGEENAN AND ALGINATE THAT ARE USED AS
THICKENING AGENTS OR
EMULSIFYING AGENTS IN A WIDE VARIETY OF DIFFERENT
KINDS OF DRINKS
AND FOODS. YOU'RE CONSTANTLY INGESTING ALGINATE
AND CARRAGEENAN
IN PROCESSED FOODS. IT'S INCLUDED IN ALL KINDS
OF THINGS. I
MEAN EVEN IN BEER, TO STABILIZE THE HEAD OF
BEERS, IN A LOT OF
BEERS ALGINATE IS USED. IT'S PUT IN ICE CREAM
TO KEEP IT FROM
MELTING AS QUICKLY AS IT WOULD OTHERWISE.
I MEAN THERE'S A LOT
OF USES THAT YOU, THAT SPAN MUCH OF WHAT WE
TAKE FOR GRANTED IN
OUR FOOD THAT COMES FROM BROWN ALGAE. AND
HERE YOU CAN SEE AN
EXAMPLE IN THE MEDICAL PROFESSION OF ALGINATE
BEING USED AS THE
MAIN MEDIUM FOR DENTAL IMPRESSIONS. SO THESE
ARE REALLY
IMPORTANT SUBSTANCES THAT ARE USED IN A LOT
OF DIFFERENT WAYS.
OKAY, SO NOW WE'RE GOING TO GET INTO THE ORIGIN
OF LAND PLANTS.
AND THIS SEGUES DIRECTLY FROM ALGAE BECAUSE
THE GREEN ALGAE AS
YOU CAN SEE FROM THIS TREE HERE, HERE ARE
THE LAND PLANTS, THE
GREEN ALGAE ARE A PARAPHYLETIC GROUP. THOUGH
THE GREEN ALGAE
DON'T FORM A CLADE BY THEMSELVES. SOME GREEN
ALGAE, EXAMPLES
SHOWN HERE, ARE MORE CLOSELY RELATED TO LAND
PLANTS THAN THEY ARE
TO OTHER GREEN ALGAE. THOUGH THE SEA LETTUCE
AND SOME OF THESE
MARINE ALGAE OR THE MARINE ALGAE IN GENERAL
ARE PRETTY DISTANTLY
RELATED TO LAND PLANTS. AND THE CLOSEST RELATIVES
OF LAND
PLANTS TURN OUT TO BE FRESHWATER ALGAE, FRESHWATER
GREEN ALGAE.
SO THE MOST IMPORTANT POINT FROM THESE RESULTS,
WHICH COME BOTH
FROM MORPHOLOGICAL DATA, MOSTLY ULTRASTRUCTURAL
CHARACTERS REALLY
YOU CAN'T SEE WITH YOUR NAKED EYE, AND MOLECULAR
DATA, IS THAT
THE LAND PLANTS EVOLVE FROM FRESHWATER HABITATS.
SO THIS
CONCEPTION OF PLANTS HAVING INVADED LAND FROM
THE OCEAN IS
MISCONSTRUED BASED ON AT LEAST THE MODERN
DIVERSITY. ALL OF THE
GREEN ALGAE THAT WE KNOW OF THAT FALL OUT
IN THIS CLADE THAT'S
SISTER TO THE LAND PLANTS OCCUR IN FRESHWATER.
SO THE ANCESTOR
OF LAND PLANTS HAD TO FIRST INVADE FRESHWATER
IN THE CONTINENTAL
SETTING. AND THEN FROM THERE, THEY INVADED
TERRESTRIAL
HABITATS. AND IT MAKES A LOT OF SENSE. I MEAN
THAT'S, THAT
SORT OF TRANSITION WOULD, WOULD MAKE ECOLOGICAL
SENSE. AND THIS
IS SOMETHING THAT'S PRETTY NOW WELL ESTABLISHED.
NOW THAT THE
MOLECULAR DATA IS AVAILABLE, PEOPLE HAVE GONE
IN AND LOOKED AT
THE MORPHOLOGY MORE CLOSELY. AND THERE'S A
WHOLE LIST OF
FEATURES THAT ARE IN YOUR TEXTBOOK YOU CAN
LOOK AT, LOOK IT UP IF
YOU'D LIKE. ONE OF MOST INTERESTING ONES,
I'LL GET TO THAT IN A
MOMENT ACTUALLY. BUT ANYWAYS, THE THING THAT'S
COME OUT OF THIS
IS THAT WE REALLY CAN'T HAVE A PHYLUM CALLED
GREEN ALGAE, YOU
KNOW, THAT DOESN'T, DOESN'T WORK SINCE THEY'RE
PARAPHYLETIC.
THE LAND PLANTS APPEAR TO BE MONOPHYLETIC.
AND THESE FRESHWATER
GREEN ALGAE THAT ARE CLOSE RELATIVES ARE MONOPHYLETIC.
THESE
TAKEN TOGETHER ARE MONOPHYLETIC GROUPS, SOMETIMES
CALLED THE
STREPTOPHYTES. AND ALL OF THE GREEN PLANTS,
ALL THE GREEN
ORGANISMS NOW ARE OFTEN REFERRED TO BY BOTANISTS
AS THE GREEN
PLANTS. SO THE GREEN ALGAE PLUS THE LAND PLANTS
TOGETHER THEY
MAKE UP ONE BIG MONOPHYLETIC GROUP OF GREEN
ORGANISMS. AND
THAT'S WHAT YOU'LL OFTEN SEE REFERRED TO AS
THE GREEN PLANTS OR
VIRIDIPLANTAE. OKAY, SO ARE THERE QUESTIONS
ABOUT THAT? WELL,
HERE'S WHAT ONE OF THOSE, OH, SORRY, SO HERE
WE GO ON TO LAND.
AND HERE'S ONE OF THOSE FRESHWATER GREEN ALGAE.
THIS IS THE
GENUS CHARA THAT THE, THE PHYLUM IS NAMED
FOR, THE CHAROPHYTES
THAT ARE THE CLOSES RELATIVES OF LAND PLANTS
LIKE MOSSES. AGAIN
FRESHWATER. THESE HAVE A LIFE CYCLE THAT IS
NOT AN ALTERNATION
OF GENERATIONS. THESE CHAROPHYTES, THE ONLY
DIPLOID STAGE IN
THESE CHAROPHYTES IS THE ZYGOTE. SO THEY'RE
MORE LIKE FUNGI IN
THAT SENSE. THEY UNDERGO MEIOSIS IMMEDIATELY
AFTER
FERTILIZATION. THOUGH THE ALTERNATION OF GENERATIONS
WAS NOT
PRESENT IN THE CLOSEST, IN THE AQUATIC ANCESTORS
OF LAND PLANTS,
BUT IT'S SOMETHING THAT APPEARS TO HAVE EVOLVED
SUBSEQUENTLY.
BUT WE HAVE AN ALTERNATION OF GENERATIONS
IN ALL THE LAND PLANTS
LIKE THE MOSSES. OKAY, SO THAT'S AN IMPORTANT
POINT TO CONSIDER.
AND THESE CHAROPHYTES INCLUDE UNICELLULAR
AS WELL AS
MULTICELLULAR THINGS LIKE THIS. SO THE MULTICELLULAR
CONDITION
MAY BE INDEPENDENTLY DERIVED AS WELL IN THE
LAND PLANTS. BRAD?
STUDENT: [INAUDIBLE].
PROFESSOR: THE ALTERNATION OF GENERATIONS
THAT WE SEE IN
SOMETHING LIKE ULVA, THE SEA LETTUCE, PROBABLY
EVOLVED
SEPARATELY. SO THE ALTERNATION OF GENERATIONS
WE SEE IN LAND
PLANTS IS PROBABLY OF SEPARATE ORIGIN. AND
YOU CAN SEE IT, I'LL
SHOW YOU AS WE GO THROUGH HERE THAT WE HAVE
A REALLY NICE
PROGRESSION IN THE EVOLUTION OF THE SPOROPHYTE
GENERATION. SO
BASICALLY THE, THE MAIN ADULT BODY OF A CHAROPHYTE
WAS HAPLOID.
AND WHAT WE SEE IN THE MOSSES AND THE OTHER
PLANTS WE CALL
BRYOPHYTES, WHICH ARE THIS PART OF THE TREE
OF LAND PLANTS,
THESE ARE ALL THE LAND PLANTS HERE, THE BRYOPHYTES
HERE, THEIR
MAIN REPRO-, THEIR MAIN VEGETATIVE BODY THAT'S
PHYTOSYNTHETIC, OR
THE MAIN PHOTOSYNTHESIS AT LEAST THAT GOES
ON IN THEM, IS THE
GAMETOPHYTE IS THE HAPLOID GENERATION. AND
THE DIPLOID PHASE IS
VERY REDUCED. I SHOULDN'T SAY IT'S REDUCED.
IT'S VERY SMALL.
THESE THINGS PROBABLY, THE LAND PLANTS PROB-,
EVOLVED FROM AN
ANCESTOR THAT PROBABLY LACKED ANY SPOROPHYTE
PHASE, A DIPLOID
PHASE. AND SO WE SEE VERY, VERY SMALL LITTLE
SPOROPHYTES IN
THESE. AND WHAT WE'LL SEE AS WE GO THROUGH
HERE IS THAT THE
SPOROPHYTE GETS PROGRESSIVELY MORE COMPLEX
AND IMPORTANT IN THE
LIFE CYCLE. THAT'S A THEME IN THE LAND PLANTS
THAT WE START OUT
WITH THE GAMETOPHYTE, THE HAPLOID GENERATION
BEING DOMINANT AND
EVENTUALLY THE DIPLOID SPOROPHYTE GENERATION
BECOMES DOMINANT IN
THE LAND, IN THE VASCULAR PLANTS, WHICH ARE
THE PLANTS THAT WE
SEE MOSTLY AROUND US THAT HAVE, THAT ARE BIG
AND HAVE MAJOR
CONDUCTING TISSUE. BUT THE BRYOPHYTES INCLUDE
THE MOSSES, THE
HORNWORTS, AND THE LIVERWORTS. AND THE ENDING
WORT, W-O-R-T,
JUST MEANS HERB. IT DOESN'T MEAN SOME SORT
OF, SOME SORT OF,
YOU KNOW, LITTLE CARBUNCLE OR SOMETHING ON
THESE THINGS. THESE
THINGS HAVE, WORT IS JUST AN ENGLISH TERM
FOR A HERB AS OPPOSED
TO A WOODY PLANT. OKAY, SO THERE ARE THREE
MAJOR GROUPS OF
BRYOPHYTES AS THEY'RE CALLED. AND THE BRYOPHYTES
APPEAR TO BE
PARAPHYLETIC. WE WERE JUST SEEING HOW THE
GREEN ALGAE LOOKED
PARAPHYLETIC RELATIVE TO THE LAND PLANTS.
THE BRYOPHYTES ARE
PARAPHYLETIC RELATIVE TO THE VASCULAR PLANTS,
OKAY. AND THE
VASCULAR PLANTS INCLUDE THE FERNS, THE, ALL
THE SEED PLANTS, THE
CLUB MOSSES AND SPIKE MOSSES AND QUILLWORTS.
THESE ARE
BASICALLY ALL THE REALLY CONSPICUOUS PLANTS
THAT YOU SEE OUT IN
THE ENVIRONMENT. AND THE MOSSES, THE HORNWORTS
AND LIVERWORTS,
ARE VERY SMALL PLANTS. THEY RARELY GET OVER
15 CENTIMETERS IN
HEIGHT, YOU KNOW SOMETHING LIKE THAT. AND
THAT'S BECAUSE THEY
DON'T HAVE THE SORT OF HIGHLY REINFORCED CONDUCTING
TISSUE THAT
ALLOWS THEM TO RETAIN LARGE SIZES. BUT THEY'RE,
ANYWAYS,
THEY'RE THREE DISTINCT GROUPS THAT HAD ALREADY
STARTED TO
DIVERSIFY INTO THESE MAJOR LINEAGES BEFORE
THE VASCULAR PLANTS
ORIGINATED. AND WE COULD REALLY SAY ESSENTIALLY
THAT THE
BRYOPHYTES GAVE RISE TO THE VASCULAR PLANTS,
THESE LARGER PLANTS
THAT HAVE CONDUCTING TISSUE, GIVEN THAT THEY
CONSTITUTE A GRADE
OR PARAPHYLETIC GROUP WITHIN WHICH THE VASCULAR
PLANTS ARE
NESTED. ARE THERE QUESTIONS ABOUT THAT? YEAH,
BRAD?
STUDENT: SO IF THE BRYOPHYTES DON'T HAVE THAT
-- (INAUDIBLE).
PROFESSOR: YEAH, THEY, THE LIVERWORTS, I SHOULD
SAY THE MOSSES
ACTUALLY DO HAVE SOME CONDUCTING TISSUE. AND
THEY'RE THE ONLY
MEMBERS OF THIS GROUP THAT CAN GET FAIRLY
SIZEABLE. THERE ARE,
IN FACT, SOME MOSSES THAT CAN GET UP TO A
COUPLE METERS IN
HEIGHT, AND THEY HAVE WHAT ARE CALLED LEPTOIDS
AND HYDROIDS.
THAT'S NOT IMPORTANT, BUT THEY HAVE SOME CONDUCTING
CELLS THAT
MOVE AROUND WATER AS WELL AS NUTRIENTS IN
THEIR TISSUES. BUT IT
ISN'T REINFORCED BY LIGNIN WHICH IS THE CASE
IN, THAT WAS WHAT WE
SEE IN THE VASCULAR TISSUE OF VASCULAR PLANTS.
AND LIGNIN
IMPARTS GREAT STRENGTH TO THE CONDUCTING TISSUE,
IN PARTICULAR
THE XYLEM, THE WATER CONDUCTING TISSUE. IT
ALLOWS VASCULAR
PLANTS TO GET, TO BE LARGE BRANCHED SPOROPHYTES,
TO HAVE LARGE
BRANCHED SPOROPHYTES. HORNWORTS AND LIVERWORTS
DON'T HAVE THOSE
LEPTOIDS AND HYDROIDS, AND THEY'RE PRETTY
MUCH AS I'LL SHOW YOU
HERE, WELL, LET'S GO TO THE LIFE CYCLE FIRST
OF BRYOPHYTES TO
MAKE THIS POINT. AND I AM NOT SO SURE I'M
GOING TO BE ABLE TO
GET THROUGH THE LIFE CYCLE OF BRYOPHYTES IN
THREE MINUTES, OR TWO
MINUTES. BUT I JUST WANT TO MAKE THE POINT
FIRST, AND WE'LL GET
BACK TO THIS NEXT TIME, BUT AS I WAS SAYING,
THE GAMETOPHYTE, THE
HAPLOID PHASE OF BRYOPHYTES IS THE GREEN PHOTOSYNTHETIC
DOMINANT
PHASE. AND YOU CAN SEE A TYPICAL MOSS GAMETOPHYTE
RIGHT HERE.
AND AGAIN, IT'S GERMINATING FROM SPORES. IT
HAS A FILAMENTOUS
FORM EARLY ITS DEVELOPMENT AND THEN GETS TO
BE MORE OF
LEAFY-LIKE, HAS A, LOOKS LIKE A LEAFY STEM.
BUT THIS IS A
GAMETOPHYTE NOT A SPOROPHYTE. SO THE, THE
STRUCTURES THAT LOOK
LIKE LEAVES ARE NOT TRULY HOMOLOGOUS TO THE
LEAVES WE SEE IN LAND
PLANTS THAT ARE IN THE SPOROPHYTE GENERATION.
BUT IN ANY CASE,
THIS IS A GAMETOPHYTE. AND THEN IT PRODUCES
GAMETANGIA UP IN THE
TIPS HERE. AND WE'LL GET TO THE GAMETANGIA
LATER. BUT
BASICALLY THE SPOROPHYTE IS JUST THIS STRUCTURE
HERE. IT'S
PARASITIC ON THE GAMETOPHYTE. IT GROWS OUT
OF IT. AND IT'S
PRETTY MUCH JUST A SPORANGIUM ON A STALK.
THOUGH WE HAVE A
HIGHLY REDUCED OR I SHOULD SAY A SMALL SPOROPHYTE
WHERE WE HAVE
MEIOSIS GIVING RISE TO SPORES. SO THIS IS
JUST AN INTRO TO THE
BRYOPHYTE LIFE CYCLE. AND WE'LL TALK MORE
ABOUT IT NEXT TIME.
SO REMEMBER TO SET YOUR CLOCK, CLOCKS BACK
AGAIN. AND GOOD LUCK
ON THE EXAM TONIGHT.