from Macaulay Culkin's
kitchen.
But most importantly, I had
enjoyed some creamy puddings.
I am Nimrod Kamer, a social
climber disguised as a
journalist, and this is my film,
"How To Make It #Huge In
The Film Industry (And
Also Get Fingered.)"
I had achieved so much already,
so I splashed out on
a food salad and a
glass of spritz.
You can put it on Michael
Fassbender's room account.
It's OK.
Room, I think, 344
or something.
The cold food made me realize
that to make it #enorm in the
film industry, I had to be
among the Venice 1%.
I want to put money in
films, actually.
I'm a merchant in Venice.
MIRAMAX CEO: Cool.
NIMROD KAMER: I want to put some
money on films, but if
you don't pay me back, I have
take a piece of your flesh.
MIRAMAX CEO: [LAUGHING]
Call it good collateral.
NIMROD KAMER: Small
piece, yeah.
- Scuzi.
It's private.
NIMROD KAMER: Private party?
See you later.
Film finance and XLS files were
so boring, so I casually
wandered down the street where
I bumped into my old pal,
Danny Huston.
Danny and I go way back and
almost always agree on
everything.
DANNY HUSTON: Yes, yes, yes.
Yes, yes,
NIMROD KAMER: Yeah, yeah.
DANNY HUSTON: Uh huh.
I had Danny in mind for the lead
role in an [INAUDIBLE]
book I'd optioned.
ARI EMANUEL: A friend of mine
that I'm talking to is selling
the movie rights to "50
Shades of Grey."
NIMROD KAMER: It's about
spanking and submissive sex.
Soft stuff.
ARI EMANUEL: We will
talk more.
NIMROD KAMER: Legitimate.
I set up a meeting with Harvey
Weinstein about a visionary
sci-fi idea I had.
NIMROD KAMER: Just for a sec.
NIMROD KAMER: I just
want to say.
NIMROD KAMER: I'm leaving.
I just want to do the remake
of the remake of "Total
Recall."
NIMROD KAMER: Yeah.
The remake of the remake,
because "Total Recall" was the
best remake ever.
You should remake that.
Good to see you, girls.
Yeah.
I have Pierce Brosnan
sex tape.
NIMROD KAMER: Thanks.
NIMROD KAMER: I could tell
Harvey Weinstein was
interested by the movement
of his chin.
It was only a matter of
time before he bid.
What I needed now was actors.
I can be your agent in London.
I can put you in corporate
infomercials and
all kinds of stuff.
JOE PESCI'S BROTHER: Really?
NIMROD KAMER: Yeah, yeah.
JOE PESCI'S BROTHER: Can
you give me your card?
NIMROD KAMER: I can represent
you in Paris and the Middle
East if you want.
I'm an agent, yeah.
I'm an agent, a manager,
and a lawyer.
I can represent her, yeah.
I can give you stationery,
because my grandfather, he
owns a stationery shop.
MICHAEL LONSDALE: What's that?
NIMROD KAMER: It's like pencils
and clipboards.
Have you ever done,
like, nude scenes?
[LAUGHING]
NIMROD KAMER: I can give you
my card, definitely.
I got some condoms here.
[MUSIC PLAYING]