Though small
compared to
the rest of the Sudan,
the three provinces
that make up Darfur
are nearly the size of France.
Far from the capital
in Khartourn,
the region has been
neglected for years
by the government.
Darfur means
"Land of the Fur."
A Muslim African tribe
indigenous to the area.
The region is inhabited
by many tribes
that are
racially and culturally
intertwined.
But despite these
cultural similarities,
groups of farmers,
who are viewed
as African
and groups of herders,
who are considered Arab,
have had clashes
over the land for decades.
Droughts,
famines,
desertification
and population pressures
have added to
the rising tensions.
Since 2003,
rebel groups
have fought against
the government
accusing it
of supporting the Arab herders
over the African farmers.
The government's response
caused a mass exodus
forcing villagers
to become refugees
in their own homeland.
In this United Nations
refugee camp
along the
Chad-Sudan border,
the women and children here
have found a safe haven
from the Janjawe,
the armed militias
of Arab herders
organized by the government
to fight the rebels
and kill civilians.
Entire villages
have been burned.
Hundreds of thousands
have died.
Beatings,
rapes
and mutilations
are used as weapons of terror.
Around 2 million people
almost a third of
Darfur's population
have fled their villages.
These refugees have
lost everything.
But they are
the lucky ones.
Most still wander the land
unable to go home.
Their lives still
at risk.
Though peace talks
have been organized,
the fighting
still continues.
And in Darfur
the people are still dying.