JACOB SOBOROFF:
I've got two words
for you guys-- human bowling.
These guys are riding a
human-sized hamster ball
called a zorb down
Mammoth Mountain.
[UPBEAT MUSIC]
JACOB SOBOROFF: If I
ever get to do this,
I would like to be the guy
inside the ball please.
Devinsupertramp has the best
job in the entire world.
This is his second
video this week,
and they're both blowing up.
For this one, he travelled all
the way to Aruba for American
Gladiators-style action.
[UPBEAT MUSIC]
JACOB SOBOROFF: He's been making
these videos for three years.
He's got over 300 million views.
Go to his channel, but be
warned, you ain't gonna leave.
LIZZIE: This next
video is a classic
Valentine's Day tale of boy
meets girl, girl leaves boy,
and then boy spends the
rest of his days cooking
single servings of sadness.
Kevin Miles is
back to show us how
to cook the perfect
Valentine's Day meal for one.
KEVIN MILES: Lay out
the dough like you
see in all those commercials
with all those people having
fun.
Hey bro, nice party,
where's the beer?
It's over by my girlfriend.
Oh wow, she's so beautiful.
And the best part is
we're still together.
LIZZIE: It's been more than six
years since these guys posted
one of these.
Go subscribe to their channel
so they make more, and happy
Valentine's day.
JACOB SOBOROFF: A week
ago Aviccii released
a 16-second trailer for
his new music video.
That 16 seconds alone
got over 2 million views.
Today, got the
full video for ya.
This was shot over
six days in Sweden
with temperatures as low
as negative 27 degrees.
It's a 1940s Bonnie
and Clyde story
starring two
Swedish movie stars.
[MUSIC - AVICII, "ADDICTED TO
YOU"]
JACOB SOBOROFF: The singer
on the track is Audra Mae.
She's the great grand
niece of Judy Garland.
Avicii's got almost a billion
views in just over two years,
so you know this video's
going to be huge.
ALEX: 3.7 billion years
ago, explorers set off
in a boat to find
cheese on the moon.
I think that that's the plot of
this amazing claymation movie.
This took nearly
three years to make,
and the creator handcrafted
this entire stop motion trailer
by himself, and it is glorious.
MALE SPEAKER 1: Well-equipped
to mine the lunar
surface for its
riches, the crew was
ill-prepared to navigate
the human tides of jealousy,
inebriation, and love.
ALEX: Here's the craziest
part-- this guy only
has four subscribers.
What?
That's it.
No.
Go over there and
show him some love.
JACOB SOBOROFF: This
next video is in French,
but honestly it
doesn't matter if you
speak English or Klingon,
because this thing is
pretty funny.
SURICATE just released
this video showing us
what classic movie cliches
would look like in real life.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
JACOB SOBOROFF:
This is the sequel
to their Movies versus Life
video from last year that
has over 5 million views.
Subscribe to their channel
for more good stuff.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
MALE SPEAKER 2: Stump Earnest.
JACOB SOBOROFF: OK.
Earnest, today's
challenger is Kanakadea.
Find me a video of a toddler
doing practical particle
physics.
EARNEST: Kanakadea,
meet romanieo.
This scientific inquiry
was filmed back in 2011
when romanieo was only
two and a half years old.
MALE SPEAKER 3: One, two three,
four, five, six, seven, eight.
What atom has eight electrons?
ROMANIEO: Oxygen.
MALE SPEAKER 4: All right.
EARNEST: I, myself,
was nine before delving
into mystifying realm
of particle physics.
Bravo, little man.
Oh, and Kanakadea?
Boom.
JACOB SOBOROFF: Get in
the ring with the champ.
Drop your challenge below
using #stumpearnest.
Guys, thank you so much for
sending your YouTube crushes.
Keep them coming.
Links are below, playlists
are about to pop up.
Remember to subscribe.
Now play us out, Chela.
[MUSIC PLAYING- CHELA,
"ROMANTICISE"]