That's your signal that
you can try that
experiment at home.
Everything else, off limits.
Look.
I've already given you homework,
and the show hasn't
even started.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
STEVE SPANGLER: I'm fascinated
with Newton's cradle.
But then, again, I'm
easily amused.
It's the coolest demonstration
toy because it teaches the
laws of conservation
of momentum and the
conservation of energy.
Pendulums are just cool.
As much as we'd like to think
that Isaac Newton sat around
and played with this toy, it
was actually invented by an
English actor by the name of
Simon Prebble in 1967.
He named it after Newton
because it demonstrates
Newton's laws of motion.
What I'm really looking
for is, instead
of making it bigger--
that seems to be what everybody
wants to do
nowadays, is to do
it with something
that's bigger and bigger.
I remember, years ago, there was
a science experiment in a
book called, Scientific
Amusements that talked about
the swing and the transfer of
energy from a pendulum.
It almost looked like
mind control.
That's what I think I want to
do is to mess with people in
our office today and see if I
can convince them that I can
control or they can control an
object with just their mind.
When in fact, it's all cleverly
disguised here in the
swing of a pendulum.
For now, I'm going to keep
playing with this.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
STEVE SPANGLER: You know, they
say the old is forever new.
And it's absolutely right.
If you want inspiration,
you turn to some
of these old books.
This is Scientific Amusements,
about 1870 or so, adapted from
Professor CG Knott.
What I'm looking at here is, as
you're thumbing through it,
there are all these
old materials.
But I remember this thing called
a coupled pendulum.
It was actually a swinging
pendulum.
You can see here that
they actually used
eggs for some reason.
And the eggs would swing
back and forth.
I want to build this because, if
you do it right, you can't
really see the science behind
it, the secret.
And you can make somebody think
that they're actually
controlling an object
with their mind.
We'll just use some modern
day materials, and
we should be set.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
STEVE SPANGLER: All right,
here's everything you're going
to need, using simple
household materials.
We're going to start
with this cord.
And it calls for about 36
inches, so about 100
centimeters of the cord here.
So that will be our
main piece.
And then the two pendulum pieces
that are going to hang
down have to be exactly equal.
And so, in this particular case,
we're going to go for
about 60 centimeters, which is
approximately 24 inches.
And all of this is going to have
to be tweaked a little
bit, I think, as
we're doing it.
But we just want pieces that are
identical in every way, so
that the pendulum, when it
swings back and forth, the
energy from one is the same.
And we transfer it to the
other one as well.
So we have to keep absolutely
everything the same.
So we need those two pieces.
And now, instead of hanging
something like a jewel or
something ornate, I thought
just these soda
cans would be fine.
And I can't just do the soda
cans, so I emptied them out,
washed them out and added
the same amount of
water to each one.
So we're looking at about 175
milliliters in each one.
It doesn't really matter.
I'm just showing you what I'm
doing for this if you're
trying to replicate it exactly
the way that I'm doing it,
hoping that it works.
So that's the set up.
Now we just have to tie
everything together and see if
we can get this system
in place.
There you go.
So I just need to make sure that
the cord is the same on
this one as it is this one,
got it so this is in place
here, and be sure that this one
looks exactly the same by
using the same amount of cord,
so that will be perfect.
OK?
And now we need to tie both of
these onto this main one here.
And I'm going to be able
to move them around.
I just want to be able to put
some knots in them, so that
the cord stays and that I'm,
again, using the same amount
of cord on each one.
And now we just need to hook
them onto something.
It has to be extremely steady,
because I don't want that
other structure moving.
So we're going to go tie it
around something or use these
super strong magnets that we
have here to hold it in place.
So I'll use these neodymium
magnets and
put them on the ends.
Hold them in place.
And we should be set.
Well, here's our pendulum
system, right?
Both cans are equal
in their weight.
The cords attached to the top
are equal in their length.
And you can see how it's
attached up here,
and it can't move.
I'm just using these super
strong magnets
to hold it in place.
All right, so if we swing both
of them, it'd be just like
swinging a kid at
the playground.
It just moves back and forth.
You know, when you push a kid
and you push him just at the
right moment, you can add
some energy to it
like we're doing here.
Here's what we want to do with
this experiment, though.
The book says that you
start with one can.
So let's just say we
pick the Coke.
You pull back.
And you move the one can.
As you start that in motion,
the energy is actually
transferred to the other can.
And now both of them
are in motion.
But now you're supposed to focus
on the first one here.
Focus on the Coke.
You notice how it stops.
And then it let's go.
And now refocus your energy
to the Diet Coke.
Look at this.
And then it moves.
So literally, these two
swinging bodies are
transferring energy from
one to the next.
So I think, if you do it
correctly, you might be able
to convince somebody that
they could slow it
down with their mind.
Watch this.
Slow it down.
And it keeps moving.
So it's really good,
after the first or
second one that's there.
Transfer your energy
over to the Coke.
It's pretty cool.
Regardless if you can fool your
friends or not, it's a
very, very cool pendulum kind of
trick with the transfer of
energy from one pendulum
to the next.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
STEVE SPANGLER: All right,
everybody, get ready.
I'm going to allow
you to control an
object with your mind.
This is going to be great.
You're going to really
like it.
Don't worry about us.
We're just going to be
rigging something.
Don't worry, all right?
This is perfectly fine.
That's really good.
Hey, Zarah, come here.
ZARAH BROWN: Oh, but I'm just
afraid I have to work.
STEVE SPANGLER: Come here.
I'm going to blow your mind.
ZARAH BROWN: OK.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK, you ready?
ZARAH BROWN: Yeah, I'm ready.
STEVE SPANGLER: So watch this.
This is an experiment
in mind control.
OK, come here.
ZARAH BROWN: OK.
STEVE SPANGLER: All right,
so watch this.
So I have a Coke can and
a Diet Coke can.
ZARAH BROWN: Yeah.
STEVE SPANGLER: And what I want
you to do is I want you
to pick one of the two cans.
Which one do you have
the biggest
connection with mentally?
ZARAH BROWN: OK, I got it.
STEVE SPANGLER: [WHISPERS]
This is all crap.
Which one is it?
ZARAH BROWN: It's-- well,
I-- should I tell you?
STEVE SPANGLER: No,
let me divine it.
Diet Coke.
ZARAH BROWN: No.
STEVE SPANGLER: That's--
I was saying not Diet Coke.
You want Coke, right?
ZARAH BROWN: Yes.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK.
So here's what's going
to happen.
See, these little things will
swing like this, OK?
ZARAH BROWN: OK.
STEVE SPANGLER: So I'm
going to swing the
cans back and forth.
But because you picked Coke,
I'm going to swing
Coke first, all right?
ZARAH BROWN: OK.
STEVE SPANGLER: I want you
to focus your attention
on Coke, all right?
ZARAH BROWN: OK.
STEVE SPANGLER: Just stand
right back here.
ZARAH BROWN: All right.
STEVE SPANGLER: Focus your
attention on the Coke.
I'm going to pull it
back like this.
I'm going to start it swinging.
Ready?
ZARAH BROWN: OK.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK?
Focus on the Coke, because
both cans are
going to start to move.
Now use your mind to
slow the Coke down.
ZARAH BROWN: OK.
STEVE SPANGLER: Use your
mind to slow the--
[GASPS]
STEVE SPANGLER: Now transfer
your thought
waves to the Diet Coke.
Ready?
Slow them down.
ZARAH BROWN: What?
STEVE SPANGLER: Look at this.
Now go back to the Coke, since
that's the one that you
started with.
Slow it down.
ZARAH BROWN: That's crazy.
STEVE SPANGLER: Let it go.
ZARAH BROWN: OK.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK?
Now go to the Diet Coke.
Ready?
ZARAH BROWN: OK.
STEVE SPANGLER: Look at this.
You're amazing.
ZARAH BROWN: I should
get a raise.
STEVE SPANGLER: You
should not--
ZARAH BROWN: Yeah.
STEVE SPANGLER: You should go
back to work now, all right?
All right, thank you.
And no, it has nothing
to do with the
period of the pendulum.
Don't worry.
This is actual mind control
right here.
All right, I need
another victim,
somebody that's gullible.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
STEVE SPANGLER: This is the
amazing mind control
experiment.
ANN: All right.
STEVE SPANGLER: Got it?
Right.
Now you may walk in between
them, because
this is mind control.
ANN: Do I have to
say right here?
STEVE SPANGLER: No,
you can come here.
ANN: OK.
STEVE SPANGLER: All
right, so watch.
ANN: OK.
STEVE SPANGLER: So you see
the two pendulums?
ANN: Mm-hm.
STEVE SPANGLER: They're actually
hooked with a piece
of rope or string
that's this way.
And if you take both of them and
pull back-- go ahead and
take both of them and pull
them back gently
and let them swing--
it's like pushing
kids on a swing.
Right?
ANN: OK.
Yeah.
STEVE SPANGLER: All right.
So what I want you to do is that
you're going to focus on
one of the two of them, OK?
ANN: OK.
STEVE SPANGLER: So here,
I want you to
stare at both of them.
And I want you to think of
one of the two of them.
Ready?
Which one?
ANN: OK.
STEVE SPANGLER: Which one?
ANN: I want that one.
STEVE SPANGLER: That is what I
was thinking in my mind you
were going to pick.
ANN: Really?
STEVE SPANGLER: Yes.
Magic.
All right, so now watch.
I'm going to pull
this can back.
And we're going to start
to let it swing.
And what I want you to do is I
want to focus your attention
on this can.
Ready?
Focus your attention
on the can.
Focus it.
You notice how The other one
starts to swing as well?
I want you to slow this one
down with your mind.
Use your mind and
slow it down.
Use your mind.
Slow it down.
[GASPS]
You notice how the other
one is swinging?
Good.
Let it go, Ann.
Let it go.
ANN: OK.
STEVE SPANGLER: Got it?
ANN: Yeah.
STEVE SPANGLER: All right, now
focus your mind on the Coke.
Ready?
ANN: OK.
STEVE SPANGLER: Slow it down.
Slow it down.
Take the energy away from it.
Good.
Let it go.
Ready?
[GASPS]
Grab both cans.
You have now been controlling
objects with your mind.
ANN: This is very exciting.
STEVE SPANGLER: Yes.
ANN: OK.
STEVE SPANGLER: So now, for
$19.95, I have a full system
and a seminar that you could
attend, all right?
ANN: Oh.
STEVE SPANGLER: It would
be really, really good.
ANN: OK.
STEVE SPANGLER: All right?
I think you're going
to like it.
ANN: OK.
STEVE SPANGLER: So just give
me your credit card.
And I'll just write down--
ANN: Sure.
STEVE SPANGLER: Just your
expiration date.
ANN: OK, yeah.
No problem.
It's all in my phone.
STEVE SPANGLER: She's coming
to the seminar.
OK?
So watch this.
Ready?
So I'm going to pull
it back here.
Pull it back just a
little bit more.
OK, take it right
to your eyes.
And now don't move.
Let go.
See how it doesn't hit you?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yes.
STEVE SPANGLER: That's the
conservation of energy.
No, you're moving your head.
See, now it hit you.
If you don't move--
I should put you against
a brick wall.
This is even cooler.
You know what we should do is,
if I had a great big, huge
wrecking ball, I could pull
it right back to your
nose, let it go.
It would swing out.
It would not hit you
in the nose.
FEMALE SPEAKER: I
don't want to.
STEVE SPANGLER: I'm
doing that.
That's an idea.
Here we go.
It's a bowling ball, 13 pounds,
hooked onto a rope.
And so here's what we're going
to do, put you right there,
your back against the wall.
You can't move.
So according to Isaac Newton,
you can't get any more energy
out of something than
put into it.
So if I pull this back, we have
all this potential energy
coming right to your nose.
If I just let go of this,
it should not come
back and hit you.
OK, so watch what happens.
This would be our mannequin.
Pretend like it was
a mannequin.
I'm going to swing out,
add some energy,
and let it come back.
Watch.
Ready?
Here it comes.
It's out and--
[SCREAMS]
[LAUGHTER]
MALE SPEAKER: Well, that
would be disaster.
STEVE SPANGLER: That would
be kind of a problem.
[LAUGHTER]
STEVE SPANGLER: But I don't
think that'll happen with a
human being.
Let's try one.
Newton said that we shouldn't
get any more energy out of
something than we put into it.
So here's all this potential
energy right
up to Beau's head.
Ready?
So you've got to
kiss your nose.
There you go, right there.
No, not yet.
BEAU: Oh.
[LAUGHTER]
STEVE SPANGLER: All right.
So here you go.
Right there.
And now let go!
Hands down.
Here it comes.
Oh!
FEMALE SPEAKER: Oh!
[LAUGHTER]
STEVE SPANGLER: You see
it coming towards you.
Now, if you do this, if you put
it right up to your nose
and then do one of these, like
this, and you swing it out,
you put more energy
back into it.
Yeah.
It'll smash your head.
[LAUGHTER]
BEAU: Smash your head.
[LAUGHS]
STEVE SPANGLER: She just
has to trust that
it's going to be OK.
So are you ready?
ZARAH BROWN: Yep.
STEVE SPANGLER: So I'll do the
release, of there's no
possible way she could
swing it wrong.
So it's going go right
to your nose.
You got it?
ZARAH BROWN: Yep.
STEVE SPANGLER: Can you see
right on the nose, Bradley?
Right to the nose.
You ready?
Set.
Don't move.
Here it comes.
Stay there.
Don't move.
ZARAH BROWN: [LAUGHS]
STEVE SPANGLER: Ah!
See?
You proved the laws of
science are correct.
ZARAH BROWN: Hallelujah.
STEVE SPANGLER: La!
It's just touching your nose.
Then let go.
Don't move!
Ah!
MALE SPEAKER: It's really
intimidating.
STEVE SPANGLER: Scared, huh?
MALE SPEAKER: That's really
intimidating.
STEVE SPANGLER: Hands down.
Hands down Hands down.
Don't move.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Oh!
[LAUGHTER]
MALE SPEAKER: God.
[INAUDIBLE].
MALE SPEAKER: Back.
[LAUGHTER]
STEVE SPANGLER: We're going
to come back and smash
[INAUDIBLE]
[LAUGHTER]
MALE SPEAKER: Woo!
[LAUGHS]
STEVE SPANGLER: Here it comes.
It shouldn't have any more
energy than you put--
oh!
FEMALE SPEAKER: Oh!
That was close.
[LAUGHS]
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
STEVE SPANGLER: That's back--
[LAUGHS]
[LAUGHTER]
STEVE SPANGLER: There it is.
There it is.
It's there.
[LAUGHTER]
STEVE SPANGLER: That's
a little too much.
Oh!
[LAUGHTER]
STEVE SPANGLER: Did
you see her hair.
Isn't that great?
Put your hands down.
Don't move!
FEMALE SPEAKER: Don't move!
STEVE SPANGLER: Don't move!
Don't move!
Oh!
[LAUGHS]
[LAUGHTER]
STEVE SPANGLER: See?
You were fine.
Oh!
[LAUGHTER]
STEVE SPANGLER: You're
OK, Marie.
No possible way.
Don't move.
Don't move!
FEMALE SPEAKER: Oh, my God!
My face!
[LAUGHTER]
STEVE SPANGLER: See?
You're OK.
Don't move.
ANN: [LAUGHS]
[LAUGHTER]
[APPLAUSE]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
STEVE SPANGLER: Here
it swings.
It's coming back.
Do move.
Oh.
See?
Beautiful.
It works with no--
oh!
It works with no
problem at all.
And Isaac Newton was correct.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
STEVE SPANGLER: Well, if you
enjoyed this week's episode,
go ahead and click the Subscribe
button here.
You'll be the first to know
when a brand new episode
appears each week.
This button right here will
show you some more cool
science experiments that we
do outside of the show.
This button right here will
take you to last week's
episode, just in case
you missed it.
And if you want to see something
you shouldn't see,
that's the bloopers and the
outtakes, well, just click
this one right over here.
And if you want to hear me stop
talking through the magic
of television, just click
this button right here.
Go ahead.
Click it, and I'll stop.
[MUSIC PLAYING]