Trust me, sir, every newspaper
in the world will fly here
instantly to talk to me.
Yes.
Will you please forgive
my appearance?
I need a tailor that can
very quickly, sir,
make a suit, a shirt.
Because I cannot speak
like this.
Thanks, [INAUDIBLE]
SAM VANEGAS: I forgot!
[INAUDIBLE]
JOHN MCAFEE: So I
need to do it?
I need my suit.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
JOHN MCAFEE: Do you have the
power, sir, to make this man
sew a little faster?
TELESFORO GUERRA: Of course.
JOHN MCAFEE: Okay, good.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
TELESFORO GUERRA: Of course.
JOHN MCAFEE: I think there's
nothing to prove.
I was not there.
I was with Sam the
entire night.
I have more than half a dozen
witnesses to the fact.
I had no motive.
I had no access to
a 9-millimeter.
I don't what there is
to prove, really.
Whatever it is they want to talk
to me about, I think, has
very little to do with the
murder of Mr. Faull.
And very much to do with their
collecting me on any charge
whatsoever.
Where do we have to go?
We'll do it right now.
Just do it now.
Come on.
Right now.
You've never seen this
before, have you.
SAM VANEGAS: No, never
in my life.
JOHN MCAFEE: This is my life
in America, sweetie.
So you'll see that I am quite
comfortable with this.
I have for five years lived
in Belize peacefully.
Seven months ago, the Belizean
government sent 42 armed
soldiers into my property.
They killed one of my dogs.
They broke into all
of my houses.
They stole.
They arrested me and kept
me handcuffed in
the sun for 14 hours.
I was taken to jail, and it was
only the intervention of
the US embassy that got
me out of jail.
Since that time, I have been
continually harassed by the
government.
They have attempted to charge
me with every crime, ranging
from running an antibiotics
laboratory without a license,
to hiring security guards
without a license, to having
improper paperworks
for my company.
And most recently, the murder
of my neighbor.
I had to leave, but the
story has to get out.
I have documentation that proves
the intense corruption
at all levels of the Belizean
government.
Now that I am in a safe place,
I can speak freely.
I will be talking on my blog,
whoismcafee.com, starting
tonight, revealing the
truth about Belize.
And thank you very much.