GIVE YOU A SETTING FOR THE EXAM QUESTIONS.
AND
SOMETIMES THE EXAM QUESTIONS ARE GOING TO
PRESENT YOU
WITH AN INTERMEDIATE STAGE. LIKE YOU MIGHT
SAY SPORE,
AND YOU ARE GOING TO HAVE TO BE ABLE TO MOVE
FORWARD
IN THE DEVELOPMENT OF WHAT COULD COME FROM
THAT SPORE.
AND MOVE BACKWARDS WHAT MIGHT HAVE RESULTED
IN THE
PRODUCTION OF THAT SPORE. AND I AM TALKING
TO SOME OF
YOU I GET THE IMPRESSION THAT YOU ARE TRYING
TO
MEMORIZE IT. AND IF YOU TRY TO MEMORIZE IS
IT IS
GOING TO BE HARD BECAUSE YOU WON'T BE ABLE
TO PUT THIS
IN THE CONTEXT OF YOUR MEMORIZATION. BUT IF
YOU
UNDERSTAND IT, YOU WILL BE MUCH BETTER PLACE
FOR THE
MIDTERM.
AND FOR THOSE OF YOU WHO I HAVE SPOKEN TO
AND
EXPRESSED A SENSE OF FRUSTRATION BECAUSE
YOU ARE
CLEARLY MEMORIZING IT, I WANT TO TELL YOU
THAT I AM
THERE TO HELP YOU AND TRYING TO IMPRESS UPON
YOU THE
IMPORTANCE OF UNDERSTANDING NOT MEMORIZING.
THOSE OF
YOU WHO TRY TO MEMORIZE WILL REALLY NOT VERY
ABLE TO
ANSWER THE QUESTIONS WHEN I CAME THROUGH THE
LAB. AND
I GUESS YOU SORT OF SENSED THAT WHEN I TALKED
WITH
YOU.
ARE THERE ANY QUESTIONS? ALL RIGHT. TODAY
WHAT WE ARE GOING TO START DOING IS TO TALK
ABOUT THE
FIRST ORGAN IN THE PLANTS THAT WE ARE ENCOUNTERING.
AN ORGAN IS SOMETHING WHICH IS MADE UP OF
A NUMBER OF
DIFFERENT CELL TYPES, A NUMBER OF DIFFERENT
TISSUE
TYPES. AND THE FIRST ORGAN WE ARE GOING TO
TALK ABOUT
BEGINNING TODAY IS THE ROOT SYSTEM. NOW FOR
MOST OF
US THE ROOT SYSTEM IS THE PART OF THE PLANT
THAT IS,
WE NEVER THINK ABOUT, WE NEVER SEE. IT IS
THE PART OF
THE PLANT THAT IS UNDERGROUND, AT LEAST THAT
IS YOUR
IMPRESSION OF IT AND IT FITS THE OLD SAYING,
OUT OF
SIGHT, OUT OF MIND. I WANT TO SHOW YOU SOME
SLIDES TO
ILLUSTRATE TO YOU THAT ROOTS COME IN VERY
MANY
DIFFERENT FORMS OTHER THAN WHAT YOU CONSIDER
TO BE THE
STEREOTYPICAL FORM BELOW GROUND. BUT I WOULD
LIKE TO
BEGIN FIRST BY DISCUSSING SOME OF THE MAIN
FUNCTIONS
OF THE ROOT. SOME OF THESE MAIN FUNCTIONS
AND WE WILL
DISCUSS SOME OF THEM IN MORE DETAIL TODAY.
THE FIRST
ONE IS ANCHORAGE OR SUPPORT. AND YOU WILL
SEE SOME
GOOD EXAMPLES OF THIS. ANCHORAGE OR SUPPORT.
THE SECOND, AND IT IS A MAJOR FUNCTION THAT
WE
WILL SPEND QUITE A BIT OF TIME TALKING ABOUT
IT, IS
ABSORPTION OF WATER AND NUTRIENTS. A THIRD
FUNCTION
AMONG THE MANY WHICH ROOTS HAVE AND WHAT WE
WILL
BRIEFLY TOUCH UPON TODAY IS THAT THEY CAN
BECOME
A STORAGE ORGAN.
AND MANY OF YOU WITHOUT REALIZING THAT IT
IS
A ROOT OR REALIZING IT IS A STORAGE ORGAN
ENCOUNTER
ROOTS DAILY IF NOT WEEKLY. HERE ARE TWO
EXAMPLES OF
ROOT STORAGE ORGANS, CARROTS, BEETS, THESE
ARE STORAGE
ORGANS WHERE SUGARS AND STARCHES ARE PLACED
IN THE
ROOT SYSTEM AND THEY PROVIDE THE PLANT MATERIAL
TO
START GROWING THE FOLLOWING YEAR WHEN THE
SPRING COMES
ALONG. WE CAN CONSUME THESE BECAUSE THEY ARE
SWEET OR
BECAUSE THEY HAVE STARCH IN THEM.
A LESS COMMON, AT LEAST TO MANY OF YOU ROOT
SYSTEM, IS CASABA. FOR THOSE OF YOU WHO COME
FROM
TROPICAL CULTURES OR MAYBE EAST ASIAN CULTURES
THIS IS
SOMETHING THAT YOU WOULD USE. IT REPRESENTS
A ROOT
SYSTEM IN WHICH LARGE AMOUNTS OF STARCH HAVE
BEEN
STORED.
AN EXAMPLE OF A ROOT SYSTEM WHICH IS NOT STORAGE
BUT ALSO HAS PLAYED PROMINENT ROLES IN MANY
CULTURES
PARTICULARLY IN ASIAN CULTURES IS OVER HERE,
THIS IS
A ROOT OF A GINSENG. GINSENG SUPPOSEDLY HAS
MEDICINAL
PROPERTIES AND THE PROPERTIES OF THE GINSENG
ARE
SUPPOSEDLY DICTATED BY THE SHAPE OF THE
ROOT BY
WHETHER IT HAS BRANCHES. THIS IS SORT OF A
CULTURAL
ONE. IT IS A THICKER ROOT. IT IS A STORAGE
ROOT, BUT
IT IS MAINLY INVOLVED IN CULTURAL PRACTICES
NOT FOR
THEIR STORAGE PROPERTIES. AND FINALLY WHAT
I WANT TO
MENTION AS FAR AS THE FUNCTION OF THE ROOTS
IS THAT
AND WE PROBABLY WON'T HAVE TIME TO TALK ABOUT
IT, BUT
IT IS AN IMPORTANT FUNCTION, IS THAT ROOTS
FREQUENTLY
ESTABLISH SYMBIOTIC ASSOCIATIONS WITH SOIL
MICROORGANISMS.
AND, THIS ESTABLISHMENT OF SOIL MICROORGANISMS
BENEFITS BOTH THE ROOT SYSTEM AND THE MICROORGANISM.
WE ARE HAVING SOME PROBLEMS HERE. OKAY. LET'S
BEGIN
WITH THE SLIDES, AND I WOULD LIKE TO SHOW
YOU SOME
SLIDES NOW TO ILLUSTRATE THE DIVERSITY THAT
ROOT
SYSTEMS HAVE BEYOND WHAT YOU NORMALLY ASSOCIATE
WITH
A ROOT SYSTEM.
THE FIRST SLIDE IS OF A TROPICAL, THESE ARE
MOSTLY TROPICAL ROOT SYSTEMS, PLANT CALLED
SCREW PINE
OR PANDANUS, AND IN THIS PARTICULAR PLANT
THE ROOTS
FORM ON THE STEM AND WE WILL TALK ABOUT THAT,
AND THEY
SUPPORT THE PLANT. THEY KEEP IT UPRIGHT AND
THEY ALSO
ABSORB WATER ONCE THEY ENTER THE SOIL. HERE
IS
ANOTHER EXAMPLE OF A ROOT OF A TROPICAL PLANT
OF
A RELATED TO THE FIG FAMILY. THESE ARE ACTUALLY
ROOTS
HERE. THEY LOOK LIKE BRANCHES, WHAT THEY DO
IS THEY
SUPPORT THESE VERY LARGE BRANCHES WHICH ALLOW
THIS
TREE TO COVER A LARGE AREA. HERE IS AN EXAMPLES
OF
A ROOT SYSTEM IN A, OF A VERY TALL TREE IN
THE
TROPICS, AREA WHICH IS RECEIVES VERY HIGH
WINDS
OCCASIONALLY. AND THESE ARE SO CALLED BUTTRESS
ROOTS,
TO GIVE YOU AN IDEA OF THE DIVERSITY OF ROOTS,
AND
THEY PROVIDE SORT OF EXTRA SUPPORT FOR THE
TREE IN
WINDY WEATHER. FOR THOSE OF YOU WHO HAVE BEEN
TO
FLORIDA OR DOWN TO MEXICO, YOU MAY HAVE ENCOUNTERED
MANGROVE SWAMPS AND IN MANGROVE SWAMPS THE
WATER COMES
IN WITH THE TIDES SEVERAL TIMES A DAY, AND
THESE ROOT
SYSTEMS ACT TO ELEVATE THE TREES, THE MANGROVE
TREES,
ABOVE THE LEVEL OF THE WATER. THE MANGROVE
ROOTS CAN
ALSO BE MODIFIED TO GROW UP ABOVE THE LEVEL
OF THE
WATER AND PROVIDE AN AIR TUBE SO TO SPEAK
FOR AIR TO
COME DOWN TO THE ROOT SYSTEM, WHICH OTHERWISE
WOULD BE
FLOODED AND WOULDN'T HAVE ACCESS TO OXYGEN.
HERE IS
A ROOT SYSTEM THAT MANY OF YOU ARE FAMILIAR
WITH, WITH
THE ROOT SYSTEM OF CLIMBING IVY. THIS ROOT
SYSTEM
SECRETES A GLUE AND THIS GLUE, IF YOU TRY
TO PULL THE
IVY OFF FROM THE BUILDING, FREQUENTLY WILL
STAY ON THE
BUILDING, IT STICKS SO TIGHTLY. FOR THOSE
OF YOU WHO
ARE INTERESTED IN BIOMIMICRY THAT IS USING
NATURE TO
DESIGN VARIOUS THINGS, THIS GLUE FOR EXAMPLE
WOULD BE
A GOOD START. NO ONE HAS EVER ANALYZED THIS
GLUE TO
SEE WHETHER IT IS SOMETHING WE AS HUMANS MIGHT
BE ABLE
TO USE IN OUR LIVES.
HERE IS AN INTERESTING ROOT SYSTEM, NOT
UNDERGROUND, THIS IS A ROOT SYSTEM FORMING
ON THE STEM
OF A PALM TREE. AND THESE ROOTS, WHICH GREW
OUT OF
THE PALM TREE, STOP GROWING WHEN THEY ARE
RELATIVELY
SHORT AND THEY TURN INTO SPINES. AND THIS
IS
PRESUMABLY TO PREVENT ANIMALS FROM CLIMBING
UP THE
TREE AND EATING THE FRUITS OR THE FLOWERS.
HERE IS A ROOT SYSTEM OF A PLANT WHERE
ESSENTIALLY THE WHOLE BODY OF THE PLANT CONSISTS
OF
THE ROOT SYSTEM. EVERYTHING YOU SEE HERE THAT
IS
GREEN, AND IN FACT EVEN THIS WHITE STUFF,
THIS GREEN
IS ROOT SYSTEM. THE SHOOT SYSTEM IN THIS PLANT
HAS
BEEN REDUCED TO A VERY SMALL PORTION OF THE
BODY. AND
ALL OF THE BODY THAT YOU SEE HERE, WHICH IS
GREEN, IS
THE ROOT SYSTEM AND THE ROOT SYSTEM IS THE
PHOTOSYNTHETIC PART OF THE PLANT. SHOW YOU
AGAIN USES
OF ROOTS IN OUR LIVES WHERE WE HAVE CASABA,
BEETS AND
CARROTS. THESE ARE STORAGE ROOTS WHICH STORE
LARGE
AMOUNTS OF SUGAR AND STARCH. AND FINALLY,
I WANT TO
MENTION THAT ALL OF OVER THE UNITED STATES,
IN FACT,
ALL OVER THE WORLD, ROOT SYSTEMS CAUSE TREMENDOUS
DAMAGE. VERY EXPENSIVE DAMAGE. THIS IS A PICTURE
INSIDE A SEWER. AND MANY OF YOU HAVE EXPERIENCED
HAVING YOUR WATER PIPE OR YOUR DRAINS BACKED
UP. MOST
OFTEN IF IT IS NOT WITHIN THE HOUSE. IF IT
IS OUTSIDE
OF THE HOUSE, IT IS BECAUSE ROOT SYSTEMS HAVE
INVADED
THE PIPE AND ARE SUCKING THE MINERALS UP.
IN THIS
CASE, IN A SEWER, AND THESE MINERALS THEN
ARE
NOURISHING THE PLANT, BUT AT THE SAME TIME,
I THINK I
WILL LEAVE THIS SCREEN DOWN, SORRY, AT THE
SAME TIME,
BLOCKING YOUR, YOUR WATER TO LEAVE. NOW, WHAT
I WOULD
LIKE TO DO, IS TO BEGIN A DISCUSSION OF THE
DEVELOPMENT OF THE ROOT SYSTEM. AND I AM GOING
TO
LEAVE THIS SCREEN DOWN BECAUSE I AM GOING
TO SHOW YOU
MORE SLIDES IN A MOMENT. AND I WOULD LIKE
TO BEGIN
WITH THE EMBRYO. IN THE EMBRYO THE FIRST ROOT
SYSTEM
IS PRESENT. SO, THE FIRST ROOT SYSTEM IS PRESENT
IN
THE EMBRYO.
AND WE CALL THAT FIRST ROOT OR ROOT SYSTEM
THE
PRIMARY ROOT. IT IS OFTEN REFERRED IN YOUR
TEXT BOOK
OR IN COMMON LITERATURE AS A TAP ROOT.
A TAP ROOT.
NOW, IF THIS WAS A EUDICOT THE TAP ROOT GROWS
DOWN. GROWS STRONGLY DOWNWARD.
AND GOES DEEPLY INTO THE SOIL.
SO, YOU WOULD FIND THIS FIRST ROOT, WHICH
COMES
FROM THE EMBRYO GROWING DOWN, IT BECOMES PROMINENT,
THE MOST PROMINENT OF THE ROOTS.
IT CAN ALSO PRODUCE BRANCH ROOTS.
AND THESE
BRANCH ROOTS ARE KNOWN AS SECONDARY ROOTS.
AS OPPOSED
TO PRIMARY. OR LATERAL ROOTS. ANOTHER TERM.
WE ARE GOING TO TALK ABOUT THE ORIGINS OF
THE
BRANCH ROOTS AND LATERAL ROOTS IN A FEW MINUTES.
THIS
IS WHAT OCCURS IN A EUDICOT. IN A MONOCOT,
IN
A MONOCOT EMBRYO, WE ALSO HAVE A PRIMARY ROOT
IN THE
EMBRYO.
BUT THIS ROOT IS SHORT LIVED. THAT IS, IT
DOESN'T LIVE VERY LONG. AND IS QUICKLY REPLACED
BY
SECONDARY ROOTS. I WILL ABBREVIATE SECONDARY
WITH
A 2. SECONDARY ROOTS.
THIS DIFFERENCE IN THE ROOT SYSTEMS RESULTS
IN
THESE MONOCOTS HAVING A FIBROUS ROOT SYSTEM.
FIBROUS
ROOT SYSTEM. AND BECAUSE MONOCOTS PRODUCE
A RELATIVELY SHALLOW FIBROUS ROOT SYSTEM,
FOR THOSE OF
YOU WHO HAVE EXPERIENCE OR WHO KNOW OF A FOREST
FIRES
OR FIRES WHICH BURN THE LAND, SAY IN SOUTHERN
CALIFORNIA. BEFORE THE WINTER RAINS COME,
THE LAND
WHICH HAS BEEN BURNED IS BROADCAST AND COVERED
WITH
SEED USUALLY BY HELICOPTERS OF MONOCOT, MONOCOT
SEEDS.
AND IT IS HOPED THAT THESE SEEDS WILL GERMINATE
AND
BECAUSE OF THE FIBROUS NATURE OF THE ROOT
SYSTEMS,
THAT THEY WILL KNIT TOGETHER THE SOIL AND
PREVENT
EROSION. SO, THESE ROOT SYSTEMS HAVE A COMMON
USE AS
FAR AS WE ARE CONCERNED. NOW, WHAT ABOUT
THE SIZE OF
ROOT SYSTEMS. BECAUSE THEY ARE UNDER GROUND
MOST OF
US DON'T REALLY HAVE AN APPRECIATION OF THE
SIZE OF
ROOT SYSTEMS. THE RATIO OF SHOOT TO ROOT FREQUENTLY
CHANGES THROUGHOUT THE LIFE OF A PLANT. WHEN
A SEED
IS TRYING TO ESTABLISH ITSELF, IT USUALLY
HAS MORE
ROOT THAN SHOOT. BECAUSE IT WANTS TO BE ABLE
TO GET
LOTS OF WATER AND NUTRIENTS BEFORE IT MAKES
A BIG
SHOOT SYSTEM. AS A PLANT AGES AND GETS TO
BE AN ADULT
OR MATURE INDIVIDUAL, THE ROOT AND SHOOT SYSTEM
COME
INTO BALANCE WITH EACH OTHER, SO THERE IS
A ABOUT A 1
TO 1 RATIO BETWEEN THE VEGETABLE MATTER AND
THE ROOT
AND THE SHOOT SYSTEM. FOR THOSE OF YOU WHO
ARE
GARDENERS, WHEN YOU TRANSPLANT THE PLANT AND
WHEN YOU
CUT IT OUT OF THE SOIL AND MOVE IT SOMEPLACE
ELSE,
WHAT ARE YOU DOING IS ESSENTIALLY SEVERING
OR CUTTING
OFF PART OF THE ROOT SYSTEM. YOU ARE CHANGING
THAT
RATIO BY CUTTING OFF THE ROOT SYSTEM. AND
THAT IS WHY
IT IS RECOMMENDED WHEN YOU TRANSPLANT A
PLANT TO CUT
OFF SOME OF THE SHOOT SYSTEM AT THE SAME TIME.
TO BETTER KEEP THIS RATIO IN ORDER. SO WHAT
I
WOULD LIKE TO DO NOW IS TO SHOW YOU A FEW
SLIDES OF
DIFFERENT ROOT SYSTEMS AND SHOW YOU SOMETHING
ABOUT
THE PRIMARY ROOTS. HERE IS A SEEDLING OF A
RADISH
WHICH HAS JUST GERMINATED AND HERE IS A EUDICOT.
HERE
IS THE PRIMARY ROOT. HERE ARE THE COTYLEDONS
AND THE
PRIMARY ROOT GROWS STRAIGHT DOWN. THIS IS
A, AS
OPPOSED TO THE ROOT SYSTEM OF A MONOCOT. THIS
IS A
CORN PLANT. MANY OF YOU HAVE SEEN CORN PLANTS
BUT
HAVEN'T REALIZED THAT THESE ARE ROOTS WHICH
ARE
FORMING ON THE STEM AND THEY ACTUALLY REPLACE
THE
PRIMARY ROOT, WHICH HAS DIED. SO, THAT IF
WE COULD
PEEL AWAY THE SOIL FROM A CORN ROOT SYSTEM,
WE
WOULDN'T FIND ANY ROOT PARTICULARLY PROMINENT,
WOULD FIND A LOT OF ROOTS AT THE SURFACE AND
THESE ARE
ALL, THEY ARE NOT PRIMARY ROOTS, THEY ARE
ALL
SECONDARY ROOTS OR ANOTHER TYPE OF ROOT
SYSTEM. BUT
THEY ARE NOT PRIMARY ROOTS.
THIS IS, AS OPPOSED TO SOMETHING LIKE EUDICOT,
IN WHICH THE PRIMARY ROOT IS STILL EVIDENT
HERE IN
THIS PARTICULAR PLANT. THIS IS CLOVER, OR
ALFALFA AND
YOU CAN SEE THE PRIMARY ROOT GROWING STRAIGHT
DOWN.
BUT IT ALSO, THIS ROOT SYSTEM HAS MADE SECONDARIES
OR
BRANCH ROOTS ALONG THE SURFACE OF THE SOIL.
HERE IS
AN EXAMPLE OF A MATURE INDIVIDUAL, AN APPLE
TREE, IN
WHICH THE ROOT SYSTEM WAS EXCAVATED. HERE
IS THE
SHOOT SYSTEM, AND TO GIVE YOU SOME IDEA OF
THE BIOMASS
THAT IS IN THE ROOT SYSTEM, THIS EXCAVATION,
NOTICE
THAT THE ROOT SYSTEM HAS FREQUENTLY MORE EXTENSIVE,
GOES OUT FURTHER THAN THE SHOOT SYSTEM DOES.
AND
PERHAPS THE BEST EXAMPLE I CAN SHOW YOU OF
THAT, OF
THE EXTENT OF THE ROOT SYSTEM, THIS IS TAKEN
DOWN IN
SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA IN THE DESERT. HERE IS
AN
INDIVIDUAL OVER HERE AND HE HAS EXCAVATED
A ROOT
SYSTEM OR COMING FROM THIS PARTICULAR PLANT.
SHOWING
THAT THE ROOT SYSTEMS CAN HAVE QUITE EXTENSIVE
AREAS
THAT THEY COVER AND DEPENDING UPON THE ENVIRONMENT
IN
WHICH THE PLANT IS GROWING, THEY CAN COVER
CONSIDERABLE AREAS.
SO, THESE ARE THE ROOT SYSTEMS AS FAR AS THEIR
DIVERSITY, AS FAR AS THEIR COVERAGE.
AND NOW WHAT I WOULD LIKE TO DO IS TO BEGIN
TO
TALK TO YOU A LITTLE BIT ABOUT ROOT DEVELOPMENT.
AND,
THIS WILL BE A SETTING FOR SOME OF THE GROWTH
AND
DEVELOPMENT THAT WE WILL BE TALKING ABOUT
LATER IN THE
CLASS. AND, FOR THIS PARTICULAR INTRODUCTION,
I HAVE
BROUGHT A MODEL ALONG, AND YOU WILL HAVE THIS
SAME
MODEL IN THE CLASS. AND WHAT I WANT TO POINT
OUT TO
YOU ON THIS MODEL IS THAT THE PEOPLE WHO MADE
THE
MODEL AND THIS IS REALLY PRETTY GOOD FOR OUR
CLASS,
HAVE DIVIDED THE ROOT SYSTEM INTO TWO PARTS;
INTO THIS
KIND OF GRAYISH PART, WHICH IS AT THE TIP
AND THIS
DARKER PART OVER HERE.
WHAT I WOULD LIKE TO DO IS TO TALK ABOUT THESE
TWO PORTIONS. AND WE WILL BEGIN FIRST WITH
THE GRAY
PART. SO LET ME FIRST MAKE A SECTION DOWN
THROUGH THE
CENTER OF THIS ROOT. A SECTION, WHICH IS A
LONGITUDINAL SECTION, WHICH IS ON THIS SIDE
HERE. WE
ARE GOING TO CUT THAT LONGITUDINALLY AND I
AM GOING TO
DRAW THAT SECTION FOR YOU UP HERE ON THE BOARD.
SO,
HERE IS A LONG STUDENT SIGNAL SECTION OF A
ROOT. WE
ARE GOING TO DRAW THESE TWO MAIN TISSUES THAT
ARE
ILLUSTRATED BY THIS MODEL HERE.
THE GRAY TISSUE TOWARD THE BACK OR TOWARD
THE
BOTTOM, IS A TISSUE WHICH IS KNOWN AS THE
ROOT CAP.
AND THE DARKER TISSUE, WHICH COMPRISES MOST
OF THE
MODEL OVER HERE, IS THE MAIN ROOT BODY.
MAIN ROOT BODY. AND I WANT TO PUT ONE MORE
LANDMARK ON THIS PICTURE BECAUSE WE WILL BE
REFERRING
TO IT AS WE GO THROUGH THE TALK TODAY. AND
THAT
LANDMARK IS A GROUP OF CELLS IN THIS REGION
HERE,
WHICH IS THE REGION OF THE ROOT APICAL MERISTEM.
AND
NOW WHAT I WOULD LIKE TO DO IS TO BEGIN TO
TALK TO YOU
ABOUT THOSE TWO MAIN TISSUES WHICH COMPRISE
THE ROOT.
THE MAIN BODY OF THE ROOT, AND THE ROOT CAP.
AND
LET'S BEGIN FIRST WITH THE ROOT CAP. THE ROOT
CAP HAS
A NUMBER OF REMARKABLE FUNCTIONS. THE FIRST
FUNCTION
IS THAT IT PROTECTS THE ROOT MERISTEM AS THE
ROOT
ADVANCES THROUGH THE SOIL.
JUST LIKE IN THE SHOOT
WHERE WE SAID THERE WERE EITHER THE BENDING
OF THE
EPICOTYL OR THE HYPOCOTYL OR A SHEATH COVERING
THE
SHOOT APICAL MERISTEM, THIS ROOT CAP COVERS
THE ROOT
APICAL MERISTEM AND PROTECTS IT AS THE ROOT
GROWS
THROUGH THE SOIL. ANOTHER RELATIVELY INTERESTING
FUNCTION AND AGAIN SOMETHING WHICH WE HAVEN'T
EXPLOITED, WE HAVEN'T REALLY ANALYZED, IS
TA IS ROOT
SYSTEM OR THE ROOT CAP SECRETES A LUBRICANT.
AND THIS
LUBRICANT IS THOUGHT TO HELP OR EASE THE PASSAGE
OF
THE ROOT THROUGH THE SOIL. AND A THIRD FUNCTION
THE MANY, WHICH THE ROOT CAP DOES, AND WHICH
WE CAN
ONLY TALK ABOUT TODAY, A THIRD FUNCTION IS
THAT THE
ROOT CAP IS THE SITE OF PERCEPTION OF GRAVITY.
IT IS
THE SITE WHERE GRAVITY IS PERCEIVED IN THE
ROOT
SYSTEM. IN OTHER WORDS THE ACTIVITIES OF THE
CAP
ALLOW A ROOT TO ORIENT TO GRAVITY. AND I WOULD
LIKE
TO DISCUSS WITH YOU BRIEFLY HOW THIS OCCURS,
BECAUSE
IT IS REALLY QUITE A REMARKABLE SYSTEM. I
WILL DRAW
FOR YOU ON THIS PARTICULAR DIAGRAM JUST THE
ROOT CAP.
NOT THE MAIN BODY. SO THE ROOT IS HERE AND
HERE IS
THE CAP. AND I WANT TO PUT A COUPLE OF CELLS
IN THIS
CAP, WHICH ARE INVOLVED, WE BELIEVE, IN THE
PERCEPTION
OF GRAVITY. AND I AM JUST GOING TO MAKE TWO
OF THEM,
ALTHOUGH THERE ARE MORE OF THEM IN THE CAP.
THESE
CELLS ARE CALLED STATOCYTES. AND IF WE COULD
LOOK AT
ONE OF THESE CELLS MORE CAREFULLY IN HIGHER
POWER,
A HIGHER POWER VIEW, WE WOULD FIND THAT ON
THEIR
LOWER-MOST SURFACE, ON THEIR LOWER-MOST
SURFACE, THEY
WOULD HAVE COLLECTIONS OF MEMBRANE-BOUND STARCH
GRAINS. MEMBRANE-BOUND STARCH GRAINS WHICH
HAVE
COLLECTED ON THE BOTTOM SURFACE OF THE STATOCYTE.
THESE MEMBRANE-BOUND STARCH GRAINS ARE GIVEN
A NAME. THEY ARE CALLED AMYLOPLAST. AND NOW
I WOULD
LIKE TO TALK TO YOU ABOUT HOW WE THINK THE
AMYLOPLAST
ARE INVOLVED IN THE PERCEPTION OF THE GRAVITY
VECTOR.
YOU NOTICE THAT I SAID THAT THE AMYLOPLAST
ARE ON THE
LOWER MOST SURFACE OF THE PARTICULAR STATOCYTE
THAT
THEY ARE IN. THEY ARE ON THE LOWER MOST SURFACE
BECAUSE THEY ARE HEAVY. THEY ARE DENSE. SO,
LET'S
TAKE A STATOCYTE AND WE WILL ONLY LOOK AT
ONE
STATOCYTE HERE. IT IS IN THE CAP. AND WE ARE
GOING
TO CALL THIS SIDE OF THE ROOT A, OF THE STATOCYTE
A,
AND THIS SIDE B. AND AT TIME ZERO, THE ROOT
IS IN
THIS PARTICULAR ORIENTATION LIKE SO, AND NOW
WE ARE
GOING TO DO IS TAKE THE ROOT AND TURN IT ON
ITS SIDE.
TURN IT ON ITS SIDE LIKE SO. SO, NOW WHEN
WE TURN IT
ON ITS SIDE THE NEW LOWER SURFACE IS GOING
TO BE B AND
A IS GOING TO BE OVER HERE. AND WHAT IS GOING
TO
HAPPEN IS THAT THESE STARCH GRAINS ARE GOING
TO FALL
TO THE NEW LOWER SURFACE. AND WE BELIEVE THAT
IT IS
THE MOVEMENT OF THESE STARCH GRAINS TO THE
LOWER MOST
SURFACE WHICH ACTUALLY ACCOUNTS FOR BOTH THE
PERCEPTION OF GRAVITY AND ULTIMATELY WITH
TIME THE
REORIENTATION OF THE ROOT TO THE GRAVITY VECTOR.
THIS
IS A VERY INTERESTING MECHANISM. IT WAS STUDIED
BY
DARWIN AND HIS SON FRANCIS AND THEY HAVE WRITTEN
A LARGE NUMBER OF PAPERS ON THIS PARTICULAR
SYSTEM AND
IT REALLY FASCINATED THEM. AND DARWIN WAS
ONE OF THE
FIRST TO APPRECIATE THIS PARTICULAR ACTIVITY
WHICH
WENT ON IN THE ROOT. NOW, IF YOU TAKE OFF
THE ROOT
CAP OF A ROOT, WHAT DO YOU THINK WOULD HAPPEN?
WELL,
IF YOU TAKE OFF THE CAP OF A ROOT IT, YOU
WILL SEE IN
A SLIDE THAT I SHOW YOU, IT DOESN'T RESPOND
TO GRAVITY
ANYMORE. IT CANNOT FIGURE OUT WHERE THE
GRAVITY
VECTOR IS. AND NASA HAS ACTUALLY TAKEN ROOT
SYSTEMS
AND THEY HAVE TAKEN THEM UP INTO THE SPACE
SHUTTLE OR
INTO THE SPACE STATIONS AND SEE WHAT HAPPENS,
WHICH
WAY WOULD THE ROOT SYSTEM GROW. ANYBODY HAVE
ANY IDEA
WHICH WAY THE ROOT SYSTEM WOULD GROW IN THE
MICROGRAVITY OR GRAVITY?
ANY IDEAS? EVERYWHERE. THAT IS EXACTLY RIGHT.
IT GROWS EVERYWHERE. THERE IS NOTHING FOR
IT, RANDOM,
NOTHING FOR IT TO PICK UP ON BUT IN FACT WHAT
IT DOES
PICK UP ON AS THE ASTRONAUTS WALK AROUND THE
SPACE
SHUTTLE OR THE SPACE STATION THEY IMPART SMALL
MONTH
MEN TA AND THE ROOTS ARE ABLE TO PICK THAT
UP AND SO
THEY DO HAVE A LITTLE BIT OF PERCEPTION, BUT
MOSTLY
THEY GROW EVERY DIRECTION BECAUSE THEY DON'T
HAVE
ANYWAY OF SEDIMENTING THEIR STARCH GRAINS.
NOW, WHAT
I WOULD LIKE TO DO IS TO SPEND SOME TIME LOOKING
AT
THE MAIN BODY OF THE ROOT. THIS OTHER PORTION
OF THE
ROOT WHICH IS REALLY OCCUPIES MOST OF THE,
ROOT, THE CAP IS ONLY A VERY TINY PART. AND
LET'S
MAKE ANOTHER DRAWING OF THAT SAME ROOT, WHICH
WE HAD
BEFORE. AND THE POINTS I WANT TO MAKE TO YOU
ARE THE
FOLLOWING: WE HAVE THE MERISTEM, WHICH WE
SAID WAS
A ZONE OF HIGH DIVISION. THAT IS WHERE CELLS
ARE
BEING PRODUCED. IF WE GO A LITTLE FURTHER
BACK ON THE
ROOT WE FIND WE HAVE CELLS ELONGATING. CELLS
ELONGATING. AND IF WE GO EVEN FURTHER BACK
IN THE
ROOT WE FIND THAT THE CELLS ARE DIFFERENTIATING.
THAT
IS, THEY ARE BECOMING THE VARIOUS CELL TYPES
THAT WE
TALKED ABOUT BEFORE, COLLENCHYMA, FIBERS AND
XYLEM AND
PHLOEM. NOW, BECAUSE THESE 3 DIFFERENT EVENTS
OCCUR
WITHIN A SINGLE ROOT, DEVELOPMENTAL BIOLOGISTS
HAVE
BEEN USING ROOTS FOR STUDIES FOR A LONG TIME.
BECAUSE
IN A SINGLE ORGAN YOU CAN HAVE CELLS DIVIDING,
ENLARGING AND UNDERGOING A STATE OF DIFFERENTIATION
ALL AT THE SAME TIME. AND SO, ROOT SYSTEMS
HAVE
ATTRACTED A LOT OF INTEREST FROM PLANT MOLECULAR
BIOLOGISTS BECAUSE ALL OF THESE EVENTS GO
ON WITHIN
A SINGLE PLANT, A SINGLE ROOT SYSTEM. NOW
WHAT I
WOULD LIKE TO DO IS TO TAKE THIS ROOT SYSTEM,
WHICH WE
HAVE DRAWN AND LONGITUDINAL SECTION AND TO
LOOK AT IT
IN CROSS SECTION, TO MAKE A CROSS SECTION
OF THIS
ROOT. YOU WILL HAVE THIS MODEL IN THE LAB,
YOU ARE
ALSO GOING TO HAVE A MICROSCOPE SLIDES TO
ALLOW YOU TO
LOOK AT THESE VARIOUS CELL TYPES, BUT WHAT
I WOULD
LIKE TO DO IS TO PUT THE LANDMARKS OF THE
CELL TYPES
ON NOW IN A DRAWING BECAUSE YOU ARE GOING
TO BE SEEING
THEM IN THE LAB, I THINK NEXT WEEK. SO, LET'S
NOW
BEGIN WITH A CROSS SECTION, A CROSS SECTION
OF
A TYPICAL EUDICOT ROOT. WE ARE MAKING A CUT
ACROSS
THE ROOT. AND WE WILL BEGIN WITH A ROUND PICTURE
WHICH IS THE CROSS SECTION OF THE ROOT AND
LET'S START
WITH A COUPLE OF LANDMARKS FOR OUR DISCUSSION,
IN THE
VERY CENTER OF THE ROOT IS THE VASCULAR TISSUE,
THAT
IS THE XYLEM AND THE PHLOEM. VASCULAR TISSUE
WHICH WE
TALKED ABOUT BEFORE. AND HAS VARIOUS ARRANGEMENTS
AND
YOU WILL SEE SOME OF THE ARRANGEMENTS IN THE
SLIDES
THAT I SHOW YOU AND ALSO IN THE LAB. AT THE
VERY
OUTSIDE YOU HAVE THE EPIDERMIS. AND YOU MIGHT
EVEN
HAVE A ROOT HERE.
THE MAJOR BODY OF THE ROOT, THE
MAJOR CELLS OF THE ROOT ARE IN THIS REGION
HERE AND
THEY ARE THE CORTEX. THEY ARE MOSTLY PARENCHYMA
CELLS. MOSTLY PARENCHYMA CELLS AND THEY FUNCTION
IN
STORAGE. THAT IS WHAT MAKES UP THE BODY OF
THESE
ROOTS, MOSTLY PARENCHYMA CELLS. THEY FUNCTION
IN
STORAGE OF STARCH AND SUGARS. NOW WE HAVE
ONLY A TWO
MORE REAL IMPORTANT CELL TYPES TO PUT ON HERE
FOR
DISCUSSION TODAY. AT THIS POINT OVER HERE
THE
INNER-MOST LAYER OF THE CORTEX, INNER MOST
LAYER OF
THE CORTEX IS GIVEN A SPECIAL NAME. AND IT
IS GOING
TO FIGURE PROMINENTLY IN A MOMENT WHEN WE
TALK ABOUT
HOW ROOTS FUNCTION. THAT INNER MOST LAYER
IS CALLED
THE ENDODERMIS. THE ENDODERMIS.
AND THE LAST LAYER
WHICH I AM GOING TO PUT ON FOR YOU HERE IS
THE LAYER
DIRECTLY INSIDE THE ENDODERMIS.
A LAYER DIRECTLY INSIDE THE ENDODERMIS THAT
IS
THE LAST LAYER YOU HAVE TO KNOW.
AND THAT LAYER INDIRECTLY INSIDE THE ENDODERMIS
IS CALLED THE PARACYCLE. NOW WHY IS THE PARACYCLE
IMPORTANT? WHY AM I POINTING IT OUT TO YOU?
THE
PARACYCLE IS THE SITE OF ORIGIN OF THE BRANCH
ROOT OF
THE LATERAL BRANCH ROOTS.
IT IS THE PLACE WHERE WE
FIND THAT LATERALS ARE PRODUCED AND WHERE
THEY
ORIGINATE AND THEY HAVE AN IMPORTANT FUNCTION
AS FAR
AS INCREASING THE SURFACE AREA OF THE ROOT.
WE WILL
TALK ABOUT THE LATERALS A LITTLE LATER ON
TODAY. NOW,
WHAT I WOULD LIKE TO DO IS TO SHOW YOU SOME
PICTURES
OF THESE VARIOUS ITEMS THAT I HAVE JUST BRIEFLY
INTRODUCED YOU TO. THE FIRST PICTURE IS GOING
TO BE
OF A ROOT WHICH IS SORT OF IN PREPARED TWO
WAYS. ON
YOUR LEFT IS A LONG STUDENT SIGNAL SECTION
THROUGH THE
ROOT, AND ON THE RIGHT IS A WHOLE ROOT, THEY
HAVE SORT
OF BEEN PUT TOGETHER IN A SINGLE PICTURE.
HERE IS THE
BODY OF THE ROOT, AND HERE IS THE ROOT CAP.
AND WHAT
I WANT TO POINT OUT TO YOU IS THIS SORT OF
TRANSLUCENT
TYPE OF MATERIAL HERE. THIS IS THE LUBRICANT
WHICH
COMES FROM THE ROOT AND FROM THE ROOT CAP,
AND WHICH
IS USED IN HELPING THE ROOT GET THROUGH THE
SOIL.
NOW, HERE IS THE SITUATION WHERE WE HAVE TAKEN
A CORN
SEEDLING AND THE ROOT WAS ORIGINALLY GROWING
DOWN.
AND WE NOW REORIENTED IT AT 90 DEGREES AND
THIS
REPRESENTS TIME ON THIS AXIS. AND AS TIME
GOES ON YOU
NOTICE THAT THE ROOT SYSTEM IS PRECEDING GRAVITY
AND
AS IT IS GROWING IT IS REORIENTING WITH REGARD,
SO
THAT ITS ORIGINAL ORIENTATION WITH REGARD
TO THE
GRAVITY VECTOR HAS BEEN RESTORED. THIS IS
BECAUSE THE
AMYLOPLAST NOW HAS FALLEN TO THE NEW SURFACE
AND HAS
STARTED THE PROCESS TO THE DETECTION OF GRAVITY
AND
THOSE PROCESSES WHICH RESULT IN THE REORIENTATION
OF
THE ROOT. AS A CONTRAST WITH AN EXAMPLE HERE
IN WHICH
THE ROOT CAP IS TAKEN OFF PRIOR TO THE TIME
THE ROOT
IS REORIENTED, IT IS THEN REORIENTED AND THE
ROOT
CONTINUES TO GROW ALONG BECAUSE IT DOESN'T
HAVE A CAP
NOW TO INDICATE WHERE THE GRAVITY VECTOR IS
LOCATED.
TO GIVE YOU A SORT OF SOME CARTOONS OR BETTER
VIEWS OF
THESE STATOCYTES, AS I SAID THERE ARE MORE
THAN TWO IN
THE CAP. HERE ARE THE STATOCYTES. HERE ARE
THE
AMYLOPLAST THESE ARE MEMBRANE-BOUND STARCH
GRAINS. IF
WE CHANGE THE ORIENTATION OF THE ROOT, THAT
IS OF THE
STATOCYTE, THEY FALL TO A NEW LOWER SURFACE
AND THAT
IS HOW THE ROOT DETECTS THE NEW DIRECTION.
AND THIS
IS JUST WHAT WE DRAW UP ON THE BOARD BEFORE
WHERE WE
HAVE THE SURFACE WHICH IS HERE. WE NOW REORIENT
THE
ROOT 90'S DEGREES AND THE STARCH GRAINS WHICH
WERE
RESTING OR COLLECTING ON THIS SURFACE NOW
COLLECT ON
THIS NEW LOWER SURFACE NOW AND COLLECT ON
THIS NEW
LOWER SURFACE AND THIS IS THE SIGNAL OR
AT LEAST THE
BEGINNING OF THE PROCESS FOR NOTING THAT THE
GRAVITY
VECTOR HAS CHANGED IN ITS DIRECTION. HERE
ARE SOME
AMYLOPLAST, THE ELCTROMICROGRAPH TO SHOW WHAT
THEY
LOOK LIKE. EACH OF THESE DARK BODIES IS A
STARCH
GRAIN AND YOU CAN SEE THE MEMBRANE, THE
ELECTROMICROGRAPH MEMBRANE SURROUNDING THIS
COLLECTION
OF STARCH GRAINS, WHICH MAKES THEM VERY DENSE.
CROSS
SECTION OF A TYPICAL DICOT ROOT, THE VASCULAR
TISSUE,
THE XYLEM AND PHLOEM ARE IN THE MIDDLE AND
I WILL SHOW
YOU A HIGHER POWER OF IT IN A MOMENT. MOST
OF THE
ROOT IS MADE UP OF CORTEX AND THESE PURPLE
CELLS ARE
DYED PURPLE BECAUSE OF THE STARCH, WHICH IS
IN THE
CORTEX. WE HAVE THE EPIDERMIS ALONG THE OUTSIDE
AND
NOW IF WE LOOK AT THAT CENTER PORTION WITH
A LITTLE
MORE DETAIL THIS LAYER OF CELLS WITH THE RED
ON IT IS
THE ENDODERMIS. AND DIRECTIONALLY INSIDE,
BY
DEFINITION, IS THE PARACYCLE. THAT LAYER OF
CELLS IN
WHICH THE LATERAL ROOTS FORM. AND THIS IS
THE
VASCULAR TISSUE. THE XYLEM AND THE PHLOEM
AND WE WILL
TALK ABOUT THAT A LITTLE MORE.
WHEN THE LATERAL ROOTS GROW OUT, THEY GROW
OUT
IN A PATTERN, THEY HAVE TO PUSH THEIR WAY
THROUGH THE
CORTEX. HERE IS THE PARACYCLE WHERE THEY ORIGINATE
FROM AND THEY HAVE TO PUSH THEIR WAY THROUGH
THE
CORTEX, ESSENTIALLY DISSOLVING THE CELL WALLS
OF THE
CORTEX UNTIL THE LATERAL ROOT FINALLY MAKES
IT OUT TO
THE SURFACE AND THEN BEGINS TO FUNCTION AS
A ROOT ON
ITS OWN. OKAY. SO THESE ARE SOME OF THE LANDMARKS,
SORT OF THE GENERALIZED CHARACTERISTICS AND
ACTIVITIES
OF ROOTS.
NOW WHAT I WOULD LIKE TO DO IS SPEND THE LAST
MINUTES OF TODAY TALKING TO YOU ABOUT PROBABLY
THE
MOST IMPORTANT FUNCTION OF THE ROOT. AND THAT
IMPORTANT FUNCTION HAS TO DO WITH WATER AND
NUTRIENT
UPTAKE. AND I WANT TO BEGIN BY SAYING A ROOT
IS
GROWING IN THE SOIL, LET'S TAKE THIS CARROT,
IT IS
GROWING IN THE SOIL AND IT IS EXPOSED TO LOTS
OF
DIFFERENT THINGS IN THE SOIL. MANY OF THE
THINGS THAT
ARE IN THE SOIL SURROUNDING THE ROOT SYSTEM
THE CARROT
WANTS NITROGEN, MAGNESIUM, CALCIUM, THESE
ARE ALL
IMPORTANT ELEMENTS FOR THE CARROT TO BE ABLE
TO
SURVIVE. BUT, THERE ARE A LOT OF TOXIC COMPOUNDS
IN
THE SOIL. A LOT OF COMPOUNDS IN THE SOIL THAT
THE
CARROT DOESN'T WANT. IT DOESN'T WANT SALT,
IT DOESN'T
WANT SODIUM. SODIUM IS BAD FOR ITS SYSTEM.
SO THE
QUESTION IS, HOW IS THIS ROOT SYSTEM ABLE
TO
DISCRIMINATE TO FUNCTION, TO TAKE IN MINERALS
WHICH
ARE BENEFICIAL, BUT TO EXCLUDE THOSE TOXINS
OR
POTENTIALLY TOXIC ELEMENTS OR OTHER COMPOUNDS
IN THE
SOIL WHICH WOULD NOT BE SUITABLE FOR THE GROWTH
OF THE
ROOT. WE WANT TO TALK ABOUT THIS AND IN ORDER
TO
CONSIDER THIS TOPIC, I WANT TO DRAW FOR YOU
A COUPLE
MORE LANDMARKS THAT WE WILL BE DISCUSSING
AND TO
MAGNIFY AND ABBREVIATED SOME WAY THE PORTION
OF THE
ROOT THAT WE HAVE ALREADY HAD. SO, WE WILL
NOW MAKE
ANOTHER CROSS SECTION OF A ROOT. AGAIN, BUT
WE ARE
GOING TO DO IT IN HIGH POWER AND WE ARE GOING
TO DO IT
ONLY WITH A FEW CELLS. ON THIS SIDE WE ARE
GOING TO
HAVE THE VASCULAR TISSUE, IN THE VARIOUS CENTER,
SO
THIS IS THE XYLEM AND THE PHLOEM. THEN WE
ARE GOING
TO HAVE AS WE MOVE OUT THE CELLS THAT WE NEED
TO KNOW.
WE ARE GOING TO HAVE THE ENDODERMIS AND THEN
WE ARE
GOING TO HAVE, I WILL JUST MAKE ONE LAYER
HERE RIGHT
NOW, WE ARE GOING TO HAVE A NUMBER OF CELLS
OF THE
CORTEX. AND THEN FINALLY, WE ARE GOING TO
HAVE THE
EPIDERMIS.
NOW, IN ORDER TO UNDERSTAND HOW THIS ROOT
IS
ABLE TO TAKE IN ONLY THOSE THINGS THAT IT
WANTS TO
TAKE IN, AND EXCLUDE THOSE THAT IT DOESN'T
WANT, WE
HAVE TO PUT A FEW MORE THINGS ON HERE FOR
YOU. THE
FIRST THING THAT WE NEED TO PUT ON AND THEN
OUT HERE
WILL BE THE SOIL, OF COURSE, FIRST THING
WE WANT TO
PUT ON THIS, WHICH IS IMPORTANT, IS THAT EACH
OF THESE
CELLS WHICH MAKE UP THE ROOT HAVE A MEMBRANE.
SO,
THIS IS A MEMBRANE. VERY IMPORTANT. AND IF
WE COULD
LOOK WITH WITH AN ELECTROMICROGRAPH, AND I
WILL SHOW
YOU SOME PICTURES OF THESE ELECTROMICROGRAPHS
IN
A MOMENT, WE WOULD NOTICE THAT RUNNING BETWEEN
CELLS
ARE TINY PORES.
TINY PORES.
WE CAN'T SEE THESE PORES WITH OUR EYE, WE
NEED
AN ELECTROMICROSCOPE TO BE ABLE TO VISUALIZE
THESE
PORES. BUT, IF YOU WERE A MOLECULE, IF YOU
WERE AN
ATOM OR A MOLECULE OF SAY A CALCIUM, TO YOU
THESE
PORES WOULD LOOK GIANT. THEY WOULD BE ABLE
TO, THEY
WOULD BE LIKE FREEWAYS, YOU COULD MOVE THROUGH
THEM
WITHOUT ANY, ANY PROBLEMS AT ALL.
THESE PORES ARE, AS I SAID, VIEWED ONLY WITH
THE
ELECTROMICROSCOPE AND THEY ARE CALLED PLASMODESMATA.
AND I WILL SHOW YOU A PICTURE OF THEM VERY
SHORTLY.
NOW WHAT I WOULD LIKE TO DO IS AN EXPERIMENT.
AND IN
THIS EXPERIMENT WHAT WE ARE GOING TO DO IS
WE ARE
GOING TO HAVE A SOLUTION WITH WATER, DOESN'T
MAKE ANY
DIFFERENCE, AND IN TO THIS SOLUTION OF WATER
WE ARE
GOING TO DISSOLVE TWO COMPOUNDS. WE WILL CALL
THEM A
AND B. A AND B. AND THEN WE ARE GOING TO PUT
A PLANT
IN THIS WATER WITH ITS ROOT SYSTEM, IN THIS
WATER, AND
ITS GOING TO SIT IN THERE AND WE ARE GOING
TO ALLOW
FOR SOME TIME TO PASS. ALLOW FOR SOME TIME
TO PASS.
SO HERE WE HAVE THIS PLANT SITTING IN THE
WATER
WHICH HAS A AND B IN IT. AND NOW SOME TIME
HAS PASSED
AND WE ARE GOING TO ASK WHAT IS HAPPENED TO
A AND B.
WHERE ARE THEY? WHERE DID THEY GO INTO THIS
PARTICULAR PLANT? LET'S SAY FOR THIS EXAMPLE
WHAT WE
FIND IS THAT A MAKES IT ALL OF THE WAY TO
THE TOP OF
THE PLANT. IF WE LOOK FOR B WHERE DID B GO,
B IS
CONFINED. IT APPEARS TO BE CONFINED TO THE
ROOT
SYSTEM.
IT IS CONFINED TO THE ROOT SYSTEM.
NOW, IN ORDER TO EXAMINE THIS A LITTLE MORE
CAREFULLY TO SEE WHAT IS GOING ON IN THE ROOT
SYSTEM,
I AM GOING TO DRAW THIS AGAIN. NOT QUITE AS
DETAILED,
BUT I AM GOING TO PUT SEVERAL LAYERS ON THIS
ONE FOR
YOU. SO, WE WILL START OUT AGAIN WITH THE
VASCULAR
TISSUE AND NOW WE HAVE SEVERAL LAYERS OF ENDODERMIS
AND NOW I AM GOING TO PUT ON SEVERAL LAYERS
OF CORTEX.
AND THE EPIDERMIS. HERE IS ANOTHER EPIDERMAL
CELL.
SO IT IS THE SAME THING YOU SAW BEFORE. NOW
I AM GOING
TO PUT SEVERAL LAYERS OF CELLS ON. LIKE SO.
SAME THING, THIS IS A CROSS SECTION OF A ROOT.
AND NOW LET'S LOOK TO SEE WHERE A AND B ARE
IN THIS
PARTICULAR ROOT, IN WHICH THAT PLANT HAS SHOWN
US THAT
A HAS GOTTEN ALL OF THE WAY TO THE TOP. IF
WE LOOK TO
SEE WHERE A IS, WE FIND THAT A IS INSIDE THE
CELL OF
THE EPIDERMIS INSIDE ALL OF THE CORTEX CELLS.
INSIDE
THE ENDODERMIS AND HAS MADE IT TO THE INSIDE
OF THE
VASCULAR TISSUE. THAT SEEMS LOGICAL BECAUSE
A IS
CLEAR UP AT THE TOP OF THE PLANT. THIS PATHWAY
THAT A
HAS TAKEN, THIS PATHWAY THAT A HAS TAKEN IN
ORDER, WE
ARE WRITING THIS DOWN TO YOU, THIS PATHWAY
OF A
INVOLVES CROSSING A MEMBRANE.
SO, LET'S GO BACK TO
THIS BIG PICTURE THAT I DREW OVER HERE AND
IN ORDER
FOR A TO GET INSIDE OF THIS CELL IT HAD TO
CROSS THE
MEMBRANE. THIS IS THE CRITICAL PART OF WHEN
THE PLANT
DECIDES TO MAKE A CHOICE. IF IT ALLOWS A TO
CROSS THE
MEMBRANE ITS MAKING A CHOICE. IT IS SAYING,
I WANT
YOU A, I WANT YOU TO COME IN, WHATEVER YOU
HAPPEN TO
BE. ONCE A ENTERS THOUGH, KEEP IN MIND IT
NOW HAS
FREE ACCESS TO ALL OF THE CELLS THROUGH THE
PORES.
FREE ACCESS AND IT CAN GO ALL OF THE WAY TO
THE
CENTRAL PORTION BY PASSING THROUGH THE PORES.
ANY
QUESTIONS ON THAT? AN IMPORTANT POINT.
THIS PATHWAY, THIS PATHWAY WHICH IS INSIDE
A MEMBRANE, IS KNOWN AS THE SYMPLAST OR
THE SYMPLASTIC
PATHWAY.
SYMPLASTIC PATHWAY.
ONCE AN ION ENTERS A SYMPLASTIC PATHWAY, THIS
PATHWAY, IT HAS ACCESS TO THE ENTIRE PLANT.
NOTICE THAT IT DOESN'T HAVE TO CROSS THE
MEMBRANE HERE, IT CAN CROSS THE MEMBRANE OVER
HERE,
BUT WHENEVER IT CROSSES A MEMBRANE, ONCE IT
GETS
ACROSS IT HAS ACCESS TO THE ENTIRE PLANT.
THAT IS AN
IMPORTANT PATHWAY. NOW, LET'S LOOK TO SEE
WHAT
HAPPENED WITH B. WE SAID B DIDN'T MAKE IT
UP TO THE
TOP OF THE PLANT. LET'S SEE WHERE B IS IN
THE ROOT
THOUGH. IF WE FOLLOW B WHAT WE FIND IS THAT
B IS
LOCATED IN THESE SPACES BETWEEN CELLS. THESE
SPACES
ARE KNOWN AS INTERCELLULAR SPACES.
AND IF WE HAD A
ELECTROMICROSCOPE WE WOULD ALSO FIND THAT
B IS IN THE
CELL WALL. IT IS IN THE CELL WALL. B IS IN
THE CELL
WALL. TO US THE CELL WALL MAY SEEM TO BE VERY
SOLID.
BUT, TO A SMALL MOLECULE THE CELL WALL IS
A MESH. IT
HAS LOTS OF SPACES AND PORES INSIDE OF IT.
AND IF WE
FOLLOW B WE FIND THAT IT IS IN THE CELL WALLS,
IT IS
IN THE INTRACELLULAR SPACES, IT GETS ALL OF
THE WAY TO
THE ENDODERMIS IN THE ROOT SYSTEM. ALL OF
THE ENDODERMIS. AND THEN IT IS STOPPED. IT
CANNOT GO
ANY FURTHER.
THE PATHWAY WHICH INVOLVES THE INTRACELLULAR
SPACES AND THE CELL WALLS DOES NOT INVOLVE
CROSSING
ANY MEMBRANES SO THE PATHWAY INVOLVING INTRACELLULAR
SPACES IS NOT INVOLVED IN CROSSING A MEMBRANE.
SO, WE GIVE A SEPARATE NAME TO THIS SECOND
PATHWAY, WHICH INCLUDES THE INTRACELLULAR
SPACES AND
THE CELL WALL. WE CALL THIS THE APPLEPLAST
OR THE
APPLEPLASTIC PATHWAY.
SO, THE PLANT DIDN'T WANT B, IT
DECIDED NOT TO ALLOW B TO CROSS THE MEMBRANE.
BUT, B
WAS ABLE TO FUSE INTO THE ROOT SYSTEM, TO
A CERTAIN
POINT, THEN IT WAS STOPPED. AND THIS IS THE
SECRET OF
HOW THE PLANT WORKS. BECAUSE THIS SPECIAL
LAYER HERE,
THE ENDODERMIS, WHICH I POINTED OUT TO YOU
BEFORE HAS
A PARTICULAR FEATURE WHICH STOPS ANYTHING
FROM MOVING
FURTHER INTO THE ROOT UNLESS THAT THING IS
IN THE
SYMPLAST. IT ESSENTIALLY IS THE GATE FOR THE
APPLE
PLAST. AND HOW DOES THE ENDODERMIS WORK?
I HAVE HERE A CARDBOARD BOX WHICH IS MEANT
TO
SORT OF ILLUSTRATE FOR YOU AN ENDODERMAL CELL.
AND
YOU NOTICE ON THIS CARDBOARD BOX, THAT I HAVE
THIS RED
CIRCLE GOING AROUND. THIS RED CIRCLE, ASSUME
THE
CARDBOARD BOX REPRESENTS THE WALL OF THE EPIDERMAL
CELL, AND THIS RED MATERIAL EXTENDS INTO THE
WALL AND
IT EXTENDS INTO THE INSIDE, IT GOES THROUGH
THE WALL.
WHAT IS THIS RED MATERIAL? WHAT DOES THIS
RED
MATERIAL FUNCTION AS? THIS RED MATERIAL IS
CALLED
SUBERIN. IT IS THE SAME MATERIAL WHICH MAKES
CORK
FLOAT. IT IS WATER IMPERVIOUS.
WATER IMPERVIOUS.
THAT IS, BECAUSE IT IS WATER IMPERVIOUS AS
SOMETHING
IN THE APPLE PLASTIC PATHWAY IS MOVING THROUGH
THE
CELL WALL IN A WATER SOLUTION, ONCE IT ENCOUNTERS
THIS
SUBERIN LAYER IT CAN'T GO ANY FURTHER. IT
CAN'T REACH
THE SITE OF THE CELL WALL BECAUSE OF THE BLOCKAGE.
THIS SUBERIN LAYER IS CALLED THE CASPERIAN
STRIP.
YOU
MIGHT SAY, OKAY, WELL, IT CAN'T GO THROUGH
THIS WALL
ANY MORE, IT CAN'T GO THROUGH THE APPLE PLAST
ANY
MORE. WHY CAN'T IT JUST GO AROUND IT, WHY
CAN'T IT
JUST GO THROUGH THE CELL AND WIND UP ON THIS
SIDE OVER
HERE? LET'S PRETEND LIKE THIS BALLOON REPRESENTS
THE
MEMBRANE SYSTEM OF THE ENDODERMAL CELL. THIS
MEMBRANE
SYSTEM IS TIGHTLY OPPRESSED ON ALL SIDES TO
THE
CASPERIAN STRIP INSIDE. IT IS RIGHT NEXT TO
IT. SO
THERE IS NO SPACE BETWEEN IT AND THE CELL
WALL. SO,
IF AN ION WANTS TO ENTER WHERE I AM, FROM
WHERE YOU
ARE, IT CAN'T SQUEEZE THROUGH THE CELL WALL.
IT CAN'T
SQUEEZE THROUGH THE SPACES BETWEEN THE MEMBRANE
AND
THE CASPERIAN STRIP. THE ONLY WAY IT CAN ENTER
IS BY
NOW PASSING ACROSS THE MEMBRANE.
ONCE IT IS ACROSS THE MEMBRANE, IT IS NOW
IN THE
SYMPLAST AND IT IS HOME FREE. AT THIS POINT
THE
PLANT, THOUGH, HAS STOPPED B FROM GOING IN
BY
PREVENTING IT FROM SQUEEZING THROUGH BETWEEN
THE
MEMBRANE AND THE CELL WALL OR BY CONTINUING
MOVEMENT
IN THE APPLE PLAST OF THIS CELL WALL. AND
TO GIVE YOU
SORT OF A BETTER EXAMPLE OF THIS, IT IS HARD
BECAUSE I
AM ASKING YOU TO THINK 3 DIMENSIONALLY HAVE
THESE 3
XEROX BOXES AND I WANT TO PRETEND LIKE THESE
ARE TWO
ENDODERMAL CELLS AND YOU SHOULD REALIZE THAT
IF I AM
THE VASCULAR TISSUE THEY EXTEND ALL OF THE
WAY AROUND
AND ALL OF THE WAY UP, BUT I CAN'T GO TOO
FAR UP OKAY,
SO THEY EXTEND ALL OF THE WAY AROUND. THE
CASPERIAN
STRIP IS REPRESENTED BY THE RED. AND THE CELLS
ARE
TIGHTLY GLUED TOGETHER WHERE INDIVIDUAL CELLS
COME IN
CONTACT. SO THERE IS NO WAY OF GETTING BETWEEN
THE
CELLS INSIDE WHERE I AM. THIS BUBBLE WRAP
IS MEANT TO
REPRESENT ONE OF THE MEMBRANES BETWEEN THE
CELLS. SO
THERE WOULD BE CORTICAL CELLS OUT IN THE
AUDIENCE OUT
WHERE YOU ARE AND THE BLUE REPRESENT THE
PLASMODESMATA, THE PORES. SO, ONCE YOU ARE
INSIDE THE
SYMPLAST YOU ARE ABLE THEN, TO MOVE WHERE
I AM IN THE
VASCULAR TISSUE. AND IF YOU WERE IN THE SYMPLAST
AND
YOU MADE IT THROUGH THIS PARTICULAR MEMBRANE
AND LET'S
SAY NOW YOU WERE INSIDE THE ENDODERMAL CELL,
WHAT
WOULD YOU SEE? IF YOU WERE INSIDE THE ENDODERMAL
CELL SAY YOU ARE RIGHT IN THE MIDDLE OF THIS
CELL
HERE, YOU WOULD LOOK UP, AND DOWN, TO THE
SIDE AND
AROUND. YOU WOULD SEE THE CASPERIAN STRIP.
BUT YOU
WOULDN'T CARE BECAUSE YOU ARE ALREADY IN THE
SYMPLAST
IN THE CASPERIAN STRIP IS A LONG THE OUTSIDE.
THE
CASPERIAN TRIP IS NOT A CURTAIN, IT IS ONLY
IMBEDDED
IN THE CELL WALL AND THE PROTOPLAST OR THE
MEMBRANE IS
WHAT PREVENTS MOVEMENT BETWEEN THE CELL WALL
AND THE
SYMPLAST, BECAUSE IT IS DIRECTLY AGAINST THE
CASPERIAN
STRIP. SO MAKE SURE YOU READ THIS IN THE BOOK.
IT IS
AN IMPORTANT POINT AND I KNOW THAT I AM
ASKING YOU TO
THINK 3 DIMENSION ALLEY ABOUT THIS. LET ME
NOW SHOW
YOU A FEW PICTURES OF THIS TO HELP YOU PUT
IT IN TO
CONTEXT AS FAR AS 3 DIMENSIONS. I REALIZE
IT IS HARD.
HERE IS THE CROSS SECTION OF THE ROOT JUST
AS WE
LOOKED AT BEFORE. HERE WOULD BE THE CORTEX
AND WHAT I
WANT TO POINT OUT TO THE CORTEX, HERE ARE
THE INTRA
CELLULAR SPACES BETWEEN ADJACENT CORTICAL
CELLS. SO,
IN THE APPLE PLASTIC PATHWAY, AND ION COULD
MOVE ALL
OF THE WAY THROUGH THE CELL WALLS AND INTO
INTRACELLULAR SPACES. UP TO THIS POINT HERE,
WHERE IT
WOULD ENCOUNTER THE CASPERIAN STRIP. ONCE
IT GOT
INSIDE THE CELL THOUGH, JUST LIKE I DREW THOSE
LITTLE
BLUE DOTS, THESE ARE THE PLASMODESMATA. THESE
ARE THE
PORES THAT YOU WOULD SEE IF YOU WERE MOVING
THROUGH
FROM ONE CELL TO ANOTHER. NOW, I WANT TO JUST
POINT
OUT TO YOU THE CASPERIAN STRIP AGAIN AND ITS
LOCATION
AROUND THIS HERE. IF YOU WERE A CELL MOVING,
AN ION
MOVING IN, THIS IS WHAT YOU WOULD SEE. HERE
IS THE
ENDODERMIS, AND HERE IS THE CASPERIAN STRIP
ALL OF THE
WAY AROUND. IF YOU WERE IN THE SYMPLAST YOU
COULD
MOVE DIRECTLY THROUGH FROM THE CORTEX TO THE
CENTRAL
CYLINDER TO THE VASCULAR TISSUE. BUT YOU NEED
TO BE
IN THE SYMPLAST. AND THE SLIDE THAT WILL TAKE
THIS
HOME AND I WANT TO MAKE SURE YOU LOOK AT IT,
IF NOT
HERE, IN YOUR TEXT BOOK, THE SLIDE WHICH WILL
TAKE IT
HOME IS THE SUMMARY SLIDE SHOWING YOU THE
TWO
PATHWAYS. THE APPLEPLASTIC PATHWAY IN WHICH
THE ION
IS STOPPED, HAVING TRAVELED THROUGH THE CELL
WALL AND
INTO INTRACELLULAR SPACE. AND THIS SYMPLASTIC
PATHWAY
WHERE THE ION HAS CROSSED THE MEMBRANE IN
THIS
PARTICULAR CASE, CROSSED IT AT THE ROOT HERE.
ONCE
HAVING CROSSED THE MEMBRANE, IT IS IN THE
SYMPLAST AND
CAN MAKE IT ALL OF THE WAY TO THE VASCULAR
TISSUE.
MAKE SURE YOU UNDERSTAND HOW THIS FUNCTIONS.
IT IS AN
IMPORTANT WAY THE ROOT WORKS.