I used to fuck with everybody.
Shit, when I was bored at
school, I used to draw people
and then have little arrows
pointing at different things
wrong with their gear
and shit like that.
[LAUGHTER].
And then I would show everybody
at EMB and shit.
You got to edit that out man.
[LAUGHTER],
PATRICK O'DELL: Hi, welcome to
the "Epicly Later'd" show.
This episode is about
Henry Sanchez.
Henry is famous for
skating EMB.
It was this spot in San
Francisco at the
end of Market Street.
It just was like the central
point of skateboarding.
Almost every skater
in the crew was
sponsored or became pro.
And Henry was definitely one
of the most influential
skaters of that group,
along with Mike Carol
and some other people.
Henry really brought in
a new set of tricks to
skateboarding.
Like, sometimes people get
really technical and skate
slow, but not Henry.
And I asked him a lot
of nerdy questions.
This is me getting nerdy on
Henry Sanchez at EMB.
It seemed like the ground's
really rough.
Like the bricks.
HENRY SANCHEZ: Yeah, I
don't understand how
we did that, man.
Because back then the wheels
were even smaller.
And it wasn't a problem
back then.
I guess when you get better
you start getting pickier.
Tripping on little cracks
here and there, but
look at this place.
It's a mess.
PATRICK O'DELL: Like
each one of these
little holes is a axle.
HENRY SANCHEZ: I always wanted
to do something different.
But not really try to draw
to much attention
to myself, you know?
Just do me.
I was intimidated because
everybody was
rude to all the newcomers.
And people were ignoring
me for a little while.
And then I just started
skating.
And if you're good, they're
going to be
cool with you, I guess.
THORIN RYAN: You definitely had
to be able to put up with
people talking shit to you.
You know what I mean?
You couldn't be fake.
Like, fake ass dudes just
weren't allowed to hang out.
It didn't matter who you were.
You could be pro, you
could be just some
300 pound black dude.
If you were straight up and was
cool, you could hang out.
If you weren't, it wasn't
going to happen.
Being a pro didn't mean
shit down here.
You get smacked up just
like everyone
else if you act stupid.
LAVAR MCBRIDE: And having
your own board.
It's just about--
MALE SPEAKER: Gold teeth.
LAVAR MCBRIDE: Huh?
Gold teeth?
Oh.
AARON MEZA: There was like--
dude, you hear about Jamie
Thomas who was supposedly a dude
who came to Barcadero and
had a hard time.
HENRY SANCHEZ: We had it
out for Jamie Thomas.
He was a pro back then.
I have no idea why.
[LAUGHTER].
It was just a local thing
or something.
Maybe because he came to
California and we thought that
he was just trying to juice
it too much or something.
I don't know.
It was really stupid.
I actually emailed him and
apologized for whatever I may
have done to him.
[LAUGHTER].
That's just how it was.
We were assholes.
[LAUGHTER].
AARON MEZA: I think people
have this whole idea that
anybody who went there that
wasn't from there was getting
their boards stolen.
But they would also do that
to each other a lot of
times too, you know?
JAMES KELCH: Yeah, yeah, I'd
throw my board and break it
all the time.
Throw it at kids.
There would be posses of kids
sitting there watching me
skate, and I'd think they
were laughing at me.
They probably weren't.
I was just--
not kids, either.
I always say the word "kid"
and people get it wrong.
People the same age as me.
I'd throw my board right
at their whole crew.
Smash right into them without
them looking because I thought
they were laughing at me.
But yeah, yeah, no doubt.
I probably broke a
board every day.
HENRY SANCHEZ: It all started
with skating.
I was a kind young man.
I never really stressed out on
anything before skating.
Then I started skating and I
just started stressing out.
And then it started going
into my personality.
Like if someone would say the
wrong thing to me, I'd be
like, what, grrr.
THORIN RYAN: He was the original
tantrum kid as far as
focusing boards, and dipping
boards, and screaming at your
board, throwing your board,
he was the original
dude to start that.
ROB WELSH: He was a little
stress case.
He would just skate around
and be better
than everyone, basically.
He was really good, even then.
But he would stress real bad.
He'd fling his board around
and freak out.
We called him "Hen-Punt."
He was a little
asshole, but I loved him.
THORIN RYAN: There'd be like
literally 400 kids
skating in the park.
And Henry, and Mike, and
sometimes Javontae would come
through, and everyone would sit
down because they would
just want to watch.
I mean, even people who could
skate and who were down here
everyday like me, you'd just
want to sit down and just
watch what they were doing.
It was ridiculous.
Like the switch stand stuff
and the nosegrind stuff.
AARON MEZA: He would just
be like, hey, let's
just try to film this.
He wouldn't be like, hey,
I want to do this.
This is the trick.
It was just like, hey, grab
the camera, let's
get this, you know?
But it was just that thing where
every day he would do
something that you'd
never seen.
Or one thing that I really
remember that he did first,
and I was really tripping out
pretty hard and I was like,
wow, that was super gnarly,
was he did a fakie.
Filoed a fakie flip out.
And you just see him
getting close to it
right away, like, whoa.
And it probably didn't take
him that many tries.
But he had that terminator
board.
I remember just seeing
it like--
[CHUCKLE].
You can just see the graphic.
He just did it completely
perfect.
MIKE CARROLL: We skated a lot
together when we first met
each other.
And it's weird because
I remember him.
There was a point where he was
trying all kinds of shit.
He was trying and trying and
sometimes he'd do it.
And this was when we were
skating together a lot.
And then, it's the same summer
that I went down to San Diego.
And I came back and it was
just like, holy shit.
Dude, this dude got
fucking sick.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
ROB WELSH: The best way to
describe Henry's skating is
he's kind of like
a bowling ball.
He was just plowing through
ledges like
there was no tomorrow.
And I think Henry's part of
the main reason they skate
stopped all these ledges here
because they're so round and
gouged out.
It's pretty sick.
It's like, oh, if it got skate
stopped, it got skate stopped
for a reason.
There's no more ledge,
anyways.
He just used it up.
You should go to a clip right
now, if you got one.
MALE SPEAKER: I think when they
do that, it's uglier than
any skate mark possible.
DAEWON SONG: He skated
just raw.
He was like the raw guy.
Raw street.
He always did the newest shit
that none of us could do.
He came down and you
were like, how
can you be that good?
You know what I mean?
And then we were all like the
guys who just watch and going,
all right, what's Henry
going to do now?
And then he would do it and
we were like, fuck.
How's that?
MALE SPEAKER: How's that?
DAEWON SONG: How's that?
HENRY SANCHEZ: I hooked up with
Guy Mariano and Daewon.
And Guy was really cool and he
was like, come stay with us
and blah, blah, blah.
Stay down here.
And that was Guy Mariano
and he was like one
of my favorite dudes.
So I was like, hell yeah.
And then I went skating
with Gonz one day.
And then Guy was like, do this
trick, do that trick, like
tricks that they saw
me do before.
[LAUGHING].
And then I did a couple tricks
and Mark's like, you're on.
It was the best day of my life
in skateboarding, man, to be
accepted by him.
If Mark was happy with my
skating, then that's all that
mattered, you know?
And he was happy with
it, so I guess
that's all that mattered.
JAKE PHELPS: I mean, after he
did the backside noseblunt,
that was his pinnacle moment.
It was like, wow,
who's this dude?
And then everybody wanted it,
but skating was so small that
there was no way that
people could--
he's the guy, I want a zillion
of his boards or whatever.
There was no marketing
behind any of it now.
Now it's like if some guy does
some mega trick, that's the
guy for that moment.
And then until that time or
somebody ups it, guess what,
you're out.
HENRY SANCHEZ: Those were
some dark years for me.
I wasn't too into skateboarding
and improving
myself at that point.
I was just sad.
I don't know why.
In reality, I didn't
have any worries.
All I had to do was ride
my skateboard.
[LAUGHTER].
But I was young though,
so, oh well.
But yeah, this is the place
where I could've proven
myself, but I didn't.
I proved to be a drunk.
[LAUGHTER].
I would sit on that bench
right there and drink
all day, with Geez.
It's like the cool thing to say
you don't have regrets.
But yeah, of course.
I could look back at a
lot of things that I
should have done better.
I should have took advantage
of the skill that I had.
And I didn't realize that until
my skill had diminished.
And yeah, when I look back and
I'm like, fuck, why didn't I
just skate?
I could've took more advantage
of the opportunity that I had.
I didn't.
You know Girl skateboards, I
should've rode for them, too.
I had a lot of bills because
I was making
good money with Blind.
I couldn't sustain my lifestyle
or even keep my car
or my apartment.
If I were to ride for Girl, I
would have had to take my car
back or something drastic
like that.
And I didn't want to do that
but I probably should have.
It was a dumb mistake.
I should've went with
those guys.
PATRICK O'DELL: So what have
you been doing lately?
HENRY SANCHEZ: A lot of people
just totally counted me out.
And there's a lot of lost
time, and a lot of
making up I had to do.
And I just felt the flame from
inside get heated up again,
and I was on a mission to
prove myself once again.
I didn't like where I was
standing in terms of my spot
in skate history.
I thought that I deserve more.
You know, more recognition.
So I had to prove
myself again.
I'm already happy now.
I'm in a new career.
I'm a auto body tech at
a auto body shop.
It's good man.
And I'm going to be making
my own hot rods
and shit like that.
So if you're a pro out there and
you want a hot rod, holla.
Because I'll hook it
up for cheap, dog.
Like a sick one.
No rust buckets.
[LAUGHTER].
PATRICK O'DELL: You can
fix up Brady's van.
HENRY SANCHEZ: Oh yeah,
yeah, definitely.
I could definitely hook
that shit up.
I saw it.
It doesn't look like it
needs much fixing.
But under the carpet,
you never know.
It could be a lot of rust and
shit like that underneath.
But all the trim and the
interior exterior looks clean
on the shit.
I was actually stoked to see
somebody invest money into a
old school vehicle like that.
It was tight.
I like that.
[CHUCKLE].