HARVEY FOSTER: You have to
believe in traveling.
You've got to go out
and do stuff.
Of course I've had fun.
I have fun everywhere, man.
Every single spot we went to
there's something to remember.
Like when my bike broke down.
The roughest moments
you remember a lot.
Well, at least my fucking bike
broke down on the Baja and not
in Victoria.
The day before though, I knew
my bike was running hard.
I need that wrench.
It's too loose.
We rode for half an hour, people
started passing me
because I wanted to slow
down and just enjoy it.
So I got all that out of me.
And fucking, the Canadians
are behind me--
Ky and Keegan.
He pulls up beside me and
I was smoking man.
I was smoking.
KYNAN TAIT: I don't know.
He was ahead of us and we pulled
over and there was just
oil everywhere.
He was leaking oil last night,
and then it just looked it
blew up today.
HARVEY FOSTER: A man's always
got to push his bike.
That's sick, hey?
That was dope.
I don't know, I wanted
to push my bike.
I got a moment with
her right now.
And he knows I don't have many
possessions in life except for
my motorcycle.
And he makes fun of me for being
a free spirit-- yeah,
I'll go whatever, do whatever.
But I'm going to sound like a
total typical Harley Davidson
dude, but my bike is my life.
When my bike broke down, Keegan
handed me the machete.
All right, cool.
It's not like all my anger
and all my shit is gone.
But it was like, whatever, make
the best of the situation.
I like the way this
guy thinks.
Got my fucking captain
right there, with me.
Actually, I like that you
were there a lot.
I was really fucking stoked.
I don't know if that's like a
teary moment or something for
people who don't know
me and this guy.
But we kind of do a lot
of shit together.
So when it broke down I was
like, who else would I want to
be beside me other than
the guy I'd go
across the country with?
KYNAN TAIT: Good riding
with you, Harvey!
HARVEY FOSTER: I didn't
get to do this trip.
Like, I did the trip
a different way.
That's all I think about in the
truck is like, oh man, I
hope we pull over somewhere
where they need gas and we can
skate some.
Yes!
That thing was really tight.
And it sucks, too, because there
was like professional
skateboarders there and
I couldn't do it.
When they could have done
a really good trick.
[SCREAMS]
Heath and Keegan placed a bet
whether I'd do it or not.
Heath said no one could do it.
Keegan said I could do it.
So then when I heard about
that, too, I was like I'm
letting Canada down.
Because we're used to stupid
spots that are really fucking
stupid to skate and we have
to work to skate them.
So I was kind of like fuck,
I blew it there.
But I don't have patience
for things like that.
I don't have patience at all.
If I didn't do it in ten
tries, I was over it.
[INAUDIBLE]?
No way.
It was hot, that's my excuse.
No, I'm over this.
But, I don't know, I think the
next two days are going to be
a lot of fun.
I can even feel it in
the group, too.
Because I think it's been hard
on them riding a lot in hot
weather, bugs, windy roads.
But I think the next few days
are going to be a lot of fun.
This is good to think
about, too.
BILL BRYANT: We're coming
out of Mulege.
It's about 15 miles south
and we rounded a
corner up on a hill.
And looking down onto that
bay, I think everybody's
stoked meter just went
through the roof.
That's what everybody
expects from Baja.
You want to see some crystal
clear water, you want to see a
big, white beach and hardly
anybody there.
And we rode down there and
stripped off our clothes and
ran out in the water
in our underwear.
I think that was an epic point
of the trip, it was just fun.
ARTO SAARI: Sorry about it.
Floating in paradise
with a beer.
I'm sorry.
I rode a motorcycle here.
HIME HERBERT: That was insane.
That was like a postcard.
Fuck, man, this is what
I signed up for.
KEEGAN SAUDER: I honestly can't
think of one high point.
Like, it just kind
of blends in.
The whole thing is
pretty magical.
Just the fact that we're all
doing this, the whole thing is
just amazing.
This is like, this is
living right here.
This is how it should be.
I know one day it's going to
end, so I'm definitely trying
to take full advantage of it and
just appreciate the hell
out of it right now.