and to inspire people to care about the planet,
when I'm home, I have just as much fun exploring
our corner of the world with my family.
These are my daughters Emma and Eva and today
we're going to explore our local park.
Let's go! Let's go!
Whether you have fifteen minutes or a full day,
there are so many wonderful lessons
for young explorers to experience locally.
Whether it's the backyard, the park, or a nearby beach,
there are many things to explore.
Some things I always like to bring along are
a digital camera.
Photographs are a great way for children to show
how they see the world.
A magnifying glass, to look closely at a piece of grass,
flower, or insect,
a net to catch little critters,
a little notebook to document what you found,
and binoculars, to take a closer look.
Remind your children to be gentle with whatever
they discover.
For me, the most important thing is just to get outside,
and most often, adventure will find you.
You can find more tips, ideas, and great activities
for exploring your surroundings
on potterybarnkids.com.
Get out and explore!