A REMINDER, FOR THOSE OF YOU WHO WERE NOT
HERE ON
WEDNESDAY, NEXT WEEK, NEXT FRIDAY WE START
THE BOOK
CLUB. SO 20 PEOPLE SIGNED UP SO FAR. IF ANYONE
ELSE
WANTS TO SIGN UP PLEASE COME UP AFTERWARDS
AND PUT
YOUR NAME AND EMAIL HERE. I WILL BE HOLDING
OFFICE
HOURS TODAY, OFFICE HOURS IN 20 WHATEVER.
SAME
ROOM THAT LOU WAS USING PREVIOUSLY, 13 MAYBE.
SO COME
ALONG IF YOU HAVE QUESTIONS I AM HAPPY TO
TALK TO YOU
ALL. OKAY. SO IN THE LAST, THE OTHER THING
I WANT TO
REMIND YOU OF IS THE UNDERSTANDING EVOLUTION
WEB SITE.
I TOLD YOU ABOUT THIS ON WEDNESDAY. IT IS
A REALLY
GOOD RESOURCE. AND A LOT OF USEFUL INFORMATION
THERE
PARTICULARLY, TO DO WITH PHYLOGENETIC'S AND
THE TREE
OF LIFE WHICH IS OUR SUBJECT TODAY. SO,
IN THE LAST
LECTURE WE WENT THROUGH THE FOUNDATIONS OF
THE
SO-CALLED THEORY OF EVOLUTION. FOUNDATIONS
OF
EVOLUTIONARY BIOLOGY. WE SORT OF ENDED UP
WITH TWO
BIG IDEAS.
THE FIRST WAS THE PRINCIPLE OF DESCENT WITH
MODIFICATION.
AND THE SECOND WAS THE PRINCIPLE OF
NATURAL SELECTION.
SO WHAT I WANT TO DO TODAY IS JUST TAKE YOU
THROUGH EACH OF THOSE. INTRODUCE YOU TO EACH
OF THESE
IDEAS AND THEN WE WILL GO ON TO LOOK AT THE
TREE OF
LIFE. HOW WE UNDERSTAND RELATIONSHIPS AMONGST
ORGANISMS GIVEN THEY HAVE DESCENDED THROUGH
EVOLUTION
THROUGH NATURAL SELECTION FROM A COMMON ANCESTOR.
TODAY IS ABOUT THE TREE OF LIFE AND IT CONNECTS
WITH
A LAB THAT YOU HAVE MAYBE NEXT WEEK OR THE
WEEK AFTER.
I AM NOT SURE WHICH.
SO, LET'S LOOK FIRST OF ALL THIS IDEA OF DESCENT
WITH MODIFICATION. SO THE ORIGIN OF THE
SPECIES IN
DARWIN'S BIG BOOK. THERE IS ONLY ONE FIGURE
IN THE
WHOLE BOOK. THE REST OF IT IS A BUNCH OF WONDERFUL
WORDS. BUT THE FIGURE, THAT FIGURE WAS REPRODUCED
IN
THE LECTURE NOTES FROM WEDNESDAY, THE LAST
LECTURE.
BUT IT IS SORT OF CARTOON VERSION OF IT WOULD
LOOK
SOMETHING LIKE THIS. AND SO ON.
THIS IS TIME COMING TO THE PRESENT. THIS IS
THE
PAST. ACROSS HERE WE HAVE SOME PHENOTYPE.
IT IS THAT
THE CHARACTERISTICS OF ORGANISMS COULD BE
LIFE
HISTORY, COULD BE GROWTH FORMS, COULD BE A
WHOLE
VARIETY OF THINGS WE WILL SEE LATER.
SO, SOME OF THESE THINGS DON'T GO ALL OF THE
WAY
TO THE TIPS. THESE ARE EXTINCT FORMS. DEAD.
OFF THE
PLANET. AND WE HAVE A COMMON ANCESTOR.
SO THESE TIPS
OF THE TREE ARE LIVING FORMS. THAT IS WHAT
WE CAN SEE
ON THE PLANET NOW AND THEY ARE DERIVED FROM
A COMMON
ANCESTOR OVER TIME AND BECOMING EXTINCT OVER
TIME IN
PHENOTYPE IN APPEARANCE IN THEIR TRAITS
AS A RESULT OF
THIS PATTERN OF DESCENT COMBINED WITH EXTINCTION.
YEAH IT IS EARLY, ISN'T IT. SO COMMON ANCESTOR,
DIVERSIFIED OVER TIME AND THEN DISCONTINUITIES
ARISING. GAPS IN THAT DISTRIBUTION OF PHENOTYPES
BECAUSE OF EXTINCTION.
SO WE HAVE DISCONTINUITIES
ARISING THROUGH
COMBINATION OF DIVERGENCES IN FORM OVER TIME.
COMBINED WITH EXTINCTION, WHICH IS ESSENTIALLY
PUNCHES
HOLES IN THE DISTRIBUTION. LINEAGES BECOME
EXTINCT
CREATING GAPS IN THESE PHENOTYPES. SO HOW
DOES THIS
ALL RELATE TO WHAT WE SEE TODAY? WELL, WE
SEE
VARIETIES OR SUB-SPECIES AMONG THE MOST CLOSELY
RELATED THINGS. THEY ARE CLUSTERED INTO SPECIES.
NOW
WE ARE COMING BACK TO THE LINNAEAN HIERARCHY
OF
TAXONOMY, VARIETIES OF SUB-SPECIES, SPECIES,
GENERA.
MAYBE THIS WHOLE THING IS A GENUS. SO, THAT
IS A
SPECIES. MAYBE ALL THIS IS A GENUS. SO, THIS
FIGURE
OUT OF DARWIN'S BOOK REALLY ENCAPSULATES
ALL THESE
IDEAS OF A COMMON ANCESTOR, DESCENT, EXTINCTION.
GIVING RISE TO THE BIOLOGICAL DIVERSITY WE
SEE TODAY.
VERY SIMPLE IDEA. AND, IN FACT, DARWIN DIDN'T
REALLY
SEE HUGE DIFFERENCE BETWEEN VARIETIES OR SUB-SPECIES
AND SPECIES. THE BOOK ULTIMATELY WAS ABOUT
SPECIATION, ABOUT THE FORMATION OF NEW SPECIES
THROUGH
EVOLUTION. HE SAW SPECIES AS ONE PART OF THIS
CONTINUUM OF EVOLUTION THROUGH TIME. AND THAT
THEY
ARE MAPPED BY THESE DISCONTINUITIES. AND THAT
THIS
WHAT ENDS UP AS ONE CLUSTER. IF YOU LACK PHENOTYPES
OR
THE INDIVIDUALS ARE MORE SIMILAR TO EACH OTHER
THAN
THEY ARE TO ANYTHING ELSE. HERE IS ANOTHER
CLUSTER
HERE PERHAPS. ANOTHER CLUSTER HERE. SO NOW
YOU HAVE
3 SPECIES HERE. BUT THE REASON WE CAN DISCERN
THEM,
DETECT THEM IS BECAUSE OF THESE DISCONTINUITIES
CAUSED
BY EXTINCTION. PUTTING HOLES IN THIS DISTRIBUTION
OF
PHENOTYPE. MAKE SENSE? NO? ANY QUESTIONS?
O'CLOCK IN THE MORNING IS BRUTAL.
IT
DEPENDS ON WHERE YOU GET THESE
DISCONTINUITIES THROUGH THIS DIVERSIFICATION
PROCESS.
YOU MIGHT CALL THIS A SPECIES, THIS A SPECIES
AND THIS
A SPECIES. THEY ARE ALL SIMILAR BECAUSE THEY
HAVE
A COMMON ANCESTOR SO THEY ARE GROUPED INTO
A GENUS.
OKAY? AND SO GENERA ARE GROUPED IN FAMILIES.
FAMILIES ARE GROUPED INTO ORDERS.
SO, SOMETIMES YOU HAVE A SINGLE SPECIES IN
A GENUS. HOMOSAPIENS IS THE ONLY EXTANT HOMO.
IT IS
WITHIN THE HOMINIDS WHICH IS A BIG GROUPING.
DOES
THAT MAKE SENSE?
SO, IN THIS PARTICULAR EXAMPLE WE HAVE GOT
SPECIES IN A GENUS. IN OTHER CASE YOU MAY
HAVE
SOMETHING THAT IS REALLY DISTINCTIVE OUT HERE.
SO, IT
IS THAT MORE DISTINCTION THAT DISTINCT MIGHT
BE A
SINGLE SPECIES IN A SINGLE GENUS.
CAUSED BY BOTH. THE BRANCHING PROCESS OVER
TIME
AND EXTINCTION OF INTERMEDIATE FORMS. THINK
ABOUT
BOTH THINGS HAPPENING SIMULTANEOUSLY. OKAY.
ALL
RIGHT. WE CAN COME BACK TO THIS AS NEED BE.
LET'S
LOOK AT THE SECOND IDEA, WHICH IS THE PRINCIPLE
OF
NATURAL SELECTION.
WE WILL COME BACK TO THIS IN MORE DETAIL LATER.
BUT ARISES FROM SEVERAL OBSERVATIONS AND A
SORT OF
CHAIN OF LOGIC THAT DARWIN AND WALLACE PUT
FORWARD.
THAT IS, INDIVIDUALS VARY FOR TRAITS. THAT
IS;
CHARACTERISTICS, ALL VARY IN HEIGHT, EYE COLOR,
HAIR
COLOR, A WHOLE BUNCH OF PROPERTIES. EACH ONE
OF THOSE
IS A TRAIT.
IF THOSE TRAITS ARE AT LEAST PARTLY
HERITABLE,
THAT IS, PASSED FROM PARENT TO OFFSPRING,
IF INDIVIDUALS CARRYING THOSE DIFFERENT TYPES
OF
TRAITS VARY IN SURVIVAL OR REPRODUCTION,
THAT IS,
SO-CALLED FITNESS, SO IF THOSE THREE CONDITIONS
ARE
MET, THEN THE TRAITS THAT INCREASE SURVIVAL
AND
REPRODUCTION WILL BECOME MORE COMMON IN THE
NEXT
GENERATION. IT IS A MATHEMATICAL INEVITABILITY.
IF
SOME VARIETIES, LET'S SAY GET BLUE EYES, INCREASE
THE
SURVIVAL AND REPRODUCTION FOR SOME REASON.
WE KNOW IT
IS HERITABLE. IF THE INDIVIDUALS WITH BLUE
EYES IN
THIS AUDIENCE LEAVE MORE OFFSPRING TO THE
NEXT
GENERATION, BLUE EYES ITSELF WILL BE MORE
COMMON IN
THAT POPULATION. OKAY?
SO, YOU INCREASE THE PROPORTION OF FAVORABLE
TRAITS IN THE NEXT GENERATION. SO, VERY IMPORTANT
THING HERE. INDIVIDUALS THAT REPRODUCE OR
DIE. IT IS
POPULATIONS OR SPECIES THAT EVOLVE. INDIVIDUALS
DO
NOT EVOLVE. OKAY? ONLY POPULATION, ONLY GROUPS
OF
INDIVIDUALS HAVE THIS CHARACTERISTIC POPULATIONS
AND
SPECIES.
BUT THEY DO SO BECAUSE OF THE DIFFERENCES
IN
REPRODUCTION AND SURVIVAL AMONGST INDIVIDUALS
ACCORDING TO THE TRAITS THAT THEY CARRY.
OKAY. AND WE ARE GOING TO COME BACK TO THIS
PRINCIPLE, FOUNDATION OF EVOLUTIONARY THEORY
IN MORE
SOPHISTICATED MATHEMATICAL TERMS LATER ON.
SO, BRIEFLY MENTIONED, I WILL COME BACK AND
REVISIT THE IDEA OF THE WAY THEY KNITTED TOGETHER
THE
EVIDENCE FOR THIS IDEA. TWO IDEAS, DISSENT
WITH
MODIFICATION, NATURAL SELECTION. THEY ARE
THE TWO
OBSERVATIONS. SO AGAIN, SOME OF THE EVIDENCE
THAT, I
CAN'T SPELL TODAY, THAT THEY BROUGHT TO BEAR
ON THIS
WAS ARTIFICIAL SELECTION. THAT IS, BREEDERS
OF
PIGEONS AND DOGS AND SO ON AND SO FORTH. AND
THAT
SHOWED IF YOU PREFER A PARTICULAR VARIANT
IN THE
POPULATION AND ONLY BRED WITH THOSE INDIVIDUALS,
FOR
EXAMPLE, THAT YOU SAW THE INCREASE IN THE
PREFERRED
TRAIT.
THE OTHER LINES OF EVIDENCE THAT I MENTIONED
IN
THE LAST LECTURE WERE THE FACT THAT THERE
WAS
POPULATION PRESSURE. THERE IS COMPETITION.
MORE
OFFSPRING ARE PRODUCED THAT CAN SURVIVE. MORE
ZYGOTES
ARE PRODUCED AND CAN SURVIVE GIVING RISE
IN
DIFFERENCES IN REPRODUCTION AND SURVIVAL.
THE FOSSIL RECORD
WHICH SHOWS BY EXTINCTION
AND
PROVIDES DIRECT EVIDENCE AS WE WILL SEE LATER
TO
TRANSITIONAL FORMS.
BY RECONSTRUCTING CHARACTERISTICS
BACK FROM THE TREE OF LIFE, YOU CAN PREDICT
THAT THERE
SHOULD BE SOMETHING IN THE PAST THAT HAS A
PARTICULAR
COMBINATION OF CHARACTERISTICS. AND, IF YOU
ARE
FORTUNATE YOU CAN TEST THAT PREDICTION IF
YOU HAVE
A REALLY GOOD FOSSIL RECORD BY LOOKING FOR
THAT GROUP
OF ORGANISMS. YOU CAN TEST IT BY LOOKING FOR
THAT
COMBINATION OF FORMS. AND WE WILL SEE AN EXAMPLE
OF
THAT LATER ON. WE TALKED ABOUT BIOGEOGRAPHY,
ISLAND
RADIATIONS, AND SO FORTH. AGAIN, DARWIN AND
WALLACE
SAW THESE OR CONTRIBUTED TO THIS IDEA. THE
OTHER ONE I
WANT TO SPENT A MINUTE ON HERE BECAUSE IT
RELATES TO
HOW WE ESTIMATE RELATIONSHIPS, COMES FROM
THE
EMBRYOLOGY AND COMPARATIVE ANATOMY. WHICH
IS, THE
IDEA OF HOMOLOGOUS STRUCTURES. THAT THERE
ARE
PARTICULAR STRUCTURES THAT DIFFER AMONG RELATED
GROUPS
OF ORGANISMS BUT THEY ALL COME FROM A SINGLE
ANCESTOR
CONDITION THROUGH DESCENT OF MODIFICATION.
SO, LET'S LOOK AT THIS IDEA A BIT. PRINCIPLE
OF
HOMOLOGY.
SO, AT THIS POINT I WANT YOU TO TURN TO THE
FOURTH SLIDE. I HOPE YOU CAN ALL ACCESS THESE
NOW ON
THE WEB. PRINT THEM OUT, BRING THEM ALONG.
DID YOU
REMEMBER TO DO THAT? I TOLD YOU SO.
PRINT THEM OUT. MY DRAWING IS TRULY AWFUL.
ANY
QUESTIONS?
OKAY.
SO, LET'S LOOK AT AN EXAMPLE ON SLIDE 4. I
WILL
NOT DRAW IT. BUT CONSIDER TETRAPOD VERTEBRATES,
THAT
IS THE BIRDS, MAMMALS, REPTILES, AMPHIBIANS.
THAT FALL
IN VERTEBRATES. SO, IN HUMANS OR MAMMALS YOU
HAVE A
FOREARM. THIS THING. IN CATS YOU HAVE FULL
A LIMB.
I WON'T IMITATE A CAT, KIND OF PATHETIC.
IN WHALES
YOU HAVE A FLIPPER AT THE FRONT. IN BATS YOU
HAVE GOT
A WING. IF YOU LOOK IN DETAIL AT THE ANATOMY
AND THE
DEVELOPMENT ACROSS THOSE TETRAPODS YOU SEE
THEY ARE
ALL DERIVED FROM A COMMON STRUCTURE. THE TETRAPOD
FOUR LIMB. IT ONLY MAKES SENSE IN A LOT OF
EVOLUTION.
FUNCTIONALLY DIFFERENT STRUCTURES FLYING,
SWIMMING,
WALKING, WAVING. ALL COME FROM A COMMON ANCESTRAL
CONDITION, WHICH IS THE ANCESTRAL FOUR LIMB.
AGAIN YOU
CAN SEE THAT IN DEVELOPMENT AND MOLECULAR
DETAILS OF
DEVELOPMENT AND THE COMPARATIVE ANATOMY. TURNING
TO
EMBRYOS, IF YOU COMPARE THE END EMBRYONIC
STAGES OF AN
AMPHIBIAN, A REPTILE, A BIRD OR A MAMMAL,
THEY ALL
START OUT AS AN EARLY ZYGOTE. SIMILAR PATTERNS
OF
DIVISION AND THEN BECOME SOMEWHAT DIFFERENT.
AND THEN
DURING SOME STAGE OF THEIR DEVELOPMENT YOU
CAN SEE
A SORT OF COMMON STRUCTURE. THEY CONVERGE
AGAIN ON
A COMMON APPEARANCE WHICH IS SOMETIMES CALLED
THE
PHYLOTYPIC STAGE. YOU ARE GOING FROM THE
EGG
FERTILIZED TO GIVE YOU ZYGOTE.
THIS DEVELOPS AND THEN
THIS PARTICULAR STAGE OF DEVELOPMENT, THE
SAME IS TRUE
OF INSECTS, YOU LOOK WITHIN GROUPS OF INSECTS
AND
ACROSS VERTEBRATES. THIS PARTICULAR STAGE
OF
DEVELOPMENT, SO CALLED PHYLOTYPIC STAGE, THEY
ALL LOOK
REALLY, REALLY SIMILAR. THEN I DIVERGE TO
GIVE RISE
TO THE, THROUGH BIRTH, THE JUVENILE THEN TO
THE ADULT.
THERE IS A STAGE WHERE YOU CAN SEE VERY COMMON
APPEARANCES AND STRUCTURES.
NOW, IF WE LOOK AT SOME OF THESE STAGES,
PARTICULAR PHYLOTYPIC STAGE, WHERE ALL THESE
THINGS
THAT ARE VERY DIFFERENT IN THE ADULT FORM
LOOK VERY
SIMILAR AS EMBRYOS, YOU CAN SEE PARTICULAR
STRUCTURES,
THAT AS THEY DEVELOP FURTHER, TAKE ON VERY
DIFFERENT
FUNCTIONS. THE EXAMPLE I HAVE GIVEN YOU HERE
IN THE
COMPARING A CHICKEN AND A HUMAN EMBRYO IS
THE
PHARYNGEAL POUCHES.
WHICH YOU CAN SEE IN COMMON ACROSS ALL OF
THE
VERTEBRATE EMBRYOS. IN FISH, THAT GOES ON
TO FORM THE
GILLS. YOU JUST FOLLOW THE DEVELOPMENT STAGE
BY STAGE
BY STAGE. IN MAMMALS, IT IS GOING TO TURN
A DIFFERENT
FUNCTION. IT IS NOW FORMING PART OF THE STRUCTURE
OF
THE EARS AND THE THROAT. REALLY DIFFERENT
STRUCTURE
IN THE ADULT FORM BUT THEY HAVE A COMMON DEVELOPMENTAL
STAGE IN THESE PHARYNGEAL POUCHES. SO JUST
A FEW
WEEKS AGO PEOPLE SORT OF WONDERED WHY DO YOU
START
FROM A EGG THEN BECOME DIFFERENT AND SIMILAR
AGAIN AT
THIS STAGE AND THEN BECOME DIFFERENT AGAIN?
AND JUST
A FEW WEEKS AGO IN NATURE THERE WAS A SERIES
OF
STUDIES WHERE THEY TOOK EMBRYOS AT EVERY STAGE
DEVELOPMENT. ONE GROUP DID IT IN VERTEBRATES,
IN
ZEBRA FISH AND RELATIVES AND ANOTHER GROUP
DID IT IN
DROSOPHILA OR FLIES. AND THEY FOUND THAT THE
PHYLOTYPIC STAGE THESE THINGS LOOK SIMILAR,
MOST OF
THE GENES THAT WERE EXPRESSED AT THIS STAGE,
GENES
THAT AROSE VERY EARLY IN THE DEVELOPMENT
OF THAT
LINEAGE, ANCESTRAL GENES IF YOU LIKE. THIS
IS WHERE
WE ARE GETTING ANCESTRAL GENES EXPRESSED.
AS YOU
BECOME MORE AND MORE DIFFERENT LATER IN DEVELOPMENT
YOU ARE GETTING NEWLY ARISEN NOVEL GENES BEING
EXPRESSED. WE CAN UNDERSTAND THIS BY LOOKING
TO
PHYLOGENY OF THE GENES. WHICH GENES WERE PRESENT
AND
HAVE COMMON FUNCTION WAY BACK IN THE COMMON
ANCESTOR
OF ALL OF THE VERTEBRATES OF A COMMON ANCESTOR
OF
INSECTS. THE OTHER ONES THAT ARE EXPRESSED
AT THIS
STAGE WHERE YOU GET SIMILAR STRUCTURES SORT
OF MAKES
SENSE. ONLY RECENTLY WE HAVE GOTTEN THE DIRECT
EVIDENCE TO SHOW THAT. WE ARE GETTING AN IDEA
OF
MECHANISMS THAT UNDERLIES THESE OBSERVATIONS
THAT HAVE
BEEN MADE IN EMBRYOLOGY FOR 100 OR MORE YEARS.
PRETTY
COOL.
OKAY. WHAT ELSE HAVE I GOT THERE. THE NEXT
SLIDE, SLIDE 6, AGAIN I WON'T DRAW IT OUT,
IS
MOLECULAR HOMOLOGIES. OF COURSE, DARWIN
DIDN'T KNOW
ABOUT HOW INHERITANCE WORKED AND DNA. DIDN'T
KNOW
ABOUT DEVELOPMENTAL PATHWAYS OF GENES. YET,
THE
THEORY OF EVOLUTION THAT HE AND WALLACE PUT
FORWARD
EXPLAINS A LOT OF NEW KNOWLEDGE THAT WE ARE
GETTING
FROM MOLECULAR BIOLOGY. OF THE SIMPLEST, THE
GENETIC
CODE. THE WAY WE TRANSLATE FROM THE DNA SEQUENCE
TO
AMINO ACIDS AND A PROTEIN IS IN COMMON ACROSS
THE
EUKARYOTICS, PLANTS AND FUNGI AND ANIMALS.
IT IS
COMMON BECAUSE THEY AROSE FROM A COMMON ANCESTOR.
EVEN BETTER YOU CAN LOOK AT THE ARRANGEMENT
OF GENES
IN PARTICULAR DEVELOPMENTAL PROGRAMS. YOU
SEE THE
ARRANGEMENT OF GENES AND THEIR PATTERN OF
EXPRESSION
IN THE EARLY EMBRYO IS THE SAME BETWEEN DROSOPHILA
AND
MOUSE. YOU CAN TAKE ONE OF THESE GENES OUT
OF MOUSE
AND RECOVER A MUTATION IN DROSOPHILA. SO THESE
ARE
GENES THAT ARE DORSAL OR VENTRAL PATTERNING,
THAT IS,
PICKING OUT WHICH PART OF THE EMBRYO WILL
BE THE
DORSAL OR TOP OR WHICH WILL BE THE BOTTOM,
VENTRAL.
IT IS THE SAME DEVELOPMENTAL PROGRAM WITH
SOME
MODIFICATIONS IN INSECTS AS IT IS IN VERTEBRATES
IN
MICE. YOU CAN SEE THAT WHEN YOU SEQUENCE THE
DNA.
DARWIN DIDN'T USE THIS AS EVIDENCE BECAUSE
HE HAD NO
CLUE ABOUT THIS. AS WE HAVE GONE ON GETTING
MORE AND
MORE FROM DEVELOPMENTAL BIOLOGY AND SO FORTH,
AGAIN,
IT ALL MAKES SENSE IN TERMS OF THESE IDEAS
OF
HOMOLOGIES AND MODIFICATION AND SO ON. IT
JUST GETS
BETTER AND BETTER.
SO PEOPLE WILL TALK ABOUT THE THEORY OF
EVOLUTION. JUST A THEORY. JUST SOMEONE'S CRAZY
IDEA.
THE MARK OF A THEORY THAT WORKS IS AS YOU
ACCUMULATE
MORE AND MORE EVIDENCE THAT EXPLAINS MORE
AND MORE
THINGS. AND PEOPLE TEST IT CRITICALLY AND
WE ARE
STILL REFINING THE DETAILS BUT THE THEORY
ITSELF IS
HELD UP SIMPLY AS THE BEST IDEA IN BIOLOGY.
IT
EXPLAINS MOST OF ANY POSSIBLE THEORY. OKAY.
BLAH BLAH BLAH. LET'S, I AM GETTING ON MY
SOAP
BOX AGAIN. I AM STARTING TO WAKE UP YOU SEE.
LET'S
MOVE ON TO THIS IDEA OF THE TREE OF LIFE.
THIS
CONCEPT OF HOMOLOGIES IS GOING TO COME UP
AGAIN AND
AGAIN AS WE SEE WHAT IS THE TREE OF LIFE AND
HOW DO WE
ESTIMATE IT AND HOW DO SCIENTISTS GO ABOUT
UNDERSTANDING THE TREE OF LIFE. WHAT WE ARE
GOING TO
TALK ABOUT IS ESTIMATING A PHYLOGENY
AND THE BRANCH OF
SCIENCE THAT DOES THIS IS CALLED SYSTEMATICS.
DISCOVERING SPECIES ALL RELATED BACK INTO
THIS LARGER
TREE OF LIFE. WHEN I WAS A LAD, WHICH WASN'T
SO LONG
AGO, REALLY JUST A FEW WEEKS, WE THOUGHT THERE
WAS
SORT OF THE PROKARYOTES, SINGLE CELLED ORGANISMS
WITH
NO INTERNAL ORGANELLES AND SO FORTH. AND THEN
THE
EUKARYOTES FOR THE ORGANISMS WITH INTRACELLULAR
ORGANELLES, MITOCHONDRIA, CHLOROPLASTS, ENCLOSED
NUCLEUS, ALL THAT STUFF. AND THEN WE SPLIT
THEM OUT
INTO MAJOR GROUPS OF PLANTS, FUNGI, ANIMALS,
SINGLE
CELLED EUKARYOTES, WHICH WE CALLED THE PROTISTA.
WE
WERE PRETTY SMART. WE THOUGH THAT WE HAD IT
NAILED.
THIS SCHEME GOES WAY, WAY BACK TO LINNAEUS.
TURNS OUT
WE ARE DEAD WRONG. MOST PEOPLE STARTED SEQUENCING
HOMOLOGOUS GENES FROM ACROSS ALL OF LIFE.
THEN
DISCOVERED WE HAVE THIS TOTALLY WRONG. TURNS
OUT
THERE WERE 3 MAJOR DOMAINS OF LIFE. ONE IN
EUKARYOTES, WE GO THE THAT RIGHTS. PROKARYOTES
WERE
SPLIT INTO TWO FUNDAMENTALLY DIFFERENT GROUPS.
THE
ARCHAEA AND THE EUBACTERIA. AN EXAMPLE OF
EUBACTERIA
IS E. COLI. IT IS INSIDE ALL OF YOU. IT IS
HUMAN
COMMENSAL. AN EXAMPLE OF ARCHAEA'S ARE FIRMUS
AQUATICUS. ANYONE EVER DONE PCR? ANY OF YOU
AT THIS
STAGE? THIS SO-CALLED TEC ENZYME THAT YOU
USE AND
WHICH WORKS AT VERY HIGH TEMPERATURES. THE
FIRMUS
AQUATICUS, THIS IS AN EXAMPLE OF ARCHAEA THAT
COMES
FROM, TO US AT LEAST, TO AN EXTREME ENVIRONMENT.
IT
WAS ISOLATED FROM THE HOT SPRINGS AT YELLOWSTONE
IN
WHICH YOU WOULDN'T THINK YOU COULD HAVE
NORMAL
BIO-CHEMICAL PROCESSES. SO THESE ARCHAEA HAVE
TURNED
UP IN A LOT OF, TO HUMANS, EXTREME ENVIRONMENTS.
TURNS
OUT THEY WERE A RELATED GROUP VERY DISTINCT
FROM
EUBACTERIA. SO THOSE THREE DIVISIONS SHOWN
ON THE
LOWER LEFT, YOU CAN GET THIS NEST OF PATTERN
SO WITHIN
THE EUCARYA, YOU HAVE PLANT, ANIMAL, FUNGI
AND THEN
YOU HAVE SINGLE CELL, ANIMALS TO PROTISTS.
THEY ARE
NOT A NATURAL GROUPING. THEN YOU SORT OF GO
IN
FURTHER WITHIN THE TREE OF LIFE, HEADING UP
TOWARDS
THE TIPS YOU COME TO THE (INAUDIBLE) YOU GO
IN FURTHER
YOU COME TO THE VERTEBRATES AND YOU GO ON
FURTHER YOU
COME TO THE MAMMALS YOU GO IN FURTHER COME
TO PRIMATES
GO IN FURTHER COME TO HUMANS. (INAUDIBLE)
IS ONE
LITTLE MISERABLE TWIG ON THE TREE OF LIFE.
THINK ABOUT
THAT.
AGAIN, THESE FIGURES COME DIRECTLY FROM THE
UNDERSTANDING OF EVOLUTION WEBSITE. COOL RESOURCES
THAT YOU CAN DO TO STEP THROUGH THIS TREE
OF LIFE.
WHAT EVIDENCE DO WE USE, WE DON'T JUST MAKE
THIS STUFF
UP, HOW DO WE COME TO SOME HYPOTHESIS ABOUT
THE TREE
OF LIFE? IT IS ALL ABOUT DEVELOPING AND TESTING
HYPOTHESIS. WHAT IS THE SORT OF EVIDENCE THAT
WE CAN
BRING TO BEAR. SO, IN GENERAL THERE ARE TWO
MAIN
CLASSES OF EVIDENCE. MORPHOLOGY AND MOLECULES.
MORPHOLOGY WAS THE MAIN SOURCE OF EVIDENCE
BACK
IN DARWIN'S DAY. AND NOW THAT WE CAN SEQUENCE
DNA
EFFECTIVELY AND EFFICIENTLY, MOLECULES COME
IN AND
THEY ARE BOTH IMPORTANT.
WE CAN STUDY BOTH FOSSILS AND THE LIVING OR
EXTANT SPECIES. SO, FOSSILS WE CAN GET MORPHOLOGY.
NO PROBLEM. EXTANT FORMS WE CAN GET MORPHOLOGY
AND WE
CAN ALSO SEQUENCE MOLECULES FROM THE LIVING
TAXA. IN
SOME CASES FOR FAIRLY RECENT FOSSILS AND RECENTLY
EXTINCT FORMS WE CAN ALSO GET MOLECULAR DATA.
IN
FACT, WHOLE GENOMES. THAT IS, REALLY TECHNOLOGY
HAS
EVOLVED THE LAST FEW YEARS. YOU CAN'T DO
IT WITH THE
THINGS THAT HAVE BEEN DEAD FOR MORE THAN A
MILLION OR
SO YEARS.
SO EACH OF THESE ALSO BRINGS SOME ADDITIONAL
INFORMATION. AGAIN, WITH THE FOSSILS, WE CAN
GET AT
ANCESTORS. WE CAN LOOK DIRECTLY AT THE ANCESTORS
GOING BACK ON THIS TREE OF LIFE, IF WE HAVE
ENOUGH
FOSSIL EVIDENCE, AND LOOK AT THE CHARACTERISTIC
THEY
HAVE PARTICULARLY FOR MORPHOLOGY. IT ALSO
GIVES US
SOME ESTIMATE OF TIME. WHEN DID THOSE ANCESTOR'S
EXIST FOR THE COMMON TAXA. SO WHEN WAS THE
COMMON
ANCESTOR FOR HUMAN AND CHIMPANZEE. WITHOUT
FOSSILS WE
CAN'T REALLY NAIL THAT DOWN AND THERE IS A
BIG GROUP
OF PEOPLE HERE WHO WORK ON THAT.
FOR THE EXTANT TAXA, WE CAN AS I WILL EXPLAIN
A
LITTLE BIT LATER, WE CAN ALSO GET AN ESTIMATE
OF TIME
AS WELL AS RELATIONSHIPS. BUT, WE CAN'T DIRECTLY
SEE
THE ANCESTORS. BUT WE NEED THE FOSSILS TO
DO THAT.
WE DON'T JUST USE ONE LINE OF EVIDENCE WE
USE MULTIPLE
LINES OF EVIDENCE. NOW, I NEED TO INTRODUCE
YOU TO
SOME PRINCIPLES AND TERMINOLOGY THAT WILL
COME UP IN
YOUR LAB.
THERE CAN BE A LOT OF WORDS BANDIED ABOUT.
SO
THE PRINCIPLES ARE FIRST, THAT WE, OUR HYPOTHESIS
OF
PHYLOGENY IS BASES ON SHARED, DERIVED CHARACTERS.
I
WILL EXPLAIN WHAT THIS IS IN A MINUTE. WE
USE SHARED,
DERIVED STATES OF CHARACTERS TO GROUP TAXA.
WE WILL
SEE AN EXAMPLE IN A MINUTE. DON'T PANIC. SECOND
PRINCIPLE IS THAT WE SHOULD GROUP FORMS INTO
SPECIES
OR GENERA OR CLADES THAT ARE MONOPHYLETIC.
SO WHAT THE HELL IS THAT I HEAR YOU ASK?
DID I HEAR YOU ASK? GOOD. VERY GOOD. OKAY.
SO LET'S LOOK AT A DIAGRAM. THESE ARE STATES
NOT
STATICS. MY WRITING IS TERRIBLE. SO, LET'S
DRAW A
PHYLOGENY. I WILL REFER TO SLIDE NUMBER 9.
THIS IS
ALSO IN YOUR TEXT BOOK.
JUST TO CONFUSE YOU, I WILL DRAW IT SIDEWAYS
BECAUSE IT TURNS OUT TO BE EASIER FOR WHAT
I WANT TO
DO.
SO HERE WE HAVE THE LIMITED FORM. J AND K.
THEY HAVE A COMMON ANCESTOR. I.
OVER HERE WE HAVE GOT SOME MORE LIVING FORMS
G,
H, G, E AND D. THESE GUYS HAVE A COMMON ANCESTOR
CALLED C. THIS ONE HAS A COMMON ANCESTOR CALLED
F.
HERE YOU HAVE COMMON ANCESTOR CALLED B. IT
WILL ALL
MAKE SENSE IN A MINUTE. COMMON ANCESTOR THERE
CALLED
A.
REMEMBER TO START, WE DON'T KNOW THIS GENEALOGY.
WE DON'T KNOW THIS HISTORY. BUT WE WILL START
AS IF
WE DO KNOW IT AND WORK BACKWARDS TO EXPLAIN
WHAT I
MEAN BY A SHARED DERIVED STATE OR MONOPHYLETIC.
SAY
YOU HAVE A CHANGE IN THE MORPHOLOGICAL CHARACTERISTIC.
HERE, IT GOES FROM STATE A TO STATE B. SO
THESE ARE
ALL TAXA SPECIES GENERA, WHATEVER LEVEL YOU
ARE
WORKING AT.
A, B AND C ARE STATES FOR A PARTICULAR CHARACTERISTIC.
PRESENCE OF NAILS, EVOLUTION OF LIMBS, WHATEVER.
THEY
ARE HOMOLOGOUS. DIFFERENT STATES OF THE HOMOLOGOUS
CHARACTERISTIC. SO, GOING BACK TO VERTEBRATE,
YOU
HAVE GOT A FLIPPER, YOU HAVE GOT A WING, YOU
HAVE GOT
A LEG, A FOREARM, AND SO ON. THEY ARE ALL
STATES OF
THAT HOMOLOGOUS CHARACTERISTIC WHICH IS A
VERTEBRATE
FOUR LIMB. SO HERE, YOU HAVE GONE FROM STATE
A, WHICH
IS ANCESTRRAL FORM AND ANCESTRAL STATE TO
STATE B THAT
IS A SHARED DERIVED CHARACTERISTIC BECAUSE
ALL OF
THESE FORMS, LET ME FINISH THE DIAGRAM BECAUSE
IT WILL
GET A LITTLE MORE CONFUSING. HERE WE ARE GOING
TO
CHANGE B TO C. SO WE LOOK ACROSS THESE DIFFERENT
CHARACTERISTICS, WHAT WE ACTUALLY SEE IS A.
LET'S TRY
TO GET THIS RIGHT; B, B, C, C. THAT IS WHAT
WE
OBSERVE. NOT JUST ONE CHARACTERISTIC BUT HUNDREDS.
SO, IN THIS CASE B AND C ARE SHARED, DERIVED
CHARACTERISTICS. B IS SHARED BETWEEN THESE
TWO AND C
IS SHARED BETWEEN THESE TWO. BUT, IF WE HAVE
FOSSILS
WE CAN SEE THAT A TURNED TO B BACK HERE AND
B TURNED
TO C HERE. THESE ARE SHARED DERIVED STATES.
JUST TO COMPLICATE THINGS FURTHER BECAUSE
I LOVE
COMPLEXITY. IMAGINE UP HERE YOU HAVE A INDEPENDENTLY
GIVE RISE TO THE STATE C. LET'S CALL IT C
STAR. IT
IS NOT REALLY THE SAME THING. IT JUST LOOKS
LIKE IT.
SO, IN THIS CASE A B AND C ARE THE SHARED,
DERIVED
STATE. THEY ARE HOMOLOGOUS. C STAR IS ANALAGOUS.
ARISEN QUITE INDEPENDENTLY IN EVOLUTION. SO,
INSTEAD
OF SHARED, DERIVED STATE, IT MAY LOOK LIKE
IT BUT, IF
YOU LOOK AT ENOUGH CHARACTERISTICS YOU SEE
THIS
ARRANGEMENT COMING OUT IN COMMON SO THEN YOU
KNOW THAT
IN FACT J IS NOT RELATED TO THESE. IN FACT
IT IS
RELATED TO K THEN YOU CAN BACK OUT AND THEN
YOU SEE
THIS ONE IS HAS RISEN INDEPENDENTLY. SO THE
IDEA HERE
OF HOMOLOGOUS CHARACTERS, SHARED, DERIVED
STATES AND
TRYING TO ASSEMBLE FROM A WHOLE RANGE OF
CHARACTERISTICS THE TRUE HISTORY. WE ARE ESTIMATING.
IT IS A HYPOTHESIS.
AGAIN, WE WILL LOOK AT SOME EXAMPLES OF THIS
IN
A MINUTE. I WANT TO INTRODUCE TO A COUPLE
MORE TERMS.
SO, A MONOPHYLETIC GROUP IS A GROUP OF TAXA
THAT
CONTAINS ALL OF THE DESCENDENTS FROM A PARTICULAR
COMMON ANCESTOR. SO, D AND E IS A MONOPHYLETIC
GROUP.
THESE HAVE COMMON ANCESTOR C AND THE GROUP
INCLUDES
ALL OF THE LIVING DESCENDANTS FROM THAT GROUP.
THIS
IS A MONOPHYLETIC GROUP. H, G, D, AND E ALL
HAVE A
COMMON ANCESTOR B BACK HERE. AND THAT GROUP
CONTAINS
ALL OF THE DESCENDANTS FROM THAT COMMON ANCESTOR.
IF
YOU LIKE, THIS IS MONOPHYLETIC GROUPS. NOW
THERE ARE
OTHER COMBINATIONS OF TAXA YOU CAN IMAGINE
HERE THAT
DOESN'T HOLD TRUE. SO, IMAGINE IF YOU HAD
TO, MAKE
SURE IT IS SAME AS THE SLIDE, IMAGINE YOU
HAD THIS
GROUP OF TAXA. H G AND E. THAT IS NOT A MONOPHYLETIC
GROUP BECAUSE YOU HAVEN'T INCLUDED D. THIS
IS CALLED
A PARAPHYLETIC GROUP. THEY HAVE A COMMON ANCESTOR,
BUT THAT GROUPING DOESN'T INCLUDE ALL OF THE
OF
PERCENTAGE FROM THE COMMON ANCESTOR.
YOU CAN ALSO
IMAGINE ANOTHER GROUPING HERE OF THIS PLUS
D AND E. J
K E AND D DON'T HAVE AN EXCLUSIVE COMMON ANCESTOR.
THIS WHOLE GROUP HAS A COMMON ANCESTOR BACK
HERE BUT
IF YOU JUST GROUP THESE SPECIES YOU ARE EMITTING
THESE
TWO WHICH HAVE A COMMON ANCESTOR. THIS IS
CALLED
POLYPHYLETIC.
AS J AND K HAVE ARISEN INDEPENDENTLY OF
A AND D. THE HISTORY OF LIFE. BELIEVE ME I
AM BEING
GENTLE. A LOT OF THIS FIELD WAS INVENTED BY
GERMANS
AND THERE IS A REALLY HORRENDOUS SET OF TERMINOLOGY
THAT GOES WITH IT. YOU NEED TO UNDERSTAND
THE
PRINCIPLE THAT TAXA, SPECIES, GENERA, FAMILIES,
SHOULD
BE MONOPHYLETIC. THAT IS WHAT I MEAN HERE.
GROUPING
OF TAXA SHOULD INCLUDE ALL OF THE DESCENDANTS
FROM THE
COMMON ANCESTOR. AND WE DEFINE THEM BY THE
PRESENCE
OF SHARED DERIVED TRAITS. THAT IS WHAT THIS
IS.
LET'S LOOK AT A COUPLE OF EXAMPLES AND I WILL
STOP AND TAKE QUESTIONS. I THINK EXAMPLES,
THIS IS A
VERY ABSTRACT KIND OF, EXAMPLES MIGHT HELP
MAKE IT
MORE TANGIBLE. SLIDE 10, I WILL NOT DRAW THIS
ON THE
BOARD, WE HAVE THE ESTIMATED PHYLOGENY OF
MAJOR GROUPS
OF VERTEBRATES OR IS THAT CHORDATES?
WE HAVE THE
OUTSIDE OF THE GROUP HISTORY OF, WE HAVE THE
NEXT
LETTER WHICH IS CALLED THE OUT-GROUP. IN THIS
CASE IT
IS A CHORDATE, THE LANCELET. THEN WE HAVE
THE
DIFFERENT MAJOR GROUPS OF VERTEBRATES; WE
HAVE GOT THE
LAMPREY, THE FISH, AMPHIBIANS, REPTILES AND
MAMMALS.
BIRDS, BY THE WAY, ARE JUST FLYING REPTILES.
THEY ARE
NOT A SEPARATE GROUP AS WAS LONG THOUGHT.
WHAT IS
SHOWN HERE ON THE LEFT IS A CHARACTER MATRIX.
SO FOR
A PARTICULAR SET OF CHARACTERISTICS, I SHOULD
HAVE
PRINTED THIS LARGER, HINGED JAWS, WALKING
LEGS, HAIR
AND SO ON, SHOWS WHERE THOSE PARTICULAR TRAITS
ARE
PRESENT ACROSS A GROUP OF ORGANISMS. ON
THE RIGHT IS
PHYLOGENY WHICH SHOWS YOU THE CHARACTER STATE
THAT
UNITE GROUPS OR CLADES. HERE IS ANOTHER TERM.
WE
CALL THESE GROUPINGS CLADES. MONOPHYLETIC
CLADES.
THE CLADE IS A GROUP OF TAXA. YOU CAN SEE,
AS YOU GO
THROUGH THAT, THAT ALL OF THE VERTEBRATES
SHARE A
VERTEBRAL COLUMN. THAT IS A SHARED DERIVED
CHARACTERISTIC STATE, IF YOU LIKE, THAT DEFINES
ALL OF
THE VERTEBRATES. THE NEXT GROUPING IN, THE
BONY FISH
AND THE REST HAVE HINGED JAWS. SHARED, DERIVED
STATE
OF JAWS.
THE TETRAPODS, THE AMPHIBIANS, THE BIRDS,
THE
MAMMALS AND REPTILES, ALL HAVE FOUR LIMBED
LEGS. THAT
IS WHY THEY ARE CALLED TETRAPODS. REPTILES
INCLUDING,
BIRDS AND MAMMALS ALL HAVE AN AMNIOTIC EGG.
MAMMALS
ALL SHARE THE CHARACTERISTIC OF HAIR WHICH
IS MODIFIED
IN OTHER ORGANISMS, THAT IS SCALES. IN MAMMALS
IT IS
HAIR. A SHARED DERIVED STATE. OKAY. SO, THESE
PRINCIPLES WILL BE REINFORCED IN THE LAB.
BUT, I
WANTED YOU TO THINK ABOUT THE TERMINOLOGY
AS WELL AS
THESE MAJOR PRINCIPLES. SO, WE CAN ESTIMATE
PHYLOGENY
GIVEN NOT JUST THIS MISERABLE 4 OR 5 CHARACTERS
BUT
HUNDREDS OF THEM. CONSIDERING THE DEVELOPMENTAL
PATHWAYS AND THE FOSSIL RECORD TO IDENTIFY
HOMOLOGOUS
RESTRUCTURE, HOMOLOGOUS AND SHARED ANCESTORS
AND
FINDING TRANSITIONAL STATES, AND SO ON. OTHER
EVIDENCE
THAT HAS COME TO THE FLOOR, IS DNA SEQUENCE
VARIATION.
HOW DO WE TREAT THAT?
DNA SEQUENCES. SO WE CAN TAKE THE PARTICULAR
GENE, THE SAME GENE ACROSS ALL VERTEBRATES,
ACROSS ALL
OF LIFE. FOR EXAMPLE, THE RIBOSOMAL RNA GENES
THAT
ENCODE PART OF THE RIBOSOME THAT IS IN ALL
OF THE
CELLS OF THE ORGANISMS, CAN BE SEQUENCED ACROSS
ALL OF
LIFE. OF COURSE, THERE ARE 4 DIFFERENT NUCLEOTIDES
IN
THE DNA.
A T C AND G. ADENINE, THYMINE, CYTOSINE,
GUANINE. SO THEY ARE AT DIFFERENT STATES.
SO THEY
HAVE A SEQUENCE AT A T A C G. IN A PARTICULAR
ORGANISM WE SEQUENCE THAT SAME PART OF THE
GENE FROM
A DIFFERENT ORGANISM, A T C C G T. WE LINE
THESE
SEQUENCES UP SO THAT ALL OF THE POSITIONS
CORRESPOND.
THAT IS THIS IS A HOMOLOGOUS BASE WITHIN THAT
GENE.
IT IS THE SAME BASE POSITION IN ALL OF THESE
TAXA. SO
IN THIS CASE, THIS IS NOT VERY FORMED THAT
THESE TWO
HAVE THE SAME STATE. BUT SOMEWHERE BACK IN
THE
HISTORY OF LIFE THERE HAS BEEN A MUTATION
AND YOU CAN
FIGURE OUT WHICH WAY BY SEQUENCING THE OUT-GROUP
SOMETHING OUTSIDE OF THAT. HERE IS ANOTHER
ONE. SO
THESE ARE DIFFERENT STATES OF THAT BASE POSITION
IN
THAT GENE.
SO SLIDE 11 SHOWS YOU A MATRIX, JUST A MADE
UP
ONE. SO ACROSS THE TOP IS THIS BASICALLY,
JUST A FEW
MORE LINES OF THIS STUFF ACROSS DIFFERENT
SPECIES.
AND THEN YOU SEE THE STATES IN THE GENE. AND
ON THE
BOTTOM IS THE INFERRED PHYLOGENY BASED ON
THESE
CHARACTERISTICS AND MANY OTHERS. YOU CAN DO
THIS FOR
WHOLE GENOMES NOW, MILLIONS AND MILLIONS OF
BASE PAIRS
IN GENES.
SO, HOW DO WE ESTIMATE THAT TREE IN THERE
ARE
TWO METHODS THAT ARE IN USE. A LOT OF THIS
IS
ACTUALLY DEVELOPED BY, WE HAVE SOME OF THE
WORLD
LEADERS IN DEVELOPING THIS STUFF HERE. PARTICULARITY
JOHN HUELSONBECK AND OTHER PEOPLE. JOHN HAS
SHOWN ON
THIS SLIDE THAT THERE ARE TWO BASIC PROCESSES.
REASON
I PUT JOHN HERE, HE TEACHES BIO 1B IN THE
FALL. I
TEACH IT IN THE SPRING. KIND OF FUN. BASICALLY,
TWO
DIFFERENT APPROACHES TO ANALYZING THIS DATA
TO
ESTIMATE THE PHYLOGENETIC TREE. ONE IS THE
PRINCIPLE
OF PARSIMONY. ACROSS ALL OF THESE DIFFERENT
CHARACTERS AND STATES WE WANT TO ESTIMATE
THE
RELATIONSHIPS THAT MINIMIZE THE AMOUNT OF
EVOLUTION
THAT YOU NEED TO PROPOSE. SO, BASICALLY YOU
MINIMIZE
THE AMOUNT OF CHANGE. IN DNA SEQUENCE OR
MORPHOLOGICAL CHARACTERS ACROSS THAT SORT
OF TAXA. SO
THE TREE THAT HAS THE SMALLEST AMOUNT OF EVOLUTION
ON
IT IS THE FAVORED TREE. IT IS THE SIMPLEST
EXPLANATION OF THE DATA. WE ALWAYS TRY TO
HAVE THE
SIMPLEST EXPLANATION. THAT IS WHY IT IS CALLED
PARSIMONY. SIMPLEST POSSIBLE EXPLANATION OF
THE DATA.
THERE ARE COMPUTER PROGRAMS THAT DO THIS.
YOU
WILL WORK THROUGH SOME EXAMPLES IN YOUR LAB.
THE
OTHER APPROACH IS MORE STATISTICAL.
WHERE WE HAVE THE
SAME GENERAL AIM OF TRYING TO FIND THE TREE
THAT BEST
EXPLAINS THE DATA, BUT WE BRING INTO IT, PARTICULARLY
FOR DNA SEQUENCES, WHAT WE KNOW ABOUT THE
MODEL OF
SEQUENCE EVOLUTION. HOW DOES THE MUTATION
PROCESS
WORK? SOME TYPES OF MUTATION THAT ARE MORE
COMMON BY
CHEMICALLY THAN OTHER TYPES OF MUTATIONS.
HERE WE
BRING IN AND TRY TO MINIMIZE CHANGE, BUT ALSO
BRING IN
A STATISTICAL MODEL OF HOW SEQUENCES EVOLVE.
AND YOU
CAN DO THAT BY SEEING WHAT TYPES OF MUTATIONS
ARE MOST
COMMON AND THEN APPLY THAT KNOWLEDGE TO IMPROVE
YOUR
ESTIMATE OF RELATIONSHIPS. A VERY SIMPLE WAY
TO DO
THIS IS JUST TO LOOK AT HOW MUCH DIFFERENCE
THERE IS
IN A GENE. IS THERE 1 PERCENT DIFFERENT, 20
PERCENT
DIFFERENT, 30 PERCENT DIFFERENCE IN ALL OF
THE
PAIRWISE COMBINATIONS OF GENES. YOU MIGHT
TRY TO
ESTIMATE THE TREE WHICH ONE HAS THE LARGEST
AMOUNT OF
CHANGE GIVEN THE MODEL OF SEQUENCE EVOLUTION.
THIS IS
SOPHISTICATED STATISTICAL SCIENCE. FOR EXAMPLE,
AT
THE BOTTOM OF SLIDE 12 ON THE RIGHT HAND SIDE
THERE IS
A TREE SHOWING SOMETHING THAT IS IMPLAUSIBLE.
IT IS A
POOR EXPLANATION OF THE DATA BECAUSE THE BRANCH
LENGTHS ARE ALL SKEWED. THEY ARE ALL OVER
THE PLACE.
SO, IN THAT CASE, JOHN HUELSENBECK, SHOWN
IN THE
PHOTOGRAPH, IS MOST CLOSELY RELATED TO A PLANT.
BEST
ESTIMATE OF PHYLOGENY IS THAT JOHN HUELSENBECK
IS MOST
CLOSELY RELATED TO A FUNGUS WITH THE PLANT
BEING THE
MORE DISTANT RELATIVE. EXPLAINS A LOT ABOUT
JOHN
HEULSENBECK. TO FINISH UP I WANT TO COME BACK
TO THIS
QUESTION OF TIME. HOW CAN WE ESTIMATE THE
TIMING OF
MAJOR EVENTS IN EVOLUTION? AS I HAVE SAID,
WE CAN DO
IT FROM THE FOSSIL RECORD IF WE CAN FIND THE
TRANSITION INTERMEDIATE FORM AND COMMON ANCESTORS
BACK
IN THE RECORD AND DATE THAT PERIOD IN THE
ROCKS IN THE
ROCK RECORD AND WE CAN GET A DIRECT ESTIMATE
OF THE
COMMON ANCESTOR, WHEN WAS THAT COMMON ANCESTOR
PRESENT? WE WILL TALK MORE ABOUT THAT LATER.
THE
OTHER APPROACH IS SO-CALLED MOLECULAR CLOCK.
WHICH IS
THE IDEA THAT THESE MUTATIONS IN GENES BECOME
ESTABLISHED AND ACCUMULATE IN THE ROUGHLY
TIMED
INDEPENDENT MANNER. IF YOU HAD A FOSSIL RECORD
AND
YOU KNEW THAT THE DIVERSION HISTORIES, THIS
AXIS IS
TIME AND THIS AXIS IS DIVERGENCE, AND THIS
IS HOW
DIFFERENT THE TWO GENES ARE, MOLECULAR CHANGE
IS
ACCUMULATED ROUGHLY, IT IS NOT A PERFECT LINE,
SORT OF
A LOT OF NOISE AROUND IT, THEY ACCUMULATE
OVER TIME.
SO IF YOU HAVE A TREE WHERE, JUST ABOUT DONE,
IF YOU
HAVE A TREE WHERE THIS IS TIME COMING THIS
WAY, AND
YOU CAN FIX A COUPLE OF POINTS FROM THE FOSSIL
RECORD,
LET'S SAY YOU KNOW, YOU CAN ESTIMATE WHEN
THAT COMMON
ANCESTOR WAS FROM THE FOSSIL RECORD, YOU CAN
CALIBRATE
THIS CLOCK AND ESTIMATE THE SLOPE OF THIS
LINE FROM
SAY, IMAGINE YOU HAVE ANOTHER ONE HERE AND
A FEW
OTHERS, THAT GIVES YOU THE RIGHT OF DIVERGENCE
OF THAT
GENE. HOW FAST DO ACCUMULATES CHANGE. THEN
YOU CAN
LOOK AT MOLECULAR TREE AND ESTIMATE TIME FOR
THESE
OTHER BRANCHES BASES ON YOUR KNOWLEDGE OF
THESE. IF
MOLECULAR EVOLUTION IS APPROXIMATELY CLOCK-LIKE
AND
ROUGHLY FOLLOWS THIS RULE, AND THIS WAS DEVELOPED
BY
ZUCKERKANDLE WHO WAS A PROFESSOR HERE AND
NOW IS THE
BASIS FOR A LOT OF TIMING OF EVOLUTIONARY
EVENTS. WE
WILL LEAVE IT THERE HAVE A NICE WEEKEND STAY
DRY, SEE
YOU MONDAY.