PATRICK O'DELL: So we're near
where you're from, right?
We're near Vancouver.
RICK MCCRANK: Yeah, we're
really close to
Vancouver right now.
It's like an hour and a half
from here maybe on the road.
PATRICK O'DELL: Have you
been here before?
RICK MCCRANK: Yeah, I've been
to Orcas once before.
I came here just on a regular
motorcycle camping trip.
Look around, and it's amazing.
You know what I mean?
Like birds chirping,
water lapping.
PETER HEWITT: The
park is huge.
It's the only park that was
built by Dreamland and
Grindline together.
They kind of came together
on this one.
It shows.
Came out really good, just
really different.
PATRICK O'DELL: P-Stone,
what's the
deal with your shirt?
PRESTON MAIGETTER: It got
signed by everyone.
PATRICK O'DELL: Everyone
in the world?
PRESTON MAIGETTER: Just
on this trip.
Even the O'Dell signed it.
PATRICK O'DELL: I
didn't sign it.
PRESTON MAIGETTER: You
didn't sign it?
MIKE CARROLL: Tight.
PATRICK O'DELL: Is wizard
status messing
with your demo skills?
MIKE CARROLL: We're
doing a demo?
Yeah, I guess so.
PETER HEWITT: I truly think that
the wizard staffs aren't
as magical on the board as
they are at the campsite.
That's just an opinion
of mine.
I could be wrong.
Some people could
wizard it up.
I'm in no mood for sticks
or wizards,
warlocks, any kind of dragons.
It's over.
MIKE CARROLL: My eyes
feel really soggy.
Is that fair to say?
I don't even know.
But just like, they just feel
like gooey and soggy.
PATRICK O'DELL: Damn, that's
a very wizardy move.
MALE SPEAKER: I know.
PATRICK O'DELL: You have
wizard status, right?
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
PATRICK O'DELL: Who's
more Canadian, you
or the other Rick?
RICK HOWARD: Rick is really
Canadian right now, the way
he's fucking cruising
around out here.
Look at all his friends!
He's way more Canadian
than me.
PATRICK O'DELL: You
go [INAUDIBLE]
with Keegan and stuff?
RICK MCCRANK: Yeah, I go--
Keegan's like the guy
that I hang out
with when I'm at home.
But since he's been making a
run at being a pro skater
finally, we seem to
be like, I'll be
home, he'll be traveling.
And then he'll be
home and I'll be
travelling kind of thing.
I don't really see him
all that much.
But he's coming here today.
So pretty excited to
hang out with him.
PATRICK O'DELL: Keegan.
KEEGAN SAUDER: Yes.
PATRICK O'DELL: Is Rick
Howard any less
Canadian than Rick McCrank?
KEEGAN SAUDER: No.
Same.
Same thing.
From the same land.
PATRICK O'DELL: But
you guys all came
out to see Rick McCrank?
KEEGAN SAUDER: Yeah.
ERIC KOSTON: Me and McCrank
almost had worst time ever
over there.
I don't know if you saw
that, but that was--
I was maxed out.
PATRICK O'DELL: On this tour,
do you ever feel like, since
all these guys drink so much and
like grill hamburgers and
stuff, is it weird to be-- do
you feel like an outsider even
on the tour?
RICK MCCRANK: Since I've been
doing this, I've been
vegetarian and I've been
straight, whatever.
I don't drink.
And so I'm just used to it,
you know what I mean?
I don't trip on it.
Sometimes I get a little bummed
when they bum other
people out.
I don't know, I just feel
bad for other people.
I really don't like being a
nuisance and stuff like that.
I can't stop that train.
It's nothing against anybody,
you know what I mean?
It's just my problem.
RICK HOWARD: It could get
weird here tonight.
I think it's going to happen.
MALE SPEAKER: I thought you
were a better dancer.
I was about to centipede up
under the [INAUDIBLE].
No, it's OK.
I'll appreciate what I got.
But that was kind of budget.
PETER HEWITT: At the park, they
were like, you guys can
party at the house, but just
don't break anything.
You might as well
broke something
before they came over.
Like it was ridiculous.
Like, don't break anything.
All right, head through
the window.
Let's start it off
with someone's
head through the window.
MALE SPEAKER: All right, let's
not make a big deal out of it.
MALE SPEAKER: Are you
fucking kidding me?
Who the fuck broke this
fucking window?
PATRICK O'DELL: Did
they get mad?
I don't remember
what happened.
MALE SPEAKER: I think they just
kind of gave us the boot.
It was pretty mellow.
Sorry, Moose.
He's a nice host.
I think somebody ended
up stealing his--
he had a big inflatable Coors
can that somehow made it back
with us, too.
Sorry again, Moose.
MIKE CARROLL: But seriously
dude, we were so psyched on
all the dudes that
were skating.
MOOSE: The Orcas park
is fab dude.
Seriously, I was supposed
to be here for a week.
I've been here 11 months.
MIKE CARROLL: No, but all the
dudes that were shredding
today, dude.
That was so sick.
MOOSE: All because
of that park.
MALE SPEAKER: Preston carrying
a wizard staff that drug
behind him.
And people were like, jocks kept
making jokes like, nice
beer collection.
MALE SPEAKER: You won't make it
through the door with that.
You'll get stuck.
MIKE CARROLL: That's
wizard staff.
That's where the party-- when we
showed up, and we were all,
all the girls on this
island are taken.
Or no, they said, yeah, all the
girls on this island are
spoken for.
Like, dude.
They were so weird.
I mean, most of them
were cool.
But they seemed like they
were starting to
get a little uptight.
That was a fun party, though.
This party's hella
epicly later'd.
We gotta go.
Later.
MALE SPEAKER: Some girl just
punches [INAUDIBLE]
in the face.
That was pretty awesome.
That was weird last night.
PATRICK O'DELL: What happened
at the party?
MALE SPEAKER: It was
actually rad.
It was like--
PATRICK O'DELL: What happened
at the party, Carroll?
MALE SPEAKER: What happened
at the party?
MIKE CARROLL: Nothing.
Fucking, they're
all spoken for.
PETER HEWITT: The
gold jacket--
PATRICK O'DELL: He brought
that with him.
PETER HEWITT: That was his.
PATRICK O'DELL: He brought
that with him.
He knew that he was going
to break it out.
PETER HEWITT: He knew that there
was going to be a party
that required a gold jacket.
So let's ride Orcas
out in this thing.
Ding.
PATRICK O'DELL: Did you
bring that from here?
MIKE CARROLL: No.
We were in Portland.
Someone wanted to go grab a
sweatshirt or some shirts.
So we stopped at like
an American Apparel.
So we were just messing around
and just trying on
all this gay shit.
And then I just put that thing
on and some glasses or some
other shit with it, whatever I
was buying, some other stuff.
So I was like, fuck it.
I'm just going to
take this thing.