Because people are going to do
what they're going to do.
So I might be able to do a good
tattoo now and then and
somebody's going to get it.
But there's still going to be a
thousand other people lining
up to get fucking really
horrific tattoos.
HENRY LEWIS: He's a well-rounded
tattooer.
You can tell he has
like a background
in traditional Americana.
I think that's kind of like
working with Hardy, where he
got that from, and working with
Aaron Cain and Marcus
Pacheco, that biomechanical
work that he does.
I would say his style is
definitely rooted in Japanese
work from the Masters.
He's taken notes from like
Horioshi III, Filip Leu, and
he's well-rounded in all these
different facets of tattooing.
He's coined the "Grime Style."
And that's all taken from
these educated styles of
tattooing and mastering them
and then flipping them.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CIV: I like the unexpectedness
of his work, where I'm a fan
of all the black claw stuff,
and the silhouette, and the
really strong images.
But then he'll just bust out
some pain in the ass little
single needle stuff just
to show skill.
I think anybody who has
identifiable work, whether
it's traditional, or Japanese,
or just their own style,
people are going to want
to collect from you.
I think tattooers took notice
quicker than just fans.
Because I think when you're in
it, you can kind of see when
something is special.
CHRIS O'DONNELL: It just seemed
like he had some other
ideas in his head that he wanted
to get out and not just
emulate his favorite
tattooers.
Grime started doing lots
of eyeballs with fire.
-Is this the kind of fire that
people would copy from him?
CHRIS O'DONNELL: The second he
started doing this kind of
stuff with this signature fire,
it was horrible how many
people were ripping him off.
Everybody started doing that.
It was so obvious what they
were looking at when they
would draw a tattoo.
GRIME: I did some strange style
of fire for a little
while that people definitely
borrowed some of that stuff.
But the thing is, it wasn't that
good what they borrowed.
I thought they borrowed
it, whatever.
But it wasn't that good.
I would never tattoo
that flame now.
I guess it just made me maybe
frustrated, but it also made
me just try to be even more
creative, try to make me push
my work in a way which wouldn't
be able to be copied
in a way that would make
it look like I did it.
I think my work, for the most
part, is too specific for the
client, I think, to be taken
and just pieced together in
another way and then look like
a straight rip-off of me.
CHRIS O'DONNELL: That's part of
what makes Grime Grime is
that he doesn't want
his tattoos to look
like anybody else's.
He wants to express himself,
desperately express himself
through what he's creating.
And why not?
That's what he's here for.
But it also spills over in ideas
like I guess I'm going
to submit work to that person
for that book they're
publishing.
And he'd be like, I'm just going
to publish my own book.
Why wouldn't I just publish
my own book?
Why do that?
That's how he thinks.
He's like, why don't I just
create it myself?
When he used to live with me
in Richmond, I would go to
sleep 1 o'clock, 2 o'clock
in the morning.
And he'd stay up all night with
headphones on and tons of
tracing paper, just really
aggressively drawing all
night, and then he would
be up before me.
That definitely made me feel a
little lazy, having him on my
couch doing that every night.
This is a picture of Grime
working on his sketchbook, or
journal that eventually turned
into "Two Year Autopsy." He
had a brand new sketchbook that
I think Chris Duncan had
given him for an art show.
And the idea was a year would
go by and him and a bunch of
different people would fill
up their own sketchbooks.
He would do caricatures
of himself.
He would do collage.
He would write.
He would put anything that
he was working on.
It was like a diary,
a visual diary.
He was traveling a lot, too.
We would go to conventions
in Europe.
We did Tin-Tin's Convention two
years in a row in Paris.
That was great, because we would
go with enough time to
explore the city.
There's a couple days in Paris
where he would go out by
himself with his camera
and just do
self-portraits with a timer.
He wasn't just tattooing.
Everything was an art project
at that point because he
wanted to use material
for the book.
I like reading about
what he's thinking.
GRIME: Yeah, on one hand, I like
to stay fairly private,
but it is a little cathartic.
But it also is like aiming
in two ways.
I put it out there as an
exercise, but I also--
the writing itself is
an exercise for me.
I enjoy writing.
The words I choose and how I
express the thought and the
feeling, it's rewarding.
It's real.
I like it.
CIV: When Grime did the book
"Two Year Autopsy," it was
like two years on the road of
tattooing, but mostly two
years of torturing himself
over predominantly women,
which everyone enjoys doing.
-Do you feel like a lot of
people come and try to speak
to you about some things
that are more personal?
GRIME: No.
I don't think people-- no,
most people don't.
Maybe they just don't feel
comfortable doing it.
Maybe they just feel
uncomfortable going,
so like, hey, so--
I read about that one
part where you're
spilling your guts.
Should we talk about it while
you're tattooing me?
Yeah, I think most people
probably have a lot more tact
than that, in some
ways, you know.
CIV: He sent it to a
psychologist to read and then
critique it.
And the psychologist said
something like--
I'm paraphrasing, but it said
something like this is the
most self-righteous bunch of
masturbation and pompous blah,
blah, blah, just crushed it.
And he was so excited that he
got this horrible review from
a psychologist about it.
"Two Year Autopsy," I think,
is an example of travel,
torture, hard work pays off.
It seems the more frustrated and
tortured he is, the work
gets better.
YUTARO SAKAI: We all do, but
he's almost like chipping away
his life to make it.
I think that people, whoever has
his tattoos, they have a
piece of his life.
Being this type of tattoo
artist, like fully custom
every day, I think it's a
really stressful life.
GRIME: Oh my God.
Fucking people.
YUTARO SAKAI: He's definitely
kind of a
celebrity of tattooing.
And he seems to not have much
of his personal time
sometimes, and it's hard
for some people.
CHRIS O'DONNELL: I don't know
if I've seen Grime get burnt
out or in a burnout
phase tattooing.
But he always kind
of seems like he
was up too late drawing.
You know what I mean?
Like he always just seems a
little tired or preoccupied.
He looks like he's always
stressing about whatever
project he's working on.
GRIME: Some of it's my ego, I
think, not wanting to say no
to a project or a thing that
I know that I can do
or I'd like to try.
Although I've obviously learned
how to say no over the
years, and I'm better at it as
time passes, but there are
still some things that I think
maybe get out of my control,
and that creates difficulties
for me.
Dude, that's shit.
Conventions suck.
I just want to go
and make maybe a
couple tattoos or something.
Now it's like a whole
fucking thing.
GRIME: It's my job.
GRIME: No, there's no fun.
I work every day on there.
There's nothing to do but work.
That's it.
GRIME: What if I didn't feel
like it's just all pressure
and it's all everything
is everyone wanting
something from me.
GRIME: I know.
HENRY LEWIS: The man's always
working on something, I can
say that much.
There's always some
iron in the fire.
Which is amazing, too,
because it kind of
keeps me on the ball.
And it just keeps me wanting
to produce and create.
And like I said, art for
the sake of art.
GRIME: Maybe a little bit ego,
just wanting to say I'm here.
Some kind of base--
somewhat of a base artistic
kind of bend, which
is, like, I'm here.
This is my mark I've
left kind of thing.
There's something about that.
-These are all the paintings
that are in the--
GRIME: Yeah, my "Two
Year Autopsy."
-Let's see them back here.
GRIME: I'm just pissed
off all night.
I don't feel like I'm
an artist right now.
I have in the past.
I don't feel like I've
been creating lately.
So it makes me feel less
accomplished as an artist.
-Do you have any concepts
started or--
GRIME: They're in
my head, dude.
What do I need to do?
Either you do it or
you don't, yeah.
There's not a thing
that I want to do.
I just feel like I get ideas
for things I want to do.
And then I'm like, OK,
I'll fuckin'--
I'll write them down or I'll
have an idea about it and get
some stuff.
And I want to do other shit.
Do I want to do a fucking
watercolor of
a traditional tat.
Fuck that, you know?
I want to do shit that's
in my brain.
I want to do cathartic work.
Because to me, that's
what art is.
It's the expression
of yourself and
your point of view.
If you don't have a point of
view, what the fuck you got?
And I think that's what makes
people drawn to art, is they
feel the person's emotion or
personality come through.
GRIME: No.
Don't remind me.
I think I'm going
to do that soon.
I need to.
I need it.
I have responsibilities
though.
I have two dogs.
I can't just go fuck off.
They're human.
Jones, motherfucker.
Right?
Owww!
Hey, whose head's that?
And you know, I think
we change as people.
I change as a person as I age.
And so I seek different
things.
And maybe things become more
difficult than they were when
I was younger.
Or maybe I just get
tired of them.
Or maybe I have more work
than I ever have had.
Maybe it's a combination
of all those things.
Jones!
Mr. Jones!
Come!
Get your ass down here!
Leave it!
Ah, all right, what am
I standing here for?
-Because we are walking
up here.
I guess this is where you bring
your dogs a lot, huh?
GRIME: Yeah, sometimes.
Did you get that?
Me and the dog drinking
at the same time?
-Uh-huh.
GRIME: OK, good.
What kind of soundtrack are
we doing for this thing?
-What kind of what?
GRIME: Soundtrack we doing
for this thing?
[MUSIC PLAYING]