plea
meaning that he did not reach a plea
agreement with the prosecution
nonetheless he is agreed
to uh... plead guilty on some of the
lesser charges
so you pled guilty to misusing
classified material
overall with ten of the lesser charges
that he pled guilty to any now
faces a maximum of uh...
twenty years in prison because of that
position of those charges carries
and maximum both two years now when he
did this
he read a thirty five page statement in
court that he had written himself
and it appears that he did that
because he's saying look
this is a reality
i did it because i thought it would help
the country
and it was me and i did give it to
weaken leaks
but well other charges like aiding the
enemy are absurd i didn't do that
and i will fight that
as a strategy in the defense i don't
know a lot of people are concerned
uh... you it's giving away some of your
leverage in some way
on the other hand
manning continues to be a man of
tremendous principle
i don't know anybody else who comes and
says look
uh... pleading to this cuz i did
and it's not going to give me any
advantage in my trial 'cause the
prosecution continues
snot like
prolific all well he's being honest
so will let 'em off don't they don't
care the whole reason they're
prosecuting him
is because he was honest
right and they're trying to set an
example with them
so they're gonna try
it appears for a life sentence anyway
but the man as usual is true his
principles
and we found out some other interesting
things from his uh... testimony today
first of all it turns out that he
actually
uh... contacted the washington post in
the new york times and try to give them
the story first
so that's amazing
neither of those papers were interested
in what turned out to be
one of the biggest stories of a
generation
and his story so gigantic there try to
put this guy awake for a life
and and they're doing their national
manhunt basically enjoyin assigns 'cause
he didn't carry this torch that's how
much government cares about it
the new york times larger post like that
and i'll tell you why in a second but
here's what the guardian reports about
his interaction with the washington post
quoting contact in the washington post
and asked would it be interested in
receiving information
he said would be in
norma sli important to the american
people
and their answer was i'm not really
now y
is it because they look at the
information they were scared us that are
now in a nana
that in person the wife impose
uh... have to check with my senior
editors and we'll get back to you and
was dismissive
the new york times he left voice mail
messages skype messages
on many different reporters editors et
cetera
none of them either return his call
because he's not an important person
you see
our media so he used to being fed
information by the government
that is pro-government
and it could be pro republican report
about democrat to depending on who's
leaking information
that they do
but that's not only legitimate source of
information
well if i have a high esteem government
official give me a
press releases that is the skies as my
you know article
then of course i shot the return of talk
radio lee
on this guy
has a treasure trove
of incredibly important government
information
specialists
for example in their past helicopter
video
that week
murdered
civilians children
and reporters we killed two workers
reporters
you'll find that to be interesting news
no it doesn't matter
cousin on important person
and so i'm not gonna take notes from you
i'm i'm gonna ignore your permission
horrible reporting
horrible journalism
so that's why he had to go to with unix
'cause await your weeks was only people
journalism business at the time
born people actually cared about
information that would expose of the
government was doing
that's why the rest of
the so-called journalist
or soul insanely jealous
of julian assigned
and try to from one of the bus that
every opportunity
okay now why did manning do it
starting continues to explain
referring to the warlords from iraq and
afghanistan
he said he felt they would reveal the
true cost award
now does that sound like a guy who's
trying to keep the enemy
cells where you guys were stranded the
the u_s_ public
in understanding neutral cost the war
so that we can make an informed decision
on whether we stay in iraq whether we
stay in afghanistan
so that we know what our governments
actually do it
them asinine as we killed in afghanistan
what we're doing diplomatically and by
the way some of those diplomatic cables
anne released change the world there
were part of what led to the revolutions
in tunisia and egypt by the way the new
york times the washington post
all those world changing
documents not that important cuz you're
not an important person who usually
feeds me crap from the government rally
many explained in his all the worse
we were obsessed with capturing and
killing human targets are lists
and ignoring goals admissions
i believe that the public particularly
the american public
concede this because spark a debate on
the military
an art form policy in general
as it applied iraq and afghanistan
it may cause society do we considered
the meeting gauging counter-terrorism
well ignoring the human situation of the
people we need to use with everyday
you know who says something like that
whistleblower
that someone who's trying to help the
enemy someone who's trying to help us
he is that classic definition of a
whistle-blower
and he was right
we did kill those civilians in that
helicopter attack
we didn't kill those reporters
report number civilians lead killed in
iraq and afghanistan
accurately
he was right about it all
and we would have been better off had we
known that every permeation earlier
we're better off knowing about what's
also veto songs egypt as all the rest of
the world
but for that in america you do not get
rewarded
you get sent the president
so because of his own admissions is now
facing a maximum of twenty years at
least but the government immigrate blood
lust here
to put away someone who's actually
trying to help our democracy
says it's not enough
it's not enough
we wanna life sentence
and the thing that they want most of all
is a one day it would connect many
to julian assigns
so they can go get him to
because we had a rare moment of
journalism break out here
and what happened at the soviet and know
what i government
is actually doing
in our so-called democracy
and that is what the government
isn't live in and out
that's why they want on issue than a
to the health and that's why would they
want to go get it signs
and try to put him away for life too
it's sick
we should all be against it
and we should free bradley many as soon
is humanly possible