bands were.
So we decided to meet up with
Cui Jian, the grandfather of
Chinese rock.
Cui Jian is the biggest rock
star in China, and he's
probably more punk than all the
new bands put together.
He wrote the song, "Nothing to
My Name," that became the
anthem of the student
revolution of '89.
And the album it was featured on
was the best-selling record
in China's history.
Since Cui Jian has witnessed
China's massive change, we
thought that he might have
some answers to why the
country that invented stuff
like paper and the compass
hasn't really come up with
anything new lately.
We've been here in Beijing for a
week and a half already, and
we've been meeting a
lot of young bands.
It's basically all
rock and roll.
Has China kind of run
out of new ideas?
Or why all these Western
influences?
CUI JIAN: You know, we start
from Western classical music.
When I was 14 years old,
I started the trumpet.
Someone doesn't really think,
this is Western, as they would
say, this is the fashion,
this is international.
Don't believe someone
said Chinese rock
and roll is so active.
Only in Beijing, few clubs in
the weekend, the huge country.
No, it's joke.
It's a joke.
It's not culture yet.
Everybody copying.
Something wrong, because they
lose their own creativity.
They listen to Western music.
They have a much better system,
but they don't create.
So the real situation in China,
what the young people
really thinking about
in China.
But I don't think you can get
this from a CCTV, or we can
get some more on [INAUDIBLE].
I don't think you can
get something who
tell you the truth.
People telling the truth is a
good image for the country,
for the government.
The young people say something
bad about this country, it
doesn't mean they don't
like this country.
Maybe it's just because they
love this country, and they
don't feel satisfied and they
say something because they
want changes.
MILENE LARSSON: Shouldn't
China still be creating
something new, since you're
such a big nation?
CUI JIAN: I want to say I
appreciate you asking me these
questions, why China has such
huge history and culture, and
then they just want to leave
them alone and listen to the
Western music or culture.
So it's a good question.
And a lot of people will
keep thinking about it.
I don't think my answer is
right, even from now.
In a lot of things, I have
to keep thinking.
But it's very, very important,
because I don't think it's a
matter of Chinese
young people.
I think this is a big matter
of the whole world, because
China's big, and China has
really beautiful culture.
Confucius has totally destroyed
the culture of China.
It's the worst part of China.
Confucius teach people how to
be nice to people, but not
nice to themselves,
how to be polite.
My parents, I have to
be nice to them.
But we have totally lost the
direction about searching
themselves.
This is the bad part
of the culture.
Don't listen to him.
He's old guy, born
2,000 years ago.
And he said something.
For that moment, it's
OK, but not for now.
We [INAUDIBLE]
young people.
We have Chinese young people.
Don't believe that.
MILENE LARSSON: The fact that
Cui Jian is so popular and
outspoken has put him in
difficulties with the Chinese
government.
People can buy his records,
since he's managed to get
around the censorship
boundaries
through allegoric lyrics.
But to see China's biggest rock
star perform live is a
whole different deal.
He hasn't been able to play
any major venues in China
since his inappropriate stage
behavior on the fundraising
tour for the 1990 Asian games.
And according to Western media,
he's been banned from
playing live.
MILENE LARSSON: How do
you make sense of it?
MILENE LARSSON: Still, you
managed to kind of
not play the game.
You did your own--
MILENE LARSSON: You've been
playing a lot of shows abroad.
You told me you were
in the US.
What do you feel is the Western
world's perception and
opinions about China?
MILENE LARSSON: Yeah.
MILENE LARSSON: When you're in
the US or in Denmark, or
wherever you are, how do Western
people react to China?
[MUSIC PLAYING]
MILENE LARSSON: We started to
understand why Cui Jian is
such an icon, as our chat with
him turned into one of the
most keen and precise
explanations of the Chinese
psyche that we've ever heard.
Even though over a fifth of the
world's population lives
in China, it's rare to find
Chinese music that actually
has something to say.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
MILENE LARSSON: Almost everybody
that we meet knows
your songs and say that you
mean a lot to them.
MILENE LARSSON: I kind of get
the impression that you're
important to them.
And it makes me wonder,
makes us wonder, what
are your songs about?
MILENE LARSSON: I read an
interview where you said
something about, people used to
be heroes and now they care
more about having
a nice salary.
Do you think why this generation
have a lot of money
concerns is because they are
the generation under the
capitalism?
MILENE LARSSON: What do you
listen to right now?
MILENE LARSSON: Missy Elliott?