-Do you still have
your Grime ring?
GRIME: Yeah, man.
What do you think?
That's 10 years old now.
I made that ring 10 years ago.
There it is.
-Yes.
GRIME: You said this was going
to take three hours, you guys
here eating up my Sunday.
-Yes.
GRIME: Hurry the fuck up.
-You're more than welcome
to go and do some stuff.
Bet it would be very interesting
to see you go to
the post office.
GRIME: Fuck you.
-Do you have to go to
the post office?
GRIME: No, fuck you.
-Why?
It's just like your every day.
Anyone can go see you
tattooing or sitting somewhere.
GRIME: They can?
-Yeah.
GRIME: That sounds horrifically
banal.
-All right.
GRIME: All right.
Oh fuck, I don't know.
Now, you didn't tell me
you wanted to look
at a bunch of shit.
Fuck, I don't know.
There's a box laying here.
It's been sitting here for
months with blood all over it.
Some of it's tracing, some
of it's drawings.
I guess some of these
are tracings.
Maybe there's not a
lot of drawings in
here, I don't know.
GRIME: Oh, should I
throw them away?
I'll fucking sell them to
people like you later.
-We could just do a basic sit
down now and then we'll go
rifling through everything.
GRIME: Is that what you think
is going to happen?
-Uh huh.
In my mind, that's how it's
going to play out.
GRIME: What kind of rifling
do you intend to do?
Who are these viewers?
-This'll probably get at
least a million views.
GRIME: All right.
I've got a garage that
fits your desires.
-Really?
In here?
GRIME: Yeah, in here.
All right, are you going
to follow me then?
-Lead on.
GRIME: I don't know how much of
my personal life you need
to have in this thing.
Come on, mister fucking I like
to dig through shit.
Oh, there's a lot
of shit in here.
Oh, you'll want this one.
You got to see this board.
This board's awesome.
Here we go, here we go-- this
is the gem right here.
Yeah, this is Mark Gonzales's
personal board from back in
the day.
-From?
GRIME: Yeah, this is his board
from when he was a kid.
This thing's sick
though, right?
I bought that shit through
the internets.
I bought it fucking cheap.
But, yeah, Mark Gonzales's
personal board.
This thing's so sick.
I got this for like
maybe $200.
It's so stupid to think
it's so cool.
I don't know why people
didn't want it.
They wanted original boards
that were unskated.
I don't see how they lost out on
how cool that is, you know?
HENRY LEWIS: And you see
his board collection.
I mean, if you look at that and
you mix that with modern
tattooing and illustration work,
I think that's where it
all stems from.
Like, his style and his color
schemes in tattooing.
Like, for example, that
biomechanical sleeve.
It has neon pink coming
off of it.
And then the majority of color
that was kind of like a weird
looking baby blue, that crept
into this little organic dark
umber green, going into
olive sappy green.
I think it's based
from old school
'80s skateboard graphics.
And all that whole skater
culture back then when he was
in love with that stuff.
You can tell that's where
he came from.
GRIME: How about that?
-It's nice.
GRIME: This thing's
fucking sick.
How about this thing?
This thing's a fucking gem.
I love this board.
This board's the shit.
Now, this one has such
a good theme.
-I've never even seen it.
GRIME: How about this thing?
Don't touch that.
You can't touch this board.
-I've never seen this color.
GRIME: Yeah, that's because they
made like three of them.
I know for sure there's two
of these that exist--
two.
But I don't know if
there's more.
I got it from the guys
who screened it.
They were trying out
some new primer and
then the black coat.
And the coat, like they sprayed
a bunch of boards and
then they came back the next
morning I think and then they
all reacted.
And they were like fuck it,
we'll print them anyway and
they printed them anyway.
This board's awesome.
GRIME: No, it's not a Chris
Cole graphic, dude.
It's a Rodney Mullen graphic.
When'd you start skating?
Fucking '89?
-Did you have all these boards
when you were younger?
GRIME: No, I had some of them
but I didn't have all of
them-- no, of course.
I grew up in Grand Junction,
Colorado.
-What was your town like?
GRIME: Shit.
-High school was--
-It was shitty?
GRIME: Stupid.
-What were you into?
GRIME: Skateboarding
and punk rock.
Skateboarding and punk rock.
-Were you always "The Grime?"
GRIME: Yeah.
-Is that a nickname?
-Like, when you went to college
did you introduce
yourself as "Grime?"
GRIME: No, no, no.
I used it for my creative
life, my artistic life.
I started doing graffiti when
I was really young.
I was painting my name.
I know that I had a tag running
in Junction that had
my name and next to
it I wrote 1984.
So I had tags running on
a bridge from '84.
And I don't even know why
I did that, really.
I mean, I know it's
like a thing-- you
people do that shit.
But it wasn't like a one-time
thing, it was a thing that I
kind of enjoyed in a weird
way or wanted to do.
I think I enjoyed being
creative, if you will.
But I didn't see a line where
to pull that creativity.
Or how to use it, or that it was
a viable thing outside--
that it could be
an occupation.
It never occurred to me that
I could be an artist as an
occupation, I don't think,
for a long time.
When I was 19, I moved to
Arizona to go to school, get
out of my town.
I'd been there a few times,
and you could
skateboard a lot there.
There was good skateboarding
there, and there was a lot of
year-round skateboarding
because of the weather.
And I figured OK, fuck
it, I'll go there.
But also because I
had been there.
It was familiar, so it felt
easier than like oh, maybe I
should go to San Francisco.
I've never been there,
I should go.
That would have felt
a little too crazy.
So I went there.
And then after a while
I thought oh, I got
to get out of here.
I had a desire to make tattoos
since I was, I don't know,
like maybe 15?
And I remember it surfacing
again maybe when I was 19 to
20 years old.
It surfaced again, and I thought
I'm going to do it,
I'm going to do it.
When I had no idea
how to do it.
It was almost as hard
as figuring out how
to get to the moon.
Oh, God, there's going to
be some gems in here.
This is some early
shit right here.
Oh shit, graffitis.
This is like '90--
oh God, I don't even
know what.
God, this stuff is terrible.
This stuff is just terrible.
Oh shit, first portrait
I ever did.
-What?
You mean Arizona?
GRIME: Yep.
I didn't get very many tattoos
at first because I
didn't have any money.
And I knew the kind of work
I wanted to get and I
couldn't afford it.
So I waited until I got
some money and I got
tattoos that I wanted.
I got tattooed by Marcus and
Guy Aitchison and Eddie
Deutsche and Aaron Cain.
Those are the people I was
getting tattooed by early.
Yeah, I got tattooed
by Marcus in '93.
I came to SF-- it was maybe the
second time I'd been to
San Francisco.
Marcus Pacheco was a huge
influence on me.
And he was one of the reasons
I wanted to start tattooing
anyway, seeing all of his
work in tatt mags.
-Marcus Pacheco owned
Primal Urge.
GRIME: He owned Primal
Urge, yeah.
Yeah, he did.
-And that was what?
GRIME: It was a tattoo
shop, actually.
They made tattoos there
back in the day.
It was in San Francisco,
California.
-Known for traditional
sailor tattoos?
GRIME: Yep.
No, they weren't known
for fucking--
oh, shit the bed.
They were not known
for sailor tatts.
They were known for
very progressive
tattooing at the time.
Very, very progressive
tattooing.
They were doing stuff
that really hadn't
been tried in tattooing.
If it had been, only in really
small increments and in a kind
of unheralded way,
if you will.
CHRIS O'DONNELL: For sure, it
was like a very exciting time
period for San Francisco.
It seemed like a new phase
was about to explode.
I had a stack of magazines back
in the early '90s just
filled with so much garbage.
So much awful work, but there
was some good stuff, too.
And I figured, obviously, I'll
just take all the good stuff
out, put it all in a book.
So yeah, Marcus was doing all
these really interesting
tattoos, very painterly.
Just very unique for the time.
He was really pioneering that
sort of idea that you could do
more with it than just outline
and shade and just things that
nobody else was doing.
Just very complicated work--
very painterly.
I definitely responded
to that really early
on, and so did Grime.
GRIME: For me it was so
attractive and creative.
And his stuff was also
technically always super solid
and super perfect, basically.
That it was a big draw when
you saw something that was
executed so well, it's just
really attractive.
My eyes really liked it.
I was really drawn towards it.
Marcus is the man.
He taught me a ton of things.
I definitely wouldn't be
the tattooer I am if
it wasn't for Marcus--
like, 100%.
Well, we worked together
a few different times.
CHRIS O'DONNELL: In my mind, his
life started when he moved
to San Francisco to work
at Primal Urge.
I can remember him being kind of
quiet back then, actually.
I didn't get a real sense
of his personality
when I first met him.
I think he was just really
involved in getting set up in
San Francisco.
GRIME: I was just focused on
learning how to tattoo.
There was no time to
express myself.
I was too busy studying
tattooing.
I was just drawing and
looking at stuff and
thinking about tattooing.
LANGO OLIVEIRA: I know he was
learning a lot from Marcus.
And Marcus was like the biggest
influence on my work
and at the time like
the biggest idol
and all this stuff.
So I really want to get a tattoo
actually from Marcus.
I tried kind of hard, but
it would never happen.
So I needed to get tattooed.
So it was like fuck it, if this
guy doesn't tattoo me
I'll just get it from this
guy Grime because he
looks pretty good.
This is supposed to be like a
zombie chick or whatever.
I was like 20 years
old or something.
On this one I didn't
say anything.
I was like, dude, just draw
me something sick.
I don't fucking know.
CHRIS O'DONNELL: His style
of tattooing was way more
exaggerated than it is now.
I mean, every detail you could
put into a tattoo, he was
doing more than that.
GRIME: I don't think I suffered
for too long in the
beginning of tattooing.
I think I did pretty well with
the technical side, but it
then takes forever
to get a vision.
CHRIS O'DONNELL: He was just
trying everything.
Grime had a huge buzz.
His work was immediately so
unique that everybody
immediately noticed.
And that was back in the day
when if you had a magazine
article in "International Tattoo
Art," or whatever, it
would get you noticed
in the industry.
Now there's so many magazines
and no one notices if you have
an article anymore.
But back then, that
was a big deal.
And that kind of solidified
his status in the San
Francisco scene.
GRIME: Oh look, that
was in a magazine.
Look, it's so flashy.
-So at the time what'd
you think when you
finished that tattoo?
GRIME: I was psyched.
So were a lot of other people.
All right, I think we're done.
I don't think there's anything
extra special in here.
I don't know what else
is down here, dude.
I don't have anything.
Look at me, I can't
even go out.
I got you guys fucking
keeping me in.
-We're going to go
get ice cream.
GRIME: We're good?
-Yeah, we're good in here.
GRIME: You done?
-No, we're not done.
GRIME: Make you happy?
-We are not done.
GRIME: That make you happy?
-I'm almost happy.
A little bit.