You got a new favourite show
been watching HBO
It's called Game of Thrones
Well, I read the fucking books!
I said, I read the fucking books!
I read them years ago
so don't tell me bout Jon Snow
Cause I already know
I've got a signed copy of "A Feast for Crows"
Then a six year wait for "A Dance With Dragons".
A six year wait for "A Dance With Dragons".
I waited six fucking years for "A Dance With Dragons"
and now you jump on the fucking bandwagon
I read the fucking books!
I said I read the fucking books twice
Don't talk to me about spoilers
Winter has been coming for sixteen, fucking years
You motherfuckers!
His name is Joffrey not Geoffrey!
Get a fucking library card!
Or a Kindle!
What's wrong with you people
no one reads anymore
Your imagination is a fun place to explore
Go to a library or a fucking book store
take it from me, you'll enjoy the book more
"Harry Potter", the book was better
"The Hunger Games", the book was better
"The Lord of the Rings", the books were probably better
"The Cat in the Hat", the book was better
and whilst I'm on the topic
what the fuck is with movies based on board games
Battleship: The Movie
D-9, I sunk your battleship
Movie over. Fuck off!
Hollywood cannot live up to the power of imagination
Hey guys, thanks for watching Rage of Thrones
Be sure to subscribe to our channel
check out all our other videos
go to our website to check out our tour dates
and be sure to tune into game of thrones' season three
I'm certainly looking forward to the parts where...
Hey, hey... no spoilers
Oh, for fucks sake... where's Lee?
Where are my dragons?
seriously, where are my...
where are my... I need... Jordan?
Benny? Jordan
I got no pants