CARL AZUZ, CNN ANCHOR: That Calen, he`s a
real card.
All right, first up today -- an issue that`s
getting a lot of attention in Washington -- immigration
reform. President Obama talked about it yesterday.
He says it`s a top priority for this second
term, and he thinks the time is right to overhaul
the current immigration system. Undocumented
immigrants, like these next two students would
probably want to see that.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
ROLANDO ZENTENO, ARMSTRONG UNIVERSITY FRESHMAN:
I identify myself with the American culture,
but sometimes the American society is like
no, you are not part of us.
JESUS ARROYO, ARMSTRONG UNIVERSITY SENIOR:
It`s amazing to see that, you know, they are
willing to help us now, because all my life,
you know, I`ve been here, not knowing what`s
going to be my future, not knowing where I`m
going to go.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: You may remember that a group of U.S.
Senators announced an immigration reform plan
earlier this week. It would include a path
for undocumented immigrants, people who were
in the country illegally, to become citizens.
President Obama agrees with that idea, but
some folks think it`s a bad one.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
REP. MARSHA BLACKBURN, (R ), TENNESSEE: Why
don`t we talk about a pathway to legality?
Why don`t we talk about a pathway to green
card? Why don`t we talk about some other things
rather then going straight to pathway to citizenship.
You know, is this fair to those that have
been in the queue for a long, long time, going
through the legal process, trying to get into
this country?
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: So, a lot of talk about immigration
reform. What are your thoughts on this issue?
Head to our blog at cnnstudentnews.com, or,
if you are on Facebook, you can talk to us
there at Facebook.com/ cnnstudentnews.
Interesting weather fact -- the U.S. has more
tornadoes than any other country on the planet,
about a 1000 of them are reported every year.
Most of those show up during spring and early
summer, but some states were dealing with
tornado watches this week. We talked with
chief CNN meteorologist Chad Myers, and the
first question we asked is, why don`t we see
more tornadoes in the winter?
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
CHAD MYERS, CHIEF METEOROLOGIST: We do see
tornadoes in the winter. It`s a little bit
odd, but we don`t think about them, we get
them in the overnight, late night hours, in
the southern part of the United States, follow
the jet stream. In the winter, the jet is
over Alabama, Mississippi, Georgia and Florida.
That`s where the severe weather is. Then it
moves north, in March, April and May, that`s
tornado alley -- Oklahoma, Texas, all the
way up to Illinois, Indiana, Ohio. And then
by the summer, it`s all the way to Edmonton.
It`s in the Canada, because that`s where the
jet stream is, the jet stream is the energy,
that`s where the severe weather always is.
First thing you need to know is that when
these storms that happen in the dark, those
are the most dangerous. You`re sleeping, you`re
probably not watching TV, you don`t have radio
on, all of the sudden those are the storms
that can really hurt you. They are not going
to be big, maybe, you know, F1s or 2, small
tornadoes. But if it hits your house, it`s
a big deal, isn`t it? That thing where you
can do to protect yourself is that there`s
an iPhone, iPad iTouch app, you keep that,
it will go off, it will alarm you when a tornado
was happening, or just going to know where
the radio. That`s the old standby.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today`s first "Shoutout"
goes out to Mrs. Hill`s English and language
arts students at Elkton Middle School in Elkton,
Maryland.
Which of these countries share the border
with Syria? Here we go, is it Iran, Lebanon,
Saudi Arabia or Afghanistan? You`ve got three
seconds, go!
Lebanon is the only one of these countries
that border Syria. That`s your answer and
that`s your "Shoutout."
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: In the nearly two years since Syria`s
civil war started, more than 150,000 people
have crossed that border, going to Lebanon
to escape the fighting that has killed more
than 60,000 people.
When you`re seeing news about Syria, you hear
about the government forces, about the rebels.
What about people your age? Teens who went
from living their lives to living in the middle
of a war? Kayana (ph) is 14. She lives in
Lebanon now. She wrote something for a school
project about how the war has changed her
life. This is her story and her words.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: My name is Kayana (ph),
and I`m 14 years old, and I`m from Aleppo,
Syria. I used to think everything was perfect,
like the fairy tales, and now like I don`t
know any more. I don`t know how anything is,
I don`t know how anything is going to turn
out to be.
I miss the most how we would be like so care
free, you know. We would love all the time,
and like we were also happy, every one like
the old and the young, everyone was like really
happy. Like my school, my friends -- everything.
I always dream that we are in school right
now, and for me, that`s actually nightmare,
because I want it so bad, but not like I know
it might not happen again.
The bombing that happened close to my house
was in the morning, and my sister was at basketball
practice at school, and they could see like
a lot of smoke and like bits of bodies were
flying everywhere. And so when I woke up,
my mom was really scared because my sister
was there. But then she told me that everything
was OK. And when I tried looking at the TV,
she switched the channels. But I was able
to see like everything -- like the dead bodies
and everyone.
Where I`ve been through changed me a lot,
because it changed me in two ways. For example,
when I used to complain about really silly
things, I realize that there is like a much
bigger world down there where people die and
like people are killed. It also changed me
in another way, because I always -- like I`m
always angry right now at everyone, and like
I`m not like happy the way I used to be.
What makes me angry is how people are so selfish,
and they are killing each other, like without
considering how people are dying, and like
-- the -- like the situation they`re putting
their parents into (and their family. Now,
everyone is crying everyday, and there is
no electricity, there is no food. How people
are like struggling just to survive now.
I don`t blame anyone specific, but I blame
everyone that`s just holding a gun right now.
Like for whatever reason they think they are
doing it.
The day my family decided to come to Lebanon,
it was really hard for me. In the beginning,
it was all a blur -
I always try to hope and I look at other people
how they have no food, no home, and I thank
God for what I have.
My mom goes back and forth to help the refugees
and she like donates a lot of food and our
old toys, and our old clothes. And like the
reason I want to go back, basically, is because
I want to make a difference. I want to help
these people and go with my mom and like -- try
to like at least make someone happy in there.
Yeah, I`m scared for like, for more to happen,
for more people to die. And I`m scared that
the hope I have right now to go back, like
at the end will all be erased, and then like
I won`t really have anything left to look
forward to.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: It`s time for a "Shoutout
Extra Credit." Who was the winning coach in
the first Super Bowl? You know what to do.
Was it John Madden, Knute Rockne, Mike Ditka
or Vince Lombardi? Put another three seconds
on the clock and go!
Lombardi`s Green Bay Packers won the first
two Super Bowls, and the Super Bowl trophy
was later renamed the Lombardi trophy. That`s
your answer and that`s your "Shoutout Extra
Credit."
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Anthony is rooting for the Baltimore
Ravens in the upcoming Super Bowl, because
he wants Ray Lewis, a linebacker on the team,
to have a Super Bowl win in his last season.
Riggy is pulling for the San Francisco 49ers,
saying with Kaepernick and Gore running against
them, the Ravens will have too much to handle.
But like Nick said, no matter what, "Harbaugh
is going to win." Jim and John Harbaugh are
the coaches of the two teams. They are brothers,
and they`ll be battling each other in Super
Bowl XLVII, which are Roman numerals for 47.
A lot of folks know about that, not a lot
of folks know this: their parents will be
at the game. Who they root for? They don`t
know. They are just worried it`s going to
be heart-wrenching for whoever loses.
Retiring Ravens linebacker Ray Lewis has played
for 17 years. His first sack, against Indianapolis
Colts quarterback Jim Harbaugh, who is now
coaching the 49ers. In previous games between
these two teams, the Ravens have won three,
the 49ers, one. Both teams have perfect Super
Bowl records. The 49ers have won five of five,
the Ravens one of one. So it`s somebody`s
perfect Super Bowl record is going to be broken,
unless Jackie Harbaugh, the two coaches` mother,
gets her wish, that it will end in a tie.
Well, Andrew Gray had a problem. Whenever
he left his parrot alone, the bird would go
nuts. The solution -- the bird buggy. Since
Pepper piped up anytime Andrew left the room,
he figured he needed to give the parrot a
way to follow him around. So he built this,
posted it on Youtube, and now Pepper can use
his beak to drive himself around instead of
driving Andrew crazy. Best of all, Andrew
can walk out of a room now, and he doesn`t
have to worry about ruffling any feathers.
It`s a good thing he thought of that solution,
otherwise the noisy bird might have been given
his squawking papers. And since the story
has gone viral, you can probably expect some
parrot-ies. Really, there is no talon what
people might come up with, assuming they have
the drive. It`s time for us to fly, CNN STUDENT
NEWS, we`ll be beak tomorrow, we`ll see you
then.