ADRI MURGUIA: On any given
Friday night, thousands of
Peruvians gather in Lima to
attend Huayno concerts.
As a sign of industry success,
the queens of Huayno take the
center of the stage, wearing
dresses that look like a
combination of Virgin
Mary cloaks and a
flair of kabuki theater.
Located in the outskirts of the
city, El Arte Dorado owned
by Francisco Herrera, is
regarded as the best Huayno
dress shop in the country.
FRANCISCO HERRERA:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
ADRI MURGUIA: Francisco's
craftsmanship is responsible
for launching the careers of
some of the most iconic women
in the scene, amongst them,
national idol Dina Paucar.
FRANCISCO HERRERA:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
DINA PAUCAR: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
ADRI MURGUIA: Acquiring one
of these dresses is a huge
investment for aspiring
musicians, but it's impossible
to perform without one.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
FRANCISCO HERRERA:
ADRI MURGUIA: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
ADRI MURGUIA: Rising star and
YouTube sensation Wendy Sulca
is also one of Francisco's
most prominent customers.
FRANCISCO HERRERA:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
ADRI MURGUIA: Francisco owns
several buildings on this
block, but he took us to his
studio next door, where his
team of artisans assemble
his designs.
He wanted to show us the
intricacies that go into
making them.
ADRI MURGUIA: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
FRANCISCO HERRERA:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
ADRI MURGUIA: The blend of Incan
symbols with baroque
influences not only help the
singers narrate their personal
stories, but also serve to
represent Peru's culture
around the world.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
FRANCISCO HERRERA:
ADRI MURGUIA: Playing for
Peruvians that have migrated
abroad is a big deal
for Huayno stars.
It's an unmistakable sign
that you've made it.
Considering the burning desire
for Huayno starlets to show
off these ensembles convinced
me that I just had to bring
one back with me to New York.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
FRANCISCO HERRERA: