Take cover, everybody,
take cover.
Can we survive our own
homegrown Armageddon?
Oh, oh!
I'm Travis Taylor.
I'm a rocket scientist in
the space and defense industry
here in my hometown of
Huntsville, Alabama,
where my daddy helped
build the rockets
that sent us to the moon.
DADDY: Have y'all been drinking
rocket fuel again?
TRAVIS: Sometimes big science
moves too slow for me,
so come the weekend,
I round up my best friend Rog...
ROG: Hey!
TRAVIS: ...my nephew Michael
and my buddy Pete
to tackle important problems
with a little down-home
ingenuity.
ROG: Damn it, boy!
TRAVIS: Right on.
Hey, is there any more beers
in the cooler?
PETE: I got some more cars.
TRAVIS: Alright.
Me and the guys,
we're getting ready to destroy
a giant dollhouse.
ROG: They playing house, man.
MICHAEL:
Three grown men playing house.
I show up and see Uncle Travis
playing with a dollhouse.
I don't know what's
gotten in to him.
ROG: What in the world?
DADDY: I was kind of hoping
y'all wouldn't see this.
ROG: Ain't that the dollhouse
he had when he was a little boy?
TRAVIS: It's the dollhouse
you used to play with.
ROG: Whatever.
TRAVIS: Uh-huh,
I remember going over
and seeing you with that
Ken doll right there.
ROG: Mine was camouflaged.
TRAVIS: Uh-huh.
Now that everybody's here,
Pete and I get to do something
that I've always wanted to do.
Light that thing up and
throw it over in there.
The bomb's about to hit
in three, two, one.
Wow, oh, look at that!
Look at it go!
Man, I think it needs a bigger
fireball than that.
Now that's a fireball!
Now, there are a lot of folks
out there
who call themselves preppers.
They build shelters in their
homes to protect themselves
from stuff like a nuclear war
or an asteroid strike
or a civil war or whatever.
I wanted to demonstrate
what would happen
to the average house during
something like that,
and show why that's not
such a good idea.
This is what's gonna happen if
you're stuck in your shelter
and there's a multiple
thousand degree...
Oh, there goes the structure,
it's collapsed!
If you know that something's
about to happen,
like a missile attack
or something like that,
you don't want to be
stuck in one place,
you want to get as far away
from that as possible...
Woo!
...'cause otherwise you might be
like the doll in the dollhouse
and get dry roasted.
MICHAEL: He's gone now.
ROG: I told Ken to
get out of there.
But he wouldn't listen.
TRAVIS: The answer for surviving
doomsday is simple.
You got to get away from this.
This weekend we're going to
apply our ingenuity
to create an apocalypse shelter
that will survive the most
likely doomsday scenario
here in Huntsville, Alabama,
and that's either a military
or a terrorist attack.
I've heard that
during the Cold War
the Soviets made Huntsville
one of the top cities
for a nuclear attack right after
Washington, DC, and San Diego.
Huntsville is a major hub of
the defense and space industry,
and today a terrorist group
or a rogue state
might also want to hit it
for the same reason.
But most doomsday scenarios have
a lot of the same elements,
whether it's an attack or a
pandemic or an asteroid strike.
If the apocalypse happens,
you want to get out of Dodge,
and that means our survival
plans will have to be mobile.
ROG: Man, stank.
TRAVIS: Woo.
So we went back to the garage
to figure this thing out.
So what do you got to do
if you're gonna be on the move
after the Armageddon?
ROG: Well, the main thing
you need
is food, water and shelter,
right?
TRAVIS: Food, water and shelter.
Well, that's your key
right there.
MICHAEL: If it's the end
of the world,
I don't know what I'd want
to take with me.
You'd probably want to take
a bar of soap,
you'd smell yourself
after a few weeks or something,
but I don't really know what
else would you want to take.
TRAVIS: So it's all
got to be mobile.
In a real apocalypse, you're
gonna have to stay on the move.
And you're gonna have to do it
on foot.
You won't have cars, or
you won't have them very long.
You won't have oil
or a power grid
or any other modern convenience.
So everything you have you'll
have to carry on your back.
And that's why the design
of our shelter
is going to revolve
around backpacks.
The packs will carry
all our gear.
Then we can connect them
together
as supports for the shelter.
We'll add a tent, roof and walls
made out of bulletproof Kevlar,
and we'll have a five-man,
mobile doomsday bunker.
We were thinking about
what kind of backpack
would be strong enough to
withstand Armageddon,
and then Daddy comes rolling out
the perfect material...
DADDY: Look out.
TRAVIS: A waterproof barrel.
DADDY: 27.5 pounds.
ROG: Boy, that's heavy
without nothing in it.
DADDY: Of course, first thing,
we've got a problem.
TRAVIS: What'd you say it was?
DADDY: 27 pounds.
TRAVIS: Even though
they're heavy,
I like these barrels better
than a standard fabric pack.
They're rigid and they'll help
repel incoming gunfire.
And I've got some ideas about
how we can make
the barrels useful
in life after the apocalypse.
TRAVIS: Oh, it ain't that bad,
actually.
MICHAEL: Yeah, but you ain't
got nothing in it.
PETE: Yeah.
DADDY: Once we get those barrels
loaded up
with everything we need,
not one of us is gonna be able
to lift them off the floor.
TRAVIS: You three start working.
Me and Pete are gonna start
thinking about
how we're gonna build a tent.
ROG: Yeah, Michael and I are
headed outside to get to work.
How many beers we gonna
take with us?
MICHAEL: I would say a couple
a piece anyhow.
ROG: A couple a piece?
I hear ya.
MICHAEL: Me and Rog are sitting
on side of the garage,
and we got to talking about
what we were gonna do
at the end of the world
if we run out of beer.
I don't think you could tote
enough beer in your pack
to get you very long.
Probably SOL.
That's sad.
TRAVIS: Spread it out
and see what we got.
Pete and I are unrolling
the bulletproof Kevlar
we're gonna use to make the top
and walls of the shelter.
We've got to lay down on it
to see how much we need to use.
Yeah, see,
that's plenty of room.
PETE: Oh, yeah.
TRAVIS: Alright, so we need
twice this.
Then Rog comes in and sees us.
ROG: Y'all gonna leg wrestle,
hold on,
y'all stay down there
and leg wrestle one time.
TRAVIS: You get down there
and leg wrestle with him.
ROG: I ain't gonna do it
with Pete.
I'm not going to
mess around with Pete.
He's got that black belt
in aikido.
But I think I can take Travis.
Let's do it.
TRAVIS: Come on.
ROG: Phew, man,
hold them glasses.
MICHAEL: Alright, I'm gonna
hold his glasses.
TRAVIS: Damn,
this floor is hard.
TRAVIS: You ready?
ROG: Yeah.
TRAVIS: One...
ROG: One...
TRAVIS: You can't even get
your leg up there.
TRAVIS: Two...
ROG: Two...
ROG: Three.
TRAVIS: Three.
TRAVIS: Oh! Rog, you put
your ass into it.
ROG: That's how you do it, man.
TRAVIS: Rog is the champion
leg wrestler.
ROG: Well, I guess now we know
if there's any leg wrestling
that needs to be done after
the apocalypse, I'm the guy.
TRAVIS: You whooped me.
Actually,
a post-apocalyptic world
is probably gonna be
pretty dangerous.
If a missile hits Huntsville,
we might have terrorists or
foreign troops coming in,
or we could have roaming bands
of marauders coming after us,
so I put our resident
optical sensor expert in charge
of creating a simple
early warning system.
That will let us know if
our camp is ever infiltrated.
Alright, Pete, show me what
you got going on in here.
PETE: Okay, this is our
garage door opener/sentry post.
MICHAEL: Pete came up with this
really cool defense system
using lasers to set up
a perimeter.
PETE: There's gonna be three
sensor posts like right here.
Our camp will be in the middle.
This laser shoots over
to this guy,
this laser shoots
over to this guy,
and this receiver picks up
that laser beam.
Just like a garage door opener,
but using a laser will give us
a lot longer distance.
TRAVIS: Right, right.
MICHAEL: And if somebody
crosses it
or breaks the plane of the
laser, a siren's gonna go off.
PETE: And we've got just a small
five-watt solar panel.
So that'll charge up
the batteries.
The great thing
about this system
is that it uses a bunch of
inexpensive stuff
you can buy at
any hardware store.
So you won't need
a generator or gas.
It's off the shelf,
and it's off the grid.
TRAVIS: Now I'm having Michael
weld together some square frames
that will attach to the barrels.
MICHAEL: That's the first
finished product.
TRAVIS: It goes right there,
and then we'll ratchet strap it
here, right?
MICHAEL: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Just go around
and hold it.
Then we'll put a pack right
here, like that right there,
and that's how we'll carry it.
PETE: Once we got that frame
attached to the barrel,
it was my job to give it
a test run.
Seeing what happens
just standing up there.
ROG: Stay with it, man.
TRAVIS: You look like
you're walking around okay.
Go get him a shotgun with
birdshot in it, Daddy.
DADDY: What are you gonna do
with birdshot?
TRAVIS: See if he can
shoot a gun
while he's holding that thing.
After any apocalyptic situation,
if things go bad,
you can bet that the bad guys
are going to be heavily armed.
So we're gonna have to be
heavily armed, too.
ROG: Stay with it, Pete.
TRAVIS: I'm gonna stand behind
you in case you fall back.
We set up a target
using that Kevlar
that we're gonna use
to make the shelter,
'cause we wanted to see how
bulletproof it really is.
He didn't fall.
Both Pete and that Kevlar
held up pretty good.
[gunshot]
So it looks like we're ready
to go ahead with our plans.
First thing, we got to make
four more of those backpacks.
MICHAEL: Alright, there's that
and I need one more
ratchet strap now.
ROG: It's the end of the world,
man, we need everything.
MICHAEL: Alright, here's one
that goes right here.
TRAVIS: Next we'll connect them
all together
to make the base of the shelter.
ROG: There's the A,
where's the A at?
MICHAEL: I got an A mark
and a G mark.
There's so many pieces that
make up the frame,
we labeled them alphabetically
so we can keep them
all straight.
DADDY: There's  an A, a G, a D,
and me, and the chimpanzee.
TRAVIS: Chimpanzee, agree,
one day soon he'll be
a celebri-tee.
ROG: I got a C.
DADDY: Okay, wait a minute,
you've got it right here.
ROG: Where's D?
DADDY: There you go.
ROG: We got this crazy,
complicated contraption.
And you can't find
all the pieces,
the frame's labeled
up to the letter Q,
and we're supposed to put this
together during the Armageddon?
We can't even put it together
in the garage.
TRAVIS: I'm confused, man.
MICHAEL: I want to make things
a little simpler
by making a color code
instead of just letters.
Now, I can make this one
yellow with a dot.
But I think that might have made
things even more confusing.
That'll be the green one
right there.
ROG: Look at that boy going.
You ought to be a tagger
for a living, man.
This is gonna be the prettiest
y'all ever seen.
TRAVIS: Yeah, but how are
we gonna make the tent now?
[horn honks]
What's Sloth doing here?
ROG: My neighbor Sloth is
one of them doomsday preppers.
So when I told him
we were making a mobile
apocalypse shelter,
he said he'd bring some of his
buddies over to check it out.
TRAVIS: I can't see
none of them,
they're all wearing camouflage.
SLOTH: Well, Rog told me
y'all been prepping
some kind of portable shelter.
And, you know, I've been doing
a little prepping, too.
TRAVIS: Yeah?
If I didn't know better,
I'd say that Sloth thinks
that him and his buddies
are better prepared for doomsday
than we are.
Is that a challenge?
SLOTH: If y'all are gonna be out
running around
traipsing about
through the woods,
we're gonna come hunt y'all down
and take your stuff from you.
TRAVIS: Oh, you think so?
SLOTH: Oh, I know so.
DADDY: W...or is than an M?
TRAVIS: We're building
a doomsday shelter.
MICHAEL: That's a B.
Is that A over there?
TRAVIS: But since I think the
best way to survive Armageddon
is to get away from it,
we're making our shelter mobile.
DADDY: There you go.
TRAVIS: When our buddy Sloth
found out about it,
he stopped by and challenged us
to a doomsday duel.
SLOTH: If y'all gonna be out
running around
traipsing about
through the woods,
we're gonna come hunt y'all down
and take your stuff from you.
TRAVIS: Oh, you think so?
SLOTH: Oh, I know so.
SLOTH: Look at this team, man,
are you kidding me?
TRAVIS: If he gets too close,
we'll have to leg wrestle him,
Rog.
You know you'll whoop him then.
SLOTH: Since we can't use
real guns,
I figure we'd go with this--
paintballs.
TRAVIS: Looks like we got
a doomsday showdown here.
Team Sloth versus Team Travis.
We got an air horn up in there.
SLOTH: Alright.
TRAVIS: Y'all go on down
about a mile or so
down back past the church
or something.
SLOTH: Okay.
TRAVIS: And when you hear
the air horn,
we'll say that's
the end of the world.
SLOTH: Alright.
TRAVIS: And then, everybody,
it's go time.
This competition might seem
like a lot of fun,
but in an actual
doomsday scenario,
mobs and bandits could be
a serious problem.
So tomorrow morning
we're gonna put our apocalypse
shelter to the test.
Not only are we gonna take it
out into the woods,
and deploy it,
and see if it works,
we're gonna do it
while being hunted
by Mad Max-style marauders.
DADDY: Paint "loser" on
the side of that truck.
TRAVIS: There you go, Daddy,
that's the spirit.
The only problem is we haven't
even finished our shelter yet,
and we don't even know how
we're gonna make the tent.
Oh, no, no, no, we got extra--
we do an A with the poles.
Then Rog had a brainstorm.
ROG: Hey, we got them things.
Let's tape them together and
make a covered wagon-hickey.
TRAVIS: So hand me some of that.
DADDY: I've got those
fiberglass rods
I used to make
bow and arrows with.
They're really strong,
but they're flexible.
So we're gonna take a few of
those and connect them together,
and they'll be the frame
for our tent.
TRAVIS: Now if we have another
one right there...
DADDY: We Velcroed them
into place,
and they formed the perfect dome
to stretch that Kevlar over.
ROG: Stay with it.
TRAVIS: All the way, so you can
shove it up under the barrel.
MICHAEL: There you go.
TRAVIS: There it is,
there's your tent.
This whole thing took a lot
longer than we thought it would.
It was dark by the time
we had that frame all together.
And now we've got to work
into the night
to put together our bug-out bags
and have everything in it
we need for the end
of civilization.
Doomsday is tomorrow.
Let's load it up.
Let's figure out what we got to
do to get it all in the packs.
I want to make this
a real world test.
We're focusing on a single
doomsday scenario--
a missile or bomb attack
on Huntsville.
It's big enough to
knock out the grid
and call for an evacuation
of the city,
a disaster the size of
Hurricane Katrina or bigger.
It'll be chaos!
Experts say that looting and
mob behavior can begin quickly
when the grid goes down
and police are unavailable.
So hoards of bandits
like Sloth's boys
could actually be targeting
people who are already prepared.
SLOTH: We're gonna get
geared up,
and then we'll a do check
on these paintball guns.
TRAVIS: But the guys and I
have added a little twist
to our doomsday shelter
that I think is gonna give them
marauders a real surprise.
SLOTH: They're probably gonna be
headed up toward the river.
So what we'll do is
we'll get geared up,
and we'll just start
heading north,
and as soon as we hear that
buzzer Travis was talking about,
we'll go hunt them down
and get them.
TRAVIS: It's zero hour.
The apocalypse is
about to begin.
Imagine that
the missiles have fallen
or the asteroid has struck.
The grid is down,
so there's no electricity,
and once there's no electricity,
things fall apart quick.
You can't buy gas because
the pumps won't work.
You can't drive because
the highways are jammed.
You can't use an ATM.
The phone lines and cell towers
are down.
Crowds of panicked people
are trying to flee,
and other crowds are looting.
The cities are burning,
and the marauding hordes
are on the rampage.
It's time to bug out,
rocket city style.
Here we go, end of the world.
[horn blares]
SLOTH: Uh-oh.
We got to hurry up.
MAN: They work.
We're good to go.
SLOTH: Alright,
let's go get 'em.
TRAVIS: We're carrying food
and water for three days--
enough to get us to another
supply source.
We've got our weapons...
DADDY:
Is the gun already loaded?
TRAVIS: My gun's full of ammo.
...and some power tools.
Best of all, we've got
our mobile shelter.
PETE: Let's head towards
the tree,
at least there's some cover.
TRAVIS: Everybody be ready,
they could be in this
tall grass somewhere.
ROG: Here's a cow trail.
MICHAEL: Hey, where's the cow?
If this is the end of the world,
we could...
TRAVIS: We could eat cows.
PETE: We could blind it
with a paintball gun
and then wrestle it
to the ground.
MICHAEL: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
[laughter]
DADDY: There's a place
right through here we can camp.
TRAVIS: I don't think
there's anybody
who knows these woods
better than Daddy.
So he found us a good spot
to set up.
DADDY: You'll have to walk
around this limb.
That's kind of part of the plan.
In major disasters,
you don't want to be in a city.
Sometimes the worst thing
you can face is other people.
I'm a country boy.
When things go bad,
the safest place to be
is out in these woods.
Right over here, guys.
TRAVIS: Good-looking spot,
Daddy.
DADDY: We chose this place
for its tactical advantages.
We could see the road, but the
folks on the road can't see us.
MICHAEL: Let's come out
of these packs.
DADDY: We got a good field
of vision on all sides,
and we got tree cover up above.
It's a good, safe spot for
a defensive position.
If they approach,
they're gonna have to come
out of the southwest.
PETE: So that's where we got
to set up our sensor system.
DADDY: Come here and help us
figure this thing out.
MICHAEL: There's G.
Where's D? Is this D?
ROG: That's E.
MICHAEL: E, oh, D's up there.
ROG: Hey, you got a C
over there?
You got any threes?
MICHAEL: Go fish.
ROG: Oh, go fish, dang.
TRAVIS: Daddy, catch that end.
MICHAEL: We got the Kevlar sheet
stretched tight
and pegged down at the base.
With a little practice, we could
set this thing up pretty fast.
TRAVIS: It looks kind of like
an igloo or something.
PETE: It does.
TRAVIS:
That's a lot of hard work.
I think we ought to
eat something.
I'll get the MREs out.
ROG: I saw that Travis
had packed some MREs.
I thought I'd bring something
a little bit tastier.
PETE: Oh, heck, yes.
DADDY: Oh, man.
TRAVIS: You been carrying that
all day long?
ROG: Yeah.
TRAVIS: It ain't bad.
Give me one of them.
Rog?
ROG: It's the end of the world,
man.
TRAVIS: Yeah, it's the last
pizza you'll ever get.
PETE: Oh, that ain't no good.
Man.
[alarm sounds]
MICHAEL: Oh, hold on, get down.
TRAVIS: Sloth's marauders
hit us.
Take cover.
But our early warning system
gave us the time
to get into our
bulletproof shelter.
Still, the best defense is
always a good offense.
So we took the fight
to the enemy.
Let's go get 'em.
MICHAEL: Let's do it,
let's do it.
TRAVIS: Spread out, everybody
spread out and take some trees.
Oh! Oh, oh, oh!
Then Daddy was down.
[alarm sounds]
MICHAEL: Hold on, get down!
TRAVIS: We built a portable
doomsday shelter
that we're defending from Sloth
and his group of
marauding bandits.
Oh, shoot, that come
right by my head!
But just when it looked like
we're getting the upper hand...
Everybody spread out
and take some trees.
Oh! Oh, oh, oh!
I saw Daddy hit the ground.
MICHAEL: You alright, Papa?
DADDY: He got my head.
[laughs]
PETE: You okay?
DADDY: I mean, it cut right
across the top of my head
and knocked my hat off.
TRAVIS: Stay low, Daddy.
DADDY: That was a close one.
They just knocked my hat off,
so I'm still in the game.
I'm fine, keep going.
TRAVIS: We could have stayed
safe inside the Kevlar igloo...
Alright, let's go get 'em.
...but we weren't about to let
those marauders surround us.
Go, go, press advantage.
PETE: Go!
SLOTH: Guys, retreat, retreat!
PETE: Is everybody good?
Everybody okay?
ROG: Shoot, man.
TRAVIS: I think they left.
The alarm system worked good,
man.
We'd have been in trouble
had it not gone off.
SLOTH: I thought they were
gonna be sitting ducks,
and we were gonna just walk in
and take their stuff.
And then that alarm went off,
and we were in a firefight.
We'll be back, though.
TRAVIS: Let's get this thing
loaded up,
and let's get down to the river
and get away
so they can't ambush us again.
We've proven that our
shelter concept works.
But I know they're coming back,
and that's why we made
this thing mobile.
When civilization collapses,
you're going to want to
be able to move.
In the Balkan War in the '90s,
people survived by fleeing
the cities to the woods
and keeping ahead of
the bad guys.
So we're gonna tear this thing
down and get back on the move.
We got to get going.
Putting the bolts in this jar
right here.
Since we need to get out of here
as fast as we can,
we're leaving the main part
of the frame
still connected together.
ROG: Crap.
MICHAEL: You all right?
ROG: Yeah, I'm all right.
TRAVIS: Let's go.
None of us are real happy
about putting these backpacks
on again.
I'm checking my luggage
next time.
But we're carrying part
of the frame by hand.
Alright, here we are.
Because we're gonna deploy
our secret weapon
once we're at the river.
PETE: Alright, guys, it's clear.
TRAVIS: These backpacks don't
just turn into a shelter,
they also turn into a boat.
DADDY: When I saw those barrels,
I thought,
those things can float.
MICHAEL: Push them all the way
through, Rog.
DADDY: So our shelter can also
transform into a water vehicle.
PETE: It's not going, Michael?
MICHAEL: Yeah, it's just...
ROG: Stay with it.
MICHAEL: On the riverbank,
it ain't as easy as you'd think.
DADDY: Most of this country
was explored by waterways.
MICHAEL: There it is.
DADDY: And escaping from
Armageddon by boat
is a lot easier than
doing it by foot.
TRAVIS: Hey, let's put all
the guns in here,
and then our shoes when we get
ready to get out in the water.
We don't need
to get them all wet.
MICHAEL: Here's a gun.
TRAVIS: We ready?
Woo, the water's cold,
by the way.
Daddy, you get on,
I'll push you.
ROG: He got the best spot.
MICHAEL: Yeah, I did get
the best spot.
TRAVIS: We're out, we're out,
get on, Pete, get on.
PETE: We're gone, guys.
TRAVIS: Alright.
SLOTH: There they are,
there they are!
PETE:
Paddle for your lives, boys.
SLOTH:
Let's see if we can get 'em.
ROG: I had my own secret weapon.
TRAVIS: Go that way.
ROG: I knew Charlie packed
some battery-powered drills,
so I thought I'd bring along
a big paint stirrer,
so now we have
an outboard motor.
[laughter]
SLOTH: I thought we had them
trapped down by the riverbank.
Oh, man.
I knew they were
gonna be mobile,
but I didn't know they were
gonna have a doggone boat.
That's it.
They got away.
Good effort, guys.
I mean, if it wouldn't have been
for that stupid trip wire,
I think we'd have had them.
MAN: Yeah.
SLOTH: We'll get 'em next time.
SLOTH: It ain't
the end of the world.
[laughs]
TRAVIS: We got away from them.
They're over yonder,
and we're out of range.
Our barrel boat is
floating just fine.
It's taking us on down the river
to our new lives
after Armageddon.
Kind of peaceful for
the end of the world.
DADDY: Hand me the fishing rod,
I want to see if I can
catch us a fish.
TRAVIS: A fishing rod?
DADDY: Yeah.
TRAVIS: We didn't bring
a fishing rod.
ROG: It's at the bottom
of this barrel.
TRAVIS: Your barrel's over here.
DADDY: No, I didn't pack it,
I told you to pack it and put it
in that middle barrel.
TRAVIS: I didn't bring
any fishing stuff.
MICHAEL: Well, it's in one of
these other barrels.