above their heads, and not only
spy satellites, but all
kinds of satellites.
And by a clear night, they can
see all the satellites passing
over their heads.
So in a sense, they
are not so secret.
Yes, I think that it may
interest some people to know
that these satellites are
visible, and even that we can
catch some details with
a telescope--
like a game, spying
spy satellites.
We are in the Astronomy and
Space encounter, the main
forum or encounter place for
astronomy in France.
It happens every two years, and
there are several thousand
visitors during three days.
My speech is about, of course,
photography of space station
and other satellites, like
geostationary satellites or
other funny satellites.
My name is Thierry Legault.
I'm an engineer.
I live in the suburbs
of Paris.
My hobby is astronomy,
and more precisely
astrophotography.
It's a nice feeling to be able
to transmit our passion to
other people and help them
through to practice and to do
the same kind of photography as
I do-- or better, I hope.
And I would like to try to
find all the ways to be
different because I like
to do things that
have never been done.
This website called Heavens
Above gives us the list of the
brightest satellites visible
in the evening tonight.
And a good candidate
is the Cosmos 1782
because it's quite bright.
It's an intelligence
satellites--
Russian intelligence
satellite.
So I go into the other website,
which is CalSky, to
get some calculations.
When I was a teenager,
I asked my parents
to buy a small telescope.
And then I was the happiest
child in the world with my
telescope, looking at
the stars, the moon.
And then I continue with a lot
bigger means now, and bigger
telescopes and cameras, but
in the same principle.
The satellite will come from
there, like this, over the
house like that.
I got started watching
satellites quite by chance.
Six years ago, I've been
writing a book about
astrophotography.
And since I wanted to take all
of the photos for the book, I
needed any kind of a photo of
the sky including the passage
of the space station in
front of the sun.
So I took one.
And I said, OK, this is funny,
so took a picture of the space
station and the space
shuttle just
beside, just after undocking.
And this photo has had big
success on CNN, and the
"Guardian," and "Popular
Science," and a lot of
magazines in France
and also in other
countries in the world.
And so I continued to
take such shots.
OK, good.
More than three years ago,
I contacted a friend of a
friend, which is named Emmanuel
Rietsch, to modify my
mount to be able to track,
automatically, the satellites.
Basically, there were two
parts in the project.
The first part was to make the
mount able to track the
satellite manually, with a
joystick, like a joystick of a
video game.
And so the second part of the
project has been to make the
system, and especially the
software, with an additional
camera, tracking camera, able
to track to satellites
automatically.
This is a Unix system.
In a matter of-- thank
you, Emmanuel.
This telescope will take
the high resolution
video of the satellite.
This one is used just to
track the satellite
with a second camera.
There would be the main camera
here, second camera here.
And this one is to center the
satellite visually, just at
the beginning, when it appears,
to be sure that it's
visible through this camera.
With the solar or lunar transit,
almost all of them
are successful--
95% or more.
But for satellites like
that, it's much less.
It's, say, 50%.
Sometimes there are
some clouds.
Sometimes they are too faint.
Sometimes computers don't want
to work exactly as you want.
Especially, just at the critical
moment, you have a
blue screen saying, everything
is crashed.
It happens sometimes.
Astrophotography is not
something that's very easy.
The stars, and the nebulas, and
the galaxies are faint.
The planets are small, and
so it's quite difficult.
Light pollution is a very,
very big problem for
astronomers because they have to
go farther and farther from
the cities.
And it's just like people are
prisoners in a prison of light
because they can't see outside
this prison of light.
They don't see the nature, and
the stars, and the Milky Way.
So in my opinion,
light pollution,
is a kind of prison.
So I have to align everything
first on a star, the polar
star, which will appear later.
And then, after all this
alignment, I have to focus the
camera on the star.
And then I have to change the
alignment in the mount to
align it on the trajectory of
the satellite in the sky.
So far.
The weather is the biggest
enemy of the astronomer
because the telescope that
looks through the clouds
doesn't exist.
Unfortunately we see
some clouds coming
over the area of Paris.
Paris is the red dot in the
north of France here.
And so we'll have a sky which
that is partly cloudy so we
need some chance.
It's not the funniest part of
the game, driving and trying
to find clear skies.
But when it's successful, it's
more rewarding, let's say.
All the clouds are coming now.
The sky is completely covered.
And this is one of the reasons
why we go in sunny countries
to observe the sky.
OK, we have quite a hole, but
other ones coming after.
These clouds coming again.
I think it's over.
It's full of clouds now.
This is a pity.
They have clouds everywhere,
so nature has won.
She's always the stronger,
at the end.
I'm a little bit sad,
of course, but I
know that it's a risk.
So if I don't want to take the
risk, I'd just stay on my sofa
watching TV.
And so it's a part
of the risk.
Of course, I'm not very happy.
But an activity where there is
no in risk, and where you win
every time, it's something
that is too easy.
I photograph satellites because
it's difficult.
It's a kind of challenge
with myself.
And each time I say, OK,
you succeed or not.
And next time, can
you do better?
Can do another satellite?
Something else?
Something more difficult?
So it's a way to improve my
skill with a telescope.
And yeah, it's like a game or
a challenge with myself.
Next time, I will get them.