Kennedy's assassination.
And every year on my birthday
there's been televised
specials on practically every
channel talking about magic
bullets, grassy knolls, other
shooters, as well as CIA, FBI,
and mafia involvement.
Even by the age of 10
this spoke to me.
And, of course, there were UFOs,
the Illuminati, occult
Nazis, organized satanic
networks, faked moon landings
and CIA mind control programs.
Hell, even if this is
all bullshit, it
was fun to read about.
It was in 2000 that I first
discovered David Icke's book,
"The Biggest Secret." In it
he writes about a global
conspiracy.
A hidden hand manipulating
humanity's destiny through the
shadows using those who
seem to be in power.
And the goal of these
shadow people?
Nothing less than an Orwellian
global super state with total
control at the hands of
an ancient reptilian
shapeshifting race.
So we took a ferry to the Isle
of Wight to spend the day with
David Icke, Britain's leading
conspiracy evangelist, and the
one man standing between us
and total enslavement.
NARRATOR: Hey!
DAVID ICKE: Ah.
NARRATOR: Mr. Icke.
DAVID ICKE: Kev, nice
to meet you.
NARRATOR: Nice to meet you.
DAVID ICKE: Good trip?
NARRATOR: Yes.
Yes.
It was.
DAVID ICKE: Welcome
to my abode.
There's not much to see,
but I like it.
NARRATOR: What have
we got here?
DAVID ICKE: Well, this is things
that I've collected
over the years.
This is fantastic.
Someone in Hawaii actually
painted this.
This is what the painting is.
This is the original of the
front cover of my last book,
"Human Race Get Off Your Knees:
The Lion Sleeps No
More." And I asked my great
friend, an artist called Neil
Hague, to paint this picture
for me with, particularly,
those eyes.
And that's humanity
saying, no more.
Enough.
No more little me.
We're not having it anymore.
NARRATOR: In 1991 David Icke
didn't believe in secret
shapeshifting lizard fascists.
He was a television celebrity.
After arthritis had ended a
promising career in football,
he'd become a broadcaster.
But that all ended in one
remarkable appearance on the
Terry Wogan show.
-David Icke.
NARRATOR: In a turquoise
tracksuit he'd announced that
he was the son of God.
And the world would be
ending that year.
It didn't, and Icke seemed
destined to disappear beneath
a typhoon of public laughter.
-It's quite funny really.
2000 years ago had a guy called
Jesus sat here and said
these same things, you would
still be laughing.
It's really, really funny that
we've not really moved on that
much.
-They're laughing at you.
They're not laughing with you.
-Fine.
NARRATOR: But Icke wouldn't
disappear.
He began to write.
And over a series of
increasingly successful books,
he began to outline
his philosophy.
Humankind was not in charge
of its destiny.
It was the unwitting prisoner
of a race of shapeshifting
lizards who occupied
the roles in the
highest echelons of society.
From presidents to royal
families, all trusted public
figures were secretly part of a
reptilian satanist pedophile
group who had been on this
planet for centuries.
People began to take notice of
Icke, and today he spends most
of his year preaching to
amphitheaters full of fans.
He's still making startling
revelations, and recently he
declared the moon to be a
hollowed out planetoid space
station from which our
minds are controlled.
The lizard's very
own Death Star.
Don't mention the reptiles,
chapter two.
DAVID ICKE: Don't mention
the reptiles, yeah.
Because people-- when they
started to come in people were
kind of into my stuff
up to that point.
Which was kind of regular--
well it was a bit strange.
It was all the way the world was
manipulated by few people,
but it was all kind
of regular stuff.
And then I came across with this
stuff and it was like--
NARRATOR: Get it
out of the way.
DAVID ICKE: --don't mention
the reptiles.
They'll just laugh
at you again.
I said, I know.
But I've seen enough
and heard enough to
believe that it's real.
And so I say it.
I don't care about the
consequences for me.
Are you frightened?
No.
I'm not.
I don't care.
Because the consequences for the
world and my children, and
my grandchildren, and everyone
else's, of humans not
intervening in this process
that's going on now ever more
quickly, are that we are
condemning our children and
grandchildren--
indeed ourselves, it's
that close--
to a world that George Orwell
so massively understated.
NARRATOR: Can we have a look at
where the work gets done?
DAVID ICKE: Yes.
NARRATOR: Where it
all happens.
DAVID ICKE: This is where
it all happens.
As you can see it's
really small.
NARRATOR: It is really small.
DAVID ICKE: Because I look at
my life and I don't see my
life as a life anymore.
I haven't for a while.
I see it as a job.
NARRATOR: So this
is the new one.
In German?
DAVID ICKE: Yeah.
This is the German version,
isn't it?
Look at the size of that.
NARRATOR: Jeez, yeah.
DAVID ICKE: 250,000 words.
That, in one book, is the scale
of information that has
come into my life about
these things.
See, that is not a theory.
That is evidence supporting
a fact.
NARRATOR: What was the first
book that really struck you?
Because, I know, there
was a couple for me.
Are you familiar with
Robert Anton Wilson?
DAVID ICKE: Yeah.
Yeah.
NARRATOR: And I just liked it
because it was funny and it
tied a lot of points of
interest together.
And he sort of pointed me
in different directions.
Even though he wasn't really a
conspiracy theorist trying to
say anything.
He put things together
I never saw.
DAVID ICKE: Right.
NARRATOR: He'd connect dots that
had never occurred to me.
Which turned me to "Holy, Blood,
Holy Grail," and some
of these other things.
DAVID ICKE: You've just hit the
nail right on the head of
my work and what you need
to do to understand
what's going on.
Connect the dots.
See, there are dots, like
banking, government, all these
different things, 9/11, which
in and of themselves are
interesting.
And you can see that something's
not right.
But when you connect the dots
between apparently unconnected
people and situations and
organizations, that's when the
tapestry appears.
And you go, whoa.
So that's what's happening.
NARRATOR: David had told us
that his first moment of
enlightenment had occurred when
a voice entered his head
while shopping with his
son on the sea front.
DAVID ICKE: This is the news
agent I told you about where,
basically, it all started.
I was walking along here and I
walked in this door and turned
to where Gareth was reading
his Spin Train books.
And this is where it happened.
Just the other side
of this door.
Where I'm like, what's
going on?
Go and look at the books
on the far side.
What?
And that's where it started.
1990.
March, 1990.
And I never thought it was going
to lead where it has.
But it has.
Yeah.
NARRATOR: Well, it was
a great beginning.
Platform Fun.
DAVID ICKE: In simple terms,
there is a predator race which
take a reptilian form.
They're feeding off humanity.
They've turned humanity
into a slave race.
They demand human sacrifice.
That's where satanism
comes in.
They feed off human energy,
particularly feed off the
energy of children.
NARRATOR: David's latest
revelations have
been about the moon.
Far from a lump of benign rock
orbiting us, it is in fact an
artificial construct, a gigantic
spacecraft, probably
a hollowed out planetoid.
It is from the moon that the
nefarious Illuminati
manipulate the collective
human mind.
Warping our perception
of reality.
DAVID ICKE: I'm saying it's
broadcasting something.
That it acts as a blocking
frequency that stops us seeing
and perceiving things that we
would normally perceive.
That is creating what I call the
moon matrix, or the satin
moon matrix.
And it's basically having the
effective of the fake reality
in "The Matrix" movies.
NARRATOR: I guess that makes
David the Isle of
Wight's very own Neo.