you know israelis
protest saying marching
sometimes yelling at sudanese women
and men and calling them a lot of matter
words
uh... basically say sydney's go home you
not welcome here your criminals in one
instance shouting at them your force and
saturn
now of courses are irony there israel
was created
because nobody would take in the jews
during the holocaust
that seems like an excellent
justification and the one that is used
most often understandably so
now the sudanese
have not been treated well not just in
sudan the ones that are fleeing
but also in inject and other muslim
countries as well
golombek christian an airplane because
they're being persecuted because of
religious reasons
now you would hope that
of all the countries in the world israel
would understand that that's
but that's actually the least of their
immigration problems
they also have the hundred and thirty
thousand easy opiates now in this case
they've europeans are george so it does
really matters and jewish state so that
they should be welcome right
well not exactly
their health ministry has just admitted
that they were doing forced
sterilization
of ethiopian women even though there
george
as they were coming into the country
now thank of association is not
permanent
but he did last for a long time in front
of the last ten years
the birth rate among ethiopians in
israel has dropped
fifty percent
you know not to speculate as to why as i
just told you
israel's health minister has admitted
they did the program and in fact he sent
out a note saying
not to renew prescriptions for double
pro-growth for women of the ethiopian or
chin if for any reason there is concern
that they might not understand the
ramifications of the treatment
i don't think the issue was that they
didn't understand the ramp dishes the
treatment issue was as they were coming
in they were told
had to get that
sometimes they were lying to us at all
you had said back soonish minutes
but their help you with your health
one of the women that were interviewed
the thirty different one saying the same
thing i was uh...
saying quoted as saying quote they told
us their inoculations they told us
people who for quickly give birth supper
we can get every three months
we said we didn't want to
israel's not the only country with
racism
mainly the united states of america we
had slavery here and proms a recent
still
exists in this country as well as many
other countries
but that inspired
really embarrassing
i mean if you're going to be a jewish
state and that you do this to fellow
jews what just 'cause they're african
because they're black or
people of israel should be a livid over
that
and i wish they were also livid over the
sudan situation
on forcefully pepole out
is really frightening
uh...
fifty two percent of israelis say
that uh... afrin asylum-seekers or
quartet cancer
that's fifty two percent that's a
majority
and one-third of israelis said that they
support
violent attacks
on african seeking asylum
that is at terrible number
parable
there's a lot they could be improved
upon in
all the different countries in the world
including the u_s_
that's something that israel
definitely needs to work out
young turks