An alleged plot to blow up the Federal Reserve
Bank of New York, that`s where we start today.
Federal authorities say, they`ve broken it
up and arrested the suspect as part of an
undercover investigation. The Federal Reserve
is the central bank of the United States.
This one in New York is a regional branch
of it. Officials say the suspect was planning
to set off an explosion there with what he
thought was a 1000 pound bomb. No, it wasn`t
real. The false explosives came from an undercover
agent. Quazi Nafis is 21 years old. He`s from
Bangladesh, came to the U.S. on a student
visa. But prosecutors say, his real goal was
to carry out a terrorist attack. He was arrested
after he tried to set off the device.
There are a lot of ways to pay for college.
Scholarships, financial aid, savings, working
through it. Another option is student loans.
Now, those have to be repaid, and a new report
says today`s college seniors are graduating
with more student loan debt, more money that
has to be repaid than ever before.
This report says, the two thirds of the class
of 2011 had student loan debt, and the average
borrower owed nearly $27,000. Part of this
depends on what school you go to. At the colleges
this study looked at, the low into the average
debt per graduate was 3,000, the high end,
more than 55,000. A couple of explanations
were offered for the debt increase from previous
years. One is rising tuition prices, the other
is the tough job market for college graduates
looking for work.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: What`s the word? The
amount by which spending exceeds income.
Deficit. That`s the word.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Right now, the U.S. government is running
a deficit, it has been for years, it`s the
topic that comes up a lot in politics, and
as you might expect, it`s come up a lot in
this year`s presidential campaign. In fact,
during this week`s debate, between Barack
Obama and Mitt Romney, the word deficit came
up nearly 20 times. Both candidates have plans
for how to do with it, Tom Foreman compares
their ideas.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
TOM FOREMAN, CNN CORRESPONDENT: Both candidates
have made it a cornerstone of this election
to talk about the deficit, the difference
between how much money our government is spending
and how much it is taking in in taxes. This
is the deficit right now, $1,090,000,000,00.
If we all wanted to pay it off, every man,
woman and child in the country would have
to kick in about $3500. That`s a lot, and
yet each candidate says confidently, I can
reduce the deficit. How would they do that?
Well, first, let`s talk about what they agree
on.
They all say that we`re going to have to contain
the spending of the government and control
it, but we`re also going to have to rewrite
the tax code, and we have to get the economy
moving again, because that`s what going to
produce money and revenue, and really solve
the problem, but beyond that, they don`t agree
on much.
Let`s look at the Romney plan first. If these
were to represent everything he wants to spend
money on, and he needs this much to cover
it, he knows he`s not going to get it, because
he has a deficit. So, how is he going to deal
with that deficit? He says he is going to
do it with tax cuts. Now, tax cuts initially
are going to make the deficit worse, so he
needs to offset them. He says he is going
to do that by looking at deductions and loopholes,
things that people use to avoid paying taxes.
Says, he won`t go after things like the mortgage
deduction, or the health care deduction, things
that many middle class people rely on, at
least he suggests he won`t go after those,
but that`s the problem. Economists say, if
you grab up all the other deductions that
you might put on wealthier people and you
put them all back in this pile, it`s not going
to be enough, you are going to end up eventually
having to tax the middle class or watching
the deficit just get bigger, at least based
on the plan as I know it right now.
Barack Obama, he has different version of
the same song. He`s got all the things he
wants to pay for, he also will not have all
the money he needs for it. He is going to
have a deficit, too, and he says you can deal
with it by taxing the wealthy. This is a popular
plan with many voters, but it also has a fundamental
flaw. There are just not that many wealthy
people in the country. If you define wealthy
as being people who individually make more
than $200,000 a year, as he often does, for
every one there is like that in the country,
this is how many there are who don`t make
that much money. You would have to tax these
person at a much higher rate than the White
House is talking about to solve this problem,
and even then you probably wouldn`t get enough
money to really make up the deficit. The simple
truth is, both of these plans are woefully
short on important details to tell us if they
would really reduce the deficit.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
PELLEY: All right, discussing politics with
your friends, that can be kind of tricky,
especially if you don`t agree on every issue.
It could lead to some arguments, it could
lead to some hurt feelings, but doing it online?
That could lead to some downright unfriendingness.
Karin Caifa takes a look at how this year`s
presidential election is effecting some people`s
friends and followers on social media.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
KARIN CAIFA, CNN CORRESPONDENT: While the
candidates have squared off here and here
and here, another intense debate has played
out here.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: When you get a chance
to watch debates, you can kind of just go
on Facebook and figure out exactly what happened.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: If we go back and forth,
I don`t know, I mean there are statuses in
mind, we do, we do that a lot.
CAIFA: Social media traffic during the major
political events has exploded during the 2012
campaign season, and soak in emotions as Facebook
and Twitter feeds get jammed with more political
statements than ever.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: There are some times
entertaining, I just usually ignore them most
of the time.
CAIFA: Some time it`s too much to ignore.
A survey from the Pew Research Center earlier
this year found roughly one in five social
media users has cut someone off for a political
post that went too far.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: He got personal, I said,
no, no. You are out! You are out!
CAIFA: But for every post that makes you want
to hit delete, think about this, Kelly Fincham,
assistant professor at Hofstra University,
says that not having any debate among connections
may not be good either.
KELLY FINCHAM, HOFSTRA UNIVERSITY: It does
act a little bit like an echo chain. You are
usually following people who they are already
your friends. It`s harder to hear other opinions.
So it`s harder to seek out alternative opinions
and voices.
CAIFA: Users can always hide updates from
friends or followers during big political
events, or until the electoral overload stops
after November 6th. In Hempstead, New York,
I`m Karin Caifa.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: So, this brings up an interesting question,
would you un-friend someone for making political
statements you didn`t agree with? Would you
just hide their posts or would you just ignore
it. We are asking on our blog today, if you
head to CNN STUDENT NEWS.COM you can tell
us what you think, but only if you use your
first name, no last initials, no classes.
If you`ve never been in a plane and flown
over a landmark, the captain might get on
the speaker and draw your attention to it.
It`s kind of what happened on an Air Canada
flight this week. The plane was almost at
the end of a 14-hour flight to Australia when
the captain dropped down from 37,000 feet
to 4,000 feet. Then he asked people to peek
out the window and see if they could find
something. This yacht, it was stranded out
on the water, no fuel, broken mast, the sailor
set off an emergency signal. Officials asked
the Air Canada flight if it could help out,
and the people onboard did. Passengers and
crew spotted him, authorities eventually arrived
to pick up the sailor. Total time from when
he set off the signal to when he was spotted
by the plane, 25 minutes.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today`s "Shoutout" goes
out to Mrs. Rader`s social studies classes
at Warren Hills Regional Middle School in
Washington, New Jersey.
The U.S. presidential election is traditionally
held on what day of the week? Here we go,
is it Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday or Saturday.
You`ve got three seconds, go!
The presidential election is held on the Tuesday
following the first Monday in November. That`s
your answer and that`s your "Shoutout."
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: Tuesday is also when new video games
are traditionally released. The new "Halo"
comes out on Tuesday, November 6. That date,
the day of U.S. presidential election.
This was the kind of line that formed when
"Halo 3" came out in 2007, people going to
stores for midnight release parties. Some
folks are wondering if this year`s release
could impact the election. One point of view
says people who are motivated to vote, are
going to vote. Another says, people might
skip voting to dive into the new game. What
do you say? If you are already on Facebook,
talk to us at Facebook.com/cnnstudentnews.
And finally, that old cliche about being sent
to bed without your dinner? I think this is
the exact opposite. These twins are so totally
tuckered out, they are slipping in their sleep,
as they slurp up spaghetti. The one on the
left gave in pretty quickly, the one on the
right keeps chewing, even as he nods off.
Youtube video is great, and it`s understandable:
you`ve got kids who are obviously ready for
bed. Even with the temptation of delicious
spaghetti, you can`t expect them to stay awake
pasta certain point. All right. How do we
come up with brilliant puns like that one?
You just got to use your noodle. That eats
up our time for the day. Have a great weekend,
and we`ll see you on Monday.