Right now, what time is it?
ANTHONY PAPPALARDO: 7:15.
MALE SPEAKER 1: 7:15 what?
ANTHONY PAPPALARDO:
In the morning.
Gotta get a little footage, but
can't even have a board.
Joke!
Look what you're making
me skate.
You forget to send me boards.
Look at this soggy, chipped
piece of wood that you expect
me to get footage on.
Are you serious?
I was going to Philly a lot, and
then I just finished high
school, and Bill had a house out
there with his girlfriend
at the time.
I just was staying with him a
lot of weekends and stuff and
ended up just getting my
own place out there.
Still at that time, 17 years
old, skating was so consuming,
and Philadelphia was complete
skate, too.
And we would just skate all
day and night, have some
beers, go to bed, skate, and
that's all there was.
BRIAN WENNING: Where is it at?
[LAUGHTER]
ROB PLUHOWSKI: Philadelphia was
a great fit for anybody.
You know, there was love
at the prime time.
It was, like, everyone would
skate in the park all day.
It was just love all day--
City Hall, love City Hall.
I mean, those guys definitely
put it more on the map, you
know, with the Habitat video,
and the Workshop video.
It came down to, just, turning
things around for everyone,
you know, skateboard-wise.
And they really opened people's
eyes to who they were
really fast.
You know, when those guys first
came down, it was nose
grind pop out era.
You know, everything
was nosegrind
pop out at the ledge.
And they just do it all.
They could just-- and, fuck,
none of us could even
nosegrind the Love ledges,
you know, besides Kalis.
And those guys just come down
there and just blew everyone's
minds away.
I mean, Wenning was doing shit
on ledges that he couldn't
even, like, fathom.
You know, it was amazing.
I would say Wenning,
more first.
But Anthony was kind of--
Anthony came up real fast,
you know what I mean.
They weren't much alike,
that's for sure.
I mean, Wenning was, like--
Wenning always wanted the
attention, You know, he was,
like, doing stupid shit to get
people to look at him.
And then, you know, Anthony
would just be skating.
ANTHONY PAPPALARDO: You know,
I look at my skating when I
was 15 or 16, now.
I don't regret a lot of the
stuff I did, but it's just,
definitely, you change.
I hope you would change.
I hope everyone would change
from when they're 15, 16 years
old, otherwise, it would be
a fucked up place, man.
But I don't have the fucking
mentals to do a lot of the
skating I used to
do back then.
MALE SPEAKER 1: Oh, oh.
ANTHONY PAPPALARDO: Did
I almost do it?
MALE SPEAKER 1: You all right?
ANTHONY PAPPALARDO: Yeah,
let me see it.
ROB PLUHOWSKI: I would say the
one that stands out in my
mind, right now--
that was the switch ollie into
the fountain, for sure.
They had never even ollied it.
You know what I mean, they
didn't even try to ollie it,
ever, just straight
to switch ollie.
That blows my mind away.
MALE SPEAKER 1: Ugh.
ROB PLUHOWSKI: He,
just, did it.
I mean, he got broke.
He got beat up.
I mean, I was scared
for him, sometimes.
Yeah, like, switch ollie into
the fountain at night, what
the hell are you thinking?
AUDIENCE: Woo!
[CHEERS]
AUDIENCE: Whoa!
BRIAN WENNING: I don't know.
Hanging with PJ Ladd in
California, sometimes, it
gives me the feeling
that hanging with
Anthony back then.
AUDIENCE: [CHEERS]
BRIAN WENNING: That's why
we were in competition.
It would help both of us.
AUDIENCE: Oh!
BRIAN WENNING: I don't know
if he just forgot
about himself or what.
I mean, I still skate
the same exact shit.
But maybe he thought it
was time to move on.
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
BRIAN WENNING: That was the time
when, like, he'd be at
the spot at Love Park, and
we wouldn't even talk.
[CHEERING]
MALE SPEAKER 2: But you
switch 180'd it.
BRIAN WENNING: Oh, yeah.
MALE SPEAKER 2: Did you have
it in mind that, OK, he
switch ollied it?
BRIAN WENNING: I don't know.
Somebody was telling me, in the
background, like, when I--
because he did it, like,
a week before.
Then I, like how, that Vern
Larid character likes to say
it on video--
"oh, that was before Brian did
switchbacks." I went hey, whatever.
So I landed that.
I got a cheesesteak, and like,
everybody went crazy.
And then you look over, and
Anthony's, like, trying to do
a nollie tre-flip no spin or
nollie flipout no spin or
nollie flipout, or something
to make [INAUDIBLE]
But yeah, I don't--
we just separated.
That was it.
That was, like, the breaking--
That was, just ridiculous.
He claims-- there was something
in some magazine--
I remember, that we only had
skateboarding in common, but.
It's probably true,
but whatever.
ANTHONY PAPPALARDO: Yeah,
I don't know, man.
I think we just, kind
of, grew apart.
Like, you know, when you're
young, something like
skateboarding could just--
you know, you just have that
little thing that two people
do, and that you guys could just
grow and be, like, the
sickest friends, ever.
And it's just skateboarding,
you know.
But as you get older, it's,
like, you kind of get involved
in other stuff--
good, bad--
it doesn't even have to be,
like, other, you know.
And I think that's just, kind
of, what happened with us.
You know, I think at a point,
all's we did have was skating.
BRIAN WENNING: I don't know.
I don't know.
I could talk to him, now,
like, man to man, easy.
ANTHONY PAPPALARDO:
Is that swollen?
MALE SPEAKER 1: [INAUDIBLE].
BILL STROBECK: Everyone regrets
shit they do when
they're 16, you know.
He had, like, huge gear.
He was, like--
he looks totally different,
you know what I mean.
He grew out of that.
He was, like hip hop-- like,
he looked funny.
I mean, we all looked
funny back then.
We were young, you know.
He skated very conventionally,
then, you know what I mean I
think he was, like, doing what
he thought other people
wanted him to do.
I think that now he kind of does
what he wants, and that's
what makes him happy.
And I think that's fine.
MALE SPEAKER 2: By the time he
got to Mosaic, do you think he
was a different person than he
was from Photosynthesis?
BILL STROBECK: I feel
like around the end
of Mosaic, he was.
But people change every,
like, 10 minutes.
Like 10 minutes ago, I was in
my sweatpants in that bed,
right there, you know
what I mean.
He was, definitely, changing.
I mean, those years from like 16
to 24, people change, like,
significantly.
You're a kid.
You don't know what
you're doing.
You're trying things to
see what you like,
you know what I mean.
And then, eventually, down the
line, you know what you like.
AUDIENCE: Whoa!
BILL STROBECK: All his
friends that skated
don't skate no more.
He skated with Rob Pluhowski,
who has two kids and works in
fucking sanding wood all day.
What's up, Rob?
I love Rob.
Rob is one of my best
friends, man.
I haven't seen him in
a long time but--
we were real--
us three were real close.
Like, we were, like--
hang everyday.
MALE SPEAKER 1: Come on, Papp.
Get off of this.
ANTHONY PAPPALARDO: You
know, they were
just my friends growing--
like, since 15 on.
You know, in skating or outside
of skating, we could,
like, we could have a cup of
coffee and have a chat or
something, talk about
normal shit.
Rob always had a good
attitude of kind of
knowing this isn't--
and kind of trained
me, where--
I think it's a good mentality,
where people take this skating
thing too serious.
And it's, like, you're not a
fucking rock star, and like,
just, skaters have a problem
being, like, a realist, and
just, you know, it's
going to end.
And Rob always had a good level
head of, like, well this
isn't going to last forever.
So while we have off time, and
we're getting paid to do
nothing, you know, let's go to
Cook-- like, let's go do
something, and go on a road
trip or something.
And it was always fun.
It was cool.
ROB PLUHOWSKI: Philly
was dead.
It was just--
It wasn't--
there was-- it was just dead.
I felt like I needed a
change in my life.
So I always wanted to
live in New York.
And Anthony was--
he's always--
You know, he's from
Long Island.
He came up there with me.
We got an apartment together.
We lived together.
It was great That was a
good year of my life,
living on 1st and 10th.
And then things started
to change, and,
like, I had a kid.
And I had to do what
I had to do here.
And then I got kicked
off of Habitat.
You know, then I started to
realize that skateboarding
wasn't for me, you know,
in the long run.
I would skate with them
everyday, kind of.
You know, I think when I left,
it was, kind of, like a last
friend on the team, you know.
It's like, Anthony is a really
down to earth guy, you know
what I mean.
He's like, there's
no ego involved.
There's no, like--
He just wants to go skateboard
and have a good time, you know
what I mean.
He, just, enjoys his
time, there.
And you get in a van and you go
on a trip, and within five
minutes, like, dudes, they
won't stop talking about
themselves.
ANTHONY PAPPALARDO: Hey man,
it's a great company.
It's, like, at one time, I
think, when I first got on
Alien, it was heavily East
Coast and had all those
influences and those people
behind it and style and ideas
and aesthetics.
And I think that did die
out, you know, and
I don't think it's--
And I don't know who to
say if that's a good
thing or a bad thing.
It just, that's what makes
it just skating.
And It's just--
I'm sure there's tons of kids,
you know, in California, that
love Alien now, that
didn't like it, you
know, when it was more.
So it's just, like, who's to say
that it was better then,
but I think it was more of an
East Coast vibe, at a point,
like one of those older
types of teams-- like
Rick and those dudes.
You know, you'll catch them
all skating together in
California.
BILL STROBECK: I feel like--
I mean, dude, he was
Workshop forever.
I mean, he had the tattoo.
He had a Workshop tattoo,
you know.
I don't even know if
he still has it.
I think he does.
It's right on his wrist, but--
And then, you know, Alien
changed, but like, it was like
that, dude.
It was, like, then all these
new dudes got on.
Anthony got in Chocolate
right after that.
It was like, seriously, like,
I feel like a couple months
after that, he was just, like,
you know, I'm on Chocolate.
ROB PLUHOWSKI: I don't know.
You know, Anthony just wanted
to be with dudes
that kind of, like--
you know, like Mike Carroll,
Rick Howard.
You know, they went out and
skated and had a good time,
came home--
like, did their own thing, had,
like, a little family
feeling thing going on.
But at Workshop at that time, it
was kind of like, everyone
was out to be number one.
He was, like, you know, I just
need something changed,
something more me.
You know what I mean?
Something more--
more, his style.
ANTHONY PAPPALARDO:
So this is it.
You guys made it over here.
No one's really seen it to
this level in a while.
Everyone, kind of, when I first
got it, people came over
here and were, like, what are
you going to do in this
dungeon, just be by yourself
like you always do?
And it's just like-- no, no,
like, I'm going to fix it up
and do what I want to do
and, like, make stuff.
[SAW RUNNING]
ANTHONY PAPPALARDO: This
stuff's beautiful.
It looks like a painting,
almost, you know.
But it's just like skating-- you
know, you just get older.
And it's like skating can--
you want it to, but physically,
your body doesn't
let you do what you
want to be doing.
And it could frustrate you, and
you could put that energy
into something totally negative,
which is sad.
I think a lot of people in
the skateboard world do.
Or you could try to
do something.
I don't know what's cooler.
I don't know, you could
try to make something,
and do other stuff.
That's pretty much
what this is.
Yeah, I mean, woodworking and
just trying to make stuff--
you know, if this is what I'm
going to be doing for the next
50 years, I don't know.
You know, it's keeping
me busy, now.
I really enjoy doing it.
And like I said, it's, like,
East Coast Pro, it's like, I
mean, you see it.
It's a lot of downtime,
not skating.
You know, you piss away
a lot of free time.
And I think I just hit a point
where that free time was
killing me.
I couldn't do it anymore.
I needed a place or something
to make myself feel like I'm
doing something productive when
I'm not skating, instead
of, you know, sitting at
the bar or something
or watching TV or--
which I, you know,
no hard feelings.
You know, to each their own, but
I just know, as a personal
thing, where I was at a year
or two ago, I just needed
something more than just numbing
myself out when I was
done skating.
You just have to
keep it going.
TED BARROW: I guess I met
Pappalardo in late 2003, when
he moved to New York.
I don't know, you know, like, on
one hand, like, you sort of
have a preconceived idea.
You know, like, you think about
dudes that skate for
Alien, and you think of, like,
Van Englen and fucking Kalis
and people like that.
And they're, like, sort
of intimidating.
So you've got to think like a
kid from the East Coast that
came up skating in Philly,
essentially.
Like you know when you see his
first couple parts, like, he
might be kind of a dick.
He definitely was a lot more
down to earth, it comes to
meeting him, you know.
I mean, every interview where
people are talking about the
Lakai video, they're like, oh,
there's such this, like, big,
long expectation.
Everyone's hopes are so high,
like, blah blah blah.
Like, I'm sure he doesn't
respond to that at all.
Like that's the last thing
he wants to think about.
And so like, probably
woodworking or whatever he's
doing off the board is probably,
like, in some ways
therapeutic, or it's just,
kind of, keeping him
grounded, you know.
BILL STROBECK: Anthony's
just like, not--
I feel like he's just not
gung ho about it.
Like I don't feel like he,
like, wakes up and, like,
"fuck, dude, I got to, like, go
out and backslide 360 flip
tailslide on this ledge, right
now." Like I think he does
what he thinks looks
good, and it's not
about impressing anyone.
It's not about impressing
anyone at all.
It's kind of just being
true to yourself.
AUDIENCE: Woo!
ROB PLUHOWSKI: Yeah,
he doesn't--
he's definitely not a spotlight
person, you know.
He doesn't really--
yeah, it, definitely, frustrates
him, for sure.
You know, he doesn't like people
caring or even wanting
to care about what he's up to.
He's just to himself,
you know.
He's just a normal person,
who just--
he's good at skateboarding.
And people might say, hey, you
know, what's Anthony doing,
what's he up to?
Like, he's out skateboarding
in Brooklyn somewhere.
You know what I mean?
Maybe he's by himself.
Maybe he's with Bill, you
know, I don't know.
MALE SPEAKER 1: Is that
asphalt all right?
TED BARROW: I had to go to
Williamsburg early in the
morning on a fucking Sunday,
8:00 in the morning.
I rode my bike over the bridge,
and I get a text from
Pappalardo, like 15
minutes later.
And he's, like, riding
your bike over the
Williamsburg Bridge?
And I was, like, what
are you doing up?
And he's like, "killing it."
Like, where the fuck was he?
Like, I don't-- you know, what
was he doing at 8:00 the
morning on a Sunday?
TY EVANS: Like, the root of
skateboarding has, and always
will be, fun.
And making skate videos, you
definitely have to put in
work, and it takes the
fun aspect out of it.
You know, we've got to go
[INAUDIBLE] this, we've got to
go write this up.
We've got to go here.
We've got to do that.
And skating's not like that.
You know, skating's like, what
Pappalardo's part's about.
It is about going out
your door and
skating down the street.
I don't think you'd ever see
Papps skating like one of
those makeshift jump ramp
ledges, or something.
You know what I mean.
It's like, he skates, like, true
stuff that you would find
just lurking around.
Out of all the parts in the
video, look at Papps' part,
and it's the most
true to skating.
It's the less contrived part out
of everything, you know.
And that's what makes Papps'
part stand out, you know,
aside from the fact that it's
all on the East Coast.
You know, that's the totally
raw, pure form of skating.
That's, basically, the
equivalent of jumping out of
your front door and
skating something.
MALE SPEAKER 2: Do you think,
like, the vibe of Fully
Flaired or the vibe of, like,
the rest of the team had
anything to do with him not
skating for Lakai anymore
after that?
TY EVANS: No.
I mean, I don't know if it's
common knowledge, but that was
going on before the video
was even over.
You know, it's like--
I think the one thing about
Lakai is that there's so many
good guys on there, they all
deserve to have shoes and
these great deals.
And I don't care what company
you are, it's like, how do you
support 19 pro shoes?
That's a huge salary.
You've got to be, like, the
swoosh or the three stripes to
support some shit like that.
You know, and I'm sure when
Papps was filming his part, he
knew, like, I'm just going to
get through this Lakai fucking
thing, get through this beast,
and then I'll get on a shoe
company and pay some bills.
Like you know, I think it's
great that someone like Alex
and Papps can go and live
a little bit more
comfortably, you know.
You know It's not affecting
their positions on
Chocolate or Girl.
I think, like, what Federico
was saying, like, you know,
it's pretty cool that, like,
everything just kind of worked
out, you know.
BILL STROBECK: Like, he's
doing all right.
He's doing good.
He's stoked.
And out of everything, I think
leaving Lakai was a
good thing for him.
I think it was like, you know,
Rick and Mike left their,
like, companies, you know, when
they're younger, like, to
try their own things and
to see if they like it.
I mean-- and they seem to be
doing well themselves, so.
Hmm.
He seems to be like
the forefront--
like, he seems to be, like, the
dude at Converse, you know
what I mean.
So that's, like, a good thing,
you know, because he's like,
oh, I want this shoe,
like, I can get it.
You know what I mean?
Like, I can tell them I
want this in suede--
I want this, like,
and it's there.
You know, they're super
down for him.
MALE SPEAKER 2: Is Converse--
they get behind this
kind of stuff?
ANTHONY PAPPALARDO: Yeah,
they were psyched.
They were, like, the initial
people that helped me out with
the space and getting the space
going, and then pushing
me to do some more
of this stuff.
And that's a good feeling
to have, you know.
Not just like, "send me your
footage tape for 30 seconds of
footage."
And you know, they know I'm
skating when I'm skating.
And in here, I'm not trying
to fool anyone, or--
it's a really good
relationship.
And I think some of the first
20, 25 people, like shops and
stuff that kind of order
Converse, and just shops in
general that carry the product
and back it will get, like,
one of these benches
or something.
We're trying to work
something out.
Not like the dudes
at the skate shop
give a shit, but whatever.
If I'm not skating,
I'm in here.
It used to be the bar, so yeah
I'd rather just come here and
just play around, and try
to make something.
Yeah, cocobolo is really
interesting.
This stuff's really cool, like
this spalted maple--
like, I want to do a huge table
of just this stuff.
Yeah, my grandfather gave
me a lot of stuff.
He was an electrician, and he
always did this as, kind of,
like a hobby, as well--
kind of woodworking
and anything craftsman.
He would just--
he, like, built his own
house, type of guy.
So he gave me a lot of his old
stuff to play around with.
And it was actually cool.
He came over here about
a month ago.
And he's, just, like the guy
that you can never get a
reaction out of, and he
was, like, proud.
It was cool.
Stray.
MALE SPEAKER 2: Stray's
the friendliest dog.
ANTHONY PAPPALARDO:
Friendliest dog.
MALE SPEAKER 2: She looks like
Santa's Little Helper, but the
black version.