new droppings weekly tuition here with
george
their red noses and noises
with no ordinary circuit academy meeting
hate with hate really hate was lost
the colorful come have a message dated
met peter i
if you guys looked really to enter the
rally buchanan defense of white hair all
over the country made rather nomad ten
or just like around here the one deluxe
money counter protesters at saturday's
national socialist movement and klan
rally outnumbered the visitors climbed
to one
answering champion white power with
the white power
and white flour kenneth city council
anticommunist existed rate being happy
helping bata
one of the other signs said wife jalan
but it's also a lot
question no
offutt but the uh... at first it was
like
on this issue
with the closer today to make the nazis
mike that's not really how it's going to
have historically
uh... but then by the
to wipe our school and is supplied
flower
at that
with the truth
and eaten totally countless their
mission
they may be neo-nazis look
rediculous absolutely and and and and
looks a little embarrassed in that fight
it you know when they were met with the
counter protesters so i thought that
that was a great way to handle the
situation instead of getting violent and
getting loud and angry just make fun of
them
and in the hands of the new nazis lovely
clones and
and but the sad class yet not even close
having fun with white flour
that you know is that this is their
alike
stone colour
personally for catalyst
events so and that's the
the problems like from other side
it with the word