we will start by attaching a slip knot to the crochet hook
take the loose end, wrap it over the main strand, take your loop
wrap it over the main strand
put your hook below the center strand, back up the opposite side
this creates the slip knot
the multiple is six, we will be working chains in increments of six
that's the first set
one...two...three...four...five....six
that's the second set
I will be working, two extra chains
I can get it to work with with one or two
some times the amount, the plus amount does not  matter, the two extra chains will be the plus amount
I'm going to work the first
single crochet
now i'm skipping one, two chains, in the third chain
I am putting my hook right below the chain
below these two loops
and i'm working five
double crochet
putting my hook right through the chain
like that
working the second
there will be five double crochet in each shell
working the third, fourth
fifth double crochet
this is showing how to do the basic shell which is five double crochet
you can modify it however you want to
we will skip, one, two chains
work a single crochet in the third chain, just like that
this is what it looks like
i'm going to skip one, two more chains
work another series of five double crochet
which is called the shell, all in the same chain
we will skip one, two chains
in the third chain, work a single crochet
skip one, two chains
in the third chain
will be working our last shell which is
our third shell
five double crochet in the same chain
skipping two chains
working in the last chain
working last single crochet
and we've completed for a one
will be working this show
in a single crochet
so i'm going to change
that will be my step up
and i'm going to work
double crochet
use too
now i'm going to point out
that you are going to come across
some written instructions the way you
scene three
walls that's why i like
if you prefer to use it
you're welcome to use that instead
now we will skip one
and working right through the top of the
state
putting my foot through right like that
wrecked the arnold
the single crochet
which is the first part
single crochet and working five
double-crossed
if this will be a full shell
so we will have
implement the great food the single
crochet working tall
double crochet in the same
that completes degree
put your foot through the third stage
and putting it right below these two
moves
working the single
novus get to mars
working in the single crochet
double crochet
sket two stitches
breakfast nook round shape in the third
will work three double crochet
and that completes wrote
just closer together down here at the
bottom
is sparkling
berga larger crochet
go back down to a smaller crocs
row three
double crunchy
joel crochet we just completed
put your cookbook
where casino crocheting
cruciate in the next single crochet
to double crochet
work a single crucial
single crochet
sket two double crochet
brick a single crochet break through the
top of the third
approaching
and that's working in the center of the
stitch
you may hear call
in the center of the next
work five double crochet
in the next single crochet
sket two stitches
we're casino crush
double crochet
and this is what we have to prove three
rooms
growth for her
intern
work three double crochet
in the single crochet
work a single crochet through the next
double crochet
work five democrats
skip to democracy
work a single crochet
double crunchy
will be no sound
that completes wrote for her
profile
chain one
bertha single crochet
double crochet
single crochet
stitch because they're democrats
it's going to be this one because
crochet
that's number three
ditches so the center is going to
just work in the center
workout cracked
but the next separate stitches
work five double crochet and the next
single country
work a single crocheting
skip to stitches work fire
double crochet
single crochet
work a single crochet
double functioning
this is what we have proof i've grown
will continue repeating
for the length of the project
works six additional chains
the with my conclude