DAVID CHOE: Day 14 on
"Thumbs Up," our
cross-country adventure.
We're in the Big Easy.
We're in New Orleans.
Caught a ride late
last night out of
Lake Providence, Louisiana.
We want to just--
I guess it's exactly one
year after Katrina.
I'm sure you see this shit on
the news all the time, but I
want to see it for myself, so
we're going to walk over
there, check it out, and try to
find a decent bowl of gumbo
and then get the fuck
out of Dodge.
All right, we're here
with Thomas.
THOMAS KING: King.
DAVID CHOE: Thomas King?
He's from, uh-- where
you from?
THOMAS KING: New Orleans.
I'm on Ninth Ward.
DAVID CHOE: Let's see.
Ninth Ward.
We're--
we're about to head over that
way just to check it out.
You think two Asian guys will
be all right walking around
the Ninth Ward?
Yeah,
THOMAS KING: Yeah, man.
I mean, y'all would
be straight.
All y'all gotta do is, you know
what I'm saying, keep
your head up and look for, you
know, you gotta keep your eyes
open, you know what I'm saying?
'Cause ain't no
telling what might happen,
you know what I'm saying?
Right now, like I said,
it's hot and
everybody wants something.
Everybody hungry, ain't got no
money, they hurting out here.
And they'll jack you quick, so
you just got to be careful.
You know, just watch yourself.
DAVID CHOE: All right.
Hey, thank you so much
for talking with us.
THOMAS KING: Oh, for sure.
Y'all be cool.
DAVID CHOE: All right.
Thanks.
So this is where the levee
broke, and then all these
houses got blasted.
But I guess they fixed it now.
Everyone wants to come out
to New Orleans to party.
And it's just sad.
Talked to a fellow today in the
restroom while I was in
the bathroom, and he said the
heart and soul of the city's
gone, and it'll never
come back.
And now all the scavengers
and pirates and--
it's the Wild West out here.
I can't believe this
is America.
Hi, David.
TIARA: Hi, Tiara.
DAVID CHOE: Tiara?
We're just traveling
cross-country, and we just got
to New Orleans today.
And I mean, I mean,
I'm pretty much--
I don't know what to say.
I can't believe it.
But you're-- you're from
the Ninth Ward?
TIARA: No, I'm really from the
Third Ward, but I stayed back
[INAUDIBLE].
I just really came back here
when my brother and my cousin
got shot in Houston.
DAVID CHOE: Your brother and
your cousin are from here?
TIARA: Yeah.
DAVID CHOE: They
went to Houston
after Katrina and they--
TIARA: Got into with them people
out there, and they
killed them.
DAVID CHOE: Who?
TIARA: I don't know the boy's
name, but my brother's named
Vincent Williams and my cousin
named Yolanda Stiles.
DAVID CHOE: And they
both got shot?
TIARA: Yeah.
DAVID CHOE: And are--
are they OK? or--
TIARA: No, they passed.
They passed away.
DAVID CHOE: Oh my goodness.
So what's the situation now?
I mean, it looks
like there's--
TIARA: It's really terrible
out here.
It's terrible.
DAVID CHOE: I mean, what--
TIARA: It's bad.
It's not really fit for
people to come back.
DAVID CHOE: So, so
why did you?
TIARA: 'Cause my mama wanted
to [INAUDIBLE]
'cause where we stay
at, it's kind of
straight, and then it ain't.
DAVID CHOE: So roots is here,
you stay here, home is here.
TIARA: Home is here.
DAVID CHOE: Even if it's
bad like this?
HARRY KIM: Who are
your neighbors?
TIARA: I don't really
have neighbors.
I don't really have neighbors.
DAVID CHOE: So it's just you?
Just walking around the
street by myself?
TIARA: Yeah, fixin' to
go to the bus stop.
DAVID CHOE: We're up
in the Third Ward.
We're gonna hang out
with these guys.
So I'm Dave.
BLING BLING: I'm Bling Bling.
DAVID CHOE: Bling Bling?
This is Harry.
BLING BLING: Bling Bling.
DAVID CHOE: Tell us where
we're at right now.
BLING BLING: Oh.
MALE SPEAKER: You on Josephine,
heard me?
Uptown Josephine Third
Ward, you heard, we
doing it big out here.
We got a little grill going,
little [INAUDIBLE] on, little
food, you heard me?
This my dog Eddie right
here, heard me?
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
DAVID CHOE: Is that
the General?
The Third Ward General?
BLING BLING: Yeah.
Oh oh.
DAVID CHOE: The General is
cooking all kinds of goodness.
The General definitely takes
care of his army.
They're fed well.
People are smiling.
Where are we?
This is the world?
THE GENERAL: Pretty much.
Out of all 50 states.
This state.
DAVID CHOE: Out of all 50
states, Louisiana, this is the
center of the world?
THE GENERAL: The center.
DAVID CHOE: This is the world.
THE GENERAL: This
is the epitome.
DAVID CHOE: I'll tell you
what, you're the most
hospitable, that's for sure.
THE GENERAL: I was born and
raised in Metairie, Louisiana.
I went to school with whites.
Asian, Indian.
Matters not the different.
The only thing my mother told
me about any individual is
when that person hits you?
You hit that person back.
She never taught
me about color.
Because they were
all my friends.
Yeah.
DAVID CHOE: What you got
in there, sausage?
THE GENERAL: Turkey
necks and sausage.
DAVID CHOE: Turkey necks.
THE GENERAL: A little celery.
That's delicious.
Josephine, Third Ward clique.
That's where we're at.
HARRY KIM: New Orleans.
DAVID CHOE: See you
guys later.
Josephine Third Ward clique.
MALE SPEAKER: Uptown.
HARRY KIM: Uptown.
MALE SPEAKER: Uptown
Josephine.
DAVID CHOE: Uptown Josephine.
HARRY KIM: Uptown.
DAVID CHOE: Third Ward.
HARRY KIM: Third Ward.
DAVID CHOE: Third Ward clique.
Third Ward.
MALE SPEAKER: [INAUDIBLE].
Y'all be cool.
[INAUDIBLE].
DAVID CHOE: Third Ward.
MALE SPEAKER: Byyyye!
HARRY KIM: Bye!
DAVID CHOE: By far the most
at home I've felt
on this entire trip.
By far the best food I've
had on this entire trip.
Unbelievable.
I'll always remember.
We'll always have a home here.
Take it all the way Miami.
Be there hopefully
by tomorrow.
As the sun sets over the
Big Easy, we head home.
And hopefully get to the
Atlantic Ocean by tomorrow.
Pretty much had the most
amazing experience
of the trip so far.
I can't believe how nice these
people were and how delicious
the food was.
The sauce--
I don't know what
was in there.
Spicy as fuck.
Got all the sinuses going.
Delicious.
But as the sun sets over New
Orleans, we head, hopefully,
on our last leg of the race
towards the east, and
hopefully soon, these mosquito
bite-ridden, diseased,
sunburned toes will get to
touch the Atlantic Ocean.
HARRY KIM: [LAUGHS]
DAVID CHOE: Is it cool
of we film the ride?
MALE SPEAKER: Film the ride?
DAVID CHOE: Yeah.
How 'bout--
MALE SPEAKER: See y'all
[INAUDIBLE],
I said wait a minute.
DAVID CHOE: How about just
a "fuck yeah, Miami."
MALE SPEAKER: Fucking
right, Miami.
That's where y'all from?
DAVID CHOE: No--
MALE SPEAKER: Hey, Miami, I'm
a coon-ass from the south,
from right now!
Yeah!
Fuck me, I'm on Medicare.
Hey, how you like me now.
You gotta be on Medicare if
you don't drink and drive,
right, you guys--
DAVID CHOE: Oh, no, that's
the American way, man.
MALE SPEAKER: That's right.
DAVID CHOE: That's
the American way.
Every single person that--
MALE SPEAKER: All right, well
I'm going to be St. Louis,
Mississippi.
Where are y'all Americans
are going?
DAVID CHOE: Everyone that picks
us up is drinking and
they have broken windshields.
That's like, you have
to pick us up.
Anything else you want to say?
Anything else you want to say.
MALE SPEAKER: Man, hope you all
fucking best of luck, man.
DAVID CHOE: Thank you so much.
HARRY KIM: Thank you.
MALE SPEAKER: I'm going to
hell if I don't pray.
Y'all coming with me?
[ALL LAUGH]
DAVID CHOE: Thank you so much.
MALE SPEAKER: Hey, man, nobody
ever fucking filmed me before
in my life.
DAVID CHOE: Well, anything
you want to tell us?
Anything you want to say?
MALE SPEAKER: Hey babe,
y'all be careful.
I love y'all--
DAVID CHOE: No, tell us
something about yourself.
MALE SPEAKER: I'm crazy.
I'm going to work
in the morning.
And that's the American way.
DAVID CHOE: Yeah?
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
DAVID CHOE: Thank you
so much, man.
HARRY KIM: Thank you.
MALE SPEAKER: Shit, I'd give
you a ride anywheres y'all
want to go but it would
my pocketbook.
I probably--
I got enough gas to
make it to my job.
That's the American way, bro.
I'd seen y'all three poor
motherfuckers on the side of
the road, seen y'all with a
camera, said, wait a minute,
what the hell's going on?
[ALL LAUGH]
DAVID CHOE: Well, thank you
so much for the ride.
MALE SPEAKER: All right, bro.
DAVID CHOE: Go easy
on that, and--
MALE SPEAKER: Oh, yeah, I'm
going to my job right now.
DAVID CHOE: Hey, stick to soft
porn and soft drugs.
Soft porn and soft drugs.
Stay off the hard stuff.
MALE SPEAKER: I just
smoke weed.
DAVID CHOE: Barbecue!
Hell, yeah.
Let's take a look at this.
MALE SPEAKER: Hey,
that's coon ass!
DAVID CHOE: What is this?
This is coon ass barbecue?
Oh my god!
HARRY KIM: Oh god!
Oh my god.
DAVID CHOE: Thank you.
You want a bite?
Take a bite.
MALE SPEAKER: Coon-ass!
DAVID CHOE: Coon-ass
American barbecue.
I love you, man.
I love you.
MALE SPEAKER: Y'all
be careful.
DAVID CHOE: All right.
[HORN HONKS]
MALE SPEAKER: Let me
get out of here.
DAVID CHOE: So here we are
in Theodore, Alabama.
And I was in the Pilot getting a
drink and taking a piss, and
I noticed this guy Jerry
moping around.
And I noticed the jail tattoo,
got a cross right here.
And the skulls--
the skulls, that's that?
Treasure chest.
Seahorse, that's hard-core.
Jerry just told me something
very strange.
He said he's locked up.
He's in jail.
JERRY: In prison.
DAVID CHOE: But obviously he's
not locked up 'cause he's here
talking to me, so what's--
JERRY: I'm on a-- we have a work
release program in the
penitentiary.
There's one in Mobile.
This is like the Mobile area.
And we get to come out and work
during the day and at
night and stuff.
When we get paid, they
get all our money.
It really sucks.
DAVID CHOE: And then you
gotta go back to jail.
JERRY: Yeah, I gotta
go back tonight.
DAVID CHOE: So if you don't
mind me asking,
what was the crime?
JERRY: DUI.
DAVID CHOE: DUI?
JERRY: Yeah, too many.
You get four DUIs,
it's a felony.
DAVID CHOE: Wow, you
like to drink.
JERRY: Yeah, I like to drink.
DAVID CHOE: How was-- so prison
doesn't seem that bad.
Is it horrible?
JERRY: Well, until you
get to where I'm at,
it's kind of horrible.
I've been locked up
for three years.
DAVID CHOE: With a DUI?
JERRY: Yeah.
DAVID CHOE: What are you
not telling me, Jerry.
JERRY: Oh, I mean for real.
DAVID CHOE: Three
years for DUI?
Then you really like to drink.
JERRY: I got a 10-year
sentence for DUI.
DAVID CHOE: Wow.
10 years.
Don't drink and drive.
What is the biggest problem day
to day that you face while
you're in prison?
JERRY: Money.
DAVID CHOE: Money?
JERRY: Yeah.
They take all your money.
DAVID CHOE: So you work here.
JERRY: And they get it.
DAVID CHOE: And they
take 90% of it?
JERRY: 40% and then 25%
for restitution.
DAVID CHOE: So you get like
a dollar an hour.
JERRY: I get like, let's see,
$30 out of $100, maybe.
HARRY KIM: Fuuuuck.
DAVID CHOE: Well, did you
learn you lesson?
JERRY: Oh, yeah, I've learnt
my lesson, no doubt.
DAVID CHOE: Can I buy you
a drink right now?
JERRY: I'm fine.
No more drinking.
HARRY KIM: Not even
on your time off?
JERRY: Not even on
my time off.
DAVID CHOE: I totally don't
believe you, but all right.
All right.
So let's talk--
we're drifters.
We're on the road.
We're hitch-hiking.
JERRY: OK.
DAVID CHOE: Let's make
a run for it.
JERRY: Naw.
DAVID CHOE: Come on, man.
JERRY: That's escape.
DAVID CHOE: Yeah, you got
seven more years.
Fuck this, man, let's
go to Miami.
JERRY: No, let's
don't do that.
DAVID CHOE: Let's go
to Florida, man.
JERRY: Let's don't do that.
DAVID CHOE: All right, Jerry.
You're no fun.
Let's escape.
Come on, man.
JERRY (LAUGHING): No way.
DAVID CHOE: Let's get the
fuck out of here, man.
JERRY: I got to get
back to work, man.
Nice meeting you.
DAVID CHOE: Fuck work, man.
C'mon, Jerry.
Let's get out of here.
JERRY: I can't do it.
Good luck.
DAVID CHOE: We're here in
Alabama at the dog park.
We're only gonna be through
Alabama 'cause it's this big,
where we're going
through, the 10.
Theodore, Alabama.
The dog races.
Santa's little helper.
It's fucking on.
I'm ready for my trifecta.
Superfecta.
Today's is day 15
on our journey.
We're somewhere in the
panhandle of Florida.
We're trying to get to Miami,
and look at what we found.
Fellow drifter, fellow
train-hopper.
FREDDY: Right.
DAVID CHOE: Used to jump
the train all the time?
FREDDY: All the time.
DAVID CHOE: So during all your
years of train-hopping, what's
the craziest thing
you ever seen.
FREDDY: I seen [INAUDIBLE]
I seen sexual acts
on the train.
I seen-- oh, man.
DAVID CHOE: What--what did
you see on the train?
You saw--
FREDDY: Oh, I seen a lady
give a man a blow job
DAVID CHOE: On a--
FREDDY: On the train,
the train ran along.
I seen 'em cooking
on the train.
They have their pots and
stuff for cooking.
DAVID CHOE: Wow.
FREDDY: You sees a lot of
wild stuff on a train.
DAVID CHOE: But you haven't
done it in a while?
FREDDY: No.
I ain't in shape--
I'm a old man now.
I ain't quite the shape
I used to be.
DAVID CHOE: How was that
blow job, though?
FREDDY: It wasn't on me,
but I'll say, I'll say
it aroused me, huh?
I was sitting there listening,
I'm listening,
you know what I mean?
It ain't embarrassing.
I'm sitting their listening--
DAVID CHOE: Hey, man.
If you're hopping trains and
there's people getting blow
jobs, wouldn't you want to hop
the trains all the time?
FREDDY: No.
Not really.
DAVID CHOE: Hey, what
do you do--
last question.
What do you do when you're, you
know, you're on the train
and you gotta do number two?
FREDDY: Boo-boo there and
throw it out the door.
DAVID CHOE: You boo-boo there,
and you throw it out the door.
Throw it out the door.
Thanks, Freddy.
FREDDY: Yeah, man.
DAVID CHOE: Wish us luck.
FREDDY: I wish y'all
luck, man.
DAVID CHOE: Whew!
All right, Florida.
It's a lonely road.
So we just got a ride in, uh--
I have no idea where we are.
Somewhere in the panhandle
of Florida.
And the trains are very
sporadic, so we might just
hitchhike to Miami.
If we could catch a train,
that'd be great, but if not
we'll just thumb it out.
Thumbs up, America.
Fucking love you.
MIKE: Hey.
DAVID CHOE: What's your name?
MIKE: Mike.
DAVID CHOE: Mike, I'm David.
This is Harry.
We're just going
cross-country.
This is our 15th day.
We came all the way from LA.
We're hopefully going to
hit Miami tonight.
We're tired, dirty.
MIKE: 15 days, you just
come from LA?
DAVID CHOE: Yeah, hitchhiking,
hopping the trains.
So we're tired, dirty.
You know.
MIKE: You look like you can
use a couple shirts.
DAVID CHOE: I mean, I don't--
if you got it, that
would be great.
We smell really bad, but I don't
want to trouble you.
MIKE: Yeah, man.
Here, let me give
you something.
DAVID CHOE: Are you serious?
MIKE: Yeah, hang on.
Here, he's one.
You like pink?
DAVID CHOE: Hey, we'll
take whatever.
MIKE: There you go,
there's one there.
DAVID CHOE: Oh, thanks, Mike.
HARRY KIM: Thanks a lot, Mike.
DAVID CHOE: Take care.
Thanks for the ride.
Wow.
You want pink or orange?
HARRY KIM: I'll wear
the pink one.
DAVID CHOE: All right.
Thank you.
I guess one size definitely
fits all.
Best shirts ever.
Wow.
HARRY KIM: I guess we'll
sleep warm tonight.
DAVID CHOE: Oh my god.
Oh my goodness gracious.
We're definitely, definitely
going to get rides in these.
HARRY KIM: Huaahhh.
DAVID CHOE: I don't know if
they'll be the rides that we
want, but we'll definitely
get rides in these.
HARRY KIM: Yeah.
DAVID CHOE: Thumbs
up, America.
We love cats and flowers
and butterflies.
HARRY KIM: [MEOW]
DAVID CHOE: So we just got
dropped off by Mike, and then
this bus pulled up
right behind us
with a bunch of workers.
I don't know where they're going
to work, but they just
stopped and a bunch of them got
off to use the restroom.
And Jacinto, our cameraman
that is very fluent in
Spanish, asked them
if we could have a
ride and he said yes.
And now we're on the bus.
Hola.
I'm not sure exactly what
happened, but somewhere in the
panhandle of Florida, we got
on a bus and I think we're
somewhere near Miami.
We got on a bus that was
predominantly farm workers.
They're tomato farmers.
And the boss said if we worked
for free he might give us a
ride closer in to town.
So off to make salsa.
Thumbs up, America.
We made it.
We're in Miami.
We went from the Pacific
to the Atlantic.
Well, America, we did it.
Here we are in the beautiful
Atlantic Ocean on Day 16 as
the sun comes up.
But I gotta tell you, boy, do I
got a lot of words for you.
I mean, I have a lot of--
I got a lot of mixed
emotions right now.
America, you're like the bossy
know-it-all, you're like the
kid I want to beat up.
You're like--
I want to like--
you're like the half-sister that
I want to fuck, or the
actual sister that
I want to fuck.
You're like, you're like my
ex-girlfriend that I want to
duct-tape and shit
on her chest.
But like I fucking love you and
I hate you and I want to
like slap you and I want to
dry-ass-rape you, but then I
want to like pet you and cuddle
with you and like dry
hump you and like cuddle with
you and spoon you and hold
hands with you.
I love you and I hate you and
I have very mixed feelings
toward you, but I feel like
I'm gonna cry right now
because it has been one of
the most amazing American
adventures ever.
Every day I woke up, I had no
idea what was going to happen,
and it was just--
the people are so crazy and
so diverse and so--
the good, the bad and the
ugly, it's all American.
And I'm really sad 'cause I'm
gonna be home soon, and it's
gonna be, like--
16 days to trek across this
country, through land, ocean,
lakes, rivers, cars, trains,
automobiles.
And then we're just going to
fly back in five hours, and
tomorrow morning I'm
gonna wake up.
I know exactly what I'm gonna
eat for breakfast.
And it's just going to be like
hitting a brick wall.
But America, Dave and Harry
are on the road.
We're here, we're there,
we're everywhere.
Who knows where you'll
see us next.
HARRY KIM: The romance
is back, America.
DAVID CHOE: We love you.
HARRY KIM: We love you.
DAVID CHOE: No matter how many
harsh things you said to us
and no matter how many bad
things we've said to you, in
the end, we forgive.
HARRY KIM: We love.
DAVID CHOE: We--
we love.
We're full of so much love.
We forgive.
We forget.
And it's-- tomorrow we go to
sleep and we wake up and it's
just a whole new day.
And--
HARRY KIM: Au revoir.
DAVID CHOE: Thumbs
up, America.
We love you.