This is a variation of something
he taught me
over 25 years ago.
The old is forever new.
And chances are he'll have no
memory that he taught me this
25 years ago.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
STEVE SPANGLER: I'm
Steve Spangler.
And I'm all about making
science fun.
For the last 20 years, I've
been teaching ways to turn
ordinary science experiments
into unforgettable learning
experiences.
I have an amazing team who will
do whatever it takes to
affect the way people
think about science.
And to do that, I live by one
motto, make it big, do it
right, give it class.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
STEVE SPANGLER: Oh, here he is,
my first chemistry teacher
ever, the amazing Doug Houdus.
DOUG HOUDUS: Hi, Steve.
How are you?
Geez, where is--
I thought you said we
were having lunch?
STEVE SPANGLER: Yeah.
And I thought you were going
to be here two hours ago.
Did the home, the nursing
home bus not pick
you up on time or--
DOUG HOUDUS: Well,
what day is this?
STEVE SPANGLER: Thank you.
DOUG HOUDUS: OK.
I thought this was Thursday.
STEVE SPANGLER: Oh my god This
is going to be a long taping.
Here's what I'd like
you to do.
I have got a new demo for you
that I thought it would be fun
to show you.
DOUG HOUDUS: Oh, excellent.
STEVE SPANGLER: I just made it
a little bit bigger in size.
So, here, watch this.
So it uses an Erlenmeyer
flask.
DOUG HOUDUS: Yeah.
STEVE SPANGLER: And of
course, safe science.
DOUG HOUDUS: Oh, you
always have to
have your safety glasses.
STEVE SPANGLER: Put your
safety glasses on.
Isn't it weird that I'm
now telling you this?
Isn't that strange?
DOUG HOUDUS: I think
it's great.
STEVE SPANGLER: All right.
So here's what we're
going to do.
There's fire, and then
there's a balloon.
So instead of doing
the classic way,
this is a water balloon.
Got it?
DOUG HOUDUS: Uh-huh.
STEVE SPANGLER: So the object is
to put the water balloon in
the bottle.
DOUG HOUDUS: OK.
STEVE SPANGLER: So here's how
we get the water balloon in
the bottle.
We have to have paper here.
So you can light the
paper on fire.
I know you're pretty
excited about this.
But you get to be in
charge of this.
OK.
DOUG HOUDUS: Wow.
I love fire.
I--
STEVE SPANGLER: In today's
day and age, this
is how we make fires.
This is--
DOUG HOUDUS: We don't
need a match.
STEVE SPANGLER: This is a little
stick that you squeeze,
like magic, fire comes out.
All right.
So you're ready?
So light it up.
DOUG HOUDUS: You really
want to get a good,
good flame, like this.
STEVE SPANGLER: Yeah.
There you go.
So a good flame that
goes down inside.
Nice.
DOUG HOUDUS: Put
that in there.
Oh, perfect.
STEVE SPANGLER: So this
goes here like this.
DOUG HOUDUS: Oh, look
at it vibrate.
STEVE SPANGLER: All over
the [INAUDIBLE].
Good.
Here it goes.
All right.
Come on baby.
Come on.
[POP]
DOUG HOUDUS: Oh, wow.
STEVE SPANGLER: Yes.
That's good, huh?
DOUG HOUDUS: That's
really good.
STEVE SPANGLER: Because
it's visual.
It's huge for an audience.
DOUG HOUDUS: Yeah.
It's bigger.
I never had a flask like this.
Where did you get a
flask like this?
STEVE SPANGLER: Actually, from
your lab, so that's why you
didn't have a flask like that.
DOUG HOUDUS: Yeah.
STEVE SPANGLER: You know, right
before you retired--
DOUG HOUDUS: I was
just wondering.
STEVE SPANGLER: --obviously,
that came to you.
Now it's mine.
DOUG HOUDUS: I was wondering
if we could do it--
STEVE SPANGLER: When
you had your--
DOUG HOUDUS: -- the old
traditional one.
STEVE SPANGLER: -- that's
all you had.
DOUG HOUDUS: Yeah.
But I think everybody would like
to see the traditional
one with the egg going
into the bottle.
Is that possible?
STEVE SPANGLER: It's
pretty easy.
You just take an egg and
put it in the bottle.
DOUG HOUDUS: Ohh, no, no, no.
STEVE SPANGLER: How
hard is that?
DOUG HOUDUS: What I want
you to see is this.
And don't take your
eyes away from it.
I want you see that egg actually
going bla, la, loo,
loo, loo, a little fluttering.
STEVE SPANGLER: How
does that go?
DOUG HOUDUS: Bla, la,
loo, loo, loo.
Can you do that?
STEVE SPANGLER: No.
I can't.
DOUG HOUDUS: [INAUDIBLE].
STEVE SPANGLER: OK.
And what is the fluttering
action that we're seeing?
DOUG HOUDUS: Well, let's
actually see
how this takes place.
STEVE SPANGLER: All right.
DOUG HOUDUS: And then we want
do the experiment of course
first and the explanation
second.
STEVE SPANGLER: You
know what this is?
This is a fuse--
DOUG HOUDUS: Yeah.
STEVE SPANGLER: -- so that
you'll get going with this.
All right.
DOUG HOUDUS: Gotta
get it going.
OK.
Now watch this.
STEVE SPANGLER: Good.
Good.
[POP]
DOUG HOUDUS: It didn't
flutter.
STEVE SPANGLER: It didn't?
There was a little
bit of flutter.
I saw that.
DOUG HOUDUS: No,
there was not.
STEVE SPANGLER: Video will
show there was a little
fluttering.
DOUG HOUDUS: Watch this.
STEVE SPANGLER: Good.
[GROWLING SOUND]
[POP]
DOUG HOUDUS: It didn't
flutter.
STEVE SPANGLER: It didn't?
There is a little
bit of flutter.
I saw that--
DOUG HOUDUS: No,
there was not.
STEVE SPANGLER: Video will
show there was a little
fluttering.
And I liked your way
of getting it in.
So, again, just as
a quick review.
The hot air that was inside,
as soon as you put the fire
that goes down inside,
you now have all that
air that heats up.
As the air heats up, just as we
saw with the balloon and a
little bit with this, you
see the air escaping
from the very top.
Then when the fire goes out,
that warm air inside begins to
cool, contract.
And the outside air pressure
pushes the
egg into the bottle.
DOUG HOUDUS: Well, the
gravity, also,
because the egg has mass.
And why I was trying to
get a little bit more
fluttering in there--
STEVE SPANGLER: Did you just
say gravity to me?
Yes, the egg will fall
into the bottle.
But don't you think the air
is pushing it in more than
gravity is pulling it down?
Here let's see how well--
DOUG HOUDUS: Yeah.
STEVE SPANGLER: --
gravity works.
DOUG HOUDUS: Wait.
STEVE SPANGLER: Let's just sit
here and wait for gravity.
Hmmm.
Wonder how well gravity
is doing?
DOUG HOUDUS: No.
STEVE SPANGLER: All that
gravity is pretty good.
DOUG HOUDUS: No.
Yeah.
You were right.
STEVE SPANGLER: Doug, I got
another way to put the egg
inside the bottle.
It's the upside down
egg in the bottle.
DOUG HOUDUS: No,
it won't work.
STEVE SPANGLER: It is.
Watch this.
DOUG HOUDUS: No, un-uh.
STEVE SPANGLER: So new
Erlenmeyer flask.
DOUG HOUDUS: OK.
STEVE SPANGLER: Got it.
And let's find an egg this time
that actually seals all
the way around.
All right.
DOUG HOUDUS: [INAUDIBLE].
STEVE SPANGLER: So why don't
we look and see if this--
DOUG HOUDUS: OK.
STEVE SPANGLER: You just want
to make sure there's a seal
all the way around.
OK.
Perfect.
In fact, that would
be even better.
OK.
So now watch.
So now instead of putting paper
inside because you got
to warm up the air inside.
You--
DOUG HOUDUS: Absolutely.
STEVE SPANGLER: -- want
the air to escape.
So now we just simply
put birthday candles
down inside like this.
DOUG HOUDUS: OK.
Got it.
STEVE SPANGLER: So here's a
little birthday candle.
And here's your birthday
candle.
DOUG HOUDUS: Can I light
it this time, Steve?
STEVE SPANGLER: Yes.
DOUG HOUDUS: All right.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK.
Here we go.
Ready?
DOUG HOUDUS: All right.
STEVE SPANGLER: This
goes over the top.
Watch how it works.
It's here like this.
DOUG HOUDUS: So we're going to
heat that air up inside again.
STEVE SPANGLER: [INAUDIBLE]
air like this.
Watch.
See the fluttering?
DOUG HOUDUS: [INAUDIBLE]
the air.
STEVE SPANGLER: Watch
when it goes out.
It's going to go out.
DOUG HOUDUS: Yeah?
[POP]
DOUG HOUDUS: Amazing.
STEVE SPANGLER: Ta-da!
DOUG HOUDUS: So the
air heated up.
STEVE SPANGLER: Upside down
egg in the bottle.
Pops up.
You could actually feel
the little fluttering
that's going on.
DOUG HOUDUS: So I guess maybe
it's just the air heating up
instead of the gravity
doing it.
STEVE SPANGLER: I don't think
gravity has anything to do
with this, Doug.
It's not--
DOUG HOUDUS: [INAUDIBLE].
STEVE SPANGLER: --
a gravity thing.
Why did you say gravity?
DOUG HOUDUS: I just wanted
to say gravity.
STEVE SPANGLER: I don't know
why you would say gravity.
DOUG HOUDUS: I [INAUDIBLE]
STEVE SPANGLER: We got
to get the egg out.
DOUG HOUDUS: OK.
STEVE SPANGLER: And the way
you get the egg out is you
just take a knife, and you kind
of cut it up inside--
DOUG HOUDUS: No, no, no.
We don't want to do that.
That's not a scientific
way of doing it.
Remember, we had a decrease in
air pressure, OK, and that
made the egg actually fall in or
get sucked into the bottle.
Now we want to is just
the opposite.
STEVE SPANGLER: I'm so proud.
That's exactly what was on the
script, and he remembered.
DOUG HOUDUS: We're both going
to blow into the bottle.
STEVE SPANGLER: Right.
DOUG HOUDUS: And we're going to
create extra air in here,
extra air pressure--
STEVE SPANGLER: So you push
the air that's in here.
DOUG HOUDUS: -- and that's
going to blow it out.
STEVE SPANGLER: Yeah.
And then air comes out.
DOUG HOUDUS: But what happens
if we get the egg caught in
our throat?
STEVE SPANGLER: I don't know.
You choke.
DOUG HOUDUS: Yeah.
But does anybody in here know
the Heimlich Maneuver?
STEVE SPANGLER: Oh, I do.
DOUG HOUDUS: Yeah.
But you'll be doing the egg.
STEVE SPANGLER: I'll help you.
DOUG HOUDUS: OK.
STEVE SPANGLER: I've
got your back.
DOUG HOUDUS: OK.
You got me back?
STEVE SPANGLER: Yeah.
DOUG HOUDUS: OK.
STEVE SPANGLER: So
you're ready?
This is a race?
DOUG HOUDUS: Yeah.
Wait.
Three, two--
STEVE SPANGLER: OK, I say,
three, two, one, go.
OK?
Ready?
Three, two, one, go.
[SWOOSH]
STEVE SPANGLER: Oh, perfect.
And this is my egg right
out of there.
The most amazing thing that
can happen along the--
oh, oh, I'm sorry.
DOUG HOUDUS: Ahh.
Ohh.
Oh, my own student
saved my life.
Oh, I am so thankful you
were here, Steve.
You are my hero.
Give me five.
Oh.
STEVE SPANGLER: I think
it's going well.
Here's what I'm afraid.
In all the kind of having fun,
that we might have missed the
actual science behind this.
So let's do it again using what
people would normally
probably use.
DOUG HOUDUS: [INAUDIBLE].
STEVE SPANGLER: In fact, I have
to tell you that this
technique was really shared by
Don Herbert, so Mr. Wizard
shared it with me in about 1997
or 1998 at Sacred Heart
University when he was
doing a presentation.
He said that over the years
that he found that a water
balloon worked even
better than that.
So I made this water balloon.
Of course, it's bigger, and it
would be impossible to push it
in the bottle.
One of the reasons why
is because there's
air inside the bottle.
So when you push down like this,
you can't get it down
inside the bottle.
DOUG HOUDUS: You're
forcing the air.
STEVE SPANGLER: Correct.
So the object here is this, is
if we use the fire here like
this, and we heat it up, as
you heat up the air, the
molecules will move away
from each other.
It forces the hot air out.
That's the fluttering that you
said that you saw before.
And then when it cools down, as
soon as this goes out, you
see, it cools down, the air
contracts, and the outside air
pressure kind of pushes
down inside.
DOUG HOUDUS: That air goes
up 30 miles, and
it's pushing down.
STEVE SPANGLER: Tremendous
amount.
And the other secret here is
sometimes I'll get this a
little wet just so that it will
slip past here a little
bit easier.
DOUG HOUDUS: That's an
[INAUDIBLE] idea.
STEVE SPANGLER: That's kind
of what's going on there.
You handle the fire.
DOUG HOUDUS: I will.
STEVE SPANGLER: And we'll
do it together.
Ready?
DOUG HOUDUS: All right.
STEVE SPANGLER: So
this goes in.
We're going to get this burning
pretty well because we
need to have that fire
down inside.
And you'll actually see
the fluttering here.
So this goes in.
DOUG HOUDUS: We want
to heat up that air
inside really good.
STEVE SPANGLER: So listen,
hear the fluttering?
[BANG]
DOUG HOUDUS: Whoa.
Wow.
STEVE SPANGLER: Bam.
Isn't that a great one?
DOUG HOUDUS: That
is excellent.
I think much more dramatic.
STEVE SPANGLER: Now the kicker
here is getting it out.
Using the egg, you can
kind of blow in and
kind of get it out.
But I have not found good
success this way.
And it's fun to have people
try to do it like this, so
it's almost like a bet.
DOUG HOUDUS: Oh, yeah.
STEVE SPANGLER: Can you
get the balloon out?
DOUG HOUDUS: You're creating a
slight vacuum back here when
you're doing that.
STEVE SPANGLER: Right.
So I could say, I'll give you
$20 if you can get the balloon
out of the bottle.
DOUG HOUDUS: How about $100?
STEVE SPANGLER: How about $20?
All right.
So how would you
do that, Doug?
DOUG HOUDUS: I think if you had
something like a straw,
you could actually put it
along the side here.
STEVE SPANGLER: Look at what
your star student has.
DOUG HOUDUS: Wow.
STEVE SPANGLER: A straw.
DOUG HOUDUS: Where did
you get that at?
STEVE SPANGLER: Watch this.
So here we go.
We push this down
here like this.
DOUG HOUDUS: Yes.
STEVE SPANGLER: All your--
[SHHHHH]
STEVE SPANGLER: Did you hear
that little shhhh there?
DOUG HOUDUS: Yes.
STEVE SPANGLER: So now watch.
If we stick a straw down
inside like this.
OK.
And this is here.
DOUG HOUDUS: Ahhh.
You're going to avoid that
vacuum creation, huh.
STEVE SPANGLER: So now if we
pull like this, we should be
able to let the air come in
and the balloon come out.
[POP]
STEVE SPANGLER: Ahh.
DOUG HOUDUS: Don't you
just love science?
STEVE SPANGLER: Isn't
that good?
But there's something
you need to know.
You don't have to use fire to
get the egg into the bottle.
Here's the solution, 320
degrees below zero.
So we had heat.
This time why don't we
go to extreme cold.
And this is perfect.
So this is our bath of
liquid nitrogen.
And unlike using the other
bottles that we were playing
with before, you have
to use an Erlenmeyer
flask for this one.
Got it?
DOUG HOUDUS: That's because
it won't crack.
STEVE SPANGLER: So here's what
we're going to do with this.
If we got it hot on the first
time, and it forced the air
out, and then when it cooled
down, the outside pressure
pushed it in, why don't we start
with the air at room
temperature, put this on top,
and submerge it in here, get
it cold, and see if the
contraction will allow that to
push it in?
DOUG HOUDUS: So we're going to
see if some of those molecules
will actually come a
little bit closer,
creating a partial vacuum.
STEVE SPANGLER: All right.
You're ready?
This goes on top
here like this.
And now we put it in the liquid
nitrogen like this.
Make sure that we've
got a good seal.
It's getting colder.
Doug, it's working.
DOUG HOUDUS: It is.
STEVE SPANGLER: Bam.
DOUG HOUDUS: Excellent.
STEVE SPANGLER: That is
how to get the egg--
DOUG HOUDUS: Very, very cool.
STEVE SPANGLER: --
in the bottle.
Isn't that cool?
DOUG HOUDUS: Yeah.
STEVE SPANGLER: Sticking
to the bottle.
[BANG, BANG]
DOUG HOUDUS: Yeah, it is.
Maybe because it's cold.
STEVE SPANGLER: There
it is, bingo.
Here's a cool thing.
You could possibly get the egg
back out of the bottle.
You have to warm this
part of it up.
DOUG HOUDUS: OK.
STEVE SPANGLER: Do you do
pretty good clucking?
Can you go [CLUCKS LIKE ?
CHICKEN].
DOUG HOUDUS: Do I have to
scratch while I'm doing that?
STEVE SPANGLER: Can you do--
DOUG HOUDUS: [CLUCKS
LIKE A CHICKEN].
STEVE SPANGLER: Hold
on to this.
Hold onto this.
And just make chicken sounds.
Hold on right here.
DOUG HOUDUS: [CLUCKS
LIKE A CHICKEN]
STEVE SPANGLER: OK.
Hold onto it.
You can do it.
DOUG HOUDUS: OK.
We've got to warm this
up and increase the
pressure, right at this--
STEVE SPANGLER: Just
warm it up.
DOUG HOUDUS: Yeah.
STEVE SPANGLER: Use our hands.
Warm it.
DOUG HOUDUS: Yeah.
Use your hands.
STEVE SPANGLER: Come on.
Come on.
[CLUCKING LIKE CHICKENS]
DOUG HOUDUS: Maybe if I
scratch a little bit.
[CLUCKING LIKE CHICKENS]
STEVE SPANGLER: Come on.
Do it harder.
[CLUCKING LIKE CHICKENS]
STEVE SPANGLER: Ahh.
DOUG HOUDUS: It did--
[COUGHS].
STEVE SPANGLER: Isn't
that great?
Are you OK?
DOUG HOUDUS: Yeah.
I have a cold, see.
STEVE SPANGLER: This
is your lunch.
DOUG HOUDUS: Wait a minute.
STEVE SPANGLER: There you go.
There's your lunch.
DOUG HOUDUS: Thank you.
STEVE SPANGLER: Thank you.
DOUG HOUDUS: This is what
I came here for?
STEVE SPANGLER: Oh, guess
what I hear right now?
Beep, beep.
Oh, that's the bus.
The bus is here.
DOUG HOUDUS: Oh, it is?
Will I be going back
to the home?
STEVE SPANGLER: [SINGING]
The wheels on the bus
go round and round--
DOUG HOUDUS: [SINGING]
Round and round--
STEVE SPANGLER: Goodbye, Doug.
See you later.
DOUG HOUDUS: -- and the
wipers on the--
STEVE SPANGLER: Bye-bye.
DOUG HOUDUS: Bye-bye.
DOUG HOUDUS: See you again.
STEVE SPANGLER: Thank you.
I think that went pretty well.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
STEVE SPANGLER: Oh,
my goodness.
DOUG HOUDUS: It's on fire now.
It's still on fire.
STEVE SPANGLER: The [BLEEP]
are you thinking?
DOUG HOUDUS: Well, he said
he wanted a good fire.
STEVE SPANGLER: Yeah.
DOUG HOUDUS: I'm going to hold
this piece of [BLEEP]
in my hand--