It's funny, because Rick Howard
trips on Eric probably
just as much Stevie
Perez does, still.
He's just talented.
MIKE CARROLL: He's
like, one of the
greats, and it's longevity.
It's not like this one dude
who's fucking doing really
good for these last
three years.
He's been sick for 21
years or something.
He's just Koston.
[SKATEBOARDING SOUNDS]
PATRICK O'DELL: What's up.
Welcome back to Epicly
Later'd.
This series we're beginning
is about Eric Koston.
I think when you take a look
at the all-time greats in
skateboarding, there's
definitely Tony Hawk, Mark
Gonzales, Danny Way, Rodney
Mullen, Andrew Reynolds, and
right up there is also
Eric Koston.
It's undeniable that through the
last couple decades, he's
been far and above one of
the best skaters around.
Filmed some really
amazing parts.
And he's always not only ahead,
but ahead on skating
gaps, on hand rails,
and perfect style.
Just one of those unbeatable
skaters that everyone looks to
as one of the best street
skaters of all time.
And I'm super stoked
he's on the show.
It's kind of interesting, I
interviewed Meza, and at the
end of the interview, he was
like, you don't really know
much about Koston, do you?
And I realized, I kind
of didn't, other
than his skate tricks.
ERIC KOSTON: You
son of a bitch!
You're a fucking
PATRICK O'DELL: We get glimpses
at who Koston is, but
it's kind of tough.
It's like kind of an enigma
a little bit.
So we're going to go
over to his house.
We're going to go to
Girl Skateboards.
We're going to find some
people from his past.
The next couple of weeks, it's
all about Koston, one of the
best skaters of all time.
And I'm super stoked.
I hope you enjoy it.
ERIC KOSTON: That's
how she rides it.
That's how I learned how to
ride a skateboard too.
FEMALE SPEAKER: It don't
have brakes.
ERIC KOSTON: It doesn't
No, it does not have brakes.
FEMALE SPEAKER: No, it tips.
ERIC KOSTON: It tips.
It's very tipsy.
That's me.
PATRICK O'DELL: Which one?
ERIC KOSTON: That's
me as a baby.
PATRICK O'DELL: So you were
born in Thailand?
ERIC KOSTON: Yeah.
I was born in Bangkok.
My dad, he's American.
He was in the Air Force.
And then he met my
mom in Thailand.
He was stationed there, and
then eight or nine months
after that, we moved
back here.
I grew up in San Bernardino
because that's where the Air
Force Base was.
They got a divorce
pretty young.
And so that's the only place
she really knew.
TIM GAVIN: You know Eric's
from San Bernardino.
And San Bernardino's basically
just east of hell.
I think his dad split and he had
a step-dad or something.
And it was pretty
much the exact
scenario that I was living.
So that was another
connection we had.
ERIC KOSTON: This
is a good one.
Beautiful hair, look at that.
I could grow that
back out, too.
I was 12 there, wearing this
Lance Mountain shirt.
I got into skating because
of my older brother.
It was the mid '80s, and so
he was super into it.
It was '85, '86.
First board was a Gonz.
The one Gonz with the face.
Tail was already pretty
worn out.
It was like a hand-me-down.
Because my mom was like-- they
were not buying new shit.
I remember I used to push
around on my knee.
I remember somebody telling me
some horror story of somebody
else doing it and hitting
a crack and
smashing their teeth out.
That's what made me actually
stand up and push.
MALE SPEAKER: Do it again.
PATRICK O'DELL: Would you say
you were good right off the
bat at skating?
ERIC KOSTON: Not right off the
bat, but I guess I progressed
probably pretty quickly.
I remember just being freaked
out, like what if I
just don't make it?
What if I hook up and flip--
that's all you could think--
hook up and flip over
straight to my face.
And eventually I worked
my way up slowly,
gradually, to the top.
You know, finally like, oh,
that's all you had to do?
PATRICK O'DELL: So how did
you get sponsored?
ERIC KOSTON: I got sponsored
because Eddie Elguera-- he
lived in Redlands, which was
right next to San Bernardino.
And so we just ended up
meeting that way.
EDDIE ELGUERA: Slam-ola.
Slammy-ola.
ERIC KOSTON: Eddie, he was like
an OG vert and pool dude.
EDDIE ELGUERA: Ah.
Ooh, got to skate.
ERIC KOSTON: He was really good
on mini-ramps, and lot of
dancing on the coping.
He invented the frontside
rock-- or maybe
Duane Peters did.
It's still-- there's
controversy there.
I still think there's
some beef.
He invented the Elguerial, which
is kind of like going up
fakie, kind of a full
cab into an invert.
He was that mix of ripping
backyard pool guy, and still
skating vert as well.
EDDIE ELGUERA: When I got
connected with Eric, I was
doing a vert demo in Highland,
California.
And he lived in San
Bernardino.
So he was always
hanging around.
And they said, this guy
is just tearing it up.
[SKATEBOARD SOUNDS]
EDDIE ELGUERA: From that time,
we kind of hung out a lot.
I had a half pipe in my
backyard, a little mini-ramp.
It was just straight for hours,
filming, videotaping.
He was doing all
kinds of stuff.
He was just busting out.
So way back then, when he was
like 15 years old, he would
just do stuff like that.
And I think it helped him,
really, into street skating.
Just being able to do that stuff
on the mini-ramps, or
the vert, or transition--
helped him when he
went to street.
[SKATEBOARD SOUNDS]
EDDIE ELGUERA: Eric was
always tearing it up.
I'm telling you, he just had
that talent that you knew that
he was going to be great.
ERIC KOSTON: Yeah, I
was probably 14.
Eddie started giving me boards
from that point.
No, I didn't really
state like him.
I just skated with him.
EDDIE ELGUERA: Ohh.
[INAUDIBLE].
ERIC KOSTON: I mean what
I'd call it, a protege?
Or more of like a
mentor, I think.
EDDIE ELGUERA: Yeah,
do that puppy.
I used to flow him.
We used to take him to demos.
We used to go out and demo.
ERIC KOSTON: There was a demo in
San Bernardino, and Hensley
came, and Steve Ortega.
And I was just skating this
quarter pipe, just trying to
hometown hero it, little dude.
And skating with Matt Hensley,
it was like the most insane
dream session too by the way.
At that point, he was the
best, in my eyes.
Hensley was like the gnarliest
dude out at the time.
I guess after that, Hensley
had gone back and said
something to Mike Ternasky
about me as well.
So than Eddie told me that
Ternasky wanted to meet me.
EDDIE ELGUERA: At that time,
he wasn't sponsored.
I was trying to get him
sponsored, even with H-Street.
At first, they were like,
no, we're not sure.
We have a lot of guys
on the team.
I'm telling you, you
need this guy.
You need to get him on the team,
because if not, you're
going to blow it.
Because I'm telling you
right now, this guy
is going to be amazing.
TIM GAVIN: I remember when
we first met him.
We were just like talking to the
dude, and going, there's
no way this dude is getting
on H-Street.
I remember seeing the dude,
and he was this
nerdy-looking dude.
I was like, who the fuck
are these losers?
But for some reason, maybe it
was an Asian bond between us,
but I just went up to him and
tried to make the guy feel
comfortable.
There was a Castle contest
that same day.
We went to the contest.
First time I've ever seen this
guy skate, I was like, this
guy's unbelievable.
He was doing those 540 ollies
on the quarter pipe.
But he was fucking--
he was doing everything.
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah!
[CHEERS]
EDDIE ELGUERA: But then finally
they came around and
said, yeah, you know
what, you're right.
And then he just went from
there and got sponsored.
AARON MEZA: I first heard of
him in the H-Street video.
That's the first time anybody
heard of him.
And it was true, you kind of
got the idea that it was
Eddie's little protege.
His only footage is
in his driveway.
So this must be his
little buddy.
EDDIE ELGUERA: He really wanted
to be a professional
skateboarder, gave
his time to it.
Actually, I think, he quit
school and just was stating
all the time.
And I really wanted to
see him succeed,
because I saw the talent.
What was that?
ERIC KOSTON: Impossible
to nosepick.
EDDIE ELGUERA: I was the
director of a skateboard camp
in Wisconsin, Lake Owen.
ERIC KOSTON: Yeah, Eddie.
Oh.
Where'd that one come from?
EDDIE ELGUERA: I took him up.
He was one of the skate
instructors.
ERIC KOSTON: Sorry, camera.
EDDIE ELGUERA: All right,
come on, man.
Come on, now.
You need to make it or die.
Yeah, Steve.
I recently heard from some
guys that were campers.
And then they look back
now and say, man,
he was my camp counselor.
But he wasn't pro or anything
at that time.
But they knew that, man,
this guy, he's amazing.
I remember him doing ollie
impossibles down hand rails.
And it's like, people can't
even do ollie impossibles.
He'd be doing them
down hand rails.
He was doing stuff back then
that was just amazing.
It was just--
it was cool to see.
Yeah.
Killer footage.
Those were great times.
We celebrated his
16th birthday.
Yeah.
So it was kind of cool.
And I just took him under
my wing, in terms of--
just to be there for
him, in terms of--
maybe a father figure at
that time in his life.
It's OK, it's OK.
Hopefully I imparted some things
into to him that maybe
helped him to be who he is.
Yeah.
[INAUDIBLE]
amateur.
Super good.
I just believe sometimes, when
you have that person in your
life that believes in you when
nobody else believes in you--
not believe in you because of
what they can get out of you,
but believe in you for who
you are as a person.
I think that's important.
Whoo.
[SKATEBOARD SOUNDS]