(END VIDEO CLIP)
CARL AZUZ, CNN ANCHOR: That was seriously
one of the best I-reports segments I`ve ever
seen, so big thanks to the Coronado Quartet
for an awesome introduction on this Friday.
I`m Carl Azuz, we`ve got a lot to talk about
today: current events, cultural events, even
a couture event. We are starting with a political
crisis.
A leader who says he`s doing what`s best for
his country. Some of his people accusing him
of having too much power. The streets filled
with protests and violence. It`s happening
in the country that`s seen this before, in
fact, less than two years ago - Egypt. This
was the scene in Cairo on Tuesday. People
who support President Mohamed Morsi and people
who are against him fighting right outside
the presidential palace. At least six people
were killed, more than 670 were wounded. In
a speech yesterday, President Morsi spoke
out against the violence and said that people
responsible will be punished. Military tanks
in the streets of Cairo are just one sign
the tension is not going away.
Next up, we are moving to Asia and focusing
on North Korea. The country says that sometime
between December 10th and 22nd, it`s planning
to launch a rocket. But the North Korean government
claims that the rocket is for science and
research purposes. The thing is, if this launch
happens, it would involve the same technology
that would be used to launch a ballistic missile.
It would also violate a pair of resolutions
from the U.N. Security Council. The U.S. has
spoken out against this launch plan, it`s
also keeping an eye on it. Experts say this
satellite image shows increased activity at
the North Korean launch pad.
Let`s bring it back to the U.S and head to
Washington D.C. President Obama and U.S. House
Speaker John Boehner talked on the phone Wednesday.
If you`ve been watching our show, you probably
know what they were talking about -- the fiscal
cliff. Negotiations about this cliff and any
deal to avoid it involve two main things:
taxes and government spending. Today, Jessica
Yellin looks at one of those and compares
the plans from the two sides in the debate.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
JESSICA YELLIN, CNN CORRESPONDENT: In the
New Year, taxes go up on everyone, unless
Washington takes action. But the government
needs more money. President Obama wants to
get some of it from the top two percent of
wage earners. He wants to raise their tax
rate and limit how much they can deduct. The
White House says this will bring in $1.6 trillion
over ten years. Republicans say they`ll agree
to bring in more money, but not by raising
tax rates, in fact they want to lower tax
rates for everyone. Instead, they raise money
only by limiting deductions and closing loopholes.
Speaker Boehner says, this will raise $800
billion over ten years.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today`s first "Shoutout"
goes out to Mrs. Peterson`s social studies
classes at Richard Ira Jones Middle School
in Plainfield, Illinois.
What city is the headquarters of the U.S.
Navy`s Pacific Fleet? Here we go, is it San
Diego, California, Pearl Harbor, Hawaii, San
Francisco, California or Norfolk, Virginia?
You`ve got three seconds, go!
Pearl Harbor has been the U.S. Pacific`s Fleet
headquarters since February 1941. That`s your
answer and that`s your "Shoutout."
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: Today, the Pacific Fleet includes 180
ships, nearly 2,000 aircraft and 140,000 sailors
and civilians. It wasn`t quite that big in
1941, but the potential military might of
the U.S. Pacific Fleet led to what happened
71 years ago today.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
FRANKLIN DELANO ROOSEVELT: December 7, 1941,
a date which will live in infamy.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: President Franklin Roosevelt talking
about the Japanese surprise attack on Pearl
Harbor, more than 2400 Americans were killed,
more than 1100 others wounded, more than 300
air crafts destroyed or damaged, 21 ships
were sunk or damaged. The attack struck a
serious blow to the Pacific fleet, which was
Japan`s goal. It also led the U.S to officially
enter World War II the very next day.
Aimee Copeland, you may remember hearing that
name. In May, the 24- year old contracted
a deadly flesh-eating disease. Doctors gave
her a one percent chance of survival. Seven
months later Amy is out of the hospital, living
at home and planning to go back to school
and finish up her master`s degree. The disease
has taken its tall: doctors had to amputate
both of Amy`s hands, her feet and one of her
legs. She has prosthetic limbs and uses an
automated wheelchair now. She talked with
CNN this week about some of the struggles
she`s faces through all of this.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
AIMEE COPELAND, FLESH-EATING DISEASE SURVIVOR:
I have really hard moments, definitely. When
things aren`t, you know, going right or if
a lot of times I`m by myself, I can`t do something,
I can`t get to something. And I think it`s
really necessary to fully experience those
moments of grief, of just absolute exhaustion,
and, you know, to experience them, allow to
accept them, allow them to pass, and over
the horizon there`s always more sunshine and
more love, so you know, even in those dark,
dark nights of the soul, you know, we wake
up and it`s spring. So, I definitely am learning
as much as possible from those moments and,
you know, trying to heal, slowly but surely.
(END VIDEO CLIP): .
AZUZ: Absolutely amazing story, and absolutely
amazing person. All right, we want you to
think back for this next story today. What
was the coolest thing you ever brought to
school for show and tell? It doesn`t matter.
A seventh grader in Minnesota has you beat.
She showed up with Minnesota Viking starting
quarterback Christian Ponder as part of a
contest she won. Ponder certainly seem to
have a good time, and he had some advice for
the students.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
CHRISTIAN PONDER, VIKINGS QUARTERBACK: That
was like the coolest introduction I`ve ever
had in my life going through that longest
line of people ever. Looking back on this,
you know, seventh grade, how so important
that I thought I fit in, but who cares? What
is someone else thinking about you is not
going to determine how your life goes.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: It`s time for a "Shoutout"
extra credit. The Maccabees are involved in
the history of what world religion? You know
what to do, is it Hinduism, Buddhism, Judaism
or Daoism. Rewind that clock to three seconds
and go!
In Judaism, the Maccabees are central to the
story of Hanukkah. That`s your answer and
that`s your "Shoutout" extra credit.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Well, here is how that story goes: around
165 B.C. The Maccabees led a revolution against
Syrians who were oppressing the Jewish people.
Now after their victory, the Maccabees rededicated
the main temple in Jerusalem, and there`s
a light in the temple that`s supposed to be
lit all the time. Now, according to the story,
there was only enough oil for one night, but
the oil lasted for eight days. That`s why
Hanukkah lasts for eight days, and why the
Hanukkah menorah includes eight candles plus
one that lights them. This was a National
Menorah lighting from a couple of years ago.
This year, Hanukkah starts on Saturday night
and it runs until sunset on the following
Sunday. The word Hanukkah means dedication,
and the holiday is sometimes known as the
Feast of Dedication, the Festival of Lights,
or the Feast of the Maccabees.
We all know someone with a bad holiday sweater.
Some have reindeer on them, some have other
things, like this gem I got as a Christmas
gift last year and wore just long enough to
get the photograph taken. I`m sorry, Bab (ph)
it`s ugly. It didn`t come from 18-year old
Jack McCarthy, but a lot of people have done
their sartorially unsavory sweater shopping
with him. He`s kneaded up a stockpile from
trips to flea markets, thrift stores and yard
sales. If there`s anything pretty about this,
it`s the pretty big money they`ve made Jack.
And that may be why he doesn`t think they
are ugly in the traditional sense.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
JACK MCCARTHY: The more colorful, the more
- the more action, the more eyepopping things,
that`s our definition of ugly.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Well, at least now we all know what
to ask Santa for. And when you think of doing
that, visiting Santa, you might picture a
line of crying kids at a shopping mall. Well,
they were lining up here all right, but not
to sit on Santa`s lap, at least not without
a wet suit. Forget a clatter on the roof -- this
scuba center stunt is making a splash under
the waves in Texas. He needs a waterproof
list to check twice, and a tank full of oxygen
to keep those cheeks rosy. After all, nobody
wants a blue Christmas. And while some sea
Scrooges might say, scoo-bah humbug, I have
to admit, I laughed
when I saw him, in spite of myself.