SUROOSH ALVI: The next morning,
we headed back to
Lyari to meet up with the
infamous Uzair Baloch, the
most revered and most feared
figure in Lyari.
We're stuck in traffic
surrounded by squeegee punks
and monkeys.
Squeegee punks are
7-year-old girls.
Uzair Baloch's political group,
The People's Aman
Committee, was actually banned
by the Pakistani government
under anti-terror laws.
So now, all the posters
featuring his face are just
promoting Uzair himself.
We met up with our escorts from
the night before who had
promised us a tour of Lyari so
we could see for ourselves all
the good the Baloch brothers had
done for the neighborhood.
I don't understand why they
wouldn't just go into Baloch's
house because they know
where he lives.
The police want him so bad.
Why don't they just drive
it and get him?
SUROOSH ALVI: He bought
them off.
He paid off.
Everybody's so corrupt
in this country.
SHABAZ JAN: Yeah.
SUROOSH ALVI: A group of women
were protesting the latest
murder charge against Uzair.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
SUROOSH ALVI: It had
been four years?
ZUBAIR ASLAM: Four years.
SUROOSH ALVI: Since
he visited Lyari.
While Nabil Gabol, the
politician responsible for
Lyari, hadn't visited his
constituents in four years,
Uzair Baloch has positioned
himself as man of the people,
building sporting facilities,
and giving residents of the
slum access to some pretty basic
services, like water.
BASIM USMANI: There's was
no clean water until the
committees came here and they
put pipes in the underground.
And people come from all over
just to go to that pipe and
fill up buckets full of water.
SUROOSH ALVI: But we'd also
heard stories of the Baloch
brothers and their Peoples Aman
Committee extorting local
business owners.
But nobody wanted to
talk about that.
When they were willing to speak
on camera, they only had
praise for Uzair and Zafar.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
BASIM USMANI: Capture
our people.
SUROOSH ALVI: Oh, another
operation is starting?
Even though the police looked
like they were gearing up for
an assault, we crossed our
fingers and hoped that they'd
at least wait until our
interview with Uzair was over.
We've been informed
that the big
operation's happening tonight.
That there's going to be police,
the rangers, the army
coming in to try and get all the
criminals and kill them.
That should be happening in
about three or four hours.
And basically, they're
after this guy.
In the middle of the slums of
Lyari was the Baloch's pimped
out compound.
With the police gearing up to
take Uzair out, it felt like
we were in the Pakistani version
of Scarface, but with
an empty swimming pool.
After our tour of the hood, it
was easy to forget that this
was the guy that the police
alleges is responsible for
Lyari's drug and gambling dens,
a kidnapping extortion
record, and a slew
of killings.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
SUROOSH ALVI: Our interview was
interrupted when a news
channel called Baloch and put
him on the air to make a
statement about the police
operation gearing up just down
the street.
While Uzair stomped around the
compound defending himself and
talking shit about everyone
else, we watched the interview
on live TV with his
brother Zafar.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
SUROOSH ALVI: With the police
operation apparently imminent,
we said goodbye to the Baloch
brothers and drove straight
over to hang out with the people
who were trying to
capture and/or kill them.
Camera crews were everywhere.
And who was there but
Lyari's most reviled
politician, Nabil Gabol.
Seems like something's about
to happen, right?
BASIM USMANI: Yeah.
SUROOSH ALVI: It's
got that vibe.
BASIM USMANI: It's
There's some electricity in the
air right now definitely.
SUROOSH ALVI: We heard
about you.
NABIL GABOL: Yeah.
And the reason is that I'm here
because of the law and
order solution here.
And people think that he has
become a noble [INAUDIBLE]
which is not true.
There are some criminal elements
which have created
again [INAUDIBLE]
solution here in Lyari.
So the government has decided
to wipe them out.
SUROOSH ALVI: If Nabil Gabol
was going to try and prove
that Lyari was safe by making
his first visit to his
constituency in four years, we
had to have a front row seat.
So we talked him into letting
us ride along with him.
NABIL GABOL: Your
door is open.
Because this car
is bulletproof.
SUROOSH ALVI: Good.
I'm happy we're in a
bulletproof car.
Accompanied by carloads of armed
guards and every news
crew in town, we headed
to Lyari.
NABIL GABOL: You might hear
some fire shots now.
This is so troubled area.
I have to get him out
on personal quest
because it's mean.
Anything can happen, you know.
So I don't trust Uzair.
I trust myself and
my pledge of God.
This was once a very
dangerous area.
And now we have decided
to get these cameras,
whatever the cost is.
I mean, I'm here on my life.
Anytime you can hear the rocket
launcher [INAUDIBLE]
SUROOSH ALVI: That's
good to know.
NABIL GABOL: So this is a
situation here in Lyari.
[NABIL GABOL TAKES PHONE CALL]
SUROOSH ALVI: And it's
a mafia style crime
syndicate here, right?
NABIL GABOL: It is big
mafia like once
there was in Chicago.
SUROOSH ALVI: Sure.
I mean, who are the top guys?
NABIL GABOL: The top was,
their name was Uzair.
He's a multi billionaire guy.
Money coming from
drugs actually.
They have their gambling
debt here.
They have their drug
dens here.
He has about a dozen murder
case, kidnapping, extortion.
SUROOSH ALVI: Against
him right now?
NABIL GABOL: Against
him right now.
SUROOSH ALVI: Wow.
NABIL GABOL: A dozen cases.
This came out, about 12
people from this area.
They have tortured [INAUDIBLE]
And they cut their nose.
They cut their hands.
And even they cut their
throat out so.
[SIRENS SOUNDING]
NABIL GABOL: Now see all their
shops are open here.
SUROOSH ALVI: Rocket launchers,
drug dens, cutting
people's noses off,
no problem.
As we drove through Lyari, the
streets were deserted.
But as the car came to a stop,
hundreds of Nabil Gabol
supporters suddenly appeared.
[MUSIC PLAYING, SIRENS
AND CHEERING]
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
NABIL GABOL: Gabol looked pretty
nervous being outside
of his bulletproof car.
Not surprisingly considering all
the enemies he has in this
neighborhood and the tendency
of other members of his
political party, the PPP, to get
assassinated, like former
Prime Minister, Benazir
Bhutto.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
SUROOSH ALVI: After a few
words with the local TV
stations and a few sips of his
milkshake, we were battling
our way back to the safety
of Gabol's car.
[MUSIC PLAYING AND
CROWD CHEERS]
NABIL GABOL: So now you see?
That [INAUDIBLE]
people for me.
SUROOSH ALVI: Yeah.
NABIL GABOL: So they're
not against me.
This is what impression, some
elements want to give.
SUROOSH ALVI: Back at police
headquarters, Gabol gave
himself a pat on the back for
his five minute visit to his
constituency.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
SUROOSH ALVI: He failed to make
any mention of the fact
that for all the hype of the big
police operation to wipe
out the Baloch brothers, Uzair
and Zafar remained
the bosses of Lyari.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
SUROOSH ALVI: Jahavis, that's
what they're hunting for.
The new gang in town.
MALE SPEAKER: Surrender.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[MUSIC PLAYING]