one can reach it
by immediately called bullshit they said
there's no way
there's a governor that's inside the
united states of america a hiking trail
we can find
date you can find was hidden away
look at it now in hindsight it looks
like lockhart of course it was one of
his route
the epidemic at that moment everybody in
the nation presently well you know it's
probably argument relevo rabino traveler
forum on the trail grammar errors
they have to accept everyday in
politician says
at face value
and i don't have to accept that ido bs
what i see it
of white separatist covered in bs
so
is this christ when he doesn't resign
but of course we found out that he had a
mistress in argentina and those who don
the visit but it gets worse
dat used
taxpayer blankets
this time google school career on are
aria first gold as a player in
weinberger frugal and spending taxpayer
money wisely
elisa for some using it
the enola played have sex with my
mistress
that he had to use it in that case women
an eight years earlier he had used
taxpayer funded
plane trips to go outside of his
mistress outcome
albrecht that mentioning
grant republics again
you know that this cloud
for impeachment of bill clinton he said
what clinton did ngos white that way and
lying about it
web reversible
he should be driven from office he
should resign
when he initiates resigned as governor
wouldn't take it
what he knew he had an affair he lied
about
so now he's back he's are in the first
district
is south carolina that is ed deeply
conservative district that is to discuss
former district he went to the senate
ten scott now the most conservative
under probably in all of the united
states senate
so who was uh... severed a runny sbc
just won the primary
he wound up being
curtis pasig fifty seven forty three
last night so here love you i mean just
elizabeth kolbert abortions of course
they would go bears
sister
now she's lady in the polls forty seven
forty four to credibly close
but we haven't had the campaign he had
and it is very conservative so it is
very likely
now mark sanford
could be back in the united states
congress
by the way did republicans seem at
rensselaer sanford
you know what he was in congress before
he was governor
he said onli firm believer in term
limits
three terms than i am out
except for when i come back it
he's going to force beyond the three
terms now
he's mark sanford
so uh... he's now of course
brown got so all this is ok
let's hear from
you know one thing that consist of into
this campaign is
to acknowledge the fact that that that i
feel back in two thousand nine
but there's been a lot of time since it
was a great sermon just uh... last
sunday
if the church that i can where he said
you know do the events in your life
refined or define your life and i think
that political opponents national enough
wanna make any event define your life
you know what i think we find whether to
you me or any of us out there will have
different events when we wish we could
have done things differently we wish we
could handle them better
but in fact they help us to read illsley
were finalized makers that much better
person maybe walk out into the the the
arena of politics a bit more humble than
we were before yachts also most
democrats eliot spitzer anybody we know
you're the well-intentioned dog
you're gonna camera because there's a
lot of family values
this guy was on family values
well you know there was a moment where i
slipped up you mean the moment where you
repeatedly went to argentina
have sex with your mistress and share
your white
acting iran on family values your entire
political here
all of those moments
but always with the republican and
surrounding the star began in terms of
care
anymore either
so how has this event
changed to as a as a public servant
changed you as a menu said
it might make you more empathetic
how would you be a better public servant
because of what you went through and
because of of this scandal
i think the do too many people in
politics who think that they know it all
uh... and i think that the project this
whole image of
of perfection
that the uh... the perfect family move
the perfect person the perfect fit
the reality is
none of us are perfect
and i think
the the sooner we recognize their inner
cells as a senator who we begin the real
conversations with other people
sentence every cell pastel questions
what is the white house correspondent
what the hell is that
how has this made you a better candidate
abadaka
officiant
leader of the peril
isn't even better
events in lawrence
we realize what brought you was all long
you should be asking that question not
happen
you know i was having sex with your
listeners
winds up i why am allows buccaneer
mistress make you a better candidate are
you kidding me
are you can get a little better get
and he turns around like
it's ok turns out i'm not perfect
on ocean mark
audino that or that there was a large
you're not perfect
all more than white welcome right back
in office
why do you ask him about them pa
cristiana peacemaker
a spending government money at this guy
was charged
we're taking a plane ride to get a
haircut
you think he cares about your money the
main thing is running out
it
yeah about your money
and he's about to use dot again he was
in the primary here is last night
and i think my god
um... of you know i used to cringe when
somebody would say okay i want to say my
god it was at that point okay this is
getting uncomfortable but what g_m_
relinquish the god's grace
encino reflected in others
you cannot stop
and stop for a moment a republican
knowledge that grades
oh also i think that is not
white people is about the on top of his
mistress the cab drivers lost combine
they got well you get out now so i can
you also tell our right
all used at night almost
but there's got again
well wonderful coincidence that it
since the founding
who wise this load of crap apparently
what was in south carolina
has it all believe in family values
either this is an excuse to haiti a
people when you have a guy
who cracked all his family values
destroyed his marriage
less distance behind
what do you say it all in all friend i'm
second chances might not have also been
but propaganda logs it year discussion
that quiet
he should be embarrassed
anybody want from a south carolina ought
to be embarrassed it should be
prohibited from advert measuring family
values again or let alone talking about
how their fiscally conservative
cuz you at the warm no such that it
by the way i had that executive director
of the staff of the republicans in south
carolina on young turks last night on
current television
we had this whole debate about that used
at the ad
he won a missionary is again
on on on my watch
and then i'm sure that all amazed event
mark sanford or porkers bostic never
polka nominee will will go back to
congress who will go to carve a
first-time but there's a live report was
just a value from one of the federal
accounting but dot please please again
not all over the issue at a real
otherwise out your naked argument
battle groups
her
don't like it was dealt a lot of
virginia parallel use don't match up
why is she got a publisher does on the
sign
is to go down in brazil thousands of
other people
this issue on a big don't accept
district so what about is the first
district debauchery orgies
unfaithful until spouse
the spending other people's money to go
get america's while those are those of
us is not about the versus rd a south
carolina
furqan outrageous man and by the way
just the rub it in your face you know
what marcia evernote he brought out his
mistress for his victory celebration and
by the way
on on morning shows twenty cent all i
know she was indeed a alok wat out
awhile anomaly will like
yet really possible at what time has
been tapped unto richard off course that
land that
you'll believe has got to say it
all right well watches mistress the
pampered
the
do buyers though
so has either put
and there's a lot of republican guys in
south carolina god you know might erode
my guess is is also the bill of women in
south carolina or like i do not care
you'd left your wife to be with that you
know woman right there high now you are
but in our face and
known for its own
what what was a elizabeth kolbert bush
you know that sounds pretty good