(END VIDEO CLIP)
CARL AZUZ, CNN ANCHOR: Hi. Welcome to a new
week of CNN STUDENT NEWS. I`m Carl Azuz. First
up today, a little history in the making:
four of these famous first were heading over
to South Korea. As of today, that country
has a brand new leader. Park Geun-hye is 61
years old. She won the presidential election
last December and by now you`ve probably guessed
why her win is historic. Park is South Korea`s
first female president. But it`s not the first
time she`s been connected to the South Korean
presidency. In fact, her experience around
this job started when she was younger than
all of you.
While the world may not know much about South
Korea`s first female president, the life of
Park Geun-hye and her family fill her nation`s
history books. Born into politics, her father
Park Chung-hee was described by some as the
country`s first dictator. He seized power
when the military took control of the government
in 1961. Park was just nine years old then.
Her father would rule South Korea with an
iron fist for the next 18 years overseeing
huge economic growth as well as human rights
abuses. Personal tragedy hit Park Geun-hye
while she was studying overseas in 1974. Back
in Seoul, her mother was shot dead by someone
loyal to North Korea. The bullet was intended
for Park`s father. The failed assassination
attempt drastically changed the course of
Park Geun-hye`s life. Her dreams of being
a professor were set aside. She had act as
South Korea`s first lady putting the nation`s
interests above her own. Five years later,
there was another assassination attempt on
her father. This time it was successful. His
intelligence chief shot him at a dinner party
saying he wanted South Korea to become a free
democracy. It was two decades later that Park
Geun- hye decided to return to the public`s
spotlight and launch her own political career.
And then last December, as head of the Conservative
Party, this 61 years old who never married
and doesn`t have children was elected president
with an overwhelming majority. One of her
major challenges as president will be dealing
with North Korea. She met the late Kim Jong-il
in 2002 in an attempt to end the bad blood
between the two families. Park Geun-hye says
she wants to resume talks with North Korea
and restart the aid program on the condition
that North Korea abandons its nuclear weapons
program. But after its third nuclear test,
analysts believe North Korean leader Kim Jong
Un clearly isn`t interested.
Heading to Japan for our next story. Engineers
there getting rid of an old hotel in Tokyo.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
(EXPLOSION)
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: But not like that. They`re trying a
different demolition approach. Say hello to
the incredible shrinking building. This hotel
is 40 stories tall, and engineers were taking
it away one story at a time. May not look
like much on the outside, but check out what`s
happening on the inside. The crews go floor
by floor using temporary jacks - those hold
up the higher floor while the workers take
out beams, support columns and debris. Then
the jacks lower what`s left and the crew moves
on. Why do it this way? That`s a lot quieter
than a standard demolition which keeps the
neighbors happy, and new chance of an implosion
damaging other buildings. It`s also more expensive
and it takes longer - in this case, and estimated
six or seven months.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: See if you can I.D. me:
you`ll find me in space about 93 million miles
from Earth. Also, I`m made up of different
gases. Astronomers consider me a yellow dwarf
star and I`m the closest star to your planet.
I`m the Sun. And the temperature at my core
is believed to be 27 million degrees Fahrenheit.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: So, the sun is hot. And what you`re
seeing according to NASA is an eruption on
the Sun surface. It`s set up a bunch of fiery
plasma, and that appeared to rain back down
in a circular ark. Look, how in comparison,
the Earth is so much smaller than this eruption
alone. The sun is thought to be about 109
times the width of the Earth. A couple of
other things here: this was recorded last
summer, and it`s sped up. Every second you
see is about six minutes of real time. Scientists
say the Sun`s magnetic field caused the plasma
to cascade in a circle. And fans of Adele
might appreciate how the Sun set fire to the
rain.
Yesterday, was the Daytona 500. We`re not
worried about who took the checkered flag
on Sunday. We`re talking about what happened
there on Saturday.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
TONY STEWART, NASCAR DRIVER: I`ve never seen
anything like that. I mean we`ve seen Petty,
you know, we`ve seen a lot of big ones here.
And I`ve been a part of a couple of big ones
here, but I`ve never seen anything like that.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: He`s talking about a wreck in the final
lap of a warm-up race. Sports come with risk,
that`s something Nascar drivers all deal with,
but not usually the fans. Some of the debris
from this crash flew into, over and threw
a protective fans. At least 28 people in the
stands were injured, some were taken to hospitals,
others were checked out by a medical staff
at the track.
It`s been about four months since the so-called
Superstorm Sandy hit the northeastern U.S.
People are still feeling the effects of the
storm, working to rebuild homes and businesses.
But it`s not just people who were affected.
Natural disasters can take a toll on the natural
habitat of animals as well. When that happens,
the creatures may be forced into new areas.
In the New York City, that`s causing some
problems.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Night descends on New
York City, and things can get pretty creepy.
And after Superstorm Sandy, even creepier.
Terry Riggio says the rat problem in her hard-hit
Lower Manhattan neighborhood exploded.
THERESA RIGGIO, NEW YORK RESIDENT: It`s crazy.
You come home from work, you see a rat. It
could be daylight, you see a rat. Your walk
your dogs past nighttime, you see rats frolicking
like they are playing like they are pets having
fun. It`s disgusting.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: When Sandy flooded subways
and tunnels, the theory is rats were literally
flushed out, forced to relocate and they`re
staying put. Traps to try and catch them dart
streets in Lower Manhattan where construction
has only compounded the problem.
Timothy Wong says, his pest-control company
is constantly trying to stock up on supplies.
TIMOTHY WONG, M&M PEST CONTROL: We even have,
believe it or not, for these really nice fancy
areas in Manhattan where they can`t use really
ugly base station, they have live rock base
stations where, you know, it looks like a
rock and you can`t tell, but inside there`s
actually a whole where the rats can go in,
where you can actually put poison in there.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Wang says his company,
M&M pest control has gotten more than twice
as many complaints about rats and mice compared
to a year ago at this time. It`s not what
the Health Department says it`s seeing. Saying
that while large storms can flush out rats,
they can also drown them.
JEFF WOODS, M&M PEST CONTROL: Some poison
up in the ceiling ...
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Growing numbers are not.
M&M exterminator Jeff Woods says he sees New
York in a whole different light.
WOODS: So it is three years of doing it, we
kind of get a - you`re always looking over
your shoulder.
WANG: It`s been keeping us busy. People`s
nightmare is really, you know, a good day
for us.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today`s "Shoutout" goes
out Ms. Flatebo`s class at Lincoln Intermediate
School n Mason City, Iowa. Which of these
is a measurement of the imperfections in a
diamond? Here we go, is it cut, color, carat
or clarity? You`ve got three seconds, go!
A diamond`s clarity refers to how many imperfections
the stone does or does not have. That`s your
answer and that`s your "Shoutout".
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Diamonds and people have imperfections,
but what Billy Ray Harris did when he found
a diamond ring was flawless.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
BILLY RAY HARRIS: What I actually feel like
is what has the world come to when a person
to return something that don`t belong to him.
AZUZ: Billy is homeless. He lives in Kansas
City, so does Sarah Darling. One day Sarah
gave Billy some change, and accidentally gave
him her ring, too. When Sarah came back, Billy
was ready to hand the ring back over.
SARAH DARLING: So, I just am so grateful.
RAY HARRIS: I could tell exactly how much
it meant to you the moment I held it up like
that.
(LAUGHTER)
DARLING: Yes.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Billy says, he acted the way his grandfather
who raised him would have expected, and wasn`t
looking for a reward. Sarah and her husband
started the fundraiser to thank Billy, though.
Their goal was to raise $1000. As of yesterday,
donations were up to $139,000 and counting.
Some friends of mine were debating this, if
they found $5 in the ground and no one was
around, they`ll probably keep it. But for
something as valuable as a ring, they`d try
to find its owner or at least a lost and found.
What is the cut off? Join in today`s blog
at cnnstudentnews.com.
We`re going to wrap things up today with a
little friendly teasing. The frog is a little
odd, but that`s not what this Youtube clips
are about, it`s about how the dogs react.
Some flip out, some are confused. What they
do seem to know is that it sounds exactly
like one of their squeaky toys. Unfortunately
for them, there is no chance the dog sinking
their teeth into this thing, which means there
is no danger of the frog croaking. We`re going
to end with that ribbitting story. Teachers,
don`t forget to visit out page and give us
your feedback on today`s show. We`ll hop back
tomorrow with more CNN STUDENT NEWS.