WINSTON SMITH: [INAUDIBLE]
later.
THOBEY CAMPION: Pleasure
to meet you, Thobey.
WINSTON SMITH: Thobey,
good to meet you.
Yeah, that's it.
It's like awesome, two worlds.
THOBEY CAMPION: Thank you.
So this is it?
WINSTON SMITH: Welcome
to Grant's Tomb.
We're right under
Grant Avenue.
So this is mainly my work that
I've had up for a show, and
then I generally pull curtains
across so people don't have to
look at my chaotic
studio part.
I was born in Oklahoma.
Then when I was a teenager, I
had the brilliant idea to go
to art school.
And went to study Renaissance
art in Florence.
My mom's a painter and
a sculptress--
really talented.
And I didn't, unfortunately,
inherit her skills.
I can sketch and draw, if I
wanted to, really well-- but
usually too much effort.
So it's easier to cut
up other people's
drawings and use those.
And I kind of discovered
the medium of collage.
Before there were photocopy
machines, I
would make my own drawings.
And then realized if I cut them
I could mix them together
and come up with really
absurdist compositions that
were startling.
And once I did see a photocopy
machine, I
think Xerox or Olivetti.
In Italy we had Olivetti.
And that kind of changed
everything.
Because you could rearrange
pictures together, photocopy
it, and it would make them
all look like one unit.
At that time, and for a long,
long time afterward, whenever
I would present this work or
composition, especially for
commercial work like
illustration for a magazine,
the art directors would say
well, it's not a painting, and
it's not a photograph,
so what is it?
So I'm trying to create
instant surrealism
that you could get.
I could take a bunch of
completely normal things and
put them together and
they're not right.
The [INAUDIBLE] one time said
you take things that are all
wrong, put them together and
suddenly make them right.
That's a piece we used
for a Dead Kennedy's
record in the middle.
Mowing down the people, it was
on the inside of a record.
THOBEY CAMPION: Do you ever have
brushes with the law or
calls from authorities about
any of your work?
WINSTON SMITH: No I think I'm
either so much under the radar
or they probably figure oh,
let him keep doing that.
That way he won't cause
any real trouble.
He's just an artist.
THOBEY CAMPION: A lot of
articles talk about you coming
back to the States after
being away for six
years or so was a real--
WINSTON SMITH: Culture
shock, yeah.
When I first arrived in America,
I had two friends who
lived here, one who
lived in Boston--
New York and Boston, he moved
to Boston-- and then one
friend who lived out
in San Francisco.
The part of Boston I
lived in was right
by the Charles River.
The shock was that there were
TV cameras everywhere.
Not just at banks and office
buildings, but at donut shops.
And these little cameras would
follow you around.
And like son of a bitch,
it's like Orwell.
THOBEY CAMPION: So you
were in Boston then.
And then how did you get
over to San Francisco?
WINSTON SMITH: I hitchhiked
across the country.
San Francisco was
full of energy.
It's a small city, it's only
seven miles across so you can
walk around.
In fact, there was a bus strike
for a couple of weeks
and I did have to walk around
everywhere to find anything.
Where I would up working was
like a rent a roadie joint
working for different bands like
the Tubes, Crosby, Stills
and Nash, Santana, Journey.
A bunch of other local bands
would come in and perform at
our sound stages.
I did run into lots
of interesting
people in that industry.
And it was right just before
punk rock had begun to rear
its ugly head.
THOBEY CAMPION: So what year
span are we talking right now?
WINSTON SMITH: '76 and '77.
A lot of places wouldn't book
punk bands at that time
because of too much trouble.
The insurance wouldn't cover the
place if the windows got
broken or someone got hurt.
And that's why punk rock,
I think, was born.
Because so many people who
didn't want to perform were
kind of pissed off that all
there was was these giant
stadium bands.
All there was was just big
show business stuff.
And punk rock was about no, just
get up on stage in the
corner of someone's room in
a basement someplace.
San Francisco was more
of an art movement
for the punk scene.
Because there were people who
were artists that couldn't
play anything, but they'd
perform and
they'd have an act.
Usually it was funny or it was
absurd, it was something
interesting.
THOBEY CAMPION: You mentioned in
some interviews about that
time and the spirit that infused
the music and the art
was kind of resemblant
of Dadaism.
WINSTON SMITH: Totally.
Advertising here doesn't take
the form so much of TV ads, or
radio, or billboards--
it's posters.
And we had the opportunity
because people have to walk
around to put posters or
propaganda for a band, or for
anything really, on the walls
that you'd have to see if you
were waiting for the
bus service or
walking down the block.
Sometimes I'd see these
and I'd think
well, I could do that.
I don't think I can do better,
but I could do
something like that.
And I didn't know a lot of the
people in the current scene
that was coming up.
I didn't know people in bands.
So I just made up my own punk
bands and put up posters for
like The Twits--
nonexistent bands.
There was no Kinko's then, you
had to go to the Rexall and
put a dime in the thing.
Or we'd go to the public library
and there's be a
Olivetti machine or
a Xerox machine.
You could do whole
'zines at Rexall.
One of these was--
the people must believe that
they are not manipulated in
order for them to be manipulated
effectively.
That turned into a compilation
album.
THOBEY CAMPION: The name Dead
Kennedys I think inspired how
you first reached
out to Jello?
WINSTON SMITH: We're kind
of at the same age.
He's a few years younger
than me.
So I have a vivid memories of
JFK's assassination as an
11-year-old, as a teenager, and
what that did to the rest
of society.
THOBEY CAMPION: Your career,
there's been points where
people will have reacted to
your work negatively, and
sometimes extremely
negatively.
And I think that the example
that yeah, you pointed across
there, I think that the Pat
Robertson 700 Club instance
was an interesting one.
WINSTON SMITH: We used a picture
I had done a few years
before for a Dead Kennedy's
record, it was an EP.
My piece was a cross of American
dollars with a Jesus
on a cross.
It was about greed and religion
and corruption and
essentially how money
controls things, how
people worship money.
It wasn't really
very profound.
So we used it for the record.
And then in Great Britain they
banned the record cover and
big posters up in the window,
like table-size posters, from
record shops.
Because people complained
because
they said it was heresy.
Which meant they took the
records out of the shops.
And Biafra thought
it was horrible.
This is terrible publicity!
And I was going,
no, it's great!
There's no such thing
as bad publicity!
You should write the
cops a check.
You should send them
a thank you note.
THOBEY CAMPION: Have you always
had a purpose, either
political or social,
with your work?
WINSTON SMITH: No.
THOBEY CAMPION: Thank God.
WINSTON SMITH: Yeah.
Sometimes a lot of things I have
I'll put together because
they look funny, or interesting,
or kind of
intriguing, or enigmatic
that way.
THOBEY CAMPION: Some of your
work has a definite intent.
One of the pieces that gets
brought up a lot is the baby
being fed by the--
WINSTON SMITH: Oh, the bomb.
THOBEY CAMPION: The bomb.
WINSTON SMITH: Baby
and the bomb.
Force-fed war.
That was about when
Ronald Reagan was
President in '82 or '83.
And he cut-off the school lunch
program for children,
which sometimes was the only
meal they had in a day, and
give all the money
to the Pentagon.
The best thing about that rocket
that the baby is being
fed, the real thing on the
tail said 666 DBH or some
other code number.
I just had to blackout the code
number and the 666 was
already there.
THOBEY CAMPION: What
drives you?
Is it frustration that drives
you to continue to be working
like 59 years?
WINSTON SMITH: That actually
is a good motivator.
A lot of it is just the desire
to put what is subconscious
onto paper.
We have a responsibility as
artists to express ourselves.
I think.
Even us, we might change our
mind 10 or 20 years later, and
go oh, you know, I could
be wrong about that.
Now I see it differently.