You see, we're a bunch of gutter
punks, and hip hop kids
going to this frat party.
From the moment that we walked
into the party, it was just--
MALE SPEAKER: What the--
TRAVIE MCCOY: You could
feel the tension.
You could cut it with a knife.
We definitely didn't
belong there.
The first thing I do is dart
straight for the refrigerator.
And there's all these colorful
jello shots that
didn't belong to me.
But in my head, they did.
So I just started
destroying them.
And all of a sudden, this girl
rushes in to the kitchen like,
who the fuck are you?
These are my jello shots.
I spent all night making
them, blah, blah, blah.
Proceeded to go upstairs.
I remember speaking to this
girl, trying to woo her.
The jello shots started
to kick in.
I started sweating.
The next thing you know, it was
just like this bomb pop of
nastiness, which was the jello
shots flying out of
my mouth onto her.
All those beautiful colors
ended up on her shirt.
I remember going downstairs, and
the first thing I see is a
chair fly across the hallway.
It was just madness.
People were being thrown, chairs
were being thrown.
There was a kid that was
actually in the corner with
pool balls, throwing
them at people.
And they'd duck, and he's just
throwing them at people.
What the--
A friend of mine, Kathy.
She looks like me without--
minus the beard, I think.
So I don't know, if this
dude mistakes her
for a dude or not.
But all I remember was him
hitting her, and I seen that
from across the room.
I just remember locking
eyes with this dude.
Like, with the power of
Jesus, I cocked back.
Boom!
And tried to knock this dude's
lower jaw off of this face.
There was beer all over the
floor, so when I followed
through, I slipped and
landed on my back.
And I looked to my right.
And my right foot had bent up.
Looking down and seeing this
basketball sized chunk of
flesh beating to the same
rate of my heart.
Crazy part is, after the whole
night, we actually had to rush
back and get ready
for this funeral.
So I'm on crutches, trying
to make my way
up to pay my respects.
Now I have this nifty Robocop
leg compartment that I can
keep guns in and shit.
It's kind of awesome.