We all know when everybody's
starting to get hungry.
We give each other the
eye a little bit.
Craig.
Get out the menu book.
We want four veal
cutlet heros.
We're going to see what
one of these seafood
salads is all about.
STEVE: Craig is our shop
assistant at Smith Street.
Craig's sort of a little
different from the rest of us.
Craig's very dark, and he's very
quiet and sort of morose
and listens to really fucked
up dark music.
Craig does everything.
We make Craig do everything.
We can abuse him, and
he will not flinch.
DAN: Plus we all need
to eat immediately.
All these other guys will tell
him, that light bulb's out.
This needs to be dusted.
I'm like, yo, I need
that bagel order.
He has no interest in food.
He says that if there was a pill
that could sustain his
life, he would just swallow
that pill and never eat.
Doesn't like food.
It's the strangest--
it's disturbing.
CRAIG: Can I get three
veal cutlet heros?
And can I have sides of
mayo for all those?
Yeah, I don't really
like eating.
I don't really find any
enjoyment in eating.
I'm not a foodie by any means.
DAN: A real dinner
usually ensues.
We still do the massage
table family style.
We do what we call Tuscan
dining, and Craig waits on us.
Hey Craig, are there any
IPAs or anything
there in the fridge?
Craig, come look at your worst
nightmare over here.
One time, when Craig was a
little boy, and he was
swimming in the ocean, one
of the fish brushed
up against his leg.
And he's never eaten a piece
of seafood since.
See, if that was me, it would
be my mission to eat all the
eels in the world after that.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
ELLI: We definitely enjoy
busting each other's chops.
Dan and Craig have a lot of
squabbles at the shop.
I think he likes to blame Craig
for a lot of stuff.
And I think that's when you know
he's flustered, is when
he starts yelling at Craig.
DAN: Because he gets snippy.
He does like the whole, get
it yourself, thing.
Even though he'll
always get it.
He'll just say get
it yourself.
And some days I think it's
the funniest thing ever.
And some days I'm
like, you know
what, Craig, fuck yourself.
Get it right now.
STEVE: It makes him the
perfect floor guy.
Because you can just give him so
much shit, and he just lets
it roll right off his back.
And it'll be very hard
to replace Craig.
Craig is a great
shop assistant.
I think as shop assistants go,
I feel like a lot of shops
make their assistants
do nothing.
And I'm like, what the fuck
are you getting paid for?
DAN: Most floor guys
are bumbling.
If someone comes up to the
counter, and is like, how much
for this tattoo?
And they're like,
[STAMMERING].
They don't even know
what to say.
They're like, uh.
They get all nervous and shit.
Whereas Craig's like
cool, calm.
He's like the minimum is $100.
He just handles it every time.
I met Craig for the first
time at a Pratt party.
He was visiting from Buffalo.
Craig has a decent amount
of my tattooing.
When he first started visiting
me in New Jersey, he'd always
bring me these biblical
engravings, like Saint Peter
being crucified upside down.
There's this old wood cut, kind
of thing, of old scribe
drawing in a book.
And the book said something
about hate humanity, something
or another, real misanthropic
stuff.
So when he first started getting
tattooed by me, he
just wanted these real metal
style biblical engravings.
So he's got a lot of that
stuff on his forearms.
And then he started to realize
that you can make a tattoo
look like a tattoo, but it
can still be brutal.
That's when I started
doing some of the
bigger stuff on him.
We did the back piece.
The back piece is a depiction of
Snakeland, which are these
abandoned grain silos
in Buffalo.
It's kind of a metal icon.
And there's a lot of
satanic stuff.
And luckily Craig lived
right down the street.
He grew up in there.
He crucified a deer
in the place.
The deer was dead.
But he crucified a deer, among
some other things.
So Craig needed to have that
on his back, as sort of an
homage to his childhood,
and to Satan.
Craig's not a killer.
He's not a murderer.
He's just a fucking weirdo.
Yeah, he's just bad.