I have a bunch of things at the top.
I want to start by noting that our Reuters
colleague and Arshad's partner, Andy Quinn,
is moving on after 25 years at Reuters and
more than three years here at the State Department.
He's heading to the Aspen Institute to lead
a new Africa-focused program. Those of you
who are briefing regulars know that Andy is
an extraordinary colleague, that he was completely
committed to the story and to reporting it
with integrity and with passion. He was also
a joy to travel with and to be with. We're
going to miss you, Andy, but we're very glad
that you're staying in the foreign policy
realm and continuing to contribute internationally.
I have one other thing, which is with regard
to the Jordanian parliamentary elections.
We want to take this opportunity, since we
didn't brief yesterday right after the elections,
to congratulate the people of Jordan on their
January 23rd parliamentary elections. We view
these elections as an important step in the
ongoing reform process initiated by King Abdullah
II. We note that international election observers
found that the voting process saw an improvement
over past elections and that the elections
were conducted in a transparent and credible
manner. But they also offered recommendations
about continuing to improve Jordan's electoral
process going forward.
In particular, the observers praised the work
of the independent electoral commission which
administered these elections for the first
time. We look forward to the Government and
people of Jordan building on this milestone
and carrying out additional political and
economic reforms for the benefit of all Jordanians.
Jordan is a vital strategic partner of the
United States, and we will continue to support
Jordan's leadership and the Jordanian people
in their reform process.
Let's go to what's on your minds.
QUESTION: One quick thing, Toria. Thanks so
much for your comments about Andy. Speaking
for myself, but I suspect also for my colleagues
here and at Reuters, he really is an unusually
elegant writer and a decent and thoroughly
good-hearted man, and a very wry - with a
very wry and gentle wit. And I will miss him.
Maybe we can go to substance, now that we've
--
QUESTION: (Inaudible) say is that we're going
to miss Andy, I guess.
QUESTION: North Korea threatening to go to
war with the South?
MS. NULAND: As you know, my colleague Jay
Carney spoke to these issues yesterday. These
statements coming out in North Korea are needlessly
provocative. Any kind of further test would
be another significant violation of UN Security
Council resolutions and only will serve to
further Pyongyang's isolation. As you all
know, the UN Security Council passed Resolution
2087 earlier in the week in response to the
December missile launch, and that resolution
tightens the sanctions on North Korea and
works hard to ensure that it cannot succeed
as a proliferator of missile technology, et
cetera.
And it's just - it's really a pretty sad story
because the new North Korean leader has a
choice to make, as the Secretary has said
so many times. He can serve to focus on the
needs of his people, to bring his country
out of isolation and back into compliance
with international obligations, open it back
up to the world, or he can continue to waste
what little money the country has on missile
technologies and things while his people go
hungry. So --
QUESTION: I have a question on that. The new
leader is not all that new. I mean, you have
a pattern of events that you can look at - the
original failed test, the subsequent missile
test that was successful, and now the threat
to conduct a third nuclear test. Does it seem
to you all now that he has made his choice
and how - what kind of a strategy, a diplomatic
strategy, can you pursue if he is not interested
in serious talks about his nuclear and ballistic
missile programs?
MS. NULAND: Well, you're not wrong that the
pattern of choices is concerning, which is
why we felt very strongly that the international
community - oh, we seem to have some guests.
Hi, guys. Not sure who they were, but I think
they were lost.
So again, the pattern of choices appears to
be quite concerning. That's why it's been
so important to keep the international community
united in response to these negative choices,
why we took the time we did to get it right
with Resolution 2087, to make clear to North
Korea that particularly the Six-Party states,
including all of North Korea's neighbors,
are united in ensuring that there is a price
to say, that there will be increasing sanctions,
that we are going to be vigilant about their
proliferation activity, the activities of
their banks, and that it's going to take the
country in the wrong direction.
I think you know that Ambassador Glyn Davies
is out in the region now. He is in Beijing
today, had very productive and useful meetings
with counterparts there, including Vice Foreign
Minister Fu Ying, his counterpart Special
Representative for Korean Peninsula Affairs
Wu Dawei, and others. He was in Seoul yesterday
and he's going on to Tokyo tomorrow. So very
much a project to stay coordinated with our
Six-Party counterparts in watching this and
in ensuring that North Korea gets the message
that nothing good is going to come from this.
QUESTION: And turn back to the China issue
in this whole mix. Today, the Chinese press
seemed to be suggesting that they've told
North Korea that if it goes ahead with its
nuclear test that they will actually - Beijing
could cut its aid to Pyongyang. That seems
to be an interesting move on the part of the
Chinese. What would you have to say on that?
MS. NULAND: Well, I didn't see those particular
comments. But we have, as you know, regularly
encouraged Beijing to use the significant
influence that it has with Pyongyang. They
have, at various times, been able to make
clear that the continued support of Beijing
in terms of trade, aid, the energy relationship,
et cetera, depends on North Korea making the
right choices. Again, China joins strongly
with us in Resolution 2087, which was important,
and we, as Glyn Davies said - he had a very
good visit to Beijing in terms of plotting
the course forward together.
QUESTION: How important - if they go ahead
and do something like that - how important
could such a cut in Chinese aid to North Korea
be in changing the calculations of the North
Korean leadership?
MS. NULAND: Well, I don't want to speculate
on scenarios to be determined. But obviously,
North Korea remains quite dependent on its
aid and trade relationship with Beijing.
Jill, still on this?
QUESTION: Toria, are the Six-Party Talks off,
as they seem to be indicating in the North
Korean statement?
MS. NULAND: Well, we've made clear for more
than a year now that the Six-Party Talks couldn't
go forward to a new round unless we saw real
evidence that the DPRK was prepared to meet
its obligations. So we're still in the state
that we've been for more than a year in terms
of not having the kind of intent that we need
to go forward.
QUESTION: New topic?
MS. NULAND: Still on North Korea?
QUESTION: Still on North Korea.
MS. NULAND: Yeah. Please, here.
QUESTION: Do you - this time around, do you
have any reason to believe the North Koreans
will get that message and actually take astep
on - well, make the - what you would call
the right choice and actually open up to dialogue,
or perhaps discontinue their programs or even
do anything in the right direction?
MS. NULAND: Well, anybody who endeavored to
be predictive about North Korean behavior
is probably foolish. But what's been important
to us is strong unity among the Six-Party
Talks countries, strong unity in the region
about a positive course forward, and the fact
that there will be consequences if they keep
making bad choices.
QUESTION: One more?
MS. NULAND: Yeah.
QUESTION: What types of consequences?
MS. NULAND: Well, I think --
QUESTION: Because there's been few besides
UN resolutions that haven't changed their
behavior. There hasn't really been any significant
consequences otherwise.
MS. NULAND: I would reject that, Brad. If
you look at UN Security Council that was just
passed, 2087, and go through it, and I would
commend to you the fact sheet that USUN put
out on this, it imposes new sanctions on North
Korean companies and government agencies,
including a broad range of sanctions against
their space agency, which was responsible
for the launch, as well as the Bank of East
Land and several individuals in the North
Korean system who had previously not been
sanctioned. Six entities and four individuals
will have their assets frozen and will be
prohibited from engaging in financial transactions.
This is UN sanctions, not just U.S. sanctions.
There's an updated list of nuclear and ballistic
missile technology that's going to be banned
from transfer to or from the DPRK. I could
continue. But --
QUESTION: Do you think there's space to squeeze
them further on the sanctions route, that
this country which is perhaps the most heavily
sanctioned in the world can still be - there's
still consequences along this sanctions route
left?
MS. NULAND: Well, obviously, and we wouldn't
have put new sanctions on them if we didn't
think that they would be effective.
Please.
QUESTION: I just wanted to follow up quickly
as far as North Korea's missile technology
or missiles are concerned. Despite UN Security
Council resolutions or UN sanctions, international
sanctions, still North Korea is continuing
and not listening to the international community.
So if China is with you, Madam, since China
was always helping North Korea. But who else
is behind this technology or behind North
Korea?
MS. NULAND: Well, again, I think what we just
have been through here is the fact that the
international community now with this new
resolution has spoken with one voice in putting
on increasingly tough sanctions on the DPRK,
including getting at the space agency, getting
at the banks, naming individuals who had not
previously been named, as contributing to
taking the country in the wrong direction.
And we will continue to look for further opportunities
to make our views clear in this kind of a
way if the DPRK doesn't change course.
QUESTION: And when this new leader came in
North Korea, everybody hoped that things will
change to the right direction for the people
of North Korea, but still they are going in
the worst direction as far as the people are
concerned.
MS. NULAND: Well, again, we would certainly
agree with that. I mean, as you know, we were
a year ago engaged in trying to work out some
kind of a food assistance deal, but we didn't
get the kind of assurance that we needed from
the government that it was going to go to
the right place. So it's very disappointing.
Please.
QUESTION: Thank you.
QUESTION: Does the United States have any
separate plan for additional sanctions toward
North Korea for the third nuclear test?
MS. NULAND: In response to the December test,
what you will see and what you've seen in
the last couple of days are U.S. decisions
that implement the larger UN Security Council
decisions in 2087. So you're starting to see
us put out our own sanctioning information
to ensure that we are complying now in our
own law with 2087.
Said.
QUESTION: Can we change topics?
MS. NULAND: Yes.
QUESTION: The Israeli elections?
MS. NULAND: Yeah.
QUESTION: Okay. I wonder if you have a reaction
to the outcome of the election, the election
result, and how is that likely to impact the
peace process?
MS. NULAND: Well, I think we said, whether
it was - I guess it was on Tuesday before
the election or on election day that Israel
has a vibrant democracy. We are at the stage
now, as you know, where we're going to have
to wait and see what the makeup of the Israeli
Government is going to be and how it approaches
the longstanding critical issues that we share.
But we've been absolutely clear that as soon
as the parties are ready, we want to make
a renewed push to try to get them back to
the table.
QUESTION: Do you believe that the new coalition
is likely to be more inclined towards some
sort of a peace resolution?
MS. NULAND: The new coalition which hasn't
yet been decided and announced?
QUESTION: I mean, there is - okay, let me
rephrase that. Do you expect the new coalition
to be more engaged in the peace process than
the former one?
MS. NULAND: I think we're not going to be
evaluating a coalition that's still trying
to come together, Said.
QUESTION: Okay. Let me just - let's follow
up with another point.
MS. NULAND: Yeah.
QUESTION: I asked a former U.S. ambassador
to Israel yesterday what is the overriding
message of this Israeli election, and he said
that the message to the Palestinians is that
you are not on our radar screen. Do you see
that as the case?
MS. NULAND: I don't think we've had any indication
from Israel that that is the case. As you
know, before these elections there was - there
were - there have been public statements from
both Israelis and Palestinians that they want
to try to get back to the table. And we're
going to try to work on those as soon as we
can.
QUESTION: Can I ask you, did you find it reassuring
that centrist movement performed better than
expected and that parties that seem to be
more hostile to the two-state peace solution
performed worse than had been prognosticated?
MS. NULAND: Again, I think the wonderful thing
about democracy is that the people get to
speak, then politicians have to take the lessons
from that and move forward. In the case of
a system like Israel, they've got to form
a government, and we're not going to prejudge
how the Israeli - those elected --
QUESTION: I'm not asking about the coalition.
I'm just talking about what the Israeli people
chose, what they voted for. Do you find that
reassuring that they voted primarily for parties
that agree or in broad brushstrokes agree
with the principles you've espoused?
MS. NULAND: I think what we find reassuring
is that Israel continues to be a democratic
beacon out there in the world and to have
a very vibrant system and process for ensuring
that the people's voices are heard in the
political process. But how that's going to
translate in terms of either government formation
or government policy is to be determined.
QUESTION: All right. But I'm asking you specifically
about the peace process --
MS. NULAND: I understand, Brad, and I don't
think --
QUESTION: -- and there was a wide range of
views regarding the - how peace should be
pursued or not pursued or however. And do
you find it reassuring that parties that seem
- that want peace and that have publicly called
for a two-state peace solution, according
to the principles you've outlined, are in
the driver's seat?
MS. NULAND: Again, you can ask this question
however many ways you want, Brad. I'm not
going to comment or opine or speculate as
to how the election results are going to --
QUESTION: Speculation? It's just not even
a speculation question.
MS. NULAND: Will you let me finish? How the
election results are going to translate into
either coalition formulation or the policies
of the government, which are what will matter,
obviously, until the Israelis have had a chance
to make those decisions.
QUESTION: (Inaudible) a renewed push on that.
You're ready to make a - the Administration
is ready to make a renewed push in the region
for peace. Have you ideas on how to set that
forward, where we talk about direct talks
between the two sides, are we talking about
another exchange of letters? What would it
consist of it?
MS. NULAND: Well, we've always favored getting
the parties to direct talks, to a table together,
as quickly as we can. So we will continue
to talk to both sides about what makes most
sense and how quickly we can move.
QUESTION: Because I think there might have
to be some kind of guarantees on both sides.
I mean, obviously the Palestinians have long
asked for the settlement building to be halted,
and that would bring them back to the table.
And on the Israeli side, there are also obviously
similar conditions that they'd like to lay
down. Do you see some kind of the United States
facilitating some kind of conditions? How
would it - how would it work?
MS. NULAND: Well, for decades, as you know,
we have endeavored to facilitate this process
however appears best based on where the parties
are at the time. But I think again, at the
stage that we're at, which is three days after
an Israeli election and before a new government
is formed and we've had a chance to talk to
them about policies going forward, I'm certainly
not going to speculate on the how. We know
where we want to go and we know where we believe
they also want to go. If we can be helpful,
we will continue to try.
Jill.
QUESTION: Syria?
MS. NULAND: Yeah.
QUESTION: Before we go on to Syria, I have
one more question. What steps should the Palestinians
take as a result of this election right now?
What kind of thing do you urge them to do
immediately?
MS. NULAND: I'm not going to be, from this
podium here, giving advice to one side or
the other. You know the general principles
that we're speaking of here in terms of undergirding
an environment for peace. I think we've spoken
both in the Israeli context and in the Palestinian
context about avoiding unilateral actions
that could undercut the environment for peace.
That's still our message for both sides as
we get to a place where we've got interlocutors
who are ready to talk.
QUESTION: And finally, I know the Secretary
has been very busy, but did she call Mr. Netanyahu
personally to congratulate him?
MS. NULAND: To my knowledge, she has not made
any calls out to Israel at this stage.
QUESTION: On Syria, there was a bit of confusion
yesterday about the former spokesman either
being in the United States, somebody - the
U.S. wanting to give him the visa, et cetera.
Can you set the record straight, please?
MS. NULAND: I can. Mr. Makdisi is not in the
United States. Ambassador Ford misspoke. He
is not here.
QUESTION: Is there any intent to bring him
here?
MS. NULAND: I don't have anything for you
on that. I don't - I also don't have anything
for you on where he actually is.
QUESTION: Do you have anything on where Assad's
mother may be?
MS. NULAND: I do not.
QUESTION: So there was a statement attributed
to Ambassador Ford suggesting that Assad's
mother was in the Gulf region. Is that wrong?
MS. NULAND: Again, on that one, I'll leave
Ambassador Ford's comments where they were.
QUESTION: But you have no reason to doubt
them?
MS. NULAND: I don't.
QUESTION: Thank you.
QUESTION: Okay. And also rumors that Mr. Brahimi
is submitting a very bleak report on Tuesday,
and thereafter he might turn in his resignation
that - because he's meeting a brick wall.
Do you have any comment on that?
MS. NULAND: Well, obviously, I think we need
to let Mr. Brahimi bring his report forward
before we prejudge where it might go. We have,
as you know, tried very hard to be supportive
of his efforts, to collaborate with him in
his work, to flesh out the transitional government
idea, to work to bring the Russians in. But
we look forward to hearing what he thinks
needs to be done now when he reports.
QUESTION: Do you believe that his mission
and his effort has run its course?
MS. NULAND: We have not had those indications
from him, but we await to hear what he has
to say. We continue to believe that the role
that he is playing, the facilitation he's
trying to do, can be useful in conjunction
with a lot of other things that we're also
working on, as we've been clear about.
QUESTION: And finally, in his testimony yesterday,
Senator Kerry said that we want to bring in
the Russians on the Syria situation. In what
ways, what different ways would he do that
other than what, let's say, Secretary of State
Hillary Clinton has done so far with the Russians?
MS. NULAND: Well, Said, let me just say, and
let me say to everybody for the record, just
to remind you how our democratic process works
here, as you all saw, Senator Kerry had a
chance in his confirmation hearings yesterday
to have a really full exchange with the members
of the Senate Foreign Relations Committee
on a huge range of issues, not just Syria
but it was really a tour all the way around
the world. That is American democracy in action.
We want to see his speedy confirmation. But
until we have the Senate's advice and consent,
it would not be appropriate for me to speak
from this podium for him or to try to parse
his words or speculate as to where a secretaryship
led by a Secretary Kerry will take us. He
obviously spoke extremely eloquently for himself,
and I would commend the transcript to you.
Please.
QUESTION: New subject?
MS. NULAND: Yeah.
QUESTION: Follow up Syria? A U.S. delegation
has visited Jordan and Turkey. I don't know
if they are still in the region. Is there
any readout or update? We have seen some photo
ops. But I'm - what's your readout on those
visits?
MS. NULAND: Well, you are right, Ilhan, that
we have a U.S. delegation comprised of our
Assistant Secretary for Population, Refugees,
and Migration Anne Richard, USAID Assistant
Administrator Nancy Lindborg, and Ambassador
Ford. They visited the Islahiyah refugee camp
in Turkey yesterday. They also had a chance
yesterday to be in Ankara to meet with Turkish
officials and some of the members of the Syrian
Opposition Coalition Assistance Coordination
Unit. This is the unit that the SOC created
to try to work better with the international
community both on humanitarian and on other
kinds of assistance to the Syrian people.
Tomorrow, Assistant Secretary Richard and
Assistant Administrator Lindborg will go to
Amman to continue their consultations on the
humanitarian situation. And Ambassador Ford
is going to go to Paris to attend a meeting
on assistance to the Syrian opposition that
the French Government is hosting. It's a - they're
calling it a partner support meeting on better
targeting assistance. I think we'll have a
little bit of a announcement right after the
briefing. One of the things that they are
announcing on this trip is an additional $10
million from the United States, primarily
directed at getting flour into the north of
Syria, into bakeries in Aleppo, where there's
a real crying need. And we'll have more on
that for you later in the day. And then from
there, Ambassador Ford goes on to Kuwait for
the humanitarian assistance meeting.
QUESTION: In recent days, one of the Syrian
groups start petition. It's about this new
program by the UN revised Humanitarian Assistance
Response Plan launched by the United Nations.
And apparently it's about half a billion dollars,
about $519 million. This petition, it says
that the plan states that it aims at supporting
the Government of Syria. So there's a partnership
with the current Syrian Government to send
half a billion humanitarian assistance to
Syrians. So there is this apparently the problem
that how this, the government is going to
help Syrians while they keep bombing across
country.
MS. NULAND: Well, I don't - I'm not sure what
you are looking at there, Ilhan, as your backdrop,
but the humanitarian aid situation has been
difficult and complicated for a long time,
as you know. UN agencies are required to work
with the host government in order to get access
in the country. And so the UN doesn't have
any choice but to continue to pound on the
Syrian regime to let them get into the most
difficult areas. And you know that this is
not a new problem, particularly when the regime
is conducting military operations. And we've
seen this for more than a year, whether you're
talking about Homs or Hama or Aleppo or Damascus.
So that is one of the constraints. And as
we look - as we work with UN agencies, we
are continually urging them to find new and
different ways to get assistance into Syria.
So that's one problem. But it also speaks
to the need to work with nongovernmental organizations
and others who are in the border states who
are able to get assistance directly to Syrians
who are going back and forth, because sometimes
they are able to get access to areas that
the UN is not.
QUESTION: I have a bunch of questions on that,
but I'm going to - not going to ask today.
This apparently raises some questions. First
of all, the government doesn't have control
of most of the country. And second, in the
past experiences, apparently there is a huge
corruption. Even the humanitarian aid goes
only to places that the regime has control
over.
Yesterday, I believe, the president of Syrian
coalition said that they need $3 billion for
a transitional government, to create transitional
government. Do you have a comment on that?
Everybody pressures them to create this transitional
government, and they say they - we need $3
billion to do that.
MS. NULAND: I hadn't seen that number or those
comments either. However, we are in broad
consultation with the Syrian Opposition Coalition,
including at this meeting that the French
are going to host tomorrow, about moving forward
on transitional governing structures, about
what the needs are going to be, and this is
one of the reasons to bring the major donor
partners together with the SOC.
QUESTION: Change of subject?
MS. NULAND: Yeah.
QUESTION: Can I --
MS. NULAND: Still on Syria, Jill? No?
QUESTION: The French also announced that there
is a meeting in Paris on the 28th (inaudible).
Who's representing the United States in that
meeting?
MS. NULAND: I think I just said Ambassador
Ford.
QUESTION: Ambassador Ford - I'm sorry.
QUESTION: Okay. On Russia, can you tell us
--
MS. NULAND: Still - Scott on Syria.
QUESTION: One on Syria, sorry.
MS. NULAND: Yeah.
QUESTION: Does contact between U.S. officials
and the Free Syrian Army include the issue
of combat between FSA and Kurds?
MS. NULAND: We are, in our contacts with the
FSA, expressing concern about including the
Kurds in a broader opposition approach, that
when opposition groups are in conflict with
each other, it doesn't help the broader cause
of a unified opposition to take the country
in another - in a more democratic direction.
So one of our messages, both to the Kurds
of Syria all the way through and to other
groups in Syria in the opposition, whether
it's the FSA or whether it's the political
opposition, is that their cause is better
served by unity and common cause. But we are
aware of some of these skirmishes that have
been going on in the north, and we're concerned
about it.
QUESTION: Can we - can I ask you about Russia?
MS. NULAND: Yeah.
QUESTION: Can you explain the U.S. decision
to end the Civil Society Working Group, a
U.S.-Russian working group?
MS. NULAND: As you know, this is a working
group that we set up a couple of years ago
in the interest of exploring how we could
support civil society as a key underpinning
of the U.S.-Russia relationship. We have now
decided to withdraw from the Civil Society
Working Group of the U.S.-Russia Bilateral
Presidential Commission in light of recent
steps taken by the Russian Government which
impose really strong restrictions on civil
society. This working group was a bilateral
mechanism that was designed to foster the
development of civil society, and the United
States will continue to work with Russian
civil society organizations and to help them
in their efforts to support the Russian people
and support their full human rights, their
access to healthcare, all of these other kinds
of things. And we remain committed to a dialogue
with the Government of Russia on democracy
issues and human rights issues, but this particular
working group was not working.
QUESTION: Why is it not better to stay in
the working group and try to convince your
interlocutors there either to try to reverse
some of the recent moves that you oppose or
to do other things that would promote civil
society? I mean, did you just come to the
conclusion that that was never going to happen
in this working group?
MS. NULAND: Well, as I said, the working group
was not working. The new restrictions that
the Government of Russia was placing on civil
society in recent months were increasingly
calling into questions whether maintaining
this government-to-government mechanism was
either useful or appropriate, and it was not
advancing the cause of civil society in Russia,
so we will do that other ways.
QUESTION: One other thing. Sorry. Just sticking
with Russia, I don't know if you are aware
that the Duma today voted - I think it's 388
to 1 in favor a law that would criminalize
what it describes as homosexual propaganda
and that would allow for - it would ban the
promotion of gay events across Russia, and
it would allow fines of up to 500,000 rubles
to be imposed on organizers of such events.
Do you have any comment on that specifically?
MS. NULAND: Well, we are aware and we are
deeply concerned by this draft legislation
in Russia that severely restricts freedom
of expression and assembly for lesbian, gay,
bisexual, and transgender individuals and
indeed for all Russians. This is similar to
legislation that already exists in St. Petersburg
that we have been expressing our concern about
including in the Secretary's bilateral meetings
with Foreign Minister Lavrov for more than
a year and in several other regions of Russia.
We call on Russia as a signatory to the International
Covenant on Civil and Political Rights to
meet its obligations to protect its citizens'
rights to peaceful assembly and freedom of
expression without discrimination. You know
how strongly we feel about LGBT rights around
the world, how strongly the Secretary of State
personally feels, that nobody should be discriminated
against for who they love. I would note that
Russian citizens are also concerned. I understand
that there was a kiss-in outside the Duma
today to protest this legislation.
QUESTION: So Toria, on that, in other words,
just getting back to that civil society group
withdrawal, then we could - from that organization,
we can interpret as a protest by the United
States?
MS. NULAND: We formed the group in an effort
to have government support for the development
of civil society. Our concern is that what
we're seeing from the Russian Government is
taking the position of civil society in Russia
in the wrong direction. So we would rather
direct our efforts in other ways and continue
to work on our direct support for civil society
organizations who want to work with us.
QUESTION: And yet direct support now is more
difficult than ever.
MS. NULAND: Absolutely.
QUESTION: So how do you propose to do that?
MS. NULAND: Well, we do continue to work with
a broad cross-section of Russian civil society
organizations. They obviously have to manage
to do that within their own law. I think you
know that there are lots of countries where
we do this from the United States. We do it
from offices in third countries. But as long
as there are Russian civil society activists
who want our help, who want our support, who
want to connect with civil society organizations
in the United States, we will help them.
QUESTION: Can I just ask you, these working
groups were established as part of the reset,
if I remember correctly. And if I remember
right, it was this notion that you'd work
together where you can and talk through differences
where they exist. In this case, you're now
not even going to talk about this central
difference of opinion on civil society. So
what does that say about the reset three,
four years on?
MS. NULAND: Well, let me say that we will
obviously continue to talk about human rights,
we will continue to talk about civil society
issues, we will continue to talk about democracy
in Russia in our bilateral conversations with
the Russians at every level from the President
on down. That's a different matter than whether
it makes sense under the Bilateral Presidential
Commission to have a working group when that
working group is not advancing the ball. So
you'll remember that as part of the reset
we established this Presidential Commission
with lots of different working groups on everything
from economy to health to nuclear things to
many other issues that we work on together.
This particular subgroup is not doing what
we set it out to do, and so we've withdrawn.
QUESTION: So I suppose the question is: Are
the other groups working? Are the other working
groups working on the different issues you
-
MS. NULAND: Yeah, and in fact, I would - I
can't remember when we last - I think it was
in the context of the President's meeting
in - on the margins of his Asia trip with
President Putin that we released a joint statement
that went through the work of many of these
working groups. I would commend that to you.
It was on the White House website.
QUESTION: Do you see - because we've got this
now, you withdrawing from this group on civil
society, there was the decision towards the
back end of last year to - by Moscow to kick
out USAID. Are these just bumps in the road
of your relations with Russia, or is it indicative
of something much more serious?
MS. NULAND: Well, I think beyond saying what
we've been saying, which is that we will continue
to work with Russia on as many areas as we
can where we see interest in cooperation,
whether they are bilateral issues, whether
they are regional issues, or whether they
are global issues, but we will also speak
straight when we have disagreements, as we
have, whether it was on the sovereignty and
territorial integrity of Georgia, whether
it was on human rights, whether it was on
Syria. I don't think it makes sense to try
to give that relationship a grade. It has
always been something that we've both had
to work hard on, and I think we'll continue
to have to do so.
Please.
QUESTION: Speaking of USAID, some in Congress
now are questioning USAID, demanding information
on this investigation into a contract that
apparently some would allege was steered toward
a former USAID employee. What can you tell
us about that, the status of that right now?
MS. NULAND: Well, let me first say that my
understanding is that this relates to an investigation
that is still ongoing, so I am quite constrained
in what I can say in terms of discussing the
details. What I will say is from this building,
we are confident that the investigation has
not been compromised, and that USAID has cooperated
with the investigation. But I think we have
to wait until it's completed.
QUESTION: What do you mean you're confident
that the investigation has not been compromised?
MS. NULAND: There were some concerns about
that, and I would just like to affirm here
that it is our view that it has not been compromised.
QUESTION: And are you confident that the employees
that - who are alleged to be under investigation,
or are reported to be under investigation,
acted properly?
MS. NULAND: I'm not in a position to make
that judgment in the middle of an investigation.
That's why the investigation is ongoing.
QUESTION: And when you - last thing - when
you refer to the investigation, you are indeed
referring to the Justice Department investigation
into this, correct, not into an IG investigation
or a congressional investigation?
MS. NULAND: My understanding is we were talking
about an IG investigation. I don't know what
else you would be talking about.
QUESTION: The AP reported yesterday that the
Justice Department is conducting a criminal
investigation into possible contract-rigging
by the general counsel at USAID.
MS. NULAND: What I have pertains to an IG
investigation. If we have anything more on
that or how they might link, I'll get back
to you.
QUESTION: Victoria.
MS. NULAND: Yeah.
QUESTION: You said you didn't want to give
the relationship with Russia a grade. I mean,
why not? How do you evaluate your relationship
with Russia? I mean, the President spoke of
a reset policy, I think, at the time, provided
that Russia cooperates with you on a number
of issues. So when do you know that the situation
or the relationship is so tense that you cannot
cooperate?
MS. NULAND: I don't think it's useful in any
context to be giving grades unless you're
in high school or elementary school. I think
I have enough of that at home.
QUESTION: No, I don't mean a grade, per se,
but how do you say - how do you put a status
on that relationship?
MS. NULAND: Said, I think I spoke to the general
principles that undergird the relationship.
QUESTION: (Off-mike.)
MS. NULAND: Yeah, go ahead.
QUESTION: Firstly, we had a story a few days
ago on Saeed Abedini, this U.S. citizen jailed
in Iran, reporting that he might get bail.
Do you have any information on that and on
his status?
MS. NULAND: We remain very concerned about
U.S. citizen Saeed Abedini, who is detained
in Iran on charges related to his religious
beliefs. Mr. Abedini's attorney had only one
day to present his defense. And we remain
deeply concerned about the fairness and the
transparency of his trial. We condemn Iran's
continued violation of the universal rights
of freedom of religion, and we call on the
Iranian authorities to respect Mr. Abedini's
human rights and to release him. We are in
close contact with his family as well and
we're actively engaged in the case.
QUESTION: So no indication that he was let
out on bail as, I think it was, this Iranian
news agency seemed to suggest that might be
--
MS. NULAND: I don't have any positive news
to report on this, unfortunately.
QUESTION: Okay. And then on another issue,
there's been some reports about a mysterious
gold transfer that seemed to have made its
way from Ghana to Turkey, had a brief pause
there, then to Dubai, and then to Iran. Do
you know anything about this, and do you know
what it means?
MS. NULAND: I don't appear to have much on
this other than to say that we continue to
consult closely with Turkey and on all countries
regarding the scope of U.S. sanctions against
Iran, and we will pursue any evidence of sanctionable
transactions. But I don't have anything on
this particular set of alleged circumstances.
QUESTION: You haven't had any discussions
with Turkey specifically on this?
MS. NULAND: I don't have anything to share
on that one way or the other.
QUESTION: Okay.
QUESTION: Staying in the region, Iraq?
MS. NULAND: Yeah.
QUESTION: A very quick question: According
to reports, five protestors got killed today
in Fallujah, Iraq. Have - are you able to
confirm - during protests by the Iraqi security
forces.
MS. NULAND: I'm not in a position to confirm
numbers, but I will say that we are concerned
about the use of deadly force during today's
protests in Iraq. We understand that the Iraqi
Government has now issued a statement indicating
that they are initiating a very prompt investigation
into the incidents, and that they have called
for restraint by security forces. We obviously
stand ready to assist in that investigation
if asked, but we would also say that as the
government and government forces show restraint,
the demonstrators also have a responsibility
to exercise their right to protest in a nonviolent
manner, as well as to continue to press their
demands through the political process.
QUESTION: On Mali?
MS. NULAND: Please. Arshad.
QUESTION: I have two (inaudible).
MS. NULAND: Yeah.
QUESTION: One is: We have a report saying
that P-5+1 talks with the Iranians that had
hoped to be held next week are actually likely
now to slide into February. Do you have anything
on that?
MS. NULAND: Other than to say we are continuing
to consult with the Iranians to determine
dates and a venue, unfortunately I don't.
We've been surprised that the Iranians keep
coming back again and again with new preconditions,
new dates and venues. And we haven't been
able to settle yet, but we're going to keep
trying.
QUESTION: They've been coming back with substantive
preconditions or with date and venue-related
preconditions?
MS. NULAND: They've been coming back with
preconditions on the modalities for the talks.
We're not to the point of substance yet; we're
still trying to figure out when and where.
QUESTION: And then one other one: We have
reported that South Korean petrochemical company
Samsung Total Petrochemicals has revived a
contract to buy Iranian oil after more than
a year of not buying any. And it appears that
the reason they have done so is that they're
getting the oil pretty cheaply. I realize
that the NDAA sanctions refer to purchases
by a country as a whole and not individual
companies, but are you troubled by the - by
this, by the prospect that one of our ally's
oil companies, after stopping buying Iranian
oil, is now starting up again?
MS. NULAND: Arshad, let me take that one because
I need to check on whether our facts and yours
are the same and how we would react.
Please.
QUESTION: On Mali?
MS. NULAND: Mali, yeah.
QUESTION: There have been increasingly harsher
tones coming out of Paris both from the President,
President Hollande, and the Defense Minister
with regard to the determination of the French
of going further to clean up this situation
in Mali, whereas initially it was seen on
the French side as a temporary operation by
French troops which would be replaced by these
ECOWAS. The French were not so inclined to
get deeply involved in Francophone Africa
for obvious reasons. They are treated like
heroes, people are putting out French flags,
but that's not going to last forever if the
French remain a long time.
Now, after the statements of Prime Minister
Cameron, the intervention, I think, of the
EU is going to get involved in this. This
looks like it's going to be a much longer
war and more serious operation. What is the
U.S. view of the situation as it's developing
in Mali?
MS. NULAND: Well, let me just commend to you
some of the comments that the Secretary made
during her Benghazi hearings with regard to
the challenge that we are all having to confront,
not only in Mali but in the entire region.
I think she obviously spoke quite eloquently
about the challenge; that it's not only a
security challenge but it's also a challenge
of governance and democracy and values. Our
understanding of the ground situation is that
French and Malian forces have been able to
have some success in recent days. We talked
about Diabali the other day and Kona. They
are now taking up positions in the city of
Menaka, which is just to the east of Gao,
and moving up into Gao and Timbuktu.
But you're not wrong that the strategy here
depends on both Malian and ECOWAS forces being
able to come in behind, secure the gains,
not only hold them but extend them, and also
prepare the country for a restoration of democracy
through elections this spring. So in that
context, as you know, in addition to supporting
some of the French requests, we are focusing
our efforts on facilitating the ECOWAS forces,
the AFISMA forces to get into Mali. Our understanding
is that there are currently some 600 AFISMA
troops in Mali, including 44 African staff
at ECOWAS headquarters. We've got 162 from
Nigeria, 50 from Benin, 204 from Togo, 36
from Senegal, 159 from Burkina. And we have
some 500-plus Nigerian troops on the Niger
border getting ready to go in.
The U.S. is also, as we've been talking about,
using our ACOTA facility to work with Niger,
Nigeria, Burkina Faso, Senegal, Togo, Ghana
in the coming weeks to ensure that they can
sustain and continue these deployments, and
with longer-term training in terms of what'll
be necessary to not only come in behind the
French, but also to train and support the
Malian forces in eventually being able to
secure their country themselves.
QUESTION: Your what facility? You said our
--
MS. NULAND: Our ACOTA facility, which we've
talked about before. I'll see if I've got
it written out here - the African Contingency
Operations Training and Assistance program.
I think I'm going to - we're going to put
out a fact sheet shortly on ACOTA. Yeah.
QUESTION: There's a P missing from the acronym
at the end.
MS. NULAND: Is there?
QUESTION: Anyhow.
MS. NULAND: African Contingency Operations
Training and Assistance, ACOTA.
QUESTION: Okay.
QUESTION: Staying - just moving slightly in
the region, on Algeria, has there been any
contact since the end of the hostage crisis
between the Algerian authorities and the State
Department to update you on how the attack
at the oil facility took place, and their
subsequent - the subsequent decisions that
were made by the Algerian authorities in handling
the situation and releasing the hostages?
MS. NULAND: Well, we are, obviously, in close
contact with the Algerians, including via
Ambassador Ensher on the ground there. I think
I mentioned that we have an open FBI investigation
now, so I'm not going to get into details,
as that moves forward. But we, like the Algerians,
are obviously looking to get a full understanding
of exactly how this transpired and what the
motives were and who was involved so that
they can be brought to justice.
QUESTION: So that understanding hasn't evolved
since we spoke on Tuesday?
MS. NULAND: I don't have anything to share.
It certainly has evolved, but you understand
that once these things become a matter of
investigation, there's very - not a lot we
can say until the investigations are complete.
QUESTION: New subject, ma'am?
MS. NULAND: Goyal quickly, and then we'll
go to Scott, and poor old Dana that was way
in the back and I missed her.
Okay, go ahead.
QUESTION: New subject?
MS. NULAND: Yeah.
QUESTION: My question is the Chicago courts
on India. As Indians celebrate the Republic
Day of India tomorrow, and India is shocked
and Indians are very angry as far as the Chicago
court's outcomes are concerned for Mr. Rana
last week, only 14 years, what they are saying,
and now yesterday, 35 years for David Coleman
Headley.
Now, what they are saying is this is the price
of - cost of the 166 people killed in Mumbai
attacks, and including six Americans. And
what Indians are really saying, that why this
has happened - only 35 years, but why he was
not extradited to India to face justice, because
U.S. and India both believes in - that anyone
who - criminals must face justice?
MS. NULAND: Let me just underscore what the
Justice Department announced when this trial
completed - it was completed. David Headley,
a key conspirator in the Mumbai terrorist
attacks, has been brought to justice in the
United States. He will serve 35 years in prison
for his role in these heinous acts that claimed
the lives of 166 people, including six Americans.
He also gave - the investigation and the prosecution
of David Headley stems from the unprecedented
and intense collaboration between the United
States and Indian authorities in the counterterrorism
sphere to bring all the people responsible
for Mumbai to justice.
Let me just add, and I would commend to you
the fact sheet put out by our Embassy in Delhi
and the comments made by the Justice Department
yesterday, not only did he stand trial, face
conviction, now have to serve 35 years. But
in the context of this prosecution, Mr. Headley
provided information of substantial value
in our efforts against terrorism, including
testifying against co-conspirator Mr. Rana,
providing extensive detail about accused terrorist
Kashmiri and his network, who was indicted
in 2009, as you know, and as well as submitting
to questions from Indian law enforcement and
working with U.S. investigators.
So from our perspective, justice was served,
and this is a very positive example of U.S.-Indian
collaboration in the counterterrorism realm.
QUESTION: Madam, what message would be from
the Secretary of State Hillary Clinton to
the people, or the victims of 166 people and
their loved ones, and including six Americans
on this day?
MS. NULAND: That we promised that justice
would be served, that justice is being served
in this case.
Please, Scott.
QUESTION: On the same subject --
MS. NULAND: Scott. Yeah, sorry. Go ahead.
QUESTION: So the two ministers, Indian ministers,
expressed concern that they wanted to keep
up the effort to extradite him. Are you continuing
to that dialogue, or is this just a matter
of - because of the U.S. legal system, this
is a closed, locked door that they're banging
at?
MS. NULAND: The Justice Department spoke to
this. He's been tried, convicted, and will
serve in the United States.
Scott?
QUESTION: Well, just quickly --
MS. NULAND: Scott - I think we're - I think
we've done this one.
Scott?
QUESTION: Azerbaijan.
MS. NULAND: Yeah.
QUESTION: Do you have anything? There's been
some instability in Ismaili. There was a warning
for U.S. citizens. But do you have anything
more specific to talk about the violence in
Azerbaijan, police response?
MS. NULAND: Let me take that one as well,
Scott, and we'll get to you.
Dana.
QUESTION: I have two unrelated questions.
The first is a follow-up to Mali, and I'm
wondering about the funding for ACOTA and
these troops. Has the State Department asked
Congress for more money beyond the initial
$8 million that was allocated, and how much?
MS. NULAND: We have, Dana. We have the 8 million
that we already had, and then we've just notified
Congress either yesterday or today requesting
an additional 32 million for the ACOTA effort,
and we will continue to evaluate what more
we might need as we work with our African
partners.
QUESTION: And secondly, I just wondered if
you would be able to confirm that the specialty
glasses that the Secretary is wearing have
a Fresnel prism in them, or how long she's
expected to wear the glasses.
MS. NULAND: Well, let me just say in response
to lots of speculation, the Secretary is going
to be wearing the glasses instead of her contacts
for some period of time because of lingering
issues that stemmed from her concussion. She
sees just fine with them, and she also enjoyed
some of the comments she saw in the press
about the extra sort of diplomatic lift she
gets from gesturing with them. So - all right?
QUESTION: May I just --
MS. NULAND: Thank you very much. I think we've
gone a long while here, Goyal. Thanks.
QUESTION: Thank you.
MS. NULAND: All right.