the Antilles.
60% was tropical rainforest.
Deforestation has depleted this
pearl, which as devastated the
land, causing soul
erosion, flash floods,
and desertification.
By 1988, only 2% of the land had
tree cover and nothing better
symbolizes a cycle
of poverty like the
process of deforestation.
But the trees are not cut down
for mere sport, but they are
used for life sustaining
purposes like charcoal for
heating and cooking and
wood for the building of
homes for families.
The Haiti Connection has joined
efforts with our Haitian
brothers and sisters to
replenish the land with trees
and cover the mountaintops with
green hats.
The reality is, Haiti will never
be able to be reforested.
Nevertheless, it is still
possible to stop the erosion,
to create many forest, and to
empower young people to protect
the land for their future and
to create a landscape that
shows the depth and the
beauty of its people.
[Singing].
[no dialogue].
>> Roy Lahman:
You know, all of our studies
and all the things we did before
to get ready to go to Haiti,
we knew that Haiti was called
the Pearl of the Antilles.
That it provided for a third of
the GDP, this little part of the
island, a third of the island
the size of Maryland provided a
third of the GDP for France when
it was one of its colonies.
That's why France was willing to
sell the Louisiana Purchase in
order to keep Haiti.
It's crazy when you think about
it but that's how beautiful
Haiti was at one time and we
recognize and realize that where
once was 65% tropical rain
forest was now less than 2% even
by the time we go there.
And so it's always been in our
heart, I think, when we started
walking with people, we hear
stories, we hear stories about
how beautiful Haiti was and all
that and it is still beautiful,
it's so gorgeous.
But you think such denuded, so
denuded the mountains are so
denuded and poverty is a cruel
mistress, a horribly cruel
mistress or master--which ever
one you want to say, I guess I
should say it's a cruel master,
whatever.
And so with poverty, farmers cut
down the trees.
They cut it down for the number
one culprit, chabon--charcoal to
cook with because they need to
make a living and you can't
blame them.
My definition of deforestation
is actually two-fold.
Okay, one is sort of the
functional sense, meaning when a
forest loses its ability to, to
work as an entity.
What I mean by that is that is
that a forest serves in many
different capacities.
One, it serves as method for
collection rainwater.
In areas they get an awful lot
of rain, particularly if that is
coming at high velocity, you
know, during the tropical storm
or something of that nature.
The forest serves to soak up
that excess moisture and reduces
flooding, so that's one problem.
So deforestation occurs when
enough of the forest is removed
where that function is missing.
Deforestation also occurs,
though, when it leads to--from
an economic standpoint, the lack
of the ability of people to
utilize that for basic needs,
okay.
In other words when they cut
down too many trees, there are a
lack of trees for charcoal
production for example, for home
heating, for building and things
of that nature.
When you cut down all the trees,
particularly in an area where
you have some sort of slope,
that's going to lead to erosion
being advanced.
It's also going to lead to
flooding being a problem.
So people who have built and who
live in these areas, they're
subject to flash floods on
greater bases.
Their fields, if they begin to
farm those fields, are not very
stable, they grow erode very,
very quickly.
And obviously this is not
sustainable situation for a
country that is already--they
have a tenuous ability to
provide for themselves anyway
from an agricultural standpoint
or from an economic standpoint.
So that's one of the major
problems with deforestation.
Another, in a more broader
perspective has to do with, you
know, global temperature and
climate change because these
forests serve as method for
dealing with carbon.
They collect carbon rather than
admit carbon into the
atmosphere, so these are what we
call carbon sinks, are no longer
available to do that job.
So that's kind of the more broad
perspective, a more localized
perspective, increased
flooding, increased erosion
are big problems.
There's a very famous--you can
find this on the
Internet--photos where you see,
they show the boarder line
between the Dominican Republic
and Haiti.
The Dominican Republic, because
that is a protective boarder,
there are plenty of trees on
that side; the other side is
denuded of trees.
There are several reasons for
this, one is because of the lack
of opportunity for many
Haitians, they are forced to use
that lumber for basic needs.
For heating, for building
and things of that nature,
charcoal production.
So they've cut down the trees,
with very little official
oversight, even in resent years
so that's lead to the complete
denuding of that land scape.
Unfortunately, when you do
something like that, you open
the area up to flooding and
flash flooding is a major
problem in much of rural Haiti.
But once again, you can't blame
the people for cutting down the
trees, they need those
resources to survive and, you
know, until another method for
fuel and other types of building
material, till that happens, you
will continue to see
deforestation being a major
problem in Haiti.
>> Roy Lanham:
So when you begin to look at
this, you begin to think, what
is possible and as we begin to
look at my Haitian brothers
and sisters, once again,
walking with and not doing
for, but walking with.
How keys is that?
And we've learned over the years
that we've found a couple folks
that kind of changed our lives
and how we saw the issue of
reforestation in Haiti.
One was a woman named sister Pat
Dillon, an American, works in
Gros-Morne we met her twelve
years ago now.
She is the Lorax of Gros-Morne
The women loves tries beyond
belief and she believed in
beyond belief that what could be
transformed, how Haiti can be
transformed and Haitians lives
can be transformed if they
can just begin to reforest
if you will.
Now they all know they can't.
The farmers need the land, they
can 't totally reforest by they
can have "ti fore", small
forest, quarter acre forest and
they can begin and begin to do
fence rows and things like that.
And they will begin to save the
land and they begin to work on
this and educate and the whole
bit and what she was doing up
there in Gros-Morne has made
such an impact, we started
working with a group of
individuals called AJGR.
This is the kind of impact they
had.
A group of Haitians, young
Haitians got together and they
wanted then to make their land
more beautiful, to make Haiti
more beautiful for future
generations.
We had the opportunity to begin
to work with them.
And we begin to work with them
on a reforestation project and
it was just a little hillside,
it was a learning center so that
they can teach future
generations about the power of
caring for the earth, caring for
the land.
Being good stewards of what God
has given us.
It was amazing, it was really
cool.
It never really get
off the ground,
as it should of, unfortunately.
These are one of these things
that we've learned when
we've been in Haiti, that
not everything is going
to be successful.
Not everything's always going
to be where we come out the
other end and say, "Wow, look at
us, look what we did."
Naw, some things are going to
fail and maybe something will be
learned, not just on our side,
but also on the side in Haiti.
AJGR and our relationship with
them failed.
We did somethings, we tried,
we tried, we tried, we built a
cistern, we did all these
things, we planted thousands of
trees, you know, but it just
never clicked because it always
came off as us doing for them.
They kind of went there separate
way and guess what, AJGR is
blooming and blossoming and
growing in ways we could have
never imagined, had we stayed
with them.
They began to realize that they
became so dependent on us doing
for them, and we had realized
that we were so frustrated that
actually parting the ways
allowed for some really cool
things to happen with them.
And that's been a cool thing,
but it didn't take away our
desire for reforestation
and to do some real things
with reforestation.
And what happen was, it really
kind of once again, it had
everything to do with
the relationships
first and foremost.
Down there is Barada once again,
and Fonds-Verrettes.
We wrote for a grant, one of our
alums wrote for a grant to see
if we could--with the company
that she had worked with--and to
see if she could get some money
for a reforestation projects.
It was called the ti fore
project, we called it,
Project Lorax.
Lorax is this famous character
from Dr. Seuss, you know, its
kind of speaking for the trees
and we didn't get the grant, we
didn't get it.
But here is what's amazing; the
students said this is too
important because we had talked
to the people in Haiti.
Especially after the floods that
happened that destroyed
Fonds-Verrettes in the area, it
is because they didn't have
trees and they really long for
that.
They long for a partner with
this, so we decided we will,
we'll partner with you but we
said we needed to find a guy on
the ground that can be our
partner.
Well, we found him, his name is
Rodrigue Manigar, he is the
Lorax of Fonds-Verrettes.
♪ [music playing] ♪♪.
>> Roy Lanham:
He believes in
reforesting Haiti.
He knows it can't be all put
back together, he knows that
there can be green hats on every
mountaintop, there can be green
hats that would help with the
watershed.
He knows that on every mountain,
there can begin to look at how
the waters flowing and build
rock walls and put in trenches,
channels so the water just
doesn't wash down the hill, it
can feel up first and then go
down.
He knows that they can plant
native trees, trees that can
produce fruits.
They won't cut them down for
charcoal because theirs
another way.
Avocados can give farmers a
source of income, mangos can
give farmers a source of income,
sweet oranges and sour oranges
can give farmers a source of
income, so they won't cut the
trees down.
We begin to look at that, so we
begin to look at it.
And it also brings back native
hardwoods because eventually
they do need--if we're really
going to listen to the Haitian
people and we have, they also
realized we still need to cook
with wood and right now this is
what we've got.
We need to explore some
possibilities but how can we
also be planting some trees that
we know in 15 years, we can cut
down as a source of fuel but use
it as a crop, if you will.
So we've begun to look at that
and we found a tree that they
liked that can work with
that, so why should we deny
them that opportunity?
So working together, walking
together.
So right now its in its infancy
but its working and its
Project Lorax.
We've got too many nurseries,
we've got two distributions
during the rainy season.
These are 5000 tree nurseries,
it's not huge, they are mini
nurseries but then what happens
in May is they--every may during
the rainy season--they give away
20 trees per person, anyone who
can come an get them, 20 trees
per person and they've got to
care for these trees, plant
them, care for them, keep the
goats from eating them.
And then they get visited, they
actually get visited--everybody
that takes the trees get visited
and they see how your trees
doing and you're rated.
And they do it, I think, four
times in six months, they'll
come by and visit you and you
don't know when they're coming
so you have to be ready.
And so they'll come and see how
your trees are doing and this is
to encourage them to keep doing
it.
We've recognized while walking
with Rodrigue is that people
will always take trees but they
won't care for them and the
goats will eat them, we've got
to give them some incentive, the
incentive is food.
Twice a year we have a contest
and the top 20 folks get their
names put in a hat and the first
three people who get their name
pulled will get a bag of rice
and a bag of beans and oil for
their family, they get to
provide for their family.
Food securities a huge issue,
even with farmers, is a huge
issue in Haiti and this gives
them food security, helps them
with food so they can provide
for their family.
And so, if they win, they get
this bag of rice, bag of beans,
oil and we just started the
contest and it worked.
And he goes, "The idea Roy
is..."
this is what's so cool, he goes,
"in six months a different 20
people could be in it."
So it encourages them to keep
doing this so its really
excellent program that...
And what even more important
is education, education
about reforestation.
So we translated this book
called the Lorax and we took it
down there and it in creole
and now their using it
in the schools.
Rodrigue got on the radio,
everybody in Fonds-Verrettes,
everybody knows about the Lorax.
What's so amazing is that on New
Years Eve at a party on New
Years Eve, two thousand people
were gathered and Rodrigue read
the story of the Lorax to
them and how they need to
protect the trees.
Exciting beyond belief.
We never would have thought that
would be possible.
And so our project Lorax now and
reforestation is in its infancy
but we see the possibilities of
where it can go.
We recognize that maybe it's
going to take us to a place with
alternative fuel sources,
already one of them said, maybe
we need to think about
alternative fuel sources, see
they're beginning to think about
it and then we can begin to look
at this.
You know, Brian Flannigan
who's a man who works in Haiti
in reforestation says, "When
you're doing this, what you can
do is start small."
And he goes, "what you're doing
is planting these many
nurseries, you getting people
talking about it and you get
them excited about it and before
you know it, it become theirs."
It becomes their own and they
will begin to find solutions and
they'll begin to see how it can
work and how it can work for
them to make their country more
beautiful.
♪ [music playing] ♪♪.
>> Bobson Mercier:
Deforestation is a complex
issue with serious consequences
for Haiti and the
international community
if something isn't done.
We have joined hands to counter
the cycle of deforestation by
educating each other in the
importance of the trees and the
environment, and to cover the
mountain tops with green hats,
with aspirations to return Haiti
back into the beauty when she
was called the Pearl of the
Antilles.
♪ [music playing] ♪♪.
>>Roy Lanham:
So much though, this is one of
our trips to Haiti, we were
approached by the citizens of
Fonds-Verrettes, the mayor, the
second major the third mayor
and one of the other leaders of
the community, they presented
us with a letter to take back
to our congress on how to help
protect a water shed area.
So because they know there are
800,000 trees in this area and
if they can protect it with a
[unclear dialogue] with a wall,
with a rock wall they know that
they can protect those trees so
that it can protect farm land
and homes down below.
They didn't ask us for money
they asked if they can go back
and talk to our congress with
USAID, that does projects all
over the world because they know
its a major project.
Will they consider helping them
save these trees?
Amazing!
And that's how relationships
can begin to transform lives
and its possible.
And so that's what we're doing
now, we're talking to our
congress people about how can
we, how can...
That's just an example of
what can happen when we put
our heads together.
[unclear dialogue] as they say
in Creole.
When we put our heads together
what is possible?
Will Haiti ever be 62%
rainforest, no, I'm not a dummy
and they know that too.
But can it be more beautiful,
can it be sustainable, can we
begin to see the rains come
back?
Can they begin to realize that
every time it rains they don't
have to live in fear that their
house is going to wash away?
Yes, yes and we can be a part of
that and that's the gift that we
can bring as we walk with our
brothers and sisters in Haiti,
regarding reforestation.
♪ [music playing] ♪♪.