BETH HOYT: Good evening,
ladies and gentlemen.
Welcome to the final night of
YouTube Comedy Week in sunny
Playa-- who gives a shit.
I'm Beth Hoyt.
MICHAEL GALLAGHER:
Thank you, Diane.
As you can see, all the
stars are here tonight
for Set List Live.
You can literally smell
the glamour.
Isn't that right,
Steve Greene?
STEVE GREENE: Michael, if you're
not here you might as
well be dead.
BETH HOYT: Or you can just watch
it from home on your--
on youtube.com/comedyweek, so.
MICHAEL GALLAGHER: Diane, if you
missed any of this week's
webtastic events you can use
your mouse and literally walk
the red carpet--
that is, your mouse pad--
youtube.com/comedyweek.
STEVE GREENE: If you're not
drinking yet, crack open a
bottle because Smosh, The
Annoying Orange, and The Onion
all have uploaded new
videos on YouTube.
BETH HOYT: As well as two new
videos, Henry Phillips' "You
and Your Fucking Coffee" and the
Eric Wareheim Major Lazer
video collaboration,
"Bubble Butt."
MICHAEL GALLAGHER: I don't know
about you, Steve, but I
have a boner.
BETH HOYT: OK.
MICHAEL GALLAGHER: Diane,
how you doing there?
BETH HOYT: See, well, my name
is Beth, so there's that.
But also, you guys are really
going off book.
STEVE GREENE: Diane, I don't
know how you are, but I could
fill a cup.
With excitement.
BETH HOYT: Right.
MICHAEL GALLAGHER: That's
what I'm talking about.
Male juices.
Comedy Week!
BETH HOYT: Can we-- can we
get security over here?
Is that--?
MICHAEL GALLAGHER:
Thank you, Diane!
Thank you, America!
STEVE GREENE: Enjoy
the glamour!
Enjoy the Hollywood!
MICHAEL GALLAGHER: Good night!
Good night!
We're this way, Steve.
BETH HOYT: Awesome.
OK, great.
Once again--
OK.
Right.
Great.
Also, just to throw it in there
again, my name is Beth.
Beth in Show, Beth Hoyt.
Thanks a lot.
Thanks, guys.
OK.
We'll be back a little later for
the second show, but right
now here's Set List Live.
[INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC]
MALE SPEAKER: Hey, YouTube!
Welcome to Set List, Stand-Up
Without a Net.
Now here's your host,
Paul Provenza!
PAUL PROVENZA: Thank you.
Good evening.
Hello, YouTube.
What are you doing
with your lives?
Welcome to Set List, Stand-Up
Without a Net.
It's very exciting.
This is our first live
stream ever.
It's really, really exciting
for us because stands--
Set List is a different kind
of stand up comedy show.
Set List is unique.
Now normally when you see a
stand up comedian perform,
you're seeing them give you
material that they have
created, they have crafted,
they have honed, they have
perfected, to give
you the very best
for your comedy value.
That's too much hard work.
None of that happens here.
What happens here is
far more dangerous.
The comedians are going to take
a leap into the comedy
unknown, ladies and gentlemen.
Now let me explain what
a set list is.
A set list looks something
like this--
something like this--
there you go.
This is a set list for a band.
It's basically the names
of their titles--
the titles of their songs--
in the order
they're going to do them.
Everybody knows what
the show is.
A comedian's set list?
A little bit different.
Generally written on the back
of the hand, because nobody
else has to see it.
And these words here--
who knows what they mean?
Only the comedian knows what's
on their set list.
Two words could be 15
minutes of material.
It could be a phrase they want
to remember to try out.
Who knows?
It could mean anything.
Only the comedian knows.
Well, tonight, ladies and
gentlemen, we are taking out
of that comfort zone
some of the finest
comedians in America.
They are coming up
here without a
set list of any kind.
We are going to give
them a set list.
They are going to improvise a
stand up comedy routine out of
thin air for your sadistic
enjoyment.
[APPLAUSE]
Here's an example of some of
the kinds of items we'll be
giving them.
Shame Ringtone, I think you know
when that one comes in.
Caucasionally.
Violent Vegan Poetry.
Frenema.
I could do 10 minutes on
that myself, folks.
But we guarantee that none of
the set list items that the
comedians will be given tonight
have appeared on any
comedian's set list ever.
They've never seen them.
You've never seen them.
They will come up here, they
will appear on the screen one
at a time, the comedians will
see their set list topics at
the exact same moment that
you see them for
the very first time.
We're not only taking them out
of their comfort zone by
leaving them up here with set
lists they have never
imagined, we're also taking them
out of their comfort zone
with subject matter or
topics or whatever.
The whole point is to watch
the moment of creation.
It is a journey, ladies
and gentlemen.
Enjoy it.
The comedians have one rule.
That is, use your material--
excuse me.
Sorry.
I just said the worst
thing you could say.
Their rule is use your
imaginations, not your material.
You play a very big part here.
Your role is, don't be a dick.
OK?
They're coming out here, leaping
into the comedy abyss
with nothing protecting them
but really fragile egos.
You must be the wind
under their wings.
You must carry them to
the comedic heights.
You're a big part of this.
You can watch the process, you
can see how each comedian
deals differently with this.
Show them your support.
Show them your love.
Don't be the guy who goes to
the circus and hopes the
tightrope walker doesn't
make it.
That's all you have to do,
ladies and gentlemen.
And I think it'll become
self-explanatory.
Should we just crack on
and give it a go?
[APPLAUSE]
All right!
Keep that energy going,
ladies and gentlemen.
For your first fearless set
lister, here at Set List,
Stand-Up Without a Net, live
streaming on YouTube, ladies
and gentlemen, the never
before seen set
list of Mr. John Dore!
JOHN DORE: Hi.
Thank you, Paul.
Oh, boy.
Here we go.
Stand up without a net.
Set list.
All right.
I'm gonna let you in on a little
secret I've never told
anyone ever before, but
this is a fact.
I am straight.
Never told anyone that before,
but that's one of the reasons
the US government asked me to
do something very special.
They asked me to go and
spy for the Chinese.
And you're probably wondering,
whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, Steve.
And I would say, name's John.
And then you would say, sorry.
John, I thought you were
spying for the Chinese.
It's like, yeah, but who you
think funds the operation?
The United States.
And that's right.
I spy for the Chinese.
You're probably wondering what
I do for the Chinese.
Like, are you concerned?
Like, do you wonder what
I do for the Chinese?
Do you want to know what
Well I'm not going to fucking
tell you, am I, because then I
wouldn't be a very good spy.
You saying yes, I want to know
what you do for the Chinese,
means you want to see me dead
right here on the spot.
So that's what you want?
Unbelievable.
Unberievable, as some
people would say.
But I'll tell you
this right now.
That's only when I'm spying,
I'll say unberievable.
Only when I'm spying.
Because, yes, I stereotypically
have to fit in
with the Chinese, all right?
And they traditionally have
trouble with L's and R's.
Now let's move on to the next
topic before I get really
racist, all right?
I [? confess ?]
for every one at home and in
the audience and myself.
Oh, boy.
Oh, yeah.
One summer I went camping with
my uncle, and, uh--.
[APPLAUSE]
All right, let's move on.
Let's move on.
All right.
Sometimes that's all
you need, I guess.
I don't know.
Let's move on.
Or maybe there's more.
Don't move on.
Maybe there is more.
Oh, we moved on.
Can we go back?
Oh, we can't go back now!
What do you mean, oh no?
I don't know if you can hear
at home, but a lady
just said, oh no.
Like you've had an abortune.
You don't even know what
an abortune is.
You can't oh no it.
That word doesn't exist until
it came up on the screen.
Oh no, he's going to talk
about abortunes.
Unbeliev--
my daughter had an abortune.
You don't have to be a girl
to have an abortune.
Guys have abortunes.
You don't even know what
an abortune is.
It's not what you think,
all right?
You're thinking it is-- it's
a musical abortion.
That's what you're
all thinking.
You're not far off, I'll
give you that.
You're not far off.
You're very close.
I'll tell you what
an abortune is.
You've heard of the
band Nickelback?
Have you ever heard of
the band Nickelback?
That's an abortune.
Oh, that's a little--
don't clap.
I feel bad about that
one for two reasons.
It is a little too easy.
Also, they are from my home
country of Canada, so I feel
terrible about that.
Let's move on from-- let's
go back to Rock, Paper,
Handjob if we can.
Oh, too late.
Speaking of rock, paper,
handjob, I've got to, to tell
you story here.
This is all part of it.
Oh, god.
I used to pace like this
when I was in the
lunch line at school.
Oh, fuck me.
You get one and you're just
like, oh, no what do you do?
But you know what?
You just talk it out.
And I'd get to the front of the
line at the cafeteria and
be handed my order and I'd say,
excuse me, what is this?
And the lunch lady would say,
none of your business.
And I'd say, no, no, no, it
actually is my business.
I paid for it.
I want to know what it is.
She'd say, well, it's
not in my job
description to tell you.
And I'd say, you know what?
I think it is.
I want to know what I'm putting
in my body, all right?
I want to know if I'm going
to be replenishing my
carbohydrates while my glycogen
windows are open.
And the lunch lady says,
I don't know what
you're talking about.
I didn't graduate high school.
And then I say, that's
a mean joke.
Like if someone were to say that
on stage, I'm glad you
said it, and some of this--
this is factual-- yeah.
Long story short, you're going
have to buy my CD if you want
to hear the end of it.
Because I haven't quite
written it yet.
Don't clap.
This is horrible.
Trust me, this is horrible.
Get rid of that one.
[APPLAUSE]
Uh, OK.
For this one I'm going to need a
volunteer from the audience.
Uh, sir, if you don't mind
just come on up here.
Thank you very much.
OK.
And stand right there
for a second.
Yeah.
OK, can sit down now.
Thank you very much.
So remember where
he was, right?
So my uncle would take us
camping and every now and then
he would say, hey, you want
to play a little RPH?
And I would say, I'd say,
yo yo, what are
you, a lunch lady?
What's your agenda?
What's that mean?
And he'd say, no, I'm
not a lunch lady.
It's called rock,
paper, handjob.
And I'd say lookit, I'm not very
comfortable with rock and
paper, but other than that, I
think we've got a deal here.
And long story longer, um,
ladies and gentleman, I'm
going to introduce my uncle
to you right now.
Actually, no, he's not
here to do that.
But if he was here, I'd be very
proud to say he gives one
of the better handjobs,
because--
and I know you're thinking
that's disgusting.
It is not disgusting.
It's tender.
It was very tender.
He wasn't rude about.
It wasn't rude about
it at all.
It didn't feel like incest
at any moment.
It just felt natural.
It felt fun.
It felt--
felt familiar.
Do you know what I mean?
And the reason it felt
familiar's because of course
we share genes.
And we share jeans.
So he's like--
OK, let's skip it.
I don't know what else is going
to happen with that one.
The people watching
at home just--
hey, anyone know the score
of the Sens game?
That'll prove this is
live, by the way.
No?
Anyone know who the Sens are?
They're a hockey team
from Ottawa.
Grow the fuck up.
All right.
Um.
OK, here's the thing.
Don't transfer me, OK?
Leave me in the jail.
I do not want you
to transfer me.
I do not need to go anywhere.
I got a really funny feeling
about this and besides, you
haven't even heard me
out yet, all right?
You ever gone duck hunting
in the city?
It sounds crazy, but I'll
tell you something.
It is loads of fun.
And rarely--
the problem is, he didn't hear
me say duck, all right?
So that's what city
duck hunting is.
You yell duck and hope
the gentleman ducks.
And if he doesn't then the
lady's going to have brain on
her dress and that's
just a fact.
OK, lookit, I know I'm
in America, and--
too soon?
Too soon, is that it?
Probably too late
is what it is.
It's too late.
And guys, you can ew
it if you want, but
this is my big closer.
You know what?
Fuck it.
I'm done.
I'm absolutely finished.
[APPLAUSE]
Hey, Paul.
Sorry about that.
No, I'm--
I'm done.
PAUL PROVENZA: What are
you sorry about, John?
JOHN DORE: Oh, just I'll
see you later.
If you hear a gunshot
go off, that's me.
PAUL PROVENZA: John Dore,
ladies and gentlemen!
[APPLAUSE]
Oh, ho ho.
Oh.
That was some fancy skating
there, John Dore.
You Canuck.
Um.
Well, that's how
Set List works.
Pretty clear, eh?
It's like weaving gold
out of lead.
It's alchemy, what happens
here on the
stage, ladies and gentlemen.
And we're going to
kick it off again
with this next gentleman.
A Set--
a favorite of Set List, he's
one of our UK cousins.
Ladies and gentlemen, are you
ready for your next fearless
Set Lister?
Ladies and gentlemen, the never
before seen set list of
the brilliant Mr.
Matt Kirshen.
MATT KIRSHEN: Yeah.
Yeah.
Hey.
Hello, the internet.
Uh, I just want to thank you
for being here in the room.
For those you all watching at
home, if you do choose to
comment underneath our
video, just remember
my mum reads them.
So maybe call her something
as well.
She'd love to be a faggot.
She would.
She would love--
she's a woman in her
sixties, you know.
No way she'd be as well-dressed
as a derogatory
term for a gay man.
I did one of their shows
on Monday, and eh.
That seemed to be the go to.
So never read the comments.
Let's see what you got.
One of the things that's nice
about growing up in Europe is
how much more fancy
things seem.
It's the joy of coming
to America as a Brit.
You're like, everything just
sounds that little bit nicer.
Is it a burning sensation
as you pee or is
it a tingling fountain?
Is it a unsightly rash
or are you dappled?
Speckled, if you will.
Horribly, horribly infected with
a disease that's caused
exclusively by sticking
a part of a human in
another part of a human--
or koala.
That's the only other species I
know of that gets chlamydia.
That is a fact.
Most of these people are
connected to the internet.
Check it out.
Koala chlamydia.
Genuine problem.
So like to point out, nothing
to do with me.
I don't necessarily want
that association.
I know how Google
bombing works.
I know it wouldn't take too much
effort for it to be the
case that when you start typing
in my name, koala
chlamydia is the next
thing that comes up.
It's a the risk I'm willing
to take, the internet.
Here's the thing.
If you're in prison--
I've never been in prison, but
I imagine if I were, I would
be kneeling a lot.
[APPLAUSE]
There's very little that I
could get in [? Cajun ?].
Maybe--
I don't know--
I could be a librarian, maybe.
Teach some of the fellow
prisoners how to get through
their prison degree.
But we know that's not
my job's going to be.
I will at best--
I would probably be on my knees
in a cell, but I'd maybe
be able to find religion, find
faith, go to the chaplain's
room and be on my knees there.
I wouldn't escape it,
is what I'm saying.
I--
you don't want to be in prison
with a face and cheekbones of
a choir boy, which I have
and will always have.
I think I could be like,
seventy, gray, and balding,
and I'll still look like a sort
of withered choir boy.
I'll look like a choir boy
with a wasting disease.
Those diseases--
it's like that genetic condition
that very few people
have the way they look 60
from the age of 12.
That that'll be me, age 60.
Probably be me and
the real thing.
We could talk together.
And I'd be in prison
with that.
I don't know why I'd
be in prison.
There are very few things that
I'd be willing to do that
would put me in prison, but--
we've all killed a man.
We've all done a bit
of murder, right?
No one's watching this.
This isn't a confession.
Next topic.
There must've been,
there must've been
some sheepish ones.
There must've been some, like,
there must've been these some
closet-- like, I think once
you got to the mid, mid to
late '30s in Germany, you pretty
much-- like it's harder
to not be a Nazi than
to be a Nazi, right?
I think, you know, people
mostly went for
the whole Nazi thing.
But there's got to be a few
like at the beginning, you
know, late '20s, early '30s,
where there'll be like one guy
who's all proud.
He's like, heil Hitler
and he's doing--
I don't--
I was about to do the mustache
but I don't think
they did the mustache.
But they'd be doing like the
thing and there'd be a couple
in the back who were
like, oh, maybe.
Just sneaking their way there.
One day, one day I'll have
strength in numbers.
For the moment I'm just
going to hate
them lot from a distance.
I'm going to hide
there and just--
it's quite adorable until you do
the full salute, isn't it?
I never realized how lovely.
Like until you-- like once you
full up do the whole straight
and throw it right up then
that's like no, that's bad,
that's unpleasant.
But just a little
bit of the ways?
You know, if you go a little--
go the full way and it's full
on heil Hitler.
But you just go a little
bit it's like cooey.
You know?
Kind of adorable, it's--
it's the way you'd, you'd
wave to, like, the
daughter of your neighbor.
That's the difference.
Just a slight flex in the
arm and a wiggle.
That's all it takes.
That--
that's the difference between
genocide and adorable.
OK.
You're going to have to move
it on to the next topic.
I could bluff off this one.
I could bullshit my way through
this one, but I did
Set List a month ago
and that topic came
up and I'm not cheesing.
Next topic.
Can we go back a topic?
I was raised Jewish, and--
no.
I can't--
I can't do Nazi and then
instantly going into
anti-Semitism as well.
I can't do that in a row.
Really engaging.
It's gotta be--
it's a bit suspicious that
we all lose our teeth.
It's a little bit suspicious,
isn't it?
Supposedly it's so that bigger
teeth can grow through, but do
we really need the
bigger teeth?
Like I--
I think--
I think I would do perfectly
well with--
I've got quite big teeth
and I don't think they
need to be this big.
I think if I just had the
original lot, I'd look fine.
I don't think it's evolution
that is responsible for us
having the second set of
teeth coming through,
the first half leaving.
I don't believe in God.
I don't believe in Santa.
But I once put a tooth under my
pillow, and when I woke up
in the morning, that tooth was
gone and money was there.
Explain that, science.
Explain that, Professor
Richard Dawkins.
If that is your real name.
You explain that.
Some stuff you can't work out.
Occam's razor.
Likeliest solution
is the most--
happened.
It's the exact wording,
including that pause.
Go to the Oxford English
Dictionary.
That's how it happens.
Maybe not Webster's, maybe
not in America.
Oxford has got that
awkward pause.
Go to Oxford Dictionary,
that's the definition.
Occam's razor.
Most likely solution
is m-- happens.
That's how we do it. 'Cause
in Britain, more adorable.
We already proved that.
So--
no, what's more likely?
That there's a genetic, there's
an evolutionary reason
for one row of tooth-- of teeth
to leave and another row
of teeth to grow in?
Or that there's some weird imp,
some freakish, smaller
than average, semi-magical
creature, that wants
children's teeth for a reason?
We just tell our kids this.
We tell our kids there's the--
that's the-- that's
fucking horrible.
That is a awful thing--
I mean they--
no, not adult teeth.
They just want children's
teeth.
The tooth fairy, there's only
one thing, and it specifically
wants the teeth of children.
Once you're over a certain
age it's teeth are of
no interest to you.
The children's teeth,
they do it.
Just for a ritual.
Just so--
I don't actually imagine the
tooth fairy lives in some
building this made entirely
of children's teeth.
That's--
I've never got that noise out
of people on stage before.
I've been doing stand
up for a while.
I've never said something
that has actually got
people to go, ughhh.
That was a visceral reaction
I got off that.
That was as if at one point in
your childhood you actually
went to a building that was
all children's teeth.
And I just stirred up a
horrendous memory and now
you're gonna have to go to
counseling and it's my fault.
Well, you'd have to write it
in blood, wouldn't you?
I guess if you were, like,
if you were a--
if you were a graffiti artist
who was a bit sad--
well more than a bit sad.
You have to be very sad
to commit suicide.
If you're a bit sad
don't commit--
don't commit suicide anyway.
If you're watching this
and complement--
contemplating suicide, I mean I
shouldn't be the one to tell
you this, but, like, get help.
OK?
Don't--
I hope I've cheered
you up a bit.
I hope I haven't stirred up a
memory of you being in a house
of teeth and that was
the final straw.
Go open a different tab.
Stop watching us for a second
and go to-- there's plenty of
help things.
But if you do insist on
it, if you've really
made up your mind--
and I mean really--
but still get help.
But if you've really made up
your mind, make an effort.
You know, there aren't
enough adventurous
suicides these days.
If you--
draw-- draw something pretty
with the blood as you're--
you know, you've got a limited
amount of time, so don't go
too adventurous.
We're not talking Sistine
Chapel here.
Maybe something funny so when
they discover you they're
like, ahhh-- ha ha ha.
Like a rabbit with a massive
cock and balls, or
something like that.
Just in blood.
Just something that makes them
go, well, this is sad.
But not as sad as it could be.
It's what he would
have wanted.
A final little giggle.
And just-- and they don't call
it-- and that-- but like the
person would hear that noise.
They'd go like, what happened?
What happened?
And they'd burst in as well and
do exactly the same thing,
one after another, including--
and then the ambulance
guys as well.
But they probably
seen it before.
Listen, it's been a pleasure
talking to you.
Enjoy the rest of your show.
I've been Matt Kirshen.
Thank you, the internet.
PAUL PROVENZA: Matt Kirshen!
Matt Kirshen, ladies
and gentlemen.
Uh, and it's true what he about
koalas, by the way.
It's not just a cover story.
It's true.
Um, yeah, you guys having
a good time?
You folks at home?
All of you when you get a chance
check out the Nerdist
Channel series of Set List,
Stand-Up Without a Net.
One going up every week.
Just check when-- soon as you're
done watching th--
not now.
Fuck it.
Let's bring out our
next fearless Set
Lister, what do you say?
Ladies and gentlemen, will you
welcome the never before seen
set list of another favorite
of ours, the brilliant Miss
Kira Soltanovich!
KIRA SOLTANOVICH: Thank you.
It's Paul Provenza,
guys, right?
It's exciting stuff.
Look at you.
You got dropped off here
by an adult, right?
Good for you!
That's exciting!
You're out.
You're on a date.
With your-- with Jude Law.
You're going to lose your
virginity tonight.
It's going to happen
for you, right?
It's going to happen.
You excited?
OK.
I'm excited for you.
Can I watch?
Is that inappropriate?
All right.
Hey, you guys who are watching
on the internet!
Pull your pants up,
you perverts.
Nah, keep 'em down.
It's fine.
It doesn't matter to me.
I don't care.
I'm just going to talk to fine
folks, youngsters over here.
Oh, is this like
a high school?
Did a bus drop you guys off?
Holy cow.
All right.
Let's have some fun, you know?
We're going to discuss
some things.
A lot of them will go directly
over your head, young
man, but it's OK.
Whatever anyone around you is
laughing, you laugh too.
All right?
And you will be just fine.
Oh, man.
Speaking of feeling
old, right?
You know, I'm just a
creature of habit.
I'm going to tell you
guys right now.
I really am.
Here's what it is.
You know, you do get
set in your ways.
You know what I mean?
You get set in your ways.
I was just printing up
something-- like something I
wrote-- on my dot matrix
earlier today, and--
it's a printer that goes
like this, [BUZZES].
And then after that
one line is done--
you don't even know what
dot matrix is.
Do you have any idea?
You don't know.
Is it a shoe brand?
Is it the new Christian
band out there?
Is it--
the Dot Matrix!
Ahhhh!
For Jesus!
No.
It's a printer, all right?
And I'm not going to get
rid of it, all right?
I'm not.
With your fancy I can print
off a smartphone, wh--
how smart is a smartphone
if you can't
type in the word boobless?
How smart?
Oh, did I just blow
your minds?
That's right.
You don't even know what
a pager is, do you?
You don't even know.
Oh, my god.
Do you even know what
a crackhead is?
Because that's what pagers
were used for--
for crackheads.
Were your parents born
in the '80s?
How old are you,
is my question.
I do.
I still use one.
I still use it.
I'll tell you why.
And it's not because I'm
a drug dealer from
a few decades ago.
It's because I never went
to medical school.
And I'm constantly waiting
for a table.
I figure, why not beat
'em to the punch?
Boom.
We'll let you know when your
table at the Cheesecake
Factory is ready.
I go no.
No.
I'll let you know.
When this goes [BUZZ]
boobless [BUZZ]
I will seat myself.
Boom.
In your face.
And then I also pretend
like I have surgery.
Oh, goodness.
So, uh, if you guys don't know
anything about me, Soltanovich
is my last name, Soltanovich.
So yes, I am a Soviet
Communist.
Thank you.
And uh--
you don't even know
what that is.
Uh, just--
nothing in the front row is
going to [? know ?] that one.
Um, so the first stereotype you
think of when you think of
Russians, liquid people.
That's right.
We eat our breakfast,
lunch, and dinner.
Guess what?
We don't care.
That's the stereotype that
you think about us.
Thank you for saying hot.
I appreciate that.
That's also the second one.
We are.
We are liquid people.
It's one of those things where
we don't like to talk about
it, because why bring it up?
Why talk about something
that is both fun--
vodka--
and destructive--
drinking every meal?
We don't bring it up.
We don't want to be judged
by you, or you.
Everyone else is cool.
I don't mind if anyone else
judges us, just not this boy
band in the front row.
They're making me very uneasy.
But it's true.
It's true.
Hey, are Asian people
bad drivers?
Not all of them, come on.
Not all of them.
When they're doing math
while driving,
yes, that's very dangerous.
Do all Mexicans have
lawnmowers?
I don't know.
I don't hang out
with Mexicans.
Are all Russians
liquid people?
Yes.
Yes, we are.
And we're not ashamed of it.
Or of our pagers.
I'm not going to be ashamed
of a pager, everybody.
I'm not going-- you're not
going to shame me.
Oh, if I could impart
any kind of wisdom
on you young people--
you young, young people-- first
thing I would do is take
out your smartphone and
Google Lionel Richie.
'Cause you don't know
who that is.
If I could impart-- seriously,
I'm being serious right now--
let's just really get
down to brass tacks,
as they say, right?
Which is a new band.
We sometimes in life-- you know
what I mean-- you come to
a fork in the road.
It zigs when you want to zag.
Which way do I go?
What do I do?
Do I finish junior high?
Go to DeVry?
What-- what do I?
Change my liquid every meal?
What do I do?
And if you don't believe in a
higher power, you know what I
mean, and if no one on Facebook
is giving you good
advice, do what I
do, you guys.
And I have lived by this.
And I have lived a very
fulful-- fulfil--
I don't want to even say
the word because it's
that full of fill.
It's a very fulfilled life.
It's fulfilling out
of my face.
Alliteration.
Boom.
You try it.
Here's what I do when I
get stuck and I say,
god, what do I do?
Please, universe out there?
And it's always the
same thing.
It is always the same thing.
Dancing on the ceiling.
Think about it.
It's all you have to do.
Just look up to that ceiling
and you dance on it.
Look him up.
Wikipedia.
Thank you so much.
My name's Kira Soltanovich.
PAUL PROVENZA: Kira
Soltanovich!
Kira Soltanovich.
Folks, this is a nice time to
give a big round of applause
to the evil genius creator and
the man behind the Set List,
Mr. Troy Conrad.
And I'm anxious to see this next
journey we're going to go
on, ladies and gentlemen,
because this tour guide takes
us to places we don't
often go.
Ladies and gentlemen, are you
ready for your next fearless
Set Lister?
Give it up for the never before
seen set list of Mr.
Moshe Kasher!
MOSHE KASHER: All right,
all right.
OK.
It's been pretty good
so far, huh?
Yeah.
I'm about to take a shit
on that right now.
I don't know, straight up don't
know, I straight up
can't do this.
I just fucking can't do it.
In the back I heard them.
They were talking.
They were like, we're running
a little low on time.
Make 'em go quicker.
This is the fucking internet.
Why-- there's nothing--
is something else happening
afterwards?
Is there a live stream of "Two
Girls, One Cup" we're
about to get into?
I think we'll be OK if we go a
little long on the internet.
You know, the place where they
store all of the information?
Sometimes I write jokes that I
find disrespectful myself.
The very topic of my own joke
I find to be offensive.
I wrote a joke about this when
I was younger, when I had a
less nuanced idea
of sexuality.
I thought oh, it'd be funny if
I wrote a long joke about how
I fuck old-ass people--
brittle-ass hips,
popping bones--
from the streets.
I'm a straight up gangster.
I'm a Crip.
What's up?
Find me.
YouTube.com/anonymous.
So I wrote this long bit about
how I sleep with old people so
that you don't have to.
But then I started
doing it for real
because what would happen--
I started off comedy
like, 1920, 1922.
I was basically the
first dude.
It was me, it was Mel--
Mel B-- we called him Mel
B back then, Mel Brooks.
It was Sammy Davis, Jr. We
didn't like him because of--
you know.
And--
because of the lazy eye.
What was happening for
you guys in that?
Anyway, I was the young dude.
They call me the young cat,
the Crip of comedy.
The Crips had started
at that point, 1922.
And I started doing my big
closer, which was I sleep with
the elderly.
And then I-- and then I'd go
like this and everybody would
say, so that you
don't have to.
And I'd be like, that's
my time, y'all.
And then I'd just ejaculate.
That was what comedy was
like before all those
standards and practices.
That's why we're getting
back to the internet.
I first started comedy on
the internet in 1922.
Here's the point.
What ended up happening was as
a result of my big closer--
I sleep with the elderly so that
you don't have to-- after
the show I would just be lined
up, just like the guy-- just
like lines of just
senior citizens.
I mean straight up cr--
people-- dialysis,
they were just like.
You know what I mean?
They were just like,
one favor. .
Just pound it out before I go.
You know what I mean?
Pound it out before I go.
That's what they would say.
They were very weird
old people.
And so I would.
I would do that.
I started to-- slowly, over the
time, over the course of
my comedy career--
I started to just knock boots
with many an old person.
And I started to realize
the flaw in my very--
in my own joke, which is that I
don't sleep with the elderly
so you don't have to.
I sleep with the elderly
so that I can.
It's the best.
It's better than-- what do you
want a young woman for?
[INAUDIBLE]
I fuck women, surprise.
What do you-- you know
what I mean?
Like, what do I want
a young woman for?
Bad conversation and,
like, perfect body?
No thanks.
I want some--
I want some leather.
You know what I mean?
I want to slide--
I want to pull it around
myself like a lap band.
I sleep with the elderly
because I can.
Yeah.
Yeah, there's a lot of people
that are going to have a lot
of explaining to do when they
get up-- first of all, Jesus.
I'm a Jew.
Not real.
But--
no, he's real.
He's just--
a really real great guy.
No, I'm just--
I'm sure, I'm sure
he's up there.
I'm sure he's got a beard and
he's going to be all floating
when-- you know what I mean?
He's going to be like, hello,
and welcome to heaven.
You'll be like, uh, Jesus, why
do you sound like a ghost?
He's like, I always
have been a ghost.
And then he'll pull off is own
face and it'll be like the--
it'll be the father--
God, the Father, and he'll pull
it off again and it'll be
God, the son, and he'll pull it
off again and it'll be the
Holy Ghost.
Holy Ghost, get it?
A ha ha ha.
And then it'll be like, you
laugh like the Count and he'll
be like, I'm also the Count.
I am all things.
All things are possible
for me.
No one gets to heaven
but by me.
And I'd be like, I'm Jewish.
And he'd be like, me too.
The point--
the point is, if Jesus is
standing at the pearly gates
or whatever, and people
get up there,
there's a lot of people--
I'm on Twitter, @moshekasher,
please follow me--
and there's a lot of people
who're going to have a lot of
explaining to do.
A lot of you YouTube people
are going to have a lot of
explaining to do.
You know what I mean?
We go to church on Sunday, but
then you log onto the internet
and bully some kid--
you know what I mean-- maybe
some kid who's maybe 33 years
old and trying his best to
make a career at stand up
comedy that doesn't need
these negative
comments all the time.
You're going to have to explain
your maker, Jesus--
the magic man--
why you say I look like Buddy
Holly, why you say I look like
Harry Potter, why you say I look
like every white person
with glasses that has
ever existed.
And then Jesus will be like,
have you met Rob Delaney?
I love that guy.
Great jokes.
And then I'll be like,
yeah, I met him.
He was the main bully on Twitter
this whole time.
I'm into some freaky
shit, right?
No, I am.
But I'm not--
I'm not, I'm not the best.
I mean, I'm--
I'm the best stand up comedian
you'll ever see, obviously.
Thank you so much, guys.
But I'm not the best at S&M.
I didn't invent the shit.
You know what I mean?
I'm an amateur at best.
Every year there's the AVN in
Las Vegas, where they-- they
honor all the best pornographers
in the world and
they give awards away for
things like that.
I've won many an award--
the best lap band act out,
I won that award--
but not everybody knows this.
That's the hotels in Las Vegas--
the AVN pornography
awards-- if you go to that--
the AVN awards--
you take the elevator to the
basement and then you walk
down five more flights.
In the dungeon of the AVN
awards is the dungeon
captivity awards.
Now, some of the first winners
of this were of course the
Spanish, for the Spanish
Inquisition.
They won a lot of great
awards for that.
There was course the "Goodbye
Horses" guy.
Tuck your dick between your
legs, that was his move.
"Goodbye Horses," that
was an improv.
That was-- he was
doing Set List.
I'm serious.
The "Goodbye Horses" guy, this
was straight up-- it just said
fucking do some freaky shit.
And he just tucked and
he went for it.
That guy was the first winner.
Now, I did win an award one
time for spooling thread
around my own balls for
more than a week,
but that was an accident.
People thought I was doing it as
a performance piece because
I did film it, of course, and
live stream it on [? Josh. ?]
But no, that was just
an accident.
I won an amateur award.
But the greatest winner, of
course, of all time--
the greatest dungeon captivity
winner of all time--
do you guys know who it was?
It was the last dude.
It was the dude you have
to explain Twitter to.
It was that Jesus dude for his
wonderful trick, stay in a
cave for three days, float up to
heaven, come back down, and
change the world.
That was Jesus.
[LAUGHS]
I mean, it's the
old dichotomy.
It's the old pussy-dick
dichotomy,
you know what I mean?
Which way do you go, you
know what I mean?
Like, sir.
You seem like a dude that has
fucked a hermaphrodite or two
in your day.
Like--
no, I'm saying.
When you go out to-- let's
say you're a herm--
OK, so most some hermaphrodites
have made a
choice, right?
Or not a choice.
It's not a choice.
There's no choice.
But you're--
most hermaphrodites do
identify with gender.
But as we all know, gender
is mostly a myth.
So let's say you're a person
that's really straight down
the middle, know what I mean?
Maybe you are person that has
not decided male or female,
but you've got a-- you've got
maybe-- you've got a Moshe
Kasher sized dick, you know what
I mean, and you've got a
real nice tight teenage pussy.
And you have to make--
come on, guys, go with it.
It's the internet.
And you guys--
you've got to make a decision.
Tonight am I going to
get fucked or fuck?
But you know what?
Here's the deal.
Here's the field.
Here's the seal.
Here's the Seal, "Kissed
By A Rose." I've
been kissed by a rose.
As we all know-- as we all know,
except for the people on
the internet who've never
experienced the touch of
another's-- of a lover, that
at times it's difficult.
At times it's not worth
the effort.
You got out to the club.
You meet somebody.
You meet the pr-- you
go to the club.
You know the club.
We all go to da club, right?
We all do that, right?
Strikes?
OK.
The point is, you go out.
You meet somebody.
You have to engage in boring
conversation then you bring
them home and you guys-- you
guys rut like little animals.
And you come and you're like,
fuck, you're still here?
You know what I mean?
Sometimes it's not
worth the effort.
There's no tough hermaphrodite
decision.
You stay home, wrap
into yourself,
close the deal on yourself.
It's the greatest thing
anyone could do.
Don't oh.
Think, I wish.
I wish that could be me.
I truly do.
I wish you all could've
experienced what it was like
to perform for you because
it was a really great.
Thank you guys very much.
I'm Moshe Kasher.
Good night.
PAUL PROVENZA: Moshe Kasher!
Wow.
That was fun.
Folks, if any of you watching
out there are in Montreal or
Chicago, we'll be at Just for
Laughs festivals, we'll be at
the Edinburgh Fringe Festival
in Scotland.
Come see Set List Live.
And this is really exciting.
We always have people drop in
unexpectedly to do Set List
and we have a very special
treat just stopped in.
We're-- this is so exciting.
Ladies and gentlemen, are you
ready for your next fearless
Set Lister?
Are you ready for your next
fearless Set Lister?
Ladies and gentlemen, we welcome
the never before seen
set list of Mark Wahlberg!
DAN VAN KIRK: How
you guys doin'?
You guys doin' good?
How you doin'?
I like the way you look, OK?
You guys like my Voss bottle?
Celebrity edition.
You can't buy this.
It has to be given to you.
I was like, hey,
you know what?
I'm a movie star.
But I can do comedy too, OK?
Did you guys see "Ted"?
I destroyed that
fucking movie.
Did you guys see "Pain
and Gain"?
I let The Rock be in
that fucking movie.
He was like, Mark, can I
be in a movie with you?
I'm like, yes you can, Rock.
But you're going to stand
behind me the
whole fucking time.
He did.
You guys ready to do this?
You're welcome.
You guys ever feel like things
were made for you?
You know, you go into a house
and you're like, I could buy
this house.
Or you put on a pair of shoes
and you're like, did they make
these shoes for me?
That's how I feel about
reflections.
Sometimes I'll just be walking
places on Robertson's.
It's like a street
for rich people.
And I'll just be like, who
the fuck is that dude?
He looks like a hot
Donny Wahlberg.
It is a hot Donny Wahlberg.
It's me.
Let's do another one of these.
I'm gonna teach you guys
something, OK?
If you didn't learn this from
the movie "Pain and Gain," I'm
just going to fucking spoon
feed it to you.
Don't trust people
in tank tops.
I'm talking about all
of them, too, OK?
Out here in L.A. we got
this neighborhood.
It's called Echo Park.
Don't trust those people
in tank tops.
They got credit cards with
their dad's name on them.
All right?
Here's another thing.
If you live outside of the
Midwest, and you're not doing
manual labor, and you have a
tank top on, your car better
be broke down somewhere and
you just had to walk here.
Here's another thing.
I'm saving you guys time right
now, you know why?
'Cause I'm Mark Wahlberg.
I do good things.
Did you see "The Fighter"?
Maybe somebody else should have
gotten an Academy Award
for that fucking movie, that's
all I'm saying, OK?
I really fucking boxed
in that movie.
They were like, Mark,
do you have a
problem fighting people?
I'm like, what?
No, I don't have a problem
fighting people.
I'm from Boston.
I fought my kindergarten
teacher.
When I was 22.
I went back.
Here's the last thing
I'll say about this.
If you've got a pattern on your
shirt, but a different
pattern on your collar, don't
talk to that person.
They don't deserve to
be here and they're
willing to wait in lines.
At clubs.
In Las Vegas.
And you know what I do?
I don't wait in fucking lines,
I'll tell you that much.
That's called a Donny thing.
Line waiting.
All right, here's the deal.
When you're a former rap star
and then A-plus list
celebrity, some rules
don't apply.
For example, maybe I can't
read or write.
I can--
fucking assholes for laughing
at that shit-- but
maybe I can't, OK?
I got problems with
the alphabet.
First of all, I never liked
that fucking cereal.
It was like Apple Jacks
for smart kids.
I don't fucking want
this shit.
One time I spent two and a half
hours just trying to get
my own fucking name
in the bowl.
But I got it!
M-A-R-R-K. Fucking
nailed that shit.
But people invent things to
fucking make you wrong.
Like, for example--
I don't know if this applies
to you guys--
but you can drive as
fast as you want.
Sure, they have fucking rules
for that shit, but
one, pay for it.
You guys are in movies
like me, right?
We're all friends, this
is a safe place?
The other thing is you just tell
them when they pull over.
Be like, that's a rule
you set for yourself.
That applies to other people.
I'm Mark Wahlberg.
That doesn't apply to me.
You can try saying that.
I don't know how fucking
far it'll get you.
But if you whisper it, you can
get pretty fucking far.
I'll beat one more of these.
By the way, for the record--
don't tell this to everybody
else you saw tonight--
I'm winning.
I used to not be rich.
But I still wanted to
be with a girl, OK?
So sometimes you get
what you pay for.
But it's about the
exchange, OK?
So you might say to a girl, what
are you willing to do for
this amount of money?
She only fucking
blinked at me.
But here's the deal--
here's the deal, OK--
I put on the song
"Drive." Right?
She blinked to the beats.
That was extra.
You guys might not get that
shit, because you know why?
Newsflash.
You're not even Donny
Wahlberg.
You're like Linda Wahlberg, who
nobody even fucking talks
to and I only see at
family reunions.
Which you're all more than
welcome to, but nobody gets to
be my partner for the
egg toss, OK?
That's reserved because
I like to fucking win.
Let's do one more of these.
You guys, I've got to
tell you a secret.
I got a movie coming out, OK?
Yes, for the 32nd time,
I play a cop.
People got mad at me.
Did you guys see "The
Happening"?
Everybody got so mad
at that movie.
So what?
I wanted to be a teacher
for one god damn
fucking time in a movie.
I wanted to be something
other than a cop, OK.
But then when I sat down to
write a movie, I still ended
up writing myself as
a fucking cop.
Here's the deal, though.
I wrote it myself.
By hand.
You guys ever try to spell
check something
you wrote by hand?
There's no fucking red lines.
Problem being Mark fucking
Wahlberg is, by the time I got
done, I went to go hand it to
people, I had already sold it.
Now we established earlier
this is a safe place, OK?
So I'm going to tell
you guys this.
I don't know have the heart to
tell these people it's not
called "Investibation." It's
called "Investigation." But I
already fucking sold
that movie.
So now I had to write in, I'm
like, I'm a cop who can stop
touching himself.
And they were like--
which, to be honest, I fucking
do that shit anyway.
Thank you, guys.
You're awesome.
PAUL PROVENZA: That was
Daniel van Kirk!
Dan van Kirk.
Ladies and gentleman, you've
been fantastic.
Keep it going for all the
amazing, fearless comedians
you saw tonight.
You saw John Dore, Matt Kirshen,
Kira Soltanovich,
Moshe Kasher, and
Dan van Kirk.
Thank you for tuning into
Set List Live Stream.
Check us out on the
Nerdist channel.
Thank you everybody
at Nerdist.
Thank you [? just ?].
Thank you YouTube and all you
folks watching at home.
I'm Paul Provenza.
This has been Set List, Stand-Up
Without a Net.
Thank you.
[INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC]
BETH HOYT: We're here once more
at the YouTube space in
the lovely Playa del Rey,
named after Ghostbusters
singer Playa del
Rey Parker, Jr.
LANA MCKISSACK: Now is the last
live show of Comedy Week,
the music show, available
to watch on
YouTube.com/ComedyWeek.
We've had some great
stuff so far.
BETH HOYT: Yeah.
It's really--
I mean, it's really so sad.
It is.
LANA MCKISSACK: What's
the matter, Beth?
Are you sad that Comedy
Week is over, or--?
BETH HOYT: Yeah.
Yeah.
LANA MCKISSACK: Look, it was a
great time in all of our lives
but all things come to an end.
Just know that it will live
on in our hearts forever.
BETH HOYT: Well, yeah.
It's not that.
It's that-- it's just,
I never got paid.
LANA MCKISSACK: Oh.
BETH HOYT: Is the thing.
LANA MCKISSACK: I did.
BETH HOYT: Anyway, OK.
Let's take a look at what's been
going on here at Comedy
Week YouTube one final time.
MARK DOUGLAS: Welcome back to
Day Five of Comedy Week.
This is the Daily Rundown.
TODD WOMACK: And as a great poet
once said, it's Friday,
Friday, got to get
down on Friday.
So we've brought out the sexiest
man on YouTube to
announce today's big
events and debuts.
Toby--
MARK DOUGLAS: Thank
you very much--
TODD WOMACK: --Turner--
MARK DOUGLAS: --for the
Information and I will let the
people know in a very
sexy manner.
TODD WOMACK: --Toby Turner from
the channel Tobuscus.
MARK DOUGLAS: I think that's
supposed to say Mark Douglas,
because as we all know I am the
sexiest man on YouTube.
I was on the cover of "Shapely
Male" three times and so,
what's-- where's the info?
TODD WOMACK: We're going to
agree to disagree on that one.
We already a segment with Toby
so let's just roll that and
get away from this shot
as soon as possible.
[VIDEO PLAYBACK]
-[MOANING]
Oh.
Hey.
I'm sorry.
I've got to call you back.
I mean, you call me back.
I'm Toby Turner.
I'm YouTube's sexiest--
do I have to say that?
-Just do it!
-It doesn't look, like, douchey,
you don't think?
-Do it!
-Did you like the glasses
thing, though?
-Do it!
-Hey.
I'm Toby Turner.
YouTube's sexiest human.
I like walking, beaches, horses,
nuggets, biscuits,
funny videos also.
[WHIP NOISE]
Do you want to watch
a funny video too?
Then check out Set List Live,
where we throw out notes and
riff on subjects to see right
when the audience does.
Tonight on
YouTube.com/ComedyWeek--
no, I don't know where
you put your keys.
I don't know who you are.
Don't forget Smosh,
two naughty boys--
listen to me--
who made a video about their
favorite apple cider company,
Dixon Cider.
Get it?
[VIDEO PLAYBACK]
-But wait, there's more.
[? Tim ?] and [? Erica ?] also
released Major Lazer, "Bubble
Butt," featuring--
MARK DOUGLAS: Welcome to
another edition of
InterviewTube with Tobuscus.
TODD WOMACK: Toby, what
have you got going on
during Comedy Week?
TOBY TURNER: We posted an
animated episodes of "Tobuscus
Adventures" this week,
which is--
it's about zombies taking
over the world.
The character's trying to raise
money through a fund
raising campaign to buy weapons
to kill the zombies.
[VIDEO PLAYBACK]
-And, start campaign.
And now we wait.
-I said if they donated fifty
dollars you'd kill a zombie
with your fork.
-You can't tell them I'm
going to do stuff.
-Think fast.
TODD WOMACK: That was amazing.
Now we shed a tear of
fond farewell as we
bid you good day.
MARK DOUGLAS: Now get out there
and watch some more
Comedy Week videos
and subscribe to
the things you like.
We'll be back tomorrow.
TODD WOMACK: Adios.
"Shapely Male" magazine?
MARK DOUGLAS: Yes.
It's for women who like
something to grab onto.
TODD WOMACK: What?
MARK DOUGLAS: I'm tired
of these waif types.
Tobuscus.
TODD WOMACK: Who
told you that?
MARK DOUGLAS: The editor of
"Shapely Male" magazine.
TODD WOMACK: Is that
guy-- is it you?
MARK DOUGLAS: Maybe.
MALE SPEAKER: Just do it!
BETH HOYT: Welcome to
the big music show.
Tonight is the night where we
wrap up comedy week with our
tribute to one of the
things YouTube does
best, musical comedy.
Coming up tonight we have live
performances from Reggie
Watts, Nick Thune, Karen
Kilgariff, Dragon Boy Suede,
and Nice Peter.
Holy crap.
Our first performers you may
have seen on Conan or at Largo
here in Los Angeles.
We are lucky to have them as
they are on their way to the
airport to play to Sasquatch!
Music Festival tomorrow night.
So right now with a little bit
of relationship advice are
Megan Mullally and Stephanie
Hunt as Nancy and Beth.
[MUSIC]
SWYNN: What is going on,
C-Zoners out there, you guys?
Your girl Swynn here, joined
by a very special guest.
We've got Bob the Baker
in the house.
BOB THE BAKER: Mike, call me
back if you get a chance.
SWYNN: What is it about
the album that
you're most proud of?
BOB THE BAKER: I'm real proud of
the album artwork, done by
my homie Mike who I haven't
talked in a couple days.
Mike, call me back.
SWYNN: If you were going to be
any reality show, what reality
show would you choose?
BOB THE BAKER: The
Surreal Life.
It doesn't come on no more.
SWYNN: I was gonna say--
BOB THE BAKER: It was
cool, though.
It was like washed
up celebrities.
Vanilla Ice was on there--
heavily influenced by him.
I'd like to do things that
he does in life.
Mike, call me back.
SWYNN: If you could collaborate
with anyone, who
would you want to collaborate
with these days?
BOB THE BAKER: I don't like
anybody is on my dopeness
level but if I could collaborate
with anybody, Mike
knows this question.
Mike call me back if you--
if you can tell her
this answer.
SWYNN: Another exciting thing
you have going on right now,
the Pop Pop Fest 2013--
BOB THE BAKER: --yeah--
SWYNN: --coming up here
you're headlining--
BOB THE BAKER: I'm really
excited for that shit as you
could tell.
Mike, take me back.
This is where most of my
dope-ass beats come from.
I usually lay them
down myself.
And this is called the pan
because it looks like
something that I would fry
some orange chicken in.
I call this thunder.
And this is-- and this
is little thunder.
And this is the one that hurts
my ears, but I love it the
most because it builds character
in my brain.
SWYNN: Tonight you're going to
play one of the songs off your
album, so let's go
forward, right?
BOB THE BAKER: Yeah.
Um, this is a track called,
"Dude, I Miss You." It is not
written about anybody in
particular, but if you it was
it would probably be
about Mike, who
hasn't called me back.
He should do that.
[VOCALIZES SONG]
SWYNN: Um, so are you
OK there, Bob?
Do you want to talk about it?
BETH HOYT: What's
up, music night?
All right, coming up soon we
have a set from YouTube
sensation Nice Peter.
Our next performer is a rapper
who doesn't represent a
neighborhood or a city--
don't do that, Beth-- he
represents a season.
As King of Summer he has
released three albums,
performed on Jimmy Kimmel Live,
and hosts his on podcast
on the Earwolf Network, called
"Who Charted?" When he's not
out dispensing summer gum he's
in the studio fighting off the
winter blues.
Ladies and gentlemen, please
welcome Dragon Boy Suede!
DRAGON BOY SUEDE: Hello!
Hey, guys.
Soak me in.
Soak me in at home.
How you doing?
You guys excited?
I'm making eye contact.
Who's not excited?
Who's depressed?
Who's really depressed
right now?
I'll aim my show at you.
Where are the depressed
people?
When I say--
when I say it's all too much,
y'all say, I know!
It's all too much!
When I say what, y'all
say, --'s the point.
What--
Exactly.
You guys got it.
All right, I came here
to do some music.
You guys want to hear
some music?
All right, here we go.
This first song is about the
time that I drank two bottles
of sake, ate three Vicodin,
and attempted
to do a comedy show.
It's called May 24, 2013.
Let's do it.
Give it up for my DJ.
Sounds good back there.
All right.
I'll tell you a little
bit about myself.
I'm wearing a dumb blue hat.
Thanks for catching that.
I could be any villain from the
movie "Taken." If it was,
like, cold in Bulgaria, or
wherever the hell they
happened to be.
Isn't that right, sir?
You're on the internet.
It's exc-- who's never been
on the net before?
A couple people.
It's exciting.
This is gonna be it.
This is gonna be
the only time.
I'll probably be on.
I'm not that excited.
Guys, if you like what you're
enjoying so far next Thursday
night I'll be doing a show at
the Ross Dress for Less on
Sunset and La Brea.
Thank you.
You got it.
I'm also a consultant there.
I consult them on how to keep
the place looking like a
disaster area at all times.
I'm very hands on about it.
I'll actually move a children's
story into the size
58 jeans section.
The ones with the Fat Albert
painted on the side.
Yeah, that's it.
All right.
Next Friday I'll be doing a show
at the kids Foot Locker
at the Glendale Galleria.
I noticed some of you not that
into my stuff, but Armenian
children being fitted for
size three Nikes--
that's my demographic.
All right, let's do
another song.
Here we go.
This one's called "Applebee's,
We Found a Way to Fuck Up
Salad." Here we go.
Sounds good.
Give up for my DJ,
Scratchitory--
Scratchitory Rape.
He's right back there on
the ones and twos.
The music sounded good.
Well, why don't we just
do another one?
Here we go.
This song is about the curative
powers of my wang.
It's called, "I Heal With
My Steel." Here we go.
Let's do it.
Oh my god, real song.
Hands!
Side to side!
What's going to happen?
Oh, no.
There you go, yeah.
Side to side, people.
Like you're at a Jay-Z
internet only show.
Keep 'em moving, keep
'em moving.
Here we go.
[MUSIC]
Cut that off, Scratchitory.
Beautiful.
Give it up for the ladies.
Oh, yeah.
Wow, that was something.
I don't know if you
guys enjoyed the
lyrics to that song.
My target demographic is boys
between the age of 15 and 15
and a half.
I think we nailed
it right there.
I think we did.
Hey, you know, I'm trying to get
out of the comedy business
and I've been trying
for a while now.
It's tough.
I came up with a business
idea, Shreds-taurant.
Shreds-taurant, a guitar
themed eatery.
All the waiters can shred
on the guitar.
We give them a custom made
guitar, they take
your order on guitar.
I'm still speaking
English, right?
Just checking.
Let's make believe we're
at Shreds-taurant.
Hi, ma'am.
Welcome to Shreds-taurant.
What can I get you to drink?
A beer, no problem.
[HUMS]
--a beer.
And they send that.
It's a beautiful thing.
You know you'd eat there.
Hello, sir, what can I get you
for dinner tonight, even
though I'm looking at a lady?
Hello, sir.
We're not really at
Shreds-taurant.
It's OK.
It doesn't matter.
What can I get you
to eat tonight?
A steak.
You got it.
[HUMS]
--a steak.
Pick it up on this
side, come on.
Laugh or the bit
will continue.
There, that-- now you
see how it works.
All right, let's do a song.
Here we go.
You know, before I got into the
rap game I didn't have a
lot of cash.
I had to do creative things to
keep the ladies interested.
This song is called, "Buy You
Clothes, Do You In Them, Take
Them Back." Thank you so much.
Give it up for Scratchitory
Rape on the ones and twos.
Fantastic.
Really fantastic.
Tell you a little
about myself, I
recently bought a goldfish.
Turns out it's epileptic.
Weird thing is, as long
as I leave it in
the bowl it's fine.
Second--
come on, corner--
second you take it out, just
seizure city, flipping out all
over the place.
Fantastic.
Let's add another song.
Let's do it.
This song is called, "A Strip
Club Shouldn't Smell Like
Pierogies." Spearmint Rhino
Oxnard, that's right, sir.
You got it.
That's the one.
That's the place.
Guys, it feels good to be
here, working the net.
Anybody else make money
on the net?
Any eBay people?
All right, let's do a song.
How many people here are
in a relationship?
All right.
Out of those people, who here's
in a relationship with
someone who likes
to talk back?
Who's in a relationship
with someone who
likes to give you lip?
This song's for you.
It's a tale of revenge.
This song is called, "You Won't
Sass Me Like That When I
Can Summon Wolves."
Here we go.
[MUSIC]
All right.
Let's hear some wolf
noises, everybody!
Give it up for the wolf.
All right, cut that,
Scratchitory.
Hey, let's hear some wolves'
noises in this corner.
There you go.
You're gonna be ready once we
crank this thing up and really
show it on the net.
How are you?
All right.
Tell you a little bit more about
myself, I could turn any
cat against its owner.
Something about the
way I pet them.
Do you have a cat, sir?
Same lady as before.
Sir, do you have a cat?
No cat.
All right, I won't come
over and prove it.
Until you get one.
Buy yourself a cat.
Hey, guys.
I'm giving the people at home
a chance to go to the men's
room, maybe get themselves
something to drink.
Let's do another song.
This song is called, "A Baby's
Hand Is Cuter Than An Adult
Hand." But if you're sitting
on the toilet and a hand
reaches up out of the bowl, the
baby's hand is creepier.
It's an unwieldy chorus, but
I think we made it work.
Yes, we did.
Give it up for Scratchitory.
One final song to do for you.
This one is on the new album
"Douche Manouche." Pick it up
on iTunes, pick it up on
YouTube, [? Jash, ?] wherever
they sell it.
Ladies and gentlemen, this
song is about when
you're kind of, uh--
been doing some work in the
bedroom, sir, right?
And you've been pound it in an
aggressive way, and then the
girl when she gets up to walk
away, she's wobbling like a
newborn baby colt.
Here we go.
This song is called,
"Newborn Baby Colt." [MUSIC]
Have a good weekend, YouTube!
Thank you so much.
Comedy Week was fantastic.
Give it up for the dancers.
I'm Dragon Boy Suede.
Take care.
Good night.
TERRY SILK: [YAWN]
Hey.
That was easy for me.
I know how to yawn.
What about you?
How many times have you
been in a situation
where you need to yawn?
Whether you're at school,
playing some milk caps at
recess, or down by the local
pond with your friends,
yawning is essential
to acting.
[VIDEO PLAYBACK]
TERRY SILK: The yawn is a
perfect way to sabotage other
people's game--
for example, that guy trying
to get into the panties of
that girl you like.
You could roll up to him, yawn
while he's trying to fuck her,
and ruin the whole thing.
Off the top of my head,
probably the
best yawning scene?
"The City Just Ain't
White," maybe.
It's a pretty solid one.
[VIDEO PLAYBACK]
TERRY SILK: Well, you've seen
some pretty serious yawns from
some pretty seriously talented
people, but what about if
you're not just yawning in a
play, but you're on an actual
motion picture set?
Knowing when to yawn and
how to yawn isn't
as easy as it looks.
Sometimes you have to wait hours
in between takes, so
freezing the yawn on your face
isn't always an option.
That's why I sell these.
It's a yawn sack.
Keeps your yawn good up to 24
hours and they're available on
my website.
Just freeze the yawn and use
it when you need it.
Well, thanks for
watching, guys.
It's been a blast.
I'll be back soon.
And like that old dude said,
all the world's a stage.
So why stop acting?
It will only show people who
you really are, and that'll
give them the upper hand.
BETH HOYT: Welcome back
to our big finale.
Coming up, get ready for the
godfather of musical comedy,
Weird Al Yankovic.
But first, our next performer
is a very funny lady.
You may know her from the
classic sketch comedy show
"Mr. Show," or from a time as
head writer for "The Ellen
Show," or maybe even from her
time as creator of The Girls
Guitar Club.
Please give it up for
Karen Kilgariff!
KAREN KILGARIFF: Thank you.
[MUSIC]
Thank you so much.
Thank you very much.
It's an honor to be here.
This is one of my favorite
clubs to play.
I like to come here on Saturdays
and listen to smooth
jazz so it's amazing.
I'm going to sing a
little song about
all of us right now.
[MUSIC]
Thank you.
Thanks, I know that
one's heavy.
It's a lot to take for one
audience and you probably want
me to joke you out of it right
now, but I'm not going to
because you're adults, OK?
It's really nice to be here.
I--
just tell you a little bit of
something about myself--
I have a really mean dad and
so I'm really funny.
And this is just an example--
I'm sure he'll see this and he'd
like to argue, but this
is my example.
My dad came down to visit me
once and we went to get in the
car together.
We walked out into the driveway
and I could smell the
lemon tree that was
in my backyard.
And so I was like, ooo,
it smells like lemons.
And immediately, without pause,
my dad goes, what are
you, half Iroquois?
Yeah.
Drink that in.
You do know Iroquois
are Indians, right?
Native Americans?
They're very attuned to nature
and they can smell things from
a distance.
[MUSIC]
Thank you.
BETH HOYT: Ladies and gentleman,
tonight isn't just
about the wild and the giddy
fun of musical comedy, it's
also about the hard road
back to the spotlight.
Our next guest recently had a
fall from grace and has only
recently began to put his
life back together.
Nick Thune has fallen, and it
may surprise you how he gets
back on his feet.
Please take a look.
[VIDEO PLAYBACK]
-So tonight's my first night
back on stage since the break.
I've been scared.
I thought maybe I wasn't going
to make it back on stage.
Doctor said I'm never to
play guitar again.
For about six weeks.
Bo Jackson broke his hip.
He did not give up.
First game back, first
pitch, first swing,
he hit a home run.
Will I get a standing ovation
on my first joke tonight?
I don't know.
That's my goal, though.
-Please put your hands together
for Mr. Nick Thune!
-I can't do it.
I'm not going to do the show.
What am I even thinking?
It's an unattainable dream.
Should I jump?
Should I just break
my other arm?
It's like I'm re-learning
everything.
I'm re-learning how
to love again.
My wife, she says, you're
not the man I married.
The man I married
had two arms.
I actually feel sick
right now.
I don't even know who
I am anymore.
A standing ovation
off of one joke.
Now I know why people compare
me to Bo Jackson, you know,
because that's what I'm
going to do tonight.
Doctor said he would
never play a
professional sport again.
Bo can't hear that.
He started working out.
I got a letter last week from
an 11-year-old boy in Fort
Lauderdale who broke
his wrist.
He was trying to light
a fart in his bunk
bed and he fell off.
He said knowing that I'm going
to go out on stage tonight,
that he wants to live.
It sounds so stupid, but
I feel like I can
almost smell his fart.
It smells good.
BETH HOYT: OK, guys.
That's a tough, tough
road for Nick.
Tell you what, it's been hard
for me tonight, too.
I came in and the hairdresser
said I was having a bad hair
day, but she fixed it.
So that's why I look
like Heidi.
But ladies and gentleman, don't
worry about it, because
please welcome Nick Thune
featuring The Narcs.
NICK THUNE: Thank you
guys so much.
I know it means a lot
for you to be here.
I'm honored to be in the front
row of your audience.
Could we get just a little more
laughter in these monitors?
Thank you.
I know you guys are looking at
me and you're thinking, this
guy's an athlete.
And I love sports.
I'm not going to tell you guys
I don't love sports.
I do.
But I don't play any sports.
What's my favorite sport?
Thank you.
Great question.
I'd say my favorite sport's
a back flip.
It's just a guy on the streets,
jumping up, no
trampoline, no diving board.
The cement.
A guy who can jump off the
ground, flip his whole body
around backwards and land on his
feet, any time of the day,
any street, any pair of
shoes in their closet.
I'm not talking about
back handsprings.
cartwheels.
Nick, do you have a joke
about back flips?
Another great question
from the back.
No.
I'm-- right now, and knowing
that there's at least hundreds
of people watching this live,
for me to just to get the word
out there-- back flip
awarenesss--
and if I can get that
camera to zoom in on
my face right now.
Teach your children
back flips.
If you're a child,
learn back flips.
It's never too late, unless
you're over 15.
That's it.
That's just the public
service part.
If you have a stage, you've got
to use it sometimes for
the right thing.
Now that that's behind us,
again, thank you guys for
being here.
And I want to tell you a little
story about something
that happened to me recently
at the bank.
[MUSIC]
I was at the bank,
pretty crowded.
Standing in line for 90 minutes,
an hour and a half.
I don't want anyone doing math
out there right now.
Hour and a half in line at the
bank, it's inappropriate.
It's unacceptable.
And ATMs are down outside.
All the pens aren't working.
You've all been there.
At one point a fire marshal
comes and says, listen up,
we're at maximum capacity.
Nobody's coming in this
bank until somebody
walks out of this bank.
I'm running it like a
fucking dance club.
Excuse my language.
He walked out.
There's a line around
the corner.
Lot of banking needs.
When I finally got up to the
teller, I was right.
She was a C-cup.
She was this amazing C-cup.
I started to open up a second
savings account.
I don't have money in my
first savings account.
I'm just--
just trying to create
conversation.
And as I'm talking to C-cup,
having the time of both of our
lives, a gentleman walks
into the bank.
Kitty-corner from where I'm
standing, from here to the
other end, a regular guy, got a
baby in his left arm, about
two months old.
It's a beautiful kid.
I'd seen maybe about 30 kids
that day, it was the best
looking baby I'd seen.
In his right hand he
had a handgun.
This guy jumps up on a table
disrupting everybody's
business in that bank and
screams out, I will shoot!
I will shoot this fucking baby
in the face right now, right
now, unless somebody in this
bank does a fucking back flip.
People are freaking out.
Nobody could do a back flip.
Everybody know it.
C-cup's bouncing all
over the place.
I got to calm her down.
I said, listen, don't press
the red button.
Don't press-- we've
seen every movie.
We know where the
red button is.
It's under the table.
If you press it, the
cops are coming.
This guy doesn't
want any money.
He just wants to see
a back flip.
There's nothing illegal
about that.
Just give me two minutes,
let me talk to him.
She said, will you
come back for me?
And I said, yeah, now I will.
When I walked across the bank
everybody got out of my way.
Why?
Because everybody wants to see
a back flip, that's why.
They're amazing.
Are people worried
about the baby?
Great question.
No.
No one gives a shit about
that when there's a
million babies out there.
Two people know this
specific one.
No, no one's worried
about that baby.
When I get to the middle of the
bank a circle forms around
me like I'm in the middle of
some kind of dance facility.
I looked up at the guy with the
baby and I said listen, I
didn't hear what you said.
I was talking to my lady
friend back there.
He said, I'm going to shoot this
baby in the face, that's
what I said, unless
I see a back flip.
I said it doesn't have
to be like that.
He said, I need to see
one pretty bad.
And I understood him.
I understood what he
was going through.
I looked over to my right.
Cuba Gooding Ju--
Cuba Gooding Joinier--
Cuba Gooding Junior was standing
in the corner.
He had a cast on his left leg,
he's got crutches under each
arm, he's injured.
We've seen Jerry Maguire.
We've seen his Wikipedia page.
We know he can do back flips.
We know he does his
own stunts.
And there he is.
Rod Tidwell's injured
on the sideline.
Probably the biggest game
of his life, he
can't do a back flip.
It's up to me.
So I just jumped.
I know that's step one.
I started leaning
back, step two.
Next thing I know, I
land on my feet.
Everybody sits down.
They stand back up.
That's a standing ovation
in my country.
They let me keep the baby,
I didn't see that coming.
When I was walking out of that
bank for a late lunch with
Cuba, C-cup comes bouncing
up behind me.
And she says, Mr. Thune, Mr.
Thune, before you go I just
want to know we caught that
whole back flip on our
security cameras.
My dad works at YouTube.
I could cut a video together.
We could get it on
the front page.
I mean, maybe not this week,
it's Comedy Week, but
definitely next week.
And you're going to be a hero
all over the world wide web.
I just need you to sign this
release form and then we'll
put the footage out there.
And I said no.
Thanks but no thanks, C-cup.
I didn't do this back
flip to be a hero.
I did this back flip
to be a father.
And right now the most important
thing to me is I
want to be a good dad to Nick
junior and I want to be a good
friend to Cuba Gooding Junior.
We named him after both of us.
He took Cuba's last name.
I said, so you can't
put it online.
And as I turned to walk away
she said, but Nick, we just
caught everything you
said on camera.
And I said yeah, I know.
Now you can put it on YouTube.
Thank you guys.
You're welcome.
Keep it going for The Narcs.
[VIDEO PLAYBACK]
-Three time LPGA champion Linda
Munns is back, but not
on the course.
She's out of prison and headed
to your kids' school to talk
to them about drugs.
Hey, Linda.
Who's that cutie?
-Hey, guys.
This is my friend Little Linda
and you can tell she's been
smoking a little bit
of marijuana today.
Linda, marijuana is bad.
-No, girl.
It's good.
You used to be a lot more
fun when you smoked.
-That's true.
But that's what caused me to
crash my Miata into that
Loehmann's.
-After your kids listen to
Linda Munns they'll never
smoke marijuana, guaranteed.
Watch Linda deal with
peer pressure.
-You could take a puff of this
sweet green shag carpet and
have everything back that
you used to have.
-Nice try, Little Linda.
I'm stronger than you, drugs.
-She's talking diet.
-Gimme, gimme.
-Linda, that's junk food.
You're going to get fat.
-I don't give a shit.
-She's talking cardio.
-You can't do a push-up.
-Yes I can, Linda.
-And real life lessons
from the streets.
-[HUMS]
If you get caught smoking weed,
you're going to go to
prison and then you're
going to have to
stab people to survive.
-Let Linda Munns inspire
your kids.
Everyone is going nuts for
Little Linda and Big Linda's
dynamic.
-Why don't we go outside
and get a
natural high from exercise?
-Screw that.
I just want to watch Borat
and masturbate.
-And she's handing out quan.
-It's fresh quan.
You just have to let it
defrost a little bit.
-I'm fucking rich.
I wrote a spec script
with [? Anzizan ?]
[? sorry ?]
-Who cares?
-If you like "Book of Mormon,"
you'll love this.
-Man, Linda, maybe I
should quit smoking
and be a better person.
-Yeah.
If you want to book me for your
next event email me at
lisa@TucsonWomen
sCorrectionalFacility.com I
don't have a phone right now.
-She'll have you saying, quan!
BETH HOYT: Our next performer
is a true YouTube sensation.
He's been called the king of
dot-comedy and has over a
billion video views on YouTube,
which evens out to 10
views on every video he posts.
He's one of the creators of Epic
Rap Battles and a Streamy
award winner.
Ladies and gentlemen, please
welcome Nice Peter.
NICE PETER: Hi.
This is a song about
the internet.
Kind of.
One, two--
[MUSIC]
Thank you so much.
So this next song is very
important because we have a--
we have an important
guest with us.
There's a young man
named Devin.
Devin, are you out
there somewhere?
Hey, Devin, how's it going?
Devin, why don't you
come up on stage?
So let me tell you a little bit
about Devin, and uh, well,
I'll tell you a little story.
So about six months ago I
realized that I had been
losing my hair for approximately
17,000 years and
I decided to just take the
plunge and shave my head.
So about, it was in
last May, Devin--
Devin kicked the crap out of
cancer, that's what Devin did.
I never had to do that.
But, you know, part of kicking
the crap out of cancer means
you've got to go through
chemotherapy and get a lot of
chemicals in your body and it
messes with your hair and
that's what happens.
So your hair starts falling out
and being weird and it's
one of those things you just
kind of take the plunge on and
you've got to do it.
So tonight we're going to shave
Devin's head right here
on stage while we sing
a song to him.
That's a good thing,
you can clap.
Not just because, I mean--.
But the thing is, when I dealt
with it was tricky.
It was hard.
I didn't even have to beat
cancer in the process and it
was still emotionally
difficult.
But I had my subscribers out
there-- hi, if you're out
there-- and they kind of helped
me through the whole
experience.
I made a video about it and
shaved my head in the video
and they were all very
supportive and nice.
So tonight if you're out there
on the comment boards, stop
typing hateful things that
are misspelled for
one second and let's--
let's all be Devlin
subscribers.
We're-- we're--
I subscribe to you,
Devin-- hello!
So if you could say hi to the
people at home-- don't worry
about these people, they're
not real-- look at
how purple they are.
No one is that purple.
Say hi to the people at
home, and all the
people, say hi to Devin.
You guys can say hi
to Devin, too.
I'm just kidding.
So we have my friend
Sue Lions here.
Sue Lions, come out.
She's going to help us and she's
going to shave his head.
So we're going to do
this all together.
This is a moment.
We're going to help him
take the plunge.
Any other guys out there losing
their hair right here
in the audience?
Anyone?
It's kind of-- yeah,
it's a pain, man.
That guy's like, yeah!
That's all right!
Tonight, we're the cool guys!
It's you and me!
Hey man, look at the
hair on that dork.
Nice hair, dork.
And there's some people
at home probably too.
So this is our moment.
This is our shiny-headed
moment.
I see the future in your head.
Ready?
Here we go.
[MUSIC]
Oh, man, you look
good right now.
[MUSIC]
Oh, man, you look good.
You kinda look like
a criminal.
Like right now I wouldn't
go into a bank.
[MUSIC]
Devin and his new look,
ladies and gentlemen!
Devin, will you stand with
us and take a bow as a
proud new bald man?
That was awesome.
Thank you for being here.
Thank you for being
there at home.
Devin, that was awesome.
Cheers.
This is Dante.
My name's Nice Peter.
Thank you crew.
[VIDEO PLAYBACK]
BETH HOYT: Hi, guys.
It's me, Beth, again.
I'm here with you.
I feel like I'm the baby
sitter and then the--
before the parents come out.
I babysat.
Well, I had a babysitting
job when I was 10.
My first one I babysat twins--
this is just me time.
I'm talking to you about
how I babysat twins.
I lost one of them--
Diane--
I never found her.
I-- the parents came home.
I said Diane is--
they're playing hide and seek.
So this is my chance
to ask the world if
Diane has been found.
But I was only 10.
It's not really my fault.
Here's what I think.
How old is someone who's 10?
I don't know the difference
of the like, four to 11.
Especially--
I live in New York City and I
feel like kids there, like you
ask them, how old are you?
Can you show me with
your fingers?
And they're like, we're going to
be late for Mandarin class.
I'm like, I totally
missed that one.
But guess what I didn't
miss, is that our next
performer is ready.
And he is a titan in the
musical comedy scene.
He stars in the IFC TV series
"Comedy Bang Bang," and he has
performed with acts like Regina
Spektor, [? Bergy ?]
Man, and LCD Sound System.
One of the most creative acts
currently touring the world,
he's here with a word of advice
to the easily confused.
Please welcome Reggie Watts!
REGGIE WATTS: [MUSIC]
MALE SPEAKER 1: Yo, Reggie, what
if I still think it's OK
to smoke in a public place?
REGGIE WATTS: Nah, man,
that ain't fuckin'.
MALE SPEAKER 2: Hey, Reggie,
what if I pretended to be gay
in order to get free
STD testing at the
men's health clinic?
REGGIE WATTS: Then you're
super fuckin', bro.
MALE SPEAKER 1: Yo, Reggie,
Reggie, what
if I shot JFK, brother?
REGGIE WATTS: Ha ha.
He probably--
you're fuckin'.
MALE SPEAKER 1: Yeah!
MALE SPEAKER 2: All right.
Reggie.
I'm at a Slipknot concert and
I've taken so many mushrooms I
think I'm in the band.
Am I fuckin'?
REGGIE WATTS: Um, I would say
most likely you probably are
not fuckin'.
Sorry.
MALE SPEAKER 1: Reggie,
one more question.
What if my name's Perry and his
name's Randy Callahan and
he's a casting director?
REGGIE WATTS: Then you takin'
all the shits you've got and
you fuckin' the fuck out
of that situation.
MALE SPEAKER 1: Yeah!
REGGIE WATTS: That's what
I'm talking about.
MALE SPEAKER 2: All right,
all right, all right.
REGGIE WATTS: What?
MALE SPEAKER 2: What if I'm at
home watching YouTube watching
you do your thing
on [? Jash? ?]
REGGIE WATTS: What can I say?
You definitely fuckin'
them motherfuckers.
MALE SPEAKER 2: Yeah!
REGGIE WATTS: Know
what I'm saying?
Yo, to all the people out there,
YouTube be all confused
and shits about all this fuckins
and shits, know what
I'm saying?
Lots of peoples be's
like, is this the
fuckin' shits and stuff?
Is this working like we said
that we thought that it would
be, like with my sexes
and shits?
Let me tell you something.
You might be fuckin', but you
might not be fuckin', but the
one thing is, you're always
going to be a part of the
fucking ecosystem.
So y'all take care now.
All right.
Peace.
BETH HOYT: All right.
Reggie Watts.
He does lots of voices.
Let's see, I can do things
with my face.
I will show you guys.
This is my impression of Claire
Danes when she found
out she was going
to have a baby.
This is for all you guys.
It's for all of them.
This is my impression of you.
OK.
That's when you think you left
your iPhone at the restaurant.
This is my impression of
Claire Danes when--
when she orders a salad.
OK.
I missed something.
There's something else I want.
Um.
Oh, you guys got--
that translated.
Um, here's another
one for you guys.
This is when you get an
email from Louis CK.
Right, because you know,
everybody, so.
Guess what?
Our final performer for the
evening is a legend in music
comedy, comedy music, comedy
comedy, and music music.
He's sold millions of albums,
been on hundreds of TV shows,
and toured the world.
And his work is the inspiration
for everyone on
the show tonight.
He's got a tour this summer, a
children's book available for
pre order, and even a spot set
for Bonnaroo this year.
Ladies and gentlemen, please
welcome the godfather of
musical comedy, Weird
Al Yankovic!
WEIRD AL YANKOVIC: [MUSIC]
Thank you, ladies
and gentlemen!
Thank you!
BETH HOYT: That was awesome!
Were we going to be like--
I'm fine.
Oh, come on.
You guys, I did it
all for you.
That was amazing.
Have you seen a digger
like that?
I wish I could see it.
Everybody, that is Comedy Week.
I--
could I have planned that
pratfall better?
OK.
Wow, was amazing.
We've seen stand up, improv,
Set List, and music.
Thank you to everyone who made
it happen, especially the
comics and improvisers
who gave so much.
We've had a blast doing it and
we can't wait to do it again.
So the teleprompter has stopped
working so I'm going
to go ahead and say it.
Everyone who watched gets
free Google Glasses.
Pretty sure--
I'm pretty sure I'm supposed
to say that.
OK, watch your email
for details.
Special thanks to everyone
who watched.
Thank you for making the
week such a success.
Good night!
Yeah.
Thank you so much!
[MUSIC]