should we believe the fishy fishapod
story?  this is Genesis Week.
[Music]
And a welcome to this episode of Genesis
Week, the weekly program of creationary
commentary on news, views and events
pertaining to the origins controversy,
proudly brought to you by CORE Ottawa -
Citizens for Origins Research and
Education, and exclusive right here on
youtube.  Showing the glory of God in the
Creation, and broadcasting from our
secret underground lair rented from the
now retired batman, we bring you the
information the anti-creationists don't
want you to see or hear.  One of the most
talked about shows in Science and
Technology on youtube.
You can find us at wazooloo.com or
genesisweek.com, or click the
ever-so-convenient subscribe link up top,
and don't forget, you can also peruse
other episodes by following the links in
the upper corners of each episode. I'm
your host, Ian Juby
Today we're going to cover a composite
of several news items from the past week.
The first article, loaded with a lot of
evolutionary assumptions and written by
Mulkidjanian et al appeared in PNAS.
Citing the problems of life arising in the
oceans, as well as a contrast of the
chemical composition of what is believed
to be the first life, with the chemical
content in the water of hot springs on
land.  Their conclusion: the first life must
have started in hot springs on land and
not the ocean.  Now there are a few
problematic facts here: no one was there
at the beginning to  get a sample of the
first life, so the organisms of which they
were comparing chemical composition are
assumed to have been the first life.  Such
assumptions are also ignoring the glaring
issues of chemicals assembling into life in
direct violation of scientific and natural
laws. Then there are the other
evolutionary scientists who claimed that
land was inhospitable for life 3.8 billion
years ago due to meteor bombardment,
therefore life had to have started in the
oceans!
Only a couple of weeks prior to the PNAS
article, the South African Journal of
Science carried a report by Brain,et al, on
what is claimed to be our earliest animal
ancestor - a sponge allegedly 760 million
years old.  This fossil sponge was found in
limestone which evolutionary geologists
have deduced was deposited on the
ocean floor, so obviously this sponge
lived in the ocean.
Still yet another article of interest came
out this past week in The Proceedings of
the Royal Society by Vega and Wiens
who, using cladistic comparisons,
concluded that the majority of saltwater
fishes evolved from freshwater fish
ancestors.  I'm going to ignore all of the
evolutionary assumptions involved here,
as cladistics do not prove nor disprove
evolution, they are simply interpreted
within the evolutionary paradigm, and
evolution was simply assumed within the
comparisons.  But let's assume for the
moment that they are correct.
You'll also recall a couple of weeks back
where I mentioned a British Museum of
Natural History article talking about the
venerable Horseshoe crab. I pointed out
how it hasn't changed in some 450 million
years according to the evolutionary
timescale.  The British Museum article
even pointed out that the horseshoe crab
has remained unchanged even though it
survived 3 of earth's major extinction
events!  Several people objected
vociferously to my comments, citing the
usual evolutionary mantra that change
only occurs because of environmental
pressures - the horseshoe crab saw no
change in its environment, therefore it did
not change!
Really? Well try to tell that to the trilobites
who are now apparently extinct, yet lived
in the same environment, right alongside
the horseshoe crabs. But better yet - let's
examine the coelacanth, which also lived
in the ocean, unchanged,  in some 407
million years as it is still around today -
yet the coelacanth was consdiered part of
the line of fishapod ancestors - the half
fish/half tetrapod line.  You know - the
evolutionary descent where the fish grew
legs and walked up onto land to become
land dwelling creatures? So, did the
coelacanth change, or didn't it? Did it
experience environmental pressures to
change? Or didn't it?
According to the evolution myth, once
land creatures evolved, they got bored of
the land and went back into the sea,
evolving into sea creatures.  Last fall,
Motani delivered a paper at the Society
for Vertebrate Paleontology showing how
it appears that the plesiasaurs and
ichthyosaurs evolved their way back into
the seas from an unknown, cold-blooded
ancestor, in tropical areas.  It's simply
assumed that plesiasaurs and
ichthyosaurs were cold blooded cause
nobody has actually checked the body
temperature of a living plesiasaur or
ichthyosaur. (ichty screams)  For some reason, cold
blooded marine reptiles, dolphins, whales,
and 28 other groups of marine creatures
all evolved back into ocean dwelling
creatures from land animals, according to
the evolution myth.
So - before we go any farther, let us line
up all of these reports to paint an
evolutionary picture thus far.  I mean no
offense to my evolutionary friends, but
you need to see just how ridiculous the
story has become:
According to all of this latest and greatest
evolutionary research, the first life arose
in warm ponds or perhaps hot springs on
land.  This first life somehow survived the
alleged heavy meteor bombardment of
earth.  Perhaps this life was blasted out of
the hot springs and into the ocean - I
don't know, I wasn't there and neither
were you. All we do "know" is that
somehow THIS life wound up in the
oceans and evolved into a sponge.  That
sponge allegedly evolved into a fish,
which decided it preferred freshwater
instead of salt water, and moved into the
rivers, streams and lakes of the
continents.  It diversified. Apparently
those fish got bored and went back out
into the ocean, where after diversifying
some more, got bored of the ocean, grew
legs and walked up onto land.  These land
creatures diversified and some of those
land creatures got bored and decided
they wanted to live in the oceans again,
so they evolved into sea dwelling
creatures.  31 different times 31 different
groups of land creatures evolved into sea
creatures.
All this time, the horseshoe crab, sea
pens, tadpole shrimp, bristle worms,
limpits, sea lancelets, sea anenomes,
stromatalites, jellyfish, and fishes like the
coelacanth, didn't evolve whatsoever.
In fact that transition from fish to
landlubber is an interesting tale which I've
discussed on the show before. The
coelacanth was considered to be the
precursor to the tetrapod, because of its
four, large lobed fins - CLEARLY a fish
attempting to evolve legs to walk on land!
This was believed in spite of the fact that
the coelacanth doesn't even have a spine
- it has a notochord - which is like a
rubber tube in place of a spine.  The
coelacanth vanishes from the fossil
record at the end of what is called the
cretaceous - or about 65 million years ago
according to the evolutionary timescale.
Assumed extinct, it was sensational to
find them alive, swimming off the coast of
Africa in the 1930's. This was just as
stunning as finding a stegasaurus
nibbling on your garden vegetables.
There it was - living in very deep water
with absolutely no interest in walking on
land.  And if it was still around unchanged,
then that would mean it had nothing to do
with fishapod evolution.
However, evolutionists believed they had
a pretty good fossil sequence of fish to
tetrapod - a four legged amphibian.  Now,
ignoring the speculative nature of off it,
there was a missing link if you will, a gap
in the sequence, right at the 375 million
year mark.  So Neil Shubin from the U of
Chicago, took a team up to the Canadian
high arctic in 2004 to go looking for this
missing link in 375 million year old rock.
They found what they believed they were
looking for - Tiktaalik.
Tiktaalik was heralded as such a stunning
discovery - and victory - for evolution,
after all, evolution had actually made a
prediction and it was fulfilled!
The anti-creation blog the sensuous
curmugeon went hog wild over Tiktaalik
saying in their August 10, 2009 blog post:
Actually, it is the scientific evidence that
prohibits one species evolving into
another, but I digress
They referred to what they said in a
previous, July 7 post of the same year
discussing the spectacular Tiktaalik find :
Wow! Slam dunk right? Not only did they
have what sure looked like an impressive
sequence of fossil transition from fish to
tetrapod, they even made a prediction
based on evolutionary theory and found a
fishapod to fill in the gap!
But neither geology nor evolutionary
theory predicted what had already been
discovered in 2002 - before the discovery
of Tiktaalik - fossil tetrapod footprints in
rocks dated by evolutionary geologists as
395 million years old.  OOoooops!
So based on the evolutionary
assumptions, tetrapods were obviously
already around with fully formed legs,
wrists, feet, toes, etc., before ANY of the
fishapods that were allegedly trying to
evolve legs, wrists, feet and toes.
Some have tried to desperately salvage
Tiktaalik, saying "Oh maybe the age is off
a little bit" - for example, the Royal Tyrell
Museum in Drumheller Alberta
mysteriously has Tiktaalik's age listed as
400 million years old - even everyone else
lists its age as 375 million years old.  While
there's a lot of women out there who
would love to be able to change their age
like that, changing Tiktaalik's age does
not fix the problem.  You can't change the
date of Tiktaalik without abandoning the
alleged "predictions" that evolution and
evolutionary geology made. You can't
change the date of Tiktaalik without
changing the date of all the other
fishapods. And if you were wrong on all of
those dates, then where on earth are you
getting these dates? Clearly your dating
and assembly of the fossils cannot be
trusted! The Polish footprints didn't just
throw Tiktaalik out of the evolutionary
tree - it threw out all of these fishapods.
The sensuous curmugeon finished off
their August 2009 post with the question
Now that the Poland fossil footprints have
thoroughly destroyed all the predictions
of evolution and has completely falsified
the fishy fishapod story, and
simultaneously refuted the validity of both
geology and evolution theory, will the
anti-creationists to whom this is explained
be convinced? Alas, probably not. But at
least you'll know you gave it a good try.
As I mentioned previously, and as you can
see here today, the evolution myth will
conform to whatever evidence you give it.
Therefore evolution is not falsifiable,
therefore, it is not science. It is, as the
Apostle Paul wrote: "'science,' falsely so
called." Evolution is a myth.
[Scary, dramatic music]
Wahoo! Mail for me?
(beeping timer sound)
Hmmmm...I forget - am I supposed to cut
the blue wire, or the red wire?
Or, maybe I'll just pull the detonator!
[Scary, dramatic music]
I was SOOOo excited about Darwin's
birthday last weekend that I accidentally
got my dates mixed up and celebrated his
birthday a day early. His birthday was
Sunday, not Saturday as I said in last
week's show.  Well done to those who
caught this mistake and somehow think
its discredits me when I get my days
mixed up.  Hey - at least I'm not off by 20
million years.
I'd like to give a special shout out to
callingheyzeus who was sharing his
testimony in the comments last week -
kudos. It takes courage to share like that,
and also to youtuber pumpstations for
sharing their story. I commend you both
for your courage, and I'm sorry you had
to put up with the typical youtube trolls
who selfishly butt in with incredible
insensitivity.
Let me see what I can do - there is
copyright issues involved. I'm allowed to
post it in some forms due to fair use, but I
would definitely need permission to post
the whole article.  I also apologize for the
delay in getting the newsletter out, I
wanted to add some more of the original
photos, and I only got permission to
reproduce them a couple of days ago.
Actually - I agree, don't take my word for
anything - do your own research. In fact,
research the claims of what others like
BandofAtheist say, so you can see where
they are lying and misleading people.  I'm
ready, willing and able to back up my
commentary, you can verify the facts for
yourself! by the way - if you're going to use
the internet: trueorigin.org, creationwiki.org,
great resources for further research.
Uhhh. I have never, ever claimed to be a
professor - ever. Now some people call
me by the nicknames of professor Juby,
Doctor Juby and Doc Juby. Nicknames
that were given to me by another teacher
at the high school I taught at 17 years
ago!  Students from that school, friends
and even the Vice Principal still call me
Doc Juby! Sorry, but someone else giving
me an affectionate or respectful nickname
does not make me a liar.
Thank you for the clarification.  If you'll
recall however, as Dr. Criswell explained:
so the point remains the same.
The comments always take fascinating
rabbit trails, as this week several
youtubers got to debating genetics:
TCchapman500 quoted and responded to
TheScienceFoundation:
And as I point out in my "Natural
selection" rant - natural selection doesn't
work the way evolution needs it to!
I've decided to leave ratings turned on for
the whining anti-creationists.  I discovered
that much to their dismay, ratings really
do not affect the viewership....at all......  So
there you go! Rate and rant away!  Thanks
to all who gave input on that matter.
That's enough for this week, I'm your host
Ian Juby, I hope you'll join me next
Thursday for the next episode of Genesis
Week, and hopefully I'll finally get caught
up and get some more videos out here
shortly. So make sure you subscribe up
above.  Remember those famous words of
warning by the Lord Jesus Christ: I am
the Way the Truth and THE LIFE, no man
comes to the father but through me."
[music]
Production Software was provided for
Genesis Week by the Big Valley Creation
Science Museum, located just 25 minutes
north of Drumheller, Alberta. In the heart
of the dinosaur badlands, the Big Valley
Creation Science Museum was built from
the ground up to give credit to our
Creator, portraying the scientific evidence
showing that creation is the faith that fits
the facts, and that evolution is the faith
that the facts have failed.
Visit BVCSM.com for more details