(objects clattering to floor)
Shopkeep: May I help you, traveler?
Hmm, something drew you to my shop.
Something powerful.
Ah, you have a keen eye.
The Alicorn Amulet is one of the most mysterious
and powerful of all the known magical charms.
(stuttering) Uh, I'm-I'm afraid this is...
(gravely) far too dangerous.
(bag of bits clatters onto counter)
(genially) Would you like that gift-wrapped?
(foreboding musical sting)
(theme song begins) My Little Pony, My Little Pony, ah, ah, ah, ah,
(My Little Pony) Twilight: I used to wonder what friendship could be
(My Little Pony) Until you all shared its magic with me
Rainbow Dash: Big adventure
Pinkie Pie: Tons of fun
Rarity: A beautiful heart
Applejack: Faithful and strong
Fluttershy: Sharing kindness
Twilight: It's an easy feat
All: And magic makes it all complete, yeah
(My Little Pony) Do you know, you're all my very best friends
Fluttershy: (gently) Don't be scared, little friends.
Twilight is wonderful with magic!
(threatening) ANYTHING happens to them, Twilight,
so help me...
Spike: Aw, don't worry, Fluttershy.
Twilight's magic has gotten a lot better since
she accidentally crushed me and Applejack
with a giant snowball.
Fluttershy: Of COURSE she's good with magic.
Twilight's GREAT with magic.
I guess I just don't want my little friends to be scared.
(whimpering) Oh, oh, look how scared they are!
(animals making noises genially)
Twilight: I promise, Fluttershy.
Nothing bad will happen to them.
Fluttershy: (agitated, teeth chattering, muffled)
I KNOW!
(magical humming)
Fluttershy: STOP! STOP! I can't take it!
(animals cheering)
(Fluttershy biting hooves)
(animals chittering)
Spike: Twilight, that looks amazing!
Twilight: Phew!
(animals chittering)
That's all for now, little ones.
Maybe we can practice again later,
if Fluttershy says it's all right.
(animals chittering)
Spike: Your magic has really improved since
we came to Ponyville, Twilight.
Spike: Princess Celestia's gonna love it!
Twilight: Thanks, Spike.
I have to be at my best when she arrives with
the delegates from Saddle Arabia [Saudi Arabia].
I can't believe she's trusting me with the entertainment-
(Twilight and Rainbow Dash crash into ground)
Rainbow Dash: (frantic) Twilight! Come quick!
It's an emergency!
(magical poofing)
Rarity: (shrieks) You BEAST! This shade of brown
should ONLY be used for accents!
Pinkie Pie: C'mon, Applejack. We've got to get
her into a nice, soothing pink, STAT!
Twilight: What's going on here?
Trixie: Well, well, well, if it isn't...
Twilight Sparkle.
Twilight: (gasps) Trixie...
Spike: What's SHE doin' here?
Rainbow Dash: You call THAT "great and powerful?"
(magical poof)
(Rainbow Dash yelps, big wing blasts wind)
Snips: Whoa, she's Rainbow Wobble now!
(Rainbow Dash yelping)
Snails: Yeah! (laughs goofily)
(Rainbow Dash's big wing beats past)
Great spell, O Great and Powerful Trixie!
Trixie: You two, quiet. (magical poof)
Snips: (dazed) H-hey! What happened?!
Snails: GET OFF OF ME!
(overlapping, panicked arguing)
Twilight: Stop picking on my friends, Trixie.
Trixie: You and I have some unfinished business.
My magic's gotten better since I was here last.
And I'm gonna prove it.
Me and you, a magic duel.
Winner stays, loser leaves Ponyville...FOREVER.
Twilight: Forget it! I'd NEVER make a deal like that!
Trixie: Hmph, your choice.
(Spike yelping)
(Spike bouncing on ground)
Twilight: (losing patience) Trixie, put him down.
(Spike rolling on basket's rim)
Twilight: Why are you doing this?!
Trixie: Why?! Because you HUMILIATED ME!
After you showed me up with that Ursa Minor,
I became a laughingstock!
Everywhere I went, I was laughed at and ostracized!
I even had to take a job on a rock farm
just to earn a living.
A ROCK FARM!
Pinkie Pie: (scoffs) You're LUCKY a rock farm
would take the likes of YOU!
(magical poof, trash can lid clanking)
Trixie: Now I want revenge.
And I'll just keep casting spells
'til you agree.
(library uproots, books start flying out)
Trixie: Well, what do you say?
(ponies voicing discontent)
Twilight: ...All right, Trixie.
Let's duel.
Trixie: Excellent.
(library crashes into ground)
(poof)
(Pinkie muttering unintelligibly)
Trixie: If I lose, I won't set hoof in Ponyville again.
But if YOU lose, YOU'RE the one banished
from this one-horse town.
(others gasping, Pinkie muttering unintelligibly)
(foreboding background music)
Trixie: DRAW! (poof)
(ponies gasping)
(Shoeshine Wilhelm screams)
(Twilight grunts, cart and apples land gently)
Twilight: Phew... (gasps)
(poof)
(parasprite swallows pies messily,
then hacks up another parasprite)
(poof)
(snow thuds heavily onto ground)
(ponies laughing)
(scissors snipping)
Trixie: (crossly) Snips, Snails, step forward.
Snips: (apprehensively) Wh-what is it,
O Great and Powerful Trixie?
(high-pitched humming)
(poof)
(baby Snips wailing)
Twilight: An age spell...?
But how could you do an age spell?!
That's only for the highest-level unicorns!
Trixie: (rubs Amulet, snidely) Well, Twilight? Give up?
(Twilight sighs, then grunts with exertion)
(high-pitched humming)
Spike: Come on, Twilight...! You can do it!
(humming distorts and fades out)
(Snips and Snails land on ground;
Snips wails, Snails' back cracks)
Trixie: Trixie IS the highest-level unicorn!
(nefarious laugh)
And now it's time for you to LEAVE PONYVILLE.
(imitating Pinkie Pie) FOREVER!
Applejack: That's ENOUGH, Trixie!
Rarity: You proved your point,
but you can't possibly expect Twilight to leave Ponyville.
Trixie: You fools. She's already gone.
(Twilight screams)
(Twilight crashes into ground repeatedly)
(poof)
(glass bowl lands heavily on ground)
Twilight: It's okay, guys. I'll figure something out.
Just...take care of each other.
And keep an eye on Trixie.
There's something strange about her.
Spike: Twilight...?
(Twilight grunting)
(Twilight groans in frustration)
Twilight: It's impossible. How could Trixie
know such advanced magic?!
Without Spike, I can't get a message
to the princess in Saddle Arabia.
So, who else do I know who understands
strange and powerful magic?
(Zecora's "theme" plays in background)
Zecora: (metric) Your tale of woe
upsets me so.
No wonder you're dour.
It's an abusive power!
Twilight: I don't know what to do, Zecora.
I feel like I've abandoned my friends.
But I can't take her on horn-to-horn.
Zecora: (sips tea) If you train with me,
so good you'll be,
I'll show you the way
to make sure she won't stay.
Twilight: YOU'LL train me in magic?
But she was doing age spells,
weather spells, you name it- (knocks over cup)
Zecora: When it comes to magic, it would be tragic
if somepony licks me, especially Trixie.
Twilight: You really think I can beat her?
Zecora: Mm-hmm.
Twilight: (knocks over cup) Okay!
When do we start?!
Trixie: You two! Hurry up with my throne!
(Applejack squashes apple)
And YOU. How long do I have to wait
for my applesauce facial?! [Ed. note: ewww]
Applejack: Forget it, Trixie. I ain't doin' nothin'
'til you let Twilight come home.
(poof)
(Applejack laughing and gasping for air)
O-okay, I'll do it! Just make it stop!
(crash)
Trixie: I thought I told you to DANCE!
Rarity: (sighs) Trixie's cruel magic
is ruining Ponyville- (pricks self with needle) OW!
(sniveling) Oh, somepony has to help us!
Zecora: Ah, no noise, no sound, no din, no fuss
must interfere with your focus.
Unlearn what you have learned.
Only then can victory be earned.
(Twilight moans)
Trixie: (voice-over in Twilight's head)
Trixie IS the highest-level unicorn!
(Trixie's laugh echoing)
(Twilight yelps and splashes into water)
Zecora: There is much, much that I can teach,
but the answer you need may still be out of reach.
Twilight: I'm sorry, Zecora. I'm trying my best, but...
I can't stop thinking about Trixie.
There's something different about her.
It's like she's gone from high-and-mighty
to mean and nasty.
Zecora: Your thinking needs a readjust.
Total concentration is a must.
(wind howling, banners flapping)
Rarity: (scoffs) This really doesn't seem
to be getting us anywhere.
(Pinkie mutters incoherently)
Applejack: I hear ya, Pinkie. I can't find ANYTHING
that describes the kinda magic Trixie's doin'.
Spike: (sighs) There must be SOMETHING.
Twilight has every magic book there is.
Fluttershy: (quietly) Um, I think I may have found something.
Rarity: (melodramatic) Yes, it's time for us to consider
our futures in this new Trixie-led Ponyville.
Fluttershy: Um, this sounds an awful lot like Trixie's magic-
Applejack: She wants me to grow apples with no peels!
Now, how the hay am I supposed to do that?!
Fluttershy: Um, there's a picture here of that necklace-
(Pinkie muttering unintelligibly)
Fluttershy: It's called the "Alicorn Amulet," and
whoever wears it is blessed with untold-
Spike: Hey, everypony! Look!
This book has a picture of Trixie's necklace!
It's called the "Alicorn Amulet," and
whoever wears it is blessed with untold powers!
Fluttershy: I-if you read a little further, you'll see-
Rarity: "Even though it provides great power,
it also corrupts the user!"
Fluttershy: Yes, but, um, you can't-
Spike: You can't just take the Alicorn Amulet off her neck.
It has a magical lock. Trixie's the only
pony who can take it off.
Fluttershy: Maybe we should-
Applejack: We need to get this information to Twilight.
Applejack: She'll know what to do.
Fluttershy: But, how-how...
Rarity: If any of us try to leave,
Trixie's magical force field will tell her!
Fluttershy: Maybe we should-
Rainbow Dash: I'VE GOT IT!
Trying to sneak past the force field
would be impossible without help.
But I know who's got the GOODS
to get into those WOODS.
Fluttershy: It must be-
Rainbow Dash: FLUTTERSHY! (Fluttershy shrieks)
Applejack: What do ya say, Fluttershy?
Can ya handle the mission?
Fluttershy: NO! I'll crack under the pressure!
I'll snap like a twig!
Rainbow Dash: Perfect! Fluttershy'll sneak
out of Ponyville and find Twilight.
Fluttershy: (protesting) B-but I- (crashes into ground)
(teeth chattering)
Fluttershy: (sighs) Okay...
(ponies cheering)
Rarity: I know just the design for
a dangerous mission outfit!
(Snips and Snails grunting and groaning)
Trixie: PULL, you fools! (cracks whip)
Somepony set off the magic force field,
and Trixie intends to punish them!
Snips: But...wouldn't it be faster if we
had some...WHEELS?!
Trixie: The Great and Powerful Trixie doesn't
trust wheels. Now, pull FASTER!
Snails: (fearfully) I'm tellin' ya, Snips!
She's getting weirder and weirder! (whip cracks)
(Snips and Snails resume grunting,
beaver tails impacting magic barrier)
Trixie: Stop! You there, what are you doing!
(beaver chattering angrily)
(barrier crashes to ground)
(poof)
Snails: Why is she so MEAN to us?!
Snips: Yeah! I miss the days when she was...
just a fraud!
(whip cracks)
(beaver chattering)
(crash)
Fluttershy: (stalling) O-oh dear! Rarity's
dangerous mission outfit is ruined!
Guess we'd better go back! (nervous chuckle)
(animals chattering)
Oh...okay, okay, you're right.
Need to be brave and find Twilight.
(bird chirps) Oh! You found her?
(bird chirps) And she's in the Everfree Forest?!
Oh, this IS me being brave!
I wanna be brave at home,
locked in my closet, with my TEDDY BEAR!
(jungle drums)
Twilight: I can't believe I didn't recognize
the Alicorn Amulet.
Fluttershy: The more she uses it,
the more it will corrupt her.
Twilight: But how am I supposed to beat that amulet?
My magic's not good enough.
Zecora: Twilight Sparkle, much work have you done.
You've learned all of my lessons. All...but one.
If Trixie's tricks have you in a fix,
you must mix your magic and use the Six.
Twilight: (ruminating) "Mix your magic, use the Six..."
"Mix your magic, use the Six."
(epiphany) "Use the Six," that's IT!
Zecora, you're a genius!
Now I need to get you back inside Ponyville, Fluttershy.
(throne dragging on ground)
Trixie: This better not be another false alarm,
or the Great and Powerful Trixie will- (gasps)
(venomously) YOU. (echoing inside barrier)
What's the matter, Twilight Sparkle?
Not enjoying your exile?
Twilight: I know about the Alicorn Amulet.
I know you cheated.
Trixie: "Cheated?" Moi?
Twilight: Yeah, and I thought you might
wanna see what a REAL magical amulet looks like.
Zecora gave it to me. It's from
beyond the Everfree Forest.
And it's WAY more powerful than your measly
little Alicorn Amulet.
Trixie: (false bravado) HAH! NOTHING'S more powerful
than the Alicorn Amulet.
And NOPONY'S more powerful than the
Great and Powerful Trixie!
Twilight: (unfazed) Care to put your amulet
where your mouth is?
Twilight: How about another duel?
Trixie: Why should I? I already beat you.
Twilight: That's up to you.
(teasing) But I guess you'll never see the totally
awesome magic from beyond the Everfree Forest...
C'mon, Zecora.
Trixie: Wait!
(barrier dissipates)
Okay, okay, you're on.
A second duel.
(thunder rumbling)
(peal of thunder)
Trixie: Let's start with a simple age spell,
shall we?
Twilight: Let's.
Trixie: Snips, Snails!
(poof)
(Snips and Snails wailing)
(haughty) An oldie, but a goodie. Now,
let's see what your little "charm" can do.
Twilight: No problem. Um, Applejack, Rarity?
Could you help me, please?
Applejack: Huh...?
Rarity: Huh?
(poof)
Trixie: (feigning disinterest) Eh, ho-hum.
So you can do an age spell. Big deal.
(poof)
(repeated poofs)
Trixie: (shocked) But...that's IMPOSSIBLE!
Twilight: That's nothin'.
(poof)
Rainbow Dash: Yow!
Trixie: How did you-?!
Twilight: Duplication spell.
Ever seen one pony play
ten instruments?
(poof)
(Pinkie playing upbeat polka melody)
Trixie: (incredulous) This...this can't be!
Twilight: Ooh, one more! I can turn a mare...
into a stallion.
(poof)
Applejack: (deeper, bashful voice) Eenope...
Twilight: Well, Trixie, looks like my amulet
is more powerful than yours-HEY!
Give it back!
Trixie: (nefarious laughter) With this amulet,
I shall now rule ALL OF EQUESTRIA!
(laughs nefariously)
(amulet's magic fizzles out)
Witness, my subjects! Gaze upon an ever-greater
and powerfuler TRIXIE! (peal of thunder)
(Trixie laughs nefariously, but cuts out)
Trixie: HEY! (scoffs) I don't need that
old Alicorn Amulet.
I have THIS.
(poof)
Rainbow Dash: (laughing uncontrollably) Stop it!
That tickles!
Trixie: (confused) "Tickles?!" Th-that was
supposed to make you writhe in agony!
This amulet is defective.
(zap) Give mine back.
Rainbow Dash: Sorry. This is goin' back
into hiding, where it belongs.
Twilight: By the way, Trixie? The amulet around your neck?
It's one of Zecora's doorstops.
(bauble shatters)
Trixie: (cowed) But...how did you do those spells?
Nopony can do those spells!
Twilight: You're right, not even me.
(voice-over) Zecora taught me so much about magic
while I was in exile.
She even taught me when not to use it.
My magic alone wasn't powerful enough to take on
the Alicorn Amulet head-to-head,
so I needed to use a different kind of magic:
the magic of friendship.
I also knew that the only pony who could
get the amulet off your neck was you.
Trixie: But...what about the pony
with the ten instruments?
Twilight: That's not magic. That was just Pinkie Pie.
(Pinkie playing upbeat polka)
(ponies cheering)
(ponies "ooh" and "ahh")
(fireworks)
Twilight: Trixie...?
Trixie: (remorsefully) It's the least I could do.
I treated you and your friends so horribly
when I was wearing that Alicorn Amulet.
I just couldn't control myself.
You can forgive me, can't you?
Twilight: Hmm...sure.
Trixie: Oh, good. (usual tone) Don't you think
the Great and Apologetic Trixie
is the most magnificent humble pony
you've ever seen?
(poof, Trixie trips and falls)
(Pinkie spreads iris wipe and mutters unintelligibly)
(poofs, Pinkie gasps)
(ending theme begins) My Little Pony
[Thanks for watching my captions again this week.]
[Season three has been a blast so far,
and I'm rather enjoying captioning the episodes.]
[Remember, if you have any suggestions for what
I could do better, drop a PM by BeanyOne!]
[See you next week. Same pony time, same pony channel.]