DITULLIO: HELLO AND WELCOME TO
SPORTSZONE. I'M JOHN DITULLIO.
LAST NOVEMBER ALUMNUS STEVE
SCHULTZ DONATED ONE MILLION
DOLLARS TO RIT OFFICIALLY
KICKING OFF THE SCHOOL'S POWER
PLAY CAMPAIGN TO HELP FUND THE
CONSTRUCTION OF A NEW ARENA HERE
ON CAMPUS FOR HOCKEY. NOW ONE
YEAR LATER RIT'S POWER PLAY HAS
SCORED ITS MOST SIGNIFICANT
DONATION YET. SHELBY HILL HAS
THE LATEST. HILL: CONSTRUCTION
ON THE FUTURE HOME OF RIT HOCKEY
HASN'T EVEN BEGUN, BUT THE NEW
FACILITY ALREADY HAS A NAME,
THANKS TO A 4.5 MILLION DOLLAR
PARTNERSHIP WITH THE POLISSENI
FOUNDATION AND TOM GOLISANO, THE
HOCKEY PROGRAM WILL SOON CALL
THE GENE POLISSENI CENTER THEIR
NEW HOME. DESTLER: THIS IS AN
AMAZING STORY AND WE JUST
COULDN'T HAVE A BETTER NAME FOR
THIS ARENA. YOU KNOW, GENE
POLISSENI AND TOM GOLISANO WERE
CHILDHOOD FRIENDS. WHEN TOM
GOLISANO DECIDED THAT HE WAS
GOING TO TRY AND START A
COMPANY, WHICH EVENTUALLY BECAME
PAYCHEX, TOGETHER THEY BUILT THE
COMPANY INTO WHAT IT IS TODAY.
IT'S A TREMENDOUS STORY OF
PERSONAL FRIENDSHIP, HARD WORK,
PERSEVERANCE AND I THINK RIT OF
COURSE IS THE BENEFICIARY OF
THAT EXTRAORDINARY RELATIONSHIP,
AND WHAT A BETTER WAY TO HONOR
GENE POLISSENI'S MEMORY THAN TO
HAVE HIS NAME ON THIS
MAGNIFICENT NEW FACILITY. HILL:
NOW WHAT DOES THIS DONATION SAY
TO THE POLISSENIS AND TOM
GOLISANO'S COMMITMENT TO THE
COMMUNITY? WILSON: WELL, I
THINK, AND MAYBE NOT AS
PUBLICIZED ALL THE TIME THE
MONEY THAT THEY CERTAINLY HELP
OUT MANY, MANY CAUSES THROUGHOUT
OUR COMMUNITY. THE COMMUNITY IS
VERY IMPORTANT TO THEM. THESE
ARE PEOPLE THAT YOU KNOW,
ROCHESTER'S VERY SPECIAL TO THEM
AND REALLY HELP ROCHESTER
THRIVE. WE REALLY, REALLY
APPRECIATE EVERYTHING THAT
THEY'VE DONE. HILL: HOW
GRATIFYING IS THIS TO YOU AND
THE CAMPAIGN? DESTLER: YOU KNOW,
IT COULDN'T BE BETTER! IT'S
EXACTLY THE BIG GIFT WE NEEDED
TO GET THIS CAMPAIGN GOING. I
THINK WE'RE OVER HALFWAY THERE
NOW. I THINK THIS WILL BUILD
EXCITEMENT TOWARD THE CAMPAIGN
AND HOPEFULLY IF WE RAISE A
COUPLE MILLION DOLLARS MORE,
THIS SPRING WILL GET AN
ARCHITECT AND MAYBE IF WE GET A
COUPLE MILLION AFTER THAT WE'LL
START CONSTRUCTION IN THE FALL.
HILL: SO HOW MUCH HAVE YOU
RAISED SO FAR? DESTLER: A LITTLE
OVER EIGHT MILLION DOLLARS AND
WE'RE VERY ENCOURAGED BY WHAT WE
HEAR FROM THE COMMUNITY. WE HAVE
SOME OTHER LARGE ASKS OUT. IT'S
NO QUESTION, WE'RE REALLY GOING
TO BUILD THIS THING, THE ONLY
QUESTION IS WHEN. HILL: NOW DO
YOU THINK YOU'RE GOING TO START
BUILDING BEFORE YOU GET THE 15
MILLION OR WAIT UNTIL THEN? NEW
SPEAKER: WELL NOW THAT WE HAVE A
NAME FOR THE CENTER, IT MAKES IT
EASIER FOR US TO START LOOKING
FORWARD TO GETTING AN ARCHITECT
AND THINKING ABOUT THE PLACEMENT
AND MAKING SOME MORE FIRM PLANS
TO MAKE THIS HAPPEN. IT'S
EXCITING! HILL: WHAT DOES THIS
DO TO THE MOMENTUM OF THE
CAMPAIGN? DESTLER: IT'S A BIG
SURGE, LET'S PUT IT THAT WAY.
YOU KNOW, WHEN YOU GET A 4.5
MILLION DOLLAR GIFT IT SENDS A
MESSAGE OUT TO FOLKS THAT WE'RE
SERIOUS, WE'VE GOT SOME PEOPLE
BEHIND US WHO ARE SERIOUS ABOUT
IT AND I THINK IT'S GOING TO
DEVELOP KIND OF A SNOWBALL, A
LITTLE DOMINO EFFECT, WE'LL GET
MORE GIFTS, BIGGER GIFTS,
HOPEFULLY. WE'LL GET TO THAT 15
MILLION DOLLAR POINT SOONER THAN
WE THINK. HILL: ARE YOU TALKING
TO SOME OTHER MAJOR COMPANIES
AND IS THERE ANOTHER MAJOR
DONATION IN THE WORKS? DESTLER:
WE HAVE SEVERAL THINGS IN THE
WORKS, THEY'RE NOT NEARLY AS BIG
AS THIS, BUT WE HAVE QUITE A FEW
THINGS IN THE WORKS AND YOU
KNOW, THEY ALL ADD UP AND WE'RE
GOING TO GET THERE AND I
COULDN'T BE MORE THRILLED, NOT
ONLY WITH THIS WONDERFUL DAY AND
THIS WONDERFUL ANNOUNCEMENT, BUT
THE TEAM'S PLAYING WELL TONIGHT,
SO WHAT'S NOT TO LIKE? HILL: IS
IT KIND OF HITTING YOU THAT A
NEW RINK IS GOING TO COME TO
CAMPUS? WILSON: YEAH, IT IS, I
MEAN WE'VE BEEN TALKING ABOUT IT
FOR A WHILE AND VERY HOPEFUL AND
WE'VE HAD SOME VERY GENEROUS
GIFTS ALREADY AND THE THING THAT
I GUESS I APPRECIATE MORE THAN
ANYTHING ELSE OR I THINK
ESPECIALLY ABOUT THIS IS THAT
IT'S COMING FROM PEOPLE WITH
SINCERE INTEREST IN HOCKEY, AND
I THINK IT MAKES IT THAT MUCH
MORE MEANINGFUL. THE NAME GENE
POLISSENI WILL LIVE ON FOR A
LONG, LONG TIME AND IT WILL BE A
VERY SPECIAL BUILDING IN OUR
COMMUNITY. NEW SPEAKER: WHEN YOU
SEE THE PRESIDENT STANDING OUT
THERE SAYING THAT THIS THING IS
GOING TO BECOME A REALITY, AND I
KIND OF WATCHED, I LOOKED UP IN
THE STANDS AND I JUST SAW THE
EXCITEMENT IN THEIR EYES AND
THEIR VOICES. WHAT WE HAVE HERE
IS A PRETTY DARN SPECIAL THING.
NOW WE HAVE THE GENE POLISSENI
CENTER; WE'LL HAVE PEOPLE WHO
KNEW ABOUT GENE, HIS WORK, HIS
CONTRIBUTIONS TO THE COMMUNITY.
I DON'T KNOW HOW THIS CAN'T
SUCCEED NOW. DITULLIO: TO DATE
RIT HAS RAISED OVER HALF OF THE
CAMPAIGN'S 15 MILLION DOLLAR
GOAL. NOW FOR MORE INFORMATION
ON HOW YOU CAN JOIN THE EFFORT
TO HELP BUILD THE GENE POLISSENI
CENTER, VISIT RIT.EDU/POWERPLAY.
WELL STILL TO COME ON
SPORTSZONE, A FAMILIAR FACE
RETURNS TO THE ICE AFTER A FIVE
GAME SUSPENSION AND MEN'S SOCCER
PLAYS FOR ITS FIRST LIBERTY
LEAGUE TITLE. HIGHLIGHTS ARE ON
THE WAY. YOU'RE WATCHING RIT
WELCOME BACK TO SPORTSZONE.
SINCE 2007, RIT AND AIR FORCE
HAVE BEEN THE TEAMS TO BEAT IN
ATLANTIC HOCKEY, WITH THE
FALCONS CLAIMING FOUR AHA CROWNS
AND THE TIGERS EARNING ONE. RIT
WELCOMED THEIR RIVALS TO
ROCHESTER FOR THE FIRST TIME
THIS SEASON LOOKING TO HALT THE
FALCONS SEVEN GAME UNBEATEN
STREAK. BATTAGLIA: EVERYONE
TAKING A LOOK AT SHANE MADOLORA.
HOW ABOUT THE APPLAUSE, JOHNNY,
FOR SHANE MADOLORA TONIGHT.
DITULLIO: SHANE MADOLORA BACK IN
NET AFTER SITTING OUT FIVE
GAMES, MORE ON HIM IN A MOMENT.
LATE FIRST PERIOD ADAM MITCHELL
SHOT IS STOPPED BUT BRYAN POTTS
IS THERE TO PUT HOME THE
REBOUND. ONE NOTHING RIT AFTER
ONE. SECOND PERIOD, MITCHELL
FORCES A TURNOVER, MIKE
COLAVECCHIA FINDS POTTS, CROSS
ICE FOR HIS SECOND OF THE NIGHT,
RIT LED TWO ZIP. SHANE MADOLORA
STOPPED 25 OF THE 26 SHOTS HE
FACED AS RIT HELD ON TO BEAT AIR
FORCE AS THEIR NUMBER ONE GOALIE
MADE A SUCCESSFUL RETURN TO THE
LINEUP. HILL: SHANE MADOLORA
RETURNED TO THE LINEUP TONIGHT
AFTER SERVING A FIVE GAME
SUSPENSION FOR VIOLATING AN NCAA
RULE. THE INFRACTION INCURRED IN
2009, WHEN MADOLORA FORGOT TO
OFFICIALLY ASK THE NCAA TO
CERTIFY HIM FOR COMING TO RIT.
BUT NOW WITH THAT BEHIND HIM,
MADOLORA AND THE TIGERS ARE
READY TO MOVE FORWARD. YOU WERE
BACK IN THE NET TONIGHT; WHAT
WERE YOU THINKING? MADOLORA: I
SORT OF GOT REALLY EXCITED WHEN
I CAME OUT BECAUSE LIKE I SAID,
THE FANS WERE CHANTING MY NAME
AND ALL THAT, BUT I HAD TO CALM
MYSELF DOWN AND JUST REMEMBER
THAT IT'S ANOTHER HOCKEY GAME.
I'VE BEEN PLAYING HOCKEY MY
WHOLE LIFE, SO I HAD TO SETTLE
BACK DOWN AND GET BACK INTO THE
GROOVE OF THINGS AND FOCUS ON
THE FIRST SHOT OF THE GAME.
HILL: YOU DIDN'T PLAY FOR FIVE
GAMES. CAN YOU TELL ME THE
REASONING BEHIND THAT? MADOLORA:
I GUESS IT HAS SOMETHING TO DO
WITH THE CLEARINGHOUSE AND THE
NCAA AND THEY SAID THAT WHEN I
WAS GOING THROUGH THE WHOLE
PROCESS OF CLEARINGHOUSE THAT I
DIDN'T SIGN A WAIVER OR CHECK A
BOX OR SOMETHING, SO I GUESS
THEY DEEMED THAT A FIVE GAME
SUSPENSION. WILSON: REALLY, HE
TOOK A WRONG SCIENCE COURSE, HE
TOOK AN AGRICULTURAL SCIENCES
CLASS. HIS DAD'S A FARMER OUT IN
CALIFORNIA, AND IT DID NOT COUNT
TOWARDS THE REQUIRED THREE
SCIENCES THAT HE NEEDED TO TAKE.
HE SAT OUT THE YEAR AND THEN
WHEN HE CAME IN, HE DID ALL HIS
PAPERWORK. HE WAS CLEARLY
ELIGIBLE, BUT WHAT HE FORGOT TO
DO WAS CHECK A BOX BASICALLY
THAT SAYS REQUESTING TO BE
REINSTATED. THAT'S ABOUT THE
BEST I CAN EXPLAIN IT. FOR HIM I
GUESS THE PUNISHMENT WAS FIVE
GAMES BECAUSE HE PLAYED FIVE
GAMES. THANK GOD HE DIDN'T PLAY
30 GAMES. HILL: WHEN YOU HEARD
THE NEWS THAT SHANE WASN'T GOING
TO BE PLAYING FOR A FEW GAMES,
HOW DID YOU AND THE TEAM REACT?
NEW SPEAKER: I THINK IT JUST
KIND OF BLINDSIDED US. WE REALLY
HAD NO IDEA. WE FOUGHT THROUGH
IT WELL. OBVIOUSLY SHANE'S OUR
GO TO GOALIE RIGHT NOW AND HE'S
PROVEN WELL AND IT'S NICE TO
HAVE HIM BACK IN THE LINEUP, BUT
JUST FOR A LITTLE TIME THERE IT
WAS A LITTLE WEIRD. NO ONE
REALLY KNEW WHAT WAS GOING ON
AND THEN THERE WERE JUST RUMORS
HERE AND THERE AND WE KIND OF
FIGURED IT OUT AND THAT'S THAT.
NEW SPEAKER: WE TRIED TO STAY
POSITIVE ABOUT THE WHOLE
SITUATION. I DON'T KNOW ALL THE
DETAILS, BUT SHANE'S A GREAT
GOALIE, HE'S THE BEST IN THE
LEAGUE AND HE SHOWED IT AGAIN
TONIGHT. HILL: WAS IT HARD TO
WATCH YOUR TEAM AND YOU COULDN'T
DO ANYTHING ABOUT IT? MADOLORA:
YEAH, IT WAS DEFINITELY
FRUSTRATING TO COME TO THE GAME
AND TO HAVE TO SIT IN THE STANDS
AND HAVE PEOPLE COME AND ASK
YOU, "WHY AREN'T YOU PLAYING?
WHAT'S GOING ON?" EVERY SINGLE
GAME FOR WHAT SEEMED LIKE A HALF
HOUR STRAIGHT ALMOST, BUT IT WAS
DEFINITELY FRUSTRATING TO HAVE
TO SIT THERE AND WATCH,
ESPECIALLY WHEN WE WERE
STRUGGLING A BIT FOR A FEW
GAMES. IT WAS HARD; IT WAS
DIFFICULT. HILL: HOW GOOD DOES
IT FEEL TO HAVE SHANE BACK?
WILSON: GOOD. COMFORTING THAT
YOU'VE GOT YOUR NUMBER ONE
GOALIE BACK, SOMEONE THAT YOU
CAN RELY ON, SOMEONE THAT'S BEEN
TESTED, SOMEONE THAT'S PROVEN
HIMSELF, CERTAINLY LAST YEAR AND
EVE IN SOME GAMES AND THE YEAR
BEFORE. NEW SPEAKER: SHANE OVER
THE LAST YEAR OR YEAR AND A
HALF, HE'S PLAYED REAL WELL FOR
US. HE'S A GAMER, AND HAVING HIM
BACK IN THE NET TONIGHT HE
SHOWED WHY HE'S THE NUMBER ONE
GUY. HE PLAYED REAL WELL. HILL:
NOW WITH SHANE GONE FOR ALMOST A
MONTH, WERE YOU WORRIED HE MIGHT
BE A LITTLE RUSTY COMING BACK
IN? WILSON: I THOUGHT MAYBE HE
WOULD BE A LITTLE BIT RUSTY AND
THEN MAYBE JUST PRESSING A
LITTLE BIT. HE WAS HIS OLD SELF.
HE JUST KIND OF PLAYS VERY
STRONG AND HE DOES A GREAT JOB.
HE DOES GIVE US CONFIDENCE AND I
THINK WE'RE ABLE TO BUILD OFF OF
THAT AND A COUPLE SAVES EARLY IN
THE GAME I THINK SOLIDIFIES THAT
FOR US AND HE WAS GOOD TO HAVE.
HILL: WHAT DOES IT DO FOR THE
TEAM'S CONFIDENCE, NOT ONLY TO
HAVE YOU BACK, BUT YOU KNOW,
BEAT AIR FORCE, A BIG RIVAL? NEW
SPEAKER: IT WAS A HUGE
CONFIDENCE BOOST JUST BECAUSE
AIR FORCE BEAT US LAST YEAR IN
THE PLAYOFFS AND THEN THEY EVEN
WENT ON TO THE REGIONALS, SO
THEY'RE ALWAYS A TEAM THAT'S
GOING TO BE AT THE TOP OF THE
LEAGUE AND UNTIL WE GET TO THE
REGIONALS, THAT'S THE TEAM WE
HAVE TO GO THROUGH. NEW SPEAKER:
IT WAS A BIG WIN FOR US. WE WERE
IN A LITTLE BIT OF A RUT THERE
AND TWO BIG WINS, WE'VE HAD TWO
GOOD WEEKENDS IN A ROW AND
HOPEFULLY WE CAN MOVE ON FROM
THERE. HILL: HOW MUCH OF A
WEIGHT IS OFF OF YOUR SHOULDERS
NOW THAT YOU'RE BACK ON THE ICE?
MADOLORA: A HUGE WEIGHT! BECAUSE
TO START OFF I WAS DOWN ON
MYSELF JUST BECAUSE I WAS
SUSPENDED, I DIDN'T KNOW WHY, I
DIDN'T KNOW HOW LONG AND JUST
ALL THE UNKNOWNS ARE JUST
DIFFICULT AND FRUSTRATING AND
NOW THAT I'M BACK IT FEELS LIKE
A WEIGHT'S BEEN LIFTED OFF MY
SHOULDERS AND I CAN JUST FOCUS
ON PLAYING AND THE REST OF THE
YEAR AND THE REST OF THE SCHOOL
YEAR TOO. DITULLIO: AHEAD ON
SPORTSZONE: FROM RIT TO THE
SILVER SCREEN, WE'RE GOING TO
SHOW YOU HOW THIS FORMER NTID
STUDENT'S LIFE STORY IS
INSPIRING COUNTLESS INDIVIDUALS.
1755 HILL: MATT HAMILL WAS THE
FIRST DEAF WRESTLER TO WIN A
NATIONAL COLLEGIATE
CHAMPIONSHIP. AND THE FORMER RIT
STUDENT WAS ALSO THE FIRST DEAF
STUDENT TO PARTICIPATE IN MIXED
MARTIAL ARTS. THROUGH THE YEARS,
HAMILL'S BEEN AN INSPIRATION TO
MANY, BY OVERCOMING ADVERSITY TO
MAKE HIS DREAMS COME TRUE. NOW,
AFTER YEARS OF PRODUCTION, HIS
LIFE STORY, FILLED WITH MANY UPS
AND DOWNS, HAS FINALLY HIT THE
BIG SCREEN. NEW SPEAKER: OK,
WE'RE ROLLING, AND ACTION! HILL:
IT'S BEEN OVER TWO YEARS SINCE
THE BRIGHT LIGHTS OF HOLLYWOOD
CAME TO RIT TO FEATURE ONE OF
OUR OWN. NEW SPEAKER: HE WAS
ALWAYS THE CENTER OF ATTENTION
WHEREVER WE WENT, WHEREVER WE
TRAVELED, YOU KNOW, PEOPLE, YOU
COULD ALWAYS HEAR THEM WHISPER
UNDER THEIR BREATH, "OH, THAT'S
MATT HAMILL! I'VE GOT TO WATCH
HIM WRESTLE!" HILL: MATT HAMILL,
A FORMER RIT NTID STUDENT AND
THREE TIME DIVISION THREE
WRESTLING CHAMPION FIRST CAUGHT
HOLLYWOOD PRODUCER'S ATTENTION
WHEN HE BECAME A CONTESTANT ON
THE ULTIMATE FIGHTER REALITY
SHOW. NEW SPEAKER: MY WRITING
PARTNER, EBAN CASPAR, SAW IT ON
THE UFC REALITY SHOW A FEW YEARS
BACK, AND THOUGHT MATT WAS AN
INSPIRING GUY HIMSELF AND WE
LOOKED INTO IT, WE TRACKED HIM
DOWN, MET HIM, INTERVIEWED HIM,
THOUGHT IT WOULD BE A GOOD IDEA
FOR A SCRIPT AND WROTE THE
SCRIPT. I THINK THE WRITING
PROCESS WAS DIFFICULT IN THE
BEGINNING BECAUSE TO TRY TO
EXPLAIN TO SOMEONE, WE'RE GOING
TO WRITE YOUR LIFE STORY BUT
WE'RE GOING TO JUST FIT IT INTO
A THREE ACT STRUCTURE AND IN AN
HOUR AND A HALF FILM. NEW
SPEAKER: WE'RE GOING TO COMBINE
YOUR DAD AND YOUR GRANDFATHER
INTO ONE CHARACTER. HILL: NOT
ONLY IS HIS STORY UNIQUE, THE
FINAL RESULT IS THE FIRST OF ITS
KIND. NEW SPEAKER: ONE OF THE
REALLY COOL THINGS I THINK THAT
WE'VE BEEN THINKING ABOUT THIS
PROJECT FROM THE BEGINNING IS
THAT IT'S GOING TO BE TOTALLY
SUBTITLED SO THE HEARING PEOPLE
WILL BE ABLE TO HEAR THE
ENGLISH, BUT THEY'LL HAVE TO
READ THE SUBTITLES FOR THE ASL
AND VICE VERSA FOR THE DEAF
PEOPLE. NEW SPEAKER: I TOLD YOU
YOUR WHOLE LIFE YOU DON'T HAVE
YTO BE TREATED DIFFERENT! NEWE
SPEAKER: BUT I AM DIFFERENT! NEW
SPEAKER: THERE AREN'T A LOT OF
MOVIES THAT YOU CAN GO TO THE
THEATER AND WATCH HEARING AND
DEAF TOGETHER UNLESS THEY'RE
FOREIGN FILMS BECAUSE THE DEAF
PEOPLE NEED THE SUBTITLES, SO
IT'S KIND OF THIS ONE OF A KIND
MOVIE WHERE DEAF PEOPLE AND
HEARING PEOPLE CAN WATCH IT
TOGETHER IN THE THEATER. HILL:
AFTER YEARS OF PRODUCTION, THE
MOVIE TITLED "THE HAMMER", AFTER
HAMILL HIMSELF, HAS ALREADY WON
EIGHT FILM FESTIVAL AWARDS AND
HAS FINALLY HIT THE BIG SCREEN
IN OVER A HUNDRED THEATERS
NATIONWIDE. NEW SPEAKER: LET ME
TELL YOU THAT YOU HAVE A HIGHLY
INTELLIGENT GRANDSON WHO'S
PROFOUNDLY DEAF. NEW SPEAKER:
ALREADY WE'VE GONE EIGHT FOR
EIGHT IN FILM FESTIVALS, WHICH
IS AWESOME. I THINK IT WAS AFI
IN CALIFORNIA, MAUI, CLEVELAND.
WE JUST WANT IT TO HIT THE RIGHT
AUDIENCES AND KIND OF BRIDGE THE
GAP AND HAVE IT BE A "THE
BLINDSIDE" MEETS "ROCKY" MEETS
"RUDY" TYPE OF FILM. NEW
SPEAKER: WE KNEW THE FILM WAS
SPECIAL FROM THE BEGINNING. AND
EVERYBODY'S BEEN INVOLVED WITH
IT, ESPECIALLY I MYSELF WAS VERY
LATE IN THE PROCESS, BUT IT'S
BEEN PHENOMENAL TO SEE THAT
EVERYBODY ELSE IS COMING OUT AND
SUPPORTING IT AND THE VAST
MAJORITY OF THOSE AWARDS CAME
NOT FROM CRITICS, BUT THEY CAME
FROM THE AUDIENCE MEMBERS
THEMSELVES WHO LOVED THE FILM
AND JUST WANT TO SEE IT SUCCEED.
(CHEERING) HILL: WHAT'S IT LIKE
FOR YOU, THIS FEELING THAT YOU
HAVE NOW THAT YOUR LIFE IS MADE
INTO A MOVIE? HAMILL: WELL,
YEAH, IT'S SOMETHING THAT, UHM,
IT'S SO WEIRD, IT'S REALLY
WEIRD, BECAUSE IT WAS A STRANGE
THING TO ME. I THINK IT'S BEST
TO (INAUDIBLE). I MEAN, LET'S GO
BACK A LITTLE BIT. THIS MOVIE,
"THE HAMMER", IT TOOK US SIX
YEARS FOR THIS PROJECT. I
THOUGHT, YOU KNOW, IT WON'T BE
REALLY SPECIAL OR ELSE I THOUGHT
IT WOULD BE REAL SHORT
(INAUDIBLE).I REALIZED THAT THE
MOVIE PRODUCERS DID NOT GIVE UP,
BUT OVERALL, YOU KNOW, WOW! IT'S
VERY SPECIAL. IT'S A SPECIAL
MOMENT YOU KNOW, TO HAVE
SOMETHING YOU KNOW, ABOUT MY
LIFE SHOWN ROUND THE WORLD. IT'S
REALLY AMAZING. HILL: HAMILL'S
STORY WILL CERTAINLY SERVE AS AN
INSPIRATION TO BOTH THE DEAF AND
HEARING COMMUNITY. NEW SPEAKER:
YOU KNOW I HOPE THAT THEY JUST
ENJOY THE FILM AND FEEL GOOD
ABOUT IT. OBVIOUSLY THE MESSAGE
IS ABOUT OVERCOMING STRUGGLES AT
ANY POINT IN YOUR LIFE. I
HAVEN'T SEEN THE FILM UNTIL
TONIGHT, BUT THE PARTS I'VE SEEN
ARE REALLY UPLIFTING AND YOU
KNOW, IT'S A GREAT MESSAGE AND I
THINK IT COMES AT A PRETTY COOL
TIME. HILL: ALTHOUGH MATT HAMILL
HAS ACHIEVED SO MUCH IN HIS
LIFE, AT THE YOUNG AGE OF 35, HE
SAYS THERE'S STILL MORE TO COME.
HAMILL: I'M STILL RETIRED FROM
UFC, BUT I'M GOING TO SEE WHAT
HAPPENS AFTER CHRISTMAS. I HAVE
A TORN ROTATOR CUFF. I'M JUST
GOING TO LET IT FLOW AND SEE HOW
IT GOES FROM THERE. I'M 35. I
DON'T WANT TO REGRET WHEN I GET
OLDER, I'M JUST HOPING THERE
MIGHT BE A LITTLE BIT OF A SPARK
(INAUDIBLE)BUT RIGHT NOW I'M
JUST TAKING CARE OF MY BODY.
HILL: YOU'RE A MOTIVATIONAL
SPEAKER, YOU'RE A UFC FIGHTER,
YOU CAN SPEAK SIX LANGUAGES,
LIKE FOR YOU, WHAT IS YOUR
BIGGEST ACCOMPLISHMENT? HAMILL:
WELL, I'M STILL NOT SATISFIED;
I'M STILL NOT SATISFIED. IF
EVERYBODY COULD SEE MY EYES,
YOU'D KNOW I'M JUST NOT REALLY
HAPPY, BUT I STILL HAVE MORE TO
PROVE TO A LOT OF THE WORLD. I
STILL HAVE SOMETHING TO PROVE,
BUT LET'S WAIT AND THERE'S
SOMETHING BIG IN THE WORKS FOR
AND AUTO. HILL: IN JUST THEIR
FIRST SEASON IN THE LIBERTY
LEAGUE, THE RIT MEN'S SOCCER
TEAM PROVED THEY BELONG. THE
TIGERS SHUT OUT NINTH RANKED
HOBART IN THE LEAGUE SEMIFINAL
EARNING THE RIGHT TO HOST THE
CONFERENCE TITLE GAME. DITULLIO:
TIGERS HOSTING VASSAR, A TEAM
THEY BEAT TWO NOTHING EARLIER
THIS YEAR, BUT VASSAR CONTROLLED
THINGS EARLY. THE FIFTH MINUTE,
OFF THE CORNER KICK, JULIANO
PEREIRA FINDS THE TOP RIGHT
CORNER TO GIVE THE BREWERS AN
EARLY ONE NOTHING LEAD. RIT
WOULD ANSWER, THE 28TH MINUTE
OFF THE THROW IN, MATT BROEDEL
WITH THE CHANCE AND HE PUTS IT
IN TO KNOT THE GAME AT ONE.
(CHEERING) SECOND HALF TIED AT
TWO, THE 85TH MINUTE OFF THE
FREE KICK, ZANDER MRLIK ELEVATES
AND HEADS IN THE EVENTUAL GAME
WINNER AS VASSAR ENDS RIT'S
SEASON WITH A THREE TWO VICTORY.
HILL: THE RIT MEN'S SOCCER TEAM
SUCCESSFUL RUN IN A NEW LEAGUE
ENDED IN DISAPPOINTMENT. THE RIT
TIGERS WERE DEFEATED THREE TWO
AGAINST VASSAR TO LOSE THE
LIBERTY LEAGUE CHAMPIONSHIP AND
A BID TO THE NCAA TOURNAMENT.
(CHEERING) SO IT WASN'T THE
IDEAL OUTCOME, BUT WHAT DOES IT
MEAN TO YOU TO HAVE SUCH A GREAT
SEASON AND COME TO THE
CHAMPIONSHIP YOUR FIRST TIME IN
THE LIBERTY LEAGUE? NEW SPEAKER:
IT WAS GREAT FOR THE TEAM. YOU
KNOW, WE WANTED TO GO OUT STRONG
AND YOU KNOW, MOST OF THE TEAMS
IN THE LIBERTY LEAGUE DIDN'T
EXPECT US TO DO WHAT WE DID AND
I'M PROUD OF OUR BOYS, THE
COACHING STAFF, EVERYBODY, WE
GAVE IT OUR ALL AND IT'S TRAGIC
THE WAY IT ENDED, BUT IT WAS
STILL A GREAT RUN AND WE LOOK
FORWARD TO SEEING THEM HERE NEXT
YEAR AGAIN. NEW SPEAKER: WE WANT
TO WIN CHAMPIONSHIPS. TODAY WE
HAD A SHOT; DIDN'T PLAY OUR BEST
GAME AND RAN INTO A TEAM THAT'ST
BEEN FLYING LATELY AND HATS OFF
TO THEM. UNFORTUNATE FOR US
TODAY. HILL: BEATING VASSAR TWO
NOTHING EARLIER IN THE SEASON,
DO YOU THINK IT MADE YOU GUYS A
LITTLE TOO OVERCONFIDENT COMING
INTO TODAY'S GAME? NEW SPEAKER:
NO, IT DIDN'T. WE KNEW WHAT WE
HAD TO DO. WE ONLY EXECUTED FOR
PART OF THE GAME. THEY'RE A
GREAT TEAM. ALL THE TEAMS IN THE
LIBERTY LEAGUE ARE SO
COMPETITIVE THAT ONE DAY YOU
KNOW YOU CAN BEAT A TEAM FIVE
NOTHING, THE NEXT DAY YOU CAN
LOSE, SO IT'S A TOUGH
CONFERENCE, ONE OF THE TOUGHEST
IN THE NATION, AND FOR US TO BE
IN IT IS A REAL PRIVILEGE. HILL:
HOW DID NOT HAVING YOUR STARTING
GOALTENDER IN NET AFFECT THE
TEAM CHEMISTRY? NEW SPEAKER:
WELL, WE DIDN'T HAVE HIM TUESDAY
EITHER. THERE'S SOME EFFECT,
SURE, SEAN WAS ARGUABLY ONE OF
THE BEST GOALIES IN THE REGION
ALL YEAR, STRONG PART OF OUR
SUCCESS, BUT THIS IS A TEAM, WE
HAVE OTHER PLAYERS TO STEP IN.
BEN STEPPED IN AND GOT A SHUTOUT
TUESDAY AGAINST THE 8TH RANKED
TEAM IN THE COUNTRY. I THOUGHT
HE DID, YOU KNOW, HE DIDN'T HURT
US TODAY, BUT SURE, WE MISS, YOU
MISS A PLAYER OF CONWAY'S
CALIBER, NO QUESTION ABOUT IT.
HILL: WHY DO YOU THINK YOU GUYS
MATCHED UP SO WELL TO THE TEAMS
IN THE LIBERTY LEAGUE AND DID SO
WELL? NEW SPEAKER: WE'RE A
SIMPLE TEAM; WE LIKE TO PLAY
SOCCER, YOU KNOW, BUT A LOT OF
THE OTHER TEAMS PLAY MORE
DIRECT, PLAY PHYSICAL, THAT'S
THE AMERICAN WAY, BUT WE LIKE TO
PLAY SOCCER AND WE BEAT TEAMS BY
WEARING THEM OUT WITH OUR
FITNESS AND THEN IN THE END WE
BEAT THEM WITH OUR PLAY AND GET
A FEW GOALS. NEW SPEAKER: I
THINK WE DID WELL AGAINST IT
DIDN'T MATTER WHO IT WAS BECAUSE
WE HAD SOME RELATIVELY TOUGH
PLAYERS MENTALLY WHO FOUGHT AND
WE PLAYED A SIMPLE GAME. WE HAD
A LOT OF CLOSE GAMES, WE GOT A
LOT OF POSITIVE RESULTS IN CLOSE
GAMES, SO THAT TELLS YOU A
LITTLE BIT ABOUT THE MENTAL
MAKEUP OF SOME OF THE GUYS. WE
BELIEVED, WE WORKED HARD AND IF
YOU DO THOSE THINGS SOME GOOD
THINGS CAN HAPPEN. WE GOT A WAYS
TO GO, BUT I THINK WE GOT A
TASTE THIS YEAR, ESPECIALLY FOR
SOME OF THE YOUNGER GUYS, YOU
KNOW WE WERE STARTING TWO OR
THREE FRESHMAN MOST GAMES. TODAY
WAS ABOUT TODAY AND ABOUT THIS
YEAR, BUT WE'VE GOT TO TAKE A
LITTLE BIT OF LOOK AND SAY, YOU
KNOW, WHAT DOES THIS PRESENT FOR
US FOR THE FUTURE? HILL: WHAT
WILL YOU TAKE AWAY FROM THIS
SEASON AND YOUR TIME HERE
PLAYING WITH THE TIGERS? NEW
SPEAKER: JUST THE GREAT MEMORIES
ON AND OFF THE FIELD, IN THE
LOCKER ROOM, YOU KNOW, I MET
SOME OF MY BEST FRIENDS THAT
I'LL KEEP FOR THE REST OF MY
LIFE AND YOU KNOW, THE MEMORIES
WHEN I TALK TO MY GRANDKIDS
ABOUT ME PLAYING COLLEGE SOCCER
IS WHAT I'M GOING TO KEEP.
DITULLIO: WELL THAT DOES IT FOR
THIS EDITION OF RIT SPORTSZONE.
HILL: DON'T FORGET YOU CAN STAY
UP TO DATE WITH SPORTSZONE BY
FOLLOWING US ON TWITTER AND
LIKING US ON FACEBOOK. DITULLIO:
SO UNTIL NEXT TIME, THANKS FOR
JOINING US HERE IN THE ZONE.