and glaciers grow and recede
the earth's crust is carved in numerous and fascinating ways
leaving a trail of geological mysteries behind
In this episode, Iceland
the wolrd's largest volcanic island is explored
This barren and alien landscape generates 1/3 of the world's lava
Steam billows from the ground
and boiling water is thrusted into the air
It's a land of violent extremes
where fire meets it's nemesis, ice
where clues to understanding Iceland's formation
also provide a window into the formation of the earth itself
In the middle of the North Atlantic ocean lies Iceland
a lone island only 300 miles (480 Km) wide
a volcanic hot pit
it holds some of the most diverse geological wonders known to mankind
To understand how it formed
and the dynamic forces that are shaping this land
scientists are scouring the strange landscape for clues
And the investigation starts here
in the southwest of Iceland: Thingvellir plane
This broad inland valley runs through the centre of Iceland
giant cracks scar the valley floor
leaving this unusual landscape behind
Geologist Mike Poland believes there are major clues in the mystery of Iceland's formation
I'm standing at a really spectacular place. There's evidence for volcanic activity all around,
this valley is covered in lava, and the plane has been ripped apart
Everywhere I look there's massive tears in the ground like this one right here
This crack is getting bigger and bigger every year
In fact, this entire valley is spreading apart
at about the same rate the fingernails grow
Imagine the forces that must be involved to rip the land apart like this
Something powerful is spreading this valley at a rate of 1 inch (2,5 cm) per year
A force so inmense it's pulling the entire country apart
But what force on earth could have such power?
In 1912 german climatologist Alfred Wegener,
found an essential clue.
Browsing through maps,
he noticed that the great land masses of the Americas and Eurasia appeared to fit together
This observation led Wegener to propose a radical new theory:
That these great continents had once been joined together.
So some unseen force must have pushed them apart
allowing water to rush into the space between them
creating the Atlantic ocean
It was inspired detective work, and a major step forward
in the search for what was pulling Iceand apart
But with no method to prove such a force existed
Wegener's theory was ignored for the next 40 years.
Then in 1946, new evidence was discovered to support Wegener's ideas
The U.S. navy, using a technology called SONAR IMAGING
mapped the Atlantic ocean floor for the first time
The pictures revealed a 10.000 mile (16.000 Km) network of underwater mountains
separated by a giant tear which passes through the center of the Atlantic
Scientists called this the Mid-Atlantic Ridge
This huge tear through the earth's crust is the boundary between the American and Eurasian plates
and the tear runs right through the center of Iceland
I'm actually standing on what's the center of the ocean floor
Where the Mid-Atlantic Ridge comes on the land
and this puts the North American plate on this side
from the Eurasian plate on this side
and the Mid-Atlantic Ridge starts way south, down by Antarctica
comes all the way up through the Atlantic
and splits this country right in two
Scientists suspected this was pushing the continents and Iceland apart
They came up with a theory: Deep below the ocean,
convection currents of molten rock tear open the earth's crust
allowing magma to seep up and push the continents apart
But there was a problem: It was so deep, scientists had no way of proving
where the magma was seeping through the crust at the centre of the ridge
Until in 1974. Alvin, a human-operated submersible
was launched by the Woods Hole Oceanographic Institute
with its ability to withstand deep-sea pressures, scientists could finally travel down
to the depths needed to reach the Mid-Atlantic Ridge
It was by examining the tear that runs through the center of this ridge
that they spotted the evidence they had been looking for
Hot volcanic gases billowing into the ocean
Finding this told them that the Mid-Atlantic Ridge was highly volcanic
and, like a giant wedge, was capable of spreading great land masses apart
Iceland's cracked Thingvellir Valley is a continuation of the Mid-Atlantic Ridge
The same process that is pushing America further away from Europe
is happening here, on land
Finally, here was a force powerful enough to explain why the cracks are getting wider
and Iceland is getting bigger
As the ridge continues to spread, it's going to add more and more land to Iceland
so in a way Iceland will start getting longer and longer
in an east-west sense, as the plates spread apart from one another
So, in a way, Iceland is not getting torn apart so much as it's getting built
The investigation into how Iceland is growing has revealed:
Cracks on the Thingvellir plane are widening at a rate of 1 inch (2,5 cm) per year
And hot gases prove that this spreading force is volcanic
forming the Mid-Atlantic Ridge, which cuts right through Iceland
Scientists concluded it's THIS that's widening the country
Convection currents of hot rock pull the Mid-Atlantic Ridge apart,
magma surges up to fill the cracks,
and as it approaches the surface it cools, hardens, and forms new land
Like a conveyor belt, it continually pushes Iceland apart
But something didn't add up: Why wasn't Iceland at the bottom of the ocean,
like the rest of the Mid-Atlantic Ridge?
There's something strange about the amount of volcanic activity on this island
Because this is not a normal section of the Mid-Atlantic Ridge
There's a tremendous amount of volcanism that's happening in this part of the ridge
as opposed to the ridge that's off in the Atlantic Ocean
The hunt is now on to discover how Iceland rose a mile and a half (2.400 m) off the ocean floor
and became the biggest volcanic island in the world
Iceland
There are more active volcanoes concentrated here
than anywhere else on the planet
Geologists are searching for what has helped to push Iceland off the ocean floor
and lights the firy volcanoes that rage across this barren land
On the hunt for clues, the investigation heads to one of Iceland's most active volcanoes,
Hekla
Known locally as the "Gateway to Hell"
Like all active volcanoes in Iceland, Hekla sits alongside the Mid-Atlantic Ridge
Volcanologist Dr. Pete La Femina is taking a High-resolution scan of the volcano
to see if its geology hides any clues about its inner workings
This is a terrestrial laser scanner
and the laser produces a 3D image of the earth's surface
and that allows us to see parts of Hekla volcano here that we can't see with the naked eye
His scan reveals a giant crack, or fissure, running right through the centre of the volcano
similar to those found in the Thingvellir Valley
But this fissure doesn't just expand the width of the volcano,
it extends either side along a 5-mile (8 Km) tear in the earth
It's this tear that is key to understanding how Iceland's volcanoes erupt
When Hekla erupted in the year 2000 it wasn't just a volcanic cone that exploded
The earth actually ripped open along the entire 5-mile (8 Km) lenght of the fissure,
a weakness created by the stretching along the Mid-Atlantic Ridge
In the geological world these are known as "Fissure Eruptions"
Forced open by the sheer volume of magma pushing up from below,
the tear spewed out a terrifying 750 million cubic feet (21 million m3) of molten rock an hour
flodding the land with lava
These fissure eruptions are so huge they can change the landscape drastically in a matter of days
leaving behind mountains like these
You can see to the North here, where the earth's surface actually opened up
during a fissure eruption, and lava erupted out
This fissure starts to the north and extends 8 Km through
Hekla volcano here
The sheer volume of magma produced can be seen very well here
at Hekla volcano, specially with these lava flows
that have graved the land's surface
And to me this is really exciting, because you can see very large volmes of erupted material
produced over very short amount of time
and Hekla is a beautiful place to study that
But what is creating the vast quantities of lava that are forced out during these eruptions?
For many years the answer remained elusive
until geologists found incriminating evidence locked inside the rocks
The composition of the rocks here in Iceland is quite different
to what we see in other places
By taking this rock back to the Lab we can get a very good idea
of under what conditions it formed
whether it formed deep within the earth or near the surface
This rock was once molten lava which erupted from one of Iceland's volcanoes
Analysis of the chemicals in the rock revealed unusually high concentrations
of rare earth elements, lanthium and cesium,
chemicals which are only found in magma with a very deep origin
It's the breakthrough scentists had been searching for
It was evidence that another, much deeper heath source
was combining with the Mid-Atlantic Ridge
to power the volcanoes of Iceland
The rock evidence suggested this second force laid hidden from view
deep beneath Iceland's surface
But, it is possible to get a glimpse of what's happening down there
Scientists monitor the seismic waves triggered by earthquakes all over the world
As the earth's plates move, they release shockwaves called seimic waves
that pass through the earth's crust
These travel at a steady speed unless they hit a region of hard rock
Then, they slow down
Now as seismic waves arrive in Iceland
they're travelling very slowly through the subsurface
and this is something unique to Iceland and a few other places in the world
It tells us as there's a very hard column of rock
perhaps even some molten material beneath the surface
These massive columns or "plumes" are known as HOT SPOTS
and are not unique to Iceland
They're found beneath certain volcanic areas in the world, like Hawaii and Yellowstone
Hot Spots are these unwavering plumes of hot material
including molten rock -magma- that stream up to the surface from deep within the earth
The scientists finally had a snapshot of the second force
that was helping to create Iceland
The Hot Spot that lies beneath the island
is almost 100 miles (160 Km) wide
and 400 miles (640 Km) deep
It channels rock slowly upwards at temperatures over 700º Fahrenheit
It pushes against the crust, heating the land from below
and forcing magma up onto the surface, as lava
The investigation has identified the two colossal forces that built Iceland
The Mid-Atlantic Ridge
and the deeper Icelandic Hot Spot
Millions of years ago,
the Mid-Atlantic Ridge drifted eastwards
creeping towards the fixed Icelandic Hot Spot
Finally they met, and have been locked together in a deadly partnership
ever since
The result: A truly formidable volcanic beast
capable of creating magma on a monumental scale
As the Mid Ocean Ridge pulls apart
there's decompression of the material underneath it, and that creates melting
Decompression is simply removing the pressure from a pile of rock
it's much like opening a can of soda
or popping the cork off of a champagne bottle
The removal of so much pressure
makes the rock melt into liquid magma
And the Hot Spot is transporting heat directly from the interior of the earth to the surface
which also creates melting
So this combination of decompression of existing rock beneath the surface
and the direct transport of heat from the center of the earth created huge amounts of magma
This incredible meeting of the Mid-Atlantic Ridge and Hot Spot
began to build the island beneath the waves
pushing it upwards and giving birth to Iceland
Scientists have dated the island's emergence to 20 million years ago
but could only imagine what this might have looked like
But on November 14th, 1963, off the south coast of Iceland
The world watched an action-replay of Iceland's spectacular birth
A column of rock and ash blasted out of the ocean
18.000 feet (5.400 m) into the sky
So high it could be seen 70 miles (110 Km) away in Iceland's capital city, Reykjavík
A new island was forming, right in front of the world's eyes
Scientists called it Surtsey after the Norse god of fire: Surtr
Located 20 miles (32 Km) off the mainland,
the small island of Surtsey is now a magnet for geologists
It offers a wealth of forensic evidence for Dr. La Femina,
who is investigating how Iceland first formed
It'a amazing to see Surtsey for the first time
I've seen pictures, I've seen aerial photographs
but actually be here and get a chance to
to go out and see it up close and actually look at the geology
it's just inspiring
This type of eruption that formed Surtsey has now been named after Surtsey
We call them "Surtseyan Eruptions",
and they're very, very explosive
The interaction of hot magma or lava with the ocean
causes these very steam-rich and highly explosive eruptions
of ash and water
When scientists first stepped foot into the island in the summer of '64
they found it hard to believe that this was an island whose age
was measured in MONTHS, not millenia
In about 9,5 months this whole volcanic cone built up
In addition, lava flows came out of the volcanic center here
and we seen those as nice black cliffs in front of us
Now geologists had an insight into how early Iceland might have formed
In only 20 million years, Iceland grew from a tiny island into a 40.000 square mile (104.000 Km2) landmass,
as big as the state of Kentucky
The forces that powered Iceland's volcanoes
have been revealed
Cracks along Hekla volcano unleashed gigantic fissure eruptions
and rare chemicals in the rock proved
that these eruptions were fuelled by two separated forces:
Mid-Atlantic Ridge and the Hot Spot
Iceland grew to become the world's largest volcanic island
But volcanism alone doesn't explain how the land of Iceland was formed
The investigation will honour another equally dramatic force
that sculpted the distinctive shape of the Iceland we know today
A force which would challenge the might of Iceland's volcanoes
If Iceland was formed by fire alone,
it should look like other volcanic islands such as Hawaii or Tahiti
But something else was at work here to transform this island
into the distinctive shape it is today
Its shape is another clue to Iceland's formation
An extraordinary force indented Iceland's Northern coastline
burrowing deep fjords which extended far inland
But, what colossal force could cause such a dramatic change to Iceland's volcanic landscape?
There's an obvious suspect that is found scattered across the island:
Ice
As its name suggests, Iceland has a long history of being covered in ice, like this
Today it covers 10% of the island
all year round
And in the middle of the country lies Europe's biggest ice cap:
The mighty Vatnajökull
Over 3000 square miles (7.800 Km2) in size
Vatnajökull is so large it even has its own climatic conditions
Up to two thirds of a mile (1 Km) thick,
it squashes the land like a giant slab of rock
and at its edges great tongues of ice
flow out through deep valleys
Glacier expert Dr. Mattew Roberts
is investigating how ice can gauge out solid rock
and discover the role it is playing in Iceland's past
This is a GPS receiver, just like in car satellite navigation
it's used here to measure glacier movement
this will be left on the ice surface for a few days
and I'll come back and analyse the data
to discover just how far the glacier has moved
Dr. Roberts data reveals that this whole glacier is sliding forward
at an astounding rate of 2 feet (0,6 m) ... per day!
This is an amazing ever changing environement: The ice around me is like
an icy sea that has been frozen in place
As the ice flows out to the confines of the valley
it expands, it spreads to occupy a greater area
Now as it expands, crevasses form
In large depressions, just like the one here,
(here's a smaller crevasse that is formed)
ocasionally when these crevasses open, as it begin to open,
sounds can be heard
Also, the glacier ocasionally makes a groaning sound
it's all signs that the glacier is alive and moving forward
very slowly
Vatnajökull is one of the largest ice caps in the northern hemisphere
flowing down the valleys, the great mass of ice
bears down with the weight of 100 tons per square foot (975 tons/m2)
Dr. Roberts believes this moving giant is a force
capable of eroding solid rock,
and he has found crucial evidence to prove it
This is an excellent example of the power of glacial erosion
This boulder would have been trapped beneath the base of the ice
and, as the ice flowed over the surface of it,
it would have progressively eroded the surface of the boulder
to produce these very distinctive marks, called striations, in its surface
We can even tell the direction in wich the ice was flowing
If I take a rock, I can illustrate this
Imagine this is the base of the ice,
the material trapped inside the ice
being dragged across as the glacier moved
to produce this very distinctive marks in the surface
This is just like sandpaper over wood,
the same erosive effect
The erosive process that's happening on this boulder
is the same process that's happening on a much larger scale
along the surface of these valleys
The glacier is responsible for literally carving the landscape,
producing very distinctive throughs and basins
which were formerly infilled with solid rock
This really testifies the erosive power of a glacier
The ancient fjords on the north coast
are the same deep-basin shape
Which means they must once have been filled with ice
Scientists now know that around 1,5 million years ago
changes in the earth's orbit and the tilt of its axis
began to cool the planet
An enormous ice sheet descended from the north
and shrouded Iceland in a cloak of ice
As the ice advanced and retreated,
it carved out deep fjords
and indented Iceland's northern coastline
Ice was a formidable force in Iceland
and many volcanoes laid at tomb beneath it
Fire and ice were now locked in a titanic battle of supremacy
When the giant ice sheets that carved the fjords
put out the fires that created Iceland
The first clue lies in this ancient valley, 5 miles (8 Km) west of the glacier
The valley floor is strewed with hundreds of giant boulders
but it's how they got here that interests Dr. Roberts
These boulders provide a lot of insight into how this landscape was formed
The boulders clusted together and, interestingly,
this boulders are rounded, which shows they've been rolling
And the boulders have been brought together by some dynamical force
We can also see smaller boulders trapped in the center
And it's quite clear that flowing water is the cause of this
But this would haven't been water in the stream that we see in the background
this would have been water produced by a much larger, faster flow
that would have inundated this entire valley
Dr. Roberts has an extraordinay theory about what happened here:
In ancient times, a cataclysmic flood 100 feet (30 m) high cut through this valley
It was so powerful that it rolled this giant boulders like pebbles in a stream
before dumping them on the landscape
But what could create such a colossal flow of water?
Dr. Roberts suspects the flood came from the mighty Vatnajökull glacier
and he's hunting for clues
With such a huge area to cover, Dr. Roberts takes to the air
His investigation leads him to a crucial peace of evidence:
This strange bowl-like depression on the surface of the ice
This is an amazing location. This giant depression in the ice has been formed
as a pocket of water drained from beneath the base of the ice cap
The beautiful concentric crevasses that you see on the ice surface were formed
as the ice slowly crept into the hole of this pit created as the waters drained the way
Beneath the ice, a dynamic process is happening
Hot magma and steam are melting the glacier from underneath
The meltwater collects in a huge ice basin at the top of the volcano
The basin slowly fills. But as it does, the surrounding ice becomes unstable,
cracks up here, in the ice basin. And as the hot water drains away,
it forms a tunnel which channels the water to the edge of the glacier
This would suggest that volcanic eruptions still happen even under the enormous weight of ice
Is this process the key to explaining the ancient cataclysmic flood?
To answer this, we must go to one of Iceland's largest volcanoes:
Grímsvötn
Lying entombed beneath the ice in the heart of Vatnajökull
This massive volcano violently erupts every 10 years
Here fire and ice spectacularly collide, with Iceland's volcanoes emerging victorious
Ice cannot supress the invincible power of Iceland's volcanoes
which have now found a new way to vent their anger
During a huge eruption like this, Grímsvötn can melt enough ice
to fill America's largest man-made reservoir: Lake Mead
But this vast volume of water cannot be held back by the ice for long
and leads inevitabily to a massive glacial flood
Such a force of nature struck Iceland in 1996 with devastating consequences,
the floodwater taking out everyting in its path
Bridges were torn down and swept away
and the highway was submerged under water
The flood itself reached a peak discharge of over 1,8 million cubic feet per second (50.000 m3/s),
that's a remarkable discharge, prevalent to the summertime discharge of the river Amazon
Imagine that sort of condition over a relatively small area
The sheer force of the water carried icebergs the size of 4 storey buildings
It's floods like these that can change the landscape in a matter of days
The erosive power of the flowing water can result in tremendous amounts of rock
being eroded, literally being fractured away by the high water pressure that is being created
so, literally a landscape can form before your eyes during a very severe glacial flood
The story of Iceland's bizarre landscape is taking shape
Striations on rock prove that ice is a formidable force
that carved out Iceland's unique coastline
Boulders strewn in an empty valley
reveal cataclysmic floods of the past
And depressions in the ice confirm that Iceland's volcanoes could not be supressed
But 12.000 years ago the great ice sheets retreated
and Iceland was liberated from their wintery grip,
Now, the effects of Iceland's volcanoes would be felt on a global scale
For thusands of years Iceland's volcanoes were locked in a titanic battle with ice
But then, 12.000 years ago, the giant ice sheets finally retreated
This would open a new chapter in Iceland's volcanic history,
as they were now free to wreak havoc
But, what effect would this have on Iceland and its surroundings?
One of the most dramatic effects can be found in the south-central region of the island
This alien landscape is known as Laki
A road of strange craters and solidified lava flows
that have bubbled up from a huge tear in the earth
A massive fissure eruption, it stretches for an astounding 16 miles (25 Km) across the landscape
Volcanologist Dr. Thor Thordarson is investigating Laki,
the site of one of the greatest eruptions in recent history,
one which would have devastating effects worldwide
The Laki fissures, which extend from here in the southwest,
continue here through the landscape as roll cones, up in through Mount Laki
which was split into 2 during the eruption
and continue futher to the northeast all the way to the margins of the glaciers here
Eyewitness accounts accurately date the eruption to 1783
This was one of the most disastrous years in Icelandic history
Fallout from the eruption caused harvests all over the island to fail
75% of the livestock died, plunging Iceland into a great famine which killed 10.000 people
But mysteriously, at the same time the rest of the northern hemisphere
reported freakishly cold weather
Averaging 2,3 ºF (1,28ºC) below normal, the northern hemisphere froze over
The North Sea along the coast of Holland froze,
so people skated between villages along the coast
There was on Mississippi down by New Orleans in that winter
For many years it was thought the Laki eruption and this climatic events were unrelated,
but advances in geology found it wasn't just a bizarre coincidence
Comparing eyewitness accounts with the geological remains
Dr. Thordarson has reconstructed what happened
He discovered that the eruption started with a bang on the morning of June 8, 1783
It sent rocks flying high into the air
and ripped the earth open along a 1 mile (1,6 Km) tear
But this was just the beginning
3 days later, a second eruption ripped open, then a 3rd, 4th, 5th...
In total, the earth unzipped along 10 vast tears in the crust
erupting lava continuously for over 8 months
The mammoth amounts of lava that poured out of the ground here
would have buried Manhattah to a depth of 830 feet (250 m)
But how an eruption on this small, remote island could cause climatic chaos
thousands of miles away, remained a mystery
The evidence that would link Laki with this worldwide catastrophe
was locked inside these boulders
The story is in the rocks. This rock here is part of
the material, the magma that came out during the eruption
These holes are cold bubbles,
and they form as the magma raises from deep within the ground and approaches the surface
and it really starts to boil!
The gas, which is dissolved in the magma at depth, goes into the bubbles
then it escapes into the atmosphere
When this bubble rock erupted onto the surface
it would have poured gas out into the Icelandic atmosphere
Could this gas have caused climatic chaos across the globe?
The identity of this gas can be found in the microscopic structure of the rock
If you look closely at this rock, you can see a lot of white specks
these little white specks are the crystals who grow in the magma at depth
Sometimes this crystals, as they're growing, they would encapsulate
pristine magma and bring it up to the surface
Like time capsules, the white crystals contained untouched magma from deep in the earth
locked away since 1783
Dr. Thordarson has analysed this magma and found it to contain poisonous Sulphur Dioxide
And because there was so much lava here, it would have released enormous amounts
A staggering 100 million tons of Sulphur Dioxide gas was pumped into the atmosphere
But how could gases released from Laki cause bitterly cold weather across the globe?
The answer laid in accounts of a thick, red fog reported over Iceland in June 1783
Within a few weeks it had been blown over London and Paris
By July, it had dispersed across the entire northern hemisphere
Scientists now know that the red fog was caused by the Sulphur Dioxide which rose high into the air
Mixing with water, it created a Sulphuric Acid haze
The haze blocked out the sun, and it sent temperatures plummeting
As a result, the northern hemisphere endured 3 bitterly cold winters
which brought spring floods, famine and widespread poverty to Europe
Some historians have long believed that these climatic conditions
triggered social and political unrest, which led to the French Revolution in 1789
But scientists now suspect Laki had ramifications even further afield
The cold temperatures in the north changed air currents in the south
causing dramatic climate changes
India was hit by a terrible drought
People say that more than half a million people died from the drought in India
Also, this change in atmospheric circulation caused a very cold summer in Japan
It was cold and wet
The rice harvest failed,
and the result was the greatest famine in japanese history
It is estimated that Laki killed over 2 million people worldwide,
and was one of the most devastating volcanic eruptions in the history of mankind
The evidence has proven that Iceland's recent volcanic history
has had a devastating effect on the island and the rest of the world
Enormous lava fields reveal that Laki was a gigantic eruption
Bubbles in the rock indicate that huge volumes of gas were released from Laki
The white crystals reveal that this gas was poisonous Sulphur Dioxide,
evidence that Iceland's volcanoes caused climatic mayhem across the globe
But eruptions like Laki may not be confined to the past
Some believe that the balance between fire and ice is shifting,
and has the potential to propel Iceland into another hell on earth
The evidence is mounting, that Iceland has the potential to be the most lethal island on the planet
A fearsome volcanic force lies beneath it, creating powerful volcanoes
capable of generating gigantic lava flows and altering global climates
Yet many of Iceland's volcanoes are covered in glaciers,
fire and ice are held in a delicate balance
Scientists fear if this balance were tipped the volcanoes favour,
Iceland could become even deadlier
If the remaining ice were to melt,
what effect would it have on the activity of Iceland's volcanoes?
The first clue in the investigation lies in these innocuous-looking piles of rock and rubble
They're found all over Iceland,
and yet this rocks don't come from a volcano
They're Morraines:
The geological term for rock piles deposited at the mouth of a glacier
These deposits are evidence that the glaciers are shrinking
Year by year, the glacier has melted and retreated back up the valley,
leaving a Morraine like this behind
Dr. Roberts has studied the Vatnajökull glacier for the last ten years
and has noticed this dramatic trend
The glacier is retreating at a remarkable rate since I've been visiting the area
I've seen tremendous changes. The ice has retreated annually at a rate of about
200 feet (61 m) per year. This lake over here used to be filled with ice
I've seen the ice progressively melt, this morraine has formed,
this whole valley has become almost bare
Maybe in the next 20 years this whole glacier will disappear and a lake will form in that valley
Iceland's glaciers are melting at an unprecedented rate
With 5% of Iceland's ice caps melting in the last 40 years,
the question that scientists are keen to understand
is: What effect this rapid melting will have on the volcanoes that lie beneath?
The only other time that glaciers have melted this quickly
is when Iceland came out of the last Ice Age
But what can past events tell us about the future?
Geologist professor Bill McGuire is investigating how volcanic activity changed
at the end of the last Ice Age
And he's unearthed some surprising results
Around about 11 or 12 thousand years ago you started to see quite rapid melting of glaciers
in Iceland and elsewhere
And that triggered a recognisable increase of volcanic activity,
because you were removing this large mass of ice very, very quickly
The rapid melting of ice kick-starts volcanic eruptions beneath
Volcanic eruptions are triggered by the gas in the magma,
which expands to form bubbles and the bubbles drive the eruption
It's rather like taking the cork out of a bottle of champagne
Now, if you have a very heavy weight on top of a volcano,
if it's a heavy mass of water or ice,
that can help supress eruptive activity
But when ice melts quickly, this downward pressure is suddenly released
and that's when the trouble starts
As the ice melts, so the pressure on the magma underneath is reduced,
the gas in the magma can form bubbles, they can coalesce and they can eventually
drive the magma upwards towards the surface and trigger
other explosive eruptions or effusions of lava that are spared out at a huge distances
Iceland's glaciers are melting rapidly
This has led scientists to believe that a devastating eruption on the scale of Laki
could happen again
The question is WHEN? These are things that we have to think about
and try to prepare ourselves to deal with if they happen in our lifetime
Is it possible that we can get another eruption like this in Iceland?
Definetely
The investigation has revealed how the vast and voilent island of Iceland was formed
Cracks in the Thingvellir plane and traces of chemicals in the rocks
revealed how the Mid-Atlantic Ridge and Hot Spot joined forces to create a collossal volcanic force
Massive fissure eruptions ripped the land open
Hemorrhaging millions of tons of lava, Iceland rapidly formed
Deep northern fjords were evidence that a giant ice sheet eroded the land
and entombed the volcanoes, locking fire and ice in a titanic battle
Boulders strewn in an ancient valley reveal how fire emerged victorious
unleashing cataclysmic floods
And specks of Sulphur in the rocks showed how Iceland's volcanoes
have the potential to cause global destruction
Now, glaciers melting above some of the world's most deadly volcanoes
are increasing the threat of future eruptions
Over the last 20 million years, Iceland's almighty volcanic force
has created a vast, alien landscape
Volatile and unpredictable, it may one day unleash a massive eruption
which could devastate both Iceland and a wider world beyond
English captions and subtitles by Marc Gelizo     --for a non-profit use--