There has been a break in the fighting between
Israelis and Palestinians. A cease-fire started
to take hold last week. And the two sides
are scheduled to meet today in Egypt where
they`ll discuss what they want as part of
a longer term peace deal. The most recent
conflict lasted eight days in mid-November
and left dozens of Palestinians and six Israelis
dead. Palestinians fired rockets from the
region of Gaza that exploded in the Israeli
communities, and Israel launched air strikes
targeting Palestinian militants that also
caused civilian casualties. Israeli forces
had been preparing for a possible invasion
of Gaza last week, that`s when the U.S., the
U.N. and Egypt got involved, helping get the
two sides to agree to a cease-fire. That happened
last Wednesday, and though there has been
some limited fighting since then, the cease
fire appears to be holding.
Egypt, meanwhile, is having some trouble of
its own: in the capital city of Cairo where
massive protests led to the ouster of its
formal leader in 2011, there were clashes
yesterday. They were between protesters and
government forces. Many Egyptians are angry
with their new president Mohamed Morsi. Last
Thursday, Morsi issued this edict that basically
says: any decree or law that he has made since
he took office cannot be overturned by Egyptian
courts until a new constitution is finished.
That can happen in six months, and that, along
with some of his other actions, has some Egyptians
calling him a dictator. Morsi is promising
his new powers are only temporary.
China is the third stop in our international
coverage today. Something you don`t see very
often: a house on a highway. Look at this.
A neighborhood was torn down to make way for
the road you see right here. But the farmer
who lives in this house, says the government
offered him $35,000 to leave his property
when he paid $95,000 to build it. The government
raised the offer to 41,000, but that still
wasn`t enough for the farmer. So officials
literally built the road around the house.
It`s not yet open to traffic, and the local
officials expect the homeowner to work out
a deal with the government soon. But this
has become symbolic of the struggle between
Chinese homeowners and the government that
they say doesn`t offer them enough money to
relocate.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: It`s time for "The Shoutout."
The term "bicameral" means having two of what?
If you think you know it, then shout it out!
Is it: parties, lenses, cylinders or chambers?
You`ve got three seconds, go!
In
a bicameral legislature, there are two chambers
or houses. That`s your answer, and that`s
your "Shoutout."
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Those who serve in America`s bicameral
legislature, are back at work today, and along
with the president, representatives and senators
have a major challenge ahead in December:
the fiscal cliff you`ve heard us talk about.
Senators and representatives and the president
are trying to find a way to avoid this. And
it all comes down to agree on how the government
spends money and takes in money. But with
Democrats controlling the Senate and Republicans
controlling the House of Representatives,
Athena Jones explains how compromise is going
to be the name of the game.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
ATHENA JONES, CNN CORRESPONDENT: After meeting
with President Obama before the Thanksgiving
holiday ...
BARACK OBAMA, PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES
OF AMERICA: Well, I want to welcome the congressional
leadership here ...
JONES: Congressional leaders expressed optimism
about reaching a deal to avoid $500 billion
in tax increases and spending cuts set to
take effect next year.
REP. JOHN BOEHNER, (R ), HOUSE SPEAKER: We
had a very constructive meeting with the president
to talk about America`s fiscal problem.
SEN. HARRY REID (D), NEVADA: We have the cornerstones
of being able to work something out.
JONES: Staffers have been working behind the
scenes to find common ground. Among the big
sticking points, how to bring in more tax
revenue and reduce spending on programs like
Medicare.
But it`s not yet clear when lawmakers and
the president will meet next. And even if
some progress is made this week, a final deal
could still be a long way off.
JENNIFER LIBERTO, CNNMONEY.COM SENIOR WRITER:
We barely see the Hill and the White House
make decisions early. They tend to do better
when they have a deadline.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: That deadline at this time is January
1. That`s how long Congress has to reach an
agreement on the fiscal cliff.
The U.S. northeast, still cleaning up from
Superstorm Sandy, it will be for quite a while,
officials say sanitation crews have picked
up 280,000 tons of trash and debris in New
York alone. But while gas rationing is over,
transportation is getting back to normal,
thousands of people in New York and New Jersey
still didn`t have power going into the weekend
and many still didn`t have heat.
That, along with some other factors have created
some new problems for storm victims. Mary
Snow reports on the dangers you can`t see.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
MARY SNOW, CNN CORRESPONDENT: Lurking in the
devastation from Sandy is yet another worry
for homeowners. Exposure to toxins, mold and
dust and in some places, sewage.
Long Beach homeowner Fred Morello will only
enter his house wearing a protective suit
and mask as he clears out areas that were
submerged in several feet of water.
FRED MORELLO, LONG BEACH HOMEOWNER: I`m concerned
about molds? Sure. But at this particular
point, I don`t have a time for it. I have
things to get done. And they`ve got to get
done. So I protect myself as best I can.
SNOW: While Morello says, he has no time to
get checked for the cough he now has, others
have been showing up to MASH-like tents set
up by federal disaster medical assistance
teams.
(on camera): You`ve been to other disaster
areas.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Correct.
SNOW (voice over): Commander Kevin McGuillakati
(ph) says besides people seeking psychological
treatment, they`ve mostly come in complaining
of coughs, bronchitis and asthma. Since the
base was set up November 13th.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: What`s the word? The
major online shopping event that follows Black
Friday? Cyber Monday, that`s the word.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: And we have reports on both of those
shopping days. First today, Cyber Monday when
discounts are offered online. Definitely,
it doesn`t look as hectic as many Black Friday
events, but Cyber Monday shoppers who will
be dressed in everything from business suits
at work to pajamas at home will be surfing
for sales.
A couple of interesting notes this year: Cyber
Monday 2012 actually started last week. Online
discounts were offered before and on Thanksgiving
and during the weekend. Also, more Americans
are doing their shopping on phones and tablets
this time around, and many are looking for
phone and tablet discounts online as well.
As far as Black Friday itself went more shoppers
turned out for the event than last year, but
they didn`t appear to spend as much money.
This Youtube clip shows you one of the hectic
Black Friday scenes: crowds clamoring to get
in the malls and big box stores like Target
or Toys "R" Us. Black Friday store visits
went up 3.5 percent from 2011, but spending
was down by almost two percent. That could
be partly because many sales started before
Black Friday, so some folks might have shopped
early. Retailers and analysts pay close attention
to all of this stuff to get a sense of how
Americans are spending in a slow economy.
Don`t know yet how they are spending, but
we do know what many Americans are eating:
leftover turkey, a bird banquet is part of
Thanksgiving tradition for many of us. But
there is another tradition dating back to
1989 that you might not have heard about:
the presidential turkey pardon. It guarantees
at least one bird won`t wind up on anyone`s
table. Karin Caifa tells us where these lucky
turkeys go to leave.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
KARIN CAIFA, CNN CORRESPONDENT: An annual
reprise:
BILL CLINTON: I`m told that Jerry the Turkey
travel all the way here from Wisconsin.
CAIFA: A long line of lucky birds:
GEORGE W. BUSH: May and Flower, they are certainly
better than the names the vice president suggested,
which was Lunch and Dinner.
(laughter)
CAIFA: On Wednesday, President Obama added
Gobbler and Cobbler to that least, the annual
White House turkey pardon.
BARACK OBAMA, PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES
OF AMERICA: I have one more gift to give,
and it goes to a pair of turkeys named Cobbler
and Gobbler.
CAIFA: But after the camera stopped rolling,
and the president heads back to the Oval Office,
what does happen to those pardoned turkeys?
Well, they`ll come right here, to the home
of the nation`s first president. First stop,
this specially prepared pen on the grounds
of Mount Vernon, George Washington`s historic
estate in Virginia. They`ll be a main attraction
at a holiday festival for six weeks. Then,
a tranquil retirement.
DEAN NORTON, MOUNT VERNON HORTICULTURE DIRECTOR:
After the six weeks, they`ll move back to
our livestock department, and be with all
sorts of other animals, and you are just always
thrilled when they get back there.
CAIFA: Historically, it`s appropriate. It
was George Washington who suggested a national
day of Thanksgiving in 1789. Giving thanks
for life beyond Thanksgiving dinner. In Washington,
I`m Karin Caifa for CNN STUDENT NEWS.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: It`s hard to think of puns for the word
"turkey" I mean there are other ideas we could
shout from the rafters like that gobbles up
our time for today. When we couldn`t a leg
up on any great ideas, and when the whole
gang couldn`t cook up anything better, we
just decided to wing it. CNN STUDENT NEWS
continues tomorrow. I hope to see you then.