[EASTERN THEMED MUSIC]
JESSE HUGHES: Well we're
at my house.
It's like my getaway
from the desert.
It's the back house
in Atwater.
And a preacher and his wife
live in the front house.
I come from a really strong
Christian background.
I believe in the Ten
Commandments, but I break 'em.
I just don't need to believe
in magic talking monkeys to
break the rules, you
know what I mean?
But I love these guys, and I
respect what he's doing.
It's really weird, but I expect
preachers to be good so
I can be bad.
[MUSIC-EAGLES OF DEATH METAL,
"WANNABE IN LA"]
JESSE HUGHES: See the evidence
of throwing knives?
An all night throwing
knife session.
Tuesday, my baby, is one of the
deadliest knife throwers
in the world.
In here is a gratuitous mess.
A lot of classic gear hidden
all around here.
And someone talked.
This is very critical.
I think this is the operating
paradigm for
the road crew member.
A sailor sinking into
the waters is
because someone talked.
We're all in a big ship called
the rock and roll tour bus,
and when someone talks,
everything goes down.
They find the hooker's
body, you go to jail.
I think this man found a genie,
and he got one wish,
and he wished for
a little head.
[LAUGHS]
Oh, hello.
Just kidding.
Hi, I'm Boots Electric, sitting
here, admiring a
painting of myself.
I was stricken with something.
The road is an amazing,
dangerous, unbelievable place.
And when you come to the end,
ultimately it's a big show
with a giant flashing
smoking head.
And then there's the man
behind the curtain.
And in many respects the man
behind the curtain, the Secret
Service agent, the one
who takes the rap
and never gets credit--
is the road crew member--
the roadie.
Starting with tonight at Queens
of the Stone Age, and
using one of the finest road
crew members of all time--
Hutch--
Patrick Hutchinson--
I think we're going to answer
these questions.
What is the roadie?
What does it mean?
What does he do?
Let's find out who this shadow
warrior is of rock and roll.
[MUSIC CONTINUES]
JESSE HUGHES: Soundchecks are
a private world between the
crew and a band.
A time where trust is key.
[BAND SOUNDCHECKING-PLAYING
CIRCUS THEME]
JESSE HUGHES: When you are
working with someone like
Hutch-- and I should say
now that Hutch--
he's a man of integrity,
a man of respect.
But it's his job every night
to get that show up and
running, to make these
boys sound as
beautiful as they can.
He's the air brush in the giant
bulge on that cover,
guaranteed.
He is the extra girth
in the balls.
When you are working with a band
like Queens, it goes with
it the reputation and foreboding
of an almighty god.
Terrible, vicious,
and jealous.
JOSH HOMME: Hey Hutch?
HUTCH: Yes, Josh.
JOSH HOMME: Did you know
that Rush Hour 3
take place in Paris?
[SNARE HITS]
HUTCH: I didn't know that.
TROY VAN LEEUWEN: I've been
working with him for about 15
years, and if he believes in
something, he will walk over
glass and fire and hot lava
to help see it through.
JESSE HUGHES: It's like there's
a lot magicians
running around, and
he's a wizard.
TROY VAN LEEUWEN: He is
definitely the wizard.
[SOUNDCHECKING]
JESSE HUGHES: You know when
every rock and roller finally
hits that road and takes up the
dream, they dream of going
to certain places, and I
guarantee you one of the
places they want to go to is
the Wiltern Theater, one of
the most magical venues
that Sunset and
Hollywood has ever known.
HUTCH: When they come out of the
gate, you can't simulate
that in soundcheck, you know?
They're gonna come out of the
gate like 10 times harder than
they soundchecked.
Always.
Boom!
Like trying to jump on
a bomb to smother it.
JOSH HOMME: Well, well, well.
If it isn't our old friend
Los Angeles.
How you doing tonight,
everybody
[MUSIC-QUEENS OF THE STONE
AGE, "IF ONLY"]
JOSH HOMME: Hutch became a
soundman because DOA won a
battle of the bands competition
and Joe Shithead
goes Hutch!
You're the soundman.
And they won a PA, which they
then took and did all their
shows with.
And then that was how
Hutch cut his teeth.
Starting from going, what are
all these knobs, to figuring
out at least what a third
of the knobs do.
HUTCH: A friend of
mine entered a
contest in Creem magazine.
JESSE HUGHES: Is that how you
got into it mixing sounds, as
a fluke of random chance?
HUTCH: Yeah.
We won a sound board
and somebody had to
learn how to use it.
JESSE HUGHES: You, in my
opinion Hutch, are the
benchmark and the standard for
what is required and what is
the best of the best
in rock and roll.
And you do much more than just
mix sound for a band.
And Queens--
there's so many phot shoots
where you're pictured as a
band member without
even question.
HUTCH: In the early
days, for sure.
JOSH HOMME: You know Theo van
Rock, who used to do sound for
like Rollins and I think Black
Flag, they used to take photos
with him and stuff.
When we met Hutch--
in the tradition of Theo van
Rock and things like that--
we've taken many photo shoots
with Hutch because Kyuss was
so in a bubble and naive about
so much stuff that we didn't
realize there was such a
division between band and crew
in most band situations.
HUTCH: So my friends were
learning how to play their
instruments, and I was always
into the theater side of
things-- the production,
the presentation.
So it just naturally seemed
like you do that part,
I'll do this part.
And so that's how I got started,
but it wasn't til I
started for bands like DOA that
I got to see the country,
and that what I like doing
took me places.
JOSH HOMME: It's DOA, No Means
No, Taj Mahal, The Cramps,
early Hole.
That sounds funny.
Early Hole.
Like in the morning when
you wake up and
you have early hole.
[LAUGHS]
And you're like, oh my god,
is this even mine?
It's real.
And Kyuss, and basically his
pedigree kind of stops there
in a way for a long time because
the way Hutch has
always approached it--
like a family--
was coincidentally the
way we approached it.
So I haven't played a gig
without Hutch since I was 18.
JESSE HUGHES: So I'm wondering
what was the first band where
you saw people that you were
like, I like this, this is the
way to do it.
HUTCH: I noticed a chance to
open for some big acts, like
when Kyuss supported
Faith No More.
Those folks were really friendly
and really helpful,
and we got to see how a larger
scale presentation was put on.
Up until then we were five guys
nuts to butts in the van.
JESSE HUGHES: You
know how I am.
I really take very seriously the
reverence aspect of this
rock and roll thing.
And when someone like Hutch gave
me his approval for the
first time, it was like getting
a fucking graduation
diploma in a way, you know.
JOSH HOMME: When you work with
Hutch, like in a way you're
performing as much for a
Hutch as any audience.
There's a certain
Hutch pressure.
Like Hutch is never going to
say that boy, you guys were
super good.
Like that.
In all the years that Hutch has
done sound with me, he's
said, I think, about three
or four times,
that was fucking amazing.
You know?
And each time I was sort
of like, you know, just
[UNINTELLIGIBLE EMOTIONAL
NOISES]
[MUSIC CONTINUES]
JOSH HOMME: Thank you so much.
So this is it.
This is the last show of our
first wreck of tours.
So I'm just going to shut
up and keep playing.
[MUSIC-QUEENS OF
THE STONE AGE]
JESSE HUGHES: I trusted you to
tell me what's going on, and I
know if something sucks
you'll tell me.
There's really no
one like you.
Not everyone can tell a band
look dude, that sucked.
And A, be able to get away with
it in a way, but also B,
make it-- it's true when you say
it, you know what I mean?
HUTCH: I care.
I'm passionate.
I want to see it better.
JESSE HUGHES: Absolutely
HUTCH: How can we make
this better, yeah.
And I've always worked with
music that I loved and that I
could be passionate about.
It really keeps coming
back to that.
That the sacrifices you make
touring-- leaving things and
people behind--
I'm out there with guys that
I would take a punch for.
JESSE HUGHES: And you've
lived that--
HUTCH: I love the music.
I love what happens when
the audience and
the band gets together.
That's addiction.
I get addicted to
that, for sure.
[CHEERING]
JESSE HUGHES: My grandpa used
to say son, if it looks like
an Indian and smells like an
Indian, it sure as shit ain't
John Wayne.
And tonight really
proved that.
I saw in Hutch everything
I hoped and I knew
that I would see.
A true wizard.
But I'll tell you what
right now, people.
I am hungry for this.
I've got an itch.
We've seen the integrity side.
We've seen the noble element
and the shiny
eagle of rock and roll.
Well let's get to
the underbelly.
The snake's tongue.
[MUSIC-EAGLES OF DEATH METAL,
"WANNABE IN LA"]
I want answers, god damn it,
and I shall get them.
[MUSIC CONTINUES]