[ROCK MUSIC]
JESSE HUGHES: When you think
about rock and roll, and you
think about the road, you're
thinking about a mystical,
mythical place that seems like
everybody in the whole world
dreams about being on,
but nobody really
knows what it's about.
Legalize it.
Don't criticize it, you
know what I'm saying?
Those who do go down that road
soon come to a realization at
their life that it's the place
they always knew they should
be, and the place they always
wanted to be, even
before they knew it.
She loves me not.
She loves me.
I believe the most thankless
element of the rock roadie
must truly exist within
the metal world.
The harbingers of the strip club
and the strip pole, and
the true strokers
of the self ego.
We're going to go to the Golden
God Awards and see how
much they truly love the
road hero that they
sing so much about.
[ROCK MUSIC]
[ROCK COVER OF CLASSICAL
MUSIC]
JESSE HUGHES: Yeah, so I realize
that turning up to a
parade of '80s rockers wearing
a "Legalize Gay" shirt could
be a little close to the bone,
so I switched to something a
little more appropriate.
[MUSIC CONTINUES]
JESSE HUGHES: Now this is
supposed to be heavy metal.
Is that William Shatner?
Is that his toupee as well?
It's William Shatner
and his toupee.
Would you like to see a reward
recognizing the meritorious
achievements of the road crew?
SEBASTIAN BACH: What a-- look.
You just gave me fucking
chill bumps, dude.
JESSE HUGHES: Oh, thanks.
SEBASTIAN BACH: Cause that
would be really cool.
You know, the bands make
it rock, but the
crews make it roll.
CHRIS JERICHO: Without
a good road crew, you
don't have a good band.
I mean, that's the truth.
That's why bands like Maiden
have had their same crew for
like 20 years.
MALE SPEAKER: It'd be like
Elton John going
out without a toupee.
You couldn't do it.
CHRIS JERICHO: You
just couldn't--
[LAUGHTER]
DAVID COVERDALE: Oh,
are you kidding me?
They're the cowboys of
the 21st century.
Totally.
ROBB FLYNN: That would
be a good award.
DAVE MCCLAIN: It would be a
sleazy award, I would imagine.
JESSE HUGHES: The road crew
members are what we're
doing a story on.
Do you have any experiences with
road crew that you would
like to tell us about?
JENNA HAZE: With road crew?
I don't-- like, you mean like
the roadies and stuff?
JESSE HUGHES: Yes.
SEBASTIAN BACH:
[MAKES HORN SOUND WITH MOUTH]
DEZ FAFARA: They're more
important than anything.
They get up while
we're sleeping.
JESSE HUGHES: Have you ever
killed any hookers and used
the road crew to
hide the body?
DEZ FAFARA: No.
JESSE HUGHES: Have you ever
attempted to kill any member
of a road crew, or has any
member of a road crew
attempted to kill you in
any way, shape or form?
JENNA HAZE: No, not at all.
I have good security, so.
SEBASTIAN BACH: [SINGING]
Like what note--you know--
JESSE HUGHES: Yeah, what
the fuck is going on?
SEBASTIAN BACH: What
note is this?
JESSE HUGHES: How do
you feel about the
road crew in general?
TAYLOR MOMSEN: Fantastic
FRANK BELLO: I used
to be a road crew.
I used to be a roadie
for Anthrax before
I got in the band.
So I relate, brother.
It's all good.
VINCE NEIL: There are
so many guys that
could win this award.
SHAWN CRAHAN: They actually
work harder than
the band, you know?
So much respect to
all those people.
STEVEN ADLER: The band
don't play unless
there's a road crew.
Road crew eats first.
VINNIE PAUL: The road crew
really is the unsung heroes of
everything, man.
And without them this doesn't
happen, you know?
So we appreciate them, and we
always made them part of our
families, part of our
home videos, and it
really was our family.
JESSE HUGHES: Well I think we've
learned that the metal
gods truly love their boys
of the road crew.
Machismo in the brodeo
goes without saying.
There's a little bit
of a broner.
And I saw a big broner
in the metal scene
for their road crew.
But you know what?
We're not getting the
whole picture yet.
We need to uncover the
rock and let the
cockroaches run free.
[ROCK MUSIC]
JESSE HUGHES: So we've caught
wind, and in our scent is now
Mr. Hickey himself.
He is one of the last,
and a true god of
the road crew scene.
This man has seen it all.
He's been naked with Nick
Oliveri on stage, and he's
swapped heroin with more junkies
and trannies than
anybody would ever
care to know.
I'm going to take you all
to see the Hickey.
Now the Hickey, he's gonna
leave more than a mark.
JEF HICKEY: My first
day on the road?
Well, it was Megadeth, and it
was in Providence, Rhode
Island, [GRUNTING].
And--
[GRUNTING]
near the end of the night, they
asked me if I wanted to
go with them.
I said, can I go home and
get some clothes?
And they said, no, we don't
have time for that.
You got to come with us now.
So I left with the clothes on my
back, and then that night I
was sleeping in the back of
a Ryder truck, cradling a
shotgun, laying on top
of Marshall cabinets.
It was the ultimate
life-altering decision that
changed everything.
I don't think I slept
the whole tour.
It was--
I absorbed everything.
I did every drug for the first
time on that tour.
I saw my first, like, nine guys
fucking one chick, and
then throwing her out
of the Winnebago.
And then I had my first
taste of speed.
And then my first
taste of coke.
I fucked a stripper with a
broken leg in the ass in
Mississauga, Ontario, at the
Coronet Motor Hotel.
JESSE HUGHES: Hickey is
a slippery snake.
I had to get my grips on him
outside a tattoo parlor, and I
ended whipping him and his
tattooist back to my place.
Hickey reveals one of the
uncompromising facts of the
rock world.
If you love it, it will twist
you and leave its
mark upon your body.
JESSE HUGHES: Put it anywhere?
JEF HICKEY:Yeah, right there.
JESSE HUGHES: You can't fall
asleep without the rumble of a
tour bus or without being wedged
between two flight
cases in an uncomfortable
position
at a midnight airport.
You just wanted to go where
the rock was, see your
favorite brands and you saw,
wow, if I do this, I get to be
where the rock is, right?
JEF HICKEY: Yup.
JESSE HUGHES: And then next
thing you know you're in a
fucking Ryder truck
with a shotgun.
JEF HICKEY: Shotgun.
Protecting the gear.
Scared out of my fucking mind.
I was with of my favorite thrash
metal bands, and I was
in awe, because I was working
with Dave Mustaine and--
JESSE HUGHES: And
you went for it.
Never looked back.
JEF HICKEY: Never looked back.
DAVE MUSTAINE: It's real!
Fuck, it's real!
MALE SPEAKER: Two, two.
Hey, yeah, two, two two.
JEF HICKEY: And then it was just
kind of word of mouth.
I went from Megadeth to Celtic
Frost, to Nuclear Assault, to
Samhain, to Danzig,
to Tora Tora.
I just get jumping from
band to band.
I did Mariah Carey.
I did Madonna.
I learned with Billy Joel that
if the red cup was in the
dressing room, that meant
Christie's not coming.
Put booze in there.
But if there was a blue cup,
that meant Christie's coming.
They're better be water
in every cup.
And Luther Vandross would
FedEx his toilet
seat ahead of time.
And we would have to install his
toilet seat, so that when
Luther came in, he would
sit on his toilet
seat, and it was his.
I did Lemmy from Motorhead.
I got the Maker's Mark ready at
the end of the night, with
the cigarette going.
I had to hand him both.
I was a glorified waiter,
is what I was.
But man, it was the best
cigarette I've ever lit.
And it was the greatest drink
I've ever poured.
And I did it every night.
And I was looking forward to
that moment, because I knew I
had made it through
another war day.
And he didn't break a string,
and he wasn't giving me that
dirty look, or he wasn't
screaming about this or that.
It was awesome.
He was just--
it was great.
JESSE HUGHES: So I want hear
this burger story.
JEF HICKEY: I make it
across the border.
I'm out of it.
I've been up for three days.
And I'm fucking hungry.
And Phil--
the guitar player from
Motorhead-- tells me that
there's some burgers on the bus,
and I should go have one.
So I go into the bus, and I grab
the burger off the plate,
and everybody's looking at me.
And it's just one of those
moments where you're like,
wait, something's not right.
I go to bite, and then I realize
it's a patty of shit.
JESSE HUGHES: I personally have
seen people walk off the
stage for far less.
JEF HICKEY: Sure.
I've had guitars broken
across my leg.
I had an SG thrown at me.
I've been hit with mic stands.
I've been kicked.
Yeah, I was just kinda caught
in the line of fire.
I'm the guy.
JESSE HUGHES: This is
a calling, almost.
JEF HICKEY: Oh no, dude, I
would do anything for the
show, dude.
Anything for the show.
Because every show that I went
to, some guy put it on.
And that show changed my life.
So I'm hoping that the show that
I helped put on changes
some other kid's life.
And then he's the next Lemmy, or
the next Josh, or the next
Nick, or whoever.
JESSE HUGHES: That sums
it up, right there.
But would you recommend this?
And if you would, who would you
recommend it to, and what
would you recommend?
JEF HICKEY: I'm not here to
tell anybody what to do,
'cause I didn't want anybody
telling me what to do.
But it's a lot of fun, man.
It's a great fucking
existence.
I got to some really
great shows.
I got to meet a lot
of cool people.
I got to fuck a lot of amazing
chicks that normally wouldn't
even serve me dinner.
So.
JESSE HUGHES: Any regrets?
JEF HICKEY: Uh, wow.
Yeah, herpes.
Herpes.
That's it.
JESSE HUGHES: There's a phrase
often said that if you can't
do the crime, do not
do the time.
Rock and roll is a beautiful
and amazing vicious animal,
but it takes no prisoners,
and it will leave
its mark upon you.
It's definitely not for those
who want to lead the
disciple's life of Christ.
And it's certainly not for
people trying to save whales
or stop global warming.
In order to be alive in the
belly of the whale, you have
to be just as mean.
If not meaner.
JEF HICKEY: that's--
[LAUGHS]
that feels fine.
[LAUGHING/CRYING]
I just really miss my
mom, right now.
Simultaneously, just
coincidentally at the same
time that this tattoo's
happening.
You know, and I'm just
thinking about,
like AIDS and cancer.
Just makes me sad.
[LAUGHTER]