TREVOR GRAVES: In Portland I own
Nemo Design with a couple
other guys and we have a 20,000
square foot building.
And Dave Seoane rents
the basement.
So he's part of our folklore.
And when people come through
the shop and do the factory
tour and they're like, "yeah,
there's this weird guy that
lives in the basement."
The editors come in.
"Hey, we're going to do
a story about Nemo.
And Dave steals the show.
It's always about Dave.
So that's cool.
We like it that way.
DAVE SEOANE: Well I guess
I could-- the truth is--
can I say anything about
the fire marshals, or--
because technically this space,
which I don't live
here, because you're not
supposed to live here.
But I do get tired and I do
have to take naps here.
So the couch is not a
good place to really
concentrate and focus.
So this is why I built the
Mobile Sleeping Device that
you can wheel around anywhere
in the house.
It has a complete surround
sound, bed, the bare basics.
I have this.
This is my tactic in case
anybody breaks in.
What are you going to do?
Are you going to shoot them?
I don't have a gun.
So you take this and you
just go [SIREN SOUND]
That would scare the shit out
of you, right, if you walked
into a dark warehouse trying
to rob something.
You'd run.
I don't know.
That's my theory.
But the best room is this
one right here.
This is the room the fire
marshal [INAUDIBLE].
Every room should have
a soundproof room.
-Every house?
DAVE SEOANE: Every house,
every warehouse.
This belongs to a friend of
mine, Jason Brown who is a--
as you can see, his set up--
he's very experimental.
It's got two layers
of drywall.
It's kind a six-inch air pocket
that's insulated.
And it's got another two by
four wall with another two
layers of sheet rock all
the way around it.
So it's completely--
it's pretty soundproof.
You can't-- you can hear,
like, the lows.
You can hear the kick drum.
But you can't hear any of the
highs at all and everything
else is muted out.
-That's awesome.
DAVE SEOANE: So it works
out really well.
I have this but I have
no affiliation to it.
Squaw Valley art
sale for $0.98.
I remember as a little kid,
seeing this as a skate shop,
like, wow, you just put those on
your skateboard and you can
go down the snow?
That's incredible.
It was like, this old stuff.
But I didn't learn on this.
I learned on a Burton
Backhill.
But I do definitely share
my respect for Shuman.
He's a good man.
MIKE BASICH: Dave Seoane, met
him '86, Donner Ski Ranch,
first contest ever entered.
I actually met Chris Roach that
day too, and Monty Roach,
Tucker Francis.
Seoane's someone I've
always kind of
related to pretty well.
We've always been curious
about creating stuff.
And Dave was a bit of a
scavenger in the younger age.
He's always the guy who
slept on someone's
deck out on the curb.
He was always someone that came
in with a surprise and
something new.
DAVE SEOANE: I have the original
Squaw Valley Gas
Station sign that I'm going to
sell to somebody that lives in
Squaw Valley, for $60,000.
Exhibit A, this is the--
Can I interest you in an SR?
A K100?
Scrap yard.
-Which one you shoot, though?
DAVE SEOANE: I shot,
probably, this ASR.
This is probably the one
that I use the most.
This was the work horse.
That thing's been all
over the world.
What's that?
-Is that my lens?
DAVE SEOANE: No
TREVOR GRAVES: My relationship
with Dave has been like the
high school buddy you're
friends with forever.
Like I say, he goes, he figures
out to weld, figures
out how to cut movies, how to
film, how to snowboard.
He just kind of has that--
he always wants to
keep learning.
I think that's why I like
hanging out with him and I
respect being around him.
He, he gets it done, you know?
He's got the best program.
Dave's on the best program,
I'm telling you.
DAVE SEOANE: This, see this
right here though?
This is my future home.
This is what I'm working
towards right here.
-This is the proper
mobile home?
DAVE SEOANE: This is the
proper mobile home.
This will be a legal
mobile home.
It's a 1949 Silver
Streak Clipper.
It's going to be put back
to original form.
-Are you going to chrome
it and everything?
DAVE SEOANE: Well you can see
I polished an area here.
So it is possible to get
some sheen out of it.
Oh, this is an English wheel.
This is for pretty much bending
aluminum and rolling.
It's what they made cars, and
that's what they made
airplanes out of back
in the day.
Probably they're still
with us today, a lot
of prototype parts.
But it has been taken into the
motorcycle industry, and it's
been popularized.
This is the wood room here,
which is building a lot of
table tops and furniture
and prototypes.
So it's good to come up with
ideas and concepts.
And then you can come in here
and build it out of wood.
And then I do a lot of welding
as well out there.
So I can put pieces together
and build it up and fab up
whatever comes to mind.
So it's nice.
It's a complete luxury to have
all this at my fingertips.
MIKE BASICH: Seoane and Jamie
Lynn were probably the two
snowboarders that started
marketing
their image as artists.
And Jamie was the painter and
Seoane was the welder.
And it's good stuff.
He makes good stuff.
It's stuff within reason.
It's not non-purpose art.
He made a chair.
He needed to sit
down somewhere.
DAVE SEOANE: I moved to
Tahoe in probably '87.
In Tahoe area, I mean there was,
like Terry Kidwell and
Shaun Palmer, and
Keith Kimmel.
Like, those guys were-- and
Jim Zellers and Tom Burt.
Those guys were all kind
of established.
And it was like, Chris
Roach and Palmer.
Those guys were the ones
that started getting
sponsored by Sims.
And they were the first
real, like, force of--
the start of getting product.
This is like right after the
second or third World Cup.
But I think it was probably
in '88 or '89 that the Cal
Series, they had an event that
went all around California,
amateur and pro snowboard
contest.
And that's where Chris Roach
and Tucker and everybody
would, we would all
tour around that.
And so there's that kind
of first generation.
And I feel like I'm kind of
the second generation with
Chris Roach and Tucker
Francis.
Steve Graham and Damian Sanders
came up to Tahoe a
little bit later.
So they're kind of like third
wave, I should say.
I didn't know Steve
before Look.
So we hooked up and met through
Look Snowboards
through Burt Lamar.
STEVE GRAHAM: That was pretty
much my partner in crime for
traveling with and living with,
because we were both on
Look and filming together too.
We just had so much fun back
then, probably because our
equipment sucked so bad.
We rode for Look.
And there was no real design
there for years.
We were both screwed.
But we would make
the most of it.
DAMIAN SANDERS: Dave's
a great guy.
We actually lived together.
So yeah, when Steve Graham and
Dave and I all started riding
together, we got this place in
Donner, three or four bedroom.
And they moved in with me.
And it was just a blast.
So three pro snowboarders living
together, and my wife
Brandi at the time.
And we'd wake up, go to
squaw, meet the rat
pack, ride all day.
And then back to our house.
And then we kind of lived
in a mountainous area.
So we were always just up on
the hill, building jumps,
building rail slides.
It was just nonstop snowboarding
from the time we
woke up to the time
we went to sleep.
DAVE SEOANE: Right at that
time is when snowboarding
started to get more
recognized.
And there was a French guy at
one of the trade shows.
We'd go there and these French
guys were in suits.
And we're like, oh shit,
this is serious stuff.
These guys are in suits.
These guys are all biz.
And the guy who was running
Look, his name was Jacques
Gris, this French gentleman.
And we went out that night and
had the funnest time ever.
He was like the loosest
guy I've ever met.
He was hilarious.
And after that, it was
like, OK, no problem.
I can easily work
with these guys.
Waking up, going to work,
and complaining
about work all day.
If you're complaining
about it so much,
then why are you there?
And you should just be out doing
what you want to do, no
matter what you're doing, as
long as you're having a good
time, that's all that counts.
MIKE BASICH: He's the one guy
that really never competed.
He made a pretty new career.
Because back then, everyone
competed to be sponsored.
And Seoane, he went straight
into filming, pretty much.
He did a few contests.
But he got sponsored for being
in Fall Line Films.
TREVOR GRAVES: Usually where
he works is "Snowboarder
Magazine," which sponsors
Snowboarders in Exile.
My job was to go and cover it
and make stills and write a
story about whatever it was
that we were doing.
And so I'd sleep on Jerry's
couch countless nights.
And that's where I met Dave.
So Seoane--
it's funny, I lose track
of it, actually.
I've been on some of my best
road trips with Seoane.
Juneau, Alaska, we've been to
New Zealand, so I'm stoked
that we've still got a
good relationship.
DAVE SEOANE: Yeah, we did
actually go to the contest.
But it was never, we never had
any pressure that we had to do
good in the contest.
It was more like a great way to
see your buddies and have
few hundred cases of beer
and have a good time.
Yes?
-What's the most important
thing to you right now?
DAVE SEOANE: Trying to find
a '59 dying station wagon.
-And food.
DAVE SEOANE: I'm not
worried about food.
Once I get the wagon I'll be
able to drive anywhere in the
world and eat.
I just need to get there.
MIKE BASICH: Yeah, Seoane's,
like I said,
he's a bit of a scavenger.
I mean, I've been in Japan with
him and seen him pull out
an ice cream upside down in an
ashtray and eat it for $10.
Not because he wanted to, but
mostly because he was in Japan
and didn't have $10.
DAVE SEOANE: The old
ice cream story.
Well what happened was we--
Steve Graham and I were Japan.
I think I had probably
$23 to my name.
I think Steve had, maybe-- he
probably had, like $100.
And I just walked by the table
and they were making
all these big bets.
And, like, who would need this
ice cream cone with cigarette
butts and hair and gum on it.
STEVE GRAHAM: It was Brushie,
Jeff Brushie was
eating this ice cream.
We were all sitting around this
table and it has this
huge Japanese ashtray in there
which just nothing but
cigarette butts and gum and
just all this crap.
And for some reason, Brushie
grabs the ice cream--
yeah, Dave.
Remember this one?
We got the money up to
like $80 or $100.
And we're going to get $20 from
Jacobi, even, and from
him and getting $20 from
him was tight.
Then Dave walks up
and goes, what?
How much for that?
Just grabs it and just, boom,
take a huge bite.
He was pretty much supposed to
eat pretty much anything that
was on that ice cream.
Not the whole thing, but spit
out the cigarette butts.
DAVE SEOANE: And I walked by
and they were like, yeah,
we're not sure who's
going to do it.
And so I was like, wait, $120
to eat that right now?
And they're like, yeah.
And I just grabbed the
thing and I ate it.
And I spit out the cigarette
butts but I ate the
cigarettes.
There was probably like three or
four cigarettes that I ate.
And that's probably the sickest
I've ever been in my
life, for three days.
I was completely dehydrated.
I couldn't take on any
food or water.
I shit the bed like
four times.
Don't eat tobacco.
It's the worst thing
for you ever.
It was the hardest $120 I've
ever made in my life.
STEVE GRAHAM: He was
sick for four days.
But he got his--
he got his electronic item
he wanted the $80 for.
He was sick the whole
damn trip.
DAVE SEOANE: No, with that money
I bought beer out of the
vending machine.
MIKE BASICH: Sometimes after
that he got so curious about
the filming part, he
got involved on the
other side the camera.
That's what he does now.
JERRY DUGAN: I taught Seoane
how to shoot film.
Then he went off to make his
own films after a while.
DAVE SEOANE: I think I came
into the picture doing a
little bit on Critical
Condition, doing
the helmet cam stuff.
The only reason why the helmet
cam came into play is because
the Blizzard of Ozz.
Like, those guys were
skiing with it.
And the only reason I got
chose to wear the helmet
camera is because I was the
closest to the ground and I
had the fattest neck to
support the thing.
Because the thing probably
weighed like--
I think it had to weigh
like 15, 20 pounds.
It had a camera and then they
were putting on lead pieces to
counterbalance.
So it was a pretty cumbersome
contraption.
Yeah, if you're short and have
a fat neck, you're going to
have a helmet cam
thrown on you.
The other reason I got thrown
onto a helmet cam is because I
can keep up with the
other snowboarders.
There was a trip to go to
Valle Nevado, Chile with
Palmer and Roach.
And I wanted to go
to snowboard.
And there was no room to
go as a snowboarder.
But Jerry had offered me a
chance if I wanted to go to
shoot second camera angle,
or third camera angle.
And it wasn't even
a hesitation.
I just got a camera.
And we did a little film
test and it worked out.
And I'd always had an interest
in still photography.
So I can adapt to the
film playing.
CIRCE WALLACE: Seoane
is such an art fag.
I don't even think he
knew what an art fag
he was early on.
I think now he would totally
embrace that title.
So I think he got--
I think he saw a great
opportunity for him to get
involved on a creative level.
And I think Jerry and
Artie needed it.
He had a really fun idea.
Let's go on a road trip.
DAVE SEOANE: That's when I
talked Jerry and Artie into
letting me do a couple little
side projects with them.
And that's when I came up the
concept and directed Roadkill
and 8-Tracks and RPM,
those three films.
Which we try to do same season
releases, so we'd go out the
first, like November, December,
January, and try to
release it in February.
And we did that for three
years in a row.
I mean snowboarding was like,
the progression of it was
going pretty quick.
When we first did Roadkill, at
the end of-- what was that?
I think, like, Riders on the
Storm-- at the end of that,
everybody started buttering
tricks and nose presses and
all that funky stuff.
But this was a way to, instead
of waiting a whole other year
to capture this and show this,
was to be like, OK.
This is what's going on now.
So here you go.
[OUT-OF-TUNE GUITAR PLAYING]
JASON BORGSTEDE: Oh yeah,
Roadkill and RPM, those--
I think Roadkill was
the first one.
And that was our hard
core movie.
That was our first half-hour
movie, just
quick, quick, quick.
But they put together a super
sick lineup right when
freestyle was really busting
out, when this gear here right
here was the stuff to be.
Blind Jeans, what's up?
And Brushie right here
was killing it.
And that's why, it must have
been 15 years later, I'm on
the internet looking to buy a
Brushie board, because of
those videos in those days.
Reminded of the time when we
were first getting into it and
first really pushing to
try to get better
and emulate our idols.
DAVE SEOANE: Roadkill was with
Terje Haakonsen and John
Cardiel was in it, Bryan Iguchi,
Graham, Palmer, Jamie
Lynn was in it, Circie was in
it, a couple others that I
can't think off the
top my head.
But that was--
we started off in Tahoe.
We took a limousine.
And then Palmer came with us
with his limousine, because he
has a whole garage full of
limousines for some reason.
That was like, in a matter of
like a month and a half.
And that was a brutal
month and a half.
And Bud Fawcett was--
we were driving down
in Colorado.
We were on one of the
main interstates.
And it was 11 o'clock at night
and one of the belts
blew off the car.
And Bud was driving.
So luckily Bud--
I don't know how he did it--
but got us there safely.
We found a gas station.
And I'm trying to--
they're just getting
ready to close.
But I found a replacement
belt.
And in the car, and
I'm trying to--
I mean, it's cold.
It's like 11 o'clock in the
middle Colorado at night.
And then I'm--
those guys are all
just hanging out,
partying in the limousine.
And I'm out there getting
my hands dirty and
trying to fix this belt.
And I open the door try
to get something.
And the Gooch, I remember, Bryan
Iguchi, he was like,
Dave, can you shut the door?
It's cold out there.
And I was like, you
fucking asshole.
And I just totally snapped at
him and yelled at him so hard.
I was so pissed.
And then after they all
came out of the
car, and were quiet.
And they were like,
we're sorry.
Do you need a hand
with anything?
And I was like, thanks
you guys.
So that was one of just many
little highlights.
CIRCE WALLACE: I really remember
Jamie and Palmer
jumping the Donner cliffs, that
little section in Roadkill.
I remember watching Palmer
backside 360 that Donner
cliff, thinking like that maybe
was one of the gnarliest
things I've ever seen.
And he had that clown hairdo.
DAVE SEOANE: Yeah, it was Jamie
Lynn and Circe actually
came down from Washington to
do a segment in Tahoe.
That's when we went out into
the back country in Donner
Summit and just built a jump.
He was just one of the guys that
I wanted to work with.
And I think Jerry already
had enough
credibility where people--
they were approached
by people--
that people wanted to
work with them.
So it was kind of nice that
they had established
themselves.
And people were coming to them
and we were already kind of
grandfathered in there.
JAMIE LYNN: I just remember
hiking up Donner Pass, and
Sugar Bowl, and the
Donner Ski Ranch.
And the days we rode
after that were the
days that were filmed--
that we got to film all the
shots for Roadkill.
Because it had just snowed,
like, 10 feet.
And then Tahoe is so
concentrated with different
areas, you can just go from one
area to the next and just
pick, like--
and with those guys's kind of
pass to access that stuff, it
allowed us to get up into some
really, really good snow.
Like early up, some KT-22
at Squaw Valley.
No one does that.
DAVE SEOANE: While I was making
those films, Roadkill
and 8-Tracks and RPM, I was
still working with Rossignol
at the time.
So I was just going
to work in film.
And then Rossignol offered me a
position to design and build
boards and still keep doing
what I was doing.
So I couldn't say no to it.
So I was working with Rossignol,
helping them design
boards and helping to promote
Rossignol, and like a little
bit of film segments.
But it was kind of dying off.
And that's when I just got into
more of the filmmaking
aspect of it.
And the reason why I got in the
film aspect of it was just
because I had a really
good relationship
with most of the riders.
So it was pretty seamless.
MIKE BASICH: I think he jumped
ship just a year or two early
from the pro snowboarder
to filming.
But I think he was so interested
in the filming
part, he just dove into
that pretty quick.
It's been good for the sport.
I mean, he's brought the athlete
side of the eye more
on the other side of the camera
to capture the sport a
little better from the rider's
point of view.
I think Fall Line was working
with him for so long he
learned a lot from them.
DAVE SEOANE: Let's get these
girls to start working here.
It's getting late here.
JEFF CURTES: I always knew of
him from the videos, like
watching Snowboarders in Exile,
and watching him fly
off huge cliffs in Jackson Hole,
but definitely part of
different circles of people.
He wasn't part of the Burton
world in his pro snowboarding
scene at all.
So he was part of a Tahoe
kind of scene.
So the paths really didn't
cross for me until he got
behind the camera.
Burton hired him to kind
of come on a shoot.
We became friends there.
He's got a really cool way about
him, a really quirky
style, and really different than
the way I shoot photos.
So I just watched
him do his deal.
And I'm like, wow, I can learn
a lot from his approach and
how he interacts with the
riders and things.
Full immersion, like
just, party scene?
He's in there.
Or a shred scene?
Like, he's such a sick rider.
And he has evolved quite
a bit as well.
He was just super loose and part
of the scene and would
just capture it better
than anyone else.
He made Haakonsen movies,
Subjekt Haakonsen.
And he's just shredding, and
probably just right in there
with Terje, living the
lifestyle, and just getting it
all on film.
So nothing that you
can really learn.
I think you just have to be that
person, be part of it.
Be a good friend first and then
get the relationships on
the camera.
SHAUN WHITE: I'm not sure
exactly how we met.
I know it was a long,
long time ago.
We were probably either
around Mount Hood or
something like that.
But all I remember was watching
Subjekt Haakonsen and
just thought that was
the best movie ever.
I love the riding.
I love the way it was put
together and the music.
And it had a vibe to it
and I liked that.
DAVE SEOANE: That
came through--
I'd been friends with Richard
Woolcott and been friends with
Terje at this time.
So we had kind of like thrown
the idea around to do it.
So Richard Woolcott, Terje, and
I, we just sat down and
talked about it to see how
it would work out.
And we were like, yeah, it
totally makes sense.
And Terje was totally into it.
Volcom put up the dough for
it and produced it.
It was good because this was
kind of before Terje would be
so like, closed off to
everybody, when he was still
kind of user friendly
for the public.
But he was into it, so we
definitely had to take
advantage of that.
And that was a lot of fun too.
That was a lot of traveling.
Terje is, like, he's funny
because once you get out there
and turn the camera on, you
can't really stop him.
ANDREAS WIIG: So I had his main
movie that was called
Subjekt Haakonsen.
I've probably seen it, I don't
know, like 2,000 times.
I can't watch it anymore because
it's a VHS and it's
just too old now.
I liked a lot of parts.
I remember I really liked the
part when him and Daniel Frank
are riding the half pipe--
I think it was at Mount Hood--
and had a part together.
That's one of my
favorite parts.
Other than that, there's this
part where it's hailing.
He's doing this huge
back flip.
The whole movie just has
so much variety.
It's way more work to film
a whole movie than
just to film a part.
You have to be a pretty
complete rider to
be able to do that.
At the time when his movie came
out, it was for sure the
best movie ever made as far as
snowboarding, trick-wise and
how technical he was riding.
Not just like technical as far
as doing tricks, but just the
way he was riding the terrain.
DAVE SEOANE: Yeah, and not
just through the movie, I
think, just his in general
popularity.
It seemed like he's more of an
icon and in the US and Japan
than he was in Europe.
I don't know if that's
because he spent so
much time over here.
Because even in Norway--
it's different now.
But back then in Norway, when
you'd walk around with him, he
wasn't such a recognized guy.
He was still, like, low key.
We tried to get into
some club.
And he had no pull to
get us in there.
But here in the US, people
recognize him a lot more.
But that's changed now.
He's a big name in his
hometown, or in Oslo.
What was after that?
Then I did another film with
Terje, The Haakonsen Faktor.
Terje's riding had developed
more into bigger free riding.
So we were just trying
to capture that.
But we got skunked
on so many trips.
And then it was the end of the
season and we didn't really
have much in the can.
And we were like, OK, we've
got to go to New Zealand.
So we'll go there for a couple
weeks and see what we can get.
And then we were there
for six weeks.
And there was times when--
it was like, Iker Fernandez,
Michi Albin, the Gooch, Terje.
Like, we were there for
the fourth week in.
And they were like, it's
just not happening.
We want to go home.
And I was just like--
I almost broke down in tears.
I was like, you guys
can't leave.
We're so close.
We have a helicopter.
I had to convince those
guys to stay.
Because I mean, we were all
completely burnt down on being
in one place, snowboarding
in the summertime.
So they stuck it out.
And we ended up--
the weather finally cleared
and we got good shots.
So it was worth putting in
the extra two weeks for.
But it's hard traveling
and being in one
spot for that long.
-Man, I thought you said no
one was going to be here.
-It's that red-headed
snowboard kid.
-Isn't there snow somewhere?
-Yeah, there's some freshies
on the super
jib in Tahoe, bro.
-Come on.
I got an idea.
-Hey.
What's up, guys.
-Tomato, how are you?
-How you doing?
SHAUN WHITE: I was about 16
and we paired up to do a
movie, The White Album.
And it was awesome.
And it was just funny because
he's just this kind of like--
I don't know how to describe
his personality.
It's just one of a kind.
It's awesome because we'd
be hanging out and
shooting the movie.
And I totally would forget
the fact that he just
shreds on his own.
And he's a really talented
snowboarder, especially back
in the day.
He had stories, but they were
mostly, like, oh this is when
Farmer jumped out the window
at this hotel.
Something like that, you
know what I mean.
Just random, random
things like that.
Because it was a wild
time back then.
Because it was just a lot
different than now.
So it was a humbling experience
to have him working
on a project with me.
DAVE SEOANE: I came up with the
idea of the Shaun White
album probably--
I wanted to do it the
year before--
two years before it
was even released.
And the reason for that is Shaun
White came on the Tony
Hawk state park tours.
And you could just see him, in
like a two week period of his
progression was just
so much higher.
And his snowboarding was
starting to pick up, and like,
this is the year.
Things are going to happen
for this kid.
And it would be great
to document it.
And I've known Shaun since he
was probably like eight years
old, since he was
a little kid.
And I've just watched him
grow up and develop.
And his progression curve
was way bigger
than anybody else's.
So that year we were
going to do it.
And then there was like,
he wasn't sure.
And then his brother
wasn't sure.
And then Renee from Burton
was like, no, Shaun's
not ready for it.
And Shaun won all these contests
all year round.
And Renee and I just
butted heads.
And I was so frustrated.
But it gave us time to set
up for the next one.
And so it gave us
more prep work.
Then everybody was
completely in.
And Renee and I are
now friends again.
So it's nice.
Oh, yeah, we used to totally get
into verbal feuds all the
time on the phone.
But it's funny now.
We joke around about it.
But Shaun was 17 at the time.
And it just--
that was a really tough film
because that one, he blew his
knee out twice.
And we thought for sure that
was another one, like, OK.
And we're so far into this.
And I had committed everything
to doing this.
But we just had to wait and
see how his knee went.
And we went down and we all sat
down with our negotiator,
Richard Woolcott.
And he said OK, this
is the deal.
In two months, we shouldn't
throw the towel in yet.
You should try and make
the call in a month
and a half from now.
And we just waited out and he
just snapped right back in.
And we ended up, we went to New
Zealand for a month and it
worked out fine.
So it was John Gotgart, Sean
Aaron was on that New Zealand
trip, and myself.
So it was pretty much the
three of us shooting.
But mostly G and I, and
a lot of G traveling.
SHAUN WHITE: It was fun.
It was really nice to be able
to work with someone who had
their own vision.
Because he knew how the movie
was going to play out way
before I did, and way before
anyone else that was working
on it with us really thought.
So it was cool to see him
kind of, go OK, well we
really need this shot.
Or, you know what?
This doesn't even matter.
Because it was a really heavy
point my life because I had my
first actual injury, I felt.
I had to get surgery
on my knee.
And we were going through
all this drama.
And he just turned it
into such a cool
thing for the movie.
So I was surprised.
Normally it's like,
oh, movie's over.
Can't do anything.
But he's like, no,
we can work it.
We can figure it out.
MIKE BASICH: His movies
he's done are usually
pretty unique and--
he's done the Haakonsen one,
and White's album.
I think he's the one for
unique projects.
I never see him going in the
business of making a movie
every year.
It's just something to really,
if it's right, right recipe
for him, he dives into
that project.
DAVE SEOANE: As far as future
films, if there's something
that comes along that I'm
completely inspired, that I
can see the beginning, middle,
and end to do on a--
whether it's an athlete
or a film, then
I'd like to do something.
But I don't really-- there's
enough really good filmmakers.
And there's really a shortage
of athletes who go out and
just, like, turn a film out.
But if something unique
really comes about, I
definitely want to do it.
And I think that's the
biggest thing.
And everything is like, unless
you're passionate about it,
it's just going to
be watered down.
And I've had projects where
I wasn't really
passionate about it.
I felt like I just had to make
a film because I did one the
year before.
And I did it.
And it was really
watered down.
And it was just like, ugh.
It just takes all the
fun out of it.
But The White Album,
I was completely
passionate about it.
And it worked out really well.
And I'm really proud
of that film.
That's like the one film I love
showing people, like that
and the movie with Terje.
So those two films.