locker room.
I got to tell plan B jokes.
I told jokes about panda shit.
You can't really do that
anywhere else.
It's fun.
And we're not knuckleheads.
We're not idiots.
We are telling stories that mean
something, but in our own
vernacular.
And that's what I really love.
So there it is, the
whole shebang.
Vice presents Munchies
with Eddie Huang.
FEMALE SPEAKER 1: This
famous cook?
EDDIE HUANG: What is this?
I don't know this.
Oh, I would definitely
chef here.
I'm going to create a
special health menu.
EDDIE HUANG: Chinese juices,
dragon sweat,
panda shit, the best.
Mmm.
My name is Eddie Huang.
The name of my restaurant
is Baohaus, and we serve
Taiwanese-style street food.
Bao just means bun or
bread in Chinese.
Everybody has variations
on pork bun.
But I was like, yo, let's take
a step back and do the OG
shit, the real, authentic,
Taiwanese way they've been
doing since the '50s.
So I wanted to red cook the pork
and topping with peanuts
and sugar and cilantro, like
how we do in Taiwan, and it
just really took off.
It's not like my mission in
life was to open a bao
restaurant.
This was the item that
made the most sense.
It's portable.
It's the Asian answer
to a taco.
The names for the
baos are cool.
The original's named after
Chairman Mao, because Mao's
from Hunan.
And my technique for the
red-cooked pork belly is from
Hunan the province.
That's where my family's from.
And then we got the
bird house bao.
It's chicken.
The inspiration for that was
Robin Givens because she's the
biggest bird in the world.
I hate that bitch.
Ruined Mike Tyson.
So yeah, we're going to go hang
out with detective Max
Koshkerman.
He always sounds like he's
interrogating people.
MAX KOSHKERMAN: What do you got
for breakfast, a salad?
EDDIE HUANG: The other dude
is Simonez Wolf, Chef Sez.
I know Sez from the
door at Le Band.
He's always clowning
motherfuckers outside, not
letting anybody in.
He's a funny cat.
EMILE HAYNIE: How's it going?
EDDIE HUANG: This motherfucker
is the latest one man.
What's wrong with you?
You all know Emile.
He produced "Runaway".
He produced Lana Del
Rey's new album.
Honestly, we should just eat the
fucking, that new pot pie.
That new KFC pot pie
is the moves.
Really we all just hang out.
And we like to eat.
So we're going to go
eat at Nan Xiang
Shanghai-style breakfast.
After you Mr. Jimenez.
So Flushing's an interesting
neighborhood because a lot of
people feel like the
best Chinese
food comes from Taiwan.
After the revolution,
most Chinese master
chefs fled to Taiwan.
They came to New York, set
up shop in Flushing.
SIMONEZ WOLF: Which way?
You know the way.
EDDIE HUANG: First restaurant
we went to was Nan
Xiang Xiao Long Bao.
They do the best Shanghainese
breakfast I've had in New York
hands down.
Deep bow.
That's a dismissive one.
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
EDDIE HUANG: You think Chinese
breakfast, and everybody just
assumes dim sum.
But dim sum is a Cantonese
thing, southern
China on the coast.
A lot of the rest of the eastern
coast of China, people
like to eat soup dumplings,
hot soy milk, cruellers.
These are dishes that you
don't usually see in the
American canon of
Chinese food.
So I like people to see
it because that's
what I grew up with.
MAX KOSHKERMAN: I'll
tell you what man.
Only eat fresh soy milk.
People don't even understand--
EDDIE HUANG: Game over, dude.
Game over.
MAX KOSHKERMAN: --how
incredible it is.
EDDIE HUANG: This is a beef
scallion pancake, one of my
favorite dishes.
This dish, it's beef and tripe
together, spicy oil.
But the folk name for
it is [CHINESE],
husband and wife platter.
Now soup dumpling 101.
I'm going to show this.
You see a lot of goons poking
holes right in the top.
Hooligans.
This is what you do.
Soup dumpling gets a sauna.
You put it in the vinegar.
Let it chill out, maybe 30
seconds to a minute.
It'll cool.
Then you eat it.
This is the only way to do it.
You do it any other way--
MAX KOSHKERMAN: Don't
be a hooligan--
EDDIE HUANG: Don't be
a fucking hooligan.
MAX KOSHKERMAN: --while eating
a soup dumpling.
EDDIE HUANG: Yeah.
And you see all these
motherfuckers on Facebook, oh
my favorite food is
soup dumplings.
They're like poking
them like this.
MAX KOSHKERMAN: Respect
the dumpling.
Don't be a hooligan.
SIMONEZ WOLF: Can I do this?
This is good?
MAX KOSHKERMAN: I don't know.
EDDIE HUANG: That looks like
some crazy French shit.
See, I should host a show
teaching people how to do this
called, "So You Think You Want
to be a Chinaman." "So You
Think You Can Chinaman."
Oh thank you.
Thank you grasshopper.
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
EDDIE HUANG: Oh and then after
that, we went to probably the
best Cantonese restaurant in
any of the five boroughs,
Imperial Palace.
MAX KOSHKERMAN: Respect
for that.
I can't reach that.
Oh now hold on.
SIMONEZ WOLF: Oh ninja.
Oh, can't reach you.
EDDIE HUANG: [SPEAKING CHINESE]
EDDIE HUANG: I got the
crab on rice, seafood
on pan-fried noodles.
I got a little fried grouper.
I think we're good.
MAX KOSHKERMAN: Is that
lobster in that?
EDDIE HUANG: [SPEAKING CHINESE]
MAX KOSHKERMAN: What
are you saying?
EDDIE HUANG: [SPEAKING CHINESE]
EDDIE HUANG: So Max was
being extra difficult.
I usually don't go to restaurant
and order all
fucking shellfish dishes.
I asked Max what he wants.
He goes, oh, lobster.
Son, we're getting
dungeness crab.
You still want to get lobster?
He's like, I only want
to eat lobster.
He wants lobster.
He's going to be difficult
until he
gets his fucking lobster.
MAX KOSHKERMAN: I just want to
try that Cantonese style.
EDDIE HUANG: How difficult.
I thought you were difficult.
This guy's fucking difficult.
SIMONEZ WOLF: I'm difficult?
EDDIE HUANG: No he's
difficult.
MAX KOSHKERMAN: I'm just
high maintenance.
SIMONEZ WOLF: I'm
not difficult.
I'm just proper.
EDDIE HUANG: We got
only shellfish.
That's some bowl of shit.
We only ordered shellfish.
Cheers.
And we got dungeness crab
over sticky rice there.
They take a live dungeness crab,
butcher it live, take
the top off.
They'll take sticky rice.
Then they'll throw it
in the wok a little.
Then it goes on top of lotus
leaves into a bamboo steamer.
Game over.
It's probably the illest dish
out there in any restaurant in
the north right now.
Go ahead.
Go ahead Emile.
You go in.
Go dig in Emile.
This is the best part,
see inside the brain?
That yellow shit.
Get up in the brains.
This shit is the best.
So this is steamed oyster with
XO sauce, chili oil, dried
scallop, all kinds
of good stuff.
And then the fried rice dish
that we had was a salt fish
fried rice.
The protein that you see in
there is diced chicken bits.
But the flavor for that fried
rice is coming from salt fish.
And I think I just
said fried rice.
[LAUGHS]
EDDIE HUANG: That
Chinglish just
pops its head up sometimes.
So ugly.
SIMONEZ WOLF: Oh look,
look, look.
EDDIE HUANG: Oh here we go.
I want you to take a photo
with your lobster.
Yo, if people knew Sim was
geeking out, taking food
photos like that, I don't think
he could control any
door in the city because
he stunts on everyone.
He the coolest guy you know.
But now he's got his Yelp on,
fucking taking photos of food
for his blog.
So it's a funny dynamic,
all of us.
But we don't give a fuck.
We'll geek out over shit.
We act a fool.
Anywhere we go, you
see we act a fool.
After Imperial Palace,
Emile pussied out.
He didn't want to
go to the Baths.
SIMONEZ WOLF: You coming?
EMILE HAYNIE: No,
definitely not.
No.
EDDIE HUANG: So then we went
to the Russian Baths.
Just sweat it out, because we
felt gross from all that food.
How are you Simonez?
We are here at the Russian
Baths right now.
SIMONEZ WOLF: Whoa
whoa, gangsta.
EDDIE HUANG: Max was in there
with a bunch of dudes with no
drawers on eating a pear.
Definitely let the streets
know, that's Max's shit.
See, he was eating
the fucking pear.
You see him eating
No better place to eat a pear
than in a locker room full of
naked dudes.
Yo, I like to just get
blazed and sweat.
It's kind of cool.
It's the perfect thing to do
high because you don't have to
think about anything.
Your mind is just consumed
with sweating.
And you feel like
you worked out.
You feel like you burnt
some calories,
even though you didn't.
So we just fucking
go to the baths.
Look at this shit.
Some intense negotiations going
on here at the baths.
Max, the price is listed man.
The prices are listed.
Max is always fucking
negotiating with people.
He don't ever want to pay
full price for anything.
He'd go to Chipotle and fucking
negotiate if he could.
MAX KOSHKERMAN: This plug, I
want one more round on the
house next time I come here.
EDDIE HUANG: These Persian
people are the cheapest.
FEMALE SPEAKER 1: Yeah, but
he know how to deal.
EDDIE HUANG: You should take
another photo here of him.
Put it up.
This man steals.
Stealing memberships.
MAX KOSHKERMAN: I'll
see you later.
EDDIE HUANG: Take care.
FEMALE SPEAKER 1: Good luck.
EDDIE HUANG: After we went
to the baths, we
just had the munchies.
And we were like, what
could we make?
We're going to go to Baohaus and
make fried bao ice cream
sandwiches.
It's going to be good.
It's this way.
MALE SPEAKER: We're happy, no.
SIMONEZ WOLF: Neighborhood
watch.
EDDIE HUANG: Damn, you just
stunted on him in front
of his girl, yo.
You stealing shorties tonight?
You stealing shorties?
All right, we're going
to make this.
Drop eight baos in the fryer.
EDDIE HUANG: No, just for fun.
You want one?
We'll make one for you.
FEMALE SPEAKER 2:
Can I have one?
EDDIE HUANG: Yeah, we'll
make you one.
No problem.
MALE SPEAKER 2: Can
I have one too?
EDDIE HUANG: Had them fried baos
with the red bean paste,
the little shiso leaf, all
the finest greenery.
And then vanilla ice cream or
green tea ice cream, depending
on what your flavor is.
Oh delicious.
Here you go Sim.
You want ice cream sandwiches?
All right, come get it.
Don't be shy.
Y'all scared of ice
cream sandwiches?
MALE SPEAKER 3: I'm a little
confused about this.
EDDIE HUANG: Yeah, what are
you confused about?
It's fucking ice cream
and fried baos.
What's there to be
confused about?
We're going to feed the streets
right now, everybody.
SIMONEZ WOLF: It's like a soup
kitchen for ice cream.
EDDIE HUANG: Yeah, it's
a soup kitchen.
This is a ice cream
soup kitchen.
Here you go.
Enjoy man.
Yeah man, motherfuckers
love free shit.
They like anything free.
I could've taken a shit
in a bao and they
would've loved it.
See this high munchie shit, it
doesn't need to be pretty.
It just needs to be delicious.
It's a fucking recession.
I'm going to feed people.
I'm going to run on this
platform, ice cream.
If your platform can be like,
no, you cannot use Plan B.
I'll be like, I'm a nice guy.
I want you to eat ice cream
and use Plan B.