for "Take Care." I think that
we should talk about "Take
Care" first, just because
it's the least
interesting of the two.
The video is directed by the
guy who directed the video
where Lana Del Rey dies
in a car crash.
But for this one, in lieu of a
shirtless face-tatted alt-bro,
there's Rihanna.
Both videos feature
wild animals.
I think in Drake's there's some
sort of eagle, and then
what looks like a
water buffalo.
So the video is mostly Rihanna
and Drake hugging with kind of
like an anguished look
on their face.
There's also some slow-mo
nature shots.
But for the most part, it's
all just in a gray room.
The director described the video
as humble, but I think
really it's just generic.
It's sort of like when you go to
an art gallery, between the
really great pieces, the master
works, there's just
kind of filler stuff,
so there's enough
to make an art show.
It's a really instead of being a
meaningful rap video, it's a
simulacrum of a meaningful
rap video.
So the "HYFR" video, it starts
with footage from Drake's
actual bar mitzvah with the
13-year-old Drake dancing.
And it's [BLEEP]ing adorable.
And then the rest of the videos
claims to be real
footage of Drake's
re-bar mitzvah.
It basically shows Drake and
his crew with some really
pretty girls and some dorky
old white men wowzing out.
At one point, Drake gets
hoisted on a chair.
A cake get smashed.
Also, Lil Wayne has a panda mask
and a skateboard, kind of
solidifying his ascension into
cautionary tale status.
The video is funny.
It's exciting.
It's easily made into GIFs.
It's really everything that a
rap video should be in 2012.
I don't think the video's going
to do much to help solve
the Israel-Palestine conflict.
I don't think that BBNet and
Yahoo and the members of Fatah
are going to watch it, but
it could only help.
[MUSIC PLAYING]