The Leaning Tower of Pisa is
simply an impossibility.
More like something you dream
than something that can exist.
For hundreds of years, the world
has watched in amazement
as the building defies gravity
teetering on a razor's edge.
It really is quite miraculous
that it has not fallen over.
And thank goodness it hasn't.
If the Tower were to fall no one
would feel it
more than the people of Pisa.
For them the Tower is the heart
of their city.
It is what draws hundreds
of thousands of tourists every year,
each one anxious to give
a helping hand.
It really needs one. The Leaning
Tower of Pisa can tumble
in an instant.
For 800 years architects and
engineers have been trying to
fiix the Leaning Tower of Pisa.
Nearly every attempt
has been disastrous.
But somehow the Tower
has serenely survived.
Today the Tower is in greater
danger than ever.
It's lean is so extreme
that the Italian government has
closed it to avoid a potential disaster.
It's been more than ten years since
anyone has walked up its marble
stairway which leads to its
stunning bell chamber
until now.
We will take a behind the scenes
look inside the Tower
that's been locked off to the
public for so long
and climb to the top for a rare
view of its breathtaking vistas.
We'll examine the bizarre history
of the 800 year effort to
save the Tower and introduce the
current plan that some believe
just may make the
Tower safe forever,
that is if it doesn't
destroy it first.
Today, the Tower is in crisis
a patient in intensive care.
830 tons of lead have been added to
hold down its north side.
Steel bands cinch its waist.
340-foot long cables are wrapped
around it to prevent
an impending catastrophe,
while a group of international
experts struggle to fiind
a permanent solution.
Michele Jamiolkowski
a geo-technical engineer
is the chairman of the current
team to save the Tower.
This is not an easy task.
Not only me, but all the other
members of the committee
became acquainted with the
responsibility and with the risk
which we are incurring
with this task.
Their goal is to reduce the Tower's
lean by about 16 inches.
This would take the Tower out of
danger, but keep it looking the same.
After all, no one wants a straight
Tower of Pisa.
We never considered straightening
the Tower, because the inclination
is part of its character.
It's absolutely central to Pisa.
So there are two unacceptable
scenarios really, aren't there?
One would be a straight Tower
but the other one would be
one that fell over.
The common perception is that
the Tower is in danger of tipping over.
In fact, that is only one of two
perils that could reduce it to rubble.
One problem is the very well known
continuous increase of inclination,
which was bringing the Tower
to falling over.
And the second problem was the
concern about the structural collapse.
The first problem, the Tower's
increasing slant is due to the soft
soil it is built on.
Professor Carlo Viggiani is a member
of the committee to save the Tower.
He has been studying
the Tower for over 35 years.
The leaning was by change.
Probably because on the south
side of the Tower
the subsoil was weaker
than the north side.
So, and once it started to lean
from that side, then the weight is
going on that side
and the thing is
continuously increasing.
By 1990, the Tower was leaning
at an astounding five
and a half degrees,
or 17 feet off the perpendicular.
It literally defies the laws
of physics.
Committee member John Burland
is a professor of soil mechanics.
I think it's miraculous.
I mean, when we came here in 1990,
we couldn't get it to stand up
on our computer.
It's leaning at 5.5 degrees.
We could only get our computer
Tower to lean at 5.44 degrees
and then it used to fall over.
So it really is quite miraculous
that it has not fallen over.
The Tower isn't just in danger
of falling,
it can collapse under
its own weight.
Part of the problem stems
from its structure.
Although the Tower
appears solid,
it's actually a hollow cylinder
reaching 185 feet into the sky.
Within it, a staircase winds
up to the top.
Most of its 14,000 tons are
supported by its walls.
Its walls, however, aren't
solid either.
They're stone, lime and mortar,
covered with a thin marble facade.
One side with all of the stone is
getting a lot of pressure.
The other side with all of its stone
is not getting that pressure,
so there is an inequality.
As the Tower's lean continues
the pressure intensifies.
Eventually the marble in this
second floor section
will give way the building
will collapse upon itself.
It could explode at any time, or this
was the case in 1990 anyway.
So we've got a Tower that's just
about to fall over and it's
on the point of exploding.
And that makes it probably the
biggest civil engineering
challenge there is.
Solving the challenge of the
Tower has stumped
generations of engineers.
Its problems began almost
as soon as it was built.
When plans for the Tower were
first drawn up in the 12th Century,
a spot was chosen with
a commanding view of Pisa.
It was beautiful.
But not a very good place
to build,
since in ancient Italy
the site had been a lagoon.
Piero Pierotti, is an art historian
and professor of medieval architecture
at the University of Pisa.
Pisa was a system of islands in the
middle of a very wide lagoon.
This lagoon was slowly filled in
by the two most important
Tuscan rivers.
The Arno and the Auser.
And where the rivers had filled in,
they left mud,
which is softer and wet.
The soft wet soil left behind by the
rivers was where the Tower was built.
The ground is so soft that it's
really like building a brick Tower
on a soft carpet.
You can go to a certain height,
and no matter how straight you try
and keep that Tower,
it will start to lean
and then fall over.
Why build a Tower
doomed to lean?
Although the medieval architects
knew that the soil was soft,
they may not have known how soft.
They thought they had found the
perfect spot to build a monument
to the glory of Pisa.
Today, Pisa is a quiet university
town of 100,000.
In the 11 th Century, it was
a powerful city-state.
Its navy roved the seas
conquering other cities.
In 1062, the Pisa navy sailed to
Palermo, the capital of Sicily,
bent on conquest.
When Pisa's fleet arrived in Palermo...
the Sicilians they encountered there
said that the citizens of Pisa
were the meanest and most ignorant
people they had ever met.
In reality, there was this strong
arrogance of considering
themselves the first, the best.
This arrogance made it easy for
other cities to fiind allies against Pisa.
In 1063, the victorious Pisan navy
returned,
their chests bursting with pride
and their pockets bursting
with Sicilian money.
They decided to build a glorious
square, the religious center
of medieval Pisa,
the square known today as the
Piazza dei Miracoli,
Square of Miracles.
It would have a magnificent
cathedral, one that would surpass
any other church in Italy.
Next to it would be a baptistery
where Pisa's richest citizens
could be baptized.
It's crowning glory,
the masterpiece of Pisan civilization
would be the cathedral's bell Tower,
or campanile.
On August Ninth, 1173, the foundation
for the Tower was laid,
directed it is thought, by Pisan
architect, Bonnano Pisano.
By the time the third level was built
the Tower was starting to
settle unevenly.
It was leaning north
not south as it does today.
The Italians weren't worried.
Many buildings in Pisa
leaned a little.
They simply compensated
by making the columns and arches on
the north side of the third
level a little taller.
Pisa had something
like 10,000 towers.
It was known that an adjustment
of the ground was necessary.
They would start construction and
they would look onto
which side the Tower was leaning
and would build up the other side.
They didn't have the technology
which we have now.
If we were doing the Tower now
we would have driven
what are called piles
down onto that dense
sand 40 meters down.
But they didn't have
that technology in 1173.
They just learnt that you could
build towers to a certain height
from years and centuries
of experience.
But what they had learned
from experience,
did not hold true for this Tower.
The soil here was softer and the
Tower would have fallen
if they continued building.
But they didn't.
In 1178, construction stopped.
Some historians say it was because
the Tower was tilting too much.
Others say it was political and
military troubles in Pisa.
Whatever the reason, the delay
lasted 100 years.
The Tower survived only because
the interruption allowed
the soil beneath the Tower
to settle to include the resistance
and to support the fiinal
lot of the Tower.
When work resumed in the 13th Century
the Tower was leaning
about seven inches to the north.
As building continued upwards,
the Tower began to tilt
in the opposite direction.
This time, the masons tried to
correct the tilt by making the stones
on the south side taller.
They corrected the shape just to
bring the Tower in a vertical position
so that the Tower is
not actually straight.
It is like a banana.
It is shaped in this way.
In 1278, work on the Tower stopped
just short of the fiinal floor.
82 years passed before architect
Tomasso Andrea di Pisa came
on to build the bell chamber.
By 1370, the Tower was complete
and the original vision of the great
square with its Tower was realized.
But as soon as the Tower reached
its full height,
the lean started to accelerate.
They didn't realize that by putting
the little bell chamber on top
it was really going to start moving.
They didn't have that
understanding at that time.
It was thought at the time that the
bell chamber would stabilize the Tower
The bell chamber is designed to
correct the problem, to balance out
the whole preexisting structure.
The 14th Century solution was to
build a different number of steps
on each side of the bell chamber.
On the north side were four steps,
on the south, six.
In total, the south side ended up
being 34 inches higher than the north.
To further balance the weight larger
bells were placed on the north side.
Finally, Pisa's cathedral had its
Tower, and the Tower had its voice.
Next to the entrance to the Tower
masons sculpted a relief of two ships
entering the Pisan port, as
a tribute to Pisa's
mighty marine power.
Unfortunately by this time, Pisa's
marine power wasn't very mighty.
The Tower conceived as symbol of
Pisa's grandeur,
was now, a crooked testament to the
city's faded dreams.
I am sure that many explained to you
in a precise, technical way
why the Tower is leaning.
But if we wanted to joke, the Tower
could be leaning for another reason.
Its imperfection could be considered
a symbol of the death
that was already inside
the society of Pisa.
The Square was supposed to be
completely paved in marble.
It was never paved
the grass is still here.
It wasn't supposed
to be this way.
And all of this gives the idea
of what was thought that
this city would become
and never became.
The people of Pisa would try for
centuries to straighten
the whole thing out.
>From the moment it was complete
the leaning Tower was crooked
and loved by the people of Pisa.
It is one of the miraculous
structures of the Middles Ages.
And especially
since it started to fall,
it gave it a kind of reclame that
normally it might not have.
It quickly became the center
of public life.
Big feasts and celebrations
took place on the Piazza.
Standing on the balconies
every family and even their guests
had a privileged space.
They could come out like they did
from the balconies
of their own palaces.
It was like having a reserved
box for the theater.
In 1590, the Tower even played host
to a little known local scientist,
named Galileo.
Legend has it he conducted his famous
experiments with gravity
from its bell chamber.
While the Tower's lean wasn't
increasing much,
the building was sinking.
By the 19th Century, the Tower was
slumping down
about 10 feet into the ground.
And a part of the first floor was
completely obscured.
And in 1838, an Italian architect
Alessandro Gheradesca,
decided to do something about it.
Alessandro Gheradesca said "Wouldn't
it be a wonderful idea
to dig out around the foundation
so everyone can look in
and see these lovely columns going
down to the base of the Tower?"
So he went in there and dug out this
walkway around the base of the Tower
that's called the catino.
Unknown to Gheradesca, there was
a water table
within yards of the surface.
No sooner had he dug down, than
water came gushing in.
Suddenly, the Tower that had stood
serenely and safely for five centuries,
lost its balance.
It lunged over a foot.
And how it didn't fall over,
we really don't know.
It was another miracle
that it didn't.
The Tower had survived the first
modern attempt to improve it.
And for 70 years, no further
attempts to help it were made.
Then, in 1902, Venice's
St. Marco's Square, a bell
Tower came crashing down.
It had stood more than 1,000 years.
But on the morning of July 14th,
a huge crack snaked up the Tower
and the whole structure collapse
into an 18,000-ton pile of dust
and rubble.
It took some two days that collapse
so there were no people
killed by that.
But it was impossible to stop
that collapse.
Scared by the disaster in Venice
the Italian government
formed a committee to
study Pisa's Tower.
Experts reviewed the leaning Tower's
condition, but nothing was done
to stabilize it.
That is until 1933, when fascist
dictator, Benito Mussolini,
turned his attention to the Tower.
Mussolini was obsessed with returning
Italy to the glory it hasn't
known for several centuries.
It was unthinkable that Italy's
national symbol should be
a tilting Tower.
He had made the trains
run on time,
how difficult would it be to
straighten a Tower?
The idea was to try and inject
cement into the foundation
masonry, not into the ground
but into the masonry.
And the reason being that water
was seeping
up through Gheradesca's catino
up through the masonry
and washing out the mortar.
Mussolini's engineers thought that
excess water under the Tower
was weakening the foundation.
They decided to seal the base of
the Tower with concrete to prevent
water from seeping in from below.
Workers drilled over 361 holes into
the Tower's foundations.
Then they pumped in over 80 tons
of cement.
Once again, the Tower's delicate
balance was shattered
and it lurched southward nearly
three and a half inches.
Now the Tower was in real danger
but there was no time to fiix it.
World War II had started.
American soldiers were hitting the
back door of Hitler's fortress.
This was Italy.
Bombs were raining down on Italy,
reducing large sections to rubble.
In 1944, the Allies entered Pisa
hoping to control the Arno River,
which ran through the city on its
way to the Mediterranean Sea.
The Allied troops found themselves
under attack by artillery fire
from above.
But where could it be coming from?
The Germans, as they were retreating
demolished all the bell towers
because they could be
observation posts.
So the bell towers of important
churches were demolished.
Obviously the most important of the
bell towers was this one
and it has not been demolished.
The Allies suspected the Germans were
firing from the Leaning Tower of Pisa.
US Sergeant Leon Weckstein, a scout
with the 91st Infantry division,
received his orders in July 1944.
He was to take out what soldiers called,
The Tiltin' Hilton,
and if he detected any enemy action
blow it to smithereens.
Weckstein would recall his
mission 50 years later
in his memoir, Through My Eyes.
I was sent out to get as close as
I could to the Tower.
And if I saw any action up there
at all, I was to direct all
these weapons against the Tower
to get it out of the way.
In those days, we were very gung-ho.
If it meant the life of one of
our men, we would have destroyed
the Tower very easily.
Weckstein watched for hours.
Nothing seemed move inside
the Tower.
He thought about blasting it to
pieces anyway, just in case.
On a basis of suspicion, I might
have just said, go ahead,
fire, you know?
But there might have been an ounce
of sentiment in seeing
this beautiful Tower and what it was.
And probably that registered
strongly enough for me to withhold
any rash movement on my part.
Then, artillery bursts began
exploding above Weckstein's head.
Judging by the direction of the fire,
Weckstein reported to his commander
that there were Germans in the Tower.
The fate of the building hung on the
US Army's next decision.
At the last minute, Weckstein was
ordered to retreat.
The army had spared the
beautiful building.
The Leaning Tower of Pisa had
survived World War II,
for the most part.
The only serious damage to the Tower
during the war was the breaking
of a small column,
not due indeed to the Allied Forces
attacks, but simply to a mistake of the
Pisan anti-aircraft, which was not
capable of striking one aircraft
during the whole war,
but was able to strike a small
column of the bell Tower.
In the post war years, the Tower
became a favorite attraction
for tourists in Europe.
Meanwhile, it continued its
slow swoop downward.
At the beginning of the century
there was not a great concern
about the tower.
And even in 1940,1950, the increase
of inclination was very, very little.
But the speed of inclination
increased so in 1990 it was doubled.
By the end of the 1980's, the Tower
was leaning 17 feet off
the perpendicular.
The more the Tower leaned, the more
its unevenly distributed
weight pressed against
the blocks of marble
that made up its thin facade
and the greater the risk that
the marble would give way.
The Tower obviously was ever
in the danger of collapse,
but with the progressive inclination
the safety margin was decreasing.
The collapse of Tower was expected in
next 30 to 50 years.
Despite the growing risk,
the Italian government didn't authorize
any action until 1989,
when a 900-year old bell tower in
nearby Pavia came crashing down.
And it wasn't even leaning.
This was sudden collapse.
It took ten or 20 seconds, not more.
And unfortunately we had some
people killed in that collapse.
The Italian government announced
that Pisa's Tower was unsafe.
No longer would the Leaning Tower
be able to welcome the hundreds
of thousands of people who traveled
from everywhere to see it.
At three o'clock on January seventh
1990,
Italy's most famous building
closed its doors.
To see the Tower closed for the
first time in its history
for security reasons,
it made you realize that there was
a real risk, a concrete danger.
That day I cried.
What a sin.
It was beautiful.
Then to see the Tower without anyone
in it, it was no longer beautiful.
It was sad, very sad.
The closing of the Leaning Tower
of Pisa could have been
easily avoided.
This was done to dramatize the
problems that the Tower faced
and in order to justify this
radical intervention.
Because when there is
a dramatic case,
a close danger, then the money
is forthcoming.
In 1990, the Italian government
formed a committee of engineers
to save the Tower once
and for all.
They began by reviewing
potential solutions.
Proposals poured in from
all over the world.
You get some really wacky ideas
like balloons and growing
trees up the middle
and so on,
which are good fun
but not very serious.
As creative solutions were studied
engineers gathered data.
Measurements taken throughout the
century, were used to
track the Tower's lean.
And in 1992, a computerized
monitoring system was installed
to keep track of the Tower's
smallest movements.
Sensors were attached to
very major crack.
If a crack widened, it could be
the start of a structural collapse.
These instruments, measure the
thickness of the crack in real time,
so we have nine years of recording
of the movements of these cracks.
A routine was established that
continues to this day.
Every morning a technician enters
the tower to check on its condition.
Through a horizontally leveled
telescope,
any increase in the tower's tilt can
be detected up to
one 100th of a millimeter.
Taut wires cut across the tower to
measure any distortion
in the structure.
Three pendulums incased in gray tubes
track any shift
in the tower's center.
They hang from the seventh level
down to the first floor.
After two years, the team studying
the Tower still couldn't agree
on how to fiix it.
But they were ready to try some
temporary solutions.
Their first task was to strengthen
the Tower at its weakest point,
the critical zone.
The inclination of the Tower is
creating very high compression
on this side,
because the Tower is inclined
in this direction.
This edge is really the position
in which the compression
stress is the highest one.
So the fail of the collapse would
begin certainly in this position
if would happen.
Workers wrapped a belt of plastic
covered steel cables
around the Tower's second story in
an effort to keep the cracks
from widening further.
The operation went smoothly.
The band of steel was discreet enough
not to arouse any protest.
Then, over the course of six months
600 tons of lead weights
were methodically added to the base
of the north side to keep the lean
from getting worse.
The first lead weight was added on
July 13, 1993.
Nervous engineers recorded every
step of the process
with their own cameras.
Tests were carried out to calculate
how the Tower was reacting
to the lead weights.
But nothing is certain with
a building that is so unique.
We put the first lead weight on
and we got a positive response.
Because it was by no means certain
that we would,
it was very nerve wracking.
The tension was really very high indeed.
After the last weight was added,
monitors registered a northward
movement of almost an inch.
The intervention had been a success.
It was a historical moment.
For the first time in 800 years
the Leaning Tower of Pisa
moved back the other way.
There was just one snag.
The lead weights were an eyesore.
Art experts protested.
The people of Pisa complained.
The weights had to go.
The lead weights are rather ugly.
And in Italy they have a saying
that anything temporary
becomes permanent.
And so, the Tower's engineers came up
with a daring and complex plan,
a plan that some feared would destroy
the treasured Tower.
The plan to eliminate the weights
holding the Tower down was
so controversial and so
filled with danger,
that it's outcome came to be
known as Black September.
The idea was to build a concrete
ring round the Tower's base
from which ten cables would be
driven 50 meters underground
to anchor the Tower in place.
Laying the concrete ring was
a dangerous task.
Workers would have to dig under
the catino, the walkway
around the base of the Tower.
The ground was full of water and
once digging started,
the water might gush up.
But the engineers in charge were
confident they had a way around that.
The ground would be frozen
using liquid nitrogen.
The frozen ground would form
a physical barrier
that would stop ground water
from flowing into the shallow
excavation the concrete ring
would be built in.
Before the freeze started, engineers
came across something puzzling.
There was already another concrete
ring in the ground,
and it was attached to the Tower.
Engineers guessed that it dated
back to the 1800's.
There was nothing about this ring
in historical records,
but it seemed safe to go ahead.
On September seventh, workers
started freezing the ground.
They made some holes
around the tower.
And inside these holes
they put liquid nitrogen,
practically transforming all the
ground underneath the tower
into a freezer.
For 36 hours liquid nitrogen
was pumped into the soil.
At first, the Tower didn't react.
Then over night, the Tower suddenly
moved one 16th of an inch,
an amount almost equal to what the
tower moves in a year.
As we froze the ground
the ice reacted against
this concrete in the ground
and caused the tower to
move adversely.
And as soon as that happened
we stopped the job.
When the water in the soil froze
it expanded.
The expanded soil pushed the
concrete ring down,
leaving a gap between the Tower
and the ring.
Once the soil defrosted, the tower
sank down into this space,
and lurched further south.
I was extremely worried.
And this was really a very
very difficult week.
We faced a serious risk of losing
the tower, because
when Tower started to rotate toward
the south with this rate,
nobody was able to evaluate
if the Tower will stop or not.
Desperate to stop the Tower from
leaning further,
engineers quickly added another
230 tons of lead weight to
the Tower's base.
The Tower stopped moving.
But instead of fewer weights
there were now more.
And the tilt, instead of diminishing
was increasing.
Nothing had gone according to plan.
This is a strange monument and one
that has had too many doctors
trying to fiix it.
The Tower has most often been
at risk of falling down,
not from what ails it,
but due to the mistakes of its doctors
who have been exaggerating
with their cure.
In effect, the Tower has most often been
in danger when there
were external interventions.
All of Italy was outraged.
After five years of studying the Tower
with the most advanced
technology available,
somehow the problem was worse.
Shortly after the deep freeze of 1995
all work on the Tower stopped.
The Tower remained closed.
No one in Pisa knew when, if ever
it would open again.
It was a painful situation for a city
that identified so completely
with the monument.
It's the maximum.
It's the emblem of the city.
Because when we go around the world
when we say where we are from,
that we are from Pisa, the first the
first association is the Tower.
The Tower is a universal symbol
for the citizens of Pisa.
As a little girl I used to always
come here to the Piazza.
And slowly, a passion began to
grow within me as I became aware
and began to understand the
importance of the monument.
The Tower was like a lung
something that we felt.
Not only because people had once
climbed it, that makes it alive,
but also because closing it brings
a little economic damage.
Pisans from all walks of life felt
the closing of the Tower
in their hearts,
not to mention their pocket books.
It's the Tower
that attracts the tourist.
As soon as tourists arrive, they see
the Tower and that's it.
They don't see the other things.
When the Tower was open, there was
a line, the people would climb
on the Tower, they would have
time to eat, they would come
to our restaurants.
A lot of people would stop to
have a cappuccino.
And then they would go inside
the Tower.
Now instead, since the Tower is
shut down, our work is a
hit and run.
Tourists arrive, they take some
pictures, they do a little bit
of shopping for some souvenirs,
and then they run away.
With the Tower closed, tourism
fell by 20 percent.
It was a frustrating situation
for the people of Pisa.
They depended on tourism and tourism
depends on the Tower.
It is considered one of the most
famous structures in the world.
I believe that there cannot be
a person on earth that doesn't know
what the Tower of Pisa is.
Tourists come from Japan, from
America, from Canada,
from Australia.
These are people that have never
seen the Tower before,
and they come here expressly to see
the Tower.
Not to see the city.
For us, the Tower is an artistic
wealth, a priceless property.
There was great concern about the
alterations being made to
this priceless property.
At Columbia University in New York
James Beck, a professor
of art history has founded Art Watch,
a non profit watchdog organization
dedicated to protecting
artistic treasures.
Beck advocates an open exchange
of ideas to save the Tower.
It's very bad for the preservation of
the Tower that they're so secretive.
They put in a particular cure
and then that cure fails
and they put in another cure,
but there's never discussion
and careful explanation.
If you believe that this is an object
that belongs to the world,
then you have to have all of the
input that's possible.
Beck believed that the Tower was
not in imminent danger.
There was time enough to debate
the options openly.
The estimates are 35 to 70 years.
Therefore, the rush to do
these rather stupid interventions
in some cases, was totally unnecessary.
Everybody wanted to get credit for
saving the Tower of Pisa,
just because it was good publicity.
Whatever the objection of critics,
by 1998, a new plan
had been set in motion.
And if it worked, the Tower would
be safe for hundreds of years.
Italy's team of engineers felt
confident that it had come up
with a way to stabilize the Tower.
Their solution was a process
called soil extraction.
Engineers would remove soil
from the north side of the Tower.
The remaining soil would start to
compress to fill in the gaps
and the north side would literally
settle down.
We looked at, at least 12 different
methods of doing it.
But the more we looked at it
the more we felt
that we had to get gravity
to work for us.
Most of the solutions had been
try to lift the low side.
Do something to support
the south side.
But in doing that the ground
is so soft you would disturb it
and probably the Tower would
fall over.
And so this solution developed
that maybe we could cause
the north side of the ground to
subside in some way.
And the tower would follow that
gravity would cause
the tower to rotate northwards.
If the project succeeded,
the Tower's lean would be reduced by
half a degree, or 16 inches.
Visually, the change would be
imperceptible.
That means that for American
and Japanese tourists
this will make practically
no difference.
The local Pisans greeted the
new plan with skepticism.
They've required a lot of time
to fiind a way that could insure
security and stability to he work,
that won't present any problems,
because the Tower could
go down very fast.
One mistake is enough,
and when the Tower comes down
who's going to stop it?
Soil extraction is a relatively rare
technique, but far from new.
As early as the 1800's,
it had been used to diminish the lean
on St. Chad's Tower in England.
More recently it had been used
successfully
on the Metropolitan Cathedral
in Mexico City.
But remarkably,
the technique had been recommended
for the Tower of Pisa in 1962,
when Fernando Terracina, an Italian
architect, had submitted the idea.
What has the committee done
in the end?
After spending ten years and 25
million dollars, what does it do?
It accepts a project by Fernando
Terracina,
a project of under-excavation
from the 1960's.
Terracina's suggestion was easy
to miss.
It was buried in a technical report
three decades old.
What further astonished critics was
that the idea had been
suggested again in 1990
by Vittorio Novelli and Nazareno
Paccaloni, surveyors
from Cesna, Italy.
They told us it was a process that
was too violent
and impossible to carry out.
I kept in with the president of the
committee who, very cordially,
told me that he was trying to fiind a
unanimous decision
on the choice of an intervention.
And that our project wasn't taken
into consideration.
Yet, in the end,
the committee adopted an operation
with many similarities to ours.
In fact, we were a little bit
astonished after such a long time,
nine years.
With so much at stake
and with the eyes of the world upon
the current team of engineers,
everyone's nerves became strained.
It's been incredibly tense.
You can imagine you don't rush into
a tower that is on the point
of falling over
and start digging furiously.
This risk is huge because the Tower
could feel unstable
from one moment to the next
since it has been in this position
for so many centuries.
We are now all in the hands of
these people, waiting.
It just seems to me it's
Keystone Cops.
And that fact that they had five
different operational plans
in ten years,
shows that they're not very secure
about what they're doing.
The committee believes in its plan.
But just in case the Tower moved
the wrong way,
it proposed wrapping two steel cables
around the Tower's third level.
The cables were to be anchored into
the ground, 100 yards away.
If catastrophe struck during the soil
extraction, the cables could be
tensioned to hold the Tower in place.
There was never any intention
that we would use the cables to
pull the Tower back.
I think there was one newspaper
article, which said,
"They are going to irresponsibly
drag the Tower back by the cables."
That was never the intention.
They're simply there to gently hold
the Tower if it began to move.
The cables would in that event
be tensioned by lead weights
so the load on them
would be constant.
Work began in December 1998.
Putting the cables in position
was a major and perilous task.
Each cable was 340 feet long
and two inches thick.
They were enormously heavy. Just ten
yards of cable weighed a half a ton.
We felt that it was necessary to have
those there just so that
if something went wrong, we could
hold the Tower and
fiind out what was happening
and correct it.
So they are simply a safe guard
and the contractor
calls them his parachute.
With parachute in place, the way
was clear to start
extracting the soil.
On the tenth of February, 1999,
engineers recorded the start
of the process.
First 12 pipes were placed
approximately four yards
from the edge of the Tower.
Then, with a kind of mechanical
corkscrew, the ground was
removed very gradually
from beneath the bell tower.
At the end of five months
the results were in.
The Tower had moved over half
an inch north.
For the committee, the victory
couldn't have been sweeter.
Finally, after ten years, they had
found a method to stabilize the Tower.
The response has been beyond our
wildest expectations.
It's been very positive.
We've moved the top of the tower
northwards just
by drilling a few holes.
Far fewer than we are going to use
with the full intervention.
So at present, it's looking good.
But you don't raise the flag when
you've taken the first
step up Everest.
So we have to be very
very careful.
We've got a very, very long
way to go still.
As it turned out, they had even
longer to go than they thought.
Just as they began making progress
the money ran out.
It's a paradox that at the exact
moment when the right project
has fiinally been found,
there is a risk that the funds to
develop it are lacking.
So, we can see that the relationship
between the committee's work
and the government's response has
always been a difficult one
and sometimes even dramatic.
The Tower that had survived 800 years
of danger,
was now facing a truly formidable foe
the Italian bureaucracy.
Although many people were infuriated
with the committee's slow pace,
the committee placed the blame
squarely elsewhere, the government.
The whole project has taken
an inordinate length of time...
largely due to Italian bureaucracy.
We are set up by a law, which has to
be renewed every two months,
and very often it isn't. And we have
long, long periods of time,
anything up to six months or more,
where we have no mandate.
And people say, "Why haven't you
done anything?"
The simple answer is, ask the Italian
government.
The mission to save the Tower was
once again on hold.
While the bureaucratic wheels turn
slowly, life in Pisa goes on
as it always has.
The tourists who visit the Tower know
little of its complex history
or how close it's
come to destruction.
I read that they did something on
the foundation
to keep it from falling over.
They didn't want to set it
up straight, they'd lost tourism, hey?
And I think they shouldn't.
It's like if they take the smile away
from the Mona Lisa.
It looks like it's going to fall over.
Well, it was crooked when they
first built it,
so I'm not surprised that it is still
crooked now.
It does look different now when you
see it in real life compared
to seeing it in books and magazines.
It's quite different when you're
actually right there in front of it
and you're trying to figure out how
it actually got like that
and how it stays up.
So, it's amazing.
It's one example of something
that went wrong.
But at the same time they're trying
to fiix it and it's going to
be a nightmare.
Just imagine somebody tries to
straighten it up and it falls apart.
We wait.
Who knows when it will fall?
It is something everyone
wants to witness.
As the Tower waits for the Italian
government to release funds
so the soil extraction project
can resume,
everyone else waits too.
We are waiting of the Italian
government, because we are now
not in position to start for a number
of bureaucratic
and fiinancial problems.
So that we are ready for May and now
we are in November waiting
for someone saying to you, go.
For everyone, even the engineers
working on the Tower,
it has been a long journey.
When the work will be fiinished
I shall be extremely
happy to become a free citizen
and not be involved in Pisa Tower
and not
be involved, the mass media, not be
involved in the relations
with politicians and so on.
Pisans long for the day
the Tower will reopen.
But no one expects that day
to come any time soon.
Some political problems.
Some fiinancial.
The funds arrive
they don't arrive.
They close the building site
they threaten to close,
then the money returns
and we start again.
In short, these are all the things
that we Italians are used to
and we have to be used to.
Often I hear the elderly people of
Pisa say,
"But how could it possibly be,
in the year 2000, when everything
has been invented,
and we live in an information age
where man has gone into space,
that a tower like this one takes
more than ten years to stabilize?"
At the beginning they were talking
about six months, then a year.
Nobody could have known that the
work would last ten years
and still continues.
Once the soil extraction can be
exhumed and completed,
the Tower will, presumably, be
stabilized and can be open to
the public again.
Or will it?
The problem to open the Tower has
not yet been discussed
by the committee.
Because a large part of these people
believe that the Tower
should be admired from the square
not climbing up.
We expected that the Tower would
have opened again for the millennium.
Instead we found out
that the work will go on
and that nothing is certain
anymore.
I fiind all of this deeply unfair.
We are fighting to have the tower
reopened so that everyone
can once again admire its beauty.
We have faith and we hope to see
the Tower soon beautiful
and smiling like once it was.
No one can imagine a Pisa
without its Tower.
The Tower is simply unique,
with a unique hold on the imagination
of Italy and the world.
There's a little quirk
in the wonderful Italian romance
that likes things that are
a little different.
And the fact that this is
a leaning tower,
as opposed to just an old building,
is romantic in their eyes.
Actually, I'm convinced that no
architect in the world today
would be capable of creating
a thing like this.
They could dream of it, but
defiinitely not build it.
Nature decided it would be tilted,
that it would come out inclined,
therefore people come to see this
miracle this is still standing.
It is so magnificent.
Such a beautiful structure.
And the whole Piazza
is so beautiful.
It really would be unthinkable
that the Tower should be
lost really to the world.
I hope the future is at least
another 300 years.
The future of the Leaning Tower
of Pisa remains as uncertain as ever.
But for 800 years the Tower
has risen above human folly,
serenely surviving friend and foe.
And it continues to do so today
soaring into the sky,
magnificent and improbable
beautiful and strange,
a wonder of the world.