JAKE BURGHART: Starting to have
a bit of a breakdown.
Let's see.
I'm going to take this tape out,
put it in my pocket after
I shoot it, and--
I don't even know why I'm
shooting it right now.
It's sort of a--
I just kind of really need
someone to talk to.
I don't know where to start.
I came into this trip with a--
really excited about it.
Just nothing more than
getting to be on the
ocean for three weeks.
Now I don't have any idea
what's going on.
I can't sleep at night.
I'm, like, feeling sick, feeling
really sort of trapped
on this boat.
There's nowhere to go.
It's a 50-foot boat, you know?
It's like, if you want to take
a walk around the block, it
doesn't happen.
You want to like run or do
anything to sort of forget
about what's going on, and
it's just not there.
We're all here, all
on this boat.
There's no getting away
from each other.
We have two watches a day, and
I don't think I've slept in
three days.
This is my first time I've ever
gone night diving, or
diving in the ocean, or diving
this far away from anything,
or diving with a camera, or
diving with a knife, or diving
with a captain.
MEREDITH DANLUCK: It was like
going into outer space.
Like, the point of something
being so crazy and scary that
it's really fun.
[LAUGHING]
THOMAS MORTON: Jake and
Meredith are under
the boat right now.
I'm still on watch, apparently,
which I guess was
never factored into
the schedule.
I puked pretty ferociously at
around eight or so, and then
had kind of a long drying off
spell where I probably would
have preferred to get a
little bit of sleep.
JAKE BURGHART: That
was pretty insane.
[LAUGHING]
CAPTAIN CHARLES MOORE:
All right.
This was quite a
wonderful test.
I'm quite pleased.
The creatures you saw tonight
will pale by comparison.
THOMAS MORTON: So watch
just ended.
It gets really, really boring
up there with absolutely
nothing going on.
So I'm going to make my own
little log entry here, and
then call it a night.
Good luck with your watch.
JAKE BURGHART: So once every
hour, we have to do the log
and check the engine rooms to
make sure that they're not
flooded with water.
Before you know it, it's 3:00.
It's time for your second
log and engine check.
From there it gets
really slow.
This made us all kind of start
doing really nerdy things.
I'm wearing a turtleneck and
learning about the stars.
Oh shit, I think I just
deleted the course.
MEREDITH DANLUCK: What?
JAKE BURGHART: I think I just
deleted the whole course.
I was just--
I was just clicking on these
things, and I don't know.
The whole course disappeared.
There's no Undo.
This program is stupid.
Fuck.
Goddamn it.
Captain, we're going
off course.
We're dropping below 190.
MEREDITH DANLUCK: [LAUGHING]
THOMAS MORTON: No, you shouldn't
have done that.
You should have put a sad
face there, perhaps.
So it is day five.
I'm on watch with Joe now,
and we are working out.
That's right, keep
our strength up.
Kind of realized this, uh,
this boat's almost like--
it's like being in prison
but without, like--
I don't know-- like the
punishment and the
gang rape and all.
You don't have shit to do.
You can either read, or
as we decided, you
can try to work out.
Shit, fuck.
Here they come.
Oh, man.
This is fucking exciting.
Dolphins.
[SINGING]
Dolphin party, USA.
Dolphin party, coming here
to play with dolphins.
Jesus Christ, there's,
like, 20.
They're still coming
from the distance.
[LAUGHING]
There are so many fucking
dolphins.
Dude.
This is great.
You get so bored out here.
And then all of a sudden,
you got fucking
dolphins and trash.
It's amazing.
Like, this is the highlight
of our day.
It's kind of getting
ominous out here.
For the past, like, two or three
days, we've been kind of
occasionally seeing shit and
kind of picking and choosing
what we want to pull out.
I'm still holding out hope for,
like, half a kewpie doll
with, like, a fish coming
out of its other arm.
MEREDITH DANLUCK: Hey,
what's going on?
JAKE BURGHART: Probably kelp.
JOE: Good show then, mate.
You see the other two
that came close?
Right there, look at that.
THOMAS MORTON: So what
are you doing there?
Are you severing its gills?
JOE: Yes, its gill.
It's a gill artery.
THOMAS MORTON: OK, yeah.
So you're cutting that so it'll
bleed out the right way.
I'm kind of glad I was
on watch for that.
I'm not too squeamish, but I
just don't like fish when
they're put together.
So it's kind of a double doozy
when they're coming apart, or
when you're taking them apart.
[LAUGHING NERVOUSLY]
He was saying we're safer to
eat smaller fish, even when
we're out towards the gyre.
They've had less time to
accumulate all the toxins in
their system, so--
I feel kind of bad that we've
been eating fish that have
been swimming in this
fucking water.
I don't even want to
think of all the--
just looking at the
big particles--
all the shit we're probably
ingesting.
But at this point, I'm
sure it's too late.
CAPTAIN CHARLES MOORE: These
compounds are lypophilic,
meaning fat loving.
So they stick in fat.
A million plankton, a thousand
sardines, a hundred mackerel,
eaten by, say, a mahi-mahi
or a tuna.
And then the higher cetaceans,
they accumulate this whole
chain of accumulation
of these chemicals.
Polycarbonate has Bisphenol-A in
it, which leaches into the
water and can cause
reproductive
harm and other defects.
For instance, one out of four
male swordfish in the
Mediterranean are producing
female egg yolk hormone that
you wouldn't expect a
male fish to make.
THOMAS MORTON: It's screwing
with their genetics.
CAPTAIN CHARLES MOORE: It's
screwing with their genetics.
So that's an indication of
disruption of the hormone
system, probably caused by
industrial chemicals.
I mean, we're starting to see
problems like when we talk
about how the Eskimo women
have toxic milk for their
babies and are being asked to
use formula instead to feed
their babies.
THOMAS MORTON: Are
they particularly
susceptible to them?
CAPTAIN CHARLES MOORE: Yeah,
because they eat high off the
food chain.
They eat marine mammals that
have high fat content when
this stuff is stored
in the fat.
And they're producing fewer
males and smaller males.
It's conceivable that there
could be population crashes in
many sexually reproducing
species that loses its males.
JAKE BURGHART: Was that
your first swim?
THOMAS MORTON: Ever,
in the ocean.
It's as terrifying as
I fucking thought.
MEREDITH DANLUCK: What?
THOMAS MORTON: Getting out of
the water, there was a little
chunk of, like, yellow debris
that was kind of caught on the
corner of my lip.
And then later, Jake got out
of the water, and it just
like-- it looked like he had
body glitter on part of him.
There was just little
particulate waste.
I've been like eating shit with
my hands all day, too.
There's fucking plastic
in my mouth.
I guess I can properly empathize
with the fish and
filter feeders now.
But still, that's
fucking gross.
I was in the water for all of,
like, 10 minutes with a
snorkel in my mouth.
And somehow a piece of plastic
fucking worked its way in.
I don't think we ever showed--
we ever did a little
tour of the boat.
This is where all of us
have pissed and shit.
What happens when you use
it is it is empty.
It's basically, you fill it up
with water, or if you're
peeing, you just fill
it with that.
And then you stand here
with your face about--
what, a foot and a half--
from your own fucking
excrement.
The best part is when the boat's
rocking and things
start to slosh around.
This is also our shower, too.
A lot of stuff gets
done in this room.
I don't know.
There's been so much of that,
like, this isn't cool to you,
but I've been in a boat
for seven days.
And it's really neat that
we can see a bird.
MEREDITH DANLUCK: [LAUGHING]
THOMAS MORTON: The days
just kind of melt into
the nights and shit.
And it's just kind of like one
big long hunk of walking
around a boat and doing stuff.
I don't know.
It sounds like I'm retarded, but
I've just never looked at
the sky so much out
of pure boredom.
MEREDITH DANLUCK: [LAUGHING]
Trash at starboard.
You got it?
That's good trash.
What is it?
Piece of something?
MEREDITH DANLUCK: Looks
like a flowerpot.
JAKE BURGHART: There's a
really big problem with
flowerpots in the Pacific
Ocean right now.
So stop throwing them in here.
THOMAS MORTON: Garbage island is
less a physical place than
really a state of mind.
At some point, we all find our
garbage island, whether it's
out here in the Pacific or at
home, comfortable, surrounded
by people you care about and
enjoy interacting with on a
regular basis.
CAPTAIN CHARLES MOORE:
I showed you--
stop, stop, stop.
JOE: Charlie.
CAPTAIN CHARLES MOORE: I
gave you an example--
JOE: Charlie.
Charlie.
CAPTAIN CHARLES MOORE: And
you totally ignored it.
JOE: Charlie.
Charlie.
CAPTAIN CHARLES MOORE: Don't
tell me Charlie, Charlie,
Charlie, Charlie.
Then Joe, Joe, Joe, Joe, Joe.
Joe, it's-- look,
it's so easy--
JOE: Hey, hey, hey, hey.
CAPTAIN CHARLES MOORE:
Hey, you're making
more trouble for yourself.
You're cutting it smaller
than it has to be.
JOE: Hey, respect, Charlie.
I've respected you.
You need to respect me.
CAPTAIN CHARLES MOORE: Respect
the way you're doing it wrong?
JOE: If this isn't done
right, then say
something at the start.
CAPTAIN CHARLES MOORE: That's
what I'm saying.
JOE: You looked at me two
minutes ago, and I
was doing it fine.
CAPTAIN CHARLES MOORE:
No, I didn't--
JOE: No, you need
to have respect.
I'm respecting you as a man.
CAPTAIN CHARLES MOORE:
[LAUGHING]
JOE: Respect me, or we'll
have further words.
Do we understand ourselves?
CAPTAIN CHARLES MOORE:
OK, I'm sorry.
JOE: Thank you.
Now how would you like it?
CAPTAIN CHARLES MOORE:
Like this.
Bigger.
THOMAS MORTON: Want to
go catch the sunset?
Oh, my god.
I am totally having a
"Joe-berdose" as of today.
I'm kind of lightening back
up to it-- to the humor--
the humor that is Joe.
I don't know.
I was having a bad--
a bad time with it today.
Just like, being around
a guy who's living
through the riff Holocaust.
I've heard every statement
I've made, basically--
I wouldn't even limit
it to jokes--
repeated back to me.
The one thing I will never grow
tired of is his politics.
He's one of those real just
garden-variety California liberals.
He's just like baffled by any
other sort of worldview.
He called 19th-century
whalers idiots.
[LAUGHING]
We've gotten a little bit
of a radio signal.
We know the outside world
still exists, basically.
We don't have, like--
we don't have any idea what
exactly is going on there.
I like these weird towers,
or dicks--
dicks of cloud.
One thing that's been killing
me, horniness.
It's--
first few days I was fine.
But it's slowly waxing.
I'm starting to, like, really
fucking pore through the
memory card up here in my--
I'm not even trying to.
I'm just catching myself
in off hours.
Our minds are just folding
in on themselves.
Oh, as far as trajectory, if
this hand is California, and
we started here in Long Beach,
we kind of did this.
And now we're plunking our way
down into the gyre, which is
right there.
I think the current estimate is,
like, two or three days,
when we're right in the
fucking thick of it.
And then we can get
down to business.
It'll be good to get out
to the patch because
A, it'll give us--
I mean, we'll be working out
there, as opposed to just,
like, sitting around
and talking about
how fast it's going.
Also, it can serve as a
scapegoat for any tension
that's building up, you know?
You can just redirect your anger
towards the garbage.
And also, I think it being a
bummer will help kind of level
everybody's moods.
Thar she blows!
MEREDITH DANLUCK: Oh, god.
The only thing that exists is,
like, this boat, and the
people on it, and whatever this
leviathan we're searching
for, this Captain Ahab, Moby
Dick situation we have going
on here for this trash island,
which I'm starting to get--
If We don't fucking
find something--
MEREDITH DANLUCK: --I'll
really lose my mind.
MEREDITH DANLUCK: That's what's
freaking me out, man.
Captain, how far now until
the garbage patch?
CAPTAIN CHARLES MOORE: Yeah,
we're a day away.
We're just penetrating into
the second cell right now.
JAKE BURGHART: This is where
we expect to find the--
CAPTAIN CHARLES MOORE: That's
where we'd expect to find the
highest concentrations, yeah.
JAKE BURGHART: We just
officially passed
the 1,500 mile mark.
We got 1,500 miles to go, so
we're halfway, which is
insane, because we've been
here for so fucking long.
Thomas is up spotting
pieces of trash.
We've been seeing pieces of
trash every day, just, you
know, here and there.
I think in my mind--
and probably
Meredith's and Thomas--
we were eventually going
to arrive somewhere.
We're going to get to the place
where this is where all
the trash is.
CAPTAIN CHARLES MOORE: Everybody
says, show me a
picture of the garbage.
OK, well, it's spread out.
It's diffuse.
This is an enormous ocean.
So you're not going to find--
THOMAS MORTON: I understand
that.
CAPTAIN CHARLES MOORE: You're
not going to find a dump.
There's no trash
dump down here.
JAKE BURGHART: I was sort of
under the impression that
there was going to be a visible
patch somewhere, where
it's like--
where you could walk out on the
deck and just be like--
CAPTAIN CHARLES MOORE: Well,
there's a windrow.
JAKE BURGHART: --there's
garbage, garbage, garbage,
everywhere.
Yeah, like you were saying--
CAPTAIN CHARLES MOORE:
A windrow of garbage.
--patterns in the garbage.
CAPTAIN CHARLES MOORE:
But it's a line
and it's not a pattern.
JAKE BURGHART: We just need,
like, for the big--
we've got everything we need,
so much good stuff, so much
good information.
And I'm really happy, I think
it's a really good piece.
But we need the big--
CAPTAIN CHARLES MOORE: Well, I
think that it's your job to
stay on deck.
MEREDITH DANLUCK: Yeah, but we
also have to sleep for at
least a few hours every day.
JAKE BURGHART: We're all on the
same team, we just need to
get something that--
CAPTAIN CHARLES MOORE:
Well, we're ready
to move to any location.
It's not so important
where you look.
It's looking at the calmest
part of the ocean.
Because that's when the stuff
floats up to the top.
The crap is everywhere.
But it floats up to the
top in the calm.
Well, that's where
I've brought you.
I've brought you to the calm.
This is the calmest
part of the ocean.
JAKE BURGHART: Woo!
Fuck you!
Spring break, the gyre, 2007!
Woo!
Boo-ya!
MEREDITH DANLUCK:
Another buoy?
THOMAS MORTON: That's a--
or is it a helmet?
MEREDITH DANLUCK:
It's a helmet.
THOMAS MORTON: Dude,
that's creepy.
MEREDITH DANLUCK: That
is so creepy.
THOMAS MORTON: Creepy as shit.
MEREDITH DANLUCK: With a
big chunk out of it.
JAKE BURGHART: Put it on.
[LAUGHING]
THOMAS MORTON: That shit's
alive, asshole.
Ew, it's fucking moving.
[LAUGHING]
THOMAS MORTON: That
wasn't worth it.
What kind of shot was that?
Hang on.
Should I be saying something?
It's hard to believe,
looking at this.
I mean, this water is, like,
beyond Crayola blue.
JAKE BURGHART: We got
some fucking--
MEREDITH DANLUCK: Ew!
THOMAS MORTON: Ew!
MEREDITH DANLUCK: I don't
want that one.
[LAUGHING]
THOMAS MORTON: That's
glass though, right?
So that's not as bad?
Or--
JAKE BURGHART: That's not
so much of a concern.
[ENGINE REVVING]
MEREDITH DANLUCK: Wait,
wait, wait.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Jake.
[LAUGHING]