done in a very disciplined manner. Please
notice there is no subduction, no rotation
of tectonic plates, no twisting, no form fitting,
no altering shapes or sizes. It would be impossible,
impossible, for these continental plates to
fit together perfectly without this being
true, and yet the upper tectonic plates fit
together perfectly – on a much smaller planet.
Yes, there’s been some erosion, landslides,
blah blah, but overall this activity is insignificant.
There is a kind of conspiracy of silence among
certain scientists, they know but are not
telling you that the upper tectonic plates
of Earth also join in the Pacific. Not partially,
they join totally. You are asked to believe
that the continents swim or drift about willy
nilly bumping and crashing as if they were
on a greased skillet. This is not true. The
simple truth is apparently too upsetting to
too many apple carts. We are now going forward
in time to show how the actual growth of the
Earth took place. Imperfect in details, but
the overall is nailed.
Antarctica as you see has become sub-tropical.
Africa on a smaller globe moved way down under
the globe. In fact for hundreds of millions
of years the bottom of Africa was the South
Pole. South America’s tail goes under and
wraps around the bottom of Africa, then incredibly
joins coasts with Antarctica. 65 million years
ago and more these continents were joined
and marsupials like the duck billed platypus
roamed from Australia, Antarctica and across
southern South America and up into Africa;
the platypus.
Dinosaurs roamed all over this world on the
upper tectonic plate because there were no
oceans, just shallow seas. Here today Antarctica
is frozen over and Australia and its surrounding
islands are the remaining home of marsupials.
Do you see how broadly the Pacific is opening
compared to the Atlantic? This is exactly
why the knee jerk Pangea theory exists. The
Pacific spread is to difficult to easily visualize
because its so big.
The Atlantic spread is so obvious that a child
would recognize it. But they are the same.
Check this map out. The Navy and others took
core samples to find the ages of the sea bottom.
Low and behold no part of the undersea was
found to be much more than 70 million years
old. Does that shock you? It should. It shocked
the scientists. Where did they get ancient
fish fossils from? From the land, like in
Mississippi, and Utah, and France, and China.
Most of the undersea wasn’t there 70 or
80 million years ago. The measurements of
the core samples give the age of the sea floor.
Newest, 10 million or so, is red. As we go
back in time we go back in our rainbow, orange,
yellow, green blue. Okay? So we bury the new
sea floor back to the fault lines dictated
by color or age. Ten million years back, these
are the ages of the sea floor as measured
science and they’re generally true. Earth
grew.
Twenty million…
I’m not making this information up. This
map comes from the scientific community.
30 million…
You can find this same map in many places
on the internet. It’s common knowledge.
40…
The ocean bottom is from 1 year to 180 million
years old.
50…
70% of it is no older than 60 million years
old.
60…
The upper plates, the continents, are as old
as 2 billion years old and more.
70…
10 to 20 times as old as the undersea plates.
The undersea plate is new and spreading at
the rifts. Why does the scientific community
desperately cling to and promote the idea
that the ocean bottom is sliding under the
continents and into a magma which is twice
as dense as solid granite, a totally unsupportable
and scientifically unsound idea? They have
to. Or else they would have to observe and
admit that the Earth is growing. And that,
viewers is a very big deal. That would change
everything in science, from the smallest particle
to the whole universe. 100 years of scientific
theory out the window. That’s a lot to give
up.
It’s important to remember that science
and the universe should and must be easier
to understand as we go back in the universe’s
evolution.
This is an undersea map. As a kind of test
for ourselves, we deemed it important to show
that not only the upper plate had to fit properly
together, but the undersea had to spread in
a logical and uniform pattern that we could
see and understand as rational humans. Do
you see those lines in the undersea, which,
beyond information show direction. The direction
of movement apart and away from the rifts.
In fact it’s like a movement diagram isn’t
it? Ah, we’re moving now.
Let me point out that the newer undersea near
the rifts is smoother and more regular than
the older land further away from the rifts.
Here in the Atlantic the rift goes right at
the middle. Half the Earth’s growth has
happened since the extinction of dinosaurs.
This means that the Earth is accelerating
in its growth.
In the last 65 million years Earth nearly
doubled in size. The last redoubling took
600 million years, at least.
We’re continuing all the undersea directions
like following a blueprint. The Earth guides
us.
And now the land masses will come together.
Perfectly.
As we now go forward in time from 185 million
years ago, please notice there is no subduction.
No raising and lowering of land masses, there
can’t be. It’s hell in the form of magma
down there. Local raising and lowering yes,
but not on a massive basis. It can’t happen.
There’s no turning or rotating of land masses.
The land masses sit in their individual plates
and don’t move. The rifts open and that’s
all.
For examination I’m going to run a few vignettes
of areas of Earth that you have the right
to be curious about.
The North Pole. Man, I love this map so much.
There was a piece in the National Geo. It
shows that the trees in Asia and North America
were exactly the same trees. Well, this is
why; the land was together when the trees
evolved.
The
South Pole…
The oceans have absolutely nothing to do with
tectonic spreading, except that they cooled
the thickening mantel. Tectonic spreading,
even according to the most conservative scientist
has created two thirds of the Earth’s surface
in the last 200 million years. And therefore,
the same, the same must be true on all planets,
including Mars. Must. And we can see the younger
spreads on Mars just as on Earth.
But there is, just as clearly, no subduction
on Mars. It can’t be both ways. You either
have spreading and subduction or you have
only spreading, and you must have spreading.
Or, you can continue to ignore the facts and
say as the ancients said, that the Earth is
unique and singular in the universe and that
we are the center, and the universe rotates
around the Earth.