We have a nice bit of skirt. So I'm going
to just literally cut a little butterfly,
I don't want to go all the way through, just
enough so it opens out up like that.
We want to bash it out, okay to make it flat
enough to roll it.
Nearly there. Looking good, looking fresh
to me.
What was that you say? No bread, bread is
dead. You don't need no bread for this one.
It's all about the filling.
Trust me, this will be the best couscous you
will ever make.
Here we go, I've got some lovely couscous
here. Right, about 100 grams there. You know
when it's ready when it just flakes like that.
We've got our dried apricots, chopped up.
Now they bring a really nice sweetness to
it. A little bit of a bite. And we've got
some onions that Have just been caramelised
with some caraway seed and some cumin.
Peppers, when you're making this, try and
chop everything the same sort of size.
That way you get a little bit of everything
when you take a bite. Grated beetroot. Gives
it a nice acidity, a nice crunch. Olives,
chop them up. Beautiful.
Already, it's like a rainbow of love. Toasted,
whole almonds. You can use flake. I'm just
going to crush them up a little bit.
Coriander. Bit of basil, bit of tarragon there.
So let's chop these up.
Are you licking your lips right now?
Bit of garlic. Background flavour. Bit of
salt on there. We've got to make sure it's
minced up.
Now halloumi.
Chilli. We're going to spice it up a bit.
Take the seeds out.
I just go like that, over the bin.
Nice little rings in there.
Bit of seasoning. Salt and pepper. The best
food marriage in the world.
We're going to lift it up in the air with
a bit of orange and lemon zest. A little bit
of oil. Let's get a bit Jamie Oliver about
it,
He loves doing all of this doesn't he!
It adds like a peppery, grassy, creamy sort
of taste to it. Right, that's done. Ready
to go, it's got every texture, every flavour
going on in there you can imagine.
We've got three layers of cling film down
there. Get our beef of here. You might have
to coach it a little bit. There is a few little
bits that are broken. It's not a problem.
Little bit of salt and pepper. Not too much
because remember we seasoned our filling over
there.
I've got some creme fraiche you can use. Yoghurt.
Let's put a little bit of that on. We're pasting
the wall.
Right?
I'm going to put a little splash of horseradish
in there.
Basil leaves these are going to be like wallpaper.
With loads of flavour. It's going to fill
it up look!
This is the way I think.
Wonderful, now we're ready for the filling.
I'm going to grab a big old handful like that.
You can imagine being on the streets of Mexico
city, or somewhere like that, you know what
I'm saying. Boom, they're putting this all
out. The sun's shining.
Use the cling film to bring everything together.
So I'm trying to get this as tight as possible,
yeah? And the other hand here. I'm sort of
pulling and tucking, pulling, making sure
the cling films nice and straight. Tie a little
knot in the side.
The idea is we want it to set. As a sausage
In the fridge.
So, that is it. Er, ready to go into the fridge.
Ready to chill for about half an hour, an
hour if you've got the time. See you in a
bit.
Thirty minutes is up and this is ready to
be grilled. So nice bit of oil on there.
Never put the oil in the pan because it will
start smoking up. That's a noise that you're
looking for there. Back to the Building tray.
We're going a bit of welding now.
Alright? So we're just sealing that crack
down there right. Be patient. We want those
really nice dark brown grill marks. Come on,
come on baby.
It's still a little bit pink in the middle.
That's fine, that's the way I like it.
That's ready.
Very important. Leave that to rest for about
5 to 7 minutes. There you go it's rested.
Now you just need to wrap it up and eat it!
Oh my god look at this! I'm going to pout
ti down for a minute and do this.
WOW. W O W. There's more of these out there.
I've got a steak tortilla. It's up there now,
press it.
Ohh mate! That beautiful couscous. Loads of
flavours going on.
No bread, just meat.
If you do like it, subscribe now. Put you
comments down below.
Ohh, I need to be alone with this right now.