Standing by for back shell separation.
We are in powered flight.
We are at altitude of1 kilometer and descending.
Standing by for sky crane.
Sky crane has started.
Touchdown confirmed! We're safe on Mars!
Cheering, applause
We had a major success when we deployed the
arm for the first time on Mars.
This is critical to ensuring that we can get
sample into our instruments and use the arm
for its scientific purposes.
The ChemCam unit, or chemistry and camera
instrument, fired the laser for the first
time on Mars, using the beam from the science
instrument to interrogate a fist-sized rock
called coronation.
Before we could drive curiosity, we wanted
to wiggle our toes a bit and test the steering
actuators.
This is the first time we moved the wheels
on Mars.
We hit a major milestone on Mars.
We completed our first drive of the curiosity
rover.
We drove approximately 3 meters forward and
performed 2 60-degree rotations in a clockwise
direction with imaging in between.
We then drove backwards just under 3 meters
in order to test the wheels in the opposite
direction.
This put us in a great configuration to make
observations of the scours left by the descent
stage engines.
We’ve got a very interesting science experiment
coming up here on Mars.
We are turning on the sample analysis at Mars
instrument for the first time to do an atmospheric
experiment.
This is where we let in atmosphere into the
instrument and perform various science experiments
that determine the composition of the atmosphere.
This is the first time that this is happening.
Within days, we will start our journey to
our first chosen destination on Mars, Glenelg.
We hope to obtain our first drilled rock sample
on Mars at this location.
The team named the landing site this week
after the famous science fiction author, Ray
Bradbury, on his birthday, august 22nd, and
he would have been 92.
Curiosity is still is heading to Glenelg.
We've just stopped at the Bathurst rock formation
to check it out with the robotic arm mounted
instruments: a hand lens imager and a spectrometer.
Got some great science data there for the
science team and now we're moving to a new
rover location called Rocknest. And we've
come to Rocknest because it has nice windblown
sand drifts.
At the Rocknest location we really are entering
a new phase in Mars exploration with Curiosity.
We're starting the surface sampling part of
the mission. The reason this is a one-ton
rover with a 200-pound robotic arm, is because
we have these tools to acquire bits of Mars,
you know, either with a scoop or with a drill;
process those samples for our very sensitive
analytical lab instruments.
So our scoop - this is not a giant backhoe
on Mars - we basically have more like an oversized
tablespoon attached to the end of the arm
and we grab on the order of 20 grams of material
and we position the arm over the soil target
and then we just actuate the scoop, do a little
bit of vibration to kind of level out the
sample and then raise the arm up, close the
scoop and carry on with our sampling activity.
When we first arrived at Rocknest, we performed
a wheel scuff maneuver. This is our rover's
version of kicking up the dirt with your hiking
boot to determine if the Rocknest area was
indeed a good first scoop target.
The first scoop was successfully performed
on Sol 61 and the entire team was excited
to see the MastCam images showing the scoop
full of dirt, as well as the video of the
vibration activities performed with the turret-mounted
tools. This vibration allows the team to level
out and remove any excess sample before closing
the scoop, and it also provides some insight
into the makeup of the soil.
Any large particles would tend to float up
to the top as the entire sample is vibrated,
much the same way you would shake out the
marshmallows in your box of Lucky Charms.
Curiosity processed the scoop sample through
CHIMRA, our labyrinth of passageways at the
end of the arm that we use to sieve and portion
the soil sample. We did some internal sandblasting
by vibrating the sample at different orientations
on the turret in order to remove any internal
contamination.
A soil sample was dropped off to the rover’s
observation tray for assessment by the science
team. This sample was determined to be suitable
for drop off to the CheMin instrument.
The CheMin instrument uses X-rays in order
to image the sample and determine what minerals
make it up. This helps geologists understand
how the rock formed and how it's related to
other rocks we've studied so far on Mars.
Scientists identified numerous bright grains
in the soil. Because of the small piece of
plastic from the landing event that had been
found earlier in the week, the team proceeded
cautiously, dumping the second scoop collected
and imaging the bright grains.
These bright grains were later determined
to be components of the Martian soil, and
therefore, the sample was deemed to be suitable
for delivery to the CheMin instrument for
analysis.
The science team requested MastCam and NavCam
mosaics of the outcrops in the direction of
Glenelg, to plan Curiosity's journey to this
next science destination.
In its spare time, Curiosity has also been
making measurements with other instruments,
including the ChemCam instrument, which is
what I work on.
ChemCam is actually two instruments in one.
It includes a camera with a telephoto lens
and it also has a laser that vaporizes a very
small amount of rock so we can tell what its
chemical composition is.
We've been analyzing rocks in an area called
Rocknest, and I'll tell you in particular
about one called Zephyr. This one is interesting
because it appears to be made of 2 different
types of materials.
It's got this harder, more resistant material
on the top, capping it, and then beneath it
has a lighter colored softer material that
appears to erode more easily. It's actually
eroded into a set of natural arches, so some
of our team members have taken to calling
it "Stonehenge."
This feature is really only an inch long.
We're shooting this from about 8 feet away,
making the pointing very difficult.
So that's why we decided to do 9 points instead
of just 2, just to make sure we would hit
the material of interest.
Coming up, we'll be able to use this information
that we've learned from ChemCam in order to
decide which targets we should hit next with
other instruments.
CheMin performs what we call X-ray diffraction
measurements on powdered rocks and soil samples.
An X-ray diffraction is the best method for
telling us what minerals are present in a
rock or soil because it is sensitive to the
arrangements of atoms in minerals. As the
X-rays strike the soil sample, CheMin shows
us how mineral crystals distinctively interact
with X-rays, and this image shows our first
X-ray diffraction results. The diffraction
signals appear on the detector as rings that
represent the fingerprint of the individual
minerals. The rings tell us not only what
minerals are present in the soil but also
how abundant they are.
The CheMin data provide us with distinctive
signatures of the minerals: plagioclase feldspar,
pyroxenes, and olivines. Peridot is a variety
of olivine; just keep in mind that the olivine
in the soil sample is much smaller than these
crystals. Roughly half of the soil consists
of poorly crystalline material, such as volcanic
glass. Thus, this Martian soil appears very
similar to some weathered basaltic soils that
we see on Earth, in places like the flanks
of Mauna Kea, Hawaii.
You can appreciate how revolutionary CheMin
is when you consider that instruments of this
type on Earth are typically about the size
of a doublewide refrigerator and the CheMin
instrument on the Mars Science Laboratory
is about the size of a shoebox. CheMin has
been modified for use on Earth in places such
as Antarctica and the Arctic.
It's also been applied for the detection of
counterfeit pharmaceuticals around the worlds
and a modification of the instrument has been
used in archeological studies to help us understand
the nature of the surfaces and how we might
protect them.
In the coming weeks and months, we're excited
to measure more X-ray diffraction data on
soils and rocks to tell us much more about
the geology of Gale Crater.
While our robotic explorer has been busy characterizing
the surface of Mars, the SAM team has also
been busy, but we've been looking at something
invisible, the Martian atmosphere.
SAM, or Sample Analysis at Mars, is not one
instrument, but three, all of which are designed
to work together to chemically characterize
Mars. SAM measures chemical elements and molecules,
in a mass or size range between 2 and 535
mass units and we do this by looking at gases.
We can bake solid samples until they give
up their volatile components or their gases
or we can directly inhale the Martian atmosphere
through our inlet ports.
With our QMS, SAM is able to detect the most
dominant gas in the Martian atmosphere, carbon
dioxide. We've not only measured its abundance
and the ratio to other gases in the Martian
atmosphere but we've also measured its isotopic
character. The other instruments are a tunable
laser spectrometer and a gas chromatograph,
the latter being used mostly to look for organic
molecules in solids.
Now, the tunable laser spectrometer has a
special role for SAM in that it can very sensitively
detect the organic molecule, methane, which
has been observed from the Earth telescopically
and also by the Mars Express orbiter at very,
very low limits in the Martian atmosphere.
We're trying to discover whether or not we
can see this molecule from the Martian surface
and if it has any variation from season to
season. In the coming months, wherever Curiosity
goes, SAM will continue to sniff the Martian
atmosphere, periodically looking for changes
on a seasonal or maybe even diurnal basis
and that will tell us something about the
dynamics of the exchange between the surface
and the atmosphere.
A lot of what this mission is about is figuring
out the possibility that ancient Mars was
a habitable environment. But we're also studying
the present environment. Two instruments that
help with that are the RAD instrument and
the REMS instrument.
The RAD instrument is a radiation assessment
detector. It measures the high-energy radiation
coming up from the cosmic rays and the sun.
That radiation is changed as it goes through
Mars' atmosphere to where we detect it on
the surface.
These measurements are helping to understand
what the environment is like on the surface
so that future astronauts will know how to
protect themselves from this radiation.
Another instrument that Curiosity has that
measures the modern environment is called
the rover environmental monitoring station.
It's basically our weather station. We measure
a lot of things including pressure and humidity,
temperature and wind.
It's been seeing little dips in pressure around
noon that seemed like the signature of dust
devils. Only thing is our pictures haven't
turned up any dust devils.
Spirit and Opportunity saw lots of dust devils
moving across the horizon. Our best guess
at what's going on is that Curiosity is seeing
dust devils go right over it.
So what we think is happening is the same
sorts of vortexes, driven by convection are
occurring on Mars at the Curiosity's site
but just not picking up dust.
Another thing that REMS has been measuring
is winds. Turns out we're in a pretty interesting
place inside of Gale Crater. We're right at
the base of a 5-kilometer high mountain to
the south of us and then there's a pretty
tall crater rim to the north of us and we're
sitting in kind of a flat depression between
the two.
The winds blow up and down the mountain as
the temperature changes during the day and
up and down the crater slopes and then along
the depression where we're at. So right now
we're trying to figure out from the REMS data
exactly which parts of that wind field we're
measuring.
After several weeks of being stationary at
the Rocknest site, we began driving again
on Saw 100.
This marked a significant milestone on the
mission as we reached about a half-kilometer
of total driving distance on the surface of
Mars.
The left front wheel is sitting on a rock
that we’ve dubbed “Bell Island”.
We plan to back up off that rock to bring
the rock into the arm’s workspace and we’re
going to do some contact science on it with
APXS and MAHLI.
After completing our science campaign at our
current location, we’re going to be moving
to the east to a place called Point Lake.
From here, we’re going to be looking for
a target to perform our first ever drill on
Mars.
We've wrapped up our scientific study of Rocknest,
which also means that we've completed the
checkout and first scientific use of all our
instruments on the rover and it truly is working
great.
We began the Rocknest campaign by searching
for a suitable drift of sandy soil using our
MastCam color cameras. We used out ChemCam
laser and our APXS chemical sensor to do an
initial chemical analysis of the soil, determining
whether it was similar to soils that we understand
from Spirit and Opportunity and therefore
safe for scooping and sending to our laboratories.
We use MAHLI, our hand lens imager to take
close up views of the soil to look at different
particle sizes, shapes and colors and how
they change with depth.
We then scooped up the soil and analyzed it
with our X-ray diffraction instrument that
can identify minerals in the soil based on
their unique crystal structure. But it turned
out that a good amount of the material in
the soil was not crystalline but that's no
problem for our other laboratory, SAM.
SAM heated up the soil in an oven, measured
various gases released as the soil components
broke down, such as water, carbon dioxide,
oxygen and sulfur.
Not surprisingly, the results show a composition
that is typical of Mars soils studied at other
sites with perhaps some very simple carbon
containing molecules and perchlorate salts.
We haven't yet seen any complex organic molecules
but sand isn't the best place to look.
Finally, it's worth remembering that the big
questions in science, whether Copernicus finding
that the Earth goes around the sun or Darwin
showing that natural selection drives biological
evolution, were answered only after many measurements
were taken compared against one another and
hypotheses were proposed and tested against
data. Only then can the big picture emerge
and the theory get accepted.
It'll be no different for Curiosity in its
mission to understand the habitability of
ancient Mars at Gale Crater. There won't be
any single image or measurement that'll answer
everything. We're in it for the long haul.
But now we know that we have a fantastic rover,
a great set of tools, and a fully functional
scientific payload, so let's get on exploring.