So this is a big sport
here in Jamtland?
MALE SPEAKER: It's
a big sport.
CHRIS: Hopefully today
we can give it a go.
And especially with my hangover
after too much
Presidential beer, I
won't make too much
of a mess of myself.
KRISHNA: I can't wait to
see tomorrow Chris.
MALE SPEAKER: Today is
biathlon practice.
We're going to start
with shooting.
CHRIS: Cool.
MALE SPEAKER: And then we will
go out and do the skiing.
CHRIS: All right, sounds good.
MALE SPEAKER: The green
targets are hits,
red light is a miss.
KRISHNA: And so in real life
is this the distance?
Chris, perfect.
MALE SPEAKER: OK, so winner?
KRISHNA: Winner.
MALE SPEAKER: Now it's
time for skiing.
KRISHNA: All right.
I feel like just get
us on that course.
Men's pursuit, 12:15, that's
going to be us.
CHRIS: We need to warm-up.
KRISHNA: Got to warm-up
for men's pursuit.
Look at this guy.
He's like who the fuck
are these guys?
MALE SPEAKER: Remember to
keep your hands close.
Look at me first.
Bend your knees, pull
down on the poles.
That's it!
CHRIS: Oi.
MALE SPEAKER: Ready?
Go!
And we're heading out with
a good start for Chris.
Krishna has gained a half
of the lead two
yards from the start.
And it will be a close finish!
A tactical finish!
And as the referee, I
can still not see
anyone passing the line.
And Krishna goes
over the line.
Winner!
KRISHNA: Yes!
CHRIS: Should get a
little pose here.
KRISHNA: Oh, of course,
of course.
MALE SPEAKER: The winner.
Hooray!
KRISHNA: Thank you sir, I get a
handshake from the President
of Jamtland.
Thank you sir, thank you.
Photo finish.