BILL: You are a beautiful
reckless woman.
JANE: Damn right I am.
BILL: You're going to
be the death of me.
JANE: Probably.
BILL: I don't care.
JANE: All right.
It's your funeral.
[LOUD BRASSY MUSIC]
NARRATOR: Bill was the town
pariah, the most hated man in
a 20-mile radius.
The reasons for this
were unclear.
Maybe it was because he spent
his youth in and out of jail.
Maybe it was because he fought
and drank and used the Lord's
name in vain without remorse.
Maybe it was because he was the
greatest firefighter the
town had ever seen--
so brave, he made the others
look like cowards.
So they conspired to have him
dishonorably discharged.
But Jane was madly in
love with Bill.
She taught him things she'd
learned at university, like
how wealth redistribution was
the only solution to the
world's problems.
He taught her how
to shoot a gun.
The town was notorious for
the amount of miraculous
interventions that had
occurred there.
People traveled from all
over the country
in order to be healed.
Jane's father was
the town pastor.
PASTOR: We must agree that
unclean spirits shall be
purged from our lives!
We shall all--
NARRATOR: Needless to say,
he was not fond of Bill.
PASTOR: --at the last trump,
when the Rapture comes!
When we mount that
white horse.
NARRATOR: Bill's only
sympathizers were
the men in his group.
BILL: I know I could
be a good person.
I just have these terrible
things inside of me.
NARRATOR: Bill's best friend
was Paul Mermelstein, a
disgraced engineer.
Bill assisted Paul with his
scientific endeavors.
PAUL: It's a debacle!
BILL: It'll work.
PAUL: You should have seen
me 30 years ago!
I was gorgeous!
The police would have to escort
me down the street
because the girls literally
would rip the
clothes off my back!
[STATICKY RADIO ANNOUNCEMENT]
BILL: It's a two-alarm.
PAUL: I'll get the car.
JANE: Oh, come on!
Stop terrorizing the
fire department!
BILL: I'm not terrorizing
them.
They can't do their job.
NARRATOR: When the firefighters
arrived, Bill and
Paul had already put
out the blaze.
Bill was a danger to
the community.
It was decided that something
had to be done.
PASTOR: Bill, have you sinned?
BILL: Yes.
PASTOR: Have you felt lost?
PASTOR: Are you ready to allow
the Lord to exile your
destructive ways?
BILL: OK.
PASTOR: We allow this troubled
spirit to receive a blessing
from the Holy Ghost!
Will you give him the glory and
reign of your atonement,
Jesus Christ!
JANE: I didn't know he
was going to do that.
BILL: It's OK.
JANE: I'm sorry.
He can say whatever he wants.
Doesn't mean anything anyway.
NARRATOR: But the pastor had
asked for a miracle.
And a miracle did occur.
For God had put a curse
on Bill's axe.
There was nothing the
doctors could do to
reattach Bill's arm.
So Paul built him a mechanical
limb, one made of tin.
PAUL: It's the best
I could do.
NARRATOR: But Jane still loved
Bill and stood by him.
And soon things returned
to normal.
But the curse was still there.
Bill quit his job
as a lumberjack.
Unfortunately, the only job
he could find was at the
slaughterhouse.
-Help!
There's a problem with
the machine!
NARRATOR: Bill was in a
coma for two months.
During this time Paul worked
tirelessly to save his
friend's life.
Though by now he was more
metal than flesh.
PAUL: I managed to save your
eyes, your heart, some of your
other organs.
Honestly, I have no idea
why you're still alive.
TINMAN: I gotta see Jane.
PAUL: I don't think that's
a good idea.
JANE: Stay way from me!
Get out of here!
NARRATOR: Paul told the Tinman
what had happened.
PAUL: Here.
Have a drink.
NARRATOR: How Bill's
remains had
disappeared from the morgue.
How they had returned the next
day, walking upright, a
creature without veins
or lungs or heart.
How the pastor had called
it a miracle.
How happy Jane was to have her
man back in some form.
The next day the Tinman
went to see his
love, but to no avail.
FIREFIGHTER: She doesn't
want to see you.
TINMAN: Did she say that?
FIREFIGHTER: Get
lost, or else.
TINMAN: I'm not going anywhere,
you damn cowards.
FIREFIGHTER: We found
these in the woods.
TINMAN: She doesn't want
anything to do with me.
I'm hideous.
PAUL: Don't say that!
TINMAN: I feel like
I'm gonna explode.
How do you make someone
love you again?
What's the noblest thing
you can possibly do?
PAUL: You can steal from the
rich and give to the poor.
TINMAN: All right, I'll do it.
I guess I have nothing
else to lose anyway.
PAUL: I was joking.
NARRATOR: So the Tinman
reinvented himself as a
revolutionary in order to
win Jane's affection.
He successfully redistributed
87% of the town's wealth.
PAUL: Stick it to the pigs!
TINMAN: Jane!
I know you don't love him!
JANE: You don't know that.
TINMAN: He doesn't even
have a heart!
-Come on.
The revolution needs you.
NARRATOR: They stole every car
in town, and cut down all the
telephone wires.
Not a sound came in or out.
Soon the town descended
into chaos.
PAUL: What makes a king
out of a slave?
NARRATOR: The Tinman
orchestrated a coup and
installed Paul Murmelstein
as Mayor.
PAUL: --to reach beyond, not
to sink into the abyss!
PASTOR: Satan walks among us!
We must rise now!
JANE: Why are you doing this?
TINMAN: I just want
to make you happy.
I miss you.
JANE: I miss you, too.
NARRATOR: Drunk with power,
Paul Murmelstein declared
himself the reincarnation of
John the Baptist and tried to
burn down the church.
The faithful of the town fell
into a persecuting frenzy.
The pastor declared that the
Meat Puppet was sent from Hell
to destroy them all.
-Wake up!
They're going to hang
your fiance!
-Let him die!
-Yeah!
TINMAN: Do you really
love this guy?
JANE: I think so.
TINMAN: All right.
Let him go!
-It's the Rapture!
NARRATOR: The Tinman knew the
only way to prove his love for
Jane was to save the life of
the one she truly loved.
He ripped his heart out of his
chest and placed it inside the
Meat Puppet.
TINMAN: Why are you
still here?
JANE: Because I'm a sinner.
TINMAN: That's what I always
liked about you.
JANE: I still don't love you.
TINMAN: That's OK.
I don't have a heart anymore.
JANE: Would you hold me?