EDDIE HUANG: Crazy.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
EDDIE HUANG: I like the sound
of this motor, man.
LARGO: Yeah, it runs
real good.
EDDIE HUANG: So you
live in East LA?
EDDIE HUANG: What's
that known for?
EDDIE HUANG: Low riders
and gangs?
I like that.
Real easy living.
LARGO: Yeah, [INAUDIBLE].
EDDIE HUANG: Where
we headed now?
BENNY: Low riding's my life.
I've been in it since I was 10
years old-- since 1982 I've
been a member.
EDDIE HUANG: Yeah.
BENNY: We have our meetings
once a month, so we try to
come out here, grill, bring the
families, and see what's
cracking, what's up.
EDDIE HUANG: You know, the thing
is that growing up in
America, you follow hip hop, you
watch movies, you always
see low riders.
But I never got to ride in one
going down the freeway in LA
doing my thing.
Now I get why people are into
low riders, because you get in
and you feel like you're
a kid again.
You remember riding in the back
of your parents' Lincoln,
like that just big sofa couch.
BENNY: Yeah, exactly.
EDDIE HUANG: It's fresh, man.
BENNY: First, it's
a art form, bro.
You know, everyone has
their own style.
And this is us.
We grew up with it.
This is our lifestyle, bro.
PETER: In the '30s, '40s,
'50s, they had what were
called cigarette dispensers.
You would put your cigarette
in here, and as you're
driving, you would actually
open it and it would light
your cigarette and you smoke
it while you're driving.
EDDIE HUANG: These cars are
like time machines.
You get in, these dudes
are bumping tunes from
the '60s and '70s.
It's beautiful to see.
REDWOOD: What up, man?
Big Redwood chilling
right here.
Hot ass day, Southern
California.
Chilling with my brother,
Techniques Car Club, you know
what I mean?
It's what we do on
Sundays, man.
We bring the family out, have
a couple beers, everybody's
cool, cook up some good
meat for the kids.
You know what I mean?
It's all love, man.
We can't just have
anybody in here.
EDDIE HUANG: Yeah.
No hooligans.
REDWOOD: Yeah.
And there was a long time when
there was the whole era of the
car club wars.
EDDIE HUANG: Yeah.
REDWOOD: Unfortunately, there's
still that stigmatism
that's left over.
And they associate low riding
with gang banging and all this
other stuff.
But we're all just working
guys, dude.
We ain't just a bunch of
knuckleheads out here, man.
EDDIE HUANG: Yeah.
What did you marinate
the short ribs in?
REDWOOD: There's a little bit
of lemon, there's some
cilantro, there's some secret
stuff going right there.
EDDIE HUANG: Secret stuff?
You want to break me off with
some of the secrets?
REDWOOD: That's the secret!
EDDIE HUANG: Yeah?
Oh, some Bud?
Some Bud Light?
UNKNOWN SPEAKER: Right.
You know what I mean?
EDDIE HUANG: Cilantro,
paprika.
REDWOOD: Turmeric.
EDDIE HUANG: You got
a little turmeric.
REDWOOD: Garlic powder.
EDDIE HUANG: Yeah, onion salt.
REDWOOD: Granulated onion.
EDDIE HUANG: Yeah.
REDWOOD: You can't flavor the
meat too much, because the
meat is the flavor, right?
EDDIE HUANG: Yep, exactly.
REDWOOD: You know that, right?
You need to tell me some
of your secrets.
EDDIE HUANG: What I do with the
short rib to tenderize it,
beer will tenderize it,
anything carbonated.
I like to use a Dr. Pepper
or cherry cola,
tenderize it overnight.
REDWOOD: Cherry cola!
EDDIE HUANG: Definitely,
definitely.
[INAUDIBLE] grab me
a little space.
[INAUDIBLE].
No, you know I'm Chinese, man.
I just eat rice.
[LAUGHTER]
EDDIE HUANG: The short rib?
It was just hanging out there.
Here.
We'll share some of it.
FEMALE SPEAKER: [INAUDIBLE].
Give him a piece, please.
EDDIE HUANG: I got tons of it.
I got tons of it.
[LAUGHTER]
FEMALE SPEAKER: Hey!
EDDIE HUANG: No, I love it.
I like this!
Yo, so I want to ask you this.
It's definitely not to be
sensational or whatever.
But he was telling me about
the car club wars.
How did that happen?
PETER: It was a sad time
in low riding.
If you disrespected another
club, they're gonna get you.
They're going to catch you on
the boulevard, pull you out of
your car, and beat you
down right there, and
jack up your car.
Bumper jacks, crow bars,
whatever they had.
Back then, the guy riding
shotgun had a shotgun.
EDDIE HUANG: Yeah
PETER: I said, the person
sitting in the passenger seat
now is my kid.
I said, and that's a little
girl or a little boy.
And I don't need nobody shooting
at me or doing
something to me because
of old beefs.
Since then, everybody's got
respect for everybody.
You see low rider--
EDDIE HUANG: Well, people
learned the respect from the
war, most likely.
PETER: You had to.
EDDIE HUANG: 'Cause you
want to avoid that.
PETER: We fought for
that respect.
We fought for that.
But one day you gotta grow up.
A lot of people don't
talk about it.
It's a black eye
in low riding.
You know what I mean?
We had to go through that
to get where we're at.
But we've done it now.
It's in the past.
And our kids will be able to
do this the rest of their
lives with no problems.
EDDIE HUANG: Yeah.
Things ain't always
what they seem.
You see low riders affiliated
with gangs.
And that shit definitely
happened, but that shit
doesn't tell the whole story.
This is something that people
really live since birth.
They're not trying either.
They're not like people going
to vintage stores trying to
adopt another era.
This lifestyle has pervaded
them, and
they've hung onto it.
And for me to come here and be
taken in for a day, it's life
changing shit.
From East LA to Persian LA, to
here, this is just people
living, man.
Keep your eyes peeled.
Watch for the real, all right?
Fresh Off the Boat
with Eddie Huang.
We out.
ALL: Fresh Off the Boat!
[MUSIC PLAYING]