Now while most people think that
being in a prison is like being
cut off from the rest of the
world, it's not.
Recently, the California
Department of Corrections
offered access inside the prison
systems to look at a problem
that afflicts prisons across
America.
Contributor Janet Choi went to
check out.
(Janet) I'm driving in the
middle of nowhere, halfway
between Los Angeles and San
Francisco, heading to Avenal
State Prison.
I've been invited there to
follow the prison's internal
security unit, the first time
any camera crew has been allowed
to see the ISU team in action.
Their mission: to stop
contraband from getting into
prison.
It may not make sense, but
prison's aren't totally
sealed off environments.
And I was invited to Avenal to
see just how hard it is to keep
inmates from getting stuff
they're not supposed to have.
Contraband is a problem in
prisons across the the country
because nearly all violence and
gang activity in prison can be
traced back it.
They promised full access to
their division, and an
introduction to a new epidemic
in prisons.
Something that you and I didn't
even know was a problem.
>>This is all prison property
that you'll see.
(Janet) As we drove up to meet
with the ISU something was going
on.
>>Yeah, gear it up.
Let's roll.
>>There was a stabbing out
there.
>>So we were about to go inside
and interview the guys who seize
the contraband, only they got
called out because there was a
stabbing on the yard.
>>All right and two visitors.
(Janet) While the ISU was busy I
asked Sargeant Carter, to show
me the prison block and
introduce me to prisoners.
I wanted to find out what the
prisoners were allowed to have.
What do they have in each, what
do you call it, bunk area?
In each dorm?
>>Let's go take a look.
>>Yeah?
You have so little space, what
do you keep in your space?
>>Mostly everything is under my
bunk.
Nothing really fits in my locker
because it's too small, so
we've got everything under our
bunks.
Bags and stuff.
I got a lot of tattoos.
That's my daughter right
there.
Dora, Spongebob.
It's all for my daughter.
It's just, you know, something
to tribute her.
To remember her, because I
don't really see her that much
because I'm incarcerated all
the time.
Since I was about 16, I've been
on the streets probably for
about five months.
I was in and out, juvenile hall,
jail, prison.
>>This is my bunk.
I got a college book that I'm
reading.
This is a watch that I have, got
in a package.
This is a radio that they no
longer allow you to have...if
you already got them, you get to
keep them.
This is a list of CDs.
These are me and my bunkie's
combined, because you're only
allowed to have 12.
It's not much.
It helps to do your time in here
a little better, you know.
So you're not going to be as
stressed out.
If you get stressed out, you can
jump up, read a book, listen to
some music, calm yourself down.
>>You actually have more stuff
than most of the guys we've
seen here.
>>Yeah well actually I've been
down a little longer you know
and over the years things
accumulate.
>>How many pairs of shoes do you
guys have because I'm just
seeing fifty pairs of shoes
under there.
>>I got these and I got the ones
I play outside in.
Tall white guy's got to play
volleyball.
(Janet) Prisoners are allowed a
large variety of things, many of
which surprised me.
Guitars, televisions, ramen.
I rejoined the ISU for a tour of
prison contraband.
>>This is just a fraction.
A lot of stuff, we've gotten
rid of, like the tobacco, we
obviously throw that away.
But a lot of the stuff we get
rid of it, so...
>>From month to month, I try to
photograph our discoveries.
A tobacco, narcotics,
weapons...It's amazing the
stuff that they try to smuggle
in.
It's weird.
Like I think this stuff was,
uh--
>>Rogaine.
Yeah.
>>Oh, that's funny.
>>Yeah, they got to look their
best when they're in the
inmate population.
Pounds and pounds of tobacco.
We brought only just a few out
because we dispose of the stuff.
Because we don't have enough
evidence space, space in our
evidence room to hold this
stuff.
>>Right.
Is that what it looked like?
>>Yeah, this is ready to go.
A little bit of lube and this is
going in.
Prison wallet, their rectal
cavity is where this will go.
>>Most guys will be able to
bring three of these at a time.
There are some seasoned veterans
that can do quite a bit more
than that.
They'll just cover up the
sharp parts, and insert it where
it needs to be.
>>And then what?
You give them a laxative or
something?
>>No, we'll put them on
contraband watch.
They're not going to tell us
what's up there.
During the unclothed body search
he has to cough, you'll see
packaging, or some part of it,
and then: Oh, that's a clue.
Might want to put him on
contraband watch.
>>Or they'll lube themselves
up.
They'll have a lot of Vaseline
or lubricant in that area.
>>A wet spot on their pants.
So you can only imagine where
someone would hide one of these,
right?
>>Pounds and pounds of tobacco.
Roughly, this is a can of
Bugler.
OK.
This has been vacuumed sealed.
A can of Bugler on the street
goes for about 12 bucks.
>>With papers and all.
>>With rolling papers.
This here in the institution is
about 400 dollars?
>>If you buy it at the can rate,
it's about three to $400.
If you break that down and sell
it at individual cigarettes like
most of them do, you're
probably looking at a $1,000.
>>It's a big lucrative
business right now.
>>And is it organized crime?
Is it randoms just trying to
make a buck?
>>Well, um, it's gang related.
A lot of it's um, for the
gang.
Bottom line is, gangs and dope
and gangs and money, and
that's what you have.
That is their sole mission is to
make money.
It's $1,153.
As you can see.
He counted it and wrote it on
the envelope for us, so we
didn't have to do the math.
But I'm sure that's just one
small sample of what's out
there.
>>Contraband is big business.
And all business in prison is
run by the gangs.
I returned to yard to see if any
of the inmates would share their
experiences in the prison
economy.
They were reluctant to speak.
You guy been having some issues
up here?
(producer) Can you say why
there's been rioting?
(man off camera) No.
>>Well, some of us just don't
get along sometimes.
There's some things that we
can't talk about.
Because it's our world in
here.
>>Yeah, you can stay by
yourself, but then, if something
happens, if you get in trouble
by yourself, you're on your
own.
>>And like a lot of people, like
I just had a visit last weekend,
and my mom asked me, "Well why
do you have to get involved?"
Well, that's just prison mom.
>>So, you're always prepared?
>>You have to always be ready.
(Janet) The inmates were
signaled from off camera to stop
answering questions and our
interview was over.
It made sense.
I was being escorted by an
officer.
And they they were being watched
by a gang member who refused to
be filmed.
I was starting to understand, 90
percent of prison is spent
watching.
The guards watch the prisoners,
and the prisoners watch the
guards.
It is a never ending game of
hide and seek, where the stakes
are anything but playful.
So when we met you today, you
immediately left because there
was an assault on one of the
yards?
>>There was an assault on one of
the yards.
And a Code 2 was called, and
what we do is we go out to
assist.
>>Is gang related activity so
prevalent that you assume
automatically, that I know
you're still investigating,
but you assume that an assault
like that is because someone
didn't do their end of the
deal?
>>Something like that needs to
sanctioned.
They can't just same, come on
dude, let's go out there and
hit this guy.
They have to get the OK from
their superiors to go do this.
A lot of your assaults depend on
depend on this right here...on
the flow of contraband coming
in.
This is all business.
It's all about money.
Don't let anybody tell you
anything different.
It's all about money.
(Janet) I travelled to Avenal to
embed myself with the ISU, the
internal security unit charged
with rooting out prison
contraband.
Avenal state prison was designed
to hold 2,500 prisoners.
It currently holds 6,500.
That is 260 percent capacity.
Avenal is a level two prison.
That means there is open
housing.
And the prisoners are allowed
more freedom.
The fact that they don't have
cells with doors, does it make
it easier or harder to find
contraband?
>>I would say it makes it a lot
harder, because they can more
the contraband around a lot
easier.
Because they don't have any
cells or doors, if we search one
dorm, and they could have just
taken it out and moved it to the
next one.
>>So I'm sort of playing a
mental video game as I'm
standing here.
There's like a thousand
different places where you could
hide things.
Like under your hat.
>>Yeah.
Anywhere.
Like in their socks.
Anything they have they could
sew it into their clothing.
It's very difficult to find
contraband.
How would you secure a place
like this and keep it free of
contraband?
Is there anyway to actually do
it?
>>Totally, 100 percent?
No.
I don't think there is a way.
Conservative estimate, we catch
maybe 50 percent of it.
That's conservative, because
there's just too many ways for
the inmates to bring stuff in.
(Janet) With open cells and
thousands of hiding places,
finding contraband seemed
hopless.
The ISU wanted to show
me the newest trend in prison
contraband.
An item that was showing up in
prisons across the country.
>>These three bags are from
December of '08.
And this is just a portion of
what we found that month.
This isn't everything.
>>Now if you look at this
photograph, this was one
seizure.
You see all the cellphones?
They had them all individually
marked up in little packages,
they had little initials, as to
who was getting what.
>>Oh.
So it was already pre-sold.
>>It was all ready to go.
Somebody had already purchased
this phone.
Different various types cell
phones, from low end to high
type cell phones.
From little what we call throw
down, throw away phones up to
the Blackberrys, the iPhones.
>>The new Blackberry.
These just came out so...
>>Here's a Blackberry.
>>What is that?
The Storm?
>>Yeah, that's what I got.
Do you have any idea what this
stuff is going for?
>>Sure, the low end phones,
they're going for now, three
to five hundred, because the
more we apprehend the stuff,
price and demand of course goes
up.
The higher end cell phones
you're looking at $1000-
$1500 depending on like
Blackberry, iPhone.
If it's camera capability, it's
about five to seven hundred.
>>This one here is the newest
Blackberry Touch, I think
it's called the Storm.
>>That just came out
a couple months ago.
>>Yeah, they're very expensive
just to buy, so...
They'll alter their books and
they'll put their cell phones
in there, chargers.
You open it up and it look like
a soup, however.
This is how ingenious these guys
have gotten.
You open this up and there's a
cellphone.
Get the bars of soap out.
There's a...there ya go.
Hollowed out for a cellphone.
>>They'll get DVD players, and
movies, and they'll rent it
out to this guy over here for an
hour or so.
Different movies.
All recent titles.
A lot of it porn.
>>It's an all male facility.
>>There's a market.
>>There was a guy that was
conducting a little video
rental.
He had a sheet of paper of
videos that he had, and he'd
give it to his other
homeboys, "here you go," and it
was a rental.
The same guy that owned that
iPhone too.
Didn't have a job, but you
looked inside his locker, and he
had food and shoes, and he was
just hooked up.
>>Charging?
We'll show you what happens
with that.
When they get the charger, the
first thing they do is modify
it.
>>This is a cell phone charger
with the housing broke off of
it.
That's what you have left, a
little circuit board.
They open up their radios.
They graft it in.
They wire it in.
And they put another headphone
jack.
And now that's all they need
to charge their phones.
>>Who are they calling?
What are the pictures of?
>>Well, a lot of them are
calling loved ones.
The girlfriend.
A lot of them are using it for
their illegal clandestine
business of orchestrating more
contraband drops.
Narcotics drops.
Doing business, not just here at
this institution, but up and
down the state with other
instutitions.
We have inmates
who are coordinating
escapes.
May 4, we had an escape, walk
away from the institution,
inmate had cell phone.
Inmate had a cell phone, was
able to coordinate with somebody
out on the street, and they
picked him up in the city of
Avenal within half an hour of
him leaving the institution.
They're coordinating drug drops
Gangs can conduct their business
now, they can conduct assaults,
murder.
And there's no way to detect
it because they've got a cell
phone.
(Janet) I felt like I understood
the dangers of having cell
phones from the officer's
perspective.
But I was curious to hear what
inmates think of the ban.
I was surprised to hear
that you're not allowed to
have cell phones.
>>You were surprised to
hear that?
>>We love the internet.
>>Phone's down there, but
you're gonna pay
five, ten dollars a call
Do you think cell phones should
be allowed in prison?
>>Personally yes.
I don't think it's a major
problem, just being honest with
you, you know.
It would save my momma a whole
bunch of money on collect calls,
just for one.
I guess people can make phone
calls that are unmonitored and
make threats or what have you.
But the same thing can be done
anyway.
If somebody was trying to get
something done to somebody, they
can do it.
There's no limit to it.
There's no stopping it
actually.
So I don't think cell phones
add to that or subtract from
that.
>>What about cell phones?
Were cell phones around--
>No, no.
There wasn't no thing
like cell phones when
I went to jail.
>>Have you ever used a
cell phone?
>>No, I don't even know how
to use it.
I never even heard or seen them
so I don't know what they are.
Welcome back to our
look at contraband in
prisons.
So far you've seen how
difficult it is to keep
contraband such as
weapons, drugs, and
cell phones out of prisons,
no matter how secure
they may seem.
How do officers in prisons
actually discover this
contraband?
Contributor Janet Choi
finds out.
(Janet) California State Prison
Solano, in Vacaville, CA, is a
three hour drive from Avenal
prison.
I travelled to Solano because I
was curious to see how other
prisons were dealing with
contraband.
Cell phones off.
I was especially curious whether
cell phones were showing up in
the prison population.
>>Right there's just about
1,800 phones.
(Janet) They were.
Wow.
I haven't seen one of those
before.
I think Armani would probably be
a little disappointed.
>>This was in-- He had this one
secreted in his anal cavity.
>>What's the word for that?.
Kavitzing?
What's the word?
(producer) Keister.
>>Keistering.
[laughs].
>>Keister.
Yes, he had it keistered.
>>How do you find that?
>>Pardon me?
>>Sometimes when we do a full
body search, and the way
that's done is they have to
bend and squat and spread their
cheeks, and if you don't have
enough light, you use a
flashlight and shine it on their
anal area.
A lot times you can see, let's
say maybe this was a string that
was tied around this for him to
get ahold of pull out, so you
look for something that really
shouldn't be there.
>>Right.
>>Or if it's got moisture
around it, maybe as you would
use a lotion or something like
that, or a glistening.
Sometimes you ask them to give
it up and they will.
We had one guy who basically
couldn't, and so he had to go
out to the hospital, and they
had to give him a little help in
removing it.
There are some things
that I can't force you to do.
>>Can't use my grandmother's
method and rub your
belly for a while.
(Janet) I had been impressed by
the ingenuity of the inmates in
Avenal.
I asked if the inmates here had
any tricks.
>>Remove this.
And you can see where he has
this circuit board installed
here, that he's added to the
fan motor.
And there's another wire
coming out the back.
And if you turn it around, you
can see where he's added thatu
circuit board to basically
connect this charger that leads
to the cell phone.
We've been finding these quite
often now.
This is probably the eighth or
ninth fan we've found like
this.
(Janet) Cell phone's have
become a necessity for the
outside world, but I was curious
why the prisoners were going to
such lengths to have them
on the inside.
Prison...you either adapt
or you don't.
I'm in a cell, you're looking
at maybe 12 hours a day,
maybe longer.
You don't understand how
lonely prison can be.
>>I miss, social life, being
with...with significant others.
I miss being with my family.
>>Do you have visitors that come
and visit you?
>>Of course, I've been married
three times.
>>You have?.
But you've been here for nine
years?
>>19.?
I've been down for 19 years,
married three times.
>>So you what you're saying is
you knew all these women before
you came in here.
>>Not necessarily.
I mean I put an ad in one time
in the Sacramento Bee.
And that's how I met my first
wife.
>>Wow.
>>And then you have people on
the internet.
Things are different, times have
changed.
And I'm about to get married
again...maybe.
(Janet) Inmates were
reluctant to talk about
contraband, fearing
retaliation from the gangs.
As silly as it seems, we're
forced to use code words.
If you wanted to get a
certain type of cereal that
wasn't in the catalog, you'd
be able to get it?
>>If I really wanted a cell
phone and I had the money
to buy it, I'd probably go
get it.
>>How?
>>You could proabably bring
it in.
If the money's right, she's
probably willing to do it.
Now, you wonder how I'm
able to meet people, that's just
one sure way of doing it.
If it comes down to that.
(Janet) Talking to this inmate I
understood perhaps the biggest
allure of cellphones.
They were a way off the yard.
If only for a moment.
(producer) Want to show us your
whistle?
>>So, hopefully, I won't have
to use this thing.
This whistle is in case I find
myself in trouble.
In a typical cell, what are you
looking for?
>>In this case, we're looking
for any kind of contraband.
Could be weapons, could be
drugs, could be drug
paraphernalia, could be cell
phones.
Could be any type of article
that they can't have.
And where we're looking is
virtually any area inside the
cell.
Common areas are their books.
Inside their coffee pots.
Under the lids of the toilets,
and some of their hiding places
now, as I was telling you
before, could be behind these
safe plates.
Because...you see these gouges?
They could have twisted this,
gotten behind there and put cell
phones there.
>>Just got a paper clip.
So this toilet is empty.
Come inside here.
Come all the way in.
They've actually figured out a
way to remove these rivets off
these doors.
And this door's hollow.
So once they remove these
rivets, they could basically pry
that plate off, right?
And we've found when they need
to access it, they just pull it
off, and they have their
contraband tied to a string, at
the bottom of the door.
(Janet) Wow, it's hard to breath
in here.
It's hot; I'm sweating.
There's no open windows
in there.
>>This is pretty much a staple
food.
>>Good old ramen noodles.
College food.
>>Yeah.
It's cheap.
Filling.
They'll have like a hundred of
these things in a bag, and
usually the one at the bottom is
the one with the contraband.
(producer) Is this guy an
affluent inmate, because he has
all this stuff?,
>>This isn't anything.
Some of these have, five, six,
seven, eight bags of canteen.
Typically, if they have a lot of
canteen, it's typically a sign
that he's involved in some
kind of illegal activity.
Maybe drug related.
Maybe cell phone related.
But he's being paid.
This is their source of payment,
too.
They use that to pay off debts.
These guys bet in here too.
They bet on college teams.
They bet on sports teams.
This is the money.
(Janet) It takes an hour or so
to search a single cell which
makes the battle against
contraband seem hard to win.
But then Officer Medina found
something.
>>He has a phone in here
somewhere.
>>Why do you say that?
>>He has an alternate AC
adaptor.
You can tell that it's been
added on there.
See where it's cut?
So that, more than likely, fits
a phone.
>>How do you know it's in here
and not on him?
>>It could be.?
He could have it walking around
on the yard.
Or it could be in here.
Just have to find it.
(producer) But the AC adaptor is
contraband?
>>Now that it's been altered.
Yeah, it's contraband.
When you find something like
that, you tend to step it up a
bit.
Now you want to find it.
So the next step is to go find
him.
Or he could have passed it off
to one of the homeboys also.
It's like finding a needle in
a haystack at this point.
Well, we got beat this time.
Sometimes you win, sometimes you
lose.
>>We leave a receipt, letting
the inmate know, these things
have been confiscated.
>>That's rather considerate.
>>Oh yeah.
Are you going to show him that
you have the adapter?
>>Yeah, I believe this is the
inmate here, those two guys.
>>That's my cellies.
>>That's your cellies?
OK.
I'll leave you a receipt for
the search.
What I like to do is, uh, let
the inmate know what I took.
Why I took it.
So that's what I did.
(Janet) Solano State Prison is
designed to hold 2,610
prisoners.
It currently holds 6,047.
I was inside California State
Prison Solano to investigate
contraband in prison.
In my search I had been
surprised to see how many
things the prisoners were
allowed to have.
We're standing in front of the
canteen.
This is where inmates can buy
stuff off of a list.
It's where money can be useful.
So on this list you have
everything from brown rice, to
razors, to TV adaptors.
Is there anything they don't
have that you wish that they
had?
>>There's a lot things I wish
they had like shrimp.
Clams and stuff.
But we have to get them from
quarterly packages.
But other than that, they have
most of the stuff that I eat
anyway, you know.
Sausages, doughnuts, lollipops.
A lot of sweets.
I already have food from
yesterday.
>>You got a sweet tooth.
>> OK, then can I please get,
uh, ten more sausages?
>>Ten more sausages?
>>You're going to eat all that
sausage by yourself?
>>Yeah.
I'll eat it, but over a period
of time.
>>The Prisoner passed out
popsicles to his friends on the
yard.
At first I thought he was
simply being nice, but I
recalled in here, food is
money.
Was this a friendly gesture, or
payback for a debt?
I found this inmate listening
to a walkman.
>>Is there any stuff you wish
you can have that you wish you
did have?
>>DVD players.
>>You miss DVDs.
>>Yeah, we don't get DVD
players.
Wish we had that, though.
That'd be cool.
I'll give it to them.
They played "The Spirit."
You seen "The Spirit?"
>>Uh-uh.
>>It's a new movie out.
They played that on Channel 7.
It's like a movie channel for
the prisoners, all across the
prisons, Channel 7.
You know what I mean?
>>Popcicles, dominos, walkmen.
They had it pretty good.
But like all things in here,
the truth is not on the
surface.
[beeping]
[woman talking on the
loudspeaker]
>>An alarm went
off in one of the buildings.
So that's why if you look
around, everybody is seated
right now.
It was a false activation.
>>I had been told that violence
and contraband are intimately
linked, and nearly all violence
is sanctioned by the gangs.
>>If you look in the yard, you
can start to see how the
prisons are segregated.
In this corner, you can see the
Southern Hispanics, on the
other side, on the other side
you can see the blacks and the
Northern Hispanics and whites
over here.
(lead officer) If you look at
these two gentlemen over here
on this bench that just sat
down with the baseball hats on.
They're Nortenos, and that's
where they're supposed to be
when yard opens up.
That's their post, that's their
bench.
And they stay there.
Now the rest of the Nortenos
will walk the yard.
And like Officer Sandoval said,
they'll count.
They'll count the other
factions out on the yard, and
they'll let everybody know,
okay, this is the number we
have out here on the blacks,
this is what we have on the
Surenos, on the whites, and so
on.
And then they'll adjust their
yard activity, and they'll post
up on various areas of the yard
and they watch for us walking
on the yard also and they'll
give little cues to each other.
And if they see us coming down
the run here he may take off
his hat and put it on backwards
he may scratch his head,
something to signal everybody
else on the yard that the
squads coming on the yard, and
all that illegal activity tends
to stop.
They don't like us out here.
(Janet) With so many different
gangs, sharing the yard at the
same time, violence seemed
inevitable.
Part of the ISU's job is to
keep prison weapons off the
yard.
>>Sandoval is probably looking
for weapons as we speak.
There he is see him over there
by building nine?
>>Oh yeah.
>>He's got a nose like a dog's
have it for drugs.
He's got a nose for weapons.
>>What do you find knives?
>>Oh yeah, lots of knives.
Usually knives in here.
Rods.
Or flat stock.
Sharpened up, handles ready to
go.
Look at this.
But if there had been something
there, they might have been,
they might have moved it
already.
(Janet) How often do you find
stuff out here?
>>Um, sometimes you'll find
like three or four a day,
you can find weapons
buried all over.
You can find them buried around
their exercise areas.
They have one guy responsible
for doing that.
To hide the weapons out here.
If the time comes that they
want to stab somebody or going
to use the weapon, that one
person will tell them, go here,
it's right there, go pick it
up, take it, and use it.
So if they order a guy to go
hit somebody, they'll tell him
where to go get the knife from.
Sometimes I get lucky sometimes
I don't.
(Janet) Prison gangs are
organized.
But they are so closely
monitored I wondered how they
taught each other their codes
of conduct.
Sgt.
Sandoval introduced me to
wheelas.
What do you call it?
Wheelas?
>>Wheelas.
They are called basement
filters.
This one is an address min.
Proper new arrival seating.
They even tell their new
arrival inmates, where to sit.
How to do an assault, to how to
set up weapons.
Everything.
>>Who's on their hit list,
who's good, who's bad, who's
running what yard, who's
running what institution.
>>It's...
what?
It's like eight lines of text
the size of my fingernail.
Nortenos recognize the true
purpose of our struggle in a
close knit raza, let us be the
enlightenment and inspiration
to those behind the walls and
stand victim to the prejudice
and movement of the misused.
It does remind me of high
school, when, not that I ever
did it, but what other students
would do.
>>Now, when they get done
writing this, they roll it up,
roll it up, roll it up until
they get a bindle about that
big around, about that long,
and then they hide it.
>>So they walk in, they go to
the bathroom, they pull a
string or whatever it is?
>>Or just catch it in their
hand.
>>And they pass them out?
>>What he'll do, he'll pass it
off to another guy.
He'll wash it off, and then the
other guy will wrap it in
another glove, or some more
cellophane, and he'll put it up
his, and so on and so on.
>>Oh my gosh.
I had not idea that there was
movement.
>>The pass it.
They pass it off.
It goes from Point A, all the
way to Point Z, Z being the
main man.
He collects all of that.
>>And a little more.
>>But by the time it gets to
him, it's been in 20 other
rectums.
Honestly.
It happens that way.
I've got thousands of these.
It has all their information.
See this.
How to make a weapon.
>>Wow.
>>Tells you detailed
instructions on how to make
one.
>>These are both instructions.
This is obviously some kind of
stabbing ...
It says, Final Product.
Wow.
These are bigger than the ones
we saw yesterday.
>>They have the machine that
cuts these.
Some of these guys will be up
there and they'll cut them, and
then hide them, and then throw
them over the fence, or
[keister them, and bring them
down the hill.
>>You say that if that's so
natural, to put a knife.
>>To these guys, it is.
>>They do that every day.
>>Drugs.
>>Cell phones.
>>How is that even physically
possible?
>> What he'll do is he'll wrap
it with a sheet.
When it goes up, he doesn't
puncture himself.
And we've had instances where
the inmate has gone to the
staff and said, I need to go to
the doctor, I'm having
problems.
Well, what's wrong?
I think my weapon is stuck up
there and I can't get it out.
Yeah.
And he'll be in pain, because
it punctured his intestine and
he couldn't get it out.
>> Or, you know, they walk
around with them, and used to
walking, then all of a sudden,
the yard has to get down, and
they have to get down, quick,
and it can puncture them that
way.
>>Right.
>>I had a guy tell me that he
needed to go to the doctor.
What's the matter?
He was in his cell, and it
wasn't a weapon.
He was just seeing how many
pencils he could keister.
Why are you doing that?
Well, I just want to see how
many I can get up there.
>>I was still curious.
Besides weapons that were made
on the yard, how does
contraband get into the prison.
I was told the visitors room
was another entry point.
I asked for a tour.
>>Hello, we're going to go
through the court into the
visiting room, OK?
It's really open.
I pictured like a glass window
You can give them, hand over
all kinds of stuff right?
>>Yeah?
>>That's why I was so confused.
I couldn't figure out, how are
visitors, how can you pass
things through the glass.
>>Contact visiting.
It's contact visiting, so.
Like say you were here visiting
somebody and that person, as
long as we have them.
The tables are low for a
reason.
>>Right.
So you can't hand anything
underneath.
>>Because if it was up here
then we couldn't monitor really
what was going on under the
table.
>>You can have up to 250 people
in this room, and how many
people would be monitoring
them?
We have two officers that are
on the floor.
Actually one is up on the
podium, we have a monitoring
system up there.
And one is monitoring the
cameras that are all over the
visiting room.
They're all over the room.
And an officer stays up there
to do that.
And then one is constantly
roving the visiting room.
>> What percentage gets in
through visitors?
>> Mostly what gets in through
visiting in going to be drugs.
The balloons.
So what I'll do, because
there's a lot of people in the
visiting room, I will open
this.
I'm over there by the machine.
If I came in with something
inserted in my body, I would go
into the bathroom, okay, take
it out, put it in my pocket,
and then come in here, and go
over here, or we've actually
seen it on video where they're
sitting here and they're kind
of like this and they'll take
it out of their pocket and drop
it in here.
OK?
And then I hand it to you, and
as you're eating your chips,
OK, you'll eat a couple of
chips, and then you'll go like
this, and then you'll start
putting balloons in there and
swallowing them.
Not too many cell phones,
because they're harder to get
from here, from wherever she
has it into here, into ...
Because it's easier to insert
rectally than it is to swallow.
But we've actually had inmates
that will actually take
something out of here if it's
too big to swallow, and they'll
actually kind of go like this
and sit there and the next
thing you know and then on the
video you see them go "oop!"
well, we know what that is.
Day three without a cell phone.
All right ready to go.
>>For the first time, Solano
State prison was allowing a
documentary crew to film its
officers searching for
contraband.
So far they had found a cell
phone charger, but no phones.
The prisoners were skilled at
keeping their valuables hidden.
>>Alright.
>> Solano was showing off their
newest weapon.
Meet Caesar, the cell phone
sniffing dog.
Is he friendly?
Very friendly, he's not an
attack ranger, very friendly.
>>Hi!
Oh you gave me a kiss.
This early in the morning.
Hi!
Sweetie.
>>Do you want to play ballie?
Want your ball?
>>Officer Conrad offered to
give us a demonstration of
Caesar's talents.
>>Go find it.
What's in there?
See the cell phone?
On the bottom.
>>Oh yeah.
>>Oh yeah, that's a good boy.
What do we got in there, we got
something?
>>So he thinks he's looking for
that toy?
>>Just a piece of canvas.
Just his toy.
That's all it is.
>>And he thinks he's looking
for that?
>>Yeah.
>>So what do you do?
Rub a bunch of cellphones onto
the toy?
>>Actually what we do is take
it in its beginning of it's
called transfer odor.
I'll take a big glass jar and
what I'll do is I'll take rags
and we permeate the odor into
them, roll em up, like this.
And just play throw toys.
And what we'll do is transfer
that odor into the real
substance.
In other words when I'm
searching I'll put his toy say
over here in a stack of boxes
and then a foot away I'll put
the substance we're looking
for.
And as he comes across he'll
hit on that, and then hit on
the real thing.
>>Got it.
>>Is there another one?
Let's go find it.
What you got in there?
What you got?
You got something?
Get it out of there!
There you go!
Let's see what you got.
(Janet) I was impressed by
Caesar.
And I wanted to see him in
action.
I joined the ISU for a random
cell phone sweep.
>> As soon as we hit the yard,
We've got to move right to
the building.
We can't stop.
We've got to go right there.
Because as soon as we hit the
yard all the
signals are going to go
up and everyone's going to
start getting alerted.
>>Sure.
I'll just follow you.
>>Just keep up.
(Janet) As soon as we hit the
yard the inmates began warning
the other inmates Listen for
all the woof woofs, they see
the dog coming.
>>There's the whistles.
>>Yeah, you hear the whistles.
The inmates alerting each other
that we're coming.
>>And now you start hearing the
toilets flushing.
It is difficult to hear on
camera, but dozens of toilets
are flushing at once.
>>Boy, no.
>>Caesar seemed really excited
but could not find a cell
phone.
>> Are there days where he's
off?
You know there are days.
It's like everything else.
Like now, at the beginning,
he was so energetic.
He's been sitting in the car
for an hour, and what happens
is he's got so much energy
built up.
When you see him, he starts
biting on stuff, he's
frustrated.
He just searched that over
there by the desk in the
corner.
>>Did you snoop through your
brother and sister's things
when you were a kid?
>>No.
Well, I can't say that.
I had two older sisters and I
tended to look through their
drawers.
Read their diary a few times.
>>[laughs]
>>More than likely
he has a cell phone.
>>Phone numbers.
>>He's got phone numbers.
1-87--
1-877-476-BLOW.
>>You learn from the clothes.
Presence of the odor is still
there.
Same thing as something like
this.
We'll just keep our eye on it.
>>The warning system, whistling
and barking, had worked.
The ISU found nothing beside a
list of pornographic phone
numbers.
At that moment, Officer
Sandoval came up to tell us
that he'd just found something
in the first cell that we were
in.
It was above the area Caesar
could search.
It turned out Caesar had been
right..
>>It was right in here.
>>Wow.
Looks like a part of the radio.
>>Yeah, it does.
It blends right in....
So we'll process it as
evidence.
The inmate who lives in this
rack will get a 115, a rule
violation report.
He'll probably get another
phone within a couple of weeks.
>>Did you try turning it on?
More than likely, what they do,
so we can't access the
information, cause this one
feels kind of light, he removed
the battery.