One of the best rock
climbers in the entire world
just did something that
is so terrifying you
have to see it to believe.
This is Alex Honnold free
climbing a 1,500 foot rock
wall in Mexico.
That means by himself.
No safety gear.
And it's already got
over 4,000 years.
Nobody has ever climbed this
wall in this way ever before.
Alex holds a bunch
of speed records,
including one for the
Yosemite Triple Crown.
That is three famously
difficult climbs
and he did them
in under 19 hours.
If that didn't stop your heart,
we got a playlist for you
right after the show
they just might.
LIZZIE: Want to know why Gravity
is up for 10 Academy Award
nominations but don't
have 90 minutes to spare?
Here's a 60 second version.
Israeli animator Leigh Lahav
just released this entry
for Jameson's annual Done
in 60 Seconds competition.
CARTOON GEORGE CLOONEY: Have
I told you about the time--
CARTOON SANDRA BULLOCK: Oh my
god, oh my god, oh my god, oh
my god!
How did you?
CARTOON GEORGE CLOONEY:
It doesn't matter.
What matters now is that
we always stick together.
Always!
CARTOON SANDRA
BULLOCK: My movie!
CARTOON GEORGE
CLOONEY: You bitch!
LIZZIE: Lee's been
posting for nine months,
and she's already won the
hearts of nearly 80,000 people,
myself included.
JACOB SOBOROFF: What
would a car look
like if it was built
for a goldfish?
You don't have to
wonder anymore.
This is all over the
science blogs right now.
A camera uses image
recognition software
and it allows the fish to steer.
We've playlisted more
unnecessary robotic inventions
for you after the show, and
they're all completely awesome.
EARNEST: I'll never
forget the day
that I saw my first DeLorean.
Norman, Oklahoma.
The year 2003.
RegularCar reviews
is know for giving
straightforward
critiques of everything
from Saturns to Subarus.
This time he gets to check
out everyone's dream car.
REGULARCARS GUYS:
We're not worthy!
This is the first Delorean
I've ever touched,
and I'm still driving it.
Uh!
EARNEST: You can find more
great reviews on his channel,
including a particularly
illuminating look
at the legendary
1991 Nissan Stanza.
JACOB SOBOROFF: Two days to
Valentine's Day, and love
is in the air.
It is time for some
video love notes,
or what we like to
call YouTube Crush.
MC: It's a YouTube Crush!
Kick the bass!
Ha!
ALI: My biggest YouTube crush
is Amy Poehler's Smart Girls.
It's a celebration of
extraordinary individuals
who are changing the
world by being themselves.
AMY POEHLER: Feminism.
You know what it is, right?
GIRL: Yep.
I think boys and girls
are of equal value.
That means that if a boy
can do the monkey rings,
so can a girl.
ALI: They have a few web
series including Ask Amy, where
Amy Poehler herself gives
really wonderful advice.
AMY POEHLER: Opening your
heart, and being courageous,
and telling people you care
about them or like them-- that
only attracts more
love in your life.
ALI: Amy, will you
be my Valentine?
MC: YouTube crush!
Ha!
JACOB SOBOROFF: We'll be
rolling out some more video love
notes from very special
the rest of the week,
and we want you to
be a part of it.
Make a video of yourself telling
us who your YouTube crush is,
and then post it with the
hashtag #youtubecrush.
MC: Because you have
a YouTube crush!
JACOB SOBOROFF: You guys
have been sending us
so many great videos.
Here's one from our
friend Paul Dateh.
PAUL DATEH: If you
were lucky enough
to download Flappy Bird from
the app store before was pulled,
you may very well be obsessed
with this simple yet addicting
game.
Luckily your friend over
at Dumb Stupid videos
has the best strategy
for beating it outright.
See, right there?
JACOB SOBOROFF: One, two.
Ah!
Even though you
can't get it anymore,
Flappy Bird mania
is in full effect.
That video got over 10 million
views in one week alone.
Until tomorrow, links are below.
Playlists are coming up.
Hit that subscribe button.
And we want to hear
your YouTube crush.
Post a video using the
hashtag #youtubecrush.
Now play us out,
Y-Titty and MC Fitti.
[MUSIC PLAYING: "#HASHTAG" BY
Y-TITTY]