It's pretty much
a pot festival.
It goes for a couple of days.
This is a Friday.
It's about to start.
Usually, Nimbin only has a
couple of hundred residents in
it, but over the weekend,
there's expected to be 10,000
to 12,000 people here.
It's pretty weird already.
And apparently, it's going
to get even weirder.
[FOLK MUSIC PLAYING]
-That's the official gong.
HANNAH BROOKS: Nimbin's a
country town in the hills of
eastern Australia.
And it's known worldwide as
the center of Australian
cannabis culture.
Unlike the rest of the country,
which prides itself
on its pubs and beer, it's
almost impossible to get a
drink in Nimbin.
But pot smoking is encouraged
in everywhere.
It's a big reputation for
small, one street town.
I'd heard how easy it is to
score drugs in Nimbin.
And as soon as I arrived, I
was offered weed, hash,
cookies, mushrooms, and acid.
But the old hippies who run
the town hate the street
dealers, particularly the ones
selling harder drugs like
heroin and ice.
-Welcome to Nimbin.
And remember, don't panic.
Because it's organic.
HANNAH BROOKS: OK.
And so what exactly are you?
-I'm called The Plantom.
And he's the mascot for
the MardiGrass.
It's a spoof character
from the phantom.
Instead of the phantom,
there's The Plantom.
Because the quicker you learn
how to plant them, you won't
have to buy any off the dickhead
across the road,
you'll have your own.
HANNAH BROOKS: Recently, some
locals made an effort to clean
up the town's reputation and set
up the Hemp Bar, which is
a place where you can
buy and smoke weed.
It's tiny and full of people
getting stoned, even though
the police station is just
around the corner.
They said we could
film anything
there, except the dealer.
Hi, what's your name?
DAVE CANNABIS: Dave Cannabis.
HANNAH BROOKS: And
what's your name?
BIG BONG: Big Bong.
HANNAH BROOKS: And what
are you doing here?
DAVE CANNABIS: We're doing a
webcast of the MardiGrass.
BIG BONG: We're actually in year
seven of what's called
the Reefer Madness De-creation
Demonstration, where people
and governments from all over
earth can see people using
cannabis and see that it doesn't
turn them into an
insane, ravenous beast
that's going to jump
down and kill them.
HANNAH BROOKS: We arrived
just before 4:20.
DAVE CANNABIS: 42 seconds!
HANNAH BROOKS: When every day,
they light a massive joint to
exercise their right
to smoke weed.
DAVE CANNABIS: 4.20 seconds.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
DAVE CANNABIS: 4:20!
[COUGHING]
DAVE CANNABIS: [INAUDIBLE]
BIG BONG: Every day for many,
many years now, we've been
doing this, day in, day out.
-God, that's smooth isn't it?
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
BIG BONG: So that's the thing.
At 4:20, think peace for
pot and pot for peace.
HANNAH BROOKS: It's Friday.
We haven't done that
much today.
We got out of bed a bit
later, had our break--
what?
I'm stoned.
It's Saturday, apparently.
We've realized that Nimbin time
runs different to the
rest of Australia.
It's very slow, because
everyone's fucking
stoned all the time.
Nothing's run on schedule.
No one knows where anything is,
and there's no one to ask.
We went to the Festival Office,
and they told us to
smoke a joint and relax.
So we did and then got talking
to some of the locals, like
The Goddess.
And so why are you The
Goddess, may I ask?
THE GODDESS: Well,
yeah, I channel.
HANNAH BROOKS: You channel?
THE GODDESS: I channel.
HANNAH BROOKS: Where
do you live?
THE GODDESS: In Heaven.
I hang out with Jesus and
Muhammad and those guys.
HANNAH BROOKS: What does
The Goddess do?
THE GODDESS: All the
ceremonies--
baptisms, weddings, exorcisms.
HANNAH BROOKS: The Goddess runs
the Church of the Holy
Smoke, which is faith that
promotes the use of cannabis.
He's trying to get it officially
recognized as a
religion and holds services at
the Hemp Bar every Friday,
where he lights a joint with a
burning hundred dollar note.
So do people officially call
themselves married to the
Church of the Holy Smoke?
THE GODDESS: Yes, married.
HANNAH BROOKS: Do you
want to marry all
of us into the church?
Can you explain what that is?
THE GODDESS: Technical
term is God has come.
And it's used in the sacred
marriage ceremony.
HANNAH BROOKS: What
does it involve?
THE GODDESS: I just rub a little
bit of sacred ointment
on their forehead and
join them, make them
one with the church.
That's beautiful girls!
You've got a [INAUDIBLE]
magazine called Vice.
-I love it.
THE GODDESS: Couldn't
we get into that?
-I love it.
THE GODDESS: I reckon
I could write them a
story straight away.
-Every last one of us is mad--
not that we all admit it.
And in fact, it goes
way beyond Nimbin.
But if you're a bit madder
than the other mad
ones, you come here.
You'll fit in.
The saner that you are, the less
likely you are to fit in.
So behind all this MardiGrass
and the smoking--
behind that, are people
who keep it
together, who don't smoke.
And if they have a drink, it
would be in moderation.
HANNAH BROOKS: Somehow the
stoners and the straight
people coexist.
The stoners need the straight
people to provide essential
services that make the
town function.
And the straight people need
the stoners, because weed
keeps the town's
economy alive.
Everything in Nimbin, in
one way or another,
runs on green money.
[FOLK MUSIC]
HANNAH BROOKS: Nimbin was once
a quiet, country town with a
thriving timber and
dairy industry.
But in the early 1970s, Nimbin
hit hard times and was almost
a ghost town.
In 1973, a bunch of hippies,
attracted by the cheap
infrastructure and beautiful
landscape, came to Nimbin and
held the Aquarius Festival.
Many of them stayed and set
up communes and sought to
establish a new type
of society.
The hills surrounding the area
also made it the perfect place
to grow lots of weed.
Nimbin and cannabis quickly
became synonymous.
However, since it's illegal to
grow, sell, and smoke weed in
Australia, there are always
going to be problems.
15 years ago, some locals held
a protest to highlight what
they saw as the stupidity
of the drug laws.
This became a tradition and over
the years, turned into
what is now known
as MardiGrasss.
-A group of people march down
the street with a big joint,
went into the police grounds of
the police station, made a
lot of noise and hoo-hah.
And there was a collection
of local people.
The next year, they decided to
try and attract more people.
And it sort of went
on from there.
As the people arrived, peoples
thought, oh, well we better
start creating other things
to attract them.
And out of that came the
Hemp Olympics and
all the other events.
-Take this Johnny!
-And the yell was, "Take this
Johnny." -Fly bong!
Fly!
-"Fly bong!
Fly!" was the yell.
And a nice powerful throw trying
to cut underneath the
oncoming breeze.
HANNAH BROOKS: I'm a
little bit nervous.
I don't know whether to
go over or under arm.
[INAUDIBLE]
HANNAH BROOKS: I am.
-What's your name?
HANNAH BROOKS: My
name's Hannah.
-And Hannah, where
are you from?
HANNAH BROOKS: Melbourne.
Free the weed!
-"Free the weed,"
was the yell.
[APPLAUSE]
-That was a throw
of 13 meters.
-13 meters for Hannah.
[FESTIVAL DRUMS AND MUSIC]
-The purpose was protest
the drug laws.
There was a realization that
our youth were being
incarcerated, that health
issues were not being
addressed because of the
criminalization.
-Cannabis law reform.
The law ain't working.
[FESTIVAL DRUMS AND MUSIC]
-Hello, how are you going?
HANNAH BROOKS: Good day.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
HANNAH BROOKS: Sure.
What are you checking for?
-Drugs with the dog.
HANNAH BROOKS: Yeah.
-[INAUDIBLE] for the drug dog.
And just run a breath
test, as well.
HANNAH BROOKS: There was quite
a few police here last year
last year, is that correct?
-That's correct.
There was a substantial number
of police last year.
HANNAH BROOKS: And
why was that?
-Given the nature and the size
of this particular event, we
wanted to have adequate police
out here, just to ensure that
there was a safe environment.
There is a perception that when
MardiGrass is on that
certain activities involving
cannabis are legal, such as
the possession of,
administration of, or supply
of cannabis.
That is not the case.
If the police catch people in
possession of cannabis, if
they catch them supplying it, or
indeed, administering it--
in other words, smoking it--
they will be arrested.
And they will be charged.
-And your time starts now!
[INAUDIBLE]
[APPLAUSE]
HANNAH BROOKS: Instead, Nimbin
promotes its own kind of law.
It's got a street code that
stresses tolerance and self
and community respect.
The locals' disdain for the
law and the police that
enforce it is obvious.
While many cops do turn a blind
eye to it all, sometimes
they make token arrests.
And when they do, the locals
are always there
to police the police.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
-If you go out to the
cops with all
the M.U.N.C.H vehicles--
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
HANNAH BROOKS: With the
introduction of saliva testing
for drugs this year, the locals
set up the M.U.N.C.H
van, which follows the cops
around monitoring unfair
Nimbin cannabis hype.
THE GODDESS: We had the media
down in Pete's Park, and we
had the testing kits.
And we tested them.
And they were all wrong--
100% wrong.
The people that smoked
didn't show.
The people that didn't
smoke did show.
The people that smoked
showed amphetamines.
People that took amphetamines
didn't show anything at all.
[FESTIVAL DRUMS AND MUSIC]
THE GODDESS: This year
it was great.
The cops stayed out of it.
They got the message.
Basically, it's a losing
deal for them.
They can't win.
HANNAH BROOKS: That
seems to be true.
While there were heaps of
police, they were outnumbered
by people smoking weed and
having a good time.
And that seemed to eliminate
any paranoia.
[TRIBAL MUSIC]
HANNAH BROOKS: It's a totally
grassroots kind of festival.
Half the scheduled events didn't
happen, and the ones
that did, ran hours late
and changed locations.
But no one seemed to notice.
And if they did, they were
way too stoned to care.
And everyone agreed
that this year's
MardiGrass was a success.
[FESTIVAL MUSIC]
HANNAH BROOKS: The people of
Nimbin see nothing wrong with
smoking weed.
And like Big Bong said,
weed doesn't turn you
into a crazy beast.
Hearing kids in Nimbin say,
"Happy MardiGrass," like they
say, "Merry Christmas," shows
that their efforts to
normalize pot are working.
THE GODDESS: Basically,
it's a normal thing.
Bring it back to that.
And I think yeah, it does.
I think it has done that.
Successful--
mission accomplished.
[INAUDIBLE]
[DRUMS]