THAT THE QUESTIONS ARE UP ON BSPACE. AND
THAT I WON'T PUT ANSWERS UP ANYTIME SOON.
SO THE INTENTION IS THAT YOU WILL TRY THE
QUESTIONS AND TALK ABOUT THEM WITH YOUR
COLLEAGUES AS A MEANS OF LEARNING ABOUT THEM.
ANY QUESTIONS ON COURSE LOGISTICS THAT I
CAN HELP YOU WITH NOW? YES. STUDENT: DO
YOU KNOW HOW LONG THE MIDTERM IS? PROFESSOR:
NO. THE MIDTERM IS 33 QUESTIONS. SHE ASKED
IF THAT'S HOW LONG THE MIDTERM IS. NO, THAT'S
NOT MEANT TO REFLECT THE MIDTERM IN ANYWAY.
THIS IS THE DANGER OF GIVING YOU GUYS PRACTICE
QUESTIONS. I DON'T THINK ALL THE INSTRUCTORS
WILL DO THAT BECAUSE STUDENTS TEND TO THINK
THIS IS WHAT THE MIDTERM IS LIKE. CAN'T PROMISE
THAT. HAVEN'T WRITTEN THE MIDTERM YET. I DON'T
KNOW WHAT THE MIDTERM IS GOING TO BE LIKE.
IT MIGHT BE A LOT HARDER. DON'T KNOW. BUT
IT'S IMPORTANT FOR YOU GUYS TO UNDERSTAND
WHAT A MULTIPLE CHOICE QUESTION IS LIKE
THAT I WRITE. I DIDN'T WRITE ALL THE ONES
I JUST GAVE YOU BUT I WROTE SOME OF THEM.
AND THEY ARE MUCH LIKE THE TYPES THAT YOU
WILL ASK YOU. BUT THEY COULD BE HARDER ON
THE TEXT. SO DON'T SLACK OFF, PLEASE. WHAT
ELSE? ANYTHING ELSE? OKAY. FEEL FREE TO
E-MAIL ME IF ANYTHING COMES UP THAT YOU NEED
ANSWERS TO. WE ARE CONTINUING TODAY WITH
ECOSYSTEM ECOLOGY. AND WE WILL FIRST
COVER SOME GEOLOGY REALLY. AS A MEANS OF UNDERSTANDING
THE  PHYSICAL BASIS FOR OBSERVED PATTERNS
ON A GLOBAL SCALE IN THE BIOTA IN BIOLOGICAL
COMMUNITIES AND ECOSYSTEMS. WE WILL REVIEW
THE TERRESTRIAL BIOMES OF THE WORLD  VERY
BRIEFLY. YOUR BOOK COVERS IT WELL. IN THE
CONTEXT OF GLOBAL PRECIPITATION AND TEMPERATURE
PATTERNS, CLIMOGRAPHS, WE WILL LOOK AT AQUATIC
BIOMES, FOCUSING ON THE PHYSICAL STRUCTURE
OF LAKES AND OCEANS. AND CONSIDER NUTRIENT
LIMITATION AND PRODUCTIVITY OF SUCH SYSTEMS.
AND THEN CONSIDER PRODUCTIVITY OF ECOSYSTEMS
ON A GLOBAL SCALE COMPARING BIOMES TO ONE
ANOTHER. WE, I PUT SOMETHING IN HERE ON DIVERSITY
GRADIENTS. AND THE CAUSES BEHIND HIGH TROPICAL
DIVERSITY. HOPEFULLY WE'LL GET TO SOMETHING
I HAVEN'T PUT IN BEFORE AND I WANT TO GET
TO DURING THE LECTURE CYCLE. I PUT IT IN BUT
I DIDN'T BULLET IT HERE. AND I'M NOT SURE
IF WE'LL GET TO HYDROLOGICAL AND BIOGEOCHEMICAL
CYCLES. IF WE DON'T I MAY JUST GIVE YOU
THE SLIDES AND ASK YOU TO REVIEW IT IN THE
BOOK BECAUSE I DON'T WANT TO GO INTO MUCH
MORE DETAIL THAN THE BOOK ALREADY PROVIDES.
ALL RIGHT. FOR SOME OF YOU THIS WILL BE REVIEW.
FOR OTHERS PERHAPS NOT. FOR EVERYONE THIS
IS OF INTEREST AND IMPORTANCE. BECAUSE YOU'RE
EARTHLINGS AND YOU ARE SUBJECT TO THESE FORCES
OF GLOBAL CLIMATE. AND MORE AND MORE PRESSING
ARE THESE FORCES WITH THE CHANGES THAT WE'RE
SEEING IN RECENT DECADES, RECENT CENTURIES
AS A RESULT OF HUMAN ACTIVITIES. THE FIRST
THING TO CONSIDER AND I WON'T REVIEW MUCH
HERE IS THE FACT THAT THE EARTH AS A RESULT
OF BEING SPHERICAL RECEIVES SOLAR ENERGY
WITH GREATER INTENSITY IN THE EQUATORIAL REGIONS
AS A RESULT OF MORE DIRECT STRIKE OF PHOTONS
IN THOSE REGIONS. THE SUN'S RAYS STRIKE
MORE OBLIQUELY TOWARD THE POLES AND THIS MEANS
LESS SOLAR INPUT. THE EARTH IS ALSO
TILTED ON ITS AXIS AND IT ORBITS THE SUN.
AS A RESULT WE HAVE OUR SEASONAL CYCLES.
DETAILS OF THAT PHYSICAL PROCESS ISN'T OF
IMPORTANCE BUT YOU CAN READ ABOUT IT IN THE
BOOK IF YOU WANT. IT'S NOT OF IMPORTANCE FOR
OUR PURPOSES. NOTE THAT BECAUSE OF THE INTENSITY
OF SOLAR ENERGY AT THE EQUATOR, THAT WATER
EVAPORATES IN THIS AREA AND AS THE AIR IS
HEATED IT RISES. UPON RISING THIS NOW MOIST
AIR RELEASES THAT MOISTURE, IT CONDENSES
OUT IN RAINS AND GENERATES OF PHENOMENON OF
THE HOT WET TROPICAL REGIONS. AS THE AIR
CONTINUES ITS ASCENT LOSING MOISTURE, IT
COOLS AND BECOME DENSER AND IT'S DRY AND IT
DESCENDS. NOTE WHERE WE ARE ON THE EARTH.
SOME 23 DEGREES NORTH LATITUDE HERE. BUT
THE SAME PHENOMENON IS HAPPENING IN THE
SOUTH OF THE EQUATOR. AND THIS DRY DESCENDING
AIR ABSORBS MOISTURE, ACTUALLY PULLS MOISTURE
FROM THE LAND AND OUT OF THE AIR. AND AS
A RESULT, THESE TEND TO BE VERY ARID REGIONS.
AND YOUR GREAT DESERTS OF THE WORLD ARE
INDEED SITUATED AT THESE LATITUDES, NORTH
AND SOUTH. THE ATACAMA DESERT, ONE OF DRYEST
PLACES ON THE EARTH. YOUR NORTH AMERICAN
GREAT SOUTHWESTERN DESERTS. THAT DRY AIR SOME
OF IT WILL THEN TRAVEL NORTHWARD. IT'S WARM,
IT'S GOING TO RISE. IT'S PICKING UP MOISTURE.
AND IT DROPS IT AGAIN IN THIS PART OF THE
WORLD. NOT AS MUCH AS IT'S DROPPED IN THE
TROPICS BUT STILL A LOT. THIS GENERATES
OF PHENOMENON OF OUR TEMPERED RAIN FORESTS
LIKE WE HAVE ON THE OLYMPIC PENINSULA SAY
IN THE WASHINGTON OR EVEN SOME AREAS OF CALIFORNIA
WHERE YOU GET VERY BIG TREES AND VERY DENSE
FORESTS WITH LUSH VEGETATION GROWTH AS A RESULT
OF THIS VERY PHENOMENON. SOMETHING SIMILAR
IS HAPPENING IN PATAGONIA IN SOUTHERN CHILE
AND ARGENTINA WITH THESE TEMPERATE
RAINFORESTS AS OPPOSED TO TROPICAL RAINFORESTS.
AND THEN FOLLOW YOU CAN FOLLOW IT FURTHER
THAT AIR, SOME OF THAT RISING AIR DESCENDS
NOW DRIED DESCENDS OVER THE POLES, DRY AIR
ABSORBING EVEN MORE MOISTURE. AND THE POLES
ARE QUITE DESICCATED AND COLD, OF COURSE.
SO WE CAN SEE FROM A SOLAR DRIVER AT THE
EQUATOR HOW MUCH CAN BE EXPLAINED ABOUT
NOT ONLY GLOBAL AIR CIRCULATION PATTERNS AND
PRECIPITATION BUT VEGETATION. ALSO VERY
COOL. THE DETAILS ARE NOT CRITICAL. I'LL
JUST HIGHLIGHT A FEW THINGS HERE THOUGH. THE
FACT THAT THE WARMING OF THE OCEAN SURFACES
AT THE EQUATOR AS A RESULT OF INTENSE SOLAR
ENERGY PRODUCES A NORTH CIRCULATING CURRENT
ON THE SURFACE WATERS, THE HOT AIR, THE
HOT WATER BEING AT THE SURFACE. IT COOLS AS
IT TRENDS NORTH. AND THAT COOL DENSER WATER
DIVES DEEP, THIS IS THE GULF STREAM, DIVES
DEEP AND CIRCULATES IN DEEP CHANNELS ALL
AROUND THE WORLD. AND THIS DEEP WATER MAY
REMAIN IN THESE CURRENTS FOR AS LONG AS
A THOUSAND YEARS OR MORE BEFORE IT MAKES
ITS WAY BACK TO THE SURFACE IN THE WARMER
WATER CONDITIONS. THESE, THIS INTERACTION
BETWEEN WARM AND COLD CURRENTS IN THIS AREA
PRODUCES A LOT OF FOG. AND SOMETHING RELATED
IS HAPPENING IN OUR AREA WITH THE FOG THAT
WE SEE HERE. THIS IS IN OUR AREA RELATED
PRIMARILY TO THE TEMPERATURE DEFERENTIAL BETWEEN
OUR OLD CURRENTS, THEY'RE SHOWN AS GETTING
WARMER, BUT THEY'RE STILL VERY COLD CURRENTS
THAT WE EXPERIENCE OFF OUR COAST. AND THE
INTERACTION OF THOSE COLD CURRENT WITH WARM
AIR MASSES IS IN PART RESPONSIBLE FOR THE
GENERATION OF FOG OVER OUR WATERS, OFF-SHORE
HERE.  NOW WITH THE GENERATION OF THIS
FOG, OVER THE OCEANS HERE, SOME OF IT'S
PULLED ONTO LANDS. SOME OF ITS PUSHED ONTO
LAND BY WINDS BEHIND IT, BUT SOME OF IT IS
PULLED ONTO LANDS AS A RESULT MUCH ACTION
OF WARM AIR OVER THE LAND RISING, THINK
OF HOW HOT IT GETS IN THE INTERIOR OF CALIFORNIA
OR IN THE HILLS OR JUST OVER THE HILLS HERE
IN SUMMERTIME. THIS WARM AIR IS RISING.
AND THE COOL AIR FROM THE OCEANS IS BEING
DRAWN IN TO REPLACE THAT WARM RISING AIR.
AND THERE'S OFTEN FOG IN THE SUMMERTIME
IN THAT AIR BEING PULLED ONTO LAND. SOMETIMES
WORKS IN CYCLES WHERE THAT AIR CONDITIONING
FOG COOLS THE AIR OVER THE LAND AND INTERRUPTS
THIS KIND OF CYCLE. SO HIGHLIGHTING THAT IN
RELATION TO THE FOG HERE. BUT THIS HAS A MODERATING
EFFECT ON CLIMATE IN COASTAL AREAS IN GENERAL
BECAUSE THE WARM LAND AIR IS GOING TO BE
REPLACED BY COOL MARINE AIR. AND THAT'S WHAT
MAKES THE COASTS MORE MODERATE IN THEIR
CLIMATES THAN AREAS INLAND. AND SOMETHING
SIMILAR IS HAPPENING OVER THE OCEANS THEMSELVES.
WHERE THE WARM AIR FROM THE LAND IS WARMING
UP THE COOL OCEANIC AIR. BUT LET'S LOOK
AT THIS FOG PHENOMENON BECAUSE IT'S ONE OF
THE REALLY INTERESTING CHARACTERISTICS OF
OUR POSITION RIGHT HERE ON EARTH. AND IT
HAS A GREAT EFFECT ON LOCAL ECOSYSTEMS AS
EVIDENCED BY RESEARCH CONDUCTED IN THIS
DEPARTMENT. IN RELATION TO THE VEGETATION
AND IN RELATION TO REDWOOD COMMUNITIES. LOOK
AT THE LEVELS OF FOG ACROSS THE YEAR. IT'S
REALLY FOGGY IN THE SUMMER, RIGHT? THAT'S
WHAT SAN FRANCISCO IS SO DARN COLD IN THE
SUMMER. BECAUSE OF THIS FOG. WE'VE HAD A
VERY FOGGY SUMMER, AT LEAST  THE EARLY
PART OF THIS SUMMER AND NOT MUCH SUNSHINE.
WHEN THESE FOG LEVELS ARE SO HIGH, LOOK
AT THE RAIN FALL. RAINFALL IS AT THE LOWEST
POINT AROUND THE SAME TIME THAT THE FOG PEAKS.
THINK OF THIS IN TERMS OF THE PLANTS AND
ORGANISMS NEED FOR WATER. HOW DO WE POSSIBLY
GET SUCH MASSIVE FORESTS GROWING IN THIS AREA
WHEN RAINFALL IS SO LOW DURING THE HOTTEST
TIMES OF THE YEAR? AS YOU MIGHT SUSPECT
IT'S RELATED TO THIS FOG. SOME OF THE RESEARCH
ON THIS IS JUST FABULOUS. DONE BY VARIOUS
TEAMS OF RESEARCHERS INCLUDING THE DAWSON
LAB, TODD DAWSON'S HERE. THESE ARE, THESE,
THE STUDY I'M GOING TO SHOW YOU IS A STUDY
IN ECOPHYSIOLOGY. AND THE DATA THAT THEY
RELY ON FOR UNTANGLING THIS PHENOMENON IS
THE SCIENCE OF BIOGEOCHEMISTRY INDUSTRY.
I HOPE YOU'LL INVESTIGATE IT FURTHER. I'LL
TALK MORE ABOUT BIOGEOCHEMISTRY NEXT WEEK.
HERE'S, SHOWING THE FOG OFF-SHORE. I MEAN
BURR. I HEARD ONE SAY IT'S LIKE A COZY BLANKET.
IF YOU THINK OF IT THAT WAY IT'S A LITTLE
MORE ACCEPTABLE.
IT CAN REALLY MAKE THINGS FRIGID THROUGHOUT
MUCH OF THE SUMMER. YOU DON'T NEED TO UNDERSTAND
ISOTOPE CHEMISTRY TO UNDERSTAND THIS IS
STUDY IN BIOGEOCHEMISTRY. JUST SKIP BACK TO
THAT REAL QUICK.
LOOK AT THAT WORD. BIO, LIGHT. RIGHT? GEO,
EARTH. CHEMISTRY, CHEMISTRY. SO BIOGEOCHEMISTRY
IS THE STUDY OF THIS KIND OF INTERACTIVE SYSTEM.
IT'S THE USE OF CHEMISTRY TO STUDY THE INTERACTION
BETWEEN LIFE AND EARTH. IT'S CHEMISTRY TO
STUDY LIVING ECOSYSTEMS. ECOPHYSIOLOGY,
PHYSIOLOGY RELATED TO THE ECOLOGY OF INDIVIDUAL
ORGANISMS IN THE CONTEXT OF LOCAL ECOSYSTEMS.
THESE ARE GREAT INTEGRATIVE FIELDS. AND
NO SURPRISE THAT THERE ARE THOSE IN THIS
DEPARTMENT IN INTEGRATIVE BIOLOGY WHO ARE
SUPERB IN THIS WORK. AS I SAID,  YOU
DON'T NEED TO UNDERSTAND ISOTOPES IN A CHEMICAL
SENSE TO UNDERSTAND THE WORD. JUST TO SAY
THAT ATOMIC ELEMENTS EXIST IN DIFFERENT
ISOTOPIC FORMS AS A RESULT OF DIFFERENCES
NEUTRONS IN THEIR NUCLEUS. SO ISOTOPE RATIO
IS THE RATIO OF A HEAVY ISOTOPE TO A LIGHT
ISOTOPE, IN THIS CASE HEAVY HYDROGEN TO
LIGHT HYDROGEN, DEUTERIUM TO HYDROGEN. BUT
JUST RECOGNIZE THAT THIS IS A QUANTIFICATION
OF ATOMIC NUCLEI IN RELATION TO THE WATER
IN FOG AND THE WATER IN RAINFALL. SO RAIN
WATER HERE AND FOG WATER HERE QUANTIFIED BY
THEIR HYDROGEN ISOTOPE RATIO. FOG WATER
IS VERY HEAVY IN HYDROGEN ISOTOPES. IT HAS
A LOT OF THE HEAVY ISOTOPE DEUTERIUM IN IT.
MUCH DIFFERENT FROM RAINFALL. NO OVERLAP.
THEY'RE COMPLETELY DISTINCT. WHEN YOU LOOK
AT VARIOUS PLANTS THAT GROW IN THE RAINFOREST
COMMUNITY INCLUDING, I'M SORRY, IN THE REDWOOD
COMMUNITY, INCLUDING REDWOODS THEMSELVES,
SEQUOIA SEMPERVIRENS, YOU SEE THAT THE WATER
INSIDE THESE PLANTS IS OF AN ISOTOPIC RATIO
BETWEEN THE FOG AND THE RAINFALL. AND THAT
IT CYCLES IN RELATION TO BOTH OVER THE COURSE
OF EACH YEAR. THESE BEING THE 12 MONTHS
IN THREE DIFFERENT YEARS. YOU CAN DO THE
MATH AND THE DETERMINE THAT ALMOST A THIRD
OF THE WATER USED BY THE PLANTS IN THESE
SYSTEMS IS COMING FROM FOG ITSELF. IT'S, THE
PLANTS, THE LEAVES ARE NOT DRINKING THE FOG
BUT THE FOG IS COLLECTING ON THE PLANTS
AND DRIPPING IN THE SOILS AND BEING CONSUMED
BY THE PLANTS. AND THAT'S FANTASTIC, THAT'S
REALLY COOL. THAT'S WHY YOU CAN GET SUCH
MAGNIFICENT FORESTS OF SUCH COMPLEXITY PROBABLY
IN THESE REGIONS AS A RESULT OF FOG INPUT
DURING THE DRYEST AND HOTTEST TIMES OF THE
YEAR. THUS, AND YOU MIGHT ALSO  THINK
ABOUT WHAT CHANGES IN FOG LEVELS, WHAT KIND
OF IMPACT THAT WOULD HAVE ON LOCAL COMMUNITIES
IN THE CONTEXT OF GLOBAL CLIMATE CHANGE.
FOG IS ONE PHENOMENON THAT'S LIKELY TO CHANGE
QUITE A LOT. YOU MAY HAVE HEARD OF THIS
PHENOMENON OF AIR, WHEN ASCENDING AGAINST
A LAND MASS DROPS ITS MOISTURE DURING THE
ASCENT, SUCH THAT WHEN IT FINDS THE LEEWARD
SIDE OF MOUNTAIN, IT'S LOST ALL ITS MOISTURE
AND HAS NOTHING TO RAIN OUT. SO ON THE LEEWARD
SIDE OF THE MOUNTAIN YOU OFTEN GET AREAS OF
GREAT ARIDITY. THINK OF NEVADA OR THE MOHAVE
DESERT IN THE SOUTH AS A RESULT OF RAIN
SHADOW CREATED IN THE SIERRA NEVADA, THE GREAT
BASIN. THIS IS A PICTURE OF THE MOHAVE DESERT
WHICH MANY OF YOU HAVE PROBABLY BEEN TO. SOME
OF YOUR GREAT CLOUD FORESTS AND ALPINE WET
FORESTS MAY OCCUR IN THESE CONDITIONS.
SO THAT'S SOME OF THE GLOBAL BACKGROUND TO
THE DISTRIBUTION OF VEGETATION ON A VERY
BROAD BRUSHSTROKE. BUT IT'S HELPFUL. THIS
IS A SCIENCE OF MACROCLIMATE AND MACROSCALE
COMMUNITY STRUCTURE. A BIOME IS A COMMUNITY
AT A VERY LARGE-SCALE. IT'S A COMMUNITY,
IT'S ACTUALLY MANY COMMUNITIES THAT SHARE
CERTAIN CHARACTERISTICS SUCH THAT THEY ARE
DISTINGUISHABLE FROM COLLECTIONS OF COMMUNITIES
IN NEIGHBORING AREAS. AND THESE ARE BIOMES.
THEY'RE DISTINCT IN TERMS OF THE ORGANISMS
THAT LIVE THERE, IN TERMS OF THE CLIMATES
THAT THEY'RE EXPOSED TO AND PARTLY DRIVEN
BY THOSE CLIMATES. THEY'RE DISTINCT IN MANY
WAYS. YOU NEED TO TAKE YOUR MACROSCOPE AND
STUDY THESE THINGS. SOME OF THE  ECOLOGISTS
SPEAK OF LEAVING THE MICROSCOPE IN THE LAB
AND TAKING OUT THE MACROSCOPE AND GOING
OUT TO THE FILED AND SEEING WHOLE SYSTEMS
THROUGH THAT. IT'S A METAPHOR OBVIOUSLY.
HOW DO YOU DISTINGUISH THESE BIOMES? YOU CAN
DO IT YOURSELF BASED ON WHAT YOU ALREADY
KNOW AS A RESULT OF WHAT IS, PHYSIOGNOMY
OF THESE SYSTEMS. IT'S REALLY JUST THEIR GESTALT
APPEARANCE, HOW THEY LOOK TO YOU. THIS ONE
HAS A BUNCH OF WAVING GRASSES, SOME TREES
ON THE EDGES. THAT'S A PRETTY HEAVY FOREST.
AND A GRASSY PATCH IN THE MIDDLE. YOU MIGHT
NOT KNOW SPECIFICALLY WHAT KIND OF ECOSYSTEM
IT IS BUT IT LOOKS LIKE A DRY FOREST. IT
LOOKS LIKE A SEASONAL DRY FOREST OR SOMETHING
LIKE THAT. SEASONAL DRY FOREST. THAT MIGHT
LOOK LIKE NEAR SOME NATURAL AREA WHERE YOU
GREW UP. MANY OF YOU ARE FROM CALIFORNIA.
THAT'S A CHAPARRAL, THIS NEAR AREA WITH THESE,
THE TREES ARE JUST SMALLER. THEY'RE SMALLER
IN HERE. MOSTLY SHRUBBY LOW-LYING GROWTH
THAT WE CALL CHAPARRAL. IN THE DISTANCE YOU
SEE MORE CONIFER FOREST. IT'S JUST HOW IT
LOOKS. THESE ARE BIG TREES. THESE ARE SMALL
SPINDLY TREES AND THESE ARE YOUR SHRUBBY LOWER
LYING BITS OF VEGETATION. THIS IS THE PHYSIOGNOMY
OF THIS SYSTEM. THAT'S A VERY LUSH SYSTEM
WITH LOTS OF EPITHETIC GROWTH, PLANTS GROWING
ON OTHER PLANTS. THESE TRUNKS ARE CAKED WITH
GREEN LEAVES. YOU HAVE VINES HANGING DOWN
FROM THE CANOPY. YOU HAVE MOSSES GROWING
ON THE ROCK. WHAT KIND OF SYSTEM DO YOU THINK
THIS IS? SOMEONE SAID A CLOUD FOREST. YEAH,
IT COULD VERY
WELL BE A CLOUD FOREST OR A RAINFOREST. A
TROPICAL FOREST ENVIRONMENT PROBABLY. SOME
LUSH FOREST. THIS ONE LOOKS MORE TO ME VERY
LUSH ALSO, LOOKS MORE TO ME LIKE A TEMPERATE
RAINFOREST. THE FERNS AND I DON'T KNOW MAYBE
SORO [SP?] YOU'LL KNOW BETTER AFTER THE BOTANY
MODULE WHAT THESE THINGS ARE. OR THIS, VERY
CHARACTERISTIC, OPEN GRASSLAND, TENDS TO BE
DRY. OCCASIONAL SPOTTY TREES. IT'S A SAVANNA.
RIGHT.  IT'S A GREAT SAVANNA. YOU CAN
TELL BY THE STRIPPY HORSES HERE YOU'RE IN
AFRICA.
THAT COULD BE VERY NEARBY HERE. THESE LOW,
GRADUALLY SLOPING HILLS. ERODED, THESE ERODED
HILLTOPS, GRASSLANDS MODIFIED THROUGH AGRICULTURE
OR GRAZING PROBABLY. SCATTERED TREES, OAKS.
SOMETHING LIKE THAT, COULD BE A PARK IN THE
EAST BAY. SO I'M JUST GIVING YOU A HINT
OF HOW YOU CAN LOOK AT THESE SYSTEMS. AND
YOU RECOGNIZE THESE DIFFERENCES, YOU ALREADY
DO. IT'S BECAUSE YOU HAVE THESE SENSORY
SYSTEMS YOU USE TO DISTINGUISH AMONG THEM.
IT'S JUST A NATURAL THING TO DO. SO NOW
LET'S PUT SOME TECHNICAL NAMES ON THEM SO
YOU KNOW WHAT TO CALL THEM IN THE SCIENTIFIC
SENSE AND THAT WOULD BE THE PROCESS OF NAMING
OUR TERRESTRIAL BIOMES. THIS IS A CLIMOGRAPH
WHERE ON YOUR AXES OF PRECIPITATION AND TEMPERATURE,
YOU CAN ANALYZE THE DISTRIBUTION OF TERRESTRIAL
VEGETATION MORE OR LESS ACCURATELY. THIS
IS A, THIS IS SOMETHING OF A CARTOON, BUT
IT'S BASED ON REAL DATA. YOU CAN SEE HOW
NICELY THESE BIOTYPES, THESE VEGETATION TYPES
CAN BE MODELED ON JUST THOSE TWO AXES OF
TEMPERATURE AND PRECIPITATION. SO IF IT'S
REAL HOT, BUT REALLY DRY, YOU GET A DESERT.
SUBTROPICAL DESERT. A BIT MORE WATER, YOU
MIGHT HAVE A TROPICAL DRY FOREST LIKE YOU
SAW IN THAT ONE OR A SAVANNA. AND IF IT'S
REALLY HOT BUT REALLY WET, TALKING ABOUT A
RAINFOREST. DOES ANYONE KNOW ANYTHING ABOUT
SAVANNAS? WHAT ELSE HELPS TO DRIVE AND STRUCTURE
THEM? WE CAN TALK ABOUT THAT IN A MINUTE.
I JUST LIKE SAVANNAS. OR IF IT'S REALLY
COLD AND REALLY DRY, THE TUNDRA. SOMEWHAT
MORE MOISTURE. THE HIGH LATITUDE FORESTS,
BOREAL FORESTS. I'LL SHOW YOU PICTURES OF
ALL OF THESE. OKAY. YOU GOT THE IDEA. AND
THEN OUR TEMPERATE RAINFORESTS WHERE
STILL THERE'S A LOT OF MOISTURE. NOT AS MUCH
AS IN A TROPICAL RAINFOREST PROBABLY AND
NOT AS HOT. BUT THAT'S OUR TEMPERATE RAINFOREST
THAT YOU WOULD GET NORTH OF HERE IF YOU
DROVE UP THE COAST. COOL. AND JUST ANOTHER
VIEW FOCUSED MORE ON NORTH AMERICA, AXES SWITCHED
JUST FOR YOU TO LOOK AT ON YOUR OWN TIME.
SO THESE ARE THE BIOME TYPES THAT YOUR BOOK
PROVIDES. AND WE'LL JUST STICK WITH THOSE.
AND PLEASE LOOK AT THE BOOK FOR SOME OF THE
DETAILS ON THE STRUCTURE OF THESE SYSTEMS,
WHAT DISTINGUISHES THEM. I WON'T SPEND TOO
MUCH TIME ON THAT. I ALREADY MENTIONED MOST
OF THESE. YOUR TROPICAL FORESTS, DISTRIBUTED
AROUND THE WORLD, THIS ONE FROM BORNEO.
BUT CENTRAL AFRICA. THE AMAZON FOREST, OF
COURSE. SOME FABULOUS ONES IN CENTRAL AMERICA.
SOUTHEAST ASIA. THESE ARE THE TROPICAL RAINFORESTS.
THESE ARE INTENSELY MODIFIED ECOSYSTEMS
FOR LIVING SPACE AND FOR AGRICULTURE, FOR
HARVESTING OF TIMBER, AND THESE ARE THE SO-CALLED
LUNGS OF THE EARTH BECAUSE OF JUST HOW MUCH
THEY'RE MAJOR IMPORTANCE OF THESE SYSTEMS
IN PROCESSING CARBON DIOXIDE, FOR EXAMPLE.
SO THE LOSS OF THESE SYSTEMS IS OF GREAT IMPORTANCE
TO ALL OF US AS A RESULT OF ITS INFLUENCE
ON THE GLOBAL ATMOSPHERE. AND MUCH IS BEING
DONE TO TRY TO CURTAIL THE DESTRUCTION OF
THESE SYSTEMS. CONTRAST THAT WITH THE DESERT
WITH YOUR PLANTS HEAVILY MODIFIED FOR RETAINING
MOISTURE. SOMETIMES THE LEAVES ARE JUST
REDUCED TO SPINES THAT SERVE A PROTECTIVE
FUNCTION BUT ALSO HELP TO AVOID WATER LOSS.
SPACING IN BETWEEN THE INDIVIDUAL PLANTS.
YOU WOULDN'T SEE THIS KIND OF THING IN A RAINFOREST
WHERE THE CANOPY, THE CANOPY JUST BEING
THE LAYER OF LEAFY GROWTH OF  PHOTOSYNTHETIC
CAPTURE WOULD BE CLOSED. YOU WOULD SPEAK OF
A CLOSED CANOPY.
THIS IS A VERY OPEN CANOPY, THERE'S A LOT
OF GAPS IN THE CANOPY HERE. AND SAVANNAS,
SO WHAT IS IT ABOUT  SAVANNAS, WHY I DON'T
REALLY APPRECIATE PUTTING TJE, JUST UNDER
A CLIMOGRAPH SO SIMPLY. WHAT'S ONE FACTOR
IN SAVANNAS THAT'S SO IMPORTANT TO THEIR
MAINTENANCE? SOMEBODY MUST HAVE AN IDEA.
STUDENT: HERDS OF ANIMALS.
PROFESSOR: HERDS OF ANIMALS, YEAH. GRAZING
IS OF BIG IMPORTANCE IN A SAVANNA. AND VERY
GREAT IMPORTANCE. SO YEAH, THAT'S ONE FACTOR.
YES. STUDENT: THEY HAVE VERY DRASTIC WET
AND DRY SEASONS. PROFESSOR: THEY OFTEN DO
HAVE VERY DRASTIC WET AND DRY SEASONS. SO
DOES A DRY SEASONAL FOREST. SO WHY A DRY SEASONAL
FOREST WITH THICK FOREST PATCHES THAT COULD
STILL SURVIVE AN INTENSATIVE DRY SEASON
BUT IN THE SAVANNA JUST THESE SCATTERED TREES?
STUDENT: FIRES.
PROFESSOR: FIRES PLAY A MAJOR ROLE IN THESE
SYSTEMS. AND HELP TO STRUCTURE WHAT YOU
SEE OF ITS PHYSIOGNOMY HERE.
JUST INDIVIDUAL TREES OFTEN GROWING NEAR BEAUTIFUL
SPREADING ACACIA
THAT THE GIRAFFE MIGHT BE NIBBLING ON AS OPPOSED
TO MORE EXTENSIVE PATCHES OF FOREST THAT
MAY NOT SURVIVE REGULAR BURNS OR SOMETHING
LIKE THAT. SO SAVANNAS ARE, AT LEAST THE
AFRICAN SAVANNAS, ARE PROBABLY IN MANY WAYS
EVOLVED TO DEAL WITH REGULAR FIRE INPUT.
AND IT'S CERTAINLY INTERESTING TO THINK
ABOUT THAT IN RELATION TO HUMAN EVOLUTION
THAT'S BEEN OCCURRING THERE FOR MILLION
OF YEARS AND THE DOMESTICATION
AND USE OF FIRE HUMANS OR HUMAN ANCESTORS.
CALIFORNIA CHAPARRAL. NOTE THAT WHAT WE
CALL CHAPARRAL OCCURS HERE IN THIS MEDITERRANEAN
CLIMATE WHERE WE HAVE THE HOT DRY SUMMER AND
A COOL MOIST WINTER. FORGET FOG IN THE EQUATION
FOR THE MOMENT BECAUSE YOU GET THE CHAPARRAL
OCCURRING WITHOUT MAJOR FOG INPUT IN, FOR
EXAMPLE, IN SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA. SO HOT DRY
SUMMER AND A COOL FAIRLY WET WINTER, THAT
OCCURS NOT ONLY HERE IN CALIFORNIA BUT
AROUND THE MEDITERRANEAN. YOU SOMETIMES
HEAR OF THIS AS A MEDITERRANEAN CLIMATE,
OUR CLIMATE AS A MEDITERRANEAN CLIMATE. AND
THIS TYPE OF VEGETATION AS A MEDITERRANEAN
VEGETATION. IT'S NICE. IT THINK YOUR BOOK
IS THE ONE THAT USES CHAPARRAL. THAT'S GREAT
BECAUSE THAT'S REALLY A TERM FROM CALIFORNIA.
LET'S EXPORT  THAT TO EUROPE. YOU ALSO HAVE
SOMETHING SIMILAR GOING ON AT THE TIP OF
AFRICA. MAYBE A BIT IN AUSTRALIA, CERTAINLY
A BIT IN CHILE. BUT ONLY IN THOSE SPOTS.
YOU GET THIS KIND OF STRUCTURED VEGETATION
AS A RESULT OF THIS UNIQUE COMBINATION OF
CLIMATIC FACTORS. IT'S REALLY PRETTY COOL.
THESE ARE ALSO FIRE PRONE SYSTEMS TOO AS
WE KNOW ALL TOO WELL HERE. TEMPERATE GRASSLANDS.
SOME OF YOUR GREAT AGRICULTURAL GROWING REGIONS.
FROM THESE WHAT ONCE WERE VAST TEMPERATE GRASSLANDS.
THE NORTHERN CONIFEROUS FORESTS OR BOREAL
FORESTS MARKED PRIMARILY BY THE CONIFER
TREES, SOFT WOOD TREES, THE PINES AND SPRUCES
AND HEMLOCKS AND THINGS
LIKE THAT. AND THE BOREAL FOREST ZONE. IT'S
A HUGE REGION. SO IF ONLY FOR THAT REASON,
IT'S OF GREAT GREAT IMPORTANCE. ALSO INTENSELY
HARVESTED FOR TIMBER AND THINGS BUT WE SPEAK
OF THE LUNGS OF THE EARTH DOWN HERE, THIS
REGION IS ALSO INCREDIBLY IMPORTANT FOR
GAS CAPTURE ON A GLOBAL SCALE. TEMPERATE
BROADLEAF FORESTS. THESE ARE THE TYPES OF
SYSTEMS I GREW UP IN AND I JUST LOVE THEM.
YOU GET YOUR FALL FOLIAGE COLORS AS A RESULT
OF DROPPING THE LEAVES OFF THE TREES IN THE
FALL AND WINTER. IT SNOWS A LOT IN SOME
OF THESE AREAS BUT IT'S REALLY DRY BECAUSE
SNOW IS NOT AVAILABLE FOR UPTAKE BY PLANTS.
SO THAT'S A TIME OF ARIDITY FOR MANY PLANTS
IS A PERIOD OF WINTER WHEN IT'S MAYBE A
LOT OF PRECIPITATION BUT IT'S NOT AVAILABLE
FOR USE. AND IT'S ALSO JUST COLD AND MANY
PLANTS CAN'T FUNCTION IN LOW TEMPERATURES.
SO ONE OF THE SOLUTIONS PLANTS USE IS TO
DROP THEIR LEAVES. THEY'RE DECIDUOUS. THEY
DROP THE LEAVES DURING THAT SEASON. THE TUNDRA,
TREELESS.  THIS IS LATITUDINALLY ABOVE
TREE LINE. YOU CAN GET SOMETHING SIMILAR
IF YOU ASCEND A MOUNTAIN. YOU CAN ASCEND A
MOUNTAIN
THROUGH THE FORESTS AND GET ABOVE TREE LINE
AND GET A TYPE OF ALPINE TUNDRA. YOU CAN
DO THAT IN THE SIERRAS OR IN THE ROCKY MOUNTAINS
AND THAT HIGHLIGHTS THE FACT THAT MOUNTAINS,
AS YOU MOVE UP A MOUNTAIN, IT'S ANALOGOUS
TO MOVING UP IN LATITUDE. SO YOU CAN SEE
AS YOU ASCEND A MOUNTAIN IN SOME CASES, A
MARCHING THROUGH OF THESE PHYSIOGNOMIES,
THESE BIOMES THAT YOU SEE AT HIGHER AND HIGHER
LATITUDES. SO YOU WOULD WANT TO DISTINGUISH
THE TRUE TUNDRA OF NORTH AND THE HIGH LATITUDES
AGAINST AN ALPINE TUNDRA THAT YOU WOULD SEE
UP IN A MOUNTAINOUS AREA. LOTS OF HERBACEOUS
GROWTH. NO TREE GROWTH AT ALL. OKAY. LET'S
SWITCH TO THE AQUATIC REALM. MOST BROADLY
WE WANT TO DISTINGUISH FRESHWATER FROM MARINE
WATER BASED ON ITS CONCENTRATION OF SALTS.
AND WITHIN FRESHWATER SYSTEMS, IT'S HELPFUL
TO DISTINGUISH STILL WATER SYSTEMS FROM
FLOWING WATER SYSTEMS. TERMS, FANCY TERMS
IF YOU WANT TO USE THEM. LENTIC AND LOTIC.
THE BOOK USES THEM. I FIND THEM HELPFUL
FOR FLOWING WATER SYSTEMS. THE LOTIC SYSTEMS.
SO, IN A STILL WATER SYSTEM LIKE A LAKE,
WE DIVIDE IT UP IN A SIMPLE WAY. AND THESE
TERMS IF YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT AQUATIC COMMUNITIES,
YOU'LL BE USING THESE TERMS JUST ALL THE
TIME. WE DISTINGUISH THESE SYSTEMS IN TERMS
OF THE LIGHT PENETRATION, SO THE PHOTIC ZONE
WHERE LIGHT DOES PENETRATE AND PHYTOSYNTHESIS
OCCURS WITH THE MAYBE ROOTED PLANTS IN THE
SHALLOWS OR ALGAE AND BACTERIA IN THESE OPEN
AREAS. AND THEN APHOTIC ZONE WHERE THERE'S
LESS LIGHT PENETRATION OR NONE AT ALL AT
THE DEPTHS. ALSO IN TERMS OF THE DISTANCE
FROM THE SHORELINE AND THE DEPTH. SO THE LITTORAL
ZONE IS THIS NEAR SHORE ZONE WHERE YOU GET
THESE ROOTED PLANTS. AND THE  LIMNETIC
ZONE, FURTHER FROM SHORE AND USUALLY DEEPER.
AND LET'S TALK ABOUT THE PELAGIC, YOU'LL
OFTEN HEAR THAT TERM. THE PELAGIC ZONE,
THIS OPEN WATER ZONE AS AGAINST THE BENTHIC
ZONE, THE ZONE ON THE SUBSTRATE ITSELF MARKED
BY THE COMMUNITY OF ORGANISMS CALLED THE
BENTHOS, B-E-N-T-H-O-S, THE BENTHOS. THE UNIQUE
ORGANISMS THAT LIVE IN THE MUCK AND MIRE
AND ON THE SURFACES OF THIS ZONE. FANTASTIC
CREATURES THERE. SO HERE ARE TWO LIMNETIC
SYSTEMS. ONE HIGH ELEVATION SYSTEM WITH
VERY CLEAR WATERS. NOT MUCH VEGETATION GROWTH.
AND ANOTHER SYSTEM WHERE THE WATERS ARE VERY
DARK, CAN'T SEE THE BOTTOM HERE AT ALL.
AND WITH ABUNDANT VEGETATION GROWING IN IT.
BESIDES AN ELEVATIONAL DISTANCE HERE PERHAPS,
LET'S ASSUME THEY'RE AT THE SAME LATITUDE.
THEY COULD BE. WHAT'S ONE DIFFERENCE IN THESE
SYSTEMS IN THE AQUATIC ENVIRONMENT HERE?
SUBSTRATE? WELL, MAYBE THIS IS A ROCKY SUBSTRATE
HERE. YOU JUST CAN'T SEE IT BECAUSE IT'S SO
DARK. THE WATER IS SO DARK. STUDENT: THE
WATER SOURCE. PROFESSOR: THE WATER SOURCE
PROBABLY DIFFERS BUT LET'S JUST SAY THAT
THIS IS FROM STREAMS COMING DOWN OUT OF THESE
HILLS AND THIS ONE, THERE'S HILLS IN THE
FOREGROUND WITH STREAMS ENTERING IT TOO.
STUDENT: TEMPERATURE.
PROFESSOR: TEMPERATURE. IT CERTAINLY LOOKS
WARMER HERE THAN IT DOES THERE. SO THIS IS
SOMEWHAT HIGHER. BUT LET'S FOCUS ON DIFFERENCES
THAT MIGHT EXIST WITHIN THE WATER ITSELF.
THE TEMPERATURE COULD EXIST WITHIN
THE WATER ITSELF. THIS IS PROBABLY A WARMER
BODY OF WATER, I WOULD GUESS FROM APPEARANCES
BUT LET'S ASSUME NOT.
STUDENT: OXYGEN? PROFESSOR: OXYGEN? OXYGEN
IS LIKELY TO DIFFER PARTLY AS A CONSEQUENCE
OF THE THINGS I'M THINKING OF, YES.
STUDENT: LIGHT PENETRATION? PROFESSOR: LIGHT
PENETRATION WILL DIFFER. PARTLY BECAUSE OF
THE VEGETATION AT THE  SURFACES, BUT
ALSO AS A RESULT OF THE LACK OF CLARITY SIGNALING
MORE SEDIMENT AND MORE STUFF IN THE WATER.
YES?
STUDENT: NUTRIENTS?
PROFESSOR: NUTRIENTS IS THE ONE I WAS THINKING
ABOUT FIRSTLY. BUT AS A CONSEQUENCE OF DIFFERENCES
IN NUTRIENTS A LOT OF THE OTHER THINGS YOU
GUYS MENTIONED WOULD BE TRUE ALSO. NUTRIENTS
ARE TYPICALLY THE MAJOR LIMITING FACTOR IN
THE PRODUCTIVITY OF AQUATIC SYSTEMS. WHICH
NUTRIENT IT IS MAY DIFFER SYSTEM TO SYSTEM
BUT IT'S USUALLY NUTRIENTS. AND THIS SYSTEM
IS POOR IN NUTRIENTS. AND AS A RESULT HAS
LITTLE VEGETATIVE GROWTH. LITTLE LESS BIOLOGICAL
ACTIVITY IN GENERAL. AS A RESULT OF LESS
BIOLOGICAL ACTIVITY, THERE'S GOING TO BE GREATER
AMOUNT OF OXYGEN AVAILABLE, LESS USED BY THE
RESPIRATION OF THE ORGANISMS. THIS SYSTEM
WITH MUCH MORE BIOLOGICAL ACTIVITY, LESS
OXYGEN IN THE DEPTHS, IT HAS MORE NUTRIENTS.
AND OUR TERMS WE NEED ARE OLIGOTROPHIC AND
EUTROPHIC. OLIGOTROPHIC AND EUTROPHIC.
I THINK AT LEAST EUTROPHIC IS HERE. A GREAT
EXPERIMENT, A CLASSIC EXPERIMENT IN ECOLOGY
SHOWED THE IMPORTANCE OF NUTRIENT INPUTS TO
LAKES BY DIVIDING THIS SORT OF DUMBBELL-SHAPED
LAKE AT THE MIDDLE AND PUTTING NUTRIENTS
INTO BOTH SIDES OF LAKE. NITROGEN, CARBON,
AND PHOSPHORUS INTO THIS SIDE. SORRY, NITROGEN,
CARBON AND PHOSPHORUS INTO THIS SIDE. AND
ONLY NITROGEN AND CARBON INTO THIS SIDE.
THIS IS UP IN NORTHERN CANADA. AND THIS WAS
AT A TIME WHEN LAKES WERE SEEN TO BE SHOWING
THESE KINDS OF EFFECTS WHERE YOU HAD BLOOMS
OF ALGAE OR BLOOMS OF BACTERIA, IN PARTICULAR
CYANOBACTERIA IN PARTICULARLY IN POLLUTED
WATERS. AND IT WAS OF BIG CONCERN TO PEOPLE
WHEN YOUR WATERS GO FROM BEING CLEAR AND
SWIMMABLE TO CHOKED WITH UNDESIRABLE GROWTH.
AND WHAT THESE INVESTIGATORS SHOWED SO
STARKLY WAS THE ROLE OF PHOSPHORUS AND
PHOSPHATES AS A LIMITING NUTRIENT. PHOSPHORUS
AS A LIMITING NUTRIENT. THAT WHEN INPUT COULD
CAUSE THESE TYPES OF BLOOMS THAT WOULD ABSOLUTELY
CHOKE OTHER ORGANISMS OUT AS A RESULT OF DEPLETION
OF OXYGEN AND ALTERATION IN THE PHOTIC ZONE.
AND PHOSPHORUS WAS ENTERING WATERWAYS AS
A RESULT OF SEWAGE INPUT AND RUNOFF FROM FARMS
AND DETERGENTS THAT WERE HEAVY IN PHOSPHATES,
MAKING THEIR WAY INTO WATER SUPPLIES AND INTO
LOCAL WATERS. AND WHEN THESE IMAGES WERE
SHOWED IN CONGRESS THEY HAD A BIG RIPPLING
EFFECT ON OUR LAWS ABOUT DETERGENTS AND
POLLUTION. HERE'S A LOVELY EUTROPHIC SYSTEM
SOMEWHERE IN THE WORLD. I DON'T KNOW WHERE.
I JUST LIKE THE PICTURE. I LIKE THESE SYSTEMS
ALSO. SAVANNAS I LIKE, BUT PARTICULARLY
THESE WETLAND SYSTEMS AT THE ECOTONE. AT THE
ECOTONE BETWEEN  WATER AND LAND. OFTEN YOUR
SAVANNA IS BACK BEHIND HERE IN AFRICA. YOU
HAVE A RIM OF TREES, VEGETATION, A RIPARIAN
ZONE IF THIS WERE A FLOWING BODY. AND THEN
THIS ECOTONE, THIS INTERFACE, BETWEEN WATER
AND LAND. THAT'S THE SYSTEM I STUDY IN AFRICA.
OKAY. SO A COUPLE EXAMPLES OF FLOWING SYSTEMS.
OF COURSE, A BIG RIVER LIKE THIS STARTS
AS A BUNCH OF LITTLE CREEKS AND STREAMS
AND SMALLER RIVERS THAT GATHER TOGETHER TO
FORM BIG A RIVER. RIGHT? AND YOU MIGHT IMAGINE
THE ORGANISMS THAT OCCUPY A SYSTEM LIKE
THIS AND A SYSTEM LIKE THIS DIFFER A LOT FROM
ONES IN LAKES.
THERE ARE MANY DIFFERENT PHYSICAL FORCES TO
DEAL WITH.
FLOWING WATER IS VERY DIFFERENT FROM STILL
WATER. ULTIMATELY THE RIVER IS GOING TO
FLOW INTO THE SEA TYPICALLY. THERE ARE COUNTER-EXAMPLES
BUT MOST RIVERS FLOW ULTIMATELY TO THE SEA.
AND AT THE COAST THEY MAY FORM DELTAS LIKE
THIS WHERE THEY BACK UP AND FORM CHANNELS.
IT'S A DELTA SYSTEM,
DELTAIC SYSTEM. AND AN ESTUARY, THIS AREA
WHERE, THIS AREA INFLUENCED BY THE TIDES
OF THE OCEAN WHERE YOU GET SOME SALTWATER
INPUT, SOME MARINE INPUT BUT WITH CONTINUOUS
FRESHWATER OUTPUT IS A MIXED WATER SYSTEM,
A BRACKISH SYSTEM IF YOU WANT THAT WE CALL
AN ESTUARY. AND THEY'RE VERY PRODUCTIVE
SYSTEMS, THESE ESTUARIES. HIGH NUTRIENT INPUT
FROM THE  CONTINENTAL SURFACE AND ORGANISMS
AND SALTS FROM THE OCEAN MINGLING TOGETHER
AND ESPECIALLY IN TROPICAL ENVIRONMENT.
THIS IS A RECIPE FOR A LOT OF BIOLOGICAL ACTIVITY.
MARINE ZONES WE DIVIDE UP MUCH LIKE WE DO
THE FRESHWATER ZONES IN TERMS OF LIGHT PENETRATION.
PHOTIC AND APHOTIC. DISTANCE FROM SHORE. JUST
SWAP TERMS A LITTLE BIT. NERITIC ZONE, THE
OCEANIC ZONE. AND AGAIN OPEN WATER OR BOTTOM,
PELAGIC AND BENTHIC. SO THOSE ARE THE SAME.
THOSE TERMS ARE THE SAME. THE CONTINENTAL
SHELF. AND THE INTERTIDAL ZONE. THE INTERTIDAL
IS REMEMBER IS JUST THAT ZONE BETWEEN THE
UPPERMOST HIGH TIDE AND THE LOWER MOST LOW
TIDE WITH ITS CHARACTERISTIC ORGANISMS.
AND IN SOME WAYS YOU CAN CONSIDER THIS AN
ECOTONAL SYSTEM, AN ECOLOGICAL SYSTEM BETWEEN
TWO OTHER MAJOR SYSTEMS, AN OCEANIC ONE
AND A TERRESTRIAL ONE. IT'S AN INTERTIDAL
SYSTEM. THAT TERM ECOTONE I WON'T FORMALLY
DEFINE BUT HOPEFULLY YOU ARE GETTING THE IDEA
OF WHAT I MEAN BY IT.
AN INTERTIDAL SYSTEM. PISASTER PERHAPS. THEY
ARE YOUR MUSSELS AND BARNACLES, YOUR ALGAE,
NICE SYSTEM WITH YOUR KEYSTONE PREDATOR
PRESENT. BEAUTIFUL ANEMONES. YOU CAN SEE THIS
RIGHT DOWN COAST HERE.
YOU CAN SEE TIDE POOLS LIKE THIS ON OUR COAST.
AND I URGE YOU
TO GO CHECK THEM OUT. AND CORAL REEFS, OF
COURSE, JUST OFF-SHORE, THESE SHALLOW WATER
REEFS THAT RECEIVE SO MUCH SOLAR INPUT AS
WELL AS NUTRIENTS COMING OFF OF THE OCEANS.
OCCURRING IN WATERS THAT ARE VERY NUTRIENT
POOR TYPICALLY. TROPICAL WATERS, YOU GO TO
YOU BEAUTIFUL TROPICAL BEACH WITH YOUR PALM
TREE BEHIND YOU AND YOU'RE SIPPING ON YOUR
DRINK AND GAZING ON THE LOVELY BLUEGREEN
SEA THAT YOU CAN SNORKEL IN AND SEE 25 FEET
DOWN TO THE BOTTOM. IT'S SO CLEAR AND BEAUTIFUL,
THAT WATER, PARTLY BECAUSE IT'S SO NUTRIENT
POOR AND THERE'S VERY LITTLE GROWTH. BUT
THEN YOU CROSS THE LAGOON AND YOU'RE ON A
REEF LIKE THIS, THAT'S JUST A RIOT OF BIOLOGICAL
ACTIVITY. HOW CAN YOU GROW A REEF LIKE THIS
IN NUTRIENT POOR WATERS? I PUT AN ARTICLE
RELATED TO  THAT ON BSPACE IN THAT
NEWS FOLDER. SO PLEASE READ ABOUT IT THERE.
IT'S REQUIRED READING. JUST A SHORT NATIONAL
GEOGRAPHIC ARTICLE. IT CAN HELP YOU UNDERSTAND
OR AT LEAST THE HYPOTHESIS FOR HOW THAT WORKS.
CHLOROPHYL, PLANTS THAT RELY ON CHLOROPHYL
FOR PHOTOSYNTHESIS ABSORBS
VISIBLE LIGHT AND TENDS TO REFLECT OTHER WAVE
LENGTHS OF LIGHT LIKE INFRARED LIGHT. WHEREAS
PHYSICAL SURFACES, NON-GROWING SURFACES
REFLECT LIGHT DIFFERENTLY. SO YOU CAN TAKE
SATELLITE IMAGES OF THE EARTH AND MAP AND
TRANSLATE REFLECTANCE OF LIGHT, OF WAVE
LENGTHS OF LIGHT INTO DIFFERENT SUBSTRATE
TYPES, VEGETATION VERSUS STONE VERSUS SAND.
IT REFLECTS NOT ONLY THE VEGETATION BUT
PRODUCTIVITY. SO IN A SATELLITE IMAGE LIKE
THIS, I DON'T HAVE WHAT THE SCALE BAR IS
HERE, BUT THIS IS MEASURED IN SOMETHING
LIKE KILOGRAMS OF CARBON PER UNIT SPACE. YOU
CAN GET A SENSE FOR HOW PRODUCTIVE THESE
SURFACES OF THE WORLD ARE. THE GRAY HERE
IS NO NET PRIMARY PRODUCTIVITY LESS THAN ZERO
NET PRIMARY PRODUCTIVITY IN THIS GREAT DESERT
OR ON THESE POLAR CONDITIONS. AND YOUR REDS
AND YELLOWS ARE MORE PRODUCTIVE AREAS AND
SO FORTH. THE OCEAN TENDS TO BE VERY LOW IN
PRODUCTIVITY WITH SOME HUGE DEAD ZONES IN
TERMS OF PRODUCTIVITY. BUT BECAUSE OF ITS
ENORMOUS SIZE, THE OCEAN HAS ALMOST AS MUCH
PRIMARY PRODUCTIVITY AS THE LAND SURFACE
JUST BECAUSE IT'S SO BIG. BUT NOTE CAREFULLY
HOW LOW IN PRIMARY PRODUCTIVITY IT IS. AND
THIS IS PRIMARILY A CONSEQUENCE OF NUTRIENT
LIMITATIONS. IT'S MOST PRODUCTIVE ON COASTAL
SHELVES WHERE YOU EITHER HAVE UP-WELLING
OF DEEP WATER ORGANIC NUTRIENTS OR THE FLOWING
OFF OF NUTRIENTS FROM THE CONTINENTS THEMSELVES.
AND THIS I'LL LET YOU READ CAREFULLY. IT
BREAKS DOWN VARIOUS ECOSYSTEM TYPES AND BIOMES
IN RELATION TO THE PERCENTAGE OF THE EARTH'S
SURFACE THEY OCCUPY  AND THEIR AVERAGE
NET PRIMARY PRODUCTIVITY. AND YOU CAN SEE
THAT SOME SYSTEMS LIKE SWAMPS AND MARSHS
OR ALGO BEDS AND REEFS ARE VERY PRODUCTIVE
BUT THEY JUST DON'T OCCUPY MUCH OF THE EARTH'S
SURFACE. SO IN TERMS OF EARTH'S TOTAL PRIMARY
PRODUCTIVITY THEY'RE FAIRLY LOW. AND THE
TROPICAL RAINFORESTS BECAUSE THEY'RE BOTH
SO PRODUCTIVE AND SO NUMEROUS IN TERMS OF
SPACE THEY OCCUPY, THEY ACCOUNT FOR SO MUCH
OF EARTH'S PRIMARY PRODUCTIVITY.
I'M LOSING YOU GUYS. SO YOU CAN STUDY THESE
THINGS ON YOUR OWN TIME AND READ ABOUT THEM
IN THE BOOK. ALL RIGHT. SEE YOU NEXT TIME.