You really got to have
the right attitude.
You've got to have a big heart
and a ton of motivation.
DANNY WALKER: You've got to
compete against the best kids
in front of 200,000 fans.
If that's not pressure,
I don't know what is.
ADRIANA SOLIS: They say,
aren't you scared?
Yes, I am, I'm scared.
KEVIN SCHWANTZ: At any level,
MotoGP is what you strive to
be if you want to be the best
that there is in the world.
[BASS MUSIC PLAYING]
JAKE GAGNE: Yeah, coming over
here to race in Europe, it's
definitely a shock.
It's hard to get around
sometimes, not knowing the
language and whatnot.
But overall, it's fun.
It's adventure, and you get to
see a lot of new things.
HAYDEN GILLIM: I think it's a
positive thing that I'm doing
this, and that it's a blessing
because God gave me this
talent and I want to use
it as best I can.
BENNY SOLIS: I was watching
every race on the
Internet and all that.
And I was like, talking to my
dad, wouldn't that be cool if
I was there.
And once I got accepted,
I was so happy.
-Scholtz has got an absolute
fire there, his head down,
looking behind him.
It's fanned out behind him.
Stuck with 20 forwards in the--
oh, and he got caught up
with somebody else.
Fagerhaug is crashed, my
goodness, what an absolute
disaster for Sterla.
It's all gone wrong for
him this weekend.
Now who's going to make it?
Who's bravest?
It's Mayer that's bravest on the
brakes, but Scholtz got a
better drive on the
inside coming out.
It's side by side, they're
rubbing elbows now.
Scholtz and Mayer, rubbing
elbows into the left hander.
Oh, and that's Harry
Stafford!.
He's gone down, and he's clipped
by another rider.
Harry Stafford goes down,
let's hope he's OK.
Holding up the inside
comes Fagerhaug.
Fagerhaug with the red helmet,
way up the inside, he does the
Valentino last lap
maneuver there.
He's done it brilliantly.
absolutely sensational job.
Sterla Fagerhaug turned his
weekend around completely, and
it's Sterla Fagerhaug who
wins from Matthew
Scholtz and Danny Kent.
[BAND PLAYS]
KEVIN SCHWANTZ: Red Bull Rookies
Cup's main initiative
is to try and create a program
for 13 to 17-year-old kids to
be able to then step directly
into grand prix racing.
It's a program that, last
year, had kids from 14
different countries competing
in eight different races.
When I started racing in the mid
'80s, it was a set of my
uncle's borrowed dirt track
leathers, and probably a
helmet that didn't fit exactly
right, and whatever boots I
could find at the time, and
going and racing on a bike
that I had prepared.
The Red Bull Rookies Cup gives
these kids a first class
operation, first class
equipment, the best tires, the
best suspension, engineers
set behind everything.
MotoGP is what, if you've ever
become a road racer of any
kind at any level, what you
strive to be if you want to be
the best that there
is in the world.
So from a rider's standpoint,
it's the toughest playing
field that you can play in.
It's a sport that, at
the top, pays some
really, really big paychecks.
Any place in Europe, anybody who
races grand prix bikes is
obviously just as big
a name as any sports
star here in America.
PETER CLIFFORD: We start here
in Harris, where Sunday sees
like 200,000 people packing
the place, and that just
really buoys the level
of intensity about
the whole race meeting.
And the kids sort of rise
to the occasion.
HAYDEN GILLIM: It's just a
little different than what a
normal teenager's
life is like.
BENNY SOLIS: Last season went
really good for me actually.
I won four races out of,
I think it was nine.
And ended up winning
a championship.
So that's why I'm here,
racing this.
PETER CLIFFORD: There's no doubt
that coming into 2009,
we have some favorites
for the cup.
That's still Fagerhaug in
his third year now.
It was tremendous
force last year.
STERLA FAGERHAUG: Considering
I've been one of the fastest
guys from the beginning, it's
hard to improve on your riding
when you're at the top
already in this cup.
Still, it's not like I'm
freaking out, like it's too
much pressure on me.
It's not like that.
PETER CLIFFORD: We know that the
three Americans that are
here are strong.
Benny Solis won the
AMA Cup, and he
didn't do that by accident.
So I would expect that as he
gets into his stride, Benny
and Jake Gagne and Hayden
Gillim, they'll be fighting at
the front as well.
Really, there are two ways that
riders can get into the
Rookies Cup.
Riders can send in their CVs
and convince us that they
really should be considered
for selection.
Than there are championships
around the world, which we
take a look at and really invite
the best riders into
the selection process.
KEVIN SCHWANTZ: We look for kids
that have good attitudes.
We look for kids that don't,
after the first practice
session and they're not the
fastest kids out there, they
come out with a list
of excuses.
We look for a kid that
asks questions.
Hey, how can I better myself?
How can I work better?
How can I work with
the team better?
There's lots of kids out there
that, given the right
opportunity, I think
could do this.
But you really got to have the
right attitude, you got to
have a big heart and a
ton of motivation.
PETER CLIFFORD: There's
a very intense level
of competition here.
I've heard some of the young
Americans say that things are
a bit rough here.
There's a lot of elbowing that
goes on, and that's something
that they've got
to get used to.
But it is a bit of a shock
for them at first.
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYS]
-From the third row, but it
looks like Scholz has got
another good start.
Scholz [INAUDIBLE] pulls across
to the left hand side
to get a run into the
first corner.
And Hayden Gillim seems
to have problems.
He's not going anywhere
in a hurry, I think.
Now Fagerhaug pulls out of the
slipstream, Scholtz comes
across the track.
Now Emery is there, number
21 as well there.
Hard on the brakes.
Fagerhaug goes up the inside
and into the lead.
Trying to chase this man, Alex
Christian, down goes Christian.
These guys have not learned
from yesterday.
It shows their lack
of experience.
-Marino with Fagerhaug
in the red helmet has
a lock on the inside.
Very nicely through.
Fagerhaug and three of
them in side by side.
Well that's desperate stuff
as they go past on
either side of Fagerhaug.
Absolutely sensational
stuff there.
Fagerhaug passes now by Danny
Kent, and it's his favorite
passing move, but Kent has done
that to Fagerhaug now
three times.
Danny runs wide, Fagerhaug
gets [INAUDIBLE].
Kent is in front of him.
Really, Kent should have it.
It's Danny Kent that's going
to win his first Rookie Cup
Race on Sterla Fagerhaug.
[MUSIC -- "GOD SAVE
THE QUEEN"]
HAYDEN GILLIM: In Europe,
everybody's more aggressive--
brake a lot earlier, but run
the corners a lot faster.
It's just a little bit harder.
JAKE GAGNE: This is where
you want to be.
If you want to be at the top and
race against the fastest
guys, then Europe is where
you want to be.
DANNY WALKER: You're 12, 13, 14,
15 years old, you've got
to travel clear across the world
to be here, and then
you've got to compete against
the best kids in front of
200,000 fans.
If that's not pressure,
I don't what is.
BENNY SOLIS: The race didn't
go like I wanted it to.
Second to last lap the bike
started sputtering, so I
didn't finish the race.
Yeah, we're going straight
home now.
And then, hopefully, when we get
to Italy it'll be a better
weekend for me.
[BASS MUSIC PLAYING]
BENNY SOLIS: This was actually
the Red Bull suit from the
first year of the Rookies Cup.
I'm just afraid to wear it.
I don't want to crash in it
'cause I'm kind of keeping it
as a memory, 'cause that year
went really good for me.
Most I'm I'm just nervous,
but I'm trying
to calm myself down.
But before a race, if
I'm real calm, I
normally don't do good.
So I know it's a good sign
when I'm nervous.
I can do sometimes 50 to 100
laps 'cause it's pretty small.
But it's a good work out.
I like it.
I play the video game a lot.
I just like to know where the
track goes around, the
configuration and what
turn comes up next.
But the game doesn't help
much with anything,
like bumps or anything.
It's just the shape of the
track and all that.
ADRIANA SOLIS: When they ask
me, like, what kind of
motorcycles?
And I usually say the one
that drags the knee.
And they're like really?
Then I'm like, yeah.
It's like, aren't you scared?
Aren't you?
Yes, I am.
BEN SOLIS: I get scared, but
I've been there, and I know
what Benny's feeling.
And when you race, it's like
OK, crashes are normal.
So when I see my boy crash,
and as long as he gets up
right away or he's moving and
he's OK then I feel OK.
ADRIANA SOLIS: I guess I
changed from fear to
excitement.
It's really exciting
to see him race.
BEN SOLIS: Sometimes we stretch
it to the limit, like
OK we can't pay this bill
because we've got to go buy
tires for the 125.
So my wife kind of gets mad, and
she tells me, well you're
not going to pay the
bill, you're going
to buy him the tires?
And I said well, we
got to go race.
BENNY SOLIS: My mom and my dad
also support me because they
work really hard to
help me do it.
ADRIANA SOLIS: It's
what he wants.
I have to support
him either way.
Because if I was in his
position, he'd be doing the
same for me, right?
Right?
[LAUGHTER]
ADRIANA SOLIS: This is a gift
that God gave my son and he's
putting all his energy
and effort to it.
Now we need to be with him.
BENNY SOLIS: We're
leaving tomorrow
around 11, around there.
And then we arrive Italy, in,
I think, the next day.
ADRIANA SOLIS: I'm the one who
takes them to the airport.
So I stay home nervous, waiting
for them to come back.
BEN SOLIS: I got to think
about it like,
is this really happening?
So it's amazing.