GRADO: Hello.
GREG: Hello, is that
you, Grado?
GRADO: Is that you, Greg?
GREG: It is , aye.
GRADO: Hey, you're live on
fucking, you're on a
documentary.
GREG: That's really
good, Grado.
Right, see that Red Lightning?
See if you don't kick
his ass in it.
I'm telling you, I'm going to
come up and fucking rag doll
him right out of ring
for you, pal.
DAVEY: This is Grado?
GREG: This is Grado, Davey.
This is the one I'm
telling you about.
DAVEY: Well, boot that
fucking Red Lightning
right in the balls!
GREG: Grado!
Grado!
GRADO: Grado!
GREG: Grado!
GRADO: It's Grado.
GREG: Hey, get to that cunt
today, by the way.
GRADO: Aye, I will do.
I will do.
This is the Salt Cot where I'm
going to be getting my Grado
hat off my mate.
There's a space to park.
You alright?
MALE SPEAKER: Who's
that in here?
GRADO: I'm a professional
wrestler.
You never heard of me, Grado?
MALE SPEAKER: Come on over,
I want to talk to you.
I hope it's not on
Crimewatch UK.
GRADO: Are you opening
back up the Metro?
MALE SPEAKER: Aye.
GRADO: This is the most popular
nightclub in Ayrshire.
But it's been shut down.
But this guy's gone and opened
it back up, haven't you?
MALE SPEAKER: Cost
me 90 grand.
GRADO: Is that how much it's
going to cost you?
MALE SPEAKER: Aye.
There's a lot of work
to be done inside.
GRADO: Here, you want to put
on a wrestling show when it
opens back up?
MALE SPEAKER: Well, I
can't promise you.
GRADO: I'll come back down
tomorrow morning.
You should be here
tomorrow morning?
MALE SPEAKER: I'm here
seven days a week.
GRADO: Ideal mate.
MALE SPEAKER: I've been
here 10 years.
GRADO: 10 years?
MALE SPEAKER: Aye.
GRADO: Right, I'm away
anyway my man, right?
MALE SPEAKER: You nervous?
GRADO: Am I nervous?
I'm like that.
Check this out.
MALE SPEAKER: That's for
him for later, yeah.
Here, you want to just
take that now?
GRADO: You think I'll
need these?
MALE SPEAKER: Aye.
GRADO: Go shout,
we want Grado.
MALE SPEAKER: No!
GRADO: We want Grado!
Send it.
Let's do this.
I'll see you tonight.
What time are you going
to be there at?
MALE SPEAKER: Hey,
I'm going up at
about four-ish or something.
GRADO: Don't work
too hard, mate.
MALE SPEAKER: See you later.
GRADO: See your later.
My girlfriend thinks that
I think that I'm famous.
She's always like, just because
you've put up a couple
of YouTube videos doesn't mean
you say you're the man.
You think you're famous.
'Cause I'll say to her listen,
honey, I'm a Z-lister.
I'm a Z-list celebrity,
by the way.
You know what I mean?
She's like all right,
give us a break.
My girlfriend doesn't
even tell her
family that I do wrestling.
She was that affronted.
She was embarrassed,
mortified.
She just doesn't like the idea
of me in a leotard, jumping
about and kidding and fighting,
which is fair enough.
She hates wrestling.
See, going to Glasgow is like
going into London for me, do
you what I mean?
This is like--
I mean, look at Glasgow
now, man.
It's like still a buzz for
me to go into Glasgow.
A lot of folk will think it's
so stupid man, it's Glasgow.
But because I live next to the
sea and live in a wee kind of
seaside town, you come into
Glasgow, man, it's still a bit
of a buzz, do you know
what I mean?
It's a bit of a buzz.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Well,
it's Mark Dallas'
birthday, good friends.
FEMALE SPEAKER: So everyone's
going to get really fucked up.
FEMALE SPEAKER: I'm the manager
of Mikey Whiplash.
FEMALE SPEAKER: She's also a
valet, so she comes on and
gets dirty.
FEMALE SPEAKER: I'm
just her fan.
I'm the fluffer.
FEMALE SPEAKER: That's
fluffing.
Here is real, the blood is real,
the pain is real, the
sexy bits are real, it's
making it for real.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Buckfast,
cider and blood.
FEMALE SPEAKER: And balls.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Oh, well.
FEMALE SPEAKER: All
about the balls.
FEMALE SPEAKER: And boobs.
Boobs.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Balls
and boobs.
FEMALE SPEAKER: I like this.
FEMALE SPEAKER: ICW attracts
the most crazy and the most
daring and individual
of talents.
And we all get together and get
sexy and kick the fuck out
of each other.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Why you rubbing
my back when you could
be rubbing my tits?
DAVEY BOY: My name
is Davey Boy.
WEE MAN: My name's Wee Man.
STEVIE BOY: Stevie Boy.
DAVEY BOY: And together
we are The Bucky Boys.
The gimmick is, we're a couple
of hard NEDs, a couple of
cheeky bastards from Glasgow.
A NED is a Non-Educated
Delinquent.
Say, somebody that doesn't
really pay
attention in school.
He more or less gets stoned,
fights a lot at
weekends, gets jailed.
Just basically breaches the
peace, causes trouble.
STEVIE BOY: We've got
the Wee Man and all.
DAVEY BOY: This is the guy that
started to do it, do you
know what I mean?
Like, singing his wee songs.
I loved them, they
were amazing.
I used to sit there on MSN
like, oh, fucking look
at this cunt, man.
This video's amazing.
DAVEY BOY: Oh, it
was brilliant.
Honest to God, one of the
best guys to manage.
WEE MAN: The Buckfast
is a fortified wine.
I think because it's so highly
caffeinated, that's why the
folk drink it.
STEVIE BOY: It's the "wreck
the house" juice.
WEE MAN: So not only does it get
you steaming, but it gets
you hyper as well.
DAVEY BOY: It's a very
well-known drink in Glasgow.
A lot of your junkies,
your alkies, your
NEDs, they drink it.
So Dallas decided because that
was our gimmick with the NEDs,
he says you'll be called
The Bucky Boys.
And we come out with a box of
Bucky, we drink it, we get mad
with it while we wrestle,
and that is the
best part about it.
WEE MAN: Well, I read somewhere
that even though
it's brewed by Benedictine monks
in Buckfast Abbey in
Devon, England, about 80% or
85% gets sent to Scotland.
They should be praying
to us, not God.
You do get groupies.
DAVEY BOY: "Ring rats," is the
Glasgow version for it.
Quasiomos, Sloths,
you name it.
WEE MAN: They're not so much
belles of the ball as those
that ring the bells.
DAVEY BOY: Ring rats
sometimes get done.
It's like Sauchiehall
Street, down there.
Right, this place is packing
with clunge.
It's amazing.
We're the Bucky Boys,
that's why we're all
dressed like NEDs.
And we're playing there
tomorrow night.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Really?
DAVEY BOY: Aye.
We're going to go for a drink
if you want to come with.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Uh huh.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Where
are you going?
DAVEY BOY: Anywhere we can
get in with trackies.
STEVIE BOY: This is how
you pull in Glasgow.
Tell lassies to go out and see
your poster and then you slip
a pill in their drink,
and fuck on.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Oh, have
you got that on camera?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
DAVEY BOY: Yeah, they'll
fucking believe us now.
There you go, look at that.
FEMALE SPEAKER: That's you!
FEMALE SPEAKER: That's you?
That's actually pretty
good though.
DAVEY BOY: Have you
got Facebook?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
Hey, what's your name though?
I'll add you right now.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Will you
take our names down
and we'll add you?
Thank you!
Bye!
STEVIE BOY: Oh yes.
DAVEY BOY: My boys
grow up so fast.
I'm going to fucking
shag one of them.
Oof!
Yeah, wrestling's
fake alright.
We represent coming out, having
a laugh, smashing
people's heads in,
getting drunk.
I think a lot of people
are like that.
So I think that's why when we
come out, everybody loves us.
STEVIE BOY: I don't care who
you are, what you say, what
your background is, everybody
was a NED at one point.
You hung out at the park, you
smoked dope, you drink.
You had a good time with your
pals, you had a laugh.
I think it just kind
of brings back
those memories to everybody.
Before you went into your
working life and you were
working the 9-5, just
doing the same
mundane piss every day.
All my family were NEDs,
my brothers and
that were all NEDs.
A training center opened
up literally two
minutes from my door.
And it just kind of gave
me something to
channel myself into.
When all my pals were at house
parties, getting steaming and
pumping bods and all that,
I was traveling up
and down the country.
You hear your name getting
called, then all of a sudden
the roof just comes
off the place.
And you walk out there and you
know that every single person
in there's paid a tenner to come
and see you do what you
love doing.
I don't know, it's weird.
It's like you walk out in front
of that crowd and I'm
not just that boy that
came from Paisley,
I'm not just a nobody.
I'm literally a superstar,
if you will.
I'm actually living my dream
for that 10-15 minutes.
But wrestling definitely gets
a bad name for all the drink
and drugs and all that.
But from my personal point of
view, it literally saved me
from what would have been.