Easily snuffed out in an instant,
what is life's meaning?
Oh, man!
I see it, I see it.
We're gonna get closer,
we're gonna get closer.
Over 1,000 tornadoes rip through
the United States every year.
Most do little damage.
This one was different.
There it is.
Oh, my gosh! It's going to go
down that road right there.
Oh, gosh, that is a monster tornado!
Right up there on the back wall,
that was the sanctuary,
that's where the altar was.
Behind that was the house that
I was in, just real close to it.
The tornado destroyed
the city of Joplin, Missouri
and killed 162 people.
That was Green Briar Nursing Home,
and there were five people
died in there.
It's a terrible, terrible sight.
It's an awful sight.
In the face of catastrophe,
this Catholic priest finds comfort
in his religious faith.
I have to believe there's a plan
and that God is going to accomplish
something through this.
I feel like God
is doing something for us.
I think we have to see somewhere
a higher power.
Father Monaghan's faith
must have been tested to the limit
by this terrible experience.
For those of us who don't believe
in any kind of Gods, how do we cope?
More and more people now realise
there is no God.
Yet religious values have dominated
our lives for hundreds of years
and still have a hold over us.
In this series I'm exploring what
reason and science can offer us
in the place of religion
to bring comfort
in the face of death,
help us tell right from wrong,
or provide meaning in an indifferent
and uncaring universe.
So do you think that we in the west
are too materialistic?
I think so.
I suppose Jesus
is an unpaid babysitter.
It's like, if I'm not watching you,
Jesus is.
Do you think mothers are ever
going to meet their babies again?
Yes.
The mothers believe it,
and the fathers.
If there is no God,
what is the meaning of life?
Some of the greatest minds
in history have battled depression
and even toyed with suicide,
struggling to answer
the ultimate question
that we all face - what's the point?
For many, there is no point
if there is no God.
One of the questions I'm most often
asked after giving a lecture
is, "Why do you bother
to get up in the mornings?"
This film is my attempt
to answer that question.
Like most English children,
I was sent to Christian schools
and I was confirmed into the
Church of England at the age of 13.
I believed in the Christian God.
A couple of years later,
I realised it wasn't true.
There was no God.
There was nothing out there.
Many people have had that experience
and different people respond to it
in very different ways.
One of the oddest reactions to
facing up to life without God
was that of the great
Russian novelist Leo Tolstoy.
Like me, Tolstoy was brought up
a Christian
and, as a young man, lost his faith.
He had wealth, a family,
and celebrity status
thanks to his novels War And Peace
and Anna Karenina.
But in his late 40s, he began
to question everything.
Tolstoy was in despair, staring into
an abyss of suicidal depression.
He could find no answer to what
tormented him.
Why do I live?
Is there any meaning in my life
that will not be annihilated
by the inevitability of death?
Desperate to believe that life
had a greater purpose,
Tolstoy scoured philosophy and
the sciences for what it might be,
but his torment only deepened.
You are a temporary incidental
accumulation of particles.
You are a randomly-united
lump of something.
Eventually, Tolstoy found an answer
and stepped back from the abyss.
Mount St Bernard Abbey
in Leicestershire
is home to 36 Cistercian monks.
And this, in essence,
was Tolstoy's solution -
spiritual retreat and devotion.
There are no special announcements
this morning.
Our order is what's called
a contemplative order
so we stay within the confines
of the monastery.
We don't have schools, hospitals
or parishes.
We stay within the monastery.
And you're silent
for part of the day, is that right?
We are, for a good part of the day,
especially in the early morning.
Yes.
So the library is just up here.
Oh, my, this is very nice.
It is a very nice library indeed,
yes.
'Like Tolstoy,
these monks live between two worlds.
'Their library is better
than I would have expected.'
Stephen Hawking's Universe,
Just Six Numbers, Carl Sagan.
Excellent, very good.
I wish I'd brought some of my books
to present to you!
Oh, there's one, there! We have one.
Oh, really?
Richard Dawkins,
Modern Science Writing.
Oh, excellent! The Oxford Book of
Modern Science Writing. Very good.
There may be others, erm...
Well, I won't do that usual thing
authors do of looking for them!
Tolstoy's answer to the threat
of meaninglessness
was to go back
and consciously embrace God.
He does exist.
I had only to recognise this
for an instant
and I would feel the possibility
and joy of living.
I returned to a belief in God.
I now knew
that I could not live without it.
As an old man,
Tolstoy separated himself from
society to lead a Christian sect.
He ended up, like these monks,
a religious recluse.
But I want to know, can a person
find meaning and fulfilment,
devoting himself to spiritual life?
Brother Michael, one of
the youngest monks in the order,
has, like Tolstoy, given up
the world and earthly possessions.
My life I direct towards God
and finding a relationship with God,
and I find meaning in that,
and as...hopefully I grow towards
God, I'll grow towards other people.
What do you miss about the life
you could've had?
Erm...
This morning I had to go to
the chemist,
and on the way out,
there was a young lady with her child
and as they walked down the street,
they had Tigger the tiger
holding between their hands.
Tigger from Winnie the Pooh?
Tigger from Winnie The Pooh,
and it stirred my heart.
My heart sort of...
You feel you'd have liked
to have had a child of your own?
Yeah. It's just like...yeah.
I've given up a family,
which is part of the life.
I worry that these men
are running from reality
and squandering their lives.
Isn't facing up to the challenges
of the real world
what makes life worthwhile?
Can you talk while polishing?
Yes.
Brother William gave up a career
as a banker
to join the monastery ten years ago.
The meaning of life for me
is being there for other people.
Yes.
And it's a sacrifice
that I'm willing to make.
But if you want to do good
to other people,
it seems a slightly odd way
to go about it
to shut yourself away
in a monastery.
Couldn't you do more good if you
were out there in the outside world?
You can see how our prayers
affect people's lives,
and how they've come through
a personal problem,
that they've felt our support here.
(THEY CHANT)
These monks find meaning in devotion
to God, in prayer and solitude.
They're entitled to their beliefs
of course.
But, what a slender life to lead
when you could be out there
in the real world,
teaching, learning,
maybe doing good.
It seemed to me to be a sort of
sadly inadequate life.
Not really a life at all.
Just very, very sad.
Of course, I don't believe in God,
but I do understand
Tolstoy's predicament.
I just don't see how cloistering
yourself away like this
can add meaning to life.
Perhaps a better approach would be
to embrace life's uncertainties
and take a few risks?
Many of our greatest minds
have struggled with the idea
that if there is no God,
life has no meaning.
One of the bleakest reactions
was that of Graham Greene.
Greene was of course to become
one of the great Catholic writers
of the 20th century,
but as a young man he was agnostic.
He was also reckless
and extremely bored.
He carried what he called
his "war against boredom"
to a shocking and dangerous extreme.
Greene lived
to the ripe old age of 86,
but statistically he shouldn't
have made it past 19.
"I remember very clearly
the afternoon I found the revolver
"in the brown deal corner cupboard
"in a bedroom which I shared with my
elder brother.
"It was the early autumn of 1923.
"I slipped the revolver
into my pocket
"and the next I remember,
was crossing the Berkhamstead Common
towards Ashridge Beaches."
Greene had been reading a book
about soldiers during the Russian
Civil War.
Away from the frontline,
they invented hazardous games to
avoid boredom.
"This was not suicide, whatever
a coroner's jury might have said,
"it was a gamble with five chances
to one against an inquest.
"I slipped a bullet into a chamber
and holding the revolver behind
my back spun the chambers round.
"I put the muzzle of the revolver
into my right ear."
CHAMBER CLICKS
"There was a minute click and
looking down I could see the charge
had moved into the firing position.
"I was out by one."
Graham Greene lived by chance.
He had absolutely no control
over the outcome
when he pulled the trigger.
What Greene did was utterly crazy.
No matter how bored I was,
I would never trust my life to
chance in such a way.
But the reality is that
we have less control over our lives
than we might like to think.
When a tornado struck Joplin,
Missouri in May 2011,
death and
destruction were indiscriminate.
The young Graham Greene would have
embraced the truth of that tornado.
Joplin's fate hung on chance, just
like his game of Russian roulette.
While 7,000 buildings were blown
away, others survived unscathed.
There is tremendous survivor's guilt
in the community.
That, I haven't experienced before.
Survivor's guilt meaning why did I
survive when someone else died?
Why did that little child die, I'm
70 years of age, why didn't you take
me, God?
Why should that mother
lose that child?
But do you think he could have
stopped the tornado?
Of course he could, he could stop
anything he wants.
Then, why didn't he?
Er...because we don't understand,
it's a mystery, he is a mystery.
I can't intellectually explain that.
And if someone tries to do that,
they're gonna come to a dead end
and say it makes no sense.
It's almost moving the way religious
people struggle, twist and turn
to find some excuse for this,
some sort of meaning,
some part of God's plan.
If it was part of anybody's plan,
what an unthinkably awful plan it
would have to be.
But even if you're an atheist, the
idea of living or dying by chance
alone is hard to accept.
Atheists may think
they've given up God,
but it's only human to cling
to the idea that "things happen
for a reason".
If you look at the misfortune
and fortune in human life,
in the universe generally,
there is no pattern as relates
to people,
the pattern is entirely
related to physics.
The universe has exactly the
properties we'd expect if there was
no plan, no design,
no aim, just blind
indifferent...forces of nature.
If, like Graham Greene, you
understand life as a game of chance,
and if you believe there is no God
pulling your strings, making plans
for you, why not just play the game?
The great gambling game of life.
Unbelievable place.
It's sort of trying to be
the seven wonders of the world.
Look at that medieval castle there.
There's the Statue of Liberty.
There's a replica
of Venice somewhere.
There's the Chrysler Building.
I'm often told that my vision of a
godless future is just as devoid of
meaning as Las Vegas.
That without God,
all you're left with is materialism
and mindless slot machines.
But I've come here
because I think Las Vegas
reveals something fascinating,
humanity's deep-seated belief
that we can prevail over chance.
People come here filled with hope.
Everybody knows the casinos
have a terrific mark-up percentage
for the house
and yet they still go on feeding
that hope and feeding the slot
machines and losing their money.
Hey, Richard. How's it going?
OK.
You winning?
No, I've lost every time so far.
Well, now your luck's gonna change,
because I know physics!
OK. He may look like a card sharp,
but the gentleman in the shades
is actually a physicist.
Leonard Mlodinow is fascinated by
how human beings are incapable
of understanding chance.
32.
I won and I lost.
When people are playing
these games we see around us,
am I right that many of them,
even if there's absolutely no bias
between red and black,
many people will say, "Oh, well it
has been red, red, red, red for such
a long time, it's black's turn."
That's right. That's called
The Gambler's Fallacy.
I you flip a coin a zillion times,
you're going to get
about half a zillion heads
and half a zillion tails.
So people's thinking goes, if they
bothered to logically think about it,
is that,
"OK, I've seen 10 tails in a row,
"so if it's gonna be half heads
and half tails, the heads better
catch up."
But that's not the way it works.
OK.
You could throw it a zillion times
and get all heads.
The point about our brain is that it
insists on seeing order, meaning and
pattern even where thereis none.
It's a very human characteristic
to fool ourselves
that we are in control.
In today's world,
it seems that we make more mistakes
seeing patterns that aren't there
rather than missing patterns
that are there.
In fact, there's a great experiment
on that, they put a rat in front of
a red light and a green light.
And the red light and the
green light flash without any
pattern, at random.
But the green light flashes 75% of
the time, and the red light flashes
25% of the time.
And the rat, if it guesses
correctly which is going to flash,
it gets a little sugar water.
So when they let the rats do this,
they see after a while that the
green light is flashing more than
the red light
and they just start guessing
green, green, green, green, green
every time.
And they get it right 75% of the
time and are happy with that.
That's what you should do.
Yeah.
But people, we think we know better,
right?
So when they put humans
in front of such an experiment,
they won't do what the rat does.
They've seen that it's 75% green
and they'll guess a pattern.
They'll go, green, green, red,
green, green, green, red.
They'll start spewing out
these red and greens
in some weird pattern
that's tailored to be 75% green
and 25% red,
thinking that they can beat the
system, just like the people here
in the casino think they can.
And when you do that, you end up
about, I think, 60% of the time you
get it right, instead of 75%.
And so the humans are out performed
by a rat.
That's because we see patterns
where there aren't any. That's
just the way our minds work.
Too clever by half. Or too clever
by three quarters, in this case.
Yes.
I'm going to throw everything
on my birthday.
Yours is the 26th? Mine is the 26th!
Oh, wow!
Both our birthdays are the 26th!
So... (LAUGHS)
26 is even so I'm going to win
that too. Maybe I should put this
on odd?
Perhaps this is part of the
explanation why religion evolved in
the first place,
it satisfied our desperate desire to
find meaning and order in the chaos.
In playing the ultimate game
of chance, Russian roulette,
the young Graham Greene
grasped what so many of us fail to,
there is no pattern.
26! 26!
We have no control.
Ooh! We came so close!
Greene took his chances
and pulled the trigger
on another five occasions
before the effect of what he called
"his adrenaline drug" wore off.
What Greene did may seem crazy, but
there is a grim logic to it. Seize
the reins. Dance with death.
You're going to die anyway.
CHAMBER CLICKS
Happily for Greene,
he beat the odds.
Greene would later convert to
Roman Catholicism,
but Russian roulette of a kind
stayed with him.
As a journalist and spy,
Greene risked his life
in numerous war zones.
"The fear of ambush served me
just as effectively
"as the revolver from the corner
cupboard in the life-long war
against boredom."
Tolstoy found meaning
by hiding himself away.
Greene
went in the opposite direction.
But the next great mind
I shall consider
tried to argue meaning into even the
most meaningless toil imaginable.
More and more of us now do not
believe in God or life after death.
We live and then we die,
and that's it.
We are born by chance and our lives
are shaped by chance events.
I know this is a difficult pill
to swallow for many people,
especially those for whom religion
still has a hold over their lives.
Many people have struggled
to come to terms with the reality
of a purely physical universe.
So, how do we find meaning?
The Second World War laid bare the
extent of man's capacity for evil.
In Paris, philosophers like
Albert Camus met in cafes like this
to try to make sense
of the brutality.
"Without the aid of eternal values,
it is legitimate
"and necessary to wonder
whether life has a meaning."
Camus was interested
in what he called "the absurd",
that our life must have
meaning for us to value it,
but we live in a world
that offers no meaning.
Unlike Tolstoy and Graham Greene,
Camus rejected religion
as a source of the meaning
he craved.
He found inspiration
in another myth.
The story of a man whom
the Ancient Greek gods had cursed.
Camus consoled himself
with the myth of Sisyphus,
in which Sisyphus was condemned
to spend his whole time
rolling a boulder up a mountain and
then it rolled to the bottom again,
he went to the bottom
and rolled it up again,
and this went on forever.
For Camus, accepting even this
most futile and repetitive of tasks
and not giving up, itself had value.
"The struggle itself towards
the heights
"is enough to fill a man's heart.
"We must imagine Sisyphus happy."
Camus took comfort from this
because by going to the bottom
of the mountain again
and rolling the stone back up,
he was at least doing something.
But can we really find meaning
in futile work?
Sisyphus may seem admirable
to a French intellectual,
but I don't see the appeal
of resigning oneself
to life's injustices.
India -
one of the fastest developing
and most unequal
economies in the world.
The human condition doesn't
come much more human than this,
or much more extreme.
Everything's going on -
the noise, the bustle.
It's like an ant-heap of activity.
It's a terrifying
and yet rather a moving sight.
This latter-day Sisyphus
is called Hori Lal.
His struggle is to clean the streets
and the public lavatory
here in Varanasi.
His task is as endless as Sisyphus'
boulder-rolling.
These streets are never clean.
Do you enjoy your job?
TRANSLATION: Yes, yes.
I enjoy doing my job.
Do you do the same thing every day?
TRANSLATION: Yes, I do it every day.
How long have you been
doing this job?
TRANSLATION: It must be 20 years now.
What hope do you have
for the future?
TRANSLATION: What hope can I have?
I have a job to do
and I will continue doing it.
It's fate. What we have been made,
we will remain. It can't be changed.
I suppose there is something
a bit inspiring about Hori Lal's
cheerfulness and good humour
in the face of life's hardships.
Perhaps it's what Camus saw
in the myth of Sisyphus,
and it's certainly a wonderful
antidote to us whingers
in the rich West,
when we dare to moan about
patchy mobile phone reception,
or the cost of supermarket food.
But what bothers me is why Hori Lal
has been cursed like Sisyphus.
It's because here,
life's lottery begins at birth,
thanks to the confines
of the ancient caste system.
This is the Sunday edition
of the Hindustan Times
and it's got a section called
"Matrimonials",
in which fathers advertise
for husbands for their daughters.
And there's a section
called "Brides",
where men advertise for wives.
And the men are usually described
as handsome.
The women are often described
as homely,
which I presume means home-loving.
But a curious thing
about this matrimonials page
is the way it's classified.
There are headings like Brahmin,
and other names from
the ancient Hindu caste system,
whereby society is stratified
into levels, into separate castes,
which are not supposed
to marry each other.
Ancient Hindu scripture
divided society
into four distinct groups
that you could be born into -
scholars...
warriors...
merchants...
and labourers.
Falling outside this system
were the Dalits, the untouchables,
who, like Hori Lal,
were condemned to shovel
the excrement of the higher castes.
This is where I think
Camus got it wrong.
Rather than accept fate,
surely meaning is found
when we revolt
against outrageous fortune?
Mahendra?  Yes.
Very nice to meet you.
Please come.  Thank you.
TRANSLATION: When my father died,
I was told that
because there is no money
in the family now,
you can't study any more.
At that time I was very sad
because I had this dream
from the start, I have to study.
Like Hori Lal, Mahendra is a Dalit.
His father died when he was 14 years
old, leaving the family penniless.
Mahendra spent the next four years
working as a bonded labourer,
weaving saris.
But, unlike Sisyphus,
Mahendra defied the gods
and threw his boulder away.
TRANSLATION: I had to face so much
discrimination in the society
for being a Dalit that I felt
education could be a good medium
to get out of the system.
A lot of people in your position
would probably have given up.
I hugely admire you for not giving
up, but what drove you at that time?
TRANSLATION: I had always felt
that I have to become
a part of the mainstream society.
And that is why I have this thing
that I have to study a lot
and earn money so that
I can reach mainstream society.
Today, Mahendra is studying
for a master's degree
and wants to fight the Dalit cause -
help other boulder-rollers break
free from their struggle.
It is wonderful to see how
an individual can bring himself
out of poverty and downtrodden-ness.
With Mahendra,
we come closer to finding
at least one worthwhile
meaning of life.
He is creating his own meaning,
but it has a deeper purpose, making
a difference to others as well.
We can find meaning in struggle,
but we have to define
our own meaning in our own struggle,
not one dictated by the gods, by
authority or by accident of birth.
So I think meaning is subjective,
something personal
we may not all agree on.
But that shouldn't be an invitation
to egotism or self-absorption.
Here in northern India,
Westerners still come in droves
in the hope of finding some deeper
meaning in Eastern mysticism.
People go up mountains
for refreshment,
they go up mountains for wisdom.
Moses went up Mount Sinai
and came down
with the tablets
of traditional Hebrew wisdom.
There are lots of people
who come from all over the world
to a place like this,
up a mountain like this,
where there's a Tibetan monastery,
seeking what they would call
spiritual wisdom.
Geshe Lhakdor
is a Master of Tibetan Buddhism.
He's the Dalai Lama's
official translator and archivist.
The complete teaching
of the Buddha is aimed towards
transforming your mental outlook
because the ultimate purpose
is to remove all kinds of problems
and sufferings, and problems
and sufferings and disturbances
cannot be removed
by relying on external forces
or external material sources,
or your relatives and friends.
At the end of the day,
the real source of long-lasting peace
and happiness
has to come from within.
For a Buddhist,
what matters is accepting
that reality will always change.
To be happy in this changing
reality, Buddhists teach that
we must eliminate our attachments
to people and possessions.
I sort of half understand that.
They try to get that sense
of direction or happiness
from material accumulation, from
marriage, from wealth, from name,
but in all these cases here or there,
they get a lot of problems,
a lot of difficulties.
So do you think that we in the West
are too materialistic
in our way of life?
I think so, to be honest.
I think so, I think so.
I think I would agree with you
that one doesn't want to devote
one's life to accumulating material,
hedonistic happiness.
I'm not sure that
I would look inward though.
I think I would I might get
happiness from...
music and from science....
Exactly. When you do something
that is creative,
something that really satisfies
your inner arts, you know.
Yes, but meditating and looking
inwards doesn't sound to me
as though that's really doing that.
Perhaps it helps...
Of course, of course.
The peace and happiness,
the tranquillity that you get
when you know how to stay alone
and go within
cannot be measured by anything else.
While I agree that
an unhealthy consumerism
dominates our lives today,
how convincing is it
that we should detach ourselves from
the real world through meditation?
The great minds we've looked at,
Tolstoy, Greene and Camus,
all stood out
in deeply religious times.
But we are now at a point
in history, in the West at least,
when more people than ever
are atheist.
So if we are finally shaking off
the influence of God,
how nowadays do we find meaning?
I'm going to talk to an outspoken
satirist of modern life.
That's that. No. That's that.
Religion is that "nooooo!"
We've seen that there isn't
a simple, single answer
to the meaning of life
in a world without God.
Meaning is something
we need to carve out for ourselves.
We have to find our own meaning
from the opportunities
and challenges
that life throws our way,
even if that does mean
defying convention sometimes.
I'm going to meet a man who has
definitely defined his own way
and made a huge success of it,
but he has ruffled
quite a few feathers in doing so.
Thanks to everyone in the room
for being good sports.
Thanks to NBC.
Thanks to Hollywood Foreign Press.
Um, thank you for watching at home.
And thank you to God
for making me an atheist.
When I signed off the Golden Globes
by saying...
and thanked God
for making me an atheist,
now, clearly,
that was a play on words.
Um, it was a little bit of
a redressing the balance to everyone
who thanks God for winning an award.
I've never seen so much outrage
as thanking God
for making me an atheist.
Now, correct me if I'm wrong.
If God exists,
He did make me an atheist, didn't he?
Didn't He? Why did He do that?
I read about that.
It was astonishing.
It really did cause outrage, did it?
You usually have to murder
and eat someone
to get that much publicity
in America.
How funny.
Yeah.
How very funny.
When did you first realise
that you didn't believe in God?
My next brother, Bob,
when I was about eight...
He was 11 years older than me
so he was about 19.
And I was drawing a picture
of Jesus for Bible studies
and he, er...
He came in and he looked at it
and he went,
"Why do you believe in God?"
And my mum went "Bob!"
And I knew from body language.
Why didn't she even want
the question?
Oh. She was hiding something from me.
And I thought about it
and it all made sense.
Then I started reading
and, um, I've, er...
I've been an atheist for 40 years.
I love that some people
mistake atheists for Satanists.
Oh, yes.
I go,
"No, I don't believe in him either."
He's just as ludicrous.
I don't believe in him.
Why can't God sort out Satan?
Why can't he? He's all-powerful.
What's he doing? What's he doing?
'So, why does a 21st-century British
atheist get up in the morning?'
I think you have to have worth.
I think you have to feel in yourself
you have worth.
Friends, family,
a loving relationship...
Um...
Just because we're human
and that's how we're built.
And for me personally,
something creative.
It doesn't have to be painting
the Sistine Chapel.
It can be gardening,
but I think you have to do something
and enjoy it
and fill you free time and stand back
and think, "I did that."
These are all reasons to stay around
for as long as you can.
I would agree with all that,
and I think I would add
"understanding" as well.
Religious believers tell me
they're puzzled that non-believers
like Ricky Gervais and me
can find any meaning or purpose
in a godless existence.
But, for me,
the world teems with meaning.
It is up to each of us
to give our own lives meaning
through our work,
our relationships, and passions,
and, I think,
through one other thing -
understanding who we are,
and trying to understand
why we're here.
That has been the mission
of Western science,
the most important tool
I believe mankind has ever invented.
For centuries,
human eyes could see clearly
no further than only a few miles.
Telescopes enabled our eyes
to leap outwards,
and see distant stars
millions of miles away.
Even better than that,
a telescope
is a kind of time machine.
Because it takes light so long
to reach us from a distant star,
when you look at a distant star
you're looking backwards in time,
maybe hundreds of millions of years.
And if you look at a distant galaxy,
you may be looking at the origin
of the universe itself.
You're looking at the very beginning
of space and time -
the Big Bang.
Humanity's gaze has also turned
towards inner space.
Microscopes have unlocked
our understanding of the cells
that make up all living things
and revealed the world of
the smallest and simplest organisms
around us and in us.
The new science of genetics
has unexpectedly
completely revolutionised
and unified our understanding
of life on Earth.
Meanwhile, physics has discovered
particles smaller by far
even than the atom.
And at laboratories like CERN,
scientists studying the collisions
of these particles
are on the cusp of understanding
how the universe got started
in the first place.
The poet John Keats voiced what
many people fear about science -
..that, in explaining the world,
it makes it less amazing,
less extraordinary, somehow banal.
"Philosophy will clip
an Angel's wings,
"Conquer all mysteries
by rule and line,
"Empty the haunted air
and gnomed mine -
"Unweave a rainbow."
Keats could not have been
more wrong.
Isaac Newton's unweaving
of the rainbow
led directly to a massive
deepening and widening
of our understanding
of the universe.
It led to James Clerk Maxwell's
theory of electromagnetism
and from there to Einstein's
special theory of relativity.
If you think the rainbow has poetic
mystery, you should try relativity.
Science does the opposite
of making things banal.
It's about unleashing curiosity and
uncovering more mysteries to solve.
We take so much for granted,
we've become anaesthetised by our
familiarity with what's around us.
Science shakes off the anaesthetic
and we look again
with new and clearer eyes.
If you found
a bramble in your garden,
you'd probably think it
an annoying weed.
But like every other plant
and every other animal,
it is an astonishing piece
of natural engineering.
A leaf is a chemical factory.
It's a flat-roofed factory and
on the flat roof are solar panels
gathering sunlight to drive
the machinery of the factory.
There are wheels, almost literally
wheels going round and round,
biochemical wheels,
driven by the energy from the sun
and manufacturing food
for the plant - sugars.
And the sugars are then piped
in this, what almost
looks like a river system,
into the central stem
and into the rest of the plant.
That's where all the food
for the plant comes from
and even OUR food comes from that
because we eat plants,
or we eat animals that eat plants,
and so the energy
that drives our bodies,
every one of our trillions of cells
comes ultimately from the sun
and it flows down a river system
like this
ultimately into us.
It gets even better - the genetic
code that's used by this plant
is the same as the one
that's used by you.
Even 50% of the genes are the same.
This plant is your cousin.
Just a weed?
'Some people would say that
'the scientific view is rather bleak
and cold. Do you find it bleak?'
There's no God-fearing person
of any religion
who...feels as much awe as me
as when I see...
a mountain or a tree.
Or the stars.
Or, um...
anything in science
and nature and art.
And you and I are privileged
to be here to enjoy it,
even if for a short time.
That's a wonderful thought.
We cherish this life.
It's sacred...
so enjoy it.
This is all we've got
and it's brilliant.
Make the most of it.
It's brilliant!
It's amazing!
We are lucky to be born.
We win the lottery
just in being here at all.
Your unique identity
is the result of one sperm
amongst hundreds of millions
fertilising one particular egg
in one particular sexual exchange.
And the same lucky break
had to favour your ancestors
in every generation
back to the very beginning of life.
And we are luckier still as
individuals to have been born NOW.
We have so much available to us -
possible only through
the understanding
that science has already given us.
Just look how far
we've come in my lifetime -
we've got life-saving medicine,
super-computers, the internet.
We can travel further and faster,
higher and deeper than ever before.
We constantly push
at the frontiers of possibility.
Imagine what's still to come!
We are made by the laws of physics
working through
four billion years of evolution.
We have a brief window of life
through which to see the universe
and understand
how we came to be in it.
The truth may not always be
comforting in the face of suffering,
but it has a majesty of its own.
That's what I tell people
when they ask me,
"Why do you bother
to get up in the mornings?"