Like at all our Extension meetings, as our gentlemen know that were on our
2009 dairy days, we start on time and end on time.
So, we really
want to respect to your time.
commitments as well.
So,
we're just about ready to to launch here,
are we not Jim?
According to my watch, I've got about
a minute to go.
We had about 150 people indicating
interest for signing up for it.
Some locations have more than a couple of
people at a couple of universities had indicated
were never going to pull in and I know of one
feed company that thinking also
of utilizing the information.
We will see where it goes from there and
our list just keeps keeps getting
longer and that's exciting to see.
Good news Jim! The price is right
and I'll be honest with you, we were kinda
hoping that maybe the webinar is
method
that we may explore even further here in
the future and that's all you are well
aware of state budgets certainly at Illinois
and Extension are really really tight and
at some point this may go cost-recovery.
Which means there will be a fee
attached to this and you should be thinking about
that. There will be a survey at the end,
I believe,
that's going to ask the questions.
This time we are not going to ask that
but, the question is do you see value in this
and sometime in the future, maybe
it will be Dave's webinar.
We will ask if you would
pay a dollar or would you pay
five dollars for it
or something like that. At this point
where he's trying to get our feet wet
and and hopefully we don't have too many
glitches today.
This is our first launch and
we have our IT group here.
Jim Baltz leads that
group here and there are a
couple others along with us.
Louann Wilcox and in Jen Roth.
They're all players in this one as well
and then of course online you'll
hear Dave Fisher bit later and Dick
Wallace. So, they'll be part of this
as a resource people
they have microphones turned out so if
have a specific health question
Dr. Wallace it would to be very logical if
he first took a
look at it. If we get some questions in
terms of
forages and facilities and things like that
obviously Dave Fisher would be
a logical choice andof course
you can also type in answers,
questions, and comments
as you go on as well.
So, I think we ar ready to go.
Are we not Jim?
We want to welcome everybody to the first
University of Illinois, Dairy webinar!
Co-sponsored with DAIReXNET.
At this point our topic is feeding
challenges with todays milk prices.
We all know that it's pretty a hot topic at
least here in the United States. I think our
Canadian colleagues have to feel
a little more reassured  but Im not sure
about our colleagues in China
and places like that.
We have several different countries
represented here today and so hopefully
you will
find value for that.
I'll be driving the power points here
today
and as we mentioned earlier we are going
to have a second one
and you'll see this at the end of
the program as well but we thought we'd
just indicate that we'd like to try this
again. You can see the the date,
the time, and the player
listed up there and there's the
registration URL or if you are
somewhat motivated,
click on that just like you did for
this one here today.
So lets go and get moving on if we can and
I'll get into this.
and this slides says
"Economic Expectations"
and maybe the worst should be survival.
at this stage of the game. Notice the work profit
doesn't pop up here because most dairymen
now in the Midwest and the U.S. see no
profit at all.
The bad news now is that milk prices have dropped
5 dollars per hundred-weight and in some areas
ever higher than that because of their
blend prices.
The good news, feed prices have
also drop somewhat from before
when we were back at
7 dollar a bushel of corn
and some of these higher feed price. So,
there's a little bit help there as well.
If you're milking a less than about a
130 cows the MILC program, this is the
milk income lose
program that's done by the
government is now available, you see
that will help us out a little bit.
The bad news is that we saw this
in fact on the news in Illinois,
if you want to call the good
news, switch about a 100 dollars per
month is what we're looking at kind of a
lose.
The folks out in  New Mexico and
Arizona just last week said the numbers
close to a 150 dollars per
cow per month.
There is some liquidation going on at this
stage of the game.
I'm going to my next power point that
looks at
one of the questions we have a one like,
when might this thing turn around?
Folks, there really is a
pretty good news on that one to be
vey honest.
Perhaps, I will update that
for you right now.
The first quarter of these were
the projections, just literally
a week ago, the first quarter
of 2009 this is class 3
milk just be well aware.
We will get into the details on that
but, for us in Illinois we'll probably
put 1 dollar, 1.50 dollar, to maybe
2 dollars on top of that depending on the
blend price and the differential and
from the quality premiums and milk components.
The second quarter eleven 11.24,
the good news is,
we just found this yesterday the milk
went up
to its max level.
and those of you who want to go online right now
we now have it in May, June and July.
As of today we're looking at are almost
12.50 to 13.00
dollar milk.
So, the second quarter could be up 1.5 and
the fourth quarter is all
over 16.
So, that's kind of exciting news at
this point and along with 16,000
cows that left the dairy industry
here in February.
Certainly, things are happening out there
on the farm.
We did mention briefly as we talked
about surviving in these times,
again in the U.S. this is your
deficiency payments.
Again, you know it only counts for your first
2.9 million pounds of milk
but, in the February price it was 1.63
If we look forward that prices
almost going to be at 2 dollars in March.
At least projections if you
look at what's ahead
that's what the tables are showing,
1.93 in March a 1.60
in April.
So anyway, that's
another factor that'll come into play
and certainly you know if
you're doing a farmer here you
usually want to be aware of this program,
regardless of your herd size because it looks
like that the next 2 or 3 months.
What's the good news on this chart?
It looks like in September
numbers get very low which means
the price of milk is coming up.
Well what are we going to talk about then? I
thought we just set the stage a little bit
to get an idea about where the prices are,
when they might change, what are some of
the strategies,
and of course being one of the question
we would all like an answer from the three
of us is: where can i find
that 5 dollars per hundred-weight?
More specifically: what changes
can i make
to save 5 dollars per hundred-weight?
Unfortunately, there is one right answer
there Jim, the answer is don't feed your cows.
If you don't feed your cows you will
save about 5 dollars
per hundred-weight.
I think there is some negative downside to
that but at least they're sure academic
answer you have.
So, what I'm going to go through our these
three points: feed benchmarking, the
three golden rules, and then
alternatives. Dave and Dick will come in
and be players in that part of the
program as well.
Let's start going through what I call
feed benchmarking.
I put this up the same this to say from
Illinois dairy days back in January
and some focus meetings in February
in Illinois. Farmers are making
decision.
Bankers are forcing farmers to make
decisions. Farmers are asking nutritious
and veterinarians to make changes
well.
All these are pretty scary,
all these have been told,
and the one that really scares me is two
bankers have told their people
you'll feed only what's on the farm.
Which means
corn
and forages.
That has some serious ramifications
as well.
Let's go look at this economic
benchmark.
We will go through this modestly fast but,
every dairy farmer, every consultant,
every individual
has this type of a budget.
This is illinois, we will be very clear at
times that
the data is very biased and
specifically laid out but, this says
pretty much today what is the cost but
groceries in front of our girls.
You can see we have broken down into
six different categories. I go right up
and say I'm going to pay someone
10 cents a cow
to do that do the work.
That may include balance rations,
interpreting test results,
maybe spotting good feed buys, and things
like that.
Here you can see here that magic
50 pounds of dry matter
that is costing 4.44.
Now, let's go to the next  one and this
is the one you want to circle
or go back to or write down quickly.
Here's is where you are going to get
your grades.
See that top number? There is
your 4.44.
It then generates these next four
benchmarks.
The first one is feed cost per pound of dry
matter and that is .09 cents. If you can feed cows
for .09 per pound of dry matter
here in the Midwest but
when I was in Arizona about a
month ago that is .02 cents higher.
.02 cents of dry matter per pound higher.
Well those folks are now
looking at another extra dollar in their
feed cost but, luckily we hear in Illinois,
Wisconsin, and Iowa don't face that
as far as that goes.
So, .09 cents becomes a aid.
Feed cost per hundred-weight of milk notice
that sits somewhere around 6 to
6.50 to 7 dollars.
What do you have to see?
You have to see those cows that
produce more milk in the same feed stuff
produces cheaper. So, anytime you start
messing with milk yield then be well
aware you're gonna start
playing the game of losing some of these
benchmark numbers.
I'm saying if you can't feed your
cows 6.50 per hundred-weight here in the
Midwest you're doing a very nice job.
If you get it down below 6 dollars
more power to you.
Income over feed cost
actually gets outdated everyday
and some people love
this figure.
I don't use it very much because I can't
control the price of
my milk.
That drives this number. I mean a
year ago this number looked a lot
better and you as a producer had nothing
to impact.
You do impact feed cost per amount of dry matter,
feed cost per weight of milk, and the last
one feed efficiency.
This one is getting lots traction
now.
Feed efficiency and suddenly dairy farmers
are interested.
Consultants are interested saying, maybe
that's important to know how much milk
do I get from each pound of dry matter.
Your aim
is 1.5.
If you get your feed efficiency over
1.5
you're doing an awfully good job. You are doing a
really job.
Why is that important?
All I did was take a cow,
a herd,
a string of cows producing
70 pounds of milk
at .09 cents a pounds of dry matter.
If I can support that 70 pounds
of milk with 50 pounds of dry matter
versus 44 pounds of dry matter
that's a savings of .56 cents
a cow per day.
A huge number, that's a huge number.
I would argue if you are in a room and
lectured with me in class or
at a conference
all of us should be able to find
.50 cents a day
and if after this seminar is over and you
have not found .50 cents
then Dave Fisher, Dick Wallace, and
Mike Hutjens haven't done a very good job.
bIwould argue all of you should
be able to get some worth
between 1.5 and 1.6
by doing some rather interesting
strategic thing
that we will touch on here very briefly.
So, that's a powerful power point where
feed efficiency is this critical,
critical number.
Now, if you don't think it varies, it is
a very busy slide, in fact  Jim Anders put
this slide together.
I just shows about 67
different farms here in Illinois collected
in January
of 2009.
Guys and gals these are pretty good farms.
Notice the yellow number that's
the low ball number and
the blue number is the high number.
Just look at the differences
on the bottom 3 numbers
on feed cost. We see some herds here
on feed costs getting down
as low as 1.41 so, that's
a high group TMR.
Now notice that is also the most
expensive cost of pound per dry matter.
Don't you miss that!
In other words, this dairyman
has gotten a
very good ration put together
very expensive ratio. His cows
understand that
and so they respond very well.
There's a low group versus a high group.
We will touch on that very briefly
and remember this slide.
Look at this slide over here
on feed efficiency.
One of my herds is 1.4,
most of my herds are sitting around
1.51-1.61.
This shows us, all of these herds are in
Illinois, that in most cases almost are literally
within a 20
to 30 mile radius of where our meeting
was being held
over at Freeport. So it is
some amazing data.
So, let's look at the bottom line as we
finish up here
and this comes from Bruce Jones,
Doctor Bruce Jones, at the University of
Wisconsin Madison and this came out of
one of its publication several months
ago he said
here are 3 of the big items.
He's got feed cost in a range.
most of my Illinois guys are
going to be on the right side.
I've got an Illinois herd, probably going
to be the left side, he's milking
either 1,200 or 3,000
cows so,  certainly
it makes a difference. Feed cost,
non-feed cost,
labor costs, in fact Dave Fisher
and a colleague down in
his area other, work with these numbers and
they come out almost identically coming
at a little different direction.
The point simply is that notice that top-line:
no debt payment,
no return on assets, no return management
skills or salary
but, simply says we probably need
in Illinois somewhere between
15.50 for milk
to cover everything
You can see some of the other farms
can get around
11:50 to 12 dollars because they can
survive at least covering these costs
as well.
So, that's another question that has been
raised by some of our students and that is
well where do we have to be to cover
costs?
That's why I'm pretty excited this morning
to see that actually you could lock in
16 dollar milk
for the last three months of
of of this year
and of course you can actually contract
your milk. Now question is are you going to do
that?
That's another question for
another story and
we can do that for a Q&A.
Okay, that part care of takes
care of the first third of the
presentation.
Something what I call benchmarks numbers
comparisons
how competitive are you, what do you
have to have and where is your profit margin
going to start to occur?
I'm not going to my second part and every
time you see these jersey cows
it simply says were changing a topic
or an emphasis to try to keep you with me
as we go through the webinar.
Webinars are deadly and
they can be really tough
because there's no way to see
faces
and see what people are saying like what is this
guy talking about?!
So, let's go to through these golden rules
and we'll go through them modestly
fast.  If you read
a couple of farm magazines these have
been picked up
a couple of different sources. These
are golden rules that simply state
number one:
I'd never give up milk
and if you are a banker get
your ears on.
If you're a consultant get your ears on.
If you're dairy farmer having a hard time
paying bills
you've just gotta live with
that.
The reason is that I bring up
this point now a useful guideline and
it simply says if we look at dry
matter, that means
grocery that feed the cow,
versus what she produces in milk sales.
The thumb for for Jersey's is
2 pounds of milk per pound of dry matter.
Actually Holstein's is about 2.5
but let's just say to because it's easy
to see.
So, most dairy cows should give you
that extra pound of dry matter
or that pound of dry matter you takeaway
that's going to cost you 2 pounds milk.
So, if milk is sitting at 12 dollars
and we're looking at 2to 1 ratio it
simply says I'm going to put .09 cents
in front of my Jersey cow, it says I
would be getting .24 cents back
or .30cents back.
I'm simply saying that's an offly
nice trade.
That's awfully good trade. I have to
be very, very, very careful
when I start pulling back because that's going
to mess with milk yield and milk performance
as far as that goes. Now the next line simply says
yes let's do some shopping!
Here are 3 different energy sources
and will be calculated out with the cost
per Mcal of energy.
It could be a pound of TVM
whichever numbers you like to work with.
If you are in
France it would be
metabolizable energy, it depends
on what country you are in
and what system you are working with but
at the point it is very simple.
You can see those numbers and the answer
is the cheapest source of energy
on these feeds would be corn silage. Now,
recently there's a new winner in Illinois and
its called wet gluten feed.
We're seeing prices
of gluten feed somewhere around
60 dollars a ton
and gluten feed is a tremendously,
tremendously good energy source.
So, yes I would say don't cut back and
energies.
The question is are you buying the best
economical source of energy. The same thing
would apply to forages, applied to
protein supplements, and apply to
byproduct feeds.
The question is
don't cut down on nutrients but are you getting
the best bang for your dollar.
Golden Rule number 2
follows the rule number one and it
simply says
that most of us, unless you're living in
Florida or Georgia or some of those
other milk markets, we are paid on pounds of
components.
This is a fairly sobering and you'll notice
that just about a year ago
at this time, by the way that's 2009,
milk fat was, thats the last numbers i
have since the March numbers aren't out,
a 1.09 for milk bath
and that should be 1.92.
That protein prices should be at 1.92,
a 1.92 out side of that it looks
really good. Of course that milk price
is around 12 dollars outside of
that all those numbers look pretty good.
I just want make sure people are top of things
here.
0:17:36.790,0:17:39.730
The point that was simply is that
milk
components have value
and that's another number to take a look.
So rather than dwell on these
wonderful numbers,
James is rapidly making corrections here,
let's look at and simply say well are
you getting your cows to get their
genetic potential out of them?
This comes out Hoards Dairyman every year
they put their DHIR and these are
the
basically registered breeders
here in United States. They get
these rather exact high-tech
records
and basically what it says that if I
have Holstein cows in the United States
these cows on DHIR tests in the United
States average about a
3.6 to 3.7
The true protein, those of you who
are in Canada,
you've gotta put 2/10ths on top of
that,
most of you in China have to put 2/10ths
on top of it and in Europe you have
to add 2/10ths to that
because what we're reporting the U.S.
is true protein
because that's what drives cheese yield.
So, we're not paying you for NPN
and that's why I'd be a little bit careful
to who don't live in the U.S.
your numbers are going to be put at 2/10ths
point higher we have on the screen here.
The point is that if I have Holstein cows
and they're giving me a 2.8
true protein test
than we would ask you to leave some money
on the table.
Why are your Holstein cows not
producing components? Because we
just saw on the last slide
those components have value
and we've got to get those corrected
out there as well.
The third golden rule is one that really
scares me.
Of all the ones I have seen,
this is the one that's causing me the
most concern
and that is long-term.
Long-term make people say well you know
I've gotta get July.
So, I'm not going to use AI, I'm not
going to use my consultant, and I'm not
going to use the the veterinarian. Let's go to
the nutrition side and simply says
your long-term if you're going to be out
of the dairy business in
2 to 3 months then
you can do anything you want
but, if you're going to back it a webinar
year from now with us
than I'm simply saying certainly we've got to
get animals calving.
So when we start pulling out minerals
and vitamins from the heifers
we are going to slow down in growth
and you can see what that cost is. Now the
good news is
you don't pay that all your checkbook
but, the problem is
2 years from now those heifers
are not going to be there.
Accelerated calf program
have some controversy on this point but, the
Drackley work and  the New York work
indicate about 1,000 pounds more milk
because of the accelerated high-protein
diets feed
in the first 5 or 6 weeks. That's
going to cost you 50 dollars and
that is you're problem.
I'm going to have to pay 50 dollars in March
to recoup something from way back 2 years
from now that may give me a 1,000
pounds more milk that's to be worth
a 110 dollars or to make
more life simple hopefully even
more than that. Dave Fisher will talk
more about this
in his webinar in a couple of weeks,
Getting cows pregnant, this is in Wisconsin
that
open days are anything more than 120
days or 2 dollars a day
they say are over 200 days
that is 8 dollars
So, there is a curvilinear response
that says the longer these cows
are not pregnant
the more money you lose because
they don't come in as fresh cows.
Wisconsin's somatic cell count
and of course from California lame cows.
So, if you are not hoof trimming or
you are not paying attention to
those kinds of things,
another 6 pounds of milk again you
never see that running down the
milking parlor it is just that the
cow
doesn't produce.
These are scary ones because
people are
really jeopardizing long-term impactors.
So, the point is if you make a change
today or last week or last month
than the cows are going to respond
these are all different types of cow
responses that you and I might see out
there. Milk Urea Nitrogen,
if it changes by more than 3 units,
I will read the first one
the rest can read yourself but, it simply
says if your MUNS has changed by
2 to 3 units.
than something has happened in the cow.
So, in the normal range I expect to see the
MUN to be somewhere between 8 and 12.
So, you elect to pull out something out of
your diet and the MUNs go up to 14.
Wow, something has happened
in the cow in other words, the cows are telling
you whatever you did
it has impacted
her utilization of protein
in the diet.
That applies to all those other
factors listed on your screen here today
as well and we in fact already covered
the bottom 3.
in some other golden rule.
Cows always talk and cows responds.
Keep your eyes wide open and listen to them
because they will probably give you
some feedback as well.
Now we are moving on to the last page
and we are in  pretty good shape time wise actually
of the last phase of this. What are
some things that we should be thinking
about
and talking about once we have said I'm not
going to violate the golden rules.
I understand there are some economic benchmarks
on the feed side that we have to be aware of.
I understand the price of milk, at least in
the U.S., looks like it's coming back up
which it is for this Friday at this
stage of the game.
What are some things we can look at the
that we can cheat?
I'm going to cheat it's been a
really tough 2 months
for those of us in extension because
farmers are saying "Mike, I
just can't pay the bills anymore.
I've got have got to make some adjustments."
Here we go, we are going to let you do some cheating
but be careful to not violate my golden rules!
We are going to look at starch.
and we've got one power point on most of
these and Dave will come back on forage
quality a bit later.
We learned some lessons a year ago
with 7 dollar a bushel of corn.
We discovered we don't have to feed
30 percent starches because
there are some other
strategies out there
as listed here.
Rumensin, reducing fecal
starch losses,
looking at rumen fermentable
carbohydrates and byproduct feeds.
So, we are saying all of you with this line
should know it pretty much what is your
starch levels in your feeding programs.
The low number 19 comes from a
minor institute
and they've actually
cranked this number down but using higher
levels of corn silage and other unique feed stuffs
to get that job done.
We are saying you don't need to be at
30, 31, 32, or 33 percent starch.
So, maybe there's an
opportunity to reduce some of that input
cost as far as that goes.
Let's go to the next power point
and then say well is corn really working for
you?
This data simply says how you've
processed corn
and i know we have one company online
here today that has steam flaked corn.
You can see that has a higher energy
value
than say a cracked corn.
Some of you online have high moisture corn
and that will feed
hotter than dried corn assuming that it is at
least 26 percent
moisture.
So, you can see in orange, that
was because Illinois won their
basketball game last night and
they did not. So, Jim I think we
should have put it all in black today
but anyway
it will help you read.
But the point simply says is that
corn
how you process it, how you handle it
how you make it makes real
difference. Now for a dairy farmer if you
look at some work from Penn State
and from Farmland Industries
the difference between the top corn and
the bottom corn in a mid-lactation cows
is 6 pounds
of milk.
So I can support 6 pounds more
milk because you and I have processed
corn
to make the starch more available
in the rumen of to a maximize/optimize rumen
fermentation and microbial growth.
That's a take-home message. Now some of
you are saying, well I grind my corn
on the farm.
Here's your action,
sneak out after the seminars or don't let
your wife or spouse catch you
and take a cup corn and put it through
your flour sifter
and see how much goes through your flour sifter
if it's dried corn.
2/3s of it should go through the
flour sifter.
Now you can also send samples to a commercial
lab and get you the exact number listed on
this slide
but these are some things you can
consider and look at out there on
your dairy farm.
Another one is to make sure we process
corn silage properly.
This is some work done by Joe Harrision
and he looked at all the published
studies and there are two or three
take-home messages.
Published studies means that
good research
in a journal of the dairy science or animal
science. Notice a response there is
around 2 pounds
of 3.5 fat corrected milk
because generally speaking butter fat
test was higher and we saw some more milk.
But look up there he noticed under that
1.1 pounds of milk
there's a minus
and there's a plus. Obviously,
some corn was processed
more optimally or correctly than others. So
the answers did you do it right?
We're basically saying
I don't need to see the kernels,
I'd like now to crack them
and hammer those dudes
so i get rid of the kernel
and expose that starch here in the
rumen of the animal
and the small intestine.
You will see some other advantages
as well. So the question is:
have you looked at your corn silage? Have
you seen kernels in them? Do you have a
3/4 inch theoretical length of chop
to maintain good rumen mass
and goo rumen function? So, just because we
process corn
doesn't we've got it done right.
Now there's nothing I can do about that
here in February and March but
that's a take home message.
Another one is rumensin, lets look at
the bottom one.
300 milligrams of rumensin replaces
about a 1 to 1.5 a pounds
of corn.
That rumensin will cost you 2 to 3 cents.
So there is not that many places in the United Stages
where you can buy corn for 2 to 3
cents. There is no way you are going
to get there.
So there's another strategy according
to Hoard's Dairyman
survey in 2008 about 22%
of our farmers
reported
they were feeding rumensin.
There sits an opportunity. Now look
at the levels we can feed.
You can see it can vary anywhere
from about a
120 milligrams to 660. So,certainly
you have to ask, do I have the
optimal level?
And you and I are probably going to monitor
such things as manure consistency
and butter fat test
to try to get a handle on that.
Dick Wallace told me here at the
University of Illinois
yesterdays class working about 325.
We're like everybody else we start at
275 to 280
and Dick has raised that up gradually
because they're cows appear to handle
the higher levels of rumensin and
because the response in terms of
feed efficiency
impact is linear.
The longest the the rumen can handle those
higher levels of rumensin
or monensine
whichever name you want to use.
Another one is to steal some of that
starch out of the manure.
This is the form from Jim Ferguson's
lab at the University of Pennsylvania
This represents about 18 or
20 herds about 75 groups
of cows. I've talked to Jim about
couple months ago and he said they've expanded
this and what you see here is how much
starch there is in the manure.
All your commercial labs are 13
to 15dollars
can't calculate, excuse me, can't measure
fecal starches and on the right (vertical axis)
you are going to see what is called
apparent digestibility of starch. So, that
point 8 is 80 percent utilization,
point 9 is 90 percent utilization to 100
which  means of all the starch
there is theoretically  going to
be consumed.
0:28:27.200,0:28:30.510
Notice, we don't get much higher than about
95 to 96 percent.
There's always going to be some starch
that gets through for various reasons
because of a biological system
of the cow and her rates of passage
digestive track.
But look at this guys and gals
some of these groups of cows are at
8 percent to 10 percent
starch.
Dave Lighty at Illinois did a study on
this
for me last summer and the range in Illinois
4 and 10 percent.
So the question is: so what?
And the so-what answer sits right here.
The two trouble items.
Let's take the second one first, if you
can reduce fecal starch to by one unit
in other words from
6 percent to 5 percent or
9 percent to 8 percent. Jim Ferguson and
said
that represents about 7/10s of a
pound of milk.
I think it's a pretty good idea. I would
take
starch out if the  which I don't get
paid for and at letting the cow make
milk out of it.  Sound like a no-brainer to
me at this stage of the game.
Notice he also said that we should be at
least at 90 percent starch
digestibility
which means you should be something less
than 5.
Dave Fisher knows some of these herds.
I think we had 3 or
4 hers out of 19 that  met this
criteria.
So as we would say there are
opportunities and again
I'm not charging you
more cost perhaps to get this done.
Then we going to go to the next one,
feed additives and let me tell you these
are being jerked out  a mile a minute.
So what I did was to put together two
lists.
The first one is what I call and no
brainer.
These were questions at our focus
group and says well Hutjens
I'm only going pick one or two but
I can't buy all of them.
So these are my magic ones, in fact
Dick Wallace's class actually ranked these
yesterday. The number one was rumensin
and I'll tell you the best students got it right.
So my view, I'm going to rank these for you,
I would put rumensin number one.
i think probably put silage inoculants
number two.
That is going to be a
tough one because
you don't sell corn silage you
only reap that advantage and
decide once you feed it.
Rumen buffers and yeast cultures as three
and four.  Organic trace minerals and
then Biotin.
That's how
I would rank them out.
We can spend a whole seminar or
webinar I guess I should of this
whole list.
And If you are interested, Jim is going to survey
you if you want to do that sometime in the
future, we'd love to come back and do a
webinar on feed additives:
which one, how much, and why we can use it.
Now I also have a second list here and
notice the name change on this it
says additives as
needed.
So these are ones that I'm saying are
specially need. What do I mean by that?
Well for example if I've got body
condition score three seven five cows,
little pud suckers,
then rumen protected niacin right
into the diet.
If i have to have fatty liver diagnosed by
my veterinarian with lots of
ketosis then lots of rumen protective
choline
would come into place.
If I'm going to drench cows at calving
to try to get blood glucose levels up to
reduce ketoine production
then propylene glycol becomes a very
favorite product. If I'm going to be
finding molds in my feed stuffs
mycotoxin binder can be very effective product
as far as that goes.
In July my feed get hot in the bunk
I may out an acid in this case a
probionic di-acetate acetate
preservative in with my feed to keep from
it from getting hot
so the cows will eat more of it. So these are as
needed. You may need to them in summer,
may need them for fresh cows,
for fat cows,
and you try it target them because i'm
not sure i can justify selling
it to you for every cow
in your herd
let's say on the
20th of March.
The next Jersey cow pops up and says well
okay we've talked
0:32:01.480,0:32:05.380
about additives and I think I've got
that sorted out or at least I think I have.
What about by-products?
Now this is Illinois again so be very careful
and I'm looking at my list of people from
all over at this stage of the game.
Here we can see
a list and let me tell you what I've
done and then you know what which read
it.
Again, Jim Baltz is also showing where you
can find this. These are all loaded
online and Jim will come back and show
that at the end of the seminar when the Q&A
period but, let's just read this
let's pick on the bottom one:
distillers grains. That's the hot one.
Distillers grains is in yellow which
means in Illinois that's a good buy.
The next column or in the next one it says 10
to 15 percent of the ration
dry matter.
So, the cows are eating 50 pounds of dry
and you can add 5 to 7.5 pounds of
dried distillers grains or wet
distillers grains dry matter equivalent.
Now the question is why is that ranged
and the answer is
the oils
you have in the distillers grains.
If you have under 12 percent oil
then you can go higher because that oil
tends to be a risk factor in high producing
dairy cow rations.
If its a low oil, I go that backwards.
If it's a high oil I can only go 10
percent if it's a low oil
I can go as high as 15 percent.
Dakota Gold some of you in the Midwest
will recognize that name.
Dakota Gold is probably the cadillac
in distillers grains.
They control the amino acid profile,
they control of the variability, they
control the oil, so it becomes a
very good product.
Got to pay a little more for it usually but by
the large you can push a little higher
level.
Then in yellow down there, fighting in
the yellow down there, we ran this
through Feed Valve. Feed Valve 3 developed by
University of Wisconsin.
Some of you out there may use Sesame
that's the Ohio State's program.
The break even price 2.98 a ton.
The price that we saw and that this was
a month ago 1.62. Now low and behold,
I just got my cheat sheet in here, that
came in the mail this morning, here
in the eastern corn belt and Iowa
1.15 to 1.25 a ton.
Wow, they are almost giving
this stuff away.
So, it simply says at this time
of tight economics
distillers grains, wet brewers and of course you
have got to be living fairly close to
Saint Louis at least in Illinois or close to
Milwaukee
or close to Lacrosse your in the middle
parts of the state.
They are a very good buy. You are not
going to carry water very far
because the price o diesel and gas
has gone back up.
Corn gluten feed a
very good price
and that price I've seen now drop down to
100 dollars. In fact, from
one of our shippers here in
Illinois, you could lock in
through August
85 dollars.
85  dollars a ton and now the is
FOB and you still have to get it to your farm
but, there's some real opportunities out
there.
Fuzzy cottonseed
the newest price I just got in
basically in Wisconsin,
Minnesota, and northern Iowa
2.40 a ton.
So, you can see while
they're not giving the stuff away it's a
pretty good deal. Southern Illinois, Dave
at one of our focus groups, we had just a
week ago
we had 2.14
delivered in.
Wow.
I know Dr. Wallace you've been looking at
that as well.
So again, here's another opportunity to look
at and are using some of these,
what I call very
very competitive,
nutrition sources out there in your feeding
program.
Well let's look at another one, this is
called weigh back. Weigh backs is what the
cow doesn't eat.
Shrink something that blows away, what the
birds eats, the rains spoils, or whatever the
case is going to be.
Well here's a huge huge list.
Huge list.
I'm only going to pick out about
two of  these.
The first one is the big one.
Historically, we have recommended
2 to 4 percent weigh back.
Basically, were saying get that down
below 2 percent
and if you are a
really good
feed bunk manager go to the empty bunk.
Dick mentioned yesterday in class that
here at the University of Illinois,
in a group of 100 cows,
they are taking away 50 pounds of wet
feed
total from other cows.
That means that they have got
about 2 pounds
excuse me a .5 pound of weigh back,
a .5  pound of weigh  back
and that's less than a .25 of a
pound.
So basically,  they are almost at 0
but, what are they doing?
Fresh feeds when they com out of the parlor.
They're not running out of feed until
about 20 minutes to a half hour before
they're going to the parlor.
So, they're really managing the bunk.
Second bullet point says if you are
over 4 to 5 percent
you can't feed it to steers,
0:36:22.830,0:36:25.470
you can't feed it to heifers because
it is too valuable.
You've got to go back to cows with it.
For example, Fair Oaks several
years ago Dr. Gordon Jones said
they feed  to a 7 percent weigh back
in their high string. They pick up their
weigh back and then use that as an
ingredient in their low cow string.
They don't sort so there is lots of
weigh back in there and it's a very pretty
predictable product and almost predictable
as
corn silage
or soy bean meal or any other ingredient
you might have on the farm.
Then they feed that to an almost empty bunk.
So, you know that's the strategy
as well.
Make sure sure the cows do not sort it and
make sure you clean out the bunks. There are all
these tricks of traded that say
you want to manage weigh back but we've changed
our number.
We'd say 2 to 4 is good.
Back at the University of Illinois, Dr.
Wallace manages our herd and they have
to feed to a 10 percent weigh back because
that's what it's called ad lib, ad lib
free choice all the cow can eat.
So basically, now what they're doing
it how do we manipulate that to try to
reduce that in the non-research cows.
Another one is the one group versus the
multiple TMR
and we have changed our answer.
Let's look at an example and
then we will discuss that.
What I did was I went to Spartan 2.
This is the least cost computer
program out of Michigan State.
I looked at 2 different rations. I
look at an 80 pound TMR
and a 60 pound TMR and said
what's the trade-off here guys
and gals?
The 80 pound TMR
there is no
there is omega lakin here, there's no
additives in here, there is no bypass
protein here. It is
corn,
corn silage, soybean meal and
alfalfa forage. Which could be haylage but
it does not make a difference since it is
alfalfa forage. We put the prices in (the
typical prices). In fact, we will show you
those prices here in just a few minutes
and you can see here
to feed 80 pounds of milk
should take about 52 pounds
of dry matter. That cost is at 11.8 cents
per pound of dry matter and costs
6.15 cents per cow.
This is very similar what we saw the earlier
in our benchmarking.
The 60 pound TMR,
is down to 4.90.
Notice we are down to 45 pounds of dry matter
and I've dropped a penny per pound
of dry matter off because I can use more
forages in this feeding program.
Now remember I do not have any of those expensive
additives or any other bells and whistles in here.
So, then I go to my next powerpoint and
say okay
what's the savings. Just looking at the savings
per cow per day: 1.25.
Holy smokers!
That's huge!
Huge.
Remember they are going to eat
about 6.5 pounds less dry matter.
So, I'm go ing to take that away
because the cows won't eat as much of it.
Some take in 6.7 pounds of dry matter
away from that 1.25 and I
was going to use a high TMR
because that what we are looking
at and that's  about 80 cents a day.
So, that's the good news. They do not eat
much so that helped me out.
There are still 45 to 46 cents
laying on the table.
Now here comes your big question
and you talk about an argument out in Reno.
This one was hot
and that says when I move a cow
from the high group to the low group
does she drop in milk
and if she does how much and how long.
Our university data shows a 2-pound
drop.
This is some work done by Travis
Michael who sent it to us.
Another research study says 5 or 6
pounds.
Another study says 2 to 4 percent.
So, you talk about a critical number because
you can see if I drop 4 pounds
of milk when I switch those cows
because they interact, they fight,
they eat less dry matter and they never
come back.
When they don't come back
then that's going to cost me .40 cents.
So, my 1.25 that I saved
is down to .06 cents.
I'm down to .06 cents
but, I think I recommend that we look at
multiple groups
because remember many of my fresh cows are
gonna have some added fat,
they are going to have bypass protein in there,
there are probably going to have some buffer in there,
going to have made this organic and trace
minerals for reproduction,
some of you may have some POFA's
(some polyunsaturated fatty acids) for
reproduction in there.
So, I'm saying we're gonna look at
multiple groups
and we're looking like high and low,
thin cow and fat cow group,
heifers,
to me if you have a heifer group
and a high group it is all the same.
They are going to get the same ration in these
different groups but here comes the controversy.
One farmer says,
well should I leave my mastitis group, my staff
group and combine them with my clean cows?
I don't think I am going to do that.
So here sits a farmer because of
mastitis
or because of
reproduction in other words
he has got a bull pen.
So, he said I got all my pregnant cows
in one pen and the cows I want exposed
to the bull in another pen.
That we should pass on that one as well
so that's not a very clean one
but some of you and i need to think
about we look at one group versus two
groups as far as that goes.
My last power point is fats and oils and
all we are simply saying it
you've got to make a decision.
You've got to make a decision when
you're going to use it. I'm using
70 pounds
of 4 percent fat corrected milk. So, any cow
that is giving me about
2/3 quarters pounds of milk fat
I'm going to add oil.
Oils are expensive fuzzy cottonseed,
soybeans, megalac, organic tallow,
or whatever you want to call
it
they're there.
So, at some point I'm gonna add that and
I'm gonna bring up about
5 to 5.5 percent of the ration.
I'm going to add to that 2 to 3 percent
from oilseeds or distillers grains
first choice, animal fats my second
choice and my inert fats third choice.
If you are feeding distillers grains extruded
soybeans a 1/2 a pound
of those fats and oils, i should say,
or otherwise we can
bugger up the rumen as far as
that goes. Then my strategies on
the rumen inert fats I would be like
to make a lecture energy booster
100. I would use that as a add on to
really improve reproduction,
reduced body weight loss,
to prevent ketosis and keep my cows
it pretty good health and shape
at this stage of the game.
I go to my next power point and Dave Fisher,
I think we've got you turned on.
Dave Fisher from Edwardsville is going to
cover these next couple of power points.
So, Dave I'll turn the program over to you.
Okay, thank you Dr. Mike and certainly I
appreciate to visit about
the role of corn silage and forages
in the ration. We will go to our next slide
to begin the discussion. Certainly,
we often hear and
understand that forages are the
foundation of the total dairy
feeding program.
I suggest that corn silage should be
the foundation
of that forage portion of the
feeding program
and I say that because we you've seen
many herds
work very well with
a high-level of corn silage in the diet.
What level should it be?
I suggest that perhaps a ratio of
2/3's corn silage, 1/3 alfalfa
and on a dry matter basis
really fits well for high producing dairy cows
because of the need for a high energy
fed
while still maintaining adequate
fiber levels.
Matter of fact, I believe that Dr.
Dick Wallace, who will come in later,
at the U of I herd has them at
2/3rd and 1/3rd.
The portion of corn silage to alfalfa
also though will be influenced by other
feed stuffs or byproducts.
I think Mike that earlier in the
discussion about
byproducts and how they could reduce
the cost of of the ration. So
certainly again, we are going to take into
consideration of byproducts in the diet
and
basing that on the quality of our
harvested forages
we now
had a chance to to really build really
neat ration.
In order to do that we have to be
evaluate
the quality
and a lot of times people say well it
looks good, it smells good, the cows are eating,
but they really do not have a good handle.
We suggest again that you
use some good tools.
The Newark test that came out a few
years ago and
the NDF Digestibility test
is really is a great tool.
That helps to determine which forage
or which specific variety will be
better it my ration to provide the
needed energy to the diet. So, again
that NDF Digestibility that
test and
many laboratories are doing that
and we'd like to see corn silage
greater than 57 percent
NDF Digestibility that is on a
48 hour test. We can talk more
about that in the unit we want to. Also,
we look at different types of
varieties or different types of
corn silages such as the role of
BMR, brown midrib. We'd like
to suggest here again to we're looking
for high-quality forages in
brown midrib corn silages.
Which brings that to the table because of the
whole lignin,
high digestibility, and we can also get into
the starch numbers and things of that
nature as well.
One thing that we always have to
remember if we would and that is
strategic use of those forages,
by that I'm saying,
we really have to take a look at
how do we position those to the various
animals that we'd feed. For example, heifer
verses dry cow high cow
verses low cow
in the lactation.
My final point is that because
of that forced position of
those feeds to meet the
animal needs;
we really also need to understand
the importance position forages
to meet the challenges
of lowering the feed cost
and here again corn silage
fits that role.
The next slide gives us a bit of a
demonstration or a chance to make
some assumptions
and compare
how forage costs will come out.
We're going to look at a 1350 pound
Holstein cow
with 80 pounds of milk, in a positive
energy state,
using alfalfa hay at
180 dollars a ton,
corn silage at 45 dollars a ton,
and you can read the
corn grain at 4.50 and
soybean meal 300.
Now, I understand that these prices will vary
from place to place
but the point is those numbers
represent
was showing up now in the slide
economics of the corn silage. We took
the Spartan 2 program to do a comparison
of this corn silage at various
levels of the feeding program.
As we start to look at this and
compare
it's pretty easy to see
as we'd increase corn silage in the diet
we decrease the total feed cost to the cow.
If we look at that the 0 on corn silage
or all alfalfa hay diet it gets to be
the most costly and if we go to all
corn silage and  no alfalfa diet
we can save about 1 dollar per cow per day
but, yet
in reality even though the Spartan
program can do that in reality on the
farm you do not want to have a diet of
all alfalfa or all corn silage.
We bring both together
and their again we start looking at
should that be a 50/50,
80/20.
You need to make that decision
as a dairy producer or nutritionist
but the point that we need to make here is
that corn silage is an excellent source
of feed stuffs that will bring, as Mike
Mike Hutjens said earlier, the cheapest
source of energy to the ration.
So we really want to use corn silage
as our foundation of the forage program and then
bring in our good quality alfalfa
and then bring in out byproducts
etcetera, etcetera, etcetera,
to cheapen up our ration as best we can.
Well, I skimmed over that pretty
quickly and I think we can talk more about
this in the Q & A
if you want to.
I think if we bring up the next slide it
will lead me into introducing my
colleague Dr. Dick Wallace our U of I
Extension dairy veternarian who's going to
visit with on culling strategies, Dick.
Okay, thanks Dave. I don't have a lot to
contribute
here except for this one slice. If you want to
jump to the next slide.
It's probably good that Mike only has one
slide for me today because of
my head cold and
I've been muted the whole time so I'm not
coughing
through the entire seminar.
When were thinking about
these marginal cows we need to
think about what we're gonna do moving
cows out that are not profitable.
So, move them out of the herd out if
she's not producing milk. You need to really
determine on a herd by herd basis what
is the break even milk deal.
Is it 45 or 50 pounds?
What's your break even milk
yield for cows in your herd.
Then you need to develop a strategy. Obviously,
if the cow is pregnant you're probably going
to keep around.
Maybe what you need to do with that
cow if she's down below say a 30 pound
level
is  to move her under some kind of a lower
energy diet or even a non lactating diet and dry
her off.
Hopefully, she's not going to get too fat
which leads to health problems later on
but certainly she still is a
valuable asset to the farm and
potentially depending again on how long
it's going to be until she calves again.
It is really going to depend on how many
holes you have in the herd.
If you have spots to put cows
verses if the herd is at maximum
capacity from a parlor stand point.
Those are a lot of different strategies you
need to think about that
certainly moving those those marginal
cows out certainly is another
possible to think about. One of the
things that were doing it university is
were basically feeding our cull cows
to increase their value
at a later time. So, we might
be them from 30 to 60 days. Now,
Dr. Hutjens mentioned earlier that
we need to be feeding that expensive
lactating cow weigh back
back to other cows.
Certainly, that is one strategy and
you know there are some concerns
possibly about bio security and
if there is any fecal contamination.
I don't know if we really want to be
feeding that to other lactating cows from either
salmonella or johns disease or
depending on what the
diseases are in the herd.
We take any weigh back that we have
for me from the tie stall barns
or free stall barns as mentioned
Travis has us feeding
down to
pretty much 0 weigh back in the
free stall lots
but any weigh back that we might have been
picking up we have been feeding our
cull cows to
increase their value. We move them from
a thin
yellow fat cow to a white fat cow
that's going to bring you maybe
up to .05 cents more per pound
once she goes to slaughter.
So, just some strategies to think about
and I'm going to turn it over back to Dr. Mike.
Well thanks very much Dave and Dick. This
wraps up the formal part of our
seminar.
Our summary looks pretty straight
forward to me. I think if
you're going to be in this dairy business
those 3 points we can't argue very
much about at this stage of the game
and they are pretty
straight forward. Again, if you found value
in this write this date down now. This
is our next webinar Dave Fischer will be leading
on that. Both Dick and I will be online and
be part of that one as well. You can see
the time and we are going to do it at noon.
I understand in China that's not a
very good time but
that gentlemen has all he needs
I think at this point.
There is the URL and you will be able to
find that in other places as well.
We would certainly welcome your
involvement if you
have that time to sneak in for one hour
as far as that goes.
We also welcome you to come to our
website you can
go there as I said earlier the Dairy
Net sites are excellent ones as well and
you can get to us from there
as well. We welcome you to
come and visit those websites I think
there is really good information there
for you.
So, at this time we welcome your questions!
Jim we've got a couple of good ones
already here and any of you that want to
type in a question.
I will go right ahead and Jim will monitor one
as I will at this stage of the game. We
had a comment from an Illinois
farmer who says, you know what
we can make all corn silage work
very well. In fact I have
been on this farm and they are almost at
100 percent
corn silage on their farm and of course
becomes very
economical as Dave pointed out. So, just
a comment Dave that you do have one detracter
out there and you probably
know who that crook is.
If not I will tell a little bit later.
We had a comment
that came in from a colleague in
Pennsylvania who said,
Mike I haven't seen any data on
finely ground corn is higher than
than high moisture corn
or steamed flaked and he questions that.
His point is well-taken and the
good news is that I can to say blame it on
the NRC 1999 because I lifted
those numbers
directly out of NRC. So, I think
the point we have to make is that
if your high moisture
corn is too dry,
if your steam flaking and it doesn't have
the right density, if you're grinding your
corn is the right particle size you are
going to lose some value.
My view is I think that by the finely
ground corn, the steam flaked corn,
and the the high moisture corn are
kissing cousins. If you really want to play
hardball
I think the real winner is steamed flaked
corn. I say that not because of my
Pennsylvania colleague but basically because
if you look at the data
that was done at Ag Way was not
statistical. There's a little bit
more kick on on the protein site on
the steam flaked corn.
We had another question it came up here bit
earlier who said,  what about
this break even. The question is what do
I mean by break even.
I'll answer in 2 or 3 ways and
then Dave I'll let you in because you worked
with one of our
co ops on this one here. One break
even simply said I'm just going to
cover my costs. I'm not looking at
debt retirement or principle.
that looks to be around fifteen fifteen
fifty or somewhere in that range there.
Most of us have debts
that number i've seen from FBM
that number around 18 and 19
dollars here in Illinois. Then some
of you want to make money on this thing and
that means you're going to be around
20.  In fact, if you look at USDA they
cut the corn belt break even pricing
some where between 20 and 21 dollars
per hundred weight.
So, I think that all goes into play. So,
one of my students said, Hutjens how do you get
away with that crap. I mean if you are
getting 12 dollars from milk and
that's what looks like it's going to be
for February
here in Illinois and the minimal
cost is 15 . The answers is  well
you don't make 3 dollars for labor.
You know you don't pay yourself on that
or you have other ways to differ some
of those costs
try to get that job
done as far as that goes.
Okay, Dave any comments on that?
Yes, I disagree. I think also then
we're seeing actually paying
cash costs  and some of these
costs are for going at this
time
when you only get the 12 dollar milk.
When we talk about that
5.15-50
cost-production
we do have that included in there certainly
a value for the facilities, a value for
the cost of the cow but, we just do not
have that return on investment or that
ability to pay
off debt etcetera like Mike said.
Well David, James thinks that I have
screwed up answering that
question and I lead you astray as well.
He's thinking that the the question
may relate  to that break even price on out
byproduct feeds. That break even price on
byproduct feeds is based on
the 5 target ingredients.
We're using shelled corn as an energy
source.
soybean meal as a source of protein
and rumen undegradable protein,
we are using tallow as the price for fat
or oil, we are using dicalcium phosphate as a
source phosphorus and using lime stone as
a source of calcium. So, if you got a
byproduct feed like distillers grain
that's high in phosphorous then it adds
value. Some of you in this line will say,
Hutjens you are cheating because
a lot of that phosphorous and this is way too
high already and that we have
some problems with environment about it.
Well, I'm sorry that's how the program
works.
So, we are simply saying when
you can get that feed delivered to your
farm at that price that's below
break even than it's a better buy than
those 5 basing base ingredients. Norman Saint Pierre
used a combination of feed stuffs.
So, instead of looking at an ingredient
he is looking at the prices of hay and corn
silage and has a fairly,
I assume complicated,
system that says
then cottonseed then breaks even at a
certain point but he's using feeds
while were using feed ingredients.
I there are a couple other private
companies have some other internal
software program.
In fact, Spartan also does this in what they
call shadow prices and
it will give you the same kind of thing
as far as that goes.
David, do you want to make a comment
here on a comment that says what
are the disadvantages of all core silage
and basically 0 alfalfa diets?
WEll, I thin one of the  disadvantages
would be that
corn silage  brings a low amount of proteins
to the diet so
unless you can bring in that protein
and a reduced cost or lower cost
in the form of by-products like you said
corn distillers or whatever
unless you can do that then
you have to stay with the
alfalfa because it
brings in that protein.
Advantage of course is that high
energy
with processed corn silage
your able to maintain
good effective fiber and so as our
Illinois dairyman mentioned he was
going all corn silage and that can be done.
A lot of times I'd say
and 80-20
would certainly maybe play it well
because I like to have about
5 pounds of that longer
alfalfa scratch backer. Again,
I think the point is if you
can balance that ration
with good economical byproducts to bring
up my protein you can get bye with very little
alfalfa in the diet.
David great answer and I just wanted you
to know that our colleague in Illinois
says, this is interesting, he knows
4.28
feed costs.  I assume that's per cow per day.
Wow, that is a
really good number ands he's going to
do really well. I don't think it's
per hundred weight but
respond back if it is. We had another quick
question and I'll answer these quickly. I don't
know if other guys see them or is it just me?
Well, I'm just seeing them.
Okay, here comes a question that
says give me an example of an acid base bunker
extender. Well certainly the easiest one
to go to is Camin, not that
I'm being paid
by Camin industry, but
basically they have something
called bunk curb
Which is simply is a proprionic acid based
additive
and for 6 or 8 cents you mix this into
your TMR mixer. Its  got
prop in it and it retards the secondary
fermentation. So, it tends to keep the
feed cooler for a longer period of time.
I've also seen another product that has
di-acetate in it.
Which is an acetic acid type
byproduct and that also seems to hold
back the secondary fermentation. Some of you
guys will put that in the top of your
silos.
The top 10 feet of your silo, you'll put
some proprionic acid in there because it
doesn't pack as well and you don't want
that stuff to get moldy and get hot on
you as much. They'll treat the top
top 10 feet, the top 3 or 4 doors,
of their silo to get that same thing done.
Question came in here,
do you have any comments or
recommendations how to maintain rumen
health and function to prevent
rumen acidosis
that can impact feed efficiency.
Boy,
this is the kitchen sink and
we may delay the full answer to that. We
are simply saying if you have acidosis that
we are expecting the feed efficiency to
.drop about a tenth of a point. I have
no research to back that up but it we know
what does impact.
That means if you have acidosis probably
thats 30 cents per cow per day range
is going to cost you.
We do that by such things like looking at
fecal consistency, we look at
dry matter variation,
we look at lameness
scoring on cows,
you could maybe use milk components in some
cases butter fat but Wisconsin people argue
that's not a very sensitive test on that
but, that's how I would try to do
that.
Then if you  have acidosis then
comes the big laundry list such things
as,
Dave's already pointed out,
cud chewing,
such things as moisture of the
ration, such things as grain levels, such
things a slugged feeding, such things as heat
stress, and
all these things pop in
that can have some impact on rumen
function and health.
I know that list was fairly short as
far as that goes.
Got another quick question. We are burning
through these offly fast. When I can't answer
one Dick and Dave I
will let you know. We
have a question that's coming in
that is very specific.
It's a product that comes from Agri-King
and we answer that it is called Rumimax
verses Rumensin. Rumensin is an
antibiotic so it actually selects
against the gram-positive
bacteria.
So, it's a microbial
inhibiter that david that's how you
trained it yesterday at this point
so that's what we're men's and that's
that's a blacks microbes and that meant
literally will decrease per pranic asset
which has to be fishes he built into it
and integrity works against a four-day
disconnect here is a small extent and
that's why sometimes you can see some
impact
in room and help the relax product gives
them of a combination of products out
there i'd think they have a they have
some uh... direct that micro goes in
there i think this and he's culture in
their i do not think they have ruins and
in their but then again i i'm not that
close the private what one is more of
the room and stimulate pet product the
other one is an antibiotic so that there
is there a vastly different
and if somebody wants to jump in on it
on the max they can we can really backed
another quick question how much corn
gluten kenya p animus court would
replace
my answer very simply as i gotta keep my
targeted start level and if i say that's
twenty four percent
but island target twenty four percent
starch and i've died and i will bring
inasmuch pollutants replace court as i
can
to maintain that that that number about
beating up like my colleague in illinois
heavy corn silage i'd probably to
replace all my corner of corn gluten at
the stage gave because i've got started
twenty eight thirty thirty two thirty
four percent starts coming from a corn
silage so basically that's how i would
go analysis be simple about we simply
say the formerly replaced after court
with corn gluten as a pretty safe thumb
rel
you can replace the backlash that we're
farmer in southern illinois i want him
is running out of course i was i think
what corn gluten is a no brainer
and so i would suggest in many places
all his corn silage with what corn
gluten feed assuming he can buy it
and its price for a t_v_ coastal resort
audit again watch such things as
particle size because now corn silage is
gone i'm losing some part of
the whole discussion be that here just a
bit earlier and went on as far as i a
course
and um...
and uh... i just have a comment uh... oh
uh... where no question that can we feed
a huge
quantity of corn side and summer day do
you wanna read your spot that kenai
kid we feed a huge
amount of corn silage in the summer
years i don't think there will be a
problem with that i think the key actor
shooter
pump life and make sure that uh... yeah
fresh ito paris new york deep two or
three times as a person on tax day but
certainly not the sport caledonian
intake it would be able to win
i would certainly
not be breaking boards monson coincides
like any other thoughts
i die i figured that shade the only
thing i would have to give it is that
the courts i think very high let yes it
is all for my smokestack stabilizer
i think and get away maybe a little with
a look at less risk of security mechanic
at all that lactic acid there's an it
might even help will what scares me is
my farmer runs out of court sized at a
temperature to be some degrees tomorrow
what a bad deal cut down picks up
probably his most stabilizing ingredient
is diet and and and and i was replacing
with something that that could be nearly
a stable with some in the front five six
seven percent lactic acid as far as i a
course
we have two comments from to our people
like this kind of fun actually they said
they're pretty confident now that that
kemon produce called t_m_ are saver
instead of when i called moultrie
herb or or barker over something like
that you can see i'm getting all i'm not
staying up today but i got that from two
different people
and new hampshire has the same functions
as far as that goes had another quick
question came in here about that
way arm
jemison uh... ways cheap how much we can
it be to pay for child
can it be ad lib their market will need
to be a
our number is that you could probably
speed
uh... wing is going to be chevrons on
the back in a two-way we say you can't
be probably about a camp out of town
have sugar to the rational way out
lactose bob's going to be a sugar
replacement as far as that goes so i'm
saying if you start adding about five
percent five percent
that's a bunch that's mug shots
i would add more like two four percent
two to four percent on a dry matter pace
too mighty ammar spark that caused it'll
go very very quickly could lead to be a
if i had to pass a bill says iraq amazed
to know if i ruined with with baby dead
point to fill factor and i drop it some
really fast real carbohydrate um...
meyer of processes question he ap i i
think it could cost them ph
just because of the weapon this
of the fermentation profile so i have
the room another aaj and it's kinda like
say well contract the eggs too much
corvette club the d_a_ well academically
dole but if it's the wrong situation you
better believe it supposedly a saving
what the hell it will with the wayside
take two to four percent by the way of
ways cheap and and it is getting quite a
bit cheaper then i would go him and look
at that also has a great additive for my
image
if you want to put a_t_f_ nutrients are
said to him to make it really for men a
larger you're not doing are at about ten
percent
way dried weight to or even liquid way
and holy smoker those bacteria think
they'd i'd like to have it because they
got all that sugar in their te llamo
like might you be and many of the spark
that caused
our colleague espy deny levels all bar
court here in illinois came back and
said
he speedy about uh... four pounds uh...
if we don't eat four pounds of corn he
says
the man or starz a stepping up so he set
he can't replace all his core but
obviously
that's a lot less than camp over
fourteen pounds at many farmers would
feed
at this point
another quick question came in here and
i don't want reading racism ego takeoff
assign office park that caused canyon
venad dry corn gluten feed along with
two thirds ailish
one-third karzai space diet
we discern about too much time bull
protein
yeah i think you can
yeah i think you uh... e dilip
new york communicative
uh... two-thirds eulogy in my view idea
to do the jump in with me rather enough
here
two-thirds hedge almost always have to
assign a protein
and that's one reason to go the higher
court sized added diets because we get
our months about and we we can bring in
the right of the glasses to compliment
of the profiles grief microbes from the
corn silage spark that goals so i i i
would say yes it is and yes um... or
gluten feed us have side of a protein so
the answer is yes
uh... i understand and i say hi change
your life you keep because now you're
telling me i should use corn because
it's cheap
and so the question is do i uh... once
an environmental concerns that are used
farm and i say that california and what
you trouble like that
our president the blue that last night
on
uh... talk show but the point is
uh... we're going to make some decisions
in the next couple months ect maybe
environmentally are quite silent
or make maybe we wouldn't do uh... if it
but at this point if i can save twenty
cents a colony but maybe just enough to
keep me in the very best given any
comments on the sidewalk protein looking
at
at those kinds of peas did you hear what
i said
anger or just a reminder superiors
leaves at this point
okay why don't we go all the answers all
the questionnaire from this point if
after one o'clock my apologies
running along at this stage the games
yet we don't work what job
uh... dead equality bay fish thanks very
much for joining us we thank you for
many participants set aside in here
today are great questions we came in and
uh... we hope we'll see something about
theorist in uh... uh the eight of bob
it broken with um...
the title looking at d replacement helm
heifer webinars so until then
we're gonna sign off and uh... jim
what's gonna happen are we going to get
the values
altigen said you're going to get a
survey epic and when you sign off it's
about pop right up
so it's not a common in the outskirts
will keep you signed off ops you hear me
anymore but you're gonna get a survey
that will
take a minute and send it back to us. It's got
about 2 or 3 questions we'd like
to learn a bit more about what'd you
think and man are we signing off. So, if you
have a chance give me another minute to
sign off at this stage.
Jim, thank you very much to you and Luann
and to Jen for your support
and given the source run out and will be
curious to hopefully here
how it worked out. I understand we had a
couple of glitches.