God, I hope not.
- No, I'm not Princess Leia.
- Okay, my turn.
Are you in all six Star Wars movies?
- Yes.
- Interesting.
- Are you a droid?
- Yes.
Do you kind of look like a shiny Sheldon?
Yes.
- C-3P0.
- You got it.
That's preposterous.
I do not resemble C-3P0.
Don't get me wrong, I'm flattered,
I just don't see it.
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
Leslie Winkle. Ahem.
You've reached Friends with Benefits.
For a booty call, press 1 now.
What exactly does that expression mean,
"friends with benefits"?
Does he provide her
with health insurance?
No.
Look, imagine you maintained a friendship
with someone you had sex with...
...but you were free to date
whoever you wanted.
I'm sorry, I can't imagine any of that.
All right, back to the game.
I believe it's my turn.
You may begin your questions
whenever you're ready.
Are you Spock?
I don't like this game.