what if any more i think i wanna sleep
around with dilutes
okay this is one way
notebook back
appetite another lie wife with that girl
scout on that woman's hut
for this bob
but that path
anyway wanted like that have happened
jenny edmark bentley colin writes about
a info on
and it's a really fascinating case
because he realize you know years into
his marriage
he loved his wife there is no question
about it but he as he says and i'm
quoting him verbatim start the habit
hankering for men
manhattan without them
cell actually decide
hookup
tread activity and the three that was on
the witness stand up
so happy
he can play with his wife he told her
what the reality was that he act had
been sleeping with
uh... half a dozen men
and uh... she
hello would want more than a career
it's like i was trading arms for the
rest of the sixties
cake yeah alright
so her response was the most fascinating
first of all questions that set because
she felt like
she didn't trust her enough to let her
know from the very beginning he had lied
to her
but she also seems very openminded when
it came to his sexuality and
experimentation so try to the following
a salon
he said shiatsu felt constrained by
marriage and she came to see
that it was our spirit of adventure that
had run us together in the first place
and want to continue on that adventure
with me
but you're not the only one who wants to
experiment sexually and sleep with other
people would run on the right back atcha
sunday
did not divorce they both understood
that their marriage was over
that they retire marriage was over that
phase of their marriage is over and they
wanted to move on to a different phase a
new and improved relationship where they
say it would be to see if he cuts
so they did something known as m_f_n_
which is male female male uh... and
basically it's a threesome with regard
to that seat you get the picture
and work on the same yet
celebrate
but anyway but that the fascinating part
about this was the open-mindedness and
the fact that
they both realize that monogamy is a
societal expectations right and we've
all kinda signed onto that societal
expectation and we all struggle with it
and it's something that we could really
try to be
faithful and committed to
uh... but they're like you know what we
don't necessarily have to do that and
through their experimentation and
through their sex decades they've
realized
they've been really truly loved each
other and they've been together for
nineteen years
so now they have been during all that
i'm a firm suffer ninety years in the
side is that m_f_m_
they go their pollyanna recess they say
they go and it's weighing these trade
with couples and
you know and
evaluated all the sufferings the popeye
of what i think it's a lot bravery for
this guy to write about this is that
to kids that are
pretty much grown at this point
and they're reading a and he's breaking
all the rules in that sense
now one thing i did agree i didn't
believe his wife to swim if ever you
cheated and woman always says a poor the
guise of whatever it might be
uh... it wasn't that she did
it was that you liked it
thank god i was a cheated out what was a
guy got a bit like
hey you know what
come home one day and night are largely
shop at the office in career good to me
and a m thinking about you did you would
like that
cake that instant you know it's not how
it's going to establish a obviously
didn't have a problem with him and
gauging intercourse with other people
eventually wish your listeners is hockey
tradition that goes with other guys do
haha so
as i was upset that everything was
happening behind your back now that
that's what is your opinion anyone did
she went on
acquires in that pretty much do you not
that but i think by far the worst part
people there but mutual friends for
instance
find out about it because then you feel
embarrassed says that this is going on
behind that
is that i get that
but look at the bottom line is when they
finally came out local event
unworthy to live with it now there's
another
personal report closes that marc watts
not peace
saying
uh... when buying guys come out there
was a
that is all anecdotal stuff it's there's
no hard research behind it but
about a third of them
the in need of wars
and third
are uh... did worse than about two years
and therefore
continue to have uh...
and much more interesting marriage
whether in illinois one of the standard
is a more open about their sexuality
then every sentence or two
there were people
if they're open about it enable like
that
had lost i wonder how many of them stay
together for the sake of their so called
family like make sure we don't split up
because it'll be to charm attic for the
can sure huge
demolishes there we'd we don't really
love each other we don't care for women
in other but we do have an understanding
that we both can and go to work on other
people
it if that's what pressing not known as
item that's on the depressing
look you know you love your kids and if
europe
any you have a mutual agreement the
latter have relations with the people
that's what's what's that about