NAS: Yo, what up?
This is Nas, and this like a
crazy party, crazy thing I
remember from back
in the days.
I went to a party in the city
for the Shaft movie premier
with Samuel Jackson--
New York City nightclub.
All of the sudden, I'm in the
middle of Wesley Snipes and
Grace Jones.
Wesley had on black.
And he was chilling.
And Grace was chilling--
very beautiful.
Grace Jones knocked my drink on
my arm, and some of it got
on her arm.
She's didn't see me there.
She just did it by mistake.
And I looked.
She looked at me.
She grabbed me and she--
her arm, it was sleeveless.
She looked at her arm where the
drink had fell and just
licked her arm where
the drink had fell.
And I was a few things--
I was starstruck, turned
on, I thought I was in
the Twilight Zone.
And she probably didn't
even who I was.
But I knew who she is--
I'm a fan.
And someone else grabbed me.
It's Wesley Snipes.
Oh shit, he pushed me.
And he's asked me: are you
a rapper or a scientist?
And I'm like damn, Wesley Snipes
pushed me kinda hard,
like, that's Wesley and
everything, but he's pushing
me, like, what's going on?
"I said, are you a rapper or a
scientist?" And I'm like damn,
Wesley Snipes is about to do
some Blade shit to me.
So I pushed him back.
Boom!
And I said, you won't make it
out of here alive, man.
Wesley realized, why
am I pushing Nas?
And I'm like like, why am
I pushing back Wesley?
And where's Grace Jones at?
It was just a weird little
moment right there, so.
And that was some crazy-ass
shit from back in the days
around the way.
Love those days.
ANDREW GREEN: I thought Wesley
Snipes was in prison.
Next up, we check back in with
our real-life Muppet, Hanson
O'Haver, for another installment
of, "What's Up
With Drake?"
HANSON O'HAVER: I'm
Hanson O'Haver.
This is "What's Up
with Drake."
So I'd like to take some time
today to address what's kind
of the most common criticism of
Drake, which is that he has
no sense of humor
about himself.
And you know, I don't know Drake
personally, so for all I
know he could be a perfectly
modest and just
affable young man.
But I'll agree that the way he
presents himself is as someone
who takes himself
too seriously.
For example, he tweets things
like, "I don't have an
addictive personality, but I'm
hooked on it." Or, like, posts
ridiculous photos of himself
on his own blog.
And in any normal situation this
would take away from an
artist's charm.
We like people that are
kind of self-effacing.
And musicians who take
themselves really seriously
are the worst.
For example, think of Creed,
or, like, Bono with this
tinted sunglasses and his arms
spread like a sort of rock and
roll Jesus.
Every once in a while due to a
combination of synergy, and
luck, and whatever else, for
a brief period of time,
everything that a musician
does is flawless.
And during this period, if
they were to present
themselves in a
less-than-serious manner, it
would only take away
from their charm.
For example, think of Prince's
Purple Rain.
Everyone agrees that
it's amazing.
But it's also totally insane.
Yet if Prince were to
acknowledge this and to, sort
of, wink at his audience and
say, hey guys, I know that you
guys know that this is totally
silly, the whole thing would
have been ruined.
I think that right now we've
reached this sort of "peak
Drake," where everything that
he does is amazing--
from his albums, to his videos,
to his guest spot on
the new Meek Millz song.
And as long as he continues in
this manner, there's no reason
that he needs to present himself
as anything less than
just a totally serious guy
making serious music about his
really serious emotions.
ANDREW GREEN: Why do I have
this weird feeling that
Drake's going to steal Hanson
from Vice just to
become his hype man?
And finally, we check back in
with our buddy Thomas Morton,
a Dickens character that time
forgot, to get his take on all
of the shit that we waste our
lives on instead of getting
anything productive done.
It's time for another episode
of "Whatcha Watching?"
THOMAS MORTON: Hi, welcome
to the Vice offices.
As you can see, everybody here
is doing a very good job
looking busy.
They're all at computers,
though, which means what
they're actually doing is,
basically, what you're doing--
screwing around on
the internet.
I work on a computer, too.
I'm no stranger to
YouTube links.
And so I've decided to put
together a few of my favorites
from this week.
So come enjoy the cream
of the crap.
Hey, so it's been
a little bit.
I thought we'd play
a little catch-up.
This first video is actually,
I think, the first video I
watched on the internet.
It's a short and quick one.
It's titled "Burrito Punch." A
tormented, heavy-set, Angus
kind of kid is pelted with a
burrito and then exacts really
quick schoolyard justice.
MALE SPEAKER 1: Oh shit.
MALE SPEAKER 2: What
the hell, man?
ANDREW GREEN: So, continuing
on the sort of ad hoc theme
we've got going of justice and
comeuppance is a stark
morality play called "The Story
of Mr. Dollar." Mr.
Dollar, as you can see, is kind
of a ramshackle dollar
store operation out
in Bushwick.
And here you see its owner doing
a less-than-effective
job cleaning up standing
rainwater on its roof.
And in a moment of Buster
Keaton-esque comedic timing,
you can see the ladder raises
and marches off frame.
So the second part takes place a
month later and is basically
a static shot of the damage
that the standing water he
never fully removed from his
room has done, which has
basically destroyed
his business.
[LAUGH]
What starts as your basic kind
of angry human baby berating
service industry employees video
is turned on its head by
the interruption of this skinny
little nerdlinger.
If you read the comments, it
turns out to be a varsity
Greco-Roman wrestler who
just happens to be a
Whataburger at 3:00 AM--
probably stoned,
visibly stoned.
MALE SPEAKER 3: I asked you
for a cheeseburger.
FEMALE SPEAKER 1: I'm sorry,
what did you say?
MALE SPEAKER 3: I asked you
for a cheeseburger!
FEMALE SPEAKER 1: Shut up!
MALE SPEAKER 4: Let them go.
Let them go.
[LAUGHTER]
MALE SPEAKER 4: Let them go.
THOMAS MORTON: To keep this
from getting too kind of,
like, morality-heavy, next is
a simple slice of life from
either North England
or Scotland.
It's basically a guy who
sees a trampoline
passing by in a storm.
MALE SPEAKER 5: Oh my god.
Trampoline.
FEMALE SPEAKER 2: Oh yeah.
MALE SPEAKER 5: Oh my god.
Oh my god.
THOMAS MORTON: A picture-perfect
sort of
life-imitates-art callback to
one of the greatest moments of
1990s animation.
HOMER SIMPSON: [GASP]
Oh my god!
LISA SIMPSON: What is it?
HOMER SIMPSON: Tramampoline!
Trambopoline!
THOMAS MORTON: I don't think
I've ever said trampoline
right since the airing
of that episode.
To close this week, I wanted
to show you guys a favored
video of a, it's sort of, it's
a flying lawnmower that I
think they sell to model
airplanes enthusiasts this set
to the tune of the moon level
from NES's Duck Tales, adding
a twinge of nostalgia to the
general air of serenity that
this should instill in you.
[8-BIT MUSIC PLAYING]
THOMAS MORTON: Well,
that's it for now.
We'll be back next week.
Thanks for YouTube-ing
in and subscribe
to this stuff, please.
ANDREW GREEN: I hope you enjoyed
another episode of
Vice Today.
Come back every Monday and
Thursday for new episodes.
And as always, if you like what
you saw, click up here to
subscribe, and thanks
for watching.