students in Quebec began
striking against the 75%
proposed tuition hike.
Since the Quiet Revolution in
the '60s, low tuition rates
have been part of the socialist
package deal
promised to Quebecers.
For student protesters, a
doubling of current rates
represents a complete
abandonment of the fundamental
ideals of their education
system.
To make matters worse, critics
see the increase as being more
to do with corruption than the
spending within government,
especially since Quebec has the
highest income taxes in
the country.
Instead of balancing the books
by attacking pensions and
corporations, the government
has seemingly attacked the
weakest demographic
in the province.
Alienation and apathy has made
the movement a rallying point
for youth to rebel against
a mostly non-responsive
government, led by their
Premier, Jean Charest.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
NARRATOR: Faced with fewer jobs,
mounting personal debt,
and the prospect of an aging
boomer generation sucking
public coffers dry,
and you have a
recipe for civil unrest.
Some romantic types are even
calling this Quebec's Spring.
Things seemed destined to come
to a head on May Day, as
student unions were set to join
other workers groups and
the infamous anarchist black
bloc in a crowd of close to
10,000 behind Montreal
City Hall.
MARIE: May Day has a long
revolutionary tradition.
And we want to remind that
to our [INAUDIBLE].
It's about decent housing,
decent lives, decent jobs.
And it's about having people
before profits.
[CHANTING]
NARRATOR: Once the spirited
crowd took off, French
anti-capitalists and "fuck
the police" chants were
everywhere, while some talked
of riot squads.
[CHANTING]
NARRATOR: Eventually, they
made their way to Saint
Catherine Street, the heart of
downtown Montreal, where after
one window was broken,
everything completely devolved
into chaos.
[CHANTING]
[PUNK MUSIC]
[EXPLOSION]
MALE VOICE: Oh fuck!
Shit!
Fuck!
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
NARRATOR: After an hour-long
skirmish between cops and
protesters, everyone regrouped
in a downtown park to prepare
for a night march.
STUDENT: It turned
pretty violent.
People throwing rocks
and stuff.
It was predictable, kind of.
Tonight, I don't know.
So far, it's been
pretty peaceful.
I've been to a lot of
demonstration at night, and it
was peaceful.
STUDENT: Every week, I think
the end is here.
Because every week, I see that
the movement is very strong.
But now I'm not sure.
It's long.
It's hard.
But like you can see,
it's not over.
It's not over.
So there's no reason that
we're going to stop now.
There's just no reason.
You have to fight if
you want something.
You have to fight.
NARRATOR: By the end of the
day, over 100 people were
arrested, with almost as
many hospitalized.
And since May Day, things
have only gotten worse.
Small towns have turned into
temporary war zones.
There's been smoke bombs in
the Montreal metro system.
And clashes between
riot squads and
protesters are daily.
MAYOR TREMBLAY: What do
you want me to do?
Are we going to stop living?
NARRATOR: The Quebec government
even enacted a
draconian anti-protest
law, Bill 78.
Which has only served to
galvanize movement, and
attract even more followers
from all over the world,
including the vigilante hacker
group, Anonymous.
The protest shows no signs
of slowing down.
In fact, at this point, Quebec
is bracing itself for what may
be the longest summer
in its history.
[PUNK MUSIC]