The cathedrals in the cities are made of stone.
Yet they require millions of logs for their basis and frames.
Larches are needed for roof supports.
Solid logs of oak, alder and elm are sunk into the ground to create foundations.
Wood is indispensable for pillars and ceilings, posts and roof panels.
ax handles and cart wheels.
European castles, cathedrals, monasteries and churches consumed entire forests
in Germany, France, Italy, Spain and England.
No wonder that all the great social and economic struggles in the Middle Ages
are fought in the forests around the forests and about the forests.
In this competition for timber
those who have money make the rules.
And the money is now in the cities.
Perhaps the richest city of all is Venice.
It's built on wood, literally.
Piles sunk into the mud to create the platform on which the great stone façades can float.
But behind all this is commerce and a great maritime republic.
The goods that are bought and sold are transported in wooden galleons.
Venice has denuded the forests all around them to build its fleet.
The city's demand is insatiable
and they started to deplete the Alps.
Spruce for masts, larch for planking,
elm for capstans,
walnut for rudders and most importantly oak for hulls.
When that is not enough
they cut a swath across Europe
all the way to the Baltic.
The Europeans have exploited their natural resources,
leaving a continent where there are few fish in the rivers
and less and less
timber in their forests.
Their towns are crowded with people
and they don't know what to do with them.
Rivalries between princes and kings have grown intense.
Religious fervour, curiosity and greed are widespread in 1491.
And there's a constant hunger for new ideas.
The printing press is invented, books and ideas spread.
But where do they go from here?
Where can all this raw energy be channeled?
This is the time when European kings and queens send explorers beyond the horizon
to expand and enhance their power.
Some explorers go around Africa to find the sea route to India.
One has the vision to sail west to arrive in the east.
He's a seaman from Genoa, Italy.
A fervent amateur who has the crazy idea of sailing into the unknown to reach India.
Christopher Columbus has spent five years trying to gain royal support to
finance his voyage.
Isabella, queen of Spain, finally agrees. What does the Spanish crown have to lose?
It doesn't cost much to finance three ships.
Spain has so much to gain from a shortcut to India: treasures,
trade,
and land.
At first
no one wants to board his ship.
Finally he drags together a motley crew of eighty-seven men.
Many are illiterates, petty criminals, even murderous who
choose probable death at sea in preference to the gallows.
Many are soldiers with nothing to do since Spain expelled the Moors just months before.
Now they are soldiers of fortune.
With his band of desperadoes Christopher Columbus sets sail from the port of Seville.
It is the summer of 1492.
He promises the queen that his expedition will be a success.
And in a matter of weeks
he will change the course of history.
It is October twelve 1492 when Columbus sights land.
"I saw neither sheep, nor goats nor any other beasts.
All the trees were as different from ours as day from night.
And so the herbage, the rocks and all things."
Three Spanish ships sailed west for three months in search of India.
Then finally they arrived.
Eighty-seven men, among them conquistadors,
pig farmers, murderers.
But this is not Asia.
It is an island in the Caribbean.
They have no idea that they have come to a new world.
The air is hot, water is warm.
They have survived the voyage and have found land
for the Spanish crown.
And in the name of God.
They are exhausted, tired, but thankful.
What land is this?
Where are the ports, the cities,
the ships and traders they expected?
The natives have seen many people arrive from the sea.
Other tribes,
but no one like this.
They will both soon discover
that this is just the beginning.
Columbus and his men stay for three months in the Bahamas
and have no idea that they are on the edge of two great continents.
About ten times bigger than Europe.
From the tropical seas
to the arid deserts.
It is vast
and there is space,
with room for every possible landscape.
Stretching from the northernmost
almost to the southernmost points of the globe.
Spain's ** monarchy made Columbus's voyage possible.
It is 1493
and they've waited eagerly for seven months to learn of his discoveries.
Upon his return he delivers the news and reports to Queen Isabella.
In a few pages
Columbus describes the paradise he has found in her name.
Land to conquer,
converts for Christianity
riches to exploit, and gold.
In Europe no news stays local for long.
Traders, armies and pilgrims carry news across the continent in weeks.
Columbus's letter is translated, copied and becomes a bestseller.
Now many Europeans are aching for their share of the treasures.
A few months later
in Spain men are moving towards the ports of the Atlantic and the Mediterranean.
Men who have no land
and no work.
They cross the barren Spanish regions that offer little to live of.
Desperadoes with nothing to lose.
Men in need of a job.
And the queen needs them.
Anyone can come along, anyone can be a conquistador, even a pig farmer
can win glory and riches in faraway lands.
In 1493
seventeen ships arrive in the new world
on an island in the Caribbean Sea,
carrying twelve hundred Spaniards.
Columbus's second voyage begins a stampede of Spanish exploration and conquest.
Some will go south, some to the Andes,
some along the Mississippi.
It is the conquest
of the Americas.
Driven by greed,
carrying weapons
and with one animal
that does not exist on this continent.
With the horse
the Spanish are able to annihilate whole empires in just a few decades.
Within forty years
the Inca in the Andes fall to Pizarro.
And the Aztecs in Central America to Cortez.
Where there were towns and cities inhabited by millions of people,
the Spaniards leave only ruins,