SHANE SMITH: Hello.
The next morning we got back
onto our one-car train and
headed off into the
wilderness.
Every once in a while, there'd
be a break in the trees, and
we'd pass these massive logging
camps that butted up
against the train tracks that
were obviously North Korean.
We're on our little train
going into the
middle of the forest.
This is a logging camps
run by North Koreans.
You can see there's a North
Korean flag and North Korean
propaganda in here.
There, there's some
North Koreans
waving at us over there.
All this wood is going
to England.
When we get off this
train, [LAUGH]
we're going to go out into the
campus where they actually log
out in the middle of Siberia.
Freaky, freaky business.
We finally started to approach
our last stop, the tiny
logging town of Tataul.
Now Tataul is a freaky place.
It's as if the Soviets had
come up to the edge of
civilization, then dropped off
their Stalinists apartment
blocks in the middle of nowhere,
and then gotten back
on the train and never
looked back.
At the train station, we met
our new driver, a colorful
local type known simply
as "the Fish."
SIMON OSTROVSKY: He
just brought a
shotgun into the car--
[LAUGH]
just in case.
SHANE SMITH: Dog
in the sidecar.
Dog in the sidecar.
SIMON OSTROVSKY: It looks
like a Doberman.
SHANE SMITH: His mouthful of
gold teeth and his shiny track
suit confirmed what we
already suspected--
the Fish and his crew
were the local mob.
SIMON OSTROVSKY: They've
actually moved here from the
camp, the abandoned camp that
we visited yesterday, so--
SHANE SMITH: Right, so the
camp we were at is done.
Now this is the new camp,
even further afield.
SIMON OSTROVSKY: Right.
Yeah, we're going to their new
camp, where they're actually
operating now.
SHANE SMITH: Ask him, maybe,
if he thinks if
they'll be angry or--
IGOR "THE FISH" RYBAKOV:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
SHANE SMITH: [LAUGH]
And he brought a shotgun.
SIMON OSTROVSKY: Yeah, I think
that's probably pretty useful.
SHANE SMITH: Is this
the camp here?
So we're here in a North Korean
logging camp in the
middle of Siberia.
SIMON OSTROVSKY: This is where
they bring the logs from the
forest and put them
onto railcars.
SHANE SMITH: So there's
Korean propaganda.
There's some Korean writing.
SIMON OSTROVSKY: It says, "we're
going to take action to
increase productivity during
the winter time."
SHANE SMITH: [LAUGH]
OK.
Here comes a Russian lady that
we're going to have to--
SIMON OSTROVSKY: She
doesn't look happy.
SHANE SMITH: Hello.
FEMALE SPEAKER 1:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
SHANE SMITH: She immediately
made a lot of phone calls and
a lot of threats.
Should we get arrested?
SIMON OSTROVSKY: Yes.
FEMALE SPEAKER 1:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
SHANE SMITH: While we were
arguing with her, a van
straight out of 1957 pulled up,
and, lo and behold, out
came some North Koreans.
SIMON OSTROVSKY:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
MALE SPEAKER 1:
SIMON OSTROVSKY:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
SHANE SMITH: Jason's
gone AWOL.
He's in the camp.
Jason's being shuttled back to
fucking Pyongyang as we speak.
Jason, our producer, slipped
away with a small camera and
started filming the camp.
SIMON OSTROVSKY:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
MALE SPEAKER 2:
SIMON OSTROVSKY: He's saying
we've got to get permission
from the embassy before
we can show anything.
MALE SPEAKER 2:
[SPEAKING KOREAN]
SHANE SMITH: Now what he was
saying was a revelation.
We had come all this way so we
could actually talk to North
Koreans, and one of the first
ones we met was admitting that
the standard of living was a
problem in the home country--
which would never be admitted
to in North Korea proper.
In fact, when the political
boss stepped in, he also
admitted to living
a hard life.
But of course, he blamed
it on America.
MALE SPEAKER 3:
[SPEAKING KOREAN]
TRANSLATOR: [SPEAKING KOREAN]
SHANE SMITH:
[TALK-SINGING IN KOREAN]
OK.
So they won't let us in.
They don't want to get
in trouble, which is
understandable.
So they're kicking us out.
We're going to try to go to the
forest to actually find
some North Korean workers
who are actually
cutting down the trees.
You want a beer?
Hello.
[SPEAKING KOREAN].