It's, it's... I remember when I first saw
some Photoshop,
the very first version of it called Pixel,
in fact a very early version,
and I saw some things it could do, and I couldn't
wait
to put it on to floppy disks into my computer
and I raised my fingers and I thought:
"Oh, I don't have any artistic talent. Ha-ha-ha...
what's the point?"
It's like if you get a great keyboard, but
you got nothing to express musically
it doesn't matter how good midi is
and how many synthesized sampled instruments
you have, it facilitates it.
The great thing about social networking,
which at the time we're talking of course
is still growing in what seems an exponential
rate
all the time upper curve of it is that everybody
has a talent to interact with other people
short of being on autistic spectrum of course,
which is something many people are in very
small ways or in greater ways.
And even that could be helped by the interactions
off the internet.
And I think, forgetting the technology, forgetting
what your device can do,
forgetting how good the camera is or anything
like that,
the most successful usage you can make of
for example Twitter or Facebook
or any of those social networking services
are completely down to your personality, absolutely
to do with who you are.
I think, particularly in America, it's common
more across the World
there is this yearning for people to find
answers to techniques that will make them
happy or rich.
In fact probably the other order: rich and
then happy, because of course richness gives
happiness, doesn't it? Hm...
Well, to me... if I had known when I was younger,
chasing technique, chasing an answer is fatal.
And I would say this, and many people will
scream in disbelief,
the worst thing you can ever do in your life
is set yourself goals.
I think goal orientation is absolutely disastrous
in life.
Two things happen: one — you don't meet
your goals, you call yourself a failure.
Secondly — you meet your goal, you go: "Well,
I'm here, and now what?
I'm not happy. I've got this car, this job,
I'm living in this address, which I always
thought the place I wanted to be, and... what?"
Because you're going for something outside
yourself, and that's no good.
My favorite quotation almost (or at least
for the moment) is from Noel Coward
who's very great actor, producer, writer,
musician,
he is all around, he is known as the Master
by everyone who knew, because he is so good
in everything
and he said: "Work is more fun than fun."
And if I have known that real joy in life
is work, and if you
can say of the work you do that it's more
fun than fun, then you're in the right place.
Most of us of course don't have that all the
time,
but every time you look in the bathroom mirror
in the morning,
if you can say: "Is my work — more fun than
fun?
Or is it dreddy water, is it getting me to
a wage package, which allows me to go to bars,
and buy things." If that's it, then that's
bit of a treadmill I think.
And everyone has in them to express themselves
that fundamental thing that they know they
are inside
that rather beautiful afraid person, which
might get translated into aggression or silence
or shines or all kinds of other things, but
inside we know we are huggable, lovable, we
want to love and be loved.
That person is yearning for fulfillment to
be the person they know they can be.
And that's a constant journey, a process.
It's not about acquiring this thing, and then
that thing, getting to this place, learning
this technique,
finding out how this works. It's about, I
suppose to me
it's about the fact that other people are
always more interesting than oneself.
And if there is a thing... Let's forget what
successful people have in common,
but if there is a thing what unsuccessful
people have in common - it's:
they talk about themselves all the time.
"I need to do this. I need..." — the first
two words are usually "I need",
and that's why nobody likes them, and that's
why they'll never get where they want to be.
Because it's "I need, I, me, I, my..." —
there is an English word for that: egocentric
or egoistical or egotistical.
That all of it from "ego" that I think of
an "I"...
and if you just say "I" all the time, you'll
get nowhere.
If you interested in other people, if you
use your eyes to look out, not to be looked
into,
and then you connect, then you're interesting,
then people want to be around you,
and it's about the warmth and the charm you
can radiate
that is real because of your positive interest
in others
and if you expected to come to you "I've never
had this" or "I was..." you know, you hate
people...
You know I happened to love... I know a lot
of people don't.
But I happened to love the works of William
Shakespeare, the poet and playwriter,
I think they are amongst the greatest things
humanity has ever done.
Up there, with the Pyramids, or whatever it
is you want to choose.
You know the number of times you hear people
say "Oh, it was ruined for me at school"
and I, I tend to say to them "Yeah, I don't
really like the Grand Canyon, or the Lake
District, or the Mountains Of Scotland
because I’ve had really bad Geography teacher
so I don't find either of it very beautiful"
I mean just non-sensical.
You just.. It's a sign of people stopping
back and blaming something else rather than
just saying
"Oh, I wasn't ready for that, maybe I never
will be,
but I'm not gonna blame someone else for it".
It's.. It's attitude of looking in wounds
and American television is filled with people
sitting in chairs on it's sort of afternoon
talk-shows
going "I need"-whining, whining about their
lives.
"I'm beautiful, I'm lovely and yet nobody...
You know, I'm special, I have needs..."
Oh! Shut up, stop whining.
Just grow up and get a life,
and look around you to other people,
and don't expect other people to care,
don't expect people to be interested.
Who, who'd you feel more sorryful, who'd you
actually want to hug?
The person you happen to know
has a tumor and he just getting through life
not talking about it, smiling, trying not
to embarrass anybody about it,
or that kind of person "I have a leg that
hurt, that one..
and I have this pain here, and doctors don't
know what to do about it, and I get these
flashes.."
Oh, Christ, I'm sure it's terrible for you,
dear, but shut up!
You just don't... No, of course, we do our
best to feel sorry for all kinds of people
or we show sympathy, but the real heroism
of people who quietly get on with their lives
and think of others should be ruled and usually
is
by the fact they are liked and if you like
people want to be with you, people want to
be with you,
they show opportunities with you, and you
observe the way they do things and your life
can open up,
and there are opportunities everywhere, whether
it is a small town
or a tiny apartment in the huge city - there
are opportunities.
You know, you can simply by talking more to
the person in a coffee shop,
in a coffee store, in your Starbucks or whatever,
simply by just having a few extra words...
they are probably doing a concert somewhere,
in a little bar in the evening
and you might go along and you meet there,
and they need someone else and you might,
you might…
who knows... that's how some people become
managers or musicians.
They go out and they find talent, they look
at it in other people.
So that really to me... if life has any secret
it's...
it's abnegation of self, efface yourself,
don't talk, just don't say,
if you can't stop saying "me" or "I" too often
you are on the wrong track.
I think in the same way you turn in yourself
it is very negative and sort of... destructive
to finding opportunity
simply staying in the same place and knowing
what you know all the time
I once wanted to open a restaurant where you
always get the dish that the person next to
you have ordered
because that is the one you wish you had.
And I always thought this thing like Netflix
they should send you a DVD
the exact opposite to the kind that you like,
last the way you look.
So the Amazon said “I see you liked this
novel by this novelist why not try this...”
And you “Yeah, but this completely...”
Yes, that is the point, it is completely different,
it is not your usual thing.
You know how we always buy, you know how your
partner always says
"why are you buying that shirt, you got one
that exactly like it",
you say "it is not exactly like it, it has
slightly different color".
We like that in life, we tend to settle so
quickly
and the best way to stop that to keep reinventing
oneself,
I think travel is a fantastic way, that has
never been easier, there are ways now, I think,
a lot of us try to be responsible in our travel
because, of course,
you know, what we do to the environment by
travelling,
but there are ways of sharing travel, travelling
with other people, especially amongst the
young,
they travel around the world, they share books.
This thing I only discovered a few years ago,
this is very common in the places where young
people travel a lot,
like, say, in Inca Trail in Peru or in the
South East Asia, you know.
People just leave a book, and they leave the
name on it and a little note,
they just leave it in a public place, anywhere,
and someone picks it up and say “Oh, that
is good”, and they read the last note, they
read, and then they leave it.
These books have a magical history, going
round.
Travel and reading to me are such extraordinary
pleasures
I couldn't conceive a life without them. They
constantly teach you
And they don't just teach you about the rest
of the world, they teach you about where you
come from
There was this saying... I think, that was
Kipling who said it:
"What do they of England know, that only England
know?"
And what do you know about your own country
if your own country is the only country you
know?
You don't know America unless you've travelled
outside and you see...
And then you think: "Oh! Gosh, we do things
differently, I didn't know!"
"I thought the way we did it was the only
natural and normal, but they do it completely
differently!"
You learn so much about your own country by
travelling
Also, I think, to me, the people I was in
the head most..[]. I've had heroes
I'm sort of shameless about the fact that
you admire other people
If there is a phrase that makes my heart sink,
that's - "Not impressed".
People just say: "Yeah, it's so... I'm not
impressed."
As if, well... who cares with your "impressed"?
It's such a vain thing to say.
If your standards are so high that you need
to be impressed, "to impress me you've got
to be damn good",
I mean, there are things we don't like, there
are things we think of as substandard or ordinary
which we can turn away from
But it's wonderful - the rush, the headlong
of something with enthusiasm, like a puppy
for things you admire and people you admire.
Sometimes they'll disappoint you, some great
singer or some fabulous painter or writer
may turn out to have a pretty horrifying private
life or do unpleasant things to animals
or whatever, but to admire is enormously helpful.
I think because it's one of the most natural
things. And mentoring is, of course
at the heart of these most natural things
is to sit at the feet of a master and to learn,
you know, you see it in all cultures.
In the Eastern cultures you see a particular
image of the, you know,
like a kung-fu or something, you know, with
a grasshopper sitting at the feet of his Shaolin
priest,
teaching him so many things about mind and
spirit and body and so on
but also if you wish to learn, say, the guitar,
if not exactly a master then is usually a
friend
and they hand you, like, "Put your finger
like that, play that, and then play that in
that rhythm,
and then it's time for the change, and then
that one, eh?"
and then you play awhile and say: "Wow! I
found a new chord, and look at this, and oh,
it's very good"
And slowly you're learning the guitar and
the time may come when you know enough chords
"I should take a book or a video or take proper
lessons" - if you wanted proper lessons in
that way,
But you're learning with friends, you're showing
each other, you're learning together.
And that's really what education is. To me
if I was go back to me after I got in university
and there were some splendid professors there,
magnificent, world-renowned people.
And they were charming to talk to and they
knew a lot of things.
But all the learning I really did was
sitting with coffee in a room with friends
talking about everything -
cosmos, and God, and Marxism, and history,
and psychology, and truth, and lies, and honesty
-
all the things that seemed very pretentious
later on, they seemed a bit over-earnest,
perhaps.
but you may [] with your friends, you learn
of each other, you take pleasure,
like, say, "Have you seen this new chord?"
and some new ideas you've picked up
So, again, - learning is all about other people.
It's not about yourself with your head in
a book. I mean there are things you can learn
of course,
i.e. dummies' guides and serious instructional
works, but
I don't think that many people I know who've
mastered anything have done so from that.
They've done it through their interaction
with others.
I would say that probably one of the most
wonderful things you can be given in life
is the ability to give.
Sometimes, because I've had a lucky life,
I have an opportunity to give something, whatever,
it was time or money or whether it might be,
or presentation, or speech, or something,
[and people say... which I guess is ...] Which
would you rather be?
Would you rather be someone who asked for
help or money
or would you rather be someone who is in the
position to give it?
So obvious, which it is. No one wants to ask,
everyone wants to give.
And it's astonishes me when I do meet people
in my profession who are closed to turning
up to anything.
I mean I can understand somebody who wish
to guard their privacy and they don't want
to be on a red carpet just because it is a
charity event
but there are so many ways you can use any
accumulated wealth or reputation or influence
you may or may not have, that are helpful
for other people!
And that's just most natural and wonderful
thing to pass it on.
Almost everything that I do, I sort of aim
at my 14-15-year-old self
I had a very troubled childhood - it ended
up with me going to prison
I still want to talk to that young me, I still
want to do things for him
And this is the book I would like him to have
read when he was 16 - so the thing I write
Not that I hope that my books are preachy
or teachy
But I just think - sharing the benefits of
life *is* the benefit of life, oddly enough.
I think probably everybody watching me now
has more power, in any real sense, in which
power matters,
than, say, Louis the XIV or Napoleon
without the power of life and of death, which
is probably what we don't want, so it is quite
good
just in times when Napoleon wanted to know
something
even he had to send some people out to Egypt
and bring him back stones or something
and scholars will gather and talk about it
and similarly, if he wanted the spice,
he'd ships go away and come back and we could
go to a store in a corner of the street
where the bounty of all five continents is
heaped up in ways that never been known.
We have access to everything. And most importantly,
to information, to knowledge.
But is it knowledge? And where does it come
from? How can we trust it?
And is knowledge the same thing as truth?
Is knowing that the Spanish Armada attacked
Britain in 1588, actually knowledge,
or is it simply, in today's technology terms,
a sort of piece of metadata that just flagged
in history?
It's really no more than that.
Without knowing what that means - 1588, Armada
- it's pointless - or 1776, or whatever date
you choose.
And for me, I think, the history of the world
that has arrived to this point where I can
speak and it can be watched
by people in all kinds of ways and with all
kinds of devices,
and can stay for eternity, [rest you on service]
and who knows where
[the whole things] - it all comes from inquiry,
it all comes from open inquiry.
And the word really is "empiricism," which
is a strange word, but what it means is testing
things.
You don't take anything on trust. You test
it out.
If a book says, like: "You shall have no foreskin,"
or "You must not eat shellfish,"
you can choose to say: "This is the Word of
the Divine Being," if you like.
It doesn't really get you very much forward,
but it can connect you to the history of your
people. I'm not here to disrespect that.
Those happen to be a lot of that for my people,
as it happens in -- I don't know -- [] that
I have no choice and I eat sea food... whatever
But for the rest, I need to know why is that,
why somebody's telling me what is the case.
I need to question it and to test it. Authority
comes from the validity of information,
being repeatable, being open, being free,
and not coming with a threat,
and not being just told: "This is the case,
and you must believe it - or you die."
which is, as we know, probably the biggest
problem facing the world, the people who says
things like that.
And unfortunately, it's the young they appeal
to.
You're unlikely to find a 50-year-old being
converted to a fundamentalist belief in something
which means that they think people should
die for, not
believing the right thing, or using casual
language about their divinity, or whatever.
You won't find a 50-year-old who - you may
find one who's grown up, but try to persuade
a 50-year-old
They just know the world too well, they'll
go "oh, come on!".
But unfortunately, a 18-year-old, who's lost,
or feels that the world is unjust - he's right,
you know, it *is* unjust -
it might be better, if we all ordered and
well-behaved. It might be!
But we know that "ordered" is a dangerous
word.
And the riotous, chaotic freedom we enjoy,
which causes so much of a headache for all
of us,
is infinitely better than rigidity of tyranny
and control.
And religious fundamentalism is just another
kind of fascism, it's another kind of communism,
it's an extreme, dictatorial way of telling
people how to behave.
And given that my power comes from a book,
whether it's Karl Marx or it's a holy text
- that's, to me, the dangerous thing.
The truth is [bully] and complicated and difficult
and all but an [ "oooh, huh..."]
I trust people, you know, the great, one of
the wisest heads who ever lived on this planet
was a philosopher called Socrates, and he's
famous for asking questions
he never gave answers
but the questions are so acute; the innocence
of a Socratic question:
"I wonder what we mean by that." You know?
and even down to, you know, ethics
at what age might it be right ever to abort
a foetus, on what age?
if you did it on Wednesday, it would be child-killing
if its on the Tuesday before, it's okay, how
can that be?
You know, these things are very complicated,
and never stop thinking like that!
Never stop being a child, who says "Why? Can
that be right?"
There's Zeno, one of my favourite philosophers,
had a pupil next to him and he gave him a
bean and said
to put it on the table in front of him and
said "Is that a heap?"
And the pupil said - "No!" So he added another
one, "Is that a heap?"
Pupil said "No, it's not."
He kept adding and eventually pupil said - "that's
a heap"
So then he says, oh, then the heap is 17,
I take this away, it's not heap anymore.
Is a heap 17? And he was making that exact
point
"Oh, I see, this number of days is a life,
take one away, it's just a mass of chemicals"
Life is full of these complexities, like age
of consent is a similar one, you know?
the police enter a room and there's a couple
making love and
if they entered the day before it would be
statutory rape
but because it was the day after the birthday
- it wasn't
now, it's such a peculiar way to order a society
like that
and I think that sort of flexibility, of being
able to
to think openly about all kinds of problems
is really important for one's happiness and
one's sense of self and connection with other
people
I think, one of the interesting things about
social networking
is what it's doing to democracy and how it
is reactivating many sides of democracy
that both internationally, when there is,
you know
it's not necessarily changing the world in
one fell swoop but I think
politicians have to be so much more careful
now, because what they say is not just in
the hands of journalists
who, after all, trade favours with them and
may will let this one off for saying this
but we're all citizen journalists to some
extent by blogging or microblogging which
is what Twitter is
and I think it allows us to engage more in
politics and I think in young people
there of course still is same level of cynicism
which is a perfectly justified level to some
extent
who call it realism more than cynicism
you know, these are human beings in these
positions of power and
you can take silly, sort of conspiracy theory
view, be paranoid about it and all, but
actually, we know, because we were at school
with some people who are now
politicians of my age running the country,
and we know how stupid they are
we know how stupid we are! And the idea that
they are clever enough to conspire in some
brilliant way to, you know, with heads of
business to keep secrets...
they can't keep what they do in their trousers
a secret, the idea that they can keep anything
serious a secret is absurd!
And I think they have to be so much more honest
now... openness.
I think there's one thing that can really
transform our lives
it is increasing levels of openness
it is really allowing transparency in the
way people behave and transact
in business and in politics at all levels
and I think it's all to the good, I really
do
and I think the fact that it's harder to be
private is something, of course, that we juggle
all the time
if all this openness is around, it's like
we're all living in glass houses with no curtains
and maybe people feel a bit exposed
by participating in the openness of the world
but in ten years time
almost everything we do will be so locked
in to electronic systems and it already is
to a huge extent
and even more so. I mean, just including the
way we thought and
so much information will be known about us
and
we have to just make sure
and I think that's the beauty in it, there's
lots of guardians for us out there
who do make a fuss when liberty is threatened.
The world is full and the history of the world
is full of stories of people
who feel out of place in some way
either in their family or in their community
that they just feel that the stork dropped
them down the wrong chimney
and, I mean, a very common one, like me, is
- I'm gay
so, especially when I was growing up, it was
pretty difficult to be open about being gay
there were very few people in public life
that were known openly gay but they were somewhat
openly camp
and it was a sort of an open secret
But that's not what being gay is about
Flouncing around in purple dresses isn't exactly
the whole gay experience
But also, there may be people who are born
football player
Who grow up in a family of musicians or belly
dancers
It's not all just bright sensitive artistic
people throttled by the commonplace philistinism
of their parents
It can be quite the reverse, you can just
want to be ordinary decent citizen
who plays sport and isn't interested in all
things that your parents are.
You feel kind of trapped
Most of us feel different, I think
Teenagers in particular, but almost all life-uncertain
people.
There is this tension: on the one hand, you
want to belong, you want to be a part of the
tribe.
You want to be enclosed in a community and
feel the friendship and all the fellowship
of being connected.
And another part: one wants to stand alone,
and be an individual who is utterly different
from everyone else.
"They are the tribe -- they are the muddy
philistines, and I'm the artistic sensitive
soul."
See, you want to be a part of the tribe, but
you want to be apart from the tribe.
And it's that pull that I think gives enormous
creative tension, that allows people...
It's that spark of electricity, if you like,
that makes people creative.
It's the desire to be absolutely unique but
also a desire to belong.
[That sense of...] so they understand other
people, what is to be a part of the community.
But they also understand the status of an
alien and an outsider.
And youth cultures that old people stupidly
mock, 'cause they say: "Oh, you're trying
to be different, but you're all just the same!"
Oh-ho-ho-ho. You just don't get it, you know,
that's not the point!
They really do [here] [outsider] ['cause they
think they're being] clever!
"Ha! You all wear the same... rings and gothic...
whatevers, and now you say you just want to
be different - well, you're not!"
No, it's not this. What they are doing - as
I've described, they are belonging, but they're
outside.
And it's that paradox, what I’d call it,
that counterflow
that I think makes life exciting and gives
them [the rosin that our ballet shoes can
grip the state with], if you like.
That's a strange metaphor, I don't know where
it came from, but you know what I mean
I think, a very good point about technology
is - yes, it connects you to people who may
be as rare as you are.
Gives you a connection used to be - for example,
if you liked
a particular writer, or particular comic,
you would have to go to the nearest big town
where may be one specialist store
where you would hang around for a fat comic
guy would come out, like, "What are you people
doing?",
and you would say, "How much is that comic?"
and you meet other collectors, but then you
had to go thirty miles out of town, [by home
of your smaller town],
and you'd feel disconnected.
Now, of course, you're constantly locked with
conversations with your fellow collectors
and it could go down to the minutest form
of specialization,
but it still could be three hundred people
on the planet who have that, and they can
now be connected to each other.
Which must be very exciting.
On the other hand, I suppose, if you've grown
up with the Internet,
as we now have of course - people in their
twenties who've known nothing but the World
Wide Web
- almost twenty years old, I mean - so that
is a heck of a thought, isn't it?
And maybe they are not so surprised, they
just pick out that is natural, that have fellow
interests,
Collect! And that's a miracle! It's a wonderful
thing!
Of course, yes, against that there's a privacy
issue and everything else, but
as long as... there are dark sides in the
Internet - i mean, obviously -
it's not just the manifest [?] once to do
with terrible pornography or whatever, but
there's real problems that come back to the
personality disorders, if you like, of those
who are obsessed with self.
Either if I see a YouTube film or read a blog,
my eyes go below to the bottom of the screen
Because I get so fantastically upset by people
who write comments...
I don't even know anybody who writes comments!
I think that's the point!
The kind of people who put comments are themselves
so weird and unhappy and alone and strange
-
it's called 'trolling', you know, vicious
comments about things
I mean, really weird. Either politically weird
or religiously weird or just so intolerant
or so desperate to be heard!
So offensive! Just pleading: "Please listen
to meee!" - they're saying all the time. "Listen
to me!"
And of course you don't want to, and if you
do, it just gets upset -
you might even be tricked into replying with
an aggressive reply to some idiot, and with
vile opinions about things.
which they will use on a copmlete... it might
be a puppy running around...
Some random youtube thing, and it somehow
manages to get a thread of nastiness into
it.
and they just want to be heard, and they are
so resentful, and so annoyed, especially due
to other people's blogs
the fact that somebody's reading someone else's
blog and not theirs - is madly enough!
And they may be like someone they hate
And this even happens in technology - if you
write
"Oh, I saw my friend the other day" [?]
[] like, two pages of anti-Apple madness - talk
about 'get a life'!
But that all comes down to the same problem
- these are self-obsessed people.
And because they are self-obsessed, they just
[] build up these poisons, build up inside
them, they have to get out.
Maybe it's better that they get out in the
common pages of the Internet, than in violence
on the streets,
but it's still distressing for us all to see.
I suppose the thing that I most would like
to have known or to be re-assured about
is that in the world what counts more than
talent, that counts more than energy or concentration,
or commitment, or anything else, is kindness.
And the more in the world you encounter kindness
and cheerfulness (which is its' kind of amiable
uncle, or aunt)
the better world always is.
And all the big words: [], justice, truth
-- are dwarfed by the greatness of kindness.