Nasi Goreng. Classic dish from around the
world in the sense that you're using up leftovers.
So, back in the days when there weren't refrigerators
and stuff like that. So a nice way of adding
value, flavour and so just like dry fried
rice with fragrant things like shallots, ginger,
chilli, tamarind and I'm sure many, many other
things, meat, fish, prawns. This is the vegetarian
one so we're loving a little bit of the broccoli
and little edamames and stuff like that. And
like a little local ketchup. So it's a nice,
like stir-fried rice, delicious, little fried
egg on top and just, like chilli. It's basically
a breakfast/brunch dish and I love it. It's
really good so we're just messing around with
different textures, different temperatures,
different mixes and then we're gonna do a
little recipe and it's gonna be lovely!
Anyway, ignore the beard, I haven't shaved
for a week. I'm preparing myself for a long
voyage up a mountain. If you like the beard,
subscribe. If you don't like the beard, comment.
But keep the comments clean because I've got
feelings. I am human. Contrary to public opinion,
I am actually just like you. I've got feelings,
I get lonely. Sometimes I get vulnerable.
So when bad things are said, it hurts. There!
Right there!