Hi, I'm Ken Jeong.
And it's one of my favorite
party stories ever, from my
bachelor party.
I used to be a physician before
I became an actor.
All of my friends were doctors,
and on my bachelor
party we went to Vegas.
And you couldn't get somebody
more geeky and more
ill-equipped to party in Vegas
than me and my crew.
Then went to a strip club.
And the strippers couldn't be
less threatened by us or less
turned on by us.
Just imagine a bunch of
doctors having no
idea how to have fun.
You've got these big
tittied women just
grinding on your laps.
You have no idea what to do.
And then one of my friends was
getting a lap dance, and the
stripper was complaining
of some stomach
pains she had had.
And my buddy was like,
what do you think
it could be, Miracle?
It is your gallbladder?
Have you had your appendix
taken out?
And he actually figures out
that the stripper has got
irritable bowel syndrome.
And I literally hear him
going, well, you know,
Miracle, in irritable
bowel you get
constipation and diarrhea.
An hour later, there's literally
like a line of
chicks just waiting
to be examined.
And he's like, oh, that's
a yeast infection.
But that's, OK.
It doesn't mean you're
bad person, honestly.
I worry about STDs, so may want
to take some doxycycline,
Sweet Sensation.
Oh, you're just pregnant.
You're just pregnant.
And they're asking, so
when's the big day?
Where are you going?
Oh, New Zealand?
Oh, that's awesome.
It just felt like a group of
friends, except our friend are
just grinding on us.
So at the end of the night,
it was just so pleasant.
We hugged it out, and we
went on our merry way.
Oh, and my buddy wrote a
prescription for irritable
bowel syndrome.
You don't want a
gassy stripper.
It was one of the
funniest [BLEEP]
nights of my life.
We were out of our element, and
we went back to what we do
best, being dorks.