You are now compressing
some of the air
that's in that packet.
So I bet you think this is the
part of the show where I'm
going to say, don't try these
experiments at home.
And you're right, except
there is one experiment
we want you to try.
Just look for the graphic
that's right here
that says try it.
That's your signal that
you can try that
experiment at home.
Everything else off limits.
Look, I've already given you
homework, and the show hasn't
even started.
I'm Steve Spangler, and I'm all
about making science fun.
For the last 20 years, I've
been teaching ways to turn
ordinary science experiments
into unforgettable learning
experiences.
I have an amazing team who will
do whatever it takes to
affect the way people
think about science.
And to do that, I live
by one motto--
"Make it big, do it right, give
it class." All right.
Watch this.
There's a squid in
the bottle--
seriously.
And you just take a hair like
this-- it's a trained squid--
and you wrap the hair
around the squid.
It's almost like a lasso.
Hard to see.
See I can kind of pull
the little--
here let him go.
Just grab the hair, pull
him down like this.
And you can take him to the
bottom and just pull the hair
off, and he'll go right back
up to the top, and--
OK, that's not how it works.
But it's the first science
toy I ever invented.
And some people will ask, so how
does a science teacher own
a toy company?
And the reason why is because of
that dumb squid in a bottle
that goes up and down when you
actually squeeze the bottle.
This is it.
It's the very, very first toy
that started the toy company.
And it's nothing more than an
eye dropper and a hex nut and
this little rubber piece
that's the squid.
And let me show you how easy
it is to make the diver.
Well, here are the pieces, parts
that we're using today.
I've got just some 1 liter
bottles filled with water, a
couple of deep containers,
because we're going to need to
do some things that
sink and float.
The original Cartesian
diver, named after
Rene Descartes, used--
well, the original one, I'm sure
used something other than
glass eye droppers.
The oldest one I can remember
used a glass eye dropper.
And today, you can still find
them at stores like Walmart or
wherever, a pharmacy.
Let me show you how to do it
with the original one.
The whole idea is this.
You have to get a container of
water like this here, and you
drop the eye dropper inside.
And you say float or sink, and,
of course, it floats.
And it floats because there's
air inside that eye dropper.
Even though it's a glass eye
dropper, there's air.
If I hold it up like this--
here, take a look at this--
I can squeeze some of the
bubbles out like this, and
pull some water in.
So in essence, I'm changing
the mass, right?
And now it just barely
bobs there.
See how it bobs up and
down that way?
OK, so that's perfect.
When you make a Cartesian diver,
you've got to have that
kind of set up there, so it just
barely bounces around.
Now we've got a 1
liter bottle.
And I'm using a 1 liter.
You could use a 2 liter.
It's just easier to squeeze
with a 1 liter.
Remove the label.
It's almost full to the top.
And one of the secrets of a
Cartesian diver, to make it
easier to squeeze, anyway, is
to make sure there's just no
air inside the bottle.
The only air that we want--
if you take a look at this right
here-- the only air that
you want is the air that's
in that Cartesian diver.
All right.
So now, here's what happens.
You take a cap and put
the cap on like this.
And now, we're ready to go.
So the way it floats and it
sinks is if I can change the
mass, ultimately changing the
density-- if I can change the
mass, because the volume is
going to stay the same, then
density equals mass
divided by volume.
I know it's nerd fest here, but
I've just got to change
the density so it's greater than
1 and so it will sink.
So watch-- as I squeeze it, you
can actually see the water
level going up.
You see this here?
So I'm just barely
squeezing it.
So water's being pushed
up into here.
The air compresses, because
the water cannot compress.
And when it gets heavy enough,
it finally sinks.
Isn't that nice?
And as you let go,
it will float.
So we've got a perfect way to
be able to make something
float or sink.
And of course, we're just using
our fingers to be able
to squeeze it.
You can do all the magic
that you want to.
You pretend like you have
the magnetic finger.
And when the person comes up,
their finger follows.
And if you just don't want the
person to have the magnetic
finger, then you just don't let
them make it work, right?
But that's the classic
Cartesian diver.
I was introduced to a new style
of Cartesian diver by a
man by the name of Bob Becker.
Bob is a chemistry teacher in
Kirkwood, Missouri, and
actually showed me this version
using plastic eye
droppers called pipettes.
And they're very, very
prevalent in
the chemistry classroom.
A lot of teachers use
these pipettes.
They may be a little bit harder
for just the average
person to get their hands on,
but just befriend a teacher,
and for sure they know
about pipettes.
This one is special, because
it's graduated.
Do you see this one here?
And when you're picking one,
just make sure that you can
find one that the hex nut
will go over the top.
So if I drop this into the water
like this-- so here's
our container.
Let me drop this
into the water.
Of course it floats, right?
I want to weight it down.
So here's what we're
going to do.
We're taking a regular
quarter-inch hex nut.
And I use these brass ones,
because they don't rust.
This goes on the pipette
like that.
So here's what it looks like.
It's just right there
on the pipette.
And then I'm going to twist and
turn it into place like
this, so it kind of holds
it into place.
And that's what it looks like.
It's held into place.
A pair of scissors will help
us cut the end off.
And now we have the makings of
a modern-day Cartesian diver.
So the same thing-- of
course it floats.
So watch.
When we drop it inside,
it floats.
If I squeeze some of the air out
and pull some of the water
in, I can make it so it
just barely floats.
Of course, of we have too much
water in altogether, then the
whole thing will sink.
So I want it so it just
barely floats.
So I'm going to just continue
to play with it.
That seems to be a pretty
good buoyancy there.
Again, that whole idea is so
it just barely floats.
So now that we have it adjusted,
you just have to be
careful that you don't get
any of the water out.
It goes down inside.
Notice how it's full almost
to the very, very top.
That's exactly what we want--
no air inside the bottle.
And now we cap it off.
Again, just as it happened
before, that we saw with the
glass eye dropper, when you
squeeze, notice how the water
goes up inside.
This systems just
works perfectly.
Bob's a genius.
And there is the making of the
modern day Cartesian diver.
We had to find a
way to disguise
this diver right here.
I was working in television in
the early 1990s for a program
called News for Kids.
And so on the set, we had
a whole bunch of kids.
And they were squeezing this.
And the director kept on
commenting that she couldn't
see the diver very
well inside.
So we found other ways to be
able to glue things on, for
example, or use a Sharpie
pen to color on them.
Again, Bob Becker had a
bunch of great ideas.
But I wanted something that
was just a little
bit easier to see.
So I'll show you how we
changed everything.
It looks like a fishing lure.
It's not really a fishing lure
that would catch a fish.
These were specially made,
because the regular fishing
lure just wouldn't go
over the pipette.
Remember coming back and trying
to find a way to be
able to use this and put
it over the pipette.
So here, watch.
This is Squiddy.
So you just open up the little
opening here like this.
And then this slides over
the workings of
the squid like this.
And this is the new squid.
All right, so this
is in place.
Enough history.
As you squeeze, the water goes
inside, the little squid falls
down, and as you let go, the
squid goes up again.
And that was Squiddy.
So let's say you don't have
a squid and you don't have
pipettes and hex nuts and
everything else and you'd like
to do the Cartesian diver.
I'm going to show you
how to do one.
This is ingenious.
It's done out of a condiment.
It's just ketchup.
So you're going to
start collecting
some ketchup packets.
This is an interesting
Cartesian diver.
And it's interesting because,
in this style of Cartesian
diver, there was an open end.
So when you squeeze, water
would go inside.
You would increase the mass,
and it would sink.
But when you use something
like this, these ketchup
packets have never
been opened.
And so this means that the mass
has to stay the same.
We would have to possibly change
the volume if you want
to change the density.
So here's what you need to do.
Not all ketchup packets work.
Collect a whole bunch of
different ketchup packets and
in a container of water,
just drop them inside.
Some will float, and
some will sink.
You're hoping that a
couple will float.
And pick the ones
that will float.
OK, so this is a
good one here.
This one may float just
a little too much.
And this one right over here,
this Carl's Jr. one might do
fairly well.
So you want the two of them
that just barely float.
All right?
The other ones are out
of the question.
So again, here's our bottle.
Let's try that Carl's Jr. one.
Let's see if this one
works fairly well.
So you're going to take
the ketchup packet.
Don't open it up.
Just kind of fold it and push
it down into the bottle.
And you're going to lose some
water, so you're going to have
to fill it back up again.
Ah, so there it is.
Bingo.
Got it.
And now, cap it or top
if off this way.
And we need a cap.
So this will go on the top.
So now, look at what we have.
This is fairly cool, because
this now doesn't get ruined if
you turn it upside down
or anything like that.
It just kind of sits in here.
While you can't see it,
as you squeeze--
and it doesn't take much
of a squeeze at all--
you're now compressing some of
the air that's in that packet
and changing the density
or the buoyancy.
And that's the simplest of
the Cartesian divers.
Now that you know how Squiddy
works-- a simple science toy--
there's a big jump from having
an idea like this to actually
getting it into stores.
And the best way to do that is
a convention called the New
York Toy Fair.
It attracts thousands and
thousands of people.
These are people who own
educational stores, regular
toy stores.
And that's the best way to
be able to show people.
Well, the product line has
grown from just a couple
products that we started with
the 1993 to now over 75
products in a company
called Be Amazing!
Toys.
So I want to give you a behind
the scenes glimpse of what Toy
Fair looks like-- the normal
public isn't allowed in-- and
what happens when you walk the
aisles and ask other people to
show you some of their
best toys, as well.
Take a look.
Well, it's cold for a reason.
It's February in New York.
It can only mean one thing--
Toy Fair.
And we'd like to have you help
us out a little bit.
So we want to comment below and
tell us which toys we're
going to show you are the great
ones and which ones are
kind of-- eh.
Well, you be the judge.
And welcome to Toy Fair 2012.
All right.
This is a sneak peak
of Toy Fair.
We're actually in the exhibit
hall, because we're exhibitors
today with Be Amazing!
Toys.
It's wonderful company they
carries so many of the Steve
Spangler science items.
But they carry it for things
like Target and Walmart and
mass-market stores in addition
to small ma and pa stores.
Those brick and mortar stores
are there as well.
And this is where I get
to hang out for
the next eight hours.
And I have a feeling--
see these hands?
They are going to be
coke-covered here in no time,
because it's my job to launch
as many geysers as I can.
I have 780 bottles
to get through.
And it'll be a successful
day if I get it.
See ya.
Now, when I pull the pin, the
Mentos will fall, just like
the model here, right?
The secret is that those little
pits on the outside of
the Mentos, all the carbon
dioxide rushes to that--
they're called nucleation
points-- and it
shoots the soda out.
We're just going to turn it
sideways, see if Isaac Newton
was correct.
And if he was, we get
a little shot.
All right?
So this goes in here
like this.
All right, normally you're
outside or you're sneaking in
some place that has great
floors like Home Depot.
You'd shoot it all past plumbing
and down the--
don't do that.
This pulls like this
when it falls.
It starts to flow.
And as you let go, bam!
Isn't that a good shot?
That was.
It'll go about 150 feet at about
30 miles an hour with
what you saw there.
Now that we're done at the
booth, let's go check out some
of the cool toys at Toy Fair.
Who doesn't like a severed hand
that runs around on a
wall and scares the
crap out of kids?
That's perfect.
You know, of anybody doing
science kits today, Thames &
Kosmos has got to be one of my
favorites and one of the best.
You look at this-- they're
doing real science.
The materials that you see here
are not watered down.
So if you're looking for
chemistry along the way, this
Thames & Kosmos place
is great.
MALE SPEAKER: Straw with
flavored beads in the middle.
STEVE SPANGLER: Lobster?
Is it lobster?
MALE SPEAKER: That's it.
STEVE SPANGLER: Shrimp?
MALE SPEAKER: Taste it again.
Maybe let the beads dissolve
a little bit more.
You're not quite getting
the flavor.
Now what do you think?
STEVE SPANGLER: Strawberry.
MALE SPEAKER: Strawberry,
you got it.
STEVE SPANGLER: Strawberry
lobster.
It actually tastes like
strawberry lobster and shrimp.
Well, we're at Insect Lore.
These are people that
I've known for years
and years and years.
And there, they manufacture this
wonderful thing called
the butterfly pavilion.
And so I would stand in their
booth years ago and tell
people that the butterflies
were good to eat, and they
were just raising
them for salads.
And a lot of people would
believe that.
And then I got kicked out.
Do not eat the butterflies.
I thought it was just all
about buying bugs.
And now it's a campfire.
MALE SPEAKER: Now it's
all about camping.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK, go away.
I need to get in the camp.
MALE SPEAKER: It's
time for bed.
STEVE SPANGLER: All right, so
here's kind of a you choose it
an adventure.
You can choose what
you want me to do.
I'll either A, go sneak into
the tent at Insect Lore and
sleep there for the night, or
B, I'll pretend like I'm a
sales person, and I'll sell
butterflies, but convince
people that they're not real
and they're animatronics.
All right, well, 3D
is all the rage.
And these are 3D glasses
here from Look3D.
And not only are they 3D
glasses, they make you look
really sexy.
And watch this, I can look--
oh my god.
See that?
All contained in these
classes here.
No batteries at all.
How many pounds?
MALE SPEAKER: This
is 25 pounds.
STEVE SPANGLER: All right.
25 pounds of Aaron's
Thinking Putty.
It changes color.
This is a tremendous
amount of fun.
I don't think he was a problem
in school at all.
This is just what he does.
MALE SPEAKER: We're
going to turn that
nice lady into a butterfly.
STEVE SPANGLER: All right, let's
go see the butterfly.
How cool is that?
MALE SPEAKER: [INAUDIBLE].
STEVE SPANGLER: That is
awesome and tasty too.
Tastes like that lobster stuff
that I had at the other booth.
Look at this.
MALE SPEAKER: When you spread
out your fingers, they weave
in and out.
Here, we'll show
them his nose.
Oh, he's scared.
Put it on your shower door,
it turns your whole
shower into a speaker.
STEVE SPANGLER: You're using
the entire box to just
resonate the sound.
Here's a booth--
four million different
kinds of dice.
So here's the deal.
This nice man right here said
that I can go sneak a toy away
during a live shot.
So they wrote something like
"Hello, Denver" or something.
But during the live shot, we'll
go sneak it away and
just see how he reacts.
He's good.
So he'll react well.
CHRIS BYRNE: And you know who's
running around here?
Steve Spangler's running around
Toy Fair creating all
kinds of havoc.
And I-- wait, there he is.
STEVE SPANGLER: I'm taking
this back to the station.
CHRIS BYRNE: He's taking
it back to the station.
So we are having so much fun
here at the American
International Toy Fair.
So great to see you.
STEVE SPANGLER: You too.
There's the regular--
there's six things on a die.
And then there's this
one that's red.
And this one, it's another die,
which looks a lot like
this one, but it's completely
called the swirl die.
And this is the gator die
and the pearl die.
This would be the cow die, the
dog die, and the woodland
animal die--
not to be confused with the
bison die, the beetle die, the
scorpion die, and
the ladybug die.
One of my favorites--
the bat die.
There's the sided die--
the 16-sided die.
There's the hip dice, Chinese
dice, Amish dice, regular
dice, Japanese dice, and another
alien dice which is
probably a knock-off of that
alien dice over there.
There's spotted, spotted,
spotted, counting.
There's loaded dice, just in
case you have a craps game and
you want to win--
loaded dice.
Nothing says I love you more,
kids, than to give you a bowl
of dice for your birthday.
Happy birthday.
Here's a bowl of dice.
My all time favorite-- you can
vote on it down below--
opaque die.
One question we never get to
ask-- what do you think about
alligators?
And do you have any thoughts
on the current debate over
endoplasmic reticulum?
MALE SPEAKER: I'll show you
just a quick trick here.
You've got a ring now, right?
STEVE SPANGLER: Right.
MALE SPEAKER: If I squeeze
them together,
now I've got a triangle.
If I fold up the tips, I've
got an octahedron.
I can put it back down and smash
it and it goes right
back into a ring.
STEVE SPANGLER: Nice.
MALE SPEAKER: Now, pinch here,
fold it over, and I've got
myself a spinning top.
And if I add two, I get eight.
Eight's a cool number.
I known to be two times two
times two, or two cubed.
Just like that.
Now, I'll show you a
really cool trick.
It requires 12.
So I'm going to add
four more here.
And 12's a really interesting
number, because it allows me
to just wrap them around
my fingers twice.
STEVE SPANGLER: Right.
MALE SPEAKER: Pinch here, and I
pull these two to the side.
Now I've got myself a ball.
STEVE SPANGLER: God,
that's amazing.
[STEVE, POORLY, PLAYING "CLOSE
TO YOU" ON UKELELE]
STEVE SPANGLER: It's
out of tune.
Well, if you enjoyed this week's
episode, go ahead and
click the Subscribe button here,
and you'll be the first
to know when a brand new episode
appears each week.
This button right here will
show you some more cool
science experiments that we
do outside of this show.
This button right here will
take you to last week's
episode just in case
you missed it.
And if you want to see the stuff
that you shouldn't see--
that the bloopers and the
outtakes-- well, just click
this one right over here.
And if you want to hear me
stop talking, through the
magic of television, just click
this button right here.
Go ahead.
Click it and I'll stop.