[DUBSTEP MUSIC PLAYING]
MAYOR GAYLE OBERST:
There's a lot of
networking and getting together.
And we have some really good
kids that come down here and
they get out and clean
the beach.
It's just a really good
environment for them to be out
on their own.
OLIVIA ALLEY: Guys are finger
banging girls out
on the dance floor.
KERRIGAN SKELLY: If you were
thinking about going on Spring
Break, you need to
think again.
You need to think in
light of eternity.
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYING]
["GONNA LAY DOWN MY BURDEN"]
KERRIGAN SKELLY: What are you
doing right now with your life
that's going to bring about
death in your life?
If you think you can get away
and do whatever you want with
no repercussions and you want to
pour out your sins from out
your heart, of course you're
going to go to a place that
lets you do it.
Why do people go to Las Vegas?
Same reason.
[ELECTRONIC MUSIC PLAYING]
DESIREE: You jump off
a roof into a pool.
You go skinny dipping
at night.
You go back to the
pool and honestly
shower naked together.
Shit just happens.
You go there to do crazy
shit and to just let it
all out, let loose.
Because definitely, what happens
in Panama City stays
in Panama City.
MAYOR GAYLE OBERST: Panama City
Beach has been a Spring
Break headquarters
for 50 years.
On any given week or weekend,
we could have 100,000 to
200,000 people here.
PANARANDY: The kids, they get
to down here and they get to
blow off a lot of steam from
going to college and educating
their minds.
KRISTIN DUBOSE: People
join the gym.
People get tanning memberships
and prepare all year long for
one week to spend where
I live year round.
KERRIGAN SKELLY: Clench your
hands, you sinners.
Spring break, to me, is
simply another excuse
for people to sin.
All you bikini wearers,
all you fornicators.
Any city that supports sin or
that uphold sin and doesn't
condemn sin is a city of sin.
OLIVIA ALLEY: They drag coffins
up and down the road
that have "Jesus died for your
sins" painted on them.
KERRIGAN SKELLY: Jesus turning
water into wine does not
excuse your drunkenness,
sinner.
OLIVIA ALLEY: We have guys
dragging crosses on wheels.
I'm like, that's nice.
Jesus didn't get a wheel.
CHIEF DREW WHITMAN: That's what
people come for-- that
white sand and that water.
That's why we were titled
the world's
most beautiful beaches.
There's lots of beaches
around the world.
in America.
Why is it at Panama
City Beach?
Because it's lax there.
MAYOR GAYLE OBERST:
99% at of college
students are great kids.
OLIVIA ALLEY: I don't know what
these kids are getting a
hold of, but they are coming
here fucking up.
DESIREE: Wake up 7:00 AM, you
take a shot, you fall back
asleep for an hour, then
you keep on drinking.
MAYOR GAYLE OBERST: Well,
we try to have a lot of
activities on the sand.
DESIREE: You go to the beach,
you keep on drinking, you pass
out for two more hours,
then you drink
until 4:00 in the morning--
same routine every day.
MAYOR GAYLE OBERST: You'll see
them playing volleyball and
sand ball and those kind
of things on the sand.
OLIVIA ALLEY: We have people all
the time having sex out on
the beach behind here.
MAYOR GAYLE OBERST: Well, we to
have find things for them
to do to keep them
out of trouble.
And generally, the worst
stuff happens at night.
I guess darkness comes and
people feel like they're more
relaxed and do whatever
they want to do.
[ELECTRONIC MUSIC PLAYING]
ADAM HINSON: Every year
is different.
Every time I think I've seen it
all, something else happens
that blows my mind.
KRISTIN DUBOSE: Insane.
Absolutely insane.
PATRICK PFEFFER: But we got
10 theme rooms here.
This is the Thunder Dome.
Then there's the Underground.
There's the Night Gallery, the
Galaxy Room, the Pussycat
Lounge, the Dark Room.
So as you can see, it's
a huge facility.
MAYOR GAYLE OBERST: When you put
5,000 students together,
it is really an interesting
and challenging thing.
KERRIGAN SKELLY: I mean, if it
was 6,000 godly people, you'd
have no problem.
But 6,000 sinners
in one place?
ADAM HINSON: 2009, I think
it was, we had a full out
riot at this club.
Inside this main room, we
had 30-on-30 fights.
And we had to shut
the club down.
OLIVIA ALLEY: The girls would
be humping each other on the
poles with dresses pulled
up, top folded down.
Guys are finger banging girls
out on the dance floor.
They do not care.
No one has any shame.
We all understand the value that
spring break brings to a
community like Panama
City Beach.
MAYOR GAYLE OBERST: Some of
our businesses generate as
much as a third of their
revenue at that time.
CHIEF DREW WHITMAN: So it's a
big impact on our economy.
It's a great benefit
for the locals.
They can go out and get a job
and be employed for the year.
PATRICK PFEFFER: There are some
factions in the city that
they don't like spring break.
KERRIGAN SKELLY: If this city
and the mayor and everyone
else involved didn't have the
love of money concerning these
issues, surely, they would rise
up and say, you shouldn't
be a drunkard.
You shouldn't be doing this.
I'd expect the whole city
of Panama City--
all the churches there to rise
up and proclaim Jesus Christ
and tell people to
stop sinning.
OLIVIA ALLEY: I don't force
my beliefs on anyone.
So I don't feel like someone
should force theirs on me.
KERRIGAN SKELLY: So what
should they do for fun?
Well, there's a lot of
thing you can do for
fun that aren't sinful.
You can engage in athletic
activities.
You can have Bible study.
You can have fun with friends
playing board games, card
games-- as long as you're
not engaging in sin.
MAYOR GAYLE OBERST: We only have
maybe four days or a week
out of the year.
And they're at home the
rest of the time.
So they don't learn those
behaviors while
they're at the beach.
So it is a way of
perpetuating our
tourists through the years.
So many of them do come
back as parents.
OLIVIA ALLEY: We did have a
guy that worked here got a
phone call.
He had sex with a girl
in a t-shirt shop.
And she called a few months
later and was like, there's
this guy, he's a bartender, and
is he still working there?
So we put him on the phone.
And she's like, I'm pregnant.
I don't really know
if it's yours.
There were a few
different guys.
And he's like, click.
[DUBSTEP MUSIC PLAYING]
[PIANO INSTRUMENTAL,
"AMAZING GRACE"]