[FANFARE]
Reading something ahead, Commander.
Looks to be a nebula
Slow to Warp Factor 1,
Lieutenant Jenson
Sensor scans, Mr Bernstein
BERNSTEIN:
It's not a nebula
I'm picking up several different
kinds of energy--
Radiation readings of a kind
I've never seen before.
Put it on the main viewer.
We're heading right for it.
[MYSTERIOUS MUSIC]
Should we wake the Captain, sir?
Not necessary...
Radiation and Electromagnetic readings
are well within their tolerance limits
But doesn't the Captain like to be notified...
...whenever we come across something
that might be considered unusual.
SULU:
This poses no threat, Ensign
Take us through it at Warp 1
Survey and map it.
The Captain can review the computer
logs over his morning coffee
[DRAMATIC STING]
[WHISPERING]
KIRK:
Going for a morning swim, Lieutenant?`
You know there are green ladies
at the pool, right
Oh. Good morning,
Ensign Isel
Deltans.
[DOORS OPEN]
MCCOY:
Ah. Good morning, Ensign.
Well if you can call turning the lights
up at 0700 hours "morning"
ISEL:
I don't understand it.
I have not broken my vow.
Yet I can feel it inside me.
What's wrong, Isel?
I'm pregnant, Doctor.
[DRAMATIC STING]
[MAIN THEME]
Space,
The Final Frontier...
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise
It's Five Year Mission...
To Explore Strange New Worlds
To Seek Out New Life
and New Civilizations
To Boldly Go...
Where No Man Has Gone Before.
MCCOY:
Medical Log, Supplemental:
After a pregnancy of only three days...
Rather than the normal ten month
Deltan gestation period...
Ensign Isel is about to give birth.
The strange circumstances
surrounding her pregnancy
have raised deep concerns as
to the nature of the infant.
Contractions are spaced at two
minutes and regular, Doctor.
Dilation is at 9 cm.
The baby's heartbeat is normal.
I don't know how she's doing this.
The strain on her body
to adjust so quickly…
If she wasn't a Deltan...
There is nothing to worry about, Doctor.
She'll be out in a moment.
Are you having any pain?
Deltan women experience childbirth
as another kind of orgasm.
We feel far more pleasure
in it than pain.
Lucky you.
Indeed.
[DOOR OPENS]
MCCOY:
What the hell are you doing here?
Captain's orders, sir.
McCoy to Kirk.
[over com]:
Kirk here.
Damn it, Jim, can't we let this women
have her child in peace?
A security officer's presence
is normal procedure--
--under these abnormal
circumstances, Bones.
Now you can't tell me
that a new born infant--
--seriously poses any kind of danger
to the security of this vessel.
Bones....
MCCOY:
I won't have it.
This is my Sickbay and I won't
have this baby born--
--with a phaser pointed
at its head!
Nobody is pointing any phasers, Doctor.
It's unwarranted, Captain.
And it compromises the best care
I can provide to my patients.
KIRK:
Ensign Kirk---
Please take up your position in
the corridor outside of Sickbay.
Aye, sir.
Thank you, Doctor.
KIRK:
Mr Chekov...
Can you monitor this baby from
here, once it's been born?
Captain, given the bond between a
Deltan mother and child...
I feel that Ensign Isel
would notice.
Just the same--
I'd like you to monitor this as
an intruder around the clock.
Sir, it's a baby!
Well unless we can determine otherwise...
This is an intruder masquerading as a baby.
Indeed, considering the human instinct
to trust and nurture an infant--
--An intruder could not choose
a more perfect form.
It's not just human nature we
are talking about here--
--It's Deltan nature as well.
Deltan mothers are the most fiercely
protective in the galaxy.
I'm pretty sure that's why
this entity chose her.
Captain, any species selecting
a surrogate mother--
--would naturally select
the most protective one.
The choice does not necessarily
mean the entity is malevolent.
Well, it doesn't guarantee
that it's not, either.
What it does guarantee is that--
I'm going to be making some pretty
unpopular decisions on this ship,
Until we can determine whether or
not this really is a threat.
She's coming now, Doctor.
[MAGICAL STING]
MCCOY:
Well, you were right...
...It was an easy delivery.
Deltans always know.
You needn't have worried...
Now don't patronize me
young lady.
You know this was no
ordinary delivery.
She never pretended
it was, Doctor.
Have you thought
of a name?
Irska.
After the baby's father.
After it's father?!
Her father.
Irska means 'pure light'
in Deltan.
[SINGING]
Sir, it's just a baby.
I wouldn't call immaculate conception,
after a three day pregnancy, "normal".
Then what's to become of it?
[BOSUN WHISTLE]
Kirk here.
MCCOY:
Jim, I just did a complete scan of Isel's baby...
You'd better get down here.
I'm on my way, Doctor.
Mr Spock, you have the conn.
What do you have for me, Bones?
Well, the child checks out as human
in almost every respect.
No Deltan characteristics?
None that I can detect.
Well how the hell can that be?
I don't know.
What's even more incredible
is how fast she's growing--
--even faster now than
in Isel's womb.
By human standards, she's growing
a little more than a year per day.
Her metabolism is normal which, in theory,
means she can't possibly be processing--
--enough food to account for the
rate of growth we're observing.
What would happen if I had
them separated now?
No you can't do that, Jim.
For one thing, Isel would stop
at nothing to get her back.
That child could pose
a threat to this ship
in ways that we can't
even imagine.
No matter how much Isel
loves that child,
That child was put inside
her by an unknown alien
For an unknown reason.
Well it may be unusual, but it's not
altogether unheard of for species--
--to reproduce by depositing their
eggs in an unsuspecting host.
Exactly--
And in almost every case--
That life form it's reproducing
is almost always a parasite.
Let me see if I can set
your mind at ease.
There's something else I haven't
told you about Isel's baby...
I don't think she's going
to live out the week.
Why not?
She was born with an abnormally
high white blood cell count--
--and it's steadily increasing...
She has leukaemia.
And from all my studies--
--I don't believe she is going to respond
to any known form of treatment.
[SPOCK OVER INTERCOM]
Captain Kirk, please report to the bridge.,
We have an alien object approaching
2500 Km and closing.
Acknowledged, Mr Spock.
I'll be there momentarily.
Go to yellow alert.
Does Isel know?
Not yet.
Use your discretion, Bones.
Any sign of hostility,
Mr Chekov?
No, sir.
Sensor readings, Mr Spock?
No known life forms.
You're hedging your bets, Spock.
You think there's something
inside that thing?
Sensors indicate only a hollow
tri-tritanium shell--
--surrounding a field of what
could be "Dark Light".
"Dark Light"?
Analogous to "Dark Matter", Captain.
It seems to possess the
energy of photons--
--but without the detectable
wavelengths.
There appeared to be some in that cloud
that we encountered four nights ago.
The night Isel's child
was conceived...
Precisely.
But it is far more concentrated
inside the cylinder.
The shell exactly duplicates
the alloy of our hull.
Well that's no coincidence, Spock--
Somebody's making a point
about our technology.
Perhaps.
Sensors show no signs of machinery
on board of any kind--
--Yet it appears to have no difficulty
paralleling our course.
Well how can that be?
It cannot be.
Logic dictates there is a controlling lifeform
that our sensors are failing to detect.
Lieutenant, hailing frequencies open.
Hailing frequencies open, Sir.
This is Captain James T. Kirk
of the Starship Enterprise.
Identify yourself and
your intentions.
No response, sir.
It seems safe to assume
there's a connection--
--between the object and
Isel's child, Captain.
Well, we still don't know who's
behind all this, Spock.
For all we know, it could be
Isel's child causing this.
It has made no hostile
gestures, sir.
Scan it again Mr Spock.
This time a little more
aggressively.
If it thinks we are trying to scan it,
maybe it'll take the time to contact us.
I want to know what the
hell I'm dealing with
Before I have to do
anything about it.
Mother.
Irska.
[ECHOING]
Mother.
Irska.
[DRAMATIC FANFARE]
KIRK:
Captain's Log, Stardate 9717.7
A week has passed since the
birth of Isel's child
and the appearance of the
strange alien cylinder.
Despite an ever increasing
white blood cell count,
Irska remains healthy.
Her stage of development is now
roughly that of a ten-year-old child.
We remain unable to make contact
with the alien cylinder
or to determine why, or even
how, it is following us.
Today I resume my duties.
That means we'll be
apart for a time.
Can't I work with you?
No. My work is my work.
It's important now for you
to spend time alone
To become what
you are to be.
But, what will I do?
Whatever you want. Learn.
Discover joyfulness alone.
Once you achieve that, you
need never fear rejection.
[DOOR BUZZ]
Come.
I would like permission to
resume my duties, Captain.
And what about your daughter?
She's busy learning to have
a good relationship.
With whom?
Herself.
She must be alone and get to know herself
before sharing herself with others.
Isel, have you made any plans
for you and your daughter?
Plans?
I must love her.
Teach her what I can.
--and let her go.
Go? Go where?
To do what?
Appearances to the contrary,
she's not human--
and she's not Deltan - nor is she any
other race that we're familiar with.
Do you really think she can adjust
to that kind of aloneness?
Captain, she is my child.
Even if we are physically
separated--
the bond between us
is inseparable.
Where she goes and what she
does must be left up to her.
And what if she were to
pose some kind of danger?
She does not - could not
pose danger to anyone.
Do you have any idea whether or not she's
connected to that cylinder out there?
No. None at all. I'm sorry.
Very well, Ensign, thank you.
You can return to duty now.
Thank you, sir.
ISEL:
You are relieved, Mr Chekov.
Thanks for taking over for me.
It was my pleasure.
And how is the beautiful Irska today?
She's just marvellous.
Something is being beamed aboard
from the alien cylinder.
It's roughly one cubic centimetre
of "dark light" atmosphere--
--contained in the cylinder
Find it and isolate it.
It is in our number ten filter--
--of our atmospheric
purification system.
We've isolated the filter and
are redirecting the air flow.
What's the problem, Spock?
A small quantity of "dark light" was
beamed into our filtration system.
Lt Chekov contained it
as quickly as possible.
However, it is an extreme
biotoxin and--
we were exposed to a lethal dose
2.3 seconds after it arrived.
Unless Dr. McCoy can counteract it
within 6.2 hours, it will kill us all.
[TELEPATHIC SIGNAL]
KIRK:
Captain's log, supplemental.
It has now been more
than four hours--
--Since the alien craft
beamed a deadly--
portion of its atmosphere
into our ship.
So far, Dr. McCoy has
made little progress
toward finding a
cure for its effects.
The crew is already displaying symptoms
of the "dark light" toxin
and though they continue to
maintain the ship's routine--
Many of them have become despondent--
--hopeless.
Which one is this?
NK-one-seven platelets
with monocyte serum.
Any luck?
Worthless.
Next.
[BAGPIPE MUSIC PLAYS]
I'm sorry, I didn't
mean to hurt you...
It's all right, lass.
Aren't you with your mother?
She's at the bridge and Captain Kirk
doesn't like me to be there.
So you came to see
old Mr Scott?
You know, you're the only wee
lass I've ever known--
--who could see the beauty in
engineering schematics.
I see beauty in almost
everything, Mr Scott.
I've got a present for you.
It's like your mother's.
Oh, Mr Scott.
It's beautiful.
Thank you!
Is it possible that they are being
remotely controlled, somehow?
If that is the case, then it is being
done from a greater distance--
--than our long range
scanners can detect.
Well, something moved the "Dark Light"
into our air supply.
There must be an intelligent
life form behind all of this.
I'm convinced that they know
what they are doing to us.
Possibly. Or, it could be studying us,
learning how the toxins affects us.
If it simply wanted
to kill us--
--I suspect it could do so
far more efficiently.
That's comforting.
Really?
No, Mr Xon.
Not really.
Bones, progress report?
MCCOY:
None. The toxin makes changes to the proteins
in our cells that I can't begin to understand.
I'm just flying blind, hoping
to get lucky, Jim.
We've got less than two hours.
Doctor, when was the last
time you examined Irska?
Damn it, Spock! I don't have
time to do a complete physical.
I'm trying to create a vaccine.
If she and the object are,
in fact, connected--
--then Irska could provide a key
to counteracting the toxin.
Fine. Then send her down.
I can't do any worse
than I'm doing now.
Captain, if this is absolutely necessary,
I'd like to be with her for the examination.
I don't want her to be frightened or
to think she's done something wrong.
You can't interfere with what
the doctor has planned.
I understand.
Get her to sickbay. Fast.
[DOORS OPEN]
[MCCOY COUGHS]
Bring her here.
[DOOR BUZZ]
[DOOR BUZZ TWICE]
Come.
I thought you wanted to
stay with your daughter.
She knew I would feel
any pain that she felt--
--and that my pain would
be greater than hers.
Won't you feel it just
as much here?
Only if I focus on it, and
she asked me not to.
She felt it would make the
process more difficult for her.
I'm sorry that all
this was necessary.
Why did you do that?
To make a connection.
A sexual connection?
I'm Deltan.
Any meaningful contact between
us will feel sexual to you.
And you think you can use
that to influence me.
Captain, do you know why Deltans
agree to take oaths of celibacy?
Because Starfleet
requires you to.
Beyond that.
We live to connect as deeply as
possible with other beings.
Putting a limit on our
ability to do so--
--heightens all our senses to compensate
for what we're missing.
So, the process of being less Deltan
makes us even more Deltan.
So what's your point, Ensign?
The only bond stronger than
that between Deltan lovers
is the bond between a Deltan
mother and her child.
You felt a powerful connection
when I touched you
--but my bond with Irska
is infinitely deeper.
I can sense all
her feelings...
even the difference between
how a food tastes to me--
--and how it tastes
to her.
I hoped that my touch would
help you to understand--
--how I can know that my daughter
is no threat to this ship.
Well, that cylinder attacked this
ship and poisoned our air--
--and you know they are
connected somehow.
She feels a connection, but
has no sense of its nature.
Attacking that cylinder
could harm Irska.
That's why you're here...
My daughter is innocent.
I would know if
she were not.
She is not responsible for
what the cylinder does.
Well the evidence suggests that,
she may not be directing it--
--but it probably wouldn't
be here otherwise.
[DOOR BUZZ]
Come.
Well, I've deployed medics to all
decks dispensing injections.
I thought you'd like yours
as soon as possible.
Bones!  You found a cure!
Dr. McCoy taught me all
about life and death.
Well, Thank my young
assistant here.
She had the cure inside of her
a week before we needed it.
Those strange white corpuscles of hers
adapted to the toxin and neutralized it.
Has she been affected
in any other way?
Just her miraculous
blood adaptation.
[KLAXON & BOSUN WHISTLE]
SPOCK:
Captain, our hull is being penetrated by
an energy beam of unknown nature--
from the alien cylinder.
Shields are ineffective.
I'm on my way.
[DRAMATIC STING]
KIRK:
Damage report, Mr Sulu.
Alien energy beam is focused
on impulse engine
--plasma cooling unit 2, the
coil and shutdown servos.
Evasive manoeuvres.
ISEL:
Impulse engine plasma is
overheating, Captain.
Lock phasers on target.
Locked on target, sir.
Captain, the alien has disengaged
its energy beam.
Hold your fire, Mr Sulu.
Why did they stop?
I believe the attack was disengaged
because it has completed its goal
Our impulse engine plasma
cooling coil has ruptured.
The attack was broken off at the
exact instant the rupture occurred.
Why would they do
that, Mr Spock?
What point does
it serve?
Unknown, Captain.
[BOSUN WHISTLE]
SCOTTY:
We've got a mess down
here, Captain.
The impulse engines are spewing out
plasma and we can't shut them down.
Ensign Hemmings is in there,
trying to get a better look.
Keep me posted, Mr Scott.
Well as always, that green
blood of yours proved--
--to be a particular pain
in my posterior.
IRSKA:
Look, there's a leak in the
number 2 cooling coil.
Yes, we know.
You have to fix it or the impulse
engine will explode.
[DRAMATIC STING]
How did you know that?
Mr Scott showed me all
the technical manuals.
Medical team to
engineering!
Lt Ross has taken a massive
dose of theta radiation.
Captain, the automatic
systems failed.
I've sealed the tube
manually for now
But the leak is releasing
pure theta ionized plasma.
Can you stop it?
Our only hope is to
patch the coil.
One man could weld the patch
in about 15 minutes.
Captain, theta radiation in the
access tube is too intense.
Even with a protective suit--
No one could remain conscious in there
for more than a few minutes.
Get down there. See if
you can lend a hand.
Sulu, How much time
do we have?
89 minutes.
She's right,
Captain.
Stay on it,
Mr Scott.
Young lady, you'll have
to come with me.
But can't I--
--Oww!
I'm sorry.
I need you to come
with me, please.
You too, Mr Spock.
The theta plasma levels are
in red zone proximity.
Keep the exhaust manifolds
on full or I'm a dead man.
Aye, sir.
I'm considering
a mind meld.
I don't think it would
work, Captain.
Isel would sense
it instantly--
--and I would be flooded with
her feelings as well.
What's a "mind meld"?
Great.  Deltan sensitivity
and ears like a Vulcan.
A mind meld is a technique that would
let us share each other's thoughts.
I'd like that.
Yes, I'd like that, too.
But now is not the time.
Your mother has the ability
to sense aspects of things--
--that she can't see or touch.
Can you do this, as well?
Yes, I think so.
Can you try for me?
Can you try very hard?
Are you able to sense anything about this
cylinder that's following this ship?
[COUGHING]
Mr Scott is dying!
I have to help him!
ISEL:
No!!!
Isel...
What's wrong?
[BOSUN WHISTLE]
KIRK:
Dr. McCoy to the
briefing room.
MILLER:
Send a medical team,
Mr Scott is down.
Jim, I should see
to Scotty.
In a minute, Bones.
I need to know if Irska's blood
will adapt to the theta radiation.
It's possible...
It can.  I know it can!
You cannot allow this!
I won't allow it.
She's just a child!
I want to. I can save the
ship and Mr Scott!
That's not your job.
Yes, it is!
If I fix the leak my blood will
adapt to the theta radiation--
--and Dr. McCoy can use it to save
Mr Scott, just like last time.
Sweetheart, we don't know that
your blood will adapt again.
She's right, we can't
know for sure.
However, Ensign--
I believe it's highly likely her
blood will adapt as needed.
You may be willing to risk my
daughter's life on "highly likely"
--But I am not.
Ensign, the impulse engines will explode,
inside of an hour, if we don't fix that leak.
All of our lives are at risk,
Your daughter is the only person
capable of staying conscious--
--long enough inside
that tube to fix it.
You don't know she can
stay conscious in there.
We know that nobody
else can.
Mommy, Mr Scott is my friend.
I don't want him to die. Please.
We need to get that
suit off him.
Get Dr. McCoy down
here now.
Decker to Captain.
Kirk here, how's Scotty?
Critical.
McCoy is on his way.
I'll be on the bridge.
I should be going.
Despite my fear--
I cherish that you have
learned to love others--
--so much that you want to do this.
I'll be alright,
mother, really.
Any activity from the
cylinder, Mr Sulu?
None, sir.
How long until impulse
engine meltdown?
Twenty minutes, sir.
Mr Scott already applied
the patch to the leak,
so all you have to do
is use this torch--
--along the edges of the
patch to seal it.
It's operated by...
Mr Scott showed me yesterday.
You just press this button.
The edges of the seal will change
colour from red to blue as it seals--
--and the gas should
stop escaping.
Don't worry. I can do it.
Alright, let's go.
Well, there's nothing
more we can do.
We can only hope that Irska's blood
will adapt to the theta radiation.
I can start preparing a medium for
the serum right now, Doctor.
We might as well be ready.
Do it. I'll be on the bridge.
[COMM CHIRP]
PETER:
We're ready.
[FORCEFIELD DEACTIVATES]
I'm here. I see the patch.
Remember to keep the torch in place
until the red line turns blue--
--then move it to the
next bit of red.
I will.
How long has she
been in there?
3.2 minutes longer
than Mr Scott
Well, that's a
good sign
The pattern of recent events indicates
she will succeed in her task--
--and suffer no ill effects from
the radiation, Doctor.
However, the same pattern
dictates a new crisis--
--will follow swiftly upon
resolution of this one.
No life form in the galaxy--
--can spoil good news faster
than your average Vulcan.
I may as well head back to sickbay
and start getting ready.
Captain, I suggest a
mind meld with Irska.
Her subconscious may well hold the
reason for these consecutive crises.
I mentioned that earlier to
Spock and he thought--
--the child's connection to her mother
would make it unlikely to succeed.
For him, perhaps.
Mr Spock has struggled his entire
life to suppress emotion.
For me, it is effortless. I would have
less chance of being overwhelmed.
Are you saying this could be
more dangerous than usual?
Undoubtedly, but I suspect
the risk will be necessary.
Let's hope not.
For now, we have more pressing
matters to deal with.
How much time do we
have, Mr Chekov?
Four minutes, Captain.
Engineering, stand by to recharge impulse
engine coolers on my command.
Aye, Captain.
You have to work quickly, Irska.
One minute to impulse
engine meltdown.
Engineering! Recharge impulse
engine coolers now!
Recharging, sir. Plasma levels
are returning to nominal.
Impulse engine temperature
is coming down, Captain.
Ensign Kirk, escort Irska to
sickbay on the double.
Captain, I think the alien object
is attacking us again.
You think?
What's it doing?
I don't know, Captain, but--
--something is affecting
the integrity of our hull.
On screen, now.
There is no apparent energy
being applied to us--
--but somehow the
atoms of our hull
are being manipulated
below the quantum level.
Is the object causing it?
Unknown, sir.
But the object is experiencing
the same effect.
Evasive manoeuvres, Mr Sulu.
Take us away from it.
Anti-matter imbalance, Captain.
Warp drive engines shutting down!
What the hell
is going on?
I can only estimate--
--but if the manipulation continues
at the present rate--
--our ship's hull will cease to exist in
something less than 14 minutes.
Mr Spock, take the conn.
Mr Xon, you're with me.
You, my dear, have the most amazing blood
any doctor has ever encountered.
With you around, I could cure
just about anything.
I have the medium all ready.
I will have the serum in no time.
I need Mr Xon to mind meld
with your daughter. Now.
Is that wise? Melding with her melds
with me and everyone close to me.
Wise or not, it's the only way I'm going
to understand the threat to this ship.
Irska?
I'd be happy to join
minds with Mr Xon.
Wouldn't it be funny if we
taught him how to laugh?
Very funny, darling.
My mind to
your mind...
Your thoughts to
my thoughts...
[DRAMATIC STING]
KIRK:
Captain's log, supplemental.
An unknown entity--
--believed connected to
Isel's mysterious daughter--
is poised to destroy our ship
in less than 12 minutes.
Lt Xon, our best chance to
understand this entity's motives--
--lies unconscious in sickbay.
MCCOY:
I can try but it could just
as easily kill him.
SPOCK:
There is another way.
KIRK:
No, Spock!
I can't risk losing
you both.
Lt Xon is no longer in contact
with Isel and Irska.
Whatever shock resulting from that
contact, has already processed.
I would be melding Vulcan to Vulcan,
which essentially should be safe.
Bones?
Well, "should be safe" isn't
the same as "safe"--
--and there's no way I
can predict the risk.
I mean, I consider it a small miracle
if I can cure a Vulcan of a headache.
Vulcans do not get
headaches, Doctor.
I rest my case.
Do it, Spock.
[MEDICAL TRICORDER OPERATING]
Spock! ... Spock!
Bones, give him a shot.
Get him out of it.
Spock--
What happened?
I was overwhelmed
with a sensation--
A sense of connection--
--unlike any I've known.
It was intoxicating.
Perhaps it was Deltan love--
--Perhaps it was from
the alien entity.
I do not know.
Did you find any connection between
Irska and the entity?
Only one word, sir--
"Cryontha"
"Cryontha" [ECHOING IN SPACE]
"Cryontha"? What does it mean?
Unknown, sir.
Mr Spock--
-- use the ship's computer and run
a search for the word "cryontha"
Acknowledged.
Lieutenant, broadcast "cryontha" to the
alien cylinder on all frequencies.
Broadcasting....
Mr Kirk, lock phasers on
the alien cylinder.
Arming phasers.
Locking on target.
No response, sir.
If they won't respond to one
kind of communication--
--Maybe they'll respond to another.
Fire.
[PHASERS FIRE]
[IRSKA CRIES]
ISEL:
Stop it, Captain!
Stop it, now!
Cease fire.
I'm sorry.
I didn't want
to hurt you.
You realize this proves the connection
between your daughter and the entity.
What do you intend
to do, Captain?
I don't know--
--but I am not going to let this ship
be destroyed without a fight.
SPOCK:
Captain. I've found a
reference to "cryontha".
It was prominent in hieroglyphs found
in ruins of an advanced civilization
on a planet abandoned
by its inhabitants--
--over 100 million years ago.
What does it mean, Spock?
The translation is
believed to be--
"Unnecessary Shell"
"Unnecessary shell"?
There may be a connection, Captain,
as the planet is located--
--not far from where
Isel was impregnated.
Irska?
Does "unnecessary shell"
mean anything to you?
No, sir.
Think hard.
Think very hard.
"Cryontha"
"Unnecessary shell."
Did you think of something?
I don't know.
I don't think so.
Ensign Isel, hold
your daughter.
What are you
going to do?
Look! The phasers didn't
do anything!
They sent a message. I have no
choice but to send it back.
Mr Kirk, fire phasers.
NO!!
Mommy!!!
Security team to the bridge.
Your mother's going
to be all right.
COMPUTER:
Hull integrity compromised.
Total hull failure will
occur in seven minutes.
Shut that damn thing off!
Take Ensign Isel and her
daughter to their quarters--
--and see to it that
they stay there.
Phaser and photon torpedo controls are both out, Captain.
Go to auxiliary.
Captain, Isel was right.
Despite the pain to the child--
--the alien cylinder
experienced no damage.
I believe additional firing will
only hurt only the child.
No need to be frightened.
You've only felt pain.
Why must anyone feel pain?
It's part of life. Sometimes
it's how we understand.
Can you make me understand...
what "cryontha" is?
It's inside your mind.
Only you can find it.
And if I don't,
everyone will die?
Don't use your mind
to feel guilt.
Ask yourself what cryontha is,
and just let the answer come...
But Mr Spock said it meant
"unnecessary shell".
That's what it means to him.
Discover what it means to you.
Mr Spock, how much time?
Approximately 5 minutes, Captain.
Metallurgy, report.
No progress on a catalysing agent, Captain.
Physics lab, report.
We've tried reverse gravity and a battery of
magnetic field generators. No effect, sir.
Bones, what's your status?
All theta radiation patients have
responded to treatment, Jim
and Nurse Natal is on her way
to the bridge with Mr Xon.
The minute he regained consciousness
he insisted on coming up here.
Are you alright, Mr Xon?
The Deltan impressions were stronger
than I anticipated, but I will recover.
What you must know is that each of
the calamities that befell our ship--
--was intended to teach Irska
something about life, death,
and emotions I could not comprehend.
Irska feels incomplete,
but does not know why.
Well, what about cryontha?
What is cryontha?
I do not know--
--but I believe it to be the key to
her next stage of development.
NO! I'm not ready to lose you.
You can never lose me.
That's why you were chosen.
But I will lose this...
And this...
We will touch in other ways.
I know.  We must hurry...
Spock, what's
going on?
Unknown, Captain, but quantum
manipulation of the atoms--
--in our hull is no longer synchronized
with those of the cylinder.
[BOSUN WHISTLE]
All decks!  This is security.
Ensign Isel and her daughter
have escaped from their quarters.
Scanning all decks, Captain.
I have them.
Ensign Kirk, get to the transporter
room on the double and detain them.
Spock, your with me.
IRSKA:
Let her go!
The "unnecessary shell"
is my body!
Captain...
No!
[PHASER FIRE]
[ENERGISING]
[TRANSPORTER DEMATERILIZATION]
Forgive me, Jim.
There was no time to explain.
Where did you send her?
She sent Irska into the cylinder.
You killed her?
No, Captain--
--Her body was the
"unnecessary shell".
She learned to let it go.
[BOSUN WHISTLE]
CHEKOV:
The alien cylinder has
vanished, Captain.
Our hull has returned to normal.
Stand down from red alert, Mr Chekov.
You're all right with this?
Thousands of centuries ago, Irska's
race existed in human form.
Just as humans pass through
all evolutionary stages--
--from single cell to human being
within the mother's womb.
Irska had to experience all stages
of her race's prior development.
So what you are saying is that, Irska,
hasn't even really been born, yet?
Until she had experienced all joys
and pains of living in a body
and was ready to shed the
'unnecessary shell'--
--it represented to her, she was still in
an embryonic state for her race.
I was her first womb.
The Enterprise was her second.
I wish her life with you
could have been longer,
and wish there was some way I could
have made it easier for both of you.
Thank you, Captain.
I appreciate your sentiments, but only
our physical connection has been broken.
Besides--
I hardly expect you to make
improvements on a miracle.
English subtitles by Peter Walker & Peter Goundrill
www.startrekphase2.de