My name is Nicholas Forker.
I make drawings and
sculptures.
I encounter so many people who
feel kind of listless and just
misplaced or apathetic, and I
was trying to answer that
question, why do my
contemporaries
feel so out of sorts?
So I started to turn towards
when men felt vital.
The heroic roles, the classic
things like the deep sea
diver, the cowboy, the
Arctic explorer.
Well, then I drew a cosmonaut,
and it kind of all clicked
into place.
Here was this subject that
made perfect sense--
the explorer, the hero role,
which turned out to be more of
a metaphor for the trajectory
of the American male in the
late 20th century.
I think that it's become
more of like a Don
Quixote figure, though.
Now, anyway.
With the space program being
pushed into the private sector
and NASA's funding getting cut
dramatically, we're seeing
that dream kind of fizzle.
And we've gone from--
right, we're going to do these
things because they're hard,
to like a mess, really.
The idea to wear the suit was
seeing the use of the
astronaut as my main figure.
It was seeing that idea to
a logical conclusion.
I was able to borrow a suit, and
it was an exact replica of
Buzz Aldrin's lunar landing
suit from '69.
And my very talented friend
Clint Spaulding came along to
shoot some photos, a series of
photos of me in the suit.
The original idea was to take
all of the photos, reference
material, create realistic
drawings of them.
But the performance aspect of,
like, embodying the astronaut,
that idea of the self-portrait
as the subject, now I'm
thinking that the photographs
might stand on their own.
The reason why space is so
fascinating to me is because
of its unknown quantity.
It's more about space, to
me, than the astronaut.
Because the astronaut
is only a symbol.
It's a symbol of our attempt,
our kind of frail human
attempt, to thrust ourselves
into something that we know
nothing about.
The feeling that I would
experience in space would be
peace and quiet.
It would be a refreshing
change of pace.
That would quickly give
way to loneliness
and madness, probably.
When I walked around in this
suit, I felt that it was the
embodiment of that left-hand
path, the life of the artist.
It's monastic.
You spend most of
your time alone.
When you do you open your mouth,
you find that either
you don't understand what people
are saying to you, or
they don't understand what
you're saying to them.
So many different people tried
to make the space suit, and it
was Playtex that got the
contract for the space suit
for the Apollo mission.
It was because of their
knowledge of fabrics that they
were able to weave together,
like, I don't know-- it was
like 13 to 20 different types of
materials to make the space
suit that they landed
on the moon with.
It's just a really fascinating
idea that you could come up
with essentially what is like a
plastic bag and jump into it
and go into space.
It represents the fragility
of human life.
This work is an example of
relating that human experience
in the later half of the 20th
century in the United States.
It's like, I can only speak
from my experience.
These are the experiences
I have.
It says, take the most
triumphant hero and watch what
happens after nobody cares
about them anymore.
The dinosaur that is fine art
is quickly being replaced by
this multimedia explosion.
Like, just all your synapses
are filled with digital
information constantly.
Well, how do you make a
two-dimensional static image
that is captivating?
I thought on that long and hard,
and I think one of the
ways to do it is to demonstrate
a skill, something
that can't be done on
the computer, with
an app on your phone.
Do it with materials that are
really difficult to work with,
that people wouldn't think
about combining.
The ballpoint, the Mylar,
drawing on plastic.
Take something that has to do
with the essence of your
experience as a person, as a
human being, everything that
you've done, everything that
you've seen, everything that
you've thought of, everything
that you've been exposed to--
and condense all of that
into one image.
I chose the astronaut
because as a
symbol, it's very powerful.
It speaks of a specific
point in time.
place in time.
It talks about dreams.
It talks about hopes.
It talks about aspirations.
It talks about realistic
implication of those things.
It talks about successes
and failures.
It talks about the human mind,
space as this infinitely large
representation of something
that is infinitely small,
contained in all of us.
The artwork, for me, is about
highlighting that last stage
in the adventurer, the person
who is the frontiersperson.
I think that role,
or the landscape
for that, has changed.
I think that that has to do with
our own brain, our own
consciousness, and the way
we affect our reality.
So for me, this is more like
putting up a signpost and
saying, like, this
is where it's at.
And I'm looking forward to
possible replacements.