CARL AZUZ, CNN ANCHOR: As we begin this March
5th edition of CNN`s STUDENT NEWS, we`re heading
to the African nation of Kenya. It`s home
to a population of 43 million people. Kenya`s
government is a republic where its citizens
elect their leaders and that`s what they did
yesterday.
NIC ROBERTSON, CNN INTERNATIONAL CORRESPONDENT:
This comes after a new constitution was passed
on 2010 and is the most complex election in
Kenya`s history. People will be voting for
member of county assembly, governor, senator,
women`s member of national assembly, member
of national assembly, and finally president.
AZUZ: Part of the reason why Kenya`s constitution
changed was the violence that followed the
country`s last presidential election. The
results were challenged. Supporters of different
candidates fought each other. More than 1,200
people were killed. The changes to the country`s
government were designed to make future elections
more peaceful.
ROBERTSON: People have been turning out to
vote in the polling stations like this one
in the poor city of Mombassa since before
6 in the morning when the polling stations
opened. Some places we visited had lines half
a mile long. And that`s despite fears of the
possibility of tribal violence.
AZUZ stations. There was a stampede at another
voting site. And some police officers were
attacked. Some Kenyans were preparing for
this kind of thing before the election and
they were planning to use social media to
help reduce violence on election day. Nima
Elbagir explains how.
NIMA ELBAGIR, NAIROBI, KENYA: During the violence
that marred the 2007 elections here, citizen
journalists were crucial in helping to pinpoint
the worst effected areas, and none more than
Ushahidi which means witness in Swahili.
You have been working on different ways to
ensure that this election is transparent.
DAUDI WERE, USHAHIDI: What you see here is
a team of digital humanitarians. The people
who deal with the data that we get into the
system. Uchaguzi (ph) the Swahili name for
"election" is the name of the platform we
are deploying for this election. We have partners
across the country sending us information,
but also verifying the information that we
get. And the second tool that we use is a
technology platform (INAUDIBLE) and the various
apps that go along with it.
ELBAGIR: Because the apps are really cool.
You`ve got one on your phone right here. So
people go online, they download this app,
and then anywhere in the country if they see
something they have concern about they go
onto the app and they report it, or they tweet
it, or they take a picture and it reaches
you immediately.
WERE: You have the power in your hands (ph)
to protect your vote and that`s what we`re
doing at Ordinary Citizens - working together
to protect our vote and our electoral process.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Is this legit? Women
with HIV can pass the virus to their children
during pregnancy.
This is true. Infected mothers can infect
their babies during pregnancy, delivery, or
nursing.
AZUZ: HIV stands for Human Immunodeficiency
Virus. It affects the body`s immune system,
and it can lead to AIDS. There`s not an official
cure, but researchers say a 2-year-old girl
from this Mississippi hospital was the first
child to be functionally cured of HIV.
That`s an important difference. Functionally
cured doesn`t mean the virus is gone completely.
It means that the virus` presence is so small
that standard tests can`t find it, and the
patient doesn`t need lifelong treatment.
Here`s how it happened. The baby`s mother
has HIV. Within 30 hours of the birth, doctors
started treating the baby for HIV. The baby
was on HIV drugs for about 15 months, then
for whatever reason the mother stopped giving
the baby the drugs. She was off them from
8-10 months. When doctors saw her next, no
signs of HIV. She was functionally cured.
DR. HANNAH GAY, UNIV. OF MISSISSIPPI MEDICAL
CENTER: That`s still a possibility and we`re
going to be following the baby for a while
to make sure that the virus does not come
back. However, at this point, she`s been off
medicines for quite some time and there has
been no return of the virus. This is quite
unique. We`ve not seen this in other cases
before.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today`s shoutout goes
to Ms. Jaeger`s U.S. government class at Spring
Valley High School in Las Vegas, Nevada.
Which prefix is the Latin word that means
"field?" Here we go. Is it tapo, agri, pharma,
or tera?
You`ve got three seconds, go.
Agri is Latin for "field" and agriculture
is the culture of the field, like raising
crops and livestock. That`s your answer, and
that`s your shoutout.
AZUZ: A huge amount of the food the world
produces, up to half of it in some places,
is wasted. And this is what we mean by that.
What you didn`t finish from your meal at a
restaurant and what you don`t take home to
eat is thrown out - it`s wasted. When you
buy food at the store but wind up trashing
it later, wasted. When grocery stores don`t
sell all the fruits and vegetables they have
in time or when they won`t accept farm produce
that doesn`t look fresh but actually might
be, that can go to waste.
It`s a problem worldwide, but there are some
solutions to it. One is not buying more food
than you can eat or share. CNN`s Erin McLaughlin
found another at a store in England.
ERIN MCLAUGHLIN, CNN CORRESPONDENT: Vegetables
lie rotting in an English field. It`s not
bad weather that`s done it. It`s not insects
or pests that have made it inedible. The farmers
in charge of this field say they had to reject
all of this cabbage because it didn`t look
right.
TRISTRAM STUART, FEEDING SK: Here we have,
look at that. A couple of weeks ago, this
was a beautiful head of broccoli. Lovely sprouting
broccoli. It`s one of my favorite vegetables.
And as you can see, we have half an acre of
rotten broccoli here. It breaks my heart.
MCLAUGHLIN: Tristram Stuart and his team collect
food that would otherwise go to waste. They`re
here to salvage what`s left of the cabbages.
STUART: You can see the outer leaves have
been pecked by pigeons. That means that the
supermarkets don`t want them, even though
no one eats these outer leaves and the heart
of this cabbage is perfectly good, fresh,
delicious, nutritious food.
MCLAUGHLIN: According to a study, up to 30
percent of the UK`s vegetable crop never leaves
the field as a result of such practices. But
it doesn`t have to be this way. Here at The
People`s Supermarket in central London, chef
Arthur Potts Dawson sees beyond imperfection.
The People`s Supermarket accepts produce from
the field that would have otherwise gone to
waste.
ARTHUR POTTS DAWSON, THE PEOPLE`S SUPERMARKET:
Well, we actively went out and sought it.
You know? We really, really looked for it.
I would go into the field and there would
be pulling out tons and tons and tons of potatoes
every hour, but there was a byproduct. About
30 percent of it, misshapen, a little bit
crushed, was just discarded. I said, well
what are you doing with those? And they said,
you want them? And I said, I don`t just want
them, I will pay you for them.
MCLAUGHLIN: The result, a colorful array of
vegetables. Imperfect avocado, kale, and artichoke.
How has the consumer responded? Do people
come in here? Do they notice some of the imperfections?
And do they buy?
POTTS DAWSON: People have already been trained
by decades of supermarkets now to only buy
the perfect, you know, the perfect leek. But
the imperfect leek, if they don`t buy it,
I`ll take it.
MCLAUGHLIN: And they practice what they preach
here. There`s a full kitchen at the back of
the supermarket, complete with a chef who
uses the produce customers don`t buy to make
ready-made meals to be sold in the store.
Proof that looks don`t necessarily matter
when it comes to making delicious food. Erin
McLaughlin, CNN, London.
AZUZ: A new report from Facebook says that
teenagers may be getting sick of Facebook,
and heading to other social media apps and
sites. What do you think about this idea of
Facebook fatigue? If you`re still on Facebook,
talk to us about it on Facebook.com/cnnstudentnews.
Joseph Brunell (ph) is an eighth grader at
Vickery Creek Middle School in Forsyth County,
Georgia. He loves basket ball, but Joseph
has a medical condition called Spina Bifida.
It restricts him to a wheelchair, so he can`t
play on the Vickery Creek team. At least,
that was true until one recent game.
MICHAEL CHEEK, HEAD COACH, VICKERY CREEK BASKETBALL
TEAM: It`s going to be a surprise. It`s going
to all about Joseph Brunell (ph).
AZUZ: For the fourth quarter, they gave Joseph
a jersey and brought the game to him. Players
on both teams have been secretly practicing
in wheelchairs so that they could make Joseph
part of this game. One of his teammates said
they did this for Joseph because of what he
taught them.
UNIDENTIFIED STUDENT: We learned to never
give up, and always try our best in every
thing we do.
AZUZ: Fantastic story. It`s March, we may
be a little early for the madness, but this
video makes a great warm up. High school section
championship. Team in-bounding the ball is
down two with three seconds to go. Crosscourt
pass, stolen, Ball thrown in the air to run
out the clock, but the guy who threw the in-bound
pass gets his hands on it, and heaves up a
desperation shot. Makes it. 55-foot shot at
the buzzer. Watch it play out in real time.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: A last second shot that nets a ton of
attention. That was definitely a buzzer-beater.
Teachers, your feedback, our homepage, perfect
match. Tell us what you thought of today`s
show and we`ll meet you back here tomorrow
for more CNN STUDENT NEWS.