CARL AZUZ, CNN ANCHOR: It`s Thursday, I`m
Carl Azuz. This is CNN STUDENT NEWS bringing
global headlines to middle and high school
classrooms around the world. Today, we are
starting in the Middle East.
Fighting in Syria has been going on for almost
two years. But it could stop tomorrow, maybe
just for a little bit. It`s part of a cease-
fire proposal that members of the Syrian government
and the rebels fighting them say they agree
to in principle. Now, in principle and in
reality are two different things. There was
a cease-fire in Syria back in April, but it
barely lasted a day. This one was the idea
of a United Nations representative who is
trying to work on a solution to the fighting.
Tomorrow is the start of the Muslim holiday
called Yid Alada (ph). It lasts for several
days, the question is, will the proposed cease-fire
last that long, if it happens at all.
Out next headline takes us from the Middle
East to the Caribbean Sea. Storm named Sandy
is moving through the area, it became a hurricane
yesterday with wind speeds of around 80 miles
per hour, and it was on a path to hit the
island of Jamaica. People there and across
the Caribbean were warned to get ready for
Sandy. Their concern`s that it could cause
destructive waves and mudslides.
Forecast predicted that after Jamaica the
hurricane would head toward Cuba and the Bahamas.
It`s not expected to heat the United States.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today`s first "Shoutout"
goes out to Mrs. Jimenez`s math classes, at
Cesar Chavez Academy in Denver, Colorado.
Which of these political parties has won a
U.S. presidential election?
Here we go. Is it the Reform Party, Green
Party, Libertarian Party or Whig Party? You`ve
got three seconds, go!
There have been four U.S. presidents who were
members of the Whig Party. That`s your answer
and that`s your "Shoutout."
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: You obviously hear about the Republican
and Democratic Parties, but as you saw there
are other political parties in the United
States, there have been throughout the country`s
history. Like the Whigs back in the 1800s.
These days other parties are usually referred
to as third parties. This year`s third party
presidential candidates weren`t part of the
debates between Barack Obama and Mitt Romney.
They got together for their own debate this
week in Chicago. Here is a rundown of those
candidates and the parties they represent.
Former New Mexico governor Gary Johnson. He
is the presidential nominee for the Libertarian
Party. Jill Stein, who once ran for governor
of Massachusetts against Mitt Romney is the
nominee for the Green Party.
Virgil Goode, a former U.S. Congressman from
Virginia is the presidential nominee for the
Constitution Party and Rocky Anderson, the
former mayor of Salt Lake City, Utah is the
nominee for the Justice Party.
One of the big issues for these third party
candidates is ballot access. Other than right-in
vote, people can only vote for these candidates
if their names are on the ballot, and that
varies from state to state for each of these
parties.
Jobs. Economy. Education. Issues that all
of those candidates, the major candidates,
most voters, everybody`s focused on them.
A new national survey shows they are what
you are concerned about too. Junior achievement
spoke to more than 700 Americans ages 14 to
17, and found the two top concerns among them
are jobs and the economy. Many students are
worried, they`ll have trouble finding a job
after finishing school.
64 percent say education is up there, 32 percent
mentioned healthcare.
The survey showed the teens were almost evenly
split about whom they`d vote for. But 57 percent
said the candidates were more concerned with
winning than listening to what Americans thought.
What would your top concern be? Tell us on
our blog today, cnnstudentnews.com
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Time for a "Shoutout"
extra credit. Where was Felix Baumgartner
when he started his record-breaking skydive
from 24 miles up? Was he in the troposphere,
stratosphere, mesosphere or thermosphere?
Rewind that clock to three seconds and go.
Baumgartner was in the stratosphere, which
extends from about 12 to 31 miles above the
earth. That`s your answer and that`s your
"Shoutout" extra credit.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: When Felix Baumgartner took that historic
plunge, at least 8 million people were watching
life. I could not look away. What goes through
your mind when you are standing 24 miles up,
getting ready to free fall faster than the
speed of sound? Baumgartner told Brian Todd
in this interview.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
FELIX BAUMGARTNER: I`m going home now.
BRIAN TODD, CNN CORRESPONDENT: What is your
feeling at that point? You are on the ledge,
you can`t get back in the capsule. What are
you? What`s going through your mind?
BAUMGARTNER: Well, I kind of like that part
of the jump, because it means you are already
outside, everything worked well. And if you
have a problem, you know, probably (ph) jumping
off is the fastest and safest way, because
now you are falling towards a much healthier
environment, you know, you are falling towards
more pressure, towards more oxygen, and if
you need medical treatment, you know, this
is the fastest way down.
So to me this is an easy step.
TODD: At this point, you had us all very scared.
Did you feel like you were going to die at
that point?
BAUMGARTNER: No, no, no. I never had that
impression that I`m going to die, I always
had the impression, if, this goes on forever,
I`m not going to break the speed of sound.
TODD: How did you bring yourself out of that
spin?
BAUMGARTNER: I was slowly trying to figure
out how to stop this, so it was use your legs
and arms, but you have to do it really gentle,
because if you travel 830 miles an hour, you
cannot stick your arm out like this, because
this would create a rapid onset, and then
you cannot stop it anymore. So you slowly
put out your arm or your legs trying to figure
out what helps, and I did it, I did it a couple
of times, and I could see sometimes it was
getting worse, sometimes it was getting better,
then I figured out the way how to do it and
then I had it.
TODD ( voice over): Baumgartner says he cried
twice on the helicopter ride back to mission
control. Then celebrated all night with his
team.
(on camera): What has your life been like
since the 14th? How was your life changed
since the moment you went?
BAUMGARTNER: As a person, it didn`t change.
I`m still the same guy. But as soon as you
start traveling, as soon as you get on the
plane, as soon as you are at the airport out
on the street, people do recognize my face.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Thanks.
BAUMGARTNER: Thank you, guys.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: I was scared.
BAUMGARTNER: You were scared? I was a little
bit scared.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: You did it for all of
us.
BAUMGARTNER: Yes. Thank you very much, I appreciate
it.
TODD: You gave us all a huge charge that day.
And we thank you for it.
BAUMGARTNER: I appreciate it.
TODD: Thank you.
BAUMGARTNER: Thank you very much.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: When she was 12, Kathryn DiMaria was
thinking about something that a lot of you
probably thought about at age 12. It`s your
first car. Kathryn told her parents she`d
buy it with babysitting money, but it was
another part of a plan that really got their
attention.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
KATHRYN DIMARIA: Most of the cool part to
learn has been the engines, because there
are just so many moving parts, and you have
to do it exactly how it tells you, and so
that`s been the hardest part. I`m Kathryn
DiMaria, I`m 14 years old, I`m from Mount
Pleasant, Michigan, and I decided to build
the car because I`ve been to a bunch of car
shows and things, so I became really interested
in them, and so I (inaudible) here, because
I just like the little car.
JERRY DIMARIA: Kathryn about two years ago,
when she was 12 years old, came to us and
said, Mom, Dad, I`d like to rebuild the car.
And we kind of went -- really?
So, she had all kinds of reasons as terms
of, you know, she`d learn how to rebuild the
car, she would be able to do all of her own
mechanics. There is only two seats in the
car she wanted to rebuild, she would pay for
it all herself, and so we thought about it
and said, all right, well, let her try it
and figure it`ll last about two or three months.
Two years later, here we are at Makers Fair,
rebuilding an engine.
KATHRYN DIMARIA: All my family`s helped a
lot. My mom has helped me with most of like
the creative side of it, like here is how
you sew things together, here is how you piece
everything together. My dad`s more like my
information technician person, because he
understands where everything needs to go,
he understands the information behind it.
And then there is my sister who is our part-time
photographer, I guess, you could say.
JERRY DIMARIA: We figured, well, she`ll learn
a little bit about mechanics and how to redo
a car. She`s definitely learned that. But
at the same time, as you can tell if you are
watching this, she`s just talked to CNN. So
she`s also learned a lot about how to talk
with individuals, how to interact with adults,
how to do independent research and learn how
to do the things that she doesn`t know how
to do. And then try to apply that skill set.
So, there`s been a whole lot of learning outside
of just auto mechanics that have gone on.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: A high school in Chicago has an interesting
tradition where students start randomly dancing
in the halls. Like this guy. The man he is
dancing in front of here is the dean of students,
and the footwork is so fancy, that he dances
right out of his shoe. So does the dean have
a response? You`d better believe it. The dean
took Irish dance lessons as a kid, and did
his own sick moves. This Youtube video is
one sure way to make sure everyone shows up
in school, because once they`ve seen it, they`ll
always want to be there for attendance. The
dean stepped up, we are going to step out.
We`ll hit the dance floor again tomorrow for
more CNN STUDENT NEWS. See you then.