For the past three years,
the Egyptian revolution
has been a roller coaster.
Two presidents
have been deposed.
Thousands of people have died.
And just yesterday, the
Prime Minister abruptly
resigned his
government. "The Square"
is a newly released documentary
that gives a street-level look
at the ongoing
revolution since 2011.
JACOB SOBOROFF: It's up
for an Oscar this Sunday,
and we got the filmmaker
Jehane and the producer Karim
right here.
Hey, guys.
JEHANE NOUJAIM: Hey, what's up?
KARIM AMER: How
you doing, YouTube?
JACOB SOBOROFF: Guys, tell
us about the challenges
of making a film like this.
JEHANE NOUJAIM: All of us got
either arrested, tear gassed,
shot at at various points
in the making of the film.
JACOB SOBOROFF: So these guys
just put the movie on YouTube
for the people in Egypt.
What motivated that, and
how does it work, exactly?
KARIM AMER: YouTube
was an integral part
of this revolution.
When you live in a country where
the media is in full control
and is lying about what's
happening on the ground,
our young activists used
YouTube as their own channel
to spread their stories.
JACOB SOBOROFF: Jehane's
the only female director
nominated for an
Oscar this year.
Where can people see this movie?
JEHANE NOUJAIM:
Well, you can see it
on Netflix in 47 countries,
including the US.
And also, internationally,
you can see it
by going to our YouTube site.
JACOB SOBOROFF: Thank you
so much to these guys.
We put together a playlist
with moments of triumph
from Tahrir Square.
You can see that after the show.
ALEX: I've seen this
stunt hundreds of times
before on bikes, skateboards,
even a wheelchair,
but I've never seen it on feet.
Meet my new personal
hero, Damien Walters.
He's about to make history
as the first human looper.
MAN: Getting close.
DAMIEN WALTERS: You can't
really go any further
until you take the mats out.
ALEX: This insanity is
all over the blogosphere.
His channel is awesome.
Subscribe if you want
to see some crazy stunts
and insane back loops.
JACOB SOBOROFF: The most
interesting man in the world
has a German
doppelganger in what
is hands down the oddest
video that I have seen today.
This supermarket ad got
almost two million views
over the weekend.
The guy in it is
Friedrich Liechtenstein,
an electronic music star.
[MUSIC - DER TOURIST,
"SUPERGEIL"]
JACOB SOBOROFF: I think
Centerfold Skye said it best.
"When the apocalypse
happens, I want
to be Robin to
this guy's Batman."
ROB HUGEL: What's
up, YouTube Nation?
My name is Rob.
You might know me from the
series "I Hate Being Single."
WOMAN 1: When was the last
time you got laid, little ho?
ROB HUGEL: Stop
calling me little ho.
WOMAN 1: It's a compliment.
WOMAN 2: Ain't nothing
wrong with being a ho.
ROB HUGEL: Today
I want to tell you
about a new series I made
called "Man vs Waiter."
The man is on a date.
The waiter is a part of
that date by default.
WAITER: Can I get you stated
with something to drink?
DATE: You know,
water's fine for me.
ROB HUGEL: I'll have water also.
WAITER: Listen man,
you're on a date, right?
ROB HUGEL: Yeah.
WAITER: See, it's customary
to buy an alcoholic beverage,
at least for your date.
ROB HUGEL: Watch
to find out what
happens between man and waiter.
Definitely subscribe to "I Hate
Being Single," because there's
going to be new stuff coming
out every week, probably
for eternity.
JACOB SOBOROFF: If you
like what you see, guys,
go to Rob's channel.
Check out season
one of his series.
He's actually doing an Indiegogo
campaign to finance season two,
and that ends tomorrow.
EARNEST: Hey, it's
Earnest, and I
am sitting on something
that's pretty remarkable.
Justin Bieber's "Baby"
has passed a billion views
on YouTube and VEVO combined.
So however you feel
about Justin Bieber,
if you love him, if you hate
him, it's a billion views.
And that's pretty remarkable.
And also, see if you can
spot Drake in the video.
[MUSIC - JUSTIN BIEBER, "BABY"]
JACOB SOBOROFF: Thanks, Earnest.
The only other video ever
to cross a billion views
is "Gangnam Style."
We want you in the show.
Film yourself
talking about a video
you love, and then post it
with the hashtag YouTubeNation.
Now play us out, Chromeo.
[MUSIC - CHROMEO, "DON'T TURN
THE LIGHTS ON"]