for twenty thousand dollars in fruits
and vegetables
that's what we're going to talk about in
this video
do you realize that you can pay for the
land in most cases of profits from just
one-year of growing things
this is an even one acre of ground that
you need
two thousand plans will give you a value
of twenty thousand dollars at a cost of
about five dollars if you set up adrift
system
like the redneck one that i built
it works fine
living in the desert of arizona
i noticed a few things about plants
they died because they lack water
in california used to water my tomato
plants once a day and that was good
enough
we had the ocean nearby there was plenty
of moisture in the air and plants would
stay somewhat more distant almanacs
water in
but in arizona
years much hotter
and much drier
some people like it because they can
drink light beer all day and it
otherwise that it's a desert
and they have to have some kind of
refreshment
don't make friends with these people
when you go over to their house they are
for you light beer
i say to them
i don't want like beer
don't you have any real bear
they say what's wrong with light beer
i say it's just that friends don't let
friends drink a white beer
it's a sacrilege
lucy
lol
people who drink light beer don't like
the taste of beer they just like to pay
a lot
so if you come to arizona watch out for
those light beer drinkers
they'll corrupt you were in no time
because it's dry and you have to have a
beer and of all they got as light beer
you get stuck drinking that stuff
i'd rather drink florida it'd water
do you think the politicians drink
florida aidid water ad that they have
pure water flow in there that the
taxpayer's expense it probably cost ten
thousand dollars a glass and they use it
on their plants
if i know politicians they haven't flush
their toilets with non flor dated water
they couldn't care less of water cost
two thousand dollars a glass as long as
you and i pay for it
why do we need representatives
we can't represent ourselves
why can't we
i never could figure that out and with
four even your drinking water you
probably haven't even thought about it
have you
probably asking portable work
nevermind
or ham and finally got
come back to work
maybe or us
so i live in the body is owner which in
spanish means dry zone
unite kitten
the here will suck all the moisture out
of your skin
when hillary comes here should doesn't
even have wrinkles
her skin tightens up interface looks
like a snare drum
with the skin all pulled tight
you can do a drum roll on her face
know it's true
plans on the ground are trying to
survive
and with hot air and dry earth
they don't have a chance unless you
bring water to them
after you've played servant to your
plans bringing them water every hour
you'll want to set up an automatic
system for supplying water to your
plants
sales will of course we'll tell you that
you have to buy products to do this
those with money the burden will tell
you there's no other way because they
have a lot of money and you don't
so if you can do it almost for free
what's their advantage in being rich
it's gone
so don't listen to the rich
rednecks are smarter
i think you can do it almost for free
you don't need timers regulators
pressure gauges or expensive on off
valves
you just need a drip system to deliver
water to your plants
i have developed a redneck system that
works and i want to share it with you
i don't mind in one day
so you can do it much faster because
i'll read he did it and if you take
notes
make a list and carry out the same steps
you're going to do it in half the time
when i say one day i don't mean eight
hours
i have less than power in the entire
thing i was already using trip bottles
because i've been experimenting for some
time now
and i found that plants receiving a drop
of water every ten seconds
do just fine
high also found that empty ketchup and
soda bottles work balanced for
delivering the trip
milk containers are destroyed by the sun
in very little time don't use them
you simply catch up and soda bottles
they last a long time
don't use full soda bottles
because once that plan has tasted soft
drinks
it won't be satisfied with plain water
anymore
plans are like kids they get spoiled
if you never allow a plan to know the
good life
they don't expect the good life
for example i'd bought rabbit pellets
for the wild rabbits and that was fine
they ate them and appreciated what i
gave them
then one day
i gave those bunny rabbit subliminal
and they haven't acted the same towards
me ever since
they've gotten sort of
uppity
if i give them a nice plate of pellets
look at me like
pipes she did skate
he keeps the bananas for himself and all
we get our these dried pellets
this is slavery
he's a communist
we're not good enough for bananas
we have to eat this crap
so now i have to buy the members every
week to keep it by rabbits happy
if you introduced but those two bodies
two things will happen
one
you know of a friend for life
to you'll have a big banana bill
i'm joking of course the rabbits law of
the rabbit pellets
and they also appreciate bananas and
sweet potatoes and homemade bread when
they get it
the homemade bread
causes fights though
here are two rabbits in mid-air
this is a fight
the female saying boys born stopped the
senseless warfare
you guys should get along and share the
bread you're acting like a couple of
nazis
most of the time they get along but
homemade bread sometimes makes rabbits
fight
it also makes them fly
look at the picture
you know that rabbits throw dirt in each
others eyes in a fight
they pick up a handful of dirt may throw
it with their finance
i call them and they're actually pause
maybe they've learned that from their
poll
anyway sometimes i have twelve bunny
rabbits over for dinner
mailed leave happy
i'm going to have to get a fence because
i find coyote droppings
and they're full of rabbit hair so i
know that hitting my friends
that's just the way it is not a perfect
world so make sure you're sort of
bottles are empty and don't get anything
started with plants you'll regret it
i'm giving you good advice take it
plans they're quite happy with plain
water after drop seven internal of five
to ten seconds
you've got happy plants even with its a
hundred and twenty degrees outside
the automatic watering system if you
could draw your water from an existing
tank by gravity
and have a automatically replenish
with a tank refill valve
like you have a new toilet tank
reservoir than you would have a system
that does not depend
upon electricity
or water pressure
valves timers regulars and all that
expense of stuff
save your money and buy beer with it
that's a good investment
tap into your toilet tank reservoir for
automatic watering
you going to need to remove the lib
if you have one
benefits cracked that's even better
just move the pieces apart
and put your straw down into the water
drill a hole in the wall
and then you'll have a steady supply of
water to the outside world
of course you have to run that line up
the wall in out
in a few pain at the same color as the
wall
it's less noticeable
iran nine over the shower and help the
top
don't worry about how high you have to
go because water will flow up still as
long as the siphon hose is lower than
the tank on the other side of the wall
if their style up there just use a
hamburger break some of it
you don't need tile up there anyway
who's going to look up there
when people use your bathroom they don't
look up there
when the doors locked they look at your
medicine cabinet to see what kind of
prescriptions you're taking their snoop
here than your own government for crying
out loud
the hole in the wall is no bigger than a
bullet hole
redneck or just fired on through the
wall he'd be done with the job
he'll be having a beer before you can
say
to fire a gun to walk there are people
living next door
if you use the gun methadone use hollow
point because the holes too big on the
other side
if you have a mean life you might
already have bullet holes in your wall
you don't have to do any drilling
women are like that
they catch you with another woman pol
your waterline hole is there
and you had fun too
uh...
too many holes that was not good
so try to get caught next time
if the nazis already took your gun use a
drill
if you don't have a drill george bush
recommend c_-four
that's what he used on nine eleven
but you can only get it if you're in
government
because that stuff is highly regulated
you need special permission to blow up
the world trade center in buildings like
that
so you're on a quarter-inch waterline
from the toilet tank to the outside
world of green plants
and it becomes a siphon hose capable of
delivering water to dozens of soda
bottles
which are all at the same height
level is the name of the game
i presume that you wanna grow flowers
fruits vegetables whatever
and you have some kind of
table or bench that's the right height
if you have a bench
and you want to put plants on it that's
ok if its level
you can also build one
you can stack up palates to reach the
right height
men you know at the bend as much when
you tend to your above-ground garden
it's okay if water leaks on thu fri
pallets
craigslist always has dozens of pallets
for free i think the sizes forty inches
by forty eight inches
that's perfect for putting plans on them
their isley accessible for maintenance
and picking ripe fruits and vegetables
the level waterline is forty two inches
on mine
and if the pallets are structured like
an h
with the forty eight-inch side up
and you have a garden area that's forty
eight inches high water will flow as
long as the water level is forty two
inches or less
put your shade plants on the shady side
and partial son plans where they get son
part of the time
in your full sun plants and full song
i like several things about pallets one
they're free
to they're plentiful and three their
versatile
find them on craigslist under
but four sale the categories for sale
and then free and know that sounds
contradictory not for sale for free
they're just free
that's where you find the category
some places offer so many pallets you
can't carry them all in one trip
some of the pallets are brand new
who would still has a yellow color to it
summerall been broken but it doesn't
matter
you paint them
put them together in the form of an h_
then put your plans are on a picture of
water bottles on top
some places have pallets available
everyday
sometimes two or three available
you could even take them apart in use
each piece of wood to build something
special like uh... high bench
mountain water drops to fall but not too
far because they will splash
detailed scenes down there could splash
a seed
out of its place and it won't route
most loot and those pallets are made out
of hardwood
hardwood means deciduous trees
hardwood verses punted which is not a
deciduous tree it's an evergreen
these palace don't look good in tiller
full of flowers are edible fruits and
vegetables than everybody wants one
no nothing i like about palaces they can
take your garden three-dimensional in no
time
you can roads powers of lettuce
in a six-inch p_v_c_ pipe
look at this let us power
if you have a two-story house and a
bathroom on the second floor
you can pull your water from the second
floor because it's pressurised to get up
there
then it flows down by gravity
you could have lettuce towers taller
than a basketball hoop
you know what the square foot gardeners
say about let us
it gives you back
sixteen dollars and twenty cents for
each
square foot
you plant
it is one of the highest income plants
there's no reason to pay a dollar twenty
nine for a head of lettuce
when the save costs less than a penny
does everyone on your block need less
the chinese put lettuce and soups
and it tastes great so try to get a
letter style or to increase the dollars
per square foot that you're able to get
from your land
the sky is the limit
when you're getting sixteen dollars per
square foot you want to go as high as
possible try to get thirty two dollars
per square foot for
forty eight dollars per square foot
because if you can get three times as
much less of a square foot
one eight kirk and grow almost five
hundred thousand plants per acre
instead of the normal one hundred and
fifty seven thousand plants per acre
if let us sells for a dollar in the
store how much of a hundred and fifty
seven thousand plans were
a hundred and fifty seven thousand
dollars
but let us is selling for more than a
dollar right now
to make your ground could produce two
hundred thousand dollars worth of let us
i'm not saying you're gonna wholesale it
at that price 'cause you're not you'd
have to retail at
we'll talk about that later
prices have gone up on let us
but issues to be fifty cents then it
went to a dollar and i said dollar for a
love letter as a liberal my own
now it's a dollar thirty
and i think it'll be two dollars and
thirty cents and no time prices have
gone up and they're going to go up much
higher because we are going to have
hyperinflation now thanks to ben
bernanke e an entire game over there at
the mafia i mean the uh... federal
reserve
growing lettuce in towers and try to get
more than sixteen dollars per square
foot
it'll help with inflation
and if there are elderly people on your
block
and they're barely making ends meet give
them a gift of the head of lettuce
it only cost you a penny to produce it
unless you're able to sell at all but
uh... i don't think you can sell it all
you might be able to grow more than you
can sell
so spread a little goodwill
and help the old people
or anyone who's hungry for that matter
nice to be able to give someone a dollar
that only cost you a penny
when you give the older people head of
lettuce they might tell their family in
the family might come over and buy from
you
most of the cost of produce in the
stores transportation cost
about ninety percent
of the cost of anything in that proves
department is probably transportation
cost if your customers come to you
you get to pocket that ninety percent
you can sell below
the store prices and still make more
profits in the store does
without any overhead
you're already living in your house
give a big yard
turnout yard into productive capacity
him a little business built up when you
sell your house the business goes well
the uh... who wouldn't buy a property
that makes a thousand dollars a month if
the payments are only six hundred
dollars a month
anybody would buy that house so you're
creating value here when you start
planting seeds
i'm gonna tell you where to buy seeds
later
so if you're charging retail prices and
you have
no delivery cost
your customers come to you
you really have a nice business
it's almost under percent profit
because the water costs are small the
seed costs of small in the sunshine is
free
your nefarious government has not figure
out how to charge you for sunshine
but they will
just a long time
might develop a business of selling
ancillary products as well online now
idea is a product called those violist's
when i washed let us and spinach in the
silas
it keeps in the refrigerator for a long
time 'cause it's not
soaking in water
socal edison water in the refrigerator
and it will turned brown than you
you put it in as i listened spending
that throws all the water out and it
falls to the bottom and let us is kept
above that would little basket plastic
basket
use google type in let us
silas spinner silences e y l i s s
with the wind ally at coldly medicine so
i was bender
for about twenty dollars makes a nice
gift
you know you can almost afford to give a
customer of twenty dollars islas
for being a customer for ninety days
because you get ninety eight dollars
let's say you're charging a dollar
you get ninety dollars
and they get twenty dollars plus alba
let us
so it works for everybody
you could subband
system more you punchy carter something
that they have ninety purchases in
ninety days you give them at twenty
dollars i loves for free
with some of their customers will buy
everyday if they have kids they'll go
through a head of lettuce everyday
and if you're closer than the grocery
store they'll buy from you instead of
the grocery store 'cause that's handy
when the right now they tell go next
door and get the head of lettuce from
that guy that grows them
uh... with the toll powers i cut up let
us cucumbers and reddish and red onion
who'll
i put that on the silas and spend it
and the seller is already made before
it's time to eat
you lift that little in silence there's
your whole salad you see is the pinchers
you pull out some put it on your plate
add your dressing yourselves ready
before you can say what's to eat
i like blue cheese dressing and feta
cheese with
vinegar and all of loyal
is that your stomach growling
you're making me hungry
okay so you have a hundred and fifty
seven thousand dollars from her a cure
of ground
that's if you plant on the ground
but now you have the towers
and you using the third dimension
using left and right
forward and backward
and now using op
multiplies
the value of your land
multiplies the use
using that third dimension
instead of one layer you've got two
three four who know six or seven layers
offer one acre of ground
look at these guys with their towers of
let us they're not fooling around
they know the value of what they're
planting if you live in an apartment
you can put the tower all your balcony
and go up several stories
just make sure the towers out of the
reach of the guy who lives above you
because the sixteen dollars per square
foot will be his not yours
when you wanted to let us at the top of
the tower it trickles down like the
economy
you guys getting wet
on the bottom layer
in this economy
sometimes i think those guys the topper
peeing on us down here
anyway the water will fall from one
plant
will trickle down to the next in the
next
not on the water will be wasted
those who plan on the ground will find
that the water that reaches the ground
is good for growing parsley cilantro
basil oregano radishes or beats
if you're able to increase the number of
heads of let us from one hundred and
fifty seven thousand per acre to five
hundred thousand
how much
is five hundred thousand heads of
lettuce worth a dollar reach
you could buy a jaguar and maybe pick up
chicks again you old fart
let you go brush your teeth and look for
a girlfriend some people think it's cute
to grow strawberries in the tower
i found this image at wordpress dot com
i'll give you the link in the
description
because you tube doesn't allow you to
click on the link and go to war web page
only videos
so anyway growing strawberries in the
towers a nice idea and the birds love it
they can't wait to you start offering
strawberries on the menu
a bird can see a strawberry from three
miles away and they can smell it from
forty miles
good luck on your strawberry crop
the strawberries the grow high on the
power will be eaten by birds and the
laura ones will been bombed by the same
birds
they have no manners
they don't waste time looking for a
bathroom either
anyplace below them is okay to dump
their ordinance
you could be dressed in a suit birds
don't care
i think they look for guys in suits
me
for birds dive bombing
is covered from head to toe
in excellent fertilizer
a gift from heaven
sometimes the guy in the senate is the
puppet president
he gets what he deserves
remember when bush was targeted back in
two thousand samad
the c_i_a_ sentence perils during a mind
control test
don't tell anyone
it's still a secret but ronald arms felt
had a good laugh and sort of dickhead
cheney
these clowns who run the country give
bozo a bad name
who my voting for romney or obama
how about none of the above
they need to read the constitution and
follow it to get my vote
some of you have nice homes still you
haven't lost your jobs yet
if you have an outdoor fire place like
this one
those benches can be put to use
they're designed for parties there's
plenty of room if you're giving a party
but what do you do with those benches
the other ninety-nine point nine percent
of the time
you have to make use of them
and also cut down your food bill by
growing your own
there might come a day so when you
cannot get food in the food store
growing your own will give you access to
food is not available to anyone else
list they have a gun
if the bench in your yard has the right
height
water will flow right to it then no
changes are necessary but if the bench
is too high
just take a hammer and break off the
seat
and see if that's any better
when your wife sees it you know a bullet
holes in your fireplace to
then you can run water lines through
that as well
it might be nice to put out fires with
water instead of letting them burn out
it solves the fire hazard problem
some people have a railing
and if you put your plans on both sides
of it
you balance the load
and the only thing you have to worry
about is the way
you can use plant stands ventures made
of materials that will be affected by
the constant water
even a wrought iron bench
if the hyde works out okay but if you
sent an advantage
you might get your clothes weapon on the
water dripping nearby
i'd prefer to put plants in the black
putting platt holders yelled about two
gallons of potting soil if you buy them
there about a dollar reach
but if you know landscaper who has
access to hundreds of them every month
they can be free
just suck up to him
pelham al beautiful his landscaping is
and then ask for all has extra parts not
on the same sentence of course
space them out so he doesn't know he's
being conned
let's review of the system
reusing the automatically fill valve of
the toilet tank reservoir to refill the
water
as we use it
outside on our plants
the water levels forty two inches high
and anytime you're below that water will
flow to u if you're above that water
will flow in the opposite direction
horrible stopped flowing
and this full of water works anywhere on
your property
even if you have forty acres you know
the holes that long where you can string
together a bunch of moses you can
deliver water anywhere on your property
with this method
well you know it's a garden hose
done installing elaborate system until
you make your first million for now just
do it in the redneck style
when you have half a million cash in a
new jaguar
we can move out of your nineteen seventy
three mobile home with the leaky roof
into a nice home
you can put in underground water lines
in the new home
we don't need electricity for the system
water flows by gravity
we don't need water pressure in the
siphon line water flows automatically
from your toilet tank reservoir
to anyplace that's lower anywhere on
your property it's like having a lake
oren above-ground well
that you created with a toilet tank
reservoir
your waters always above ground
and at the same level as your reservoir
and you spend nothing other than for the
hose to deliver at their
when you put your
quarter-inch tubes in the hose and feed
your water bottles in the drip on the
plant all day
lift up the bottle that stops dripping
laurette that starr stripping again
pretty neat system
if they are not shows in the back of
your toilet tank they might allow you to
run a water line without disturbing the
balance of delivered
on the reservoir
or causing it to fall and break
this diagram the outside reservoir
provides water to the soda bottles the
soda bottles on the right
all three tanks will be at the same
level the soda bottle the outside
reservoir and the reservoir inside the
house the toilet tank reservoir as the
water drips onto the plant
the soda bottle loses water
and his immediately replenished
by the outside reservoir tank
in it could be just a hose
it's nice to have a tank because the
siphon hose will always replenish that
tank when you draw from that
tangle it's a it's a ten gallon tank you
draw from that that can recharge
overnight if it needs to
because you do have a limit to the
amount of water you can take
through that quarter inch pipe in the
toilet tank
i'm not sure you can do two thousand
plants might only be able to do the
hundred plants or even fifty i'm not
sure haven't tested that i've got seven
or eight plans when i get way too much
water already but i'm not planning to
stick with
six or eight plans when i have one in
the quarter ickes here i want to have at
least two thousand plants all kinds i
can put five hundred
h shaped palate
structures
uh... each one consists of three pallets
in the shape of an h for for balance
instability
they're tied together with uh... screws
i can put
five hundred of those on one an accord
ickes of ground
but if you want walking space
then you can put that many
but each one has eight plants so how
many do you need
you don't need five hundred
you'll need half that that gives a room
to walk around
it also allows the bunny rabbit stew get
around in uh...
uh... wild rabbits here so they like to
come in to eat and i want kodi's eating
them because in the chance to run away
even it makes a little safer for them
now since i have too much water flowing
i'd put a screw into the quarter inch
pipe
is they want in a half-inch
screw
that was already rusty my put it in that
tube in it is not a tight fit water
still flows but if it was a lot slower
so i have much fewer drips
and it's just right for now
later
if i have two thousand plants
i might want to stop watering the plans
that night
when in school
and allow my reservoir outside to fill
up a steady flow all day compensates for
the sunshine in the heat who provides
the plant with enough water
at night
you really have too much water if you
give them the same amount of water at
night
so it's best to switch to replenishing
your reservoir outside
at night
here's a different perspective
of the drawing to illustrate the concept
is a clear
you're creating a large lake of sorts
with each soda bottle maintaining that
same level
as the inside reservoir
and then that soda bottle is used to
drip water on the plants
as long as all the soda bottles have a
siphon hose free of air water will rise
over-the-top and provide water from
bottle to bottle to bottle per bottle
you get water anywhere on your property
there's a law that these sort of bottles
must maintain the same level of water
and if they don't they go to jail
without bail
if one of the bottles of the leak
it's replenished that's the law i didn't
make of the law just using it to my own
advantage
i'd like to grow things and i live in
the desert
so i need a solution and i don't believe
in buying thousands of dollars worth
of timers and valves
this would water delivered to my plants
this is the redneck solution that works
it works in a very simple principle
that water will seek its own level
in all places
if alba water bottles are connected with
the siphon hose
remember that the water will flow from
your toilet tank to any spot on your
property with a hose
and it will seek the same height
because of gravity and the weight of
water
if water and wanting gets higher the
weight of the water will push the water
through the hose until it all equalizers
like a leak
it's an above-ground well
drops of water falling on plans creates
a need for replenishing water
and water will flow to raise the level
to where it was
if you have a garden hose that runs two
hundred miles from your house
and both films are up above the ground
sixty the water level will be the same
at two hundred miles as it is in your
toilet tank
if you put a quarter-inch siphon hose
into that garden hose you can siphon
that water audra put on plans animal
automatically be replenished
water will transfer from your toilet
tank to that garden hose and then the
water flow will stop
until you start
dripping
on plans
depleting the water in your hose and
then it will be automatically
replenished
by the toilet tank
now you probably already knew that but
how many people ever use that knowledge
to water the plants very few
and the reason is because they have
florian and their drinking water
and their dumber than a darned doughnut
if you saw if in water out of your
garden hose to water your plants even
two hundred miles away what happened to
the level of the water and that holds
it drops
in the water you removed is replaced by
the toyota take reservoir
thousands of players getting a drop of
water now on them
as long as you're taking the water from
the garden hose it's going to be
replenished
but you will reach a point at which they
one quarter-inch siphon hose can't keep
up with your water use
and then you're going to have to limit
the system
but it's okay to use the system for a
small garden of twenty or thirty plants
i've got five trees
to palm trees
nectarines
a mandarin orange and a lemon tree
plus about six
plants and thousands of seeds have been
planted i'm waiting for them the sprout
i think i can supply all of those
with plenty of water
using a ketchup bottle the whole is just
perfect
you put your quarter inch hose in that
whole it fits perfectly
i was going to poke a hole in the
ketchup bottle but it's terrific
it's extremely thick
are used in the land i broke the needle
three times
so i quit
round needles
now i just loose on the capital are
flows over the top
just keeping ketchup bottle lower than
the old water level
when you go to the store to buy holds
bring the ketchup bottle with you
contests that see if it fits in that
whole in my case it's tighter than o_j_
simpson's gloves
and since johnnie cochran is dead
there's no need to fake the fifth
so the jury will acquit
johnnie cochran denied justice to you
and me
made a buck and allowed the killer to go
free
for those murders justice certainly did
fail
that o_j_ committed another crime and
today he's in jail
the moral of the story is one to which i
can attest
he who runs last rhymes best
johnnie cochran
all right p
but besides the tight fit
and the whole of the catcher bob is
another advantage to catch a bottles
when you want to stop the flow of water
users raised to catch a bottle
the water stops flowing into it
so you got your forty two inch level
line for all water
toilet tank in the entire property
after property drops a foot and you have
to add a foot
to that water level line because
that toilet tank doesn't know you have
property that drops a foot
that's going to maintain that water
level at the same height
altitude above
the center of the earth
so you might wind up with a gusher if
your property drops forty feet
might have water spewing out there with
a column of water forty feet high and
it's a pretty good pressure
so the system isn't gonna work like that
now if you raise the ketchup bottle at
night to turn off the water when you
lower in the morning to start the flow
again
it's redneck but it works
and you didn't spend any money and you
had some fun
that's how you got the bullet holes
remember
count the seconds between jobs and if
it's too much
running for awhile didn't give it a rest
you can punch a hole in the sort of all
too
but the whole is too large put something
in the hole to cover it
some people might want to use a penny to
slow down the flow
sometimes watersports also fasted
squirts over into the next plant and you
don't get any water in the plant below
them the bottle
so the penny can help you there too but
if you use a penny it's going to cost
you a penny and someone might see the
pain still it by collected six dollars
that we want i'm man that guy was mad
as water bill went up to a thousand
dollars and all has plants died
was my fault
who put the pennies there in the first
place
entrapment
now that guy uses foreign koreans
and only foreigners steelers pennies
so the problem was almost solved
now all we have to do is get rid of the
foreigners and the problem is solved
problem with that is america's all
foreigners
except in need of atlantans
who were kicked out by the native
americans because the native americans
had advanced weaponry bows and arrows
icalendar
and the number zero
they had a superior culture 'cause they
could come past nine within zero
so they took over in the atlanta games
had to find another place to live than
their island sunk and that was the end
of them
let's talk about the value of the crop
when you go to the store to buy produce
u_p_ retail prices which includes what
the farmer gets
with the truck drivers get
there's insurance involved in gasoline
and diesel you have to pay those who
sell insurance nova
store with employees in renton air
conditioning electricity in maintenance
and more insurance and taxes and on and
on and on a whole lot of middle man
if you're on a fixed income
you want to buy the seats in the water
and that's that no middleman you can
afford middlemen
retail prices are too high
because of all the middleman there's
nothing you can do about it except grow
your own
pay them or grow your own
cozier only two choices
here's an ad look at this they want four
dollars for half a pound bag of swiss
hillard
salad mix
four dollars for a half a pound
can you afford it
dollars a pound for greens
state maybe
you can buy a new york street for that
kind of money
can you get a fully mignon for eight
dollars a pound
i'll grow my own swiss chard then i can
afford fully manual how about you
greens you can grow out of your toilet
tank reservoir and i just proved it if
you're going to be the man with all the
produce everyone is going to like you
they're gonna suck up to you lyn you
sucked up to that landscaper
they're going to be flattering euro
you're gonna know you're getting conned
so watch out for the people who try to
kanya if you give away free produce to
anybody friend neighbor co-worker at
cetera you'll never be able to sell them
anything
were turned them into a pain customer
now i mention giving away things to
people that are very poor and i still
believe in that
we don't want anybody to starve to death
if we can't help it
for something that you can give them
tomato that didn't shape right or has a
spot on it birds heated they can cut
that part often use the rest
sister ways for you except for the
c_d_c_'s are worth more than the
terminal built by the way so when you
have regular customers you don't want to
give them away things free directly
because they'll never pay for something
they got free they expect at the same
way they got last time free
a handout and many of them will get
friendlier than a column and when they
see that you have something of value
that they want
besides the pennies
so i wanted to know establish that the
product
has a price tag you give them a coupon
for a discount
or a coupon for a small sample
not a normal portion
given three dollars off on a five dollar
purchase
you'll still have a profit because
produce is that profitable the scenes
cost less than a penny and each
head of lettuce is worth more than a
dollar
but you're not in business to provide
charity in all cases just occasionally
you put in ad on craigslist
pick your own farm people really like
that
you might go to a few in your own
neighborhood
your own city
just to see what they're like
see what they charge
see how many customers they have
see what they're growing and selling
because if they don't have let us and
you grow let us
you have a monopoly on let us
but if everyone's growing and selling
let us they're selling it for fifty
cents you might steer away from lattice
asking if they have any radishes or
aruba but u wanna know what your
competition is doing what people are
already buying
but developing regular customers is good
because the scenes costs you almost
nothing in the water costs almost
nothing
the fertilizer costs almost nothing
compared to the value of the produce
when it's ready for market you're
putting your time into growing these
things you're setting up these pallets
it costs money to go get them at cost
money to put them together takes time to
put them together you've got to be
compensated for that we can't just be
giving away free produced everybody who
comes along and people wrote to me and
said it aya planted a hundred season
they all grew tomatoes and i give away
forty plants cuz my yard with only
accommodate sixty plans
somebody who gave away forty plants is
going to be popular
but next year at the same people expect
the free gift again i think the guy only
plan sixty plans next time because he
doesn't need it maybe he'll be able to
sell the produce that comes from sixty
tomato plants
each tomato plants going to give him
about ten pounds of tomatoes that means
he's going to have
six hundred pounds of tomatoes and i
don't think you can use that many unless
he's scanning them
but that's a lot of pizzas in a lot of
spaghetti and a lot of lasagna and
ravioli
must have jo lee and all those other all
these
but you will quickly figure out that
this
israel money
and that fiat currency has used only to
pay bills you swap your produce for that
stuff and use it to pay off a credit
card
or use it to buy gasoline you
immediately convert that fiat currency
into gasoline for your gas tank
then your gas tank is always full
of gas and if you have extra money it
wouldn't hurt to have a gasoline tank on
your property and filled out full of
gasoline case electricity goes off cuz i
expect that the electricity will go off
in about
half of the country soon that fiat
currency could become worthless
overnight because everyone stops
accepting it and they want realmoney
lakes older
you can sell
tomatoes for ten cents a pound if they
use silver coins an old i'm slop that
for a pound of tomatoes that's a good
deal you pile up the silver you swap
your tomatoes or peppers or let us for
silver coins that's a great deal
misty eyed currency really has no value
but as long as other people are stupid
enough to accept it
then we got a game going everybody's
accepting a fiat currency all it is is a
place marker
it has no value it's not redeemable for
anything unless other people go along
with the game
but at some point the game is going to
be over
the banks are going to close nephew i
currency will be worthless
and we're reaching that with
hyperinflation anyway you'll need a
wheelbarrow just to buy a loaf of bread
would be a trillion dollars for a low
for brad
that's what happens at the end of
currency
this currency is overdue for collapse
most fiat currencies last something like
twenty eight years
when nixon ended in nineteen seventy
eight i think
he took us off the gold standard in
nineteen seventy three eight and we are
overdue there were some things put in
place they forced the whole world to
deal in dollars prolong the life of this
currency to this currency has reached
the end of its life
don't stack up a lot of dollars in the
bank especially
be better to own scenes or something
that won't go bad seasonal get all the
reward sprout anymore motion freeze them
i'm not even sure you can freeze all
sees maybe some along are killed by
freezing i don't know
some countries are already refusing
dollars especially those printed at a
certain date after a certain date
because they know what ben bernanke in
the mafia i mean the federal reserve are
doing
they know they're counterfeiting u_s_
currency and their euphemistically
calling it cute he won and q_e_ two
quantitative easing is a euphemism for
counterfeiting the currency
it's a crime against anyone who held
those worthless u_s_ notes or save money
over the years or bought life insurance
or bought church three bills and burned
and canada's crux got away with it he
should be imprisoned
along with those who own the federal
reserve a group of nazi bankers who are
intent on robbing us blind and they're
doing so at the rate of forty eight
million dollars an hour twenty four
hours a day right through the holidays
and weekends seven days a week they rob
us of forty eight million dollars an
hour
that's what we pay the interest on the
national debt than most of the national
debt came from interest charged on money
they didn't let me just printed it
sore robbery of the u_n_ me
your job is to spread the true tell
others live video of your own just
record your voice and tell us what you
think that's what we all have to do this
long because were permitted to do so we
need to do so
nazis are not going to allow us that
freedom much longer to see you better
get busy now
this is a war against the slave masters
and we need to be free okay so people
come into your place of business to buy
from you
you collect their name address phone
number email address and when you have
something they like you notify them you
ask them ask if you have any radishes no
should i call you when i have some yes
would you do that i'll send you an email
of the automatic
so soon as you have rashes or let us
look tomatoes are peppers or squash or
whatever we send an email and so i have
what you want
coming at it you could even take a nice
picture
chill in the quality of your produce
if you're worried about people picking
your own
you can have it already picked in bags
and they get there you have fired attend
available all the time they're not going
to die if you pick them in a store for a
few hours if you don't sell them pick
last the next day
okay so we talked about advertising
under farm and garden on craig's list to
develop your customers we talked about
sending out notices
now want to talk about the growing
season in arizona i created this list
and you have to do it for your state
look at all of the things you want to
grow look at the planting time in the
harvest time
then create a calendar for planting and
another calendar for harvesting i do it
on a spreadsheet let us was reading in
twenty eight days and it's worth a
dollar
so you can turn up any into a dollar in
a month lettuce seeds can do that for
you it's magic turn a penny into a
dollar and a month
actually it's less than a penny i'd pay
about thirteen cents for a hundred seeds
i get seven hundred and ninety one
scenes for a dollar
it's almost eight seats for a penny if
only half of them germany i get
four plants for a penny
we have four dollars back for one penny
invested
in the seed
and i've got water costs
i got a gasoline cost in my time
but what does the growth rate
he only got a penny
if you have a cost of a penny and you
get an a dollar back in a month
that seven hundred and seventy two
percent growth of your money in one
month that's nine thousand percent
growth
in a year now let us matures in twenty
eight days so how many times can you
multiply your money in the year it's a
three followed by sixty one zero zero
zero for that
a billion billion billion billion
billion billion
what arcade in october
november
december and january
these other crops i can grow of all the
crops i want to grow and arizona in
october
i'm limited to lettuce
turnouts
radishes
swiss chard
celery and peas
bolt onions
brussel sprouts and carrots
spinach parsley and beats
kohlrabi
broccoli
and collar flower
cabbage rue the day is
and uh... par snaps bunching onions
and salon show
and i'm very disappointed about that
in november celery drops out and
potatoes current season
something you should know about potatoes
potatoes indeed and acidic soil
this means low ph
arizona's soil is high ph
and so i'm not planting any potatoes
here
the plants can't absorb nutrients from
the soil
and the fertilizer
so i stay away from potatoes
i bought potatoes today for twenty cents
a pound at safeway
they had a five pound bag for a dollar
so i bought fifteen pounds of potatoes
because the bunnies overhaul potatoes
don't see it too loud because when i
cook french fries they come around and
wait for potato skins
sometimes i cut up for ralph potato and
give it to them
i don't want to spoil them like i did
with the bananas
because d treat me very badly
you remember the swiss chard for eight
dollars a pound
i like the way it looks too
fast growth
high-value crops only
that's the way you get the silver
to float to you
you see those prices
that's how much the square foot
gardeners and getting from these crops
and it's a good idea to plant the
highest value crops so you can swap them
for the most silver
if you're growing crops for your own you
should plan and what you eat
if you're providing food for others you
assess what they need or want
and by implant those crops
if you're doing this for money the new
supplier only the most lucrative crops
michael s
and you try to get customers to buy
these items
people won't drive to you for lettuce
but they might drive to you for peppers
and tomatoes
and when they get their bill by lettuce
cucumbers and radishes for their salads
because it's more economical to buy five
things in one stop
and just peppers or tomatoes
gasoline is expensive and we have to put
that into the equation
i'd live eleven miles from a grocery
store and my neighbors and i have to
spend four dollars to go there and back
if they walk over and buy from me they
save four dollars
they can spend that four dollars on
peppers tomatoes parsley so intro
radishes let us and cucumbers
and if they have silver coins
i'll make them a special deal like
three pounds of tomatoes for one
pre-nineteen sixty five ninety percent
silver dyin
it's attractive because you can
advertise three pounds for ten sounds
and that silver dyin can be replaced the
next time a neighbor is near the coin
dealer
in december squash and cucumbers on the
menu
and they are welcome addition to
look how many varieties of squash in
there
here is a middle eastern squash
here's more squash
these are orange cucumbers
have you ever had them
mean either but i want to try all of
them
look at this list december's almost the
coldest month of the year in north
america and just look at this list
list of things i can grow in arizona's
greatest in the colder months
look at january
tomatoes join the list and cabbage is
gone
cauliflower is gone brussel sprouts and
broccoli are also gone
when these crops come off the list
what you have this all you're going to
get
if you don't sell them it's not the end
of the world you know
you can store these they're very
delicious later so if you don't break in
the silver you cook and freeze what's
left
you can smile for months after the
season is over on color flower brussel
sprouts broccoli
those are good for at least six months
in the freezer to grow as much as you
can and have some frozen for later
here is february and march april and may
you can see in the list shortly no as
the weather gets warmer
pairs june
look at the drop off of crops like
admiral arizona
plants don't like a hundred and twenty
degree summers
and neither do i_ especially
my jacuzzi gets so hot from just
sunlight
that i have to get out to cool off
and i never feel the slightest that call
now use only the sun
and a garden hose and heat to the water
it's over a hundred and ten degrees
every day for at least two months and
summer and water in the garden hose gets
to about a hundred and eighty degrees on
the ground so i circulate that heat into
the jacuzzi with a pump
the cost nothing to operate it because
it's a swamp cooler poem
as i recall the water in the middle of
summer it was ninety five degrees and
the air was a hundred and six degrees
one-day than it was definitely too hot
to stay in the jacuzzi
on the coldest winter day can be twenty
degrees overnight and by four p m
it seventy five degrees
that's the climate here between two
someone in phoenix i'm in zone nine any
do you know about the hardiness zones
i'll give you a link at the and and you
can download the map and plan your crops
first locate your city on this map and
select all the crops you'd like to grow
bananas don't grow where they're slow so
that's a no go joel ho ho ho
use como images search engine and find
fruits and vegetables
make a list of what you like
doing research to find out when it's
planted where you live
be sure to consult the wife so you don't
have any more bulletholes try to make it
sound like it was all her idea to do the
planting
that keeps women happy
if you can work a spreadsheet
put them in columns by month
lookup each crop and read about when it
is planted in your hardiness zone
i put my fruits and vegetables in order
according to help valuable they are
because i want to swap my time
for the most valuable crops and then
they can get the most silver
because the farmer down the road who's
been growing asparagus for ten years
i'll gladly give him a dollar's worth of
let us which matures in just twenty
eight days
in exchange for a dollar's worth of
asparagus which takes two years to get
the first crop
platter fruit review could wait three
years for your first fruit
i planted three fir trees and all legal
lemon tree is bearing fruit at this time
and they're not yellow yet they've been
green foreign at least six months
both the neck during and the mandarin
orange flowered
started about
we lost that for some reason maybe it's
afraid of the dark
gets very dark in the desert i will go
out there
i'm afraid a bunny rabbit levy
well if it isn't that sheepskin
how have you know that i just got back
from the store buddy
and what did you get from a friend
don't give me any of your bunny rabbit
buttering up
i bought a couple of bunches of bananas
and one bunch is already yellow
yellow
what a lovely color
your eyes are yellow empty
know their blue
what do you take me for a reptile
on don't say that word a friend of mine
was eaten by a snake it was dreadful
well i'm sorry to hear about your friend
and paying the bills you know
what are you doing
human bananas
right now i'm doing a video for you to
what's new to i'd never heard of that
before
and we talked later
i'll tell you about your two then
he's friendlier than a con man when he
knows i've got a minimums
conduits
knows i've got
cannons
feeling a bit
we'll talk later i'm busy now
a friend in need is a friend indeed
he's probably telling on his friends
that i'm hoarding the bananas
watch at five tomorrow morning there
will be nine bunny rabbits lurking in
the dark
waiting for me to come out with rabbit
pellets bananas and oatmeal
each month i take out my spreadsheet and
look at what i can plant this month
i don't like looking six months in
advance because
those amounts are not here yet
i like looking at this month to know
what i can plant now and next month so i
can get my scenes together
and think about planting
if you order seats they come in just a
few days from the japanese selected
seeds
if you're going to become the slight
mind you need to know how cold it gets
where you live
you people in the cold war regions of
the country think that you can't plant
all year and this is not true
plants can germinate indoors
being the only two things one easter and
heat that's all
you keep your house at least fifty
degrees
you can have tomato plants that are four
inches high and ready for transplant
when other people are putting the for
seeds down
so don't let three months of snowy
winter stop you from having a
twelve-month growing season
rely on the hardiness zone to determine
which will be successful crops
and don't attempt anything that's likely
to fail unless she started indoors and
give it a good chance for survival
many people are writing about this stuff
online you can find thousands of
interesting articles every month
if you know how to use a search engine
call this one consideration in many
areas but in the desert we have another
factor dryness
it's so dry here that you could do a
drum roll in tories face when she comes
here
so the amount of rainfall you get is
directly related to how many things grow
if a lot of things grow where you live
then a lot of things die and when they
die they contribute organic material to
make topsoil organic material just means
the minerals unique birth
combined with water and sunshine and
carbon dioxide from the air that's
carbon dioxide
carbon
dioxide
that carbon makes organic materials so
that plants
take the minerals from the soil
and sunshine for energy
they convert that into food or sugars by
using carbon dioxide from the air
carbon dioxide is a nutrient for plants
it's not poison it shouldn't be taxed
in order to reduce it
it should be respected
as a plant nutrient so don't take al
gore's word for anything
now we have two presidential candidates
who both won a charges attacks for the
carbon dioxide in the air
that's going to drive up the prices of
everything across the board and who gets
the smiley this tax
the alone without e
we should all be opposed to it and you
should all be making videos to express
your opposition
anyway
the organic material makes topsoil
and you might have ten million years of
topsoil are you love
you might want to use it to your
advantage to make some extra money from
a small amount of water and free
sunshine
this will help them to meet for no and
later
you'll have food when other people have
only guns
if you have food and they have guns
who's going to win
they are
because guns trumbull food
but if they don't know you have fluid
then you'll be able to eat
and when they see off that you are the
old shoot u_n_ eat you
so anyway the guy with the gun lines up
with all the food in the end
that's why people are buying guns
government is not going to protect you
from people who have guns
there are going to be a food riots
government's not going to protect you
the government poisons your water with
fluorine
new year's your tax dollars to build
fema camps for you'll an underground
cities for them
so what's your take on government
paid off the rose colored glasses
and see the nazis at work for a change
i wouldn't mind seeing all the nazis
turned into topsoil and the sooner the
better
in arizona we don't have topsoil
we never heard of it
we live on top of the dried out all
shouldn't bottom
and it's salty
because all the rain that falls
evaporates
and only the salts that were in the
water are left behind the high altitudes
in new mexico get rain and snow
and arizona
gets the water as a result
most of that water
is used for farming
and evaporates leaving behind salts
which make it hard to grow things
the pure water that evaporates becomes
clouds
and they pass over your house
and since it's colder there
rainfalls and you get our water
this is why we hate you and what you dad
just joking
if you catch that rain it's pure water
in the nazis don't want you drinking
that water
because there's no lorena if you drink
it you'll be smart
you'll know what's really going on with
the p_s_a_ the n_s_a_ the c_i_a_ and all
the other is and government alphabet
gangs of organized criminals
you'll be out buying guns along with
record numbers of other americans
who have a clue and they're getting
ready to wipe out the nazis and bring
the constitution back
i don't like violence but if it's on tv
i might watch it because i'm used to
violence on t_v_
some people say that all bobble already
shredded the constitution and there's no
bring it back
i thought he was using it as a doormat
at the white house
and all we have to do is clean off the
mud but i could be wrong
he signed an executive order for every
power imaginable and he has effectively
made himself king or bomb a and i don't
like this one bit
if a lynch mob goes to washington to
string up that illegal alien that will
be sad but i'm not going to stop them
because they have guns and i could get
myself killed
storing the rainwater is now a crime but
killing americans who have been charged
with any crime isn't
that's the law
does that apply to the juror living in
the white house
iski fair game to buy this executive
order
well the king will have to protect
themselves because
are not interested in fighting on his
side
i think the average american should stay
out of this fight not the dictator
defenders on dictatorship
the people don't like dictators and if
anyone moves into the white house
using false documents and under
fraudulent circumstances he will have to
protect himself against rebellion
i'm personally offended by nine hundred
of the most recent
executive orders that king will buy
among has signed
anna fathers are aware and take offense
i'm not surprised
the people should see the corruption and
see the dictatorship
they conspiracies and the reason why
nazis must put fluoride and your
drinking water
if you want to opt out and drink
rainwater i don't blame you
if you drink rainwater you'll begin to
see clearly
and the nazis came out of that
bill arrested and charged with the crime
of drinking water that doesn't have
fluoride compounds and that that's rat
poison and they want you drinking that
so how do you get around it
there's a lot of moisture and watermelon
cantaloupe squash tomatoes cucumbers and
so on so you can sleep water through
these crops without going to jail
monsanto wants you to buy their seeds
and so they bought up all the seed
companies to make sure you don't need
unless they charge you monopoly prices
this is a form of slavery
but that's not all monsanto does to you
me and everyone else
they modified the seeds so they can have
full control over the nutrition and
other factors that are genetically
dependent
they're called g edible
genetically modified organisms
if you don't want g_m_ oilseeds
too bad
there is a conspiracy to diminish the
nutritional value of your
food so that you are malnourished
and if you look into codecs element
terry ellis
you'll be horrified by the crimes they
are committing against humanity and this
is what your government has on their
agenda
you need to know about it
and plant your garden so you can survive
i'm not joking
do your research and make videos tell
others about kodak's element arias
i'll give you an excellent link at the
end of this video you must watch this
lecture by doctor reema label
these nazis have full control of
congress and they passed legislation
that favors monsanto
this is one more reason for you need to
plant your own vegetables and fruits
using seats that on part
of the monsanto monopoly
this is one more reason where we need to
get rid of congress because they are not
your representatives
you pay them they're supposed to vote
according to your wishes
but they don't
they're corrupt
and we need to get rid of them
we no longer needed representatives in
this country
they will flee sue for all you have
they will keep you poor as a control
mechanism
and i'm advocating that each state
secede
from the federal nazi urine
and you drop out of their fiat currency
system as much as you can
cell tomatoes at a much lower price just
to get the ninety percent silver coins
the nazis don't counts over as a
currency so you don't have to either
they have made silver in non currency
so when you receive it it's not income
disrupt your tomatoes for the silver
do you know any laws on the books that
requires you to file a tax return
many people have tried to find it and
they can't
lawyers have tried to find it and they
can't
but nobody wants to talk about this
because they're afraid of retaliation by
the nazis
who have the average american convinced
that they have to file a tax return
this is by all definitions a mafia
it's a racket
and nobody is opposing this mob
so you have a duty to spread the truth
eric holder is not going to prosecute
the i_r_s_
he's going to run guns to mexico make a
little side money
the whole god damn system is corrupt
thoroughly corrupt through and through
the mafia is in control
they have rackets just like any other
mob
and if you make videos all you have to
do is ask the question where is the law
which states that americans working in
america have to file a tax return
why is money automatically taken of
americans' paychecks
why
all the judges or corrupt because they
they rule in favor of the i_r_s_
there are many videos about this on you
too
and if you have not watch them
what are you waiting for an invitation
i cordially invite you to watch it to a
videos on the ira s and the laws
regarding filing a tax return
when you get through in your learn the
truth your going to be very very angry
because you paid money that you might
feel
was not justified by anymore on the
books
congress' cowardly
they know about this and they have done
nothing about it
deter busy lining their pockets with
cash
from deals
they use their political influence to
make deals for their own behalf
they were staying power so they can
continue to rape the country
that's why i think we don't need these
bastards
and we need to get rid of the entire
washington band of conspiratorial spin
if he'd stayed so scenes it's done
the federal government is effectively
fired
and all the laws they pass to control
uart instantly revoked
if you believe unless tell others with
the youtube video
learn how to push record on d audacity
free software from snap files dot com
trade tomatoes for silver and get some
real money
instead of the studio currency
you're sayin' might say tomatoes ten
cents a pound if you use ninety percent
silver coins dollar upon if you use the
fiat currency
if according to its minted before in
nineteen sixty five
it's ninety percent silver the supplies
to
dimes
quarters
and half dollars only
loops i just looked it up so restraining
today at thirty two dollars and eleven
cents per troy balance
which means that those ninety percent
dimes
are valued at two dollars and thirty
seven speech
as of october twenty first two thousand
twelve
and so it would not be wise to charge
that much for tornadoes or peppers
because you won't get any silver
and that's the objective here
lower the price of tomatoes so thats
overflows to you
if you give customers three pounds of
tomatoes
for a dime silver done at that
fiat craft when it comes out to almost
seventy seven cents per pound
and this is enough incentive to make
people stop off at the silver dealer and
bison chunks over diamonds
if a thousand people buy one bag each
the nazis won't bother tracking them
but if you go to the silver dealer and
buy a thousand bags of junk silver
announces will be on you like a fly on
watermelon
they'll come to your house and take it
at gunpoint
the nazis are already doing this to
people on the highways have you heard
somebody sent me a link for you tube
clip of the news
there was a man in tennessee driving a
semi trailer truck
and he had two hundred thousand dollars
in cash on the truck and they took it
from him they didn't charge him with any
crime he wasn't committing any crime
they just took his two hundred thousand
cash from memphis is private property
it's an illegal search-and-seizure it's
unconstitutional they took
two hundred thousand dollars from this
man
and i ask you what's next
they're going to come to your house and
take your silver
we're going to take your gold they're
going to rape your daughters
because we are moving into an area of
total lawlessness
the mafia
runs the country
pulling people all over in doing illegal
and unconstitutional searches
finding one e and keeping it
why would they do this when the c_i_a_
is the mafia that's dealing in drugs in
the first place
folks we have to do something because
this can only get worse
record your opinion and make videos for
you to
we need to spread the truth about what
they are doing to us
robbing the people blind
printing money and driving up the costs
of everything through inflation as a
result of printing the money
old people on fixed incomes can't make
it
and that's intentional that is not a
accent they want to kill older people
they put a pig virus in the vaccines
that
are given to children old people and
uh... diseases that are developed are
wasting away
i did a video about this and if you
haven't seen it
uh... put the link at the end of this
video so you can watch that video your
government cannot be trusted for
anything especially vaccines
now in order to help these old people
who are starving to death you can give
them my head of lettuce
a dollar head of lettuce that only cost
you a penny
for the seed
and you've gotten a lot of bang for your
block
you probably can't sell everything you
grow
but first of all grow enough to feed
your own family
and then if you have anything left over
extra
you can swap it
for silver dimes and before you little
pet of let us go bad
walk it down to a neighbor that lives of
block or two away
and give it to them
it's better than throwing it away
want to tell you about a pick your own
fruits and vegetables farm near me
it's in queen creek
this cold snap
farms
they've been in business since nineteen
fourteen
let's see what war worry them down
world war one my grandfather was
poisoned with mustard gas
they've been in business almost a
hundred years
they let you pick your own they charge
you a dollar fifty apollo and
remembered the swiss chard
at eight dollars a pound
well how does a dollar fifty opponents
alone
let's see what they have available in
october they have swiss sharan
ko
red potatoes white potato sweet against
yellow squash and zucchini as nationals
and they have some apples
well i can beat all of these prices at
walmart i don't pay a dollar fifty for a
pound of potatoes onions or zucchini i
can do better on all three i'd just paid
twenty cents a pound it's safe for you
remember
normally i'd buy potatoes for about
thirty five cents a pound nala dollar
fifty a problem
i guess people like pick your own so
much that they'll pay through the nose
remember that when you pledge your crops
and try to get silver
fruits and vegetables are currency
system
and you need to get on board
so offer your customers away to get your
products cheaper
by buying up the junk silver as it's
called in the numismatic field and allow
your customers to come in to your place
of business
this walks over for salon troll or let
us or melons or eggplant
instead of putting your junk silver in
the bank
where anybody can seize it
put it under a pallet
and leave it there
until that's the only accepted currency
that anyone who will take
because the day is coming sooner or
later
when people will not accept u_s_
currency any longer
and all that currency will become
worthless overnight
those people who have billions and
billions of dollars in u_s_ currency
will lose it
everyone's expecting the u_s_ currency
to collapse
so i spent fifty one dollars on cns
and i think that fifty one dollars will
grow
i received ninety four thousand five
hundred seeds and i want to show you
that list now
and i want to tell you where to go to do
likewise if you care to
my order with johnny's seeds
remember the swiss chard
for me in the short season begins in
september and i can grow
shar in october november december
january february
and it ends in march
september to march
but six months is good enough for me
i bought a thousand cv's
for four dollars and thirty cents
so a hundred seats cost me just forty
three cents
will have recovered the six pounds
about four plants and i'm good
and i have a thousand chance is right
the bunny as well in a lot of that
idon't mind
vine is really really four plants so i
can break even
i'll buy them off with bananas and i'll
get the spotted ones at deep discount
the bunnies will never know cuz i'll
kill them before they see them
if they fill up on bananas delete my
swiss chard alone
it takes fifty five days to mature
but you can sneak baby sharin if you
just can't wait
in just twenty eight days
i never grew swiss chard benefits like
lettuce a grows back a few times before
going to see
catch the scenes and you can plant them
or sell them to recover your four
dollars and thirty cents for all you
chip skates who can't stand spending
money
billions in the bank let somebody else
who for thirty cents you cry like a baby
alright she wrote
you can get all your money back concedes
just get your neighbors interested and
sell them seats for ten cents each
if they buy a hundred sees dropped the
price to a nickel each
you'll be driving a jaguar in no time
and if you brush your teeth may be a
girl were ride with you
i bought calypso salon tro
for four dollars and fifty five cents
thirty five hundred seeds
i love so much oil and i want that stuff
around me
all the time
i can grow this urban arizona from
september to april
so i have eight months salon trolex
sunny cold weather like lettuce
but does not like soaking wet soil
can you imagine city cherry or salsa
without salon tro
go to jail if you try
and sleeps my god soups without so i'm
sure you should be shot
cilantro ads such a nice flavor to soups
if you haven't tried it
try it and stop being a stick in the mud
a hundred plans for thirteen cents
material germany enrichment purity
the charging me about fifty cents for a
bunch of solo intro in the store
and so the potential
is fifty dollars back
for each thirteen sounds invested
and immature
in fifty five days
leave it alone and it will go to see it
at one hundred twenty days
then you have thousands of new seats for
the next season
you don't have to buying a new seats you
couldn't even sell them to recover your
five dollars
i bought five thousand cucumber seeds
for ten dollars and seventy cents
each plant will give you a few cucumbers
so maybe you get ten thousand cucumbers
at a value of fifty cents each
how much is that word
five thousand dollars back
from five thousand sees
that's like getting a dollar for each
seed
how many seats do you have to have
germinate and produce cucumbers in order
to get back you were original cost
have five thousand seats twenty is easy
so make the investment
if you leave eleven dollars in the bank
what with the bank give u five thousand
dollars i doubt it
put your money where it will grow and
get out of that fiat currency
the fiat currency is a trial don't fall
into the abyss
he's mature in fifty eight days
i can plant
cucumbers in december january february
and march
cucumbers like cool weather
cool as a cucumber
check out which months you can grow
cucumber
your season probably ends just as my
cucumber season is beginning
i bought the parsley known as giant of
italy
there are sixteen thousand five hundred
seeds in announced for four dollars and
twenty five cents lower bottom loans
for some reason this is showing on the
fourteen thousand seeds
okay i checked and sixteen thousand five
hundred is correct
so i received a hundred seats for about
two and a half cents
parsley
it says zero point zero two five eight
if the neighbors come over when i see my
lush garden
i'll give them seeds and tell them to
get busy
i'll start each neighbor with tendencies
because they probably won't have the
patience to plant and maintain a garden
so when they come over allow some of
their governor of the chicken little
story
chicken little want some help preparing
some the bread or something i forgot
whose told to me when i was one year old
something
back then i didn't take notes
nobody wanted to help chicken little but
when the soup was made or the bread was
made everybody wanted to eat
so chicken little gave them a lecture
you don't help me you don't get any food
neighbors come over they don't want to
plant anything along the water anything
they don't want to buy fertilizer
they don't want to get out in the hot
sun work that garden
they just want to come over and have you
hand them a basket full of free food
smith told the chicken little story
this
parsley plant has an amazing eight
cycles
so you're constantly cutting off parsley
in a grows back
and winner of flowers
stop cutting it
that will go to see
that will give you a thousandth of seeds
per plant
you can try to get ten cents proceeded
from your chicken shit mayo chicken
little neighbors
i can only grow parsley in october
november december and january
i think the plant will be dead by summer
i'd bought these on sale ten thousand
spinach suits
for five dollars so a hundred seats cost
me a nickel
how much of the spinach plant worth
fifty cents
i had a potential for a hundred plants
worth fifty dollars
and only cost me a nickel
spinach matures in thirty six days
fifty dollars and spinach for a nickel
that's your potential
now does that work with inflation zaz
plant a garden
set up an automatic watering system so
you don't have to labor
here's your only chance to turned five
dollars into five thousand dollars and
just thirty six days
if i had a church
i have each member of the congregation
plant seeds
and sell them to finance the pastors
drinking addiction i mean church
endeavors brainwashing and propaganda
campaign
these guys senators cycles out knocking
on doors reading scripture
well all the pastor has to do is make
use of their land to grow savior spinach
and he's on his way to the kingdom of
heaven
but these guys are not very smart
i'm the only one who's really smart and
i know the power of numbers and i know
how to turn five dollars into
five thousand dollars in just thirty six
days
but even if you turn five dollars into
five thousand dollars worth of spinach
you still haven't sold it
you still have to have somebody saw it
the church members would attend a swap
meet and sell their
and where do you get free labor at the
church
that's where you'll find the most
gullible suckers that any con man ever
dreamed of
the pastor could afford gambling and
prostitution at the same time
instead he sees knocking on doors as the
only way
to increases in income
and so he screams as money out of the
working families
to finance his sins
spanish can be cooked and frozen eating
it
so you don't waste any
i bought wildfire let us
a quarter of an ounce
twenty eight days to maturity
i got six thousand two hundred and fifty
seeds
for seven dollars and ninety cents
so a hundred sears cost me twelve point
six sense
rounded off state thirteen cents
is a hundred head of lettuce were
thirteen cents
that your wholesale price
but if you cut that let us
that'll grow back
and that's what i like about it
so you can make
much more than a hundred dollars
from thirteen cents
and let us goes to see very much like
cilantro they've both grown about twenty
four inches tall and then the flowers at
the top turn into seeds
and you got a shake them into a bag to
collect them
you don't want to take
the green ones
you you take them when they're black and
they're ready to fall off
the wind will blow them around they'll
be
parsley everywhere
the last item in my fifty one dollar
order
which by the way include shipping
is a leg room
allegro mx is the bean family
here's a picture of many kinds of beans
that only grooms
well i bought this one llego which is
not being but it's totally ghoom
and legal means that fixes its on
nitrogen in the soil
the area's seventy eight percent
nitrogen but it's a triple bonded
nitrogen
it's very hard to break but there's a
little bacteria that grows in the bottom
of legal means
and that knows how to grab that nitrogen
out of the air and turn it into
fertilizer
ammonia or um...
you re a is actually would turns into
your ria
very similar
to the molecule for ammonia
an h three is ammonium urea i've forgot
form uh... but
very simple molecule and these little
bacteria grab the direction of the air
they fixed nitrogen in the soil so you
want to have legal who's around
plant billions just to get the nitrogen
into the soil
you need to take the nitrogen out of the
year and put it in the soil because
nitrogen helps the leaves grow on all
the plants
phosphorous is good for fruits and
flowers
phosphorus fruits
and the route plans need potassium
carrots potatoes turnips radishes
prudhoe bay is kohlrabi yall need
potassium in the soil
so when you buy fertilizer
if you've got your nitrogen covered the
first time there can be as hero
there's three numbers
yugos zero sixteen sixteen something
like that the road twenty four twenty
four
negative plenty of the
fruits and flowering mineral classrooms
new routes in order to grow strong roots
in need
potassium
i bought this lay grommets a clover
bought it for the rabbits about fifty
two
thousand seeds for less than four
dollars
and i'm hoping that the bunny rabbits
will love the taste of those and leave
my swiss sharp alone
fifty two thousand seeds
and i don't know how many months a lot
of the year that league room grows i
hope it grows continuously than the
bunnies can come and eat fresh greens
healthy greens
and leave my swiss chard alone
i have plenty of water
plenty of land
complaining of seeds
have plenty of sunshine in plenty of
heat
so i'm okay
i have a watering system that will
deliver water so i can go away
know that my plans are doing fine
october
has twenty two items that i can plant
here in arizona
but i only bought a few of those items
to test that when watering system
if you're planning carton every morning
when you wake up you're going to run to
get your basket go out into the sunshine
and see what you have
you going to go shopping for free
when you bring your basket of goodies
into the house
neighbors are going to be in the u
they're going to want to go shopping for
free to do in your garden
you have to tell on the chicken little
story
everybody wants the fruit of our labor
but nobody wants to chip in and help
when it's time to till the soil
take out the we answer fertilize the
garden
nobody wants to help you
we have one parasite living office now
admits the government
we don't need any more
the burden is so heavy now that there's
no chance for social security to survive
and the government spends so much money
that even if they eliminated all
spending
and tax the people one hundred percent
of their incomes they still would not
have enough money to pay even the
entitlements
and soldier is going to be a collapse of
the government
annual must learn how to garden
feed yourself
mature only hope of feeding yourself
when the whole system collapses
the ruined it with their greed
they care nothing about us and now it's
coming back to destroy them to the
system that is a miserable failure
and the garden must be for paying
customers only
the matter of survival in a high
inflationary world
where prices keep going up
the federal reserve is to blame for it
twenty six trillion dollars
into the money system by just printing
it
without considering the consequences of
old people
on fixed incomes and no old people must
have a garden just to survive if this is
leadership we don't need leaders
we no longer need representatives and
it's time we represent ourselves and get
rid of all the leaders
you wanna survive don't trust government
don't play their ponzi games
and don't give them any of your money
for anything
don't put money into their banks don't
buy their treasuries
everything they do is crooked
they're running rackets like a mafia and
there are no good for you and me or
anyone else
that's the truth and i've given you a
lot of good advice
you may want to buy seeds in smaller
quantities it so i found the seller
which will provide you with smaller
quantities
i'm going to showcase them now