CARL AZUZ, CNN ANCHOR: I`m Carl Azuz. Today,
on CNN STUDENT NEWS we begin by continuing
our coverage of the shooting in Newtown, Connecticut.
And we are looking at the way to help those
affected by this tragedy begin to heal.
A healing process will be a long one for many
people in Newtown. But slowly, some of the
first signs of normalcy are returning. Students
started going back to school yesterday. Teacher
groups said the classes would discuss the
shooting in age-appropriate ways trying to
help students make sense of it. Class was
not back in session of the students and teachers
of Sandy Hook Elementary. They won`t go back
until January, and when they do, they`ll be
at a different building about eight miles
away. On Monday, we covered the shooting in
depth. You can find that show on our home
page or at the CNN schools of thought blog.
Teachers, that`s also where you`ll find the
post that shares some tools to help discuss
the story with your students. Gary Tuchman
now looks at how some specially trained animals
are taking part of the healing process.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
GARY TUCHMAN, CNN CORRESPONDENT: Nine golden
retrievers on the march making their way into
a recreation center in Newtown, Connecticut
for an emotional rescue to help comfort the
children who survived the attack at Sandy
Hook Elementary and other children in town.
Therapeutic canines were sponsored and trained
by Lutheran Church Charities transported in
a van for a 900 mile ride from Illinois.
(on camera): And what is a comfort dog?
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: A comfort dog is one who
brings comfort to other people when they are
suffering or hurting or bring happiness to
people, it helps people process the grief
they ...
TUCHMAN: So they are specially trained?
TIM HETZNER, LUTHERAN CHURCH CHARITIES: They
are specially trained. These are all trained
service dogs. So we don`t use them with disabled,
but we use that training, and then we train
them additionally to work with all different
age groups and people.
To some people, and we`ve seen this with children,
it brings a sense of calmness in the time
of confusion for them during this period.
To some, it helps them process their grief,
so they are crying, and they hug the dog and
to some children now come up, and they walk
away happy.
Do you know that Luther is incapable of being
mean? Luther is a friendly dog.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Well, Katon loves dogs.
TUCHMAN: When does training begin to be a
comfort dog?
HETZNER: Five and a half weeks, we buy puppies
at five and a half weeks and turn them upside
down in how their temperament is and from
that point on, we ...
TUCHMAN: But you turn them upside down, so
if they are turned upside down and they flail,
they can`t be a comfort dog.
HETZNER: Right. Our initial screening is if
they can be relaxed in that position, then
we start the next process, which is a trainer
that works with them one on one for the next
eight months to a year.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: We`ve been asking on our blog, what
you think can be done to keep kids safer at
school. Amira says, "Schools should have more
security guards with better training and more
available defense resources for the trained
security personnel." Ian suggests, "Limiting
access points for perpetrators and educating
students on what needs to be done in case
the worst happens." From Kal, campuses could
be surrounded by fences that can be climbed
as easily as chain-linked fences.
Jack thinks the best course of action is to
have at least to or more staff in a school
with guns to protect themselves and the kids.
John writes, "The only reasonable solution
is to have stricter gun control: not a single
American needs an automatic weapon unless
it`s government issued." Macey says, "Too
many people have guns and use them for the
wrong reason." In Nick`s opinion, a change
in gun laws wouldn`t solve the problem: "We
need to focus on mental instabilities in children."
Heather also says, "We need more attention
brought to mental health care to prevent things
like this from happening. CNN is looking for
your "I- Reports." If your class or school
is taking action to honor Newtown, Connecticut,
head to ireport.com and upload your photos
in our Newtown assignment.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Is this legit? There
are mountains on the Moon. Yes, the Moon has
mountains, craters, even seas, although scientists
don`t think there`s water in them.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: One of these mountains is named for
Sally Ride, the first American woman in space,
and on Monday, that spot was the final stop
for a pair of probes, a pair of spacecraft
that have been checking out the Moon. Ebb
and Flow were about the size of a washer and
dryer, before they crashed landing into that
mountain, their mission was to orbit the Moon
and map it out. Scientists were hoping to
learn more about its surface and how it might
have formed. Researchers say they got a lot
of great information from Ebb and Flow. They
think it could take years to analyze all of
it. NASA officials say the twin probes were
intentionally sent into that mountain on Monday
because they didn`t have enough fuel or altitude
to keep going with the mission.
The group of men you are seeing here are part
of a TV crew for NBC. One of them is Richard
Engel, the network`s chief foreign correspondent.
The crew was kidnapped by masked armed men
when it crossed the border into Syria to report
on that country`s civil war. During the five
days they were held, Engel said the crew was
blindfolded and repeatedly threatened. They
were eventually freed and taken out of Syria
on Tuesday. And it`s been difficult for journalists
to report on Syria`s civil war, because the
Syrian government has severely limited their
access inside the country. When journalists
do choose to report from inside Syria, they
are potentially putting themselves in harm`s
way.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today`s "Shoutout" goes
out to Mr. Linser`s classes at Bellevue High
School in Bellevue Washington. Which of these
ancient civilizations leave in what`s now
North and Central America? Here we go, was
it the Sumarians, Phoenicians, Maya or Vikings?
You`ve got three seconds, go!
They Maya lives in parts of what are now Belize,
Guatemala and Mexico. That`s your answer and
that`s your "Shoutout."
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: You might have studies the Maya in your
history classes, you might have even discussed
them outside of school, there is this rumor
that`s been going around about the end of
the world. Now, the theory says that could
happen later on this week, because that is
when the Mayan calendar ends, but Nick Parker
caught up with some modern day Maya about
the reality.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
NICK PARKER, CNN CORRESPONDENT: Lario Kancha
(ph) is a priest, his people`s calendar ends
in a matter of days.
"It`s considered the closure of the great
cycle of Mayan time," he says. But, of course,
the next cycle begins the following day. For
the Mayans, it`s not the end of the world.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: We can`t get to the airport.
PARKER: Doomsday scenes from movies like "2012"
have helped create a different myth. So, where
does it come from? The Mayan civilization
began in several countries from around 2,000
B.C. The story behind the infamous date begins
in ancient sites like Chichen Itza where Mayans
created calendars.
ALFREDO BARRERA, MEXIAN GOVERNMENT ARCHEOLOGIST:
The Mayas were astronomers, when they go into
the tower in the upper part, they can make
observations, they relate the astronomic records
with the agriculture, with the economy.
PARKER: Temples are designed to channel sunlight,
and the number of panels correspond to years.
When academics translated inscriptions in
the 19th century, they discovered that Mayans
counted 394 years cycles, known as baktuns
and many say the significant 14th baktun expires
this Winter Solstice, December, the 21st.
Others say, it actually ends on the 23rd.
This carving made in 700 A.D. Ignited furious
debate. Monument Six, as it`s known, was discovered
at the site of Tortuguero and predicts a major
event at the end of this 13th baktun.
BARRERA: We don`t have prophecy or inscriptions
related with the finish of the world or prophecies,
it`s only a mention of a data, but it doesn`t
mention more about, because description is
not complete.
PARKER: He blames online speculation and ignorant
writing for the Doomsday belief. But the data
is certainly open to interpretation. Santiago
Pando lives outside Mexico City and is a filmmaker.
"There is a big sun, which is going to align
with the other suns in others galaxies," he
says. "This means, there will be an enormous
quantity of light, and this will give us a
wider view of reality."
Many in Mayan countries will mark the day
as a celebration, as others around the word
fear something more sinister. Nick Parker,
CNN, Yucatan, Mexico.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: Some superstitious folks might think
it`s bad luck to let a black cat cross their
path, but the students at this crosswalk probably
disagree with that, because this black cat
seems to be all about safety. It`s name is
Sable, he is 15 years old, his owner says
he makes it part of his daily routine to heat
the street right before the bell rings. The
crossing guards think of him as part of a
team, he even has his own safety vest, and
he doesn`t charge for his services.
And maybe one day he`ll call the tab he`s
been running. For now, he just seems to have
a vested interest in keeping the street safe
for the kitties. That`s all the time we have
for today. We will hope to cross paths again
tomorrow when CNN STUDENT NEWS returns. Bye
now.