Look at that! Look at
that little thing.
It all started in Iceland. I think I'm
so certain to get what I'll take
my boots off.
I never imagined that you could see
glaciers this big disappearing in such
a short time. There's a powerful piece
of history that's unfolding in these
pictures and I have to go back.
The initial goal was to put out 25
cameras for 3 years and shoot every
hour as long as it was daylight.
That would show you how
the landscape was changing.
Ahh this is the way to
travel my friend.
Putting really delicate electronics in
the harshest conditions on the planet.
It's not the nicest
environment for technology.
I do not want to go
any lower than this.
It's just bottomless. I'm going out
here on this broken fin and I assume
it won't collapse.
Every once in a while, I get to
saying what were we thinking?
Maybe that office job wasn't so bad.
This thing is loose.
Rock!
- It's not working.
- God!
All of that obsession means
nothing if it doesn't work.
Just be careful. Don't get too
close to the edge, alright?
It's terrifying!
This knee has had two surgeries
and I really could use a third.
He goes to that point
where he can't anymore
and sometimes he's going further.
This is big stuff happening right now.
Okay, onward.
This is the memory of the landscape.
That landscape is gone.
It may never be seen again
in the history of civilization
and it's stored right here.