SNOOP DOGG: What up, dog?
My name is big Snoop, D-O double
G. And this is the
craziest story I can remember
from way back in the day.
I remember going to a party
at the Playboy mansion.
I had on a blue smoker's jacket,
Playboy mansion, boo,
and had a big ol' pimp cup,
real big, about a half a
gallon of champagne, a gallon
of orange juice-- you know
what I'm saying?-- to level
it off, walking
around, me and Bishop.
And one of the bunnies says,
Snoop, can I have
some of your drink?
I say, yeah.
Go ahead, baby.
So she grabbed it
and took a sip.
Gave it to her friend and
let her have a sip.
And they passed it around.
And I turned my head and
turned back around.
They gave me my glass.
I started drinking.
And as I'm drinking, boom,
I'm starting to
feel a little different.
So I start to walk and
get a little queasy.
And there's nowhere to sit.
So I finally find some
room or a door.
And I kick through the door.
And when I go through
the door, it's like
16 flights of steps.
And I fall down all of the steps
straight to the bottom,
to the floor.
Boom.
With a couple of white girls
running down the stairs.
They start pouring
water on my neck.
And I heard Bishop Magic Juan
say, the church is down.
Call the ambulance.
The church is down.
So the girls get me
to a point where I
finally, like, wake up.
And they like, someone slipped
a roofie on you.
So I get back and walk back
through the party.
I'm like, you know what?
I can't leave the
party like this.
And now I start smoking
weed with everybody.
And I go into this
little grotto.
And there's a couple of Playboy
bunnies in there.
And I says, my dick is on
the line right now.
I gave the bunnies more
than they can handle.
I gave 'em a treat.
And it wasn't no carrot stick.
It was a pogo stick, if
you dig what I mean.
Up and down it go.
It was official like a referee
with a whistle.
A star was born.