AZUZ: Usually on CNN STUDENT NEWS we say how
Fridays are awesome. For a lot of the U.S.,
this Friday is frozen. You expect snow and
cold temperatures in the winter. What makes
this storm different, is that it`s huge. Around
60 million people -- we`re talking 20 percent
of the entire U.S. population potentially
effected by this. Governors and mayors have
declared states of emergency. The area that`s
being hit is roughly the same size as Mexico,
and the storm`s bringing some unusual weather.
You probably haven`t seen or heard that too
often, it`s called thunder snow. And you need
the right ingredients for it to happen. Cold
air on top of warm air with moist air close
to the ground. This massive winter storm is
causing trouble problems like what CNN`s Ted
Rowlands ran into outside Kansas City.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
TED ROWLANDS, CNN CORRESPONDENT: The freeways
here are a mess. An absolute mess. I was stuck
on I-29 for about an hour and a half just
dead still, I`ve gone on 35, I-70, all of
it mess. And though biggest part is not only
visibility, but the snow accumulation is just
-- it`s piling up, and people are getting
stuck, spinning out, there`s trucks all over
the road, there are (inaudible) a couple of
medical emergencies, which, of course, have
made it very difficult that the snow makes
it very difficult for first responders to
get to those people and (inaudible) is they
warn people do not drive in this conditions.
There`s a reason why. This storm is a whopper.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: There might be a silver lining here.
Some of the states getting hit have been dealing
with the terrible drought. So when all this
snow melts, the water could help relieve some
of those drought issues.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: See if you can I.D. me.
I`m a country that borders 14 others. I`m
the fourth largest nation in land area. I
have the world`s second largest economy, and
when it comes to population, I`m number one.
I`m China. And my most populated city is Shanghai.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: An American online security companies
say Shanghai is home to a group of the world`s
most effective computer hackers. U.S. Homeland
Security Secretary Janet Napolitano says Chin
is one of the biggest sources for cyber attacks
against the United States. When you picture
a hacker, you might think of one person, like
a lone wolf type, hammering away at a keyboard
in the dark room somewhere. The American firm
says this group of hackers in Shanghai is
connected to the Chinese government.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
DAVID MCKENZIE, CNN CORRESPONDENT: It`s clear
that this installation of buildings is closely
watched by the People`s Liberation Army, and
allegation is that they`re working in conjunction
with civilian hackers. As we got closer to
take a look, we got in trouble.
Keep driving. Drive away. Drive away. Drive
away.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: World of espionage is moved online.
It`s where cyber spies can get access to all
kinds of sensitive information. Hackers might
be able to access electricity grid or telecommunications
networks. This Shanghai group is accused of
stealing technology blueprints and sensitive
business plans. Chinese officials deny any
connection to hacking. They say they`re the
victim of cyber attacks, mostly from the U.S.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today`s "Shoutout" goes
out to Mrs. Bosco`s American history classes
at St. Barnabas Episcopal School in DeLand,
Florida.
What amendment to the U.S. Constitution discusses
the right to bear arms? Here we go now. Is
it the 1st Amendment, 2nd Amendment, 5th Amendment
or 10th Amendment?
You`ve got three seconds, go!
Those words show up in the 2nd Amendment.
That`s your answer and that`s your "Shoutout."
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: You often hear the 2nd Amendment mentioned
alongside the issue of guns in America. Yesterday,
a little more than two months after a school
in Connecticut, Vice President Joe Biden traveled
there to promote stricter gun control, new
restrictions on who can buy guns and what
guns can be bought. People who support gun
rights including the National Rifle Association
say new restrictions aren`t going to help
stop gun violence, and may violate the 2nd
Amendment. So, why exactly is there so much
debate over this?
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
JEFFREY TOOBIN, CNN SENIOR LEGAL ANALYST:
The 2nd Amendment may be the single most mysterious
part of the Constitution. It`s an ungrammatical
sentence, it refers to militias, which don`t
even exist anymore. And it`s been the subject
of an intense, intense controversy.
The 2nd Amendment has two parts, the first
part talks about state militias. It says that
state militias are a necessary part of national
defense. And the second part refers to the
right to keep and bear arms.
The question of how the two relate is something
people are still debating.
Militias were effectively how the United States
raised armies in the early days of the Republic.
There were essentially more or less volunteer
forces of young men who fought for their states
and fought for the country in what we call
militias.
Starting about 20 years ago, a lot of conservatives,
especially in the National Rifle Association
started to say, look, the 2nd Amendment has
been misinterpreted by the courts. It is not
just about state militias, it`s about individuals
rights to keep and bear arms. And the National
Rifle Association, academics associated with
it, other academics started writing and arguing
for an individual right to keep and bear arms.
This question about what the 2nd Amendment
means, has one final arbiter. And that`s the
Supreme Court of the United States. In 2008,
the Supreme Court said there was an individual
right to keep and bear a handgun in your home.
Justice Scalia`s opinion in the 2008 Heller
case said also the government can regulate
dangerous and unusual weapons. But what`s
a dangerous and unusual weapon? We don`t really
know. Is it an assault weapon? May be. Is
it tank? I think it`s safe to say yes. I don`t
think the Supreme Court is going back at this
point. The court isn`t going to make it 180
degree turn on the 2nd Amendment, but they
could certainly confine the right to keep
and bear arms.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Well, ready or not, prom season`s around
the corner. Onyeka and Julian who introduced
today`s show are ready. He recently asked
her to dance flash-mob style. Julian and 19
classmates choreographed a routine to a One
Direction song "One Thing." They did it in
only four rehearsals. We talked to the best
friends about that moment, but first, we want
you to check out how the group pulled off
the surprise in the Youtube video that has
thousands of views.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
(MUSIC)
OKEKE: I should have known, like all the (inaudible)
around me -- but I had no idea. I was totally
surprised.
NELUMS: Every time I watched it, I`m still
kind of like in awe that it all went down.
And I kind of like my stomach and like jumps
-- oh, my gosh, we did this, and it went perfectly.
OKEKE: I was like why are they dancing, and
why are they pointing at me and then I started
seeing more and more of my friends coming
up, and I was like oh, where is Julian? And
that is when I kind of got the clue.
NELUMS: I was just listening to everything
happening, I was like oh my gosh, (inaudible)
soon, so my heart was just pounding and pounding.
I was like I get to get this right.
OKEKE: Well, yeah, actually -- I think we
got up in the moment that he didn`t ask me
right there. Like later on, he had to (inaudible)
oh, yes, I forgot to ask you, we go and I
already said yes in my mind, so. It was yes.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Thumbs up is right. Now, I wasn`t that
creative, but maybe you were, you heard about
somebody`s fancy prom date request. Tell us
the coolest way to ask someone to prom, those
of you on Facebook can go to Facebook.com/snnstudentnews
to do it. Teachers, we are not leaving you
out. We want to hear from you, too. Tell us
what you think about today`s show. Log on
to snnstudentnews.com to do that.
Our last segment today is about a one trick
pony, but it`s a really good trick. Mariska
the Mare is a master lock picker, she doesn`t
just let herself out of the barn, she opens
the doors for all the other horses, too. Except
her mom. Probably, payback for all those lectures
about leaving the barn door open. Mariska
opens doors, she opens gates, she opens coolers.
Her owner finally latched on the idea to show
off the skills on Youtube. Did the video go
viral? Oh, that was just a lock! We just hope
Mariska doesn`t forget how to do this escape
act, because that`d be a shame to see her
stall out. And Mariska, you need to be nice
to your mother, you two should really try
for a stable relationship. Have a great weekend,
everyone.