SAMY AL-JAMAL: In the Middle
East, I think people are
warriors by nature.
They're born in conflicts.
They live their whole
lives in conflicts.
And I think that martial arts,
for them, is something that
suits them perfectly.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
SAMY AL-JAMAL: Go, fight.
Let's go.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
SAMY AL-JAMAL: My parents were
Palestinian refugees.
They went to Brazil
in the early '60s.
I was born and raised
in Brazil.
They came back to Jordan.
They acquired the Jordanian
passport and citizenship.
I also did that.
So basically, I'm
Brazilian-Jordanian but lived
all my life in Brazil.
And I've been here living for
the past five years in Jordan.
My name is Samy Al-Jamal, I'm a
fourth degree black belt in
Brazilian jujitsu.
I'm a black belt in judo.
I'm a black belt in
Karate, Shotokan.
I needed to defend myself
in the streets of Rio.
Rio is not an easy place for you
to grow up, especially in
the streets at the time
was very violent.
So I decided to start learning
martial arts in Brazil.
And since I was five years old
up to now, I'm 46, I still
train martial arts.
I decided to come here, stay
here, and teach jujitsu for
the Jordanian people, because
I thought it would be very
nice for them to learn the
true, original jujitsu.
And I stayed here and I opened
the school in order to teach
the real jujitsu, the real
Brazilian jujitsu.
Overall it's a way of life.
So I thought it was very
important for the Jordanian
people to be exposed to that.
And I actually felt a difference
here when I first
came and started wrestling
with they guys.
I thought they were
very strong.
And I don't think the Muslim
empire was an empire just by
chance, because these guys were
really, really strong
since back then.
The Source MMA is located in
Rabia, which is west Amman, in
the heart of the city.
And our dojo is about 200
meters for training.
I think we are like a
mini New York here.
It's like a melting pot of
cultures, religions.
And sometimes we have people
in the cage behind me here
praying, and right next to
them people fighting, and
right behind them people
actually doing mixed martial
arts and hitting each other,
which I think is a beautiful
scene to watch.
And not many places in
the world can have
this type of scenery.
We have foreigners that are
non-native Arabic-speaking
people, and because they become
Muslim they come to
Jordan, to live in Jordan to
live a life of a Muslim.
And they also are into martial
arts, so they come
and train with us.
And they're very religious, but
at the same time very good
martial artists.
RAMZI NABULSI: My name's
Ramzi Nabulsi.
I'm from Australia--
Melbourne, Australia.
I often get asked why did
I come to Jordan.
Why did I leave the land of milk
and honey of Australia
and come to the original
land of milk and honey?
And the reason for me was to
provide an environment for my
children and for my family
and myself where we could
spiritually grow as people.
See this is learning sensitivity
and how to stick
to your opponent.
It's very awkward,
with the idea of
always remaining stuck.
So it's like a two-man drill.
And then you can start adding
strikes and so on.
You win when you can
move your opponent.
And you want to do so without
having to muscle them.
You're just feeling and
finding their center.
The good thing about playing
with children is you don't
become aggressive.
So I live in a little town off
Sports City, what's known as
Sports City in Amman.
It's called Haya Karupsha.
And it's known for the many
scholars that live here.
The community is people from
the US, the UK, Canada,
Australia, India, and local
Arabs, Jordanians, and so on.
So it's a big mix of people.
And so we have every color of
the rainbow here and many
languages, coming under the
same banner or the same
intention to work on themselves
and improve
themselves.
There is a stereotype present
within the world that Muslims
have something in their
genetics, they just want to
get in to violence and they have
a passion for violence.
I'm interested very much in
the seeking a supremacy in
fighting in terms of the
art form itself.
So I'm looking for excellence
of fighting, which I think
comes down to something to do
with justice, and so on.
An importance put on being
able to stop people
evil with your hand.
So there's a need to do that.
And to do that, I find that
martial arts gives you the
tools to do so.
So I don't find martial arts
contradicts my faith at all.
And I find that, if anything,
it's just a tool in order to
do what I'm supposed to do,
which is support what is good
and stop what is bad.
I'm interested in competing
at some point in the mixed
martial arts arena and other
arenas, very much with the
intention to dispel any myths
within myself, what I'm
capable of doing.
I don't want to lie to anyone.
And I don't want to
lie to myself.
So I'm studying a number
of martial arts--
Brazilian jujitsu, and I come
from a background of Kung Fu,
and recently have
started Tai Chi.
Much like in the same sentiment
as Rickson Gracie
had said in his documentary,
"Choke," in order to believe
in what you're doing, you need
to be open to competition at
some point.
SAMY AL-JAMAL: Don't
take the back.
Let go.
Take the back.
Go, go.
Two points.
Move, move, move.
Pass the guard.
What are you doing?
Why is the hand and that
leg over there again?
The bottom of the leg.
Go down.
Good guard.
Stop.
Time.
You OK?
No?
It's interesting, you have a
lot of female BJJ fighters
here, more than my school in
Brazil, more than many schools
that I see outside.
And although the culture here
it's a bit restricted towards
women training martial arts,
the girls here are doing a
very good job and this year we
made two world champions.
Rana, she came to me, she had
never done any sports,
especially any sports that she
really had to push hard.
And she started kickboxing
with me.
And then she merged
into jujitsu.
And last year she competed in
the European championship and
Abu Dhabi World Pro
Championship.
She won both, the World Pro in
her weight and open weight and
the Portugal, also, her weight,
without anybody
scoring one advantage on her,
which is a huge accomplishment
for anyone.
She's the first Arab
woman to do that.
RANA QUBBAJ: I don't know why,
but people think that girls
should be delicate and they
should not be strong.
But I was never able to follow
that concept, because I think
everybody should be strong
because you cannot stand up
for yourself.
Not necessarily like being
aggressive, but every person
should be able to stand
up on their own.
My name is Rana Qubbaj.
I like to do MMA and
Brazilian jujitsu,
mostly Brazilian jujitsu.
And I train and compete
in jujitsu.
I started doing competitive
fighting by chance.
I started doing jujitsu
by chance.
I was just looking for
a workout to lose
weight and get in shape.
I was a lot overweight.
And I had to lose some weight.
And it was very hard for me to
get into working out because I
knew nothing about sports.
I tried to go to the gym,
I don't know how
to carry the weight.
to do anything.
I tried to jog, I can't jog.
Couldn't do anything.
I was totally out of shape.
I was a smoker.
I never worked out in my life.
So I tried a lot of things
for six months.
And then I started kickboxing.
There was a jujitsu
team in my gym.
And I kept on looking at them
for like 2 and 1/2 years, and
I didn't feel I'm interested.
And then the first time I tried
it, I really loved it.
The first time, the first five
minutes, I really loved it.
And six months after there was
a tournament in Abu Dhabi.
And I decided to try
my luck out.
And I loved it.
So I didn't plan for it.
OK, so my normal routine is I
wake up, like, 5:30 in the
morning, sometimes 6:00
when I'm really tired.
I prepare my food, because I
have to eat certain stuff.
So I prepare my food.
I cook whatever I want
to cook, whatever.
I have to prepare four meals.
Up to now, I have to
eat four meals.
So I prepare my four meals.
And I try to be in the
gym like 6:30, 7:00.
I start my morning workout
routine, which is basically
cardio, strength, and
weight-lifting and strength
exercises and whatever--
balance-- whatever I
need to work on.
So that goes in the morning.
And then I go to work.
I try to be on time at 9:00.
And I work 9-6.
My training is usually at 7:00,
my second training.
So I leave from work to
the dojo, to the gym.
I'm actually the first Arab
girl to win an IBJJF
tournament, which is the
International Brazilian
Jujitsu Federation.
These are the tournaments that
are organized by the
International Federation.
So they're the hardest to win.
So the Europeans was the
first IBJJF tournament
I've ever been to.
And I'm the first Arab
girl to win that one.
There are a bit of difficulties
actually.
The community's a bit
conservative about girls and
guys grappling together and
any form of being in very
close distance.
So it's harder here, because
girls outside get more
opportunities, or they
fight with guys more.
And guys are stronger,
physically, obviously.
So that helps you develop
your jujitsu more.
My family, the first time they
thought it was just a trip.
They knew I'm fighting but
nobody took me seriously.
And I still remember I was
pissed off when I lost.
And then my father called
and said, how'd it go?
And I was like, I lost.
And he was like, why
are you pissed off?
Of course you're
going to lose.
So nobody took me seriously
the first time.
The second time when
I told them I won,
it was like a surprise.
Everyone was surprised.
It's like, how can you
win in the Europeans?
The last competition,
the World Forum,
I didn't see that.
I wish I could see that.
But it was on TV.
So my sisters were telling me my
parents panicked when they
saw me fighting on TV.
And especially in jujitsu it's
sometimes complicated, because
you can be on bottom and winning
and you are the one
who's in control and you're
the one who's
not in pain or anything.
But it doesn't look this way.
So I was winning all the
fights and they were
panicking at home.
So this is my Dad.
RANA'S FATHER: Hello.
RANA QUBBAJ: My dad.
My mom went away.
I don't think that living in my
parents' house effects my
ability to be a good fighter,
because I know that our world
is conservative, but even not
every part of the society is
as conservative.
So my parents have no problem
with me going out, training,
travelling to compete.
And I've always travelled before
competitions and after
competitions.
So for me, it's not a problem.
I know it might be a problem
for other Arab girls.
But for me it's not.
Thank god.
And sometimes guys in this
country, unfortunately, have
the habit of just commenting on
girls when they're walking.
So it used to annoy me more
before I used to do jujitsu.
For example, I never would
have stopped at an ATM at
night to withdraw money
two years ago.
But now I don't care.
I had to use my jujitsu
only once.
I was walking down the street
and this guy started making
comments and I ignored him
because this is what we do.
We ignore the guys when
they do that.
And then he grabbed my hand.
He was like, I'm
talking to you.
So I had to use some jujitsu.
But not too much.
SAMY AL-JAMAL: Every part of
society, they have something
against it, which, to me,
creates a platform for them to
show freedom, for them to
actually go there and conquer
their rights and show to people
that people are wrong
through going to championships,
conquering
world championships.
And that's what I tell them all
the time, their results in
the martial arts is what's
going to make people
understand and except
them better.
[MUSIC PLAYING]