EDDY MORETTI: Look at that.
Jesus!
Another oil refinery.
I wonder how far we could get
before they send the little
surveillance vehicle to see
what the fuck we're doing.
Do you mind?
Do we care?
SIMON DYER: How we our energy
and how we do and how we
impact the environment in
getting that energy I think is
the issue of our times.
And the Alberta oil sands
represent the very worst in
terms of our desire
to extract oil.
You know basically go to
any length with it.
EDDY MORETTI: My heiny
is freezing.
When people think of oil they
think of the Middle East but
actually Canada has one of
the largest petroleum
deposits in the world.
It's just that it's
stuck in sand.
The oil sands is an area the
size of Florida and it holds
an estimated 1.7 to 2.5 trillion
barrels of oil.
However, until recently, it's
been way too expensive to
extract from the sand.
LINDSAY TELFER: It's the most
difficult to access oil in the
world and that's why it's never
been seen as a viable
option in the global
oil economy.
But because the oil prices have
gone up so much, likely
because we've hit peak oil,
all of a sudden the most
difficult to access oil in
the world has now become
accessible.
So peak oil is--
in it's very simple terms, it's
exactly what it says.
You hit a peak of production of
available oil reserves and
once you've hit that peak
you start going down.
So it's the reserves in the
world are declining.
SIMON DYER: Companies and
countries are realizing
strategically they're trying to
figure out where this oil
is going to come from as
sources elsewhere in
the world dry up.
So Canada is considered a safe,
secure source of oil.
And all the major
oil companies--
all the multinationals
in the world have
operations in the oil sand.
And you're seeing that stampede
to try and ensure
that they get a piece
of the pie.
EDDY MORETTI: We made our way
for Fort McMurray, a small
town in the middle of Canada's
tundra that is the epicenter
of the oil sands operation.
When we were there we realized
that this little town has
global consequences.
Fort McMurray is responsible
for two-thirds of Canada's
contribution to global
greenhouse gas emissions which
is kind of amazing when you
think that it's a town of
70,000 people.
The problem's so big, it's so
massive, affects so many
different people environmentally
and socially.
We basically tried to cover the
story from as many angles
as we could and we realized
that it was inexhaustible.
We met the chief of
the Athabaskan
Region First Nation.
We met the Premier of Alberta,
which is like the governor.
We also visited the work camps,
saw the pipeline that's
being built all the
way to Chicago.
We saw how they rip up the
forest in order to discover
and explore for this oil.
We also snuck onto some
of these sites.
And the snow is really
fucking deep here.
Be careful.
OK.
Here we go.
This is it.
Welcome to Alberta.
Welcome to the future of oil.
It sucks.
It really fucking sucks.
And it wreaks.
It smells.
So we came all the way from
New York because we heard
there's a lot of oil here.
LINDSAY TELFER: I guess the
other angle is scraping at the
bottom of the barrel.
It is the dirtiest to produce
oil in the world.
The oil sands industry in Canada
make up the single
largest contributor to our
growing greenhouse gas
emissions in Canada.
EDDY MORETTI: The first thing
you need to understand is how
they extract the oil
from the sand.
First they clear out the trees
and mine the sand that's close
to the surface.
But some of the sand is deeper
and to get to that they've
invented a new system.
It's called SAGD, or steam
assisted gravity drainage.
Basically they heat the soil
and suck out the sand.
SIMON DYER: The use of water
for in situ operations is a
real concern.
Companies use about a fifth of
a barrel of water for every
barrel of oil produced
in situ operations.
Oil sands companies--
oil sands mines basically
extract water directly from
the Athabasca River.
Because the process, of course,
pollutes that water so
much, it's largely not actually
returned to the
Athabasca River.
The vast majority of
it gets dumped into
these tailings ponds.
So these are basically oily
lagoons full of waste water
and suspended hydrocarbons.
If you ever get a chance to tour
an oil sands mine these
landscapes are quite surreal.
EDDY MORETTI: Once they've dug
up all the oil sand, they
stick it in these huge cokers,
which are like large furnaces
and boil it, and steam
inject it.
That's how they get the
oil out of the sand.
And this is the process where
all the greenhouse gas
emissions come from.
LINDSAY TELFER: Really, the only
real way to get the oil
sands to eliminate their carbon
dioxide emissions is to
stop producing the oil
from the oil sands.
EDDY MORETTI: And is
that your position?
LINDSAY TELFER: We need
to slow down.
But I also recognize that it's
not going to stop tomorrow.
Our communities can't
keep pace.
Our environment can't
We know we need to slow down.
I think that that in itself
is very clear.
EDDY MORETTI: And who's
pressuring us to ramp up?
LINDSAY TELFER: Industry.
Government.
I mean the Alberta government
makes a lot of money on the
oil sands so until there is a
viable alternative for them to
shift our economy I think that
they're going to continue to
create the climate that's going
to attract this kind of
business to the province.
EDDY MORETTI: We went to go ask
for permission but there
was no one in the office.
And there are a couple
of trees here.
A couple of rows of
a couple of trees.
One, two, three, four, seven,
nine, ten, a million.
Logs, logs, log, log,
log, log, logs.
It's dangerous being a logger.
But we don't know how
they cut them.
If they're chainsaws or if
they're those tree snipper
things where they
just snip it.
Then again, what do I know?
LINDSAY TELFER: Boreal forests
are the lungs of Canada.
It's what cleans our air.
It's what gives us the air
that we can breathe.
If you compare it to the Amazon
forest which is often
called the lungs of the earth,
the Boreal forest is largely
the lungs of North America
EDDY MORETTI: So we
kind of need it?
LINDSAY TELFER: And it's
the largest intact
forest left in the world.
EDDY MORETTI: Holy shit!
Look at that thing!
What are the odds of there
being oil here?
MALE SPEAKER: Very good.
EDDY MORETTI: Yeah?
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
That's why we're doing it.
EDDY MORETTI: So they
just cut, cut,
cut, cut their grids?
MALE SPEAKER: That's right.
EDDY MORETTI: And then another
crew comes in.
Do you consider yourself an
environmentalist of sorts?
MALE SPEAKER: Definitely.
EDDY MORETTI: Yeah.
MALE SPEAKER: Oh yeah,
you betcha.
EDDY MORETTI: So you have no
major concerns with the way
this business is operating?
MALE SPEAKER: Well before we can
even cut down a tree, we
have to get government
approval.
One of the major focuses in
this industry is on the
environment because that's
a key asset to
what we do out here.
EDDY MORETTI: Do you think then
these lines that have
been mulched will get replanted
or what will happen?
MALE SPEAKER: Someday,
I'm sure.
There's always tree planting
that's going on
throughout the province.
EDDY MORETTI: They just have to
catch up to the other guys.
FRANK ROUTHIER:
EDDY MORETTI: What happens
when there's no more oil?
FRANK ROUTHIER:
EDDY MORETTI: Are you going to
work in this business until
you retire?
FRANK ROUTHIER: And at
my age, my age--
I'm not that old, guys!
EDDY MORETTI: Can you tell
us how much you make?
FRANK ROUTHIER: How
much I make?
This thing is oil.
Then the oil is these
things are oil.
Everything's got oil.
Even your camera
inside got oil.
EDDY MORETTI: It's like
the economic engine of
Canada, this town.
FRANK ROUTHIER:
EDDY MORETTI: We're going to
leave the truck there.
OK.
We're going to go straight.
FRANK ROUTHIER: Yeah.
EDDY MORETTI: OK.
FRANK ROUTHIER: But I give you
a clipboard so you can write
your comments and stuff.
EDDY MORETTI: Good, good.
Great.
We're going there.
[INAUDIBLE] men working here on
the pipeline down there but
[INAUDIBLE] sector 32.
We want to go down
to sector G9.
MALE SPEAKER: So I'm sorry
I forgot your first name.
EDDY MORETTI: Eddie.
MALE SPEAKER: Eddie,
this is Jason.
EDDY MORETTI: Hey.
JASON: How's it going?
How's it going buddy?
JASON: Not bad.
Not bad.
JC: JC.
They call me JC up
around here.
I don't like being called after
a toilet because it's
what they call a
toilet, a john.
Right?
JC.
EDDY MORETTI: Oh wow.
JC: I had a chainsaw kickback
and kind of buggered me up a
little bit back a
few years ago.
EDDY MORETTI: Yeah, well you're
lucky it didn't do
anything worse.
JC: I keep the sunglasses
down now.
I hide that stuff because
the ladies don't
like to see that stuff.
EDDY MORETTI: So you
like your job?
JC: Oh I love it.
EDDY MORETTI: You like trees?
JC: I'm over here in fresh
air, nice blue skies.
Life's great.
Lots of wildlife.
Well, I hadn't seen
anything yet but--
MALE SPEAKER: You don't have
to touch anything.
EDDY MORETTI: They're
nice trees.
JC: Yeah exactly.
I hate to cut them down if
they don't have to go.
That's our oxygen, man.
You know?
I hate to cut them out because
it's not that I'm a tree
hugger but I'm not a
tree killer either.
EDDY MORETTI: Wow.
He's really good.
Oh shit!
You did a good job buddy.
You were really delicate
with that thing.
You slowly steered it
into a direction.
JC: Oh yeah.
Yeah it's great fun.
EDDY MORETTI: You like
Fort McMurray?
JC: No.
EDDY MORETTI: Why?
JC: There's too many people in
too big of a rush up here.
EDDY MORETTI: Yeah.
JC: Too many I don't know.
Like this highway, they
call it death highway.
It's scares you to
drive on it.
You don't know if somebody's
going to clean you or wipe you
out or what so you keep close
to the ditch, right?
EDDY MORETTI: What happens
to people?
They just like, do they work
too hard and then party too
hard and then the combination
gets them
into trouble or what?
JC: Oh, could be.
It could be.
There's a lot of people
that do long shifts.
Us, we usually take our days
off after 21 or less.
EDDY MORETTI: You work
21 days straight?
JC: 21 days straight, yep.
Then take five, six days off
to enjoy life a little bit.
Some of these other guys, well
they get going 30, 40, 50 days
straight and then--
EDDY MORETTI: That's got
to be-- that's just not
JC: Yeah, they get--
EDDY MORETTI: Healthy.
JC: No.
They get burned out and
they get tired.
It 's a way of life but it's
interesting at times.
Wouldn't do anything else
otherwise, if I had a choice.
Right?
EDDY MORETTI: What's your plan
then, stay here for another
couple years?
JC: Yeah.
I float the oil patch
through anyway.
EDDY MORETTI: What does
that mean, float
the oil patch through?
JC: Well, as long as there's
money here, a man will be here
working if he can fill his bank
account up, and put the
bread and butter on the table
and this is where he'll be.
If it ain't here, if it's in
BC or if it's in Sweden, if
that's where the money is,
that's where we'll
all have to go, right?
EDDY MORETTI: Right.
You have a family?
JC: Yeah.
I got a son.
EDDY MORETTI: Here in Alberta?
JC: In the Maritimes.
EDDY MORETTI: In the Maritimes.
JC: Yeah.
EDDY MORETTI: So you're
not going back home.
You're here for good.
JC: If I'm here, I'm here
for the-- as long
as the money's here.
EDDY MORETTI: As long as the
oil's flowing you're--
JC: Yeah.
Exactly.
The welfare line's not for me.
EDDY MORETTI: Right on.
SIMON DYER: George Bush's State
of the Union Address a
couple of years ago--
EDDY MORETTI: Last year.
Right.
SIMON DYER: Pretty bluntly said
we're addicted to foreign
oil and we need to get
off foreign oil.
And he didn't consider--
I don't think he considers
Canada foreign in that
respective.
MALE SPEAKER: Ladies and
gentlemen, thank you for
coming this afternoon.
And first and foremost, I want
to welcome back to Fort
McMurray our premier
Ed Stelmach.
Premier, welcome back
to Fort McMurray.
ED STELMACH: Over the past year,
I've spoken to a lot of
ordinary Albertans.
They are proud of Alberta's
position in Canada as an
economic powerhouse.
However, there is always a word
of caution and that is
Ed, don't blow it.
EDDY MORETTI: This is the new
premier, Ed Stelmach.
He took over from this
guy, Ralph Klein.
And he's the guy responsible
for kick-starting the oil
sands in the '90s.
While you were premier,
were you pressured by
multinationals
RALPH KLEIN: No.
EDDY MORETTI: To increase
production?
RALPH KLEIN: No.
Never.
10 years ago, I took a
delegation down to Houston and
I can recall holding a symposium
to talk about the
oil sands, and how Canada can
meet the reliable and secure
supply that the
EDDY MORETTI: Stable.
RALPH KLEIN: US is
looking for.
The stable supply.
First of all, we stationed a
person in Washington, DC to
focus really on the American
legislators, those in Congress
and in Senate--
EDDY MORETTI: And is working,
his work is having results?
RALPH KLEIN: His work is--
well, his work has been
highly successful.
LINDSAY TELFER: We've created
the most accessible investment
climate for oil companies.
EDDY MORETTI: Why?
LINDSAY TELFER: Heck, because
we wanted the investment.
We wanted people to come in.
So in the '90s we set up a
royalty regime that allowed
them to virtually not
pay royalties.
A majority of the oil sands,
once it's upgraded and refined
and often before it's upgraded
and refined, is
shipped to the States.
The Chicago area is one
of the sent hubs
for the bitumen upgrading.
EDDY MORETTI: This pipe
goes all the way to
Chicago, which is far.
We're good for 50 years,
America, and
after that you're fucked.
You're on your own.
SIMON DYER: The tar sands is
producing about a million
barrels of oil a day.
And there are discussions to
increase that to 5 million
barrels a day.
America, of course, uses
more than 20 million
barrels of oil a day.
So I mean the tar sands can plug
that gap for only a very
short period and it's never
going to be able to meet
Americans' needs so we need to
look at other solutions.
LINDSAY TELFER: When you're in
government, there's a lot of
pressure to be open and
friendly to industrial
development and Klein was the
best of the best of them.
And what we're seeing now is
some of those leaders going
whoa, maybe we did this
a little bit too fast.
OK.
Well obviously there's
been no plan.
That's why it spiraled
out of control.
Our communities have spiraled
Development has spiraled
out of control.
Klein came out after he left
office saying, no, we didn't
have a plan.
We just said come on in.
EDDY MORETTI: People have said
that you have said that you
didn't have a plan for the
development of the oil sands.
RALPH KLEIN: No.
EDDY MORETTI: Is that true?
Or is that misquoting you?
RALPH KLEIN: No.
We had a plan for sustainable
growth.
We had a plan for $50 a barrel
oil and gas at $6.50 a
gigajoule, but we didn't
have a plan for
unprecedented growth.
No one has a plan.
Not even the current premier or
the current cabinet has a
plan for unprecedented growth,
nor does Al Gore have a plan,
by the way.
EDDY MORETTI: Right.
RALPH KLEIN: And you're asking
for a personal opinion--
EDDY MORETTI: Yeah.
RALPH KLEIN: And I can offer a
personal opinion, and I say
let the markets prevail.