HERE THE REVIEW SESSION WILL BE HELD IN DWINELLE
AND
IT IS A PART OF GETTING ROOM IN TIME AS YOU
GUYS CAN
PROBABLY GUESS, THE CAMPUS IS VERY CROWDED.
SO, IT IS
OPEN TO ALL. IT IS A WORKING SESSION. I DON'T
HAVE
ANYTHING PREPARED. COME WITH YOUR QUESTIONS.
I WILL
ANSWER ANY QUESTIONS EVEN IF THEY ARE QUESTIONS
THAT
ARE ON THE EXAM. OF COURSE I WON'T TELL YOU,
BUT I
WILL STILL ANSWER THEM. NOW ABOUT THE QUESTIONS,
THERE ARE SAMPLE QUESTIONS FOR THE EXAM TAKEN
FROM
PREVIOUS EXAMS POSTED ON THE WEB SITE. AGAIN,
THOSE
ARE MOSTLY MEANT TO GIVE YOU AN INDICATION
OF
A FORMAT. THERE WILL BE MULTIPLE AND WE WILL
TALK
A LITTLE BIT MORE ABOUT IT AS WE APPROACH
THE END OF
THIS PORTION OF THE CLASS.
I ALSO WANT TO SAY TO YOU THAT GIVEN SAMPLE
QUESTIONS TO PEOPLE WHO HAVE COME TO OFFICE
HOURS,
WHEN WE HAVE TALKED, I HAVE BROUGHT UP SAMPLE
QUESTIONS AND WE HAVE DISCUSSED THEM. SO,
THERE ARE
PLENTY OF OPPORTUNITIES FOR YOU TO GET AN
IDEA OF WHAT
THE EXAM IS LIKE BEFORE YOU TAKE IT.
THE LAST POINT I WANT TO MENTION TO YOU IS
THAT
IF YOU ARE ILL ON THE DAY OF THE EXAM OR YOU
GET SICK,
THE ONLY WAY WE CAN EXCUSE YOU FROM THE EXAM
IS IF YOU
HAVE A NOTE FROM THE TANG CENTER. WE CANNOT
MAKE
A JUDGMENT ABOUT WHETHER OR NOT YOUR ILLNESS
IS SEVERE
OR NOT. BUT, WE ALWAYS TAKE THE NOTE FROM
THE TANG CENTER. SO, IF YOU ARE GOING TO BE
ILL OR IF
YOU ARE ILL, MAKE SURE YOU GO TO THE TANG
CENTER AND
BRING YOUR GSI THE NOTE, OTHERWISE YOU WILL
NOT BE
EXCUSED FROM THE EXAM AND YOU WILL HAVE MISSED
IT.
ARE THERE ANY QUESTIONS?
OKAY. LAST TIME WE ENDED BY TALKING ABOUT
THE
VASCULAR CAMBIUM. AND, WE HAD THIS LAYER OF
CELLS,
WHICH WE CALL THE VASCULAR CAMBIUM. AND
WE SAID TO
THE INSIDE OF THE VASCULAR CAMBIUM WE MADE
SECONDARY
XYLEM. AND TO THE OUTSIDE WE MADE SECONDARY
PHLOEM.
THESE TWO CELL TYPES OF VERY DIFFERENT. THE
SECONDARY
XYLEM CELL TYPES ARE DEAD WHEN THEY ARE FUNCTIONAL.
THEY HAVE A LOT OF LIGAND IN THEIR WALLS.
WHEREAS,
THE SECONDARY PHLOEM ARE CELLS THAT ARE LIVING
WHEN
THEY ARE FUNCTIONAL. THEY HAVE LOST THEIR
NUCLEUS BUT
THEY STILL HAVE SOME CYTOPLASMS. YET, AS DIFFERENT
AS
THESE TWO CELL TYPES ARE FROM EACH OTHER,
THEY BOTH
ORIGINATED FROM A COMMON CELL, VASCULAR CAMBIUM.
AND
TODAY, WHAT WE WANT TO DO IS TO BEGIN THE
FIRST OF TWO
LECTURES IN WHICH WE TALK ABOUT THE COMMITMENT
TO
DIFFERENTIATE. WE WANT TO TALK ABOUT THE CONTROLS
AT
LEAST AS WE UNDERSTAND THEM WHICH CAUSE A
CELL TO
FOLLOW A PARTICULAR DEVELOPMENTAL PATHWAY
TO BECOME
EITHER, IN THIS CASE, A SECONDARY XYLEM CELL
OR
A SECONDARY PHLOEM CELL. AND, THIS IS A TOPIC
WHICH
WILL HAVE AS YOU SEE, A LOT OF IDEAS WHICH
SEEM TO
CONTRADICT EACH OTHER, BUT IN THE END I HOPE
YOU GET
AN APPRECIATION AND A PICTURE OF WHAT THESE
CONTROLS
ARE LIKE OR AT LEAST WHAT WE THINK THESE CONTROLS
ARE
LIKE.
NOW, THE STUDIES OF THIS COMMITMENT TO
DIFFERENTIATE BEGAN PROBABLY IN THE 19TH CENTURY
WITH
A GERMAN BOTANIST BY THE NAME OF SACHS. SACHS
BELIEVED THAT THERE WERE SUBSTANCES WHICH
HE CALLED
ORGAN OR TISSUE FORMING SUBSTANCES.
SO, HE ENVISIONED A ROOT FORMING SUBSTANCE,
A SHOOT FORMING SUBSTANCE, ETC. SO, HE THOUGHT
THAT
THERE WERE THESE COMPOUNDS WHICH IF THEY WERE
PUT ON
THE PLANT OR FOUND IN A PARTICULAR REGION
OF THE
PLANT, THEY WOULD CAUSE A ROOT TO FORM OR
CAUSE
A SHOOT TO FORM. AND THIS WAS A WIDELY ACCEPTED
VIEW
IN THE 19TH CENTURY, AT LEAST IN THE MIDDLE
TO THE
EARLY 19TH CENTURY, WITHOUT REALLY ANY PROOF.
AT
ABOUT THE SAME TIME THAT SACHS WAS COMING
UP WITH HIS
IDEAS AND HIS HYPOTHESIS, ANOTHER WORKER WITH
WHOM ALL
OF YOU, I BELIEVE, ARE FAMILIAR, CHARLES DARWIN
WAS
ALSO INTERESTED IN STUDYING GROWTH AND DEVELOPMENT.
AND THE WORK I WANT TO TALK TO YOU ABOUT NOW
WAS DONE
WITH DARWIN AND WITH HIS SON FRANCIS. DARWIN,
CHARLES
DARWIN AND HIS SON FRANCIS DARWIN WERE INTERESTED
IN
PLANT MOVEMENTS
OR AS THEY ARE KNOWN AS TROPISMS.
TROPISMS. AND THE PARTICULAR TYPE OF TROPISM
OR
MOVEMENT THAT THEY WERE INTERESTED IN, IS
ONE THAT YOU
HAVE ALREADY BEEN EXPOSED TO. THEY WERE INTERESTED
IN
THE BENDING
OF PLANTS TOWARDS LIGHT. OR AS THIS IS
KNOWN AS PHOTOTROPISM. AS YOU HAVE ALREADY
SEEN
A RESPONSE OF AN ORGANISM TO LIGHT WHEN WE
TALKED
ABOUT THE FUNGUS PILOBILUS IN THE VERY FIRST
LECTURE.
IT ALREADY SHOWED PHOTOTROPISM AND IT ALSO
MOVED OR
BENT TOWARD THE LIGHT. NOW FOR THESE EXPERIMENTS
DARWIN AND FRANCIS DID NOT WORK WITH PILOBILUS
WITH
THE FUNGUS, BUT THEY WORKED WITH A GRASS
AND THEY
WORKED WITH A PARTICULAR PORTION OF THE GRASS
SEEDLING
THAT ALL OF YOU HAVE OR WILL BE SEEING THIS
WEEK IN
THE LAB.
THEY WORKED WITH THE GRASS COLEOPTILE OR THE
SHEATH COVERING THE SHOOT JUST BEFORE THE
SHOOT
EMERGES FROM THE SOIL. AND TO REMIND YOU OF
THE
COLEOPTILE, IF WE HAVE A SEED. HERE IS THE
SEED. THE
COLEOPTILE IS THE SHEATH PROTECTING THE SHOOT,
WHICH
WOULD BE HERE.
HERE IS THE COLEOPTILE. AND WHAT WERE
INTERESTED IN IS THEY TOOK SEEDLINGS, LIKE
THIS ONE.
AND WE WILL DRAW IT AGAIN. TOOK SEEDLINGS
OF GRASSES
AND THEY GAVE IT LIGHT FROM ONE DIRECTION,
SO CALLED,
UNILATERAL ILLUMINATION.
SO LET'S SAY THEY GAVE IT
LIGHT FROM THIS DIRECTION. UNILATERAL ILLUMINATION.
AND WHAT THEY FOUND, IF THEY WAITED FOR SOME
TIME, IS
AS YOU ALL KNOW, THE COLEOPTILE APPEAR TO
MOVE TOWARD
THE LIGHT OR BEND TOWARD THE LIGHT.
THIS IS PHOTOTROPISM, MOVEMENT OR BENDING
TOWARD
THE LIGHT. POSITIVE PHOTOTROPISM. NOW, AN
IMPORTANT
POINT WHICH WE NEED TO MAKE ON THIS BENDING
AND WHICH
IS GOING TO UNDERLIES WHAT WE TALK ABOUT LATER
IN
LECTURE IS THE FOLLOWING.
FOR THIS I WANT YOU ALL TO LOOK AT THIS AND
I
WILL WRITE IT DOWN FOR YOU. FOR THIS BENDING
TO OCCUR
THIS SIDE OVER HERE HAS TO GROW MORE THAN
THIS SIDE
OVER HERE. FOR BENDING TO OCCUR ONE SIDE HAS
TO GROW
MORE THAN THE OTHER.
AND THIS IS KNOWN AS DIFFERENTIAL GROWTH.
THE
TWO SIDES ARE RESPONDING IN A DIFFERENT MANNER,
THEY
ARE GROWING IN A DIFFERENT MANNER.
NOW, DARWIN AND
FRANCIS DID A LOT OF EXPERIMENTS AND I WANT
TO JUST
TELL YOU ABOUT A FEW OF THE EXPERIMENTS THEY
DID TO
TRY TO UNDERSTAND THE BASIS OF THIS DIFFERENTIAL
GROWTH. THE BASIS OF THIS PHOTOTROPISM. THE
FIRST
EXPERIMENT THEY DID WAS TO ASK, WHAT PART
OF THE
COLEOPTILE SEES THE LIGHT? I WILL PUT SEES
IN
QUOTES. AND, WHAT THEY DID WAS TO TAKE COLEOPTILES
SEEDLINGS AND COVER VARIOUS PORTIONS OF THEM
WITH
BLACK CLOTH OR WHAT WAS THE EQUIVALENT TO
ALUMINUM
FOIL IN THE 19TH CENTURY AND FIND OUT WHICH
PORTION
WAS NECESSARY TO BE EXPOSED TO THE LIGHT IN
ORDER TO
GET PHOTOTROPISM. AND FROM THIS WORK THEY
CONCLUDED
THAT THE TIP RECEIVED THE LIGHT.
AND, THEY
HYPOTHESIZED
THAT SOMETHING MOVED FROM THE TIP DOWN TO
CAUSE THE DIFFERENTIAL GROWTH.
THESE WERE VERY
IMPORTANT OBSERVATIONS AND THESE HYPOTHESIS,
THESE
OBSERVATIONS AND MANY MORE ON PLANT MOVEMENTS
WERE
PUBLISHED IN A BOOK. FRANCIS AND CHARLES DARWIN
PUBLISHED IT IN A BOOK CALLED, "THE POWER
OF MOVEMENT"
IN 1896. AND WE HAVE A NUMBER OF COPIES IN
OUR
LIBRARY. IT IS A VERY FASCINATING BOOK. THEY
MAKE A
LOT OF OBSERVATIONS. MANY OF WHICH, IN FACT,
MOST OF
WHICH HAVE NEVER BEEN FOLLOWED UP ON. SO,
THESE
OBSERVATIONS WERE MADE IN THE LATE 19TH
CENTURY AND
BASICALLY THAT WAS THE END OF THE WORK ON
THEM UNTIL
ABOUT THE 1930'S. AND IN THE 1930'S DARWIN'S
OBSERVATIONS ON THE COLEOPTILE AND PHOTOTROPISM
WERE
PICKED UP AGAIN IN AN ATTEMPT TO TRY AND UNDERSTAND
WHAT WAS GOING ON IN THIS PARTICULAR MECHANISM.
AND,
THE VERY FIRST EXPERIMENTS WHICH PEOPLE DID
IN THESE
SITUATIONS WERE THE FOLLOWING:
THEY TOOK A COLEOPTILE, AND WE SHOULD SAY
THAT
THIS WORK WAS DONE IN DARKNESS. IT REALLY
WASN'T
TOTAL DARKNESS, IT WAS IN A ROOM THAT HAD
GREEN LIGHT,
GREEN LIGHT AS FAR AS THE PLANT IS CONCERNED
IS LIKE
DARKNESS. PLANTS DON'T REALLY RESPOND IN THIS
WAY TO
THE GREEN LIGHT. BUT, FOR OUR PURPOSES WE
WILL SAY IT
WAS DONE IN DARKNESS. NOW WHAT THESE PEOPLE
DID, WAS
FIRST OF ALL TO CONFIRM DARWIN'S HYPOTHESIS
THAT
SOMETHING WAS GOING ON IN THE TIP. THEY TOOK
THE
COLEOPTILE AND THEY PUT A PIECE OF A FOIL,
ALUMINUM
FOIL BETWEEN THE TIP AND THE REST OF THE
COLEOPTILE
AND THEN THEY GAVE IT UNILATERAL LIGHT.
AND THEY GOT
NO BENDING. AND THAT IS EXACTLY PARALLEL TO
WHAT
DARWIN SHOULD BE, WHAT DARWIN PREDICTED. DARWIN
ALSO
PREDICTED THAT THERE WAS BEING MADE IN THE
TIP AND
THIS EXPERIMENT TENDED TO CONFIRM THAT WHEN
YOU PUT
THE ALUMINUM FOIL BETWEEN THE TIP AND THE
REST OF THE
COLEOPTILE, YOU PREVENTED WHATEVER WAS BEING
MADE FROM
MOVING DOWN. SO, ON THE ASSUMPTION THAT SOMETHING
WAS
BEING MADE, WHAT THESE INVESTIGATORS NEXT
DID WAS TO
TAKE AGAR, SHEET THE AGAR, MOST OF YOU HAVE
SEEN AGAR
BEFORE. AND ON THIS AGAR SHEET, TO PLACE LOTS
OF
COLEOPTILE TIPS. SO THESE ARE COLEOPTILE ON
AGAR.
AND THEY LET THE COLEOPTILE TIPS SIT ON THE
AGAR ON
THE ASSUMPTION THAT WHATEVER WAS BEING MADE
BY THE
COLEOPTILE TIPS WOULD DIFFUSE INTO THE AGAR.
AND THEN THEY DID A SERIES OF EXPERIMENTS.
AGAIN, THESE ARE IN DARKNESS. IN DARKNESS.
THE FIRST
EXPERIMENT WHICH THEY DID IS THEY TOOK THE
AGAR AND
THEY DIVIDED IT IN TO PIECES. DIVIDED IT IN
TO PIECES
AND THEN SUBSTITUTED FOR THE COLEOPTILE TIP.
LET'S
TALK ABOUT HOW THESE SUBSTITUTION EXPERIMENTS
LOOKED.
IN THE FIRST EXPERIMENT, AGAIN, DONE IN DARKNESS.
THEY TOOK THE COLEOPTILE, WHICH WAS LACKING
ITS TIP,
AND THEY PUT A BLOCK OF AGAR ON SYMMETRICALLY,
SYMMETRICALLY. AND IF YOU WAITED FOR SOME
TIME, WHAT
YOU FOUND IS THAT THIS GREW. GOT VERY BIG.
SO, THIS
WAS CONTRASTED WITH THE TIP WITH NO AGAR AND
WAITED
FOR TIME. GOT NO GROWTH. SO CLEARLY SOMETHING
WAS
COMING FROM THE AGAR. THE NEXT SERIES OF EXPERIMENTS
WERE A LITTLE MORE CLEVER, A LITTLE MORE INTERESTING.
THEY WERE ALSO DONE IN DARKNESS. AND, IN THESE
EXPERIMENTS WHAT THEY DID, IS THEY TOOK A
COLEOPTILE
LIKE SO, COLEOPTILE LIKE SO, JUST AS YOU HAVE
SEEN
BEFORE, AGAIN IN DARKNESS AND NOW THEY PUT
THE BLOCK
ON ASYMMETRICALLY.
ASYMMETRICALLY. AND THEY WAITED
FOR SOME TIME. AND WHAT THEY FOUND WAS IN
FACT, THE
COLEOPTILE BENT, COLEOPTILE BENT, JUST LIKE
IT WOULD
IN THE LIGHT.
SO FROM THIS EXPERIMENT THEY CONCLUDED
SOMETHING MOVING ASYMMETRICALLY OUT OF THE
BLOCK.
STIMULATING DIFFERENTIAL GROWTH.
AND THAT IS
PRETTY EASY TO UNDERSTAND IF YOU LOOK CAREFULLY
AT
THIS PICTURE HERE. BECAUSE THE BLOCK IS PLACED
ON
ONLY PART OF THE COLEOPTILE, WHATEVER THIS
SUBSTANCE WAS WOULD ONLY MOVE DOWN PART OF
THE
COLEOPTILE SIDE. AND, ACCORDING TO THIS IDEA,
IT
WOULD STIMULATE DIFFERENTIAL GROWTH ONLY ON
THE
SIDE WHERE THE SUBSTANCE WAS IN HIGHER
CONCENTRATION. EVERYBODY CLEAR ON THAT? FINALLY
THEY DID A THIRD EXPERIMENT WITH THESE COLEOPTILES.
AND THIS WAS NOW DONE IN USING UNILATERAL
LIGHT.
AND THIS EXPERIMENT THEY TOOK AGAIN THE COLEOPTILE,
THEY HAD TAKEN OFF THE ORIGINAL TIP, THEY
PUT THE
BLOCK ON SYMMETRICALLY NOW,
AND NOW THEY DID
SOMETHING VERY CLEVER. THEY GAVE IT UNILATERAL
LIGHT. THEY GAVE IT UNILATERAL LIGHT. IN THIS
PARTICULAR EXPERIMENT, IN THIS PARTICULAR
EXPERIMENT, WHAT THEY FOUND WAS THAT THE COLEOPTILE
BENT TOWARD THE LIGHT, EVEN THOUGH THE BLOCK
WAS ON
SYMMETRICALLY, IT BENT TOWARD THE LIGHT. IF
A SUBSTANCE IS BEING PRODUCED SYMMETRICALLY,
YOU
WOULD EXPECT THE COLEOPTILE TO GROW STRAIGHT
IF YOU
PUT IT IN THE LIGHT, IF THE SUBSTANCE IS BEING
PRODUCED SYMMETRICALLY. BUT, IN FACT, WHAT
THEY
FOUND WAS THAT EVEN THOUGH THEY WERE PUTTING
THE
SUBSTANCE ON SYMMETRICALLY, THE COLEOPTILE
BENT.
AND SO FROM THIS EXPERIMENT, THEY CONCLUDED
THAT
LIGHT WAS CAUSING THE MOVEMENT OF THIS SUBSTANCE
TO
THE SIDE OF THE COLEOPTILE AWAY FROM THE LIGHT.
IN
THIS SCENARIO THEN, WHAT YOU WOULD HAVE, AND
I AM
JUST GOING TO DRAW THIS FOR YOU, IN THIS SCENARIO
WHAT WOULD YOU HAVE IS, YOU WOULD HAVE MORE
OF THIS
SUBSTANCE, MORE SUBSTANCE ON THE DARK SIDE.
AND
THIS IS WHY THE COLEOPTILE BENT, BECAUSE HERE
YOU
HAD MORE GROWTH. THESE ARE VERY CENTRAL AND
IMPORTANT EXPERIMENTS. WHAT IS THIS SUBSTANCE?
OF COURSE, ONCE WE DEMONSTRATED SOME OF THE
PHYSIOLOGICAL CHARACTERS PEOPLE BEGAN TO LOOK
FOR
WHAT IT WAS. THE AGAR WAS ANALYZED, CHEMICALLY,
AND OUT OF THE AGAR A COMPOUND INDOLE-3-ACETIC
ACID
OR ABBREVIATED AS IAA OR THE COMMON NAME IS
AUXIN
WAS IDENTIFIED. THIS IS A LOW MOLECULAR WEIGHT
COMPOUND ABOUT LESS THAN 200 IN MOLECULAR
WEIGHT.
IT WORKS IN LOW CONCENTRATIONS. WORKS IN LOW
CONCENTRATION AND AS WE SHOWED FROM BOTH THE
INTACT
AND FROM THE EXPERIMENTS WHERE WE PUT THE
ASYMMETRIC BLOCK ON, THE RESPONSE IS SOMEPLACE
DIFFERENT FROM WHERE THE SUBSTANCE IS PRODUCED.
SO, WE HAVE A DIFFERENT, A DIFFERENT REGIONS
OF
PRODUCTION AND RESPONSE. THE CHARACTERISTICS
THE MOLECULE WHICH WORK IN LOW CONCENTRATIONS
AND
HAVE A REGION WHICH SYNTHESIZED AND WHICH
DIFFERS
FROM THE REGION WHERE IT ACTUALLY CAUSES
A RESPONSE, BASICALLY DEFINES A HORMONE. AND
SO IN
THE BEGINNING THE TERM HORMONE WAS APPLIED
TO
AUXIN. BUT MOST PLANT BIOLOGISTS NOW PREFER
NOT TO
USE THE WORD HORMONE, BUT INSTEAD CONSIDER
AUXIN
AND OTHER MOLECULES LIKE IT THAT WE WILL TALK
ABOUT, PLANT GROWTH REGULATOR. AUXIN WAS THE
FIRST
DISCOVERED PLANT GROWTH REGULATOR. IT CAUSES
MANY,
MANY DIFFERENT TYPES OF EFFECTS IN PLANTS.
AND
WHAT I WOULD LIKE TO DO NOW IS TO GIVE YOU
A TABLE
WITH SOME OF THE MORE PROMINENT EFFECTS OF
AUXIN ON
GROWTH AND DEVELOPMENT. BUT THESE ARE REALLY
ONLY
THE TIP OF THE ICEBERG. THE FIRST EFFECT IS
KNOWN
AS APICAL DOMINANCE. IF YOU LOOK AT A TREE
WHAT
YOU WILL FIND IS THE BRANCHES NEAREST THE
TIP OF
THE TREE GROW OUT, NEAREST THE TIP OF THE
TREE.
A TYPICAL TREE LIKE SO. BRANCHES NEAR THE
TOP OF
THE TREE DO NOT GROW OUT. WHEREAS, BRANCHES
TOWARD
THE BOTTOM DO GROW OUT. BRANCHES AT THE TOP
ARE
INHIBITED.
THIS INHIBITION COMES ABOUT AND YOUR
BOOK DISCUSSES THIS IN MORE DETAIL, COMES
ABOUT
BECAUSE THE APEX MAKES AUXIN. AND THIS INHIBITS
AXILLARY BUDS FROM GROWING OUT.
AND HERE WE HAVE SOME EXAMPLES OF APICAL
DOMINANCE. THIS IS AM IMPATIENCE PLANT GROWING
HERE
ON THE CAMPUS. IN THIS PARTICULAR PLANT, THE
APEX,
WHICH IS UP HIGHER AT THE TIP, HAS STRONG
APICAL
DOMINANCE. AUXIN IS BEING PRODUCED AND IT
IS MOVING
DOWN THE STEM AND IT IS INHIBITING APICAL
DOMINANCE.
IF WE TAKE OFF THIS TIP, THAT IS, WE REMOVE
THE SUPPLY
OF AUXIN OR AS HAPPENS IN NATURE, BY ACCIDENTS
SOMETIMES THE TIP BREAKS OFF, YOU CAN CAUSE
THE
AXILLARY BUDS TO BECOME ACTIVE. AND THEY GROW
OUT.
EACH OF THESE AXILLARY BUDS THEN HAS ITS OWN
APEX.
BEGINS TO MAKE ITS OWN AUXIN AND WILL INHIBIT
THE
AXILLARY BUDS FROM GROWING OUT. APICAL DOMINANCE
IS
ONE OF THE PRIME CHARACTERISTICS OF AUXIN.
A SECOND
CHARACTERISTIC OF AUXIN IS THAT IT ACTIVATES
AND
CONTROLS DIFFERENTIATION OF THE VASCULAR CAMBIUM.
WE HAVE SEEN THIS WHEN WE LOOKED AT THE VASCULAR
CAMBIUM, ALTHOUGH WE DIDN'T EXPLAIN WHAT THE
BASIS OF
IT WAS. A THIRD ASPECT OF AUXIN, WHICH IS
A MAJOR ONE
THAT WE WON'T TALK A LOT TODAY BUT WE WILL
TALK ABOUT
MORE IN ANOTHER LECTURE, IS THAT AUXIN EFFECTS
FRUIT
DEVELOPMENT.
A FOURTH MAJOR CATEGORY OF AUXIN EFFECTS
INCLUDE THE FACT THAT AUXIN STIMULATES THE
PERICYCLE
TO MAKE LATERAL ROOTS. TO MAKE LATERAL ROOTS.
SO, FOR THOSE OF YOU WHO ARE GARDENERS AND
YOU
HAVE A CUTTING WHERE YOU TAKE A SHOOT OFF
OF A PLANT
THAT YOU WOULD LIKE TO PROPAGATE, LIKE WE
TAKE THIS
SHOOT OFF AND WE WOULD LIKE TO GET THIS TO
FORM ROOTS.
YOU CAN BUY COMMERCIALLY AVAILABLE SYNTHETIC
AUXINS.
THIS IS CALLED RUT ONE. IN WHICH YOU DIP
THE PLANT
INTO THE POWDER AND THIS STIMULATES THE PRODUCTION
OF
A PERICYCLE WITH LATERAL ROOT FORMATION. EVENTUALLY
YOU MIGHT GET NEW ROOTS FORMING BUT THEY WOULD
TAKE A
LONGER TIME. SO, AUXIN STIMULATES ROOT FORMULATION.
A 5TH MAJOR CATEGORY OF AUXIN EFFECTS IS THAT
AUXIN
AFFECTS THE DROPPING OR AS WE SAY IN BIOLOGY,
THE
ABSCISSION OF LEAVES. A DROPPING OR THE ABSCISSION
OF
LEAVES. AND MOST OF YOU HAVE NOTICED THAT
IN FALL OR
WINTER THE TREES THAT ARE TYPICALLY GOING
TO LOSE
THEIR LEAVES HAVE BEGUN TO SHED THEIR LEAVES.
HOW IS
IT THAT THE TREE KNOWS THAT WINTER IS COMING
ALONG AND
IT IS TIME TO SHED THE LEAF? WELL, IT COULD
MEASURE
THE TEMPERATURE OUTSIDE AND SAY, IT IS GETTING
COLDER
SO I SHOULD DROP THE LEAF. BUT, YOU KNOW SOMETIMES
THE TEMPERATURE IS NOT COLD. SOMETIMES IT
IS A WARM
FALL OR A WARM WINTER. SO WHAT THE TREE DOES
IN FACT,
IT MEASURES THE AMOUNT OF LIGHT. AND WHEN
THE LIGHT
GETS TO A CERTAIN LEVEL, THAT CHANGE IS
THE SAME EVERY
YEAR, WHAT THAT DOES IS TRIGGER A DROP IN
AUXIN
PRODUCTION IN THE LEAVES. LESS LIGHT YIELDS
A DROP IN
AUXIN OR IAA PRODUCTION IN THE LEAF. AND THIS
IS
A SIGNAL FOR THE LEAVES TO BEGIN TO TRANSPORT
THE
MATERIALS IN THE FORM OF FOODS TO THE REST
OF THE
PLANT AND A SIGNAL FOR THE LEAF TO BEGIN TO
ABSCISE.
THE FINAL OF THE MANY CHARACTERISTICS THAT
AUXIN IS
INVOLVED WITH THAT I WANT TO GIVE YOU HAS
TO DO WITH
THE ORIENTATION OF PLANTS. IF I TAKE THIS
PLANT HERE
AND I LAY IT ON ITS SIDE YOU KNOW FROM YOUR
EXPERIENCE
THAT EVENTUALLY THE SHOOT IS GOING TO START
GROWING UP
AND IS GOING TO REORIENTATE ITS DIRECTION
WITH REGARD
TO GRAVITY. HOW IS AUXIN INVOLVED IN THIS
REORIENTATION OF THE SHOOT WITH REGARD TO
GRAVITY?
WHAT I WOULD LIKE TO DO THEN IS TO TAKE THIS
STEM,
WHICH IS UPRIGHT NOW, AND NOW ROTATE IT 90
DEGREES.
ROTATE THIS STEM 90 DEGREES WHICH IS WHAT
WE HAVE DONE
HERE. AND LOOK TO SEE WHAT IS HAPPENING.
AND, IN
THIS PARTICULAR SITUATION WHEN WE TURN THE
STEM 90
DEGREES, WHAT WE FIND HAPPENING IS THAT AUXIN
MOVES TO
THE LOWER SURFACE.
MOVES TO THE LOWER SURFACE AND
THERE IT STIMULATES GROWTH.
SO, WITH TIME WE GET THIS
SHOOT TO GROW UP, THE SHOOT TO GROW UP. YOU
HAVE MORE
GROWTH HERE, MORE GROWTH ON THE LOWER SURFACE
THAN THE
UPPER SURFACE AND THAT IS DUE TO THE HIGHER
CONCENTRATION OF AUXIN. HOW ABOUT A ROOT?
WHAT
HAPPENS IN THE ROOT IF WE REORIENT THE ROOT
TO THE
HORIZONTAL? IF WE TAKE A ROOT NOW AND WE TAKE
THIS
ROOT AND WE ORIENTATE THE HORIZONTAL, THE
SAME THING
IS GOING TO HAPPEN. AUXIN IS GOING TO MOVE
TO THE
LOWER SURFACE OF THE ROOT. BUT THE ROOT DOESN'T
GROW
UP. THE ROOT GROWS DOWN. SO, WE WAIT FOR SOME
TIME.
WE FIND THAT THE ROOT GROWS DOWN EVEN THOUGH
THERE IS
MORE AUXIN HERE.
THE BACKSIDE HAS MORE GROWTH. IN
THIS PARTICULAR CASE, IN THE ROOT, HIGH AUXIN
INHIBITS
GROWTH. HIGH AUXIN INHIBITS GROWTH.
SO, THIS BRINGS
UP A QUESTION, I HAVE GIVEN YOU ONLY 5 OR
6 DIFFERENT
THINGS THAT ARE REGULATED BY AUXIN, BUT WE
KNOW THAT
THERE ARE HUNDREDS, PROBABLY THOUSANDS OF
THINGS
REGULATED BY AUXIN IN THE PLANT. HOW IS THE
PLANT
ABLE TO DECIDE WHICH PROCESSES IT WANTS TO
GO AND
WHICH PROCESSES SHOULD NOT BE GOING AT THE
TIME?
THIS PICTURE OVER HERE WILL ILLUSTRATE FOR
YOU ONE OF
THE WAYS IN WHICH THE PLANT DECIDED WHICH
PROCESSES IT
IS GOING TO DO. AND SO I WOULD LIKE TO ILLUSTRATE
THAT FOR YOU IN THIS GRAPH OVER HERE. ON THIS
AXIS WE
WILL PUT ELONGATION. ELONGATION. AND ON THE
X AXIS,
WE ARE GOING TO PUT AUXIN CONCENTRATION, WHICH
IS
INCREASING IN THIS DIRECTION. HERE WILL BE
STIMULATION OF ELONGATION. AND HERE WILL BE
INHIBITION. AND HERE WILL BE NO AFFECT. NOW,
LET'S
PUT A ROOT ON THIS CURVE, WHICH HAS DIFFERENT
AUXIN
CONCENTRATIONS. TO PUT THE ROOT ON, WHAT WE
FIND IS
THAT INITIALLY THERE IS NO AFFECT AT THE
VERY LOW
LEVELS OF AUXIN. AND THEN AS WE BEGIN TO INCREASE
THE
LEVELS OF AUXIN, WE BEGIN TO STIMULATE ELONGATION
IN
THE ROOT AND AS THE CONCENTRATIONS BEGIN TO
BECOME
HIGHER WE BEGIN TO RETURN TO THE NO AFFECT
LINE AND WE
AGAIN TO INHIBIT ELONGATION IN THE ROOT. SO
THIS IS
THE ROOT. HOW ABOUT THE SHOOT NOW. IF WE LOOK
TO SEE
HOW THE SHOOT IS AFFECTED BY INCREASING
CONCENTRATIONS, WHAT WE FIND WITH THE SHOOT
IS AGAIN,
LOW CONCENTRATIONS GIVE NO AFFECT AND NOW
THE
INTERESTING THING IS THAT YOU DON'T BEGIN
TO SEE THE
EFFECT OF THE AUXIN UNTIL YOU GET TO MUCH
HIGHER
CONCENTRATIONS. TO MUCH HIGHER CONCENTRATION.
WHAT
THIS ILLUSTRATES TO YOU IS THAT ONE OF THE
WAYS AUXIN
CAN HAVE SO MANY DIFFERENT AFFECTS IN A PLANT
IS THAT
BY CHANGING ITS CONCENTRATION IT CAN HAVE
A DRAMATIC
AFFECT. FOR EXAMPLE, AT THIS CONCENTRATION
OF AUXIN
HERE, WHATEVER IT HAPPENS TO BE, X, WE CAN
STIMULATE
ROOT ELONGATION. BUT, SHOOTS ARE TOTALLY
BLIND TO
THAT CONCENTRATION. THEY ARE IN NO WAY AFFECTED.
SO
BY CHANGING CONCENTRATIONS OF THIS AUXIN,
YOU CAN
CONTROL DIFFERENT AFFECTS. THIS IS THE BASIS
FOR THE
PRODUCTION OF HERBICIDES. THERE ARE HERBICIDES
WHICH
ARE MADE, FOR EXAMPLE, IF YOU HAVE A LAWN
OF GRASS,
AND YOU WANT TO GET RID OF THE DANDELIONS,
WHICH ARE
EUDICOTS GROWING IN YOUR LAWN OF MONOCOTS,
YOU CAN
SPRAY YOUR LAWN WITH A CONCENTRATION OF AN
HERBICIDE
WHICH IS AN AUXIN ANALOG, LOOKS LIKE AUXIN.
AND THE
DANDELIONS WILL BE KILLED BUT THE GRASS WILL
NOT. AND
YOU CAN SUBSTANCE ON THIS CURVE HERE DANDELION
AND
GRASS. THAT IS, YOU CAN CHOOSE A CONCENTRATION
OF
AUXIN TO WHICH WOULD BE POISONOUS TO THE DANDELION,
BUT HAVE MINIMUM EFFECT ON THE GRASS. SO,
THIS IS THE
BASIS FOR HERBICIDES THAT HAVE SELECTIVITY
AND AUXINS
AND AUXIN ANALOGS ARE ONE OF THE MAIN TYPES
OF
HERBICIDES THAT ARE USED. OKAY, LET ME SHOW
YOU
A COUPLE OF SLIDES NOW OF SOME OF THESE.
IF I CAN
FIND MY POINTER WHICH I PROBABLY CAN'T. WELL,
NO
POINTER, WE ARE OUT OF LUCK. OKAY. THIS FIRST
ONE IS
A SLIDE OF DARWIN'S HOME, HIS ROOM, WHICH
I HAVE BEEN
TOLD IS EXACTLY THIS WAY IN ENGLAND. IF YOU
GO THERE
NOW THIS IS THE WAY YOU WILL FIND IT. I GOT
IT. HE
DID HIS EXPERIMENTS PRESUMABLY IN THIS ROOM
AND HE
COVERED THE BLINDS, PULLED THE CURTAINS. THIS
IS THE
BOOK THAT HE PUBLISHED WITH FRANCIS. THIS
IS A U.C.
BOOK. AND AS I SAID THERE ARE MANY, SEVERAL
COPIES IN
OUR LIBRARY AND IT IS CERTAINLY WORTHWHILE
HAVING
A LOOK AT IT. THESE ARE THE KINDS OF EXPERIMENTS
DARWIN DID. HE TOOK A CANDLE AND HE COVERED
VARIOUS
PORTIONS OF THE COLEOPTILE. HERE HE PUT A
BLACK PAPER
OVER IT. OR HERE HE PUT A SHEET, WHICH INTERCEPTED
THE LIGHT THAT CAME BELOW THIS LEVEL. WAS
ABLE TO
SHOW THAT IT IS THE TIP OF THE COLEOPTILE
WHICH IS
RESPONDING TO THE LIGHT AND THAT WAS THE PORTION
THAT
HE LOOKED AT. LATER ON THEN, INDIVIDUAL'S
TOOK
COLEOPTILE TIPS OFF, PUT THEM IN AGAR AND
THIS IS TO
SHOW YOU THE EXPERIMENT. MANY AGAR BLOCKS
WERE
COLLECTED AND THEN THEY WERE SUBSTITUTED FOR
THE
REGULAR COLEOPTILE TIP AND AN ANGLE WAS MEASURED
AND
THAT ANGLE TOLD YOU SOMETHING ABOUT THE CONCENTRATION
OF THE HORMONE. THESE ARE THE WAY THE EXPERIMENTS
ARE
RUN. THESE ARE COLEOPTILES. THE AGAR IS PUT
ON THE
BACK, NOT EXACTLY ON THE TOP. THEY USED TO
DO ARMIES
OF THESE COLEOPTILES WHERE YOU WOULD BE ABLE
TO DO
THESE EXPERIMENTS. HERE WE HAVE AN EXAMPLE,
AGAIN, OF
STRONG APICAL DOMINANCE IN WHICH THE PALM
TREE HAS
ONLY ONE MAJOR APEX GROWING OUT. NO AXILLARY
BUDS ARE
GROWING OUT. AS CONTRASTED WITH THIS PLANT
OVER HERE,
WHICH IS IN AFRICA, IN WHICH YOU CAN'T REALLY
PROBABLY
FIND WHAT USED TO BE THE MAIN APEX. THIS HAS
WEAK
APICAL DOMINANCE. HERE IS AN EXAMPLE NOW OF
A
CAMELLIA WHICH HAS BEEN DIPPED IN SYNTHETIC
AUXIN
WHERE WE STIMULATE ROOTS COMPARED TO A CONTROL,
WHICH
WAS NOT PUT INTO THIS SOLUTION. SHOOT SYSTEM
TURNED
ON ITS SIDE RESULTS IN HIGHER AUXIN CONCENTRATION
ON
THE LOWER SURFACE WHERE WE GET MORE GROWTH
AND THE
SHOOT COMES UPRIGHT. AS CONTRASTED WITH A
ROOT SYSTEM
IN WHICH, IF YOU TAKE THE ROOT, PUT IT HORIZONTALLY,
THE ROOT BENDS DOWN. AGAIN, BECAUSE OF MORE
AUXIN ON
THE LOWER SURFACE. BUT BECAUSE THE LOWER SURFACE
IS INHIBITED RELATIVE TO THE UPPER SURFACE.
THIS
PICTURE TAKEN OUTSIDE BEFORE THE STAIRWAY
WENT IN IN
THE SOUTH, SHOWS A TREE ALONG CAMPANILE WAY
WHICH WAS
NEXT TO A LIGHT. AND WHAT I WANT TO SHOW YOU
IS, AS
FAR AS THIS TREE WAS CONCERNED THE WINTER
AND FALL
REALLY HASN'T COME BECAUSE THE PERIOD OF LIGHT
REMAINED CONSTANT. AND SO, THE LEAVES STAYED
ON THIS
SIDE OF THE TREE. AUXIN CONCENTRATION CONTINUED
WHERE
AS, THE SIDE OF THE TREE AWAY FROM THE LIGHT
EXPERIENCED LESS LIGHT AND AS FAR AS THAT
TREE WAS
CONCERNED, THE AUXIN WAS NOT, WASN'T THERE
ANY MORE.
OKAY. SO THOSE ARE THE AUXINS, THE FIRST GROUP
HISTORICALLY OF PLANT GROWTH REGULATORS. NOW,
WHILE
THE WORK WAS GOING ON WITH AUXINS, THE JAPANESE
BEGAN
TO STUDY A DISEASE WHICH WAS CAUSING RICE
PLANTS TO
BECOME VERY, VERY TALL AND SPINDLY. THE DISEASE
CAUSED BY A FUNGUS AND WHEN THE WIND CAME
ALONG THE
RICE PLANTS WERE BLOWN OVER AND THE HEADS
OF RICE WERE
LOST BECAUSE THEY WERE INTO THE WATER. THE
JAPANESE
FROM THIS WORK DISCOVERED THAT THE FINANCING
US WAS
ABLE TO CAUSE THIS ELONGATION, THIS GROWTH
OF THE RICE
STEMS BECAUSE THE FUNGUS PRODUCED A SUBSTANCE
WHICH
THEY LATER IDENTIFIED AS GIBBERELLIC ACID
OR AS IT IS
ABBREVIATED GA. OR GIBBERELLINS AS IT IS SOMETIMES
CALLED. WE NOW KNOW THAT GIBBERELLINS ARE
NATURALLY,
EVEN THOUGH THEY WERE FOUND DUE TO A FUNGUS
THEY WERE
ALSO NATURALLY OCCURRING PLANT GROWTH REGULATORS.
THE
JAPANESE WORK WAS NOT WELL KNOWN IN THE UNITED
STATES
UNTIL THE LATE 40'S, THE EARLY 1950'S PARTLY
BECAUSE
OF LANGUAGE DIFFICULTIES, PARTLY BECAUSE OF
THE HIS OF
WORLD WAR II. BUT ONCE THESE OBSERVATIONS
WERE MADE
KNOWN TO BOTH EUROPEANS AND THE AMERICANS,
A LOT OF
WORK THEN WENT IN TO CHARACTERIZING THE GIBBERELLINS
OR GIBBERELLIC ACID. AND THERE ARE PROBABLY
OVER 100
DIFFERENT TYPES OF GIBBERELLINS. AGAIN, A
LOW
MOLECULAR WEIGHT SUBSTANCE WHICH WORKS IN
CONCENTRATION AND HAS PROFOUND EFFECTS ON
PLANT
DEVELOPMENT. THE FIRST EFFECT THAT I WANT
TO GIVE YOU
WITH REGARD TO GIBBERELLINS IS THAT IT STIMULATES,
WHICH IS THE BASIS OF ITS DISCOVERY, SELF-ELONGATION.
SO THESE ARE CHARACTERISTICS. THESE ARE GIBBERELLIN
CHARACTERISTICS. STIMULATES CELL ELONGATION.
AND,
LET ME SHOW YOU SOME EXAMPLES OF HOW WE COMMERCIALLY
USE GIBBERELLINS. THESE ARE GRAPES. MOST OF
YOU BUY GRAPES IN THE STORE AND NEXT TIME
YOU BUY A GRAPE LOOK AT THE GRAPE CAREFULLY
AND LOOK
TO SEE WHETHER THE GRAPE IS ROUND OR WHETHER
IT IS
ELONGATED AS THESE ARE. IF THE GRAPE IS ELONGATED,
CHANCES ARE THAT THE FARMER OR THE PERSON
WHO WAS
GROWING THESE GRAPES SPRAYED HIS CROP OR HER
CROP WITH
GIBBERELLINS. IN DOING SO, THE CELLS OF THE
GRAPE
ELONGATED, MORE WATER WAS TAKEN INTO THE GRAPE.
THE
NUTRITIONAL CONTENT OF THE GRAPE HASN'T INCREASED.
YOU PAY MORE FOR IT THOUGH, BECAUSE YOU ARE
PAYING FOR
MORE WATER. GIBBERELLINS CAN BE USED. THEY
ARE NOT
CONSIDERED TO BE CHEMICALS BECAUSE THEY ARE
NATURALLY
OCCURRING PLANT GROWTH SUBSTANCES TO WHICH
WE HAVE
BEEN EXPOSED THROUGHOUT OUR ENTIRE EVOLUTION.
A LESS,
ONE THAT MIGHT NOT BOTHER YOU SO MUCH IS FOUND
IN
CAMELLIA FLOWERS. FOR THOSE OF YOU WHO HAVE
FRIENDS
WHO GROW CAMELLIA'S, WHEN CAMELLIA SHOWS ARE
HELD, AND
THEY ARE NOW BEING HELD THIS TIME OF YEAR
IN NORTHERN
CALIFORNIA, PEOPLE LIKE GIANT FLOWERS. AND
ONE OF THE
WAYS THEY DO IT IS BY SPRAYING THE FLOWERS
WITH
GIBBERELLINS, CALLED GIBBING. AND IT MAKES
THE CELLS
IN THE FLOWER ELONGATE TO GIVE THESE GIANT
ENLARGED
CELLS. SO, THESE ARE SOME EFFECTS THAT YOU
WOULD FIND
FROM GIBBERELLINS. NOW WHAT I WOULD LIKE TO
DO IS
TALK TO YOU ABOUT A FEW OTHER EFFECTS. THE
SECOND
EFFECT IS THAT GIBBERELLINS CONTROL FLOWERING.
AND WE
ARE GOING TO SPEND SOME TIME TALKING ABOUT
HOW THEY
CONTROL FLOWERING AT THE LECTURE WHICH IS
THE SECOND
ONE TO THE LAST. THE THIRD ASPECT, WHICH I
WANTED TO
MENTION TO YOU, WHICH IS REALLY PROBABLY THE
MOST
FASCINATING, BUT CERTAINLY THE LEAST UNDERSTOOD
IS
THAT GIBBERELLINS CONTROL THE PHASE OF LIFE
OF PLANTS.
NOW WHAT DO I MEAN, PHASE OF LIFE THE PLANTS?
I HAVE
A COUPLE EXAMPLES HERE THAT ALL OF YOU ARE
FAMILIAR
WITH. IF YOU GO OUTSIDE AND YOU LOOK IN THE
EUCALYPTUS GROVE YOU LOOK CAREFULLY YOU WILL
SEE THAT
EUCALYPTUS TREE PRODUCES TWO TYPES OF BRANCHES
AND TWO
TYPES OF LEAVES. ON YOUR LEFT HERE, THIS IS
A TYPE IN
WHICH THERE IS A LEAF. IT IS VERY DIFFERENT
IN SHAPE
FROM THIS TYPE HERE. THESE ARE BOTH ON THE
SAME TREE.
THERE IS NO PETIOLE ON THIS ONE. THE LEAVES
ARE MUCH
WIDER. THESE LEAVES HAVE PETIOLES. THESE LEAVES
ARE
MUCH NARROWER. YOU CAN MAKE ROOTING. YOU CAN
MAKE
CUTTINGS OF THIS PARTICULAR ONE. YOU CAN'T
CUTTINGS OF THIS ONE. THIS ONE OVER HERE WILL
PRODUCE
FLOWERS. THIS ONE WILL NOT PRODUCE FLOWERS.
THESE CHARACTERISTICS OF BEING ABLE TO ROOT
IT
AND NOT PRODUCING FLOWERS MAKES THIS A JUVENILE
PHASE.
SO, GIBBERELLINS ARE INVOLVED WITH THE JUVENILE
OR THE
SO-CALLED ADULT PHASE OF EUCALYPTUS. SO LET'S
PUT
THIS DOWN HERE. THE TWO PHASES ARE JUVENILE,
AND THIS
CAPACITY OR ABILITY TO STIMULATE THE PHASE
OF
DEVELOPMENT HAS BEEN USED EXPERIMENTALLY.
HERE IS
ANOTHER EXAMPLE, AND I HOPE THAT YOU GUYS
WHEN YOU
LOOK AT IVY WILL LOOK AT THESE PARTS. HERE
IS
JUVENILE IVY. JUVENILE IVY GROWS PROCUMBENT
PARALLEL
TO THE SURFACE OF THE GROUND. IF YOU BREAK
OFF
A PIECE, IT WILL ROOT. IF YOU TRY TO GET THIS
TO
FLOWER IT WON'T FLOWER. WHEREAS, ADULT IVY,
HAS
A DIFFERENT LEAF SHAPE. IT GROWS UPRIGHT.
IF YOU
BREAK OFF A PIECE IT WON'T ROOT. BUT IT WILL
FLOWER.
IF YOU TAKE THIS ADULT AND YOU SPRAY IT WITH
GIBBERELLIC ACID YOU CAN CONVERT IT BACK TO
THIS
JUVENILE FORM HERE. ONE SUBSTANCE BEING ABLE
TO DO
THAT. PRETTY REMARKABLE. FINALLY, THE LAST
ASPECT I
WANT TO MENTION TO YOU ABOUT GIBBERELLINS
OF THE MANY
AGAIN THAT THEY CONTROL. IS THAT GIBBERELLINS
ARE
INVOLVED IN BREAKING SEED DORMANCY OR IN GERMINATION.
IN CLIMATES LIKE OURS WHERE WE HAVE A --
OR EVEN IN
CLIMATES THAT ARE MUCH WORSE THAN OURS, WHERE
WE HAVE
AT A PERIOD OF TIME WHERE THE CLIMATE OUTSIDE
IS NOT
GOOD FOR SEEDS TO GROW, THEY BECOME DORMANT
AND THEY
HAVE A DORMANCY IMPOSED UPON THEM SO THEY
DON'T
GERMINATE AND DIE UNDER UNFAVORABLE CONDITIONS.
BUT
THAT DORMANCY HAS TO END NATURALLY. AND
THE ENDING OF
THE NATURAL DORMANCY IS INVOLVED OR CONTROLLED
BY
GIBBERELLINS. AND I WOULD LIKE TO GIVE YOU
THE STEPS
THAT ARE INVOLVED IN THE BREAKING OF DORMANCY
IN
A SEED. SO LET'S MAKE A TYPICAL SEED AND WE
WILL
START OUT WITH A SEED BECAUSE I AM GOING TO
SHOW YOU
SOME PICTURES OF THIS, OF BARLEY. WHICH IS
A MONOCOT.
IT HAS AN EMBRYO. IT HAS GOT THE ENDOSPERM.
AND I AM
GOING TO ADD ONE NEW LAYER ON TO THIS THAT
YOU HAVEN'T
SEEN BEFORE. THAT NEW LAYER IS CALLED, IT
SURROUNDS
THE ENDOSPERM, IT IS CALLED THE ALEURINE LAYER,
THE
ALEURINE LAYER. HOW DOES DORMANCY GET BROKEN?
SO,
THE VERY FIRST THING WHICH HAPPENS IS THAT
THE EMBRYO,
AND WE WILL TALK ABOUT WHAT THIS IS, RECEIVES
A SIGNAL.
ONCE IT RECEIVES THIS SIGNAL, THE EMBRYO
EITHER RELEASES OR RELEASES AND MAKES GA.
THE GA MAY
BE THERE OR MAY HAVE TO BE MADE BEFORE IT
IS RELEASED.
THE GA MOVES TO THE ALEURINE LAYER
WHERE IT STIMULATES
IN THE ALEURINE THE FORMATION OF AN ENZYME.
THAT
ENZYME IS ALPHA AMYLASE.
AND FINALLY THE ALPHA
AMYLASE CONVERTS THIS STARCH TO SUGAR. AND
THEN THE
SEED GERMINATES. COMMERCIALLY, GIBBERELLINS
ARE OF
EXTREME IMPORTANCE WITH REGARD TO THIS PROCESS.
THIS
ALLOWS US TO GERMINATE SEEDS THAT ARE IN DEEP
DORMANCY
ANY TIME WE WANT. BUT, PROBABLY FOR MANY OF
YOU IN
THE AUDIENCE, I WILL SAY MALE AND I KNOW THIS
IS
SEXIST. MANY OF YOU IN THE AUDIENCE, GA'S
HAVE
A SPECIAL FONDNESS BECAUSE GA'S ARE USED TO
TREAT THE
GRAINS OUT OF WHICH BEER IS MADE AND ALE IS
MADE.
GRAIN, WHICH IS TO BE FERMENTED AND TO GIVE
THE BEER
ITS ALCOHOLIC TASTE IS TREATED WITH GA AND
THE GA
CAUSES THE ENDOSPERM TO CONVERT FROM STARCH
TO SUGAR
AND WHEN THIS OCCURS THAT CONVERSION FROM
STARCH TO
SUGAR IS CALLED THE MALT. TO THOSE OF YOU
WHO HAVE
EVER, IN SEEING THAT TERM, THE MALT. ONCE
THE SEEDS
HAVE BEEN TREATED WITH GA, AND THE ENDOSPERM
HAS BEEN
CONVERTED TO SUGAR THEN THE FERMENTATION
PROCESS
BEGINS. LET ME SHOW YOU A FEW SLIDES NOW OF
GA'S.
THIS FIRST SLIDE WILL SHOW YOU A, POINTER
ALWAYS SEEMS
TO DISAPPEAR BUT THAT IS OKAY. THE FIRST SLIDE
WILL
SHOW YOU A CABBAGE PLANT AND IN THIS PARTICULAR
CASE
THE CABBAGE PLANT WAS SPRAYED WITH GA. AND
IN THIS
CASE NOT ONLY DID CELL ELONGATION OCCUR BUT
WE ALSO
CAUSED THE CABBAGE PLANT TO BEGIN TO FLOWER.
THE NEXT
SLIDE SHOWS THE IVY. ON YOUR LEFT IS THE JUVENILE
IVY, WHERE TYPICAL IVY LEAF AND ON THE RIGHT
IS THE
ADULT IVY WHICH WILL PRODUCE FLOWERS. AND
TO SHOW YOU
WHAT THAT LOOKS LIKE, HERE IS AN ADULT IVY
PLANT
GROWING UPRIGHT. NOTICE HOW THE LEAVES ARE
VERY
DIFFERENT FROM THE TYPICAL IVY LEAF. AND YOU
ARE
PRODUCING FLOWERS UP AT THE TOP. IF YOU TAKE
THIS
ADULT IVY PLANT NOW HAVING PRODUCED FLOWERS
AND YOU
NOW SPRAY WITH GA, YOU CAN CAUSE THE PLANT
TO RESUME
THE JUVENILE CHARACTERISTICS OF THE IVY INCLUDING
BECOMING PROCUMBENT AND ALSO BY CHANGING
ITS LEAF
SHAPE. HERE IS SOME GRAPES NOW, JUST TO SHOW
YOU WHAT
HAPPENS. THIS IS AN EXAMPLE OF GRAPES WHICH
HAVE BEEN
TREATED WITH GA. AND IN THIS EXAMPLE YOU CAN
SEE THE
GRAPES ARE VERY ELONGATED. AND THIS ELONGATION
IS DUE
TO CELLS ELONGATING BUT NOT INCREASING ANY
MORE OF THE
VALUE NUTRITIONALLY OF THE GRAPE. SEED GERMINATION,
THIS IS OF A PINE SEEDLING. A LITTLE BIT DIFFERENT
BUT I JUST WANTED TO INDICATE THAT MANY SEEDS
HAVE
DORMANCY. MANY SEEDS PROBABLY INVOLVE A GA
TYPE
MECHANISM. AND THE LAST SLIDE SOME OF YOU
PAY HAVE
ACTUALLY SEEN THIS IF YOU HAVE EVER BEEN TO
A BEER
MAKING INSTITUTE. HERE WE HAVE THE BARLEY
SEEDS WHICH
ARE BEING PLACED INTO A LARGE ROOM. THEY HAVE
ALREADY
BEEN CONVERTED TO THE MALT OR THEY ARE GOING
TO BE
SPRAYED WITH THE GA TO BE CONVERTED TO THE
MALT. AND,
IF YOU LOOK IN THESE ROOMS YOU WILL FIND MANY,
MANY OF
THESE SEEDS THEY ARE BEING TREATED WITH GA
AND THEN IN
THIS SLIDE OVER HERE, THESE ARE THE SEEDS
NOW WHICH
HAVE HAD THE ENDOSPERMS CONVERTED FROM STARCH
TO SUGAR
AND THESE ARE NOW READY TO BE USED IN THE
BREWING OR
THE FERMENTING PORTION OF MAKING BEER.
WE WILL CONTINUE WITH THE GROWTH REGULATORS
ON
FRIDAY.