is an exhibition that shows
absolutely nothing, and we're
going to have a look at
what that looks like.
Both my parents are artists, so
it was kind of natural for
me to be drawing and painting,
and all the
materials were in the house.
So it was very natural for me to
go to art school and start
experimenting there.
I just noticed that when I
started using the computer, I
really liked what
came out of it.
So that's why I continued
in that direction.
I got this tattoo because I was
thinking, what's the most
important thing that happened
in the world?
And I thought, well,
the internet.
The base of my work is
these moving images.
They're sometimes interactive
and sometimes moving.
And the audience right
now, it's about 12
million people a year.
This is my first website.
I made it in the year 2000.
I was very surprised that after
I made that website, I
got a lot of response online.
And then a gallerist in Los
Angeles said, why don't you
come over and show this, and
maybe make a new piece?
And then I made this piece
for that opening.
[FART NOISES]
So this was projected very big
in the street, just a simple
mouse, and then just this
projected in the gallery.
A lot of serious art around
it, and then this one.
There's been a lot of
representations of shit.
But because most artwork's with
sculpture and painting,
you can't really depict farts.
So yeah.
New media.
"The Shift," basically the
exhibition is this.
The room is dark-- there's light
right now, but normally.
And then if you walk, you hear
the sound of a mosquito.
So we just have an intern
in the back
who watches the visitor.
And if the visitor's moving,
presses on the sound, and if
the visitor stops,
then nothing.
The interesting question, when
people ask me what's the idea
behind it, is that you believe
that you make something, but
there's actually more
to it, that the work
is sort of a puzzle.
The work is a puzzle, and then
you have to pass the work and
then get to the meaning, which
I don't believe in.
I think the work is the
meaning and the
meaning is the work.
So there's no bigger-- it's as
big as you want to make it.
And I do analyze my work,
but that's not very
important for you.
And then you can analyze
it your way.
I never liked the idea of
creating a unique object.
And then I make this beautiful
drawing, and I sell the
drawing, and then I can't
see it anymore.
And this just spreads
everywhere.
And because of the domain
name, you have a very
exclusive ownership.
It's a unique piece.
But at the same time, the work
is accessible to everyone.
And when I sell websites, the
collector also has to sign a
contract that the work
has to remain public.
I'm staying here in Amsterdam
this week, because I kind of
don't really have a home.
So this is my home
for this week.
I didn't sleep much last
night, because I
found a dead rat.
I kind of--
so I'm going to try
to find another
place to sleep tonight.
Sometimes that works
out, and you get a
really nice hotel room.
And sometimes you don't.
So that's part of the deal.
But yeah, this is my life.
[LAUGHTER]
I work on the computer,
so I can be anywhere.
Usually, rent is cheaper in a
tropical location, so I like
to go there.
And then I go for a while in
Berlin or other places.
The computer was made to make
your life portable, and I like
to live that way.
So this is my studio, my
exhibition space, my meeting
room, my entertainment room.
Everybody lives in their laptop,
but me, maybe even
more than others.
But yeah, this is it.
Right now, we're at the W139
again, the space that was all
empty for the mosquito.
And now the space is all full,
and this is BYOB Amsterdam.
I always notice that
making group
exhibitions is very difficult.
I also notice that all of my
friends own projectors,
especially in Berlin, because
people have big apartments and
they like to watch movies big.
So I figured, if everybody takes
care of their own gear,
then we can make an exhibition
in no time.
So now in about a year, there's
been 48 editions
around the world, and it's
just been moving rapidly.
For me, BYOB is just
about the internet
jumping out of the machine.
This is what we're looking at
all day, but then here, we can
see it all together
in one room.
With BYOB, I took the
approach, saying
everything is cool.
Let's just make chaos.
And then it has its
own strength.
It's sort of like
a thrift store.
So you have to dig through
all the mess and
find what you like.
Minority Report.
There's a lot of crap,
just like anywhere.
But that's kind of
the fun of it.
If anyone in the world
wants to do a BYOB,
they can just do it.
So that's the idea.