-Every year at this time,
everyone on the eastern
seaboard who knows anything
about snowboarding shows up
for the US Open halfpipe.
We're expecting crowds of up to
10,000 people here today.
This thing goes off, it's the
biggest snowboard competition
in the world.
SHEM ROOSE: The Opens through
the '90s were definitely--
they could get out of control.
JEFF BRUSHIE: People had kegs
going on the side of the pipe,
people lined up, drinking
and screaming.
SHEM ROOSE: I think one of the
top highlights from any of the
Opens was the cage.
Everyone talks about the cage.
JEFF BRUSHIE: Some years, people
would bring fencing and
make their own little beer
cage that only their crew
could be in.
It was crazy.
TRICIA BYRNES: Pat Bridges, Mark
Sullivan, all those guys,
they built this like sketchy
chicken wire cage with like
two by fours that was not
up to code for sure.
And they pretty much just got
wasted all day and cheered on
snowboarding.
It was sick.
PAT BRIDGES: So we get up
at 5:00 in the morning.
We go up to the bottom of the
pipe and we start dragging
these two by fours and all this
chicken wire up there.
Then this guy comes up
on a snowmobile--
and this is where I think it's
all going to come to an end,
and this guy's like, hey,
what are you guys doing?
We're like, oh, we're creating
a private viewing area for
Burton employees.
And the guy's like, oh really?
Can I get you anything?
You guys need some trash
barrels, some
chairs, some tables?
And we're like, we need
all of the above.
TOM MONTEROSSO: And my friends
and I had absolutely no idea
what was going on.
We saw that there was
a bouncer letting
people in and out.
People were partying in it.
And it was just all
out mayhem.
If you walked up the left side
of the pipe during the Open,
during the contest, you were
probably going to drink like
one or two beers every run.
You were going to stop, say
hello to a bunch of locals,
friends, and everybody
was partying.
And if you needed a break from
that, you would walk up the
right side--
which I never did.
It's a serious event, but at the
same time, you're partying
with the crowd and you're
partying with the other
competitors.
And yeah, left wall.
JEFF BRUSHIE: But there would
be dudes hanging out of the
cage going, Brushie!
Get over here!
Trying to drag you in.
Have a drink.
And you're trying
to do your runs.
NEIL KORN: There were so many
people in there that the cage
just broke.
And where people were standing
on the backside
fell off the halfpipe.
PAT BRIDGES: I was thinking
that these 60 people on
chicken wire were going
to fly down and
take down 3,000 people.
Didn't happen, thank God.
Nobody got hurt.
I mean, there were
some incidents.
CRIS DABICA: Pat's one of the
greatest snowboarders in the
world, and Pat did eggplants
and his weird handplant
variations in that
pipe, trashed,
wearing a tiger costume.
And it's hard enough to walk
down the road wearing a tiger
costume drunk.
And he was rolling in
from the deck doing
inverts in that costume.
And that's just mind-boggling.
BARRY DUGAN: Those are the
moments that you can't script.
People going like, we're
going to the Open,
let's fill in the blank.
Let's throw up a cage and get
some costumes and bring in
stacks of beer and
just go for it.
Why not?
TOM MONTEROSSO: And just to see
this whole thing unfold, I
mean, I think it's a really
big part as to why I kept
snowboarding because I just
wanted to constantly feel that
excited about something.
CRIS DABICA: They just went up
and acted like they owned the
place and created this thing.
And nobody asked them
to take it down.
That, I think, was one of the
higher points of participation
from the crowd standpoint.
It was symbolic of the freedom
that you had as a
spectator at the event.
The Open doesn't belong
to the sponsors,
doesn't belong to Stratton.
It belongs to the people that
have come year after year
after year, those 5,000 people
that came between the second
they started doing pipe
and the end of
that next decade basically.
TERJE HAAKONSEN: Yeah.
It was hilarious.
People climbing up in trees,
snowball fights, a lot of
drinking on the side.
A lot of cheering, a lot
of shit-talking.
JEFF BRUSHIE: It was sick.
It was like you wanted to ride
to please the crowd there.
You wanted to be up over the
crowd looking down and people
going yeah.
ANDY COHGLAN: I think that
really ups the level of every
competitor.
And that's kind of the legacy of
the US Open started by Jeff
Brushie back in the day,
I think, in 1990.
He came onto the scene and just
started doing big airs.
DANNY KASS: Brushie was just
throwing out the illest crails
and just like boning it out.
And it was just like that vibe
of this is snowboarding.
There's no rules.
TERJE HAAKONSEN: I rode with
Brushie a lot and also he went
the biggest at the time.
I was really influenced
by Craig so I was
just going to like--
my philosophy, if I can be as
technical as Craig at the time
and go as big as Brush
and Palmer, I
would do pretty good.
ANDY COHGLAN: We didn't
see Terje at
the Open as a superstar.
When he came, he was definitely
one of the up and
coming groms.
But he didn't roll
right in and win.
Took a few years.
-Was there a little bit of
a grudge match going on?
You came in second to Terje
Haakonsen at the World's at
South Lake Tahoe and today,
you squeezed him
by 3/10 of a point.
TODD RICHARDS: The only grudge
match between Haakon is
because the blasted me in the
face with champagne at the
World's, then he ran
away from me and I
couldn't get him back.
No, there's no grudge
match there.
The only thing that--
that kid just pushes me,
pushes me super hard.
His last run was probably one of
the most diverse runs I've
seen him do in a long time,
and it's rad to see that.
TERJE HAAKONSEN: All the guys
I looked up to, they were
really cool to me.
But I know there was a lot of
hate from all other guys and I
could totally feel it.
Jimi Scott was pretty
good example.
He was really trying to psych
out every newb that came out.
Not only me, but
everybody else.
But then you have Palmer and
Brushie kind of like helping
you to gain some psychological
power against him.
Like Palmer always told me when
Jimi drops, you just drop
right after him and go
twice as big as him.
He always used to tell me that
and Jimi would drop in, and
Palmer would drop,
and I would drop.
JAKE BURTON: I think that
probably my best Terje moment
at the Open was when I first saw
this sticker, the bootleg
sticker that said I saw
Terje go fucking
huge at the US Open.
It was great.
Terje really changed
the whole thing.
I think he made it more fun
and more exciting for
spectators and everybody.
ANDY COHGLAN: He came in and
he improved everyone.
And he was one of those riders
that everyone started to copy
because not only could he go
big, but he was also doing
very technical tricks and really
pushed the direction to
where it is today.
DANNY KASS: Because at that
time, he was like this god.
We didn't really know
much about him.
We just knew that one day,
we wanted to be like him.
And we kind of like snuck up
from behind and we just
literally just like
touched him.
And then he'd turn around,
look around.
We'd kind of be like
there, like what?
I don't know.
Give him a weird look.
And then he'd turn
around again.
Then the next person in
the crew would go
up and just be like--
touch.
And then we left, and it was
like, that was US Open 1998.
SKY CHALMERS: There's a few
photos that really jump out to
me when I think of all the
pictures I took at the Open.
One definitely is Terje.
CHRIS COPLEY: We used to do this
autograph session in this
courtyard at the Open.
And I mean, it would
be mayhem.
There'd be 500, 600 people
in this courtyard.
TOM MONTEROSSO: And there's that
big kind of clock tower
hotel where all the riders
would stay and they would
congregate up on
the top floor.
CHRIS COPLEY: And Haakonsen was
on like the fifth story.
And he opens up his window and
he had his board that he just
won the pipe with.
And he's dangling it
out the window.
And he threw the board
Dude, it was like a riot.
SKY CHALMERS: And then
there's a fight.
People were going
after the board.
I'm surprised someone
didn't get killed.
CHRIS COPLEY: Every cop from
down that area was called in
because people were just beating
on each other trying
to grab Haakonsen's board.
And that got ugly, and that's
where, whew, there were
certain things that--
certain rules got
put in place.
BARRY DUGAN: You had this
convergence that was pretty
rowdy snowboard-only,
not-made-for-TV event.
It was for the snowboarding
industry.
And that was pure.
PAT BRIDGES: I mean, it was
easy to see what the
importance of the US Open was
because it was the Olympics
for freestyle snowboarding
before there was an Olympics.
It was the X Games for freestyle
snowboarding before
there was an X Games.
And because it really
was universal.
You would get everybody of
relevance who had a place of
prominence within freestyle
snowboarding was there.
TRICIA BYRNES: At that point,
you're getting to see like a
bigger international field.
It wasn't on television
as much, on the
web, all that stuff.
So people would come out to
see these Finnish or crazy
Japanese riders that
you'd maybe heard
about but never seen.
And so I feel like there's a
lot of firsts at the Open.
-Here he comes in the vert--
huge frontside alley-oop,
putting that down smooth.
Just a nice old frontside
grind there.
KAZUHIRO KOKUBO: I won
two time US Open in
2010 and the 2011.
-[INAUDIBLE] got it going
on right now.
Come on, [INAUDIBLE].
-There's the double cork!
Tighten that one down smooth!
It's-- oh!
KAZUHIRO KOKUBO: After that,
it's so much better with my
snowboarding.
Yeah, everything is so free.
Yeah, it's so much fun.