like the Jews going to the Nazis for free
money to expand Jewish knowledge. Now, you
know what a real, in the old days, liberal
- a liberal can’t go to a clan meeting
and say “you guys are ridiculous” he can
talk to them, but he can’t talk to them,
he’ll talk at them. They won’t hear a
word he says, because they listen as a clans
man with those tools. Is man a reasoning animal?
He can’t be because he couldn’t change
then. If he’s subject to change then he
can’t have a fixed set of values, you know
what that means? These are very tough things,
you have to think about them a lot, toss them
around, meaning, listen to normal people,
see if there’s any signal in what they say.
Except “I like being with you” that means,
they’re not dissatisfied. But you must provide
tools and to tell people that they need tools,
they take as an insult “who the hell are
you to tell me what I need?” You understand?
The ego becomes involved because they think
you’re downing them. You know what that
means? You’re not downing them, you’re
trying to equip them, with better tools. There’s
a glass cleaner that’s available called
‘transparent glass’ are you familiar with
it? You rub it on your windshield and you
can’t see the glass. It deflects light in
such a way that the glass looks like there’s
no glass there. It’s called transparent
fluid, which they use on optics now on cameras.
But it’s temporary, it then fogs up a little.
But anyway, with the advent of science and
technology say assume we don’t kill each
other we live another thousand years, the
average person, it’s not just a laptop but
it’s what it does that’s - you can turn
pages of a book you can move it with your
fingers, it’s doing so many new things which
invite thousands of other new things especially
if people are in the business of making new
things. So the exponential curve will go very
sharp leaving people behind continuously,
that’s why an IQ test has nothing to do
with anything except your responses in relation
to a fixed set of conditions. IQ does not
measure intelligence. You may have neurons,
neurotransmitters more than the other person
has and you might remember more but that doesn’t
make you better. If you’re a specialist
say psychologist and you study human behavior
how can you study human behavior without studying
the monetary system? You know what I mean?
So you tell ‘em to give a little, she’ll
give a little, you know? Shit like that. Gotta
get a drink. If you know psychologists or
a neurologist, you ask ’em what does their
profession do? Well, it tries to adjust people
so they can respond to the culture, that would
be insane. Do you know what I mean? Do you
know what I’m talking about? A psychologist
would have to ask other questions “what
is it I want? What is it that I want? I want
a flexibility in human behavior” but a flexibility
that doesn’t bring any money in might make
the person a hobo. You know what I mean? Normal
people have ideas of well adjusted person,
a well adjusted Indian is a well adjusted
Indian, a well adjusted Mexican is a well
adjusted Mexican, but there’s no such thing
as well adjusted people. Do you know what
that means? So trying to be well adjusted
is updating your tools. Well adjusted to change.
Yeah. If you know what that means. So, the
problems become more difficult with this system
to change people, they don’t even know they
need change. I think when the laptop came
out you had to show people what it does, they
didn’t just sit there and do it. When something
new comes out they show you what it does and
they say “oh these are new tools” so.
Now if a guy lives in the south seas learning
celestial mechanics or high level mathematics,
there’s no use for it out there if he’s
a native. That’s information superfluous
to his needs. You know what that means? If
you teach a native - primitive person, biological
systems, it might be superfluous to his lifestyle
there, you know what that means? Ok. I would
imagine that if there is such a thing as advanced
people out in the universe I don’t believe
they would communicate with us. I don’t
believe they would even try. I don’t believe
they’d have “well let’s give ‘em a
hand” I don’t think they’d think that
way. It’s like you and ants, you know what
I mean? Humans think that they would welcome
a new civilisation. so you don’t think we’d
be of interest. I don’t think so, how could
we be of interest? We can’t say anything
new, especially if they land in the south
specific and they meet the natives and the
natives say “the volcanoes angry” what
can they do with that? They can leave the
area or, I don’t even think they’d know,
they’d know the guy has primitive associations,
and they wouldn’t have to ask him anything
alls they have to do is watch our TV shows,
which they watch for 2 seconds, “what a
bunch of shit” I don’t think they’d
say that but, it’s very hard - people say
to me “will people be happier in the future?”
they’re using today's standards with the
future. It isn’t happiness that people need,
it’s security and evaluation of the real
world, that brings equilibrium, and to the
extent that your notions about the world are
unreal, you will suffer. I would say, I think
you told me that your father used to beat
your mother, that was the best tools he had,
getting mad at him does not give him new tools
and when he doesn’t say “what do you think
I ought to do?” that would be rare, I don’t
think he’d ever say that to you, would he?
“What do you think I ought to do?” He
doesn’t even have that in his head. I gave
him that opportunity one time and he rejected
- I didn’t speak to him in 2 years. Yeah,
but that’s because you believe that people
can think and reason, only if you give them
the tools, that takes time for the tools to
gel too. You just can’t hand people tools
they won’t even know what it is. You know
what a stage is on a microscope? You can move
the film minuet quantities of distance that
you’re looking at the specimen can be turned
to the right, where you have to turn it 50
times to move it 1000th of an inch. So if
you’re looking at bacteria that’s extensional,
so again, all extensional devices change,
that’s why you can never become sane. You
can never become well adjusted, you know what
I mean? If all things keep changing how can
you become sane? And sane means, you’re
sane, that can’t be, because there’s so
much we don’t know, we can become saner,
but never sane. Do you know what that means?
You mean define sane? what’s that? Can you
define sane? can’t hear ya. Define sane.
Sane meaning, the most operant behavior to
fit a given set of circumstances. Now that’s
alls that it means. Now if a person comes
over and says “I broke a leg” say “call
911, go to the nearest hospital, I can’t
deal with that” that would be saner, than
saying “oh my god, how did that happen?”-
“I fell off a 20 foot ladder” you still
have to call 911 cause you can’t deal with
it. Well the person says “don’t you have
any sympathy? What do you mean call 911?”
- “yeah, I’m sorry you broke your leg”
they’d feel better with that, but sane means,
to do what you can to help them out of that
situation. Saner, never sane. Wiser, never
wise. Smarter, never smart. You know what
that means? So, when a person says “well
what’s the answer to all these problems?”
that’s a stupid question, there’s no answer,
there are answers as you go along. “I wonder
what Fresco meant by a sane society?” well,
nobody ever asked me, but that would be a
lecture in itself. “What’s a sane society?”
That society is saner, do you understand what
I’m saying? Now those are the tools I wanted
you to know about, to make sure, so when you’re
look at a neurologist, he’s just measuring
the reaction the brain has when you stick
a needle here, there, he knows what zone of
the brain, he can draw a map of feelings,
depression, he can map out the brain. Then
he can look for toxins in the brain, but he
can’t understand the mind, he can’t understand
that it’s responding organism. When you
use ‘mind’ you think like the associative
system? - Yes, that’s alls you have is the
associative system, you never become sane,
can you understand that? If there’s a society
out there that says “boy they’ve attained
the ultimate” there could be no such thing.
Ultimate means they’re all [UNKNOWN] when
you die it’s ultimate. But we all adjust
constantly? We don’t adjust, we are made
that way by circumstances. We either do or
we blow our top. There are people that insist
that the world that they have in their head
is the real world, they wind up in institutions.
What’s what they have in their head is only
their own little unique differences. So, if
you ask a person, they say “I’m not well
mentally” say “what is it that you want?”
- “well I want a fair relationship with
people” or if you went to live in a seminal
Indian village, if you don’t talk their
language you’ll never get along with them.
So do you wanna become a seminal Indian? Or
do you wanna be you in a seminal village?
You can’t be you in a seminal village, you
have to change the village. You have to go
into the village and say “everything you
guys do are wrong” and show them a new way,
that’s almost impossible, so it’s easier
to kill you, that’s what the Arab Israeli
thing is, it can go no where, it’ll never
workout cause they don’t even know what
the problem is. The problem is everybody wants
a piece of the pie. Now what does that mean?
They want same opportunities other people
have, without discrimination, can’t have
that, cause there are people already in power,
only if they lose that power. As I understand
it, things were so bad in Russia that the
people revolted, and they shot the royal family,
kids an’ all, they didn’t want any carryovers.
So, when Joe Stalin sent people to Siberia
to work, they were disruptive to his culture,
or his concept of culture. Now Joe Stalin
never said “what kind of concepts should
I have had?” he would never talk that way,
he wouldn’t be Joe Stalin if he did. If
you walked over to Hitler and said “suppose
you killed all the Jews, then what?” he
doesn’t think about those things, you know
what I mean? It isn’t the Jews, it’s the
business world that he doesn’t like. I don’t
like Jewish conditioning, but I don’t like
Catholic conditioning, I don’t like Presbyterian
conditioning, I don’t like American conditioning,
so it’s the conditioning that’s a problem.
But you only do what you can do.