We're at Burnside.
Pretty sick session.
Rick McCrank, going off.
And we're going to talk to
Julien, Cardiel, Q, who's a
local here, ask them
some cool stuff.
Anyway, pretty psyched.
It's like a historical meeting
of the minds on skateboards.
MALE SPEAKER: Here he goes.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Nice.
[INAUDIBLE] is
a constant at Burnside.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN): You
should have been here earlier
when we were here.
MALE SPEAKER: Got to say I
scratched it at least.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Weren't you here at five in
the morning?
MIKE CARROLL: I scratched
this earlier.
MALE SPEAKER: Since I missed
the 6:00 AM session.
MALE SPEAKER: You came at
the 6:00 AM session?
MIKE CARROLL: Yeah.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
All gayed up?
What brought that on?
[CHEERING]
PAT QUIRK: Yeah, man!
That's good dude.
Way to rip it man.
Kill it, man.
Wow, I see it can be done now
after seeing that guy do it.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
So how long has
Burnside been goin'?
PAT QUIRK: I think since
1991 or something.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN): It
was originally just a bank?
PAT QUIRK: Yeah, it was
that bank up there.
That thing just didn't have
any tranny at the bottom.
It just kind of went
down to like a--
[FFFT].
There was two little banks they
built side to side on the
big things so you could go
from one to the other.
Kick turn, or some people
would fakey slide.
It actually was very
hard to do.
Really, Burnside brought a lot
of heads together that didn't
get along with each other, and
they eventually had to work
with each other.
Became like a new generation.
Yeah, the park actually helped
unite a lot of people, is what
I'm trying to say.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN): You
remember Julien when he first
started coming out?
PAT QUIRK: I think so, man.
I go hey, where you from, and
he goes, I'm from the coast.
And I always thought
he was from the
Oregon coast, but wherever.
I remember people by their faces
more than their names,
because I know hundreds of
thousands of people.
I can't remember everybody's
name.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
You come up here a lot?
JULIEN STRANGER: Not really.
Not much.
At least a couple
times a summer.
But we used to just stay here.
Live here, kind of.
JOHN CARDIEL: Actually, there
was dirt over there in that
field, and we used to
fucking sleep on
cardboard boxes and shit.
It was so raw, dude.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
No tents or anything?
JOHN CARDIEL: No.
Pre-tent years.
Cardboard box on the ground.
If you had a sleeping
bag, maybe fight
somebody for a car.
Was about the best
you could do.
Was nasty, though.
I came here when the first
bowl was here.
I came up here snowboarding
on Mt.
Hood one time.
It was just one bowl.
And then now it's fucking
just advanced into the
gnarliest shit ever.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN): I
remember in the spitfire
video, it was just that quarter
coming up the bank.
JOHN CARDIEL: Yeah.
They had the love seat.
It was hella love.
But it's always been hella
love up here in fucking
Burnside, man.
PAT QUIRK: Yeah, I
remember Cardiel.
That guy was always coming up
to Portland and do just some
crazy ass shit that
nobody did here.
He actually was a pretty
humble guy, too, and
everybody liked him.
And people look up to that
dude as being one of the
leaders of skateboarding
at that time.
And one of the most
radical people.
If you look at it, it's almost
like a jigsaw puzzle because
it's all these little
sections.
The concrete guys would come by
here with the trucks, and
if they had extra mud they'd
drop it off here.
A lot of it was donations, or
just people that skated
putting their money together,
and we'd get enough money to
build another section.
Really, it's like a
patchwork quilt.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Seems a lot
easier to skate now.
JULIEN STRANGER: Much.
Much smoother.
Yeah.
But then, wheels were bigger,
so, you know.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Wheels were bigger then?
JULIEN STRANGER: Yeah.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN): The
first time I came here it
seemed so rough that I was like,
how do people-- like I
saw some of the videos and I was
like, oh, it's going to be
easy, and then you get to--
you're like [BRRRRRRR].
JULIEN STRANGER: Well, you can
see right there, it has a
whole new floor.
But the original Burnside
was on this.
So, this is what it was
for a long time.
Does look like it's in really
good shape right now, though.
[CHEERING]
PAT QUIRK: Burnside's still got
a good feeling to it, man.
It's been around a while,
and it's got roots.
Everybody tries to get along
with other people.
If you can't get along,
go somewhere else.
It's got established ways that
people do business here.
There's things you do, and
there's things you don't do.
MALE SPEAKER: Pretty nice.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Hey, Rick.
PAT QUIRK: People come here to
visit this place, they don't
even skate.
They go, alright, man, we just
heard about it, and they take
pictures of it like
it's an icon.
Well it's been in Tony Hawk's
video, or whatever, and the
Free Willy.
Burnside's been in
a lot of weird--
and I think it attracts
some weird people.
It's like a shrine to
them, or something.
It's kind of funny.
We should sell little
souvenirs.
"I visited Burnside." "I
survived Burnside."
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Alright.
Thanks, dude.
PAT QUIRK: Alright, man.
That's pretty cool, dude.
Yeah, I like talking
about Burnside.
It's better than talking
about yourself.