JOANNA: So, I've just got all
the sweets I was never allowed
as a child.
Because when I was younger, my
mom used to lock me in a
pantry with only raisins
and dry Weetabix.
Not letting me have any sweets
made me into a sugar fiend
when I was older.
Oh, god, there was this guy
at my school called Kevin.
I remember one lunch break we
all dared him to snort some
popping candy.
First of all he put it in
his ear, fair enough.
And then we made him snort it.
It was funny for
about a second,
until he was like [UGH]
and it's all popping
up his nose.
What a dickhead.
So, to make use of all my
culinary skills, I'm going to
make the ultimate feast I
never had as a child.
I'm going to have a popping
candy pavlova,
and my fantasy Alcopops.
ANNOUNCER: Popping
candy pavlova.
JOANNA: Popping candy pavlova.
It's a really easy recipe.
It's just whipped egg whites and
sugar to make the meringue
base, then I'm going to sprinkle
it with a buttload of
news agent sweeties.
ANNOUNCER: Meringue mix.
JOANNA: Mm, phlegm.
It feels like I'm cupping
a very delicate
testicle right now.
It'll be like a fucking
huge marshmallow.
Ah!
OK.
So they're nice and fluffy,
so we need to start
dumping in the sugar.
There's loads of it.
You're going to add it
gradually, but it is literally
a bag full of sugar.
ANNOUNCER: Sugar.
JOANNA: I think if I'd been
allowed sweets when I was
little, and just got it out my
system then and there, I'd
probably have a much more
refined palette.
Because everyone else my age
started eating chorizo and
liking olives and Guinness and
all the weird flavors, and I'm
still eating strawberry laces.
The next step is to plop
it onto a baking tray
just like a cow pat.
And you're going to put it
into the oven for an
hour on a low heat.
ANNOUNCER: Squirty cream.
JOANNA: So your pavlova's
cooked.
You've had it out of the oven
for a couple of the hours, so
it's nice and cool.
So it's not going to
melt your cream.
I love spray cream.
It gives me a sugar boner.
Oh, yeah.
Just put loads on.
Don't be a pussy.
Just put popping candy
everywhere.
ANNOUNCER: Decoration.
JOANNA: OK.
Got the cream on.
So now you've got
to decorate it.
I don't mind nice girly
sweets like Flump.
It's Kind of pretty and pink.
But boy sweets are
so much better.
All the characters on boy
sweets look like they're
mescaline or something.
Ah!
It's like a tongue deodorant.
It's not that she's anti-sweets,
my mum, but she
just wanted to keep us calm.
Because my brother was
fucking mental.
He was always running into
ongoing traffic.
And whenever my dad gave
me sweets, I was really
obnoxious, that's when I
discovered swearing as well.
She could have given
us Ritalin.
I would have been much
happier on Ritalin.
Ah!
ANNOUNCER: Alco-float.
JOANNA: So now, for the puberty
portion of my dessert.
When I was a teenager, I
have to say, I was a
bit of a late bloomer.
So when everyone else was
behind the park benches,
getting finger banged, I was
just on my own, downing
schnapps and playing
with my Tamagotchi.
Then just finish off with
the peach schnapps.
ANNOUNCER: Schnapps.
JOANNA: Have a swig of that.
Mm.
Peachy.
Now it's got just enough room
for a dollop of ice cream.
There we go.
Look at that.
The perfect peaches
and cream drink.
So, there's my popping
candy pavlova and my
fancy Alcopop float.
[EXPLOSIONS]
(THEME SONG) This
girl eats food.
This girl eats food.