- This is what we've spent
years working up to.
And everybody-- all the hard
work and dedication that comes
down they only got a couple
races left this season.
If they don't go now, go home.
That's it.
KEVIN SCHWANTZ: It's about
consistency and what we saw,
as Gustl talked about
everybody's results.
That one really fast lap and
then landing in the gravel
isn't going to get you the
result, it's not going to get
you the practice that
you need to turn--
to learn a technical racetrack
like this.
Great racetrack, lots
of fun to go around.
Once you find your way around,
I think everybody
will really have fun.
BENNY SOLIS: Second to last
turn, I was looking--
I was walking it, it looks
like everyone comes
in on the left side.
KEVIN SCHWANTZ: Ideally, you
want to get in, get back, and
really concentrate on getting
through that right and driving
[INAUDIBLE].
PETER CLIFFORD: Daijiro is one
of these kids, when we saw him
first in 2007, you just look at
him and you go, wow, that
kid looks so beautiful
on the motorcycle,
he's an absolute natural.
And since then it just hasn't
clicked for him.
He's always there, he's always
quick, but he hasn't--
he hasn't won another race since
[INAUDIBLE] last year.
STURLA FAGERHAUG: It sucks if
you got a bad rear position,
like I did in Sacksbury.
I was stuck in about tenth in
the first corner and had to
pass everyone.
And then trying to catch
the leader, I crashed.
And the times I started in
first this year, I won.
It helps a lot if you
qualify good.
[MOTORCYCLES REVVING]
KEVIN SCHWANTZ: It seems like
all the kids are putting that
added pressure on themselves
right now.
And I think we're seeing the
effect on some of the kids.
Nice.
- You've been having shit for
lap times on this track.
You gotta go.
And then when you win it, shit,
your times started going
boom, boom, boom.
There's only a couple guys going
quicker than you, you
just took your turn
to get there.
HAYDEN GILLIM: I didn't
want to crash.
- That's OK, I'm
all about that.
HAYDEN GILLIM: Because they said
if you crashed and your
bike was messed up you wouldn't
race [INAUDIBLE].
- Well, that's cool.
That's fine.
But you still gotta get out
there and get some laps for
tryout time you know?
That's the key.
- Most of the people that are
helping him understand that,
hey, you just gotta get through
this year, you've got
to take advantage of this,
you've got to go do the best
that you can.
Don't let yourself get down.
I believe 100% of my being, I
know Hayden has all the tools
that he needs to be a world
champion, to be a multiple
world champion.
- You better break it in when
you got new brake pads.
BENNY SOLIS: Yeah.
They told us four laps.
- And hold the brake, you
know, how I showed you.
I want to see him
in the front.
I'm really tired of seeing
him in the back.
He'll be in the front,
where he belongs.
Not twenty, fifteen, no way.
Not five.
[MOTORCYCLE ENGINES]
COMMENTATOR: Kent gets a good
start, all the men on the
front row get a good start.
Kornfeil is there,
as is Hiura.
There's the red helmet of number
33, Sturla Fagerhaug,
the Norwegian.
He's the cup leader by 25 points
from Jakub Kornfeil.
Marino leads, from Kornfeil,
from Kent, from Gagne.
And there's Fagerhaug--
absolute disaster, and
he walks away in
total dejection there.
Well, that 25 point lead
has just evaporated.
Oh, it's a collision
there, as Hiura
and Marino come together.
That was sort of going to
happen sooner or later.
- We got one out.
I think it's Solis.
COMMENTATOR: Poor old Benny.
He really has--
things have not worked.
And he just lost the front there
on the brakes at the end
of the straight.
- Last lap.
Here we go this is it.
COMMENTATOR: Gagne comes around
the outside, but Hiura
gets the drive.
It's Hiura with the
drive up the hill.
Beautiful run up the hill,
and there's the
leader Jakub Kornfeil.
Out onto the start and finish
straight he can just cruise
across the line now.
Perfect ride for Jakub Kornfeil,
the second perfect
ride in two weeks.
KEVIN SCHWANTZ: Jakub got a good
start, got out front, got
away from all the chaos that
was going on behind him.
He managed to pick up 25
points, which makes the
championship between him and
Sturla Fagerhaug absolutely
even going to the last
two rounds in Brno.
JAKUB KORNFEIL: My bike was 100%
and it was-- everything
was very, very, very good.
COMMENTATOR: And perhaps you
don't know that Sturla
Fagerhaug, in fact, crashed
out of the race.
So you've now tied on
points with him.
JAKUB KORNFEIL: It's
very good.
I have the same points,
I think, now.
[CZECH NATIONAL ANTHEM
PLAYING]
- A lot of emotions involved
at this point.
The highs and lows of racing
have become evident.
A lot of these kids have a lot
of pressure on them, and right
now Sturla is folding
under the pressure.
This is two races in a
row he's crashed out.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
STURLA FAGERHAUG: After I lost
two bad races, I've just been
home chilling with friends
and stuff.
And getting ready for
the next race.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
STURLA FAGERHAUG: For training
I do running and stuff, but
mental I'm just being myself.
It's not like I have
to prepare my
mind, really, for anything.
I've just been handling
it pretty well anyway.
Down here is mainly
where I hang out.
My TV and my Xbox down here.
This is where I hang out.
My friends come over here and
just chill, listen to music,
watch movies, play Xbox.
This says Norwegian Motorsport
Athlete in 2008.
I got 20,000 Norwegian, which
is about almost $4,000.
Just won that last year,
it was a nice prize.
GURO FAGERHAUG: We always have
been into motorbikes.
Sturla would come with
us to the races.
So since he was a baby,
he liked it.
We didn't say anything
to him like, you have
to start with this.
On the contrary, I would say.
We told him it's
very expensive.
So we'd rather not.
Certainly, if you want to
do this, you have to
get your own bike.
STURLA FAGERHAUG: They had me
collecting empty bottles,
which you get money
for in Norway.
So I collected about 10,000 of
those and bought my first 50cc
motocross bike.
GURO FAGERHAUG: He was
like a grandpa.
GURO FAGERHAUG: I feel
that I am there as a
mother, nothing more.
A person that could support him
if it's needed, or just
hang around.
I like so much to go to the
races, not only to watch him.
But also to watch some other
other GP classes, and just to
be there on the track.
STURLA FAGERHAUG: I don't know
really why my parents always
want to come to all the races.
Say you have a normal job and
then your parents is going to
come there and watch
it every day.
You understand it's
kind of weird.
I've seen some moms freak out
when their kids are riding,
and I just think, if that was
my mom, I'd punch her in the
face, you know?
GURO FAGERHAUG: If Sturla
crashes, or gets fifth, sixth,
I know that he would
be disappointed.
But I'm not disappointed.
After all, this is a race.
And they're so lucky
to be there.
They are so good at what
they're doing, and
they come so far.
STURLA FAGERHAUG: Now I'm tied
for first with Jakub Kornfeil.
I'm going to Czech Republic.
It's his home track, so
it's going to be hard.
But, still think I've got
a pretty good shot.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[MOTORCYCLE ENGINES]
KEVIN SCHWANTZ: Sturla's had a
great season up to the last
couple rounds.
And he's made a few critical
mistakes, and given a large
chunk of points away.
Coming into the last round,
know that they
Jakub Kornfeil has--
this is home track--
he's got that home
field advantage here.
And with that Sturla, I'm sure
is, of the two of them,
feeling more tension
than the other.
- Perfect, thanks.
GUSTL AUINGER: Everyone can get
passed during the race,
for many do a little mistake.
Accept this mistake.
OK, it was a little mistake,
I don't do this anymore.
Next lap I do it better.
I carry on.
I am part of the Rookie Cup.
I am part of the team, and
I am strong enough
to be in this team.
It's the last weekend
for this season.
Don't think about results
in the past,
think about the moment.
And take care of you
all, and I wish to
see 27 smiling faces.
KEVIN SCHWANTZ: Going into the
file round here in Bruno, the
excitement and the tension in
the tent is pretty amazing.
There's certain sides, like some
of the guys are going to
try and work together
off the front.
And this track's big enough,
and wide enough, and fast
enough that I think we're going
to see a pretty good
group at the front.