George Parr, you are an investment banker. I am, yeah
As such you have your fingers right
on the pulse of the financial market
yes, very much so, yes
and during this summer there has been a great deal of turbulence
and volatility
yes, volatility, volatility, tremendous, tremendous
what's caused that?
well, you have to remember two things about the market
one  is that they are made of very sharp and sophisticated people
These are the greatest brains
and the second thing you have to remember is that the financial markets
to use the common phrase
are driven by sentiment
What does that mean?
What does that mean?, well, things, let's say are just going along as normally in the market
and then, suddenly, out of the blue,
one of these very sharp and sophisticated people
my God, something awful is going to happen
we have lost everything
oh, my god, what are we going to do? what are we going to do?
shall I jump out of the window?
we've got to jump out of the window
oh, sell, sell, sell, sell
precisely
and then, a few days later, the same sophisticated person says:
you know, I feel things are going rather well
I agree with you
we are rich, we are rich, buy, buy, buy
buy, buy, buy
and that's what we call market of sentiment
surely we are exaggerating just a bit
well, I don't know
In August, middle August this year, when the market actually plunged in London
a well known city firm, State global market, issued an statement
in which, I quote, "the market participants don't know wether to buy on the rumour and sell on the news
do the opposite, do both
or do neither depending on which way the wind is blowing" unquote
yes, and this is the kind of rigourous analysis
we'll pay huge salaries for
yes, exactly
a few days later, when the market had gone up a little bit
the Senior Equity Adviser in MBA Amron Morgan said, and I quote,
We are back to happy days, again
well, no price is too high for that kind of mature wisdom
certainly
This sort of people are paid  millions of pounds in bonus
yes, of course
During this summer there had been actual causes behind the volatility of the markets
yeah
Specifically,and specially in America
granting vast numbers of mortgages
to people who can't afford them
in properties which are diminishing in value
it's the so called subprime situation,
the subprime market, yes
How did that work?
Imagine, if you can, let's say
an unemployed black man sitting on the crumbling porch
somewhere in Alabama, in his string-vest
and a chap comes along and he says:
would you like to buy this house before it falls down
and why don't you let me lend you the money?
and is this chap, who says this, is he a banker?
oh no, no, no. he is a mortgage salesman
his entire income depends entirely on
the number of mortgages that he can arrange
so, his judgement to arrange mortgages is completely objective
completely objective, yes
and what happens next?
well, then this debt, this mortgage, is taken, bought by a bank,
and packaged together, almost fit
with a lot of other similar debts
without going into much details about what is actually...?
without going into any details
that's not rewarding
so this is put into a package of debts
and then it is moved into Wall street and,  this, this, this's extrordinary what happens
somehow, this package of dodgy debts
stops being a package of dodgy debts
and starts being what we call an Structured Investment Vehicle
an SIV?
an SIV, exactly, yeah
I see, and then someone like you comes along and
and buys it
yes, I would ring up someone in Tokyo and would say
look I've got this package, do you want to buy it?
and they say, what is in it?
and I say, I haven't got the faintest idea
and they say, how much do you want for it?
I say 100 million dollars
and they say, fine, and that's it
and that's the market
and presumably this package, that kind of thing can happen several times
it could, possibly, yes
and every time it does, of course,
you, or someone like you, would get a fee and a marker
and a profit, yes, you wouldn't expect us to do this for nothing
in view of the fact that in these packages there is a lot of dodgy debts
what is it about them that attracts the, you know, financial risk-takers?
yes, because, these hedge-funds, as they are called, which specialise in these debts
they all have got very good names
you mean they are responsible companies?
no, no,  it has nothing to do with the reputation
they all have got very good names, the names they think up are very good
I'll give you an example, there is a very well-known American Wall street firm, called Bearn Stearns
who had two of these hedge-funds,which specialise in these mortgage debts
and they lost so much money, they lost so much of their value
That Bearn and Stearn announced that they would have to put in 3.2 billion dollars into one of the funds to try to keep it afloat
3.2 billion dollars. 3.2 billion, yes, yes
the investors couldn't get any money out of it they would let the other fund go
but one of these funds was called "High Grade Structures Credit Strategies"
and the other one was called the "High Grade Structured Credit Enhaced Leveraged Fund
well, that sounds very good, that's good, very trustworthy
well, this is the magic of the market
what started off as lending of a few thousand dollars to a unemployed blackman in his string-vest
has become a High Grade Structured Credit Enhaced Leveraged Fund
I like the sound of it
It is good, sounds very trustworthy
I mean, it's got good words in it
it's got the word "high"
"high" is good
"high" is good, better than low anyway
yes, yes
and "Structured" is another good word. Very good
"Enhanced". I love "Enhanced". "Enhanced" is very good
I'd buy anything if it said "Enhanced"
It might have been different if it said the "Unemployed Blackman in the String Vest Fund", but, but
yes, then alarm bells might have sound
But despite these very plausible names, surely the reality is
that the people that lend all this money have been incredible stupid
oh no, oh no, the reality is that what was stupid is that at some point
somebody asked "how much money these houses are all actually worth?"
If nobody had actually bothered to ask that question everything would have gone on as perfectly normal
but unfortunately they did
People are saying that the financial crisis is likely to turn into a financial meltdown, I mean
can it be avoided?
It can be avoided provided that Governments and Central Banks
give us, the financial speculators, back the money that we've lost
isn't that rewarding greed and stupidity?
No, no, it's rewarding what Prime Minister Gordon Brown called the "Ingenuity of the Market"
You see, I don't
We don't want this money to spend on ourselves
we want this money to get into the market so that we can carry on borrowing and lending money
as if nothing had happened, without thinking too much about it
yes, but, if the worst came to the worst
and you didn't get this money, what then?
well, then, there would be another market crash
and I would say to you what people like me always say
that is not us that would suffer
it's your pension fund
Thank you very much, George Parr