TOM CLARE: The English culture,
so many things are
dying out, and we've got
so little to hold onto.
And Morris dancing is one of
those things that goes back
hundreds of years.
I'm undertaking a journey from
Olympia, in Greece, all the
way to the Olympic Games opening
ceremony in London.
I hope that my humble effort
has a little bit of the
Olympic feel to it.
I think I could have
Morris danced the
entire 2000 mile journey.
Perhaps a little bit of support,
and a bit more time
to be able to do
it comfortably.
I really enjoyed dancing
through Greece.
I got a fantastic
reception there.
It was very much like being in
England with lots of people
waving and cheering.
And coming into France,
I've had a really
good reaction, too.
Last night I was underneath a
motorway bridge, hiding from a
thunderstorm, eating cold
beans, questioning is it
really worth it?
But then when I get to cycle
into the city, and dance in
the city, the feel of elevation
I get, and when I
see a smile on someone's face,
it's definitely worth it.
I don't have a woman waiting
for me at home.
I'm not sure that a
woman would let
me go on this adventure.
So I'm staying free and enjoying
it at the moment.
It
KEVIN BLOWE: On the 27th of
April, a dispersal zone was
created for an area
that surrounds
Stratford town center.
If there's more than two
people together at any
particular point, police and
police community support
officers can demand that
people disperse.
What the dispersal zone does
is exactly the same as the
powers of stop and search.
It's about stigmatizing
people.
It's making an assumption that
everybody who is of a certain
age is likely to be causing some
sort of nuisance to the
visitors that are
turning up here.
It's based on a fear
of young people.
It's based on the
assumption that
everybody's up to no good.
There's also a power that if
you're under 16 and you're out
after 9 o'clock at night--
and bear in mind, we're talking
about the summer--
you can be picked up
by the police.
And effectively what it's done
is create a curfew for anybody
under the age of 16 between the
hours of 9 and 6 anywhere
around this site.
MALE SPEAKER: The idea
there is good.
To keep everyone safe.
I could respect that.
But the whole fact that without
any reason, like, if
you look suspicious, we'll have
to remove you from the
whole bother.
That's a bit extreme.
MALE SPEAKER: Olympics is
only happening now.
And we've been hanging around
here full time.
We're happy that tourists are
coming, and they have the
right to be here.
But we also have our rights
to hang with our
friends and have fun.
KEVIN BLOWE: A lot of young
people are not prepared to put
up with just being told what to
do, forcing people into a
situation where they get into
conflict with the police.
A natural consequence of that
is people end up being
criminalized.
People end up in court.
MALE SPEAKER: We should have a
right to be around where we
live and hang around our area.
LEAH BORROMEO: Do Londoners
feel safer when they're
walking through the streets and
they suddenly find armed
police with big guns?
I mean, not in a country that
rather prides itself in having
an unarmed police force.
However, we are already the
most surveyed society.
We've now got drones coming
in over the sky.
You hear the sounds of
military helicopters.
Do we really want to be
living in a kind of
Ridley Scott wet dream?
BRIAN WHELAN: Well, starting
from tomorrow, there's going
to be armed police at my door,
10 soldiers stationed, 24/7,
at the end of the corridor, and
a battery of missiles on
the roof of the water tower
above my apartment.
If you look at the Olympic site,
the first thing you see
is my building and the roof
of that water tower.
Maybe if you see missiles
on the top of that,
maybe you feel safe.
If the [INAUDIBLE] comes out and
says, look, we're putting
missiles on the roof of people's
houses, it makes it
look like they're really
serious about security.
But I think the proper work of
keeping the Olympics safe is
done elsewhere.
Those missiles are
just for show.
LT.
COL.
JAMES PHILLIPS: Behind me, we
have the Rapier Air Defense
missile system.
Four of those will be deployed
on Exercise Olympic Guardian.
There is no specific threat
against the Olympics in terms
of an air threat.
This is purely a contingency.
But obviously we need
to prepare for if
that order does come.
KEVIN BLOWE: Overall security
for the Olympic Park has
increased from round
about 4,000 to
somewhere like 23,000.
Which includes G4S, the police,
the army, in uniform,
and then all the other security
from private sponsors.
500 FBI agents coming over with
the team from the US.
It's complete overkill for
what is a sporting event.
The security is predominantly
about defending the interests
of the money that's gone
into the Olympics.
PROTESTORS: G4S!
You can't hide!
We charge you with aparthied!
G4S!
You can't hide!
We charge you with aparthied!
MICHAEL DEAS: There's lots
of lovely things
said about the Olympics.
But if you're hiring a company
to provide the security that's
involved in supporting Israeli
apartheid, that's involved in
exploiting prisoners in the UK,
it's killed asylum seekers
and immigrants in the UK, then
I think that's really
undermining the message
of the Olympics.
SARA CALLAWAY: In the case of
Jimmy Mubenga, the officers
deporting him pushed his head
down, they kept him in a
position where he asphyxiated.
G4S claimed that they've
done nothing wrong.
But even their own employees
came forward, saying that they
were doing this all the time--
these very violent and
basically murderous
procedures.
STEPHEN BAYLEY: Any sane person
could be against the
idea of the Olympics.
Anything which brings prosperity
and vitality and
activity to London is obviously
a good thing.
However, that said, if you are
a fastidious aesthete--
which is one of several
definitions I apply to
myself-- if you are a fastidious
aesthete, you can
only be appalled at the
brainless detritus which the
Olympics generate.
I was recently described as
a ubiquitous know-it-all.
I'm an author and journalist,
but in the past I was
responsible for making London's
design museum.
I was briefly, hilariously,
and catastrophically the
creative director of the
Millennium Dome.
And that gave me special
insights into politicized
projects, which often
end in disaster.
I'm an expert on those.
And what's deplorable about the
Olympic merchandise, and
the terrible graphics going with
it, it assumes a very low
level of intelligence
amongst the public.
And I think that is
really despicable.
Look upon my works, ye
mighty, and despair.
I think the idea that the
mascot's there to excite
younger children reveals the
deplorable ignorance of how
intelligent and sensitive
young children are.
Young children are
not moronic.
But I think some parts of the
Olympic organizing committee
probably are moronic.
How is the person who consumes
this bit of tat going to be
changed or enhanced by
possession of it?
It's ugly, it's cynical,
and it's stupid.
Several design principles
have been violated here.
This is an ugly travesty.
Mindless, stupid, cynical,
patronizing, exploitative,
manipulative, ugly,
and useless.
We want to revive our industry
and revive the credibility of
our great nation by putting
something like this for sale?
I mean, what purpose is
this meant to serve?
It's not a clever photograph.
And it shows this sort of
laborious conceit of the
London eye as a target.
Given the ever-present threat
of terrorist activity, that
seems to me to be an unfortunate
lapse of taste.
But I think al Qaeda, their
aesthetics are too advanced to
take much interest in
this sort of thing.
The local Olympic organizers
seem to think that the public
has absolutely no appetite for
thoughtful speculation about
what the Olympics might be,
about what competition might
be, about the nature of sport,
the nature of participative
activity, the symbolic
importance of the games in a
modern culture.
Instead, what the public, they
think, needs is distorted,
debased Smurfs which you can
hang on a key rings.
Appalling.
MALE SPEAKER: I would
say I'm a pinhead.
I've been called
a pinhead, yes.
It's more than just
collecting pins.
It breaks down barriers.
It makes it easy for people
to meet each other.
MALE SPEAKER: This is now the
eighth meet that we've had.
For me, the pins are
a tangible memento.
This has really taken
over my life.
MALE SPEAKER: The reason
I love this logo--
one, it's very, very
distinctive.
Two, it's creative.
Absolutely amazing level
of discussion over it.
I think when it first
came out, we all
said ew, what's that?
That's not a great look.
Over time, we've come to
accept it a lot more.
Given what we have the
marketplace, I think our logo
is pretty good.
MALE SPEAKER: It's going to
become the biggest global
brand this year because of the
London 2012 Olympic Games.