No one tells me what I can do.
Especially you.
-I traveled all this way to--
-I can have anything I want...
and I want that diamond...
the greatest diamond in all the universe.
Let me try to explain this
just once more, Your Highness.
If anything happens to that diamond--
I don't want to talk to you anymore.
You are going to destroy everybody
in the whole universe.
-Take him away!
-You will destroy yourself.
You dare attack my power?
You can stop me, but there are others.
If only....
Where is my horse?
At least let me say goodbye to my horse.
No one is going to stop me.
It's spring!
Spring! It's in the air.
Wake up, flowers
I've been up for hours
There's work to do
Birds, start flyin'
No more me-oh-myin'
There's work to do
Everybody's got a part to play
To start each day in a beautiful way
Every mornin' when the night goes away
Every mornin' is a brand-new day
What do you take me for,
the morning bus?
Even little things
Need a helping wing
There's work to do
Sun, start glowin'
Pack away your snow things
There's work to do
Up and at 'em
You can't just hang around when
There's work to do
Everybody's got a part to play
To start each day in a beautiful way
Every mornin' when the night goes away
Good morning, Starlite.
Good morning to you all.
Every mornin' is a brand-new day
That's my job.
Good morning.
Mornin'
Rainbow Brite
Feel the sunlight
There's work to do
Good morning, everyone.
It's spring, Rainbow.
I know, Twink. Thank you.
Twink, the star sprinkles.
Okay, let's get to work.
Everybody's got a part to play
To start each day in a beautiful way
Every mornin' when the night goes away
Every mornin' is a rainbow day
Every mornin' is a brand-new day
And you've got a part to play
Come on, Starlite.
Everyone on Earth is waiting for spring.
We've got work to do.
Oh, boy.
Murky, hurry. It's almost spring.
It's never going to be spring.
One blast from my Super Gloom Boomer...
and Rainbow Brite
will never make anything beautiful again.
Oh, boy. Then do I get to
ride on her horsy?
Murky, that smells terrible.
Now, at last,
I'll be the ruler of Rainbow Land.
No more colors.
Nothing but gloom everywhere.
Get it, banana-brain!
No.
Get after it.
Okay, Murky.
I'm getting it, Murky.
Don't worry, Murky. I'll get it.
Come back here.
No!
Faster, snail-brain.
Lurky!
I wish we didn't have to go through this
every spring.
The Earth needs the winter rain, Twink.
You know that.
Everyone knows that.
But I think they've had enough winter
for this year.
-Winter isn't over yet.
-Stormy, it's time for spring.
I'm having too much fun.
Skydancer.
It's time for spring, Stormy.
Stormy, things have to happen
when it's time.
It's wintertime!
-Come on, Starlite. Let's catch them.
-My pleasure.
You'll never catch us.
There isn't a horse in the universe
who can outrun the magnificent Starlite.
Come on, Skydancer.
If they catch us,
winter's over for another year.
Now it will be winter all year round.
Come on, Skydancer.
-See you in Rainbow Land.
-See you.
No more fun for three whole seasons.
Long winter this year.
Hi, what's up?
Rainbow.
I could never let anything happen...
to the only person on Earth
who can see me.
Boy, it's about time you got here.
Look at all this snow.
Stormy got a little carried away
this year. Twink?
The rainbow didn't do anything.
Maybe the star sprinkles
are tired from the winter.
They never got tired before.
There's something wrong.
If spring doesn't get started soon,
flowers will die.
The birds won't lay their eggs.
And I don't want to think
about the baseball season.
Spring's when life comes back,
when hope starts to grow again.
All sorts of terrible things will happen
if there isn't any spring.
We'd better get back to Rainbow Land
and see what happened.
And fast.
Spring will be here
before you know it, Brian.
-Come on, Starlite.
-To Rainbow Land.
I know where we have to go.
Thank you very much.
Goodbye, Rainbow.
There's no place like home.
Every place will be like home
as soon as I get this machine fixed.
-No.
-Murky, you're dancing.
Help me!
I love dancing.
Goody.
-I'm coming, Murky.
-No!
Get off me.
Murky, look.
It's a shooting star.
Haven't you ever seen
a shooting star before?
Never this close before.
Lurky, come back here.
Stay down. It may explode.
-Go see what it is.
-Okay, Murky. I'll go see what it is.
It's a lot of smoke, Murky.
Come back here, dodo-brain.
A horsy! Take me for a ride.
Get back here.
Goody. Boy, I get to ride a horsy.
You are Rainbow Brite?
Me? No.
You're looking for Rainbow Brite?
Yes.
I'm Rainbow Brite.
Murky, I never knew.
Not now, bozo-brain.
Not Rainbow Brite.
See, Murky? Horsies are smart.
Can I have a ride now?
Not Rainbow Brite.
Just what do you want
with Rainbow Brite?
Deliver message about diamond.
Diamond?
It's right over that hill, my friend,
in Rainbow Land.
Murky, you're helping Rainbow Brite?
I'm helping us, hairball.
You tell her all about the diamond.
Boy, I get to ride now.
Goodbye.
Hurry. We've got to get to Rainbow Land
in time to hear that horse's message.
I'm hurrying, Murky. Boy.
Wait, Lurky. Wait for me.
No.
Am I hurrying enough for you, Murky?
A flying horse?
-Starlite.
-Rainbow's back.
That's not Starlite.
-Who's he?
-Where did he come from?
What does he want?
Danger, rain....
-Rain?
-It's not raining.
-Rainbow Brite.
-Here I am.
Rain.... Danger.
Brite, I am On-X. Push button.
Quick.
This'll let us hear the message, Murky?
If you stop talking long enough
to let me listen.
Danger.
Spectra's in danger.
Emergency.
-What's a Spectra?
-Spectra's the diamond planet.
All the light in the universe
has to pass through it.
Boy, Murky, I bet it's shiny.
Not after I get done with it.
This is my chance
to rid the universe of color forever.
Let's go.
Maybe we should hear
the rest of the message. Maybe....
You come on, bubblehead.
You want them to beat us
to that diamond?
If something's happened
to that diamond....
That explains what's happening on Earth.
The universe.... Danger.
The universe will die unless you hurry.
Orin says only hope is Rainbow Brite.
Orin says? And just who is Orin?
Wise one, ancient one.
The only Orin I ever heard of...
is the one that Sprites
tells stories about at bedtime.
But he's not real.
Yes, he is.
Sent me to find Rainbow Brite.
The universe grows darker.
I will go.
Rainbow.
Twink, you take care of Rainbow Land
while I'm gone.
-Can I help, please?
-Stormy.
I never get a chance to make things
bright and colorful.
-Rainbow.
-Rainbow, we need you here.
-It's spring.
-Don't you understand?
Spring will never come again
if something happens to Spectra.
I've never been there, but it's part of me.
It's part of the colors and the joy we bring.
And if Spectra dies,
happiness everywhere will die.
Without the light of life, we'll all....
All of us will die.
Come on, Starlite.
We haven't got a minute to lose.
-Goodbye, Rainbow.
-Be careful.
And hurry, Rainbow. Please. Hurry.
Hurry up, molasses-brain,
or we'll never catch up to them.
Yeah, I'm coming, Murky.
Done. That diamond's going to be mine.
Brakes, Lurky.
Yeah. Brakes.
Boy, I hope that wasn't the brakes.
-Yes. Those were the brakes.
-You....
Let's see that Rainbow brat
beat me this time.
Next stop, Spectra.
No.
-Murky.
-Up. We want to go up.
The signal isn't going through.
-There's some kind of interference.
-We have to keep trying.
-Starlite, look.
-What a magnificent sight.
It really does shine
with all the light in the universe.
But something's covering it up.
Look. Not all the light's getting through.
If we don't get it uncovered,
everything on Earth will die.
You missed a spot.
You'll scratch it.
You have no idea how hard a job this is.
Where is Orin?
Never heard of him. My name--
I'm Bombo. Polisher first-class. This is....
-Oh, no.
-Must find Orin.
No time to talk. Work to do.
Stop.
We worked all day on that spot.
There's the problem.
Why are they doing that?
I don't know. Not our job.
Just doing our job. Polish, polish, polish.
But they're shutting out the light.
Keep it bright and shiny.
Hypnotized, no response.
And the light of Spectra
is the light of the universe.
With that net all over everything,
the light can't get through.
Princess plans to pull Spectra
with spaceship.
Net is for spaceship to hold on to. Orin.
No Orin.
Krys?
Bombo.
Popo, Bodo, Baglo,
Bonglo, Beezo, his cousin Deezo...
Dazzo, Poonch, my brother, my sister,
my nephew, and his friend.
No Orin.
Krys?
Things on Earth will die
if you cover up the diamond.
Earth? What's Earth?
It's the place I bring color to,
a beautiful place full of life.
But it can't live without Spectra's light.
Who hypnotized them all?
-Not me.
-Not our job.
We have to stop them before it's too late.
-Can't talk about it.
-I'm tired of talking myself.
We can do it.
Glitterbots.
Starlite. No.
Hide. Hurry.
Glitterbot.
No Orin, find Krys.
-Krys?
-Who's Krys?
Friend.
Wait a minute.
Open.
At last.
He's not here.
-But the Glitterbots are.
-No.
Emergency.
Hurry.
-Starlite, quick.
-I will not wear booties.
Better than falling down.
My poor dignity.
-Find Orin now?
-Yes.
Boy, Murky, that's a big diamond.
What are we going to do with it?
We're going to crash into it, amoeba-brain.
Hang on.
No. The gloom pipe.
Stop. You're scratching it.
Now, how do we get the diamond
onto the spaceship?
Look what you did, you....
I'll polish it later.
Murky, the Super Gloom Boomer's
all ready.
Not yet, chicken-breath.
First, we're gonna find
that Rainbow Brite...
and use it on her, whoever she is.
Danger.
Seems like the perfect moment
for a swim. Hang on.
I can't get anywhere in this water.
Try.
I'm a magnificent swimmer.
We have to do something
or we'll get hypnotized like the Spectrans.
Get in the boat.
It's a chance for you, at least.
-Hurry.
-The boat won't hold me.
I won't leave you.
They're getting closer.
There are no oars.
And no sail.
There's no way to make the boat go.
I hope he knows where he's going.
Wherever we're going,
it seems like we're going faster.
No!
Emergency.
The rainbow can't get through this mist.
-He saved us.
-Now let's see if he knows how to land.
Well, we got away from the Glitterbots.
But now we've got to get back
and do something about that net.
You think dropping a boat on me
is gonna stop me...
you'd better think again.
Maybe I'm the last one, but I'll fight.
Krys.
On-X. Where's Orin?
Prison. Sent me for help.
-Rainbow Brite.
-Hi.
This is what you call help? A girl?
Orin's locked up someplace.
The Glitterbots have everybody on Spectra
hypnotized but me...
and that's only
because I can run faster than anybody.
The Princess is wrapping the planet up
like a birthday present...
and you bring me a girl?
What princess?
The Princess. She wants to own Spectra.
Nobody can own Spectra.
It's the life of the whole universe.
You go and tell the Princess that.
I guess I'll have to.
Sure. All by yourself?
Just tell me where to find her.
You can come with us if you're not afraid.
I'm braver than any girl.
Murky, how are we gonna get
this whole planet in our spaceship--
Why don't you just go out
and tell those robots where we are?
Okay, Murky.
Stop, rutabaga-brain!
Robots, we're over here.
Here they come, Murky.
Murky, look. A pretty rainbow.
There she goes.
There. Get after her.
We've got to stop her before she stops us.
The weather bureau reports
no sign of an end to the dreariness...
that's bringing the whole world to a stop.
The accident rate is up,
the birth rate is down...
and every country in the world
is blaming the whole situation...
on some other country.
Hospitals report their patients
have stopped asking...
when they'll get better.
Things have become so depressing,
in fact....
In fact, why am I even here?
Why should I be the only one
who hasn't given up?
When she gave it to me,
Rainbow said never to use it...
except in a real emergency.
But this sure looks like it.
If we don't get the color back in the world
soon, there won't be a world.
She said all I have to do
was put it in any door...
and it'll take me to Rainbow Land.
Even the magic's given up.
Rainbow, help!
Intruders!
I didn't invite anybody.
Children.
Children never bring good presents.
Never.
Get rid of them.
I don't like the look of this place.
Rainbow, we can't.
Go back if you want to.
I can do anything you can.
Girls.
We're almost there.
Danger.
I've got to help her.
This is fun.
We should have guests more often.
What do you seek here?
-We have to talk to the Princess.
-Please?
No.
Come on!
This way!
I want that belt.
You even need somebody to tell you
which way to run.
Some of us aren't used to running away.
Hurry.
No.
Hang on to me.
It's an elevator.
One of these
has to take us where the Princess is.
Maybe it's a trap.
Come in.
The Princess has been looking forward
to meeting you.
Where's my present?
How can you think of presents
at a time like this?
That belt is fabulous. Take it off.
Come on, give it to me.
There are some things you can't have.
Don't yell.
You're frightening him.
There, now, it's all right.
Everything's all right.
You have to leave Spectra alone.
Nobody says no to me.
I want the belt.
Stay.
No, Krys.
Got you.
It'll look marvelous with my red dress.
I don't ever want to see them again.
"And all we have to do is walk in
and explain it all to the Princess."
How dumb can a girl get?
If you hadn't been in such a hurry
to be a hero...
I'd still have my belt.
It doesn't matter much.
By the time we get out of here,
the whole universe will be this dark.
We'll find a way.
We have to keep believing, Krys.
I know everybody in Rainbow Land
will be ready to help.
I know there won't be any trouble there.
Come on, Skydancer,
we have to work faster.
More. Faster.
They've got the color console working.
Keep trying.
I've got to find a way to get out of here
without the color belt.
We don't need any belt. We need a ladder.
There's a light.
-On-X.
-Greetings, Krys.
You have to get us out of here.
Oh, no.
Somebody will hear him.
He'll never get in.
On-X, keep trying.
On-X, go and get Starlite.
Starlite. Mission accepted.
Tell him the Princess has the color belt.
A lot of good that's gonna do.
That dumb horse can't even fly
without your rainbow.
He can think.
Which is more than your horse can do.
I've got to get into that castle somehow
and get that belt.
And you've got to make sure
they don't see me.
You start flying around out there.
Plan accepted.
-Krys, look.
-What?
He's back.
Who's making all that noise?
Fire.
Go away.
Get off the bed.
You better start listening to me, all of you.
There must be a stairway
here somewhere.
Up.
Why am I the only one who can
ever do anything around this place?
Meet me at the dungeon.
I'm coming down.
If that tin horse doesn't give himself up...
his little friends
get thrown off my balcony.
Another horse?
No horses in my room.
No horse is getting teeth marks
on my belt.
I want my belt back.
Guards, to the dungeon.
Not you. You get that horse.
He's got the color belt.
Try, On-X.
We've got to find a way to get up there
and get it from him.
Danger!
Bring my belt back here this minute!
You'll never get away with this.
You'll never, ever get away with this.
We've got to get that magic jewel.
That's the only way to stop her.
I need more power.
We've got to get back to Rainbow Land
and get more star sprinkle.
And we've got to hurry.
I hope that rainbow's still strong enough
to get us there.
Banish them
where they'll never bother me again.
Danger.
Rainbow! Watch out!
Faster, Starlite!
We've got to get away from it.
Krys, get to Rainbow Land! Get help!
On-X, try.
Starlite, jump!
Oh, no!
Boy, what a ride.
-Where are we?
-Wherever we are, I'm not staying.
Oh, no. Its power's used up.
I haven't lost all my power.
-Throw down that belt.
-No.
-You'll stay up there till you do.
-You can't keep us up here.
Prisoners don't talk back.
Sgt. Zombo reporting to the Princess.
If she ever wants to come down
from there, Your Highness...
she'll give me the belt.
His name's not Starlite.
His name's Crusader.
He's my horse now.
I'll get your horse back.
We'll get him back.
Come on, On-X.
Obstacle.
Obstacle removed.
New ones.
I remember when we tried to get away.
I can't remember that far back.
Help me, hopscotch-brain! Get me down.
We've got to find out
where they put our spaceship.
I'll get you down, Murky.
I'm hurrying, Murky.
No. Put me down.
I don't see
the spaceship anywhere, Murky.
Put me down.
Lurky, there's someone coming.
No.
Where did he go?
Yes, Your Highness?
Yes, Your Highness.
The new prisoners have escaped.
Who said that?
-We'll never get in there.
-lf you're too scared, stay here.
I'm not scared of anything.
Danger.
Passenger too heavy.
Get off my horse.
I'm coming, On-X!
Over....
Overload.
Oh, no!
There.
Star sprinkles.
This way.
No.
Watch out.
Can your rainbow get us up there?
The rainbow can take us anywhere.
Where did you get those star sprinkles?
Magic and I are old friends.
How did you know my name?
I sent my horse to fetch you.
-You're....
-Orin.
I heard the Princess sent you here.
I've been searching all over for....
But there's no time for chitchat now.
Spectra grows darker by the moment.
There is one thing we have to do first.
What could possibly be more important
than saving the universe?
-Your power is his only chance.
-And Starlite's.
I think the time has come
for Krys to have this.
I knew you the two of you
would meet one day.
Its magic has endured
since the most ancient times.
He'll need the power of your rainbow
to make it work.
But with your help, he'll be the warrior
he's always dreamed of being.
If we can get it to him.
I'll get it to him.
Wipe that smile off your....
-Murky, look.
-Stop her.
Rainbow!
Stand still.
Get out of the way.
Get away from there.
Put this on your wrist.
Out of the way.
Attention!
You.
-What does it do?
-I forgot to ask.
Thanks, Rainbow.
How can they build a fort
with only one gate?
Now we'll stop the Princess.
Let's go.
We caught them trying to escape,
Your Highness.
They are not the ones I want.
I want Rainbow Brite.
And her belt.
Not on my throne.
I know they don't have a present for me.
We do have a present for you,
Your Highness.
You didn't have to.
We're going to give you Rainbow Brite.
You're going to do
what all my forces couldn't do?
Your Highness,
we've been fighting that Rainbow brat...
for years and years and years.
We know her weak spots.
Then why haven't you stopped her?
-Answer the question.
-Why?
Because, Your Highness....
Because we were waiting
until she led us...
to where she keeps all her belts.
She has more belts?
Dozens of them, Your Highness.
Go after her. Bring her back here.
Meanwhile, your spaceship
will be bringing you Spectra.
I'll have everything.
I deserve everything.
Murky, how are we gonna
catch Rainbow Brite?
We're not going to catch her,
kangaroo-brain.
We're going after that diamond.
It's not Murky and Lurky
I'm worried about.
It's the Princess' spaceship.
The only way to stop that ship
from reaching Spectra...
is to destroy the source of its power.
The magic jewel?
The source of all her power.
And she will use it all to stop you.
The castle's defenses are strong,
but there is a way in.
A way so perilous that it is left unguarded.
A wheel turns at the foot of the tower.
If you're not afraid....
-I'm not.
-I'm not afraid of anything.
You have the prism now.
-But how does it--
-Work?
Just as you saw.
All you have to do is need it.
It will do its job
as long as your purpose is true...
and the rainbow is near.
And I must do my job.
Spectra must be kept alive
until you've destroyed the stone.
I'm afraid I'll have to borrow my horse.
Old On-X, trusty steed of noble voice.
You can ride with me on Starlite.
Orin.
And remember,
the whole universe depends on you.
Be brave, be bold,
and don't fight with each other.
I don't like the idea
of you going up there without me.
I'll send the rainbow down for you
as soon as it's safe to use it.
No.
Krys, jump.
Come on. Get it loaded.
They're not taking away
any diamonds, are they?
No. Just worthless minerals,
Your Highness.
The engines melt them
and turn them into fuel.
Those spider legs...
will take hold of the net
we've woven around Spectra.
The greatest diamond in the universe
is almost yours.
Mine.
I've always loved the sound of that word.
-You broke it.
-I didn't break it.
-Do you mind?
-I didn't mean it.
-Can you swim?
-Sure.
Good.
Why, at a moment like this...
is the most magnificent horse
in the universe...
standing here doing nothing at all?
I want that ship on its way in one hour.
Less than an hour, Your Highness.
I do want that diamond.
Oh, no!
I don't know why
they don't think keep horses in mind...
when they design a castle. Here goes.
-Spectra.
-Orin.
Come on. He's doing his job. Let's do ours.
Let's get that jewel.
They never even noticed me.
Nobody ever notices me.
Just hurry, my friend.
Talk a little less, work a little more.
I don't know how just the two of us
are going to save the whole universe.
There are three more,
but they should've been back by now.
I can't even see the Earth anymore.
She'll come through. I know she will.
You have to, Rainbow.
Come on.
Lurky, get back there and fix that engine.
Murky, look. Rainbow Land.
Goody, I get to sleep
in my own bed tonight.
That's not Rainbow Land, alfalfa-breath.
That's....
It's....
My belt. You've brought it back.
-To stop you.
-You're too late.
My spaceship is all ready to take off
to bring my diamond home.
We can do it, Krys.
I need your power.
Now I've got you.
You stay right where you are.
Nobody touches that throne but me.
See, Murky? It is Rainbow Land.
Now, Krys.
No!
Stop!
It's all right. I won't let them hurt you.
-We did it.
-We won.
Not so fast.
Now I've got you
right where I want you, Rainbow Brite.
See, Murky?
I told you it was Rainbow Land.
Look.
You thought you stopped me?
You little brats.
No. She's heading for Spectra.
We've got to stop her.
Hi, I'm Bombo. Polisher first-class.
What's all this?
He's not hypnotized anymore.
They all stopped.
-You did it.
-What's that?
You can't stop me now. You can't!
Not now.
We can't be out of fuel now.
There must be something.
It's going to crash.
And this whole planet
will shatter into a billion pieces.
If I can't have that diamond,
no one's going to have it.
I always get my way in the end.
No, not the rainbow.
She did it!
Thanks, Rainbow.
See? Everything's fine.
Welcome to Rainbow Land, Krys.
Winter's a whole lot easier...
but I think next winter,
I'm taking a vacation.
We'll all help fix things up.
We have time now. The universe is safe.
The universe is alive again.
There's color, joy, and hope again.
And we'll keep it that way.
You'll need help, you know.
-You mean it?
-He's your horse now.
We'll all work together.
And keep the universe
bright and beautiful forever.
Maybe Rainbow Land is that way, Murky.
Or this way. Or maybe it's that.
English