-Tom Burt.
Where's Tom?
Is he still here?
He had to catch a flight.
[INAUDIBLE] you out there?
Shawn, you want to--
Yeah, come on up, Shawn.
Shawn, you were out there
taking runs, getting in
people's ways and stuff.
You should have two shirts.
Shawn Farmer-- two shirts
for being out there.
Wasn't in the competition,
but he was in the pipe.
DAVE SEOANE: Farmer definitely
goes through stages where he,
like, takes care of himself.
And he--
this is kind of a hard one-- but
today, he's like, I would
totally quit drinking if
I had a reason to.
Like, if I had a girl that I
was totally in love with, I
would probably quit drinking,
but I don't really have a
reason to quit drinking.
That was pretty heavy.
Because when he drinks,
he is not afraid.
And it's actually
kind of scary.
He turns into this caveman.
And you can't, you can't--
you're like, Farm.
And he's like a dog.
And you have to say, Farmer--
you can't talk to him and be
reasonable.
You have to say, Farmer,
sit, now.
And he'll, like, OK.
Definitely got to be careful
about crossing the line.
SHAWN FARMER: These [INAUDIBLE]
wool pants from
the army store.
A pair of Sorels, right?
You know when your feet hurt
too bad from the pair of
Sorels If you could get a pair
[INAUDIBLE] liners, you were
like, Jesus Christ on a fucking
popsicle stick.
Right?
That's why we're here, man,
today, because we were here
back then, man.
-Back then?
SHAUN WHITE: Dude, one of the
first times I met Farmer was
at the "My Way" premiere
video.
It was Arnette's video.
And he showed up with, like,
fur boots and some bondage
weird gear like this, with a
leash on his girlfriend in the
same sort of getup.
And I'm just like
who is this guy?
Like, he's so unreal, and he's
never been afraid to go the
distance for anything.
And he's a great guy.
He's just, like, way into
snowboarding, way into the
back country.
SHAWN FARMER: My house is
super trashed, man.
Because I've just been
on the go lately.
I've got shit everywhere.
Let me scoop some of this up.
I have one plastic cup--
probably because I don't have
any glasses.
I had one glass.
I have one plastic cup.
I've got that going for me.
If someone wants to stay with
me, they can stay with me.
I've told people all winter come
up and stay, and, like,
nobody came and stayed with me,
dude, except for the guys
I work with.
It's like an emergency thing for
the guys that I work with.
Because we plow snow and
sometimes if it snows really
bad, then they don't have
to drive home to Reno.
They can, like, stay up here.
And so I'm just like
a house man--
guy---
house mom, I guess.
I'm not a very good house
mom, but yeah.
But I've been telling my
friends, man, come up.
I have a room.
The beds are all made
and ready for you.
JERRY DUGAN: You know, Sean
Farmer's an interesting
individual on so many levels.
He's super high-functioning
intelligent and a total idiot
at the same time.
I love the guy with
my whole heart.
And he's super creative, super
talented, and is completely
ADD, as I am.
So he's just all
over the board.
SHAWN FARMER: The boot drier.
The boot drier I made.
It goes together like this
so you can, like,
transport it, you know?
You put this blow dryer
on here like this.
It's rad.
Sick, huh?
Then you put your boots in.
You put your boots in there.
You put this in your boots, you
know, and then your gloves
on top of here.
It totally kicks out the heat,
man, like in 10 minutes.
10 minutes, you're good.
-You should patent that.
SHAWN FARMER: It's so bad ass.
It's probably a fire hazard
and everything.
I want to get a timer for it
so you can just set it for,
like, 10 minutes
or 20 minutes.
Because, you know, have you ever
seen those boot dryers
that don't do anything?
Like, what is this?
It blows, like, room temperature
air on there?
And you're like, what
the fuck is that?
What you want is, like, when
you come out-- when you get
your boots out of your car
because you forgot and left
them in and they're
frozen solid?
You put that thing on there.
And I swear to god in 10
minutes, 15 minutes
tops, it's bone dry.
Shit is just steaming hot.
Maybe I should get a
different shirt.
-I just wanted to know how you
got into snowboarding, because
where are you from,
originally?
SHAWN FARMER: Missouri.
-Where at?
SHAWN FARMER: Missoura.
Jefferson City.
Some people say Missoura.
Some people say Missouri,
you know?
No, it's Jefferson
City, Missoura.
I just got on a thing--
you know, whatever.
It's just a stunt.
It's something to do for, like,
first for the actual--
yeah, I got on what we call
the snowboard at the time.
One of my buddies even had
one of those Sims ones.
It's like a plastic tray
kind of thing.
You bolt your skateboard
deck to it.
But I mean, we just did that
because it was wintertime and
you couldn't really
skateboard.
And we thought it was cool.
At one point, I graduated
from high school.
I went to college for one
semester, and I was just like
pretty much not into it.
I mean, I got OK grades, and I
was like, I want to go ski.
The idea was skiing.
It wasn't even snowboarding.
I was like, I was going to
ski out in Colorado.
I was like, I'll take a semester
off, or a year off,
and go mess around out
there and ski.
And then I went out there.
And then I saw a snowboard
video.
I think it was called "One Track
Mind," or something.
It was an old Burton one.
Once I saw that, I was just
like, I skateboard.
I'm getting one of those.
Me and my buddy, Joey
[INAUDIBLE], we went to Wave
Rave in Boulder.
And we had like our whole
paychecks for the week.
And we bought the only two
snowboards they had in that
store, which was two
Burton Elite--
yeah, Performer Elites
with no high backs.
That was '85, '86.
And so by the end of season--
well, no ski
areas allowed it, really.
We had to go to Berthoud Pass
so that we could snowboard.
That was the only place.
Berthoud Pass would allow
snowboarding.
Not Summit County, not
Breckenridge, no nothing,
until like halfway through
the season.
Then they converted it.
Then they had the world
championships in the spring.
They did a complete 180.
So then I started riding
at Breckenridge.
And by the time it was time
for like the world
championships, I was
pretty decent.
Because everyone no one around
there could like--
you couldn't ride unless
you hiked or
went to Berthoud Pass.
So I was in the mix
pretty quick.
My name's Shawn Farmer.
I've been snowboarding about
five or 10 years.
And it's pretty much all I do.
MIKE HATCHETT: Yeah.
Farmer's always been
pretty much Farm.
He's a really amazing guy.
He's got a really unique
personality.
And if he's on your
good side--
I mean if you're on his good
side, it's a good thing.
And we pretty much clicked right
off the bat, my brother
and I and Shawn.
And he's been my friend
ever since.
And some people would say he's
kind of crazy in certain ways,
and on a snowboard,
definitely.
SHAWN FARMER: I was living
in Colorado at the time.
And I was doing a little contest
circuit a little bit.
And I was not really into it,
because we'd go in the
backcountry and kind
of take pictures.
And we always looked cool.
And then I'd go to these events
and they had such a--
the stuff was not that cool.
The half pipes were horrible.
And once and a while, I could
throw a backflip or do
something pretty rad,
but I was never
consistent in a half pipe.
And I just wasn't into
the contest scene.
And then I went to the Mount
Baker Bank Slalom is what it
was in Washington.
I got second place in the event
the first time I ever
went, and then--
behind Craig Kelly.
Anyway, I got from Colorado
to Washington.
And snowed like 5 feet.
I don't know.
It just snows and snows
and snows up there.
And I was riding with
Craig Kelly.
And I was like, is this how it
is all the time up here?
And he's like, yeah,
pretty much.
And I was like, rad.
So next year I moved there.
Baker's got just crazy steeps,
and it dumps there.
MIKE HATCHETT: He was living
in Baker at one point.
And he just was one of the
first guys to really nail
[INAUDIBLE] lines and just
charge the steeps.
And he was super, super
gutsy on a snowboard.
He would just go huge.
PAT BRIDGES: Yeah, Shawn
Farmer came in and--
you got to understand, in,
like, 1990, 1991, while
everybody--
and I mean everybody--
who was making a living off of
snowboarding was competing, a
small group of guys, as opposed
to competing, they cut
down on their contest regimen.
Instead of doing one a month,
they decided to do two a year.
And they started filming.
And they saw that this is a
way to take a sport that's
cold, remote, and bring
it to the masses.
SHAWN FARMER: But to rewind
little bit, Nick Perata, I met
him when I was competing and
touring around Colorado.
At one point a buddy of his--
they were from LA.
One of his buddies
was from LA.
And he was into filming,
16 millimeter.
And they started making
this movie.
And they were just like,
hey, do you want
to be in this movie?
And I'm like, cool, let's
do the movie.
So I mean, it's sort
of a blur.
It was like the Hatchett
brothers, Nick Perata, our
buddy Jeff--
this Jeff dude from--
I can't remember his last
name right now.
Whatever.
We just started making this
movie, man, "Totally Board 1."
MIKE HATCHETT: It was
our first film.
And we really didn't have--
the concept wasn't out there of
shooting dudes' segments on
this certain person.
There was no real set formula.
Those guys were our bros.
And they were available
to shoot.
And we decided to commit
a whole winter to it.
Basically was just Nick, Dave,
and Shawn were the main stars
of that movie.
SHAWN FARMER: I mean I
did some cool stuff.
I jumped the Mount
Baker road gap--
that I'd heard talked
about forever.
But I never saw any
pictures of it.
So I was just like, right
here, right here?
This is it?
OK.
Let's got up there
and do that.
MIKE HATCHETT: He was definitely
one of the
ballsiest snowboarders back in
that day in '88, '89, '90.
We we're driving up
to Baker to shoot.
And we were like, that looks
like a place you
could jump the road.
We just built a kicker and Shawn
jumped it and didn't
really think that much of it.
SHAWN FARMER: I almost got hurt
on that a couple times,
just on the in run, coming in,
like, fell down, like,
directly over the road.
The snow just dumped off, and I
was like, oh my god, but did
it again and pulled
that pretty clean.
MIKE RANQUET: I remember I was
sitting on the road drinking
beers, just going, what
a fucking nut bag.
And he kept coming over.
He was like, hey Ranquet,
I'm going to do it
with my shirt off.
You know, peels his shirt off.
He's just cut.
I'm like, what are you doing?
And he pulled it, just did this
sweet kicked out method
air and landed it.
Didn't even eat shit
like I expected--
wanted him to.
SHAWN FARMER: Jeff Tulloch,
he did it to.
I don't think anyone even
knows that he did it.
But he did it too.
MIKE HATCHETT: Shawn had to duck
under this tree branch
right before the in run,
because it was low.
I'm sure someone hacked it off
with a tree saw by now.
But it was just a small branch
going across the in run.
But of course, back in the day,
we didn't think about
doing stuff like that.
I would never cut a tree
branch down either.
SHAWN FARMER: I think I was
the first one to hit that.
Now guys--
I did a method over it.
Now guys are doing rodeos and
who knows what over it.
Plus, they build a cheese wedge
that's six feet high.
I mean, we built like-- for
us a kicker was like,
OK, we got a kicker.
Stomp on that little bit.
That was it.
And then we got to
go to Alaska.
I don't know.
All this stuff happened in
a short period of time.
I was in Colorado.
I was riding Sims boards.
Then I was in Washington.
Next thing I knew, I
was on G&S boards.
Because what happened was, I
went from Washington to Tahoe
to film some more after we
filmed all spring and winter.
And then we got sent that summer
to Alaska with K2, just
because, hey, you want
to be on K2?
We'll pay you.
And I go, OK.
The K2 thing was probably
my best run.
And then we just started
jumping off
stuff up there in Alaska.
They dropped us off on a glacier
with an airplane.
We're flying in on the airplane
looking up at the mountain.
It's like you're down in
here in the airplane.
Here's this face.
And you're going,
[WHINING SOUND].
You're looking up at this rock
wall, just going, damn.
And then we got dropped off with
a bunch of, like, free
heel ski gear and a bunch of
crampons and backpacks.
I didn't know nothing about any
of that stuff-- a bunch of
dried food and stuff.
Luckily the people that were
with us were organized enough
to get the good stuff.
And the North Face, we had
all the North Face gear--
North Face tents,
North Face bags.
And just started climbing this
mountain, the Moose's Tooth,
which is 9,000.
Doesn't sound like a lot, but up
there, 9,000 is like 9,000,
you know what I mean?
It's like 8,000 feet
above the glaciers.
So you're up there.
We were definitely some of the
first snowboarders to get
recognition for going up there,
and certainly probably
one of only a handful of people
from the lower 48, as
they call it, to go up there
and do that stuff.
My other buddies were from
Alaska, so they were dinking
around and getting
in some hellies.
But we were some of the first
guys, probably out of a
handful of five people--
maybe Zellers and Burt and me
and Nick and Pappas were the
first guys to do it,
really, for sure.
Well it was "Totally Board" and
then Hatchett worked for
Fall Line Films one year.
JERRY DUGAN: Shawn Farmer came
into the scene in "Critical
Condition," which would have
been our third film.
And he had worked with--
it was the original "Totally
Board." And it got a little
bit of play, and then kind of
disappeared off the map.
And that year, Hatchett
came to work for me.
Farmer, who was working with
them, really had no film
company to go to.
So he called me and just was
like pretty much the cockiest
asshole you ever
would have met.
He was just like, dude,
your film needs me.
I'm like, what do you mean
my film need you?
He's like, dude, no one's
doing the kind
of stuff I'm doing.
You need me in your film.
And he just wouldn't
stop calling.
At some point, I'm just
like, dude, come on.
I saw your film.
I saw you do some stuff in it.
Yeah, you're OK.
But you've kind of got
this ape-like style.
And you're kind of Cro-Magnon.
And he just kept calling.
SHAWN FARMER: They
called me, man.
That part is bullshit.
"Farmer called us." They called
me, or they at least,
like, put the word out.
I was just like, OK, these
guys want to do it.
I'm available.
Point the camera at me.
They wanted to put
me on the map.
JERRY DUGAN: Finally
that's where we
came up with the thing.
It was like, fine, dude.
Put up or shut up.
We sent him a bus ticket because
he was stuck in Utah.
He couldn't get out to Tahoe.
He couldn't get himself
here to film.
So I was like fine.
We sent him a bus ticket and
said, put up or shut up.
You're talking all this smack.
Back it up.
SHAWN FARMER: You know, I think
it's basically pretty
close to the truth.
I don't remember
riding the bus.
I think I might have bought
my own plane ticket.
I think they said they'd
buy me a plane ticket.
And I was like, fuck you guys.
I'll just buy my own fucking
plane ticket.
And so I came out.
And then we came out of the
bus station or whatever.
Anyway, there was
some argument.
There was definitely some
argument or issue there.
JERRY DUGAN: And I think he
pretty much lived with me on
off for two or three years
after that point.
Sponsorship and him were a
really tough animal to sort of
cohabitate together.
He was a very outspoken
and not always
controllable commodity.
And he's got a million things
and a million ideas and a
million things he wants to do.
And when he gets something in
his head, he just doesn't
really let it rest until he
gets it out and does it.
And that was kind
of like his rap.
He wanted to be a rap star,
not just a snowboard star.
He wanted to be a
rap star too.
So we gave him a shot at it.
[MUSIC - SHAWN FARMER,
"FARMER'S RAP"]
SHAWN FARMER: I think I just
kept hammering on Jerry and
going, man, I want
to make a video.
I want to make a rap video.
I want to make a song.
I got this song, you know?
He's like, fine, let's do it.
And luckily, he had this
buddy who could loop.
As soon as I heard that people
were looping beats, I was like
man, you take a song that's
already a hit
and sing on it again?
How can you go wrong, unless
you're a total retard?
I was like, here's what
I want to do.
I want to take this
Doors lick.
And don't ask me how they got
away with that or what the
hell they did, if
they settled.
I have no idea.
JERRY DUGAN: My original partner
in my first company
with Artie was this guy
named Kendrick Wells.
And he was an old friend of mine
I grew up with in Marin.
And he had a little recording
studio and
recorded some rappers.
He was one of Tupac's
really good friends.
And he worked with Farmer and
myself to come up with that
first song.
SHAWN FARMER: I was loaded one
day and dropped a 40 in the
studio and broke it all over all
the wires and everything.
That was the kind
of stuff I did.
But we got it done.
And then I think I did
one take, I know
not more than two.
I was just like, man,
I feel it right now.
But if you keep making
me do this over
and over, I'll just--
I think we did one take and a
couple overdubs, and that was
it, and a couple of
punch tracks.
JERRY DUGAN: Those were the old
days before we knew you
could attach cameras.
I think I just pretty much
hung out on the hood.
It was back old school style
before I knew about cool
mounts and fancy rigging
and grips and gaffers.
You can get a lot more done in
life sometimes before you know
how to do it.
You just do it, and
it kind of works.
SHAWN FARMER: So I knew
that would work.
And whether it's a hit
or not, I don't care.
But people like it.
I dig it.
And I thought it came
out pretty good.
They did a good job.
And I think they did pretty
awesome production.
Back then, that year, that
movie was the shit.
It was like, yeah, at the
trade show or whatever.
JERRY DUGAN: There's very few
people I've been as impressed
with as him.
He is one of the ballsiest
technicians I've ever met.
We'll be on the ground.
We'll be back at the
barbie angles.
We used to call it the
barbecue angle.
And he'll look at a line-- he's
like, I'm going to make
two turns, I'm going to pop off
here, jump 20 feet, land
on that patch right there, you
know, 15-foot patch of snow,
get it together and then
pop off that 50-footer.
And I'm like, OK have fun.
I'll be down here.
I've got the angle.
You go.
And he'll go up there and he'll
just fricking do it
every time.
It's just, his awareness of
where he was in spatial
relationship to the mountains,
the snow, and his ability to
get himself to where he said
was hands down better than
almost everyone, except, I'd
say, like, Tom Burt.
DAMIAN SANDERS: Farmer
was bad ass.
He was like a bear.
He was almost like a biker.
He was a big guy.
He had all that crazy hair.
But he was just funny.
He was hilarious back
in the days.
We had so much fun riding
together-- a
hell of a lot of talent.
He could ride steep cliffs
and big jumps
like nobody's business.
He was like a Tom Burt-style
rider.
Those guys were kind of
in the same world.
TOM BURT: Farmer was kind
of a loose cannon rider.
He kind of did a little
bit of everything, but
mostly he free rode.
So he rode kind of
big mountains.
But he also did tricks
and airs and
stupid stunts and things.
But he was actually
real progressive.
He was doing back
flips to fakie.
He was the first person I ever
saw do anything with that.
Pretty early on, the only other
kind of guy landing
fakie was Ranquet
at that time.
But he brought another character
to the sport.
SHAWN FARMER: I still think
the "Critical Condition"
part's probably my best thing.
I had a lot of delusions of
grandeur and stuff, and just
get sidetracked.
I like rapping.
Really, at the time, I was like,
man, all I'm going to do
is I'm going to make
this rhyme.
And I'm just going to walk.
I'm going to step right out of
this whole thing and just
start doing hip hop.
And then, I don't know, man.
I love the mountains.
The city just fucks me up.
And that's where it seems like
all that glamour boy shit goes
on, or even the production
stuff.
If I have to actually drive
around down there and try to
figure this shit out, I'll
literally just turn around and
leave town.
I just freak out.
I freak out in Reno.
[HEAVY RAP MUSIC]
SHAWN FARMER: Jime Hale--
he's a buddy mine.
I met that guy in '85
or '86 or '87 when I
was still in Colorado.
He was always this crazy
heavy metal dude.
The band we were in
was called Soak.
But he just kind of
brought me in.
He was like, we want to put
rap with metal, which was
really a novel idea
at the time.
I still don't think anyone
is doing it right.
I mean, there's a couple guys.
There's Rage Against The
Machine and Anthrax.
We were doing it right at the
same time or maybe even before
some of those guys.
And he's just like, yeah,
you can be the rapper.
And I'm like, OK, but we were
always butting heads.
It's so hard to have
two singers.
Played in that band for quite
a few years off and on.
It's just so sort to balance.
You're trying to be a pro
snowboarder and go whatever,
around the world, and then
come back to this band.
Everybody's pissed at you
because you were gone for
three weeks.
But it was still fun, man.
We rocked.
[HEAVY RAP MUSIC]
SHAWN FARMER: And that whole
game is so crazy, but I still
am into it.
I still like rapping
and stuff.
And I love snowboarding.
I still love snowboarding.
I don't care whether anyone's
around or not.
I just dig it.
The thing that trips me out,
man, is like if things
would've fell together
differently, we'd probably be
sitting in my mansion by
the pool or something.
But it didn't.
And I don't know--
sometimes I feel like you're
just chasing that thing.
And for some people, it all
happens, and when it is
happening, you better get
it, and hang onto it as
tight as you can.
I steered.
I took a couple wrong
turns, I think.
I'd rather fucking pound nails
than deal with some of these
kooks that had nothing to do.
I could go crazy on this.
But I just saw a lot of
this stuff coming.
And I was just like, man, you
just want to be with people
that you trust or that
you believe in.
And I just think a lot of these
people are just like,
yo, what's the next big thing.
It's like, yo, fucking
the slinky, man.
I don't fucking know.
JERRY DUGAN: I think that he
scared a lot of people,
because he was a little
bit of a loose cannon.
He did kind of do
his own thing.
And if you're trying to promote
an image, and you're
trying to promote a wholesome
image, or you're trying to
promote a healthy image, and
all of a sudden, you've got
Farmer drunk, taking his clothes
off, jumping off
something, or getting in a fight
or yelling at someone.
Then that's a tough thing when
you're a company that has to
justify results to a board--
people that don't understand
the nature of the sport.
And I think that's where he
got into some problems.
That said, he had a
good run at it.
He did get paid.
He got paid well for a while.
So for sure, someone believed
in him at some point.
But he had different ideas
on things too.
He didn't want to make the board
that was the all around
everything board.
He wanted to make a big board
that he could fly 100-foot
cliffs off of.
And there's a small amount
of the market
that rides that way.
SHAWN FARMER: I don't know what
the reason was, but man,
boards were always breaking.
Those things broke too, but
they just seemed have more
life than a lot of stuff
that was out there.
I just always thought-- and
I still like big boards.
They're great for
certain things.
It's kind of a lot of work,
is all, to ride one.
JERRY DUGAN: The Farmer--
the 185-centimeter Farmer board
made by Summit was not a
board that everyone
was riding.
That thing was great if you
wanted to drop an 80-fot
cliff, and you had nice fresh
powder on the way in and
powder on the way out, and you
had enough balls and muscle to
turn the thing.
But in his sort of theory,
it's like, no, no,
that's what I want.
He had a pretty good run
with K2 for a while.
K2 had a bunch of boards under
his name that encompassed a
broader riding style.
SHAWN FARMER: I had a pretty
good run at it.
I look back, and I'm just like,
I could've don this,
this, and this different,
and maybe even
still be up in there.
But it's like, what are
you going to do, man?
You're fricking snowboarding.
What do you want?
HANNA TETER: I remember getting
asked to do that
"First Descent" movie with Shawn
Farmer and Terje and
Nick Perata.
I'd never met Nick
or Shawn Farmer.
It was New Year's before we
started filming that movie,
and I met him at a bar.
And I just thought he
was a sketchy dude.
And I was like, I have to go on
a trip with this crazy guy
for three weeks.
And I was all scared, but then
when I actually got out to the
backcountry with them, and they
were just super chill,
and made it, like, the best
experience of my life.
I mean, Shawn is a
crazy, crazy man.
And he can rap like no other.
But he's a hell of
a snowboarder.
SHAUN WHITE: I was impressed.
I mean, I know he felt a little
overwhelmed when we
built this massive jump out
there in the mountains,
because it's not really
his style.
But whatever myself and Travis
were doing on the jump, he was
beating that tenfold on just
getting down these crazy runs
on the mountain there.
I was impressed.
I was just blown away because he
looked at it so differently
from the way I would
look at it.
I'm like, oh, I want
to jump off that.
He's like, no, I'm going to
creep down this ridge, then
I'm going to cut over.
And it was impressive to see
how he looks at it, because
everybody sees something but
it's always different from
what everybody else sees.
SHAWN FARMER: I like big
mountain stuff, man.
I really like slashes.
I like doing airs.
And I'm not super focused
on tricks.
If I do a big grab or a big
method or a big back or
something, and just a really
sweet line, I like to try to
be relatively fluid.
And I like to haul ass.
I like speed a lot, like really
carrying a lot of
speed, and just getting, like,
to that point, where
I'm like, oh my god.
I can't even turn anymore.
I'm just not obsessed with
tricks or anything so much as
I just like being out on
the mountain, man.
I like snowboarding.
I don't have to try to do
a lot of craziness.
I just take whatever's in
front of me, do a couple
things, get out there,
and keep going.
MIKE HATCHETT: Shawn's one of
those guys I wish there was
more people like him today in
snowboarding, more like Farmer.
Not to say there's not great
personalities out there.
But Farmer's just one of those
guys that you just, you meet
him and he sticks in
your head forever.
And he's the kind of guy that
his personality and his
charisma, just everything
about the guy,
you just know him.
And like I said, I wish there
was more people like that in
snowboarding today.
It's almost like the
marketability of someone like
that, just someone with
that amazing of a--
he's an amazing person.
And there's not a lot of
guys like that around.
He's amazing.
SHAWN FARMER: All right.
Ready?
Like that.
-What's this shirt?
SHAWN FARMER: Jefferson City
Correctional Facility.
That's where I'm from.
Jefferson City, Missouri.
It gets the job done.
All right.
That's enough of that.
[HEAVY RAP MUSIC]