THERE'LL BE 50 QUESTIONS FROM ME AND THEN
THE REST FROM THE OTHER
TWO INSTRUCTORS. AND AS FAR AS RUNNING THIS
REVIEW GOES, AND
THERE'S A LOT OF MATERIAL TO REVIEW IN AN
HOUR, BUT I THOUGHT
QUITE A LOT ABOUT THE EXAM. AND I WANTED TO
GO OVER SOME
GENERAL POINTS THAT I THINK YOU SHOULD BE
SURE TO STUDY. I MEAN
PEOPLE HAVE ASKED ME WHAT DEPTH OF STUDY THEY
SHOULD GO INTO.
AND I DEFINITELY WANT TO REITERATE THAT THE
BOOK IS JUST
SUPPLEMENTARY TO THE LECTURE MATERIAL, SO
WHAT'S ON THOSE SLIDES
THAT I MADE PDFS OF AND POSTED IS THE MATERIAL
YOU'RE RESPONSIBLE
FOR. AND THE READING WAS JUST TO AUGMENT THAT
TO TRY TO HELP TO
UNDERSTAND THOSE CONCEPTS RATHER THAN IF THERE
ARE NEW CONCEPTS
AND TERMS THAT COME UP IN THE READING, YOU
DON'T NEED TO, TO BE
ABLE TO RECALL THOSE. SO I KNOW THAT THERE
IS SOME MATERIAL I
DIDN'T GET TO IN THE, IN THE ASSIGNED READING.
AND YOU KNOW
THAT'S REALLY JUST TO PUT THINGS IN CONTEXT
RATHER THAN TO, YOU
KNOW, PROVIDE YOU WITH NEW INFORMATION THAT
YOU, YOU'RE
RESPONSIBLE FOR. ALL RIGHT, SO ONE OF THE,
THE FIRST THINGS I
WANT TO MENTION IS AS FAR AS ALL THE DIFFERENT
GROUPS OF
ORGANISMS WE COVERED, THE MAJOR GROUPS THAT
WE TALKED ABOUT YOU
SHOULD BE FAMILIAR WITH. I MEAN WE TALKED
ABOUT THESE THREE
DOMAINS OF LIFE, THE BACTERIA, THE ARCHAEA,
AND THE EUKARYOTES,
EUKARYA, BUT WE DIDN'T FOCUS ON, ON A LOT
OF THESE GROUPS. YOU
KNOW, WITH THE MAIN ONES WE FOCUSED ON WERE
THE FUNGI AND THE
PHOTOSYNTHETIC GROUPS. AND JUST THESE MAIN
GROUPS ARE THE ONES
THAT, THAT WE TALKED ABOUT IN ADDITION TO,
OF COURSE, LAND
PLANTS. SO THE FUNGI, THE MAJOR GROUPS OF
ALGAE, AND THE, THE
LAND PLANTS. AND WE WENT INTO MORE DETAIL
THAN, THAN JUST THIS,
OF COURSE. WE WENT INTO, FOR EXAMPLE, IN THE
FUNGI, THE MAJOR
PHYLA, THOSE FIVE MAJOR GROUPS, AND, AND THE
ALGAE. WE DIDN'T
TALK IN MUCH DETAIL ABOUT THE MAJOR CLADES
SHOWN HERE AS FAR AS
TAXA WITHIN THOSE. BUT YOU SHOULD BE, YOU
SHOULD BE FAMILIAR
WITH THE CHARACTERISTICS OF THESE GROUPS THAT
I TALKED ABOUT AND
BE ABLE TO YOU KNOW DISTINGUISH A DINOFLAGELLATE
FROM A DIATOM OR
A BROWN ALGAE FROM A RED ALGAE IN TERMS OF
THE SORTS OF THINGS WE
TALKED ABOUT. NOT BEYOND THAT, BUT, BUT THOSE
ARE, THAT'S THE
LEVEL OF DETAIL I'M LOOKING FOR. I WOULDN'T
BE ASKING YOU TO
RECALL A PARTICULAR GENUS OR YOU KNOW FINE
SCALE TAXON OF SOME
KIND WITHIN THOSE GROUPS, BUT THERE WAS QUITE
A LOT OF TIME SPENT
ON THESE DIFFERENT, DIFFERENT GROUPS. AND
WITHIN THE LAND
PLANTS, OF COURSE, WE TALKED ABOUT BRYOPHYTES,
VASCULAR PLANTS,
SEED PLANTS. AND THEN WITHIN THE SEED PLANTS,
GYMNOSPERMS AND
ANGIOSPERMS. SO, AND WITHIN THE ANGIOSPERMS
YOU KNOW WE SPENT
QUITE A BIT OF TIME COMPARING THE EUDICOT'S
AND THE MONOCOT'S
CHARACTERISTICS THERE. SO IT'S THAT LEVEL
THAT, THAT WE COVERED
IN CLASS THAT I WANT YOU TO, TO STUDY. ARE
THERE QUESTIONS
ABOUT THAT? ALL RIGHT, SO AS FAR AS THE LIFE
CYCLES GO, THERE
ARE A LOT OF LIFE CYCLES THAT WERE PRESENTED
IN THE READING THAT
I DIDN'T TALK ABOUT IN LECTURE, FOR EXAMPLE,
BROWN ALGAE AND
DIFFERENT GROUPS. YOU KNOW THAT'S JUST FOR
YOUR INFORMATION
ONLY, NOT FOR, YOU KNOW, THE EXAM. BUT I DID
SHOW THIS SLIDE.
AND I WOULD LIKE YOU TO REMEMBER THE SORT
OF GENERAL POINTS ABOUT
LIFE CYCLES THAT, YOU KNOW THESE ARE, THESE
ARE SEXUAL LIFE
CYCLES WE TALKED ABOUT THAT INVOLVE MEIOSIS
AND FERTILIZATION.
AND IT'S THE RELATIVE TIMING OF THOSE TWO
PROCESSES THAT
DISTINGUISHES THESE MAJOR LIFE CYCLES, LIKE
WHAT OCCURS IN US AND
OTHER ANIMALS COMPARED TO WHAT HAPPENS IN
PLANTS AND IN FUNGI.
SO BE SURE TO BE COMFORTABLE WITH THIS MATERIAL.
YOU KNOW KEEP
IN MIND IT'S, WHETHER MITOSIS IS LIMITED TO
ONE OF THE TWO PLOIDY
STAGES IS CRITICAL TO INTERPRETING THESE LIFE
CYCLES TOO. SO
UNLIKE US, THE PLANTS HAVE MITOSIS GOING ON
IN THIS HAPLOID PHASE
AND IT ENDS UP, THEY END UP WITH A MULTICELLULAR
BODY, YOU KNOW,
A GAMETOPHYTE, A MULTICELLULAR ORGANISM THAT'S
HAPLOID, SO THAT'S
COMPLETELY ALIEN TO US AND OTHER ANIMALS BUT
IT'S COMMON, OF
COURSE, IN THE, ALL THE, COMMON TO ALL THE
LAND PLANTS AND EVEN
SOME OF THE GREEN ALGAE AND OTHER GROUPS WE
DIDN'T REALLY TALK
ABOUT. SO WERE THERE QUESTIONS ABOUT THE GENERAL
LIFE CYCLE
ISSUES HERE? SO THESE WERE THE FIVE MAJOR
GROUPS OF FUNGI WE
TALKED ABOUT. AND YOU KNOW I'M NOT LOOKING
FOR A HUGE AMOUNT OF
DETAIL HERE, JUST WHAT WAS MENTIONED IN THE
CLASS WHICH WAS
FAIRLY LIMITED. AND THE CHYTRIDS ARE THAT
GROUP THAT STILL HAS
SOME FLAGELLATED STAGES THAT CAN SWIM AROUND
AS FAR AS THE SPORES
AND GAMETES GO, WHICH IS UNUSUAL FOR, FOR
THE FUNGI. AND
THEY'RE THE SISTER TO ALL THE OTHER FUNGI.
THEY'RE AN EARLY
DIVERGING BRANCH. AND LIKE THE ZYGOMYCETES,
THE ZYGOMYCOTA,
THEY HAVE COENOCYTIC HYPHAE WHEN THEY HAVE
HYPHAE. REMEMBER
COENOCYTIC MEANING THAT THE NUCLEI AREN'T
SEPARATED BY ANY
PARTITIONS OR PARTIAL PARTITIONS IN THE, IN
THE BODY OF THE, OF
THE FILAMENTS OR THE MYCELIUM IN GENERAL.
SAME GOES WITH THESE
ARBUSCULAR MYCORRHIZAL FUNGI. THEY'RE SO IMPORTANT
WITH REGARD
TO RELATIONSHIPS WITH PLANT ROOTS. AND IT'S
THIS GROUP OF THE,
THAT MAKES UP THE MOST OF THE FUNGI, THE ASCOMYCETES
AND
BASIDIOMYCETES WHERE WE SEE THE SEPTATE HYPHAE
AND WHERE YOU GET
THIS INTERESTING SITUATION WHERE PLASMOGAMY
AND KARYOGAMY, THE
FUSION OF THE CYTOPLASM AND THE FUSION OF
THE NUCLEI IS DELAY-,
ARE WIDELY SEPARATED IN TIME. AND YOU HAVE
THIS DIKARYOTIC
STAGE. REMEMBER WE HAVE TWO NUCLEI PER SEGMENT
OF EACH HYPHA
SEPARATED BY PARTITION, PARTIAL PARTITIONS.
SO THIS IS
SOMETHING WE JUST SAW IN THE FUNGI, RIGHT,
JUST THESE HIGHER
FUNGI WHERE WE HAVE THIS LIFE CYCLE WHICH
IS OTHERWISE VERY
SIMILAR TO, WELL, IT'S, IT HAS ONLY THE, THE
ONLY DIPLOID STAGE
IS THE ZYGOTE. BUT YOU HAVE THIS LONG PERIOD
WHERE YOU HAVE THE
FUSION OF THE CYTOPLASM PRIOR TO THE FUSION
OF THE NUCLEI WHERE
MUCH OF THE PLANT BODY, FOR EXAMPLE OF THE
BASIDIOMYCETES, IS
DIKARYOTIC LIKE YOU CAN SEE HERE WITH TWO
NUCLEI PER PARTITION.
AND THEN THEY PRODUCE THESE FRUITING BODIES
WHERE YOU ACTUALLY
GET THE FUSION OF THE NEW NUCLEI AND MEIOSIS
OCCURRING RIGHT
AFTER THAT TO PRODUCE SEXUAL SPORES. THOUGH
THAT'S, AND THEN
ALSO REMEMBER THAT IN THE FUNGI THERE ARE
THESE, QUITE A WIDE
DIVERSITY OF DIFFERENT GROUPS WHERE THERE'S
NO, NO SEXUAL
REPRODUCTION THAT'S BEEN DOCUMENTED. AND THESE
HAVE BEEN PLACED
IN THIS GROUP DEUTEROMYCOTA, THE SO-CALLED
IMPERFECT FUNGI THAT
DON'T HAVE ANY KNOWN SEXUAL PHASE. AND THESE
ARE IMPORTANT IN
MEDICINE ET CETERA. BUT THEY'RE, THEY'RE AN
ARTIFICIAL GROUP IN
A LOT OF DIFFERENT TYPES OF FUNGI. SO WE DID
TALK ABOUT THIS
GROUP AS WELL. AND I DID MENTION ALSO THE
SLIME MOLDS AND THE
WATER MOLDS WHICH AREN'T TRUE FUNGI BUT HAD
BEEN PREVIOUSLY
TREATED AS FUNGI. SO ANY QUESTIONS ABOUT FUNGI
THAT ANYONE
WANTED TO ASK? ALL RIGHT SO, OH, ONE OTHER
THING ABOUT THE
FUNGI. I'LL GET, MAYBE WE'LL GET TO IT LATER,
BUT THEY HAVE A
LOT OF INTERACTIONS WITH OTHER ORGANISMS,
OF COURSE. AND YOU
KNOW IN ADDITION TO BEING DECOMPOSERS, PARASITES
AND SUCH, THEY
CAN ALSO BE MUTUALISTS. WELL, THEY CAN BE
IN ASSOCIATION,
REGARDLESS OF THEIR MODE OF NUTRITION, THEY
CAN BE IN ASSOCIATION
WITH, WITH DIFFERENT ORGANISMS, LIKE ALGAE,
GREEN ALGAE OR
BLUE-GREEN ALGAE IN THE CASE OF LICHENS, THAT
MUTUALISTIC
ASSOCIATION THAT WE GET, IT'S IMPORTANT IN
PRIMARY PRODUCTIVITY
IN ECOSYSTEMS. AND ALSO THE, THE MYCORRHIZAE.
TALKED QUITE A
LOT ABOUT THAT BOTH IN TERMS OF, IN FUNGAL
LECTURES AND LATER ON
IN TALKING ABOUT ROOTS. REMEMBER THE MYCORRHIZAE
IS AN
ASSOCIATION BETWEEN FUNGI AND PLANT ROOTS
THAT IS IMPORTANT TO
THE SUCCESS OF PLANTS. AND IT LOOKS LIKE THAT
ESTABLISHMENT OF
THAT RELATIONSHIP GOES ALL THE WAY BACK TO
THE EARLY, EARLIEST
LAND PLANTS. AND SO THAT'S QUITE A, IT'S QUITE
SUGGESTIVE THAT
THE FUNGI WERE PRETTY IMPORTANT TO THE SUCCESS
OF LAND PLANTS AND
THEY VERY MUCH ARE IMPORTANT FOR THE, THE
PRODUCTIVITY OF PLANTS
TODAY. I MEAN A LOT OF PLANTS CAN SURVIVE
WITHOUT THE
MYCORRHIZAL ASSOCIATION BUT THEY DON'T DO
NEARLY AS WELL AS THEY
DO WITH IT. SO THAT'S ANOTHER THING TO KEEP
IN MIND AS FAR AS
FUNGI, THAT THEY, THEY HAVE REALLY IMPORTANT
ECOSYSTEM FUNCTIONS.
SO ANY ... ALL RIGHT, SO LET'S, SO THE ALGAE,
WE SPENT QUITE A
BIT OF TIME ON THE ALGAE GROUPS. AND REMEMBER
THE ALGAE ARE NOT
A NATURAL GROUP. THE FUNGI ARE A MONOPHYLETIC
GROUP IF YOU
THROW OUT THE WATER MOLDS, THE YELLOW MYCETES,
AND THE SLIME
MOLDS, AND PRETTY CLOSELY RELATED TO ANIMALS.
BUT HERE THE
CELLULAR SLIME MODELS AND THE PLASMODIAL ONES
ARE CLOSELY
RELATED. BUT REMEMBER THE ALGAE ARE SCATTERED.
THE
PHOTOSYNTHETIC ORGANISMS ARE SCATTERED THROUGHOUT
THE TREE OF
LIFE. THERE AREN'T ANY IN THE ARCHAEA. BUT
WE DO HAVE, YOU KNOW
CYANOBACTERIA REMEMBER WERE FUNDAMENTAL TO
THE EVOLUTION OF
PHOTOSYNTHESIS. THEY'RE THE ONES THAT REALLY
EVOLVED
PHOTOSYNTHESIS. AND IT'S THESE OTHER LINEAGES
THAT JUST
CAPTURED CYANOBACTERIA. AND REMEMBER THERE'S
THIS, PUTATIVELY
AT LEAST, WE CAN ONLY BE SURE OF ONE EVENT
LIKE THAT THAT
HAPPENED WHERE CYANOBACTERIUM WAS CAPTURED
BY AN EARLY EUKARYOTE
THROUGH PHAGOCYTOSIS, YOU KNOW BASICALLY JUST
ENGULFING IT. AND
THEN LATER WE GET THIS SPLIT BETWEEN THE GREEN
ALGAE AND THE RED
ALGAE FOLLOWED BY THE SECONDARY SYMBIOSES
WHERE WE HAVE
UNICELLULAR EUKARYOTES THAT ALREADY POSSESS
A, A CYANOBACTERIUM
OR PLASTID AT THIS POINT IN THEIR EVOLUTION
THAT'S BEEN CAPTURED
AND RECRUITED FOR PHOTOSYNTHESIS IN THIS DIVERSE
SET OF LINEAGES.
SO ARE THERE QUESTIONS ABOUT ENDOSYMBIOSIS?
NO? BE SURE TO
STUDY THIS. I MEAN THIS IS REALLY, I MEAN
PRETTY NOVEL
INFORMATION. I MEAN NOT SO LONG AGO WE FOUND,
YOU KNOW WE'VE
BEEN ABLE TO DETERMINE THAT VARIOUS OF THESE
LINEAGES REPRESENT
CAPTURES OF EUKARYOTES. YEAH?
STUDENT: [INAUDIBLE]
PROFESSOR: SO THE RED ALGAE APPEARED TO, APPEARS
TO HAVE BEEN
THE ONE SECONDARY ENDOSYMBIOSIS THAT GAVE
RISE TO THE, THE
DINOFLAGELLATES WHICH, MANY OF WHICH ARE PHOTOSYNTHETIC.
AND
THEY'RE A BIG COMPONENT OF PHYTOPLANKTON RESPONSIBLE
FOR RED
TIDES. STRAMENOPILES ARE THE OTHER MAJOR GROUP.
THE
APICOMPLEXANS HAVE LOST THEIR ABILITY TO PHOTOSYNTHESIZE.
THEY
JUST HAVE A VESTIGIAL PLASTID, AND I DIDN'T
MENTION THEM MUCH
EXCEPT TO SAY THAT THE MALARIUM, THE MALARIAL
ORGANISM IS IN THIS
CLADE. BUT THE STRAMENOPILES INCLUDE THE BROWN
ALGAE AND THE
DIATOMS AND THE GOLDEN BROWNS. SO, YEAH, THERE
ARE SEVERAL
GROUPS OF PHOTOSYNTHETIC ALGAE WITHIN THAT
GROUP WE CALL
STRAMENOPILES, WHICH ALSO INCLUDE SOME NON-PHOTOSYNTHETIC
GROUPS
THAT PRESUMABLY LOST THEIR ABILITY TO PHOTOSYNTHESIZE,
LIKE THE
OOMYCETES, THOSE WATER MOLDS THAT USED TO
BE THOUGHT TO BE FUNGI.
ALL RIGHT, SO THEN, SO IN ADDITION TO UNDERSTANDING
ENDOSYMBIOSIS
IN TERMS OF THIS, I'D REALLY LIKE YOU TO STUDY,
I PRESENTED
SEVERAL SLIDES ON, ON THE EVIDENCE FOR, FOR
ENDOSYMBIOSIS.
REMEMBER THERE'S A WHOLE SERIES OF, OF DIFFERENT
LINES OF
EVIDENCE THAT SUPPORT THE HYPOTHESIS THAT
I PRESENTED. AND SO
YOU SHOULD FOCUS ON THAT DATA TOO IN TERMS
OF UNDERSTANDING WHAT,
WHAT'S REALLY BEHIND THE HYPOTHESIS IN TERMS
OF, OF EVIDENCE,
OKAY. ALL RIGHT, SO THE ALTERNATION OF GENERATIONS
THEN IS THE
MAIN LIFE CYCLE WE FOCUSED ON AFTER WE GOT
TO LAND PLANTS. ALL
THE LAND PLANTS HAVE THIS. AND AGAIN, WE HAVE
BOTH
MULTICELLULAR DIPLOID ORGANISM AND A MULTICELLULAR
HAPLOID
ORGANISM. HAVING A MULTICELLULAR, HAVING BOTH
HAPLOID AND
DIPLOID MULTICELLULAR ORGANISMS IS DIAGNOSTIC
OF THIS TYPE OF
LIFE CYCLE, THIS ALTERNATION OF GENERATIONS.
REMEMBER AN ANIMAL
LIFE CYCLE, THE ONLY HAPLOID PHASE IS THE
GAMETE. IT'S NOT A
MULTICELLULAR ORGANISM. AND IN THE FUNGI THE
ONLY TRULY DIPLOID
STAGE IS THE ZYGOTE. THAT'S NOT MULTICELLULAR.
WE HAVE MEIOSIS
RIGHT AFTER THAT. SO THIS IS THE, THE MAIN
LIFE CYCLE WE FOCUSED
ON FOR ALL THE LAND PLANTS, ESPECIALLY. AND
I SHOWED YOU THIS
EXAMPLE, IT'S A BIT OF AN ASIDE IN TERMS OF
THE ORGANISM, BUT
JUST TO POINT OUT THAT THERE ARE ORGANISMS
LIKE SEA LETTUCE WHICH
IS A GREEN ALGAE WHERE YOU HAVE VERY SIMILAR
HAPLOID AND DIPLOID
PHASES. AND I MAINLY SHOWED YOU THIS EXAMPLE
JUST TO MAKE IT A
LITTLE EASIER TO UNDERSTAND THIS ALTERNATION
OF GENERATIONS
BECAUSE IN THE LAND PLANTS EITHER ONE PHASE
OR THE OTHER IS SO
HIGHLY REDUCED, THE GAMETOPHYTE OR SPOROPHYTE,
THAT IT'S OFTEN
HARD TO KIND OF PICTURE THOSE AS DISTINCT
ORGANISMS, BUT THEY
ARE. AND SO REMEMBER THE SPOROPHYTE IS THE
SPORE PRODUCING
PLANT. SPORES ARE PRODUCED BY MEIOSIS. WE
GO FROM DIPLOID TO
HAPLOID HERE. BUT UNLIKE IN AN ANIMAL WHERE
AFTER MEIOSIS WE
HAVE GAMETES, HERE WE HAVE SPORES. AND SPORES
UNLIKE GAMETES DO
NOT FUSE WITH ONE ANOTHER. THEY GERMINATE
TO CREATE AND UNDERGO
MITOSES TO PRODUCE A HAPLOID GAMETOPHYTE.
AND SO IN THIS CASE
THEN WE'RE PRODUCING GAMETES BY MITOSIS RATHER
THAN MEIOSIS.
THE MEIOSIS OCCURRED BACK HERE. THAT'S TOTALLY
UNLIKE US IN
THAT SENSE. THOUGH THE GAMETES ARE GENETICALLY
IDENTICAL TO THE
GAMETOPHYTE. AND THEN WE HAVE THE FUSION OF
THE GAMETES AND
THEN THE FORMATION OF THE ZYGOTE AND THE DIPLOID
SPOROPHYTE. SO
THIS IS IMPORTANT TO REMEMBER TOO THAT THE
LAND PLANTS ARE
INTIMATELY RELATED TO THE GREEN ALGAE. SO
THE GREEN, WHAT WE
CAUSED TO CALL GREEN ALGAE AND WHAT WE STILL
DO TODAY LOOSELY IS
A PARAPHYLETIC GROUP. IT'S NOT MONOPHYLETIC.
SOME OF THE GREEN
ALGAE ARE MORE CLOSELY RELATED TO THE LAND
PLANTS THAN THEY ARE
TO OTHER GREEN ALGAE, OKAY. AND REMEMBER THESE
ARE FRESHWATER
GREEN ALGAE. SO THE LAND PLANTS DIDN'T COME
OUT OF THE OCEAN.
THEY DIDN'T DESCEND FROM SOME MARINE FORM
DIRECTLY. THE CONQUEST
OF LAND WAS VIA WATER INTO THE FRESHWATER
AND THEN TO LAND. SO
IT'S A STEP-WISE PROCESS IT APPEARS. ALL RIGHT?
OKAY, AND SO
THEN WE TALKED ABOUT THESE MAJOR SEVEN GROUPS
OF VASCULAR PLANTS.
AND THREE OF THEM ARE CONSIDERED BRYOPHYTES
EVEN THOUGH IT'S NOT
A MONOPHYLETIC GROUP. THEY'RE A GRADE OF LINEAGES,
THE MOSSES,
HORNWORTS, AND LIVERWORTS THAT I MENTIONED
THAT, THAT HAVE A
SUBSET OF THE FEATURES THAT WE, SUBSET OF
ADAPTATIONS TO LAND
THAT WE SEE IN THE VASCULAR PLANTS BUT NOT
ALL OF THEM. SO AND
THE MAIN THINGS THAT WE FOCUSED ON AS FAR
AS --
THOUGH THE
FRESHWATER GREEN ALGAE, REMEMBER THEY, EVEN
THOUGH THE SEA
LETTUCE WHICH IS A MARINE ALGA HAS THAT ALTERNATION
OF
GENERATIONS, THE CLOSEST RELATIVES OF LAND
PLANTS DO NOT HAVE AN
ALTERNATION OF GENERATIONS. THEIR ONLY DIPLOID
PHASE IS A
ZYGOTE. SO THEY JUST HAVE, ESSENTIALLY THEY
JUST HAVE A
GAMETOPHYTE. THEY JUST HAVE A HAPLOID PHASE.
AND THEN WE SEE
THE INTERJECTION OF A SPOROPHYTE IN THE BRYOPHYTES.
SO THESE DO
HAVE A SPOROPHYTE, BUT IT'S HIGHLY REDUCED.
BUT THE MAIN PLANT
BODY IS HAPLOID. IT'S A GAMETOPHYTE. AND SO
BASED ON THIS
RELATIONSHIP HERE, THE FACT THAT THIS IS PARAPHYLETIC
RELATIVE TO
THE VASCULAR PLANTS, IT MAKES IT CLEAR THAT
THE FEATURES SHARED
BY THESE TAXA WERE ANCESTRAL FOR ALL LAND
PLANTS. OKAY, SO THE
BRYOPHYTES PROVIDE US WITH SOME REAL CLUES
TO WHAT THE ORIGINAL
LAND PLANT WAS LIKE AND THE FEATURES THESE
LINEAGES SHARE WAS
LIKELY ANCESTRAL. SO THE GAMETOPHYTE BEING
DOMINANT AND THE
SPOROPHYTE BEING JUST PARASITIC AND CONNECTED
TO THE GAMETOPHYTE
THROUGHOUT ITS LIFE, THAT SEEMS TO HAVE BEEN
ANCESTRAL IN THE
LAND PLANTS. AND THESE ARE FREE-SPORING PLANTS.
THESE ARE NOT
SEED PLANTS. REMEMBER THE SEED PLANTS ARE
ONLY DOWN HERE. AND
HERE WE HAVE THE MOSS LIFE CYCLE. SO AGAIN,
WE HAVE A HAPLOID
PHASE AND A DIPLOID PHASE. BUT THIS DIPLOID
PHASE EVEN THOUGH
THIS MAKES IT LOOK FAIRLY EXTENSIVE, IT'S
JUST THIS PARASITIC
VERY HIGHLY, YOU KNOW, VERY MINOR ORGANISM
THAT'S PARASITIC ON
THE PHOTOSYNTHETIC GAMETOPHYTE BY THIS FOOT
HERE. IT'S JUST
BASICALLY JUST A SPORANGIUM ON A STALK. SO
IT'S PRETTY MINIMAL
AS FAR AS AN ORGANISM GOES, BUT IT IS A MULTICELLULAR
ORGANISM.
AND IT'S GENETICALLY DISTINCT FROM THIS GAMETOPHYTE.
OKAY. SO
THAT'S THE, THE MOSS LIFE CYCLE. ARE THERE
QUESTIONS ABOUT
BRYOPHYTES OR -- YEAH?
STUDENT: SO [INAUDIBLE]
PROFESSOR: YEAH, I'M GOING TO GET TO THAT
IN JUST A MINUTE.
BUT, BUT IT'S A WORTHWHILE POINT TO MAKE HERE
TOO. IT'S GOOD
THAT YOU SAID THAT BECAUSE IN THIS PARTICULAR
EXAMPLE FROM THE
BOOK, YOU CAN SEE THAT THERE, THERE IS IN
THIS CASE WE HAVE SEP-,
WE HAVE TWO DIFFERENT TYPES OF GAMETOPHYTES,
A FEMALE GAMETOPHYTE
AND A MALE GAMETOPHYTE. SOME MOSSES DO SHOW
THAT SORT OF
DIFFERENTIATION BETWEEN THEIR GAMETOPHYTES
WHERE THEY HAVE MALE
AND FEMALE GAMETOPHYTES. BUT THE SPORE SIZES
REMAIN THE SAME,
AND THEY DON'T HAVE DISTINCTIVE SPORANGIA
THAT PRODUCE A
MEGASPORE THAT GERMINATES TO BE THE FEMALE
GAMETOPHYTE AND A
SMALLER MICROSPORE THAT GERMINATES TO BE THE
MALE GAMETOPHYTE.
SO THAT, THAT CONCEPT OF HETEROSPORY IS GENERALLY
DISCUSSED ONLY
IN, IN THE CONTEXT OF, OF VASCULAR PLANTS
NOT THE BRYOPHYTES.
BUT NONETHELESS ONE OF THE MAIN DISTINCTIONS
BETWEEN
HETEROSPOROUS AND HOMOSPOROUS VASCULAR PLANTS
IS THAT IN
HETEROSPOROUS VASCULAR PLANTS YOU HAVE UNISEXUAL
GAMETOPHYTES.
YOU HAVE MALE GAMETOPHYTES THAT PRODUCE SPERM
AND YOU HAVE FEMALE
GAMETOPHYTES THAT PRODUCE EGGS. YOU DON'T
HAVE BISEXUAL
GAMETOPHYTES THAT PRODUCE BOTH. OKAY, SO THAT'S,
AND THAT'S
GOING ON HERE IN THIS PARTICULAR MOSS. BUT
SOME MOSSES DO IT
THIS WAY, AND SOME MOSSES HAVE BISEXUAL GAMETOPHYTES.
YEAH?
STUDENT: [INAUDIBLE]
PROFESSOR: HERE THEY CAN BE TO SOME EXTENT,
YEAH. SO THAT CAN
BE TRUE IN BRYOPHYTES. IT'S A RELATIVELY MINOR
AMOUNT OF
PHOTOSYNTHATE THEY PRODUCE COMPARED TO WHAT,
WHAT THE
GAMETOPHYTES PRODUCE. BUT, YEAH, THAT'S TRUE.
IN FACT, SOME OF
THEM HAVE STOMATA. SO THERE ARE SOME BRYOPHYTES,
NOT, NOT
LIVERWORTS, BUT THERE ARE SOME SPOROPHYTES
THAT PRODUCE, MOSSES
AND HORNWORTS THAT PRODUCE STOMATA. SO THAT'S,
THAT'S AN
INTERESTING SITUATION TOO. YEAH?
STUDENT: [INAUDIBLE]
PROFESSOR: SORRY?
PROFESSOR: OH, NO, NOT THE DATES. BUT IT SHOULD,
ONE THING
THAT'S IMPORTANT TO POINT OUT THOUGH IS THAT
IT'S CLEAR THAT THE
BRYOPHYTES, BASICALLY THE BRYOPHYTE LINEAGE
FOLLOWS THIS, IF YOU
FOLLOW THE MAIN BACKBONE OF THIS LAND PLANT
PHYLOGENY, THE
BRYOPHYTES ARE EARLY BRANCHING HERE. SO YOU
KNOW THE ORGANISMS
THAT EXISTED THROUGH THIS PART OF THE TREE
WOULD HAVE SHARED THE
FEATURES THAT ALL OF THESE THREE GROUPS HAVE.
THOUGH THE
BRYOPHYTE BIOLOGY WAS IN PLACE HERE PRIOR
TO THE, THE VASCULAR
PLANT BIOLOGY, THE DISTINGUISHING FEATURES
OF THE VASCULAR
PLANTS. THOUGH THE SPOROPHYTE DOMINANCE DOESN'T
COME INTO PLAY
UNTIL AFTER, SOMEWHERE ALONG THIS BRANCH.
OKAY. REMEMBER I
DID POINT OUT THAT THERE WAS, THERE ARE SOME
FOSSIL VASCULAR
PLANTS THAT ARE, WOULD BE SOMEWHERE ALONG
THIS BRANCH THAT HAVE
ISOMORPHIC ALTERNATION OF GENERATIONS WHERE
THE GAMETOPHYTE AND
AND THE SPOROPHYTE LOOK THE SAME. SO THERE'S
A TRANSITIONAL
FOSSIL BETWEEN GAMETOPHYTE DOMINANCE AND SPOROPHYTE
DOMINANCE,
BUT NONE OF THOSE PLANTS ARE STILL EXTANT.
THEY'RE WAY BACK IN
THE PALEOZOIC. ALL RIGHT, AND THIS IS JUST,
YOU SAW THIS
EARLIER. THIS IS JUST REITERATING THE POINT
THAT I ALREADY MADE
THAT YOU KNOW THE LAND PLANTS HAVE BOTH MULTICELLULAR
HAPLOID AND
DIPLOID GENERATIONS, WHEREAS THAT'S NOT TRUE
FOR FUNGI AND
ANIMALS. THEY HAVE ONE OR THE OTHER. OKAY,
THEN WE GOT INTO
THE, INTO THE VASCULAR PLANTS. THE FERN LIFE
CYCLE IS THE FIRST
ONE WE TALKED ABOUT. AND IN THINKING ABOUT
ALL OF THIS, YOU
SHOULD ALSO BE, AS YOU GO THROUGH THE NOTES,
THINK ABOUT THE
FEATURES THAT, THAT WE SEE HAP-, COMING INTO
PLACE WITHIN THE,
THE LAND PLANT PHYLOGENY THAT HAVE POTENTIAL
VALUE FOR LIFE ON
LAND. THOUGH, YOU KNOW, THINGS LIKE A CUTICLE,
AND I'LL GO
THROUGH SOME OF THOSE IN A MINUTE, BUT JUST
I WANT TO MAKE THAT
POINT NOW SINCE WE'RE GETTING INTO LAND PLANTS
MORE THAT THIS
THEME OF LIFE ON LAND, YOU KNOW, KEEP THAT
IN MIND AS, AS YOU'RE
STUDYING. AND THERE'S A, THERE'S A DIAGRAM
I'LL SHOW YOU IN A
MINUTE THAT'S HELPFUL WITH REGARD TO THAT.
BUT THE FERN LIFE
CYCLE THEN IS ONE WHERE, IS THE FIRST ONE
WE LOOKED AT WHERE THE
SPOROPHYTE IS DOMINANT. AND I SPENT A LITTLE
TIME TALKING ABOUT
THE, THE FERN MORPHOLOGY. SO REMEMBER IN FERNS
THE AERIAL PART,
THE PART THAT'S ACTUALLY ABOVE GROUND IS,
IS USUALLY JUST THE
LEAVES. AND THE MAIN PART OF THE PLANT UNDERGROUND
IS THE STEM
AND THE ROOTS. SO THE STEMS ARE TYPICALLY
HORIZONTAL EXCEPT IN
THE TREE FERNS WHICH ARE A PRETTY MINOR GROUP
OVERALL IN TERMS OF
DIVERSITY. AND ALSO WE TALKED ABOUT HOW THE
SPORANGIA ARE BORNE
ON THESE UNDERSIDES OF THE LEAVES IN THESE
STRUCTURES CALLED SORI
THAT ARE CLUSTERS OF SPORANGIA. AND THEN THE
SPORANGIA THEN
PRODUCE SPORES. SO I WANT YOU TO BE ABLE TO
KEEP IN MIND THE,
THE SCALE HERE, YOU KNOW, IN TERMS OF WHAT
THE, YOU KNOW, SPORES
ARE INSIDE SPORANGIA. SPORANGIA ARE INSIDE
SORI. YOU KNOW
SORI ARE ON THE LEAVES. I MEAN YOU SHOULD
HAVE SOME SENSE OF
THE OVERALL SCALE OR THE SIZE OF THESE THINGS
RELATIVE TO ONE
ANOTHER, AND, YOU KNOW, REALIZE THAT, YOU
KNOW, THAT'S SORT OF A
BASIC POINT. BUT, I KNOW IT'S EASY TO GET
CONFUSED ABOUT WHAT'S
A SPORE, WHAT'S A SPORANGIUM. BUT YOU KNOW
THE SPORANGIUM IS A
MULTICELLULAR SAC THAT BEARS SPORES, AS A
GAMETANGIUM IS A
MULTICELLULAR SAC THAT BEARS GAMETES ON THE
GAMETOPHYTE. AND
THERE ARE TWO TYPES OF GAMETANGIA. THE ANTHERIDIUM
THAT
PRODUCES SPERM AND THE ARCHEGONIUM THAT PRODUCES
EGGS. I MEAN
THAT'S SOME BASIC TERMINOLOGY THAT, THAT APPLIES
ACROSS, ACROSS
THESE GROUPS THAT, THAT YOU SHOULD BE AWARE
OF, YOU KNOW AND
SHOULD BE FAMILIAR WITH. AND SOMETHING LIKE
SORUS YOU KNOW OR
SORI, THAT'S, THAT'S A SIGNIFICANT ENOUGH
FEATURE THAT YOU KNOW I
WOULD EXPECT YOU TO REMEMBER THAT. BUT YOU
KNOW THERE'S A LOT
OF THIS TERMINOLOGY COMES UP AGAIN AND AGAIN.
THERE'S A LITTLE
BIT OF SPECIFIC TERMINOLOGY IN THE FERNS THAT,
THAT I THINK, YOU
KNOW THAT I FOCUSED ON THAT'S WORTH REMEMBERING.
QUESTIONS
ABOUT FERNS? YEAH?
STUDENT: [INAUDIBLE]. WHAT IS THE FUNCTION
OF RHIZOIDS?
PROFESSOR: OH, RHIZOIDS. WELL, THEY CAN SERVE
TO ANCHOR A
PLANT TO THE, TO THEIR SUBSTRATE. THEY'RE
NOT SO FUNCTIONAL IN
ABSORPTION AS A ROOT. ROOTS COME INTO PLAY,
THAT'S ONE OF THE
THINGS I MENTIONED IN TERMS OF ADAPTATIONS
TO LAND IN THE, IN THE
VASCULAR PLANTS WE HAVE THE EVALUATION OF
ROOTS. WE DON'T SEE
THOSE IN THE BRYOPHYTES. WE JUST HAVE RHIZOIDS.
AND IN THE
FERN GAMETOPHYTE WE HAVE RHIZOIDS TOO, BUT
NOT IN THE SPOROPHYTE.
BUT, YEAH, THEY'RE, THEY MAINLY HAVE AN ANCHORAGE
FUNCTION, NOT
SO MUCH AN ABSORPTION FUNCTION. THOUGH GAMETOPHYTES
CAN ABSORB
MOISTURE RIGHT THROUGH THEIR, THROUGH THE
MAIN BODY OF THE
PHALLUS AS IN A BRYOPHYTE. SO HERE'S HETEROSPORY
AGAIN. AND
THIS OCCURS REMEMBER IN THE LYCOPHYTES AND
SOME OF THEM, THAT'S
WHAT THIS IS, IS A LYCOPHYTE CONE FROM THE
SELAGINELLA WHERE YOU
CAN SEE MEGASPORES ON THE LEFT AND MICROSPORES
ON THE RIGHT IN
THESE, IN A MICROSPORANGIUM AND A MEGASPORANGIUM.
SO AGAIN,
THESE ARE SPORES PRODUCED BY MEIOSIS FROM
THE SPOROPHYTE, BUT IT
JUST SO HAPPENS THE SPOROPHYTE PRODUCES TWO
DIFFERENT TYPES OF
SPORES IN DIFFERENT SPORANGIA. AND THESE GERMINATE
TO BE FEMALE
GAMETOPHYTES AND THESE GERMINATE TO BE MALE
GAMETOPHYTES. SO WE
HAVE A SEPARATION OF FUNCTION HERE. LESS CHANCE
FOR SELFING.
AND IN ALL THESE ORGANISMS THAT HAVE THIS
UNISEXUAL GAMETOPHYTE,
YOU HAVE GERMINATION OR YOU HAVE THE MULTICELLULAR
GAMETOPHYTE
LIVING WITHIN THE CONFINES OF THE SPORE WALL.
SO THEY, THEY CAN
EMERGE TO SOME EXTENT LIKE THE POLLEN TUBE
YOU KNOW THAT GROWS
OUT OF IN THE CASE OF SEED PLANTS, THE POLLEN
YOU KNOW EMERGES AS
A TUBE. BUT FOR THE MOST PART THERE'S, THERE'S
CONTAINMENT
WITHIN THIS SPORE WALL FOR A LONG PERIOD OF
TIME. SO THE, THE
HETEROSPOROUS ORGANISMS WHICH INCLUDED SOME
LYCOPHYTES, A VERY
SMALL NUMBER OF FERNS WHICH WE DIDN'T FOCUS
ON AT ALL OR IT'S NOT
REALLY IMPORTANT TO REMEMBER BUT THE WATER
FERNS, AND ALL OF THE
SEED PLANTS. ALL THE SEED PLANTS ARE HETEROSPOROUS.
IN THOSE
WE GET THIS DEVELOPMENT WITHIN THE SPORE TO
SOME EXTENT. ARE
THERE QUESTIONS ABOUT HETEROSPORY THEN? YEAH?
STUDENT: ARE ALL THE HETEROSPOROUS [INAUDIBLE]
PROFESSOR: NO, THEY DON'T. THEY DON'T HAVE
ALL STROBILI. BUT
THE ONES THAT WE TALKED ABOUT DO. BECAUSE
WE JUST, REALLY THE
ONLY HETEROSPOROUS PLANTS WE REALLY FOCUSED
ON MUCH WERE, WERE
GYMNO- WERE IN THE SEED PLANTS. I DID MENTION
SELAGINELLA IN
THE LYCOPHYTES, THESE MOSS-LIKE PLANTS WHICH
THIS IS. AND THIS
DOES HAVE A STROBILUS. BUT THERE'S, THERE'S
SOMETHING CALLED
QUILLWORTS THAT WE DIDN'T GET INTO, THESE
ISOETES THAT DON'T HAVE
STROBILI. AND THEY ACTUALLY HAVE THE LARGEST
OF ALL MEGASPORES.
YOU CAN SEE THEM WITH YOUR NAKED EYE PRETTY
WELL. BUT, BUT YEAH
THAT, OFTENTIMES YOU DO HAVE, GENERALLY YOU
HAVE STROBILI OR
CONES. SO SEED PLANTS THEN,
SO IN THE CASE OF, WE WENT INTO THE
PINE LIFE CYCLE, AN EXAMPLE OF A GYMNOSPERM
LIFE CYCLE. SO
REMEMBER WE'RE SEEING THIS TREND IN THE LAND
PLANTS FROM, THAT'S
BASICALLY, OR AT LEAST IN THE WAY THAT WE'VE
LOOKED AT THESE
GROUPS, WE'RE SEEING PROGRESSIVE REDUCTION
OF THE GAMETOPHYTE
GENERATION AND INCREASING DOMINANCE OF THE
SPOROPHYTE GENERATION.
AND IN THE CASE OF THE SEED PLANTS THEN, THE
GAMETOPHYTES
REPRESENT THE POLLEN IN THE CASE OF THE MALE
GAMETOPHYTE, SO THE
POLLEN IS THE MALE GAMETOPHYTE. AND IT'S DISPERSED
IN AN
IMMATURE STAGE, BUT IT'S ALREADY UNDERGONE
AT LEAST ONE MITOTIC
DIVISION BEFORE IT'S DISPERSED FROM THE MICROSPORANGIA
OR THE
POLLEN SACS. AND, AND THEN THE MEGAGAMETOPHYTE
REMEMBER IS
CONTAINED WITHIN THE OVULE. SO THE OVULE,
THE IMMATURE SEED IS
THE HOME OF THE FEMALE GAMETOPHYTE AND IT
NEVER LEAVES THAT, THAT
SITE. SO IT'S NEVER SHED FROM THE MEGASPORANGIUM
WHICH IS ALSO
CONTAINED WITHIN THE OVULE. THE OVULE IN ITS
EARLIEST STAGE
REMEMBER IS JUST A MEGASPORANGIUM WITH INTEGUMENT
AROUND IT WHICH
IS A NOVEL STRUCTURE THAT BECOMES THE SEED
COAT. IT DOESN'T
HAVE A HOMOLOGUE IN THE, WE'RE CLEAR ABOUT
AT LEAST IN THESE
OTHER, IN THE NON-SEED PLANTS. AND WENT THROUGH
THE STAGES OF
POLLINATION AND FERTILIZATION AND, IN THE
CONIFER, IN THE PINE.
SO REMEMBER POLLINATION IN THE GYMNOSPERMS
MEANS THE POLLEN IS
ACTUALLY LANDING AT THE MICROPYLAR OPENING
INTO THE OVULE. THIS
IS DIFFERENT REMEMBER THAN IN FLOWERING PLANTS.
WE'LL GET TO
BACK IN A MINUTE. BUT HERE POLLINATION MEANS
THE POLLEN HAS TO
ARRIVE AT THE OVULE ITSELF, SO RIGHT AT THE
DOORSTEP OF THE
FEMALE GAMETOPHYTE, THOUGH IT HAS TO GET TO
THIS POINT INTO THE
POLLEN CHAMBER AND THEN THE POLLEN TUBE GERMINATES,
WE GET MORE
MITOTIC DIVISION, AND GROWS DOWN TO THE EGG
INSIDE THE
ARCHEGONIUM. OKAY. AND THEN WE'VE ULTIMATELY
HAVE
GERMINATION, OR WE HAVE, SORRY, WE HAVE THE
FERTILIZATION OF THE
EGG. AND REMEMBER THERE'S JUST ONE FERTILIZATION
EVENT IN THE
CONIFERS IN THE SEED, IN THE PINES. AND THEN
WE ULTIMATELY GET
THE EMBRYO DEVELOPING INSIDE HERE. SO REMEMBER
THERE ARE
EMBRYOS IN ALL OF THE LAND PLANTS. IT'S IN
THE SEED PLANTS
WHERE THE EMBRYO HAS THIS LONG DORMANT PHASE
OR LONG INACTIVE
PHASE WHERE THE SEED BECOMES DESICCATED. AND
REMEMBER I
MENTIONED IN THE LAST LECTURE THAT ABA, ABSCISIC
ACID, IS
INVOLVED IN PREPARING THE SEED FOR THAT. BUT
IN ANY CASE WE
HAVE THREE GENERATIONS OF TISSUE HERE. WE'VE
GOT THE ORIGINAL
PARENT SPOROPHYTE, THE DIPLOID TISSUE ON THE
OUTSIDE. WE HAVE
THE HAPLOID FEMALE GAMETOPHYTE TISSUE. THAT'S
THE NUTRITIVE
TISSUE FOR THE EMBRYO WHICH IS THE NEXT GENERATION
OF DIPLOID
SPOROPHYTE. THOUGH DIPLOID, HAPLOID, DIPLOID,
THREE GENERATIONS
OF TISSUE THERE IN THE PINE. ARE THERE QUESTIONS
ABOUT THIS?
THIS DOESN'T REQUIRE FREESTANDING WATER. WE
HAVE VERY, MUCH
MORE SHELTERING OF THE GAMETOPHYTES FROM THE
ENVIRONMENT. AND
WE HAVE A LOT OF PROTECTION PROVIDED NOW TO
THE FEMALE
GAMETOPHYTE AND TO THE SUBSEQUENT SPOROPHYTE
GENERATION AS WELL
AS DISPERSAL PROTECTION DURING DISPERSAL FROM
THE PARENT
SPOROPHYTE. OKAY, ANY QUESTIONS ABOUT THAT?
SO NOW TO THE
FLOWERING PLANTS. SO REMEMBER THE FLOWERING
PLANTS, ON THE
FLOWER IS BASICALLY A STROBILUS OR A CONE,
A CONE. AND ONE OF
THE MOST IMPORTANT FEATURES OF THE FLOWERING
PLANTS
DIFFERENTIATING THEM FROM THE GYMNOSPERMS
IS THE CARPEL OR THE
PRESENCE OF A PISTOL COMPRISED OF ONE OR MORE
CARPELS WHICH ARE
BASICALLY LEAVES THAT HAVE FUSED ALONG THEIR
MARGIN TO PRODUCE A
CHAMBER IN WHICH THE OVULES ARE CONTAINED.
SO THE OVULES ARE
PROTECTED FROM THE ENVIRONMENT. POLLINATION
INVOLVES
GERMINATION OF THE POLLEN AWAY FROM THE OVULES
ON THE STIGMA.
AND THEN WE HAVE A LOT MORE FEMALE SELECTIVITY
HERE IN TERMS OF
OR AT LEAST PARENTAL SELECTIVITY ON THE PART
OF THE PARENT OF
THESE FEMALE GAMETOPHYTES WITH REGARD TO POLLEN,
PARENT OF THOSE
GAMETOPHYTE, MALE PARENT, OR MALE MATE FOR
THESE FEMALE
GAMETOPHYTES, AND ALSO COMPETITION BETWEEN
THE MALES HERE GROWING
DOWN THROUGH THE STYLE. OKAY, SO THAT, THAT'S
ONE OF THE MAIN
THINGS I WANTED TO MENTION ABOUT. AND REMEMBER
THE CARPEL
DEVELOPS, OR THE PISTIL OR THE CARPEL DEVELOPS
INTO FRUIT WHICH
IS ANOTHER IMPORTANT FEATURE OF ANGIOSPERMS
IN TERMS OF
DISPERSAL. THE MATURE OVARY, AND SOMETIMES
OTHER PARTS,
ACCESSORY TISSUES OF ONE OR MORE FLOWERS BECOMES
A DISPERSAL UNIT
OFTENTIMES. ALL RIGHT. AND I JUST MENTIONED
THEN POLLINATION
IN FLOWERING PLANTS INVOLVING SOME SORT OF
ATTRACTANT OR
ADVERTISEMENT. SO REMEMBER POLLINATION INVOLVES
A, MINIMALLY AN
ATTRACTANT OR AN ADVERTISEMENT FOR A POLLINATOR,
IF IT'S ANIMAL
POLLINATION. THERE IS WIND POLLINATION IN
ANGIOSPERMS. IT'S
DERIVED FROM, FROM ANIMAL POLLINATION. BUT
WHERE WE DO GET
BIOTIC OR ANIMAL POLLINATION THERE'S AN ATTRACTANT.
AND
SOMETIMES THERE'S A REWARD, BUT NOT ALWAYS.
I TALKED ABOUT
DECEIT POLLINATION WITH FLY POLLINATION AND
THE BEE ORCHIDS AND
THERE ARE SOME OTHER EXAMPLES TOO. BUT USUALLY
THERE'S A REWARD
OF SOME KIND. AND REMEMBER I SPENT SOME TIME
TALKING ABOUT
DIFFERENT POLLINATION SYNDROMES THAT, WHERE
THERE SEEMS TO HAVE
BEEN CO-EVOLUTION OR AT LEAST ON THE SITE
OF THE PLANT WITH
REGARD TO DIFFERENT KINDS OF POLLINATORS.
SO YOU SHOULD STUDY
THOSE TOO, THOSE POLLINATION SYNDROMES, FOR
EXAMPLE LIKE FLY
POLLINATION, BEE POLLINATION, THAT SORT OF
THING. QUESTIONS ON
ANY OF THAT? ALL RIGHT, AND THEN AGAIN, THE
MALE GAMETOPHYTE AND
FEMALE GAMETOPHYTE EVEN BECOMING MORE REDUCED
IN THE FLOWERING
PLANTS THAN IN THE, THAN IN THE CONIFERS.
SO THE POLLEN OF, OF
ANGIOSPERMS, FLOWERING PLANTS IS ONLY COMPRISED
OF TWO CELLS AT
THE TIME OF, OF DISPERSAL. AND THEN LATER
THE GENERATIVE CELL
UNDERGOES MITOSIS TO GIVE RISE TO TWO SPERMS.
SO WE JUST HAVE
THE BARE MINIMUM NUMBER OF CELLS TO MAKE THIS
THING WORK AS AN
ORGANISM TO GROW THE POLLEN TUBE AND, AND
TO FERTILIZE BOTH THE
EGG AND, THE OTHER SPERM REMEMBER FUSES WITH
THE TWO POLAR NUCLEI
OF THE FEMALE GAMETOPHYTE THAT BECOME THE
ENDOSPERM, THE
NUTRITIVE TISSUE. SO THE ANGIOSPERMS WAIT
TO INVEST IN THEIR
NUTRITIVE TISSUE UNTIL AFTER FERTILIZATION
HAS HAPPENED. SO
THAT'S A REALLY, PROBABLY A VERY IMPORTANT
INNOVATION IN TERMS
OF, OF YOU KNOW CONSERVING RESOURCES UNTIL
THEY'RE NEEDED. SO,
THAT'S A POINT ABOUT REWARD AND POLLINATION.
AND AGAIN THE
FEMALE GAMETOPHYTE HIGHLY REDUCED BY COMPARISON
WITH THE CONIFER
OR THE PINE FEMALE GAMETOPHYTE. JUST A FEW
CELLS, TYPICALLY
ABOUT SEVEN AND EIGHT NUCLEI. AGAIN THOSE
TWO POLAR NUCLEI HERE
UNDERGO FUSION WITH ONE OF THE SPERM TO PRODUCE
THE ENDOSPERM
MOTHER CELL THAT GOES ON TO UNDERGO MITOSES
TO GIVE RISE TO
TRIPLOID. AND THIS IS TRIPLOID TISSUE. NOT
DIPLOID OR HAPLOID
BUT 3N BECAUSE TWO NUCLEI OF THE FEMALE GAMETOPHYTE
FUSED WITH
ONE OF THE SPERM. SO YOU GET THREE GENOMES
TOGETHER HERE. AND
THAT NOURISHES THE ZYGOTE AND THE, THE DEVELOPING
EMBRYO.
THOUGH THIS DOUBLE FERTILIZATION PROCESS IS
THOUGHT TO BE ANOTHER
REALLY IMPORTANT INNOVATION TO THE FLOWERING
PLANTS IN TERMS OF
WAITING TO PRODUCE THE NUTRITIVE TISSUE UNTIL
AFTER
FERTILIZATION.
OKAY, SO THEN I ALSO TALKED A LITTLE BIT ABOUT
FRUIT, SO DO STUDY THOSE FRUIT TYPES. I TALKED
ABOUT THOSE
DIFFERENT FRUIT TYPES. AND ALSO TALKED ABOUT,
SO YEAH, I MEAN
THERE WERE VARIOUS TYPES OF DISPERSAL WE TALKED
ABOUT INVOLVING
SEEDS OR WHOLE FRUITS OR PLANTS, BOTH ABIOTIC
AND BIOTIC, BOTH BY
ANIMAL AND BY PHYSICAL FORCES. AND I ALSO
TALKED ABOUT
MECHANISMS AGAINST SELFING IN FLOWERING PLANTS.
I DON'T HAVE A
SLIDE HERE TO SHOW YOU THAT BUT REMEMBER WE
TALKED ABOUT THINGS
LIKE SPATIAL SEPARATION OF THE, OF THE STIGMA
AND THE STAMENS.
DIFFERENTIAL TIMING OF MATURATION OF STAMENS
AND PISTOLS.
UNISEXUAL, EVOLUTION OF UNISEXUAL OR I SHOULD
SAY EVOLUTION OF
PISTILLATE FUNCTION OCCURRING ON ONLY ONE
SPOROPHYTE AND
STAMINATE FUNCTION ON ANOTHER SPOROPHYTE.
THE DIOECIOUS
CONDITION. THINGS LIKE THAT. MAKE SURE TO
REVIEW THOSE
IMPORTANT FEATURES IN TERMS OF MINIMIZING
SELF-POLLINATION,
SELF-FERTILIZATION. AND THIS IS THAT FIGURE
THAT I MENTIONED
THAT SHOW SOME OF THE IMPORTANT CHANGES WE
SEE IN THE, IN THE
LAND PLANTS. SO HERE WE HAVE THE BRYOPHYTES
AGAIN. AND HERE
ARE THE LAND, THE VASCULAR PLANTS. AND HERE
ARE THE FLOWERING
PLANTS. SO AGAIN THE ALTERNATION OF GENERATIONS
IS SOMETHING
ALL THE LAND PLANTS SHARE. BUT AFTER THE LAND
PLANTS DIVERGE
FROM THE GREEN ALGAE, THE CLOSEST FRESHWATER
GREEN ALGAE HERE, WE
HAVE GAMETANGIA EVOLVING, SO ARCHEGONIA AND
ANTHERIDIA. WE
ACTUALLY HAVE EMBRYOS EVOLVE. SO THESE ARE
ALL CALLED THE
EMBRYOPHYTES. THAT'S ANOTHER NAME FOR ALL
THE LAND PLANTS. AND
REMEMBER THE TRUE VASCULAR TISSUE EVOLVED
IN THE SPOROPHYTES OF
THE VASCULAR PLANTS. WE DON'T GET TRUE VASCULAR
TISSUE IN THE
BRYOPHYTES. TRUE ROOTS EVOLVE IN THE TRUE
VASCULAR PLANTS. THE
BRYOPHYTES DON'T HAVE TRUE ROOTS. AND AS I
MENTIONED THERE IS
HETEROSPORY THAT EVOLVED IN OTHER PLACES OTHER
THAN JUST IN THE
SEED PLANTS BUT THE SEED PLANTS EVOLVE FROM
HETEROSPOROUS
ANCESTORS. AND WE HAVE THIS REDUCTION IN THE
GAMETOPHYTES
EVENTUALLY RESULTING IN THE LOSS OF THE ANTHERIDIA.
THE POLLEN
DOESN'T HAVE ANTHERIDIA. AND IN THE FLOWERING
PLANTS WE'VE EVEN
LOST THE ARCHEGONIUM AND WE HAVE DOUBLE FERTILIZATION.
THE
CARPEL HERE AND THE EVOLUTION OF FRUIT. THOUGH
THAT JUST
REITERATES SOME OTHER POINTS ALREADY MADE.
OKAY SO OTHER THINGS
TO STUDY, WE GET INTO STRUCTURE HERE, SO YOU
SHOULD BE AWARE OF
THE DISTINCTION BETWEEN DETERMINATE AND INDETERMINATE
GROWTH.
ALL RIGHT, SO STEMS AND ROOTS UNDERGO INDETERMINATE
GROWTH. AND
THEY HAVE GROWTH FROM THE APICAL MERISTEM,
THE PRIMARY GROWTH
THAT RESULTS IN LENGTHENING, BOTH THE APICAL
MERISTEM OF THE
SHOOT AS WELL AS THE ROOTS. BUT LEAVES HAVE
DETERMINATE GROWTH
TYPICALLY. THEY ONLY, THE MERISTEMS AND LEAVES
LAST ONLY A
BRIEF TIME UNTIL THE LEAF IS FULLY FORMED.
AND THE SAME GOES
WITH THE FLOWER. REMEMBER THE FLOWER IS A
DETERMINATE SHOOT
AFTER THE PISTOLS ARE FORMED. IT DOESN'T CONTINUE
TO DEVELOP.
IT TERMINATES. BUT INDETERMINATE GROWTH IS
THIS WHOLE, WHAT WE
SEE WHICH IS SO DIFFERENT FROM ANIMALS WHERE
HAVE THESE TISSUES
THAT CONTINUE TO BE, THESE GROWING POINTS
THAT CONTINUE TO
DEVELOP AND THOSE INCLUDE NOT ONLY APICAL
MERISTEMS AND PRIMARY
GROWTH BUT LATERAL MERISTEMS AND SECONDARY
GROWTH OF EUDICOTS,
CONIFERS, BUT NOT MONOCOTS. REMEMBER MONOCOTS
DON'T HAVE
SECONDARY GROWTH. SO BE AWARE OF BOTH TYPES
OF LATERAL
MERISTEMS, THE VASCULAR CAMBIUM AND THE CORK
CAMBIUM THAT ARE
BOTH RESULTING IN THICKENING GROWTH. INCREASE
IN THE AMOUNT OF
VASCULAR TISSUE IN THE CASE OF THE VASCULAR
CAMBIUM. INCREASE
IN THE AMOUNT OF DERMAL TISSUE IN THE CASE
OF THE CORK CAMBIUM.
OKAY WE DON'T HAVE MUCH TIME LEFT. BUT SO
REVIEW CELL TYPES AND
TISSUE SYSTEMS. THERE ARE JUST A FEW OF EACH.
AND BE FAMILIAR
WITH THOSE. REMEMBER WE TALKED ABOUT PARENCHYMA,
COLLENCHYMA,
SCLERENCHYMA, VASCULAR TISSUE OF WHICH WE
HAVE A COUPLE OF TYPES,
PHLOEM AND XYLEM, AND THOSE CELL TYPES. MODIFIED
STRUCTURES, I
TALKED ABOUT MODIFIED ROOTS, MODIFIED STEMS,
MODIFIED LEAVES.
YOU SHOULD BE FAMILIAR WITH THOSE AND BE ABLE
TO SAY WHICH IS A
LEAF, WHICH IS A STEM, WHICH IS A ROOT. AND
AGAIN THE TYPES OF
MERISTEMS, LATERAL MERISTEMS, FOR EXAMPLE.
SOME OF THE
CONSEQUENCES OF SECONDARY GROWTH IN TERMS
OF, YOU KNOW THIS
THICKENING GROWTH AND WHAT, THERE ARE SOME
SLIDES THAT HAD TO DO
WITH THAT. I TALKED ABOUT NUTRIENTS BRIEFLY
SO MOBILE VERSUS
IMMOBILE NUTRIENTS. I'M NOT EXPECTING YOU
TO MEMORIZE ALL OF
THE DIFFERENT MACRO AND MICRONUTRIENTS. BUT
REALIZE THERE ARE
MACRONUTRIENTS AND MICRONUTRIENTS. THE CASPARIAN
STRIP HERE IN
THE ENDODERMIS AND ITS IMPORTANCE FOR SERVING
AS A BUFFER,
SERVING AS A BARRIER TO MOVEMENT FROM THE
SOIL, MOVEMENT OF
SOLUTES AND SUBSTANCES FROM THE SOIL INTO
THE VASCULAR TISSUE.
WE TALKED QUITE A BIT ABOUT THIS. AND I ALSO
TALKED ABOUT,
WELL, WE ALREADY TALKED ABOUT MYCORRHIZAL.
WE TALKED ABOUT WATER
POTENTIAL AND THE IMPORTANCE OF WATER POTENTIAL
IN TERMS OF
MOVEMENT OF WATER, FREE ENERGY OF WATER, SO
WATER GOES FROM HIGH
WATER POTENTIAL TO LOW WATER POTENTIAL. IT'S
GOING TO, WE
TALKED ABOUT OSMOSIS, VERY SIMILAR PRINCIPLES.
AND HOW WATER'S
TRANSPORTED IN THE XYLEM VERSUS THE PHLOEM,
REMEMBER? SO HERE
IT'S NEGATIVE PRESSURE BASICALLY THAT'S PULLING
THE WATER UP
WHEREAS HERE WE HAVE POSITIVE, POSITIVE PRESSURE
PUSHING THE
PHLOEM THROUGH THE SIEVE TUBES. SO DIFFERENCES
BETWEEN PASSIVE
AND ACTIVE TRANSPORT VERSUS BULK FLOW. REMEMBER
PASSIVE AND
ACTIVE TRANSPORT IS MOVEMENT ACROSS A MEMBRANE.
BULK FLOW IS
NOT. IT'S MOVEMENT WITHIN TUBES AND WE HAVE
THESE TWO DIFFERENT
TYPES HERE. AND PHOTOPERIODISM. I TALKED QUITE
A BIT ABOUT
THAT. SO BE AWARE ABOUT PHOTOPERIODISM. YOU
SHOULD BE
FAMILIAR WITH WHAT A SHORT DAY AND WHAT A
LONG-DAY PLANT ARE
RESPONDING TO IN TERMS OF STIMULI TO FLOWER.
AND I TALKED, SO
HAVE A GENERAL UNDERSTANDING ALSO OF HORMONE
ACTION. SO I
TALKED ABOUT THE IMPORTANCE OF DOSAGE IN HORMONES,
THE IMPORTANCE
OF HOW THEY CAN HAVE DIFFERENTIAL EFFECTS
ON DIFFERENT TISSUES OR
TISSUES OF DIFFERENT AGES OR YOU KNOW THE
DOSAGE CAN HAVE, MAKE,
CAN RESULT IN A DIFFERENT EFFECT. AND THAT
THE BALANCE OF
HORMONES IS REALLY IMPORTANT. SO THOSE WERE
SOME MAJOR POINTS.
AND ALSO FINALLY, THE MAJOR DIFFERENCES BETWEEN
THE HORMONES AND
THEIR PRIMARY ACTION. SO I HAD A LIST OF DIFFERENT
TYPES OF
HORMONES AND SOME OF THE THINGS THAT THOSE
HORMONES ARE MOST
IMPORTANT IN TERMS OF, WHAT KINDS OF RESPONSES
THEY TEND TO
SIGNAL. ARE THERE ANY LAST QUESTIONS? OFFICE
HOURS I'M GOING
TO CONTINUE TO HOLD THEM THROUGH, UP UNTIL
THE DAY OF THE FINAL
SO YOU KNOW JUST, JUST COME WHEN YOU CAN IF
YOU HAVE ADDITIONAL
QUESTIONS. OKAY.