And we don't have any yaks in
Australia, so we thought that
was enough of a reason
to go check it out.
We got on a plane in Melbourne
and flew 14 hours to a tiny
airport near the
Russian border.
We then drove half a day across
dirt tracks where the
vast emptiness made us feel
totally insignificant.
Finally, we found a bunch of
Mongolian herders in a field
surrounded by 500 of the finest
yaks in the country.
OK, we are in Khovsgol Province,
which is about 1,200
kilometers from the capital,
Ulan Bator.
And we're at the second annual
Yak Festival, which is a big
deal if you're into yaks.
-My yak six old.
ROYCE AKERS: Six years?
-Yeah, six.
ROYCE AKERS: How old are you?
-I?
ROYCE AKERS: Yeah.
-I 22 years old.
ROYCE AKERS: 22.
Sweet.
The yak is pretty much
Mongolia's national animal.
This goes back centuries to when
Genghis Khan laid waste
to most of Europe and Asia in
a giant yak-drawn tent,
leaving a bloody trail of
hoof prints in his wake.
Yak Festival aims to celebrate
that macho heritage with a
range of yak-related
activities.
We were told that they would
climax in an epic yak race
across the steppe, which
was the reason we came.
Here we are with the owner
of one of last
year's winning yaks.
He's going to tell us about some
of the medals that he's
won through yak racing
and yak pulling.
-[SPEAKING MONGOLIAN]
ROYCE AKERS: As you can see,
yak sports are reserved for
macho guys like this one.
Horse racing is a little
different.
Hey, can you tell
us where we are?
TOOGII UNBANYAMBA: We
are in Tuv province.
ROYCE AKERS: It's
kind of amazing.
There are no trees at all.
And everywhere you look is
just mountains and grass.
So tell us about this
horse race.
UUGII UNBANYAMBA: The five
years old horses
are going to race.
And the interesting thing
about the five years old
horses is that this
the age when the
horses are the fastest.
ROYCE AKERS: So who's going
to be riding the horses?
UUGII UNBANYAMBA: Like kids
from five to 12 years old.
ROYCE AKERS: How many horses
are going to be
taking off at once?
UUGII UNBANYAMBA: Today I heard
there going to be more
than 300 horses.
ROYCE AKERS: So this is the
finish of the race.
We were at the start, and we
were filming some of the stuff
going on, and all of a sudden
it was on, and it was just a
cloud of dust.
And so we jumped in the car and
drove the 25 kilometers as
fast as we could.
But we ran into some traffic and
whatever, so this is all
that's left of the race--
this straggler over here.
But they don't actually call
the loser "the loser." They
have some other name for it.
It would kind of suck if you
were the last of 200 horses,
but they somehow make it
all right for the kids.
OK, we're in Khovsgol Province
with Toogii's family.
And we're going to check out
some of the products we can
make with yak milk.
Could you tell us what
we have in this one?
-[SPEAKING MONGOLIAN]
ROYCE AKERS: The curd tastes
like dry, chewy, yogurt.
And the cheese kind of like
Parmesan, but not as salty.
What's in this one?
-[SPEAKING MONGOLIAN]
ROYCE AKERS: It's sweet,
it's just like cream.
It's not even sour.
After lunch, we headed back to
catch the Festival's second
biggest draw card,
Mongolian rodeo.
[MUSIC - PIERCED ARROWS,
"ON OUR WAY"]
Between events, the crowd was
treated to a few bouts of
Mongolian wrestling.
It turns out Mongolians are
exceptionally good at not
being pushed over, which makes
some matches about as exciting
as televised golf.
It was during one of these
extended bouts that we noticed
a crowd rushing down the hill.
We turned around just in time
to see the last 100 metes of
the yak race.
It was pretty unruly and a lot
less epic than it sounded on
the brochure.
The riders found it
tough keeping the
yaks running straight.
And to be honest, they probably
could have jogged faster.
Still, a race is a race, and
the winners were celebrated
accordingly.
Their jobs done, the tired
animals were let out to
pasture, where they could eat
their grass and dream of
future glory at next year's
Yak Festival.
[MUSIC - PIERCED ARROWS,
"ON OUR WAY"]