cartels because the
drug cartels
started kidnapping them.
MALE SPEAKER: The original story
is they come down for
the cause of plural marriage.
SHANE SMITH: So they wanted
to continue polygamy.
MALE SPEAKER: Yes.
SHANE SMITH: Ah!
We've come to God's country.
MALE SPEAKER: The only
people here with
weapons are the criminals.
MALE SPEAKER: And when it
comes to protecting our
family, if we have to die doing
it, we're going to.
SHANE SMITH: That's
some crazy shit.
America, America, America-- all
the guns are from America.
Holy Jesus.
Wow, it's a lot of drugs.
MALE SPEAKER: They shot him four
times in the head each.
MALE SPEAKER: His family
lives right across
the mountain here.
KELLY ROMNEY: I think
he needs to change.
As long as you have the swimming
pool over there, this
is going to be the
diving board.
MITT ROMNEY: God
bless America.
Thanks you guys.
SHANE SMITH: Have there ever
been any Romneys kidnapped?