Check in Clarksdale's
historic Riverside Hotel
and take a musical journey
with Wilco's Pat Sansone.
Mississippi Roads is made
possible in part by
the generous support
of viewers like you.
Thank you!
Support for the Arts Segment
of Mississippi Roads
comes from the Mississippi
Arts Commission
whose vision is to support and
celebrate
Mississippi's creative and
innovative spirit.
Informaiton available
at arts.state.ms.us.
♪ Down Mississippi roads... ♪
♪ Mississippi Roads... ♪
Welcome back to
Mississippi Roads.
I'm your host
Walt Grayson.
This week we've traveled
up to Clarksdale
for the 25th annual Sunflower
River Blues & Gospel Festival.
♪♪
It was always on the map, it's
just being on the map itself,
Clarksdale did not realize
how much it was on the map.
Bill and I sort of helped
along in that sense.
People were coming
here from everywhere
to hear blues and you
couldn't guarantee it.
So we made it so you
could guarantee it.
They are still
coming from everywhere,
but now they stay.
If you stick
around long enough,
people hear about you.
They will come.
We say build
it, they'll come.
Grayson:
And that's exactly
what people
from all over the
world are doing:
Traveling to
Clarksdale, Mississippi
for the 25th annual
Sunflower Blues Festival.
Freeman:
I'm feeling
pretty good
about how it is now and
where it's basing itself
after only been involved
with it for the last,
what, 15 years?
But look outside.
We're smoking along.
Grayson:
While Clarksdale
has always been
a popular destination
for European travelers
looking to trace
the Blues Trail,
The Sunflower Blues
Festival offers three days
of Blues and
Gospel music that
generations of family
members can all enjoy.
During the 2012
festival, Robert Plant,
former front man for
Led Zeppelin showed up
to give Clarksdale his
perspective on The Blues.
Plant:
The only reason
to come to America
is to come here,
really.
Clarksdale is a
sort of condition
I've had since I
was a kid.
I was so moved by the
music when I had
no knowledge of the social
structure of this state
or even the kind of
racial interplay,
if you want to
call it that.
I had no idea
when I was a kid.
I just heard the
music and I think
like so many kids
around the world,
no matter what
language you speak,
it's very evocative and
infectious and alluring.
But once you're drawn to
the sound of the music
and the scales, then you
start learning more and more
about the story
behind it all.
I was 13 when
I first heard,
I suppose, black
music generally.
I guess it was
Sonny Boy Rice Miller
and he was playing
and he became
quite a celebrity in England
when I was in school.
So I picked up
the harmonica.
I loved the way that
he played and swung.
He was a real
star in the UK.
Grayson:
And with
the popularity
of Mississippi Delta
Blues in Britain
came the British Invasion
with all of their roots
stemming from right
here in Mississippi.
Freeman:
It's important because
this is like
the Nativity.
This is where American music
actually gets its base.
All of American music,
somehow you can trace it
all the way back down
here to Blues and Gospel
right here in the Delta.
Plant:
I see my own mortality
in a different light
now to when I was a kid
and I know that when I
was a kid, I did see a lot
of the people who are now
heralded in this room who
were real space shifters.
And I come back here
because I connect.
There's a lot of unfinished
business down here.
I don't know
what it is even,
I just know that and
sometimes I feel
very evocative moments
where I can feel history
and I can feel...
I don't know.
And on that note,
I must wish you all
a very good night.
(Applause)
Grayson:
Clarksdale is located
in Coahoma County
in the heart of the
Mississippi Delta
and home
to the Blues.
We are at one of
Clarksdale's most famous
or maybe should I say
one of Clarksdale's
most infamous
blues landmarks:
the intersection
of Highways 61 and 49.
The notorious
crossroads where,
local legend has it
that world-renown blues
guitarist Robert Johnson
sold his soul to the devil.
Or was that blues
guitarist Tommy Johnson?
No, that was in Oh
Brother, Where Art Thou?
Anyway, in our first
story we're going
to visit a
Clarksdale landmark
with a reputation a
little less sinister.
1930's Radio Announcer:
We interrupt this broadcast
to bring you this
breaking news:
Jazz and Blues legend,
Bessie Smith,
has been pronounced dead
in Clarksdale, Mississippi.
Details are not
known at this time.
Please stay tuned
for more information.
Now, in memory,
Bessie Smith's,
"'Taint Nobody's
Business If I Do."
Bessie Smith was known-
or is known-
as the empress
of the blues.
She was making records and
people were buying them.
In late September
1937, late at night
coming from Memphis
to Clarksdale,
Bessie and her driver
were coming down old 61.
(tires squealing)
She was brought by
ambulance to Clarksdale's
G.T. Thomas Hospital, but
it was too late by then.
Man:
It is the most
blues-historic place
in the world
that you can stay.
It's got the rich
history of pre-hotel,
which when it was
the G.T. Thomas
Afro-American
hospital,
Bessie Smith, the
great blues singer
from the 1920s died
there in 1937.
Then in 1944 Frank
Ratliff's mother started
the Riverside Hotel and
it has been continuously
operating ever since then.
This place was built
in 1920-something.
These doors are
the originals.
August 10th, 1944
that's when my mother
brought me through
these doors
when she opened
this business up.
She's one of the
best-known ladies
that's ever been
in these parts.
She's seen the hardship and
her being a black woman,
or a woman period, she
withstood the test of time
because she kept business
going on even in the old days
and stuff when things
were really tight.
You have to consider
where we are
and what that time
was like.
Here's a lady that had
multiple businesses,
had great store credit.
She was a seamstress,
she had a café,
she had a hotel.
It was a lady who was
obviously very together
and a very strong
and intelligent woman.
When mother looked at this
place there were only 8 rooms.
From this wall
to the back,
that's what
mother had added.
I don't buy furniture.
I got furniture in here
over a hundred years old.
That furniture
there: 1944.
You look around at
all these pictures,
these people have stayed
here, lived here.
Some of them
lived here.
Room nine:
Ike Turner.
He lived here
for about four
or five years
before he left.
"Rocket 88,"
Ike Turner.
It was written by
Jackie Brenston,
the music and everything
was put together
in the basement.
They went to Memphis
and recorded it.
Everybody that stayed
here called mom, "Mom."
John Lee Hooker,
Sam Cooke,
Muddy Waters
lived here.
Stolle:
When he tells you
you're staying
in the Muddy Waters room
or the Pop Staples room
or the John Lee Hooker
room or whatever,
they stayed there.
So the music history is
just incredibly rich.
You're staying right
where it happened,
where the guys that
made the music stayed.
They played with me
when I was small,
when I was 4, 5,
and 6 years old.
They lived here and after
they'd come from a gig,
from playing, they'd
go back there
and get me out
of my bed.
You're staying here
because of its history
in a lot of ways but
part of the history
happens to be
the living guy
that owns and
runs the place.
My impression of
the place is
it's a very
unassuming place.
Appearances aren't
that important.
It's one of the most
unpretentious places
I've ever
been to.
Came in and
fell in love with it
immediately, learned
about all the people
who had stayed here.
I think we're in
Sam Cooke's room.
It's all
really cool stuff.
And then Rat, the
owner, is quality.
He's a really good guy.
Stolle:
Rat is actually
connected to the history.
He's not a tour guide
that's sort of studied
the patter and
gives it out.
He's not an MA history
student just telling you
what he'd learned.
He's actually
lived the experience.
Ritter:
Rat and the Riverside
are pillars
of Clarksdale and the
historical community.
Clarksdale isn't
like a museum piece,
it's not this thing that's
just sunk in formaldehyde.
It's still a living city.
Everyone's very friendly.
We've been hanging out
in bars and restaurants
and everyone's
very hospitable.
One of the really awesome
things for guests who stay
at the Riverside Hotel,
is that not only are you
welcomed when
you check in;
you might get a tour if
you've never been there
and some conversation
and history.
But also he'll come
down and check on you.
If you go to
Red's Lounge,
he'll come and
check on you.
Not because he thinks
something will happen
but because he wants
you to feel at home.
Try to get that out
of a five-star hotel.
Riverside Hotel:
home away from home.
See I'm just a caretaker.
The people that come
here, they are the owners.
And I tell them: if
you rent from me,
then you just bought
stock in the Riverside.
Not only is Mississippi the
birthplace of the Blues,
but County Music, Rock
and Roll and a lot
of other forms of
popular music can trace
their roots back to
the Magnolia State.
Maybe that's one of
the reasons why
so many nationally
renowned artists
have once called
Mississippi home.
I'm sitting on the
third row I can't help
but tell the person
next to me,
"You see the
guy on the right?
He's my boy!"
That's when it
dawned on me
that I think I'm the
father of a rock star.
I'm not sure.
It's like a storybook.
Some people can't
believe your boy
is playing with Wilco.
Pat's just one of the
most natural musicians
I've ever met.
I've always been involved
with music from day one.
My family
is very musical.
Pat's grandmother was a
great musician, too.
She played piano.
And my grandmother
was a great musician.
She played piano, too.
They were sisters.
So we kind of grew up in
that whole environment
of living around
a house or going
to a house on
Sundays or holidays
where there was a lot
of music going on.
That's the environment
that we grew up in.
My dad grew up in a very
musically active family.
They were always doing
shows around the house
and for people in
the neighborhood.
Show business was
kind of always part
of their mode
of being.
So he was getting music
from both sides pretty
much all the time.
The fact that my dad,
Tony Sansone,
was involved with
a festival called
the Lively Arts Festival.
He booked acts
in Meridian
at the Temple Theatre
all through the 1970's
and 1980's.
He was responsible
for bringing
a lot of legendary
acts to Meridian.
We had some
great shows here.
My boy spent a lot
of time on the stage.
That was his
growing up time.
He would come down
here with me
and do
sound checks.
He got to see Ray Charles
and Tony Bennett.
Gladys Knight and
the Commodores
and lots of great
country acts.
All these famous
people on the stage,
he can kind of relate
to that even as a kid.
Meridian is a
very musical city.
He graduated down there
and he was staying
down in Hattiesburg and
worked at a T-shirt place.
When I left Hattiesburg
and moved
to New Orleans in the
mid-1990's, John had moved
from Oxford to New
Orleans as well.
So both ended up in New
Orleans at the same time.
We had really similar
tastes in terms of music
that we bonded over
favorite records.
So I started
bouncing songs off of him.
We recorded the first
Autumn Defense record
at King's Way in New Orleans,
a really great studio.
Through that connection
and through our band,
that's how I got to know Jeff
and Glenn and the Wilco guys.
Everyone knew him
and that was
sort of the way
with Wilco.
It was always not
about auditions.
It was more about
who was in the area
and just friends.
That's the way it has
always been with the band.
Jeff knew that Nells Kline
would be a good fit
and try to make a super
band or something
to have Pat involved and
they both really raised
the level of musicianship
in the band.
He and Jeff have had this
wonderful sort of rapport
where Jeff has
more of a vision,
more of a big picture
guy and Pat is more
of a small detail-oriented
guy in the studio.
He has sort of been with Jeff
almost a musical director
at different times
with the band.
Pat:
It happened
very organically.
It wasn't really set out that I
was going to be the coproducer
of the record when we
started the record.
We started making the
record in our own studio
in Chicago without
an outside producer.
There just came a point
in the process where there
needed to be someone filling
the hole that was there
because we didn't have
an outside producer.
I think Jeff trusted me in that
situation enough to allow
me to fill that role
with this record.
They are
different animals,
the studio and the stage.
I love to perform.
Just the feeling that you
get in that conversation
between yourself
and the audience
and the guys that you
are playing with.
It can be a really
thrilling feeling
when it's going well.
There is no other place
that you can get that.
We tried to do a show
that's satisfying
to the crowd and
satisfying to us.
There is a big catalog.
The Wilco catalog is
pretty big at this point.
There is a lot of
music to draw upon.
I think of The Temple as sort
of a sacred place to me.
That was the place
where my dad put on
all of those shows
in the 1970's.
We said, "Let's see
if we can get Wilco."
So I called the office.
I told him if you want to
book Wilco at The Temple
like you always have,
good luck.
He went through
the same process
that anybody would
to book Wilco.
He still makes fun
of me about that,
but that's okay.
We were only
going to do one show,
so we didn't have
any computer
or credit cards
set up.
We didn't have
anything.
I said you are going
to be getting people
from all over the South,
maybe all over the country.
There are going to
be people from all over
that are going to be
coming to the show.
Have you got
your credit card--
do you have an online
thing happening
for ticket buyers
or credit cards?
He said oh no.
We're probably not going
to do any credit cards.
I said you have to have
a credit card set up.
How are you going
to sell tickets
to people all
over the country?
He said we'll probably just
do like we always did.
They can send me
a self-addressed
stamped envelope and the
money for the tickets
and we will send
their tickets back.
I said that is
never going to work.
You just can't do it.
We couldn't send them
to the wrong place
because they addressed
the envelope.
We sold this theater out
in three or four days.
Every single person
that sat in that theater,
he had talked to
on the phone
and helped them pick
out their seats.
I think that's the way that
Tony had always produced
and done shows and it
still worked for him
with the Wilco show.
And then the
next thing I know,
we are booked at
The Temple Theater.
It's a very rare and
unique opportunity
to be able to play
with five other guys
that get along so
well and also are
able to connect so
deeply musically.
I feel very lucky to
be able to do this
with these guys.
I think he is a goodwill
ambassador for our state.
We've had a lot of
other musicians
that were goodwill
ambassadors, too.
Chris Etheridge
who just left us
was a goodwill ambassador
for our state.
I think Pat is kind of
filling those shoes now.
I'm about as proud as a
dad can be of a son who's
done real well and
he's a nice person.
Patrick is a nice person
who happens to be
a great musician.
(Applause)
Regrettably, that's all the
time we have for this episode.
But if you'd like any
information about anything
you've seen on
tonight's show,
contact us at:
Until next time,
I'm Walt Grayson.
I'll be seeing you
on Mississippi Roads.
We close tonight with a song
written by Graham Parsons
and Meridian's own
Chris Etheridge.
We lost the legendary Chris
Etheridge a few months ago.
It's called "Hot
Burrito Number One".
♪ You may be ♪
♪ Sweet and nice ♪
♪ But that won't keep
you warm at night ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm the one ♪
♪ That showed you how ♪
♪ To do those things
you're doing now. ♪
♪ You may feel ♪
♪ All your charms ♪
♪ And he may hold you
in his arms ♪
♪ But I'm the one ♪
♪ Who let you in. ♪
♪ I was right there
beside you then. ♪
♪ Once upon a time ♪
♪ You let me feel you
deep inside ♪
♪ But no one saw ♪
♪ No one knew. ♪
♪ Do you remember
how you cried? ♪
♪ I'm your toy ♪
♪ I'm your old boy ♪
♪ But I don't want nobody
else to love me. ♪
♪ No I wouldn't lie. ♪
♪ You know I'm not
that kind of guy. ♪
Mississippi Roads is made
possible in part by
the generous support
of viewers like you.
Thank you!