to increase diversity.
Auckland: hosted the rugby world cup did wonders,
motivating it to create two new entertainment
precincts and public transport greatly improved.
Sydney: Innovative mixed use districts incorporating
cycle paths, verticle gardens are one way
the Australian waterside giant is becoming
more sophisticated. The central park complex
is a triumph in green architecture that can
serve as an example for the rest of the world.
Tokyo: hidden under the facade of a neon-lit
megacity is a small town spirit featuring
world class shopping and business opportunities.
Melbourne: Australia's cultural hub is getting
even better with a big push to ease traffic
congestion.
Munich: Unemplyment is low, but failure to
act on a few key projects has hurt Munich's
standing. Its airport needs a third runway
to compete with the other global cities on
this list.
Vienna: continues to evolve from a beautiful
relic to a modernized classic. Affordable
housing and an imminent brand new campus for
the Vienna University's school for economics
and business will inject youth into the city.
Copenhagen: the danes are the happiest people
on earth because of places like this, with
near-perfect integration between city life
and the outdoors. The city aims to be carbon
neutral by 2025.
Helsinki, Finland: crowned world design capital
2012, it is unveiling a new metro line and
converting its harbors into attractive residential
areas. Helsinki is a city where good ideas
can quickly come to life.
Zurich: with 50 impressive museums, concert
halls and theatres for a smaller city and
a strict corporate culture, this clean, beautiful
city is one larger cities should learn from.
In the end the cities that make the cut are
not just OK, but places that are benchmarks
for urban renaissance and rigorous reinvention
in everything from environmental policy to
transport. No city in the Americas made the
top 10 and no city in South America or Africa
made the top 25.
Take our poll below linked below, which city
do you think is the most-liveable? And help
this conversation spread by liking, favoriting,
or sharing the video through our social network
pages linked below.