Hey, Sonny.
Sonny Geras.
Have you seen any
of these guys?
They're pretty cool.
SONNY GERASIMONWICZ: I can't
tell if I always just wanted
to draw, or because when you're
a kid, a lot of kids
start drawing.
It's one of the things you do.
And then my dad showed me some
stuff he did in high school
that at times blew my mind.
It was probably the
'50s or something.
It was flames before flames
became this disgusting thing.
They actually were
just on hot rods.
I don't know.
Maybe you get a compliment or
something here and there.
As a kid, you don't know if
someone's just encouraging you
to keep going and doing whatever
you're doing even if
it's bad, but you're just
totally like, yeah, yeah.
Then graffiti started
popping up.
Do you know what I mean?
This is in West LA.
It's even hard for me to
remember what I felt seeing
it, but it was just so
attractive, seeing a person's
name twice.
You're like, I saw that before
on a pole, and that's exactly
the same person.
I haven't even met this person,
but he's been there
and now he's been there.
I don't who he-- you
know what I mean?
The artwork was overwhelming.
It was like seeing a mural, but
something was more geared
towards you or something.
I think it was that people did
it for no other reason but
just to do it.
It wasn't, we got a grant, or
we got money, or we're going
to get this, or we're going
to advertise that.
It's just like all it was
was just for yourself.
It was like drawing on your
notebook or something.
Dude, this shit's gnarly.
This is a sketchbook, standard
graffiti-like
piece book, I guess.
Somebody would have someone's
book, and they borrowed it,
and it's floating in sixth
period or whatever.
And I was just like, let me
fucking see that book, dude.
And the pages were so
completely done and
air-brushed and used markers
and blending and--
Even when it was straight-up
pen, you're just blown away.
You're like, I want
to do that.
OK, this is probably one of
the first books I had.
This is before I
even had a tag.
It's half my name.
Then I got in a crew,
which was AWR.
And then--
-What did AWR stand for?
SONNY GERASIMONWICZ: Stood for
All Writes Reserved, but
"writes" like graffiti
writing.
Or Art Work Rebels.
I think that was extremely
important because you're
constantly doing more
artwork now.
And you're doing color theory,
and you don't even know it.
You're just like,
it's graffiti.
But you don't realize all the
skill you're picking up and
stuff like that.
I got this photography book that
the Sex Pistols, that Bob
Gruen-- he followed the Sex
Pistols for a long time.
I don't know why I was so blown
away by the photos.
They were just so good.
And I just started copying
every single one.
This is after graffiti, kinda.
I was totally lost.
I was like, oh shit.
What do I do know?
[INAUDIBLE]
Pretty funny.
Whatever.
This was when I got
looser and better.
It's markers, colored pencil.
Here's what I did at Cal Arts.
I decided to go to Cal
Arts for fine art.
And I just wasn't into
that at all.
I just hated it, really.
I dropped out after two years
because they wouldn't let me
transfer to graphic design.
So I went and bought
a computer.
Didn't know how to
use it at all.
Like a Mac.
I would lay out t-shirts.
I'll call it graphic designer
for the sake of describing it,
but I was not by any means a
trained graphic designer.
This one company called Art
Machine in West L.A..
They did key art, which is movie
posters, one sheets.
They were building
their company.
And they didn't have
a lot of money.
And they were taking on
designers like, we're
going to train you.
And we'll pay you just not that
much at the beginning.
I just feel like I got lucky.
So I learned, it's more like
Photoshop and retouching.
You've seen movie posters.
They're insane.
Insanely bad most of the time.
It's advertising.
The goal is to make
as much money as
possible from that film.
If its "Mission Impossible II",
put Tom Cruise's head as
big as possible and a tiny-ass
missile that you can see at 50
miles an hour driving by.
It has nothing to do
with layout or
a cool poster anymore.
But if you don't give a shit
about that stuff, it's just
like you give up.
It's fine.
You're like, it's a job.
Let's do it.
-What are some films
that you worked on?
SONNY GERASIMONWICZ: I
knew that was coming.
"Deuce Bigalow: European
Gigolo".
That was one of them.
He's sitting on a bench, and
there's a building right here.
That one, particularly, has
a really bad head strips.
Head strips is when you take a
head from a photo and you put
it on another body, which
is constantly--
They don't give a--
They're like, he's signed
off on his head.
We have to use it.
So it's like this.
When I was working at the design
advertising boutique,
I'd gotten those emails from
Spike saying, we want to get
some sketches of "The
Wild Things".
I had a friend of a friend, a
friend Julian was in a band
called Liars.
And he toured with Karen.
And Karen to Spike, that
was the connection.
Spike was talking to Julian
about, he still wasn't quite
getting the right sketches for
"The Wild Things." You know
what I mean?
He's like, I think, but
I don't know, but--
Anyways, he wanted to find
somebody else to draw it.
And then I got an email
saying, I heard--
Julian said you might be able
to have something to offer
with the characters.
The first thing that I'd sent
him to get him interested,
though, were these
pictures of--
I'd never think I was drawing
a bear, but it would end up
looking like a big
grizzly bear.
And it was kind of really just
like, uhh, like [HUFF]
I don't know, maybe like they
had hangovers or whatever.
Had more human emotions.
So I drew those on my own.
And that's what I sent to Spike
to say, this is kind of
what I'm doing right now.
And I don't even know if I made
the connection of, these
are big fuzzy animals, and
those are these things.
I just sent what I want
to draw at the time.
He saw the sketches
I sent him.
Now he wants to just me do
that with the script.
And they were still really
tight in the beginning.
Some of them I was trying to
render them out and do all
this stuff.
And then as soon as I just
started doing really quick
crazy ones, they came
out way better.
One thing about Spike, too, is
you've been drawing it for 12
hours-- one drawing-- and you've
drawn one on a napkin,
he will judge it in exactly
the same amount of time.
It doesn't matter how
it's rendered.
It's the idea.
And I was doing drawings.
And they're like, Maurice
wants to talk
to you on the phone.
He wants to know who the fuck's
drawing his drawings.
And which you're like, duh.
And you're like,
fine, whatever.
I have no idea, anything
about what his real
personality is like.
If he's, going to be like, well,
you know, I just drew
this book as an artist, as a
child, and I just hope it
helps children, and
dah-dah-dah-dah-dah.
Or what.
And he gets on the phone.
Yeah, well, so what's
your name?
What's your last name?
And I'm like, Sonny.
It's Gerasimonwicz.
And he's like, what is that?
He just had no idea who's
drawing his characters, if it
was some person that draws
greeting cards, or if it was
someone that does cartoons,
animated.
No idea.
I was like, I don't
draw for a living.
I've been sort of protecting
it or something.
I just sold out and did movie
posters for five years.
And then we talked about some
other things, and somehow he
just finally loosened up.
And he was like, all right.
Well, great.
Let's talk about
these drawings.
These are pretty cool.
I like these drawings.
This is just really great.
I was just like, [SIGH].
That's just the way he is.
He's so straight up
about everything.
And it's so valuable.
It's amazing.
You're just like, oh my god.
I'm working on the
right project.
I'm just trying to get them
close to some kind of
live-action version
in the movie.
Like translate it.
I'm not trying to do his
drawings at all.
There's one right there.
Back when we originally went
over the script with Spike and
he was describing what the
movie's about and how he
wanted to do the characters,
he definitely talked more
about how individual they were,
and where they came
from, what their inspiration
was, and what makes them up,
and how they relate
to each other.
It probably took up like 90%
of the whole description of
each character.
It wasn't like, does Carol
have feathered pants?
Or are they scaled pants?
And you'd be like,
um, I don't know.
I don't know.
I never really--
It's not really like
the main concern.
After we started doing the
sketches, developing the
characters and things like that,
I kept moving into the
next step, which is going to the
effects houses and making
the creatures and
stuff like that.
My vote was with Henson, because
that's what they do is
live-action puppets.
If they can get one of the most
personalities out of a
green sock with two white little
balls on top, bring
that to these things,
we'll be good.
-What was going on with the
suit for Alexander?
What wasn't working?
How that whole process
changed with you
getting into the suit?
SONNY GERASIMONWICZ: How I
became inside Alexander?
-Yeah.
SONNY GERASIMONWICZ: Well, the
actor that was inside of
Alexander, she was really
well trained.
Think theater actor, and
dancer-performer type.
Catherine Keener and Peter
Elliott kept describing what
type of character it was, and
her performance was just not
going in that direction.
I think Keener had already
started thinking about this.
She would use me as an example
of the character that
Alexander was, maybe because I
was negative or something all
of the time.
I don't know.
I feel like she proposed the
idea or something when I
wasn't around.
And then Spike had called
me and said, how are the
rehearsals, and things
like that.
And I was like, ah, dude,
I don't know.
He's like, what about
you get in the suit?
You know, what about you?
He was cutting a million
corners, in a
smart way, I believe.
I know the character already.
I designed the character.
I'm short.
He knows if I would have got
in the suit, I wouldn't be
crying and getting out of
it, like [BLUBBERING].
I'd stick it out even
if I couldn't act.
And I was like, I think we can
do it enough because the face
is going to be done in post.
And the voice is done
by Paul Dano.
I wasn't the entire thing.
I was this element.
And it's like, are
you serious?
Because then I'll answer
the question seriously.
And he's like, yeah.
And I was like, all right,
let's try it.
After that, it was like him
and Keener coaching me.
If anyone is going to make it
happen or help me do it,
that's going to do it.
They'd have to suit everybody
up, get them all in this
special location in a warehouse
to do a couple
scenes for me, two run-throughs
or something.
That was insanely stressful.
Because not only have you never
been on a set before
acting, ever, but let's just
wrap him up in a suit so he
can't see or do anything, and
tell him to run around here
and throw this dirt
clod at that guy.
And then when he's like, hey,
Alexander, you've got to be
standing next to him
ready for that cue.
And you're like, dude,
I'm fucked.
Your opinions are welcome if
you're working on the film in
any department.
And, obviously, you have to
have an opinion if you're
doing the drawings for
the creatures.
I'd literally maybe have the
suit on and the head off and,
Sonny, how does Carol
look in this shot?
Or, what should we
do with this?
All my jobs definitely
overlapped.
Watching everybody else, the
way they approached stuff,
like KK or Spike, the idea of
what they're doing was way up
front more than anything else.
It's like, OK, is that effect
going to help us tell the
story we're trying to tell.
It's not like, is this
the best effect we
can get right now.
That's probably one of the most
valuable things that I
probably learned on it was, if
you have a good idea, believe
in it and push it.
Trying to figure out what
someone else wants is like the
worst way to do it, as
far as I'm concerned.
It comes out stiff and bad
and like, I think this
is what they want.
So do your version of it.
All right.
[INAUDIBLE].
Does it look kind of like
an olive-y skin?
Sick.