they are not able to post bail uh... and
one of the people who has felt the
consequences of that uh... is one woman
by the name that i had this year at
warez uh... in maricopa county
now this account to assure show right so
these are guys who do heinous of all
time
now looking at other sensibly at its
uh... the intend i'm sure the voters was
hailed as a dangerous criminal et cetera
this applies to any felony
including forgery it which is what this
woman was charged with
even though as your about to find out
there wasn't room or now she went to go
get passport for her thirteen-year-old
daughter and in the process of doing so
and she was told that she needed to go
to a satellite
add location to get the passport which
he thought was a little strains
therefore he started questioning her
about her i'd eat they started
questioning her about her birth
certificate and immediately assume that
she is an undocumented immigrant
family issues within she's latina
uh... once said she has spent some time
in mexico
do we have to prove anything more on
that
put her in jail
for and a
and part of the reason why she couldn't
post bell is because of this week
detials la that was passed in arizona
what's important is that it is the
reason is the reason and also she
shoot shoot or do you know i did
it's too far in the united states
they they didn't care are the prosecutor
in this situation didn't even check the
long-form birth certificate right and
the judge who heard this case was like
what are you guys doing
the bar certificate is right here
ices riding at she s the prosecutor if
he had looked at it and he admitted no i
did not look at the birth certificate
now sheriff joe isb out their busy
trying to find all bombers long-form
birth certificate
how do you worry about along former
soviet of a u_s_ citizen you kept in
jail for four dash half months
on based on
nothing
and just couldn't believe it just i
don't want she has impressed you did you
look for
is that i got a month for birth
certificate
what the what those if you are in prison
for four everyone's four
but that's what happens when you before
wists
policy when you say
i don't care if she's guilty or not
guilty i don't care if we've had the
trial
that's one thing
to say hey you know what was really
trying to be completed your get tough
sent straight
but now all contraceptive so even if
you're too was good enough
joe lieberman even in the u_s_ senate
propose a bill that if anybody to use
your terrorism
you immediately lose your citizenship
but not if you could could you just if
you were to use
right this is a kind of call for that
we've gotten the n_b_a_ national defense
authorization act
says that if the military to use your
being
and as sociated force about data
they can detain you in definitely
without a trial
so always surprises happening as owner
and so they said well you look in on
some what you're next on your father
that called you a different first name
which happens only
millions of people you know that
different first there's a setup right
i've got enough i'm suspicious of you
looked you look like you're a foreigner
uh... let's put your ass and joanne not
even bothered to look up we were right
or wrong can you on magic on the part of
their wages they honestly
is is that women on the war power
this is true
is that they don't give a damn about us
man
you think that if you're rich and
powerful usage over four and a half
months
million bankers ever seen for a half
minutes until about four ab months
and after all that front again but if
you don't have any power
yeah nobody gives a damn
change filmmaker cartridge good maker
house things that they will undermine
she has a fourteen year old daughter
that she couldn't take care of fraph
four and a half months because she was
uh... thrown in jail for something that
she didn't do right
and also i want to go back to something
you said jake about arizona voters and
how they probably thought aryan out
there by the criminals then he average
and put them away without bail them out
this is a very specific piece of uh...
this is a very specific proposition
right where they said undocumented
immigrants do not get to post bail and
i'm one hundred percent disagree with
what you said this was something that
was targeted against undocumented
immigrants arizona has a history of
discriminating against hispanics and
this is another piece of the i can say
what is it considered legislation if
it's proposition it's another
proposition that's eight
at you know destroying families in
arizona if they're brown and i'm real
and tired of it and i'm tired of making
excuses for people in arizona attack
making excuses for conservatives in the
country people who want to discriminate
against people of color
that's what's happening in this state
well done and uh... so it is true that
i'm at a summit on top of it
which is that
with dressing crazy is that okay you
want are you done document people right
ok anyway might disagree with them when
i think that there's a better way to
address that issue which is a real issue
itself right
if u judge people guilty
before there's even a trial you don't
even know what they're under outstanding
she was perfectly documented
and you think that white people get live
in the guide name robert johnson gets
locked up for being on diamond look even
blood people even black i get slide them
in arizona
uh... because uh... they thought he was
on document now the my liable for other
reasons that i a lot of over there is an
obviously this specifically allows
corrupt law enforcement to go after but
he does in america
and the guy who ascended uh... the the
top of the detective locker but the
first place
he lied on the stand and said oh yeah i
have information
that does she herd ever do
though driving it is a forgery the
prosecution literally had one at the
cabinet witness in this case right
and that witness was one of the
investigators and he claimed that vital
records which holds the purse
certificates in arizona claimed
that they had canceled this woman's
birth certificate because of forgery
that the document was completely
fabricated made up that it was not real
however vinyl records justified said no
that's not the case at all he is lying
the president again israel it always has
been it always will be
i mean it's not really mobile hot
can get away with lying on the stand
like that
lying to the grand jury about i'm sure
though that for that line which is by
the way it legal to do that on this for
testimony
that you'll spend for a half months in
jail right near doubt but
that's a good or arizona's a scary scary
place man especially if you're latino