fly with force.
And you can't just have
one ping pong ball.
It's better if you have dozens
and dozens and dozens of ping
pong balls.
I want to find a way
to launch them.
I think I have some
really cool ideas.
I'm Steve Spangler, and I'm all
about making science fun.
For the last 20 years, I've
been teaching ways to turn
ordinary science experiments
into unforgettable learning
experiences.
I have an amazing team who will
do whatever it takes to
affect the way people
think about science.
And do that, I live
by one motto--
make it big, do it right,
give it class.
As a kid, I remember this ping
pong ball popper that was
pretty cool.
It was just this kind
of rubber device
that had air inside.
You would just kind of push this
inside and squeeze it.
It would pop.
It wasn't terribly exciting,
but it was a
ping pong ball launcher.
And then I saw this
at the auto store.
It's a battery filler.
See this?
This might be perfect
for the first part.
Now, I'm not advocating
that you tear this
apart at the store.
You're going to have
to buy it first.
But that's the piece that you
want-- this to the wayside.
All right.
So here's what happens is the
ping pong ball fits perfectly
inside here like this.
It's just got enough pressure
around it, like that.
That's perfect.
And when you squeeze
it-- here, watch.
Bam.
This is a pretty good.
What if there was an explosion
inside, firing the ball out?
That would be even better.
And to do that, we've got to
go to the camping aisle.
Well, this is what you're
looking for.
It's a lantern spark igniter.
So when you twist it,
the flint inside
gives it a little spark.
This is what you're
going to need.
So take that home.
You're also going to need to
have some simple rules.
And we're ready to build
ourselves an igniter.
The first step is to take that
battery bulb and to poke a
hole in it.
The size of a screwdriver seems
to be just about right.
I don't want it too big-- kind
of see what's going on inside,
just kind of poking it
through like that.
That will be perfect.
And then you just need to take
apart the lantern lighter--
the little spark
igniter, right?
So what I did was, just with a
pair of pliers, loosened this
and took this apart.
All right?
You need to be careful, because
this is spring-loaded.
It'll pop out, and it takes you
another five minutes to
stick everything
back in again.
What we want to do is to get
this inside the bulb.
So I'm going to put this down
inside and try to feed that in
through here so it pops out
the other side, and we can
twist this in place.
Oh, that's perfect.
This is what we're
trying to do.
Take a look at this.
See how I finally get this down
inside here like this?
That's perfect.
Again, you want to be very
careful that you don't push on
this little piece here,
or it'll pop out.
Now, I'm going to try to expose
the threads that are
right there--
so you see-- so we have
something to grab onto--
that part right there.
Washer goes on top like this.
This piece goes on top.
And now you just have to
screw it together.
The entire time, I'm keeping my
finger on that little flute
mechanism that's inside so
it doesn't pop back.
So that's pretty good.
I'm even going to try to tighten
it up a little bit
just so it doesn't
come undone.
Perfect.
Now, the last part will make
you very angry if you don't
keep your finger on that flint,
because it's now time
to put this end back on.
And if you're not careful,
it'll pop
right back out again.
So put this on here like this.
All right, perfect.
I think this should be great.
Take a look down inside
here like this.
Watch.
When you spin it, watch.
See the little spark
that's inside?
That's the spark that we want
to ignite the fuel that
eventually will pop the
ping pong ball out.
I think this is great.
All right, safety first,
because now it's
time for the fuel.
And if you're a minor, make
sure that you get an adult
who's going to help
you out with this.
Here's the fuel--
90% rubbing alcohol.
I think this says 91%.
Most rubbing alcohol is 70%.
You're going to have to go to
the drugstore for this.
And since I'm only going to use
drops at a time and I want
to pour a lot out, I simply
switched a small amount to
this bottle right here.
All right.
You just need a small amount
of the rubbing alcohol, so
this is 15 or 20 drops
in here like this.
I'm being careful not to
get the flint wet.
And if you've shot it before,
because there's no oxygen
inside, you're going to go a
little bit of air inside--
just trying to move it
around so there's
enough there to combust.
Now, you need to
ping pong ball.
Ping pong ball goes down
inside like this.
So now, here's what happens.
Be careful.
This is the business end.
So when you flick it like this,
you get a spark inside.
The spark ignites the
rubbing alcohol.
The rubbing alcohol expands as
it turns into a gas, and
hopefully it shoots the
ping pong ball out.
It looks something like this.
What?
You want me to do it again?
Of course.
I have an entire bucket
of these and a
lot of rubbing alcohol.
[HUMMING 'POP GOES
THE WEASEL']
STEVE SPANGLER: Pop
goes the wea--
sorry--
the weasel.
Now, if for any reason there's
still a flame that's here,
that's why I have a
plate close by.
I just put the plate over the
top and it stops the flame
completely.
Don't put your hand
over the top.
Just put the plate over the
top and everything is set.
This is a pretty cool ping
pong ball launcher.
So we were recently contacted
by a marketing firm that
actually works for YouTube,
and they wanted us to fire
some ping pong balls.
But they wanted us to fire
of more than just
one ping pong ball.
They wanted 6,000
ping pong balls.
And if you're going to fire
6,000 ping pong balls, this is
probably not a good idea.
So I knew I needed to
have a bigger space.
So I got some liquid nitrogen,
a 55 gallon drum, 6,000 ping
pong balls, and a little
bit bigger space.
And I think we got just exactly
what they needed.
Watch out.
All right, so here's what
we're doing right now.
We just want to test just the
liquid nitrogen in the barrel
and just see kind of
what happens before
the ping pong balls.
It's actually much better with
the ping pong balls, because
they cushion them.
So this is going to be the worst
loud explosion up here.
We want to see what happens.
So this is what's happening.
We're behind the scenes.
We're just making sure that all
the cameras are set and
we're ready to go.
And everybody's got glasses
and year protection.
And come here.
Look at this.
Brian's still working.
See?
He just has his little
headphones on and he's still
working, because why
wouldn't he?
All right.
So here's our liquid nitrogen
sitting in here.
I'm going to cap it off.
It's going to go inside
the barrel.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[EXPLOSION]
STEVE SPANGLER: Did I mention
don't try this at home?
Take a look at what happens
here, right?
So please understand that
we're under a protective
environment, and just don't
try this at home.
MALE SPEAKER: Whoa!
MALE SPEAKER: [INAUDIBLE]
five.
MALE SPEAKER: Whoa!
STEVE SPANGLER: What's important
about this is we get
pristine two liter bottles.
We don't want anything that's
been crushed or wrinkled or
anything like that.
That's a bad situation.
I don't know what the stress is
on that bottle, so I want
brand new ones.
This is Brad Montgomery--
a really, really good friend,
funny, funny, funny, comedian,
magician, best friend.
This is how it works.
BRAD MONTGOMERY: New
glasses work.
STEVE SPANGLER: Yes, and he's
got his new glasses.
And the deal is we're going
stage him in my office.
And so he's just supposed to
sit there and just pretend
like he doesn't even realize
what's going to happen.
BRAD MONTGOMERY: And I'm totally
going to prank with
your computer.
STEVE SPANGLER: Yeah.
Why don't you be the
safety advisor?
BRAD MONTGOMERY: Yes.
Steve's making a big
fuss over this.
It's not a horrible idea, but
I'm telling you, it's not as
cool as he thought, because
I did this yesterday.
OK, not totally 6,000--
around 3,000, 3,500
ping pong balls.
So I mean, it's pretty cool.
You'd think he's--
woo, 6,000!
Whatever.
STEVE SPANGLER: Oh,
that's perfect.
I'm ready.
For today's experiment, we're
going to demonstrate just how
many views YouTube Mobile
gets in a single day.
So let's say this represents
YouTube.
See that ping pong
ball right there?
It represents 100,000 views
from mobile devices.
And this bottle of
liquid nitrogen?
It doesn't represent anything.
It's just really cool.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
STEVE SPANGLER: Don't
try this at home.
129,200,000 views, 129,300,000
views, 129,400,000 views,
129,500,000 views--
FEMALE SPEAKER: Steve.
Steve.
STEVE SPANGLER: What?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Do you want
tuna salad or turkey wrap?
STEVE SPANGLER: I want
turkey wrap.
FEMALE SPEAKER: OK.
STEVE SPANGLER: Thanks.
A hundred--
[SIGH]
[BLEEP].
100,000 views, 200,000 views--