cousins of stones make up the site
placed with perfect precision some
weighing more than twenty tongs
each was cut off to moved into place
using only human labor
primitive to me
built on the ambition of a
stock and crap
it is the spectacular legacy of the
greatest and file their medicare
and conquest
this is the city in the sky
macho preacher
pulleys donald razor sharp bridge
high-end e_m_t_s mountainous sits one of
the most spectacular places in the world
much of a feature
touched four hundred and fifteen inches
above the local bombardment
the city once contained everything
required for daily life
houses
fields
water channels
all with breathtaking view
but might you be chu is no ordinary city
started amongst its terraces uh...
enigmatic structures
magnificent temples somehow linked with
the sun
undergrads and disturbing
perhaps
they provide tantalizing clues as to why
anyone would build such poor beating
terrain
the sites selected is a particularly
difficult one just remote technical
standpoint
architect vince lee believes that no one
would choose to be okay
without good reason
there's very little workspaces just on a
very sharp
leverage
there's almost no flatlands
so why would anyone built
in this impossible locations
what drove much of peaches makers to
construct a city
on says lying in the forging oven and
cry
and the creation
of alleged
in fourteen thirty eight trying to what
he is
launched a massive attack on the
neighbors
income
with the enemy pleased at the gates of
his capital the bojenka and perhaps lead
to safety
but his son was defiant
are
spurred on by a vision predicting
victory
delayed the into into a seemingly
impossible struck
ayala
digestive problems incapacity invaders
and proclaimed their young leader here
bestowing upon him
a prophetic can you name
puja kooky
transformer perfectly
and pressure could be wasted no time
living up to his title
exceedingly apart from his father
he embarked upon a campaign to conquer
neighboring nations
after cookies military might
quickly prevails
within his lifetime he laid the
groundwork for an empire that would
stretch up and down the pacific coast of
south america
i think of him as a sort of alexander
the great the andes
alter and explorer peter frost has
traced income history for thirty years
press secretary was the man
pretending 'cause from regional power
and the cost of value into an empire the
biggest and by the america's ever saw
spreading from modern-day columbia is
north to chile and argentina inside
the empire of include would come undone
modality of more than ten million people
but you could keep order the series of
massive
dates that would help is on the control
this box territory
but military engineering was any part of
the empress grandparent
such a cutie also plan to stay
calculus city to demonstrate his policy
new status
much of that you can accommodate up to
one thousand people
yet it was built higher in the andes
mountains huntington sixty kilometers
from the center of his empire
some experts think it was a royal
retreat
the ruling paradigms have it at the
moment
is that this was a winter palace
of the past pretty
and he held his court here for two or
three months during the winter
the peter frost believes this theory is
too limited to seize it just slip into
thinking european you know
henry the eighth stands in court or
whatever at windsor castle and uh... for
signing might find that
inadequate
for prostate cancer is reliant
inconsiderate truly score
the inca worship natural features of the
landscape and the heavens honoring them
as gods
who stephens extended to the
anthropological t
but we have to remember that vehicle
nato and perot was quite as simple as
that gardening he was the leader of the
religion
he was considered to be sending divine
or fully designed and the son of the sun
analysis formal position within the inca
empire
as so allot of his
activity must have been a religious
that much impeaching researchers have
identified a unique combination of
natural features to create a religious
phenomenon known as axis mundi
a secret sent
the site is a spiritual union of the sky
thank goodness
sacred mountain slightly compass points
from actual petri
directly above that amount and overlooks
the site chinese the custom nation known
as the southern cross
who's perfect alignment in the courtroom
signifies the start of the hottest
much happy to be surrounded by natural
features imbued with spiritual sickness
making it a unique place perpetual kruti
to worship and communion with the calls
now that patrick routine pictures in
this site for his spiritual retreat
his engineers mia mortals
had to achieve the vision affect god
impressed
i think they are ever probably decide
well nevertheless
that's where i want my
noted
palace it so it's up to you guys to
figure out a do it
for decades vince lee has wrestled with
the mystery of how they can comfortably
system
the terrain is a jungle covered richer
fractured iraq at an altitude of two
thousand four hundred and fifty meters
how detach a coaches engineers tame
dislocation
how to take warren
tons of rock with only the most
primitive of tours
power to protect the site from the heavy
rains earthquakes
the threatened descended tumbling into
the river below
might you be chu is a truly spectacular
sight
but its location caused huge problems
for its buildings
the ridges uneven
strewn with fractured and broken ground
sheer cliffs plunge down to the forests
below
each year
torrential storms conduct two hundred
centimeters of rain onto the
mountainside
it is also prone to earthquakes
it's landslides caused by these
conditions could have carried the city
away
as they began clearing the meant to be
true site
the time is needed to work out a way to
bank of the city to a place designed by
nature to repent of humans
they're spectacular solution is clear to
see today
terraces hundreds of them carved into
the slopes of much of peaches
they hoped you buy an area roughly the
size of twelve football pitches
these terraces cobb usable space from
the mounting
uncontrolled runoff prevent erosion
that you can use these fields to grow
food than ceremonial crops
the terrace waltz also provided decadent
benefit
during the day they absorb heat from the
side
but tonight the walls radiates warmth
into the bathroom which would have
protected the crops
but the terraces had an even more
important function
reinforcing the slowed
which pulls away at a gradient of up to
fifty percent
the secret is in the design of the
terror schools
these walls a slipped back
all packed with at about
five degree angle
bracing the hillside by pushing against
it
and channeling the weight of the soul
into the ground below
the terraces were critical to support
the construction of hundreds of
structure
someone mountain slopes
and that is more to the status is than
meets the eye
recent excavations repeal one of the
hidden secrets of touch equities
engineer
sixty percent of mucho teacher is
underground
after eating up the terrain
clearing the rock
impacted in crevices
uncertainties engineer
as caffeine a download
system from swine
they put them on stands at the bottom
then increasingly smaller stands almost
immediately
continue to surface
and then they added sametime homeless
and tops
this ingenious design gave the waltz a
solid foundation
and the smaller stones on talked with
the larger below
forces rainwater to percolate down
slowly no cracks
and disperse evenly through the terrace
slowing regulating the flow of water and
preventing the erosion of topsoil
at the bottom of this uh... on the
inside if it out of school
the water is charming sideways towards
one of the larger canals to drain the
site so that it flows harmlessly into
the valley
the sophistication of the terraces is
just a hint of brilliantly adapted
income weather
that ingenuity was vital when it came to
sourcing materials to build logic which
is sacred city
he's an ambitious plan required tons of
stuff
bringing materials up the mountain
without wheeled vehicles couple forces
would have been almost impossible
fortunately patrick reduced emissions
had a solution
giant granite voters was strewn all
across the ridge
because just a little blocked that much
on the side
weighs about a hundred and seventy five
pounds which is to say you know i can
pick it up
you know and and that would be one of
the smaller stones in the project almost
all the stones in those buildings or at
least update were bigger
somehow one institution constructs
weighing up to twenty times from the
quality to the site
the logistics of creating architecture
or enormous
for professor susan miles
incas greatest challenge was the lack of
sophisticated equipment
this is not a culture with wheels with
kraft animals with
the kinds of
uh... machines that we take for granted
this is using human labor to move things
destroying end in the seventeenth
century illustrates how the income might
have pulled it off
incur we taunton animal fibers into
ficus trends
amid twisted the strands in to great
lengths of strong rope
using these groups
such approaches work crews would have
been able to drive cubes turns into
place
but even the level of service would
present a problem
this matter
the fiction created beneath the rockies
imu
and the leading edge of raw constantly
scoops up there
creating even more resistance
such a good easter masons have to find
ways of overcoming this
first to lighten the load
they rough shape the granite inquiry
chipping off the excess with
hammerstein's
but much of the choose quantity you can
still see waste in mason's left them all
you can see the all around the this this
section of the rock they've been cutting
santana stands
cutting this service end of the block
would eventually so lost and then they
would start to
work it into a shape that they could use
the building
once they had a march to mostly shaped
employed yet another shrewd trick to
help them moved
but very clever they would take that
bottom of the stone smooth off they
would chip off all the edges all the way
around so that that ended up slightly
convex like the bottom of the boat or a
barge
and that way
ticketno x_-rated easily without here
just to do
limited turner quite easily dash
the workers might also come to the
ground with small stones and gravel
which act like war zones
so that's a huge blocks from the law
this huge slab granite at metro feature
abandoned into working
gives us a snapshot work in progress
these techniques work well for smaller
stains
but as evidence from you get to the
statues of easter island suggests
moving largest earns requires the use of
other techniques
most people think lowers were used
routinely will big stones ninety-degree
rollers are very hard to use in the
field
their possible use going up going
downhill the problem is you have to
little friction you can't control the
stove
you're fighting the keystone sinet zero
round all the time
and in the tight workspace on the
mountain ridge this approved
there wasn't enough space to have dozens
of men polling groups
especially when placing stands on the
new perfectly
fees for sticking could prove to find
ways to reduce the number of workers
needed to move lobsters up and down the
slopes
what you really want is what we call
sleepers switches
like roars but they're fixed they can't
roll
and across that you can move a slight
quite easily
vince lee believes he knows how they can
come move to stands around the site
he says they may have used mechanism
sleds why this letter on the ground the
leader of a string this letter in the
wonder garages that the wrongs
stick out
beyond upright on the side to the latest
on the ground
going to take a second one for on top of
the first one
and you put your stone on top of the
second latter now with levers you can
apply force between you know rigors of
the slide the sliding sled is carrying
the stone and the latter that stuck to
the ground by gravity
rejection status routinely and i think
the intersted to in close quarters
this technique would have allowed the
inca tombstones over the city rough
terrain
it also means you don't have a fancy
road is up to the latter just sleepy
plead for all you want lower and for all
the other news call the countryside
using clever techniques incur found ways
of moving stones across the difficult
site
but the job
recruiting such an enormous workforce
might seem a clinton prospect
here in ca and prayer
this challenge was to use in the mail
and it was manage through taxation
incas subjects could pay off the taxes
that go to the empire by providing
physical labor
overseas assembled huge work crews
and these citizen workers
had passed a budget used to have a slave
labor
you know you can make slaves go to work
but you can't make them do a good job
leads and they can do is look busy all
day long
then that the workers that did this inka
stuff took the time to do it right we
think that's probably because they had
some stage in the results they work
proud of what they were doing as opposed
to simply
being forced to do it by overlords
despite the care they taken
inka builders were about to discover
that it doesn't take much to undo weeks
of work
in this land of heavy rains and unstable
slopes
one tiny mistake
can bring everything crashing down
touched on a precarious mountain ridge
machu peaches engineers were engaged in
a constant battle with gravity
the terraces they had so carefully
constructed sculpted the mountainside
supporting the city
anchoring it to the landscape
but today in the lower terraces a
disruption can be seen in the pattern
something not attended schools onto the
language
others disappeared and i think i think
blanket
higher-ups
so steep slope is no shaken off the soil
wants clinton
this
was a landslide
uh... has given away on the natural
fault line
damaging the texas
believed to be a slow but destructive of
any
it stretches a hundred and forty meters
down the hillside
remain
project which is what cruise contracted
as always assessing the coolest
implementing the plan and repairing the
damage
there so you shouldn't is familiar to
modern-day engineers but five hundred
years ago
it was revolution
but you could use manned carter drainage
channels above the disrupted terraces to
redirect surface water
and prevent for the damage
they couldn't afford to take any chances
if the heavy rains of the region had
said to the foundations
the water-logged substructure may have
slid away with catastrophic results
building by building all by war
the engineers punctuated the site with
training job placement on the spot
a hundred and thirteen
in heavy rains these channels diverted
water into a large storm sewer
fit safely emptied into the rain forest
gump one thing in that i will see an and
must be to his approval to standing on
the surface
and as much as it rains anna sometimes
there is really hot here that's always
training and why you never see it
once the land was cleared in these firm
foundations were laid off
but you could use to make sense to build
the homes classes and temples would make
up the site
as always they've worked with nature
sculpting
so that he had the buildings flute
gracefully across the mountain top
most cultures
sort of cut the top off we certainly do
for example in our culture just cut the
top off into the building on top of
somehow the incas managed to celebrate
the natural contour of the land and a
natural amenities of the land
and enhance them with their structures
rather than uh... or at work contrary to
them very unusual and beautifully done
temples for worship
poses for a living
bathing areas underground plaza for
gatherings in gangs
only the rock walls remain
thatched roofs once act on these
structures and ship the heavy rains
but that's not all they had withstand
in this half hour while you do can get
to have very strong winds sometimes in
the andes and
at flows over the top of the roof like
and flying over the top of the wing
of an aircraft and is listed underneath
anika does
left there is straight off
so the roofs needed to be launched from
each of the structure
think i had strong wrote
but little else
as always
from the solution mister
if you look at the uh... end of the
building here you can see the always
stand pegs
and if you follow the line of the table
and
you can see these rang stands
sat and sunday when this was part of the
system for securing the roofing sanden
reflects aerials
the roof makes for each of the hundred
and seventy structures that make up the
urban section of my tribute you will
build and assembled onsite
but the truly remarkable craftsmanship
using these features
windows and dogs
framed out of wrong
these distinctive trapeze illegal shapes
of the roxanne golden window frames take
us back to the height of income cult
room power
each one was carlton placed by highly
skilled stone masons
the masons joins us turns without using
cement removed
get the seems oxen
tight fate does martingale architect
you often hear people say oh you can't
get a knife blade in detroit
he can't do anything in the jury in some
of these places that the stone just
simply changes color a little as it goes
across the truth
it is racquel
party committees craftsman to achieve
such quality without i'm trumbull seems
impossible
get the stones the cross check
fit together precise
researchers have found a vital clues to
the inka technique in these large
granite chunks left unfinished much a
patient
smooth pock marks in this interesting to
take the use of smaller stones called
hammerstein
to shape the rock
interested workers pounded the surface
of the granite with these rounded stones
obtained from britain france
until
they had a smooth surface
company dust
as the next stone was laid the stone
mason used imprints in the dust as a
guide to areas needing further
using progressively smaller understands
the mason city do closer and closer
fixed until the facing top and bottom
sentences
perfect now
this method created a unique feature
income architecture
you'll never find a straight line for a
little corner
in anika
building unless it's done by accident
you'll never find that
you'll see sights which superficially
appear to be sort of square off stones
but if you started and carefully
they weren't square alderdice slightly
offs where they they
and this is very very difficult to do it
as long as always the change of chintz
people discovered that the easy way to
put two big stones together is to
flatten off the site
benefit that you flip charts together
will never see that it's a building
how would you be inka managed to get
these irregular shaped stones to match
up so perfect
once again the stones themselves provide
the clues
these walls have sexual slightly and
pulled the stands apart
what they've done here
is they've made a perfect chilling
between each stunned
all the way to the fact that hold this
is the stone
and not only that but it's once faces
conclave than the others contracts sows
that totally fitted together as very
difficult way to accomplish
the same perfect fit confirmed all over
the site
both in smaller stones and in the larger
ones
they appear to have been created by the
same method if
removing and repeating regardless of
sons
so the question is
out of the chief that fit
vince lee thinks he may have to be
honest
it's called scraping
a technique sometimes used by you don't
cut in campus defective regular milk
surfaces together
as much a teacher
the stone masons transferred the shape
of once turned to richmond
using a protracted to mirror the edge of
one surface them up to and shipped it to
fix the opposite step
well it's not important to either
surface is flat
all we know is that they will be perfect
matches for each other and then we can
one-time slide the stones together
they'll have to fit
to build a senator row upon wrote
precisely fitted stones against each
other in new york perfectly
budget committees masons also carefully
automated systems tracing them
vertically and horizontally to spread
the loot evenly throughout the temple
on top of the building the perfect
alignment of the finally fiji huge bloc
seems to be playing craft
these all stony projections
provide the clues to its construction
to access the top and bottom portions of
the rocks they used a system of
believers
this is how it works
stone collar scarf to groove into one
side granite block
labor's used to wouldn't post to lead to
the block apollo ankle
allowing sliders to shake the top and
bottom sides walk with hummus tufts
this created
into the war
that record crop in the store up in the
air which before
spooked by with some good reason
but uh... but i've done it and it works
the careful efforts apache produced in
mason's uh... evident all over the
finest structures that much of peter
at the top of the staircase and hard
opposite the palace stands the city's
crown jewel
are uniquely shaped building
extra care has been put into place
deconstruction
the buildings walls artists actually
unusual
the curve of the bedrock creating a semi
circle
the centerpiece of the structure is this
a card standpoint
opposition to play awfully jim
mysterious way
sir what was this fall
after winter solstice
it aligns perfectly with the window
but somehow
i have a randstad
actually i and i still on the first
photographs that was a mistake
on the twenty first of june nineteen
eighty
four peter frost got up before door and
waited for the sun to rise you think of
fast that nothing's gonna happen next
the sun's coming up
and there's no question like no sunday
at seven twenty realizes this
patch of lights suddenly
comes alive you know and then is tacitly
divided by that kind of stones
for peter frost this is evidence that
the temple was used as a symbol of
observatory
there's really a m
vindicates a lot of people's ideas
actually about being concerned about
what was being done here
this is the temple of the sermon
and it has been dark undersigned
what lies beneath contains puzzling
clues that continue tourist info
beneath the temple of the sunlight is
this mysterious substructure
the entire building with integrated
almost seamlessly into a colossal
greenwich boomed
a stone giant
that serves as the temple's foundation
of very fine example of the harmonious
architecture than the incas digitas
over instead of c l_ slacking off a
piece of land and plunking down a
building on it they've built around the
landscape they they made the landscape
parts of the architecture
but that's not where it ends within it
that is a flat future
some say this is a small train departure
mama
the us mother
you can see that they've
actually busted a huge block of stones
of as this front page of it
sheer project which is still nations
exploited this natural came
they expanded it
and adorned it with hand-carved nishu
picasa stepping like feature into the
natural stone
and carved out an extraordinary
hourglass shaped inlay
they made the joints square
rather than london in the classic
entrance to her
but walked was it's purpose
peter frost thinks he knows the answer
in the general aspect of this is his
uh...
some kind of
buried important ceremonial place
as it's been speculated a royal
mausoleum when a cat monies
unlike egyptian fairest incumbent
president not prepare for a resurrection
in the afterlife
they believe that after death they
entered another form of life and
continued to wield power overt daily
events
the mummies were fed and cared for
they were included responded guests
doing important rituals and ceremonies
including ceremonies of sacrifice
when the high priests solemnly offered
precious metals
on the most significant separate
occasions
offered up the lives of young children
no offering was great
budget committee chose this ritual site
because it was so close to the dogs
but the function properly
it would have to support up to a
thousand people
and those people would need water
at an altitude of two thousand four
hundred and fifty meters on a narrow
margin ridge
much impeach you is well above the most
obvious loves the organ bump over time
which snakes a dizzying
four hundred and fifty meters
yes but you could use engineers found in
this powering landscape that by some
miracle
the colts provided them with the water
they need
the inca did not have the benefit of
satellite imagery
if they had
they would have seen that the medical
was in fact due to to geological faults
immense cracks or ruptures in the
granite
at some point the ridge between these
forms collapsed
sliding down roots to form the site of
much of peaches
one of the false fronts is a giant slope
a fractured granite
offerings shrouded in cologne
the resulting rain water streams down
the granite wall and collects forming a
natural spring that was discovered by
patrick routines engineers
to capture the water the income
constructed an enormous war more than
fourteen in the hostages law
picketed the stone houston
so that water would collect behind the
wall and see-through under control
into a large basin
even today interest-free
with the site seven hundred and forty
nine meters from the reservoir
project which is engineers filter water
canals with cuts and sudden precisely
designed at the water flowed at a
perfect rate
with minimum c
whatever they did they did as
efficiently as possible
these were not wasteful people these are
not people through a time or energy or
resources they did everything as quickly
and as
well as they could
elevated on its own carries the canal
carried up to a hundred and fifty liters
of water per minute
bypassing the agricultural fields
install houses
its first destination
clearly by design
was the private function of inka emperor
punch scooty
he would have had like a spouse coming
uh... bases the splashed uh... facing
down below
and no doubt is less people to support
services trades and also this is a
debating may have been ceremonial maybe
rachel type of a million years well
every care was taken with the design
parent company she is lined the walls
there was even a train
which is this
water channel cut into sully bedrock
deep
with uh... a little bridge that they've
left here with a water flows out
the empress private box was just one of
sixteen unique hand carved pumpkins
from united made its way throughout the
city
no detail was overlooked
pick up the functions of so that the
waters spilled away from the budget
water filled the distinctive in cold
water jugs
called by the files
for the inka wateman was secret
by mustering water logic which he
demonstrated his godlike powers to
control
forces of the world
and his ambition didn't spend that
of the highest point of the site was the
focal point
patcha kuti secret axis
he controlled the f
he controls the stone
and he controlled water
budget committee
wanted to harness the sunday
tolerating high above mitchell p chu is
one of its most talked about features
but you could use mason scarface
abstract shape from a single piece of
background
i think it looks
absolutely martin absolutely
contemporary
fitness out that they would like to do
it
fatalistic in the museum of modern art
new york and it would look absolutely a
home
while experts concede the system what
purpose this remarkable sculptures serve
it's perfect alignment with the
surrounding geography provides hints to
its function
he'd lies on the north-south line the
can be drawn between monk who end up
kitchen
amounts of contain
the highest peak in the region
this north-south line can be by sick to
my auntie's waistline
drawn from the sculpture itself
two months and make it
pricier on the soda equinox is the son
sits precisely about this culture
and costs no shadow
and amazingly the pilla itself seems to
be column to represent at least tour of
the surrounding peaks
all of this points tantalizingly towards
one of the incas most deeply-held
beliefs
inka may have symbolically tied to send
to this place to prevented from
travelling too far away during the
solstice s
this is the into what time
host of the sun
despite more than five hundred years of
torrential rains earthquakes and
landslides danielle perfection of much
of the future defies logic
but there are places where the inka
engineers worked is not quite so perfect
not far away from the hitching post of
the sun
east wall of the principal tempo sinking
into the ground
what went wrong here
bill on bedrock that wouldn't happen
errors on bedrock by then
survey on the subsoil is being washed
away and it's
gradually sinking
and that any excavation revealed that
the foundations for this great temple
appear to be determine
leading scholars mystified
i don't think we can quite be sure
when the failure took place but
come but it's not typical of ink
construction so there was some other
factor it works and it is entirely
possible that they were under some
pressure to complete that part of the
project
and they just decided to cut corner in
that case
if the trouble account during
construction
why did they not attempt to repair the
damage
as they've done in the taxes
some speculate that the temple collapsed
because when they think a face that
greatest threat
did four years after budget committee
created his empire
an explorer set off to find that you
were
in fourteen ninety-two
christopher columbus sailed from the
small spanish port of palestinian from
canada
out into the atlantic he arrived india
medicare's and opened the door to the
spanish
and back home he stumbles
so it was that less than a hundred years
after project which you found it much
impeachment
the spanish conquistadors shocked at the
empire
mounted or forces and armed with weapons
are known to be in ca
towns
but less and more catastrophic for the
entire than any army fate brought a new
disease
smallpox
millions diet
inka empire crumbled
this once bustling center was up and
with some of the work are finished
stand still waiting for hands to push
them into position
today at the rear of the ill-fated
principal temple huge stones can be seen
clearly intended for the finer finish
you can say have a jut out way beyond
the playing of the wall itself
so undoubtedly this was unfinished
business
and people say uh-oh
so much of the jaws of finished and and
i admire sponsor that is is new york
city finished
no it's not because it's a living city
that constantly things being bill
constantly things being demolished there
was changing this changing that that's
the way it was a much bt tourism is a
living
uh... environment for people who are
here
with the collapse of the entire supply
lines
dinka abandoned
could lead to picture
and the city disappears for four hundred
years
until american archaeologist hiram
bingham
pushed his way through the undergrads
and was confronted by a magnificent
stole
who holds muscle control
but you could do secret city in the sky
mar
conceived to impress the goats into
astounded me a mortals
this great stone city remains unique
achievement
they didn't have much technology but
they were every bit as smart as we are
they just had fewer things to think
about they had fewer tools to work with
your materials to consider
and they probably knew more about
stilled and we will ever cream of
knowing
one of the world's greatest engineering
achievement much impeaching remains a
spot djibouti impatient
tinkers with slightly crazy
brilliantly crazy they did the
extraordinary things things that
nobody else would have thought of doing
building
this extraordinary city here
on top of the nineteen ridge
it's an enduring monument to the really
and spend ingenuity
of the income we don't think that we
know help ought to cut is workers
conquered all of these difficulties
we know that they did because not to
keep to is the evidence
completed or not the site is one of the
most amazing structures in the world
channels feeding the city with an
abundant and constant supply of water
a massive earthquake-proof substructure
supporting terraces stonewall quays
plazas homes and temples a testament to
incur engineering
and the ability to build mega structures
in the most challenging locations
time to an emperor determined to prove
his place among the costs
live
uh...