JASON CROMBIE: Hi, I'm
Jason Crombie.
And today I'm going to meet a
guy called Itsi who's New
York's only Segway instructor.
He's going to teach me
how to ride a Segway.
And I'm also going to meet the
people from the New York City
Jedi Academy.
And they're going to teach me
how to handle a lightsaber.
And then, when I'm good at
both of those things, I'm
going to fight somebody on a
Segway with a lightsaber.
ITSI ATKINS: Show the girls.
No, come on--
it's not about your breasts,
it's about--
GABI: The balance?
ITSI ATKINS: It's about
the balance center.
See-- this is the headline,
from here to here.
So directly middle of the
headline is the maximum force.
It's kind of like the pyramid
structure, where the Earth
brings the energy from
the pyramids.
Actually, chest out, and you'll
pull forward, see?
JASON CROMBIE: Oh, just leaning
forward, is that it?
ITSI ATKINS: That's it.
JASON CROMBIE: Oh.
ITSI ATKINS: Now, let me tell
you the real thing.
JASON CROMBIE: Sorry, dude.
ITSI ATKINS: Toes down,
you'll go forward.
Heels down, you'll go back.
JASON CROMBIE: Oh,
that's easy.
That's easy.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
They're bloody dangerous.
ITSI ATKINS: [INAUDIBLE].
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Jesus.
JASON CROMBIE: I'm going
to get mauled by a
cat in one of those.
[INAUDIBLE].
ITSI ATKINS: OK, let's
go upstairs.
I wanna wash my hands.
Take a pee.
JASON CROMBIE: I'm gonna
give you your bag back.
ITSI ATKINS: Here you go.
OK.
I design handbags.
It's the Bush shoe-throwing
handbag.
AMY: No.
ITSI ATKINS: Now stop.
JASON CROMBIE: What's
with the paddles?
ITSI ATKINS: It's like a
bullfight where you go by and
you get paddled.
And then, if you're not standing
up straight, I go,
stand up straight.
And it's this whole
choreography of--
JASON CROMBIE: So now I know how
to use a Segway, thanks to
Itsi and his paddling.
And now it's time for the New
York Jedi guys to show me how
to use a lightsaber.
[LIGHTSABER NOISES]
JEDI MALE 1: [INAUDIBLE],
come on.
Every idiot knows that pepper
boards do not go on the floor.
JEDI MALE 2: [INAUDIBLE]
JEDI MALE 3: They can take a bit
of a beating, and they can
give one, too.
FLYNN: You have the rebound,
the follow-through,
and then the lock.
So let's try that.
JASON CROMBIE: OK.
FLYNN: Rebound.
Follow-through.
JASON CROMBIE: So they're
actually touching--
on the follow-through?
FLYNN: Right, you actually
don't have to touch.
Like [INAUDIBLE], it's
a stage company.
JASON CROMBIE: OK.
FLYNN: So if we miss, just keep
on going to the next one.
JASON CROMBIE: OK.
FLYNN: So hit the rebound.
And follow-through.
Lock.
So what I'm doing is I'm
actually broadcasting to you,
ah, I'm coming over here.
That's part of stage combat.
I'm broadcasting
coming up here.
I'm over here.
JASON CROMBIE: Ah, gotcha.
FLYNN: In real sword
fighting--
JASON CROMBIE: Yeah, you
wouldn't do that,
you'd just be like--
FLYNN: No, I'd be like-- bang.
JASON CROMBIE: Oh, see,
you've already got me.
I'm just singed.
FLYNN: Mirror me, exactly
what I'm doing.
Right?
So, now, we now have a word.
In saber stage combat, this
is known as the Flynn.
It was not named after me.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
It's known as the Flynn?
FLYNN: Yeah, exactly,
Errol Flynn.
So, while he's acting, he's
like, Ah, I now have you where
I want you, Vizzini .
You're [INAUDIBLE].
I'm going to kill you.
Ha ha ha ha.
[GIGGLING]
FLYNN: Ha ha ha.
See, the same thing happens
with everybody.
They all giggle.
JASON CROMBIE: I'm really
bad at this.
JASON (OFFSCREEN): So I've
figured out how to use the
lightsaber and the Segway.
So now I'm gonna marry the two,
and we're gonna have the
very first Saberseg battle.
JASON CROMBIE: [INAUDIBLE].
FLYNN: Ha ha!
Oh!
[MACHINERY SQUEALING]
JASON CROMBIE: Whoa.
ITSI ATKINS: Whoa, whoa, whoa.
See what happens when you
start fucking around?
JASON CROMBIE: That
was really scary.
I thought my thing
was gonna go.
ITSI ATKINS: All right, I
think you got enough.
JASON (OFFSCREEN): I think
that's it, yeah.
FLYNN: I definitely haven't
gotten enough.