CARL AZUZ, CNN ANCHOR: Glad you`re starting
your new week with CNN STUDENT NEWS. My name
is Carl Azuz. We are going to start today
at the top of the U.S. Central Intelligence
Agency. That organization, the CIA, will be
getting a new director, because the previous
one resigned. On Friday, Director David Petraeus
turned in his resignation and admitted to
cheating on his wife. This all started with
an FBI investigation into emails being sent
by the woman who wrote Petraeus` biography.
The investigation turned up other emails that
revealed the CIA director`s affair.
Some congressional leaders, both Democrats
and Republicans, have raised questions about
why they were not told about the investigation
sooner, since it could have had an impact
on national security. The name David Petraeus
might be familiar to you. At different times,
he was the commander of U.S. forces in both
Iraq and Afghanistan. He became CIA director
in September of last year, after he officially
left the military.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
JONATHAN MANN, CNN CORRESPONDENT: I`m Jonathan
Mann, with another political jargon buster.
What is the fiscal cliff? It is shorthand
for the potential economic disaster that`s
facing Washington. In real terms, it`s the
$7 trillion in spending cuts and tax increases
scheduled to go into effect the beginning
of January. President and members of Congress
set the deadline themselves last year after
they failed to agree on how to reduce the
U.S. debt. Now, time is almost up, and Democrats
and Republicans remain far apart on a deal
that would reduce the deficit, reform the
tax system and U.S. entitlement programs like
Social Security, Medicare and Medicaid. Analysts
warn if there is no agreement, it could cripple
the U.S. economy and drive up unemployment.
Will the political standoff turn into an economic
disaster? U.S. politicians hope to avoid running
off the fiscal cliff.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: As they work to avoid running off that
cliff, one of the other things that politicians
will focus on is how much money Americans
pay in taxes. For anyone making less than
$250,000 a year, Republicans and Democrats
want tax rates to stay the same, to stay where
they are, but when it comes to those who make
more than $250,000, President Obama says they
should pay more in taxes. Republican leaders,
like House Speaker John Boehner say they don`t
want anyone`s taxes to go up.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
BAN KI-MOON, U.N. SECRETARY GENERAL: Education
is a fundamental human right. It is a pathway
to development, tolerance and global citizenship.
Join us in our campaign to put education first,
for Malala and girls and boys throughout the
world.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: All right. You heard U.N. Secretary
General Ban Ki-moon mention the name Malala.
He was talking about Malala Yousufzai. She
is the Pakistani teenager who was shot by
the Taliban because she stood up for education
rights for girls. Her efforts and the attack
on her gained international attention, and
the United Nations declared November 10 as
Malala Day. In her home country of Pakistan,
people marked the day by lighting candles
and holding vigils in Malala`s honor. Meanwhile,
she isn`t in her home country. After the attack,
Malala was transported to a hospital in England
for special treatment. Dan Rivers tells us
how recovery is going.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
DAN RIVERS, CNN CORRESPONDENT: It is staggering
to see Malala Yousufzai out of bed, with her
father looking through some of the thousands
of get-well cards she`s received. It`s exactly
a month since she was shot at pointblank range
by Taliban gunmen for her campaign for girls
education in Pakistan.
Despite the bullet passing through her head
and neck, she is able to talk. Doctors at
Birmingham`s Queen Elizabeth Hospital in Britain
are still assessing the extent of the brain
damage. Her only visitors so far have been
her immediate family.
ZIAUDDIN YOUSUFZAI, MALALA`S FATHER: I`m awfully
thankful to all peace-loving well wishers
of Malala Yousufzai, who strongly condemn
the assassination attempt on Malala, who pray
for her health, and who support the great
cause of Malala Yousufzai, that is peace,
education, freedom of thought and freedom
of expression.
RIVERS: The cards have come from all over
the world. This one from Myanmar or Burma.
Some are signed by entire households, some
by entire offices. Her story has touched people
around the world. And there is now an Internet
campaign for Malala to win the Nobel Peace
Prize. She`s yet to undergo surgery for her
skull and jaw in Britain, but judging by these
pictures, she is in very good hands, surprising
everyone with her determination to recover.
Dan Rivers, CNN, London.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: Americans celebrated Veterans Day yesterday,
honoring the men and women who`ve served in
the U.S. armed forces. Events and parades
like this on in Atlanta took place across
the country. President Obama was part of the
wreath laying ceremony at Arlington National
Cemetery. During a speech afterward, he talked
about America`s commitment to those who have
served.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
BARACK OBAMA, PRESIDENT OF THE U.S.: Each
year, on the 11th day of the 11th month, we
pause as a nation and as a people to pay tribute
to you, to thank you, to honor you, the heroes
over the generations who have served this
country of ours with distinction.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: The Purple Heart is America`s oldest
military medal. It is awarded to men and women
who have been killed or wounded in action
against an enemy of the United States. Now,
over time, some of the Purple Hearts that
had been awarded had been lost, but there
is one National Guardsman who is trying to
get some of these medals returned back home.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
BARBARA MACNEVIN, DAUGHTER OF PURPLE HEART
RECEPIENT: My dad, Ralph W. Bingham (ph).
He was the veteran of the first world war,
the big war. He lost his right leg fighting
in France, and he received a Purple Heart
for that. We had it for many years in my home,
where I grew up.
ROBERT MACNEVIN, GRANDSON OF PURPLE HEART
RECEPIENT: Unbeknownst to us, it was lost
in some manner in one his moves later in his
life.
CAPT. ZACHARIAH FIKE, U.S. ARMY: I found Private
Ralph W. Bingham`s medal on Craigslist. This
has been the calling of mine for about the
last three years. I locate lost or stolen
medals. These are all the Purple Hearts that
I`m currently working. Some I`ve located to
families, some I haven`t.
I do these on my own time. I don`t consider
it a hobby. It`s more of a calling and an
honor. I myself have a Purple Heart. It hangs
on the wall in my mother`s home, and I would
hope that one day, if my medal was lost, someone
would do the same thing for me and my family.
It is truly an honor to bring Private Bingham`s
Purple Heart home to his family, and I am
again truly humbled by his sacrifice.
It is a great honor to bring home his Purple
Heart. Thank you very much.
B. MACNEVIN: The medal means a lot to me,
especially, and to our family.
FIKE: I`m glad it is home to where it belongs,
and I`ll move on to the next medal.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: Imagine creating something that you
intend to share with the world, but then it
sits on the shelf for more than 60 years.
As World War II was winding down, U.S. Army
Colonel stationed in the States composed a
symphony, but no one ever played it until
now.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
(MUSIC)
COL. HAROLD VAN HUEVELEN (RET.), COMPOSER:
Wonderful!
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: That was the symphony that Colonel Harold
Van Huevelen wrote in 1945. That was the composer
himself, listening to the U.S. Army Band perform
his peace earlier this month. He`s 93 years
old now and traveled across the country for
the performance. Colonel Van Huevelen says
that the symphony tells the story of the war,
and it concludes with the peace that had been
announced just before he wrote it. Of course,
a lot of us here at CNN STUDENT NEWS offer
our thanks to America`s veterans. We`re going
to end today`s show with some images from
Veterans Day events around the U.S. We`ll
see you again tomorrow for more CNN STUDENT
NEWS.