the world and the culture and
politics behind them.
This time we headed out
to the wild west
of the east, Cambodia.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHARLET DUBOC: It's the crack
of dawn on the back of a
cattle truck in the outskirts
of Phnom Penh.
This is a typical daily commute
for the 400,000 female
garment factory workers
of Cambodia.
Despite the fact that the
garment industry represents
80% of Cambodia's export
revenue, these girls work six
days a week for only $2.00 a day
until, in some cases, they
quite literally faint.
We were here for the first ever
Cambodia fashion week,
not that that meant anything
to the girls in the back of
this truck.
[MUSIC PLAYING IN FOREIGN
LANGUAGE]
FEMALE SPEAKERS: Welcome
to Cambodia!
CHARLET DUBOC: Cambodia used to
be a liberal, peace-loving
country where miniskirt-clad
girls bopped to the
sounds of psych pop.
That was until Pol Pot's Khmer
Rouge not only destroyed the
agricultural industry, but also
wiped out every Cambodian
artist and intellectual, leading
to a creative brain
drain that left a cultural
black hole until now.
30 years on, the Cambodian
people are beginning to forge
a creative path of their own.
It was in this climate that the
country felt it was ready
to host it's first ever
fashion week.
We're outside this art gallery
in downtown Phnom Penh with
tuk-tuks around us everywhere.
And in there is the makings
of a fashion show by
designer Don Prutasio.
I don't know.
It's not Prostasio.
What is it?
What's your full name, Don?
DON PRUTASIO: Don Prutasio.
CHARLET DUBOC: Where
are you from?
DON PRUTASIO: From
the Philippines.
When you think about Cambodia,
you don't think
about fashion week.
But Cambodia, there's a fashion
scene going on.
It's not relevant
for the world.
But for us here, it's
relevant enough.
How many many more then?
18, right?
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
CHARLET DUBOC: When did
you first start
wearing makeup yourself?
CHARLET DUBOC: Who are
your influences?
CHARLET DUBOC: Do you have one
music video in particular?
OAK CHAN: "Vogue."
CHARLET DUBOC: Walk?
OAK CHAN: Yeah.
CHARLET DUBOC: I don't
know that one.
OAK CHAN: V-O-G-U-E,
just vogue.
CHARLET DUBOC: Oh.
I thought you said
walk, like walk.
OAK CHAN: No, not walk.
CHARLET DUBOC: You mean
vogue, like--
OAK CHAN: Yes.
Yes.
CHARLET DUBOC: Can you vogue?
OAK CHAN: Yes.
CHARLET DUBOC: Do it.
Back stage is a [INAUDIBLE].
It's quite full on.
They've got their
mouths covered.
It's kind of like military.
They've been instructed that
they have to look stoned.
So we'll see how
that pans out.
How do you feel?
MALE SPEAKER: It's amazing.
CHARLET DUBOC: Yeah.
Have you ever worn
heels before?
MALE SPEAKER: Never.
But it's amazing for me.
Come on.
I enjoy the show.
I enjoy the clothes.
Everything's just great.
Really, really great.
CHARLET DUBOC: It was an
intriguing start to the
fashion week.
A bold, conceptual, performance
arts style show
where the models practically
sleep walked.
It wasn't yet clear who Don
Prutasio's market was.
But at least his loyal all
black clad entourage were
there for support.
[APPLAUSE]
CHARLET DUBOC: The high classes
he was referring to
are otherwise affectionately
known by the local press as
the Khmer Riche, the sons and
daughters of rich and powerful
government officials.
As well as being fabulously
rich, they were also
surprisingly camp.
But not nearly as camp
as the after party.
The Blue Chili Bar is run by
fashion week's head makeup
artist, Oak Chan.
As it was Halloween,
we were told to
expect something scary.
The elite fashion crowd bailed,
and the vibe gave way
to a different form of creative
expression, appealing
mainly to the white expats
in the mood for love.
How many beautiful Cambodian
trannies can you fit tuk-tuk?
What are your names?
CHARLET DUBOC: OK.
So tell me.
This is your bar?
CHARLET DUBOC: And how do you
feel on the bar, dancing?
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHARLET DUBOC: Having had our
first taste of fashion week,
we were keen to look into the
other side of Cambodian
fashion, the garment industry.
We went to meet Phen Chou,
former garment worker and
union leader, to hear about
some of the recent issues
facing the workers.
PHEN CHOU:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: One of the
reasons we'd come to Phnom
Penh was because we've read
stories in the local press of
mass faintings in a garment
factory that produces clothes
for international high
street brand, H&M.
When the official report came
back, it claimed that the
faintings were due to, wait
for it, evil spirits.
Ghosts, not noxious fumes from
the dyes, but ghosts.
To find out more, we met with Mu
Sochua, an opposition party
leader and campaigner
for worker's rights.
MU SOCHUA: The garment sector,
it represents 80% of the
export of Cambodia, billions
of dollars.
It employs over 400,000 women
from remote villages in
Cambodia, women who can
hardly read and write.
They work in the hard
working conditions.
They don't eat enough.
Why are they fainting?
Hundreds and thousands
fainting--
When you're fired by the
factory, they don't
want to go back home.
They stay around the city, and
they take any job they can,
even sex work.
They cannot be working in these
factories for 10, 30
years until they die.
That's the end of the road.
I don't think so.
CHARLET DUBOC: We headed out to
pay a visit to one of many
such factories in the outskirts
of the city.
Come on.
We're running because we want
to catch the garment workers
leaving the factory before
it's too late.
They just keep on coming,
thousands of them.
Remember this when you're
battling down Oxford Street to
get to H&M and Gap.
No one was willing to talk
outside the factory.
So we decided to try and hitch
a ride with a group of girls
on their way back to
their villages.
We meant to get on a truck.
Everyone's staring at me
because I'm a monster.
I'm a giant.
But to be honest, my main
concern now is not
getting run over and--
[HONKING]
CHARLET DUBOC: Finding
the fucking truck.
We finally found the truck.
Apparently it's packed so I
don't even know if we're
going to fit on.
But I don't give a shit.
I'll fucking cling on
by my little toe.
Oh.
Can we fit on?
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: Hey.
My god.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: Who do
we know on this bus?
FEMALE SPEAKER 1:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: So within two
minutes of being on this bus,
we've managed to find a girl
who works in a factory.
SREY THOM:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: And she has
to leave for work to
back here at 7:00.
Which makes me think that we're
going to be on this
thing for two hours, not one.
I really need to wee.
FEMALE SPEAKERS:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: Whoa!
[LAUGHTER]
CHARLET DUBOC: I keep on trying
to ask questions, but I
keep getting smacked in the
head by bits of twig.
FEMALE SPEAKERS:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: No.
FEMALE SPEAKERS:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: OK.
I'm going to get down here.
Hey.
[LAUGHTER AND GIGGLES]
FEMALE SPEAKER 2:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: We're
getting off.
Thank you!
Bye!
[OVERLAPPING VOICES IN
FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: We're somewhere
in the middle of nowhere.
Look, bushes, jungle,
dirt road.
SREY THOM:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: OK.
You lead the way.
SREY THOM:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: Thank
you so much.
How long have your family
lived here?
SREY THOM:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: And how many
of you are there?
SREY THOM:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: I'm Charlet.
SREY THOM:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: Does she have
a day off from the factory?
SREY THOM:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
SREY THOM'S FATHER: [SPEAKING
FOREIGN LANGUAGE
FEMALE SPEAKERS:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: Who
built the house?
SREY THOM:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: And whose
clothes are these?
SREY THOM:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: So this is
her favorite outfit?
FEMALE SPEAKER 1: Yeah.
CHARLET DUBOC: Do you understand
what this means?
SREY THOM:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: Can you tell
her what it means?
FEMALE SPEAKER 1:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: Why
does she like it?
SREY THOM:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
FEMALE SPEAKER 1:
SREY THOM:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
FEMALE SPEAKER 1: No, I
don't understand that.
CHARLET DUBOC: Do you know
what fashion week is?
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
FEMALE SPEAKER 1: No.
CHARLET DUBOC: No.
How old were you when
you started working?
SREY THOM:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
FEMALE SPEAKER 1:
SREY THOM:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
FEMALE SPEAKER 1:
FEMALE SPEAKERS:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: She should just
be starting work now.
FEMALE SPEAKER 3:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
FEMALE SPEAKER 1:
FEMALE SPEAKER 3:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: And did
your friends faint?
FEMALE SPEAKERS:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
FEMALE SPEAKER 3:
SREY THOM:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
FEMALE SPEAKER 1:
SREY THOM:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
FEMALE SPEAKER 2:
SREY THOM'S FATHER:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
FEMALE SPEAKERS:
SREY THOM:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
FEMALE SPEAKER 1:
I don't know.
I forgot this word.
CHARLET DUBOC: Who
is the cook?
SREY THOM:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: Father.
FEMALE SPEAKER 4: Yeah.
SREY THOM'S FATHER:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
FEMALE SPEAKER 4:
SREY THOM'S FATHER:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
SREY THOM:
CHARLET DUBOC: OK.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: Sweet dreams.
So now everyone's going
to bed, and
we're still wide awake.
We've got to try and get some
sleep because we're going to
get up with them at 5 o'clock
in order to be back at the
factory at 7:00.
It's been so amazing.
They've brought us back here.
And they've shared with us
the little that they had.
And they had a traditional meal,
and then they tried to
offer us up their beds,
which we refused.
So we're sleeping outside.
It's a small price to pay to
kind of get an insight into
their story.
I haven't slept a wink.
I couldn't sleep.
So I'm just completely mad.
And I can barely walk because
my legs are so swollen with
mosquito bites.
And getting up [INAUDIBLE].
I'd really like to
clean myself.
[MUSIC PLAYING IN FOREIGN
LANGUAGE]
FEMALE SPEAKERS:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[MUSIC PLAYING IN FOREIGN
LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: No sooner had
the truck stopped, Srey and
the other girls disappeared
into the crowd.
We didn't even get a chance
to say goodbye.
And that's it.
They've gone in.
They've gone in to work.
They're not at school.
They're not learning anything.
They're going to make jeans
for the likes of
you and me to wear.
When I think of that girl
standing in there, working the
machines or whatever it is
that goes on behind those
gates in her Berlin fashion
week jumper, without even
knowing what a fashion week is,
and then I think of all
the high fashion designers
collecting their praise, and
champagne, and flowers for their
latest collection, it
doesn't add up.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHARLET DUBOC: Cambodia fashion
week continued in full
swing as the well-heeled crowd
move from one exclusive venue
to another.
And before we knew it, the
week was almost up.
Given that there is no Cambodian
equivalent to Rodeo
Drive, I was curious to find out
where the rich girls went
to get their frocks.
Sophy & Sina is a five-story
fashion mansion, complete with
a relaxing shoe garden, wine
cellar, tailoring room, and
fashion magazine.
All this is owned by 23-year-old
Sophy Key,
daughter of the Deputy Prime
Minister and head of the
Cambodia Fashion Council.
The place was empty.
Not a soul came in the whole
time we were there.
However, as inappropriate as
I felt this place was, I
couldn't help but be seduced
by this confection.
You never know when a
giant Barbie dress
might come in handy.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHARLET DUBOC: We went to
check out another very
different type of fashion
show being put on
by local girl Rina.
Rina, sorry.
You look busy.
CHARLET DUBOC: Rina grew up on
the street before working in a
garment factory and learning
English on her lunch breaks.
Since then, she's gone on to
open her own business, a
cafe-cum-bespoke bespoke
fashion boutique.
Who are your favorite
designers?
CHARLET DUBOC: So everything
you do just
comes out of your head?
CHARLET DUBOC: Yeah.
CHARLET DUBOC: See you
in the market!
RINA ROAT: You have
to follow me!
CHARLET DUBOC: Here we are!
We're at the market where
Rina's models are
going to get made up.
Hi, models!
FEMALE SPEAKERS: Hi!
FEMALE SPEAKERS:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: So the
1960s, that was a
good time in Cambodia?
CHARLET DUBOC: So you're
trying to sort of
remember that time?
FEMALE SPEAKER 5:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[MUSIC IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE
PLAYING]
FEMALE SPEAKERS:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[MUSIC PLAYING IN FOREIGN
LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: As Rina's models
paraded around and had
DIY creations, we wondered why
more people like Rina hadn't
been included in the
fashion week.
After all, if recycled
trash is good enough
for Comme des Garcons.
CHARLET DUBOC: The final show
of the week was by Remy Hou,
Cambodian-born designer now
living in L.A. To my combined
surprise and delight,
I've been asked
to walk in his show.
I wasn't off to a good start
and arrived late.
All the models were dressed
and ready to go.
But there were bigger problems
than me squeezing into my
dress on time.
CHARLET DUBOC: It's raining.
FEMALE SPEAKER 6: Yes.
CHARLET DUBOC: Is the show
mean to be outside?
FEMALE SPEAKER 6: Yes.
DANNY: [SINGING]
Boom!
We had all this.
We had all this, but
it's raining.
It's wet.
And this is what you get.
When it's raining and
it's wet, we take it
indoors and we respect.
Let's do this.
[MUSIC PLAYING IN FOREIGN
LANGUAGE]
MALE SPEAKER: We're live
in Phnom Penh, y'all.
All right!
The party must go on, and
it's the same old song.
CHARLET DUBOC: We haven't
even had a rehearsal.
And I haven't been styled yet.
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah, we're going
to take her and get the
line on her.
But it must be done.
CHARLET DUBOC: I'm
not nervous.
I just don't want to
fuck his show up.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHARLET DUBOC: This was one
of the more unnecessarily
theatrical shows I've
come across.
The whole thing was suspect
briefcases,
handcuffs, and fugitives.
But to be honest, I was more
concerned about getting the
bloody umbrella open at
the end of the runway.
[CHEERING]
CHARLET DUBOC: I did it,
and it was fine.
I opened the umbrella.
And it was really scary.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHARLET DUBOC: After the show, I
changed into my Sophy & Sina
party frock, hoping this
might help clinch an
interview with Sophy Key.
She was surrounded by her
impenetrable entourage and
ushered out of the building the
moment we got too close.
However, we caught up with Remy,
whose rags to riches
story was a far more positive
example of Cambodian fashion,
even if his brand of
spy fashion wasn't
exactly to my taste.
REMY HOU: I was a refugee.
My parents, they were
held captive.
And we were escaping, like,
pitch dark at night.
I don't know if they crawled
through barbed wires or
running through bushes.
They ducked because
they saw it.
But I didn't duck.
I was in the backpack.
My face was ripped open right
there, this side.
CHARLET DUBOC: Oh, my God.
REMY HOU: Yeah.
The scar is still there.
But it's a reminder, everybody
goes through challenges.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHARLET DUBOC: And
the gods wept.
Fashion week was over.
There was nothing particularly
wrong with the fashion week.
It did all the things a fashion
week should do,
lights, models, guest list.
But it happened in a cocoon.
Fashion weeks the world over
are inherently elitist.
But at the very least, the
general public in the West
knows what a fashion week is.
So there's these weird tiny
children everywhere in
dresses, and powder on their
face, and lipstick.
They come up to me
and just go--
Cambodia fashion week will
probably continue.
But as long as it's held in the
shadow of a society where
garment workers are beaten for
protesting, and mass faintings
in factories are blamed on evil
spirits, then it will
constantly be undermined by
other fashion stories hitting
the headlines for the
wrong reasons.
[MUSIC IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE
PLAYING]