JP WALKER: People are always
asking us, since the year
after we stopped going it, why?
What's up?
When's it coming back?
What's going on?
And so then, of course, when the
word came out, people were
freaking, you know?
CHRIS GUNNARSON: So that first
year, it was a collaboration
between me, Jeremy,
JP, and Downing.
And so we thought, what
would be the cool
contest/anti-contest that we
could do that would be unlike
anything else that's
ever been done.
It would be about progression,
but it'd be about vibe and
cool energy.
ANDY WRIGHT: I think the
first Jibfests were--
it was pretty sick, because it
was just like we were 12 deep
in a cabin in Big Bear eating
pizzas and drinking Budweiser.
And it was like a lot of it was
just about hidden features
that had never really been seen
before in parks because a
lot of the park stuff was pretty
straightforward, just a
down rail, a mailbox, a box,
something like that.
And then they were starting to
think of the curved rails, and
s-rails and different
kind of features.
ZAK HALE: This is sick.
You guys got the old
summit stuff?
-Kind of.
Kind of tried to replicate
a little bit of it.
ZAK HALE: Double s-rail
This is tight.
Let's go snowboard.
JP WALKER: The canvas was so
open for jibs, so everyone was
like, we want this, we
want this and that.
And now, it's kind of like so
many things have been done,
it's like I really
would like this.
There was only kind of one or
two things I was really
looking for, versus 15
things as usual.
I like the triple s-rail
and the circle.
That's my two, just because
they remind
me of the old Jibfest.
JEREMY JONES: Exactly for the
same two for the same reason.
It just brings back the feeling
of the Jibfest for me.
So it's just always a challenge
to do the s-rail,
and the first person that
50-50s it is just--
I mean, I've already
heard that cheer in
my head, you know?
-That was insane, dude.
How sick was that, dude?
-He one-upped you, dog.
180--
-Oh my god.
-One-up
DAVE DOWNING: Dude, Brian Thien
hasn't snowboarded in
like three years, and he
just did the s-rail.
-Dude, did he just
[INAUDIBLE] it?
DAVE DOWNING: First day.
In the first hour.
-Yeah, Chico.
BRIAN THIEN: I was pretty
stoked on that.
CHRIS GRENIER: Is it true, you
didn't snowboard for four
years before doing--
BRIAN THIEN: Yeah, I haven't
snowboarded in forever, dude.
The longer it's been since--
CHRIS GRENIER: You didn't
snowboard for three years and
you did the w-rail?
BRIAN THIEN: Well, I
snowboarded twice.
I went twice this year.
CHRIS GRENIER: Damn.
That's bad ass.
JP WALKER: For Brian, he was one
of those guys that was in
those old videos I used
to always look up to.
But I feel like he
kind of fell back
from filming or something.
For some reason, he wasn't
really in any
videos for a minute.
It was cool to see him
get back into it.
ANDY WRIGHT: What was so cool
about the jibbing thing, too,
is it really showcased style.
And guys like Thien and Downing
have insane style.
They shifted their direction
of what they were doing.
They could always jump and
do that other stuff.
But now they can jib, so it just
kind of makes watching
one of those guys' video part
more interesting, more
well-rounded.
BRIAN THIEN: I'm just here to
have a good time, and kind of
stoke everyone out, and ride
with them and have fun.
It's pretty awesome to watch.
DAVE DOWNING: I just
got broke off.
43-year-old, Joe.
I broke off.
That's what I'm here for, is to
spark up these kids, dude.
-How hard can it be?
JP WALKER: The very first big
box with the Lexan on it was
something that me and
Jeremy wanted.
And we'd just tell Gunny about
this thing, we used to always
jib on this box.
So of course, they came up with
just a full replica of
the box that we used to have
with the Lexan on top of it.
Back then, I was just tripping
out, you know?
Did a thousand nose-presses
on it.
Just like, this thing's
insane.
CHRIS GRENIER: I just started
trying it, and it ended up
taking a little longer than I
thought it was going to, but I
was pretty psyched.
I sprained my ankle three--
about a month ago.
Haven't been out, haven't been
able to do anything.
I was like, I have to
go to the Jibfest.
Got a shot of cortisone
in my ankle.
I was like, I don't care, it's
probably messing it up, but.
When I was 15, I was idolizing
all these guys.
And just a little shithead kid
from Massachusetts, but now
being here with all these
guys is crazy.
If you were to tell me when I
was 15 that I was going to be
in the Nixon Jibfest with JP
Walker, I'd be like, fuck you.
I had posters of the guy on my
wall when I was a little kid.
DAVE DOWNING: Need me to
tie your boots for you?
Get out there.
CHRIS GUNNARSON: Nowadays, where
we focus on a lot of the
big events--
X Games, Dew Tours, and
US Opens and stuff.
So the first thing I said was,
if we're going to bring the
Jibfest back--
the crew, and the lodging, and
the food, everything about
it-- we wanted to be so on-point
that any person that
was a part of this thing this
week would leave saying, that
was a high point in my career.
And that was one of
the coolest things
I ever got to do.
And just sitting here today
watching the circle rail.
If it even gets got, I'd say
mission accomplished.