Oh, there's kids skating
in there.
How you doing?
-Pretty good.
-What's your name?
-Jonathan.
-Pretty cool.
Nice to meet you, Jonathan.
-You were skating fast.
I'm like, oh, shit.
It's Daewon.
I saw your "Decker" video.
-Oh, the old one, yeah.
That was a long time ago.
It's crazy that it's
so long ago.
That was eight, seven
years ago.
Time flies, man.
Take advantage, dude.
-Don't do it.
Don't OK.
-We'll redo the courthouse
thing that--
-People would do lines back
then and then after they
viewed the line, people
would follow him
like yeah, Start cheering.
-The end of the camera's
part you'll see it in
"Goldfish," I think.
Skating has changed in that
way a lot, it seems.
It's got so serious.
Now it's huge.
That's good, man.
Just keep skating.
Didn't even like stuff
that they do, don't
even worry about it.
Don't ever sweat like, hey, is
this good enough or is that
good enough.
As long as you're happy
with it, it's fine.
-Yeah, he's not intimidating
to be around.
He's cool.
He make you feel like
you're hanging out.
-All right.
Welcome back to the show.
This week, I went out
to Los Angeles, met
up with Daewon Song.
Daewon brought along Daniel
Castillo, and we went to some
of the spots that those guys
filmed for the video "Love
Child," which is really kind of
trip for me because, I felt
like I went in some time machine
and went into this
video that was really important
to me as a skater in
the early '90s.
I think "Love Child" marked a
change for World Industries
and a change for skateboarding
in general.
It was just really different.
It was like these city kids
all skating these street
spots, the schoolyards Then
like '80s like Santa Cruz
speed wheels kind of
skating or like
white kids before they--
I don't know.
We just looked at some spots
those guys skated.
And that's all.
This is the Daewon
Song episode.
I hope you enjoy it.
-All right.
So I'm trying to think where
we should go first.
Seventh Street is an old classic
spot, but I think
people have seen enough
of that place.
You know what I mean?
The best spots are the ones
that just you can't even
believe it, hours and hours
of skating went on.
-Could you describe it?
-This is the school like at the
end of "Rubbish Heap" when
Rodney's part ends, Jeremy
Klein runs and folks just
gives him a street board
when he comes out
here and ollies that.
[INAUDIBLE] insane, like pretty
crazy to think about,
and he does a couple of other
things on the street board.
-It seem so weird.
It's so big.
Like I watch "Rubbish Heap"
and I was like, man.
The World never even interested
me whatsoever.
I was more like a Z-boy, Dogtown
kind of guy and from
where I grew up.
-Around our neighborhoods,
Daniel grew up in a fucked up
part of Culver City, man.
Up at Stoner Boulevard
near the projects.
Whew!
-Yeah.
I think definitely if I didn't
skate, there would've been a
chance I probably would
have done drive-bys.
Oh yeah, I got shot, man.
I was just at a party and wrong
place at the wrong time
pretty much.
They thought me and my
friends were a bunch
of gangsters, probably.
And they just unloaded
on us, like two cars.
But now, I always stay
far from that.
And skating is so good for
kids that grew up in bad
neighborhoods.
Do you know what I mean?
Because it gets them like
psyched on something else
rather than what's going
on around them.
Frescas was my World
Industries.
I'm still under the
same distribution.
Like where World started
is where I'm still at.
It wasn't the first place I've
ever gotten where I first got
sponsored and I'm still
at the same company.
It's pretty crazy
to think about.
Daniel, how old were you?
14?
13?
Yeah.
So I was like 15 or 16.
And I miss those days.
Like in 92, when they had
revamped the whole team like
and like a lot of the guys
have been on it took off.
It was like me, Kareem, Shiloh,
Chico, Spencer, Daniel.
That's pretty insane.
-Yeah, like all of the people
that were in "Love Child" were
totally city kids.
Me and Kareem used to
skate a lot together
when we were younger.
And he was like, yeah, there's
some new guy in World
Industries and I was like who?
He was like some dude
named Daewon.
And I was like, Daewon?
I was like what nationality
is he?
And this is what Kareem said.
Kareem said oh, he's
some nigger.
I don't know.
-OK.
You're gonna trip out on this.
First World ad ever.
This is the tail grab
one foot, that
first White Power ad.
-Yeah.
We had that first ad together,
me, him and Kareem.
It was pretty funny.
Spike Jones actually
shot the photos.
It was pretty crazy.
And it probably took
like an hour.
It was pretty awesome
back then.
-When we got on, Spike was
pretty much in charge.
He was the one doing the ads and
shooting so, we went over
to Tower Tide.
Daniel did a tail grab one foot
Kareem did like a 540 and
what did he do, Daniel?
-A 540 [INAUDIBLE].
-On the same bank?
-Yeah.
-And I had a tail
grab shove it.
No wonder I couldn't pick
up any other sponsors.
So it started right here.
-Recreate it exactly.
-Dude, I don't think I
could do it again.
-Did you go down the
slide in it?
-No.
That was the beginning of the
part where I go down the
slide, and then it's like
the line after that.
It's right after that.
It's the slide and then right
after that is this line where
I do a front pop.
We got to skate through.
So I just see it through.
I'll just tell you what I did.
Is that cool?
Front paw, a point down
there, huge one.
And then my board I did
an ollie tre flip.
Back then I didn't know it
was an ollie tre flip.
I just thought it was some
sort of nollie and then
flinged around.
And then I did the old faithful
like back 180 and
then switch 180.
360 ollie over this.
But I landed it.
I did the worst kick flip
ever right here.
360 flip right there.
And I went off this bump.
Bump with the manhole
was a double flip.
Then I did a poor excuse for
a pop shove it right here.
You can watch it back
and go, wow.
That's lame.
Then I was like, oh, it's
really coming now.
I'm going to prep up for this.
And I'll leap up these and just
went huge with a switch
540 big flip.
But they didn't get that one,
so I just ended up doing a
hill flip shove it.
When I did that line, were
there a lot of lines?
I think it would trip people
up, because they were like,
are you allowed to do lines
long like that?
You know what I mean?
It kind of took a minute to get
down to the grand finale.
The heel flip shove it
looked terrible.
"Love Child" was random.
Three tours plus maybe filming
for like a month
straight and that's it.
Where now, it's like, oh God.
I gotta film 7 different
people.
I hope I can get can
get the footage.
Film for a year.
-Did you like it better then?
-I liked it better then.
It seemed more like I was just
skating and all of a sudden, I
had a video part.
-Yeah.
I remember being super psyched
on the hard flip over this
little gap that he did.
It was super slick looking.
-The worst hard flip
ever documented?
-What's so bad about it?
It was the first
one ever done.
-It was the first, but
it was the worst.
So it's cool.
So it's like first and worst.
Back then too, I didn't
even know what it was.
All I know is I had to mule kick
the fuck out of my back,
front foot and just move
it out of the way.
And if you shot a photo, there
would definitely be three
frames of just something that
just did not look right.
-But you had never heard of
anyone doing that trick?
-No.
You know what?
I actually did here one
person who did it.
This guy Dan Gallagher.
Rodney was saying he
thinks he did it.
And I'm pretty sure he did do
it, but I don't want to give
him full credit.
But who got it on footage
first over a huge gap?
You got your fish with
you because--
There's borough.
God, they need a gardener.
This was a really popular
spot back in like '93.
This place is like one place
like it goes way back from
like the "Rubbish Heap" Jeremy
Klein days where he came here
and I think, did the
best stuff ever.
-They put a pole at the bottom
of the one that everybody used
to skate, and we still
skated it.
Jeremy Klein had some stuff in
it a long time ago in old
video and then now, they put
poles all over, and put those
benches to really
just kill it.
-Rick Howard had a bunch of
stuff that was good too.
-Rick Howard had a
cover switch 360?
-Yeah.
It was on that wall.
Gino actually had like a fakie
hard that was amazing and then
this is what we call the vortex,
the V. And there was a
lot of stuff they
went down here.
Jeremy Klein did some stuff that
was, he did like front
side flip in the birdhouse
video.
I know he did backside flip.
The main bank that everybody
skated was the one right next
that railing.
That's the main one.
If you watch like the old video
in "New World Order"
where Daniel is sitting at the
top of that bank over there,
and I do some weird trick where
I didn't hit my tail.
Hey, everybody did the Howard
Hail right there and then you
were talking.
That was the first try
but I hit my tail.
That was fucking sick, man.
Skating is sick.
He's the best in the world.
Yeah.
I would never leave my area,
plus well, back then I felt as
though everything was right
at your front door.
You don't have to go
far for curves.
People we're traveling around
the world for curves?
This is Alta Vista.
The curve is still waxed.
See, I got to get out
and try to hard flip
it and 5-0 it again.
Should we stop and get out?
-Yeah.
Let's get out.
-Tim Gammond had a fakie tre,
fake nose grind going on here.
Insane.
Actually, we should be coming
here on those days where we
have nowhere to go.
This one was in "New World
Order." So there was like a
hard flip [INAUDIBLE]
180 and there was a--
Everything was filmed from
pretty much that angle to
where you're at.
Thing is huge still.
You got a marker because
I want to write
down what's been done.
Don't you hate hate that?
I've been to so many spots where
people write down what
they've done.
It's me like when there is steep
walls are something like
tail block, back side
tail block.
What did Richard have on it?
I know I can't remember anything
Richard had, man.
Richard had so much stuff
it's hard to remember.
Didn't you lose your virginity
here, Daniel?
I'm just playing.
-Yeah, right.
You lost your virginity
at Kareem's.
Yeah, I did the world parks.
The craziest stuff would
happen at that place.
So many random chicks
would show up and--
-There was quarter pipes.
-There was quarter pipes they
had the beast wall like there
was actually a bunch of
stuff like this big
six foot mini ramp.
In '92 and '93, that's where
I think the most innovative
skating went down within like
Gino and Mike Keenan and
everybody and you just see the
craziest stuff going down.
You actually watched somebody
do something new.
You know what I mean?
That was crazy.
I'm sure we've stayed in every
one of these little motels.
Rocko used to put
us in like, yep.
You guys are staying here.
He would just put us in random
places or just give us money,
like one dude money the oldest
one, which was probably like
15, the responsibility
to get us a room.
And then once the World part
came along, that's when it
ended up being in like a
little place to stay.
Remember the Imperial
double set?
Dude, Daniel calling it out.
Jeremy Wray all he
did flawless.
He was Jeremy Wray though.
He could probably backside
flip it now.
I only did it with Sock filming
but, it was like when
you ollie, and you lean
back and one leg
goes up, and I fell.
And I remember telling Sock
you can't cut it.
It's so funny asking somebody
that question,
like can you cut it?
Hey, is this how Wallenburg
looks, like one more?
-Vista, you ever been there?
-No.
Yeah.
He's kept himself in like the
whole South Bay area his
entire life as far as
skateboarding goes.
I look back at like think of
all the video footage and
stuff from just the
years past.
It's all there.
I don't think I've really
noticed it too.
Do it where you want to.
That's what I say.
-There's a place like after
I kick jumped it in "Love
Child," we came back and I tried
to front side flip it.
And then the board, I don't
know if Sock still has the
footage, but I stepped on the
nose and it completely smacked
me in my face.
Jeremy Wray really killed that
thing, fakie hill, front side
flip, narly back side
flip, everything.
See?
It's pretty long because
he took three
steps on the flat part.
Pretty tall guy too.
This thing's huge.
Guy switch tre-ed one day
and some do but he
forgot to film it.
Guy was probably like
ah, oh, well.
-I think I did it once
without filming.
I went back to film it and I
think maybe it took a lot of
tries and the cameraman ran
out of batteries, so the
footage got messed
up or something.
And it is very important to
document this stuff, but it's
not what it's all about.
-It's nut.
I ain't going out to launch
at the top of this baby.
And they even made a baby ramp
too. they made like a 3 and
1/2 foot kicker.
When they go, they go big.
To switch tre though
that's nuts.
And at that time too.
-What year was that?
-That was like '93, right?
'93.
Well, it was underground
at the same time too.
And you had to wait a
year and a half to
ever see any new skating.
We didn't have YouTube.
We didn't have--
you couldn't just go to
somebody's site and watch all
this new footage that came
out within the last week.
So we're headed to the
imperial blocks.
These were the hub for
us in '92 and '93.
Now, we used to skate
these ones.
Oh, wait.
Was it those ones?
Pretty nuts.
Coming back to spots like this
and thinking about all the
stuff you couldn't do and still
can't do, probably.
I tried a lot of shit I couldn't
do but there was a
couple of guys that came here
and was I think Rick was
trying to do a front to half
calf grip crooked grind, maybe
or some back in those
days, which was nuts
to even think about.
And then in the plan B day
we had front to calf
flipped the hard way.
So like a back 50 or 5-0.
I think Henry Hambertino did
backs 180 hill fakie nose
grind on that one.
Switching on hill, switch 5-0,
that's pretty nuts too.
It's so funny how so much stuff
went down like that back
then, but you've seen so much
crazy stuff like that back
then that nothing really,
everything just went by.
It wasn't like you had one
good thing in your part.
You watched people's parts
and everything was good.
So you're just like, yeah, that
was good, that was good,
that was good, that was good.
His part's over.
OK.
Like '94 to '95, I
just was over it.
Hung out at Long Beach
all the time.
Shiloh had told me later,
like Rodney an them were
hitting them up.
Like Daewon's not
skating anymore.
He's doing something else and
Rodney was telling Shiloh
like, hey, we might have
to kick him off.
And Shiloh was telling
them, you can't
kick Daewon off, man.
He'll skate.
He's going to skate.
And I came back and
called Rodney.
I was like look, I'm sorry for
not being around, but I'm back
and I'm going to try to
work on trying to
get something going.
You know what I mean?
-I always knew that that guy
can't he probably could never
quit skating.
He loves to do it so much.
And that's when we started
filming and I did the whole
"Trilogy" part.
It put me back on the map.
You know what I mean?
There was nothing left
to really skate.
Everything got skate stopped.
Everything got blocked, all
the curbs just were curbs.
Ended up going to some school
putting tables downstairs and
we never got hassled.
So I was like look, I guess this
is where it's all going
to happen now.
It was almost like a new
type of skating for me.
Like now I'm going
to focus on this.
-Yeah.
I remember later then seeing
footage of Daewon.
I thought they said he didn't
skate anymore, and he was
fucking ripping.
I remember when he was doing
all the picnic table shit.
But I mean I always thought
he was gnarly, you know?
But there's only so many picnic
tables you can see.
-I got a lot of shit
for the picnic
table thing for a while.
There was no way of how people
try to erase things out of
their life, and that will be
there forever to haunt me,
which I'm not ashamed of it.
I used to love the whole picnic
table thing, but it got
a little too overboard.
I went on tour and my nickname
because in Australia was like
the picnic table wizard.
They would have picnic
table specifically
there so when I came.
I remember one of the guys came
up to me and was like,
Daewon man, I'm still glad
you're here, man.
I'm sorry we couldn't get
you the picnic tables.
I was like, well, God damn
it, there's nothing
I can do here then.
I'm out.
But my whole problem is I get
caught up and I over do it
like eating too much cake.
If you give me a whole cake,
I'll eat the whole thing, and
it drives people nuts.
Like dude, please no more.
-He was real crazy into
like the benches.
-Yeah, I hit those spots, but
like the way this guy looks at
shit is so crazy.
Like he would be oh,
you could skate.
I made this spot and you could
skate like this and that.
And I'll look at the spot.
I'm like, how did you even get
that from-- you know I don't
look at it like that.
He'll take it to the
extreme, man.
I I think that's the
way he does things.
He gets into something, and he
just sticks with it till he
burns it out for himself.
-Honestly, he's on a different
level than anybody.
There's only like a few guys out
there that are like at the
same level like Costen and
Reynolds and those kind of
guys, you know.
And then there's things like
the middle like me.
Daewon is definitely
on the top.
-"Round Three," he skated those
top of those fucking big
rigs, right?
And he was telling me oh, I'm
doing this big rig thing.
You should come down, dude,
like just back heel it.
I'm like what?
Like hell, no.
That shit is like
death defying.
-I've been just trying
to have fun with it.
It's really easy to stay
motivated as long as you just
kind of put yourself
in a new place.
Like for me, the whole "Cheese
and Crackers" thing, that was
just all fun, three months of
just fun, and we ended up
getting a video out of it.
But that's how "Love
Child" was.
-So you think something like
"Cheese and Crackers" couldn't
have come out in like
the mid '90s?
-No.
I don't think nobody would have
cared and plus when they
said vert died, in those days
it really did, even anything
to do with it, even if it was
just mini ramper tranny,
people were dead serious.
Like nobody wanted to see it.
Costen, he did a 360 tail
grab fakie nose
grind revert in a video.
People don't talk about that.
It's come back to that point now
where I think tranny, it's
cool again.
-Is your trucks always
like that, loose?
-M-hm.
-Is that just how
you skate 'em?
-M-hm.
-I always think like tech
skating you have to have tight
trucks.
-That's what everybody thinks,
but I couldn't do a nose
tranny unless my truck
was that loose.
Plus these days, I don't know.
-I think Rodriguez has
his trucks like that.
-He has both, because only
one of mine is like that.
-And the other one's tight?
Whoa.
-Now, Rodriguez has both.
That dude's nuts.
It's just nuts that like there's
people out there are
so good at one thing, but
they're afraid to admit it.
There's a couple of pros right
now that are afraid to admit
that they good at vert
or to admit that they
used to skate vert.
I'm not going to say any
names, but you guys
know who you are.
One dude is not afraid
though is Channie.