-Whoo-hoo.
-Whoo!
-Oh!
-So is there any key
to this thing?
BRIAN THIEN: No.
Speed and get locked in and you
hope for the best, really.
But then again, the scarier
you go, the faster you go.
The scarier it is and harder
to get locked in
where you need to.
I mean, Gunny built it.
We need to know where to take
off from, seriously.
-Whoa.
JP WALKER: That's something
that's the second time that a
circle rail has ever even
existed on the snow to be
snowboarded on.
I remember Gunny, when he told
us about them, because we drew
them up with no real dimensions
or anything, gave
them to him.
And then he came back and showed
us what he'd done, or
told us what he'd done.
And they were just a perfect
replica of that.
CHRIS GUNNARSON: I think that
SPT and our crew have, I would
probably say, contributed the
most to the evolution of
terrain parks and everything
that goes along with it,
whether it's welding techniques
or what type of
materials we use
and boxes or--
Without trying to make a claim
like, we did it all, which
would not be the case, I think
that we probably had a pretty
significant, maybe the most
significant role in how all
this stuff kind of came to be.
-You double-lining it, E-man?
Double-line or it's single?
-All right.
-All right, all clear.
-Is it good?
-Yep.
Drop it, Andy.
Three, two, one.
-Oh!
-That was sick.
-Three, two, one.
Oh!
-Sick.
-There he goes.
-Drop it.
Three, two, one.
-Oh yeah.
-Three, two, one.
-That was sick.
CHAD DINENNA: Jib factory.
-Hold up one second, Zak.
-Jib factory.
Hail to the king.
[MUSIC - TYVEK, "4312"]
-Another shot in the can.
CHAD DINENNA: Oh,
this is amazing.
You bring a bunch of good
friends together and a bunch
of hardworking people and put
them all into one place, and
everybody's laughing.
It's like Disneyland on snow.
DAVE DOWNING: Here's the deal.
You got to spin the feature,
you spin your feature, and
then you spin your trick.
And if you complete
it, you get $100.
E-MAN ANDERSON: OK,
am I going?
-You're up, dude.
E-MAN ANDERSON: All
right, I'm going.
I'm dropping in here.
-Here we go.
-OK, wait.
Here we go.
-First roll.
E-MAN ANDERSON: Are we ready?
-See, he's one of those happy
"Wheel of Fortune" dudes.
-Oh!
-Sick.
-You got to spin that.
-Is that in or out?
JP WALKER: Any way you
can put a 360--
-But I think you gotta
spin that?
JP WALKER: Yeah, you
have to spin this.
-It's all like switchblade
Bob.
-Which one's that?
E-MAN ANDERSON: Is that this?
-That's this one.
E-MAN ANDERSON: Oh.
-You could do that.
-Can you work a 360 in there?
-Go up and 360 on--
[MUSIC - BEASTIE BOYS, "LEE
MAJORS COME AGAIN"]
ALEX ANDREWS: I don't
want it to end.
I don't want to leave this place
and go home to my shitty
bed and Top Ramen because
it's been pretty sweet.
CHAD DINENNA: So here we
are on the final day.
I get everyone together
one at a time.
Pretty simple procedure--
I have a pad of paper
and a pen.
And each of the guys will write
down their top three in
order and the best trick.
And then add them all up, and
we'll have our winner for this
year's JibFest.
First off, thank you
guys for coming.
Thanks for putting
in your effort.
It's not some $100,000 cash
prize, and maybe we'll get
there someday, but.
So we're going to start it off
this year with best trick.
The spirit of the event is to
bring people together, so we
always thought for best trick
you get a custom barbecue for
your house because that's
another way that you can bring
your friends together
where you live.
So this year, the custom
barbecue and best
trick goes to Louif.
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE]
LOUIS-FELIX PARADIS: I
got the best trick.
They said it was
the double-line
here of down rails.
Or the hand-plant on the wall.
-Two, one.
CHAD DINENNA: So third place.
You know, he's going to be
a little crushed that his
eight-year reign as the champion
of the JibFest has
come down to an end this year,
but Simon, third place.
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE]
CHAD DINENNA: So second place.
It was a close vote.
This is his first time coming
out here to the JibFest.
And I'd like to think if we do
it again, we'll see him back,
but E-Man, come on up.
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE]
JP WALKER: E-Man's whole thing
is pretty sweet because he
originally wasn't on the main
list of guys to be invited.
And that just--
a lot of people just don't
really know about him.
But he killed it.
It was sick.
CHAD DINENNA: And first place.
Louif, why don't you
come back up?
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE]
LOUIS-FELIX PARADIS: When they
asked me if I wanted to do it,
I was like I don't even have
to think about it.
It's like an instant response
that, yeah, I'm down.
The reason I snowboard is pretty
much because of these
guys, like JP, Jeremy, Dave, and
that whole group of people
that used to be at the
Nixon JibFest.
ANDY WRIGHT: These guys never
get to snowboard with one
another, and it's just really
cool to see the different
meshings of styles and
approaches to snowboarding.
It was clear everybody there
had a good respect.
Somebody does a trick,
everyone's stoked.
They're clapping,
they're excited.
It doesn't matter who it is.
That part was rad.
And all the free beer.
[CHUCKLE].
[MUSIC PLAYING]
SETH HUOT: The whole burning
thing came about a
couple years ago.
JP and Kearns--
Sean Kearns-- and I were at
the top of Brandywine.
We were just so burnt,
so crisp.
Just end of the year, just
trying, trying, trying.
And dude, we just lit a fire
and just started burning
everything--
boards, helmets.
-Blow it out.
-No water.
-Oh, god.
[LAUGHTER]
-Holy shit.
SETH HUOT: And it's just,
I don't know.
And then we kind of followed
it up last year.
Just because it's such a thing
where it's like, if you have
gear, there's always snow,
you can always go up.
But if you have no gear, you
can't go, so burn it.
Just offer it up.
Send your season up in smoke.
[MUSIC - SHAWN FARMER,
"REAL RIDERS"]