NARRATOR: The Free Syrian Army
was formed by the Syrian armed
forces to the fact that the
president Bashar Al-Assad
ordered them to open fire on
civilians protesting in the
midst of the Arab Spring.
Since then, FSA brigades have
sprung up in cities all
throughout the country and
have grown to include
civilians of all stripes.
Once farmers, college students,
blue collar workers
and small business owners, these
volunteers have taken up
arms and joined the
ranks of the FSA.
On the front lines with the Free
Syrian Army in Aleppo, I
witnessed an underfunded group
of fighters embrace death,
while finding comfort in knowing
they had responded to
their brothers' calls
for freedom.
HAJI-MARA: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
NARRATOR: Haji-Mara, a former
commodities trader, commands
one of the largest groups of FSA
fighters in Aleppo-- the
Al-Tawhid Brigade.
Under his leadership in the
field, they now control over
80% of Aleppo.
[CAR IGNITION]
MAN: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
HAJI-MARA: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
INTERVIEWER: Why is
he wearing such a
nice jacket into battle?
MAN: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
HAJI-MARA: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
INTERVIEWER: You
said 15 tanks--
MAN: Yeah, 15 tanks.
INTERVIEWER: Were coming here?
Well, who made these rockets?
MAN: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
INTERVIEWER: Have you killed
many of Assad's soldiers?
MAN: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
INTERVIEWER: Has war
made you crazy?
MAN: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
NARRATOR: FSA fighters employ
homemade bombs and improvised
explosive devices in a lopsided
but increasingly
successful battle against the
tanks, jets, helicopters,
rockets, and mortar fire
of Assad's army.
[EXPLOSION]
MAN: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
NARRATOR: Much of my time in
Aleppo was spent under an
umbrella of heavy artillery.
The vibration of air raids,
daily mortar attacks, and the
constant zips from the snipers'
bullets ripped
through the air.
[MACHINE GUN FIRE]
INTERVIEWER: Where
the fuck are we?
MAN: Are you OK?
INTERVIEWER: No.
INTERVIEWER: Of course.
[DISTANT EXPLOSIONS]
INTERVIEWER: What do you hope
your Syria will look like
after the revolution?
MAN: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
INTERVIEWER: What
is this place?
MAN: An Islamic secondary
school.
MAN: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
WHITE HOUSE SPOKESMAN: Potential
for use of chemical
weapons by the Assad regime,
as well as [INAUDIBLE]
in the sense of proliferation
of weapons of mass
destruction.
HAJI-MARA: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
NARRATOR: As the threat of
chemical weapons looms,
activists say that over 40,000
Syrians have been killed in
the war so far, with another
three million
displaced by the fighting.
HAJI-MARA: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
NARRATOR: The US and other
Western nations still refuse
to provide the rebels with arms,
citing fears that they
could fall into the
hands of jihadist
elements within the FSA.
NATO has sent over 1,000
troops to the border of
Turkey, along with six Patriot
missile batteries, in an
effort to prevent spillover
from the conflict in
neighboring Syria.
Haji-Mara was recently
shot in the arm by a
sniper, but not killed.
He will live to fight another
day as his troops and many
battalion commanders like him
close in on Assad in Damascus.
The fight is just heating up.
HAJI-MARA: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
MAN: Made in Syria.
INTERVIEWER: This bullet just
came very close to us.
It's hot.