NARRATOR: On this
episode of Wicked Tuna.
WEATHERMAN: A bomb in our
coastal waters, a nor'easter.
MARCIANO: Hard
weather's coming down.
COAST GUARD: They've extended
the gale warning
through the night.
PAUL: We got a storm coming.
DAVE CARRARO: Whoa.
JAY: Yeah baby! Woo!
MARCIANO: He's sinking the
boat, he's sinking the boat.
RALPH: Reel that BLEEP
line in the back.
No, the other line.
The weather forecast
is not good.
DAVE CARRARO: What are
you doing down there?
I don't want to die out there.
MARCIANO: Hey, something's
up with the engine up here.
Last thing I want to happen is
to be stuck out here with an
engine that won't start.
Son of a bxxch.
NARRATOR: Fishing
is a hard life.
RALPH: There's gonna be
a confrontation here.
NARRATOR: And harder with
bluefin stocks depleted.
In Gloucester, Massachusetts,
there's a special breed of
fishermen, for generations
they've used rod and reel to
catch the elusive Bluefin tuna.
MARCIANO: Yeah, baby.
NARRATOR: They depending
these fish for their survival.
The competition is brutal.
SCOTT: Miserable prick.
NARRATOR: This is Wicked Tuna.
DAVE CARRARO: Go. Go. It's
great to be on top,
it's great to make all the
money, but with that nobody
likes a winner.
MARCIANO: For me, the money
doesn't fall out of the sky,
it comes out of the sea.
BILL: This gets harder
as you get older, but
I'm keeping up with the young
guns. Get out of the way.
RALPH: If it's on my mind,
you're gonna hear about it.
If you did something to me, I'm
gonna do something back to you.
There's only a few weeks left
to this season and
the weather forecast
is not good.
Stormy weather for
the next couple days.
For me rough days is a good
opportunity to catch one.
The people that just in general,
don't like to fish on rough
days, they don't belong
in this business.
The wind is coming,
yeah, I feel it.
PIRATE: I turn around, and yell
at the captain, I says hey uh,
we got the CG coming
up off our stern.
RALPH: Well, the COAST GUARD in
many cases is there to help us.
And they can also
save your life.
PIRATE: A matter
of time, you know,
they had a little rubber
boat out that way.
RALPH: Got my paperwork.
COAST GUARD: When was the
last time you were boarded?
RALPH: About two weeks ago.
COAST GUARD: I just wanted
to give you a heads up.
They've extended the gale
warning through the night.
So it's going to start getting
real snotty after noon.
RALPH: We got to follow the sea
going home, so we'll be fine.
COAST GUARD: How long are
you planning on staying out?
RALPH: Probably till the
first tide change about one,
two o'clock.
coast guard was advising us that
the forecast had changed for
the worse.
COAST GUARD: Alright sir. Take
care. Make it home safely.
RALPH: You guys too.
COAST GUARD: Have a good day.
RALPH: See you later,
have a good trip.
We appreciate that, but we
decided to stay as long as we
could and ignore the
coast guard warnings.
DAVE CARRARO: Tonight, east
wind, 15 to 20, gusts up to 30,
seas three to five.
Rain. Tomorrow, east wind,
15 to 20, gusts up to 35.
Gusts up to 30,
seas four to six.
PAUL: That's bad.
DAVE CARRARO: Yeah, and
then on the outgoing tide,
it's gonna stand up.
PAUL: That's real bad.
DAVE CARRARO: So we're gonna
stand up in the morning,
want us to go back, just.
PAUL: Absolutely.
DAVE CARRARO: Take
off when we can.
PAUL: Yep.
DAVE CARRARO: Relax.
PAUL: Yep. The weather gets
ferocious, you know,
it's really just no joke,
especially in this size boat.
We're not big boats.
We're in 30-foot boats.
For the weather we go out
in they're very small boats.
DAVE CARRARO: We'll take,
uh, take tomorrow off,
which we really, see where
we're BLEEP and we'll see,
see if it changes.
Now that we're gonna
go back to Gloucester,
the weather's supposed to get
pretty lousy here BLEEP in
the next couple days.
So, it's supposed to
be real BLEEP tonight.
As it is tomorrow
and the next day.
I don't want to come out here
and get pounded for two days
for a small fish.
Yeah, we want to make money,
we want to have, you know,
we want to catch fish,
we want to have fun.
It's a point where it's too
extreme and it's unsafe,
I don't wanna die out there.
Be kind of nice to, to be home
and just catch up on things.
NANCY: So you guys going out
tomorrow?
I guess there's a
north eastern coming.
MARCIANO: Yeah, well
we've been catching fish,
we gotta make it happen.
So we're having dinner, you
know, talking with Nance,
and once in a while she does
express a little bit of concern
for me. The weather's
been a little crappy.
NANCY: You watching the
weather, though, right?
MARCIANO: Yeah, of course
I'm watching the weather.
We're gonna be able
to get the day in.
I gotta make it happen before
I'm all out of tomorrows and
the season's over. So.
I imagine it's tough
on her being at home.
But I have to remind her, you
know, I know what I'm doing.
I just gotta do what's necessary
to get through the next week.
I gotta do what I gotta do.
Like always.
NANCY: I just worry about
you when you're out there.
MARCIANO: Yeah, we'll be
fine, you know the deal.
You know, if you've read
the book, or, you know,
saw the movie Perfect
Storm, they got, you know,
caught in weather that
was unanticipated.
That's the same, you know,
scenario that you know,
could happen to any one
of us at any given time.
But, uh, this is
the job I chose, sometimes
I just gotta do whatever
it takes to get a fish.
You know, Joe's off to college,
I know we gotta make that
tuition payment soon.
Some of the other guys
might take the day off,
but we're gonna go, you know.
What choice do we have? It's
either go fish or go broke.
Those are my options
so we're gonna go fish.
Just like always.
I can't do anything
about this weather.
I can only hope
and do what I know.
We need to catch a fish,
the bills are piling up.
So we're gonna head right
back out there tomorrow,
cause that's what I do.
PAUL: There's a big storm
coming,
gonna be here for
three or four days.
REPORTER: Storms that could
be severe are moving in.
WEATHERMAN: And here's
this huge storm.
This is a classic nor'easter,
heavy rain and
some thunderstorms.
REPORTER: Five, six inches of
rain in two to three hours.
PAUL: Gonna blow
40 miles an hour.
WEATHERMAN: It's a bomb in our
coastal waters, a nor'easter.
MARCIANO: This morning, this is
the exact kind of weather that
the missus is worried about.
But I gotta do what I gotta do
to make sure food gets on
the table.
I need a fish bad.
The only weather that really
matters is whether you need it
bad enough or not.
It's red sky at night,
sailor's delight.
Red sky in the morning,
sailors take warning.
Hard weather's coming down.
Jay and I are gonna tough
out this weather and head to
Stellwagon Bank And its gonna
cost me about five hundred bucks
for fuel, bait and ice.
The reason we go in rough
weather is the bills
gotta be paid.
On a boat we call
that the Voon de face.
JAY: That's my
jacket, that's not me.
MARCIANO: Everybody gets a
little, a little grumpy when
it's BLEEP out.
Mother nature has a good way of
always throwing you that
curve ball.
Every time we go out, there
is the potential that
we could not come home.
Number one, let's hope this
weather doesn't hurt us any,
well, the waves are
good, it makes noise,
the noise of the ocean covers
up the noise of the boat.
So we're hoping the fish
won't hear us out here,
we'll be able to
hook a big one today.
RALPH: It's gonna be
a crazy day out here today.
PIRATE and I are gonna try our
luck out Stellwagen Bank.
Hopefully this weather won't
keep us from getting there.
Probably better off
staying around here cause
we can fish in the windier
weather coming.
Maybe I'm crazy for going
out on days like today.
When it's blowing, I'm going.
PIRATE: One of the captain's
favorite figure of speech he
says all the time, if
it's blowing, we're going.
RALPH: I dropped 500 on the trip
yesterday and I'm out here today
spending 500 again, let's
just hope it pays off.
RALPH: Some guys have
other sources of income.
They don't need to fish on
days they're uncomfortable.
For me, when I need
to catch giant tuna,
I go if it's rough
or if it's calm.
My boats leaking like a sieve.
We haven't caught
anything in a while,
so we'll have to stay out
here, but the tuna like
the BLEEP weather.
So hopefully it will
be to our advantage.
Bluefin like to see
the disorientated bait.
That's what they thrive on.
They're feeding habits intensify
on rough oceans and it gives us,
as the fishing boats, a
better chance to catch them.
PIRATE: This is the only
weather that men go fishing in.
Everybody else stays at the dock
and just dreams about coming out
here and catching the fish.
RALPH: Ready Pirate?
PIRATE: Yep.
RALPH: Alright. Nasty. Ahh.
Gonna be a crazy
day out here today.
Maybe one other
boat, Dave Marciano,
he's the only other crazy
fisherman that would be
out here on a day like today.
MARCIANO: The wind's
tough, tide's tough.
Certainly not gonna
get it easy today.
We've been out here at
Stellwagen Bank
for a couple hours now.
And the weather is brutal, but
the good news is we're seeing
some tuna.
Show a little back
bone will you?
JAY: Sounds like them again.
Yeah, they came up to
like eight, again, ten,
little above ten, eight.
Ten fish on the
screen right now.
We're gonna get a bite.
Come on.
MARCIANO: Braving this weather
had better have been worth it.
We can't keep spending
money on fuel and
supplies without a catch.
JAY: Go look at the machine.
The screen looks
like fourth of July.
MARCIANO: BLEEP mother lodes
here. I don't care if
we bend a rod.
JAY: Here we go, we're on.
We're on. I watched it.
I watched it. This is a
screamer.
Never turn the fish.
Yeah baby. Wooo. Wooo.
MARCIANO: Let me know when the
water gets up to your ears.
JAY: Wooo. Wooo.
MARCIANO: The
weather was so rough,
the waves were crashing up over
the deck and it was getting
pretty deep on the boat,
which is a little bit hairy.
He's sinking the boat,
he's sinking the boat.
When I'm operating the boat, if
I simply just drive too fast,
I'm gonna swamp the boat,
or simply lose the fish.
There's a lot that
could go wrong here.
JAY: Yeah baby.
MARCIANO: He's gonna empty the
reel, he's gonna empty the reel!
JAY: Hurry up, hurry up. Keep
going, keep going.
Keep going. Keep going.
MARCIANO: It takes a little
bit more skill, I think,
to reel in a fish in
weather like this.
You've gotta have
your game face on.
You know, you can't let the
wind, the rain bother you.
You just gotta pretend
none of that's there,
and focus on that fish.
JAY: Dave, my anchors
off the port side of us.
MARCIANO: Yeah,
alright, get on here.
JAY: Go. Watch the way it's
going.
MARCIANO: Down on the bottom.
We might not ever BLEEP
see this thing.
JAY: Take it.
MARCIANO: We got a big one.
I'm worried about it,
he's pulling real hard,
he's at the bottom of the sea,
and this weather really sucks.
All of this could
spell disaster.
Wow, he's a screamer.
JAY: Yeah, he's a
pissed off fish.
MARCIANO: Plain and simple.
You ain't got him till
he's on the boat.
Fine line and a slow hook
separating me from 10,000
dollars right now.
How you doing Jay, you good?
JAY: Getting tired but, my arms
will just fall off before
I stop.
MARCIANO: We have to be real
aware of the fish and the waves,
you know, that takes a lot of
communication between Jay and I.
Alright Jay, I'll spell you.
We haven't had a fish yet this
year that took that much line.
We got a big one here.
You know, this is gonna be at
least a 500 pound plus fish.
And to be honest with you, I'm
a little bit worried with the
weather conditions we got.
We wound up about two miles from
the anchor before he finally
stopped and we could start
to fight him a little.
The first two miles we
were just following.
RALPH: Looks like Marciano's
hooked up, unbelievable.
Damn, that Tuna's giving
Marciano quite a battle.
MARCIANO: It's a big
fish. Okay, get ready Jay.
JAY: Big fish.
MARCIANO: Out here,
get this leader Jay.
Get the rod. Get the rod.
Got it. Got it?
JAY: Yep.
MARCIANO: Pull it
up, pull him up.
JAY: He's going, he's gone.
MARCIANO: No he's not. Yeah,
tail's wrapped.
BLEEP I almost had him and then
bam I dropped the gaff in the
water, but I'm prepared.
I'm like a boy scout, I had
another one close at hand.
JAY: Up, up, up.
Pull it up.
MARCIANO: There you
go Jay, get him.
JAY: Good job, Dave.
MARCIANO: Yeah, that's
what it's all about.
700 pound fish,
now he sits there.
RALPH: He got it. Damn.
JAY: That is a big fish.
MARCIANO: There's only one way
we could make this day better
and that's put one more
fish aboard this boat.
RALPH: I still can't believe
Marciano managed to get a big
fat tuna and we still
haven't seen anything.
PIRATE: It's not
really funny man.
I'm trying to get
some bait down here.
RALPH: Man, it's cold out here.
BLEEP
PIRATE: What' s the matter?
RALPH: It's cold back there!
PIRATE: Really? BLEEP Didn't
notice that, can't feel nothing.
Ahhhh, come here.
Come here, one of you guys
in the pot today. Come here.
MARCIANO: Almost anything we do
that is normally routine becomes
dangerous when it's
this rough out.
If you get a fish in this
kind of weather, you know,
you've got an 800-pound wrecking
ball swinging in the air when
we're hauling that
over the side.
JAY: Coming in right now.
MARCIANO: Now it's
official, he's in the boat.
Always put his best side up.
I want the pretty side up.
JAY: So the buyers see
the best side of the fish.
MARCIANO: Exactly boss.
Definitely bigger than
I thought.
But that explains why he
was such a tough fighter.
Oh, he is around.
JAY: He is?
MARCIANO: Maybe
he'll dress over six.
JAY: Yeah.
MARCIANO: Over the
rail and in the pail.
One thing about these fish
here is they're warm blooded.
During the fight, they
heat up internally.
It's really important to get
those heart guts out and
replace that with ice.
And that's gonna bring you a top
quality piece of merchandise.
Tails up.
DAVE CARRARO: We've got quite
a few fish under our belt in
the last couple weeks and the
weather's coming in and yeah,
we're just gonna, we just, we
just agreed to catch up
with some maintenance,
some much needed sleep and
re-energize and just get ready
to go. Joe, no sinkers yet?
JOE: Should be first part of
next week. I got sixes.
DAVE CARRARO: No, not gonna
do it. Who's catching what?
JOE: Word on the radio was that
Marciano hooked up to
a big fish.
Heard it was an 800 pounder.
DAVE CARRARO:
Marciano's unbelievable.
There's no way somebody's
gonna out fish me.
I'm gonna grab the guys head
out first thing in the morning,
screw the weather. See you soon.
JOE: Good luck.
DAVE CARRARO: Be in in a
couple days to get more stuff.
JOE: Alright, we'll
see you around.
DAVE CARRARO: Thanks Joe.
Come on, let's go. Come on.
JOE: See you Pickles.
RALPH: It's been a real
frustrating day today,
it's been birds, birds, birds.
So we're gonna call it quits
today we gotta go home.
Heading home the seas were, you
know, 20 to 25 feet with uh,
white water four to five
feet on the top and
each wave was a battle.
Now we're gonna head into the
dock in this north east 30 knots
and hopefully get out
of his wet rain suit.
Tomorrow's another day.
PIRATE: Ahhh. There's no
fooling around out here on a
day like today.
Today's a nasty day out. Oww.
RALPH: The wind is
blowing back there, huh?
Just another day of nothing,
nothing but a lot of waves,
wind and water.
Oh, another one.
I'd rather be out here and mark
a couple and get my ass whooped
then sitting at home watching
TV thinking missed something.
PIRATE: I think my underwear
is soaking wet by now,
so that's probably good
enough for me for today.
Ahhh. That was a nail
biter. Wow.
That was about like forty
feet up in the air right now.
Holy Mackerel.
RALPH: Maybe mother nature
got the best of me today,
but I'm gonna keep coming back
at her and take everything
she's got to throw at me.
The storm is still on us, it
looks like it's gonna be here
the rest of the week.
If it's blowing
then we're going.
While the charter boat guys
are home hugging their pillows,
the commercial guys
are fishing every day,
in all kinds of weather.
Soaked again. Holy cow.
They usually evacuate this
dock when it's like this.
Sometimes when you get a big
storm your life could flash
before your eyes, you know, you
think about all the good times
and bad times that you've had
until then, and, you know,
it's an eye opener of,
of life day to day. Oh.
Bad weather, it always makes
it a little extra exciting.
On top of being rough we
have uh, rain, fog, sog,
all in all adds up to BLEEP.
You know, you're a small
dot on a big sea, you know,
anything could happen,
anything's possible.
DAVE CARRARO: We're heading to
a spot where we've been catching
some uh, big fish on
Jeffrey's Ledge and I'm uh,
hoping to produce, and uh, do
the same as we've done before,
catch a big one.
It's supposed to get really,
really BLEEP today and
we can't miss a bite.
We gotta get them frenzied.
We know how to handle
ourselves during this weather.
PAUL: It's really BLEEP out.
North east, it's blowing about
20 and it's gonna get worse.
DAVE CARRARO: You know, when
it's rough out, that's when,
that's when the BLEEP hits the
fan, that's when most of the uh,
incidents, you know, do happen.
We just slow down, work together
and just really, you know,
stay alert, pay attention
to what we're doing.
I don't want to die out there.
PAUL: We got to
be careful today.
MARCIANO: You need extra
strength foot powder for Jay's
severe case of bromadrosis.
JAY: Hey, you never know when
you're gonna see a girl out here
MARCIANO: Famous words of
Frank Zappa, stink foot.
JAY: Stink foot.
MARCIANO: Since we caught
a fish here yesterday,
we spent the night and we're
gonna see if we can pull that
trick off again today.
I'm truly hoping that
being out in this BLEEP weather
pays off for us.
We need the money a good
catch would bring in, badly.
You know, the quota's due
to be met any day now,
so we're really hoping to slip
one more in before that quota's
caught up for the season
and the fishery closes.
Come on, Jay, chum
one up, will you?
JAY: It's always my fault.
MARCIANO: What are you
working for, dot com, or what?
JAY: No, I'm not working for
dot com. I'm working for you.
MARCIANO: How come
there's no fish here?
DAVE CARRARO: Come up Dave?
MARCIANO: Yeah, go ahead.
DAVE CARRARO: Yeah, there
you go, what's going on?
MARCIANO: Not much, not much.
Water is BLEEP here today.
I had high hopes for this place,
we had the bite yesterday.
DAVE CARRARO: Yeah, I
heard about that, congrats.
Where you guys at today?
MARCIANO: We're where
we were yesterday.
Out on Jeffrey's ledge.
DAVE CARRARO: Alright, I'll
chat with you in a while.
MARCIANO: Alright
Dave, standing by.
Tricky Dave of the dot com is up
to no good trying to figure out
where I'm anchored right
now because that fish
we caught yesterday.
I gave him a little
bit of misinformation,
I told him we were
at Jeffrey's Ledge,
but we're really at Stellwagen.
Dave is Dave and I'm still
feeling him out,
the jury's still out on him.
RALPH: This is the
tidal rip right here. Oh.
Tide's gonna change
right after this.
These storms are crazy, you get
little pockets of nice weather
and then all of a sudden the
weather turns to BLEEP again.
There's a break in
the weather and,
and at this time of the season
we want to stay out there as
long as we can and get a fish.
Reel this one in, give
me some rubber bands.
My eyes are focused on the
machine and the radio up in the
bow and PIRATE's responsible
for everything in the stern.
Reel in that line in the back!
Reel in that BLEEP line in the
back. No, the other line!
PIRATE: wasn't paying
attention on the tide change,
then we got a big tangle, one
of the lines got scraped on
the keel of the boat.
I'm thinking, what now.
We don't need more
BLEEP to deal with.
This weather is enough.
What the BLEEP you standing
inside looking at me for?
PIRATE: When there's a
storm coming the tension
really goes up.
The little things
erupt into big things.
RALPH: Pay attention
while this is going on.
Don't let that line
go under the boat.
Right there. Stop.
MARCIANO: That blue rod's gonna
go. We're on! Okay.
JAY: You want to do it?
MARCIANO: We unclip? Nope.
He's gut hooked,
or he's gill hooked,
which is never a good thing.
I could tell this fish
is gill hooked, you know,
the way he keeps coming at me
and the line keeps going slack,
he's shaking his head.
He's gone. Pulled hook,
and it's over that easy.
JAY: That sucks.
MARCIANO: Fortunately,
we have one on the boat,
losing a fish is never a good
thing, but that's not permanent,
this on the other hand,
now that, that's permanent.
PAUL: That's what I like,
nasty, BLEEP weather.
Well, they usually feed
good when it's rough.
They frenzy out,
they feed better.
Plus, it's better for us too.
It's gray out, it's dark out.
The lines are hidden better.
Tuna fisherman advantage today.
DAVE CARRARO: Winds supposed to
be increasing here throughout
the day.
It's only blowing 10 to 15 now.
It's supposed to blow
harder this afternoon,
so it's gonna get a
little snotty out here.
I hope Marciano's
catch wasn't a fluke,
it's gonna be irritating
if I've wasted my time and
energy coming out here today.
That's it, man, we're all set
up, putting one more bait out.
Bait out and wait it out.
That's it.
That's a big ass fish right
there. Right there.
PAUL: Yeah, off
to the side. See they hurry.
DAVE CARRARO: Yes they are,
coming up, came up from 120,
came up to 90.
So there you go, you never
know, that might be our
1,100 pounder right there.
I'm going in the back.
PAUL: Here he comes again.
DAVE CARRARO: Really?
PAUL: Yeah.
DAVE CARRARO: Come
on, get out, get out.
PAUL: Nice big one. Big
blob. You know.
DAVE CARRARO: That's
nice, that's a big boy.
I'm marking another one,
and it starts raining,
hopefully this Tuna
likes the rain. [BEEP]
PAUL: Got him, we got him.
DAVE CARRARO: Forward left.
Forward left. Bring him around.
PAUL: Hold on.
SANDRO How you doing Paul?
DAVE CARRARO: Come
here you bitch.
Stay down sea, Sandro.
It's nasty out, wind's
coming up 25, 30 knots.
BLEEP rough.
Okay, forward left.
PAUL: It's really hard
to work when it's rough.
DAVE CARRARO: Bring it around.
PAUL: It's tough fishing.
DAVE CARRARO: We're losing it.
Hurry, hurry, he's getting away.
Go, go, go.
PAUL: Got him, get him,
get him. Get him, get the work!
DAVE CARRARO: We're
gonna lose it.
Come back a little Sandro.
PAUL: Yeah, nice.
Thank you.
DAVE CARRARO: Keep it down sea
good job. Forward.
Neutral, sinker, swivel
here in a second.
Coming up soon.
Get a good look at him.
Color. There it is.
PAUL: Big blue baby.
DAVE CARRARO: Neutral. Neutral.
Gonna measure. Got one.
PAUL: He's a keeper.
DAVE CARRARO: Keep bopping,
I'm gonna back off. So gaf.
PAUL: Alright, keep going.
DAVE CARRARO: Forward, forward.
You're okay.
PAUL: Oh, he burnt my
hands, the little prick.
Little bastard burnt
my BLEEP hands.
DAVE CARRARO: Little bitch.
PAUL: Little bitch.
DAVE CARRARO: Here he comes.
There he comes.
Ready, forward, just a touch.
PAUL: Right in the tail
down back, yep, nice. Got him.
DAVE CARRARO: I don't know
if I got. I don't know if I
PAUL: You got him, right?
DAVE CARRARO: I got
the harpoon line.
PAUL: Okay.
DAVE CARRARO: Here we go.
PAUL: Got one.
DAVE CARRARO: Got one. That's a
300-pound fish right there.
It'll bring between
three and 4,000 dollars.
PAUL: Good job, he's all bled
out. Let's get another one.
DAVE CARRARO: Let's
get another one.
MARCIANO: Alright
Jay, hey listen,
this storm's coming down
pretty quick here, let's,
let's haul that anchor and
get the hell out of here.
My battery's so low.
Dammit.
I wonder what the BLEEP
the problem is now here.
It should go right over.
This ain't good.
Dammit Jay seems like we,
uh, we got a problem here.
Hang on a minute let me see
if I can figure this out.
Yeah, Tuna.com, you on
there sneaky Dave, come in.
DAVE CARRARO: Look at that one.
Whoa. Wow. Hold on. Hold on.
Yeah, we'll get
out of here soon.
It's gonna be tough
pulling this anchor,
we gotta be really careful.
SANDRO: Yeah.
DAVE CARRARO: So, we'll
stick it out till uh,
after the tide change,
then we'll get out of here.
SANDRO: Checking out.
DAVE CARRARO: I've been
in a lot worse than this.
When that wind comes up and the
ocean gets big, it's a violent,
violent place to be in, I mean,
just one minute you're sitting
there drinking your coffee,
eating your sandwich,
next minute a wave comes and
takes the boat sideways and
you're, you're under water.
Get a bite any time, and
even if we do hook up,
it's gonna be tough to get them.
What are you doing down there?
He's holding on.
He's got two hands pinned
on the side. Whoa. Hold on.
EVA: What's ten less than 75.
NANCY: Well, you've
just got to subtract.
EVA: 65?
NANCY: Yep, excellent.
That's a tricky one.
David left Wednesday morning
and we've been waiting.
It's, this is, like, it's
been the longest, but I,
we're hoping he just stayed out
to catch a fish and hoping he's
okay and just want to hear
him, that he's good and, yeah.
So. Well, you have to
take ten minus 106.
MARCIANO: Right now the
engine won't turn over,
I can't seem to raise
anybody on the radio and uh,
we got this bad weather
coming down on us.
Such a pain in the ass.
The worst could happen.
We could have a
disaster out there,
like when the boat sank uh,
from under me in my old boat,
the Angelica Joseph.
What the BLEEP we
got going on here?
Well, the boat was sinking
and I was treading water and
watching her kind of slip under
the waves, you know,
what was going through
my mind at the time was,
how was my family gonna
get by without me.
It was who's gonna take care
of them. Son of a bxxch.
Come in, can you hear me?
Any of you guys out here?
BLEEP I got to figure this
out here. Damnit.
We're having some
engine trouble here.
At this point, I'm not exactly
sure what the hell
I'm gonna do. Alright.
If this don't work this time,
we're out of BLEEP options.
It's a miracle.
And just like that it's over.
Alright Jay, we lucked out here.
I got this BLEEP thing running.
And the truth is, after
that little scare,
I was ready to get
back to my family.
Let's get out of here.
DAVE CARRARO: You want to
get out of here, or what?
SANDRO: I'm down for whatever.
DAVE CARRARO: Huh?
SANDRO I'm down for
whatever you wanna do.
DAVE CARRARO: Go home?
PAUL: You're down
with anything, man.
SANDRO: We'll do
whatever you want.
DAVE CARRARO: Wash
up, go get some beers.
SANDRO: Yeah.
DAVE CARRARO: Hot food, soup.
It's just too rough today,
it's, ah, we're not marking any
fish.
The wind's just
coming up too strong.
It's a point where it's too
extreme and it's unsafe,
you know, we're not,
I want to come home,
I don't want to die out there.
And, ah, you know, you
push the limits sometimes,
one day it's gonna come up and
bite you in the ass and
you're not gonna come home.
PAUL: Hold on.
DAVE CARRARO: Come on,
let's get out of here.
We'll pack it in slow.
Now I'm, I'm ready to throw in
the towel today. I'm...
SANDRO: Yeah, let's
get out of here.
Beer sounds good though.
DAVE CARRARO: Yep, so the guys
went home already and
we're gonna follow suit.
Like I said, it's just
getting worse and worse here.
Well, a warm bed
sounds good to me.
MARCIANO: It's just like that,
somebody turned the fan on and
the storm broke, you never know
with this New England weather,
you know, but that's how
it happens a lot of times.
NANCY: You gonna
give poppa a big hug?
EVA: Is he coming?
NANCY: Uh, he should
be on his way, dear.
MARCIANO: All right. I'm glad
that BLEEP ride's over with.
Being that we're such
a close-knit family,
for me to disappear for
days on end, you know,
sometimes four or five days,
that's tough on any family.
The good news is, you
know, by staying out,
we saved a lot of money in fuel
and a little bit of tackle.
NANCY: Yeah, the boys are in.
CINDY: Welcome home.
Welcome back to Gloucester,
Massachusetts.
So happy you returned.
Safe and sound.
NANCY: Wow.
CINDY: Wow. Look at how pretty.
Oh, wow. Oh huh.
Pretty, pretty.
Love it. Love it.
NANCY: We came for
hugs, you know.
MARCIANO: Okay. Alright.
NANCY: Mwah. Mwah.
You smell good.
JAY: Love you.
CINDY: Ah, nephew, Jason.
ROXANE: I, I said
where's my Jason.
CINDY: Oh, honey.
MARCIANO: Now, Jay,
don't make any plans,
we'll be going
right back out, son.
NANCY: Wow. Look at you.
CINDY: Yeah, going on the wall.
NANCY: Look at you.
CINDY: Going on the wall.
MARCIANO: I try and make up
for it and do all those special
things with each member
of the family, um,
so we get that
quality time and, ah,
try and keep that
family unit together.
How's the market been?
MAN: The market
was weak yesterday.
MARCIANO: Yeah, I heard guys
pissing and moaning on
the way home.
And what about that
domestic market?
MAN: Okay, we move, we
moved some fish today.
MARCIANO: All right.
MAN: Domestically.
MARCIANO: Well you guys know
the deal, I'm starving to death,
so the best we can do.
MAN: Absolutely.
We always do for you.
MARCIANO: So I can go, I can't
even write a check for fuel
right now.
MAN: Alright, take care.
MARCIANO: The weather's
been a little BLEEP lately,
but that's the name
of the game, you know,
sometimes if you want
to make a paycheck,
you're gonna get spanked
around a little bit.
You know the deal,
we're going, ah,
we're probably leaving the day
after tomorrow actually, ah,
maybe even tomorrow,
I don't know,
we gotta listen to the weather.
We just got in.
We just got to figure it out.
NANCY: Yep.
MARCIANO: And that's it, we may
be bound tomorrow morning again.
NANCY: Alright, you
gonna go out way out.
MARCIANO: We're
going back out there.
NANCY: Oh, you are?
MARCIANO: It's the, it's the
only game in town right now.
NANCY: Is...
MARCIANO: Back to hell
for another week, I guess.
The bottom line is, I'm
doing this for my family.
You know, I love my job.
I love to be able to come
out here and do it, you know,
just so I can give them
the best I possibly can.
RALPH: There's some fish around,
that's for sure.
That's him up there at 35 feet.
I'll fight the storm if it means
a big tuna is gonna be on
the end of my rod.
I think he might be up there.
The weather's not gonna stop me.
We're gonna stay out here as
long as it takes to get a fish.
Let's get a slob on
the chum now, Pirate.
It's BLEEP conditions today.
Huh?
PIRATE: Oh, we're
soaked to the butt hole.
RALPH: Fishing on a rough
day, it may not be comfortable
fishing, but, that's when I have
the most confidence that the,
the fish that come under
the boat will bite.
PIRATE: Tucked away in
my nice little corner.
Captain seemed to
think that, ah,
the rougher weather
brings the tuna fish in.
We should get a better chance
of maybe, ah, catching a fish.
Fish on. Fish on.
RALPH: Oh, yeah, he's there.
He's there.
Get rid of these other rods.
PIRATE: These rubber band
won't break on us then. Ah.
RALPH: You ready to take this?
PIRATE: Alright, I got it. Ah.
Now, it's got a good
little head shake going on.
RALPH: Let's see him.
PIRATE: Gonna be
close, really close.
I'm saying to myself, there's no
way I'm letting this one get
away, we need this one.
You could see the color already.
Get the gaf, get the gaf.
Might be a keeper.
RALPH: Get the gaff, get the
gaff. Might be a keeper.
PIRATE: Aw, BLEEP the
thing snapped on me.
BLEEP Where is he?
Right here.
RALPH: Don't lose it. Hold it.
Hold it. Get the head.
PIRATE: Alright.
RALPH: Get the tail rope.
PIRATE: I got it. Easy cap.
RALPH: That's it, he's ours.
Go tie that line there.
PIRATE: Oh, here we go,
I got it right here.
By the gills. All right.
RALPH: 76. Alright, that's a
high five now. Thank you, sir.
PIRATE: It's not the
biggest fish we've gotten,
but the streak's broken now so
hopefully we start getting back
on another good roll.
RALPH: It's some fuel
money, that's for sure.
It just goes to show you if you
make the sacrifice and you get
out on those rough days.
It could pay off.
Alright. I'll start...
PIRATE: It's a dark back.
RALPH: I'll chum, you
take care of the fish.
PIRATE: I got ya.
PAUL: Okay, Sandro. Little
more, keep going.
That's good, we got it.
PAUL: Here and here, see
I rinsed all the oil off.
DAVE CARRARO:
There's no oil in it.
PAUL: A little bit. A new
cut, you'd see different,
you know what I mean?
DAVE CARRARO: Yeah. That's the
tail cut. It's not a great fish.
Little bit of fat in the minors,
the majors, there's not much.
It's a good size fish for one
restaurant, they look for that,
I'll give it like
a c plus, at best.
It was definitely a ride
from hell coming home.
I mean, we had 40-knot
winds, it is what it is, uh,
I could hope for a better
trip next time. That's all.
We made money, happy
with that, but, uh,
I'll be a lot happier
with, ah, three next time.
So we'll see, it's alright.
Take it.
Bring him in, ready?
Say goodbye.
MAN: Woo.
DAVE CARRARO: Say goodbye.
PAUL: The majority
didn't have...
We just unloaded a
nice 300 pounder,
we need to get right the
BLEEP back out tomorrow.
Cause they're biting right
now, while it's rough,
they frenzy out.
Really fortunate and
lucky, we got one.
PAUL: Some people would say
we're out of your BLEEP minds,
but why do we do this?
You're a BLEEP addict.
You 're a tuna addict.
We caught a lot
of fish this year.
This weather separates the men
from the boys. That's for sure.
MARCIANO: What do you want to
drink? You want something?
JOE: Apple juice.
MARCIANO: You know, even
with the bad weather,
we wound up having
a pretty good week.
We had one nice fish that
brought us, you know,
a little over 8,000 dollars.
So we're gonna head right
back out there tomorrow cause
that's what I do.
But at least for now, it's nice
to spend a little time
with my son.
That was probably a 850 pounder.
It's pretty close to that.
You know, I'm real lucky that
he's really good quality.
He's got a lot of grease
in him, lot of grease.
JOE: Yeah.
MARCIANO: But that's
our score there.
JOE: How long did it
take to fight him on you?
JAY: Maybe an hour.
MARCIANO: Yeah, an hour.
JAY: Well, at least we
didn't come back with zero.
MARCIANO: That's right.
Obviously, family is priority,
but at the same point,
fishing is important too,
because ultimately that's what
supports the family.
JAY: I just wish we had
a shower on the boat.
MARCIANO: Yeah, keep dreaming.
Shower.
RALPH: Nice day. It's
a lousy day weather wise,
but we managed to
get a bite today.
PIRATE: Oh my God, you
don't have to go out there,
don't be out there.
If you brave the elements long
enough and you fish hard enough,
it pays off at the end. Oh.
RALPH: Typically the fish
like the nasty weather,
so we like to go when it's
raining and blowing and
rough and, you know, it's
usually a little fishier,
and there's less boats,
less competition.
That's right, little
fish, big checks.
MAN: Alright, let's
see what we got.
Pirate, you switched
it to kilograms.
PIRATE: I didn't touch nothing.
The, it was flopping around.
MAN: Two twelve point
five, that's a nice one.
PIRATE: Wow, that's pretty good.
MAN: Nice job, Ralphie.
RALPH: Just bring me
the big check, man.
Little fish, big checks.
PIRATE: Boy, that thing had a
little bit more meat on it than
I thought.
I'd rather catch a two hundred
pounder at 20 bucks than catch a
400 pounder at ten bucks.
Hey, I'll take it, it's a check.
but Pirate, go ahead, tell them
what went on out there today.
PIRATE: I'm sitting
here like this,
he come down through out of the
wheel house to do something and
all of the sudden, he yells,
fish on! I was like wow.
And I'm looking like this,
I didn't know what to do,
so I had to run up
to the bow like this.
Climb up over there.
Then you gotta jump
back on the deck,
come down the other
pole like this.
And then finally we
got back over here,
the captain gave me the pole,
got it out like this and
we started.
A few minutes later, we
started seeing the line and
the color and then
that was the end of that.
RALPH: You ready? Let's go.
PIRATE: Yep. Captain says
it's time to get these wet
clothes off, head back to the
house, grab a nice hot shower
and a meal and go make some
z's, call up my honey bee,
see where she's at right now.
Give her the good news.
RALPH: We got paid for today and
hopefully we can continue
the roll and, and catch
a couple more before
the end of the fall blitz.
PIRATE: Charging my batteries
up, so I can come back out here
and do it all over again.