NIALL ROWNTREE: We see the
animal's motionless.
There's no life signs.
But just to be sure,
you touch the eye.
The animal's completely dead.
OK?
No suffering, nice clean kill.
ALEX MILLER: Where's
the bullet hole?
NIALL ROWNTREE: The bullet hole
is exactly where you were
told to put it.
The bullet hole's there.
So it was where you were
practicing this morning.
NIALL ROWNTREE: The tragic thing
with this is we couldn't
get the [INAUDIBLE]
in white.
ALEX MILLER: Yeah.
It's dead now.
NIALL ROWNTREE: Yeah.
ALEX MILLER: Cutting it's just
like slicing a steak.
NIALL ROWNTREE: Exactly.
The first thing we're
gonna do is we're
gonna bleed the animal.
So we do that with [INAUDIBLE]
top of the breastbone with the
knife there [INAUDIBLE], OK?
Did you see that?
And if you remove your hat,
my friend, this is the
bit you came for.
You put that on your head
[INAUDIBLE], and you can shake
my hand if you wish.
And you've joined
the elite club.
ALEX MILLER: Murder club.
NIALL ROWNTREE: OK, make an
incision and cut all the way
up to the [INAUDIBLE].
We start the breastbone.
Turn her sideways.
And what you can do here is put
your hand on the top of it
and give it a push down
like that [INAUDIBLE].
And what you'll do here is
you'll do a quick check on the
health of the animal.
What you're looking at that
there, the stomach of the
animal is quite healthy.
So that's your first indication
that this animal,
having killed it, is perfectly
OK for the human food chain.
ALEX MILLER: Death buggy.
1, 2, 3.
NIALL ROWNTREE: We're off.
Ready?
ALEX MILLER: Yeah.
Right, now we're bringing my
kill back to the base, where
we're gonna slit it up and turn
it into real, genuine
chunks of meat.
I can really smell deer
blood on my face.
This seems a lot kinder than
battery farming or
something like that.
They just throw chickens into
tiny, little fences and let
them eat each other and shit on
each other and live and die
in equal amounts of
abject horror.
[LAUGHTER]
NIALL ROWNTREE: Well, what we'll
do is we'll process the
animal, clean it out.
We'll take out its [INAUDIBLE]
its heart, liver, and lungs.
We take its head clean
off, and then
we'll skin the animal.
[INAUDIBLE].
On three.
1, 2, 3.
You're looking right
into the womb.
ALEX MILLER: Is that the womb?
NIALL ROWNTREE: That's the womb
there you're looking at.
ALEX MILLER: Whoa.
NIALL ROWNTREE: She'd have been
mated in early October.
ALEX MILLER: OK, so when
would she give birth?
NIALL ROWNTREE: She'll give
birth probably around about
36th of June would have been
when the calf was born.
ALEX MILLER: Oh, god.
Oh, my god.
NIALL ROWNTREE: That's
[INAUDIBLE]
the sack there, OK?
And there's the fetus.
So you can see it is a
whole little deer.
ALEX MILLER: Right, can I--
NIALL ROWNTREE: And if you look
at it carefully, you can
see it's a little female.
Hopefully it's [INAUDIBLE].
NIALL ROWNTREE: Has it?
Has it?
OK.
ALEX MILLER: Yeah.
It's like a deer.
I can feel the bones
inside it.
NIALL ROWNTREE: Yeah.
Oh, it is like a deer.
Well, it is a deer.
ALEX MILLER: Yes,
it is a deer.
NIALL ROWNTREE: [INAUDIBLE].
And there you go.
It's comes out.
[INAUDIBLE].
That's the head off.
ALEX MILLER: It's like
a Giger drawing.
NIALL ROWNTREE: See,
that's coming off.
ALEX MILLER: Yeah.
What's interesting about this is
that every step further we
get into the kind of grotesque
dismemberment, it actually
becomes a lot easier
to handle.
NIALL ROWNTREE: There you go.
[INAUDIBLE].
ALEX MILLER: I feel like
such a psycho.
NIALL ROWNTREE: Are you glad--
ALEX MILLER: I finally-- yeah,
like I finally justified 25
years of eating lots
and lots of meat.
NIALL ROWNTREE: We had a group
of ladies here a couple years
ago, and they asked if we could
arrange testosterone
courses for London
[INAUDIBLE].
ALEX MILLER: I'm kind
of interested.
I mean, I'm a little bit
disturbed that I'm not more
disturbed by the
whole process.
I thought I was gonna be feeling
really squeamish.
But it all seems
quite natural.
It seems, I don't know,
just like a trade.
You know what I mean?
It just seems like dealing with
a physical issue in a
physical manner.
It's all very competent,
all very serious.
It all makes sense, you know?
NIALL ROWNTREE: Uh-huh.
[BAGPIPES PLAYING]
ALEX MILLER: That night was
Burns' night, a night in honor
of Scottish people's
favorite poet.
We'd been invited along, but we
weren't the guest of honor.
That privilege is always
reserved for locally produced
venison haggis.
-[SINGING]
[INAUDIBLE].
ALEX MILLER: Everyone was
getting pretty smashed, and so
was I. Perhaps that's why I
agreed to wear a Scottish bow
tie and read a poem I'd never
read full of words I didn't
understand.
[APPLAUSE]
ALEX MILLER: I've got a couple
of disabilities.
The first is that I'm reading
a Robert Burns poem in an
English accent, and the second
is that I'm quite drunk.
So--
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
[LAUGHTER]
ALEX MILLER: I think you'll
find they're my
special power, my friend.
You'll all be wearing
them in six months.
Don't worry about that.
-[INAUDIBLE].
ALEX MILLER: [INAUDIBLE] the
poem I'm gonna read is called
"The Trogger."
"As I come down by Annan side,
intending for the border,
amang the Scroggie
banks and braes,
what met I but a trogger.
He laid me down upon my back,
I thought he was but joking,
till he was in me to
the hilts, O the
deevil tak sic troggin!
What could I say, what could I
do, I bann'd and sair misca'd
him, but whiltie-whaltie gae'd
his eye the mair that I
forbade him.
He stell'd his foot against a
stane, and doubl'd ilka stroke
in, till I gaed daft amang
his hands, O the
deevil tak sic troggin!
Then up we raise, and took the
road, and in by Ecclefechan,
where the brandy-stoup we gart
it clink, and the strang-beer
ream the quench in.
Bedown the bents o' Bonshaw
braes, we took the partin'
yokin'; but I've claw'd a
sairy cut systine, O the
deevil tak
sic troggin!" [APPLAUSE]
ALEX MILLER: Peace out.
[MUSIC PLAYING]