and he knows what unites than the one
for it
that goes through pol pot and you know
uh...
in russia and germany it's at national
health care that's dario unified at
night guest
for obama
it's about the government running at
wants the government has control over
your health care if they control every
aspect of your life
and
as important
as health care is everybody if the
government says you've got to do any
me and see in order to get health care
you'll do it
you'll be too scared not to
healthcare has
always been nationalized health care has
always been one of the first objectives
of emi of the famous totalitarian
regimes
national socialism first thing he did
nationwide healthcare the socialists in
the u_k_ nationwide healthcare its
victims get you get that began you
control everything
about how people live
estelle unfortunate that
that official name of nazism was
national socialism
mail about that but any other is a
little more
healthcare the socialism the object
basically the same dot
the fact that i had like a re-entry
periods the u_k_ today
tonight's standing
uh... now of course
as usual he's totally wrong about faxes
date nazis did not bring in nationalize
healthcare germany thirty have
nationalize healthcare actually since
the eighteen hundreds as i write about
getting thirty and four years yet for
the yes bismarck that are going to say
that i had the pleasure of your and
suppose
is a person who wrote about this that
really great point
you know hitler
didn't need nationalize healthcare to
kill people and that he had
concentration camps
okayy
so if you show i have added some like he
was like going green roots
will start with medicare
no was all putting them on trains
breathing because it is a desperate
killing them off
knowledge as to media i wish brush
in russia's know when the challenges
i don't even know you know so i mean i
go back and forth the whether there's
even value would bring this up
you know whether showing
brush saying stuff like this would mean
so crazy
and you want someone to be like brush
refresh your saying that the biggest
priority in oxygen national health care
your dishes
you're making this up
and by the way
here she didn't provide national health
care to its citizens and and
try misstate the world has ever seen
just had
dying of starvation
throughout their entire run of communism
and and that was actually the greatest
crime sent me a little less people dot
yet so i mean it's just that you want
somebody to challenge in the managers
tend to produce
well it's it's not so i like the way
your first talking about history
also a bit
let's say that that was something that
happened back in the forties but but
they point out in our but we've got
injury still has national health care
binocular people
yet whatever than any country we need to
go back to the forties or some sort of
history lesson of what it's like to live
in a country that has socialize health
care
we got the countries that we know it's
like its superior to the u_s_ and the
results they have better health care
they're better results they live longer
enhances our
and what part of their argument
by the way do they get
other than just saying it that that old
bom bom all wants the government to run
out
the government although it's not a
normal letter i will not be getting we
need to get that partners resilience
that life
one last thing
bata nazis then aidid trains run on time
so that's why you know trains or college
sa directly
yesterday with the first thing we need
to do is get rid of all the transmitter
will first have to go to the train
station shack if it's not a few minutes
late developments in with vivica