NARRATOR: As Friday's fighting
intensified, black smoke
billowed up into the evening
sky over Aleppo.
Gathered near the historic Old
City, fighters of the Free
Syrian Army clashed with forces
of President Bashar al
Assad as government troops
advanced towards the 17th
century market in the heart of
one of the world's oldest and
continuously inhabited cities.
As the street battles ensued,
Assad's forces attacked the
local population, including
civilians, from their
stronghold located in Aleppo's
13th century citadel.
From their elevated positions,
Assad's forces fired into the
old city, devastating the
area controlled by
the Free Syrian Army.
MALE SPEAKER: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
NARRATOR: Over the course of
the following days, as the
fire continued to burn
uncontrollably, hundreds of
shops and medieval houses were
scorched and destroyed.
MALE SPEAKER: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
NARRATOR: As the best preserved
souk in the Middle
East burned, I met with vendors
and fighters with the
Free Syrian Army as they helped
small business owners
salvage silks, spices, and
perfumes from their scorched
storefronts.
FEMALE SPEAKER:
[SPEAKING ARABIC]
MALE SPEAKER: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
FEMALE SPEAKER:
[SPEAKING ARABIC]
MALE SPEAKER: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
FEMALE SPEAKER:
[SPEAKING ARABIC]
CHILD: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
NARRATOR: One of the world's
best preserved souks has been
lost forever.
The destruction of such a
significant cultural relic
further undermines any notion of
understanding and peace in
the region.
MALE SPEAKER: [SPEAKING ARABIC]