KARLEY SCIORTINO: Hi.
I'm Karley.
I've been writing my blog
Slutever for four years now.
I write about stuff like sex,
dating, and how stressful it
can be having a vagina.
And then sometimes I write
about weirder stuff, like
fetish, obscure porn, and
magical masturbation rituals.
I like to think of
Slutever as an
investigation into sexual behavior.
You know, whatever.
Recently while pondering
deep thoughts via the
web, I got to thinking--
what is the meaning
of life, anyways?
And who should I go out with?
You know what I mean?
Finding someone who wants
to fuck you back
can be really hard.
Dating is so stressful and
scary and convoluted.
There's so much to
think about.
Does this dress make
my arms look fat?
How soon is too soon for anal?
Do second cousins
count as incest?
Jeez, it's too much.
To try and make some sense of
it all, I decided to speak
with some dating experts to ask
them some of the questions
us girls have always wanted to
know about the mysteries of
the coital dance.
So I left my Brooklyn apartment
and walked over to
my mom's house.
My mom is really into Jesus.
When I was younger, she used to
force me to watch programs
about chastity that she taped
off the God channel, or
whatever it's called.
Still, she started dating my
dad when she was 16, which
means they've been together
for roughly 100 years.
So she must have some tips to
offer on how to find the one.
OK, so what should
I wear on dates?
TRACEY SCIORTINO: Showing
everything on a date is awful.
Just don't have like a really,
really tight, short
skirt and low shirt.
KARLEY SCIORTINO: Like,
vagina-like skirts?
TRACEY SCIORTINO:
No vagina-like.
Ever.
KARLEY SCIORTINO: So what
qualities do you think I
should be looking
for in a guy?
TRACEY SCIORTINO: Um, somebody
who has self-respect and
respects you.
Somebody with a sense
of humor.
He has to be handsome.
And someone that you don't have
to worry about, you know,
when-- you know, when they
walk out the door.
KARLEY SCIORTINO: What about
guys who have-- you know, date
multiple people at once?
TRACEY SCIORTINO: Don't
date them, Karley.
Wait.
Honestly, though.
Don't.
KARLEY SCIORTINO: If you're on
a date with someone, and it's
the first date, and it's going
really well, how far should
you go with a guy?
TRACEY SCIORTINO: You
should kiss him.
That's it.
KARLEY SCIORTINO: Wow.
My mom gave me some really
good, outdated advice.
But I felt like it was time to
speak with a real dating
professional.
Someone with lots of
certificates on their walls
and who owns a website.
So I cabbed it over to the Upper
West Side to sit down
with life coach and dating
expert Tracey Steinberg.
Tracy's helped dozens
of New York women
find their soul mates.
So like, why not me?
What advice do you
give to people--
we're kind of an age where
you don't want
to date losers anymore.
You know?
TRACEY STEINBERG: Good.
KARLEY SCIORTINO: We're like,
over dating DJs and we kind of
want to meet someone that you
could potentially spend the
rest of your life with.
TRACEY STEINBERG: I think the
first thing that you should
never, ever tolerate is someone
who is not healthy,
confident, and available.
That an automatic
deal breaker.
That, we don't waste
your time.
KARLEY SCIORTINO: But what
do you mean by healthy?
Because actually, I tend to like
guys that are just like
really skinny, kind
of sickly looking.
And like sometimes I'm into
guys that are disabled.
Like crazy, mentally and
physically handicapped freaks.
And maybe that's not what
I should be doing.
TRACEY STEINBERG: I
think it depends.
If it's giving you the results
that you want,
then keep doing it.
If you want different
results, you have to
do something different.
I just think to go through life
with someone who loves
you so much and who you love
so much is just a wonderful
way to go through life.
KARLEY SCIORTINO:
Love is cool.
TRACEY STEINBERG:
It's really cool.
KARLEY SCIORTINO: Also getting
too drunk around someone is
bad, 'cause you say stuff that
you wish you didn't say and
then you're like, that's
embarrassing.
TRACEY STEINBERG: Right, because
you turn off your
brain a lot.
You're shutting off
a big part of your
brain when you're drunk.
KARLEY SCIORTINO: Yeah.
Also your vagina turns off
when you're drunk.
TRACEY STEINBERG: You turn
off your brain--
KARLEY SCIORTINO:
And your vagina.
Life coach Tracy taught
me a lot.
But it felt like it was
time to get some
more practical advice.
So I headed back to Brooklyn
to meet up with my friends
Alexis Penny.
Alexis is a hooker drag queen.
He sucks dick for a living.
And also has his own dick.
So I figured he'd be the perfect
person to talk to you
about the more hands-on aspects
of dating, like how to
give a good blow job.
ALEXIS PENNY: The best way to
get a guy off with a blow job
is actually to incorporate
a hand.
And really, like, what
feels good is the
pressure of the lips.
It's not like actually that
empty space within your mouth.
Definitely watch the teeth.
That's the biggest one.
Like that's-- pretty much
the worst blow job is
a toothy blow job.
KARLEY SCIORTINO: Like
wrap your lips around
your teeth like this?
ALEXIS PENNY: Yeah.
Wrap your lips around
your teeth.
I, like, made a concerted effort
when I was younger to
get rid of my gag reflex.
I like to do sort of like a,
like a swirling motion--
KARLEY SCIORTINO: With
your tongue?
ALEXIS PENNY: Yeah.
So it'd be like--
and that way you're getting
like a lot of sensation.
You're basically like
masturbating a
guy with your mouth.
KARLEY SCIORTINO: You
don't want to go at
the head and be like--
ALEXIS PENNY: No.
KARLEY SCIORTINO: What is
the deal with balls?
ALEXIS PENNY: Balls
are really weird.
KARLEY SCIORTINO: OMG.
It seems like everyone has
really strong opinions when it
comes to love.
But before I could call it a
day, I needed to find out what
my friend Dr. Leah Kelly had
to say about all this.
She's a neuroscientist, so I
knew she'd use her smart
powers to tell me what
happens in our brains
when we fall in love.
KARLEY SCIORTINO: So Leah, what
happens in your brain
when you fall in love?
DR. LEAH KELLY: Well, they've
put people in love in brain
scanners, and what they see is
the same area light up that is
rewarding, say, when
you take cocaine.
So you get this rush of this
neurotransmitter called dopamine.
And this is actually different
to what's going on in your
brain in relation to sex.
So sex and love are not
necessarily the same thing.
But when you have sex with the
same person, what happens over
time is that you start to
form an attachment.
And that's mediated by something
called oxytocin.
And that is what
sustains love.
KARLEY SCIORTINO: Gosh,
I feel like I've
learned so much today.
But more than anything, what all
of this made me realize is
that unfortunately, there's no
formula we can follow to find
our soul mates.
We are all equally lost within
this labyrinth of love.
And realistically, dating
and sex are meant to
be clumsy and awkward.
But it's good to create an open
dialogue about this stuff
in order to make our sexuality
a little bit less terrifying.
And if you remember to read
lots of books, take your
vitamins, and not be a total
bore, one day you will find
that special person who will
love you for you, who will
give you semi-regular orgasms
and ask nicely before he puts
it in your butt.
You know, Slutever.