ROCCO CASTORO: Hi, I'm Rocco,
and today we're in Venice
Beach at the Rose Cafe,
which is a favorite
eatery of Rob Delaney.
He's a very funny comedian and
what some have termed the King
of Twitter.
He writes a column for us
at Vice on the website.
And today we're going to have
breakfast with him and chat
about eating vaginas, Rick
Santorum, hairiness, and all
sorts of other fun stuff.
ROCCO CASTORO: I'm hear on a
lovely Wednesday morning with
the lovely Rob Delaney.
ROB DELANEY: Hello.
ROCCO CASTORO: The first thing
you did for us and how this
relationship started was a piece
in our Larfs issue a
couple years back.
And the piece was
called "Comedy."
ROB DELANEY: It was.
ROCCO CASTORO: It actually
opened the issue.
ROB DELANEY: Yeah, well, I had
been approached by your
magazine to write for them
anything I wanted,
essentially, about comedy.
And I remember lamenting that
most magazines, when they do a
comedy issue, it's usually
really awful and unfunny.
So I really just tried to sort
of plumb my depths, so to
speak, psychologically and just
talk about my motivations
for doing comedy, what I think
is funny, what's not funny,
why it might be funny, what
sort of drives me.
Because I like comedians.
I like it other comedians.
And I like fans of comedy.
And I wanted to give them
something like this that would
hopefully nourish them.
I wanted them to have
the sandwich.
ROCCO CASTORO: The subject
matter of that article--
sort of lay of the land at that
point in your life, what
you're doing.
And you told me earlier
that you were--
I don't know if you were at
the time, but right around
then working at a call center
but also doing comedy, and
this was a year and
a half ago.
But you also talked a little bit
about what happened to you
10 years ago, which you can say
much better than I can.
ROB DELANEY: Yeah, well.
Yeah, first, I'll say
you're right.
I'm very lucky right now to be
making a living doing comedy,
but it was just 10 years ago
that I was in a big car
accident that prompted
me to quit drinking.
But yeah, I drove into a
building in LA and broke both
my arms and was in jail
in a wheelchair.
And it was then that I was like,
oh, if I keep drinking,
it'll kill other people.
And I didn't want to
kill other people.
I don't like to kill people.
Sorry, guys.
So after I kind of physically
got better from that accident,
I said, oh, I'm a
comedian now.
ROCCO CASTORO: So do you
remember the first time that
you found out what
Twitter was?
ROB DELANEY: Well, the first
time I heard what it was, I
think I was at a comedy show
and somebody mentioned it.
I'd heard about it maybe on
the news or something.
And it sounded very
unappealing.
Why?
Who cares?
I was on Facebook and Louis
CK had said that
he had joined Twitter.
And I thought, well, maybe--
he usually does things that
I think are funny and
intelligent.
I should check it out.
So I did.
And what I tried to do was just
post jokes rather than,
like, I ate this.
ROCCO CASTORO: So where
did your Twitter--
picture?
I don't know if it's
an avatar?
You're in Speedos.
ROB DELANEY: Yeah.
I am wearing a Speedo
bathing suit.
And that is a bathing suit
that I do genuinely own,
because I live very close
to the beach.
So if I go swimming in the
winter, I will wear that
'cause it just makes more
sense under a wetsuit.
So I totally am aware of the
fact that it's a disgusting
look on a hairy large person.
But basically, I was getting
ready to go swimming at night
with my wife, and my friend John
was there, and I took off
my clothes and had the Speedo,
and he's like, Jesus.
He took a picture.
And then when I first signed up
for Twitter, I thought, oh,
this is so stupid, I'll put
the worst picture of
me that I have up.
And that's it.
And then after a while,
people were like, you
gotta rid of that.
And I was like, no,
I'll never.
ROCCO CASTORO: And your last--
well, we'll say your
last two tweets.
Pepsi's Twitter account said,
The best place to
hide a Pepsi is blank.
And Rob responded, in
a cop's asshole.
Nothing aga-- cops--
we need 'em.
I like 'em.
But the word "cop," it's
(ENUNCIATING) cop.
So I've always taught cop
was a funny word.
I have words that I just
think are funny, just
the sound of them.
ROCCO CASTORO: Phonetically?
ROB DELANEY: Yeah, like cop--
ROCCO CASTORO: Cock?
ROB DELANEY: Ham.
Cock is a funny word.
I love the word ham.
Beef.
A lot of meat-related words.
So cop, cop's just
such a nice word.
And anyway, so, and then
asshole, that just always
makes me laugh.
ROCCO CASTORO: OK.
And your tweet before is,
Virginia is for lovers, and
then in parentheses,
of psychotic--
in all caps--
abortion bills.
So why did you tweet that?
ROB DELANEY: There are right now
in Virginia some lawmakers
who have drafted a bill that
would require women who wanted
to get an abortion to
get an ultrasound.
Now what is a big part of this
is that when a woman is in the
early stages of pregnancy,
the fetus is super tiny.
So they can't use an
over-the-belly ultrasound.
They actually have to put a
probe up her vagina to do the
ultrasound.
And it's a big fucking wand.
It's like bigger than, like,
three of my dicks.
And they're putting it up.
And that--
so it's like robot rape.
It's beyond--
I mean, that's psychological
torture.
It's physical torture.
It's unbelievable and
fundamentally wrong.
ROCCO CASTORO: One thing you
really like to talk about is
women, in a way that
I think is positive
but also very honest.
ROB DELANEY: I do like to take
a more, I don't know,
proletariat approach to like
sexuality, of like a
blue-collar, sweaty, fun
approach to sex.
And I genuinely really
feel the things that
I tweet about that.
Like, I don't like it
when women shave
off their pubic hair.
That is a legitimate
thing that I feel.
That's weird to me.
And maybe it's because I'm a man
and it's easier for me to
see, like it's easier for me to
be an other and see, like,
oh, I see this thing that's
happening to this group of
people, which represents more
than half of our planet's
population, and it's so fucking
wrong that I'm going
to do my little bit that I
possibly can to try and help.
So women usually, the
overwhelming majority, are
funny and nice.
And they'll probably write a
zinger back to me that's
funnier than what I wrote.
ROCCO CASTORO: You've had quite
a few tweets and columns
about the current Republican
candidates.
Who would you say is the
best to make fun of?
ROB DELANEY: Probably Rick
Santorum, because he's the
antipodes of how I feel
about many things.
I feel like his policies, if
enacted, would hurt people.
I feel that he would have a
really negative effect.
So if there's something I see
that I think is having a
negative effect, I'm going to
use comedy to present my ideas
and to eviscerate the ones
that I don't like.
ROCCO CASTORO: When
was there a--
we'll call it an exponential
explosion of Twitter followers?
When did you hit a marker where
you're like, wow, I have
50,000 people following
me on Twitter.
ROB DELANEY: Getting to 100,000
followers took what
felt like forever.
Going from 100,000 to 200,000
was like [SNAP].
Going from 200,000 to 300,000
was like, oh, it happened.
It's crazy.
So the speed that you accumulate
them gets faster.
But the big thing for me was
after years of submitting
packets to late night comedy
shows, and being told, like,
oh, this is terrific, but not
getting hired, I at the same
time got hired by Graham Linehan
to work on story ideas
for the fifth season of the
British show The IT Crowd.
And also I got hired by MTV to
write for a Rob Dyrdek show
called Ridiculousness.
So those two things happened
at the same time.
And Vice Magazine said,
hey, want to
write this comedy article?
ROCCO CASTORO: Some of the most
popular pieces you've
written for us, and I would
imagine tweets as well, have
concerned the nature
of celebrity.
Specifically, a piece you
wrote about suing Kim
Kardashian after her divorce.
ROB DELANEY: Yes.
ROCCO CASTORO: How would
serious were you?
ROB DELANEY: Uh, 100% about
the feelings behind it.
I think that what she
did was wrong.
We know it was fake
from the outset.
So I just wanted to say, no,
young lady, and Ryan Seacrest,
and E Entertainment Television,
and Comcast, who
were also named in
the lawsuit.
ROCCO CASTORO: You're
also writing a book.
ROB DELANEY: I'm
writing a book.
Yes.
The book has nothing
to do Twitter.
It's a memoir/novel
type thing.
Since I am a relatively young
person, I understand that
people wouldn't want to read
a book about just my life.
I wouldn't want to write that.
So I am trying to--
I'm filtering it through
the cheese grater of my
joke-writing-trained mind
to make sure that it is
entertaining.
Because as a comedian, it's my
job that everything that I do
be funny, and at the very
least compelling
and pull you along.