Our first day inside the Greek
riots have been ridiculous.
While the locals have considered
it a mild version
of what they're used to.
To me, it felt like civil war.
Old women who pat a teenage
and a kiss on the back as
militarized police threw
rocks at our heads.
Everything seemed backwards.
Today, though, George Papandreou
was taking the EU
austerity bill before
Greek parliament.
It seems certain to past and, as
it did, the blood on Athens
streets seemed certain
to boil.
The feeling was that something
had to change.
The system was broken.
They were paying for the
wasteful corruption of the
establishment and they
refused to be
governed by them anymore.
The rhetoric was exciting.
Very easy to get swept up in.
When we got there, though, the
sun was shining and everyone
seemed pretty chill.
[SPEAKING GREEK]
By the mid afternoon we were
wandering aimlessly through
the square when, in a moment,
the mood changed completely.
Anonymous bombs began exploding
as the unified
atmosphere of the day
before evaporated.
Just like the previous day the
Communists, led by PAME, had
been protecting parliament,
refusing to let anyone,
including anarchists,
through their lines.
Eventually, the anarchists
frustration boiled over.
And a massive street battle
between Communists and the
Anarchists began.
[SPEAKING GREEK OVER
A MEGAPHONE]
It seemed as though the workers
militant front, PAME,
had sided with the police.
You remember PAME?
The nice guys in the van?
Well, they charged us, and the
rest of the crowd, with
massive mallets.
Spreading terror as the police
spread tear gas.
[SPEAKING GREEK OVER
A MEGAPHONE]
While this was going on,
Parliament finally passed the
austerity bill.
Let's face it.
It's confusing being
in a riot.
I saw PAME beating
up protesters and
trying to kill us.
But, frankly, I was
shitting myself.
So maybe I'm not
the best judge.
I saw a country tearing
itself apart.
But not everybody agrees.
[SPEAKING GREEK]
As the sun set on Thursday, news
began to spread that a
man had been killed.
First people were saying that
he was an anarchist.
Then that he was a Communist
killed by anarchist rocks.
Eventually everyone seemed to
agree that the man had died of
natural causes.
Which I think means that he was
literally scared to death.
[SPEAKING GREEK]
The austerity bill was
predictably passed that day.
But the chaos outside parliament
wasn't ignored.
Days later Papandreou
dramatically announced a
referendum on the bill,
only to change
his mind hours later.
Eventually, the prime minister
would step down, while plans
for a coalition government
were drawn up.
Leaving the country looking
more screwed and
confused than ever.
While we were there the riots
felt like a revolution.
Or a Civil War.
In reality, though, it was just
a taste of the political
and social chaos that would
follow for Greece.