Wedding invitations
for two optometrists.
I need to finish another hundred
of these things.
What is this?
Oh, it's called
micro calligraphy.
How's anybody
supposed to read that?
We put a magnifier on top.
Nice, right?
Wow.
If I'd have known
you could make
something this small
look this big,
I'd have got you a smaller ring
in one of these boxes.
Aren't you supposed
to be working?
I wanted to talk to you about
me getting a new SUV for work.
Okay, what's wrong
with the old one?
I need something more
practical than that pimpmobile.
Nick, don't you remember
we just bought a new house?
We haven't even been
on a honeymoon yet.
I need this, Suzanne.
Okay.
Hold on.
You see this?
This is a giant pile of bills.
Of course it looks giant.
You're wearing
magnifying goggles.
Electric, gas,
water, insurance,
ooh, "urgent and confidential."
We owe so much on this one,
they won't even tell us
what it is.
That's it?
No?
Just like that?
It is not just like that.
Nick, we don't have
any extra money,
so you're just gonna
have to unpimp your ride.
♪ Are we there yet? ♪
The Credit Check Episode
S01x02 Original Air Date on June 2, 2010
♪ tell me, tell me, tell me ♪
♪ tell me,
are we there yet? ♪
-- sync, corrected by elderman --
-- for www.addic7ed.Com --
You know,
I'm glad I got married,
It's on.
She's got reasons
she doesn't want to do
what you want her to do.
You have to show her the reasons
why she should--
9:00, get that.
I thought I did that.
Uh-uh.
You didn't do it;
You tried to do that,
a common source of frustration
amongst married couples.
You're gonna want to switch over
to shotgun there.
See, you got to present the pros
and the cons
and convince her
that you having this car
is in her best interest,
kind of like the way
I convinced you
to let me crash here
last night.
Yeah, 'cause it was
in my best interest
not to have you crying on the
phone at 2:00 in the morning.
Bingo.
Gigi still coming over
tomorrow?
Yes, indeed.
You will die now.
She's dropping off
an autographed Jersey,
a Michael Vick
Atlanta Falcons Jersey.
You mean the Eagles.
No, no, Falcons.
I got a guy who collects
fallen athlete memorabilia.
My man's got it all.
He's got Rae Carruth's
Panthers Jersey,
a Darryl Henley Rams Jersey.
He's got a Bob Probert Jersey.
Bob Probert?
Hockey player.
Quiet as it's kept,
white guys mess up too.
You do realize that's just
a video game, right?
And you do realize those
people on your Facebook page
aren't your friends, right?
"Why...
"Is...
"My...
"Brother...
An idiot?"
Post.
Who the heck is Vin-man?
Me.
Ke-Vin, Vin-man.
It's my tournament name.
I won my first two rounds.
I'm trying to get back
to playing this kid
called the tin man.
He beat me in straight sets
last time.
I'm not letting that
happen again.
Wow!
Nice shot...
for an idiot.
I'll take that
as a compliment.
So when's the big match?
Tomorrow.
You comin'?
To your fake tennis match?
Sure.
Good.
Bring your fake friends.
Wow.
What?
Your skin is amazing.
Even under 20 times
magnification,
all I see are pores,
and it looks smooth as glass.
Thank you.
What?
Mm.
There must be a-a smudge
in these goggles.
Mm-hmm.
What are you doing?
There's a little bit of hair.
I'm gonna get it.
Uh-uh, no.
What?
It could be a start
of a mustache.
I do not have a mustache.
Not yet,
but it's like you got
a little sleeper cell
in your face
trying to take
down your upper lip.
Okay, fine.
Pull it.
Okay.
Be still.
Ow!
Much better.
Oh, goodness.
All right, well, Gigi,
let me ask you something.
What?
If you were gonna go
on a honeymoon for cheap,
where would you go?
Back to the man who would dare
say such a thing to me
and tell him
we're getting a divorce.
Why?
Because Nick wants to buy
a new SUV,
and I told him
that we couldn't afford it
because of all of our
other bills,
and then I mentioned
that we hadn't even
been on a honeymoon yet.
You slipped that in
with the bills?
Oh, that's clever.
I got to remember that.
So why does he want
a new SUV?
Well, he says that carrying
stuff around in his car
is messing it up.
Oh, girl, I know exactly
what he means.
I have a pair
of Louis Vuitton pumps.
You think I'm gonna
mess those things up
walking around in 'em?
If you're not walking
around in 'em,
then why--
forget I said anything.
Mm-hmm.
Let him get the new car.
If he makes more money,
you'll have a better
honeymoon later.
Go big, or go home.
This is a marriage.
It is not Las Vegas.
It's all a gamble to me.
Wow.
Ooh.
This is nice.
Yeah.
If it had a widescreen TV
and microwave,
I'd live in there.
You know, the Highlander comes
with one of the most
comprehensive lists
of standard safety features
in its class.
Comprehensive, huh?
Including seven airbags.
Seven?
Uh-huh.
Backup cameras.
Oh, my God.
That's right.
Large side view mirrors.
I saw those.
Uh-huh.
Sir?
I like this.
Sir.
Airbags.
Oh.
Yeah.
So what do you think?
I love it.
I just have to see my guy
down at the bank, you know,
so I can convince my wife.
Whoa, wife.
I'm sorry, man.
You can't even spend
your own money.
You know what?
Sit in the car
as long as you like.
We close at 9:00.
Kevin, watch it!
Yes.
We own you.
"My...
"Brother...Is...
"Going...
"In...
"On...
"This...
"Punk...
Hard."
I'm not sure I like that.
Could you delete that?
No.
Post.
All right, that's it.
Next up, tin man.
I'm gonna broadcast you live
on my streaming page.
For real?
Yup, that's right.
I'm putting you on.
Don't embarrass me.
Shut up.
Then what'd she say?
And what you say, dawg?
Oh, no, you didn't!
Oh, ho, ho!
That is tight!
True DAT.
Listen, yo.
Yeah, yeah, I got to be out.
Holla!
So Mr. Kingston-Persons,
I've got all your information
here for the auto loan.
I just have to put it
in the computer.
Well, see, I don't want
the actual loan yet.
I just want to see
what kind of rate I can get
on the SUV
I'm thinking about buying.
Uh-huh.
Well, just hold on.
We're gonna run
your credit here,
and if there's no problem,
I can get you that loan today.
That was for,
what, $30,000, right?
Right.
You know, we also do financing
for all-terrain vehicles,
jet skis, personal aircraft.
I just want you
to run my credit
so I can see what kind of
interest rate I qualify for.
Then I can decide if I can--
wassup, shorty?
Oh, you know, it's all
kind of busy up in here.
I'ma have to hit you back.
A'ight, a'ight.
A'ight.
All right, so where were we?
How long have you been
at your current job?
Two years.
Two years, all right.
I'll just have to input
your social now
and wait a minute or two,
and boo-yah.
Oh, excuse me.
Oh, Rafael, my dawg,
wuzzup?
What up, what up?
No, you know, you know,
grindin', grindin'.
No, oh, listen, I got to
holler back at you, a'ight?
A'ight.
[barks]
[Laughs]
Oh.
What's wrong?
Well, I'm sorry, sir.
I don't think I'm gonna be able
to give you that loan.
It says that
you're too high a risk.
What?
Yeah.
How come?
My credit should be fine.
Look, I just get approval
and rejection codes here.
You know, if you want
to know more,
you have to get
your credit report.
I'm sorry.
Excuse me for just a second.
Wazzup?
[Laughs]
"Urgent and confidential."
What's this, my subscription
to Essence is about to expire?
"Dear Miss Kingston,
your delinquent account
"in the amount of $15,000
has been referred
to my office for collection."
Damn.
That is
urgent and confidential.
Hey, honey.
Hey, babe.
Remember how earlier I was
talking about buying a new car?
And remember how earlier
I said no?
Yeah, but I was
thinking if I could maybe
make it make sense to you--
baby, I already made all the
sense I need to make out of it.
I know it already makes sense
to you,
but I figured I could get
some information.
So I went to the dealership.
Nick, you didn't.
Look, I didn't buy the car.
Okay, so far, so good.
But it turns out that
even if I wanted to,
I couldn't
because of our credit.
Well, I told you
we owed too many people.
Yeah, but I've never been
denied credit before.
So I got our credit report.
Turns out
there's a mistake on here.
This says I have a debt
in collections of $15,000.
Um...
Let me see that.
That is unbelievable.
I know.
I pay my bills.
If I wasn't gonna
pay something,
it'd be something small
like ring tone bill
or my pay-per-view movies.
Are you out in that garage
ordering pay-per-view?
We just got married.
There's more than that
on pay-per-view.
Like what?
Can we talk about
the credit report?
I will take care of this.
You already did your part
you found the problem,
even though you did it
behind my back.
I was doing research.
What?
Well, the next time
you decide to do research,
we should discuss it first,
because, you know,
I don't like the idea
that you're out there
running around,
finding out information
from God knows where.
You know, like,
I'm your wife,
and if you need
to know something,
then I need to know that
you need to know it, you know?
Oh, my God.
How are you gonna
hide the fact
that you owe $15,000
from Nick?
I'm gonna pay it.
Are you like
one of those characters on Lost
with a dark past?
Because I love you,
but if people are coming
to kill you,
I can't be your friend.
What is wrong
with you, man?
It's the student loan people.
Is that what they're
calling it now?
Gigi.
What?
You know that after
you graduate college,
you can defer paying off
your student loans.
I've been doing it so long,
I forgot.
You forgot you owe $15,000?
You forget you owe people
money all the time.
No, I have never forgotten
I owe people money.
Now, there are people
who have given me money
who believe I owe them,
but I believe we have
a fundamental misunderstanding
on the terms of the exchange.
Right.
Well, how are you gonna
pay off $15,000?
I have an account.
I've been putting money in it
for a long time.
I was saving it
for a rainy day.
Suzanne!
What?
Why didn't you tell me
you had $15,000?
I could've used that money.
Because I believe
we would have
a fundamental misunderstanding
on the terms of the exchange.
All right, got
the live streaming set up.
Good.
'Cause the tin man is about
to get his butt handed to him
by the Vin-man.
"Oh, it's on."
Post.
Okay.
All right.
Let's do this.
What's up?
Explain.
I have a tennis match.
When?
Now.
Where?
Online.
Sad.
It's not sad.
It's the future.
What's with the outfit?
Well, I happen to be dressed
as my favorite tennis player.
And that would be?
Serena Williams.
So that we're clear,
you're sleeping
on a man's couch,
playing video tennis
wearing a unitard,
and that's not sad.
It's a little sad.
Who's the tin man?
Mar-tin.
Tin man.
'Cause when I play tennis,
I'm heartless.
Wizard of oz.
Also sad.
Here's your Jersey.
Thank you.
Well, I'm here...
And I'm hungry.
That's because when you eat,
you're supposed to keep the food
in your stomach.
That was one time!
Here we go.
Hit it!
Almost.
Wow.
Yah!
Come on.
Go.
Go!
Whoa!
Get him!
Take him down!
Almost, almost.
Watch out!
What's going on?
Kevin's in a heated battle
with some guy named the tin man.
Go.
Come on.
That's how you do it.
Little bit of that backswing;
That's it.
That's right.
Man, you gonna dress
like Serena, play like Serena!
Oh!
Whoo!
Ah ha ha!
My man.
That's my boy.
You cannot be serious.
Who's the man?
Me!
You the man.
Look at my boy.
Right there!
Tin man, you were so close.
I'm sorry.
I'm hungry.
Way to go, man,
looking like Andre Agassi
out there.
Thank you
for not embarrassing me.
Shut up.
Ice cream.
What y'all celebrating?
Kevin just won
his online tennis tournament.
Yep, I finally took down
the tin man.
Wait, wait, wait.
Wow! You know what?
That's great.
Got to go!
Bye.
You got beat by a child.
You suck it up.
[telephone ringing]
Hello?
Yeah, hello, man,
this is Mr. Hartwell
from the collection agency.
Can I speak to Miss Kingston?
This is Mr. Kingston-Persons.
All right, right.
So this a courtesy call
to confirm
we received
your wife's payment,
and it's gonna be reflected
in our records
by the end of business today.
Payment for how much?
$15,000.
Thank you.
Ain't this about a--
yo, dude.
I'm still here, man.
You know,
when I first met you,
I had no idea
that I was looking at the man
who would prove to me
that there are real men
out there.
Really?
Mm-hmm.
You know what I was thinking?
I was thinking that maybe
we should go back down
to that dealership
and see what kind of good deal
they can give us on that car.
Really?
You would do that for me.
Yes, because I love you,
and it takes money
to make money, right?
Right, right.
Oh, that's good.
Um...
Did you get that business with
the credit report cleared up?
Huh?
The credit report.
Did you get that cleared up?
Oh.
[Laughs]
Yeah.
It was just a glitch.
But the people on the phone
were very nice.
Oh, I bet they were,
especially after you told them
you'd pay the bill.
Pay the what?
Who?
You.
Yeah, and you're right.
They were very nice.
[Laughs]
Oh, you better
quit playing, Nick.
I have no idea
what you're talking about.
Okay, look.
I got a call today
from the collection agency
saying our credit will be fine
'cause you sent them a check
for $15,000.
So you need to start
explaining yourself.
Damn.
Okay, okay, okay.
But don't be mad at me, okay?
Okay.
But the next time I say
"don't be mad at me,"
you have to not be mad at me.
Deal.
Hold on;
We got to get this on tape.
"I...
I...
"Suzanne Kingston-Persons...
Suzanne Kingston-Persons...
"Being of sound body
and mind...
Being of sound mind and body,
won't be mad, okay?
Start talking.
This is all Frank's fault.
Your ex-husband?
Exactly.
Okay.
We always argued about money,
and I just never felt like
Frank had my back,
and I didn't want to use
his money
to pay back my student loans.
So, you know, then I was single,
and then it was you and me,
and we moved,
and we got all swept up
in things,
and the next thing I know--
I can't get my car.
So you knew
you owed that money?
No.
Yes.
I forgot.
Wait, wait.
How do you forget
you owe somebody $15,000?
Well, I--
wait, wait.
You know, there's nothing
you can say to explain it.
Where did you get $15,000?
I started saving the money
when I was with Frank.
It was my "one day" money.
What's one day money?
One day,
I'm gonna do something fun
and not care how much it costs.
You should have told me.
Look, I'm not here
to hold you back.
I'm here to have your back.
I got you.
I know.
It'sust that...
Sometimes 's just hard
to really relax.
I'm sorry.
Just to be clear,
do you owe anybody else?
No.
Good.
I love you.
I love you too, babe.
What are you doing?
I'm getting ready for bed.
Take that off.
You're not going to sleep.
-- sync, corrected by elderman --
-- for www.addic7ed.Com --