our mailbag!  This is Genesis Week!
[Music]
And a welcome to this episode of Genesis
Week, the weekly program of creationary
commentary on news, views and events
pertaining to the origins controversy,
made possible by the supporters of CORE
Ottawa - Citizens for Origins Research
and Education, and exclusive right here
on youtube.  Pirate broadcasting live from
Superman's former secret fortress of
solitude in the Canadian high arctic - but
we're a little worried about what's gonna
happen with our broadcast with all the
solar flares going off and us being in the
arctic and stuff.  But we'll keep
broadcasting the information the
anti-creationists don't want you to see or
hear, and we'll give glory to the Creator
while doing it.  Once again, #1 most talked
about show in science and technology on
YouTube.
You can find us at wazooloo.com or
genesisweek.com, or click the
ever-so-convenient subscribe link up top,
and don't forget, you can also peruse
other episodes by following the links in
the upper corners of each episode. I'm
your host, Ian Juby
Stop me if you've heard this before!
Oh how exciting!  What are they talking
about? Tiktaalik? No, but they are talking
about another fossil in the long line of
alleged fishapods, which it seems I've
wound up talking about for like, five or six
different shows!  You'd think the press
and these particular evolutionists would
have learned their lesson by now!  But
nope!  So what is it they're so excited
about?  Well, it is a pretty spectacular
fossil find to be sure.  Found in Scotland,
these fossils allegedly fill in the famous
"Romer's gap" which was named after Dr.
Alfred Romer, an American Paleontologist
who noted missing fossils in the fishapod
timeline between 345 and 360 million
years ago.
Smithson, et al, reported on the Scottish
fossil find in the latest PNAS, and the
fossils have been assigned the precise
evolutionary age of 348 to 347.6 Ma - give
or take a week.  Particular excitement was
over a fossil foot which had five toes.
Devin Powell of Science News explains:
Even in the PNAS article itself, the
authors allude to the "fact" that this is
earliest evidence of a fossil five-toed foot:
Wait - let's take a look at the evolutionary
timescale involved here.  I discussed this
extensively on previous shows, but
apparently these researchers don't watch
this show and thus miss out on the
valuable information we bring you that the
anti-creationists don't want you to see or
hear!
Here's a pretty diagram showing how the
evolution myth portrays fishapod
evolution,  - and the approximate age that
has been assigned to the five-toed fossil
foot that was just reported.  As we go
left-to-right on the chart, we go through
evolutionary time as the fishees attempt
to grow legs and walk up on to land -
allegedly culminating in the five-toed foot.
This gradual progression of evolution
looks impressive in pretty pictures. To
falsify this myth, all we have to do is show
that there were ALREADY five-toed
tetrapods before any of these creatures
appeared in the evolutionary timeline.  And
that is precisely what was already done
years to decades earlier.  In 2010, a report
was published - by evolutionists - of fossil
tetrapod footprints in Poland dated 395
MILLION years old, according to the
evolution myth. Those footprints were
actually first found in 2002, and take a
look and count'em yourself - 1- 1 toe! hahaha!
toes!  But yet the creationists were way
2! 2 toes! mwahahahaha! 3! 3 toes! hahaha
oh enough of that.
1, 2, 3, 4, 5 toes!
But yet the creationists were way
ahead of the pack, with geologist John
Mackay publicizing fossil tetrapod tracks
in the Tapeats sandstone of Grand
Canyon in 1987!  The Tapeats sandstone
is dated according to the evolution myth
as 525 million years old - that's way off
the other end of our chart. Notice that the
Scottish researchers have interpreted the
fossil foot as having a reduced fifth toe,
and also notice that the Polish
researchers interpreted the same thing
from their footprint, and also the
reconstruction of Panderichthys has
reduced a sixth toe.
Looking at the Tapeats footprints, it
appears it also has a reduced fifth toe
impression.  So let's count'em - 1,2,3,4,5
toes!
The Scottish researchers mentioned:
Really?  Could it be that the collection
failure was caused by the preconceptions
and assumptions of evolution, which has
hindered proper research? Because
predictions based on the evolution myth
would say you will find NO tetrapods in
"older" rock formations.  Indeed it is a
collection failure, and I lay the blame at
the feet of the evolution myth.  We have
still yet another example of how evolution
has hindered scientific research and
discovery - discoveries that falsify the
evolution myth, and affirm that creatures
like the tetrapods have been around since
the beginning of Creation - just like the
Bible says. Gee, I wonder what else the
Bible is right about?
Hot off the presses - your ancient
ancestor was a worm!  Morris and Caron,
publishing in Biological Reviews of the
Cambridge Philosophical Society,
described more detail about a famous
worm from the Burgess shale of British
Columbia, Canada.  This worm like
creature is called Pikaia, and a few years
back, I participated in a research trip to
the Burgess Shale with Harry Nibourg,
owner of the Big Valley Creation Science
Museum, Vance Nelson, owner of
Canada's largest traveling creation
museum with Creation Truth ministries,
and Yours truly.  It's been touted for years
that Pikaia is our ancient ancestor
because it has a notochord - a soft,
flexible, tube-like spine.  Morris and Caron
made some more interesting discoveries
upon examining multiple fossils under an
electron microscope.  In the Royal Ontario
Museum press release, Caron said:
You and I of course, are chordates.
Morris and Caron held nothing back in
their press release:
It was very interesting that while at the
Burgess Shale, Vance Nelson noted that
Pikaia held a suspicious resemblance to
the modern sea lancelet.  In fact, some
evolutionists have noticed the stark
similarity too - but the evolutionists
pointed to minor differences such as the
lack of antennae on Pikaia.  However, a
study by Purnell, et al, in a January 2010
Nature article, actually examined the
decay of dead sea lancelets, and
discovered to their shock that the decay
of organisms can give a false story of
EVOLUTION.  Their point was that it was
assumed decay would take place at
random, and their research showed decay
was NOT random. In fact, it turns out that
the very characters of organisms that are
used by evolutionary scientists to
determine the organisms' placement on
the evolutionary tree were the FIRST
characteristics to rot away!  So in the case
of the sea lancelet, while some
evolutionists have contended that the
lack of antennae in Pikaia means it must
be a different organism than the sea
lancelet - look for yourself: The antennae
was one of the first things to rot away on
a dead sea lancelet.  Thus, Pikaia is
probably just a slightly decayed sea
lancelet, dead only a few days.
So rather than proof that we (and all the
other organisms with backbones) evolved
from a worm, this appears to be more
evidence that even organisms from the
Burgess Shale - allegedly some of the
oldest fossils in the world, have
reproduced faithfully after their kind since
the beginning of time - exactly what the
Bible says, and contrary to what
Evolution would predict.  Gee, I wonder
what else the Bible is right about?
In another case of flagrant, open bigotry
in academia, Springer-Verlag, publisher of
many scientific journals and books, had
scheduled to publish a book entitled
"Biological Information: New
Perspectives," which was co-edited by Dr.
Jonathan Sanford, co-inventor of the
gene gun and a young earth creationist.
The Panda's thumb website pointed out
this book and Sanford's "Intelligent
design" leanings, and suddenly the book
was yanked from publication.  The book
had already been peer reviewed -twice!
But upon finding out that one of the book
editors was an intelligent design
advocate, Springer pulled the book for
additional peer-review, with
Merkel-Sobotta stated that Springer was
unaware of the editors’ roles in the
intelligent design movement, and Springer
does not “endorse intelligent design as a
legitimate area of scientific research.”
Notice there was not a single thing found
wrong with the book, scientifically
speaking. It had already passed peer
review.  This is nothing less than open,
flagrant bigotry.  Even in the comments of
my videos here, anti-creationists ridicule
creationists as never doing any original
research - which is patently false and
incredibly ignorant, seeing as how many
creationists have published in secular
literature and there are four
peer-reviewed scientific journals
published by creationary organizations
around the world.  Secular academia has
even openly admitted, in print, that it will
not publish creationary material -
regardless of its scientific validity or
merit.  Therefore the claim that
creationists don't publish in peer
reviewed journals is not just incredibly
ignorant and untrue, it has nothing to do
with whether or not the creationists are
right, or whether or not what they are
saying is scientific.
In fact the evolution news website had a
couple of fascinating, well written articles
on the bogus criticism of lack of peer
review:
It isn't peer review anymore, it's peer
pressure.  And peer review is just another
avenue for the flagrant bigotry that goes
on in academia toward anyone who dares
question Darwin.  Well guess what folks,
I'm here to Question Darwin, and you can
see some of many scientific reasons why I
doubt Darwin.  And if Darwin was wrong
about evolution, I wonder what else he
was wrong about?
[Scary, dramatic music]
Wahoo! mail for me?
[clicking sounds of a geiger counter
detecting radiation]
Hmmmm....I wonder what it tastes like?
[drinking sounds]
[Scary, dramatic music]
WOW - last weeks show was catapulted
into the #1 most discussed video in
Science and Technology again, there was
no possible way for me to go through all
the comments. Sadly, the anti-creationists
once again lowered the bar with their
comments that had IQ factors containing
very large, negative integers.
LaWilson was spouting off about
polystrate trees being in-situ, when I
clearly refuted that idea, even showing
photographs so that YOU, the viewers,
could see for yourself that the roots that
are there, have been stripped of their
rootlets, and that some were
upside-down. They were not in-situ.
Wilson also went off on some tangent
about the Alberta beds being laid down on
an ocean floor - which I never said.  In
fact, it would appear that giant plants the
size of TREES would not be buried on the
ocean floor, along with dinosaurs
apparently swimming to the ocean floor
so they can walk around and leave
footprints!  Wow wilson - Really? Where
did you get this idea?  You didn't get it
from me.
Fusion840 also replied to one of
Lawilson's ridiculous assertions with:
Yes - in fact, in last week's show I even
cited the ages assigned to coal formation.
But apparently neither Lawilson, nor
anyone else who doesn't want to believe,
listened to that part. But hey - thanks for
trying Fusion; hope you were wearing a
helmet for all the beating your head
against the wall you did.
As for Derek Ager's comments about
catastrophes interspersed with long
periods of time, I thought ChrisCarlascio
did a great job dismantling that idea:
The Science Foundation also failed
completely to see his own blindness,
affirming by his comments that apparently
he believes the laws of nature were
different at the beginning, and don't apply
the "first self replicating system" - an
alleged system that has never been
demonstrated by he or anyone else.
As BenWalburn noted:
Indeed.  But I just wish these guys would
stop and think, see the error of your
ways, and repent of their sins while they
can.
Barachem wrote in:
Thanks for writing in folks.
Ya, I kind goofed there, sorry. I
accidentally left it in from the editing file
the week before and missed it in the
previews - but several eagle eyes caught
my mistake, well done!
Well that's it for this week, I'm your host
Ian Juby, I hope you'll join me next
Thursday.  Please subscribe up above and
use the convenient "share" button down
below to post this video on twitfaceplus,
or to embed it in your blog or website!  Let
us remember the words of our Creator,
the Lord Jesus Christ, who said : I am the
Way the Truth and THE LIFE, no man
comes to the father but through me." See
you on the flip side.
[music]
Production Software was provided for
Genesis Week by the Big Valley Creation
Science Museum, located just 25 minutes
north of Drumheller, Alberta. In the heart
of the dinosaur badlands, the Big Valley
Creation Science Museum was built from
the ground up to give credit to our
Creator, portraying the scientific evidence
showing that creation is the faith that fits
the facts, and that evolution is the faith
that the facts have failed.
Visit BVCSM.com for more details.