And today we`re going to one-up Phineas Fogg.
Instead of 80 days, we`re going around the
world in 80 seconds for some global headlines
at the start of today`s show.
Our first stop is in Syria, where a civil
war is driving hundreds of thousands of people
out of the country. According to estimates
from the United Nations, more than half a
million Syrian refugees have crossed over
the border. They`re looking for safety. They`re
also looking for warmth. And with predictions
for a harsh winter, that could be hard to
find.
Next, we`re heading to China, where some newspaper
journalists are protesting against the government.
They`ve accused officials of censorship and
restricting freedom of the press. Local government
officials aren`t commenting about the situation.
The people you see here are supporting the
journalists laying flowers down at the newspaper`s
headquarters.
Now, we`re going to go to Australia, where
intense heat and strong winds are fueling
the flames of two wildfires. This is happening
on the island of the Tasmania. The first have
destroyed more than 100 homes, but as of late
Sunday night, officials said there hadn`t
been any deaths reported, although they were
looking into reports about potentially missing
people.
Last stop on our global tour, Alaska, where
an oil rig was a little closer to shore than
you might expect -- right up on it. This Royal
Dutch Shell rig ran aground last week. It
happened while it was being towed back to
its winter home. There could be up to 150,000
gallons of diesel on board, but observers
are saying there are no signs that any of
it is leaking out.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today`s Shout Out goes
out to Mr. Apfeld`s social studies classes
at All Saint`s Catholic School in Fort Worth,
Texas.
The U.S. Defense secretary`s office is located
in what building?
Here we go now.
Is it at the U.S. Capitol, Pentagon, White
House or Fort Knox?
You`ve got 30 seconds. Go.
The Defense Department`s headquarters is in
the Pentagon, one of the world`s largest office
buildings.
That`s your answer and that`s your Shout Out.
AZUZ: There might be a new person behind that
desk in the Pentagon soon. On Monday, President
Obama announced his nominee to be the next
secretary of Defense, former Senator Chuck
Hagel. He`s a Republican who served 12 years
in the U.S. Senate and he`s also a veteran
who fought in the Vietnam War. If he`s confirmed
as the next Defense secretary, he`ll be the
first enlisted soldier to eventually hold
that office. Hagel has made some controversial
statements in the past and that could lead
to some challenges during his confirmation
process.
Yesterday, the president also nominated John
Brennan to be the next director of the CIA.
Right now, Brennan is the president`s chief
adviser on counter-terrorism. He worked at
the CIA for 25 years, so getting the job as
director could be seen as kind of a homecoming
for him.
And just because President Obama nominates
them doesn`t mean Hagel and Brennan will get
those jobs. We mentioned they have to be confirmed.
And that power belongs to the U.S. Senate.
There will be confirmation hearings, where
senators will get to ask these nominees questions
before deciding whether or not to vote for
them, to approve them for the jobs.
Confirming presidential nominees is one of
the responsibilities that can only be done
by one part of Congress or the other. For
example, the House of Representatives can
decide if a government official should be
put on trial, but the Senate is the group
that holds that trial.
On other things, obviously, the House and
Senate work together, like coming up with
laws.
Yesterday, Athena Jones looked at the issue
of gun control.
Today, she`s putting the focus on another
subject that could be a priority for the new
Congress -- immigration reform.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
ATHENA JONES, CNN CORRESPONDENT (voice-over):
What might comprehensive legislation look
like?
The president says it should include measures
to beef up border security, punish companies
that purposely hire undocumented workers and
give the roughly 11 million undocumented immigrants
here a way to obtain legal status.
Groups that want to restrict immigration are
skeptical.
DAN STEIN, FEDERATION FOR AMERICAN IMMIGRATION
REFORM: The president himself has said he
doesn`t think these laws are enforceable.
How -- how on earth is Congress ever going
to be convinced to pass a package of -- of
the kind he`s talking about when no guarantees
can be made to the general public that the
laws will be respected?
JONES: Doubts that could signal a long road
ahead for this legislative push.
JOHN GRAMLICH, "CQ ROLL CALL": Right now,
what`s interesting on immigration is that
everyone is talking the talk, and that includes
Democrats and Republicans. But, again, there`s
a big difference between talking the talk
and walking the walk on policy.
JONES (on camera): A big question is whether
the parties can agree on how to approach this
immigration issue.
Should it be one big bill, which many Democrats
are pushing?
Or several smaller ones, which many Republicans
favor, because they say this issue is so complex?
Athena Jones, CNN, Washington.
(END VIDEO TAPE)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: See if you can ID me.
I`m an annual celebration that includes parties
and parades. I start on the 12th day after
Christmas and I end on Mardi Gras.
My biggest U.S. celebration is in New Orleans.
I`m Carnival and I occur right before the
season of Lent.
(END VIDEO TAPE)
AZUZ: Carnival season is on in New Orleans
and it runs through Fat Tuesday. One artist
is honoring the city by using items that are
associated with the celebration.
This is a mosaic. It`s a type of art that
uses small items to form a picture or a pattern.
In this case, the artist and his helpers are
using recycled Mardi Gras beads. They`re recreating
a cityscape of New Orleans. And when they`re
finished, the 42-foot wide work of art is
expected to set a new record. All it takes
is one and a half million beads, some very
precise placements and a whole lot of patience.
While Carnival brings huge crowds to New Orleans,
a different event brought tens of thousands
of people right here to Atlanta, Georgia last
week. It`s the Passion Conference, a gathering
of young Christians who are committed to changing
the world, in part by taking on the issue
of human slavery.
Jim Clancy looks at how the movement is gaining
momentum.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
JIM CLANCY, CNN CORRESPONDENT: (voice-over):
More than 60,000 young Christians from around
the country and around the world held candles
aloft in the frosty air. Their own faces shine
back at them from a massive cube set up outside
the Georgia Dome -- faces of those who have
pledged to light up the world and put an end
to human trafficking in their lifetimes.
BRYSON VOGELTANZ, PASSION 2013: Slavery is
trapped in dark places all over the world.
It`s trapped here in Atlanta in the shadows.
It`s in the shadows in Mumbai, India. It`s
in the shadows in Cambodia. It`s in the shadows
around the world in brothels and factories.
These 60,000 students, they`re going to shine
a light on slavery.
CLANCY: For many, this is a journey of the
Christian faith, one that brings them here
to the Passion Conference to worship, pray
and learn. For the past two years, they`ve
been focusing on the unholy scourge of sexual
slavery and forced labor, the 27 million victims,
the billions of dollars churned out by robbing
men, women and children of their freedom.
These young men and women are determined to
change that.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: The truth is spoken here.
And where truth is spoken, things change.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: We`re going to raise the
awareness. We`re going to fight for those
that ho -- don`t have a voice. And we`re just
going to tell people about this. And we`re
going to let this world know that there`s
an issue and we`re not OK with it.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: To just know that this
is out there and like it - - it just opened
my eyes to all this. Like I had no idea this
was really going on. And then like I just
want to be able to help as much as I can.
VOGELTANZ: This is about students starting
a journey of justice, that their entire lives
would count for justice, their entire lives
would count for freedom. And that`s happening
here.
CLANCY: Last year, the event raised $3.5 million.
With 20,000 more participants this year, tablet
computers were used to help speed the donation
process.
Some of the money comes from the students
themselves. More was raised in their communities.
It will be used to help raise awareness, rescue
victims and help them restore their lives.
(END VIDEO TAPE)
AZUZ: Describe the civil rights leader and
Nobel Peace Prize winner in just one word.
It`s a challenge, but we know you`re up for
it. Martin Luther King Day is coming up soon.
We want you to send in iReports describing
Dr. King in just one word. The deadline is
January 15th, so you`ve got one week to do
it and one place to find all the detail, CNNStudentNews.com.
All right, we`re going to wrap things up today
in the skies over the California coast. It`s
a bird, it`s a plane, it`s Super Man?
It certainly looks like the comic book character.
It turns out this souped up soups is a remote-controlled
flier. And this YouTube video has made him
an online sensation.
Not exactly the man of steel. He`s more like
the man of lightweight foam. Of course, this
cape-fur happened in Cal-Al-Fornia. We just
wish that it happened in a city named Clark,
but I guess you Kent get everything you want.
These puns are just super bad.
We`re going to go before we get carried up,
up and away.
One real quick thing. We have a new blog up
on our home page.
One week into the new year, how are your resolutions
holding up?
Tell us at CNNStudentNews.com.
And we`ll see you right back here again tomorrow.