He got boxed in.
It's the four horse.
That four--
EDDIE (OFFSCREEN): Shh.
- --seems to intimidate-- he's
got a buffalo on him.
What are we to--
they scratched the five.
It's the four horse, he always--
something with that
four horse.
He's got, he--
EDDIE (OFFSCREEN): Butchie.
- --he got the horns
on me, I can't--
EDDIE (OFFSCREEN): Butchie.
-Listen to me.
-Can I ask you a question?
Like, say--
BUTCHIE (OFFSCREEN): But I got
to get it out of my system.
-You got to get it out
of your system?
I get it, keep torturing me.
-I'm not torturing you,
you understand?
I've been playing horses
for years.
This is an unusual case.
This guy goes from--
he goes on-- he didn't want
to go on the inside.
He messed the whole race up.
The, the jockey cocked the
whole goddamned race up.
I can't believe it.
-Butchie, I hate you.
-Listen, by the way, Lazlo's
coming over for pizza.
-What do you mean?
-He's coming for pizza,
you know?
-What, he's coming for fucking
pizza or he's coming for
"pizza?"
BUTCHIE (OFFSCREEN): Just give
him the pizza, that's all.
No commotion.
EDDIE (OFFSCREEN): I have
to give him pizza now.
OK, fine.
I'll make a special
pizza, Bingo.
BINGO (OFFSCREEN): Pepperoni?
EDDIE (OFFSCREEN):
Yeah, pepperoni.
-There's pepperoni--
BUTCHIE (OFFSCREEN): How
much we owe this guy?
-After this haircut?
I owe him $300.
-Eddie.
EDDIE (OFFSCREEN): (MUTTERING)
Oh fucking fuck fuck.
-Eddie.
EDDIE (OFFSCREEN):
What's going on?
How are you doing?
-What's going on, Butch?
What do you got for me, Eddie?
-Give me, like, a week.
-Oy, gah.
EDDIE (OFFSCREEN):
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
If you, if you, if you can--
-[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
EDDIE (OFFSCREEN): I didn't
know you were collecting
today.
-You know what, buddy?
That's what you said last
week, you know that?
-We'll give you a green pepper
pizza right now, special.
This is a special pie
that Bingo makes.
-Green pepper pizza.
-Yeah, green pepper pizza.
So we're gonna give you a
special pizza for, uh, for you
right now, if you--
-I don't like Puerto Rican
pizza, all right?
Take those green peppers.
Let me tell you something.
Next week, I want $320.
Right here on the counter.
-I'll give you the green pepper
pizza and we'll call it
an even $300.
-[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
-Was that to me?
LAZLO (OFFSCREEN): Yes.
-I don't know what the
hell that means.
-What the fuck do I know
what she said?
I'm not Polish.
I'm Albanian.
EDDIE (OFFSCREEN): OK.
-All right?
BINGO (OFFSCREEN): Want
that green pepper pie?
-Yeah, why don't you give him
the green pepper pie?
-Do you know what I said?
I said I'll cut your balls off
and put them in the spaghetti.
-That's good, she speaks
English now.
-I don't think this
guy got any balls.
As a matter of fact, take that
pizza, shove it up your ass.
EDDIE (OFFSCREEN):
OK, I'll do that.
-All right?
-Jerk.
-Let's get out of here, baby.
Let's get you dinner,
it's done.
And remember, next week.
EDDIE (OFFSCREEN): I appreciate
that, Lazlo.
BINGO (OFFSCREEN): Here's
the green pepper.
EDDIE (OFFSCREEN):
Do me a favor.
I'm gonna chop off my balls.
I want you to chop them
up, and I want you to
put them on the pie.
-What the fuck was that about?
-I'm gonna be out in the back.
If anybody needs me, I'm gonna
be smoking a massive joint.
You're in charge.
I want you to make all
green pepper pies.
BINGO (OFFSCREEN):
Sounds good.
-He wants to make an impression
in front of them,
you know what I'm saying?
He had a bad day.
One little thing--
-Yeah, come out here, Rocco.
Come into my, uh, royal
antechamber.
Have a seat.
Fuck.
-What happened?
What kind of the problem
you have?
-Huh?
-What problem?
I see the Albanian--
-What the fuck are you--
ROCCO (OFFSCREEN):
What happened?
-Fucking tree-neck
motherfucker!
ROCCO (OFFSCREEN):
What happened?
-I'll fucking cut--
ROCCO (OFFSCREEN): What
makes you nervous?
Why?
-What'd you say?
-What, you gamble--
-He comes into the store--
-You gamble, you lose
your money?
-Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I, I owe him about, uh--
ROCCO (OFFSCREEN): How
much you lose?
-It's been a hard day, Pop.
ROCCO (OFFSCREEN): Hey,
listen-- what happen?
-No, this, uh--
[EDDIE SIGHS]
You know.
ROCCO (OFFSCREEN): You gamble?
-I was gonna pay the guy the
money today, you know, but I
couldn't do it because your
beautiful daughter, uh, is
giving the kids--
at three months--
freaking violin lessons.
So, I don't know what the--
ROCCO (OFFSCREEN): How
much you lose?
You say--
you are say the business
no good, and you play?
-I owe him about, uh,
about $300, $330.
I got some fucking pressures
here, Pop, I don't know.
ROCCO (OFFSCREEN): Listen,
no need be nervous.
Everything I fix good.
-You're gonna take care of it?
ROCCO (OFFSCREEN): I see your
mother-in-law, what it do.
-Fuck.
ROCCO (OFFSCREEN): And the
business, no good.
Ed, listen.
-I'm sorry.
ROCCO (OFFSCREEN): Ed, listen.
-Yeah, I'm a little worked up.
-I will fix everything.
I am tell you.
You have one thing that they
have interest in--
the pizzeria.
I will fix, but you need to
promise to no play no more,
because these people
are very dangerous.
Hey, you good boy.
-OK, I appreciate that.
-OK?
Promise.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN): You
know where to catch this guy?
-Yeah.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
You sure?
-Yeah.
-Because this has
to happen fast.
You ready?
-I've been following him.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Want to check it?
Know what you're gonna use?
Is it clean?
-Yeah.
Yeah, it's clean.
-OK, so put it away.
Go to work.
[GUNSHOT]
[SHELL CASING HITS THE GROUND]
[BOOGIE WOOGIE MUSIC]
[BOSSA NOVA MUSIC]