is genetically inherited...or just a re..product
of genetic damage. The reason I don't believe
that is I worked with so many people, alocholics,
drug addicts..people with a prison record
and I took that out in one session. So if
it was genetic it wouldn't come out. That's
how I know it works..and I don't know if you
saved the letters. Do you? That we get from
people that said, "I was about to turn my
life in. I have no reason. You gave me a reason
to live and work." So..that's all I can go
by not genetics. I can't do anything with
genetics. If a doctor says, "Someday we'll
have a cure for Cancer." That may encourage
a person..but it won't encourage me inless
I say, "What is your approach?" and they give
me an approach..that would encourage me..
if I had cancer. Do you understand? If the
guy says, "I'm sure you'll get well. Have
faith in yourself." Cancer don't give a shit
about that. It just keeps multiplying. You
might live a week longer or three weeks longer
if you have..self-confidence..but always ask
a person...like..nobody asks any of these..T..Tea
group people, "What would you do under these
circumstances? How would you solve this problem?
How would you get the Democrats to see the
Republican point of view?" THEY NEVER TALK
ABOUT THAT. They talk about their own limitations.
I would say, therefore, most Capitalist, that
drive that system are very simple people with
a low self-image. Now I did mention in the
past that psychologist have a higher suicide
rate than normal. That means they undergo
depression..and if they really ask the question,
"WHAT IS DEPRESSION?" say, "I don't know"
Then a guy writes a theory of genetics..of
the genes. That doesn't take away the depression.
Do you understand that? Taking drugs might
tranquilize you..or drinking alcohol when
you're depressed might take you out of your
self-image. You just sit there and look around.
It makes you feel relaxed and comfortable.
Next day there's a hangover and the depression......if
you don't deal with it. Now, you can't deal
with it if you don't even know how to go about
looking into it. So let me show you how you
go about looking into, "What is a Depression?".
You read the books on genetics and you understand
that pills can make a person feel more in
equilibrium. Is the chemistry of the body
in equilibrium? If you're depressed, yes.
Your digestive system stops..alot of other
things manifest themselves,....but if you
feel positive about what you're doing. If
you're sawing a tree down and uh "I HATE to
do this!" Well you poison yourself. Do you
understand what I mean? Anything you do that
you don't like..but if you say, "I have to
repair that model or clean it and that's going
to take about two and a half hours." It depends
on your predictability. If it takes 5 hours,
you might be disappointed. Not in the vision!.
Not in the uh thing...in your estimation!
Do you understand? It's your own estimation.
If you figure it should take you three days
to do a given job. If it takes twenty-three
days, you may get disappointed. Say, "I don't
know how long it'll take but I'm gonna check
it out." and you do a certain amount of work
and you predict the next and if it comes close,
you can use that method of predictability.
Is there anything..did you get this message?
This is how you deal with depressed people...and
that's what depression is...unless you have
further questions....Put it out there let's
see how it works. If you get a response saying,
"You know that really helped alot.." Psychiatrist
don't even know what the question is. They
think some people are depressed and others
aren't...and some are 'happy go lucky' no
matter what. They have a self-image even though
it's false. If you feel/..if you're a minister
and you administer to people's problems and
they feel good about it, you feel you're doing
something useful. There are ministers that
feel that they're administering to human need..and
as long as that person says, "God Bless you.
Thank you. You've helped me alot." Whatever
the minister did helped them..but if the minister
was an operational linguist and he helped
them to understand what they're are going
through and why people get depressed, I think
that's better than comforting them and saying,
"You'll pull out of it, I have every/..confidence
that you will." Well, if your minister says
that, there may be a basis for it... but it's
not real. Knowing the difference is a problem.
"Just/.." Well the Tea Party is a group of
people that believe in the structure of this
economic system. Why? Because they're successful
in it. A military man that's awarded a higher
position, if he gets to be captin or lieutanant
colonel, he gets reward for it...so he feels
very proud. The more merit badget he has,
the greater he feels. If the Nazi has more
merit badges, the Jew don't feel too good
about that but the Nazi feels great about
it. Do you understand? So, "What is a reinforcer?"
Whatever the hell reinforces people. Except
alcohol. That's a dependency that makes you
feel like you don't/...you lose your identity
under alcohol. Say, "Did I say that when I
was drunk?" cuz you don't even know what you
said. That means you don't have your own identity.
Identity means, "Fresco likes to walk in the
Sun. He likes to make things. He likes to
talk to people about their problems..but he
feels that/..." If i share the tools I have
and say, "Keep coming to me." and uh, and
I never give them my tools, I do not help
them..really. Unless I have them the tools
that I have. The same tools that enables me
to solve a problem..okay... but I'd rather
not give these tools out because I'm afraid
of the culture. They'll commercialize on it,
use it, and../ but they won't change the way
people think about things. Not only depression,
I try to change the way people think about
most/.. everything. Now if you don't understand
what I'm saying...you might even HATE what
I'm saying. I'll say, "That doesn't answer
the question." Roxanne: "I remember in your
old lectures you use to tell people to write
a list when you're not/..when you're feeling
better, when you're not depressed. Write a
list of all the things you like to do....all
the things you don't like to do and then when
you're depressed, look at the list and just
do those things that you like to do." Yeah,
when you're depressed, you don't feel like
doing it. Roxanne: "But you used to use that
as a tool. Didn't you?" Yeeeah. Well..I..it
worked at the time. All I can say is that
I'm giving you the focal point of a depression.
LOSS OF SELF-IMAGE. "Who am I? Where am I
going? What is my life about? I don't know.
I don't even know..if i'd be successful at
anything." That's no self-image. You're always
successful at something. You can always teach
somebody something. You're not totally a total
failure. If a person comes to me and says
I'm depressed, that's better..if they come
here. Well I give them a social awareness
that futbol is really a little spot in entertainment
but when you inform people, it changes alot
of things. See, futbol just makes the game
pleasant but if you lose, you're depressed..
and they get into fights alot. I don't know
if you know that...all over the world. So,
it isn't a good thing. No competitive sport
is. When a guy hits a golf ball..ball and
it misses, he throws the stick down on the
ground. The puck? Is that what you call it?
He throws it on the ground and he feels bad..and
when the audience applauds when he hits it
and it goes into the hole they applaud. Makes
him feel good..he has a self-image.. but if
he hits it and it and it doesn't go into the
hole..the audience just looks on, and they
don't reinforce him. So, if I designed a MAGNETIC
SYSTEM in the hole, and a STEEL BALL in the
golf..even if he missed it...it would be going
into the hole. You know? What do you want?
It's such a ridiculous game...of hitting a
golf ball and looking for it. What? It's a
ridiculous game...or racing cars around in
a circle. If you get your kicks out of that,
it's because you have a low self-image..and
you love it when the audience says, "You won
that race. You did a beautiful job!" You know..that
is a, uh, a moment in time..but the things
we are working on are...are everything. The
games of the future. Things of that sort.
Now a game of the future.. typical game of
the future is not made by people who make
games. They would be like this: There'd be
a map and then.. you would find out which
state has the most cancer and you put these
little beads there and the other states that
has the least amount of cancer... and you
know when you're through playing the game,
you'd know what the hell exist in America.
You'd know the states with the highest divorce
rate, the highest crime rate, where there's
more poverty. If you find out that poverty
encourages abhorrent behavior then if you
don't want to do anything about it, you don't
understand that problem. If you give a working
man a little above the standard of living
so he can buy a television set, a radio, a
cell phone. If you just give him enough to
live on, you don't build a study person, a
loyal person. If a person has a little more
than they need, they'll come back to work.
If you give them more than they need, they
won't show up. So the money system kills incentive
to go to work. So people say, "Fuck it. I'm
not going in/. I'm going to call in sick."
Did you ever hear of that? So they call in
sick... but that isn't the answer. "You should
be obedient to your corporation." That..that's
a control device. You know. "I love my company."
If you love your company, that's no self-image
at all. The union has a self-image. They'd
like to see the company succeed but they'd
like a piece of the action. So instead of
making $18 a week, they go on strike and they
get $25 a week... but the company loses the
competitive edge... because they have to raise
the price of their product. So they HATE unions
because it lowers their standard of living.
The unions love unions, the members, it raises
their standard of living. Everybody is right...
that's the trouble with the world but nobody
knows what to do. Nobody wants to give up
their position of advantage. I don't know
how much of this your'e going to stick out
there but... okay. Take it from here.