today I'm gonna do a lovely little brunchy
sort of L.A twist on fluffy pancakes with
gorgeous smoky bacon. In the pancakes there's
gonna be sweetcorn and feta cheese. There's
gonna be avocado, it's gonna be gorgeous.
But I have a new guest, yeah! Alex is here.
French Guy Cooking is in the house. Hello
Food Tubers how are you?
Hi guys and welcome to French Guy Cooking.
This is an amazing fruit. Then blaze it! We
pour this over the steak.
He's come here to cook and he's French. And
he was one of the runner-uppers in the competition
we did to find a new Food Tube star and he
did fantastic and his channel is going down
really well.
I'm an Essex boy now.
You are an Essex boy now. There's a few more
initiations that we have to go through but
you're nearly there, yes.
And if you wanna see some pancakes, you wanna
check out his channel. You gonna do a lovely
Crepe?
Oh yeah, totally. Sweet, sweet one.
Beautiful. So are you ready to see my one?
I'm waiting for it.
It's not classic French. This is a really,
really easy recipe guys. All you need is a
tea mug, a builders mug, whatever you wanna
call it. We're gonna pour this into the mug.
See the thing is Alex, I don't really like
weighing things too much. It's all about cups
and spoons and handfuls. For one cup of self-raising
flour we're gonna do one cup of milk. Do you
mind pouring that in there for me. Yeah totally,
totally. And one egg, Okay? And then a little
pinch of salt. But if you can just whisk that
for me my French brother. Yeah totally. But
we're gonna go savoury. You don't want any
lumps do you? You can try and get rid of the
lumps, yeah.
20g of feta. But I wanna use a sweetcorn.
We're gonna hold it like this and I'm gonna
run my knife all the way down like this. So
I'm just gonna take that off like that. How's
it going Alex? It's good, it's perfect.
Lovely, I would expect nothing less from you.
Mmm. So Alex over here with the batter my
friend. And what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna
crumble some feta in there. We're gonna go
in with the sweetcorn. I've got a pan here
on a medium heat so I'm just gonna put in
my rashers here. So Alex you've got your own
channel now - French Guy Cooking.
It is.
Come on, tell them all about it.
It really is a simple channel, you know, the
most simple you can get French cooking to.
I mean, hearty dishes, don't want to be Frenchy
only. I want it to be, you know, worldwide;
Asian twists, Italian, Lebanese. But that's
nice, it's inspiring because it means if he
can do it, you can do it.
Ok push this down, let's get it crispy. It's
totally amazing! It's smelling really good.
We wanna just turn those over. Perfectly golden.
The best bit at the moment happening here
is like the caramelisation of the bacon, but
the fat coming out. So I'm gonna use that
fat to cook my pancakes. So the bacon's nearly
there. I'm gonna do a very, very simple piece
of avocado and I'm literally just gonna dress
it in a little salt, a little pepper, just
a little bit of lime zest over the top is
very, very nice and a little lime juice. This
will stop the avocado discolouring but it
will just give it the most wonderful sort
of flavour. And the whole point of this dish
is it's comforting but also it wakes you up.
So just remove the bacon, lovely and crisp.
That goes here. Just gonna turn it down a
little bit.
So I'm gonna give you bacon fat. Give it a
shake my brother. I wanna do nice, just a
couple of little pancakes there, just like
that.
Can you do the same my friend?
Beautiful. I'll try.
It doesn't matter if they're not perfectly
round. As my Nan used to say - it all goes
down the same hole.
What we wanna do is when these little bubbles
come to the top here, right I'm gonna get
in, under and just flip that bad boy over.
Look at that!
So the pancakes they're nearly done. I've
got my bacon, I've got my avocado and of course
I'm gonna take a couple of our lovely pancakes
here. I'm gonna stack them up just like this.
I'm gonna just hit up the bacon, just a couple
of bits of that with some avocado. So a little
bit of the old lime juice on the avocados
and then just a little bit of yoghurt and..
Chilli sauce!
Yes, chilli. And then just a little coriander.
So there you go. That is my Californian style
brunch. This one is for this lovely man right
here. Thank you Jamie. There you go Alex.
There's a fork to eat it with. And Alex is
gonna make a beautiful French style Crepe
with, tell us what's on the topping.
I mean the topping will be a sweet one. we
will have some caramel, some butter and you
know, it's just sweetness. What do you call
it in French?
We call it Caramel beurre sale.
Come on! If you want a little bit of Caramel
beurre sale then click on his head right now,
go through to his channel, don't forget to
subscribe. If you're cooking pancakes on Pancake
Day, or any day of the year, can you put the
picture up on Instagram or Twitter, #MYPANCAKEDAY.
And I'm gonna be looking through those pictures,
yes I will.
So there you go guys, from me and French Guy
Cooking it's bye bye. Au revoir Monsieur,
Madame. Goodbye, see you.