SHANE SMITH: After getting
kicked out of the logging
camp, we headed into
the forest in
search of actual loggers.
The Fish knew all the lumber
hot spots, and, after some
very lurchy driving, he
found us a working
cadre deep in the forest.
This guy is really going
to want to talk to us.
Maybe I should soften it up a
bit with the shotgun before we
get out, so they know
we mean business.
SIMON OSTROVSKY: Good idea.
SHANE SMITH: After our heated
words at the logging camp, we
decided to try to irrigate
the conversation with the
universal tongue-loosener--
booze.
MALE SPEAKER 1:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
SHANE SMITH: Hey,
you want a beer?
Hello.
[SPEAKING KOREAN]
Anybody want a beer?
Here.
MALE SPEAKER 2:
[SPEAKING KOREAN]
KIM YUN ZUN: [SPEAKING KOREAN]
MALE SPEAKER 2:
[SPEAKING KOREAN]
KIM YUN ZUN: [SPEAKING KOREAN]
MALE SPEAKER 2:
[SPEAKING KOREAN]
KIM YUN ZUN: [SPEAKING KOREAN]
MALE SPEAKER 2:
[SPEAKING KOREAN]
SHANE SMITH: Dude's got
an iron bar there.
Watch his back.
How long have they been
working here?
MALE SPEAKER 3:
[SPEAKING KOREAN]
KIM YUN ZUN: [SPEAKING KOREAN]
MALE SPEAKER 3:
[SPEAKING KOREAN]
SHANE SMITH: And do they
live out here?
MALE SPEAKER 3:
[SPEAKING KOREAN]
SHANE SMITH: And how long do
they have to stay here before
they can go back home?
MALE SPEAKER 3:
[SPEAKING KOREAN]
KIM YUN ZUN: [SPEAKING KOREAN]
MALE SPEAKER 3:
[SPEAKING KOREAN]
KIM YUN ZUN: [SPEAKING KOREAN]
MALE SPEAKER 3:
[SPEAKING KOREAN]
SHANE SMITH: So what he's
saying here is that the
majority of workers have a
10-year-plus labor commitment
to live and work out in
the middle of nowhere
for almost no pay.
And when we asked him about days
off, he seemed confused.
KIM YUN ZUN: [SPEAKING KOREAN]
MALE SPEAKER 3:
[SPEAKING KOREAN]
KIM YUN ZUN: [SPEAKING KOREAN]
MALE SPEAKER 3:
[SPEAKING KOREAN]
KIM YUN ZUN: [SPEAKING KOREAN]
SIMON OSTROVSKY:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
KIM YUN ZUN: [LAUGH]
SIMON OSTROVSKY:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
KIM YUN ZUN: [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
[SPEAKING KOREAN]
MALE SPEAKER 3:
KIM YUN ZUN: [SPEAKING KOREAN]
[SPEAKING KOREAN]
MALE SPEAKER 3:
KIM YUN ZUN: [SPEAKING KOREAN]
MALE SPEAKER 3: [LAUGH]
MALE SPEAKER 3:
[SPEAKING KOREAN]
SHANE SMITH: And are they
happy to be here?
MALE SPEAKER 3:
[SPEAKING KOREAN]
KIM YUN ZUN: [SPEAKING KOREAN]
MALE SPEAKER 3:
[SPEAKING KOREAN]
SHANE SMITH: Here comes a van.
We were talking to our
North Korean friends.
MALE SPEAKER 3:
[SPEAKING KOREAN]
SHANE SMITH: --and they're
now coming to get us.
MALE SPEAKER 3:
[SPEAKING KOREAN]
SHANE SMITH: Who
are these guys?
SIMON OSTROVSKY: It's the
guy in the blue jacket
who we talked to.
Oh, he's the secretary of the
party organization here.
SHANE SMITH: Hmm.
So the secretary of the party
organization has come.
They're going be told
not to talk to us.
MALE SPEAKER 3:
[SPEAKING KOREAN]
MALE SPEAKER 4:
KIM YUN ZUN: [SPEAKING KOREAN]
[SPEAKING KOREAN]
SHANE SMITH: We promised
to go away from there.
MALE SPEAKER 4:
[SPEAKING KOREAN]
IGOR "THE FISH" RYBAKOV:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
MALE SPEAKER 4:
IGOR "THE FISH" RYBAKOV:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
MALE SPEAKER 4:
IGOR "THE FISH" RYBAKOV:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
MALE SPEAKER 4:
SIMON OSTROVSKY: He's
really angry.
MALE SPEAKER 4:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
SHANE SMITH: [INAUDIBLE]?
IGOR "THE FISH" RYBAKOV:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
SIMON OSTROVSKY: He's saying
he's going to tell the Tynda
captain boss that this
guy's helping us out.
He's trying to scare him.
SHANE SMITH: It was right
around here that
things got a bit tense.
Yeah, these guys are
coming back here.
The dude with the crowbar
is coming back.
MALE SPEAKER 5:
[SPEAKING KOREAN]
SHANE SMITH: We're in a
high-speed car chase at five
miles an hour through the
wilds of Siberia.
It's a game of chicken out
in the middle of nowhere.