of this country.
Jeff Bushaw: For the
Yellowstone Super Volcano.
Steve Vanasse: Civil
unrest following a
dirty bomb blast.
Narrator: And
protect themselves.
From what they
perceive as the fast
approaching end of the
world as we know it.
Kat Perez: Thomas,
don't give 'em the gun!
Don't give 'em
the gun, Thomas!
No!
Narrator: Next, we go
inside the lives of
two committed preppers.
Who have devised
extensive plans.
Derek Price:
Bulletproof, bombproof.
Narrator: Gone to
great lengths and
made huge personal
sacrifices to
ensure their
very survival.
Derek Price: This is
a bad idea, probably.
Boo-yah!
Narrator: The experts
will assess their preps,
to see if they
have what it takes.
Brent: Are we ready?
Haven Price: If the
apocalypse comes
we'll be safe
and you won't.
Narrator: To survive.
Brent: Let's go.
Let's go.
People are hungry.
Derek Price: You're dead.
Narrator: This is
Doomsday Preppers.
Brent is a
jack-of-all-trades
living on the east
coast of Florida.
Over the course
of his life,
he's been an engineer,
a real estate broker,
and a military officer.
Lately, he's been
bringing all his various
skills together to
create his legacy.
One final project
that he wants to leave
behind for his children
and grandchildren.
Brent: This is going to
be something that
should last for
generation upon generation.
And maybe someday a
hundred years from now
or a thousand
years from now,
someone will come
up this road and say,
"How did this
all happen?
What was the
man thinking?"
Narrator: What
Brent's thinking is:
his family needs
a last bastion of
defense against
a world gone mad.
A stronghold to stand
against the end of times.
Forget bunkers, if
the apocalypse comes,
Brent's going
medieval on it.
Welcome to Brent's
Doomsday Castle.
Brent: I'm preparing for
an electromagnetic pulse.
This is the heart of
the castle, uh, over
6,000 square
feet, two floors.
Six bedrooms
will fill this,
the upper two levels.
This will be the main
hall where everybody
will be gathering.
We could put half
a cow out here.
It'll be a feast just like
the old medieval times.
This will be
the library.
Solid mahogany
shelving, 10 feet high.
A spiral staircase going
up almost three stories,
up to the roof.
In addition to everything
that you see on top,
we've got almost 3,000
square feet of bunker
that can handle anything.
Sometimes people
will ask me,
"How much money have
you put in to this?"
I'm probably
approaching close
to a million dollars.
But I built a
castle because
castles are all rock.
It can't burn.
It would probably
withstand most major
earthquakes or any
other catastrophe.
Narrator: But the
disaster scenario
Brent fears
most is an EMP,
an electromagnetic pulse,
a burst of energy that can
fry electrical circuits.
And that can be set
off by the explosion of
atomic bombs
in the atmosphere.
Brent: We have so many
enemies out there,
both religious and
non-religious that
are out to do America
in, in some way.
Many countries have
the ability to get
a small atomic bomb
25 to 200 miles
up into the atmosphere.
Narrator: A nuclear
blast large enough and
high enough over
Kansas would cause an EMP
that could affect the
entire Continental U.S.
Brent fears such
a blast could black out
the entire U.S.,
perhaps forever.
Brent: It's gonna take
anything that has a
computer chip, which
almost everything
is run by that.
There would be no way to
communicate with people.
There is no water;
there's no sanitation.
It will be only a matter
of days until people
realize that they
can't get any food.
Then everyone will turn
into basically a savage.
We would go back to
the medieval days.
My fear was: with the
large family that I have,
how would I protect them?
I've got 10 children.
My youngest is 8 years
old and my oldest is,
be 41 this year,
so quite a range.
Narrator: Today, Brent's
assembling his clan to
practice bugging
out to the castle.
Brent: We're gonna be
doing all types of
training, things
you've never seen
or done before.
Narrator: But once
they get up there,
he'll have a surprise
in store for them.
He wants his family's help
finishing the castle,
but fears few of
his ten children are
truly up to
the challenge.
Ashley: How are
we going to bathe?
How are we going
to survive?
When I told the kids
what I was going to do,
they kind of
laughed and said,
"What?
A castle?
Why are you
building something
like that out there?"
My oldest one is
Brent the Second.
I don't know what
his strength is.
He should be one of the
most knowledgeable,
but that's not the way it
is right at this moment.
Brent Jr.: You're
gonna show me how
to use this thing?
Brent: I'm sure we'll
get through all that.
Brent Jr.: Alright.
Brent: If anyone thinks
that I'm paranoid,
it's probably Ashley
that would be the oldest
child from my
second marriage.
Ashley is the model
of the family.
She is more of a primper
than a prepper though.
Ashley: My plan
is basically,
to grab my makeup, grab
my little Tebow dog
and just head out.
Brent: We had two
twins, a boy-girl twin
that are 19 years of age.
And the twins' names are
Michael and Dawn-Marie.
Dawn-Marie: I'm not
sure if the end of the
world is going to
happen but if it does,
it's always better
to be prepared than
not be prepared.
Michael: The castle.
It's not finished yet,
but I know that when
it is going
to be finished,
it's going to be
amazing up there.
Brent: Let's,
go everybody.
It's a long
walk up there.
Okay, so everything
we can carry,
we want to carry it now.
Son: C'mon guys, keep up.
A little bit further.
Daughter: We
getting close?
Brent: They thought
it was real simple.
You grab some things and
you run for the hills,
well, it doesn't
work that way.
Michael: Alright,
we gotta check
the perimeter.
Girls, get the rear.
Brent: Alright, let's go.
Let's get
everything inside.
Narrator: Now that
they've arrived,
Brent's kids are about
to learn the true reason
they've been assembled.
Dawn-Marie: Alright.
Let's set up
all the chairs.
Brent: I decided I was not
going to leave my kids
with a fortune of money.
One of the main reasons
for having you all come up
is 'cause I wanted to
tell y'all something.
I wanted to reveal it in
the midst of as many, uh,
of my family members,
uh, as I possibly could.
I'm taking whatever
money I have at,
at my death other than
some small amounts,
and, and putting it
into this castle.
It has been put
into what I call
the last retreat
family trust.
It's designed to
last 100 years,
and it can't be broken.
There is no one that can
deed it or take it over.
Narrator: Brent's
looking for
an heir to his throne,
someone he can
trust to assume the
responsibility of
finishing construction.
In days of old, the
eldest son would
typically inherit
the crown.
Brent Jr.: I'm the
obvious choice.
I'm Brent the Second
and I'm the oldest.
He's the king.
I am the prince.
Narrator: But Brent's
decided that only
two of his 10 children,
one from each
of his marriages,
will be executors
of the trust.
Brent: There will be two
people that will help be
the executors to make
sure everything happens.
Now, I have some ideas of
who I'd like it to be,
but how dedicated
are you into seeing
my dream come true?
I mean can you make
my dream your dream?
There are some
certain qualities that
I'm looking for in
those two children.
One: they have to
really want it and
they believe in it.
Second thing, they
have to be is they
have to be
knowledgeable.
They either have to
know construction,
they have to
know business,
know something.
I want to know
that they'll
carry out my wishes.
Dawn-Marie: I just
want you to know that
I'm very proud you and.
Brent: Thank you, honey.
Dawn-Marie: And I,
you're definitely a
role model to this
family and some.
Brent: Well, thank you.
Dawn-Marie: Someone
that we can look up to.
I think it would be a
possibility that my dad
would maybe pick me,
because I've definitely
come up here a lot of
times and helped my dad.
All the sheetrock,
downstairs,
me and my dad
did all of that.
Ashley: Amazing, that's
awesome and this is the
best gift, better than
any Christmas present,
better than anything
that I could get,
this right here.
I'm shocked, I
didn't expect this.
I think he's
gonna choose me.
Um.
I say that because
I know more.
I have proven
myself more I think.
Brent Jr.: I wanna take on
your dream, like you said,
and help you get this,
get the roof on this place
and get this
place completed.
So I'll be working
twice as hard.
Michael: I think what's
important is if you
actually care about
this mountain house,
then you should
just prove it.
Dawn-Marie: Yep.
I agree.
Michael: He needs you
to do something, do it.
Use your actions
and not your words.
Brent: Dawn-Marie's
spent the most,
most time with me.
Michael would be second.
Brent has never
been up here really,
he's really not
contributed.
And Ashley really hasn't,
she's been up here as a
little child, but not what
I would call contributing.
Narrator: Brent wants
today to be the day he
decides which two of his
offspring are prepper
enough to fill his shoes.
So he's about to put his
kids through the ultimate
series of prepper tests.
Narrator: Brent has
spent the last dozen years,
and a small fortune,
building a literal
castle to serve as
his family's fortress
in the Carolina's
during the end times.
Brent: My particular
piece of property is
50 acres surrounded
by 1,000 acres.
There is
only one way in.
It is literally
almost cliffs on
each side to get up.
The property has a
400-foot well with a
stream running
right past it.
I bought 40,000
heirloom seeds so we
can grow any kind
of a vegetable.
Narrator: To determine
which two of his
kids will become
heirs to his throne,
he's assembled his
extended family at the
castle this weekend
for a series of tests.
Brent: I'm going to be
looking at these kids,
each one of them today to
see how they interact,
how tempers flare,
how, who helps who.
Narrator: Brent fears
America's enemies could
one day detonate a nuclear
device in the atmosphere
creating an EMP, an
electromagnetic pulse,
which could
blackout America.
So for his first test,
he's judging their
prepping ability by
having them construct a
power supply
for the castle.
Brent: We need
batteries.
We need windmills.
We need solar panels.
We need to be able to
run on 12 volt, 24 volt,
48 volt or the
standard 120-volt.
Dawn-Marie: Dad, what
exactly are we doing?
What are we making?
Brent: It's called
a solar panel array.
We're gonna have
eight solar panels,
mounted to this
bracket that can tilt
however we want it
so it's facing the sun.
Narrator: Brent plans to
use solar panels to charge
a bank of batteries,
which will then help
provide electricity
for the castle.
If his kids can
figure out how to get
the array assembled.
Ashley: Where are
the instructions?
Michael: We don't
need instructions.
Brent: We put it together
12 years ago, now we.
Ashley: Women read
instructions, men don't.
Brent: We're gonna be
facing south because the
sun comes from east to
west and that's a southern
direction right there,
so we want the most sun
during the day to
these solar panels.
Dawn-Marie: How do you
know that's south?
Brent: I have a compass.
Dawn-Marie is the wild
child of the family.
A true "A" personality.
But when it comes to
counting on somebody I
know that we can
always count on her.
Oh!
Michael!
Michael: Come on,
it's right there.
It's fine.
Brent: Michael, I know
he's gonna be a great
asset to the family.
I would say his weakness
is Michael still has
not yet learned
responsibility.
Narrator: With the solar
panel assembled Brent's
one step closer to
being able to power his
castle after doomsday.
But he's still no
closer to deciding who
his two trustees will be.
Brent: I need to look more
in depth at each child as
far as seeing who
I think should be a
leader in the trust.
It's gonna take
some more time.
We're gonna have
to go through maybe
a few more tests.
Okay, we're done.
Let's go see what
the next project is.
Narrator: Having
assembled their alternate
power supply,
Brent takes time to work
with his firstborn
son, Brent Jr.,
on what he feels
is his weakest
prepping
skill, defense.
Brent Jr.: What
can I learn today?
Brent: Some of my
children that don't live
right next to me
really have no idea
how to handle a weapon.
Brent the Second, which
is my oldest child,
worries me the most 'cause
I've never seen him,
to my knowledge he's
never had any training.
I asked him to choose a
weapon and he picks up
an AK47 and the first
thing I said is,
"Do you know how
to use that?"
This has to be down.
Brent Jr.: Okay.
Brent: 'Cause that
is your safety on
this particular gun.
Now we're loaded.
Brent Jr.: Okay.
So it's live?
Brent: It's live.
Please do not point
it in my direction.
Brent Jr.: Okay.
Brent: We chose
guns that were like
police-type weapons.
Or army-type weapons.
An AR15 or an AK47.
It needed to be something
that was pretty standard
and there were a lot of.
You're ready to shoot.
Brent Jr.: Alright I am.
Just aim and shoot?
Brent: Hold up a minute.
Uh, you wanna put some
earplugs in here.
Brent Jr.: Do you really?
I don't need earplugs.
Brent: Alright.
Brent Jr.: You ready?
Brent: Well since
it's your first time,
let's go for the
biggest target which
will be that
can up top.
Brent Jr.: Did I hit it?
Brent: I have not the
foggiest idea the
way you were firing.
Brent Jr.: My ears
are ringing now.
Brent: Do you know
what happens when you
fire that many times?
Brent Jr.: What's that?
Brent: Because the
gun is pulling back.
Brent Jr.: I need
you to speak louder.
Brent: You're
going up higher and
higher and higher.
I'd be more fearful
of him shooting one of us
than shooting somebody
else that might be out
there so we're definitely
gonna have to spend
some time with him.
Okay, put it in
your shoulder.
Dawn-Marie is
coming along.
After she shot the gun a
couple time she settled
down and she really
got serious about it.
Ashley had never
shot a shotgun.
She was a little scared,
she didn't know how
noisy it was gonna be.
Ashley: I'm so scared.
(Screams).
I don't like that.
Brent: Probably
the best shooter was
probably Michael
out there.
Narrator: A severe
thunderstorm rolls in,
but they're not
taking shelter.
During medieval times, as
few as 20 men inside a
well-fortified castle
could hold back
an army of thousands.
Brent's using the storm as
an opportunity to see if
his potential heirs
can defend the castle
as a unit under
harsh conditions.
Brent Jr.: Alright.
Are we ready?
Let's go.
It's a rainy day;
you know there's
people out there
getting ready
to attack.
Brent: After one person
shoots, you move back.
Son: Let's go.
Brent: And another
person moves in.
When the girls are out,
the archers come in,
two at a time.
Amanda: Pull back.
Now push it back in.
Pull down, but
not all the way.
Ashley: But
not yet though.
Amanda: Yeah.
Brent: Alright,
two more people.
Son: Alright.
Brent: Good, very good.
The reason for the
shooting drill tonight was
to see how everyone
would react under a
simulated firing condition.
Could everybody
work in unison?
There was some
complaining.
Brent Jr.: I feel like I
just jumped in a lake.
Brent: Everybody
was tired;
everybody was hungry.
That is the worst
situation you could
ever have in any
kind of a firefight.
You two are taking shots,
you're taking a shot.
I was real proud
of all of them.
They did a good job.
Narrator: Exhausted and
soaked to the skin,
Brent's kids are eager
for a chance to rest
and get some food.
But this weekend,
everything is a test.
Even dinner.
Brent: Let's go!
Let's go!
People are hungry!
We did something
that none of the
kids have ever
done on this trip.
We gave each
of them an MRE.
Narrator: "Meals
ready to eat"
or MRE's are essentially
1,200 calorie canned
meals in light
aluminum pouches that
can last at least
three years
when stored at a
cool temperature.
Brent's had some
of his for 12.
Ashley: Are those
still safe to eat?
Brent: Well, I've had
one every year to
test it myself, ate it,
never got sick, so.
We tried to make this
training exercise
as real life as possible.
I chose probably the
worst thing to eat out of
everything that we could
have possibly have made.
I had to make sure
they could at least
stomach the MRE's.
Brent Jr.: Alright,
who wants to take a
bite of this
12-year-old beef patty?
Brent: They weren't too
happy about those things.
Girlfriend: It
smells terrible.
Brent: Nobody got sick,
that was a good thing.
Actually Michael thought
it was tremendous.
He was sharing it with
everybody ah, there.
Dawn-Marie: Does it
taste like ravioli?
Michael: Yeah.
Tastes good.
Brother: It's
not that bad.
Michael: It's
not bad at all.
Brent: Taste it.
Come on.
I thought you
were the one that.
Dawn-Marie: It is good.
Brent: Dawn-Marie when
she put the MRE in her
mouth she was gagging
on it a little bit.
What are you doing?
Dawn-Marie:
I'm not hungry.
Brent: She's gonna
have to remember,
when it comes down to a
true survival situation,
she's gonna have to
take what she can get,
and be satisfied with it.
Narrator: As night falls
on Brent's kingdom,
he reflects on his
kids' performances.
But Mother Nature
is about to unleash
one more unexpected
trial on them all.
Shane: I got sparks.
Narrator: And this one
will rattle even the king.
Narrator: Fearful
that an EMP attack could
knock out
America's power grid,
Brent has been
constructing a
medieval castle in
the Carolina Mountains.
If a medieval castle's
outer defenses ever fell,
the king could often
retreat to a fortified
tower within,
called a keep.
As a violent thunderstorm
besieges Brent's castle,
he and his kids retreat
to a keep of their own,
a 2,000-square-foot
bunker,
stocked with almost
two years of supplies.
Brent: We put in a
complete water and
sanitation system with
a water tank inside,
250-350 gallons.
We put showers in.
We have bedrooms and a
kitchen in so that if we
ever had to live there,
we could do that.
Narrator: But as the
storm rages outside,
Brent and his kids
discover the bunker itself
could be the greatest
threat to their safety.
Brent: This is a
little strange.
Here we build a
whole house out of.
[circut breaker pops]
That was pretty real.
[girl screams]
That's even realer.
Dawn-Marie: Power's out,
power is out.
[electricity pops]
Brent: We saw something
I had never seen before,
and that was sparks
and lightning jumping
across the walls.
Narrator: What began
as a series of tests
has just turned into
a real potential
disaster scenario.
Brent: Don't anybody
touch any of the metal
that's in this door.
Narrator: This gives Brent
the unexpected opportunity
to observe how his kids
deal with the crisis.
Brent: Some got
really, really scared.
Some just kinda sat there
for a little while.
Brent Jr.: I think
this bunker, is, is,
could be a death
trap right now and
it could electrocute us.
I'd hate to be preparing
for the end of the world,
and while we're
preparing get killed.
Brent: Whoa, we just
blew out the lights.
Even I wasn't sure what
to do because it was so
unexplainable and I think
in a true cataclysmic
event that's exactly
the way it's gonna be.
Nothing was
making any sense.
We, we're just
running around with
lights exploding.
Ashley: Guys, is
this supposed to be
happening right now?
Brent: Now I know
exactly what it is.
Coming out of the top
of the building we
got all that rebar,
and it's acting
like lightning rods.
Shane: Right,
that's exposed.
Brent: It's all
exposed and it's going
right down through
the concrete.
Brent Jr.: It's
not grounded?
Brent: No, it's grounded.
It's going right into
the concrete here.
Looking back I think
we figured out
what the problem was.
We filled the
block with steel.
And so I realize now
that we do have to put a
lightning rod and tie it
to all of our electrical
and that should take
care of the problem.
Narrator: Brent's
children won't learn
which two have
inherited his kingdom
until after he's dead.
He had hoped that this
weekend drill would make
the choice clearer,
but instead,
the king is now
less certain than
ever about choosing
his successors.
Brent: I learned a
lot about each of
my children
this weekend.
Michael, he still
shows good leadership,
but he's very
impulsive, and
that has to be
tamed down.
Brent came here knowing
nothing about a gun.
He did pretty
well with it.
Ashley came and I saw some
strength come out of her.
Dawn-Marie was
Dawn-Marie.
She just chipped in
and wanted to be
a part of everything.
I think we still need
a lot of training.
I need to look more in
depth at each child
as far as seeing who
I think should be a
leader in the trust.
I don't think any full
decision has been made.
I thought I knew but
I'm not 100% sure.
Dawn-Marie: Family.
Brent: I love y'all.
Narrator: Brent,
the experts at
Practical Preppers have
reviewed your preps.
Much of your food
supply is outdated and
may not be fit
for consumption.
You need to implement
a re-supply plan
for the long term.
Brent: The MRE's
we've tested 'em.
Uh, but they
probably do need to
be replenished here at
the castle because
they do go back as
far as 12 years.
Narrator: Your isolated
location is ideal for
security, but your
castle is unfinished,
and the entire
structure is unsafe
during electrical storms.
You need to finish
the structure,
and address issues
that are currently a
danger to your family.
Brent: I don't think
that they really took
into account any
additional things that
we may have on order.
We do not have
everything in place yet.
Narrator: To determine how
long you could initially
survive a catastrophe,
Practical Preppers has
scored your preps in five
categories of 20 points
each, for a total
possible score of 100.
Much of your food
supply is beyond its
expiration date: 9
out of 20 points.
Water: 13 out
of 20 points.
Shelter: once your
castle is finished,
you'll be able to
take full advantage
of your remote location.
18 out of 20 points.
Security: 14 out
of 20 points.
Your bunker and
the castle's unique
defensive structure
give you 14 X-factor points.
Your total score
is 68 out of 100.
You have 11 months
initial survival time.
Brent: I think I have
to disagree a little
bit on what we have
here in our storage.
I don't think the
evaluator has any
idea what we truly have.
I do agree that, uh,
in the meantime we do
need to work on a
couple of the items
that have been suggested.
Since the crew was here,
we've done a number of,
uh, changes to the castle.
We've extended all the
pillars that are gonna
support all the decks
around the castle to full
height so that we can
pour a concrete roof
and a concrete deck.
We've also purchased
some additional food and
a couple of accessory
items for our to-go bags
in case we have
to get outta dodge.
Narrator: The
U.S. power grid
already has some
protections in place,
and experts are
contemplating additional
measures that
would help guard
against nuclear EMPs.
However, the likelihood
of such an attack
is generally
considered very remote.
Only 400 miles away
in North Carolina,
Derek Price also
fears an EMP will soon
blackout civilization
and send society
reeling back through time.
Derek Price: Got my
small pocket pistol.
Go.
Narrator: He's building
a doomsday fortress
of his own, but he
doesn't want to live
like a medieval knight.
Instead, he's taking
his family back to
the Wild, Wild West.
Narrator: In the
remote town of Bear Grass,
North Carolina
is a locally owned
amusement park
called Deadwood.
Every week, thousands
of visitors travel
back to the days of
gunslingers and outlaws.
Cowboy: Come on, come on!
This way, this way!
I got the whiskey!
We give up!
Narrator: But visitors
may not realize,
Deadwood isn't
just a theme park.
It's a front, for
one family's plan to
survive the end
of the world.
Derek Price: Initially
this was just a plan
to provide a small,
secure storage area.
Now the whole back yard is
being used as a fortress.
I'm preparing for
a solar flare and
an EMP that will
end civilization and
send us back
to the Wild West.
I've been obsessed
for a long time.
I've used the business
maybe as an excuse to,
to satisfy some, some
level of obsession.
And, you know,
maybe it is paranoia.
I would argue that
Deadwood might be a
cover for some of
me and my family's
more fringe interests.
We are concerned about
a solar flare and
loss of electricity,
possibly sending our way
of life back at least
to the Wild West.
Narrator: Solar flares
are massive bursts of
energy released
by the sun.
If an eruption on the
sun is large enough,
the shockwave of
energized particles can
slam into the earth's
magnetic field,
unloading trillions of
watts of power into the
atmosphere and frying
electric grids in its way.
Derek Price: You'd
lose refrigeration
in your grocery stores.
Your food supply chain
would break down.
People who are on
normal medications
would not have
access to 'em.
We're preparing for
the lawless days that
might ensue, if society
breaks down because
of the loss
of electricity.
I think two or three
days at the most and
we'd have complete chaos,
uh, looting, raiding.
Those people could be
people that we know.
Narrator: Derek's family
has spent the last
20 years, and more
than $100,000,
preparing for a
future Dark Age.
Ira Price: Yeah, I think
that oughta do it.
Straight line of sight.
How about right here?
Narrator: And all the
profits they make
from ticket sales
go directly to
secretly prepping
Deadwood.
Derek wants the
park to operate as
a real outpost to
defend his family,
if a solar flare
disrupts electricity.
Derek Price: In the
event of a solar flare,
Deadwood would
come to life.
We would, uh, go back
to a time much like
200 years ago in the
frontier where, uh,
Deadwood would become
a defensive center
for our family.
Narrator: Everything
in Deadwood has a
secret prepping purpose.
To ensure his family can
stay well-nourished as
they defend the compound,
the park's restaurant
conceals Derek's
Armageddon-sized
food orders.
Derek Price: My
therapist would probably
argue that the only
reason we run a
restaurant at
Deadwood is I can
kind of covertly prep.
My system is, you know,
ten cases for the
restaurant, one
case for Derek.
I try to keep at least
a year worth of food
for me and
my extended family,
probably 15 people.
Narrator: Leftover oil
from the restaurant is
converted to bio-diesel,
which is used to
power Deadwood's train.
Derek Price: This train
runs on bio-diesel,
and I'll be able to
power it practically
indefinitely using
the leftover waste oil
that I have stored
around here.
In a post-apocalyptic
future,
I'll still be able to use
it to patrol our perimeter
and move our goods
and services in and
out of the
facility here.
Narrator: Even the
putt-putt golf course
was built with the
apocalypse in mind.
From here, Derek
and his brother,
Daniel, can fire at
unwanted visitors,
who they fear may
want to take over
Deadwood once the
lights go out.
Daniel Price: At the very
top of the putt-putt
course we have defensive
positions here that
overlook the entire
village of Deadwood.
Part of hole number 14,
crouching position
covers the roadway that
goes all along the
front side of Deadwood.
Unbeknownst to
the paying public,
this is a series of
sniper positions,
concrete reinforced
with lots of exits and
lots of fields of fire.
Narrator: Lately,
most of Derek's time,
and almost all of
Deadwood's profits,
have been funneled into
his biggest prep yet.
His doomsday fort.
Derek Price: We were
able to camouflage our
fortress in plain sight
in the period that
we've modeled our business
around the Old West,
and ah, nobody would
raise any eyebrows.
I have this ability to
build big, weird things.
And now you know
my paranoia,
my obsession has led
me to take on a project
that who else
would take on.
Narrator: Derek's
4,000-square-foot fort
is only halfway finished.
Derek Price: Okay, so
we'll just cut that 10 foot.
Narrator: A typical
amusement park building
faade is made
of plywood and
might normally cost
Derek around $100.
So far, Derek's fort
has cost him $20,000,
and he expects that
price to double.
Unlike a theme park
model, it's reinforced
with eight inches
of concrete and rebar,
which Derek believes
is enough to withstand
point blank fire
from a machine gun.
Derek Price: Bulletproof,
bombproof, stormproof.
Ira Price: Well,
not too big a bomb.
A little bomb's alright.
You'd have to shoot it 15,
20 times in a spot that
big to maybe get
through that wall.
And by that time
we can take action
to, to, uh,
shut it down.
Derek Price: It's funny
to a certain extent.
Almost wish somebody
would try to break the
door down so I could
see what would happen
if I did stick
a flamethrower out.
Narrator: Derek's doomsday
fort also includes a
series of secret
tunnels and hatches.
Derek Price: Not only
can I get out and
flank somebody, but I can
also get in undetected.
Narrator: This passage
leads to the water well,
which doubles as a
secret sniper position.
And the mini black powder
cannon atop the fort can
be reached by another
hatch on the roof.
Derek Price: I
designed this door
to be impenetrable.
It is a quarter-inch
plate steel on both
sides filled with gravel.
It's bulletproof,
bombproof, blast proof,
and fireproof.
Nothing is getting
through this door.
If an EMP were to hit,
this is where I want
to make my final stand.
Narrator: Because Derek
fears modern technology
will be wiped out by a
massive solar flare,
when it comes to defending
his Wild West compound,
he wants to rely on old
fashioned weaponry.
But when he puts
his ancient arsenal
to the test,
his entire defensive
strategy may fizzle.
Derek Price: Damn.
Cowboy: Sam, put
your pistol down.
Don't shoot us, boss!
Narrator:
Three generations of
Derek Price's family have
created a fantasy world
that pays the bills on
their real-life obsession:
prepping for an
apocalyptic solar flare.
Derek Price: Have we
spent too much time?
Too much money prepping?
Have we overdone it?
You know, I'm willing
to take that chance.
Narrator: As his fort
nears completion,
he's decided to institute
even greater defenses.
Because he fears a solar
flare will end modern
life, Derek doesn't plan
to rely on modern weapons.
Instead, he's borrowing
defense strategies
from an era
before electricity.
The first line
of defense starts at
his property line.
Daniel Price: I'm
more concerned about
the back perimeter
than anything else.
And uh.
Derek Price:
Back perimeter?
Well, let's set up
some booby traps.
Hey, hey, this one
looks good right here.
Derek Price: Bamboo isn't
native to North Carolina.
Me and my father planted
this about 20 years ago
because there's so
many uses for it.
Daniel Price: We
originally wanted to
use this as spears
and possibly blowguns,
that's one of the oldest
weapons known to humans,
but, uh, I wanted to make
lots and lots of spikes to
cover your ditches and
those dead zones and
put a lot of hurt coming
out of the ground.
At an angle!
Narrator: In
the Vietnam War,
bamboo spikes
were sharpened,
then camouflaged and
placed in the ground
to maim or kill
intruding forces who
didn't know the terrain.
Daniel Price: We can't hit
'em with small arms fire.
We'll send them
right into bamboo.
Derek Price: Be careful.
Daniel Price:
That's perfect.
This is called
a punji pit.
But in the infantry, in
the Airborne Infantry,
we called it
"(Bleep) up a stick."
Because if you
fell on these well,
you weren't up
(bleep) creek,
you were up
(bleep) up a stick.
They come through
this little area with
a little bit of momentum;
they don't just
stick their foot.
They stick a torso.
Person's dead and that's
ultimately what we want.
Derek Price: These things
may be really primitive,
but, uh, you know,
in the event we had a
solar flare we're
gonna be back to
primitive means
of defense.
You know, there's
not going to be any
fancy things we can do.
You know this right
here has been effective
since the
beginning of time.
Daniel Price: Let's
test this sucker.
Derek Price:
All right, go.
Daniel Price: Oof.
Derek Price: Oh.
Oh.
No, I don't think
he's gonna make it.
Daniel Price: That's the
one that did him in.
Derek Price: Oh yeah.
That's a lethal
blow right there.
Daniel Price: Right
below, above the ribcage.
Right in the throat.
Narrator: If intruders
make it past the pits
filled with spikes,
they'll walk into
Derek's next
line of defense.
Derek Price: We consider
our cannon probably our
crown jewel of
defensive capabilities
here at our fortress.
Initially when we acquired
the cannon I think it
was probably for
display purposes and
by experimentation
with it we realized that
we can defend a
very large area with
a weapon like that.
Narrator: Derek's
cannon is modeled on
19th century black-powder
military cannons.
During the day
it shoots blanks
for visitors' enjoyment.
But today, for
the first time,
they are filling
it with pellets to
gauge its aim
and range.
Daniel Price: Back
up about two feet,
Haven, when
you sight it.
You should only see
one circle at the front
and nothing at the rear.
Alright, there you go.
Derek Price: Let's
go 10 seconds.
Put that in there.
Daniel Price:
Fire in the hole!
Derek Price: Fire.
Alright stand
back, guys.
Hold on to your hats.
Here we go.
Or not.
Let's be ready because
this could probably
go off at any second
without any warning there.
Stand back.
Let me see if I can
prick it out with this.
Daniel Price:
Wait, wait, wait.
First tap the end of it.
Derek Price: We're
gonna clear the fuse
and refuse it.
This is a bad
idea probably.
Let's stand back.
Narrator: Derek is
switching from a
timed fuse to
a pull fuse.
If the cannon won't
fire reliably this way,
the family will
have to refigure
their entire
defense plan.
Derek Price: We
are alive now.
Okay.
Daniel Price:
Test fire!
Fire in the hole!
Derek Price:
You ready?
Here we go.
3-2-1.
Damn.
Daniel Price: Boo-yah!
That's what I'm
talking about.
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6.
Wow, we've got
a spread of at least
12 feet over a 40-feet
run right here with
a lot of dead with
a lot of kill shots.
Derek Price: This would
make a real bad day for
anybody on the business
end of that cannon.
Narrator: Although
they're pleased with the
cannon's range, they've
also learned that
vintage weapons
are unreliable.
Daniel Price: We
need to have three or
four more of these.
And so that way if
one doesn't fire,
we still have two
to three more,
with cross-sections
of fire,
and I think that would be
the most effective thing.
Narrator: Derek believes
defending Deadwood will
require every member of
the family to arm himself,
even his 11-year-old
son, Haven.
Derek Price:
Alright, Haven.
We're gonna do a
perimeter sweep.
I'm gonna take
the south side,
you take the north side.
Okay?
Narrator: In preparation
for a world without
electricity, he's
been training Haven
to patrol Deadwood in
the dark of night.
Haven Price: If a solar
flare were to happen,
probably every place would
end up looking like this.
Derek Price: I think
at some level it's
still an adventure
for him right now.
It's fun and games.
I mean, he knows
I'm carrying a
loaded weapon
at night.
So, you know, at
some level he
knows it's serious.
But you know, I don't
think it's set in
on him yet just how
serious I'm taking it.
Haven Price: I tell a few
of my friends, you know,
"My dad has a bunker
and everything.
So we're going to
be well protected.
So if the apocalypse
comes we'll be safe
and you won't!"
Narrator: So far, Haven's
only been on patrol.
But Derek wants him
trained for what
he fears is the
worst case scenario.
Multiple attackers descend
on Deadwood town square.
Cannons fail.
The only option is a gun
battle to the death.
So Derek's about to put
the entire Price family,
and all of
Deadwood's defenses,
through an extreme test.
And tonight, the
youngest Price will
be on the front line.
Haven Price: Stay
where you are.
Don't move.
Narrator: Derek
Price has built an
old west fortress
that will serve as
his stronghold
if a Doomsday
solar flare wipes
out electricity.
Tonight Derek, his father
Ira, and son, Haven,
will face off against
his brother, Daniel,
and practice driving back
intruders from Deadwood.
Daniel Price:
Gentleman, tonight we're
gonna be playing an
apocalyptic version of
shells versus skulls.
An opposing force versus
a defensive posture.
Between the hours
of 9 P.M. and 6A.M.
the three of us will
be out and about,
and we will try to attack
and take the dance hall
from your possession,
using whatever tactics
we deem necessary.
Your job is to
defend the dance hall
from our assault.
Are there any questions
before we begin?
Haven Price: Shells rule.
Derek Price:
Lock and load.
Let's go, guys.
Narrator: The two teams
are using real weapons,
but the safeties are on.
A kill will be determined
by flashing the gun's
light on the victim
for three seconds.
Derek Price: I think if
you cover the left flank,
and Haven, if you take
the elevated position
at the top up there,
you can cover both of
those spots at
the same time.
Haven Price: Alright,
since I'm taking the
elevated position I'm
thinking I'm gonna go
with my assault
rifle instead of
this four-ten here.
Derek Price:
Okay, that's fine.
Narrator: While Derek's
team plots their strategy
to hold the dancehall,
Daniel's team of
Deadwood employees is
throwing out the rulebook.
Daniel Price: If you're
playing by the rules,
you need to change
your tactics.
They're expecting
three of us, not four.
They have to see us.
They do not
have to see her.
In fact, I don't even
want you to make your
appearance known until
you're positive at
least one or all
of us are dead.
So we've got
our advantage.
Derek is our
primary target.
Without that leadership,
Haven will go into
complete shock that his
dad has been taken out
and neutralized.
Live well.
Die hard.
Let's do it.
Ira Price: They're both
trying to outsmart each
other, and, uh, Daniel,
Daniel is pretty sneaky.
He'll take an hour.
He's patient.
Haven Price: Dad,
got movement on
the right flank.
But I think it
may be a decoy.
I know, I know what
Uncle Dan does.
Stay where you are.
Don't move.
Derek Price: Alright,
I'm in position.
Haven Price: Someone's
making a noise.
Somebody's trying
to distract us.
Granddad, I need cover.
Over.
Derek Price: You're dead.
Haven Price:
Somebody hit Daniel.
Gotcha!
Derek Price: You're dead.
That's three!
Girl: You're dead!
Derek Price:
Son of a bitch.
Daniel Price: Well, that
was pretty fun guys.
Narrator: The team led by
Derek and Haven seemed to
have the advantage, but
not expecting Daniel's ace
in the hole ultimately led
to Derek being killed,
and the team
losing the drill.
Derek Price: Trusting my
brother would follow the
rules was a bad idea.
And you know, he got me.
But, you know,
that's a valuable
lesson to learn,
you know.
There's no such thing
as a fair fight.
Daniel Price: The major
improvements I see is
we've got to make it a
lot more difficult for
somebody just to walk in
and get this close to us.
We need to know
long before they're
in our perimeter.
We need to know exactly
how many there are.
Tonight they expected
three, there were four.
A fourth person came
into the very center
of Deadwood and was
not even detected.
Derek Price: She's the
stealthiest one out here.
She's a natural
born killer.
You know just from talking
to my employees and
I know that they know
what I'm doing and
some of 'em openly
can't hide the
fact they think
I've completely
lost my mind, but
you know what?
If it's the end
of the world,
you need to knock on
somebody else's door
'cause mine's
going to be shut.
I didn't spend all my
money, all my time,
sacrificing so much to
just open my door to
somebody that laughed
at me the whole
time I was doing it.
Nah, it doesn't
work that way.
Narrator: Derek,
the experts at
Practical Preppers
commend you for
turning your
amusement park
into a profit-generating
fortress that can sustain
you after a disaster.
Daniel Price: Respect.
Derek Price: Thank
you, absolutely.
Narrator: However, you
currently do not have
adequate stored water
to sustain your family.
Derek Price: I didn't
feel the need to
waste my storage
space storing water,
when I can easily
filter water.
Narrator: To determine how
long you could initially
survive a catastrophe,
Practical Preppers has
scored your preps in five
categories of 20 points
each for a total
possible score of 100.
Food: 14 out
of 20 points.
Water: 10 out
Shelter: 17 out
of 20 points.
Security: 13 out
The unique space you've
created with Deadwood
gives you an additional
14 X-factor points.
Overall, you get
a 68 out of 100.
You have 12 months
initial survival time.
Derek Price:
I'm gonna agree.
The first year would
probably be the
easiest as far as food.
But, uh, I plan
on being around
a lot longer
than one year.
Daniel Price: Absolutely.
Derek Price: Since the
film crew was here we've
begun Phase Two of our
construction on the
fortress there, which
includes our kitchen
complex and self-contained
water supply.
Ira Price: It took
less than two hours
to put this pump in.
We have all the
water we need.
Ah, yes.
Narrator: Roughly every
11 years the sun enters
a period of
maximum activity.
The next solar peak
is expected in 2013.
While estimates on the
odds of a monster solar
storm occurring in the
next decade range from
six to 12 percent,
experts are looking
into additional measures
to protect the grid,
and the majority of
solar flares pose no
threat to America's
power infrastructure.