it's much like opening a can of soda
or popping the cork off of a champagne bottle
The removal of so much pressure
makes the rock melt into liquid magma
And the Hot Spot is transporting heat directly from the interior of the earth to the surface
which also creates melting
So this combination of decompression of existing rock beneath the surface
and the direct transport of heat from the center of the earth created huge amounts of magma
This incredible meeting of the Mid-Atlantic Ridge and Hot Spot
began to build the island beneath the waves
pushing it upwards and giving birth to Iceland
Scientists have dated the island's emergence to 20 million years ago
but could only imagine what this might have looked like
But on November 14th, 1963, off the south coast of Iceland
The world watched an action-replay of Iceland's spectacular birth
A column of rock and ash blasted out of the ocean
18.000 feet (5.400 m) into the sky
So high it could be seen 70 miles (110 Km) away in Iceland's capital city, Reykjavík
A new island was forming, right in front of the world's eyes
Scientists called it Surtsey after the Norse god of fire: Surtr
Located 20 miles (32 Km) off the mainland,
the small island of Surtsey is now a magnet for geologists
It offers a wealth of forensic evidence for Dr. La Femina,
who is investigating how Iceland first formed
It'a amazing to see Surtsey for the first time
I've seen pictures, I've seen aerial photographs
but actually be here and get a chance to
to go out and see it up close and actually look at the geology
it's just inspiring
This type of eruption that formed Surtsey has now been named after Surtsey
We call them "Surtseyan Eruptions",
and they're very, very explosive
The interaction of hot magma or lava with the ocean
causes these very steam-rich and highly explosive eruptions
of ash and water
When scientists first stepped foot into the island in the summer of '64
they found it hard to believe that this was an island whose age
was measured in MONTHS, not millenia
In about 9,5 months this whole volcanic cone built up
In addition, lava flows came out of the volcanic center here
and we seen those as nice black cliffs in front of us
Now geologists had an insight into how early Iceland might have formed
In only 20 million years, Iceland grew from a tiny island into a 40.000 square mile (104.000 Km2) landmass,
as big as the state of Kentucky
The forces that powered Iceland's volcanoes
have been revealed
Cracks along Hekla volcano unleashed gigantic fissure eruptions
and rare chemicals in the rock proved
that these eruptions were fuelled by two separated forces:
Mid-Atlantic Ridge and the Hot Spot
Iceland grew to become the world's largest volcanic island
But volcanism alone doesn't explain how the land of Iceland was formed
The investigation will honour another equally dramatic force
that sculpted the distinctive shape of the Iceland we know today
A force which would challenge the might of Iceland's volcanoes
If Iceland was formed by fire alone,
it should look like other volcanic islands such as Hawaii or Tahiti
But something else was at work here to transform this island
into the distinctive shape it is today
Its shape is another clue to Iceland's formation
An extraordinary force indented Iceland's Northern coastline
burrowing deep fjords which extended far inland
But, what colossal force could cause such a dramatic change to Iceland's volcanic landscape?
There's an obvious suspect that is found scattered across the island:
Ice
As its name suggests, Iceland has a long history of being covered in ice, like this
Today it covers 10% of the island
all year round
And in the middle of the country lies Europe's biggest ice cap:
The mighty Vatnajökull
Over 3000 square miles (7.800 Km2) in size
Vatnajökull is so large it even has its own climatic conditions
Up to two thirds of a mile (1 Km) thick,
it squashes the land like a giant slab of rock
and at its edges great tongues of ice
flow out through deep valleys
Glacier expert Dr. Mattew Roberts
is investigating how ice can gauge out solid rock
and discover the role it is playing in Iceland's past
This is a GPS receiver, just like in car satellite navigation
it's used here to measure glacier movement
this will be left on the ice surface for a few days
and I'll come back and analyse the data
to discover just how far the glacier has moved
Dr. Roberts data reveals that this whole glacier is sliding forward
at an astounding rate of 2 feet (0,6 m) ... per day!
This is an amazing ever changing environement: The ice around me is like
an icy sea that has been frozen in place
As the ice flows out to the confines of the valley
it expands, it spreads to occupy a greater area
Now as it expands, crevasses form
In large depressions, just like the one here,
(here's a smaller crevasse that is formed)
ocasionally when these crevasses open, as it begin to open,
sounds can be heard
Also, the glacier ocasionally makes a groaning sound
it's all signs that the glacier is alive and moving forward
very slowly
Vatnajökull is one of the largest ice caps in the northern hemisphere
flowing down the valleys, the great mass of ice
bears down with the weight of 100 tons per square foot (975 tons/m2)
Dr. Roberts believes this moving giant is a force
capable of eroding solid rock,
and he has found crucial evidence to prove it
This is an excellent example of the power of glacial erosion
This boulder would have been trapped beneath the base of the ice
and, as the ice flowed over the surface of it,
it would have progressively eroded the surface of the boulder
to produce these very distinctive marks, called striations, in its surface
We can even tell the direction in wich the ice was flowing
If I take a rock, I can illustrate this
Imagine this is the base of the ice,
the material trapped inside the ice
being dragged across as the glacier moved
to produce this very distinctive marks in the surface
This is just like sandpaper over wood,
the same erosive effect
The erosive process that's happening on this boulder
is the same process that's happening on a much larger scale
along the surface of these valleys
The glacier is responsible for literally carving the landscape,
producing very distinctive throughs and basins
which were formerly infilled with solid rock
This really testifies the erosive power of a glacier
The ancient fjords on the north coast
are the same deep-basin shape
Which means they must once have been filled with ice
Scientists now know that around 1,5 million years ago
changes in the earth's orbit and the tilt of its axis
began to cool the planet
An enormous ice sheet descended from the north
and shrouded Iceland in a cloak of ice
As the ice advanced and retreated,
it carved out deep fjords
and indented Iceland's northern coastline
Ice was a formidable force in Iceland
and many volcanoes laid at tomb beneath it
Fire and ice were now locked in a titanic battle of supremacy
When the giant ice sheets that carved the fjords
put out the fires that created Iceland
The first clue lies in this ancient valley, 5 miles (8 Km) west of the glacier
The valley floor is strewed with hundreds of giant boulders
but it's how they got here that interests Dr. Roberts
These boulders provide a lot of insight into how this landscape was formed
The boulders clusted together and, interestingly,
this boulders are rounded, which shows they've been rolling
And the boulders have been brought together by some dynamical force
We can also see smaller boulders trapped in the center
And it's quite clear that flowing water is the cause of this
But this would haven't been water in the stream that we see in the background
this would have been water produced by a much larger, faster flow
that would have inundated this entire valley
Dr. Roberts has an extraordinay theory about what happened here:
In ancient times, a cataclysmic flood 100 feet (30 m) high cut through this valley
It was so powerful that it rolled this giant boulders like pebbles in a stream
before dumping them on the landscape
But what could create such a colossal flow of water?
Dr. Roberts suspects the flood came from the mighty Vatnajökull glacier
and he's hunting for clues
With such a huge area to cover, Dr. Roberts takes to the air
His investigation leads him to a crucial peace of evidence:
This strange bowl-like depression on the surface of the ice
This is an amazing location. This giant depression in the ice has been formed
as a pocket of water drained from beneath the base of the ice cap
The beautiful concentric crevasses that you see on the ice surface were formed
as the ice slowly crept into the hole of this pit created as the waters drained the way
Beneath the ice, a dynamic process is happening
Hot magma and steam are melting the glacier from underneath
The meltwater collects in a huge ice basin at the top of the volcano
The basin slowly fills. But as it does, the surrounding ice becomes unstable,
cracks up here, in the ice basin. And as the hot water drains away,
it forms a tunnel which channels the water to the edge of the glacier
This would suggest that volcanic eruptions still happen even under the enormous weight of ice
Is this process the key to explaining the ancient cataclysmic flood?
To answer this, we must go to one of Iceland's largest volcanoes:
Grímsvötn
Lying entombed beneath the ice in the heart of Vatnajökull
This massive volcano violently erupts every 10 years
Here fire and ice spectacularly collide, with Iceland's volcanoes emerging victorious
Ice cannot supress the invincible power of Iceland's volcanoes
which have now found a new way to vent their anger
During a huge eruption like this, Grímsvötn can melt enough ice
to fill America's largest man-made reservoir: Lake Mead
But this vast volume of water cannot be held back by the ice for long
and leads inevitabily to a massive glacial flood
Such a force of nature struck Iceland in 1996 with devastating consequences,
the floodwater taking out everyting in its path
Bridges were torn down and swept away
and the highway was submerged under water
The flood itself reached a peak discharge of over 1,8 million cubic feet per second (50.000 m3/s),
that's a remarkable discharge, prevalent to the summertime discharge of the river Amazon
Imagine that sort of condition over a relatively small area
The sheer force of the water carried icebergs the size of 4 storey buildings
It's floods like these that can change the landscape in a matter of days
The erosive power of the flowing water can result in tremendous amounts of rock
being eroded, literally being fractured away by the high water pressure that is being created
so, literally a landscape can form before your eyes during a very severe glacial flood
The story of Iceland's bizarre landscape is taking shape
Striations on rock prove that ice is a formidable force
that carved out Iceland's unique coastline
Boulders strewn in an empty valley
reveal cataclysmic floods of the past
And depressions in the ice confirm that Iceland's volcanoes could not be supressed
But 12.000 years ago the great ice sheets retreated
and Iceland was liberated from their wintery grip,
Now, the effects of Iceland's volcanoes would be felt on a global scale
For thusands of years Iceland's volcanoes were locked in a titanic battle with ice
But then, 12.000 years ago, the giant ice sheets finally retreated
This would open a new chapter in Iceland's volcanic history,
as they were now free to wreak havoc
But, what effect would this have on Iceland and its surroundings?
One of the most dramatic effects can be found in the south-central region of the island
This alien landscape is known as Laki
A road of strange craters and solidified lava flows
that have bubbled up from a huge tear in the earth
A massive fissure eruption, it stretches for an astounding 16 miles (25 Km) across the landscape
Volcanologist Dr. Thor Thordarson is investigating Laki,
the site of one of the greatest eruptions in recent history,
one which would have devastating effects worldwide
The Laki fissures, which extend from here in the southwest,
continue here through the landscape as roll cones, up in through Mount Laki
which was split into 2 during the eruption
and continue futher to the northeast all the way to the margins of the glaciers here
Eyewitness accounts accurately date the eruption to 1783
This was one of the most disastrous years in Icelandic history
Fallout from the eruption caused harvests all over the island to fail
75% of the livestock died, plunging Iceland into a great famine which killed 10.000 people
But mysteriously, at the same time the rest of the northern hemisphere
reported freakishly cold weather
Averaging 2,3 ºF (1,28ºC) below normal, the northern hemisphere froze over
The North Sea along the coast of Holland froze,
so people skated between villages along the coast
There was on Mississippi down by New Orleans in that winter
For many years it was thought the Laki eruption and this climatic events were unrelated,
but advances in geology found it wasn't just a bizarre coincidence
Comparing eyewitness accounts with the geological remains
Dr. Thordarson has reconstructed what happened
He discovered that the eruption started with a bang on the morning of June 8, 1783
It sent rocks flying high into the air
and ripped the earth open along a 1 mile (1,6 Km) tear
But this was just the beginning
3 days later, a second eruption ripped open, then a 3rd, 4th, 5th...
In total, the earth unzipped along 10 vast tears in the crust
erupting lava continuously for over 8 months
The mammoth amounts of lava that poured out of the ground here
would have buried Manhattah to a depth of 830 feet (250 m)
But how an eruption on this small, remote island could cause climatic chaos
thousands of miles away, remained a mystery
The evidence that would link Laki with this worldwide catastrophe
was locked inside these boulders
The story is in the rocks. This rock here is part of
the material, the magma that came out during the eruption
These holes are cold bubbles,
and they form as the magma raises from deep within the ground and approaches the surface
and it really starts to boil!
The gas, which is dissolved in the magma at depth, goes into the bubbles
then it escapes into the atmosphere
When this bubble rock erupted onto the surface
it would have poured gas out into the Icelandic atmosphere
Could this gas have caused climatic chaos across the globe?
The identity of this gas can be found in the microscopic structure of the rock
If you look closely at this rock, you can see a lot of white specks
these little white specks are the crystals who grow in the magma at depth
Sometimes this crystals, as they're growing, they would encapsulate
pristine magma and bring it up to the surface
Like time capsules, the white crystals contained untouched magma from deep in the earth
locked away since 1783
Dr. Thordarson has analysed this magma and found it to contain poisonous Sulphur Dioxide
And because there was so much lava here, it would have released enormous amounts
A staggering 100 million tons of Sulphur Dioxide gas was pumped into the atmosphere
But how could gases released from Laki cause bitterly cold weather across the globe?
The answer laid in accounts of a thick, red fog reported over Iceland in June 1783
Within a few weeks it had been blown over London and Paris
By July, it had dispersed across the entire northern hemisphere
Scientists now know that the red fog was caused by the Sulphur Dioxide which rose high into the air
Mixing with water, it created a Sulphuric Acid haze
The haze blocked out the sun, and it sent temperatures plummeting
As a result, the northern hemisphere endured 3 bitterly cold winters
which brought spring floods, famine and widespread poverty to Europe
Some historians have long believed that these climatic conditions
triggered social and political unrest, which led to the French Revolution in 1789
But scientists now suspect Laki had ramifications even further afield
The cold temperatures in the north changed air currents in the south
causing dramatic climate changes
India was hit by a terrible drought
People say that more than half a million people died from the drought in India
Also, this change in atmospheric circulation caused a very cold summer in Japan
It was cold and wet
The rice harvest failed,
and the result was the greatest famine in japanese history
It is estimated that Laki killed over 2 million people worldwide,
and was one of the most devastating volcanic eruptions in the history of mankind
The evidence has proven that Iceland's recent volcanic history
has had a devastating effect on the island and the rest of the world
Enormous lava fields reveal that Laki was a gigantic eruption
Bubbles in the rock indicate that huge volumes of gas were released from Laki
The white crystals reveal that this gas was poisonous Sulphur Dioxide,
evidence that Iceland's volcanoes caused climatic mayhem across the globe
But eruptions like Laki may not be confined to the past
Some believe that the balance between fire and ice is shifting,
and has the potential to propel Iceland into another hell on earth
The evidence is mounting, that Iceland has the potential to be the most lethal island on the planet
A fearsome volcanic force lies beneath it, creating powerful volcanoes
capable of generating gigantic lava flows and altering global climates
Yet many of Iceland's volcanoes are covered in glaciers,
fire and ice are held in a delicate balance
Scientists fear if this balance were tipped the volcanoes favour,
Iceland could become even deadlier
If the remaining ice were to melt,
what effect would it have on the activity of Iceland's volcanoes?
The first clue in the investigation lies in these innocuous-looking piles of rock and rubble
They're found all over Iceland,
and yet this rocks don't come from a volcano
They're Morraines:
The geological term for rock piles deposited at the mouth of a glacier
These deposits are evidence that the glaciers are shrinking
Year by year, the glacier has melted and retreated back up the valley,
leaving a Morraine like this behind
Dr. Roberts has studied the Vatnajökull glacier for the last ten years
and has noticed this dramatic trend
The glacier is retreating at a remarkable rate since I've been visiting the area
I've seen tremendous changes. The ice has retreated annually at a rate of about
200 feet (61 m) per year. This lake over here used to be filled with ice
I've seen the ice progressively melt, this morraine has formed,
this whole valley has become almost bare
Maybe in the next 20 years this whole glacier will disappear and a lake will form in that valley
Iceland's glaciers are melting at an unprecedented rate
With 5% of Iceland's ice caps melting in the last 40 years,
the question that scientists are keen to understand
is: What effect this rapid melting will have on the volcanoes that lie beneath?
The only other time that glaciers have melted this quickly
is when Iceland came out of the last Ice Age
But what can past events tell us about the future?
Geologist professor Bill McGuire is investigating how volcanic activity changed
at the end of the last Ice Age
And he's unearthed some surprising results
Around about 11 or 12 thousand years ago you started to see quite rapid melting of glaciers
in Iceland and elsewhere
And that triggered a recognisable increase of volcanic activity,
because you were removing this large mass of ice very, very quickly
The rapid melting of ice kick-starts volcanic eruptions beneath
Volcanic eruptions are triggered by the gas in the magma,
which expands to form bubbles and the bubbles drive the eruption
It's rather like taking the cork out of a bottle of champagne
Now, if you have a very heavy weight on top of a volcano,
if it's a heavy mass of water or ice,
that can help supress eruptive activity
But when ice melts quickly, this downward pressure is suddenly released
and that's when the trouble starts
As the ice melts, so the pressure on the magma underneath is reduced,
the gas in the magma can form bubbles, they can coalesce and they can eventually
drive the magma upwards towards the surface and trigger
other explosive eruptions or effusions of lava that are spared out at a huge distances
Iceland's glaciers are melting rapidly
This has led scientists to believe that a devastating eruption on the scale of Laki
could happen again
The question is WHEN? These are things that we have to think about
and try to prepare ourselves to deal with if they happen in our lifetime
Is it possible that we can get another eruption like this in Iceland?
Definetely
The investigation has revealed how the vast and voilent island of Iceland was formed
Cracks in the Thingvellir plane and traces of chemicals in the rocks
revealed how the Mid-Atlantic Ridge and Hot Spot joined forces to create a collossal volcanic force
Massive fissure eruptions ripped the land open
Hemorrhaging millions of tons of lava, Iceland rapidly formed
Deep northern fjords were evidence that a giant ice sheet eroded the land
and entombed the volcanoes, locking fire and ice in a titanic battle
Boulders strewn in an ancient valley reveal how fire emerged victorious
unleashing cataclysmic floods
And specks of Sulphur in the rocks showed how Iceland's volcanoes
have the potential to cause global destruction
Now, glaciers melting above some of the world's most deadly volcanoes
are increasing the threat of future eruptions
Over the last 20 million years, Iceland's almighty volcanic force
has created a vast, alien landscape
Volatile and unpredictable, it may one day unleash a massive eruption
which could devastate both Iceland and a wider world beyond
English captions and subtitles by Marc Gelizo     --for a non-profit use--