First up today, we`re looking at the increased
fighting between the Israelis and Palestinians.
Representatives from other countries are trying
to work out a cease-fire to stop the violence,
but until that happens, millions of people
from both sides are in harm`s ways. The attacks
are mostly made up of two things -- that`s
Israeli air strikes and Palestinian rockets.
And those rockets, like the ones that are
being launched right here, those are fired
at Israel from Gaza. That`s a Palestinian-controlled
territory. Israel says the air strikes it
launched at Gaza are aimed at terrorist targets,
including leaders of Hamas. That`s an organization
that runs the Palestinian government in Gaza,
and it`s been labeled as a terrorist group
by the U.S. government.
The U.S. and some European nations say Hamas
should get most of the blame for the current
crisis, but most Arab and Muslim nations,
though, have accused Israel of being the aggressor,
or the one who attacked first. Tom Foreman
breaks down some of the comparisons between
the two sides in this conflict.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
TOM FOREMAN, CNN CORRESPONDENT: Let`s look
at how the battlefield is shaping up over
in the Middle East. Here is Israel alongside
the Mediterranean. It`s about the size of
New Jersey. 7.5 million people, 75 percent
Jewish. The economy is good, unemployment
below 7 percent. Gaza by comparison geographically
very small, only about twice as big as Washington,
D.C., predominately Palestinian. The economy
there is quite bad and unemployment is very
high.
Globalfirepower.com has called Israel the
tenth most powerful military in the world,
so let`s break that down and see why. They
have compulsory military service, that means
every young person must go into the military
for a while. 176,000 active troops are available
and they have about half a million that they
can call up from the reserves very quickly.
Ground forces, also impressive. Some 3,000
tanks. If you count all the artillery pieces
and mortars, things like that, you get up
to about 12,000 units that can operate on
the ground. And of course, their air force
is formidable. About 800 aircraft out there,
including some 200 helicopters. This is largely
what they`ve used to have these strikes within
Gaza.
Now, if you look at Hamas, their forces are
much smaller in terms of their official forces,
certainly, if you look at people who are really
in uniform, soldiers, police, whatever you
want to call it -- about 12,500 -- and of
course they have nothing like the weapons
that the Israelis have. However, Palestinian
militants do have lots and lots of rockets,
and I want to bring in a model of one of them
here. This is a Kassam 2, you probably heard
this a good bit. These rockets are popular
because they are cheap, they`re easy to make
out of steel tubes. They only weigh 70 to
100 pounds, and they are fueled essentially
by commercial-grade fertilizer, and they can
pack quite a punch. They`re not very accurate,
but if you fire enough of them, they don`t
have to be accurate.
If you go beyond this to some of their more
robust and better targeted rockets and missiles,
then you also start talking about range. In
this conflict so far, we have reports of weapons
fired from Gaza traveling as much as 50 miles
to hit Jerusalem and Tel Aviv. In fact, Israeli
officials now believe as much as a fifth of
population of Israel is subject to these rocket
attacks. That`s something they say they simply
will not tolerate anymore, and that`s why
we keep hearing all this talk and speculation
about a possible ground invasion of Gaza.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Just the facts. Myanmar
is a country in Southeast Asia. It used to
be known as Burma. The nation got its independence
from Great Britain in 1948. Starting in 1962,
Myanmar was ruled by a military junta, a small
group that held all the power. Nearly 50 years
later, in 2011, Myanmar established a civilian
government.
LANCE: President Obama says the shift in Myanmar
toward a democratic government is a good step.
He also says the country has a long way to
go, and he`s planning to deliver that message
in person this week when he becomes the first
U.S. president to visit the nation. Myanmar
is one of three countries that the president
is visiting on a trip to Southeast Asia. He
will end up in Cambodia for the East Asia
summit, but his first stop was in Thailand.
President Obama took part in an official welcoming
ceremony with the country`s prime minister.
Later in the day, he was the guest at an official
dinner. The U.S. and Thailand have a relationship
that goes back nearly 200 years. The president
brought that up during his visit, calling
Thailand America`s oldest friend in Asia.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: See if you can ID me.
I am a microscopic agent that can cause infections.
I was first identified in the late 1800s.
I can spread in animals or plants, but only
inside their living cells. My name comes from
a Latin word that means slime or poison. I`m
a virus, and different types of me cause colds
and the flu.
LANCE: And those viruses are pretty common
around this time of year, and that`s because
from October through May, it`s cold and flu
season. So instead of just running through
some facts and advice, we thought that we`d
have a little bit of fun with this. So get
ready to shout out some answers to our flu
and cold quiz.
First, true or false? You get colds from being
cold. False. We covered this one in the ID
me. Colds and flu are caused by viruses. They
pop up more during the winter because people
stay inside more, and so that means germs
spread more easily.
Next, true or false? You need to come in direct
contact with someone to catch the flu from
them. That one is false too. You can be six
to 10 feet away from someone who`s sick and
still catch their cold or flu.
True of false? One of the best ways to avoid
getting sick is to wash your hands regularly.
That one is totally true. Experts say washing
with soap and water will keep germs from spreading.
True or false? If you get a flu shot, you
are guaranteed not to catch the flu that year.
Oh, that one is false. Flu shots are not 100
percent effective, but getting one will significantly
cut down your chances of getting sick, and
experts say if you do get sick, the symptoms
probably won`t be as bad.
OK, and the last one, true of false? If you
catch the flu, the best treatment is to get
plenty of rest. That one is true. Doctors
may recommend medication sometimes, but for
the most part, the best way to treat the flu
is with lots of rest and lots of fluids.
S if you go out to the store this weekend
and you see a Twinkie on the shelves, you
might want to remember what it looks like,
because there is a chance you won`t see it
again any time soon. The company that makes
them, and that`s Hostess, is shutting down.
It announced the decision last Friday. Closing
up shop means more than 18,000 employees will
lose their jobs. A lot of those bakers have
been on strike. They were protesting against
a new contract that would cut their pay and
benefits. Hostess says it cannot afford to
stay open through the extended strike.
With the company closing, the future of the
food it makes is up in the air. Alison Kosik
looks at one of those items, evolved from
a snack into a part of American culture.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
ALISON KOSIK, CNN CORRESPONDENT: Following
a nasty labor dispute and almost a year in
bankruptcy, Hostess Brands is closing its
33 bakeries, more than 500 distribution centers,
and selling off its assets, putting the future
of the 82-year-old Twinkie in question. It`s
been a long road for the cream-filled pastry,
now part of the American lexicon.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: It`s Twinkie the kid!
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Wow!
KOSIK: The Twinkie was born in 1930 in Illinois.
Inventor James Dewar was looking for a way
to use the Continental Baking Company`s seasonal
strawberry shortcake pans year round. He came
up with a yellow sponge cake filled with banana
cream, but during World War II, banana rationing
forced the company to change to vanilla cream
filling. The replacement was so popular, it
never changed back. Over the years, the Twinkie
became a part of American popular culture.
In the 1950s the Howdy Doody show host Buffalo
Bob gave it an endorsement.
BUFFALO BOB: Presto, and what do we have?
Hostess Twinkies.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Obsession.
KOSIK: In the 1990s there was a presidential
endorsement as President Bill Clinton included
a Twinkie in a millennium time capsule. And
in the Youtube age, we`ve seen the Twinkie
put to the test for shelf life, toughness
and microwave ability.
KOSIK: But now the Twinkie needs someone to
come to its rescue or we`ll have to say good-bye
to the Twinkie for good.
Alison Kosik, CNN, New York.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
LANCE: Before we go, we`re going to look at
a really unique bike, and this thing is so
cool. So you`ve seen a two-wheeler, probably
had a three- wheeler when you were growing
up, but this Georgia teenager came up with
a 2 by 4 wheeler. It`s a bike built entirely
out of wood, and it might not be good for
all cyclists, but it could appeal to a splinter
group. They might really pine for it. This
is the kind of thing you have to cedar to
believe, but even then you might want to take
it out for a spin. But we`re guessing that
if you could, you would. So the big question,
why did he pick this material for his bike?
And the answer, he was board. Sometimes the
puns just really write themselves here, you
guys.
But we`ll be back with more of them tomorrow
too, so for CNN STUDENT NEWS, I`m Natisha
Lance. Have a good one.