fucking town.
Let's hook it up, get
in the ring, bear.
Bear versus cobra, let's
get it fucking on.
Hi, I'm Steve Ludwin, I'm here
with Vice to respond to all
the video comments to the
documentary "Getting High with
Snake Venom." First off, I'd
like to say it's been really
exciting, and the comments have
been amazing and quite
cathartic for me to read.
Some are super intelligent and
some are pretty super dumb.
But, hey, I understand super
dumb, so we're going to answer
all the questions,
hopefully, today.
Here's one right here.
It says, "How the fuck are you
still alive?" If I ever had
another accident with snake
venom and I needed to go to
the hospital, I wouldn't.
And I've been in situations
already where normal people
would have gone to
the hospital.
I induced a heart attack, I've
had some serious breathing
problems, like paralysis
on my lungs.
And I actually thought to
myself, don't go and waste
hospital time.
You've done this to yourself.
Don't be a pussy, ride it out.
Here's another one.
"FUUUUUUUCK!
Just look at him
shaking." And I was.
My hands, as I was milking
the snakes--
which are really dangerous
snakes.
I definitely didn't want to
get bit live on camera.
It was 9 o'clock in the
morning, there was an
ambulance outside, and there
were two camera crew guys.
The paramedics had to be there
for health and safety.
But yes, I was shaking.
I was shaking like fuck.
But I don't shake.
Whoo, I am shaking there.
"I can't help relate the process
to a drug addiction.
The glorification of injecting,
the fear and
excitement at the same time,
all very reminiscent of a
heroin addict." There's a lot
of people saying that I'm
addicted to venom,
I'm an addict.
That's not true.
There's no way.
It's not like a drug.
I don't feel like, hey,
I need some venom.
Here's an interesting
question.
"Cool stuff.
He's definitely some kind
of freak super-human!
Is there some type of
Snake-Man super
hero or action figure?
If not, some comic illustrator
should make him into a
superhero."
Well, I'd total be
up for that.
So Marvel, get in touch.
The one strange thing that I
have noticed, I get these
incredible cravings, usually
once a day now, for these.
And I just sort of started
thinking to myself, well, the
snakes are eating these
mice, so why can't I?
It's good, it's protein
and stuff.
And I find that I can knock
back quite a few mice.
They're good.
They're really good.
They're healthy.
They were sort of
humanely killed.
I think mice are the future.
They taste like mice.
"I bet his sperm
tastes weird."
I don't know how
to answer that.
I don't think it tastes
weird at all.
I think it tastes like
pineapple juice.
Here's one from grambo519.
"Ever suck dick for
snake venom?" No.
I mean, yes.
Is that a trick question?
That's a trick question,
right?
Here's one from CatDonuts1234.
CatDonuts, cool.
"Awesome!
He's 46?
He looks 28."
People don't believe me.
I am 46 years old.
I was born in 1966.
What a year.
I don't know, people ask, are
there anti-aging properties to
snake venom?
And the answer is yes.
There has been an anti-aging
cream that's been on the
market for the last six, seven
years that celebrities are
using that contains
snake venom in it.
It's a big seller.
It's proven to work.
So, does snake venom have
anti-aging properties?
Apparently so.
"Isn't this also sort
of animal abuse?"
No, this isn't animal
abuse at all.
I'd like to defend that.
None of the snakes are hurt.
They're all kept in a
naturalistic way.
You saw a lot them were in
those little containers--
that was just to transport
them into the
room where I was milking.
All the animals are
well looked after.
It is not animal abuse.
Here's a question from Mat397.
"Hey, Steve, is there a main
goal you would like to achieve
with doing snake venom
injections?"
I would like to take it further
and research it properly--
like I said in the
documentary--
with a forward-thinking company,
open-minded company,
and see if there is any
medicinal value.
That's what I'd like
to achieve.
"Could you make antivenom
with his blood?"
I think that's an interesting
question.
That's what I would
like to research.
I'd like to see if I have
reached a level of immunity to
the snake venom in my blood
that can be used to help
somebody else.
We know that that's possible
because Bill Haast has
already done it.
But I would like to see at what
level my blood could be
used to make an antivenom, or
to fight anything off, for
that matter.
"Steve, have you experimented
with any venom from animals
other than snakes?"
No, I haven't yet.
But I think it is really amazing
that the possibilities
of doing so in the future.
There are millions
of undiscovered
compounds in all venoms.
It's not just snake venom.
There's sea anemones, there's
cone shells, there's
everything.
All the venomous animals on
the planet, I think their
venom should be studied.
What can kill you can
also save you.
One of the really alarming
things about this
documentary--
and I suppose I kind of knew
that it was going to happen--
was the alarming amount of
people that were saying, this
is cool, I'm going
to try this.
I definitely, definitely don't
want anyone to try it.
I don't think you should.
Like I said, I have over 25
years of experience working
with venomous snakes.
People are asking, what
snakes do you use?
This isn't a cooking show.
There's no recipe here, OK?
So don't fuck up, because
you will be underground.
And I don't want it to
be someone who was
influenced by me.
All right, guys.
Thanks a lot.
Thanks a lot for watching,
thanks a lot for sending in
all your questions.
This has been Steve
Ludwin and Vice.
And what else can I say?
One last thing--
don't be a dickhammer.