Um, why wasn't I invited?
For the same reason we didn't
invite Bernie Madoff,
because we knew
you were unavailable.
Listen, man,
you just got married.
The other guys have been married
for years,
and they still have to lie
about where they're going.
Oh, yeah?
Well, I can go if I want to,
and I don't have to lie
about it.
So you're going to tell
Suzanne
that you're gonna spend six
hours on a Sunday in a bar,
drinking beer and watching
baseball with a bunch of dudes?
$50 says that's exactly
what I'm gonna say.
Exactly?
Exactly-exactly.
Come on, mom.
That isn't fair.
That's like t.I.
Going to jail
for killing Patrick Swayze.
Lindsey, that makes no sense.
Exactly.
What's going on?
Oh, well, the kids are asking
me about their allowance,
but they haven't done any work
around the house all week.
Now, I pay you guys an allowance
to be nice;
I'm not gonna pay y'all
just to live here anymore.
Come on,
your mother is right.
You kids know an allowance
is payment for work,
just like a job.
If you don't do your job,
you don't get paid.
Thank you, Nick.
We promise to do more work
this week.
Yeah, we promise.
And I promise to pay you
when you do the work.
What about this week?
You should've thought about
this week last week.
If you don't start thinking
about next week this week,
you're going to have
the same problem next week
that you're having this week,
when you could've solved it
last week.
So we're not gonna get
our money from last week
until next week?
What about this week?
There is no "this week."
Now, I don't understand
what you're worried about.
You have everything you need.
But it's summer.
We need disposable income.
Well, by being lazy, you threw
away last week's allowance.
So I suggest,
unless you want to dispose
of this week's allowance,
you get to work.
Got it?
Got it.
Oh, hello, Martin.
Hi, Suzanne.
What are you guys
up to today?
Hmm.
What are we up to, Nick?
Today I am going to
a sports bar, on a Sunday,
for six hours,
to drink beer and watch baseball
with a bunch of dudes.
Great.
Good for you.
See?
A real man doesn't have to lie
to his wife.
Now pay up.
Next week.
♪ Are we there yet? ♪
The Booty
S01x06 Original Air Date on June 16, 2010
♪ tell me, tell me, tell me ♪
♪ tell me,
are we there yet? ♪
-- sync, corrected by elderman --
-- for www.addic7ed.Com --
hi, there.
Hi, there.
Welcome to Booty.
Hello.
Man, I thought we were going
to a regular sports bar.
You didn't tell me
we were going to Booty.
What's wrong with Booty?
It's a pirate-themed sports bar,
hence the name "booty,"
like treasure.
Hmm, hi, guys.
That's treasure.
Man, I gotta get out of here.
How am I gonna explain this
to Suzanne?
Oh, aren't you the real man
who doesn't have to lie
to his wife?
We're doing exactly what you
said we were gonna do:
We're at the bar, drinking beer,
watching the game.
Yeah, but she's gonna
want to know
why I had to watch the game
here.
Because Booty has
such amazing...
Wings.
Ah, there are the guys.
Aha.
Ahoy, mateys.
Arrr.
Ah, these wings
are disgusting.
What's the score of the game?
Uh, 36 to 24
to 40.
Wow, this is
a high-scoring game.
So what did you tell Suzanne
to get out of the house?
I told her I was coming
to watch the game.
Huh, I didn't.
I told my wife I was going
to the grocery store.
And on my way home, I'll be sure
to stop at the grocery store.
Yeah, I told my wife
I was going to a strip club,
but instead I came here.
What is wrong with you, man?
I got an idea.
Let's tell treasure
that it's Nick's birthday,
and we'll get them to give him
one of their special
birthday celebrations.
Ugh.
Love that.
What special
birthday celebration?
Come on, man.
You never had
a Booty birthday?
No, and I don't want
a Booty birthday.
I didn't know it was
your birthday, Nick.
How old are you?
Dude, I'm not...
Oh, treasure.
This scallywag be having
a birthday.
Hey.
Someone has a birthday?
Ladies, come on over here.
We got a birthday.
Happy Birthday.
Are you ready?
No, I'm not.
It's not my birthday.
♪ Chicken wings,
birthday cake ♪
♪ let me see
that Booty shake ♪
♪ chicken wings,
birthday cake ♪
♪ let me see that Booty shake ♪
♪ chicken wings,
birthday cake ♪
♪ let me see
that Booty shake ♪
♪ on your birthday,
on your birthday ♪
♪ on your birthday ♪
♪ drop it, drop it,
drop it, drop it ♪
okay, mom.
We finished all our chores.
I cleaned up my room,
and I took all the clothes
out of my hamper.
Yup, and I made my bed
and unclogged the toilet.
Kevin, aren't you the one
who clogged the toilet?
Yeah, it was a good one.
So do we get
our allowances now?
Guys, I'm really proud of you
for doing those things,
but no.
So I unclogged the toilet
for nothing?
No, you unclogged the toilet
'cause that's nasty.
So what exactly do we need
to do to get our allowance?
You need to show
some initiative,
and I'll pay you
for what it's worth.
We are showing initiative.
How?
By trying to convince you
to give us money.
I'm so glad you had a good
time today with your friends.
Where'd you guys go, anyway?
No-hitter?
No, I don't think so.
It was some other place.
Was it the scoreboard?
No, I don't think so.
Well, there's only a few
sports bars.
You guys were downtown,
right?
Yeah, I think so.
You think so?
Were you, or weren't you?
I don't know.
You know, Martin was driving.
I was just out having
a good time.
Nick.
Were you or weren't you
downtown at a sports bar,
watching the baseball game?
I was.
Well...
You weren't at the scoreboard.
You weren't at no-hitter.
So where were you?
Dang, I don't remember
the name of it.
Well, the only other place
that's open on Sundays is Booty,
and I know you weren't at Booty.
Hmm.
Which one was that again?
The one with all the girls
with the big booties
dressed in pirate outfits.
Hmm.
Come to think of it,
yeah, I think
that's where we were.
You spent
six hours drinking,
watching the game
with your friends at Booty?
Baby, you told me to go out
and have a good time.
Not when it's at Booty!
Baby, it's not what you think.
Look, they just have the most
tvs, the cheapest beer,
and the best wings.
You lied to me.
No, I didn't.
Look, baby, I didn't even know
that's where we were going
until we got there.
Okay, so why didn't you tell
me that's where you were
when you got home?
Because it didn't come up.
And when it did, I told you.
So what's the problem?
You really don't know
what the problem is?
No, I don't.
Well, you are about
to find out.
Here's some more orange juice
for you, mom.
Thank you, Lindsey.
Yeah, let me get that
for you, mom.
Thank you, Kevin.
And we also got up
extra early
and washed your car
and swept up the front yard.
So can we have
our allowances now?
No.
What?
How come?
Well, because I noticed
that your beds aren't made,
and, Lindsey, you have clothes
all over the floor,
and, Kevin,
the toilet is backed up again.
Just because you wake up early
and wash my car
and clean the front yard
doesn't mean you get to neglect
your everyday chores.
So I washed your car
for nothing?
You didn't wash my car
for nothing.
Now both of you go upstairs
and clean your rooms.
Hi, Nick.
Hey.
Where's my breakfast?
Why don't you eat at Booty,
since you love their food
so much?
Where's your breakfast?
That's ridiculous.
They don't even
serve breakfast.
Let me ask you something,
Gigi.
What do you do
when you find out
a man's been withholding
information from you?
Well, it depends
on two things:
The kind of information
and how I found out.
Like, this one time I found out
not only was this guy
cheating on me,
but he was lying
about his money.
How'd you find out?
The other woman told me.
He and I had just come back
from Aruba,
and she said he had just
taken her to Aruba.
And I was gonna stay with him,
until I found out where
he was getting his money from.
Where?
From her.
If I'd known that, I would have
gone to Aruba with her,
and we both could have got
a man.
Does that help?
Not really.
Oh.
Is Nick hiding something
from you?
Well, yesterday, he went to
watch baseball for six hours
with his friends at Booty.
Booty?
I love Booty.
You do?
I do.
It's so much fun.
How'd you find out?
I asked him,
and he admitted he went.
You--you asked him a question,
and he could've lied,
but he told you the truth,
and now you're mad at him?
Yes.
I can see that.
♪ Get it, get it, get it,
get it ♪
♪ chicken wings,
birthday cake ♪
♪ do that Booty
birthday shake ♪
We need to talk about Booty.
Suzanne, I still don't know
what the big deal is.
Look, it's just a fun place
where guys go to watch games.
Mm-hmm.
So who won the game?
The, um...
And that's why
it's a big deal.
Oh, so now I got to tell you
about every place I go
to do everything I do?
When you go grocery shopping, I
don't know exactly where you go.
Because the guys bagging
my groceries
aren't walking around
with oily pecs,
in jockstraps,
talking about paper or plastic.
♪ Helicopter,
helicopter, hey ♪
are you done?
Look, Suzanne,
it's not like that.
Okay, you're overreacting.
I told you,
they have the best wings.
All right?
All kinds of people go there.
Families, everybody.
Really?
Really.
Okay, fine.
I believe you.
Thank you.
So tonight you, me and the
kids are going to eat at Booty.
Excuse me?
We're gonna order the wings.
And you can turn your music
back on.
so you sure
you want to do this?
Yep, I really want to taste
those wings.
I can't believe we're really
going to eat there.
Me neither.
This is awesome.
I've always wanted to go there.
For what?
It's food served by pirates.
Yeah,
in Booty shorts.
Well, here we are,
just like you wanted.
Whoa, look at the size
of those jugs.
Kevin, that is no way to talk
about a woman.
He's talking about
the pitchers of beer.
Oh.
Whoa.
Look how big that Booty is.
He's talking about
the treasure chest by the door.
No, I'm not.
This place is tacky.
Are we really
gonna eat here?
Yes, we are.
I'm doing this to prove a point
to your father.
What point?
That he has no taste in food?
Oh, hey, Nick.
How you doing?
How's it going?
Treasure?
I'm Suzanne.
I'm Nick's wife.
Oh, Suzanne.
Beautiful.
I didn't know
you were married, Nick.
That's great.
Wow, and you have your beautiful
kids with you.
Thank you.
Okay, so what can I get you
to order?
We have heard so much
about those wings.
Ah, those wings.
So how about I bring you
some over?
Great.
All right, birthday boy.
I'll be right back.
Birthday boy?
Oh, I almost forgot.
Martin and the guys
thought it'd be funny
if they told the waitresses
it was my birthday.
Oh, and what type
of celebration do they do?
Oh...
You just get some free wings,
and they sing happy birthday.
It's no big deal.
All right, ladies.
Listen up.
We got another birthday.
Booty birthday, come on.
♪ Get it, get it, get it,
get it ♪
♪ chicken wings,
birthday cake ♪
♪ do that Booty
birthday shake ♪
♪ dip, baby, dip,
dip, baby, dip ♪
Kevin, eyes front.
Uh-uh!
Sorry, buddy.
You got yourself
into this one.
What are you talking about?
You're the one that dragged me
down there.
Yeah, but I didn't tell you
to turn it into
a family field trip.
It doesn't matter.
She would've gotten mad
anyway.
Yes, but if
you had told her,
she would've gotten mad
ahead of time,
which is a lot better.
None of this
would have happened
if she hadn't seen that stupid
birthday celebration.
Nick, please tell me she did
not witness a Booty birthday.
She witnessed
a Booty birthday.
Oh, come on, man.
Listen,
you say you want my help,
but then you won't even tell me
everything that happened.
You're like Keyser Soze,
just dolling out little pieces
of information,
hoping I'll figure it out like
I'm the closer or something.
Do I look like Kyra Sedgwick
to you?
You want my advice?
Here it is:
Be Nick.
Okay?
Don't be
some phony-acting Nick
who thinks he can do
whatever he wants,
even though he's married,
because if your wife
is mad at you
and you were with me,
it's only a matter of time
before I start catching heat.
And if I wanted some wife
to be mad at me,
I'd go to Russia
and I'd buy one of my own.
Okay, mom,
we finished everything.
So can we have
our allowances now?
Well, I guess you guys
have earned it.
Yes.
All right, Kevin,
go get my purse, please.
Thank you.
$50.
Okay, here you go.
$5 each.
$5?
That's it?
If would've known we were only
going to get paid $5,
we would have never did
any of this stuff.
Which is exactly why
I didn't tell you
I was giving you $5.
Okay.
I'm gonna go back upstairs,
take all my clothes
out of my hamper,
and throw them back down
on the floor.
I'm gonna go reclog
the toilet.
Freeze.
So just because I don't give in
to your demands,
you're going to go destroy
my house?
Who are you, the Taliban?
I do not negotiate
with terrorists.
So here is the deal:
You're either going to take
the $5,
or you're going to take nothing.
We'll take it.
And you'll be happy about it.
Thank you.
Ya'll better not mess up
my house.
♪ Chicken wings,
birthday cake ♪
♪ do that Booty
birthday shake ♪
♪ dip, baby, dip,
dip, baby, dip ♪
Nick, can we have, like,
20 bucks each?
Like, no.
Didn't your mother give you
your allowance?
Yeah, but it was only
5 bucks.
And a full day at the mall is
gonna cost me at least a 20.
Well, why don't you take
that 5 bucks
and spend a quarter day
at the mall?
Or you can save that 5 bucks,
keep doing work until
you have the money you need.
That's the lesson your mom's
trying to teach you.
We don't want lessons.
We want money.
Do you want to live
to spend it?
Sorry.
What do you need
the money for?
I don't know.
Stuff.
Stuff?
You guys are pulling your hair
out because you want money,
and you don't even know
what you want it for?
We want mad money.
I'm not giving you guys money
just so you can have it.
I'm sorry.
We forgive you.
Now can we have some money?
No.
Do some work.
Fine.
Maybe I'll get a job at Booty.
Suzanne,
what are you afraid of?
That he's gonna leave you
for a girl with a big Booty
and a bucket of wings?
I don't know.
Let me tell you this:
Big Booty is unavoidable.
It's at the park.
It's at the grocery store.
It's even at church.
You can't hide from big Booty.
Big booty--it's everywhere.
I know that Booty
is everywhere.
I don't need him
to pretend it's not.
But if he's gonna go there,
I just want to know about it.
That's all.
Well, have you tried
telling him that?
I mean, come on.
You're good.
Thank you.
Man, I don't know
how you do it.
I wish I was more like you.
Every time you get in trouble,
you just blurt out the truth.
They always say the cover-up
is worse than the crime.
Hey, baby.
Hey.
I just ran into the kids.
Thank you for backing me up.
Well, you're right.
You're teaching them
a valuable lesson.
I'm trying to.
You know you could've just
told me you were at Booty.
I was afraid
you would have gotten mad.
That's right.
I would have.
Then what am I
supposed to do?
You're supposed to get used
to me getting mad at things.
Great.
No, but I would've gotten
over it.
You know, I don't understand why
you even want to go there.
Okay, I understand...
Look, it's not even
that I want to go to Booty.
It's just that I don't like
knowing there are places
I might want to go and can't.
Nick, I don't care
where you go.
I just care
about what you do.
I'll tell you what:
You tell me beforehand,
and you can go to Booty
any time you want--
except your actual birthday.
Why?
What do you think I might do?
End up in the hospital
if I even think you did
something besides eat wings.
I have all the wings I need
right here.
Oh.
I forgot.
I got you something.
You got me something?
Yeah;
I mean, it's for me,
but it's mostly for you.
Oh.
Well, first we'll dive
into these,
and then we'll dive into those.
-- sync, corrected by elderman --
-- for www.addic7ed.Com --