enemies of the internet
and here's who's on the list gamma
trobe a core
hacking team
an asus
and blue coat
now these are organizations that uh...
oftentimes
did private information online
and then
they help the government's
get that information an exploitive from
time to time
at least hacking teaming gamma
of already
uh... that accuse of capturing the
passwords of journalists
so obviously is a huge issue for a
porous well quarters but it turns out
there's an even bigger issue there's a
new report out by citizen lab
with among school global affairs at the
university of toronto
and they looked into specifically one of
the organizations we just talked about
gamble
we had a program called fence pa
well what a specified here's what it
does is a surveillance tools that
infects computers to capture screenshots
logged he strokes
records skype conversations
in activate cameras and microphones
now if that does get images addy you're
not paying attention
you've got a camera
on your computer
and you all have mike's on your computer
i don't know if you know that okay
they can record you
what you're doing in your living room
what you're doing in your office if this
gets onto your computer
and now gamma is giving it
to foreign governments
and what do they do it
of course you're using it to suppress
dissidents
and amma says columbus
uh...
that issues mostly quote against
pedophiles terrorist organized crime
kidnapping
and feeling trafford what's also good
right
new report says in reality is regularly
so two countries were descending
political activity in speech
is criminalized
so they have sold it to places like easy
opr vietnam where by the way they use
the s fourteen bloggers right is an
activist who are now in jail
for opposing the government enbhat rain
who also use it to crack down on
activists in that country
anything over the the disc you will
attract
where they haven't opposing political
figures picture and people would say oh
yes i'm in favor that they downloaded
and all the sudden fin spies on your
computer
even if you didn't send an email
if you're onto something out
visit report secuestrados
it still has
you have a skype conversation with your
family it has a
you're not doing anything on your
computer
it doesn't matter the camera the micro
it has
one more quote from the study
our findings highlight the increasing
dissonance between them is public claims
that's been spies use exclusively to
track bad guys
and a growing body of evidence
suggesting that will have
and continues to be used against
opposition groups
and human rights activex
and you think the u_s_ government isn't
interested in this
using the chinese government isn't
interested in this using the russian
government isn't interested in this
you think they're not using it
for their own purposes
tracking pedophiles and
terrorist
that's the excuse they always give you
this is about as dangerous as this as a
guest
worked for me in nineteen eighty four
they know all of your counsel use
previous story we told you
they can access all of your bank
accounts
now they can access all of your email
all of your internet searches
order conversation not only online but
even in your own home in office
george orwell was genius but we didn't
listen who's warning
and works smack dab right then though in
nineteen eighty four
and we'll let them do it do this to us
day-in and day out
we should be in fort collins
political rebellion over this
they should be the most you legal saying
they're is in the country
and yet governments all across the world
or
sue on the camera off you are no aswell
valley with