CLEO: The morning after our
U-Center debacle, we went back
to Clichy Sous Bois to meet the
kids, because they wanted
to show us where they hang
out during the day.
The place was in tatters and
didn't smell nice at all.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
CLEO: They seem like
good kids.
Not at all like the
stereotypical thugs that media
or right-wing grannies
would make of them.
They played us their latest
track called "It's Time for
Action."
While it goes on a bit long for
me, I actually love the
energy of the boys.
And so we decided to make a
music video for the track.
We're in this [INAUDIBLE] little
cave shooting their
video, so they're
here chilling.
Now walking through here, Dev's
filming from backwards.
I'm not keen on this room
for various reasons.
We get to this zone which
has a strong smell.
And in here is our friend,
Mohammed, He's got very
beautiful blue eyes.
We've given him this stick
and he's going
to be here and sing.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
OK.
So Dev, I'm behind you, right?
CLEO: They're singing
the chorus.
They're getting ready, he's
got his stick, he's
very into his stick.
CLEO: This place smells
not-pleasant.
Can't wait to get out of here.
Oh my God, no way,
no way, no way.
The floor is covered
with pigeon.
Oh my God, I think I've just
walked on a piece.
I don't know if it's
rat or pigeon.
I'm not really sure.
Am I being awk?
I hope we finish soon, my
nose is not enjoying.
The kids were really getting
on my nerve and they were
really being silly
and annoying.
Because they were sitting behind
and kept giving knees
and stuff like that.
And I turned around and
I was really strict.
I told them to call
me Madam again.
Because they were calling me
Cleo and I said that I was too
angry, and--
they think I'm like an
angry schoolteacher.
But I am.
They're too annoying and
they're too noisy, and
agitated, and fed up.
One of them told me
I was pregnant.
I hate them.
After a while we decided to
stop shooting in that
awk-smelling hangout, and drove
them all to central
Paris to shoot them performing
at Parisian hot spot Le Baron.
This venue used to
be a brothel.
It is now the hottest club in
Paris, a.k.a., Le Baron.
This person here,
he's a renowned
French graffiti artist.
This is his trademark, it's a
little man, Smiley, on the
female's bum.
I don't know where the
shoes are from--
maybe Chanel or something.
I don't know whose
bum this is.
Everything's very
disorganized.
No smoke machine,
no fog machine.
A lot of noisy people.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
CLEO: While the video wasn't a
100% success, I think it was
OK considering we only had
half an hour to finish it
before the club opened
its doors to the
posh Parisian adults.
And of course our budget, which
was about half the price
of a bottle of cheap champagne.