KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: We're in
Nazca, Peru and we're going to
show you something crazy.
It's called scissor dancing.
And we're going to have to go
way, way off the beaten track
to see it in it's true form.
My co-pilot for this trip
will be Anthony.
Hi, buddy.
What's up?
How you doing?
ANTHONY VERLAINE:
Fine, thanks.
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: Let's get on
the road because we got a long
journey ahead of us.
ANTHONY VERLAINE: Yup.
Let's go.
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: All right.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: Oh, boy.
Goodbye, pavement.
Dirt roads here on in.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: So, we're
lucky enough to take these
dusty roads and find ourselves
in Andamarca, which is a
remote village in the Andes.
ANTHONY VERLAINE: OK, so we're
going to be in a really
authentic place--
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: Yeah.
ANTHONY VERLAINE: Not
in fucking Lima.
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU:
Yeah, exactly.
ANTHONY VERLAINE: Amazing.
So Krishna, are we going
to see scissor dancer?
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: Yeah,
scissor dancing.
ANTHONY VERLAINE:
What is that?
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: It's a
centuries old tradition where
two dancers and two
musicians play.
The dancers wear elaborate
costumes and they hold
scissors in one hand.
They do really death defying
sort of acts of great daring.
Just sort of crazy shit.
The origins of scissor dancing
are kind of mysterious too.
Like in the 16th century when
the conquistadors came around
and saw them doing these feats
of strength, endurance.
And they thought to themselves,
man, these guys
must have made a pact with
the devil in order
to keep this up.
ANTHONY VERLAINE: Pact
with the devil, cool.
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: Yeah.
I'm actually starting
to feel a little
nauseous on these roads.
We've been going up
and down and we're
like, dusty and windy--
ANTHONY VERLAINE: And the
altitude, like 5,000 meters
height now.
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: (COUGHING)
Maybe that's why
I'm coughing so much.
We've made it to Andamarca, a
tiny remote village high in
the Peruvian Andes.
We're at an elevation of
something like 12,000 feet.
The journey was arduous.
And honestly, we
feel like shit.
I'm going to go meet our troop
of scissor dancers alone
because Anthony was feeling so
badly that he has to lie down
and take some more oxygen.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: Is it a
competition, the dance?
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: And so we're
going to collect supplies for
the competition?
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: So what are
you going to do with the
needles and the worms?
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: Their butts?
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: During our
walk, the group explained that
cactus needles and another
sharp objects are used to
prove the dancer's resistance
to pain.
The team that performs the most
extreme feats would be
deemed victorious by the town.
What's the meaning of
scissor dancing?
What significance does it have
both to your culture and to
yourself personally?
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: One
question I've
always had is why scissors?
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: Uh-huh.
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: So all day
today Anthony was in bed
because he succumbed to what
seemed to be altitude sickness
at first, but might
be something a
little bit more serious.
ANTHONY VERLAINE: I feel really
sick because of the
altitude, so our driver tries
some local medicine on me.
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: It's the
morning of the competition.
And we're headed up a hill
overlooking the town so the
group can practice
for tonight.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: From what I
understand you don't actually
live in Andamarca anymore.
You live in Lima.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU:
I can't wait.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
ANTHONY VERLAINE: I survived.
Krishna, Krishna, Krishna.
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: Good
to see you, buddy.
How you feeling?
ANTHONY VERLAINE: Better.
Much better.
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: Good.
Good.
You ready to find some moves?
ANTHONY VERLAINE: Definitely
ready.
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: Awesome.
That's great.
How was the hospital?
ANTHONY VERLAINE: Weird.
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: Weird.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: Terrible
at this.
ANTHONY VERLAINE: Yeah.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: Jump, go like
that, jump, [INAUDIBLE]
toes.
Jump like that.
That's going to be impossible
for us.
Do you want to give it a try?
Here we go.
ANTHONY VERLAINE: OK.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: Oh, look.
They're starting.
Ola.
Remember this song?
Remember that move?
ANTHONY VERLAINE: Yeah.
I do remember.
We almost died on it.
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: Yeah, we
almost died doing that move.
So we're here at the town square
where a bunch of the
towns people have gathered to
watch these two teams of
dancers go at it head-to-head
in a series of escalating
one-upsmanship kind of moves.
Wow!
[MUSIC PLAYING]
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: Wow.
[APPLAUSE AND CHEERING]
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: It looks
like they've started the
second part of the
competition.
So we'll have our eyes out for
needles, and back flips, and
any kind of things that
they're going to do.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: Bravo!
Some guy just came and whipped
us a few times.
ANTHONY VERLAINE: Ow!
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: Ow!
I think we're not supposed
to cross this line.
But honestly, I have no idea.
And the whipping had
increasing--
ANTHONY VERLAINE: Actually,
I like it.
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: You
kind of liked it?
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: He's
going to wear it.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[APPLAUSE AND CHEERING]
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: Yes.
Jug head.
[APPLAUSE AND CHEERING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[LAUGHTER AND CHEERING]
[APPLAUSE AND CHEERING]
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: Now they're
starting to ramp this up.
They're bringing out nails,
knives, and other crazy stuff.
Oh, boy.
They're spilling their blood
as a sacrifice to the Apus.
In return, the mountain God
relieves them of their pain.
The crazier the stunt, the
less pain they feel.
Oh, I got to drink more booze.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[APPLAUSE AND CHEERING]
ANTHONY VERLAINE: I'm pretty
sure one of the guys is going
to pass away before the
end of the contest.
Because they do the craziest
things with their head.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[APPLAUSE]
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: So let's
put some costumes on.
Come on.
ANTHONY VERLAINE: Where?
Where?
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU:
Oh, my balls.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: That
got a good laugh.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[APPLAUSE AND CHEERING]
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU:
Yeah, Anthony!
[LAUGHTER AND CHEERING]
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU: This is
something that's off the
beaten track.
We had to travel through
dusty roads, brave
elevation, brave sickness.
But we really saw scissor
dancing in its purest form.
And we have to really thank
everyone for making us feel so
at home and making us feel part
of their living tradition
of scissor dancing.
So gracias!
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE]
[SINGING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]