IAN R CRANE: London getting the
Olympics wasn't exactly a
great shock to me.
Of course, London partied very
hard, and we were still
partying the following morning
when, of course, we heard the
London bombings.
And this really set the scene
for everything that has
unfolded and has continued
to unfold as we speak.
I had felt for some time that
London was going to be the
focus of a number of events
around about this particular
period of time.
Let's not ignore completely
the Mayan calendar.
2012 was always going to
be a significant year.
The symbolism associated
with the London
Olympics is not random.
The London Olympics logo is
certainly very interesting.
I really didn't know what I
was necessarily looking to
find, and then it jumped
out at me.
I mean it literally was
a case of oh my God.
That's when, for me, it became
the Zion Olympics.
The London 2012 Olympics are
going to be the most heavily
securitized event in history.
Anti-aircraft missiles will be
located on an apartment block
in East London.
There's going to be a device
installed on a barge on the
Thames which has the capacity
to disable crowds of people
through sonic waves.
And of course all this is on top
of a helicopter carrier in
the Thames.
49,000 military personnel will
be mingling with the athletes
and with spectators at
the Olympic events.
There's going to be an 11-mile
perimeter around the Olympic
area in London.
And literally the whole area
could be sealed off in a
heartbeat, and then effectively
it becomes a
concentration camp.
What's going on right
now literally is a
game of global monopoly.
And the London Olympics
are a very, very
important part of this.
This is a document that
came into the
public domain in 1967.
One of the observations or
comments they make in this
report is that if there was
the threat of an alien
invasion, it would very quickly
draw all the nation
states together under the guise
of a global government.
On the basis that you can't rely
on the extraterrestrials
to turn up on cue, you'd
have to stage it.
It's my opinion that the London
Olympics are going to
be used to stage an event of
such enormity it will give
them the springboard to
introduce their one world
government.
This is a point of humanity's
evolution which
is absolutely crucial.
MALE SPEAKER: We all know
why we're here.
We don't want missiles
in residential areas.
We do not want the
militarization of our
communities.
BRIAN WHELAN: We've seen the
biggest mobilization of troops
in the UK since the end
of World War II.
None of this is normal.
And I think what is normal is
to come out like people did
today and say no, you're
bloody not.
My name is Brian Whelan.
I'm a journalist currently
living in Bow Quarter, who
initially made a lot of noise
about the sighting of missiles
above my apartment.
And for my sins, I'm now being
forced to leave my apartment.
It's quite a complicated affair,
but let's just say
that I'm leaving five days
before the opening ceremony of
the Olympics, so the timing
is really suspicious.
It also means now I can't be
party to a legal challenge
against the MOD.
So essentially the Olympics
has left me without
somewhere to live.
That's the position
I'm in now.
I spoke out, and there's
consequences to when you speak
out and try and ruin
the fun of a really
big event like this.
ANDREW PLENTY: For the
Olympics, we'll be
anti-Maritime and air
threat security.
So we'll be supporting the
police in their job in
securing a safe and secure
Olympic games.
So our main role will be the
stop of any threat that comes
from the air or from the
maritime environment.
There's no reason for anyone to
feel any increased feeling
of threat just because
we're here.
We're here to deter
any threats.
Obviously the Olympic games
is a global event, and any
country would put in place the
measures that would ensure a
safe event occurs.
So I don't think they've got any
reason to feel more scared
at all, and I think
that's the key.
[SHIP HORN]
TOMMY SWIPE: I'm not afraid of
the Army or the police who's
going to be at the Olympics.
Don't bother me.
The Olympics, what is a
multimillion, billion pound
event coming to London.
South London, East London,
Hackney, is going to be a
great money spinner for all of
us underworld criminals.
TONY SALES: I think the Olympics
are probably the
biggest opportunity for
fraudsters and all types of
criminals that we've probably
seen in the recent years.
In Hackney, it's one of the
biggest crime places in
London, it's going to create an
absolute multitude of all
different crimes.
TOMMY SWIPE: My name
is Tommy Swipe, and
I'm a full-time swiper.
Been involved in criminal
activity all my life, since
the age of 15.
Allegations of selling cocaine,
firearms, Section 18
with intent that could cause
grievous bodily harm, three
assaults on police officers.
There's loads-- it
goes on and on.
TONY SALES: The most popular
crime at the Olympics could
possibly be the RFID reader.
You can just gain the
information just by simply
running it over any
type of RFID card.
So that might be an oyster card
or a PayPass card that we
see with the little white wave
lines in the corner.
You could then convert that
with the software that's
available to get the 16-digit
number that's on the
front of each card.
TOMMY SWIPE: Through the
Olympics, I just find it an
easy target to use the
scanner to go around.
Easy to pickpocket
people's numbers.
Sometimes I go out on me own
and do it, and I just walk
close to people and just-- it's
not really that I really
get a target really.
I just walk past someone, as
soon as it picks up their
numbers there it is.
Bingo, isn't it?
Liking walking into the shop,
buying a penny sweet.
TONY SALES: This is how easy it
is to gain the information
on the card.
That's it, we've got the
information as simple as that.
TOMMY SWIPE: I'm a space-age
Fagan, you could say that.
At the Olympics I can make up to
thousands a day just for a
few hour's work.
A few hundred quid,
just one hour.
The longer you're out,
the better it is.
FREDDIE: Hi, I'm Freddie.
We here in Scarborough shooting
Chariots of Jizz for
the Television X Olympics
special.
I just like the whole
Olympic ethos.
Even though it has become more
and more commercialized and
more professional, I still think
it's the greatest show
on Earth, really.
Some people say they watch us
just to see the funny bits,
rather than to watch
any of the sex.
So we like that, that's good.
HONESTY: The scene we're
shooting today was in the
equipment room.
And the guys come in to put
their equipment away.
And I'm in there as an athlete,
possibly typing my
shoelaces, and we just sort
of go from there really.
MALE SPEAKER: Action.
HONESTY: Hello, boys.
Have you been training?
FREDDIE: Some of the athletes
that have performed at the
Olympic games in previous years
had said that as soon as
they finished their events,
all the athletes from that
particular event would have a
big party and that often ended
up in a bit of a sex orgy.
MALE SPEAKER: Oh, that's good.
Oh, you naughty girl.
Look at that.
MALE SPEAKER: Got about
half an hour.
Another 10 minutes maybe,
and that's it.
FREDDIE: Team GB from Freddie,
bring back all the medals.
MALE SPEAKER: This whole
business has been positive on
the idea of creating a heritage
or a legacy, and
that's getting it the
wrong way round.
Nobody can say what the
future will be.
The thing you have to work
on is the present.
MALE SPEAKER: You can't set
out to create legacy.
Legacy is what happens.
And you can't just say
look, I've just
made some legacy here.
Only history will tell, but my
suspicion is we're going to
have a lot of rather large,
rather useless, rather empty
buildings left in Stratford.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Look where
Athens is now.
I'm not saying that the games
bankrupted an entire country,
but they certainly
didn't help.
Britain's not exactly in such
a great position either.
MALE SPEAKER: Are the Olympics
an opportunity or a threat?
They're a great opportunity
for thieving.
But the thieving seems to be
mostly carried out by those in
charge of running
the Olympics.
IAN R CRANE: I hope from the
bottom of my heart that the
games goes off without
a hitch.
If anything does occur, I would
say that don't take any
the news reports
at face value.
MALE SPEAKER: The government's
got good ideas, but the
execution's not there.
MALE SPEAKER: I think, generally
speaking, this is
just going to be a
sporting event.
Obviously, my biggest concern,
as somebody who lives and
works in this borough, is about
people who live here.
FEMALE SPEAKER: There was a lot
of propaganda about how it
was going to bring regeneration,
how they're
promising legacy benefits,
and so on.
But that is not what's
happened at all.
It seems to benefit only
corporations, and it's taken
over our green spaces.
FEMALE SPEAKER: My feelings are
they want Stratford city
to be the up and coming
place to be.
And they don't want the likes
of us, working-class people,
in Stratford.
No, they just want professional
people here--
money people.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Ultimately, it
does boil down to thousands
upon thousands of little
individual lives that are now
forever changed for three
weeks of a brand-fest.
MALE SPEAKER: Same reason why
I didn't get tickets.
But I can just watch
it on TV anyway.