ALL: Hello.
What's your name?
My name is Michael.
Michael.
And where are you from?
From France.
From France. 'Ah, bonjour.'
'D'accord, d'accord.'
Very good, you're very good!
Thank you.
What will you be
doing for us today?
Dancing.
I'm dancing.
You're a translator.
I'm just his translator.
In France I watch BGT on YouTube.
I really hope the judges give me the chance
to show Britain what I can do.
Do you live in the UK?
No, I live in France.
So you came over
just to audition for BGT?
Yes.
Wow, great!
Welcome!
It's magic.
Yeah.
Great!
Let's get you on. Come on.
Straight on.
The pair of you are going on, yeah?
Good luck.
'Bon chance'
That's 'good luck' in French.
Hello.
What are your names?
My name is Michael Moral.
I'm Claire, I'm just the translator.
No performance from me.
You're not in the act?
No.
OK.
Where are you from?
I'm from France.
OK, we don't need you.
It's going fine (!)
[Laughter]
AMANDA: Ahh.
DAVID: Aw.
I can handle this.
'Où habites-tu?'
[Laughter]
I live in the south of France.
'Quelle age as-tu?'
I'm 21 years old.
'Bon.'
[Laughter]
What are you going to
do for us today?
I'm a dancer.
Oh, you're a dancer.
Very very best of luck, Michael,
and the stage is yours.
Thank you.
Very very best of luck, Michael,
and the stage is yours.
'Bon chance!'
Thank you.
[Cheering & applause]
AMANDA: Why do people shave
half their eyebrow off?
[Cheering]
[Cheering & applause]
Very good!
AMANDA: 'Encore! Encore!'
That was probably the best dancing
we've had on this show.
[Cheers of agreement]
If you get voted back, I can't wait
to see what you're going to do.
It could be a magical show.
Congratulations. Terrific!
Thank you!
I agree with David.
It was amazing.
I loved that you were so fluid.
You had... Your body looked like
it didn't belong to your head.
[Laughter]
'Très bien.'
Just, 'très bien!'
We're going to vote.
David Hasselhoff,
is it a yes or a no?
It is a 'oui!'
[Cheering]
MICHAEL: Amanda?
It's a yes from me.
[Cheering]
It's three yesses. Very well done.
Congratulations.
[Cheering & applause]
Yeah!
Well done, congratulations.
Unbelievable!
Really cool.
DAVID:
Great. He's like the rubber man.
[With atmospheric vocal effects]
MICHAEL:
He was absolutely fantastic.
[With atmospheric vocal effects]
DAVID:
It was great.
[With atmospheric vocal effects]
Closed captions by Spiritman