So I'd like to start my story in 1997
when I first came to the US.
I was originally working with adult women.
I came originally to work with adult women
coming out of the sex industry.
And so in that first literally few days,
few weeks, few months,
I began to go to Rikers Island Prison
and up to Hunts Point,
which has been the subject of
numerous pseudodocumentaries on HBO,
and began to meet really young girls.
I was going into
an adult correctional facility
and yet meeting 12, 13, 14-year-old girls
who'd been told by their pimp
to say that they were 17, 18, 19.
It was incredibly obvious that
they were nowhere close to that age.
I was going out on to the streets,
and for any of you who've seen
any of those HBO type docs,
you know that for many, many years,
there's been areas in New York and
in Chicago and all over the country
where there's a very, very clear
kind of prostitution track.
And so there would be cars
literally lined up on the street,
and I would meet yet again
12, 13, 14-year-old girls
who were out there being sold.
And so, I was 22
when I first came to the States,
and as a survivor
of commercial sexual exploitation myself
as a teenager --
I'd gotten out when I was 19 years old --
I've realized that I had
a lot in common with these girls
and young women that I was meeting.
And the 40-year-old women
at that point were like:
What's this little girl going to tell me?
Whereas the 19-year-olds
were a little bit more receptive
to this very bright-eyed 22-year-old.
So I realized though, that even though
we were from different continents,
and the girls would be like:
Where's your accent, miss?
You sound like Sporty Spice --
that we had very, very similar stories,
and that cultural difference
was kind of overridden
by the similarities
of the commercial sex industry globally.
And so our stories
of growing up in poverty,
our stories of growing up
in traumatic homes
where there was lots of domestic violence
and substance abuse,
our stories of craving attention and love
from our families and generally
not getting that,
our stories of kind of getting introduced
into the commercial sex industry
through a man or through kind of
this moment of desperation
and feeling like: OK, this is
just something I'll do for the moment,
and I'll figure out my way to get out.
And then getting stuck.
And our stories of being treated like
"we were less than"
by everyone in the community:
our families, by law enforcement,
by social workers, by hospital staff.
They kind of rang the same,
whether it was my experience,
or the experiences
of the girls that I was serving.
And so, in 1998, I decided to start GEMS,
which is
Girls Educational and Mentoring Services,
kind of based on my own experiences.
And at that point, I had
absolutely no money,
I had no idea even how to write...
I think I was just beginning
to learn how to write a proposal.
And so, I started GEMS
literally on my kitchen table,
and girls would sleep on my couch,
and eat my food,
and wear my clothes,
and not bring my clothes back.
And so that was about as grass roots
as you can kind of get
in terms of starting a non-profit.
And I was 23, so I had no idea
what starting a non-profit
would look like,
which was really, really good.
So, I began to work with girls and
young women who were being trafficked.
And at that point though, we weren't using
that terminology "trafficking".
And so "trafficking" kind of
came into or lexicon,
really it began to come in in 2000, when
the Trafficking Victims Protection Act,
federal legislation, was passed.
And so, the handful of us
that were working
with domestic trafficking victims
were really excited and thought:
OK, this is the moment where our girls,
and young women, and adult women
begin to be treated as victims,
not as criminals.
And then we realized very quickly that
there was this kind of two-tiered system.
And so, in terms of how
the funding was structured,
in terms of how the training
for law enforcement and service providers,
in terms of how kind of
the media and the public
began to view this issue over the years,
it was like: Well, there's
those real trafficking victims,
there are those girls from Mexico,
or from Asia, or from the Ukraine,
and you know there's
those teen prostitutes from America,
who just kind of want to do this
and they like doing this.
And so the battle over
the last really kind of decade,
and change for us, has been about
really trying to educate people
that the sexual exploitation
and trafficking
of girls, and young women, and adult women
in this country looks the same as it does
for girls and women globally,
and that you don't have to be
from another country
to feel like you don't have options
in this country, right?
We're very good at doing the Horatio,
how to pull yourself up
by your bootstraps, kind of myth,
but if we're being honest, opportunities
aren't equal in this country,
and there are entire segments
of our young people
for whom opportunities
are frequently denied.
And so, that's what
we've continuously found.
And I will say that I think if this issue
had affected the number
of low-income girls of color
that we've seen
over the last 15 years,
both in New York
and all over the country,
if it had affected
white middle-class girls in that same way,
we would've seen a very, very different
social and political response by now.
We had to educate people to that.
Just because you weren't undocumented
didn't mean you trusted law enforcement
and went running to law enforcement
and said, "Hi, Mr Police Officer,
please rescue me."
Right?
We understand that for women and men
who are trafficked globally
whether for sex or labor,
their experiences with law enforcement
in their own countries
haven't been particularly warm,
and so they may not feel like
this is someone that they can go to.
That's true for young people
in our country too,
particularly, young people who've grown up
in communities of color,
that historically don't have good reason
to trust law enforcement.
And we also had to teach people
that you don't have to be
chained physically
to a bed or to a wall
in order to think that you can't leave.
And with the domestic violence movement,
we've begun to really work
over the last 30 years
stopping folks from saying,
"Well, why doesn't she just leave?"
And we began to recognize that it was
a lot more complex than that, right?
And that here were many psychological
and sociological factors
that would stop an adult woman
from leaving an abuser.
And so when we're talking
about particularly children,
when we're talking about girls
who are under the control of somebody
whose entire job is to make them
loyal and compliant,
we have to be able to apply
those same kind of ideas
that we've come up with
with domestic violence
and recognize that
the physical chains may not be there,
but psychological chains
are much, much stronger.
And when we think about someone like
Elizabeth Smart or Shawn Hornbeck,
who is the little boy,
who was found in Missouri,
several years after his kidnapping,
or Jaycee Dugard, we generally don't ask:
Why didn't they just leave?
We recognize Stockholm's syndrome
and trauma bonding.
We recognize whatever was done
to those young people
in the first few days, first few hours,
was enough to keep them psychologically
trapped and bonded,
and for them to believe
that they couldn't leave.
So, that's kind of been the work
over the last 15 years,
and slowly we're beginning
in the last maybe year, 18 months,
we're beginning to see
kind of some level of change,
and this slow shift in public perception,
where we're beginning
to see more media stuff,
and where we're beginning to see
kind of folks shifting their perception
of who these girls are,
who these women are.
And so, I mean, I think,
one of the most critical things
that we've been able to do,
and that we did in New York,
was be able to change,
not just kind of in concept,
but actually in policy this idea
that young people were victims,
not criminals.
And so, for many years,
as I was working in juvenile detention,
and like I said on the streets
and up on Rikers Island,
I was seeing 12 and 13,
14, 15, 16-year-old girls
who were being arrested and charged
with an act of prostitution,
that under New York State law,
they couldn't legally consent to,
because they couldn't legally
consent to sex until they were 17.
And so, in any other case,
they would've been
a victim of statutory rape.
And yet because money was exchanged,
the 40-year-old, the 30-year-old,
the adult man who was buying them,
was no longer seen as a statutory rapist,
he was seen just as a "John",
and he was generally let go
with a little pat,
same way we used to treat
domestic violence abusers
for many, many years.
And the girl, the child
who was being bought,
the child who was being sold
by adult men to adult men,
was the one who was arrested, incarcerated
and generally sentenced to a year.
We had one case, and this is the case
that kind of started the whole thing off,
where we had a 12-year-old
who was arrested,
she was sentenced upstate
to a juvenile detention center for a year,
she had been in the foster care system,
she had been totally abandoned by family,
she had a massive history
of trauma and abuse
and had met an adult man who became
her "daddy", who became her pimp.
And the judge said, "She needed to learn
proper moral principles."
And so, that was the case that kind of...
we said, "Hmm, something's wrong
with this legislation,
something's wrong with a law
that doesn't protect victims
but sees them, children, as criminals,
and isn't addressing this
as a human rights issue."
And yet we've got federal law
that recognizes children
from other countries as victims,
and technically does recognize children
from our country as victims,
but it's not happening at a state level.
And so for about 4.5 years,
the young women at GEMS and I
trekked up to Albany,
we worked very closely
with the legal aid Juvenile
Rights Division,
and in the beginning we would go
in a room, and it would be 4 legislators,
and they were totally bored and apathetic.
And we would go back and
we would go back again,
and the girls would say,
"It's all white men in suits."
And say, "Yes, let's have a conversation
about power and privileged
and what that looks like".
And so it became kind of
a civic participation lesson in action
over the course of about 4.5, 5 years.
And eventually we were able
to make New York State
the first state in the country to protect,
not prosecute, children
who have been sexually exploited
and trafficked.
That happened in 2008.
We were very conscious of kind of what
could happen nationally with that law,
And since then 9 of the states
have passed similar, what they're calling
"safe harbor", legislation.
So we are now 10 states down,
40 to go.
I would like to believe in 5 years
we will look back,
like we look back on many other issues,
and think,
"Did we really send
12-year-olds to jail!?
Did we really let the adult men
who were doing the buying and selling go?
That seems ludicrous.
We don't live in that kind of country."
So, I believe that we have
the ability to get there,
but I think what's critical
and what we need to kind of...
the next layer of where we're going
in the anti-trafficking movement,
ending commercial
sexual exploitation movement,
is really about kind of making sure
that we're tying these issues,
the issue of sexual exploitation
into like these larger systemic issues,
because oftentimes what we're finding now
with the media focus on this issue,
for anybody who's seeing MSNBC special
or something in the newspaper,
it tends to be very sensationalized
and very kind of,
"Rescue little girls, bad men
-- arrest them!"
It tends to be that kind of paradigm,
and yet we're not addressing
the social factors
that make young people so
incredibly vulnerable in the first place.
Like I said, predominantly,
what we are seeing
are low-income girls, girls of color,
girls who've been
in the child welfare system,
over 70% of the girls that GEMS serves
have been in the child welfare system
at some point,
girls who have been victims
of childhood sexual abuse and trauma.
We know that anywhere from 70% to 90%
of both children and adult women
who end up in the sex industry,
were victims of child sexual abuse
prior to recruitment.
There is no other industry in the world
that targets folks
who have been victims
of childhood sexual abuse,
one of the most traumatic things that
you can experience, in such a way, right?
That preys upon the most vulnerable people
in our society,
some of the most marginalized folks
in our entire community.
And so we have to be able to
address some of these root causes,
we have to be able to address
opportunities for all of our young people,
and make sure that we are not predicating
what your future looks like
as a young person,
based on the ZIP code
that you are born into.
We need to make sure
that we are addressing
kind of some of
these larger systemic issues,
particularly, gender-based violence.
And I will say that, you know,
for the last couple of years,
there was a point
where you couldn't get like
3 people in a room to talk about this.
And then there was a point when
you began to get folks showing up
but now, right, you do
an anti-trafficking workshop
and there's a ton of people showing up.
And yet we can't get folks now to come
to a domestic violence presentation,
because we think we've solved it,
we think we've addressed that,
we think it's one of those things we don't
really need to focus on right now,
and yet, we know that domestic violence
is happening... now.
And if I waited another few seconds...
again, and again, in our country.
And so, we have to be able to address kind
of the continuum of gender-based violence,
of which commercial sexual exploitation
and trafficking is just one component.
We have to be able to address race
and the impact of racism
on young people in this country,
and particularly how that plays out
in the commercial sex industry.
I will tell you that, and this isn't
a talk about pornography,
but I will tell you that pornography is
one of the few industries anywhere
that you can still be blatantly racist.
And I encourage you to look at some
of the links between race and pornography,
and how that plays out in our culture,
and how we're still
really comfortable in that world,
in terms of addressing people through race
and very racialized,
sexualized stereotypes.
We have to be able to think,
where do we want to be
in 5 to 10 years on this issue,
because sometimes we can go,
and I think this is true
of all social justice movements,
we can address kind of
the very exciting sexy topics,
and not really dig deeper,
and go long term
for the long-term gains.
And so, every issue
has its moment in the sun,
and right now trafficking
is having its moment.
The domestic violence movement
had its moment.
The environment kind of had its moment.
HIV/AIDS had its moment.
And that's not to say that work
isn't still being done,
but there is
a very particular point in time,
for every social justice issue
where the focus is on it,
and there's a lot of momentum,
and a lot of excitement,
and the media is all over it.
And we're kind of hitting that point
and we're very close
to hitting that point in
the trafficking movement right now,
but we have to think about:
What do we want to see
kind of 5, 10, 15, 20 years out?
And so some of those things
might not be
the most sexiest things
that we can address.
Arresting men and saving girls
sounds like a good concept,
but rescue isn't
a long-term sustainable method
of addressing folks' needs.
We have to be looking
from an empowerment perspective.
I will say that just looking
at the "Kony 2012" video,
if you didn't see it,
you were living under a rock,
it just picked up
this massive level of momentum.
But I'll say there are some things
that the anti-trafficking movement
could kind of learn from that.
It's critical that we are highlighting
voices that are on the ground,
and we are highlighting
the voices of survivors,
and not in
a get-up-and-tell-your-story way.
As a survivor and somebody who's been
in a leadership role for many years,
I'm still in positions where,
you know, the focus becomes
kind of "The sensational aspects
of my story,"
and "What did you go through?"
and "What did you experience?"
As opposed to the fact, [that] as
an executive director for last 14 years,
I actually have some ideas, about policy,
and programming, and development,
and there is some of that stuff
that I bring to the table.
And while my story is critical
in terms of informing the work that I do,
it's one part of me.
And if we're really serious
about addressing victims
and supporting victims
into becoming survivors,
and then ultimately leaders,
we have to think about: How do we move
from that very kind of,
on some levels, voyeuristic,
kind of: "I want to know all
the ins and outs of all the violence,
and trauma and all the bad stuff
that happened to you"?
And I could've gotten up here today
and done that piece,
But [it would have been] less helpful
in terms of how we're thinking about
this issue as a community, as a movement.
We can learn from "Kony"
the things that are sensational
may get the attention,
but they don't necessarily provide
the most nuanced view
of what's happening on the ground,
and that the things that may seem
to make the most sense initially
and appeal to our good, evil...
This is an incredibly complex issue.
And we have to be able
to address economic empowerment,
we have to be able to address education
and employment for girls and women,
globally, and in this country too.
We've gotten much better
about talking about the need
for economic empowerment
for girls globally.
But we're doing a pretty crappy job
about recognizing
that some of those same issues
exist right here,
right down the block from us,
right in our own backyards.
And so, that desire
to address "the other"
when it comes to particularly any issue,
but particularly sex trafficking,
and having empathy for brown
and black children in other countries,
but not so much in our country,
being able to address services
and support in other countries,
but again not in our own country,
is somewhere that we have to
move away from.
And so I encourage you
to really just think about...
in the next...
you've got a lot to think about, right?
You've heard a lot
of different talks today,
but I encourage you on this issue
to really think about
how can you tie this issue in
with the work that you're doing.
The next speaker's going to
talk about economics, right?
Sex trafficking and exploitation
is totally connected to that.
The amazing presentation today on PTSD
and memory, that's connected.
All of these issues are connected,
and when we silo stuff off,
and make it kind of its own little issue,
we do ourselves a disservice.
So, I'm going wrap here,
but thank you very much.
(Applause)