Gnarly trick.
JIM GRECO: Me and him were at
the diner one day, and we
chased down and attacked some
guy that started some shit
with us in front of the diner.
MALE SPEAKER 2: Put the
fucking board up.
JIM GRECO: Whoa, back
the fuck off.
MALE SPEAKER 2: Put the
fucking board up.
JIM GRECO: Walk away.
Walk away.
Go!
Now!
See ya.
MALE SPEAKER 2: Fucking queer.
JIM GRECO: Bye-bye.
And I was like, come
on, you can help me
chase this guy down.
And I went and smashed his
truck up with my board.
And I got him thrown right
in the middle of it.
That was my introduction
to him, but--
MALE SPEAKER 3: He helped
you beat this guy up?
JIM GRECO: We didn't
beat the guy up.
We just kind of chased him
down and scared him.
But yeah, Lizard's sick, man.
MALE SPEAKER 3: What's up?
Welcome back to "Epicly
Later'd." This episode is
about Lizard King, who's
a friend of mine.
He is a quite ridiculous
person.
He kind of is, like, friends
with everybody.
You'll see in this episode.
Not only is he an awesome street
skater that will just
do anything or jump off of
anything, he'll just do the
mega ramp, which not
many streets
skaters have done that.
So we're going to go over his
house, meet up with him, see
what he gets into on
an average weekday.
So this is it.
The Lizard King episode.
LIZARD KING: You guys should
teach your dogs how to use
toilets like normal people.
MALE SPEAKER 3: You're from
Utah, originally?
LIZARD KING: Mm-hm, Salt
Lake City, fool.
Salt Lake's tight.
Buttery ass spots everywhere,
tons of skate parks, cheap
drinks, mountains, babes.
Dude, there's lots of hot
Mormon chicks there.
MALE SPEAKER 3: And your
family's Mormon?
LIZARD KING: Nah, nah,
nah, nah, nah, nah.
MALE SPEAKER 3: That's
just a rumor I heard?
LIZARD KING: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
My mom's Catholic.
My dad's a workaholic.
MALE SPEAKER 3: Were they
supportive of you skating?
LIZARD KING: Yeah, my mom
was super down for it.
My dad, it took him a little
while to get into it.
I think he was more hyped.
Like I used to be really good
at riding bikes and shit.
And he fuckin'--
he was a pro motor cross
racer, so he's like--
could relate with the bicycle
thing, you know?
I'd asked for a new skateboard,
and he'd
be, like, get a job.
I'd ask for a fucking new part
for my bike, and he'd take me
to the bike shop instantly
and go pay for it.
[LAUGHS]
MALE SPEAKER 3: Did your mom
trip out when you had tattoos?
LIZARD KING: [LAUGH]
Oh, yeah.
Her and my dad were pretty
fucking pissed.
My dad fucking hates tattoos
more than anything.
I came home for Christmas.
This was like, maybe a year or
two ago with fuckin' Salt Lake
tattooed on my hands and the
Death Wish logo on my neck.
And I rolled in, like, wearing
gloves and a hoodie.
[LAUGHS]
I was like, I can't
pull this off.
And showed it to him.
He was fucking pissed.
Ruined Christmas.
Fool, like, when he's pissed
off, this jaw muscle, he has
this muscle right here, and it
just starts flexing, dude.
Seriously, for like five
hours straight,
that thing was like--
he wasn't hyped.
JUSTIN ROY: Lizard.
I think he showed up at my house
in Fullerton when we
used to have the old Hellrose.
Yeah, he just kind of showed
up one day with a couple of
other kids and never left.
MALE SPEAKER 3: What
was Hellrose?
JUSTIN ROY: Hellrose was just
a bunch of homeys in a place
where we lived.
Kind of a lifestyle, I guess you
could call it at the time.
So we'd always just meet up in
the mornings, hang out, skate
together, party together,
that kind of deal.
MALE SPEAKER 3: What was his
skating like at first when you
first met him?
JUSTIN ROY: Total mad man.
Mad man on a board, everywhere
we go, screaming at
the top of his lungs.
Just total madness is the
best way to describe it.
ANDREW REYNOLDS: I knew some of
those guys, like Justin Roy
and Sammy Baca.
I didn't know all of them.
But I just knew that
they were around.
And they all looked really
dirty, bummy,
and stuff, you know?
But he was part of
that whole thing.
And I saw him skate at one
night Active demo.
But he was like--
I mean, not saying he wasn't
good, but he just wasn't,
like, the same Lizard
that he is now.
It was like he was just kind of
going fast and really out
of it, like ripping trim.
MALE SPEAKER 3: Was he sponsored
at that point?
JUSTIN ROY: Pig came along,
which was right around the
time Hellrose was ending.
And then everybody kind of
went to Pig from there.
I just called the Beagle, Josh
Beagle, or whatever, and
fucking hit him up and
asked him if I could
skate for Pig Wood.
The think dude, Tony Patel
or whatever, hit me up.
He was like, dude, I'll cut you
a check right now if you
want to skate for us.
I mean, it sucks to be like,
yeah, I'm quitting for money.
But I mean, whatever.
I was fucking poor as shit,
living out here on people's
couches, you know what I mean?
It's like, I wasn't even getting
any product enough to
be going and slinging
boards and shit.
It's like, I skated
every board I had.
And then, they started
Death Wish or
whatever and then poof.
ERIK ELLINGTON: Lizard actually
got a Death Wish
tattoo before the company
was even started.
We weren't even sure we
were going to do it.
And I drew it on, like,
going down his ribs.
We were on a Baker film trip
or something like that.
And I was, like, yeah,
we want to start this
company, Death Wish.
I was like, you're on
when it starts.
And we just clicked
from day one.
And then I went skating
with him.
And I was, like, obviously his
skating speaks for itself.
And I didn't know he
was that good.
I was just, like--
I'd seen a couple of
those sequences.
I was, like, oh shit--
Cap from a board down a 12.
But then when you go skate
with him, it's like, he's
insane the way he works.
He just adapts really
well to every single
thing he tries to skate.
It's rad to watch.
JIM GRECO: When he does like a
nose blunt, like, he sawed a
bar off and did a nose blunt
indie grab into a fucking bar
bank type thing in Arizona.
Eric was telling me
how sick he was.
ANDREW REYNOLDS: And I met his
mom and like just his whole
family out in Salt Lake City.
And his brother was telling me
when he wasn't around, like,
yeah, everything he does
he's good at, always.
Like he can do hand rails
and stuff on a bike.
And he climbs rocks,
and he did the mega
jump, skates vert.
It's insane.
He's like an adrenaline
junkie or something.
LIZARD KING: I was like 15 at
the skate park, and this dude
that was like my idol, I
worshipped him, he just walked
up to me one day and said,
what's up, Lizard?
And ever since then, it was
just, like, it was on.
It's been stuck.
He's the pumpkin king.
His dad's the pumpkin master.
And his daughter's the
pumpkin princess.