PATRICK O'DELL: Oh, was the
Boneless invented in
Cincinnati?
JAMES KELCH: Yeah, actually
the Boneless
was invented at Dio's.
It's down the street
from the block.
It's the doctor's
office banks.
Gary, Scott, Davis.
PATRICK O'DELL: Oh, GSD?
JAMES KELCH: GSD.
PATRICK O'DELL: You want to go
down there and look at that?
JAMES KELCH: Yeah.
PATRICK O'DELL: Well, see it's
better if you drive, cause
then I sit shotgun and film.
JAMES KELCH: Yeah, exactly.
So then we'll just jump
my car and move the
shit out of the seat.
We might go film this.
I don't want to buy
a new battery.
It costs like $70.
This is my neighbor, she lives
across the street, Ohio style.
See her?
She walks every day,
to lose weight.
But she walks to Wendy's.
Comes back with a big-ass
bag of it hidden in her
sweat-coat.
I see it peeking out
all the time.
Had this car a long time,
bought it brand new.
You remember this?
This is that car.
PATRICK O'DELL: I
don't remember.
PATRICK O'DELL: Remember the one
we drove down on the spots
in the black Saturn in Frisco?
PATRICK O'DELL: Oh, yeah?
JAMES KELCH: This is it.
Shit still runs.
Other people's Saturns
break down.
Just got to know how to
take care of them.
PATRICK O'DELL: Remember you
lived in a house that a serial
killer used to live there?
JAMES KELCH: Yeah.
He woke up in the middle of the
night, never done nothing
wrong in his life, goes down
to the TL, gets prostitutes
and murders them.
That was it.
That was his whole shit.
He went on a killing spree.
PATRICK O'DELL: Does that
freak you out at all?
JAMES KELCH: Nah.
PATRICK O'DELL: Does it freak
your girlfriend out?
JAMES KELCH: She thought
it was strange, yeah.
Then after a while she thought
it was hella cool.
She'd tell people.
Yeah, she's just like me
she's a maniac too.
PATRICK O'DELL: Crazy you've
been going with out with her
for so long.
JAMES KELCH: 14 years,
15 years now.
PATRICK O'DELL: You're
going to have kids?
JAMES KELCH: Probably not.
PATRICK O'DELL: Never?
JAMES KELCH: I'm still a kid.
I run the streets
like a maniac.
I'm a 37 year old man, who just
wakes up, takes a shower,
eats food, plays PlayStation,
goes skating.
Then I come home and
do it all again.
I'm going to do till
I can't walk.
That's why I'm growing
my hair.
When I can't no more and
I can't skate, then
I'll move to Hawaii.
And I'll push around on a long
board and wax surfboards at a
surf shop or eat coconuts.
That's my dream.
But my girl don't
want no kids.
And I can't have one
on my own, so
we'll see what happens.
But she's changing as
she's getting older.
She might come around.
She's a rager too.
She just smokes the bong
and works hard, man.
She earns a lot of money to
take care of her mom.
PATRICK O'DELL: Is
that her mom?
JAMES KELCH: Yeah.
You guys have to take
care of her?
JAMES KELCH: Oh, totally.
She got cancer real bad.
Then they beat it, the
shit came back
gnarly, like fuck you.
Here's the banks.
You can't skate right
now, though.
It's open.
You'll go to jail.
But I actually heard them
talking to a sheriff and
talking to the skate shop.
They might make it to where
we're allowed to skate here
when they're closed.
And they'll put a trash
can and everything.
PATRICK O'DELL: Wait, is where
the Boneless was invented?
JAMES KELCH: Yeah, right here.
GSD Boneless
PATRICK O'DELL: What year
was that, you think?
JAMES KELCH: '82, '83, something
like that , I guess?
'81 even?
I don't know.
Because I can remember being
in Santa Cruz in '86 , when
the Russian Boneless was
the brand new trick.
PATRICK O'DELL: The
Russian Boneless?
JAMES KELCH: Yeah.
I was sitting there.
I had an ATV, an all terrain
vehicle, Schmitt stick.
So kid comes up to me, some
man, actually, to me.
And he was like, "have
you seen scales, eh?
Have you seen the Russian
Boneless?
I was like, no.
Showed it to me.
I learned it next day.
PATRICK O'DELL: What is it?
JAMES KELCH: I just filmed it,
dude, in this little video
clip I have on YouTube or
wherever the hell it's at.
It's in my friend's video.
I do a Russian Boneless
on a Zip Zinger.
It's where you do a regular
Boneless but then you jump all
over it, this foot and
land this way.
Then you jump back
on your board.
PATRICK O'DELL: Who are the
best skaters from Ohio?
JAMES KELCH: Cincinnati?
Kokomo Joe, Gary Collins,
Ned Keller.
Dave Cato just turned pro for
[INAUDIBLE] or whatever.
Here's the hit.
This wall, right here.
You see how we've been hitting
the top of it up.
It's fucking gnarly.
Anyway, illest thing ever,
though, is I've seen Al Davis
do a Backside 180 to Fakie
Nosegrind on it into the bank.
[MAN TALKING]
PATRICK O'DELL: We're just
talking about skateboarding.
Well this is one of the original
skateboarding spots
in all the world.
And we're filming it and
talking about it.
Do is you see a skateboard
under my feet?
I know I already went to jail
for that a long time ago.
But look under my feet,
no skateboard.
Do you know what they do for
a skateboard trespassing?
You know what happens
at court?
They throw it out.
Yeah, me too.
I go all the time.
How much trouble can you
get for trespassing?
No.
Money.
No jail.
It's not breaking
and entering.
It's only called trespassing.
What are going to go
for, two days?
A half a day?
The fine's like $80.
I'm not arguing with you.
I'm taking about
the bank, man.
Well, call the police then.
I'm going to put a note on the
website that if skate at Dios
and you come out, don't
talk to you.
What do you do for fun?
Talk shit.
Jesus.
"I like for you to put on the
website, this place is longer
good for skateboarding"
Jesus, man.
"I hope you will not skate
here." I got those new shoes
those wheels on them.
I was going to kick flip.
See that's that guy, blood.
He sucks.
Here's the block.
There's skaters on
it right now.
PATRICK O'DELL: Who
are those dudes?
JAMES KELCH: Randoms.
One of them probably be
one of my friends.
PATRICK O'DELL: All skaters in
Cincinnati have long hair.
JAMES KELCH: Yeah,
we're trash.
Jeep ain't going
to let me over?
He is.
Good man.
We just do flat land on this
street and hang out, watch all
the girls, cause there's a
tanning salon right here and
the college is right
on the corner.
But the cops are
here right now.
Alexander busting the dudes.
But Alexander's my buddy.
Watch, I'll go harass him.
He won't bust me.
Looking for a bad guy, man?
ALEXANDER: Yeah.
JAMES KELCH: What'd
he look like?
ALEXANDER: All these posers.
JAMES KELCH: We the
real skaters.
We the real skaters.
Ah ha!
Big Nate!
It's a reunion here
real quick.
BIG NATE: Yeah.
JAMES KELCH: Where it at?
BIG NATE: Hell yeah.
JAMES KELCH: Look at 'em!
Ha ha ha!
Looks like a pod.
NED KELLER: [INAUDIBLE]
JAMES KELCH: Yeah.
NED KELLER: You got hair?
NED KELLER: Damn James.
That's fucking cool.
It's like you got
ear muffs on.
What the fuck's with that?
JAMES KELCH: What'd
you do, shave?
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah, what's
going on man?
Good to see you buddy.
JAMES KELCH: Chilling.
This is the little block.
We all just hang out here and
skate for no reason at all.
PATRICK O'DELL: Nothing
to grind?
JAMES KELCH: Right there.
And if wasn't for me,
it wouldn't be.
I waxed it up and
made it work.
Everyone else was like,
what are doing?
I was like, you got to have
a curb or something, man.
We got a tail-slide over
there, a little
bank down the street.
But there's a lot of
spots around here.
We just look up here and
skate flat ground.
I like this spot.
It makes me happy.
[SKATEBOARD SOUNDS]
NED KELLER: This is my spot.
This is why everyone's
here right now, cause
this where I skate.
Everything you right now before
you is all made by me,
100% complete.
JAMES KELCH: [INAUDIBLE]
JAMES KELCH: Hamilton's
own, Cricket.
NED KELLER: I skated
fly here, for deep.
And now it's like a war zone.
Now I'm not up here to regulate,
it's all junkies and
thugs and fucking dickheads
up here, man.
JAMES KELCH: I won't regulate
no more, man.
I gave up.
NED KELLER: I'll regulate quick
though, as long as I'm
here for a week.
JAMES KELCH: I'm out a lot.
NED KELLER: I broke my finger
last night having to deal with
the junkies, man.
He was down at the bar.
And he was fucking starting
fights and blacked out on
drugs or whatever the fuck
JAMES KELCH: Yeah, as always.
NED KELLER: And he
did it again.
I picked him up by his
sweatshirt, picked him up,
took him out of his seat,
slammed him on the ground.
I drug him through the bar
like this on his back.
He was sliding through
the park.
I pull him like this and
the door on his ass.
It was hilarious.
But whatever.
He had to get kicked out.
JAMES KELCH: Yeah, gotta take
'em out of the game, man.
We beat up junkies now, cause if
it used to be junkies then
we tried to teach 'em.
But they don't listen, so
we beat 'em all up.
What's wrong with
your ankle, man.
NED KELLER: He's
faking a limp.
JAMES KELCH: Walk
straight kid.
KID: Wassup.
Ha ha.
JAMES KELCH: Embarcadero,
I mean, the
block's holding it down.
It's the new Embarco, son.
We just chill here
for no reason.
We're just here.
Want me to do a 350,
first try for you?
Alright.
With my coat on and
a cigarette?
And I ain't skated
in six days?
[SKATEBOARD SOUNDS]
Not first try.
PATRICK O'DELL: Do it again,
we'll just edit it.
JAMES KELCH: Alright.
You'll be to tell, though.
And I just busted my groin.
PATRICK O'DELL: Oh, is
that your camera?
JAMES KELCH: Yeah.
This is how James starts
his car, every time.
Cause I'm not sponsored
by Quicksilver.
NED KELLER: Last time I checked,
I didn't think it's
cause your car, man.
JAMES KELCH: I ain't getting
no Quicksilver money.
Well, you just quit jocking.
PATRICK O'DELL: You think when
you go to other cities like
San Francisco people
don't believe that
Ohio has shitty areas.
JAMES KELCH: Ah, yeah.
I used to tell the guys, back
when I was younger on the
Embarcadero, I'd tell the dudes
all the time, I'd be
like, man, if I brought all
the crazy, natty dudes out
here they'd take this
whole city over.
There's some rough, rugged
individuals.
But most of them are just
backwards as fuck.
Never been to a real place,
don't know anything except
their block.
Real closed in views
about everything.
Like any time anyone around
even hears the word San
Francisco "I heard
about that place.
All faggots."
Here look at this.
From right here, where these
two big 12-storey projects
start, all the way over, as
far as you can see, brick.
All over again, til you see
that red Sheraton, all the
way, all the way, all the
way, all the way--
So right there.
That's nothing but projects
and ghetto.
That's all that is.
You don't even want
to go through it.
It's gnarly.
PATRICK O'DELL: So your
neighborhood is not as bad?
JAMES KELCH: My neighborhood,
like you saw, I just leave my
keys in my car, my boards
on my porch.
UPS just throws the shit.
On the front yard.
Whatever.
Yeah, my neighborhood's fine.
PATRICK O'DELL: Look at
that smoke it's like--
JAMES KELCH: Factories.
It's gross.
Look at all those bubble
places up there.
You see those little white
things in the hill?
It's like some kind of fucking
crazy Avon test on monkeys
factory or something.
PATRICK O'DELL: How do you
drinking and drugs affects
skating or effected
your skating.
JAMES KELCH: Even in my early
interviews and shit, I was
dropping hella little hints.
I would say so much stuff that
strictly referred to me doing
drugs and I was out
of control.
It was hilarious.
PATRICK O'DELL: Wasn't
Hubba Hide Out?
JAMES KELCH: Hubba Hide Out was
named that because me and
people I won't mention, because
there's no reason to
drag them through the dirt.
We'd go out there we would
smoke hella rocks, man.
Crack.
Straight up.
Lots of people that
everybody knows.
So many, you would
never even think.
PATRICK O'DELL: So did
you come up with
the term Hubba, then?
JAMES KELCH: Someone tried to
give me credit for that one
time, like I made up that word.
But nah.
I used to hear the little
ghetto kid saying it.
It's just a slang term for crack
from the ghetto kids.
PATRICK O'DELL: But as a term
that's used in skateboarding?
JAMES KELCH: Ah yeah, for
sure come up with it.
I called it Hubba Hideout.
"Let's go to the
Hubba Hideout.
Let's go to the Hubba.
Let's go to the Hubba."
PATRICK O'DELL: Before people
were even skating there?
JAMES KELCH: But it was called
Hubba, just the spot.
It wasn't even that rail,
down those stairs.
It was actually--
If you went up the stairs
there's a little plaza.
You can sit on benches.
That was Hubba Hideout.
We started noticing that
they could see us from
the building windows.
So we started moving down.
We would hide on the stairs
and the Hubba
would hide our faces.
No one could tell we were
sitting there from the sides.
Back in the day, before it was
actually turned into a skate
spot, people would just be like,
"Oh let's got to the
Hubba." That's where we'd
go drink, smoke
weed, do drugs, whatever.
No one could see.
And then one day, we were
leaving after smoking weed and
drinking and Mike Carol just
flat-out olied the first set
of stairs in and then
rail slid the Hubba.
We all just fell out.
No one even knew.
No one looked at that.
No one was going to say like--
We'd jump the stairs and
thought that was sick,
straight up.
Jumping those stairs was
big back in the day.
That was a big set
of stairs, man.
Hubba Hideout.
Now everywhere is a Hubba,
every spot's a Hubba.
It trips me out.
It's like, what?
That's not a Hubba.
There's only one Hubba, nigga.
There we are.
It didn't turn her off,
she's still running.
Yeah.