previously seemed to indicate that he's
against it
uh... we have a spokesman for murrieta
ca melaka spoke so uh... woman for
discussed his campaign
uh... there's no mistaking his point of
view on this
when you look at is own prior statements
where he makes clear that people's
sexual orientation
is determined that birth
uh... so he seems to be against it now
will he actually sign a bill that would
ban this practice
if that's still in question actually and
we've got a quote from him that leaves
it very much open at this point he says
i'd love to mines just on this stuff in
general
number one i think there should be lots
of deference given the parents and
raising their children
until this is a general philosophy not
that he's built generally
philosophically on bills that mister
testability
to make decisions on how to care for
their children i'm generally a skeptic
of those bills now there could always be
exceptions to those rules and this bill
may be one of the yet his reasoning
doesn't make any sense of the reason i
say that is because we have lost
that prevents appearance for abusing
their kids and a conversion therapy is
abuse there is this is where they use
electric shock therapy and we can you
see it knowledge himself that
homosexuality is not a choice it's
something that you're bored with
so you can't change someone's sexuality
and in essence you're putting that child
to torture so i don't want to present a
favorable bell you know as a moral opt
passed in california that i was very
very happy about and i think that it
would be responsible for chris christine
not to sign up now and i can not even
sure what his justification would be
otherwise i mean we don't use unleashes
anymore in a medical treatment so you
know with the in favor of that the
parent dot that that was ok time need to
have my parental rights to but which is
on my kids and they can get over the flu
or to stop being so
returned to me and i did it doesn't make
any sense it's completely logical and
knowing that he uh... chris christy is
up for re-election in november i'd think
it's very interesting that they are
using this as rival and democratic
senator barbara born is using that as
for uh... primary act act against the
christian right now separate yeah of
course we should bear in mind that she's
really losing by quite a bit now her her
name recognition obviously quite low
levels to chris christie known around
the country so she is suffering from
every now
uh... such as jumping on the issues
using as part of our campaign report her
is intolerance has no place in our state
the governor said he doesn't know much
about gay conversion therapy
but i don't know how much you need to
know
it's a good point guard
look i personally i'm in favor of more
information regardless of if it's uh...
subject i personally find abort
uh... now there's no surprise obviously
that you should jump on that she will
jump on this it has jumped on this
i think that
you could have sort of a a debate look i
i would guess that the the conversion
therapy obviously
uh... it's easy for us to say that it's
torture i think that you could have
counseling or something like that now
you can tell you if i understand i'm
against it but i'm saying it's easy for
us to simply say it is tortured us you
cannot
but if we're looking to convince people
who think that it might be reasonable or
currently in favor of it is not enough
to simply say it's torture
son that's been a more detailed about
what the bill includes so it doesn't
straight out bad a conversion there be
offensive for up people under the age of
eighteen
if you are tied to halt side you would
be able to get dating free conversion
therapy obligor out not sure if god this
bill includes a bit in california fear
above the age of eighteen he would have
to sign some sort of form indicating
that you are aware that this is complete
and utter bullshit and it's not
medically proven to work or anything
like that uh... but
no i i don't even think that you should
have counseling that that tries to
convince you that being gay is wrong and
you should become straight states not
scientifically proven innocent either
child abuse and i've has forced kids to
go into some kind of that their api to
talk to that
a psychologist because his nose like
holidays i would hope
that would agree with the idea that you
can actually get to talk there appear
confident european order to not be
gaining via look at this industries
right now dont having psychologists are
convinced of it but having like priests
who want to get a room and to hug
therapy with these
these kids who think that the medicare
fee what they are going after the
landmark is sparkling and the kids as
rocks off by you know doing is they're
that these therapy sessions and it's not
that it's in that very carefully setting
out making up a tenant for this
yet and let's bear in mind what's
probably underlying first receives for a
waffling on this issue probably has less
to do with him not being as short work
these days and he says that he is
against it
which is admirable i think that if he
was not uh...
i think that the election that's going
on right now for further get the
governorship of new jersey ave
desperately was thinking about
begins probably looking at between
sixteen
now it's interesting because chris
christie has this mystique of being like
the new rebel in the party like he's not
just about out anything
the republican leadership says they
should do generally i think that makes
sense because he does
but the party line more than most
but he's going to be entering into a
national rural republican primary
contest and that's not the place where
being a rebel is going to to benefit you
like
there there are republicans who are very
much in favor of here at the present
because they think that it could be a
democrat
but that's very different story from
uh... beating other republicans in
if he comes out strongly against it and
seems like he's too in favor
of gay marriage and other gay rights
issues
but that's gonna be positive from our
point of view but the people voting
you know in iowa and new hampshire on
the republican side are necessarily
donald gregg