of 550 acres just outside
of Las Vegas.
Wide open expanse of desert,
so we've got
lots and lots of room.
No encroachment--
we're free to basically
develop this
facility as we see fit.
Well, Front Sight is the
creation of Dr. Ignatius
Piazza who's the founder
and director.
He was taking courses under Jeff
Cooper back in the '80s--
a long time ago.
And through the training that he
received under Jeff Cooper
and other national instructors,
he realized that
this was definitely
his cup of tea.
And more importantly, that
he could do it better.
He could reach the masses,
really spread the word.
Spread the doctrine to those
people who needed it.
Not just SWAT cops and special
forces military, but average,
everyday citizens.
MARTIN JONES: My name is
Martin Jones, and I'm
originally from England but
I live in San Diego now.
MALE SPEAKER: And how many times
have you been here to
Front Side?
MARTIN JONES: This
is my third time.
For me, it's a case I get a
chance to actually learn
skills that I've always
wanted to learn.
Not so much for personal
protection, but simply because
I enjoy shooting.
MALE SPEAKER: Why did you want
to come to Front Side?
TYSON MANN: Well actually,
I'm planning on
joining the Navy SEALs.
So I'm going to get some good
handgun training before I go
to basic training.
MALE SPEAKER: Get ahead of
the curve a little bit?
TYSON MANN: Yeah.
MALE SPEAKER: So when are
you going to go enlist?
How does that process work?
TYSON MANN: Actually
in three days.
MALE SPEAKER: In three days
you're going to be signing up?
BRAD ACKMAN: So as you can see
in the background, we have
handgun, shotgun, rifle ranges
we also cater to M16s, Uzis,
martial arts.
We're standing on the rope
and repel facility.
So it's a huge facility,
continues to
grow all the time.
That's really the nature
of the facility.
The training, as I mentioned a
moment ago, is really geared
toward the private citizen.
Those people who want to come
out and learn defensive
tactical skills.
Sometimes we get the hobbyist,
kind of the weekend
enthusiast, and that,
too, is fine.
If this is their social outlet
and they want to channel it
through a productive
activity, firearms
training, that's great.
We're happy to have those
folks as well.
But really we're training
those people who
want to stay alive.
JESSE PEARSON: Hi there.
Jesse Pearson.
P-E- A- R-S- O-N.
MALE SPEAKER: P-E-A- R-S-O-N,
right here.
Have a seat inside.
JESSE PEARSON: Thanks.
CRAIG BISHOP: Here on the range,
your weapon will only
be one of three places--
in the holster, at the ready,
or pointed at the target.
Say again.
Your weapon will only be
one of three places--
in the holster, at the ready
or pointed at the target.
I spent both time in active duty
Army and a lot of time in
the National Guard in the 19th
Special Forces Group.
Been to a lot of places and
doing a lot of Fed missions in
foreign countries with them for
anywhere from two weeks to
a couple months for
the most of it.
Spent a lot of time in
Korea, Thailand.
Right on up here to the 10.
One line, everybody the first
line come up stand right on
one of these little flags.
-Line ASAP!
Ready, fire!
[GUNSHOTS]
JESSE PEARSON: What did I get?
A, B, C or D?
TONY: Oh, I'd give you a
B, that's a strong B.
JESSE PEARSON: For
effort I get a B.
CRAIG BISHOP: If you're
not here, you're late.
We're starting anyway,
right now.
Finger off the trigger.
Let him know that, I shouldn't
have to come up and tell him.
Yell at him.
-Line ASAP!
Ready, fire!
[GUNSHOTS]
MALE SPEAKER: How's your
partner today?
JESSE PEARSON: Tony?
Tony's good, man.
He's very encouraging.
He keeps saying you can do it,
you're going to get it.
He told that lady next
to me not to quit
because she was bummed.
He said don't give up.
He's a man of few words, but
they're well-chosen words.
[GUNSHOTS]
CRAIG BISHOP: You need
to stay alive.
You need to train the way
you want to fight.
Because when you get in
a fight, you will
fight the way you train.
You will not rise
to the occasion.
You will sink to your
level of training.
So make that level of training
as high and as good and
realistic as you can,
because that is what
will keep you alive.
Any questions?
No shooting yourself
on my range.
Challenge!
EVERYONE: Stop or I'll shoot!
[GUNSHOTS]
MALE SPEAKER: How'd it go?
JESSE PEARSON: I don't know.
I think it would've stopped
him, probably.
I don't know if it meets muster
here, but it probably
would have stopped him.
MALE SPEAKER: Problem is,
[INAUDIBLE] take one.
JESSE PEARSON: I got the
top of his crew cut.
CRAIG BISHOP: I never
saw any combat.
Probably one the best trained
guys that never was in combat.
I probably would have, but I
was in Coronado, I was on a
combat dive team.
And prior to 9/11, I was there
on a training operation and
shattered the arm and shoulder
in a rubber raft.
So I was what we refer
to as "broke dick."
Go in to the hospital broken
up, 9/11 happened.
And having operations while
all my buddies ended up in
Afghanistan.
That's just the way
it worked out.
And ready!
[GUNSHOTS]
MALE SPEAKER: Did you feel
a sense of regret
on not being there?
CRAIG BISHOP: Yeah, you spend
that long training and then
something happens and everybody
else you trained
with for years is going
and you're not.
That's the way life
goes, you know?
I guess you'd say it's
good and bad.
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah,
I guess so.
What's your take on the state of
gun rights and gun laws and
the Second Amendment
in America today?
MARTIN JONES: Being British, I
don't know too much about the
Second Amendment.
But I do know it allows you to
use and carry guns in the US.
In Britain, you're not allowed
to anymore and I
think that's very sad.
TYSON MANN: They are really
starting to take away our gun
rights that are in the
Constitution which all of our
laws are supposed to
be based upon.
So that really makes me angry.
CRAIG BISHOP: I would say that
if you really look at it, our
whole Constitution
is in tatters.
We are supposed to be the most
free country in the world.
If you look at it, there's
hardly anything we can do
without buying some kind of a
license, getting government
permission.
TONY LAZADA: I hope it doesn't
come to the point wherein the
law abiding citizens will just
say forget everything, there's
too much bureaucracy red tape.
That won't be a good deal.
ALEX HARPER: Obviously, the laws
have to follow what the
people in the community
want them to be.
But at same time, a lot of
people are just so uneducated
about weapons, about guns.
And a lot of these decisions
are made based on these
reactionary stances
that people have--
just, guns are bad.
TREVOR LATHAM: And I don't
know where the
tide is going, honestly.
I don't know if the country's
becoming more programmed or
less programed, because
it is so polarized.
The crazy anti-gun people are
as crazy as they ever had.
And the crazy rednecks
are crazy rednecks.
FRANK PATTERSON: They think that
they're making us safer,
but they are actually making us
much more in danger every
time they pass a gun law.
[GUNSHOTS]
TONY LAZADA: Who's going to be
left with handguns there aside
from the cops and
the military?
Those that don't care
for the law.
They can get handguns
anywhere, right?
CRAIG BISHOP: You've
got to fill out the
paperwork to buy a gun.
You've got to get permission
from the
government to carry one.
Is that freedom?
FRANK PATTERSON: A free
society is one where
everybody's rights
are respected.
But the government isn't
respecting our rights when
they keep taking them
away from us.
JESSE PEARSON: Anybody
gone through yet?
ALEX HARPER: No, we're actually
using you as a target.
JESSE PEARSON: OK, I'll
be firing, too.
ALEX HARPER: Well, that's good
because you'll be pointed down
range as will I. So that'll be
in a universal position.
JESSE PEARSON: Nice.
MALE SPEAKER: Say that again?
TREVOR LATHAM: The hostage drill
is a live puppy, and if
you miss you kill the puppy.
So, little guy got it.
Poor little guy.
MALE SPEAKER: It's all
for the greater good.
-They got a puppy as well.
MALE SPEAKER: I think I
heard him say stop or
I'll kill this bitch.
KEN GILLETT: Situation is
you're sitting at home
relaxing, somebody starts
beating on your door.
[POUNDING ON DOOR]
Where's my drugs,
motherfucker?
Here I come!
[GUNSHOTS]
Hey buddy, you need any help?
You shot my friend!
Ahh!
[GUNSHOTS]
You missed me!
Here I come!
[GUNSHOTS]
Drop the gun, I'm going
to kill this bitch!
[GUNSHOTS]
And scenario's over, back
to the holster.
JESSE PEARSON: That ruled.
KEN GILLETT: And this guy, he's
beating on your door,
where's my drugs.
You kind of went for the gun,
but you weren't sure whether
it should come out
of the holster.
You're in your home, somebody's
beating on your
door-- unless you sell
drugs, I don't know.
Somebody's beating on your
door, where's my drugs.
Gun comes out to ready.
You want to be ready for this
guy to kick your door in.
You came up, two shots, control
pair right to the
nose, excellent shooting.
Standard response we'd like
to see is to the chest.
JESSE PEARSON: The
thoracic first.
KEN GILLETT: Again, designated
head shots do come into play.
I'm not saying that it's wrong,
but what we'd like to
see is controlled pair
to the chest first.
That's a good shot,
that's in the box.
That round is a problem.
That is now what we call a "to
whom it may concern" round.
That round is headed off
who knows where.
That could hit grandma coming
up the street from the store
with her groceries.
It could hit the baby in the
stroller or the kid at the
park, who knows.
Make sure you're seeing your
sights and they're getting
where they need to be.
Again, we'd like to see
two to the thoracic.
You did not shoot the
guy with the phone.
Why?
JESSE PEARSON: Because he was
there to try and help me.
Not a threatening position, not
saying anything that was--
KEN GILLETT: Had he said I'm
going to beat you over the
head with this phone,
what would you do?
JESSE PEARSON: I would've
said stop or I'll shoot.
KEN GILLETT: Had he raised
it overhead and
advanced toward you?
JESSE PEARSON: Two
in the thoracic.
KEN GILLETT: Good.
That's the exact response
we're looking for.
JESSE PEARSON: OK, great.
KEN GILLETT: The first one's a
little low, still in the box.
Your second one, however,
couldn't be any more centered
in the box.
Right there on the bridge of the
nose is at dead center of
the box, it's exactly what
we're looking for.
JESSE PEARSON: Excellent.
KEN GILLETT: Excellent job
on the hostage shot.
JESSE PEARSON: Thanks
very much.
CRAIG BISHOP: In the dark
it's hard for us
to clearly see everybody.
So we're going to need your help
a lot in maintaining a
safe range.
My finger does not go on the
trigger until I've identified
positively that that's a target
that I want to shoot.
In your house you may
hear the noise,
you're doing the search.
Your finger's on the trigger.
The room's too light
and you come up--
that's the kid sneaking home
through the window.
JESSE PEARSON: I think this is
probably the most excited I've
been the whole time
we've been here.
I can't wait to shoot this.
CRAIG BISHOP: Remember,
we do not start
until the go command.
MALE SPEAKER: [INAUDIBLE] and
then the gun starts flipping.
Maximize the contacts to the
back of [INAUDIBLE].
[GUNSHOTS]
MALE SPEAKER: How'd you do?
JESSE PEARSON: Can you
light me up, Mike?
I don't know, we're about to
find out, moment of truth.
Oh, I'm low a lot.
Oh, not bad, actualy.
Better than I fucking
do in the daylight.
I'm meant to shoot at night.
I'm not meant to shoot
in the daytime.
I'm meant to shoot when
everybody else is asleep.
CRAIG BISHOP: Ready!
[GUNSHOTS]
JESSE PEARSON: Oh!
MALE SPEAKER: Oh, those aren't
head shots, dude.
JESSE PEARSON: This
is fucked up.
MALE SPEAKER: How'd
you do this time?
JESSE PEARSON: Not very well.
MALE SPEAKER: Think
he's dead, man.
JESSE PEARSON: Well, the thorax
I still got a bunch.
MALE SPEAKER: Tell you what, why
don't you take this one?
JESSE PEARSON: All
right, all right.
Maybe I'm better at shooting
never in the daytime
[INAUDIBLE].
[GUNSHOTS]
MALE SPEAKER: How'd you
do this time, Jesse?
JESSE PEARSON: I
don't know man.
Just get that camera and
shove it up your ass.
CRAIG BISHOP: It's the same
thing I'm doing was doing in
the military.
I am teaching these people
skills to stay alive if they
need to do it.
Line ASAP!
Ready, fire!
[GUNSHOTS]