nuclear facilities
of this country.
Jeff Bushaw: For the
Yellowstone super-volcano.
Steve Vanasse: Civil
unrest following
a dirty bomb blast.
Narrator: And
protect themselves.
Derek Price: Boo-yeah!
Narrator: From what they
perceive as the fast
approaching end of the
world as we know it.
Kat Perez: Thomas,
don't give 'em the gun!
Don't give 'em
the gun, Thomas!
Narrator: Next, we
go inside the lives
of two committed
preppers who have
devised extensive plans.
Christine: Okay
we need to speed
this up a little bit.
Come on.
Narrator: Gone
to great lengths.
Bryan Smith: I'm getting
tired of you, like,
tellin' me that
I need to listen.
Ron Hubbard: You are the
most stubborn son of a
bitch I've ever
met in my life.
Narrator: And made huge
personal sacrifices
to ensure their
very survival.
Bryan Smith: I've never
shot a transformer
before so let's
see what happens.
Narrator: The experts
will assess their preps,
to see if they
have what it takes.
Christine: I have no
problem barking orders.
Don't forget, I need
that water over there.
We need some
paper products.
Narrator: To survive.
Ron Hubbard: When I
say kill it, kill it!
Just do what I say!
Narrator: This is
Doomsday Preppers.
Bryan Smith: I've
hunted wild boar.
I've wrestled
alligators.
And I've lived in the
jungles of Costa Rica.
And once I've had to shoot
a man in self-defense.
Narrator: Bryan Smith has
lived an eventful life.
He grew up in
Central Florida,
living off the land.
Bryan Smith: My
father growing up in
South Alabama grew
up very poor working
as a sharecropper.
And so when he moved
down here to Florida,
we still didn't have a
lot of luxury items and
so part of our
bonding with our
father was going
hunting all the time.
But that's how we
kept our freezer full.
Narrator: Bryan didn't
realize it at the time,
but his childhood was
a prepper handbook.
When he grew up and got a
good look at the world,
he was grateful for his
wilderness training
because he thinks he's
going to need it.
Bryan Smith: I'm
preparing for a total
collapse of the U.S.
monetary system.
Ron Hubbard:
(Bleep), Bryan.
Bryan Smith: When
the Chinese start
selling the U.S. dollar,
you're going to see a
collapse of the U.S. dollar.
And when they start
shutting down the banks
that's when you're
going to feel the hurt.
The urban areas are
gonna be a nightmare.
Population densities
are so packed tight.
Grocery stores are few
and far between and the
produce isn't growing
anywhere near where the
people consume it.
Once people start
panicking and
they realize they
can't get food
you're looking
at total chaos.
You're looking
at roving gangs.
You're looking at the
worst-case scenario.
One of the reasons I'm so
passionate about prepping
is because I was raised
to not rely on anybody.
You don't count
on the government,
you don't count
on your neighbors,
you count on
yourself first.
Narrator: The state of
Florida has the fourth
largest population in
the United States and
hundreds more people
move there every day.
With such a high
population,
Bryan fears an economic
collapse will destroy the
infrastructure so that
goods can't be imported,
quickly making
food scarce and
he has a family
of 12 to feed.
Bryan Smith: We've
stockpiled thousands of
cans of freeze-dried food,
along with close to a
ton of rice and beans.
Narrator: Bryan believes
he has enough food
to last his
family one year.
He currently stores
most of it at his
lamination factory, but
his plan is to move it.
He's spent a
quarter-million dollars on
47 acres of land that
will serve as his secret
bug out location
elsewhere in Florida.
But these 47 acres
aren't for growing more
food for his family of 12.
If the economy
is destroyed,
Bryan's plan is to
grow his own money and
create a veritable
doomsday county store.
Bryan: Prepping
isn't just about
surviving the collapse.
It's about rebuilding
afterwards and
we needed to have a
piece of property of
our own where we
could grow resources
that we can either
barter or trade.
Our barter crop would be
tobacco or sugar cane.
By having these products
for barter we can trade
these for other
livestock and
other farm grown goods.
Narrator: Today, tobacco
is a $500 billion
a year industry.
But for Bryan's doomsday
trading post business to
show a profit the world
will have to end.
Bryan Smith: Throughout
history when things
collapse, you'll find that
the items that tend to
bring the most money are
the ones that are kind of
like the bad items, be it
coffee, alcohol, tobacco.
The great thing
about sugarcane,
it's going to
have a couple of
uses in the future.
One is the old
famous one: rum,
which could be a great
barter item down the road.
The other is we could
refine that down to 180
proof and actually run
a generator that we've
converted to work
on alcohol alone.
Narrator: Today,
Bryan's showing Matt,
a childhood hunting buddy,
the ropes of turning
sugarcane into alcohol, so
that Matt can one day join
Bryan's post-apocalyptic
business venture.
Bryan Smith: What's gonna
happen is the alcohol will
vaporize and it's gonna
flow up through this tube
here and then come back
down and condense.
And once it condenses
it'll go into this cooling
tower to cool and as it
goes through then it'll
start dripping out
alcohol on this side.
Matt: Up in my part of
the country in Kentucky
that's called a still.
Bryan Smith: Yeah,
that's basically
what they're doing.
This is something
that if we perfect it,
bring it up to scale;
you could produce
20, 30 gallons a day.
Narrator: In addition
to bartering it,
Bryan's distilled
alcohol will also
power his generator.
Matt: All right, let's
fire this thing up.
Let's see if it runs.
Narrator: Bryan plans
to use his generator to
collect perhaps his
most vital prep.
Bryan Smith: One of the
most important things
in a survival situation is
water or access to water.
Narrator: Finding water
can be a tantalizing
challenge for
Florida-based preppers,
because it's so
close to the surface.
The state sits on top of
the Floridian aquifer,
nearly 100,000 square
miles of water running
under the entire state.
If the grid goes down,
Bryan's alcohol-powered
generator will pump that
water to the surface.
Matt: We got fresh
well water coming out
of the ground, because
of distilled alcohol.
Bryan Smith: Yep.
Now if you run
that for an hour,
at 40 gallons a
minute, you're at
2,400 gallons
in an hour.
So you could run that just
once a week for an hour.
Narrator: If
doomsday comes,
Bryan's entire plan for
pumping water could fall
apart if he can't
grow his sugarcane.
But the tractor he
plans to use to sow his
47 acres of land
runs on diesel fuel
not distilled alcohol.
Bryan's worried an
economic collapse
could bring severe
gas shortages,
so he's on the hunt for
alternative fuel sources.
And he thinks he's
found one in abandoned
electrical transformers.
Bryan Smith:
All right Matt,
I always wanted
to test this out.
Transformers are supposed
to have an oil in it,
mineral oil that we
can run in a tractor.
And of course the power'd
be off when we did this.
Matt: Right.
Bryan Smith: So my goal
is to go ahead and
see if we can just
shoot it with a gun.
Let it drain out.
We'd just put a
bucket and catch it.
What do you think?
Matt: Well, that's
one way of doing it.
You could probably
chainsaw it down too,
but that could get
a little destructive
and messy.
Narrator: Mineral oil
is used as a coolant
in these transformers.
The oil is flammable,
so if it catches fire,
it could be disastrous.
But if it means surviving
if the grid goes down
forever, Bryan's willing
to run the risk.
Bryan Smith: I've never
shot a transformer before,
so let's see what happens.
Matt: Ah, messy
stream, man.
'Cause it's not
flowing clean, is it?
Bryan Smith: Really
could shoot it again.
I think I'd do
a lot better.
Matt: You wanna try it?
Bryan Smith: Yep, let's
see if I can shoot
it one more time.
Matt: Nail it this time.
There you go.
Bryan Smith: Hang on.
Matt: Wow, oil shower.
Bryan Smith:
Come on, Matt;
give me a hand with this.
Well, we'd have to
perfect this later.
I think we uh, put a
funnel on a stick.
Matt: Yeah.
Bryan Smith: Hooked
to a garden hose.
Matt: Need a higher
caliber weapon next time.
Bryan Smith: Yup.
Matt: Grab that bucket.
All right,
lift your end.
Bingo.
Messy but it works.
I think we got
about 10 gallons
all together, Bryan.
We got two buckets.
Bryan Smith: That's
not bad, dude.
Matt: We wasted probably
another 5 gallons
in the beginning, but.
Bryan Smith: That'll run
a tractor all day long.
Narrator: There are
roughly 42 utility
poles per mile in Florida.
Bryan calculates that if
the transformer on each of
those poles contains 15
gallons of mineral oil,
that's 630 gallons of
oil per mile he could
use to power his tractor.
Bryan Smith: All right,
let's try this
thing out, Matt.
[engine starts]
So what do you think?
Matt: It worked.
Narrator: With 47 acres
of valuable resources,
Bryan's worried he
could wind up in the
line of fire of
doomsday thieves and
marauders who'd want to
take his supplies by force.
So to protect his family,
Bryan's turning to a
professional, a man
with the expertise to
build him the ultimate
defensive prep.
Narrator: In January 2012,
Bryan Smith purchased
47 acres of land
in rural Florida,
where he and
his family plan to
ride out the devastating
economic collapse
he fears is looming.
But his goal isn't just
to survive doomsday,
it's to thrive.
Bryan Smith:
Just surviving,
it's half the battle.
The other half of it is
coming back from that.
Narrator: To fill
the void created by an
economic collapse,
Bryan plans to create
a barter economy
of his own.
His farm will be a
veritable doomsday
county store,
supplying himself and
others with tobacco,
alcohol and bullets.
He's spent $100,000
building an assembly
line so that he can
manufacture his own ammo.
Bryan Smith: We have
the capabilities of
manufacturing
our own ammo,
or reloading our own ammo
after it has been used.
Currently we have a
couple hundred thousand
rounds of ammunition and
we have the
capabilities of easily
producing another
150,000 if we needed.
Narrator: Today, he's
instructing his friend,
Matt who plans to join
Bryan during a bug-out,
in what he'll be
expected to do to keep
the ammo assembly
line moving.
Bryan Smith: Let me walk
you through the process,
I'll show you the 380.
Ok, you've got your
automatic primer feed,
your powder and
your shell casings.
And basically,
just raise it up,
put a projectile on,
pull it back down,
it does all the
steps progressively,
they call it.
Matt: How many
can you spit out
an hour like that?
Bryan Smith: This
can be comfortably
about 650 an hour.
Now what you do is as
you're running along
you'll take 'em out and
you've got a caliber gauge
here that is made the
same size as the barrel
on the pistol or the rifle
you're gonna be using.
You slide that in,
it goes down flush,
it's perfect.
It'll run
through the gun.
Matt: Quality check.
Bryan Smith: All
right, you want to
try this real easy?
Matt: So you're saying
I can do about 6,000
of these a day if I
wanna spend an afternoon,
right?
Bryan Smith: Yeah.
Matt: We got an
ammunitions factory here.
Bryan Smith: It adds
up quick you know.
Narrator: Bryan
has set himself up to
manufacture 9 different
types of ammunition,
so that all his
various firearms will
remain fully loaded.
Bryan Smith: One of the
preps that we've done
is over time acquired
a lot of firearms.
If something does
happen we're able to
arm ourselves very well.
We become more of a
force to be reckoned with
so we can keep
away gangs.
Gangs are going to look
for softer targets.
Some of the other
weapons we have are
what they call
any-other weapons.
Like say, one of
them is a walking cane
that shoots a .38
caliber pistol round.
The other is a pen that
shoots a 25 automatic
pistol round and the other
one is a firearm that is
hidden in your sleeve
and just pops out like
a little James
Bond weapon.
If you walk around with
a firearm that looks
aggressive and mean,
it often can get
you into trouble.
These things can be
concealed on you and
you can look like somebody
who's struggling just to
survive and you don't look
like you're aggressive.
Narrator: Even with
multiple firearms and his
own ammunition plant,
Bryan fears his 47 acre
doomsday trading post
could still come under
attack in the chaos
of the apocalypse.
Bryan Smith: My
greatest fear is when
people start panicking,
they do crazy stuff.
Narrator: So to
protect his family,
he's decided
to purchase the
ultimate defensive prep.
Bryan Smith: To keep the
women and children safe,
we realized that
our next step needs
to be an underground
shelter or bunker.
Ron Hubbard: I can help
you prepare for a pandemic
outbreak, a dirty bomb, or
the total collapse of the
world as you know it.
My motto is, better
prepared than scared.
Narrator: A
few years ago,
Ron Hubbard was
just a regular
steel manufacturer based
in Los Angeles,
California.
But then talk of
doomsday got him
thinking about some
serious questions.
Ron Hubbard: Ask
yourself this,
what would you do if
it happened right now?
How would you
protect your family?
Do you have a plan?
Do you have
a place to go?
Narrator: Ron
started shopping
around for a bunker.
But he found few that
he felt were tough
enough to meet
his standards.
So he decided to start
building his own.
Ron Hubbard: I make ten
models of shelters,
anywhere from
$8,000 to $80,000.
I have anything from a
two-man shelter to a
14-man shelter that
I make for stock.
I've done the same
thing for shelters that
Henry Ford did for
the automobile.
I've made 'em affordable
enough that you don't have
to be a multimillionaire
to have a shelter.
Narrator: Ron has had
another Los Angeles based
business selling iron
doors for 25 years.
He used that experience
to design one of the key
features of his bunkers,
an airtight blast door.
Ron Hubbard: See
this bulkhead.
This is our
patented design.
The doors are laser cut;
they close with
laser precision.
I can't even get my
fingernail in there.
You see that, you can't
even see the daylight.
So when this door closes,
it will become an
airtight door.
Someone finds your
hatch on the surface and
they try to drop a smoke
grenade, hand grenade,
gases, anything, you've
got an airlock between the
shelter and the hatch so
the fumes won't get in,
which will give you
time to go through your
escape tunnel come
up underground and
shoot 'em in the
back if you need to.
The people buying
shelters they
may be lawyers, doctors.
But the one that
surprises me the most
is the amount of current
military officers
wanting shelters
for their families.
Narrator: When bunkers
made from shipping
containers are buried,
all the weight of the
ground above pushes
down on the flat roof.
But cylindrical bunkers
distribute that weight
all along their outer edge.
This allows Ron to bury
some of his bunkers as
deep as four stories
underground.
Ron Hubbard: My most
popular type is the
galvanized
corrugated pipe.
What makes these shelters
strong is that they're
round they're galvanized
so they're gonna last
for 200 years, and you
can bury them deeper.
The shelter we're doing
for Bryan is basically
gonna have all the
features of home,
the only difference
is he's gonna be
20 feet underground.
He'll have running water,
he'll have electricity,
he'll be completely off
the grid so he's not
dependent upon
anybody else.
Narrator: Despite two
decades of friendship and
occasionally helping
Ron with his business,
Bryan is still
Ron's client and
one who expects perfection
from his bunker.
Ron Hubbard: This guy's
the ultimate prepper.
He's going to be very
critical of anything I,
I do or uh do wrong, okay,
so I'm gonna make sure
that his shelter is the
best that I can do.
All right, when I
say kill it, kill it.
Just do what I say!
I am the boss;
what I say goes.
Even though these are
bomb shelters, uh to me,
they're homes and
I want them built to
new home standards.
I want Bryan to be blown
away, not literally.
Let's get everything
right the first time.
I can't, I don't have
time to back up and
get anything
done over again.
Dave: Always on
a time crunch.
Always on
Narrator: Ron's confident
he can get the job done.
But when Bryan arrives
for an inspection,
it could be
the end of their
prepping partnership.
Ron Hubbard: You
know some (bleep),
but you don't know
(bleep) about this!
Narrator: Preparing for
economic collapse and
the chaos that may follow,
Bryan Smith has decided to
spend $150,000 on a bunker
to protect his family.
He's commissioned the
bunker from his friend
and shelter manufacturer,
Ron Hubbard and today
he's flying from
Florida to Los Angeles
to check on its progress.
Ron Hubbard: This is
actually yours right here.
Bryan Smith: Tell me what
you've got going so far.
Ron Hubbard: It's
not ready yet.
Bryan Smith: I know.
Ron Hubbard: I mean,
we're just starting to
put the framing in.
Bryan Smith: In
case I want to
change everything around.
What is this?
Is this 3/8ths inch steel?
Ron Hubbard: Yeah, yeah.
That should stop
pretty much every
bullet out there.
Bryan Smith: How about a
gun port or something?
Ron Hubbard: Then you're
gonna give up your,
your airlock
capability if you have
a way that they
could pierce it,
so I don't, I
thought about it and
I don't want to
put one in there.
Bryan Smith: Ron's one of
the smartest people I've
ever seen but whenever
you're speaking to him he
always seems like he's
already figuring out what
he's going to say next
without listening.
Trust me.
Everything that
you've thought of or
will think of, I've
already thought of and
I've shot down or I've
built it into the shelter.
Bryan Smith: All right.
Ron Hubbard: We'll
have this thing done
for you in
probably a week.
Bryan Smith: Really?
Ron Hubbard:
Yeah and it'll be
ready to ship out.
Bryan Smith: Okay.
Narrator: While the
team puts the finishing
touches on the bunker,
Ron travels to Florida
to scout locations on
Bryan's property where
they can bury it.
The proximity of water is
one of the main factors
Ron considers when
installing bunkers.
He wants the bunker buried
close to a water source,
but not in a
potential flood zone,
which could
compromise its safety.
Ron Hubbard: The best time
to go pick the spot for
your shelter is when
you're having an inch of
rain and you can see the
areas that's getting
pounded and the area
that's high and
dry even with the rain.
Bryan Smith: Ron,
I own the property.
I know where
the water zone.
Ron Hubbard: You don't
know every spot where.
Bryan Smith: I've lived
here forever, okay?
This isn't my
first rodeo.
Ron Hubbard: You are
the most stubborn
son of a bitch I've
ever met in my life,
I swear to God.
Narrator: Ron also wants
the bunker buried away
from large structures
that might collapse on
top of it and in an
area with enough space
on several sides for
emergency exits.
But Bryan's impatience
in scouring his 47 acres
for a spot that meets
all of Ron's criteria
is causing
tempers to flare.
Ron Hubbard: You never
think ahead, Bryan.
I mean seriously.
Bryan Smith: Dude, I am
tired of driving around.
Ron Hubbard: You
know some (bleep),
but you don't know
(bleep) about this.
Let me pick the field,
let me put it in and
if for any reason
you don't like it,
I'll pay to pick it
up and move it, okay?
Okay stop.
Right here, right here.
Kill the motor.
This is the
spot right here.
I love this.
You got a water
source right there.
You got a field of view 200
yards in each direction.
Bryan Smith: All
right, I agree.
It's good,
let's do it.
Ron Hubbard:
This is the spot;
this is the spot.
Bryan Smith: All right,
put a stake in there
and put it in the ground.
All right.
Narrator: For a 500 square
foot bunker like Bryan's,
more than 15,000 cubic
feet of dirt will have
to be dug up and then
used to bury the bunker
after it's lowered
into the hole.
While excavation
is underway,
Ron returns to Los Angeles
to finish the bunker
and truck it the 2,500
miles to Florida.
He's also bringing a
special team of workers.
For security
and secrecy,
none of them
know the area.
Ron Hubbard: When I put
a shelter in the ground,
I typically will bring a
contractor in from out of
state so the customer
doesn't have to worry
about a local guy
knowing that he has a
shelter in the ground.
So he doesn't have to
worry about the guy
showing up at his shelter
in case of a crisis.
So we use as few local
resources as possible.
The shelters are
buried 20 feet deep.
That basically means
that you're gonna end up
with 10 foot of dirt
on top of your roof.
Which is more than
enough protection
from gamma radiation.
It is also deep enough
that you have enough dirt
and sod above you
that you're going to
keep a constant
temperature down there.
We got it.
Whoa.
Hold it.
We put this rock down
here so the radius
doesn't squash when
all the downward force
and all the dirt
is filled in on top.
So it needs that support.
I knew I should have
been a stockbroker.
Do you want me to choke
the chain a little more?
Dave: This is gonna
be the escape tunnel,
which is probably
gonna go straight up
or off to the side.
Ron Hubbard: Go down.
Okay, hold on.
Narrator: The final
piece to be installed
before the bunker
is buried entirely is
the main entry
blast hatch.
Ron Hubbard: Hatch
is coming in.
Come this way
about two inches.
Narrator: Ron's so
confident Bryan will
love his new
doomsday shelter;
he buried it before
Bryan inspected it.
But when Bryan gets
his first look inside,
his reaction may not be
what Ron was hoping for.
Ron Hubbard: Welcome to
your new home, Bryan.
Narrator: Bryan Smith is
about to get his first
look at his newly
installed bunker.
Ron Hubbard: I'm excited
for him to see it.
It's always a fun thing
to see your shelter
for the first time.
Welcome to your
new home, Bryan.
Is this cool?
Bryan Smith: Yeah.
Ron Hubbard: I put you in
a bathtub with a shower.
I put a flushing toilet.
You're gonna
like this Bryan.
A dinner table.
Sit down.
Bryan Smith:
I like this.
You know why?
Most people don't
realize a major part
of our survival
is just eating.
And when you're in a
stressed situation like
this, it gives you some
sense of normalcy when you
can sit back down with
your family, eat a meal.
I like that.
Has this got
storage under it?
Ron Hubbard:
Yeah, yeah.
Under the bench.
Bryan Smith:
Good deal.
Ron Hubbard: There's
no space left unused.
Anywhere I can put
storage I got storage.
Narrator: Ron's
added additional
storage under the floor.
3 foot deep compartments
run the length of the
bunker, enough room to
store a year's worth of
freeze-dried food
for ten people.
Ron Hubbard: I
stacked this thing
with a bunch of food.
Bryan Smith: Oh, yeah.
Ron Hubbard: And
55 gallon drums.
Look at this.
Down here I've got
all your appliances.
Your hot water heater.
Your macerator pump.
Your hand pump.
Bryan, this is probably
the most important thing
in the whole shelter.
This is your NBC air
filtration system.
Bryan Smith: Right.
Ron Hubbard: This is
what's gonna filter out
anything that's in the air
that's gonna kill you.
It's gonna come through
this pipe here,
it's gonna filter
through this and
it's gonna make
it breathable air.
Narrator: Extended stays
in confined spaces can
cause psychological
stresses leading to
restlessness, depression
and irritability.
So to keep Bryan and his
family from going stir
crazy in the bunker, in
addition to survival
essentials, Ron's
also included many
comforts of home.
Ron Hubbard: I put you
an electric fireplace,
a big screen TV.
Bryan Smith: I like that.
Ron Hubbard: A microwave,
a refrigerator
with freezer.
DVD player.
Bryan Smith: These
are recliners?
Ron Hubbard: Yes, yeah.
Both sides recline.
So you can sit back
and watch your TV.
Sit down here.
This is your
command center.
Bryan Smith: All right.
Narrator: This computer
station monitors
aboveground surveillance
cameras that will allow
Bryan to see what's
going on topside.
Ron Hubbard: I got four
surveillance cameras,
high definition.
Now look at this, see
that hatch right there?
Bryan Smith: Right.
Ron Hubbard: Watch this.
Hold on.
I'm going to run
up real quick.
Bryan Smith:
What an idiot.
Ron Hubbard:
Is that cool?
Bryan Smith:
Yeah, that's cool.
Ron Hubbard: Nobody's
going to get the
jump on you, buddy.
Narrator: If the
cameras spot attackers
at the main hatch, Bryan
will have to decide
whether or not to
attempt a clandestine
escape through
the bunker's other
secret access port.
Ron Hubbard: One
of the unique features
about all my shelters
is that they have
an emergency
escape hatch.
Somebody's trying to
get in the front door,
I'm gonna go to my escape
tunnel, I'm gonna go up,
release the sand out of
my emergency escape box,
let the sand come down,
then I'm gonna
start digging out.
Narrator: To protect
the bunker's inhabitants
from gamma radiation
in the event of a
nuclear explosion,
Ron's put a 10 foot
insulation layer of sand
between the escape hatch
and the surface hatch.
Bryan must first drain
some of the sand to
avoid being smothered
when opening the hatch.
Ron Hubbard: 7 minutes.
Bryan Smith: 7, yup.
Ron Hubbard:
You dog you.
Bryan Smith: When
you're on a sailboat
and you see
a storm coming,
you inflate
your life raft.
That's what
prepping is;
you've got
that life raft.
Once you've
got it set up,
you don't
worry anymore.
Now you don't live
your life in fear.
It don't get no
better than this.
Ron Hubbard: It don't.
Bring on doomsday, huh?
Whoo!
Narrator: Bryan,
the experts at
practical preppers have
assessed your preps.
You have a good
amount of food stored,
but your well is currently
your only water source.
You should create
a backup supply by
collecting
rainwater in barrels,
in case your pumps
are compromised.
Bryan Smith: The well,
the well will not fail.
We have redundant
resources but uh,
I have no intentions of
collecting rainwater.
Narrator: Your shelter
preps are strong,
but due to Florida's
humid climate,
you need to find methods
of keeping cool,
especially during
the summer.
Bryan Smith: I agree.
Our climate's very
hot and very tough.
We're currently
working on a
low energy alternative.
Narrator: To determine
how long you could
initially survive
a catastrophe,
practical preppers
has scored your preps
in 5 categories
of 20 points each,
for a total
possible score of 100.
Food, you should
grow edible crops
along with your
tobacco and sugarcane.
17 out of 20 points.
Water, 13 out
of 20 points.
Shelter, 19 out
Security, you have
abundant weapons
and ammunition,
but require
tactical training.
14 out of 20 points.
Your plan to grow
resources for
bartering gives you
15 x-factor points.
Overall you get 78
out of 100 points.
You have 16 months
initial survival time.
Bryan Smith: Well, I think
that's a little ridiculous.
My family's lived
here for 9 generations,
150 years, and
over 100 of that was
without electricity
or giant water stores.
I think we're
very prepared.
I think your experts
are a little off.
Since filming, we've
continued to add to
our store of
food supplies.
We bought some of
the most advanced
body armor out
there, lightweight.
Pretty nice stuff.
By far one of the most
interesting thing is,
since going through the
process of buying a
shelter and watching
it being made and
installing it,
I've started
promoting the
shelter business to
tell everybody else
out there to be safe.
Narrator: In spite of
the recent recession and
European debt crisis,
most economists believe
a near-term depression
is unlikely and the odds
of a global collapse
that would result in
a severe breakdown
of society are remote.
Many preppers
in the U.S. are
worried about
homegrown threats like
an economic collapse or
dirty bomb attacks.
But not Christine H.
She believes death
is coming for her
and her family.
Christine: Okay, we
need to speed this
up a little bit.
Narrator: And that
it's stalking them
from 3,500 miles away.
Christine: Hey, Randy?
Randy: Yes, dear.
Narrator: Christine
H. runs a tight ship.
Christine: Can you
get that chicken for
me in that Ziploc
bag there?
Narrator: She's
a perfectionist.
Christine: No
fuss, no muss.
Narrator: A
task master.
Christine:
Knock it off.
This isn't the time
to be messing around,
understood?
Narrator: And her
husband, son and
two young daughters
have learned not
to let her down.
Christine: They know
the drill, you know?
Don't cross me!
Narrator: But
Christine's not some
harried housewife.
Christine: Give
mama just a few
more minutes to
wrap this up.
Narrator: She believes
her discipline,
determination and
organization could be
all that stand
between her family
and a potential killer
3,500 miles away.
One she fears will one
day wash away her home,
along with the
entire East Coast
of the United States.
Christine: I am preparing
for a mega tsunami.
Come on, come
on, come one.
Let's go.
Randy: Whoa!
Chuck Connolly:
One minute!
Narrator: In 2003,
Hurricane Isabel struck
the East Coast and a
mandatory evacuation
was ordered in
Christine's county
in the Virginia Beach area.
Christine left and watched
as Isabel killed 47 people
and caused more than
$4 billion of damage.
Christine: You can't
imagine what I saw,
even when I came back.
There were down
power lines,
trees were lying
everywhere.
Standing water.
If that wind had
taken a turn,
I would have no more
house here today.
I knew I had to be
better prepared for the
next time a situation
were to come up.
Narrator: Christine
started digging into
other natural disasters
and potential threats.
Christine: I am looking
at a ton of stuff.
Different news
and documentaries
that have been done.
One of the regions that
I follow real closely
is the Canary Islands.
Narrator: 3,500 miles
away on the Canary Islands
off Africa lives
an active volcano
called Cumbre Vieja.
If it blows, some
scientists believe half
the volcanic mountain will
crumble into the ocean.
The colossal landslide
could cause a splash close
to 3,000 feet high and
several miles wide.
The result would
be a mega-tsunami,
a 500 mile per hour
wave taller than any
in recorded history.
Christine:
A mega-tsunami
for this area of Virginia
would be horrific.
A lot of these houses are
prefab, vinyl siding.
There isn't much
protection.
My house would explode in
the case of a tsunami.
Let's take a look here.
Narrator: Traveling
at 500 miles per hour,
as fast as a
commercial jet,
the 8 story tall wave
Christine fears could
cross the Atlantic Ocean
in fewer than 7 hours.
But if the time comes
that she has to bug-out,
Christine doesn't want to
evacuate empty-handed.
So she's on a mission to
create a stockpile of
supplies that
can be defined by
two simple words,
portable preps.
Christine: I have
a ready room.
I have a place to go and
gather supplies
that I need.
My ready room is
actually a two-car garage
that we've converted.
All we have to do is
back the vans up and
load it up.
I don't have to
run around the
house collecting
everything.
It's right here
ready to go.
Narrator: For Christine,
the key to portable
prepping lies
in categorizing,
organizing and
inventorying her
emergency
disaster supplies.
Christine: I
am the prepper
chick of organization.
Because the ready room
is organized we'd be
able to quickly load
up three months of food,
have our water,
have our belongings,
get it in and get it out.
About two to four
hours a day are spent
on our preps.
What I do is I decide
what's most important
for that month.
Some months I might
have $200 to spend.
have a little bit more.
That's no different than
what the average person
spends in Wal-Mart
each month.
Come on in.
Narrator: Today, Christine
has invited her niece,
Laura and her
friend Chrissy,
into her home to
reveal her secrets of
prepping organization.
Christine: This
is what I've been
telling you about.
This is what
I've been doing.
We have an
area for the food,
an area for
tools, first aid.
Water.
See those large, 4
gallon jugs up here.
We have a wall of
refrigeration and
then I have a canning
section as well for
all of my
food preservation.
I started with the cabinet
over the top of my stove,
which is this wide by
this wide by this deep.
And it was filled
with lots of Spam.
Laura: And now
you have this.
Christine: And
now I have this.
Even our bucket.
What do you think
our bucket's for?
Chrissy: If you
put a seat on top,
I could imagine.
Bella: A toilet!
Christine: Absolutely.
That's right.
It's better than
coppin' a squat.
Even for the kids
we have a potty seat
just ready to go.
Just flips up, sits
right on there.
I've covered everybody,
right down to their hiney.
Look at that!
Laura: Christine's
ready room is amazing.
There's so many things I
would not have thought I
personally would have
needed in this situation,
whereas she feels
like every situation
she's got covered.
Narrator: To be able to
bug-out with as much as
possible, Christine has
learned organizational
tricks to consolidate
her food preps,
like storing
an entire meal of
freeze-dried
foods in one jar.
Christine: We're gonna
make a meal in a jar.
What this is gonna do is
take our food storage down
to a smaller capacity
and we're gonna have a
complete meal ready to go.
From these
ingredients here
we can put together
a quick soup.
Daughter: So this
is like a dinner?
Christine: This
is a dinner.
That fits in a jar.
I want you
to go ahead and
just get about
half a scoop there.
We're gonna start
with a meat base.
What I have
here is chicken.
What's something else
that's great to go along
with protein when
you're thinking of a
survival situation?
Carbohydrates.
And we want our
jars to be colorful.
We have some carrots,
corn, a little celery.
You have your
antioxidants,
you have your vitamins,
you have your minerals;
this is a healthy meal.
I would also suggest,
drop a chicken bouillon
cube in here and that's
gonna give you all
your chicken seasoning
and everything.
You're gonna
simply add about
one cup of water to
this whole thing.
Let it sit.
And then you can
actually heat this up
straight in the jar.
This here is going
to be good for about
six months to a year.
Chrissy: Wow.
Narrator: Christine
believes her obsession
with organizing her preps
could be the difference
between life and death
if the Cumbre Vieja
mega-tsunami strikes.
But when she puts her bug
out plan to the test,
her insistence on
taking it all with her
could lead to disaster.
Narrator: Christine
H. is preparing
for a mega-tsunami
she fears will be
triggered by a massive
volcanic eruption
in the Atlantic Ocean.
She believes the colossal
wave would wipe out her
Virginia home and
cause mass devastation
along the
entire East Coast.
Christine: Following a
tsunami the East Coast of
this country is gonna be
inundated with water.
Narrator: Christine
plans to evacuate to
higher ground, a friend's
house at an undisclosed
location further inland.
Michael: You're good.
You're doing great.
Stop.
Narrator: But she's also
determined to also leave
with enough supplies to
last her family three
months as they start over.
Christine: In a (bleep)
hits the fan situation,
we're takin' our
stuff and goin'.
Narrator: A transoceanic
tsunami can travel
as fast as a jet plane.
At that speed, the
tsunami that Christine
fears could cross the
ocean from Cumbre Vieja
and hit America's
East Coast in
fewer than 7 hours.
So Christine
has been making plans
for a rapid getaway.
Christine: I think
one of the key elements
for any prepper
is to be organized.
So I've just made
sure there's a
place for everything.
You walk in and it's
nice, neat and orderly.
We know exactly
what we need and
where to get it from.
I need your help.
Narrator: But while
her preps are organized
for rapid retrieval,
Christine's bug out
plan is still
a work in progress.
Today, she's going
to test it and
her family for speed.
Christine: If you've ever
even just tried to leave
for the beach, you know
how chaotic it could be
and something will always
is left in the driveway.
You don't wanna be
second guessing
yourself wondering
what you've forgotten.
Narrator: She's giving her
son and husband 30 minutes
to load everything they
need into the trailer.
Christine: Okay,
guys, I'm gonna want
you to start over here.
Don't forget I need
that water over there.
We're working on the
sanitation over here.
You have the
maps, the candles,
the can opener, the
knives, the matches,
the lighters,
the batteries?
I believe under pressure
women are more detail
oriented and men
on the other hand,
they're your brawn,
they're your strength.
So we can use that
to our advantage.
If we're organized and
then we can put them
to work to get
the job done.
We got our water.
Randy: Yup.
Christine: Randy's
the strong silent type
whereas I have no
problem barking orders.
We need some
paper products.
Toilet paper, tissue.
Don't forget over here,
I need all the milk.
Okay, we need to speed
this up a little bit.
Come on.
I see one important
thing that's been left.
Somebody please.
No, what's up
there that I want?
Grab the potty.
Daughter: No!
Christine:
Knock it off.
This isn't
the time to be
messing around,
understood?
They know the
drill, you know?
Don't cross me!
Who said they
grabbed the cooler?
Michael: We already
have the other cooler.
Christine: You're
not taking this one?
Michael: I
guess we can.
Christine:
Coolers float.
I won't be
caught off guard.
I'm obsessed with being in
control of the situation
and having an answer
for it and having the
resources in which
to draw upon to take
care of my family.
Come on,
come on, come on.
Let's go.
Come on.
Narrator: Christine's
trailer is loaded and
they're on the
road in 30 minutes,
but many preps are left
behind in the rush.
If the more than one
million people in her
area are also
trying to escape,
she fears that they may
not be able to get out
by car no matter how
quickly they move.
So to avoid losing time,
she plans to make
her getaway by raft.
Christine: If we had to
leave here and there was
too much congestion
on the interstate,
we literally could
just drop right in the
water and we're gone.
Narrator: This
Intracoastal Waterway
is a 3,000 mile long
liquid highway that
stretches along the
Atlantic and Gulf coasts
and has an entry
point fewer than
10 miles from
Christine's home.
Chuck Connolly:
I'm Chuck.
Narrator: Today,
Chuck Connolly,
an eco tour guide and
kayaking instructor,
is going to
help Christine's
family test
out their Plan B.
Chuck Connolly:
Okay everybody!
Countdown starts
right now.
We're gonna time them
so I have an idea of
how fast they can move
and then just talk
about the general things
they're gonna need
to do in a
boat to survive.
Randy: Good job.
Christine: C'mon.
Eli: That's good.
Chuck Connolly: The raft
is not a bad scenario.
It does fit nicely
into the van.
Uh, personally I would
probably have kayaks.
A little more sturdy,
a lot faster to move.
Narrator: 30
minutes after arriving
at the dock, Randy and
Michael have inflated
the three rafts and
are ready to start
transferring
all their preps.
It is now an hour and
a half since Christine
began the
evacuation drill
and five and a
half hours until
the hypothetical
mega-tsunami strikes.
Chuck Connolly: Christine,
if I were you I would go
ahead and get those two
girls and the dog in one
raft and go ahead
and get on the water.
You have to practice
a lot before you
pursue any of
these things.
If you've never
blown up your rafts,
if you've never
put them together,
paddled them, uh,
I think your
likelihood of survival
goes down a lot.
Daughter: Mom!
Michael: Very
good, Mom.
August!
Come on pup!
Let's go.
Let's go, let's
go, let's go!
I know you're tired.
Let's go!
Narrator: By the time
they're on the water with
all their preps,
two hours have
passed since the
drill began.
Chuck Connolly: So now
we gotta figure out
if we can paddle
these things, right?
Narrator: And according
to Chuck's GPS,
Christine and her
family aren't paddling
faster than 1.2
miles per hour.
At this rate, the deadly
tsunami Christine fears
would hit Virginia before
she and her family could
paddle to their safe
house on high ground.
Chuck Connolly: Okay,
let's call time here
with the flood coming.
You got everything loaded.
But you guys are now being
swept down this waterway.
So what could we
have left behind?
Family: The dog.
Chuck Connolly: The dog.
The dog probably
would have chased,
eventually, would have
come into the water.
You had probably a
fairly good chance of
hooking up with
him later.
Don't get me wrong,
I love my dogs but
when it comes
to doomsday,
they're gonna have to
fend for themselves.
Narrator: Having
watched them struggle
to load all their preps,
Chuck thinks Christine
and her family need to
reevaluate their plan.
Chuck Connolly: Okay,
so I saw lots of things
but I guess
what's important
is what did you
get out of this?
Any changes
need to be made?
Christine: Absolutely.
Randy: Oh sure,
less load.
Chuck Connolly: When I
look at these boats,
if one of them
had flipped,
how much of the
stuff would have
stayed attached?
Michael: Nothing.
Nothing at all.
Chuck Connolly: Okay.
Christine: Aww, that's
what you're talkin'.
Randy: But under
the gun, you know.
Chuck Connolly: Their
priorities aren't
really where
they need to be.
I kept hearing the
word essentials and
I was seeing things
I didn't think were
quite essentials
here and there.
I guess the most
glaring one that jumped
out was the
paper towels.
Christine:
Toilet paper!
Randy: Yeah, but
we've got three girls.
Michael: Hey man,
we got three girls,
come on man.
Chuck Connolly: The giant
package of toilet paper.
That was pretty worthless.
It took up a lot of room
and it wasn't packaged,
it wasn't sealed.
It was just ready
to get wet and
be a bunch of garbage.
Christine: I
gotta tell you,
my own performance,
I'm not too impressed.
We were slow.
I'm, I'm not confident
in our speed at all.
It's something
that definitely
has to be worked on.
This just really makes
me rethink Plan B.
I think we're
gonna have to make
some adjustments in it.
Narrator: Christine,
you have a substantial
amount of food
and water stored.
However, in the event
that you have to bug out,
you'll need to bring it
all with you or risk
leaving yourself
vulnerable to
thirst and dehydration.
Rather than attempt to
travel with everything
you might need, you
should invest more time
establishing preps at
your bug out location.
Christine: I agree
with the assessment.
I see where some
improvements need
to be made and
that's where we're
gonna begin tomorrow.
Narrator: To determine
how long you could
initially survive
a catastrophe,
practical preppers
has scored your preps
in 5 categories
of 20 points each,
for a total
possible score of 100.
Food, you should
focus on hunting and
trapping skills, so
you have a re-supply
plan wherever you go.
11 out of 20 points.
Water, 14 out
of 20 points.
Shelter, you only
have enough fuel to
power your small
generator for a few days.
8 out of 20 points.
Security, 7 out
of 20 points.
You are very well
organized and
this will help you
during a bug-out.
11 x-factor points.
Overall, you get 51
out of 100 points.
You have five months
initial survival time.
Christine: We
better get busy.
There's work to do.
Narrator: Scientists
believe Cumbre Vieja
erupts roughly
every century and
it may take several
eruptions for the
volcano to
collapse entirely.
The probability of it
unleashing a mega-tsunami
in any given year is low.