our 13th president here at
the University of Michigan.
And we are so proud that Time
Magazine has named President
Coleman one of the 10
best university presidents
in United States.
[ Applause ]
And she's just finished her year
as the chair of the Association
of American Universities
where she ably represented
North America's leading
research universities.
And as our president, she
has been very diligent
about broadening the
university's reach
and impact whether in
Detroit or in Brazil.
And throughout her leadership,
she's been a strong advocate
of the contributions,
creativity, and the innovation
of Michigan student,
staff, faculty, and alumni.
And most importantly, for
the Board of Regents we are
so excited because Mary
Sue Coleman has brought us
so many wonderful research,
resources from raising money,
and that of course is needed
very much to help our faculty,
staff, and students do all
the great work that they do.
So please join me in welcoming
the president of the University
of Michigan, Dr.
Mary Sue Coleman.
[ Applause ]
>> Well, good morning!
[Multiple Speakers] And
thanks to all of you
for braving the weather out
there to be here with us.
And thanks to all those
who are here virtually
around the campus.
Our thoughts are certainly
with those on the East Coast
who endured Hurricane
Sandy last night
and the aftermath this morning.
We gathered in this space a year
ago, and I believe we were lucky
to squeeze onto the
October calendar this year.
When Steve Ross made his
historic gift 8 years ago,
we knew that it would
elevate everything
about the business school.
But I don't think anyone would
have predicted the demand
for this view that you
see out the windows.
So thank you, Steve, and thank
you to the Ross Business School
for hosting us this morning.
This is a special year,
for me personally,
and more significantly, in
the life of the University.
I've had the privilege now
of leading the University
for 10 years, and it's been
a decade of challenges,
transformation and
tremendous momentum.
I continue to be energized
by the life-changing work
of this institution, and by
the contributions of leaders
like you from all
three campuses.
When we talk of Michigan and
impact, the one name rises
above all others,
Raoul Wallenberg.
I hope you know his story.
After earning his architecture
degree here in 1935,
he went on to become one
of the most noted humanitarians
of the last century.
As a diplomat in Budapest,
Raoul Wallenberg
repeatedly risked his life
to rescue thousands of Jews
from World War II's
concentration camps.
He pulled them from
moving boxcars.
When Nazis forced them to walk
to the camps, Wallenberg chased
after them, shoving food
and medicine their way.
He found countless ways
to shelter terrified men,
women and children
trying to survive
in what was then the
last surviving ghetto
of Jews in Europe.
He saved some 100,000, 100,000.
And then he disappeared
at the hands of strangers.
We are still seeking
answers about his fate.
This year, 2012,
is the centennial
of Raoul Wallenberg's birth.
I can't think of no
more important occasion
to dedicate our work
as a university
to the values he lived.
He loved to learn, he had
an appetite for adventure,
and he embraced new people
and different places.
He was and is a hero
of the highest order.
He showed us, more than
any Michigan graduate,
that one person can
make a difference.
Could we, as students
and scholars,
ask for greater inspiration?
The University of Michigan
is indeed an inspiring place.
And that's because of the
ideas, discoveries and service
of our students,
staff and faculty.
In the room today, we have
students like Conor Lane,
an honors senior who
works as both an RA
at the Residential
College and a volunteer
at the Spectrum Center.
And Jasmine Injejikian,
who is leading this
year's Dance Marathon.
That's hundreds of students
dancing for 30 straight hours
to raise thousands for
children with disabilities.
We're joined by staff
like Dan Rife,
an engineer who combines
new technologies
with human expertise to
conserve energy throughout our
campus buildings.
And Lieutenant Colonel
Lisa Franz,
who leads our ROTC
program, Air Force ROTC,
one of the three officer
training programs at Michigan.
We have faculty like
Carla O'Connor,
an engaging Thurnau Professor,
who is bringing her love
of teaching and mentoring
to the dean's office
in the School of Education.
And professors like
Michael Boehnke,
a world-class statistical
geneticist
from the School of
Public Health.
His breakthroughs help us
better understand the heredity
of diabetes, bipolar disorder
and other debilitating diseases.
I also want to recognize four
deans who are in the final year
of their leadership tenures.
Terry McDonald in the
College of Literature, Science
and the Arts, Evan Caminker of
the Law School, Peter Polverini
of the Dental School,
and Paul Courant
of the University Libraries.
These four have carried out
extraordinary work in one
of the University's most
challenging fiscal eras.
Their programs are
collectively stronger
because of their good work.
I also want to acknowledge
Fran Blouin, who is stepping
down as the longest-serving
director
of the Bentley Historical
Library.
Fortunately for our students,
he will be devoting himself full
time to the classroom next fall.
At Michigan, we know-- because
it is borne out each day--
that our diversity
is the backbone
of our academic strength.
Diversity is a core value of
this institution, in this room,
across our campuses, and
wherever the University
of Michigan is in the world.
In the course of my decade
here, I have taken great pride
in Michigan being the nation's
leading voice for the value
of diversity-- in the
classroom, in the research lab,
and in all parts of the
academic enterprise.
But it's not simply an
outcome of the last decade.
This is deeply embedded in our
culture and sense of identity
from the University's
earliest days.
The first black woman in America
to train as a dentist did
so here-- more than
100 years ago.
As did the first
African-American woman
to earn a doctorate in physics.
When an Ivy League school
rejected Jose Barbosa in 1877
because of his race,
Michigan welcomed him.
Our students said they did
not care about his skin color.
In their words, what truly
mattered was "the quantity
and quality of brains
in the cranium."
Brains in the cranium.
Dr. Jose Celso Barbosa would
go on to become the father
of statehood for his
native Puerto Rico.
This legacy of inclusion
and leadership brings
with it a deep responsibility
to live out our values.
We work hard at creating
and sustaining a community
where diversity is sought and
valued across all pathways--
racial, ethnic, gender, LGBT,
global and socioeconomic.
We still have much work to do.
That's why I am so pleased
that LSA will launch
a new theme semester
in January, Understanding Race.
It is an important example of
just how critical it is for us
to think substantively
about race and identity
and to encourage a thoughtful
dialogue about these issues.
I am a firm believer that
knowledge is contingent.
The work we do today, and the
accomplishments we celebrate,
would not be possible
without the faculty,
staff and students
who came before us.
When this year's Nobel Prize
for medicine was announced,
one of the winners
was recognized
for research he carried
out 50 years ago.
Fifty years.
His discovery about tadpole
cells has a direct impact
on stem cell research
conducted today,
including in our laboratories.
This is the beauty and
power of scholarship.
The commitments we make
today will have an impact 20,
30 and 50 years from now.
That's why I'm excited
to share with you some
of our most significant
achievements and challenges,
as well as several announcements
that will take Michigan
in new directions.
Let's begin with the arts.
The Michigan environment
for arts
and creativity is remarkable.
Remarkable because it is of a
scope and scale you won't find
at other national
research universities.
We make art, we research art, we
present art and we preserve art.
It can be in this weekend's
performance of Urinetown
by UM-Flint theater students.
Or the Kelsey Museum's
study of antiquities.
It is the exhibit of priceless
Armenian books at UM-Dearborn.
Or Band-o-rama at Hill
Auditorium itself a work of art
and a campus icon
for the past century.
We do art and science very well.
What binds the two is our
capacity for creativity.
And that is because of a culture
that encourages creative work
and creative approaches.
It is an environment in which
the University has invested 84
million dollars since 2004.
That includes a stunning
addition to the Museum of Art,
a Symphony Band tour
of China, new programs
for architecture students, and
more studio and gallery space.
This morning, I'm excited
to say our creative environment
is expanding once again.
The School of Music, Theatre
and Dance is a point of pride
for Michigan, with talent
that is second to no one.
Now, these students, faculty
and staff are going to enjoy new
and improved surroundings
to express their creativity,
thanks to the vision of
longtime Michigan donors William
and Delores Brehm.
The Brehms are generously
providing 8 million dollars
toward the renovation and
expansion of the Moore Building,
a transformative project we
will ask the Board of Regents
to approve next month.
We anticipate new
rehearsal rooms, studios
and a lecture hall, as
well as improved space
for one-on-one time between
faculty and students.
With the regents' approval,
this will be a 23 million
dollar undertaking.
The University will
provide 14 million,
and we will seek additional
support from alumni and friends.
I know that the faculty
from Music, Theatre
and Dance will agree when I
say this project is overdue.
It's genuinely exciting,
and complements new spaces
such as the Walgreen
Drama Center
and the Arthur Miller Theater.
For more evidence of Michigan's
capacity for creativity,
we have the new Penny W. Stamps
School of Art and Design.
As you may know, Penny
is a Michigan graduate
who with her husband, Roe,
has made a historic 32
million dollar investment
in the School of Art and Design.
Their generosity
is wide-ranging--
supporting student scholarships,
as well as global experiences,
visiting artists and designers,
and community programs.
Art and design schools
are sometimes overlooked,
but not here.
Penny was on campus
a few weeks ago,
and was so enthusiastic
about this gift.
It is a magnificent
feeling, she said,
not only because she loves
supporting the creative process,
but because the Stamps School
is "not just an art school."
It's part of a major
research institution.
That is what gives the School
of Music, Theatre and Dance,
the Stamps School and
all of our schools
and colleges their strength,
the combined expertise
and creativity of
so many disciplines.
Indeed, the pursuit of arts
at Michigan is not a
stand-alone enterprise.
It's not about decoration,
it's about creation--
creation that is deeply rooted
in our interdisciplinary
setting.
It is this distinction
that sets us apart.
When the Stamps School underwent
reaccreditation a few years ago,
it drew high praise
from the visiting team.
Michigan, they said,
is getting it right.
To quote, "The School of Art
and Design and the University
of Michigan have
created an opportunity
to lead the academic
conversation in art
and design in this country."
We want to drive
the conversation
in other areas, too.
This month, the University
is surveying members
of our community
about sustainability.
We want to learn how
people think and behave
when it comes to
the environment.
By scientifically measuring
and reporting our behavior
as a community, we can
work to make changes
for the better of the planet.
We know of no other university
that is studying
itself in this way.
This survey will
take place every year
and will provide an
objective barometer
of our sustainability culture.
I announced this survey
a year ago as part
of a broader sustainability
initiative for the University.
Since then, we have launched
the Dow Scholars initiative,
an unprecedented program
for 300 graduate students
that accelerates how we teach
and research sustainability.
This focus has evolved and
strengthened in recent years,
with early support from
donors such as Dow,
Don Graham and John Erb.
They have shown what it means
to commit to sustainability
at the very core of personal
and institutional values.
John Erb, who is with us
this morning, recently asked
where I want to see the
University of Michigan
in the realm of sustainability
10, 20, 30 years from now.
I have been thinking
a lot about that
as we set aspirational goals
for Michigan's leadership.
I know, we all know, that
we'll need to do a better job
of building facilities,
affecting human behavior
and consumption, and
challenging our energy usage,
even as we manage the world's
largest public university
research portfolio.
But also, we must see the
University as a global leader
in educating a new vanguard
of sustainability experts.
It is here, on this campus,
where tomorrow's sustainability
leaders will build their
knowledge broadly,
across the disciplines,
and carry that into the
world of policy and practice.
We should be known
as the university
with sustainability research,
curriculum and opportunities
that make a real difference.
In that spirit, today
I'm pleased
to announce the establishment
of the University
of Michigan Water Center.
With the support of the
Erb Family Foundation,
this is a new 9 million
dollar commitment
to the Great Lakes region.
We will focus on
four critical areas:
reducing toxic contamination,
fighting invasive species,
protecting wildlife habitat,
and promoting the
health of the coastlines.
The University of
Michigan has a long history
of freshwater research.
More than a century ago,
our scientists were working
to determine why the
whitefish population was
down in Lake Saint Clair.
Today, the Great Lakes are
a source of food, recreation
and jobs-- some 1 and
a half million jobs
that carry 62 billion
dollar in yearly wages.
If you were to look for a
country with a higher GDP
than the Great Lakes
region, there are only two:
the United States and China.
As a university, we need to take
on ownership and responsibility
of regional sustainability
challenges that affect us--
close to home and where
our expertise can have
enormous impact.
The Water Center will do that.
I want to thank John Erb
and his family foundation
for supporting our work and
for continually pushing us
to do more.
The Great Lakes hold one-fifth
of the world's freshwater
supply.
One-fifth.
Compromise their
health and integrity,
and the damage will be
felt far beyond our shores.
Which is why it's so critical
to pursue not only
local partnerships,
but international ones--
relationships that pull
together different perspectives
to tackle the world's
toughest challenges.
[ Pause ]
Doing more-- more research, more
service, more collaboration--
means being more global.
Eighty years ago, when Raoul
Wallenberg was a Michigan
student, he absolutely
relished new people
and different cultures.
As an international student
from Sweden, he visited Detroit,
New York, Chicago
and New Orleans.
He and a classmate drove
to Mexico one summer.
Another summer he
hitchhiked to California,
and on up into Canada, and
then thumbed his way back
to Ann Arbor.
He called his travels "training
in diplomacy and tact."
Now, the parent in me does
not condone hitchhiking.
But as university president,
I strongly endorse more
global opportunities
for our students and faculty.
Just yesterday we learned
that Michigan students
lead the nation
in this year's Fulbright grants.
I should say, once again
we lead the nation.
For the sixth time in
the past eight years.
Fulbrights support global study
and are among the
world's most competitive
and prestigious programs.
I'm thinking they're becoming
somewhat routine here though.
But, of course, no international
experience is ordinary.
Consider Brazil.
My recent trip there
with a faculty delegation
provides fertile territory
for our work as a university.
The country has seen
enormous economic progress
in the past 20 years and
its vibrancy is palpable.
Both federal and state
governments are investing
heavily in education
and in advancing science
and technology, and
are developing ways
to move the previously
disadvantaged
into the middle class.
I anticipate exciting
collaborations resulting
from our conversations
throughout Brazil.
And several members of the
delegation are with us today,
and I want them to raise their
hands so that you can see
who went with me to Brazil.
Got a couple up here, Gary
and Don, raise your hands.
I want everyone to know how
expertly the University was
represented on this trip.
Our discussions fell into three
categories: medicine and health,
humanities and social
sciences, environment
and natural resources.
At the University of
Sao Paulo, for example,
there was intense
interest in how we
as a university are
addressing sustainability.
The Brazilian government is
making impressive investments
in education with a bold new
scholarship program called
Science Without Borders.
The goal is to educate 100,000
students by sending them abroad
for a year of study,
specifically in STEM
disciplines.
That's science, technology,
engineering and math.
Brazil wants to achieve
this goal by 2015.
At the moment, there are
1,000 students in the program,
so you can see the challenges.
But it is one that leaders
are willing to pursue.
Brazil wants half of
these students-- 50,000--
to attend college here, in the
United States, and our embassy
in Brasilia is trying to help
with this very complex goal.
We were able to meet with
the US ambassador and,
since we now better understand
the issues, I'm confident
that we can respond
in positive ways.
We currently have five
undergraduate students enrolled
with us in the Science
Without Borders program.
They are with us, and I'd
like ask them to stand,
our Science Without
Border students.
Those who are here, thank
you so much for being here.
I look forward to welcoming
more students in the future.
These students strengthen
Michigan.
[ Applause ]
These students strengthen
Michigan with their ideas
and perspectives,
their experiences.
They demonstrate why we must,
absolutely must, pursue true,
bilateral partnerships--
to succeed and thrive
as a great institution.
As one university, we
don't have all the answers.
But working together with
many, our potential takes
on a totally new magnitude.
Which is why we're partnering
with universities in China,
Ghana and South Africa, and
why I'll lead a delegation
to India next year.
It's why we, as an institution,
are communicating in Spanish,
Portuguese and Mandarin.
We've joined Weibo,
China's version of Twitter,
and are now considered the most
influential American university
in that space.
Global impact is why we chose to
be the first public university
in Coursera, a massive
online learning community.
And the key word
here is massive.
More than 1.3 million people
worldwide are enrolled
in courses.
Michigan faculty are
teaching six classes,
with a seventh planned
for January.
Professor Gautam Kaul's
introductory finance course
alone attracted a
staggering 133,000 students.
These courses are free, and
they give us a way to connect
with students, whether
in Michigan or Macedonia.
Coursera fits neatly
with our public mission
of sharing knowledge.
We are also optimistic that
it will help transform our
classroom pedagogy
on campus as well.
Optimism is an equally critical
ingredient for new discoveries
and technologies that spring
from our laboratories,
clinics and studies.
Research universities fervently
believe in improving the world,
and we do so in diverse ways.
Two months ago, the
world lost a pioneer
with the passing
of Neil Armstrong.
His walk on the moon
was truly one
of the monumental achievements
in science innovation--
not only in this
country, but anywhere.
Think of the research, the
creativity and the hard work
that went into Apollo 11.
NASA, industry, universities
and others came together
with their research
and their inventions.
It was the ultimate embodiment
of American innovation
and collaboration.
Now also think of
this, the computers
on Apollo 11 had less processing
power than your smartphone.
This is why we continually
innovate, invent and educate.
To discover new knowledge.
To move forward as a nation
and a global community.
Michigan's research
portfolio stands
at 1.27 billion dollars--
billion.
That exceeds the
entire budget of Monaco.
No public university in the
world invests more in research.
It's research that is
more relevant than ever.
We are now the first university
to lead an entire
satellite launch program,
a 52 million dollar venture
entrusted to us by NASA.
This project is designed to
better understand hurricanes,
which results in more
accurate storm predictions and,
ultimately, lives saved.
Hurricane Sandy is showing us
the importance of forecasting,
and it's gratifying to know
that our scientists
will contribute even
more refinements.
We also see lives being saved
with a new research project
that has thousands of vehicles
throughout Ann Arbor using
technology to communicate
with each other.
With the support of 22 million
dollars from the Department
of Transportation, this
technology is alerting drivers
to trouble on the road.
It may well lead to an 80
percent reduction in crashes.
That's impact.
Our health system,
including University Hospital
and Mott Children's Hospital
continues to be among the best
and safest in the country.
We have been selected
as the home
for a new 21 million dollar
federally funded center
for HIV research.
The University's
two largest grants
from the National Institutes
of Health support the
Comprehensive Cancer Center
and the Michigan Institute for
Clinical and Health Research.
Both were renewed this year,
with glowing comments
from the NIH.
The North Campus Research
Complex is attracting more
people and programs.
This includes the new
Institute for Healthcare Policy
and Innovation and more than
400 researchers committed
to promoting high-quality,
equitable
and affordable health
care services.
We believe the Institute
will be the largest
in the country for such work.
Today, we are announcing
the first director,
Dr. John Ayanian, a highly
respected researcher we've
attracted from the Michigan
of the East, Harvard.
So, John, would you
stand a minute just
for people to welcome you.
[ Applause ]
His expertise will give
IHPI national prominence
and help us recruit
even more top experts.
Dr. Ayanian is on campus
this week and I'm thrilled
that he's here with us.
I mean just introduced him, so.
John needs to be at the
Michigan Union shortly
to welcome a summit of
national health care leaders,
and I really appreciate
he's spending time
with us this morning.
The Michigan passion for
entrepreneurship is flourishing.
Our scientists are declaring a
record number of inventions more
than one a day this past year.
The Venture Accelerator, based
at the NCRC, is officially full
with 18 startup companies built
on U-M research discoveries.
We thought that the Accelerator
would take three years to fill,
and it took less
than half that time.
Students are enrolled in our
first class of candidates
for the master's degree
on entrepreneurship.
Here at the Ross School,
the Zell-Lurie Institute
is ranked second
in the country among
top graduate programs
for entrepreneurship.
The ZEAL clinic is up and
running, connecting law students
with student entrepreneurs
in need of legal counsel.
Faculty are beating down the
doors to participate in MCubed,
our new funding program
that connects researchers
across campus.
We are committing
15 million dollars
to some 250 team projects
that are admittedly high-risk,
but also, potentially,
very rewarding.
MCubed has grown out of our
Third Century Initiative,
a 50 million dollar investment
in teaching and research
that we announced a year ago.
This is a commitment taking us
up to the University's
bicentennial,
and a third century
of creative thinking.
We want to know, what are the
different ways the University
can address the world's greatest
challenges and opportunities?
What types of immersive learning
experiences can we create
for our students?
We are eager to fund
innovative answers.
And beginning next month,
the Provost's Office
will be asking you,
the members of our
community, for your best ideas.
When we talk about
innovation and creativity,
we know that Michigan staff
are essential to this culture.
We see it in Planet Blue,
with Voices of the
Staff, and with MHealthy.
Today, I'm pleased to announce
that we will recognize the
creative staff contributions
with a new Presidential
Innovation Award.
With both words and dollars, we
will honor individuals and teams
for ideas that make Michigan a
better place to work and live.
The Chronicle of Higher
Education consistently ranks
and recognizes this
campus as one
of the best university
workplaces.
It happened again this summer
and Michigan staff helped
create that climate.
That Michigan is an
invigorating place to live,
learn and work has been
known by generations.
When Raoul Wallenberg
was winding
down his time here,
he wanted to stay.
"I feel so at home in my little
Ann Arbor that I'm beginning
to sink down roots here,
and I have a hard time
imagining leaving it."
But, he observed, "I'm not doing
anything very useful here."
Isn't that what we
want from our students?
To have an amazing
experience here,
but know that their
real value is
when they apply their
lessons and move on?
Could Raoul Wallenberg have
envisioned the horror of war
and the heroics he would
display in World War II?
Of course not.
But he knew the importance
of taking Michigan with him,
because the lessons would
help shape the future.
Just how deeply is evidenced
with us this morning.
Irene Butter and Andrew
Nagy are emeritus faculty,
and I want them to
stand for a minute.
[ Applause ]
Professors Butter and Nagy
devoted more than 85 years
of combined teaching,
research and service.
Dr. Butter was a professor in
the School of Public Health
and helped write our
state's Public Health Code.
Dr. Nagy is a space scientist
with the College of Engineering
who was involved in
numerous NASA projects.
But long before they
were scholars,
they were scared
Jewish teenagers living
through the Holocaust, she
in Holland and he in Hungary.
Each survived, though members
of their families did not.
Professor Nagy was saved
by Raoul Wallenberg.
As Holocaust survivors and
members of our community,
these two scholars have
dedicated themselves
to the humanitarian spirit
with their longtime service
to the University and the
Wallenberg Lecture and Medal.
The Wallenberg Medal honors
compassionate, global work,
and past recipients have
included Elie Wiesel, John Lewis
and Nobel laureate
Aung San Suu Kyi.
Just last week, one of our past
honorees, Dr. Denis Mukwege,
was the target of assassins
because of his tireless mission
to save rape victims
in the Congo.
The words on the
Wallenberg Medal are direct,
one person can make
a difference.
Professors Butter and
Nagy, you have done just
that with your scholarship
and your dedication
to the Wallenberg legacy.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
Today, in the 100th year of
his birth, we will do more
to promote the spirit
of Raoul Wallenberg.
I'm thrilled to announce
the establishment
of the Raoul Wallenberg
Fellowship for undergraduates.
This is a new 25,000
dollar stipend to be awarded
to a graduating senior
who demonstrates deep
commitment to selfless work.
We want to help a new graduate
dedicate the first year of his
or her life path
to this calling.
It will now be among the
University's largest prizes
for undergraduates.
Its name carries
great importance
and even greater expectations.
And we will begin with
a graduating senior
from the class of 2013.
Surely Raoul Wallenberg
did not graduate intending
to become an international
symbol of moral courage.
But his remarkable deeds
provide inspiration
for today's Michigan students,
and this new award will serve
to encourage careers
dedicated to human rights.
Let me close with one
last Wallenberg snapshot.
He's just completed his final
exams and his freshman year.
In a letter home, he tells
of staying up all night,
studying chemistry with friends.
It's not his best
subject and he knows it.
He is thoroughly exhausted.
And still, he says,
it's been worth it.
He's made friends.
He enjoys college.
Not so much of good grade,
because of good grades,
but rather, "Because I feel like
that I have learned something."
This is our mission
as a great university.
That our students learn and
grow, evolve as leaders,
and come to see themselves
in a different light.
That our faculty and staff
teach and grow as well,
changing people and places
with their discoveries
and contributions.
That we all believe we can
and will make a difference,
as individuals, as an
academic community,
dedicated to transforming
our state, our nation,
our world with ideas
and actions.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
So now we just have a few
minutes and I'll be happy
to answer any questions that you
might have, anything you might
like to, to know about.
Anyone? Hi Jim.
>> Now we were talking
briefly at our table
about the ballot proposals
that are facing Michigan voters
and wondering if you
have any reflections
on ballot questions
here in Michigan
and their potential impact
upon the institution.
>> Okay. Well, thanks for the
opportunity to give me another--
to give me an opportunity
for another encouragement
for people to go and vote.
I sent out a message campus wide
just this morning encouraging
you to make sure that you're
registered and make sure
that you vote either in
person or by absentee ballot.
This is-- there are a lot of
issues on the ballot this time,
some state initiatives as
well as local initiatives.
And I encourage you
to educate yourselves.
There are several websites that
are listed in my e-mail to go
and find out what these ballot
proposals are all about.
Several of them will change
the constitution of the state
and that's a serious issue and
I just encourage you to find
out everything that you
can and please go and vote,
it's very important
responsibility as a citizen.
Well, thank you all very much
and I also want to say how--
what a great privilege
it was to grab the speech
around the centennial of
Raoul Wallenberg's birth.
It's tremendous.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]