York Aquarium.
I am an animal care specialist,
and my job is to
maintain the health of all the
animals in our collection.
We work with a variety
of species.
Mostly marine mammals,
but we also work with
some birds as well.
FEMALE SPEAKER: How often are
baby walruses born here?
PAUL MOYLET: Right now, there's
only about 20 walruses
that exist in aquariums
in the United States.
There's only been 15 births
in the United States
in the past 31 years.
And out of those 15 walruses,
only six have survived--
this guy's number six.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Tell
me about his name.
PAUL MOYLET: His entire name
is Akitusaaq, which means
"gift given in return" in the
Yupik language, which the
Inuit people speak.
But we decided to shorten
it a little bit,
kind of for our benefit.
So now we call him Tusaaq
instead of Aki.
FEMALE SPEAKER: How much did
he weigh when he was born?
PAUL MOYLET: We guesstimated
that he weighed around 115 to
120 pounds, which is just about
average for a baby walrus.
It's a little over eight months
later, and we just
weighed him this morning.
He weighed in at 364 pounds.
So he's quite large.
In fact, he's a lot larger
than his father
was at the same age.
An average weight for an adult
male Pacific walrus is around
3,300 to 3,500 pounds.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Wow.
What about the temperature
of the water?
Is it super cold?
PAUL MOYLET: The temperature
of the water has to be
maintained in a very
cold temperature.
These guys are Arctic animals,
and so they really
need it to be cold.
And it gets down to about--
the coldest
I've seen is 42 degrees.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Did they
like it when it was
snowing last week?
PAUL MOYLET: They
love the snow.
They actually make
snow angels.
What they like to do is crawl up
onto snow and just kind of
roll around, make these big
walrus-sized snow angels.
FEMALE SPEAKER: So tell
me a day in the
life of a baby walrus.
PAUL MOYLET: Well, the baby
walrus that we have, at least,
is very independent and very
curious, and he's always into
everything.
They use suction to eat, so
they suck on anything that
they can fit in their mouths.
And they're like hey,
can I eat this?
And they suck on it, what
does this tastes like?
Oh, it tastes good, it
doesn't taste good.
So that's how he pretty
much spends his day.
Marine mammals for
the most part are
very intelligent animals.
And we do train our walruses to
do a number of what we call
show behaviors.
It's just kind of fun
for the public.
They wave and they salute, they
do a lot of vocalizations
on command.
[WALRUS VOCALIZING]
FEMALE SPEAKER: Can
you hug a walrus?
PAUL MOYLET: You could
definitely hug a walrus if the
walrus wants to be hugged.
You've got to keep in mind these
guys are wild animals.
And sometimes they like a good
scratch, and they'll actually
fall asleep if you rub
them the right way.
But other times they choose not
to be touched, and we just
have to respect them.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Have you
ever hugged one?
PAUL MOYLET: I hug them
all the time.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Are walruses
your favorite?
PAUL MOYLET: I have to admit
that walruses are
my favorite, yes.