MIKE SPINELLI: Hey, welcome to
"Drive Central." Here's where
you're going to find out
what's happening
on Drive this week.
Don't forget @drive on Twitter,
facebook.com/drivetv,
comments below, or
give me a call.
I'm in the book, right Ian?
What book is that?
"Julie and the Wolves." Anyway,
this week on "Tuned,"
what is it like to drive
a drift car?
Well, Matt Farah finds out.
The car is Corey Hosford's
Formula Drift Nissan 350z.
Let's see.
That's "Tuned," every
Monday on Drive.
And remember that story we
promised last week about the
lucky son of a bitch who gets
to test drive all those
megabuck hyper cars in Sweden?
Yeah.
We're running that this week.
It's Robert from Koenigsegg.
Let's take a look at a clip.
ROBERT SERWANSKI: My name is
Robert Serwanski, and I'm the
test driver of Koenigsegg.
[ENGINE REVVING]
[TIRES SQUEALING]
ROBERT SERWANSKI: My job
is basically two parts.
I develop the cars, how they
handle, and performance wise,
and I also am a part of
the production line.
MIKE SPINELLI: That's "Inside
Koenigsegg," every Tuesday.
And this week Chris Harris pairs
up two German GT cars,
the Mercedes Benz
SL63 and BMW M6.
Is it the ultimate
GT showdown?
Could be.
Let's watch.
CHRIS HARRIS: I want you to
imagine that the year is 1988,
and that I'm wearing shoulder
pads and braces and that kind
of stuff, and carrying
a Filofax.
And we've decided to get
together the fastest BMW 6
series and the fastest
Mercedes SL.
Those would have been, according
to my memory bank,
the M635 CSI and the 500 SL.
Together, those two cars would
have had a power output of
just over 500 horsepower.
Fast forward to 2013 and their
equivalents, the SL63 and new
M6 have over 1,100 horsepower.
Sometimes I find it difficult
to justify cars like this,
because they're not sports
cars, and they're
not full-on GT cars.
So let's find out what they're
actually like to use, and
whether they're just too
powerful and too much for
modern motoring.
But I suspect they're actually
rather good fun.
MIKE SPINELLI: That's Chris
Harris on "Cars" every
Wednesday this season
on Drive Three.
No, it's just Drive One.
No, it's not Drive One at all.
It's just Drive.
And we'll have a new question
this week for you guys to
debate, and us to talk
about on "Road
Testament" this Thursday.
And watch "Shakedown" on Friday
as Leo Parente gets us
caught up with the upcoming
2013 racing season.
And as I said last week,
that's it for "Drive
Central" this week.
I'll see you guys next week.
"Drive Central," MC
Escher edition.