Have to be much more open to risk-taking today.
And I think also open to failure. And companies
don't like to hear that, but the truth is
you could try ten things. Well, if one of
them works, that’s a good thing. If nine
of them don't – I always think of the story
about how when Babe Ruth, when he got up to
bat, most of the time he struck out. But he’s
the most famous baseball player probably that
ever existed. So I think we have to have talent
today that is tuned into human behavior, consumers’
lives, is tuned into wanting to provide services
and products and brands that fulfill those
lives, and a real understanding of risk taking.
And it’s okay. It’s okay, and I think
we have to allow for that as organizations.
That’s a hard thing to do.