even today the remains of these ancient
ramparts and telescopic borderline
hundreds of thousands of men literally
this mighty for the first part of the
air
finally into sixteenth-century
they built the greatest fortifications
ever created by humans
colossus
that became the national icon of china
look great
what made the middle kingdom build this
giant walls frontier
no one truly knows all the facets of the
walls that sneak across thousands of
condolences of north china
most of these walls to say about the
world they were built to protect
armies of two
tourists paid their respects to the
stone ramparts north of beijing
does have given the world are image of
the great wall
but what is its true story
yeah
the final years of the eighteenth
century
out of golden afternoon
of the chinese empire
it's an ancient culture with unique
rights and grooves cut off from the rest
of the
but they could come in the middle
kingdom discomfort itself
has become franchise
for several months has been the british
trading nation of china
time enough to twelve year old thomas
traveling with the delegation tune and
chinese
ostracize layoff
coming up this place has an unofficial
interpreter he supplies valuable
services to the ambassador's anyway
do you understand what i need a court
officials inform the coroner i_b_m_ pro
is ready to receive them
all his summer residence
seven days right from the capitol
beijing before shooting into little
short
overnight
trucks cannot
calypso equally on this occasion the
delegation will finally be able to
present an outstanding example of
british craftsmanship and to the emperor
of china
kind of chance
they brought in china or away from her
wants
going to offer to make a blanket for the
spectacle includes commander-in-chief
action is astonishment disapproval media
k
twenty-four splendid
the officials assured him that his
siblings i just he would never see it in
such a panic win
for no one ever miss it's higher than
the emperor
and the coach monotony sits high with
his back to his passenger
we'll see about that content
the englishman would of course travel to
the entire coach
the industry delegation representing
king george is led by movement company
eighty bison george staunton
their mission is to open the chinese
market to the printouts of the british
and
a great procession companies the
injustice to strengthen beaten city to
the senate
three days after the gym
remembrance and offices to communication
political become parks
mccartney and his colleagues are treated
to a site a few europeans of tobacco
agreed
nothing to keep the englishman in their
countries
they scrambled over the wall overwhelmed
by the admiration for the architects and
builders of the structure
recruitment company notices that his
chinese escorts remain completely
unmoved
teenager wrote
renderings appeared rather on easy and
inpatient at the length of our state
upon the world
he was stunning she took a real city
though few of them had ever visited to
total
note mccartney was otherwise less than
impressed by chinese cultural
achievements
but overwhelmed by this most stupendous
with good human hands
he continued
this war was built above two hundred
years before the christian era
china must to be not only a very
powerful empire but a very wise and
virtuous nation
to establish a once
what was then sort of perpetual security
for against future invasion
the occurrence of these first european
tourists
has influenced our image of the great
wall ever since
with these british visitors have no idea
that the stone colossus they were
admiring was only about two hundred
years old
this huge structure has been built in
the sixteenth century
to stand guard over the heart of the
middle kingdom
after that would be cool costs pending
the gateway for an invasion that shook
the empire to its core
the story begins in beijing
this is where the emperor of the named
in the students
in the forbidden city
this is the center of the world
from here the emperor rules over
in stranded audiences the son of heaven
demonstrates his power
hundreds gather in front of the whole of
perfect harmony
to pay homage to the amruta
like everything else that happens at
court
the ceremony follows a strict ritual
estate without which you will is a plow
without the blade
they say
i'd like the pole star in the heavens
the emperor stands at the center of the
earth
he's the head
at the center point of the middle
kingdom
none hardly any other ruler of the named
in this state
embodies this principle more than
encourage edging
who sat on the dragon throne since
fifteen twenty two
china regarding authority
as ball bearings
diplomatic contacts in trade relations
with other people's
are considered entirely unnecessary
middle kingdom is sufficient unto itself
even the rights to pay tribute to the
emperor isn't another only the emperor
himself common ground
delegation of mongolian nomads appeared
before the officials of the new computer
they have a message for emperor judging
half of the last time the mongols osti
emperor for permission to pay tribute
they bring valuable gift
in the hope that the emperor will
present to defeat returned
only when this which was completed
country can begin
the delegation has come from whole heart
headquarters of the mumbled prince out
and cut
is just four hundred kilometers from the
pentagon city
i found confidence in the policies had
built on chinese lines
he's a great admirer of chinese culture
and he's broken with the tradition of
his fourth scandal
he's the first movie this inserting
descon
to build a permanent fortified city
refuse peoples to live in units the
traditional round tense of the movements
of the state
they live in tiny from the knife stock
wondering over this step
they pitch their units wherever they
find grazing land for their herds
for the weakest of the new man's the
children the elderly the long winter's
armed struggle for survival
many don't make it through
the chinese to the south who will about
their suffering
chinese sources report
in spring they often bago patrols to buy
the cattle one dogs for because also of
rice or beans
some would bring hides all horse hair
hoping to stave off starvation for one
more day
for the no-man's there's no way out
only trade with the chinese neighbors
could possess an indigenous rice and
grain
could bring an end to the hardship
between the imperial palace behind the
walls of the forbidden city
no one is interested in the barbarians
troubles
here in the center of the world
the rooms priorities to carry out the
prescribed rituals that will guarantee
you order indeed business
even having to consider all the time
comes request of trade relations is an
affront to the emperor
the idea of trading on equal terms with
the mongols is completely unimaginable
the emperor had already demanded that
the character representing barbarians
had to be written as small as possible
for official documents
prices put on our time cons head
and future mongolian ambassadors will be
executed
with the chinese peasants who reportedly
gmail exactly what the emperor's policy
with
no no no that's will take with force for
the emperor has denied
the peasants don't have long to wait
mongol horseman streamed across the
empires northern borders
the wheel of history which is revolved
around violence and planned uh... for
more than one thousand five hundred
years
is turning again
that was the mongols spat
we'll start with the ravaged fields
go to work on
included in the city that was two
schools of thought she had two different
views as to how to put an end to the
raids
once i dont get free trade relations the
other wanted military response basic
adventures responds carried the risk of
defeat since they couldn't agree on
trade all of all they made a compromise
she's treaty
das was the decision explained to the
deep and profound denounced
barbarians prefers aggression
we are more subdued traditions
cannot do the emperor demeanor
leader of the border troops reports to
the forbidden city to receive his orders
shaikh
generally one size appointed supreme
commander of the capital's defense
forces
his mission is to use force together
sins of document receipt
to secure the capital
when one does fortifications to the
northwest of beijing form part of a much
larger distances to the nine border
garrisons
instrument like deeds on a chain
derived from the easternmost to the
western most point of the chinese empire
last outpost in the west
is the fort
ajay one
jayu one means
cost to the beautiful valley
only the five thousand five hundred
meter peaks of mt she did
stands higher
than the powerful fortress
according to legend the master builder
of the forts calculated the construction
materials so precisely
that when they finished just one break
was left over
on the side of the time
close by the first hour of the main bol
rises up
and then the out
post on the edge of the state
the world abruptly ends on the cliffs of
the river big guy
on the other side of juggling fort
the wall continues eastwood's
over the centuries wind and weather have
torn down syndrome
for here it's not made of stone with of
ramdas
the material used to buildings walls in
china since time immemorial
sections of the wall run parallel to an
old a set of those defenses built around
the year one thousand
when general when one does task is
completed
northwest of china
is completely sealed off
the capital beijing is protected by its
alluring of walls
the or dust the northern region enclosed
by a huge curve of the ghetto rather
it has always been the gateway from them
and sent to china
here too
the wind and weather have done their
worst
the wounded style is consuming made out
on the cracks up over there
the garrison forts with the outposts of
this defensive out to wall
pool
today they use is strictly non-military
best six inches thick schools provide
shelter to the farmers hope
spent nearly five hundred years ago they
faced a greatest military test
march fifteen forty nine
the chinese are fighting off another mom
who raid
general when one dot defends the city
yes shapes as a hard time cons army
passes the fortress
intruder
at the great wall
the chinese general signals image
hack
when one does tactics of the maximum
retreat
go back to it
it was not beat
mumble horsemen have suffered severe
losses
what future now
uttarakhand
from the middle of his retreating holds
he sends a message to the chinese
defense
is it's an admission of defeat
did this raid costs too much
the downtown cons message contains a
naked threats
if trade is not allowed
he's made will be in the streets of
beijing
evol lovers luggage cart onto the laptop
gortari should pretty important to get
shirts are teaching tigers dominguez
list is great wall now but still has the
reputation of being impenetrable
if you talk to each enormous sums were
invested a lot with millions of people
with recruited to build it whole
gullible the soldiers manning and wet
excellently trained accidentally
equipment what
totally against
the broncos didn't give out somewhere on
such a long frontier kabita had to be a
place where they could breakthrough
triple quincy
that legacy for busy kobe coupons might
north of the beijing cook could see
big-time potato
smita
george jr
the chinese don't expect an attack at
that would be cool parks
it's a for gotten corner of the mansions
defended by a handful of troops
the gigantic fortifications so admired
by north mccartney
have not yet been built
okay
equity attack of the mongolian forces
was a complete surprise
it's almost too easy
the rude to beijing
and downtown cobb keeps his promise
it's just eighty kilometers to beijing
officially beijing is defended by a
force of a hundred and forty thousand
men
but less than half of these actually
under arms
general wings victory at the gates of
the fort
has made the chinese complacent
huh
decide to find some
it's centers
thrown consonants here to the suburbs of
the jeep plant new england
for three days in advance
atlast even the emperor
deep inside the fifth didn't city i'm no
longer nick norton
from within the walls of his or did you
know
and projecting watches chaos and take
the outside
there's nothing he could do
on september thirteenth fifteen fifty
out on concourse up his troops before
the ending date
the place where the chinese
traditionally hold their victory parades
he has reached his goal
the very hot if the embargo
a prisoner of war were sent with a
message to the emperor
would be a demand for his education
an ultimatum for the hand over to the
city
as out on what control of the whole
empire
the contents of the message cause
confusion
in the past
odd
because once again request the empress
permission to set up treating posts
milton morris
troubleshooting lights
here there are so i'm going to has no
intention of agreeing to the request of
the barbarians
to regain control of an extremely
delicate situation
wpm terrace summons his high officials
creek pickup
they decide to take refuge in courtly
protocol
she try to collect well-informed
compounds cars as they have a number of
reasons to doubt that his message is
genuine
number one which is not in the script of
the barbarians
number two please message did not reach
the emperor by the appropriate needs
sheet
disinclined to live there for
demonstrative of hong kong withdraw his
forces at once strategy and as you make
another formal request for trading
relations
garrison which one food
eighty or so
three three
records tactics a lift
out and con withdrew from beijing
his decisions to apostles history
silly
and are you
right-wing
top objective
cadet is one possible very interesting
explanations opening sarvesh mezzo
outdone coddle would really didn't want
to conquer china
if you know if you really did only want
to establish trade relations she's
takes no four hundred years before
genghis khan had had a quite different
go powerful pataki wanted to take over
although at the south of the entire
seventeen t if you wanted to control the
middle kingdom b and he succeeded
optical
nehemiah self-doubt on concert act
the chinese open up trading posts at
some of the northern thoughts
recently the remains of the trading
station were found that you did dennis
archaeologists uncovered the foundations
of the gate here in this war
three weeks in the transcript
cost-benefit
but the new freedom of movement didn't
last long
by the next year at the markets were
closed down
that was when construction began
on the greatest offensive structure
china and the world
had ever seen
between fifteen fifty and sixteen forty
four the storm dragon came to life
china's great wall was completed
and the wall between the monuments to
the closed world view
of them being empire
it includes their own universe
and excluded everything that was fun
to the north of beijing it curves
majestic teaching the mansion range
as follows the natural line of the
mountain peaks reaching breathtaking
heights before plunging into the deepest
revealing
i_t_t_ stand and in shanghai glenn it
strikes tracing to begin to see
to the first event out in the west
always more than six thousand kilometers
long
the sometimes bizarre roots taken by
this war
has led many experts to believe that
more than just defensive considerations
went into its planning
for generations the chinese have
believed in the practice of thing surely
the teachings of the wind and water
thanks way experts were publicly
consulted and debate before the building
of the war began
to make sure that the forces of nature
would work and it's free
when it came to the construction itself
spiritual aspects took second place
it was all about quality aggression c
and speed
an army commander who's in charge of
each building detail
she was responsible for seeing that the
key to the timetable
if necessary with the use of force
most of the workers were recruited from
the army or were pressed into service as
civilians
at christie's and harshness with which
the plans were executed put a terrible
strain on both men and the supply of
material
victims the war
scott
rental industry calamitous section of
www
was completed in six hundred days by
just three thousand
the old walls of compressed earth
could use materials that they had
happened
at the materials for the mean wall of
the sixteenth century had to be
manufactured
dismantle extensive network of quarries
kilns
and the supply routes to connect
pittsburgh works were created for the
greatest building site of the empire
the costs of this gigantic project
became heavier and heavier burden on the
state
various carried the bricks from the
jones to the construction sites in the
mountains some traveled eighty
kilometers
it took just a hundred years to build
the greatest defensive fortifications
the world and in the
but the great wall is not a single word
tool
it's actually a system of several
defensive lines
watch towers a strung out from the main
wall
when the enemy is spotted the light in
the lobby in the meantime fifty two
hundred many each tower hurry along the
top of the walls of the point of the
attack
meanwhile reinforcements arrived from
the garrison towers which holds up to
ten thousand battle ready soldiers wind
mo
beast that's the theory
the reality was rather different
two months on end the border guards were
banished to the frozen mounting regions
expo
goes to the crew with a
building the world
group the men did stick to the edge of
the ruling
and discipline among the soldiers was
cooler
was a mess and resolved rough seas they
would go months without pay
they waited in vain for the promised
waterproof clothing
there was no we'll supply chain
and your taxes were constantly being
increased throughout the empire
well
money regularly disappeared long before
it got to the frontiers into the pockets
of corrupt officers officials
the completion of the war brought with
it the financial and spiritual
bankruptcy attorney destiny
in sixteen forty four
rebel army led by a president pc chang
plundered and pillaged its way towards
beijing
and as a second trip to the creaking
dynasty in beijing
on the steps of powerful enemies
gathering
a hundred years after on time cop
the mansion
and remain
that these two men to the war to
dragon's head
an army of manchu horseman has gathered
close by is the fortress of shanghai
glenn
calligraphy decorating the east tower
announces its proud name
the first costs on behalf of
this fortress protects the came between
the mountains and the dragon's head at
the edge of the ghetto c
uh... in sixteen forty four the first pa
sunday heaven is the scene of the
fateful decision to push it to the
middle kingdom to its call
the commander shanghai gladness general
wu
one of the last army commanders still
loyal to the ming dynasty
the advance guard of the man she will
continue playing site
they make no attempt to take the
fortress
there waiting
by may sixteen forty four the situation
in the empire is hopeless
cc chang the rebel leader has taken
control of the ticket in the city sixty
emperor is dead because i just got your
check
teachings or boxing general rule has
refused to go over to the rebels
he may still be possible to throw them
out of the gene
and save the dynasty
then general rule receives news from
beijing
garden
it's about the review sheet
teaching
cd
gizatov dad
pctools has taken general was far
hostage demands the journal square in
the chance to him is that you do the
didn't sitting
or his father why body
then the ambassador hence jindal will
better supposedly polly's father shark
the old mandates the general to obey the
new look at once and so save his life
is obligations to his own father miss
override his loyalty to the media this
team
and a gift from these teaching should
make his decision is yours
how would the general decide
if you have a choice at all
on may the twenty seven sixteen forty
four
general who opens the gates of his
fortress to the invaded mention lines
rather than mention ruling the empire
than a peasant
on the dragonfly
publicity
used in listing who
to the middle kingdom until the year
nineteen eleven
they call themselves the ching
chihuahuas
one hundred and fifty years after the
gates of china were open to his
ancestors arching emperor receive the
british trade delegation for the first
time
mode mccartney had refused to kowtow the
traditional gesture a few minutes before
the end
in chinese etiquette
this is an insult
but that wasn't the only reason
mccartney failed to establish trade
links with china
we do not have the slightest need if
your country's manufactures
gives the judgment of the side of heaven
for the emperor the british envoy is and
no more than barbarians from a distant
unknown corner of the world
foreigners
who begged to be given the on her of
paying him tribute
the british envoys mission physical
it's disaster
mccartney had admire the great wall of
stone
but he had stumbled on another
that surrounded the middle kingdom for
two thousand gene
nearly fifty years later thomas staunton
throughout the company of the nation as
a boy would make an impassioned speech
in parliament calling for war against
china
to enforce kingdoms right to trade
these barbarians brought down the
chinese empire without skating and he
warns
they came across the sea
china's walls visible and invisible
crumbles over time
we're grateful could not protect
the middle kingdom from its enemies
some of the trade it with force
others found the gates were opened
yet it remains a symbol
north of beijing
where the storm dragon wines majestic
lead over mountains and across ravines
this architectural masterpiece
will still be few speechless
limits of the great wall in people's
mind
always be more powerful than the truth
of its checkered history