much remains the same.
The farmer tills his
fields today as his
ancestors did in ages past.
A heritage endures.
The people of the valley
come and go.
Life, in village and city goes
on as generations have come
and gone, the mountain streams
have flowed on.
The friendly earth still
yields its produce.
And cradling the valley, now
as always, silent, lofty
mountains keep their
eternal vigil.
DAVID FEINBERG: Every piece of
coal in China is intended to
go through one of the national
coal factories.
This is a private coal mine
that was shut down by the
authorities.
Private mining is illegal, but
since there's such a crazy
demand for coal, a lot of people
try to start their own
mine in order to profit from
the lucrative black market.
Most of them are not successful
and get fined or
put in jail.
-[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID FEINBERG: The enormous
government
factories are easy to spot.
We drove by a lot of them but
never hung out for very long
because we didn't want the
security guards to see us.
-[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID FEINBERG: To get a better
sense of the illegal
coal industry, we went into
the hills about two hours
outside of Linfen.
The area was still dense with
pollution, and we started to
see smaller factories and then
what appeared to be some
illegal mines.
Since they're not regulated
by the government and are
operated using old methods, the
illegal mines are a big
part of the pollution problem.
-[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID FEINBERG: Most of the
people we approached for
interviews were very
friendly with us.
But pretty soon they realized
that the questions we were
asking could get them
in trouble.
A lot of the residents of Linfen
have been excluded from
the economic prosperity that
has come to the region.
It's basically what happens when
a bunch of farmers are
forced to try to make a living
from harvesting coal instead
of harvesting crops.
Everywhere we went, people
seemed to be scavenging for
bricks, metal, wire
or anything else
to make some money.
After spending a week
in Linfen, my
eyes burned a little.
My throat itched, and when I
picked my nose, my burgers had
turned black.
-[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID FEINBERG: After almost a
week in Linfen, the police
came to our hotel.
They didn't come to our rooms,
but they had the hotel staff
bring us what our translator
said were registration forms.
We were afraid that our tapes
might get confiscated because,
after all, we were filming
illegally.
We were basically there as
tourists who happened to have
professional video cameras.
We got a last glimpse of the
factories and empty rivers.
It was as good a time
as any to leave.
-We are faced with a very short
tiny window to make the
right choices about
our future.
So it's not a question
about whether or not
China should develop.
China has to develop in
order to lift more
people out of poverty.
However, it's more about how
China should develop.
The local-level officials are
still very much obsessed with
just economic growth.
Really, the evaluation of
officials' performance have to
change in a big way in order
to give more incentive for
those people on the local
level to do more for the
environment.
DAVID FEINBERG: When the World
Bank first named Linfen the
most polluted city on earth,
the Chinese government set
about to improve
the situation--
closing down factories,
rerouting truck traffic, and
there were even some signs
around the city calling
attention to the problem.
As for the coal trucks, we were
surrounded by them for
another 20 hours as we drove
back to Beijing.
And we sat in our van at one
tollbooth for about six hours
in the middle of the night.
All of the fumes helped me sleep
through most of it, as
coal trucks idled around us, and
the car in front of us ran
out of gas.
Growing up, my impression of
China was of a huge boulevard
entirely full of bicycles.
They've obviously been replaced
by cars and trucks.
And if you add the burning of
coal to that, as well as all
of the manufacturing that goes
on, China is now the world's
leading polluter.
-I think that China is trying
its best, tried to host a good
Olympic game, and try to give
a good impression for the
whole rest of the word.
Measures tried to clean up air
for the Beijing Olympics--
if you look at them, a lot of
them are very short term.
It's about shutting down
factories, and it's about
having strict transport
restrictions.
You would actually be much
more smart if we tried to
think of long-term structural
solutions.
As a Beijing citizen, if I would
have clean air for those
two weeks in Beijing, and then
afterwards, I would think, why
can't I have that
have every day?
These are all things that can
lead to much long-term
thinking after the Olympics.
DAVID FEINBERG: A lot of people
say China is going
through its own industrial
revolution, but I think that
China's problem is kind
of a global problem.
One of the biggest winners from
China's economic rise are
the Americans and other
multinational companies who
use cheap labor and materials to
produce goods that are sent
all over the world.
As big a mess as China has to
clean up, the United States is
still the largest per-capita
polluter in the world.
China's claims that the blue
skies have opened over Linfen
is obviously false, especially
when you watch the sunset end
about 20 minutes early, when
the sun sets behind an
artificial curtain of smog.
However, once the sun goes down,
the stars do come out to
shine in Linfen.
-[SPEAKING CHINESE]