DITULLIO: HI EVERYONE AND
WELCOME TO RIT SPORTSZONE. I'M
JOHN DITULLIO. HILL: AND I'M
SHELBY HILL. TODAY SPORTSZONE
REACHES A MAJOR MILESTONE AS WE
KICK OFF OUR TENTH SEASON RIGHT
HERE IN THE BRICK CITY.
DITULLIO: YOU KNOW, SHELBY, OVER
THE LAST TWO YEARS THE RIT MENS'
HOCKEY TEAM EXPERIENCED A FEW
MAJOR MILESTONES OF ITS OWN. TWO
YEARS AGO THE TIGERS CLINCHED
THEIR FIRST TRIP TO THE NCAA
TOURNAMENT NAD REACHED THEIR
FIRST FROZEN FOUR IN SCHOOL
HISTORY. HILL: AS EMILY CLARK
REPORTS, LAST SEASON A FORMER
TIGER CONTINUED RIT'S STRING OF
FIRSTS WHEN HE REACHED THE
HIGHEST LEVEL IN HOCKEY. CLARK:
LAST SEASON FORMER RIT HOCKEY
PLAYER CHRIS TANEV WAS PRESENTED
AN OPPORTUNITY MOST PLAYERS ONLY
DREAM OF. AFTER LEAVING SCHOOL
FOLLOWING HIS FRESHMAN YEAR,
TANEV BRIEFLY TOOK THE ICE WITH
THE AHL'S MANITOBA MOOSE, BEFORE
RECEIVING A CALL UP TO THE NHL'S
VANCOUVER CANUCKS. TANEV: IT WAS
A LOT OF FUN. I WAS VERY EXCITED
AND I HAD A BALL UP THERE. IT
WAS A DREAM COME TRUE. CLARK:
WHAT WAS IT LIKE PLAYING IN YOUR
FIRST PRO GAME AND WHAT WAS
RUNNING THROUGH YOUR MIND?
TANEV: JUST TRYING NOT TO MAKE A
MISTAKE OUT THERE AND JUST
TRYING TO HAVE FUN AND ENJOY THE
MOMENT. CLARK: BUT THE MOMENT
AND THE GAME WERE CLEARLY
DIFFERENT FROM HIS DAYS AT RIT.
TANEV: THE GAMES ARE MORE
CONTROLLED; THE GUYS ARE BIGGER.
YOU HAVE TO PLAY YOUR POSITION
BASICALLY TO A T AND NOT DEVIATE
FROM THE GAME PLAN AND IT'S JUST
A LITTLE BIT OF A STEP UP.
CLARK: SO HOW DO YOU STAY SO
FOCUSED AND SO CALM WITH ALL THE
PRESSURE AND ATTENTION? TANEV:
IT'S JUST HOW I PLAY AND DO
NOTHING SPECIAL. IT'S HOW MY
PERSONALITY IS AND I JUST TRY TO
ENJOY THE GAME AND IT'S JUST
HOCKEY WHEN YOU GET ON THE ICE.
CLARK: TANEV PLAYED IN 29
REGULAR SEASON GAMES. HE EVEN
TOOK THE ICE IN THE PLAYOFFS AND
CAME WITHIN ONE WIN OF HOCKEY'S
TOP PRIZE, THE STANLEY CUP. SO
HOW DIFFICULT IS IT TO GET TO
THAT POINT IN THE STANLEY CUP
FINALS? TANEV: IT'S VERY
DIFFICULT. THERE ARE 32 TEAMS
AND YOU PLAY 82 GAMES IN THE
REGULAR SEASON AND THEN YOU'VE
GOT TO WIN ANOTHER 16 TO WIN THE
STANLEY CUP SO IT'S A LONG GRIND
AND IT'S TOUGH ON YOUR BODY, BUT
THAT'S WHY YOU'RE PLAYING, TO
WIN THE STANLEY CUP AND WE CAME
REAL CLOSE, BUT UNFORTUNATELY WE
DIDN'T WIN. YOU OBVIOUSLY WANT
TO WIN ONE OF THOSE LAST TWO
GAMES AND WIN THE STANLEY CUP,
BUT YOU TAKE IT AS A LEARNING
EXPERIENCE AND AFTER A FEW DAYS
PASS BY, IT'S SOMETHING YOU'LL
ALWAYS REMEMBER BUT HOPEFULLY
YOU'LL LEARN FROM IT AND GET
THERE IN THE FUTURE AGAIN.
CLARK: AS ONE OF THE YOUNGEST
PLAYERS IN THE LEAGUE, TANEV IS
HOPEFUL THIS IS JUST THE START
OF WHAT HAS ALMOST FELT SURREAL.
SO WHEN YOU TOOK YOUR FIRST STEP
ON THE RIT CAMPUS, DID YOU EVER
DREAM THAT EVERYTHING WOULD HAVE
HAPPENED AS IT HAS HOCKEY WISE
IN THE PAST YEAR FOR YOU? TANEV:
NO, I DEFINITELY DIDN'T THINK IT
WOULD HAPPEN. IT'S BEEN PRETTY
CRAZY. IT'S BEEN A WILD RIDE AND
HOPEFULLY I'LL IMPROVE MY GAME
AND GET BETTER ON THE ICE.
CLARK: THE CANUCKS MANAGEMENT
TALK SO HIGHLY OF YOU; DO YOU
EXPECT TO BE STARTING WITH THEM
NEXT SEASON OR BACK IN THE AHL?
TANEV: I'M JUST GOING TO BE
WORKING HARD ALL SUMMER, GET TO
TRAINING CAMP AND DO MY BEST OUT
THERE. I'M GOING TO TRY AND MAKE
THE BIG CLUB AND HOPEFULLY I DO,
BUT IF I DON'T, THAT'S FINE. I
DEFINITELY NEED TO GET STRONGER,
DEFINITELY NEED TO IMPROVE MY
SHOT AND THERE'S DEFINITELY
PARTS OF MY GAME THAT I NEED TO
IMPROVE A LOT TO BE THERE THE
WHOLE YEAR OR BE THERE EVEN FOR
A LITTLE BIT. HILL: IN ADDITION
TO CHRIS TANEV, FOUR OTHER
FORMER TIGERS WERE INVITED TO
NHL TRAINING CAMPS THIS FALL.
DITULLIO: STEVE (INAUDIBLE)
JOINED TANEV IN CAMP WITH THE
CANUCKS. TYLER BRENNER SKATED
WITH THE TORONTO MAPLELEAFS,
BOBBY RAYMOND WAS WITH OTTAWA,
WHILE GOALTENDER JARED DEMICHAEL
ATTENDED CAMP WITH THE DEFENDING
STANLEY CUP CHAMPION BOSTON
BRUINS. STILL TO COME ON
SPORTSZONE: THREE RIT STUDENTS
GO ON A JOURNEY OF A LIFETIME
AND THE TIGERS EARN THE TOP SPOT
BEFORE THE PUCK EVEN DROPS ON
THE NEW SEASON. NEW SPEAKER:
HOCKEY. DITULLIO: THE LAST FIVE
SEASONS RIT AND AIR FORCE HAVE
OWNED THE ATLANTIC HOCKEY
ASSOCIATION SO IT SHOULD BE NO
SURPRISE THAT THE DEFENDING
REGULAR SEASON CHAMPION TIGERS
AND TOURNAMENT CHAMPION FALCONS
ARE ONCE AGAIN PICKED TO FINISH
ATOP THE AHA STANDINGS. OUR VERY
OWN SHELBY HILL CAUGHT UP WITH
THE TIGERS AND PREVIEWS THE
UPCOMING SEASON. HILL: LAST
YEAR, HOW UPSETTING WAS IT TO
WATCH AIR FORCE CONTINUE AND SEE
YOUR SEASON KIND OF END
ABRUPTLY? WILSON: THAT WAS
REALLY DISAPPOINTING. SOME
PEOPLE WERE ASKING IF IT STUNG,
THE DEFEAT, BUT IT WAS JUST
DISAPPOINTING WHENEVER YOUR LAST
GAME ENDS WITH A LOSS, BUT
HAVING SAID THAT, I WAS REALLY
HAPPY WITH THE WAY WE PLAYED IN
THAT PARTICULAR GAME. WE OUTSHOT
THEM PRETTY BAD AND LOST ONE
NOTHING. WE JUST COULDN'T SCORE
A GOAL AND HAD A BIT OF A
HANGOVER FROM THAT LOSS FOR A
LITTLE BIT. NEW SPEAKER: THE
FEELING AT THE END OF THE GAME
LAST YEAR, LOSING ONE NOTHING IN
FRONT OF OUR HOME CROWD AT BLUEN
CROSS, IT'S JUST NOT A GREAT
FEELING AT ALL AND IT'S HARD TO
DESCRIBE. HILL: AND SO ARE YOU
GOING TO USE THAT LOSS AS
MOTIVATION FOR THIS YEAR? NEW
SPEAKER: DEFINITELY. THEY'RE ONE
OF THE TEAMS THAT WE LOOK TO
BEAT EVERY YEAR AND THEY'RE ONE
OF THE STRONGER TEAMS IN OUR
DIVISION SO I MEAN, IT'S
DEFINITELY GOING TO BE
MOTIVATION AND HOPEFULLY WE CAN
GET THE WIN BACK AND MAKE IT
BACK TO THE TOURNAMENT. HILL:
YOU LOST SOME PRETTY GREAT
SENIORS LAST YEAR. HOW'S THE
TEAM MAKING UP FOR THEM? NEW
SPEAKER: JUST BRINGING IN A GOOD
RECRUITING CLASS WITH THE
FRESHMEN CLASS. FROM WHAT I'VE
SEEN SO FAR, THEY CAN PLAY AT
THE SAME LEVEL THAT OUR SENIORS
HAVE PLAYED. WE'VE JUST GOT TO
WAIT AND SEE WHO'S GOING TO STOP
UP THIS YEAR AND WHO'S GOING TO
SORT OF FILL THOSE ROLES OF LIKE
FAVOT AND BRENNER AND THOSE TYPE
OF PLAYERS. NEW SPEAKER: WE LOST
OUR TOP TWO GOAL SCORERS AND
POINT GETTERS, WE LOST OUR GREAT
ROLE PLAYERS WITH SEAN MURPHY
AND MIKE JANDA AND YANNI. JUST
FIVE GREAT GUYS, ALWAYS IN THE
LOCKER ROOM, THE LOUDEST AND
MOST POSITIVE, SO IT'S GOING TO
BE TOUGH TO REPLACE THEM, BUT I
THINK MY SENIOR CLASS WILL DO A
PRETTY GOOD JOB OF IT. HILL: SO
CAN YOU TELL ME ABOUT THE
FRESHMEN? WILSON: WELL, IT'S
GOING TO BE INTERESTING HOW THEY
ADAPT. WE'VE GOT STARTING IN
GOAL JORDAN RUBY, THAT COMES IN
VERY HIGHLY THOUGHT OF. WE
CERTAINLY THINK A LOT OF HIM AND
I THINK HE'S GOING TO CHALLENGE
TWO GOALIES IN SHANE AND JOSH
THAT HAVE REALLY DONE VERY WELL
FOR US. ON DEFENSE, WE BROUGHT
IN ONE DEFENSEMAN TO JOIN THE
SEVEN THAT WE RETURNED, SO IT'S
GOING TO BE A DIFFICULT TASK FOR
STU BROWNELL WHO'S IN THAT
POSITION, BUT SOMEONE THAT WE
BELIEVE IN AND IS GOING TO HELP
US THIS YEAR AND IF NOT THIS
YEAR, IN OUR FUTURE YEARS. NEW
SPEAKER: DEFINITELY HAVE A LOT
OF CONFIDENCE IN THEM, JUST FROM
THE FEW SCRIMMAGES THAT WE'VE
HAD AND THE CAPTAIN'S PRACTICES.
THEY LOOK PRETTY GOOD. EACH OF
THEM BRING SOMETHING DIFFERENT
TO THE TABLE. I HAVE A GOOD
FEELING THAT THEY'LL STEP RIGHT
IN AND FILL SOME HOLES FOR US
AND START THEIR LEARNING CURVE
AND THEIR GROWTH FROM DAY ONE.
NEW SPEAKER: THE FRESHMEN ARE
VERY GOOD THIS YEAR; I'M VERY
EXCITED. THIS YEAR'S PROBABLY
THE MOST EXCITED I'VE BEEN OUT
OF THE TWO PREVIOUS YEARS ABOUT
OUR FRESHMEN COMING IN. THEY'RE
VERY SKILLED AND ALL OF THEM CAN
STEP IN AND PLAY RIGHT AWAY.
HILL: AND AS A SENIOR YOU'VE
SEEN THIS TEAM GROW. WHAT DO YOU
THINK ARE SOME OF YOUR STRENGTHS
AND WEAKNESSES? NEW SPEAKER: I
THINK ONE OF OUR BIGGEST
STRENGTHS IS OUR TEAM DEFENSE. I
THINK WE PLAY PRETTY GOOD IN THE
DEFENSIVE ZONE AND OUR
GOALTENDING'S BEEN PHENOMENAL
EVER SINCE I'VE BEEN HERE AND I
CAN SEE IT CONTINUE TO GROW WITH
RUBY AND WATSON TAKING OVER WHEN
SHANE LEAVES. OUR OFFENSE HAS
ALWAYS BEEN PRETTY TOP NOTCH,
BUT I THINK SINCE I'VE BEEN HERE
OUR TEAM DEFENSE HAS PROGRESSED
PRETTY WELL. NEW SPEAKER: I
THINK SOME OF OUR STRENGTHS
WOULD DEFINITELY BE OUR SPEED,
AGAIN, THAT'S ALWAYS ONE OF OUR
STRENGTHS EVERY YEAR IS OUR
SPEED, AND OUR PLAYMAKING AND
OUR WORK ETHIC ARE HUGE
STRENGTHS. AND THEN SOME OF OUR
WEAKNESSES PROBABLY ARE GOING TO
BE GOAL SCORING AND STUFF LIKE
THAT, LOSING BRENNER, LIKE I
SAID, WHERE HE SCORED A LOT OF
GOALS FOR US LAST YEAR AND OVER
HIS CAREER, SO WE'RE GOING TO
HAVE TO SEE WHO'S GOING TO FILL
THOSE VOIDS AND SCORE SOME
GOALS. HILL: SO WHAT ARE YOUR
EXPECTATIONS FOR THE TEAM THIS
SEASON? WILSON: OUR GOAL IS TO
GO TO THE NCAA'S. YOU KNOW, WE
SAY THAT RESPECTFULLY TO ALL OF
OUR OPPONENTS IN THAT WE KNOW
WE'RE GOING TO GET STIFF
COMPETITION AND IT'S A VERY
TOUGH THING TO ACCOMPLISH. NEW
SPEAKER: DEFINITELY SAME AS LAST
YEAR AND THE YEAR BEFORE: GET
BACK INTO THE NCAA TOURNAMENT.
IT'S ALWAYS BEEN OUR GOAL SINCE
I'VE BEEN HERE AND I THINK IF WE
JUST KEEP THAT IN OUR MINDS,
WE'LL ACHIEVE IT. I KNOW WE CAME
UP SHORT LAST YEAR AND THEN TWO
YEARS AGO WHEN WE WENT TO THE
FROZEN FOUR WAS JUST A MAGICAL
THING, BUT WE DEFINITELY NEED
TO, AND WILL, GET BACK TO THE
NCAA TOURNAMENT. DITULLIO: NOW
DON'T FORGET THAT RIT SPORTSZONE
IS ONCE AGAIN YOUR HOME FOR
HOCKEY THIS SEASON. HEAD TO
RITSZ.COM AND CLICK ON HOCKEY
CENTRAL FOR THE LATEST HOCKEY
NEWS, HIGHLIGHTS, INTERVIEWS AND
SPRING ROB GROW WILL BEGIN HIS
TWENTIETH SEASON AS RIT'S
BASEBALL COACH. DURING HIS
TENURE, GROW HAS WON MORE GAMES
THAN ANY OF HIS PREDECESSORS AND
WHILE SELLING RIT AND THE
BASEBALL PROGRAM TO POTENTIAL
RECRUITS HAS NEVER BEEN A
PROBLEM BEFORE, IT'S AN EVEN
EASIER SELL NOW. SPORTSZONE'S
JEFF BLOSSETT EXPLAINS.
BLOSSETT: ROB GROW'S MESSAGE TO
RECRUITS THESE DAYS IS PLAIN AND
SIMPLE: GROW: YOU WANT TO LIVE
THE DREAM? COME HERE AND WE'LL
GIVE YOU A CHANCE TO LEARN FROM
GUYS THAT KNOW HOW TO GET THERE.
BLOSSETT: GREG KEAGLE AND R.D.
LONG BRING A WEALTH OF
EXPERIENCE TO RIT. GROW: IF YOU
WANT TO BE A PITCHER, GREG WILL
MAKE YOU THE BEST POSSIBLE
PITCHER. IF YOU'RE A POSITION
PLAYER, R.D.'S GOING TO GET YOU
BETTER AND BETTER AND BETTER,
BIGGER AND STRONGER, FASTER,
BETTER BASEBALL PLAYER, SO WE'VE
GOT GUYS THAT CAN GIVE YOU A
PATH TO PLAY BEYOND COLLEGE NOW,
SO WHEN WE'RE RECRUITING NOW, WE
TALK TO KIDS ABOUT THE ACADEMIC
OPPORTUNITIES, THE CO OP, HOW
GREAT RIT IS ACADEMICALLY, BUT
WE'VE ALWAYS BEEN ABLE TO TALK
ABOUT THAT. NOW WE'RE ABLE TO
ADD ON ON THAT LEVEL OF, IF YOU
WANT TO PLAY AFTER COLLEGE,
WE'VE GOT GUYS HERE THAT CAN
HELP YOU GET THERE TOO.
BLOSSETT: KEAGLE PITCHED
PROFESSIONALLY FOR ELEVEN YEARS,
INCLUDING THREE SEASONS IN THE
MAJORS WITH THE DETROIT TIGERS.
KEAGLE: NOTHING THAT I TALK
ABOUT I INVENTED. IT'S ALL
THINGS I WAS SMART ENOUGH TO
LISTEN TO OTHER COACHES THAT HAD
BEEN AROUND THE GAME A LONG
TIME. IT TOOK ME A LONG TIME TO
REALIZE THAT IF YOU CAN SLOW
THIS GAME DOWN, YOU'RE GOING TO
BE A LOT MORE PRODUCTIVE AND A
LOT MORE SUCCESSFUL, AND I THINK
THAT FOR YOUNG PLAYERS, THAT'S
THE HARDEST THING. I THINK THAT
THE EXPERIENCES THAT WE WERE
ABLE TO HAVE ALLOWS US TO
HOPEFULLY INFLUENCE THE YOUNGER
PLAYERS AND THE COLLEGE LEVEL
ATHLETE TO EXPLAIN TO THEM,
"LOOK, WE'VE STRUCK OUT; WE'VE
GIVEN UP HOME RUNS. WE'VE MADE
MISTAKES." AND I THINK TO BE
ABLE TO EXPLAIN THAT TO THEM
THAT YOU KNOW, IT'S REALLY,
AGAIN, I'M THROWING QUITE A FEW
CLICHÉS AROUND, BUT IT'S NOT
WHETHER YOU GET KNOCKED DOWN,
BUT WHETHER YOU GET UP.
BLOSSETT: COACH LONG WORKS WITH
RIT'S POSITION PLAYERS. HE
PLAYED SIX SEASONS IN THE
YANKEES MINOR LEAGUE SYSTEM,
WHERE HE DEVELOPED A TIRELESS
WORK ETHIC, THANKS TO FUTURE
HALL OF FAMER DEREK JETER. LONG:
DEREK JETER BY FAR, BY FAR, IT'S
SO BY FAR, INFLUENCED ME IN SUCH
A WAY IT'S UNBELIEVABLE AS FAR
AS WHAT YOU HAVE TO DO. I
STARTED GOING THROUGH A WORKOUT
PROGRAM EVERY DAY WITH HIM,
WHICH WAS A WEIGHT TRAINING
PROGRAM. FIRST WE'D GO ON THE
FIELD AT 9, WE'D DO ALL OF OUR
STUFF UNTIL 12, WE'D GO INTO THE
WEIGHT ROOM AT 1 AND LIFT UNTIL
3 O'CLOCK. I HAD NEVER DONE
ANYTHING LIKE THAT RELIGIOUSLY.
THIS BOY, REGARDLESS OF HOW LATE
WE WERE UP, WOULD BE AT THAT
FIELD READY TO GO AT 9 O'CLOCK.
MY TIME WITH JETER THOUGH, KEPT
ME IN THE LEAGUE FOR SIX YEARS
INSTEAD OF BEING CUT AFTER TWO.
BLOSSETT: KEAGLE AND LONG NOT
ONLY SHARE SIMILAR EXPERIENCES,
BUT NOW SHARE SIMILAR
PHILOSOPHIES, AS RIT ASSISTANT
COACHES. KEAGLE: WE COACH VERY
SIMILAR HERE AT SCHOOL: I'M NOT
A BABYSITTER. WE ARE HERE AS
SUPPORT AND I CAN'T WANT IT
WORSE THAN MY PLAYERS WANT IT,
AND I THINK THAT'S WHAT HE'S
TALKING ABOUT WITH DEREK. NOBODY
WAS THERE TO TELL DEREK! HERE'S
A GUY ON REHAB AND AT THAT
POINT, LET'S FACE IT: BASEBALL,
ONE THING YOU KNOW IS WHEN
YOU'RE HURT, YOU GET FORGOTTEN
VERY EASILY. SO IT'S UP TO YOU
TO PULL YOURSELF UP BY THE
BOOTSTRAPS AND GO OUT AND DO
YOUR WORK. WE USE THIS ALL THE
TIME, THIS ANALOGY: IT'S NOT AN
ACCIDENT. YOU PUT YOURSELF IN A
POSITION TO HAVE SUCCESS,
SUCCESS WILL COME. DON'T EXPECT
IT TO JUST COME BECAUSE YOU'RE
TALENTED, FIRST ROUND PICK, THIS
THAT OR THE NEXT THING, BECAUSE
THERE'S BEEN SOMEBODY ALONG THE
WAY WHO CAME ALONG WHO WAS JUST
AS TALENTED, JUST AS RICH, JUST
AS CONNECTED AS YOU WERE. GROW:
THEY'RE ON THE SAME PAGE BECAUSE
THEY HAD THE SAME EXPERIENCES.
THEY WENT THROUGH PRO BASEBALL,
SO NOW IT'S JUST PUTTING THAT
INTO A COLLEGE SYSTEM AND MAKING
SURE THAT THESE GUYS, ON A DAILY
BASIS, GET THAT WORK DONE AND
REALLY UNDERSTAND WHAT IT TAKES.
SO THEY BOTH CONTRIBUTE AN AWFUL
LOT. I COULDN'T IMAGINE ON A
DAILY BASIS IF THEY WEREN'T HERE
HOW MUCH DIFFERENT IT WOULD BE.
OUR PLAYERS ARE FORTUNATE THAT
THEY HAVE SPECIAL GUYS INVOLVED
IN THE PROGRAM. NEW SPEAKER:
STAY ON THE ROAD. TROMBLEY TIRE
AND AUTO. DITULLIO: OVER THE
SUMMER, THREE RIT STUDENTS
EXPERIENCED THE JOURNEY OF A
LIFETIME, AS KRISTIN KLOCK
DISCOVERED, IT WAS A RIDE WITH A
PURPOSE FOR THESE PI KAPPA PHI
BROTHERS THAT SPANNED NEARLY
4,000 MILES OVER 67 DAYS. KLOCK:
THE ONLY DISABILITY IN LIFE IS A
BAD ATTITUDE. THIS WAS THE DAILY
MANTRA FOR TJ RODGERS, VICTOR
SANTIAGO AND ALEX DUNNER AS THEY
TRAVELED CROSS COUNTRY ON A
JOURNEY OF HOPE. NEW SPEAKER:
THIS ALL STARTED BACK IN 1978
WITH BRUCE RODGERS. HE WAS A
MEMBER OF OUR FRATERNITY, PI
KAPPA PHI, HE WAS DOING A CROSS
COUNTRY BIKE TRIP AND DECIDED
THAT HE WOULD DO IT IN THE NAME
OF PEOPLE WITH DISABILITIES.
EVER SINCE THEN, IT'S BECOME SO
MUCH BIGGER AND IT'S GROWN
EXPONENTIALLY EVERY YEAR. THIS
PAST YEAR WE HAD RIGHT AROUND
130 PEOPLE AND IT'S BRANCHED OUT
FROM HIS ONE ORIGINAL ROUTE TO
THREE SEPARATE ROUTES. KLOCK:
WHAT ARE THE THREE SEPARATE
ROUTES? NEW SPEAKER: THE THREE
SEPARATE ROUTES ARE THE NORTH,
THE SOUTH AND THE TRANSAMERICA.
THE TRANSAMERICA ROUTE STARTS IN
SEATTLE AND GOES TO WASHINGTON,
D.C. AND THE NORTH AND SOUTH
START IN SAN FRANCISCO AND GO TO
WASHINGTON, D. C. AS WELL. PI
KAPPA PHI IS ACTUALLY THE ONLY
FRATERNITY TO OWN AND OPERATE
ITS OWN PHILANTHROPY, SO PUSH
AMERICA WAS STARTED BY PI KAPPA
PHI AND YOU KNOW, WE JUST SEEK
TO RAISE FUNDS AND AWARENESS FOR
PEOPLE WITH DISABILITIES. THE
MISSION STATEMENT OF PUSH
AMERICA IS TO BUILD LEADERS OF
TOMORROW BY ASSISTING PEOPLE
WITH DISABILITIES TODAY. KLOCK:
THE THREE TIGERS WERE ALL CREW
MEMBERS WHO WERE RESPONSIBLE FOR
THE SAFETY OF THE CYCLISTS. WHAT
GOES INTO MAKING SURE THEY GET
FROM SAN FRANCISCO TO WASHINGTON
SAFELY? NEW SPEAKER: THERE'S A
LOT OF LOGISTICS AND A LOT OF
PLANNING THAT GOES BEHIND IT. US
CREW GUYS, WE GET DIRECTIONS FOR
EVERY SINGLE DAY OF THE TRIP SO
OUR BINDERS ARE ABOUT LIKE THIS
THICK. AND AGAIN, THE NIGHT
BEFORE WE SCOUT, MAKE SURE THAT
THE ROADS ARE FINE, AND IF WE
NEED TO DO A DETOUR WE'LL HAVE
TO RIDE IT OUT AND WE'LL HAVE TO
FIND A DETOUR ON OUR OWN. KLOCK:
AS THE LONG AND TIRING JOURNEY
CAME TO A CLOSE, THE TIGERS
BEGAN TO REALIZE JUST HOW LIFE
CHANGING THEIR EXPERIENCE WAS.
WHAT WAS IT LIKE ARRIVING IN
D.C. AND FINALLY FINISHING THE
67 DAY JOURNEY? NEW SPEAKER:
HEARING ABOUT IT FROM THE
BROTHERS WHO HAD DONE IT BEFORE
AND ACTUALLY EXPERIENCING IT,
IT'S TOTALLY DIFFERENT. THAT DAY
COMES AND YOU HAVE ALL THREE
ROUTES GETTING TOGETHER, ALL THE
CYCLISTS ARE IN THE ROAD, AND
JUST DRIVING THROUGH THE CITY,
PEOPLE ARE JUST LIKE HONKING AND
YELLING, BECAUSE SOME PEOPLE
DON'T KNOW WHAT'S GOING ON BUT
THEY SEE THAT THE COPS ARE
LEADING US, SO IT'S GOT TO BE
IMPORTANT, AND ONCE YOU GET
CLOSER AND CLOSER TO THE CAPITOL
BUILDING, PEOPLE JUST MULTIPLY.
THERE ARE PEOPLE HOLDING SIGNS
SAYING, WE LOVE YOU! OR, WE
MISSED YOU! GLAD YOU'RE BACK!
AND THERE'S PEOPLE JUST
CHEERING. THEY WERE THERE
BECAUSE YOU ALL WENT THROUGH THE
TRIP TOGETHER AND AS SOON AS WE
GOT OUT OF THAT AND STARTED
WALKING THROUGH THE CROWD OF
PEOPLE, AND JUST HAVING MOMS AND
DADS COME UP TO ME AND SAYING,
THANK YOU FOR GETTING MY SON
HOME; THANK YOU FOR HELPING HIM
GET HERE SAFELY. IT'S JUST LIKE
WOW! IT'S ONE OF THOSE THINGS
THAT IT JUST HITS YOU HARD, AND
YOU NEVER FORGET IT. HILL: ZETA
TAU ALPA AND PHI KAPPA PSI
ORGANIZED THE 16TH ANNUAL MUD
TUG. 155 TEAMS PARTICIPATED IN
THE EVENT, HELPING TO RAISE OVER
$10,000 FOR THE HILLSIDE FAMILY
OF AGENCIES. SO HOW ARE YOU
PERSONALLY INVOLVED IN MUD TUG?
NEW SPEAKER: I'M THE CO CHAIR
FOR ZETA TAU ALPHA, WHO IS ONE
OF THE CO HOSTS OF MUD TUG, THE
OTHER ONE BEING PHI KAPPA PSI.
NEW SPEAKER: WE ORGANIZED THE
WHOLE ENTIRE EVENT, GOT
EVERYBODY INVOLVED, ALL THE
SPONSORS AND EVERYTHING, SO
WE'RE PRETTY MUCH RUNNING THE
ENTIRE THING WITH OUR FRATERNITY
AND SORORITY. NEW SPEAKER: AND
HOW MUCH PLANNING GOES INTO THIS
EVENT? NEW SPEAKER: WE STARTED
PLANNING LAST SPRING, SO SPRING,
SUMMER AND THEN UP UNTIL NOW. I
HEAR FRESHMEN WHEN THEY COME IN
FOR THEIR FIRST DAY FOR
ORIENTATION SAYING, "I CAN'T
WAIT TO GO TO MUD TUG!" I HEAR
PEOPLE WALKING ON THE QUARTER
MILE SAYING, "I CAN'T WAIT FOR
MUD TUG!" IT'S GREAT. EVERYONE
LOOKS FORWARD TO IT. NEW
SPEAKER: AND WHAT EXACTLY IS MUD
TUG? NEW SPEAKER: IT'S A TEN ON
TEN TUG OF WAR COMPETITION OVER
A HUGE MUD PIT NEAR THE PLAY PIT
HERE AND IT JUST BRINGS TOGETHER
THE RIT COMMUNITY; THE WINNER
GETS FREE TICKETS TO THE FAR
EAST MOVEMENT CONCERT. NEW
SPEAKER: AND DO YOU KNOW HOW
MANY TEAMS SHOWED UP TODAY? NEW
SPEAKER: AS OF LAST NIGHT, 95
WERE REGISTERED; HOPEFULLY THERE
WERE MORE TODAY, SO PROBABLY
OVER 100. NEW SPEAKER: THE WHOLE
ENTIRE CAMPUS IS INVOLVED:
FACULTY STAFF, STUDENTS, AND
IT'S FUN TO SEE EVERYBODY GET
OUT TOGETHER, GREEK LIFE, CLUBS,
ORGANIZATIONS, FRESHMEN AND SEE
WHAT THE RIT COMMUNITY IS
ACTUALLY LIKE. NEW SPEAKER: WHAT
GOT YOU OUT HERE TODAY? NEW
SPEAKER: ONE OF MY BEST FRIENDS
IS DJ'ING AND THEY WERE MAKING A
TEAM FOR MUD TUG SO I SAID, WHY
NOT JOIN? I'VE NEVER BEEN THERE.
I'M HAVING A GREAT TIME! NEW
SPEAKER: AND WHAT'S YOUR
FAVORITE THING ABOUT MUD TUG SO
FAR? NEW SPEAKER: GETTING REALLY
DIRTY AND RUNNING AROUND COVERED
IN MUD! I LOVE IT! AND OF
COURSE, WINNING THE TUG OF WAR
PART. THAT PART'S COOL TOO. NEW
SPEAKER: WELL, WE GOT TO GO
FIRST. WE GOT TO TUG AGAINST THE
DREAM TEAM AND THAT WAS PRETTY
AWESOME. NEW SPEAKER: AND DID
YOU GUYS WIN OR LOSE? NEW
SPEAKER: WE KILLED 'EM, WE
ABSOLUTELY KILLED 'EM. NEW
SPEAKER: I AM THRILLED. I HAVE
BEEN WAITING SO LONG FOR THIS
DAY AND I COULD NOT BE HAPPIER.
DITULLIO: WELL THAT DOES IT FOR
THIS EDITION OF RIT SPORTSZONE.
HILL: DON'T FORGET YOU CAN STAY
UP TO DATE WITH SPORTSZONE BY
FOLLOWING US ON TWITTER AND
LIKING US ON FACEBOOK. DITULLIO:
SO UNTIL NEXT TIME, THANKS FOR
JOINING US HERE IN THE ZONE.