Defense, help, help, help!
Time-out. Somebody call time-out.
- Get over here! Come here. Come on!
- We're coming, we're coming.
Antoine. Son, how many times
I gotta tell you
don't knock the ball into the parking lot?
- Yes, Dad.
- Nice shot.
All right, fellas, listen up.
This is what it is.
We're down by one point,
28 seconds to go.
We gotta get the ball back.
Make 'em give it up, understand?
- Yes.
- All right.
- I want Kenny to take the last shot.
- Let me!
- This one's on Kenny.
- He'll miss it!
- Antoine!
- But the guy's all over me.
- What if I can't get open for a shot?
- Henry, can you set a pick for him?
- That's all it takes.
- Henry's wack!
Antoine, get serious.
Henry's gonna set the pick,
you gonna take the shot,
you gonna bring it up, all right?
Now give me some hands.
Hands! Last chance. Get real.
Win!
Now let's get out there
and beat somebody!
You want me to shoot
to win the game? Me?
I want you to shoot to win.
You can do it, son.
A and K, all the way!
- Oh, Ma.
- Oh, man.
OK, boys, let's play some ball!
Kenny!
Go, Kenny!
Go, go, go! Kenny, go! Shoot it!
What?
All right, all right.
- I can't believe that.
- That's so not cool.
You played great, guys.
- Come on, bro, it's all right.
- Oh, man.
- Come on.
- Dang.
- I should have made that.
- It's all right. It's all right.
Hold them heads up. It's all right.
It's all right. You're still my boys.
Come on, man.
Just give me the ball.
All right.
Can't you see I'm in the zone?
Just pass the ball.
All right.
- You missed a lay-up. So what?
- So what? So what?!
Man, we lost! We lost because of me!
Man, I don't get it.
I had 'em with the Antoine lookaway.
I had my tongue hanging out like Mike.
There's no way that shot doesn't drop.
Unless that tongue's
got some aerodynamic properties,
it's not gonna help you make a lay-up.
That's what I said,
aerodynamic properties.
Tell it to Mike.
Come on, James.
Those two need to come on inside,
get their homework done and go to bed.
- Aw, Ma, just a couple more minutes?
- Come onů please!
- Don't "Aw, Ma" me.
- Give us a minute, sweetheart.
Looků if you play the game
with passion and dignity,
it'll take you anywhere you want to go.
Cut it out. Hook up.
All you boys gotta do is stick together.
You do that, anything can happen.
Do you understand
what that means? Anything.
All right. Go on inside.
- Aw, Dad.
- Go inside.
Get in the house before your mom
come out here and snatch you up.
Hey, hold up, little man.
You know, I think you would've
made that shot today.
You gotta have faith, Kenny.
It's in here, man. Right here.
You just gotta trust it, all right?
- Go on inside.
- OK.
- Take Murphy with you.
- All right. Come on, Murphy. Let's go.
If you help me do my homework,
I'll get you a biscuit.
And Kenny Tyler
serves up the alley-oop
and Antoine Tyler slams it home.
And that's the one-two punch. And the
Tyler brothers cannot be stopped.
A no-look pass from Kenny Tyler
and a double-fisted "slam, bam,
thank you ma'am" from Antoine Tyler.
The Huskies are within one
of the Wildcats.
78-77, a ten-one run,
and Lute Olson's gonna call
a time-out here to regroup.
Bernie, what else
can we say about him?
A lot, Ernie. Let me tell you,
there's no question
he's the reason
the Huskies are 19 and six.
Antoine Tyler just will
not allow this team to lose.
Virtually overlooked in pre-season polls,
they have scraped
and clawed their way
into the top of Pac-10 standings.
You did a little scraping and clawing
yourself last night there, Bernie.
Incidentally, if they win the Pac-10,
it'll be the first time since 1985.
And that is a long, long,
long, long, long time to wait.
And here's Harry the Husky
to attempt his patented slam dunk.
Let's give him a big hand, folks.
And let's cross our fingers, too.
Harry the Husky
on the run and the flyů
Whoa! Split the crossbeams
on that one.
Did we make it?
- Huskies!
- Yeah!
OK, we were 15 down at the half. We
fought like hell to get back in this thing,
so let's not run out of steam, all right?
We gotta force a turnover.
Malik?
Malik, what are thoů Are those shorts
or a pair of damn hip-huggers?
Yo, Coach, it's the '90s. It's a style thing.
Here's my style thing.
I want you all over McCailiff, OK?
He goes to the crapper,
I want you standing ready to wipe him.
- I got him. Let's go.
- Good.
Zigiů Listen, you're
the last line of defense.
They get a breakaway,
I'll have you back in Siberia eating ice.
- It is Serbia, Coach.
- Whatever.
Listen, double-down on their guards.
I want them to think we're playing
with eight guys out there.
If they make a pass half-court,
they're gonna win the game.
- Danny.
- Yeah, Coach?
I know the game is getting intense,
but don't hit anybody.
- Not unless they deserve it, Coach.
- Hey, hey, Coach? Put me in.
Jimmy, sit down. Now, Kenny,
we need that ball. Go get it for us.
- You got it.
- Are you boys ready for this?
- Focus, baby.
- All right.
- Yeah!
- Cos it's up to you. Come on.
- Let's go!
- Dawgs up, baby!
- Come on.
- Let's go, baby!
- Hey, Coach, is that a new coat?
- Yeah.
Still got the receipt?
Antoine, no joking around.
You're my guy.
You're my guy, too, Coach. No jokes.
We got this one. Hey, Dawgs up!
Let's kick some ass!
Kenny Tyler with an alley-oop
and Antoine Tyler, 360 for the slam!
And the Huskies win!
The Huskies win it 79-78!
Somebody slammed the refrigerator
door and the butter's melting.
Antoine Tyler, he's a first-round
draft choice. Count on it.
We'll see you next week
at Pauley Pavilion
when the Huskies meet the Bruins
to clinch first place in the Pac-10.
- Kenny! Antoine!
- Mom!
You got it. You know you got it.
Oh, gosh. Your father would have
been so proud of you both today.
- I wish he could've seen you play.
- So do we.
But his spirit lives on in you.
- Hey, Ma?
- What?
Dawgs up!
It's the cabbage patch!
Yo. You know what this game is about?
It's about looking good. It's a style thing.
Do you know what I love about
this game? It's so physical.
You know, cos I love contact.
You know how I see myself?
I see myself as the African
ambassador of basketball.
Hello, ladies, I'm Zigi. Zigi Hrbacek.
I'm from Serbia. I play for UDub.
I am seven feet tall.
Today was an off night. I had 30 points,
I believe 15 assists, 12 rebounds.
- Stubbs, you never play.
- Oh, you probably had bad seats.
No, Stubbs, I go to every game.
This guy never plays.
- Antoine!
- Yeah. OK.
That's my boy right there!
Can I have a pitcher of beer, please?
- You got it, Kenny.
- Thank you.
- You go, RC!
- Yeah, that's good.
20 dollars. 20 dollars.
Easy money. Easy cheese.
Here you go, blind boy.
Hey, man!
Who took us all the way toů
And Iů
Hey, hey! Get your nasty ass outta here!
Whoa! OK! OK!
- Where am I at?
- Come on. Shoot it!
What theů?
I am soů I am so sorů
I am - I am so sorry.
Sorry.
It's over there.
Can you believe that seven-foot Serbian
tried to pay me in traveller's cheques?
Why are you taking that man's drachma
or whatever it's called?
- I need 'em, that's why. Come on.
- Lucky shot, man. Lucky shot.
Danny, don't even try it.
I'll shoot 'em on you all day.
Hey, that was a hell of a shot, dog.
I bought you a drink.
"l bought you a drink."
Sit your drunk ass down.
Hey, Cheryl. Hey, Cheryl.
What's happening, baby?
- I was just gonna call you.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- Dialing cramps your shooting hand?
No. We just got this tournament coming
up, see. I'm trying to keep my edge.
- You don't want me to lose my edge?
- Oh, no, Antoine.
I don't want you losing your edge, cos
I ain't gonna be around to help you find it.
- Come on, now. Hold on.
- Let me go.
Come on, girl. What you mean?
You not gonna be around?
- No, I'm not gonna be around.
- You really not gonna be around?
No, I'm not gonna be around.
- Uh-huh.
- You know, a little something.
- A little something?
- Yeah.
- You'll be around for me?
Can I get some?
- That's my girl. I'm crazy about you.
- You better be.
- Crazy about you, girl.
- Later, baby.
- Crazy about you, girl!
- What are you doing, man?
If you can't treat her right, cut her loose.
Stop it. Don't tell me nothing
about females. Stick to Nintendo.
- Aw, come on. What are you saying?
- Your problem is you scared to play.
Look here. I wrote the book
on macking, baby.
- Really?
- Uh-huh.
- With these hands.
- Prove it to me then.
- What?
- Prove it.
Hell, I will bet you ten dollars.
You pick any broad in this club,
I'll get that number tonight.
- OK, let meů
- You pick 'em out.
Hey, hey, no midgets, no cockeyed
broads and no toothless chicks.
- Cute ones.
- Ooh, I found her.
- Where?
- At the bar. Cutie-pie.
- Which one?
- 4 o'clock. Red bone.
- You gotta pick somebody else, kid.
- Yeah, that's your type.
Noů I'm just sayingů Hey, look,
I'm just trying to make this a fair bet.
Better yet, I'll go down and pull her,
she'll make us eggs in the morning.
You trying to play me.
I'm gonna show you a real mack, baby.
- You gonna show me?
- Call me Golden.
OK, all right. Go ahead, Golden.
I'm gonna sit up here and watch you
with your mack-daddy crisscross ass.
- I bet a Long Island iced tea.
- I'm betting, too.
Excuse me. Excuse me. Excuse me.
My bad. Excuse me. Excuse me.
Excuse me.
- Damn!
- Hey.
Hey!
For a guy with 11 assists
and eight rebounds,
you sure got a set of clumsy hands.
Well, sorry.
- I take it you saw the game tonight.
- You look good.
Thank you. I've been working out,
you know what I'm saying?
Your game. You look good.
Oh. Ow! Damn, that hurt.
How you doing?
I'm the wounded Kenny Tyler.
I know. Bit of advice, Kenny Tyler.
You shouldn't make bets you can't win.
Wait. Hold up.
Wait. Hold on. What's your name?
- RC St John.
- RC, I'm sorry about your purse!
See that girl with the bloody nose?
Got kicked out of the game
for elbowing that girl?
- Heyů
- I like her. I like her. Ooh!
- We got an article by a RC St John.
- Never heard of him.
Who?
RC St John, RC St Johnů That's that
new reporter from the UDub Daily.
Thomas told my boys,
said she's the bomb.
Yo, that's Red Bone.
The cutie I tried to talk to at the bar?
Yo, yo, yo, listen to this. Listen to this.
"And on a beautiful touch pass
from his brother Kenny,
Antoine Tyler sealed one of the
biggest upsets in college basketball."
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
Yes, I did. Yes, I did.
"While Antoine is theů" Whoa, whoa.
- "..is the engine that runs this teamů"
- Oh, she can write now.
"..it is his younger brother Kenny who
leaves his mark on virtually every play."
That's a good one.
Mouth is all open, you all cockeyed.
"I'm Antoine Tyler, star of the team."
"I'm cross-eyed, so I wear glasses."
Hey, you want me to beat
you up in front of everybody?
- Damn, why you gotta go there?
- Cos I can, crybaby.
OK, ladies, come on!
Let's move it out! We got the
vans waiting. We got a big game.
We're moving. Let's go.
Oh, yeah. I feel good tonight, boy.
It's gonna be a good one.
I'm gonna put on a show tonight.
- I got front-row seats.
- Be there!
Aw, come on now.
You know better, son.
And that's 15 for UCLA's Seward,
but the Huskies still hold on
by a narrow margin
as we near the five-minute mark.
And this seems to be the year
for the Huskies as they topple
one powerhouse after another
en route to their first berth
in the NCAA tournament since 1984.
O'Grady will bring it up. Lee guarding
him as they cross midcourt.
O'Grady on the dribble.
Goes low post Hrbacek.
Hrbacek back out to O'Grady.
Behind-the-back dribble.
He's gonna feed Kenny Tyler
on the cutter, back to Antoine from 15.
Buried it! 46 for Antoine.
15 assists for brother Kenny, as they
continue their quest for NCAA magic.
And the Huskies lead by two.
As we close in on four minutes,
Lee will bring it up, guarded by O'Grady.
Lee over to Rhem,
guarded by Antoine Tyler.
Gonna try to drive the lane,
goes up and rejected by Kenny Tyler.
They're gonna call a foul.
And that's number three on Kenny.
That seemed clean to me.
Next time down, run the fist out
and bring him hard across the middle.
- A and K.
- All the way.
- If you ain't open, who'll you pass it to?
- Who else?
Just making sure you remember.
Don't you forget it.
I can't. You keep pounding it in my head.
Rhem at the line, a 67% foul shooter.
He's been cold tonight.
Just four points on the evening.
That one, nothing
but the bottom of the net.
And he'll have another
to try to bring the Bruins even.
Box out! Zigi, rebound!
Rhem to try to tie things up. Young,
the rebound, trying to pass it out toů
Picked off by O'Grady. O'Grady
to open Tyler, he starts a fast break.
And he has brother Antoine
breaking for the basket.
Kenny Tyler on the dish
to brother Antoine
as they've done so many times before.
And Antoine for a monster jam!
Yeah!
He's a future NBA all-star in the making!
Yeah, baby!
Ant?
- All right, back off.
- Watch it, Lik!
Ant? Ant, what happened, man?
Step back. I wanna check him out.
Please stand back.
- Antoine? Antoine? Yo, you all right?
- It's OK, Kenny.
Let's get the paramedics
and get him on a stretcher.
I'm gonna come with you.
No, you stay. We still got the lead.
Finish these bums off, all right?
Step back, please.
Let's give him some room.
- Let's go!
- All right.
- You all right, man? You gonna be OK?
- I'm OK. I'm OK.
Give us some room, please.
- Nichols, go along with him, OK?
- OK, Coach. I'll go with him.
- It's OK. It's gonna be OK.
- I'm right here, kid. You all right?
- I'm all right. I'll be back.
- Ant?
I'll be back, baby.
- Respiration's 35 and shallow.
- You'll be all right.
Is he asthmatic?
Medications? Histories?
- No history.
- Let's get a BP on him.
- I'll be back.
- You'll be OK, Antoine.
Stay strong.
- He's gonna be all right, OK?
- All right.
- Move it! Move it!
- Let's move it!
- I can't find a pulse!
- What?
One, two, three, fourů
You'll be all right, Antoine.
- What are you doing?
- Just trying to get his heart started.
- Do something! Come on. Come on.
- Clear!
- Can't believe we lost this game!
- We suck. Pathetic.
Let's get the hell outta here.
Damn!
Kenny?
Hey, Coach, I'm about to visit Antoine
in the hospital. I gotta get his stuff.
- Kenny.
- What, Coach?
- We lost him, Kenny.
- What, Coach, for the season?
I told that boy to stop dunking
like he was Jordan.
- What? He dislocated his shoulder?
- Kennyů
What, Coach?
Antoine died on the way
to the university hospital.
He what?
It was his heart. They don't know why.
I mean, it justů
Coachů He just said
he was coming right back.
They tried everything, Kenny, but theyů
It happened so fast thatů
Nah. Bullshit. Bullshit, he died.
I'm going to the hospital.
- Kenny!
- Kenny, hold on.
- Move. I gotta go. Get off me!
- Come on, man.
- Get off me!
- Hold on a second.
- Get off me, man! Luther, get off me!
- Hold up, man! Hold up!
Get off me, man.
Calm down, baby.
We'll get through this together.
I'm so sorry, Kenny. I'm so sorry.
Oh, man.
Tyler slowly up court, brings it upů
Oh, and it's stolen away.
Cubby took it like candy from a baby.
This doesn't look good for the Huskies.
This is their three-game losing streak.
They need to snap that
and get on with the game.
Major scoops it out.
And Tyler will take a threeů
- Oh, another brick.
- Damn!
That's another disappointing
shocker, as the Huskies
just cannot win without their big star.
Kenny. Kenny. Just a few questions.
First your father has a heart attack
and then your brotherů
It wasn't supposed to be like this, kid.
First Pop.
Now you.
Our whole life.
Before school, after school,
at night when it was too dark to seeů
all we wanted to do
was play basketball.
Win that championship, baby.
A and K, allů
What am I supposed to do now, man?
I can't do this alone, Antoine.
I need you, kid.
- Hi.
- Come on, man. No interviews.
- I'm not here toů
- I'm tired of talking to reporters.
- I'm not a reporter.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I mean, not right this minute.
What?
I just wanted to say I'm really sorry
about what happened to your brother.
- I can't imagine.
- Thank you. But I'm fine, really.
To be honest with you, I'm really tired
of all the sympathy, you know?
So this was a bad idea? OK, I got it.
I'll just leave. Forget it.
No, wait. Wait. RC, wait!
It's not you. I'm just not used
to all this attention.
I got all these people calling me,
asking me questions.
ESPN, Time magazineů
Sticking all these cameras in my face.
- All this just cos my brother dies?
- I know, it's been awful.
Umbrella?
- Thank you.
- If you just wanna talk, you knowů
- Thank you very much.
- If you need someone to talk toů
Look, I ain't gonna thank you again.
All right. I'm joking.
- Come on!
- Watch your man, Zigi!
Come on. All right. Watch the back pick!
Kenny, set the offence!
Come on, you guys. Kenny, come on!
- Luther, move it.
- Dammit!
What is that? What is that?
Come on, Kenny.
I am!
Let's go. Come on, run the double fist.
Luther, I can't run that play if you can't
get open. Move it, Luther! Move it!
- Kenny!
- Hold it, hold it. Stop.
Give me the ball.
Luther, my wife's got a plastic
Jesus on her dashboard
- moves better than you do.
- Luther!
Listen, boys. We don't win this
next game, it's sayonara season.
It's no NCAA. It's no nothing.
What do you say, Coach?
I say we go out there and win.
All right, feed on that enthusiasm.
Set the offence.
Offence, come on, let's go.
Give 'em the ball.
- Come on!
- Here we go.
- Come on.
- Let's go, Dawgs.
- One to one.
- Come on, let's go.
- Kenny! Kenny!
- Big man for the three!
Hold it, hold it. Hold it a second!
Zigi, what the hell are you thinking?
- Wellů
- You never shoot the three.
You hear me?
You never shoot the three!
Everybody, Iů
- Hit the showers.
- All right. Go hit the showers. Take it in.
Malik, three-point line in America
longer than in Serbia.
Shut up, you seven-foot Tweety.
Shit, man. Damn!
Coach?
Hey, Coach?
Coach!
The ball, it's gone!
It disappeared! Coach!
- Hm. How you doing?
- How you doing?
- I'm fine. I'm chillin'.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- Cos I'm worried about you.
Coach, I'm a big boy.
You ain't gotta worry about me.
Well, I do.
You've been hit pretty hard lately.
I don't want to add to your problems.
But Coach Nichols thinks I should
start Jimmy at the point tomorrow.
I'd ignore him, but it's the first
original idea he's had in five seasons,
so I'm trying it on for size.
What do you think?
- You're the Coach, right?
- Yes, I am.
Jimmy can't set the pick or go to his left.
I mean, he couldn't carry this team
with a forklift. Kenny, you're my guy now.
I gotta know you're ready
to step up to the plate.
Yesterday was the worst practice
I've seen from any team I've coached.
And you didn't say a word.
Now why is that?
- Coach, I'm not Antoine, man.
- I know who I'm talking to.
I need you to take charge of this team.
Now I need a general.
- That's not my game.
- I'm asking you to make it your game.
- But if it's not my game, you can'tů
- I'mů
Kenny, you know,
it was four years ago today
that your brother signed a letter of intent
to play basketball at UDub.
I remember that day. I opened
a ten-year-old bottle of Scotch,
I went home for lunch,
I took a run at the wifeů
- I don't wanna hear that.
- That was a great day.
And the next year, we signed you
and I knew I had a team
that could take Washington to the
Final Four for the first time since '63.
And I'm not willing to say goodbye
to that dream, Kenny. Are you?
I gotta go, Coach. I got a two o'clock.
Hey, Kenny.
You don't have to play
without your brother, you know.
You got him. Right here.
At the second half, the Cal Bears
lead the hapless Huskies, 43-31.
But the big story tonight:
The continuing poor play of Kenny Tyler
with no points on no attempts.
- Hey, health food. All right.
- Mikulski, you're not eating?
No, I can't eat any more
when I watch these guys.
They make me sick.
I feel like I'm wasting away.
OK, guys. Now we're down 12,
but we don't stink.
Now, that's an improvement, all right?
OK, move 'em around on offence.
Move the basketball, OK?
- Come on. Dawgs up here.
- OK, hands in.
- One, two, three.
- Go.
- Hey, Kenny. Kenny!
- Yeah?
- You OK?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
OK, listen. If you get open,
take the damn shot.
- All right.
- OK.
And if you're not open,
who are you gonna pass it to?
Ten-foot fadeaway
and that'll drop off the rim.
Tyler comes up with a rebound.
He'll bring it up.
Let's see if Tyler will finally
take a shot this time downcourt.
- Tyler stops, calls the play.
- Anything can happen.
Tyler turns andů
We got a pass!
Nice pass.
Outside the three-point arc to O'Grady.
O'Grady for three!
- And the Huskiesů
- Great pass! Great pass!
What the heck?
Cal bring it back up.
Tyler tries to run him down.
He'll dish it off to Byron. Byron, easy
ten-footer. Got it. Nope, he didn't.
It's in and out. What a heartbreak.
Tyler with a rebound over to O'Grady.
What kind of shot was that?
O'Grady across the timeline,
he puts the move on Faby.
Serves up the no-look pass,
and Major with a slam!
And it's Dawgs up! Well, well, well.
The Huskies are back. They're on fire.
That's five unanswered points by the
Huskies. They're back in the game.
Fill me in, Bernie.
Eight seconds left in the game.
Huskies 72, Bears 73. Bears up by one.
- That makes the Huskies down by one.
- They in-bound the ball.
Cal in-bounds the ball.
Eight seconds and counting.
The Huskies need a turnover or they
can kiss the post-season goodbye.
Jacksonů on the pass, over to Stevens.
Stevens, top of the key with five, fourů
Open, open!
- And whoa! Hello!
- All the way, baby.
That ball came outta there
like a greased pig.
On the move now. Ahead to Tyler.
- Malik!
- A chest pass for Major.
And that ball loops up
to the basket and goes in!
Nice shot there. You see that? I'm telling
ya, Dawgs up, baby. Dawgs up!
75-73! The Huskies win!
Kenny Tyler with a knuckleball
three-pointer from half-court!
This is one for the highlight reels!
This is one to remember!
Here comes a bonus right now.
Kenny Tyler, folks.
Kenny Tyler, wow!
18 points, nine assists,
and a wild and wacky second half there.
The easy two would've sealed
the game. You went for the three.
Were you trying to send
the basketball world a message?
Not really. I was dribbling down-court
and I saw Malik cut toů cut to the hair.
I mean, to the hole andů
- Kenny?
- Wellů
Kenny?
I'll see you at the Barking Dog.
Did you see me elbow that guy?
Nice game.
Hello?
Hey, Kenny. I'm right here.
Do you hear me?
Hello?
Come on, y'all. Stop playin'.
- Anybody there?
- I've been here for 20 years.
Stop playin', y'all.
All of a sudden,
you don't know my voice?
That's cold.
I don't hear anything.
I might be having a nervous breakdown,
but I'm gonna be all right.
Go home and I'm gonna get me some
sleep. I'll be back on top in the morning.
I see you're gonna need
a little more convincing.
Come on, Kenny. Buggin', man.
Buggin'. Come on now.
Relax and get your shit together, Kenny.
Get your shit together.
This is all a dream. That's all.
I got you. I got you.
Kenny! Kenny, it's me!
- Back up.
- Kenny?
Back up. I will smoke you. Back upů
- Kenny. Kenny, it's me.
- I told you to back up off of me.
God, would you wake up?
- Come here.
- Get off me!
- Listen to me.
It's just like Pop said:
If you and I stick togetherů
anythingů anythingů
Anythingů
..can happen.
Lock 'em up.
Antoine? It's you?
Yes, it's really me, boy. Come on.
Come on, I told you I was coming back.
I told you I was coming back.
Man.
- I can't believe it, man.
- You better believe it.
Oh, shů Whoa.
It's a little too freaky.
I'mů I'm gonna take a seat.
I'm just gonna get me a seat.
Oh, wow. This is amazing, kid.
I don't believe it, man. Yo, wait till
I tell Mom. She's gonna be so happy.
- Kennyů
- Halloween'll be the bomb this year.
That's not the way it works.
You are the only one that can see me.
- Why?
- Because you called me.
- You said you needed me.
- This will take a lot of getting used to.
Well, get used to it fast, baby.
We got a trophy to get. All right?
- A and K?
- All the way.
- NCů
- Two A, baby!
Yeah!
- I missed you.
- I missed you, too.
- It's good to have my little brother back.
- It's good to have my big brother back.
Oh, man. My man, Antoine.
Whoo-hoo-hoo!
Oh, kid. It's is so good to see you.
Tell me something I don't know.
Folks, as the Huskies
take the floor today,
they face Washington State
in a must-win situation.
- Right.
- To clinch third place in the Pac-10
and the wild-card berth
in the NCAA tourney.
Tonight is huge, it's big, it's humongous.
It's Marlon Brando, I'll tell ya.
It won't be easy, because
when the Cougars come here
- to the Dawg House, they come to play.
- Who doesn't, Ernie?
Unless the Huskies
have lady luck on their side,
it's liable to be the end
of another long, disappointing season.
- Long, disappointing season.
- Sure is.
- Here we go. Let's huddle.
- All right. Let's go.
- Bring it in.
- Hustle up!
OK. OK, guys, here we go.
Now remember, we just
gotta play our game, OK?
Don't let them dictate the tempo.
All we gotta do is put the biscuit
in the basket, the noodles in the soup,
the cookies in the milk, the beef in theů
You said you wanted me to be
a little bit more verbal, Coach.
And when we get a leadů
Hey, Kenny. If we win this one,
we go to the tournament.
- You nervous, kid?
- Hell, no.
Kenny, you got a problem
with running the press?
Oh, no, Coach, I was just talků
Kenny, look at this. Look at this. Huh?
Kenny, look, I'm all thumbs. Watch. Oh!
OK. Now I wantů
We're gonna win this
with defense and rebounds.
- Stop it.
- I want you to watch out forů Preston.
- Watch this.
- Stop it.
Hey, cutie-pie.
Oh, shit!
- Kenny, what are you doing?
- Huh?
I got something in my throat, Coach.
Excuse me.
Keep Preston off the boards.
Water.
Oh, I am so sorry.
Oh, Iů Thank you.
I feel so much better now.
Let me help you with that.
Yeah, yeah. All right, great.
Somebody get him a towel.
That was funny.
What's the matter with you?
The start of the second half,
and the Washington Cougars, 37,
UDub Huskies, 34.
- A three-point differential.
- That's what it is.
LaSalle with the rebound
and over to Tyler.
- Tyler will bring it up.
- Hit Lik. Hit Lik.
Tyler shoots it ahead
to Major on the wingů
Bring it, baby.
Gonna work the baseline. He's forced
out of bounds. No, he's back in bounds.
And a slam! Wow!
Somebody check his feet for jet packs!
Peter Pan's in the house
and he's coming home for Christmas!
- Here he goes and he's upů
- Oh, yowza!
Oh! Did you see him fly?
I'm telling you,
the video camera does not lie!
- That was like Clyde Drexler.
- Dr J. Where you going on that?
Michael Jordan.
Major all over Preston.
Preston rolls inside.
Hrbacek steps up to try to take the
charge. Train wreck. That's a foul.
That's aů wait a minute.
No, a charge is called. Hello, Hrbacek!
The Serb takes the charge and comes
up standing like a seven-foot statue.
Preston outside for the three.
It looks good.
No, it's out. Try to tip it in.
No, not again.
It looks like a popcorn popper up there.
- Too much English on that ball.
- It's got French, Spanish and Swahili.
- There's 15 seconds left to the game.
- The Huskies are up by one.
Washington has the ball. Huskies have
to keep the Cougars from scoring.
Tyler on Davidson now
as he brings it up.
Listen. Don't blow it.
That boy gonna go left.
Davidson fakes left, goes right
and leaves Tyler faked.
He drives in for an easy slam.
- I thought you said he was going left.
- He went to our left.
Hey, what? What?
And Coach Pederson's gonna
call a time-out to regroup.
- I thought you said he was going left.
- He mostly does.
- What you mean "mostly"?
- I'm a ghost, not a psychic, all right?
- Oh, shut up!
- Hey, hey, hey, you better watch it.
- Stop that.
- I'll call Ghostbusters on your ass.
You better call somebody.
- What is Kennyů?
- Huh?
Seven seconds to go. The Huskies' ball
as Coach Pederson draws up the play.
You're gonna take the ball out.
Zigi, you set the screen here forů
Go! Go!
Go!
Tyler'll step up
to make the in-bound pass.
Throw it in. I'll do the rest.
Alley-oop at the basket.
Tyler with the in-bound
to a breaking O'Grady.
Quick pass, LaSalle.
I got it, I got it, I got it.
LaSalle, behind-the-back snow cone.
Now with a one-hand
touch pass to Hrbacek.
Between the legs of Preston.
Major steps up,
lofts one over his shoulder.
Kenny Tyler for the alley-oop.
It's gonna be close! Tylerů
And he slams it home
as the clock runs out. What a win!
The Huskies win 71 to 70. Huskies win.
- What a game!
- Where are we going?
- To the big dance!
- To the big show!
The big show in the sky!
Thank you.
That was beautiful.
Kenny. Kenny.
Kenny, not your game, huh?
- Hey.
- Great finish.
Hey, thank you. You the man, Coach.
You the man, baby.
Yeah! English!
Come on, man. You scared me.
You can't be doing that.
Whoo! Tourney time, boy!
We finally did it, kid.
We finally did it. We did it.
We did it, kid. We did it.
I bet you all wondering
what I'm doing, huh?
- Personally, I'm curious.
- Well, umů Umů
- The floor's all yours, baby.
- I was just giving myself a hug. See?
Loving me. You know why?
It's because I think that, you know,
I feel really good about all that
we accomplished here today,
and I think we should take
a moment and reflect,
and then give ourselves a big hug.
Yes, give yourself a hug.
Wow. Doesn't that feel good? Zigi?
- What's up with Kenny, man?
- He's just sad.
What do you mean, he's sad?
Sadů He is nuts.
We have to have a talk.
I'm not losing any tournament over him.
- Let's go.
- No, he's crazy, man.
- Hi.
Um, anybody sitting there?
- No, just that invisible man there.
- Oh. OK.
Kenny? Sit down. He just went to class,
so you can sit now.
Come on, sit. Sit, sit, sit.
Damn invisible people
just keep popping up, you know.
Soů
I was like, you know,
wondering if maybeů
me and youů you knowů
- Like, me and you, right?
- Me and youů
Like, together? Beů Damnů Umů
If maybe, like, me and you could, likeů
- Go out?
- Yeah?
Yeah, why not?
Yeah. Hell, yeah.
You must be proud.
The team's been kicking ass.
Oh, yeah. We've been really
hot lately, you know.
No, you've been more than hot. It's been
weird. You know what I'm saying?
Shots dropping in, hitting nothing
but net from no-business angles,
guys skying with six-second hang-timeů
Hey, well, you know, that's just
the great thing about the game.
It's like on any given night,
anything can happen.
Maybe.
Damn, where you been, boy?
I've been trying to find you all day.
- Would you stop that?
- Stop what?
Stopů looking so good
with your bad self.
Hey, man. This water's freezing.
My nipples is getting hard.
Don't nobody wanna hear
about your perky nipples.
Kenny, have you thought
about seeing someone?
RC, trust me.
I'm seeing plenty right about now.
- Uh-huh.
- Would youů excuse me, please?
Kennyů
Do me a favor. Take some advice
from your dead big brother.
- What's that?
- Keep this girl at a distance, man.
- Why?
- Trust me.
Because right now, you're a hot story.
She's a reporter.
If she breaks this story, you are the new
nut on the cover of National Enquirer.
Hey, look, the girl ain't like that.
Hey, come on, baby. Relax.
Relate. Release, baby. All right?
Don't be jealous just cos your prospects
look like all the chicks
in the "Thriller" video.
- You think that's funny?
- Necrophiliac.
You remember how I used
to whoop your ass when we was kids?
- Don't mess with a dead man.
- What? I ain't scared of nobody. What?
What? What you saying, boy?
What? What? What?
Whaů OK.
One, two, threeů
Get off me! Get off me.
Don't make me hurt you.
Remember I used to put you
in the dofey?
- No. No, not the dofey!
- It's dofey time.
Get off me. Get off me.
- Not the chicken wing!
- Chicken wing?
No.
All right, you got me. OK. All right, OK.
All right, yeah.
How you like that, Space Ghost, huh?
Hey, hey! Hey!
I hateů you!
- All right!
- Get it up, boy.
You can't deal with me.
Come on, Mohammed Ugly.
Come on, baby.
Nipples!
- Kenny!
- Hey, guys. Ow. OK. Ow, ow, ow.
Me and the guys, we want to knowů
What's up with you, man?
Nothing. I'm just loosening up.
Doing a little bit of kung chi.
- Kung chi?
- What the hell does kung chi mean?
- Yeah, what the hell does it mean?
- Kung chi.
- You know, kung chi, kung chi.
- Huh?
It's an ancient oriental art form
of loosening up.
All the sumo wrestlers do it.
See, that's how they fit their big ass
in them little diapers.
But for real, guys, I'm fine. I'm fine.
See, fine? Fine. Fine. Fine. Fine.
You're buggin', man.
Either you talk to us
or we're gonna talk to Coach.
Coach don't say nothing
to you other than sit down.
Would you shut up?
Listen, guys, wait, wait, listen.
It's Antoine.
Kennyů Big A is dead. He's gone.
You're gonna have to face it.
- Not necessarily.
- Don't do it.
He's back and he's right here, see?
Look at him, guys.
- He's back.
- You need some serious help.
- It's worse than I thought.
- You need help.
Come on, Antoine!
You gotta tell 'em, man.
I can't tell 'em.
This only works if I keep a low profile.
Negro, you invisible! How much more
of a low profile you gonna get?
- Who's he talking to?
- Let me slap him. Just once.
- No, come here.
- Let me slap him. He'll snap out of it.
Just grab him. Ready? Grab him.
- Come on, guys. Wait, wait, wait.
- Grab him tight!
Hey, man, I'm hungry. I'm going
to get some Chinese food. Bye-bye.
Ant, you gotta do something!
Please do something, man. Please!
- I can't hear you. I gotta go.
- You gotta show 'em!
You the only one that can see me.
Antoine, Antoine, please. I'll never ask
you for anything again in my life.
Please, Antoine. Just show 'em, man.
Show 'em I'm not crazy, please?
All right. I'll do it.
Wait, wait, wait.
I'm gonna prove it to you.
- Danny Partridge.
- What?
Dunk it.
- Bite me.
- Just do it.
Kenny, he cannot possibly do it.
He's just too small.
Man, who are you?
Seven foot and can't touch the rim.
- At least I'm seven foot.
- Antoine's gonna make him do it.
Oh, boy, here we go again.
Danny misses the dunk, we take you
to the coach and get you some help.
- OK. All right.
- This is stupid.
- Go!
- Will you just do it?
- All right.
- Come on, let's go.
- Quit being scared. Just do it.
- Come on, white man, jump!
Do you know how stupid this is?
This is stupid. Man, look at me.
Do it.
- All right.
- Come on, Opie, dunk it.
Goddamn! Holy shit!
See? Now do you believe me?
Oh, he-he-he's just, um,
pumped for the tourney, that's all.
- Yeah, yeah.
- Oh, this guyů
Oh, tough crowd.
Well, um, I have-I have been
working out a lot lately.
Wait, hey, hey, hey, heyů
See? See, now you done pissed him off.
Oh, my God!
- Oh, geez.
- I don't believe it.
I don't believe it.
- You better believe it, baby.
- Nice touch, baby.
Welcome back.
Welcome to the San Francisco Bay Area
and the sights and sounds
of the NCAA West Regional.
From the Oakland Memorial Coliseum,
it's the University
of Washington Huskies
against the Bulldogs of Fresno State.
First though, we got a chance
to watch Harry the Husky
as he'll perform his patented
slam-a-jam-a dunk.
Looks like he's carrying a load.
And the stat sheet says he is, um,
0 for 15 in the season so far.
Come on. Here we go.
And here he is, all set.
He's up.
- I hope that dog was wearing a cup.
- Yes, definitely.
Slight miscalculation.
Go, Dawgs. Huskies!
There's nothing like
the NCAA tournament.
It's the most special, unbelievable event.
The pageantry, the excitement.
I think it'll be awesome, baby.
It wasn't too awesome for the Huskies
in their match-up with Fresno State.
Coaches Pederson
and Tarkanian are really ready.
But Tarkanian put the hurt on him
bigtime during the regular season.
Blew 'em out by 20 points.
It was an M & M'er, a mismatch.
They're loaded. They can shoot
the trifecta. They got diaper dandies.
They got prime-time players.
They're awesome.
Pederson better have his club ready
or it'll be Embarrassing City, baby.
So you really like musicals a lot, huh?
Oh, you know, when the
showboat appeared, it was magic.
- Hey, St John, how ya doing?
- Great.
See you got all dressed up
for the tournament.
You like that? I like to look nice.
Hey, Gertz, why don't you take a stroll?
Get yourself a complimentary hot dog.
I'm gonna talk to our friend here, OK?
- What for?
- I'm shy.
What do you care? Just go do it.
Today. While we're young.
- So.
- Soů
You and Kenny are pretty close, huh?
- We've talked a few times.
- Yeah.
- But that doesn't mean thatů
- No, no, no. Hey. Relax, relax.
I know you're both adults,
and what you guys do during recess
is no business of mine.
Anyway, the thing is, there's
something going on with this team.
I have a feeling Kenny's
got something to do with it.
Hm. What are you
getting at, Mikulski?
What I'm getting at is something
you ain't got: a break.
Now if there's a story here
and you drop the dime,
you know, it could be the cover
of Sporting News.
- What do I have to do?
- Whatever it takes to get the story.
Grab yourself a cold one
and hold on to the armrest, folks,
cos it's game time. So the Huskies
and the Bulldogs set to square off.
And Hrbacek will tip off
against O'Neil of Fresno State.
O'Neil, you recall, earlier in the regular
season involved in an altercation
with Kenny Tyler that resulted
in Tyler's ejection.
Up, and controlled by Hrbacek
over to Tyler.
He'll bring it up, guarded by Seymor.
- Hey, hey. Start it off right.
- Come on, get a life. Leave me alone.
- Let's go to Zigi for a three-pointer.
- Zigi can't shoot no three-pointer.
- Hey, just do what I say, Kenny.
- Zig.
Tyler, the dish to Hrbacek
way outside the three-point line.
He's 0 for 12 outside
the arc this season.
- Zigi, what the hell are youů?
- Do it, Zigi.
- Zigi for threeů He got it!
- I can't believe it! Zigi goes downtown!
Nice shot.
This Serb is going long-distance.
Somebody call MCI.
I mean, he deserves a discount.
- You've been working with him?
- I, uhů
- Good work, Coach.
- Thanks.
Peabody brings it up,
guarded by O'Grady.
Tark will call the play.
Peabody over to Seymor.
Seymor, O'Neil.
And a drive and a slam over Zigi.
And the foul. And now tempers flare.
Malik, he better watch it. He'll get a T.
Tyler now steps in to try
to calm things down,
and there's no love lost
between those two.
Better be careful. Big brother ain't here
to protect your ass no more.
- What?
- Come on, bring it, little girl.
- That's bullshit!
- Excuse me?
I should head-butt you like Rodman.
- What's that?
- All right, easy.
O'Neil, known for his bad-boy ways.
A regular Dennis Rodman in the making,
but tonight he's more like Dennis
the Menace, out there looking for trouble.
- Pour it in now, pour it in.
- Hey.
- Whoo! Ooh!
- Shoot!
Drops back like a quarterback and
he rifles a line drive off the backboardů
Whoa. This ball is sailing,
sailing into the rafters.
Somebody call 911.
This boy needs a doctor.
Oh, yeah. That happens
on this planet all the time.
What the hell are you doing?
Keep your head in the game.
O'Neil left to ponder whether
he should've been trying outů
- The ballů It went upů
- What?
Huskies by nine now,
as we wind down here in the first half.
Seymor brings it up, guarded by Major.
O'Neil pushes Tyler.
That looks like a foul.
And Seymor dishes
to O'Neil on the wing.
You better leave my brother the hell
alone! And get your thumb outta my eye!
And O'Neil turns it over on purpose.
This boy has flipped his lid.
Somebody call Bellevue
and see if there's a vacancy.
Time-out.
So a major upset. 76-61. Dick, you
and I have seen a lot of strange games.
- This one was wild.
- I can't believe it. I mean, I'm stunned.
Tarkanian's gonna be shocked.
Look at the stats, Brad.
36 by Kenny Tyler. He was super.
I mean, he was a PTP'er. Pederson
is on cloud nine. Tarkanian's crying.
They wield some unbelievable
canine magic today, the Huskies.
- Whoo!
- All right.
- That's it, baby. Give me some!
- Chill. Chill.
That's the way we do it, boy.
A and K all the way.
- You know it, baby.
- Why don't we celebrate? Get grub.
Or better yet, let's go to the cemetery,
see if I can get laid. I need some action.
You know what? That sounds great,
but I think I'm gonna be busy tonight, bro.
Oh, come on. Hey, Kenny, man.
Will you stopů?
- We'll play that basketball.
- Yeah!
Oh, no, I couldn't. I couldn't. All right.
Go, Coach! Go, Coach!
Nichols, get in here.
- We're going to the tournament!
- Yeah!
One time, right,
my mom was being thrifty,
and she went to Kmart
and bought us these cheap-ass shoes.
- Stop.
- I couldn't tell the left from the right.
They were like some
ambidextrous shoes. It was hilarious.
Oh, man. Oh, God. Antoine.
That's my man.
- Soů
- So.
- We were talking about the game.
- Right.
Have you been doing anything special?
Wearing lucky socks?
Carrying a rabbit's foot?
Taking anything?
What do you mean, taking anything?
I've just never seen
a team play like this before, it'sů
So we gotta be on something?
No. I didn't mean for it
to pop out like that.
There it is. That's her headline.
"Huskies Shooting Up",
"Dawgs on Dope".
- Shut up.
- You're the only one that can hear me.
So hear me, Kenny. Kenny. Move.
- So what are you trying to say?
- I'm just, umů
She babbling. She's stuttering.
- Why are we talking like this?
- She ain't giving you no ass.
- No reason.
- Stop that corny smile.
- It's just that you look so bů
- Stop that. Don't get corny.
..beautiful from this angle.
Oh, you ain't gotta work that hard.
You ain't getting no ass.
- Excuse me. Gotta go to the bathroom.
- There is no rhythm.
Look, we've been through a lot together,
and I love you more
than anything in this world,
but you gotta stop popping up
all the time wanting to play.
I'm on a date.
I can't play with you right now.
Gosh. Why are you making it so hard?
People are starting to stare at me.
- You know something?
- Hey!
I have the same problem.
Trust me. My problem's
a lot bigger than yours.
Yeah.
Oh, no, wait, my man. I'm not talking
aboutů Not that kind of problem.
- That's not funny.
- You hurt him.
He thinks I'm talking to my piece.
You was having a little conversation
with your piece.
- A little conversation piece.
- Conversationů OK.
When I'm locked up in Bellevue,
I'm blaming you, OK?
Great, the food is here.
I am starving.
Look, Kenny, I didn't mean
to accuse you of anything.
Oh, girl, stop it. We cool.
Don't worry about it.
But there's been a lot of weirdů
Weird? Nah. I didn't notice anything
weird happening. You trippin'.
It's not just for steak any more.
Steak sauce. Mmm.
- Steak sauceů Mmm, mmm, mmm.
- Yes. Yeah.
I love me some steak sauce.
On salmon?
Oh, yeah. It gives it that,
uh, nice, zesty, tangy flavor.
Oh, that's gonna be good. Enjoy.
- Mmm, mmm, mmmů
- Ooh. Gets you right back here, right?
Gets you right back in the throat?
Need some water?
Need some water? Ooh.
Slow, slow, slow. Drink.
- Thirsty?
- Yeah.
- Yes. Yes. Sexy.
- I'm sorry, I'm just soů so hungry.
Would you like some zesty salmon?
You sure?
So, I had an interesting time tonight.
Well, I had a pretty
interesting time myself.
That's me.
It's late.
No. No, no, no.
Put that thing back in your mouth.
Maybe, um, maybe we're
rushing things a little bit.
Yeah, maybe we're rushing things
a little bit. Maybe we areů
- So embarrassing.
-ůrushing things.
Yeah.
Nowů take it easy.
What was that?
- It was stupid and embarrassing.
- I like to kiss on the move.
- Oh, really?
- It's freaky.
Oh, OK. It takes some getting used to.
- OK, I think I better go.
- Oh, OK.
- Yeah. OK.
- All right.
All right. OK, yeah.
- Bye.
- What's wrong with you?
- Crybaby.
- Mind your business.
- You have no right doing that.
I don't wanna hear it.
- Mind your business, man!
- You mind your business.
- Got no business telling me what to do.
- Kenny? Kenny, what's going on?
- Hey, Coach.
- Who are you talking to?
- Uhů
- Kenny.
- He'll glue your ass to the bench.
- Shut up!
I'm your Coach.
Don't talk to me that way.
You shouldn't have called me back.
- Well, maybe I'm sorry I did.
- All right then. I accept your apology.
- If you want me gone, I'm gone.
- Good.
Look. Look, Kenny, I'm not trying
to come down on you here.
- I'm just trying to help you here.
- Fuck it, I'm gone then!
- Good. Good.
- I'm gone!
- Kenny?
- You gonna be sorry. You need me!
What you doing?
You ain't gonna catch shit in here!
Stupid Frenchman. Get on my nerves.
Kenny? Just tell me
what's going on here.
Trust me, Coach.
You wouldn't understand.
Antoine?
Ant, I just wanted to say I'm sorry.
I didn't mean it, man.
You know that, right?
I know you didn't mean it. Crybaby.
Storm clouds continue
to brew from the Northwest.
What a story this has become
for the UW Huskies.
Their little guy Danny O'Grady
elevates his game to a new level.
So does his team,
as Coach Pederson's squad
upsets Dean Smith's
North Carolina Tar Heels,
sends the Heels packing
back to Chapel Hill.
For the Huskies, it's on to the Sweet 16.
O'Grady brings it up
into the front court, and the dishů
Zigi on the drive and the lay-in.
And Hrbacek's got 15.
Unbelievable!
A street brawl took place!
The Arkansas Razorbacks
cut themselves to shreds!
Three of their five starters were rejected
for fighting - with themselves!
How wacky can you get?
And their coach, Nolan Richardson,
he was sent to the showers, baby,
allowing the UW Huskies
to march on to the great A.
Husky hysteria's going wild.
So the clock's stopped.
3:20 remaining in the ballgame.
70-63 the Huskies, Dick, and they're
clinging to that seven-point advantage.
Well, Tito gets a TO, baby.
Right now, it's Maalox-mashing
time for both coaches.
Tito's talking to his team, sayin'
"We gotta speed up the tempo."
Pederson says "We gotta
spread out and slow it down."
OK, now, Danny and Kenny,
you keep that ball on the perimeter, OK?
And, guys, use the clock. Use that clock,
all right? Come on, let's go.
Let's go. One, two, threeů
UDub Huskies' ball.
Let's look for Major now to be
the triggerman on the in-bound.
Kirk will step up and force the press.
Wildcats in desperate
need of a turnover.
Major into O'Grady. And the little guy
will bring it up for the Dawgs.
And Marlowe covers him stride
for stride all the way up-court.
Four corners. Work the clock, guys.
Work it, work it!
O'Grady taking his time, working
that clock. Now crosscourt to Tyler.
- Throw an alley-oop to Luther.
- I can't. Coach saidů
Coach, my ass. Just do what I said.
I'm running this team.
And look for Tyler now to try to run
a four-corner slow-down offence.
He looks inside, fakes and now
he'll toss an alley-oop to LaSalle.
But LaSalle steamrolls Kirk
in the process.
And that is a foul. Charging call on Luther
LaSalle, Dick, and that's number five.
Wow. He's the big stork.
Goes to the sideline on a charge.
- Who they gonna put in?
- They'll have to go with Jimmy Stubbs.
- Who?
- Jimmy Stubbs.
- Jimmy who?
- Come on, move it, move it. Let's go!
- You call that using the clock?
- No, Coach, butů
Four fouls, you let yourself get called
for a charge? Sit down!
- Coachů
- Sit down!
- Sit down.
- Jimmy?
- Huh?
- You're going in.
- Who, me?
- Yeah.
Thank you. You will not be disappointed.
Nichols, huh?
Always looking out for a brother.
Lu, I just wanna say I'm sorryů
Get off me! And tell your damn
brother to get off me, too!
Whoo! Did you see that, boy?
Did you see me?
It was like old times.
Did you see how high I was, kid?
Ant, I ain't in the mood, man.
Leave me alone, all right?
- What?
- You buggin'. You're going too far.
I'm going to the Final Four, son.
I don't know where you going.
Another Husky shocker.
90-71, a 19-point win over Kentucky.
Excuse me. Kenny? Excuse me, baby.
Don't eat the cake till I get back. Kenny?
Where you at, Murphy? Whoo!
- Nice shot.
- Hey. Hey, what's up, Ma?
Whooů I remember when
you made that foul line.
I bought the paint.
You got sick of us drawing it
with your lipstick.
I, umů caught myself trying
to die a little with Antoine.
- Oh, Mom.
- Butů you wouldn't let me.
I watch you out thereů
alive and playing,
and, oh, God, it'sů
almost like he's right there beside you.
Honey, I don't know what's gonna
happen in New York and I don't care.
I just wanna say thank you, baby.
I just wish your daddy was here.
Ooh. He would be so proud of you.
- Who's your baby girl?
- You, Ma.
You better believe it.
Let's go inside. Uncle Jake's waiting.
- Oh, no, not Uncle Jake.
- Oh, yeah.
Ma, that man ain't got no teeth,
but always wants something to eat.
Look for Tyler now to try to run
a four-corner slow-down offence.
He looks insideů
- Yeah?
- Never eat a pizza after a burrito. Man!
What do you want, Mikulski?
- Talk to him?
- Yeah.
- What did you find out?
- Look, there's nothing to find out.
Mikulski, I gotta get back to this,
so if you don't mind,
I'd like for you to just leave meů
- Hello? RC, are you there?
-ůalone.
I can't believe it. Listen to meů
LaSalle steamrolls Kirk in the process.
Luther, you didn't evenů
You didn't even touch the ball.
Tell yourů
Tell your damn brother to get off me?
Yeah?
- Hey, what's up, Kenny?
- What's up, dog? What's poppin'?
Is it cool if we talk for a minute?
Is it cool I come in?
Yeah, come on.
- Come on, y'all, damn!
- Stop pushing!
- When I said "we", I meant the team.
- Damn.
- Is he here? Is Antoine here?
- Yeah, he's in the shower.
Dead people usually don't
take showers, Kenny.
And how many dead people
do you know, Zigi?
- Not too many.
- All right then.
What's up?
What y'all wanna talk about?
- Tell him. Come on.
- It's Antoine.
Yeah, what about him?
We don't want to play with him
any more. I mean, it feels wrong.
Yeah, just tell him to chill.
Maybe come sit on the bench with me.
Look, personally, I'm averaging 18
points a game since he's come back,
so I really don't give a shit, all right?
Look, look, look, look, look. He's a ball
hog. He was when he was alive.
And no disrespect,
he's even worse as a dead man.
He didn't hear us, did he?
- I think it's him.
- Me, too.
I still got that embalming fluid
in my ears. I can't getů
- Hi, Antoine.
- Calm down. Say it.
What's this? This looks like
some kind of lynch mob.
- Go ahead. Tell him.
- Huh?
- Just do it.
- You tell him, Luther.
Tell me what?
What are they talking about, Kenny?
I ain't telling him. You tell him, Jimmy.
It was your bright idea.
You're lying through
the space in your teeth.
- Talk to me, Kenny.
- They want you off the team, Ant.
Off the team? Me?
You want me off the team?!
Let me tell you something! You don't
tell me shit! You don't tell me shit!
- None of you!
- Antoine, chill!
- Shut up!
- Uh-oh. I think we pissed him off.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
Look, it's nothing personal.
- Nothing personal?!
- Don't throw that!
Nothing personal?! Nothing personal?!
I raised all your games to another level!
Me! I did that!
You on TV! You getting scouted!
Zigi, you might go lottery! I got that for you!
And this is the thanks I get?
You make me sick.
Uh, Antoine, if they don't want you
to use them, use me. I can see it now.
22 assists, 34 points, and ten boards.
Together we can win tournament MVP.
Sounds good?
- Man, shut up, Malik!
- I'm trying to go pro!
Kenny, I never wanted to die.
I had things I wanted to do. I had plans.
I know, man.
If you want me to go,
you just tell me and I'm gone.
Jimmy, this is my brother, and, umů
..if he wants to stay, then he stays.
- OK, let's take it in.
- Let's go, Huskies.
RC. RC. Hey.
Where have you been?
I've been looking for you.
You wasn't at the banquet last night
nor at the conference this morning.
- Where you at?
- Sorry, I've been busy.
Oh, you been writing?
Yes, writing, writing.
Uh, look, I have to go.
No, wait, RC, RCů I gotta talk to you.
It's really important, OK.
It's kinda difficult for me to say.
- You don't have to, really.
- No, I need to.
Sometimes things happen
that are bigger than us.
Things that we really can't explain.
Things that make absolutely
no rational senseů
- Kenny, you don'tů Really.
- I know this sounds crazy, believe me.
Butů it's about Antoine.
He's here.
Come on, Kenny.
Team meeting. Let's go.
OK.
- Sweetie, you gotta believe me, OK?
- Kenny, come on!
OK.
Coming, Coach.
Oh, yeah, it's a great hotel.
It's got hot water between 7 and 7.30.
- Here she is. You looking for me?
- Yes, I wrote this piece thatů
RC, this is David Gallagher,
Sporting News.
- Ron Hammer, the Boston Globe.
- Nice meeting you, gentlemen.
I wanted to talk to youů
Gentlemen, keep an eye on this girl,
because she has the drive.
You know, I think she'd sell
her own mother for a good story.
So, what do you got for me?
Ready to win that Pulitzer? Hm?
No. Not just yet anyway.
I got a little bit more work to do on it.
It was nice meeting you, gentlemen.
Wait, wait. Where are you going?
Come on! Come on.
I don't know. It must be my personality.
There goes the story of the year.
Welcome to The Meadowlands,
home of the NCAA,
home of college basketball's
highest honor,
and home of all the pageantry
and excitement that is the Final Four.
We kick off all the festivities
with UDub's Harry the Husky.
And Harry's gonna get set
for his patented slam dunk.
And I say "get set" because
the stat sheet doesn't look good.
0 for 16 on the season for Harry.
So, folks, this could get a little bit ugly.
- Harry's ready.
- I'm going downtown.
And he calls his shot ß la Babe Ruth.
Here we go.
Damn dog.
Oh, he got it!
Did you guys see that?
Thank you. Thank you.
Billy, it's gonna be a long night for the
Huskies unless they can find someone
to put those defensive handcuffs
on Georgetown's Jerrod Smith.
George, when you got a 6'5" point guard
that can go in the paint
and shoot the three, it's an impossible
match-up in the college level.
I don't think the Huskies have
another upset in 'em tonight.
- Kenny Tyler.
- The infamous Jerrod Smith.
- What's up?
- How are you?
- All right. How you feelin', man?
- I'm good, man. Yeah.
I'm really sorry to hear
about your brother.
- Oh, thanks, man. I appreciate that.
- I wish he was here.
Yeah. Me, too.
Get over there
and tell your team about me.
Aw, come on, man,
you better tell your team about me.
You better look up.
- I'm gonna get that ass, boy.
- We gonna get the ass.
Smith brings it up, over to Douglasů
- Pass, pass.
- Back over to Smith.
- You take it, Jerrod!
- Get on him!
Now Smith on the drive
at a 15-footer. Got it.
And that's 22 for Smith
here in the first half alone.
- Don't let Jerrod Smith do that.
- The Huskies just can't stop him.
That's 40-32 Hoyas,
as they roll on, led by Jerrod Smith.
Double-team Smith!
Get the ball, Kenny! Get the ball!
- Oh, he's got the lane.
- Help out, Malik.
- Smith for two moreů
- Damn!
They're scoring at will here.
What are y'all doing?
O'Grady now will try to guard him.
Nobody else has been able to.
Tyler in a double-team.
Jerrod passes inside Gruck
and the no-look to Bergos
on the baseline. Easy deuce.
They call a double-team on Jerrod
and he hurts 'em in other ways.
Jerrod on the dribble.
Time to play good D. Solid D, Kenny.
Watch him, going left.
Slam bam, thank you ma'am.
This guy is amazing.
You want me to handle it?
You want me to do it my way?
Cos I'll take care of him.
He ain't shit! Man.
O'Grady now, across the timeline.
He runs into a Hoyas double-team.
Pass over to Tyler. Not a good one.
Intercepted by Smith.
Smith on the break.
- Smith is down and he's injured.
- What you doing, man?
Coach Thompson
and the trainers are called in.
And, man, you hate to see this kind
of injury in a game of this magnitude.
- My shoulder.
- Jerrod, what's wrong?
- Just be careful. Take your time.
Stay there. Stay there.
And the heavily favored Hoyas
lose to UDub 78-65.
And now, the Huskies
move on to the big show.
- Kenny?
- Hey. What's up, RC? How you doing?
How is he?
I don't know. He's been
in surgery for over an hour.
I know he got a broken collarbone.
Concussion, too. Yeah.
I hope he's all right. God.
Kenny, it's your brother, isn't it?
- Yeah.
- So tell him to stop.
It's no use, RC. He ain't gonna
listen to me. He never listens to me.
He's the older brother.
He calls the shots.
Kenny, look at yourself. Antoine is dead
and he's still running your life.
You don't know what you're talking
about. First of all, you don't know us.
You just don't know what it's like trying
to live my life without my brother.
Stupidů
No, I don't know what it's like.
But neither will you until you let him go.
Antoine?
Yo, Antoine.
Antoine, I know you in here.
Yeah, I'm here.
You always did like being
first in the locker room.
Oh, that's only because
I was always so nervous, kid.
- Word?
- Yeah, man.
I'd come into the locker room,
see all these jerseys hanging,
and I'd find the one with my name on it.
And I would just sit down, stare at itů
wondering if I could go out there,
Lace 'em one more time
and live up to the hype.
Damn. I didn't know you were scared.
Baby brother, I played scared
every game of my life.
Wondering how I would do,
what people would think.
But I tell you something,
I'm not scared no more. No, sir.
This is one game I am going to enjoy.
Yeah, well, umů
You're gonna have to enjoy it
from the bench, Ant.
What are you saying?
Wait a minute, if this is about
Jerrod Smith, that was an accident.
You know me better than that.
I didn't mean to hurt him.
Antoine, look. You got us here.
No doubt about it, man.
Without you,
we'd be watching this on TV.
- Exactly.
- But, kid, this is cheating. It's wrong.
I'm sorry, Ant. You can't play, man.
- Oh, please. I'm playing, Kenny.
- You're gonna be playing alone.
Kenny, think about it.
NCAA title - one more game.
It's what we always dreamed about,
me and you.
Since we was kids, we've been partners.
Antoine, we ain't never
been partners, man.
I've been your sidekick
for over 20 years, kid.
And I was happy to be that, but I can't
do it no more, Ant. I just can't do it.
Now if you step on
that court tonight, it's over.
What are you gonna do?
How you gonna stop me? Huh?
We'll walk.
- We'll just forfeit.
- You will lose without me.
Then we'll just lose.
Welcome to the NCAA
National Championship.
Come on, get in here, guys. Get in.
Listen up now. Listen up. Come on.
You know, when I was a kid, I played in
the biggest basketball game of my life.
It was the Wilmington-Delaware
Youth League Championship.
And the winning prize
was a shiny gold medal.
Well, you know, we should've won
that game, but we didn't.
And I always felt that if I had
played just a little bit betterů
You know, if I had really played
my guts out, that we would've won.
And I would've won that medal.
Well, now this is theů This is the
biggest game of your lives.
And it's just you guys, two orange
hoops, 94 feet of hardwood.
So go out there and play
the very best that you can,
and really play your guts out.
And believe me, you will have no
regrets. And you will win your medal.
Just go out there and play the game
that you love. Come on!
Let's go! Let's go!
And the Huskies take the floor,
led by Kenny Tyler,
who's assumed leadership of this team
following the tragic loss
of his brother Antoine earlier this year.
The UMass Minutemen,
they're the favorites.
They come into the tournament
the number-one ranking
in all of college basketball.
Won't look for any upsets here.
Three future NBA stars on this club:
6'5" point guard, Rudy Olivera,
6'9" power forward, JJ Sampson,
and 6'10" forward, Mark Tucker.
I don't even think lady luck
can help the Huskies tonight.
Hrbacek and Sampson, the jump center.
And it's controlled by UMass,
over to Olivera.
You gotta push the ball, Olivera.
Push the ball.
- Sampson, down low.
- Zigi, Zigi, stay on him!
In the paint, a finger roll
and the early lead goes to UMass.
Go down! Give me two, give me two!
Tyler to O'Grady.
Hustle up, Danny.
Move that ball. Come on.
Dish back to Tyler. Tyler, with a look
and a shot that's way off the mark.
- Ooh.
- Goddamn.
Crosscourts it to Sampson,
out to Olivera.
Breakaway, easy deuce.
The Huskies are still having
trouble getting started.
We're midway through the half. UMass
leads 20 to eight. Back the other way.
The dish outside.
Moore, top of the key, he got it.
Nothing but the bottom of the net.
And the Huskies are down 14.
Get your hands off me!
Major has a look and sets,
and he'll take the three and he got it.
The Husky fans cheer their underdog
UDub squad for that three,
but it's hardly enough to send
the Minutemen packing.
Bounce pass down
to the baseline to Moore.
To Tucker. Tucker tosses it to Olivera.
Downcourt back-door lob.
And Sampson finishes that one off.
UMass just too strong tonight
for the Huskies,
as they pull to a 14-point advantage
with five minutes to go in the half.
Olivera proving his all-American
status in this half,
and he'll finish it withů a score!
Well, UMass leads 42 to 22 at half-time,
Billy, and I guess the $64,000 question
right now is, has that magic
that brought the Huskies
into the Final Four
finally abandoned them?
- Oh, man, it's over!
- We suck. We suck!
- We are pathetic.
- How many points we down, man?
- We down 20 points!
- It feels worse than that.
Let's be honest. We never
expected them to get this far.
It's amazing where they are. Too much
talent down the other end of the floor.
They're outclassed tonight.
Fellas, fellas, the hole's been dug, man.
They're just gonna bury us.
Guys, we just can't do it without Antoine.
We don't have to, Zigi.
Man, what are you saying, Kenny?
I'm saying I wanna win this. I didn't
come this far to go home empty-handed.
You don't know what
you're talking about.
Malik, we are down 20 points, man.
20 points! Do you know why?
I know why! Cos we suck.
See, that's bull. We don't suck!
They suck!
It's bullshit, man!
We're playing with no soul!
Cos we played that first half
without Antoine. Face it.
There's only one way
we gonna get back in this game.
What you saying?
I'm saying we go back out in that court,
Jimmy, and we take Antoine with us.
- No, no, no. We already agreedů
- Right here. Right here, Jimmy.
Right here.
Everything my brother wasů
Everything he gave usů is all right there.
Right here. Right here.
We gotta go out there and we gotta
shoot with him, we gotta run with him,
we gotta play with himů
We have to win with him, Malik.
Are you all with me?
- We're with you. Let's go.
- We're with you.
Let's do this. Let's go all the way now!
- We're with you, Kenny.
- Malik? Jimmy?
- Let's go. Let's do this!
- Let's go out there and win this game.
Let's go, baby!
The Huskies have hit the floor running.
Start of the second half, they're on
a 10-0 run. And they are fired up.
Kenny Tyler, top of the key, for three!
Kenny Tyler is lighting it up
on both ends of the court now.
O'Grady looks for someone.
Gets it to Tyler on the wing.
Tyler drives to the paint,
the 15-footer. It's good.
Kenny Tyler has electrified this crowd.
They're on their feet.
Holy smokes, Billy.
Kenny Tyler's on fire.
What an incredible performance
by this young man.
It really is, George. You love to see
big players come up in big games.
He's put this team on his back
and he's carrying them tonight.
Tyler fakes left, circles in,
drives, jumpshot up and it is goodů
- They're doing it, Mikulski.
- Danny! Hit Lik. Hit Lik.
O'Grady, the lob. Major with a slam!
And, ladies and gentlemen,
we have a ballgame.
- Set up. I'm coming back now.
- That's it. That's it!
In. In, baby, right here!
Go, Kenny! Go, Kenny!
Major to O'Grady.
O'Grady back to Tyler.
Fakes left, goes right,
fadeaway. He got it.
- And the Huskies pull to within 11.
- Right here!
O'Grady now, over to Hrbacek.
Way out on the wing.
Sky-hook for three, and Zigi hit it
from downtown for the triple.
That's it, you American scum, that's it!
Motion, baby. Motion.
Olivera makes the lay-in
to hold the lead at five.
Two minutes. Two minutes
and we down five, baby.
Kenny Tyler cuts it down to three.
Major into Tyler. Tyler fakes,
high archer off the glass.
He got it. And the double
brings the Huskies to within two.
And a time-out called by the Huskies.
The Minutemen clinging
to a two-point advantage
with just 16 seconds left on the clock.
OK, guys, 16 seconds left
to a National Championship.
We gotta keep Tyler from beating us.
And then we run the three
with Kenny, OK?
Kenny, you make the shot, all right?
Let's take this one home, fellas. This
is it. This is what we came here for.
- OK, come on. Dawgs up, you guys!
- Dawgs up! Dawgs up!
Come on, Zigi!
UMass!
And who would've thought the Huskies
would even be in this position.
16 seconds on the clock.
A chance at being a giant killer
of the number-one team in the country.
The Huskies are lining up. The
Minutemen'll use man-to-man defense.
We have to assume Pederson's made
the call to Tyler for the game winner.
Moore is all over LaSalle.
He doesn't want a five-second call here.
Finally, the in-bound is stolen by Tucker.
And that is it.
If they can hold on to it,
the championship is theirs.
Nine seconds to go. All UMass
has to do is to occupy this ball.
The Huskies step up the D,
but time is running out.
Somebody's gotta force a turnover
or a foul here or this one's in the books.
O'Grady on Tucker. We're down
to seven seconds and counting.
O'Grady on him like a pit bull,
trying to make something happen.
Five seconds left.
Someone needs a play here.
No turnovers. Don't turn!
Tucker trying to pass to Olivera
and Tyler gets a hand on it.
- Here comes Tyler again.
- Go! Go!
Come on!
Tyler again, he's got it. He goes up.
I got it, Kenny!
Ant, no!
Let it go.
It's good!
Yeah!
Oh, my God!
Yeah! All the way!
Number one! All the way!
- We did it, baby!
- No, you did it.
I gotta go see the coach.
I'll be right back, OK?
OK.
- Hey, RC!
- Hey!
Antoine. Wait!
Antoine!
Antoine, wait! Ant!
Antoineů
We did it, baby.
No, you did it,
like I never let you do it before.
And you looked good doing it, too.
I had a good teacher.
Yeah.
They're calling me.
They want me to play on the team.
They said I might make the starting five
if I learn not to hog the ball.
- I love you. Come here, man.
- I love you.
It's OK. I love you.
Bye, Antoine.
No, no, no. No goodbyes.
Cos I'll always be with you.
Hey, it's like Pop says.
If you and I stick togetherů
..anything can happen.
You gonna be all right, man.
But if you don't repeat next year,
I'll be back.
Here I come.
Yeah!
All right. All right!
Yeah, baby! Huskies!
Number one, baby!
Yeah, Coach! Number one, baby!
Huskies! Whoo! Huskies, baby!
Huskies!
Whoo! Yeah, baby!
- That's our sixth man, isn't it?
- Yeah, Coach.
A and Ků all the way, baby.
Yeah! Yeah!
Yeah, baby!
You the man, Coach!