FEMALE SPEAKER: Have you
always been an artist?
THOM DEVITA: What'd you say?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Have you
always been an artist?
THOM DEVITA: Yeah, for
about 40 years.
JOHN WYATT: He's the
greatest tattooer.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Greatest
tattooer?
[INAUDIBLE].
THOM DEVITA: I can
do that also.
FEMALE SPEAKER: You can, yeah.
THOM DEVITA: Every shop I went
in, I'd tell them I'm deVita.
And they never heard
of deVita.
You walk out like you're
an idiot, you know?
Who the hell is deVita?
JOHN WYATT: And now they're
honored to have you.
THOM DEVITA: Oh,
let me finish.
JOHN WYATT: When they meet
Thom, they will realize
they've never met anybody
like him before.
He's probably the most different
person, without
trying to be different, of
anybody I've ever met.
He's so many different things.
He's a tattoo artist, but
he's also a fine artist.
I think he's one of the
true originals.
THOM DEVITA: But you've got
these lines in here anyway
from the cardboard.
MALE SPEAKER: The corrugation,
yeah.
I really like it.
There's a good, strong
iconic strike to it.
Where in the city were
you located?
THOM DEVITA: On the
Lower East Side.
MALE SPEAKER: Very nice.
THOM DEVITA: It wasn't nice
when I went there.
MALE SPEAKER: I guess it's
nice today, right?
It's all about [INAUDIBLE].
THOM DEVITA: Thanks
for coming in.
Take a card.
MALE SPEAKER: Wow, deVita.
NICK BUBASH: What I try to get
across about Thom deVita to
anybody that's interested--
he wasn't just a tattoo
artist, he was
an artist who tattooed.
It was all one big ball
of wax with him.
Everything he did was art--
the way he lived, the way he
talked, the way he thought,
what he did, where he went.
The tattoos were just as
important as the floor.
And then it all came up
on onto his body.
I mean, it was everywhere.
JOHN WYATT: Have you ever done
commercial art, Thom?
THOM DEVITA: Yeah, tattooing.
Art that pays.
JOHN WYATT: When's
the last time you
set up a tattoo machine?
THOM DEVITA: Not too long ago.
Last year when I
was [INAUDIBLE]
I'd write my name
on tattooers.
JOHN WYATT: Aren't you going
to a convention this year?
THOM DEVITA: Yeah, in October.
JOHN WYATT: October?
BUBBA REEVES: I knew that Thom,
he wasn't wanting to do
a whole lot more conventions.
But I knew that his book had
came out, and his wife, Jenny,
had lost her job.
And so Thom kind of had to
be the money maker again.
And Ed loves to have him out
here, and so I've kind of been
helping Thom out with
his travels and
his sales and stuff.
He sells his artwork.
He still works all
day, everyday,
just like he tattooed.
But now he does it on paper.
So he has plenty of artwork to
sell of tattoo stencils and
rubbings and stuff like that.
When I first seen Thom's stuff,
I was wanting to get my
back tattooed from him or
something real big.
But by that time, he was
already done tattooing.
I think it's been about
10 years since he's
tattooed for a living.
Well, the main thing, when you
get a tattoo by Thom, is he's
going to have to like you.
You're going to have to pass
this thing that you want to
get a tattoo from him,
and you understand
that his hand shakes.
I tell them my hands shake
and I'm drunk,
and they don't care.
BUBBA REEVES: His signature
is what he does.
That's his last name with
his birth date.
Since he's been tattooing,
he tattoos for
$30 always, I heard.
And so he charges the tattooers
that get tattooed by
him $30 for his name.
The first time I heard about
Thom was through the "Tattoo
Times," and I was like
man, this guy's
doing something special.
ED HARDY: When we did this
"Tattoo Times" series in
magazines, my primary goal with
that was to enlighten
people, make people realize
that there was a lot more
depth and history and complexity
to tattooing than
anybody realized.
And then finally, by the fifth
issue, I was like, oh my god,
I've got to do something
on Malone, who was
a very close friend.
And he introduced
me to deVita.
And do a piece on deVita,
because deVita's was such an
important guy.
Hopefully, it woke people
up to who he was.
Culturally, it was a
subterranean practice, and
deVita was sub-subterranean.
ROBERT RYAN: When people say
that someone has a cult
following, I think that people
that know and get it really
appreciate his work and really
have a lot of love for it.
And I think it flies over
the heads of a lot
of people as well.
I was a deVita devotee
from the beginning.
It just unlocked this whole
world that I was already
totally into of the Lower
East Side of New York.
There's this creative energy
there that I think Thom's work
definitely emanates.
There's not a lot of care-taking
in trying to nail
each line so everything's
perfect.
But I think he captures the
essence and the energy of a
tattoo design.
NICK BUBASH: It had an
earthiness to it.
It had soul to it.
Thom characterizes
it as folk art.
He says all tattooing
is folk art.
That's right from his mouth.
MALE SPEAKER: Now they've turned
into things that the
Metropolitan Museum could
display proudly, some of the
tattoos that are being done.
THOM DEVITA: But it's
still folk art.
MALE SPEAKER: Those
humble beginnings.
THOM DEVITA: But it's
still folk art.
MALE SPEAKER: But once it gets
put on your body, it
becomes folk art.
THOM DEVITA: Instantly.
Some of them are
real folk art.
I work with traditional
tattoo designs.
I like repeating myself.
That's why I like tattooing.
It's just drawing the same
panthers on a hundred guys.
I have a hard time copying what
someone else had done.
But I'd start off with the
Coleman design, and I would
fill it in a little differenty,
because you just
can't copy.
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah, I
got one on my leg.
I only have one piece of his.
It's on the back of this leg.
He did it all with a shader.
It was from a design on his
wall that was some kind of
Catholic image.
CLAYTON PATTERSON: His flash
would be on pieces of wood.
Have you seen his flash?
JOHN WYATT: Yeah.
THOM DEVITA: Here's
a piece that was
done on Fourth Street.
And that's my flash
from 30 years ago.
ANGELO SCOTTO: At the time, you
didn't think people would
get those tattoos, you
know what I mean?
But it was art.
I said, wow.
I said, it's totally different
from what we were used to.
That was, you went from
Spaulding and Rogers' flash to
Thom deVita's designs, which
was a total transformation.
Like overnight, you
could blink your
eyes, you'd say, wow.
MALE SPEAKER: That's probably
the most different piece of
flash I've ever seen.
CLAYTON PATTERSON: Part of what
this whole dialogue is
about is transformation of
tattooing from kind of a
classic, conservative,
traditional style to
eventually it breaks out into
this whole new matrix.
NICK BUBASH: I never thought
of them as high art.
When I went to deVita's place,
and I saw what he was doing,
that I started thinking
of as art.
He's still kind of esoteric.
You have to know what you're
talking about.
You have go into the
history of it.
You have to find out the early
beginnings of modern tattooing
to understand we're all standing
on the shoulders of
other people.
And a lot of us are standing
on the shoulders of Thom.
ROBERT RYAN: The thing that
really struck me about
deVita's place in tattooing
was he wasn't a biker, he
wasn't military, he wasn't
carny-- he was just a guy
making his art.
And it was rooted in traditional
tattooing, but it
was his take on it.
And the people that he
influenced in tattooing after
that are definitely a lot of the
people that I also looked
up to as well as Thom--
guys like Ed, and Mike Malone,
Nick Bubash, Tux Farrar, Dan
Higgs, Cliff Raven, too.
No, none of those guys come from
that lineage of biker,
carny, hot rod.
It's just like this almost
poetic approach to tattooing
that you didn't really
have before Thom.
And for Thom, it even went
further, because he was more
into the experience.
And I think that goes back a lot
further than what we know
as our American history
in tattooing.
I think that goes back to the
beginnings of it, where it was
something that happened in
tribes and villages and small
places all over the world.
SCOTT HARRISON: The mark
itself has this sort of
significant form, to use
the [INAUDIBLE] term.
But it's just like each mark
is sort of an expression.
And Thom, he does what he's
inspired to do at the moment.
I'd been wanting to get my chest
tattooed for a while,
and so I picked out this
panther head with a
snake in its mouth.
Perfect design for a chest.
It would fit perfectly.
He initially just put it so it
was, like, half covering
another tattoo.
It was like, there's plenty of
space, but he chose to put
it-- he's like, see, it's
not going to work.
And I'm like, oh, you
could just move it.
So he washes it off.
And while I'm standing there
waiting for him, he sneaks up
behind me and puts a stencil
on the back of my arm.
He's like, that's where
it should be.
I told you when I got my first
deVita tattoo in New York, I
came and showed it
to Bernie Luther.
And he was like, it's so ugly.
And I go swimming with tattooers
and they're like,
oh, I've never seen anyone like
a bad tattoo that much.
It's like, dude, you
don't see it.
You're not stepping back out of
the commercial art form and
seeing that there's
this larger thing.
It's like the difference between
listening to something
like Kenny G or listening
to the Stooges.
You're missing the point.
My favorite wind bars.
You did the wind bars.
They're so good.
SCOTT HARRISON: You did those!
THOM DEVITA: Yeah?
SCOTT HARRISON: Yep.
Who else would have
does those?
THOM DEVITA: Whenever we
tattoo, we collaborate.
If you get something that Nick
done on somebody, or with any
tattooer, and somebody else
worked on it, on the guy's
body, it means you're
collaborating.
SCOTT HARRISON: That's one
thing Thom loves is when
there's an old advertising
pane on the wall.
And then part of it's painted
out, but you can see it
through, and there's another
one on there.
And then there's another thing
over there, and there's a
little graffiti-- he loves
that layering effect.
CLAYTON PATTERSON: Tattoos
tend to be classic--
a dragon, a tribal, an abstract,
but never the whole
combination.
Now the other thing Thom does,
which almost nobody else does,
is people will cover
up a tattoo.
And to me, there's a
richness and beauty
with really old colors.
So then he would take his new
stencil, snap it down, and
then so now he's got one of
his tribal tattoos totally
covering this area.
He might maybe blacken this
whole part in through to here,
leave this part of the eye and
head, and then maybe finish
off the tribal coming down
here, leaving this part.
And so it's like a collage.
And people now, when they're
going to redo a tattoo, it's a
standard way of thinking.
I don't care how creative the
artist is, he looks at the
tattoo, and he thinks, OK,
I'm going to cover
this whole thing up.
You get very few people who try
to integrate with the old.
You've got the tribal mixed with
the other elements, and
now you've got a whole
different look.
And some of Carlos' tattoos,
I hope there's really great
pictures of those, because
that's a classy example of
that collage weave that I've
never seen anybody else do up
until this point.
That's the one thing that's
totally unique and amazing
about Thom, which is also
the drawback factor.
Because original is not really
respected that much.
Because original, especially in
a conservative world, kind
of shakes the whole thing up.
NICK BUBASH: There's a book
called "The Tipping Point"--
have you ever read that?
That shows you how one person
or a group of people can
influence the entire world
with what they're doing.
And I think that's pretty
much what Thom did.
And I don't know that Thom knew
he was doing it, either.
It's just what he was doing,
you know what I mean?
He didn't set out saying, well,
I'm going to change the
world with this.
He's not that kind of
a person anyway.
He's a very humble man,
and he was just
doing what he was doing.
He was making art, which he does
absolutely, automatically
and completely naturally.
He's on automatic.
He never stops.
What is he, 80-years-old with
Parkinson's disease now?
He's shaking, and he's still
making art every day.
He'll never quit.
One time I asked him, are you
doing anything different?
And he says, nah, I'm just
doing the same old stuff.
He still gets excited about it,
too, in kind of a low-tone
excitement.
What are you doing?
I'm working on a bunch
of panda bears.
THOM DEVITA: What do
you want to see?
The panda scrolls?
JOHN WYATT: Did you see
the panda scroll?
MALE SPEAKER: No, I
don't think so.
JOHN WYATT: That's important.
JOHN WYATT: Did you paint this
is response to something?
THOM DEVITA: Yes, in response
of Ed's 2,000 dragons.
I was going to do
2,000 pandas.
JOHN WYATT: Did you ever
show this to him?
THOM DEVITA: Yeah, he's
seen it, sure.
You should take [INAUDIBLE]
down like this.