NARRATOR: On this
episode of Wicked Tuna.
BILL: We're on our
second week with Paul,
I was expecting better.
Go forward.
PAUL: Go, Billy, go.
DAVE: It's gonna be more
competitive than it ever
has been.
I got no problem carrying
this on at the dock.
SCOTT: Come over
here you BLEEP.
RALPH: If Pirate doesn't get
his act together, BLEEP,
we may have to make some
difficult decisions.
PIRATE: Trying my patience
out pretty BLEEP good.
RALPH: Big fish.
Fish on.
PIRATE: Fish on.
RALPH: Fish on.
DAVE: Horrible BLEEP day.
PAUL: This is
BLEEP war, bitch.
NARRATOR: Fishing
is a hard life.
RALPH: There's gonna be
a confrontation here.
NARRATOR: And harder with
bluefin stocks depleted.
In Gloucester, Massachusetts,
there's a special breed
of fishermen.
For generations, they've
used rod and reel to catch
the elusive bluefin tuna.
JAY: Yeah, baby!
NARRATOR: They depend on
these fish for their survival.
The competition is brutal.
SCOTT: Miserable prick.
NARRATOR: This is Wicked Tuna.
DAVE: Go, go.
It's great to be on top.
It's great to make all
the money, but with that,
nobody likes a winner.
MARCIANO: For me, the money
doesn't fall out of the sky,
it comes out of the sea.
BILL: This gets harder
as you get older,
but I'm keeping up
with the young guns.
Get out of the way.
RALPH: If it's on my mind,
you're gonna hear about it.
And if you did something
to me, I'm gonna do something
back to you.
It's been a rough
stretch on the Odysea.
We haven't caught
anything in a while.
We know the season's coming to
an end in the next two weeks,
so it's been getting
very stressful.
Hey, where'd that tackle
go from yesterday with
that spool of line?
PIRATE: I put it right, it's
right there by the cupboard.
RALPH: Oh.
PIRATE: Lately me and the
captain haven't been seeing
eye to eye because
of the stressfulness
of not catching a fish.
RALPH: Alright, come on.
Untie the lines.
PIRATE: I got it now. That thing
is BLEEP. Aww.
RALPH: Well, you had it. You
had it, and you BLEEP it up.
PIRATE: I'm trying, Ralph!
RALPH: But you had it,
and you BLEEP it up.
PIRATE: I was waiting for you,
and you're gonna yell at me if
I do something wrong anyways.
RALPH: No, I was waiting for you
It's too difficult to think
about how to hold the boat while
you let go of the lines.
I don't understand what your
BLEEP brain fart is with that
BLEEP.
PIRATE: You know, when the
captain gets grouchy and starts
yelling at me this early in
the morning, you know, hey,
it's part of it, so I just take
it and hopefully we go catch a
fish later on this afternoon
and smooth things out.
RALPH: I have to be able to
rely on Pirate to catch a fish.
It's not gonna happen
with his stupidity.
We've been in a bit
of a slump lately,
so we're gonna head out
to Jeffrey's Ledge today.
We haven't spent much time at
that place this year so we're
just gonna change it up and
see if we can catch a big one.
I'm just praying that we're
gonna catch a couple fish before
the season wraps up.
BILL: Hello.
SCOTT: Come on. Let's go. You
guys are late.
Let's go.
Pick up the pace.
BILL: We're in our
second week with Paul.
He left Dot Com.
We still haven't caught one,
and I was expecting better.
SCOTT: Come on, let's go.
The stakes are extremely
high for Bill and Donna.
I've heard them say to me,
if we don't catch some fish,
I'm gonna have to sell the boat.
If Paul doesn't start sharing
some of Dot Com's secrets,
he's gonna be off the boat
and we're done for the season.
BILL: Paul's taking us over
to Cape Cod Bay on this trip.
He grew up fishing there.
He knows that area like
the back of his hand.
PAUL: Take them to a
little honey hole spot.
I hope I bring some luck.
BILL: I had high hopes
for Paul, but again,
this could turn out to be
another failed crewmember.
DAVE: Paul going on
Billy's boat now, gonna be
more competitive with Billy
and I than it ever has been.
Going out to Cape Cod Bay today
because that's Paul's neck of
the woods.
I guarantee you, Paul and Bill
will be there because
Paul is predictable.
And I'm gonna catch one right in
his backyard with him watching.
That's my choice
for today's bait.
SANDRO: All set up.
DAVE: This is my
lucky rod right here.
The season's almost over now.
There's not a lot of
fish around anymore.
The less and less fish
that are out here,
the more money
that you can make.
Paul can go screw himself.
BILL: Paul brought us to
one of his secret spots,
and it turns out Dot
Com's already there.
SCOTT: Dave knows exactly
how Paul thinks.
It's a real problem.
PAUL: Alive.
BILL: Come in. Dave, come in.
Called Dave, and
they didn't pick up.
SCOTT: Bill's a really
good-natured guy at heart.
He gives everybody the
benefit of the doubt.
I'm just the opposite, Dave
Dot Com really gets to me.
PAUL: If Dave gets
the bite and we don't,
I'm gonna be BLEEP pissed.
I'm gonna stretch this.
Can people not walk on it?
I've been on the
boat couple weeks.
We haven't caught a fish yet.
I'm feeling the pressure.
I really want to catch one.
Billy, which one?
You gotta pick it.
BILL: The first one.
PAUL: This one?
BILL: I like the color.
SCOTT: Paul's the master
baiter. He's the master baiter.
PAUL: Dude, I did
that when I was young.
SCOTT: If we don't
catch some fish,
this season's gonna
be a total disaster.
BILL: We're gonna
kill a fish today, and
it's gonna be big enough.
PAUL: Or it's gonna kill us.
MARCIANO: We're going over to
get a little fuel this morning.
MAN: Hey, Dave.
MARCIANO: How goes the battle?
MAN: It's there.
MARCIANO: How's
the price today?
MAN: Ah, it's up, $3.58.
MARCIANO: Uh oh,
that's alright,
the kids just won't eat this
week, don't worry about it.
The price went up a little
bit, not devastating,
I think three cents
from the last time.
And that's it.
Just a quick top off.
Alright, thanks, I'll be over
with the check in a minute.
MAN: Alright,
sounds good, Dave.
MARCIANO: We got a real
big paycheck, you know,
for that slob we
caught last week, ah,
which is gonna give me the
ability to pay off my fuel bill.
And unfortunately, it's
gonna be a big one.
MAN: Alright, buddy, we'll
see you in a little bit.
MARCIANO: Alright. It's
important we get back in
the game and produce another
fish here so we can stay in
the black.
It's time to get cracking.
PIRATE: Oh, snagged one. Ah,
still a good one though but.
RALPH: No, no good.
Got to get another one.
Ah, once the boat's
settled up on anchor,
Pirate's number one job,
catch me a live bait.
PIRATE: Well, got
bad news for you.
RALPH: You got one?
No, that bait you
sent down got snagged up on
my jigging stick and fell off.
RALPH: Awwww.
Great. Let it go. BLEEP.
PIRATE: I was reeling
up another bait,
I thought it was another
bait, but it wasn't,
it was one of the baits
we had under the big pole.
I dropped it off, then he
got all wound up about it.
RALPH: It's extremely important
that this time that we stay
focused on the important things
that we need to do to catch a
fish, this way we can
still save the season
and catch a couple tuna.
You better jig now. You got
nothing down there.
PIRATE: Well, I
wanted to make sure.
I didn't know what was going on.
RALPH: I gotta have somebody
that's 100 percent there,
and 100 percent focused
on what's going on.
Well, how many baits we
got on the hooks right now?
None, because you BLEEP
reeled up the bait.
Trying to break out of a
dry slump is hard enough,
but when you get human
error on top of it,
it makes it miserable.
PAUL: We're gonna move into
Cape Cod Bay where
I'm familiar with the fish,
that's my backyard.
If there's fish here,
we're gonna find them.
SCOTT: Kill it dead.
PAUL: We really
gotta catch one.
What the hell?
Lot of boats here for a weekday.
And we were like, what the
BLEEP is that guy doing here?
What the BLEEP are these
guys doing on our spot?
What the BLEEP is
he doing right there?
Look at all the boats and, we
didn't talk to, look it, dude.
BILL: I can't believe he
brought me to a spot where
there's a million freaking
googans. I'm not happy.
Googan's a beginner, doesn't
ask about what he should do.
Doesn't know what to do,
and gets in the way and
cost you money.
That's all they do.
They've cost me a lot
of money this year.
SCOTT: Googan.
BILL: And, ah, tell you right
now, if he comes near me,
I'm gonna BLEEP,
I'll lose my mind.
I'm gonna get off the
BLEEP anchor and
say get the BLEEP
away from me.
I'm tired of these guys.
Just tired of them.
This is the stuff
that gets me upset.
They just have no
respect for anybody.
Hey, get the
BLEEP out of here!
We're gonna BLEEP
yell at this guy.
I'll come over there and
I'll BLEEP kill you!
He's gonna troll by us all day
long and that's not gonna happen
Come by here again,
you're BLEEP dead!
No respect. That's the
problem. Come on! Yeah,
come over here,
you BLEEP!
Come over here and say that.
No respect whatsoever.
DAVE: Yeah, he's not gonna
anchor there.
He knows better.
Success does breed enemies.
Everybody thinks that you have
something that they don't have.
Aw, he's not setting right
there. He can't.
Other boats have been following
us around all season long and
leeching off us.
And I'm getting sick of it.
It's time to make a stand.
You gotta be BLEEP me!
Why don't you just come
and take my anchor?
SANDRO: Ever since,
ah, Paul quit, I mean,
there's been a lot
of drama out here.
Forget all this drama, I
just want to go fishing.
DAVE: BLEEP unbelievable.
Alright, I'll remember that
next time I get out early.
BLEEP two things I hate,
BLEEP lack of common sense and
stupidity.
BLEEP you want the spot,
you gotta BLEEP get out
here early.
BLEEP people are BLEEP
stupid, you know that.
We get here early, so
nobody BLEEP bothers us.
They come out late, and they
BLEEP want to anchor right on
top of you.
Scumbag, who, that guy's
been around a long time,
he knows what's going on.
It's all about etiquette.
He knows I own the spot and
he's not gonna BLEEP with me.
Oh, there's gonna be a
battle here in a minute.
There will be.
He's anchoring
right on top of us.
But two can play that game.
I tied the anchor off to the
port side now we're gonna run
into him, we might hit him here.
That's what you call
precision anchoring.
SANDRO: Well, scratch one
more off that hates us.
DAVE: Let me tell
you something,
I know you've been around a long
time, but you know I was here.
You BLEEP dropped right on me.
DAVE: And I reset the anchor.
You knew what I was doing.
You've been around a long time.
You know what you did.
I got no problem carrying
this on at the dock.
You tell me where and when,
and I will meet you there.
Just come alone.
SANDRO: The other
guy was just like,
"Let's just get outta here."
DAVE: Is that what he said?
SANDRO: Yeah.
DAVE: Good, that's life.
Sometimes you gotta do
what you gotta do.
Stand your ground.
He wants to come on over
and say something, he can,
but people like to talk when
there's a big body of water
between two boats.
Had it been on the dock, it'd
probably be a different story.
MARCIANO: Oh look, we got the
salad. Oh, oh look. Hair.
Usually the difference between
a good day and a bad day is
whether you put
fish on the boat.
Looks like some rope, some
seaweed, some driftwood,
seem to be able to catch
everything but tuna.
A regular Rembrandt.
BILL: Chum's really
looking good now.
Paul brought me to a spot
where there's a million
freaking googans.
We also want to get
away from Tuna.Com.
So we decided to pick the
anchor up and make a move.
We yanked it up, and
we're already marking.
Marking it down to 60 feet now.
PAUL: You gotta be focused
on what you're doing.
Alls you gotta do is get
the right one under you.
BILL: Come on, Charlie.
PAUL: Come on.
BILL: We're starting to mark
the chum pretty good now.
PAUL: Yep.
BILL: We get one up in the
chum, we'll see them now.
PAUL: Yep. I think he's on.
What's up?
Something was just on this.
Something just grabbed this.
BILL: Oh, he might have
taken it. He's right there.
PAUL: I don't know what
happened. Grabbed it.
BILL: Could have.
PAUL: We had a bite.
We had BLEEP bite.
Look at it was in his mouth,
look at this. BLEEP.
He, he bit it and let it go.
BLEEP.
Just, he broke the bait. Mashed
it. He had it in his mouth.
I saw the line
going out a little.
I didn't know.
I thought it was the wave.
SCOTT: BLEEP.
Right where the bait was.
PAUL: Aw yeah, feel,
look at that, Bill.
BILL: Oh wow.
PAUL: He grabbed the BLEEP
bait, it went in his mouth,
down here, and BLEEP
he chomped down.
See where it's all bent?
That's what he did, and
he felt it and let it go.
BILL: Well, we didn't
have any luck today.
Hope Paul comes up with
a better spot tomorrow.
PIRATE: Oh, what a beautiful
one, what a beautiful one.
Oh ho ho ho.
RALPH: I found Pirate fishing
on the deck at the Provincetown
Marina, I saw the passion of
the fishing pole in his eyes and
that's kind of what got me
to offer him the position.
So I tried to work off of his
love and passion for fishing to
try to offset some of his other
basket of issues and to try to
leave them at the dock.
There's no guarantees here.
Just keep putting the baits
out until they work again,
that's all.
What I explained to Pirate in
the beginning, if I yell at you,
it doesn't mean I
don't love you anymore,
it means that something's
potentially going wrong.
PIRATE: Oh man.
RALPH: Look out, look
out, look out, look out.
Look what you got going
on here, Mr. Pirate.
Nice. Nice job. Nice.
PIRATE: I tried stretching
it out and all the water kept
washing it.
RALPH: Nice BLEEP job
you got here, Mr. Pirate.
BLEEP. Pirate
has one responsibility.
His main responsibility is to
pay attention to the lines.
It's real important
in giant tuna fishing,
with the type of line that we
use, not to get it tangled.
Once the line's
tangled, it's ruined.
It gets all these little
bends and kinks in it,
and potentially can break.
So that was the end of that day.
It was kind of frustrating.
Don't put BLEEP
line in moving water.
PIRATE: Sometimes, you know,
you, you might do things that
he don't want you to do, but
yet, I'm not a mind reader so.
RALPH: At the end of the
day it's the captain's
responsibility for
everything running smoothly.
Whether it's
defective equipment,
or it's a defective mate, it's
my responsibility to fix it.
PIRATE: The captain's
got a quick temper,
but at this point in the game,
it's stuff I'm used to this,
so it don't matter anymore.
RALPH: If I say something that
something ain't right and he
like shrugs his shoulders
like he doesn't BLEEP care,
it pisses me off because
I'm trying to help him.
If he doesn't care about
himself, then there is no help.
You don't care, you don't care,
that's the root of the problem.
It doesn't get better till
you care. It pisses me off.
I don't know how much
longer we can do this.
SANDRO: Yeah, it kinda sucks
with Paul not being around
anymore, you know.
It is more work, but.
DAVE: It is what it is.
SANDRO: Yep. You guys had your
differences. That's it.
DAVE: He's been
there a long time.
Hopefully we can be friends and
see what happens with that, but,
unfortunately, I think it's
gonna come in between
Billy and I.
SANDRO: Yeah.
DAVE: For sure. Remember what
I told you.
SANDRO: Yep.
DAVE: The more fish you catch,
the more drama involved.
Hopefully Paul and
I can be friends,
hang out and have a drink.
I hope it comes to that,
but right now, probably not.
SANDRO: Yeah, it's not
looking good unfortunately.
You worried about Paul telling
everybody what we've been doing?
DAVE: How many times has Paul
rigged a bait on the boat?
I do everything.
And how many mates I've had
come and go before Paul?
SANDRO: Yeah, that's true.
DAVE: I can count ten that come
for two years to gain experience
SANDRO: Yeah.
DAVE: And then they leave.
They go fish with someone or
they go buy their own boat, and
you know what they catch?
SANDRO: Nothing.
DAVE: Nothing.
SANDRO: Yeah, exactly.
DAVE: Sure you want
to fish tomorrow?
SANDRO: Oh yeah.
PIRATE: We just got done doing
some fishing,
so now I'm gonna go
uptown and see the boss.
The boss being my honeybee.
And, ah, we're gonna see
what's going on up there.
CINDY: Hello.
PIRATE: Hey honeybee.
CINDY: What's going on? I'm
Cindy, and this is Sergio
the wonder dog.
Can you wave? Yeah.
PIRATE: Can I come aboard, Cap?
CINDY: Come on in.
PIRATE: Been busy today?
CINDY: No, it'd dead as heck.
It's that time of season.
PIRATE: Yeah.
CINDY: I'm making enough.
I'm making my beer money.
He's just one of the
nicest guys I've met.
He's just really sweet.
He's definitely a character.
Why you all dressed up for?
Those aren't fishing clothes.
PIRATE: Just to
come and see you.
CINDY: Seriously?
PIRATE: Of course.
CINDY: I love that.
PIRATE: Yeah.
CINDY: Well, you look good.
PIRATE: Oh, thank you.
CINDY: I think Ralph kind of
looks at Kit at just being
another hand on the boat, but I
hope he takes care of him 'cause
he's more than that to me.
PIRATE: Hopefully we bring
something back this time.
CINDY: You didn't, didn't you
last time, no? You got a baby.
PIRATE: Last time
was a big goose egg.
CINDY: Did you see your picture?
I put in a frame over there.
PIRATE: Oh yeah, yeah,
that's pretty cool.
That's some good fish there.
CINDY: Be safe.
PIRATE: Alright, alright,
I'm gonna get going.
CINDY: Alright. Alright.
Sergio, give him a kiss.
PIRATE: Yeah, wipe
the lipstick off.
No, wipe the lipstick off.
DAVE: Good morning.
SANDRO: Yo.
DAVE: How's the bait look?
SANDRO: Good. We got plenty of
bait.
DAVE: Let's get out
of here quick, uh,
there's not much quota left,
so we gotta make it happen.
I want you to start taking the
boat out, driving out and, ah,
docking.
Just get ready 'cause you're
probably gonna have to take it
on your own.
SANDRO: That's fine with me.
DAVE: You good with that?
SANDRO: Oh yeah.
DAVE: Alright. Sandro's my
first mate, co-captain now and
not Paul, and I really want to
him to understand that. Ready?
SANDRO: Let's get it done.
DAVE: Come on, one
big jumbo today.
Alright, Captain, it's clear.
SANDRO: Yeah.
DAVE: Good job, skipper. I want
him to build his experience and
just let him feel confident
in driving the boat and
let him know we're
okay without Paul.
Paul's been with me over a
decade and I haven't let him
take the boat once.
It's all about trust and
I have that with him.
PIRATE: At the beginning
of the season you know,
we was doing pretty good,
we was hooking up on, ah,
like every other day or
two and then, you know,
after x amount of periods of
time being out that way and
not catching a fish to
bring to market,
that's making my attitude
get a little sour.
Did you eat your
bagel this morning?
How the BLEEP am I gonna eat
my BLEEP bagel when
I'm out here doing this BLEEP?
Cutting bait, every
other BLEEP thing.
RALPH: In the beginning Pirate
seemed like he had the right
attitude, and, you know, he
was committing 100 percent,
and lately, it's changed.
Alright, let that anchor go.
PIRATE: Yeah, if I don't
fall overboard doing it.
Aw, what a mess.
RALPH: Pirate knew what
he was signing up for,
so I don't understand why he's
getting all bent out of shape
with his responsibilities.
PIRATE: Ah. Son of a bitch.
What a mess, what a mess.
RALPH: Pirate's got to fasten
the,
the anchor rope to
the bow of the boat.
PIRATE: Where the
hell is it now?
I can't see the BLEEP line.
BLEEP? Ohhhh. Ahhhh.
BLEEP trying my patience
out pretty BLEEP good today.
BLEEP That wrapping myself
up in the BLEEP mess.
BLEEP worth it,
it's not a joke.
Ah, what's happened
to the BLEEP buoy?
Oh, oh, well. I don't know.
Beats the hell out of me.
Aw you....God damn it.
RALPH: My livelihood and
my safety are at stake and
I don't mess around with that.
If Pirate doesn't get
his act together fast,
we may have to make some
difficult decisions here on
the Odysea.
PIRATE: Another BLEEP
beautiful BLEEP day.
BILL: We're out in Cape Cod Bay
with my new mate, Paul.
We didn't get any
fish the other day.
Time is really pressing on now.
We're in the last couple
of weeks of the season.
Paul doesn't help us get a
fish on this boat pretty soon,
I don't know what I'm gonna do.
SCOTT: You know, at this point,
I'm ready to pack it in and
I never like to pack it in, but,
I had enough of this BLEEP.
I'm ready to just go home.
DAVE'S FRIEND: Ah,
it's coming through,
and three and four on the
screen, four and five.
I mean there were...
PAUL: Who's that?
DAVE: How many boats there?
DAVE'S FRIEND: There's
a lot of boats.
DAVE: Just the one bite there
and everybody else seen 'em too
you're talking to?
DAVE'S FRIEND: Everybody that's
out in the area's seeing 'em.
DAVE: Alright, keep me posted.
My phone's working too.
Just got a call from my friend
who's about four miles away and
he's marking them
up pretty good.
He's been there
most of the morning and
he's had them under the boat
nonstop. What to do?
Uh, sometimes you just gotta
go with your gut feeling.
BILL: Dave, come in?
PAUL: Yeah, he's going.
He's going.
I think he's going up to
the radio now or something.
BILL: We saw Dave, uh,
picking up his anchor and
getting ready to move.
I said to the crew we gotta go.
He could get on the radio
and say hey, it looks good,
and we're going, but
we don't get that call.
If Dave is gonna beat
me to another fish,
it's gonna be over my dead body.
We're out for a while, and we
got some information on the
radio, and then we saw Dave
uh, picking up his anchor and
getting ready to move.
I said to the crew, we gotta go.
PAUL: We see you, Dave.
We're right behind you.
Yeah.. Nice. Holy BLEEP, dude.
That's insane.
DAVE: Now let it go.
SCOTT: You can BLEEP run,
but you can't hide from me.
BILL: Dave, you may have had a
great season up to this point,
but things are gonna change.
DAVE: I'm an amazing fisherman,
and we're gonna do it again and
remember I said that.
PAUL: After the way Dave
treated me, this is BLEEP war,
bitch.
DAVE: We got friends
already, you see them?
SANDRO: Yep.
PAUL: I like the 80 inchers,
fish. I love them.
BILL: If there any tuna, we're
gonna be the ones that get them,
and not Dave.
DAVE'S FRIEND: INDISTINCT DAVE:
See any more?
DAVE'S FRIEND: Nope.
DAVE: Well, alright. Still
haven't seen my first one.
DAVE'S FRIEND: Are you
where you were yesterday?
DAVE: Nah, up from you.
We've had an amazing season,
we're gonna catch one,
but I don't think
Bill and Paul are.
BLEEP Paul.
He's dead to me.
Let's put one in the boat today.
SANDRO: Sure. We'll get it
done here.
DAVE: I know we made a
lot of money for the year.
SANDRO: Oh yeah.
DAVE: But, regardless, I want
to make money for the trip.
We're gonna get him right here.
SANDRO: Yep. Oh yeah.
BLEEP me. BLEEP we're
already marking them.
DAVE: Holy BLEEP. Let's go.
BLEEP Start throwing.
Oh, he's BLEEP
right here, dude.
I'm just throwing right here.
PAUL: I'm feeling the pressure,
I really want to help Billy.
How nice would it be to have
Dave watch us pull a fish out
from underneath him?
Scotty's gonna yell at him, "Get
the BLEEP out of my ocean."
BILL: That's right.
PAUL: Oh, I love it.
BILL: You don't need to be
right BLEEP next to me.
PAUL: No. No.
BILL: You don't.
PAUL: You wanna
yell at somebody?
DAVE: Good start, looks
like he's eating too.
I'm gonna hook him up hopefully.
SANDRO: Oh yeah.
DAVE: Man, what a
blessing this would be.
Keep it in the
chum line, alright?
SANDRO: Yep. I'm feeling lucky.
DAVE: He's out here, that
thing's gonna pop.
BILL: With all the
bait that's over there,
you would think the tuna fish
would be piled up over there.
PAUL: Oh, oh, oh, here we go,
here we go.
I just BLEEP did it.
Start the boat, baby.
BILL: No, I'm trying to get...
PAUL: Start the boat.
Gotta turn us.
BILL: Where is he?
PAUL: Turning to the right.
Got to let the anchor go.
Pull forward, Bill. You're good.
Back up real slow, Bill.
BILL: Holy BLEEP You're
out on the gaff line now.
PAUL: That's alright,
nice and easy. Take your time.
BILL: Hooked up tight. Real
tight.
PAUL: Neutral.
BILL: Feels good.
DAVE: Wow. Not a good sign.
SCOTT: I want to catch
a giant bluefin tuna.
PAUL: Well, let's hope
we do good, that's all.
It's a good feeling
to feel a fish.
This is what I live for.
See I'm just taking
it easy with him.
Let that hook get in there.
You know.
BILL: He's coming around.
PAUL: He's far away.
SCOTT: He's a nice fish.
Nice fish. Live cod, nice.
BILL: He's pulling us around.
Let him pull us around that way.
He'll get tired.
SCOTT: It's a big fish. We'll
get him. We'll get him.
Big fish. Let's go.
PAUL: Keep coming, Bill. Come
on. Keep up. Turn to the right.
SCOTT: Come on, Billy. Don't
let him get him to the side,
that's how we lost the last one.
PAUL: Back up. Back up. Back
up. Back up.
Back up. There you
go, neutral. Coming at us, Bill.
Coming up. He's right there.
I see him.
Be ready with that harpoon.
He's 100 feet down now.
Come on up you. Neutral, Bill.
Come back, man, come on, man.
Keep on your toes, Billy.
BILL: Yep.
SCOTT: I see color.
PAUL: Come on. Come on, let's
go. Get on this BLEEP.
BILL: Right there.
PAUL: Get on him. Alright,
now go, now go forward hard.
The other way.
SCOTT Forward.
PAUL: Oh, where
you going, buddy?
Go, Billy. Go.
Now back up.
Back up hard.
Do that BLEEP.
Now forward, come
on, Bill, Billy.
SCOTT: Forward, forward hard.
Hard.
PAUL: Back up hard, hard. BLEEP
Get him. Aww.
Back up. Back up.
Push it in.
BILL: Back up?
PAUL: Push. Push.
Don't hold too tight
SCOTT: I'm not gonna hold it.
PAUL: Tail rope. 'Cause you
don't have BLEEP till you tail
rope him. You don't have him
until he's wrapped up.
Go forward this way.
Alright, you're good.
You're good.
A gaff, you got a gaff?
BILL: Yep.
SCOTT: Here you go.
PAUL: Okay. Keep going
forward, Billy.
SCOTT: Forward.
PAUL: Alright, I got him.
Tail rope.
He's big. Billy got one.
Billy got one, yeah. Oh yeah.
Alright,
Billy, alright, Billy. Wooo.
SCOTT: Yeah.
PAUL: It's been a while, huh?
SCOTT: Good job.
PAUL: He's beautiful. He's so
pretty. good today.
SCOTT: Good job.
PAUL: Look how green he is,
Bill. Come here, you guys.
BILL: Hold on, buddy.
PAUL: We did it. We broke the
ice. We BLEEP did good today.
SCOTT: Ah, BLEEP Awesome. BILL:
Good job, Paulie.
PAUL: Good job everybody.
It was just like he won the
World Series or something.
I was happy for him.
He was so happy.
SCOTT: I feel outstanding.
Thanks, Paulie.
BILL: Paul really
proved something today,
he's a hell of a mate, and
an unbelievable fisherman.
And he's welcome on the
Bounty Hunter any time.
SCOTT: I feel so good
I can't even tell you.
That's why we bring in a ringer.
Paulie.
PAUL: Billy was so happy.
I got happy watching how
BLEEP happy he was.
I never seen someone so happy.
It was awesome.
SCOTT: That's why you do this.
Right there. Mr. Tuna Fish.
DAVE: Sandro.
SANDRO: Yeah.
DAVE: Get out of here
in a couple minutes?
SANDRO: Uh, yep. Let me clean
this first.
DAVE: Alright, finish that. Just
throw whatever out you don't
think we need, and let's get out
of here.
There's no worse feeling heading
home empty handed when you know
other boats have caught
fish and you didn't.
Good for Billy, I guess the
sun shines on the dog's
ass some days.
That was an absolutely
horrible BLEEP day.
Was that not the worst day of
fishing this whole entire year?
SANDRO: Dude, that was
definitely BLEEP.
DAVE: You think so?
SANDRO: Uh, yeah.
DAVE: Bill and them better
enjoy the moment while it lasts,
because we'll be back
on top again tomorrow.
I did not have a
good time today.
PIRATE: Scorpion walks down,
down to the edge of the creek
and there's a frog
sitting there.
Scorpion asks the frog,
Will you give me a ride,
a ride across the creek?
The frog says, "Yeah, okay,
but you can't sting me.
The scorpion says, Okay,
I won't sting you.
So then the frog says, Are you
sure you're not gonna sting me?
The scorpion replies,
No, I won't sting you.
So, the frog backs up and
the scorpion gets on there.
Just about halfway in
the middle of the creek,
the scorpion stings the frog.
The frog's about ready to die,
he says, "Why'd you sting me?"
"'Cause I'm scorpion."
So the moral to that story is, I
been still waiting to find out.
RALPH: Yeah, when you're not
catching, it gets to be
a lot of tension in the
air between the two of yous.
And there's only
one fix to that,
and that's to get tight
and catch tuna fish.
Alright, what do we got here?
We got a mark at 50.
What are we gonna
do with him now? 60.
He's right on the down bait.
That's where the down line is.
And this fleck in front
of him is the mackerel.
See this is the mackerel. Right
here. And that's the tuna fish.
PIRATE: Fish on. Fish on. Fish
on, Cap.
It's on. It's on.
It's on cap.
RALPH: Alright, get
the other lines in,
get the other lines in.
Ah, he's off, he's off.
He's off.
He's gone, God damn it.
PIRATE: We just had a fish
and, ah, something went wrong.
That's all I know,
to my knowledge.
RALPH: Nice BLEEP job
you got here, Mr. Pirate.
When Pirate got a big tangle,
one of the lines got scraped on
the keel of the boat.
Pirate reeled it in, it went
undetected and the next day of
course, that rod got a
giant tuna on it and
we busted him off.
Now we have to BLEEP catch
another one I guess.
It's just like in any sports
event, when you make an error
you give the opposition
a chance to win.
If you mess up and the
line gets scored and
you don't detect it on
the day it happens,
it's gonna come back and bite
you in the ass.
Yeah, everybody makes
mistakes one or twice,
but when you're making the same
mistakes day in and day out,
it gets to a point where
it's very frustrating.
PIRATE: One of the
lines is going underneath
the boat right now.
RALPH: BLEEP stuck
under the boat again.
Picking tangles out of the
BLEEP propeller is not
entertaining to me.
And you, before it gets to
this point, you're the deckman.
So much of this I
can put up with.
PIRATE: Sometimes I get upset
because I don't think Captain
Ralph respects me.
And I don't like the
way he treats me when
we're not catching fish.
RALPH: BLEEP joke.
PIRATE: You can only get so
much tough love thrown your way
before enough's enough.
RALPH: Put that line to
the back of the boat.
PIRATE: The yellow one, right?
RALPH: Put that one to
the back of the boat.
No, the yellow
one, the other one.
PIRATE: It's bobbing up
and down, it's right here.
Every man has a breaking point,
and I think I just reached mine.
MARCIANO: You know, some people
collect stamps.
Some people collect antiques.
Jay and I, we collect the
tails of giant bluefin tuna.
Stand on the barrel and
fill in that window now.
Be brave for crying out loud.
Whenever we get a fish,
especially a nice one, we have
a ritual, and that's nailing
those tails up on the wall.
Get up there higher though.
There you go.Every tail
up there tells a story.
JAY: Remember this one, Dave?
MARCIANO: Yeah, I
remember that one.
That's basically
our trophy wall.
That's where we get to
show how good we are.
Shows the other guys who's
catching and who's not.
Alright, Jay, what can I
say, you nailed it, man.
PAUL: Here you go, the
monkey is off your back.
Ta da da da.
BILL: We got an extra
passenger on board and uhm,
he's a good size one.
And hopefully he'll do well.
DONNA: Yippee. Yippee.
Yippee. Yippee.
Standing out on the dock,
waiting for him to come around
the corner, and I couldn't be
happier. Woohooohoo.
I couldn't wait to throw
my arms around Bill and
say yes, we did it.
Finally.
About freaking time.
MAN: Way to go,
guys, way to go.
DONNA: Yo, Paulie.
PAUL: It was good,
it was a good day.
Put a couple lines out, hung
out, had a soda, had a sandwich,
and BLEEP hooked up.
SCOTT: I'm really
excited right now.
We got a big monkey
off our back today.
This fish meant a lot to us, the
Bounty Hunter, the team here.
We didn't have bad luck,
we wouldn't've had any
luck this year.
So, this meant a lot.
It's a phenomenal feeling.
I really can't describe it.
Until you experience it, you
don't know what I'm really
talking about, but people who
are adrenaline junkies know what
it is, and, ah, it's
phenomenal feeling.
DONNA: Woo hoo. Finally,
finally, finally. Awesome.
SCOTT: What's up, man?
DONNA: Good job, Scott.
BILL: Yeah. Donna was pretty
excited when I called her at
work and told her that we had
got one and, you know,
I wish she was on the
boat but she's excited.
MAN: Weight on there
right now as it stands.
MAN #2: Come on. 503.
PAUL: Nice.
MAN: 503 pounds.
BILL: Anytime you catch one
it makes everything good.
It's a tough battle.
You can be the luckiest person
in the world and catch one all
the time, or you can put the
boat in the wrong place all the
time and never catch one.
So that's the way it works.
PAUL: You know what I mean?
That'd be sweet.
DONNA: Good job, Paul.
PAUL: Lucky.
DONNA: Good going.
SCOTT: I can't speak more
highly of Paul of anybody
I've ever fished with.
He is just a mad dog fisherman.
What he really brought to the
boat was a kick ass attitude,
which I think we really needed.
BILL: Paul fishes very
hard, he makes it happen.
And uh, today it paid off.
No doubt about it.
Billy really needed that fish.
Bad.
I'm glad I jumped on with him.
Attitude's totally different.
Very peaceful, very relaxed.
It's just comfortable.
You know, it feels like
I'm in my own home.
MAN: 96 inches, eight foot.
That's got great color, boys.
PAUL: Yeah.
MAN #2: Yeah.
MAN: That's got very nice color.
Just doing a core sample here.
We're looking at the clarity of
the inside color to make sure
there's not any
cloudiness or brown meat.
Nice. Nice. Nice.
It's a very clean
inside color and it's,
it's got very nice
fat, very good texture.
BILL: How good's the market?
MAN: This should
do pretty well.
It's a good size fish,
it's not overly huge.
I hope it does at
least 15 bucks a pound.
SCOTT: Bill Monte.
BILL: Yeah.
DONNA: Yeah.
BILL: Sometimes you have
to make your own luck,
the one thing you can't
do is stop fishing.
You can't give up.
You have to keep fishing.
That's the way it is.
Hey, Dave, suck it.
Bounty Hunter's
back in business.
PAUL: See you, buddy.
RALPH: Alright, we're down
here today without Pirate,
he failed to show up, so
because of that behavior
we've suspended
him from fishing.
So, whatever
Pirate's problem is,
it continues to be his problem.
He's got a lot to learn, he
missed on a good,
good thing here.
So, we're gonna go
back to fishing solo.
It's the work, twice the
risk, but twice the money,
so let's go get the money.
PIRATE: This morning,
my gut was turning,
I was trying to figure out
what, what the next step was.
I tell him this, he
throws something at me,
if I tell him this, he
throws something else at me,
I'm caught between a
rock and a hard place.
I don't know what to do.
I know it's probably tough love
what he's trying to do for me,
but I need some down time too.
And, that's what it is,
is what it is right now.
So I don't know.
RALPH: You know, he just waits
for me to soften up and I take
him back, but, you know,
this stage in the season,
all he did was lose his
winter work because you know,
fishing's gonna be just about
over soon and I got no problem
handling the boat myself.
I did it for five years. So.
PIRATE: Oh my god.
I'm down here this morning to
see what's gonna happen,
if we're going
fishing or not.
We'll see what happens.
I don't know if it's gonna
be a good thing for me to go
apologize or what I'm gonna do.
I'm not sure what's
gonna happen yet.
Gotta see what's going on, if
I can get my site back or not,
and, ah, we'll see what happens.
RALPH: I don't want
you on my boat today.
This is not a BLEEP game.
BLEEP. You want to show
up with BLEEP.
I ain't into your BLEEP.
This is my business.
PIRATE: There you have it right
there.
I guess that's gonna be the
end of it right there is how
we speak.
I'm not gonna have
nothing, no part of being.
Evidently Captain's still
a little pissed off,
he don't want to
take me on it, so,
he's gonna be going
out all by himself.
Good luck to him, I
appreciate the, ah,
time he gave me but what I'm
gonna do now is just, ah,
pack up and, ah, head back home.
RALPH: Even if I could go
back in time with Pirate,
I don't think there's
anything I would change.
I gave the guy an
opportunity of his lifetime.
There's people like him all over
this place that would have loved
to have his opportunity.
I wish Pirate a lot of good
luck and I hope someday
he deals with his issues.
PIRATE: I'm all done for the
season. Thanks.