CHRIS ROACH: How's that mic
sounding now, is it all right?
Yeah, I have duct tape.
We could actually kind of put a
pinch on it and tape it up.
-Yeah.
CHRIS ROACH: You want
to do that?
-Yeah, that's fine.
CHRIS ROACH: When you put a
little pressure down on it--
yeah.
Yep, 250F.
This is my son's 150 and my
other son's little TTR50.
We're all into motocross, man.
Yeah, Santa Cruz is just doing
an amateur team this year.
-Oh really?
CHRIS ROACH: Yeah, so--
oh, here they are, right here.
And I called them, you know,
I've been dealing with them
forever, but I'll be their only
rider that's, I guess, a
professional.
But I'm old.
You know what I mean?
[LAUGH]
I got a model from last
year with Santa Cruz.
[INAUDIBLE]
I don't know if you
ever saw that one.
But, this year's board,
this one here.
And this is what I did when I
rode, I think, in , like, '90
or '91 or something.
I just stickered my
board this way.
And then they sublimated it
and made those graphics.
That one right there I ride
at the Donner Vintage one.
That was my first model, the one
with the genie up there is
my first one.
And I rode that at that Donner
Vintage contest.
-We probably didn't have one.
[LAUGH]
I got lucky.
When I was younger, I gave all
that shit to my mom, you know?
I knew I wouldn't build any out
with all your friends and
shit, taking everything.
Palmer's board, for the
championship, him and Brushy
we're going against
each other.
And it was raining on the
snow, so I quit riding,
started drinking and cheering
them on because it was so
shitty, I mean, you couldn't
even get above the pipe.
It says Roach did not win the
truck, but I did get mad, and
we will get drunk [LAUGH]
in '92.
And he just destroyed
his board.
And I'm like, dude, let
me have that board.
Write me a story on it.
He should do [INAUDIBLE], too.
My biggest influence in
snowboarding was him and Noah,
for sure-- no doubt about it.
I mean, those guys were the
gnarliest guys, man.
We need Noah's rhino to
get up there, man.
We're going to have to walk.
NOAH SALASNEK: So you know,
he's an a regional Grass
Valley guy.
And though I do live here now,
I'm not from this area.
So Chris, and Tucker, and Monte,
and all these guys are
from Grass Valley.
And I always respected that
whole little crew because they
were all so talented.
So I'd see them riding and
ended up meeting then and
becoming friends with them,
I guess, over the years.
Yeah, it's always been a mutual
friendship, either
skating, or snowboarding,
and now motocross
occasionally together.
And we stayed friends,
and it's pretty cool.
He's a really good skateboarder,
too, and people
probably don't know that
he's a really good
motocross rider, too.
He's an avid rider.
And he's been, actually,
competing and doing well.
So it's good to see he's that
motivated, and he's with his
family and works hard.
He's a good guy, so much
respect for him.
CHRIS ROACH: Right now, I'm in
the process of clearing all
this shit out, all this--
you know what poison oak is?
Yeah.
You guys have that?
So you don't want to
touch any of that.
I get it horribly bad.
Well, I'm going to clear all
this out, so you can actually
walk around everywhere here.
Yeah, this would've been cool
to be able to film this.
This is like, you could've
gotten up there, the view.
This is a triple jump
right here.
That would've been
sick back drop.
Click third gear, and then it's
about a 60 foot double.
And then this one's about 82
right here, step down triple,
right here.
Yeah it's fun, and it goes
all the way around.
I mean, we could walk it.
It goes way up around the
woods over there.
It's got a sick step up, and
then another table out, and
then back round.
It's about a 45-second
long track.
I do a lot of amateur stuff.
I ride the 30-plus intermediate
class, and then
the 250 novice class.
And locally, I ride the
E-street races and
then we do hang town.
We did the MX crossover
down there.
I think I got it than that
in the monster class.
And in the intermediate
class, I got third.
Fuck, that sucks.
I wish I could write it.
It'd be so sick with you
standing up on the ditch, and
me stepping up to you.
There's a rock plant that's
just right down the street
that I work with all the time.
They're going to sell me some
sand for cheap, so I'll bring
a bunch of sand in here,
and just this'll
be like a sand track.
That'll be sick.
And then, once again,
you just land.
So this is just a third gear
little step up right here.
I tried to mimic Hangtown's
step up.
Yeah this give here that you've
going to step down,
[INAUDIBLE]
and then the line is kind
of right there.
I mean, you can see, it's like
the perfect, fastest
lines on the edge.
It's so nice.
The tracks are probably about
45 minutes away from me.
So having this here, it
gives me the exercise
whenever I want it.
And it's just so nice.
Rider's 2 and 1/2, almost
three, and he's real
interested in it.
And my other son, Talon,
he's 8, and he's
totally into motocross.
And Jaren's just, he's
got the 150.
He loves it too.
So they're all into snowboarding
and motocross.
Yeah, they love skateboarding,
but I'm kind
of hurt right now.
So it's too bad because
they should be skating
even though I'm not.
But right now they've kind of
do everything that I do.
So skateboarding's had
to take a backseat to
everything right now.
It's unfortunate.
That's what hurts the
most on my leg.
So I've got to wait to get it
fixed in early winter, and
I'll probably be back
to skateboarding.
Skateboarding, I started when
I was really young.
I started skateboarding,
probably, when I was five
years old or whatnot.
And if I could get my leg
fixed now, I'd still be
skateboarding, which
I plan on doing.
I mean, skateboarding will
always be in my blood.
Skateboarding gave me
snowboarding, is
the way I see it.
And snowboarding has given
me what I have now.
So I owe a lot to, probably,
skateboarding and
snowboarding.
They give you the same great
feelings when you learn
something, or you're progressing
or whatever.
Oh, well I grew up in
Salinas till I was
probably 10 years old.
And we were skateboarders
down there in Salinas.
And then, when I moved up here,
we met the skateboarders
that a lived in Grass Valley.
And Tucker Fransen was
one of the them.
He's the one that got me
into snowboarding.
And we start going to
Donner ski ranch
with him and his family.
We hiked around, I guess, before
we went to Donner in
the back country.
And then Donner ski ranch was
the first resort that opened
up to us for snowboarding.
And then we spent most of our
time there, probably, for the
next five years, at Donner.
Probably been John Ackright,
and Damian Sanders, Tucker,
myself, my brother--
yeah that's probably--
I don't know, those are the
guys I was riding with.
Yeah, Monty and I rode
pretty much together
the whole time we--
he drove before I could
even drive.
And so we were always
riding together.
And he had the same passions,
did the same things, so--
CIRCE WALLACE: Chris and Monty
were the quintessential Grass
Valley troublemakers.
You know, they were cute.
They were blonde..
They were very California.
They were kind of
good old boys.
So they were always
having fun.
And Chris had a really
respectable style.
I mean, to this day, I think he
was one of the most stylish
snowboarders.
He had a very distinct way of
riding that a lot of people
really responded to.
DAMIAN SANDERS: Yeah,
Chris Roach?
He's got a talent.
He's got a style that
was just insane.
He had a skate style
that was so cool.
He would poke out a frontside
air and just hold it for the
longest time like Chris Miller
on a skateboard.
And it was just the coolest
looking thing.
It's like a guy at a motocross
whipping it and just holding
that whip forever.
It was so much style.
And everybody else was,
like, get the trick
done, do it real quick.
But Roach was right out
of the stoner guy
from the surfer movies.
He was like a Spicoli.
He was fucking hilarious.
TODD RICHARDS: Roach's
style was all about
being, like, really--
fucking train--
Roach's style was all about
being super squatty, and
really tight and compact.
I mean, we were grabbing
way up on our
tip and doing methods.
Every grab that Roach
did was like full
skate, around his feet.
Everything was proper.
And there wasn't just wherever
your hand happens to hit while
you're flying through the air.
But that's what we were
doing back East.
And those guys were all tight.
Everything the super tight.
KEVIN ENGLISH: They were there
kind of what I'd say is the
next generation.
They were the young dudes when
Damian, and Sione, and Graham
were the big guys.
And I definitely got into in.
There's a shot of Chris Roach
doing a frontside I grab in
the Western Front that
is so insane.
And it's probably only like
three feet off the ground.
But he was, in my mind, the
first guy that brought style
to snowboarding.
So in terms of how you actually
rode, I would try to
more emulate, probably, Chris
Roach than anybody else.
MIKE RANQUET: Because he was
the coolest looking due I'd
ever seen at that point.
I remember first seeing
him in the Sims ad.
And I snowboarded
for Sims then.
And just doing this frontside
nose bone.
Aaron was like, dude,
that guy's so rad.
You know?
CHRIS ROACH: Well, I always just
did what felt good to me.
And I know I mean I had posters
up of Palmer and
Kidwell doing backside airs in
my room when I was a kid.
So I felt like I needed to look
like that or something
close to that.
And what I saw me riding,
or whatever I
always felt, eh, whatever.
But everyone always said that
I had good style or whatnot.
And now, I really appreciate
it more than
I did then, I guess.
SHAWN FARMER: You know what
always used to trip me out?
This is so funny, man, but I
used to look at Chris Roach
and go, that's looks
like Palmer.
That's Palmer.
I thought it was Palmer.
And I'd go, but Palmer's
riding goofy?
That's not Palmer.
Palmer doesn't ride goofy.
I used to think Chris Roach
was Shaun Palmer.
You know, I did.
But then I'd realize,
he's goofy, man.
Just in videos, when I first
started seeing him.
And then, I don't know,
I mean, I'm just
equating the style.
But yeah I talk to people who
don't know who Chris Roach is.
I'm like, really?
Fuck, come on.
MIKE HATCHETT: I'm always
impressed when a snowboarder
today knows who Damian
Saunders is, or
Chris Roach, Kidwell.
You've got to know where
it came from.
And I always give props the
kids that have done their
homework and seen the old
videos or whatever.
I mean, a lot of guys are
like, who's Damian?
Who's Chris Roach?
I was like, are you
kidding me?
Who's Chris Roach?
Hey, if you're not a
pro, that's cool.
But if you're a pro snowboarder,
you'd better know
who Chris Roach is,
in my opinion.
-So Mr. Roach, how
do you feel about
California Snowboard Series.
CHRIS ROACH: I would
do it again.
[INAUDIBLE]
GS is rad.
They set up good GS courses.
It was structured and pipes
and types of stuff.
Dude, I don't know,
[INAUDIBLE].
Yeah, fully because
I won that.
CHRIS ROACH: The California
state snowboard series, and
that was just kind of the lope
for the local mountains.
We went up to Shasta and
just all the local
mountains around here.
And I think I won that series,
but we raised gates at that
point, too, and half-pipe
gates,
moguls, it didn't matter.
We did everything
at that point.
We went to Breckenridge, and
that was the World Cup.
And I broke my Sims board that
I'd bought in the pipe.
And Tom Sims actually
watched me break it.
And I think that was my biggest
break, was from Tom
watching me snap that board
because he might have been
watching me earlier
in the day.
And then he invited me
to is hotel room.
And he had probably 100 boards
in there, and he said, you
pick one and if you do well,
we'll try to see what we can
do from here.
And that was probably the best
thing I ever could have done,
is break that board.
TODD SIMS: Well, that whole
NorCal scene had a lot of
players, like Tucker
Fransen, and Chris
Roach, and Noah Salasnek.
These guys all sort of had kind
of is the Sims soul in
those days because they had
their skateboard background,
and they were low key, and they
performed incredibly.
And that was sort of the whole
image of what a Sim rider was,
just almost by default
because these guys--
I don't remember the exact time
that each one of them
ended up on the team, but it
was almost like, sure, of
course you're on the team.
CHRIS ROACH: Oh for me, it was
a dream come true because I
was a skateboarder.
And I got all the skateboards
and all that.
And then Sims was such a big
company for means because I
was a kid, on it was Sims.
It was like skating,
snowboarding, and
knowing who Tom was.
And Terry Kidwell rode for
them, and Shaun Palmer.
And those guys were my heroes of
snowboarding then, as well,
so it was rad to be on the
same team as them.
And Sims was paying me $700 a
month, and I was, like, that's
a career, man, that's killer.
You know, when you're
that young.
And by the time I switched to
Santa Cruz, I got on with
Santa Cruz, and they were paying
me good money, and then
Quicksilver, and got with
Dragon, and Vans.
And I just felt like, at that
point, that I could probably
make a living off it.
So I don't know what year
it was or whatever.
But I knew I couldn't
work, man.
And I had to do that because I
didn't know what the hell else
I was going to do.
Didn't do good in school.
Wasn't that smart.