she might look homeless.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
ROCCO CASTORO: Hi.
I'm Rocco Castoro, the editor
of VICE magazine.
Tonight, we're going to have a
doggy fashion show at Westway
in honor of our 2012
fashion issue.
The clothes are a little on
the S and M side, and they
were designed by
Ashley Levine.
CLARA GOLDFARB: Hi.
This is Otto, and he is dressed
as the drug dealer.
Also has his backpack, which
is full of his merchandise.
NATHANIEL DAM: My job
today is to walk the
dogs down the runway.
I will not wear the leather
pants, because I feel like it
emasculates my already tiny
legs, and I'm not, yeah.
I walk dogs once a year.
ADRI MURGUIA: This is
her big debut, her
big coming out party.
Her first time at New
York fashion week.
MALE SPEAKER: These
are some amazing
dogs, you got to agree.