trading game is because they're doing
track instead of been pumped
with feminine hormones
now it is true that a lot of chicken
when i get a child so i can't cope i
mean this is so stupid this is like
everybody that we we've talked about his
work every argument against gay people
if they get married it's gonna ruin st
mary's that makes no sense that you flip
don't ask don't tell the milk militaries
to the ballpark because of the one at
the big photos evidence about that your
death
if we take in it's gonna make you gaelic
it's getting crazier like what what's
next
so he won't morales had also said
something ridiculous like that and and
and he got and of course he is that
president bolivia
and he got a lot of criticism for it and
people are rejecting the notion that you
can become gay bi eating chickens that
have been published for months
and iraq uh... chicken should be pumped
up for months it's bad for you it's not
really sure altogether fabrication
double a
cannot months for ron shipp in on didn't
like you know for causing demands to
know what you want to know if you if you
took me away it sounds sensible
regulation in that this is our unrelated
to sort of knew nothing about science or
anything like it i like how they're
pumping them for formal
landscape people like you all kind of
adds up
uh...
but that would imply that that is
building the ins and i'm sure admiral
became the deciding to lease had a
pickup date
d_-two i'd maybe they're secretly pre
hormones in our tokyo dr king and queen
just you note
where he was date was like the bigger
the light of more people will believe it
itself like this
like chickens are making people getting
seizing so crazy in that everyone's
right now
maybe yeah marianne and all the time of
delivery if you say it wasn't for you
some people be like follow
michel tension
at the santa anna
but have honestly this is a true and now
unlike that and products
that's that have happened yeah
you'd like to meet my practice