ONCE NOW WITH REGARD TO THE BOTANY PART OF
COURSE AND SEEN SOME
OF THE ORGANISMS THAT WE'RE GOING TO TALK
ABOUT TODAY AND JUST
MENTIONED BRIEFLY LAST TIME AS WELL AS SOME
WE TALKED ABOUT
EARLIER. AND THIS WEEK YOU'RE GOING TO FOCUS
MORE ON VASCULAR
PLANTS, GET INTO THE VASCULAR PLANTS, WHICH
WE'LL START TO TALK
ABOUT IN TODAY'S LAB OR TODAY'S LECTURE. SO
FIRST OFF I'M GOING
TO REVIEW JUST A BIT ABOUT LAND PLANTS, SOME
OF THE THINGS I HAD
TO SAY AT THE LAST, AT THE END OF LAST LECTURE
SO WE'RE ALL ON
THE SAME PAGE HERE NOW THAT YOU CAN FOCUS
JUST ON THIS PART OF
THE COURSE. AND THEN WE'LL EVENTUALLY GET
INTO INTRODUCING
VASCULAR PLANTS TODAY WHICH ARE THE PLANTS
THAT WE'RE PROBABLY
MOST FAMILIAR WITH. BUT FIRST I JUST WANT
TO BRIEFLY RECAP LIFE
CYCLES BECAUSE WE'VE SEEN A NUMBER OF DIFFERENT
TYPES OF LIFE
CYCLES IN THE LAST WEEK AND A HALF OR SO.
AND FROM NOW ON WE'RE
JUST GOING TO BE LOOKING AT LAND PLANTS. SO
IT'S IMPORTANT TO
NOT TO GET THEIR LIFE CYCLE CONFUSED WITH
SOME OF THE ONES WE
TALKED ABOUT EARLIER. OKAY, SO FIRST OF ALL,
OF COURSE HUMANS
AND ALSO DIATOMS, AMONGST SOME OTHER ALGAE
WE DIDN'T SPEAK ABOUT,
HAVE A LIFE CYCLE WHERE WE JUST HAVE ONE MULTICELLULAR
GENERATION, A DIPLOID GENERATION, YOU KNOW,
YOU AND ME. AND THE
ONLY HAPLOID STAGE THEN IS THE GAMETE. SO
THERE'S NO
MULTICELLULAR HAPLOID GENERATION. THE FUNGI
AND ACTUALLY ALSO
THE CLOSEST RELATIVES OF THE LAND PLANTS HAVE
A ZYGOTIC LIFE
CYCLE WHERE THE ONLY DIPLOID STAGE IS THE
ZYGOTE. AND THE ONLY
MULTICELLULAR ORGANISM IN THAT LIFE CYCLE
HAS HAPLOID NUCLEI.
AND OF COURSE IN THE CASE OF FUNGI, THERE
ARE ALSO SOME FUNGAL
GROUPS, THE MAJORITY OF THE DIVERSITY IN THE
FUNGI THAT HAVE THIS
DIKARYOTIC STAGE. BUT WE WON'T BE SEEING THAT
AGAIN. THAT'S
EXCLUSIVELY FOUND SOME OF THE HIGHER FUNG-,
IN THE HIGHER FUNGI,
LIKE THE ASCOMYCOTA, BASIDIOMYCOTA, THOSE
TWO GROUPS, WHERE WE
HAD TWO HAPLOID NUCLEI IN THE SAME CELLULAR
PARTITION. SO
THAT'S SORT OF AN ANOMALY FOR THE FUNGI. AND
WE WON'T BE SEEING
THAT ANY LONGER. NOW IN ALL THE LAND PLANTS
-- AND I ALSO
MENTIONED IN THE SEA LETTUCE, THE ULVA, ONE
OF THE GREEN ALGAE,
WHICH HAS INDEPENDENTLY EVOLVED THIS LIFE
CYCLE FROM THE LAND
PLANTS -- WE HAVE MULTICELLULAR GENERATIONS
THAT ARE BOTH DIPLOID
AND HAPLOID. SO WE HAVE THIS ALTERNATION OF
GENERATIONS BETWEEN
DIPLOID AND HAPLOID MULTICELLULAR ORGANISMS
OF SAME SPECIES.
AND SO JUST TO RECAP IT HERE IN IT'S, IN THE
ACTUAL CYCLE FORMAT
HERE YOU CAN SEE A MULTICELLULAR HAPLOID ORGANISM
WHICH WE CALL
THE GAMETE PRODUCING PLANT OR THE GAMETOPHYTE.
SO THE HAPLOID
GENERATION PRODUCES THE GAMETES, OKAY, BY
MITOSIS BECAUSE THEY'RE
ALREADY HAPLOID. THE GAMETES THEN FUSE TOGETHER
TO FORM THE
ZYGOTE. AND THEN WE HAVE MITOSES THAT FORM
A MULTICELLULAR
DIPLOID ORGANISM. REMEMBER THE ZYGOTE'S DIPLOID
OBVIOUSLY. WE
HAD A MULTICELLULAR DIPLOID ORGANISM THAT'S
ALWAYS CALLED THE
SPOROPHYTE, WHICH IS THE SPORE-PRODUCING PLANT.
PHYTE JUST MEANS
PLANT. AND THEN WE HAVE MEIOSIS OCCURING TO
PRODUCE SPORES, SO
WE GO FROM DIPLOID TO HAPLOID HERE IN MEIOSIS.
AND THEN MITOSES
TO GIVE US ANOTHER MULTICELLULAR HAPLOID ORGANISM.
SO IT JUST
GOES BACK AND FORTH OR IT GOES AROUND AND
AROUND HERE BETWEEN THE
DIPOLID AND THE HAPLOID ORGANISMS. AND THE
STRUCTURES WHERE THE
GAMETES ARE BORN ON THE GAMETOPHYTE ARE CALLED
GAMETANGIA.
THOSE ARE JUST HOLLOW SAC-LIKE, SAC-SHAPED
STRUCTURES THAT BEAR
GAMETES. AND SIMILARLY IN THE SPOROPHYTE THE
STRUCTURE THAT
BEARS THE SPORES WHERE MEIOSIS OCCURS IS CALLED
THE SPORANGIUM.
SO THOSE ARE REALLY SIMPLE CLEAR STEPS. AND
THEY'RE CONSISTENT
THROUGHOUT THE LAND PLANTS. BUT THERE'S ELABORATION
IN THESE
THAT YOU REALLY NEED TO, YOU NEED TO HAVE
THIS DOWN IN TERMS OF
THE MAIN STEPS IN THIS ALTERNATION BETWEEN
THESE STEPS TO REALLY
UNDERSTAND THESE SUBSEQUENT LIFE CYCLES. SO
PLEASE AS I
MENTIONED EARLIER, TRY TO EMBRACE THIS AND
MEMORIZE IT AS SOON AS
POSSIBLE AND IT'LL HELP YOU A LOT. OKAY SO
NOW WE ALREADY
TALKED ABOUT HOW THE, THE LAND PLANTS ARE
A MONOPHYLETIC GROUP.
SO THE LAND PLANTS APPEAR TO HAVE EVOLVED
FROM, ALL THE MODERN
LAND PLANTS AND SOME LAND PLANTS THAT HAVE
ACTUALLY GONE BACK TO
AQUATIC SITUATIONS OF WHICH THERE ARE SEVERAL,
THOSE ARE A
MONOPHYLETIC GROUP THAT DESCEND FROM PART
OF THE GREEN ALGAE.
SO THE ORGANISMS WE WERE CALLING GREEN ALGAE
EARLIER ARE ACTUALLY
PARAPHYLETIC, THAT IS SOME GREEN ALGAE ARE
MORE CLOSELY RELATED
TO LAND PLANTS THAN THEY ARE TO THE OTHER
GREEN ALGAE. SO THESE
ARE THE BASE OF TREE HERE. THESE ARE THE ANCESTRAL,
THE
ANCESTORS OF THIS GROUP AND THE TIPS HERE,
SO YOU CAN SEE THAT
THE, THE MOST RECENT COMMON ANCESTOR HERE
OF ALL THE GREEN ALGAE
IS ALSO SHARED WITH THE LAND PLANTS. SO THE
TERM GREEN PLANT
HAS COME TO BE USED FOR ALL OF THE GREEN ORGANISMS,
INCLUDING THE
LAND PLANTS SINCE WE KNOW NOW THAT THE GREEN
ALGAE DON'T
CONSTITUTE A NATURAL GROUP WITHOUT INCLUDING
THE LAND PLANTS.
OKAY, AND SO THE CLOSEST RELATIVES OF THE
LAND PLANTS ARE
FRESHWATER GREEN ALGAE, NOT SALTWATER GREEN
ALGAE. SO THE
COLONIZATION OF LAND HAPPENED NOT DIRECTLY
FROM THE OCEAN OR FROM
MARINE SITUATIONS TO LAND BUT WITH AN INTERMEDIARY
STEP INTO
FRESHWATER BEFORE COLONIZATION OF LAND. SO
THAT'S, THAT'S
SOMETHING THAT'S BECOME WELL-RECOGNIZED NOW
WITH A LOT OF RECENT
EVIDENCE, BOTH MORPHOLOGICAL AND MOLECULAR.
OKAY. THOUGH THESE
ARE THE SEVEN MAJOR GROUPS OF LAND PLANTS
THAT WE'RE GOING TO
FOCUS ON IN THIS COURSE. THERE ARE OTHERS
BUT THESE ARE THE
SEVEN MAJOR LINEAGES OR CLADES. AND HERE'S
THE MOST RECENT
COMMON ANCESTOR OF ALL OF THE, THE LAND PLANTS
NOW EXTINCT. AND
YOU CAN SEE THAT THIS, BASED ON MOLECULAR
AND FOSSIL DATA, WE
THINK THIS IS BACK IN THE EARLY PALEOZOIC,
SO RIGHT AROUND THE
TIME WE HAVE A LOT OF MULTICELLULAR LIFE EVOLVING.
WE HAVE THE
LAND PLANTS EVOLVING. AND THEN ABOUT 50 MILLION
YEARS LATER WE
GET THE ORIGIN OF THE VASCULAR PLANTS WHICH
ARE THESE FOUR MAJOR
LINEAGES THAT I'LL GET TO IN A MOMENT. BUT
THESE ARE THE ONES
THAT HAVE RIGID CONDUCTING TISSUES, AND THEY'RE
SPOROPHYTES THAT
ALLOWS THEM TO GET TO VERY LARGE SIZES AND
HAVE BRANCHING,
BRANCHING GROWTH FOR THE SPOROPHYTE. SO THE
GROUPS LIKE THE
SEED PLANTS, THE FERNS AND RELATIVES AND THE
LYCOPHYTES THAT I'LL
MENTION WHICH HAVE OFTEN BEEN CALLED FERN
ALLIES, THESE ARE ALL
THE VASCULAR PLANTS THAT HAVE THE MAJOR CONDUCTING
TISSUE. THEY
HAVE ROOTS. THEY HAVE A LOT OF FEATURES THAT,
THICK CUTICLES OR
WAXY COVERING ON THEIR PLANT BODY THAT ALLOWS
THEM TO WITHSTAND
DROUGHT. SO THEY HAVE A LOT OF FEATURES THAT
MAKE THEM WELL
ADAPTED TO LAND. YOU CAN SEE THAT THERE ARE
THESE OTHER THREE
GROUPS HERE, THE MOSSES, THE HORNWORTS, AND
THE LIVERWORTS THAT I
STARTED TO INTRODUCE LAST TIME WHICH ARE NOT
A MONOPHYLETIC GROUP
BY A BASAL GRADE HERE WITHIN THE LAND PLANTS.
SO YOU CAN SEE
HOW THEY BRANCH OFF IN A SEQUENTIAL FASHION
HERE. THEY DON'T,
THE MOST RECENT COMMON ANCESTOR OF ALL THE
BRYOPHYTES IS ALSO
SHARED WITH THE VASCULAR PLANTS. AND THE VASCULAR
PLANTS ARE
MORE CLOSELY RELATED TO SOME BRYOPHYTES THAN
TO OTHERS. AND THE
INTERESTING THING HERE IS THE BRYOPHYTES HAVE
LONG BEEN
CONSIDERED A NATURAL GROUP BUT IN FACT THEY'RE
ACTUALLY A GRADE,
A PARAPHYLETIC GROUP. SO THE FEATURES THAT
THEY SHARE IN COMMON
THAT LEAD TO THEM BEING CALLED A GROUP OF
PLANTS, THE BRYOPHYTES,
GIVEN THAT THEY'RE PARAPHYLETIC, WE'D INFER
THAT THOSE FEATURES
WERE FOUND IN THE COMMON ANCESTOR OF ALL THE
LAND PLANTS,
INCLUDING THE VASCULAR PLANTS, OKAY. SO UNDERSTANDING
OF
BRYOPHYTES REALLY ALLOWS US TO UNDERSTAND
THE ANCESTOR OF ALL THE
LAND PLANTS, THE MOST RECENT COMMON ANCESTOR.
SO THAT'S A REALLY
IMPORTANT FINDING. AND THIS WAS DISCOVERED
BACK IN THE 1980S,
BASED ON MORPHOLOGY. ACTUALLY BRENT MISHLER
IS ONE OF THE
FACULTY IN IB, MADE THAT DISCOVERY INITIALLY,
AND IT'S BEEN
REINFORCED WITH MOLECULAR DATA. THE PRECISE
BRANCHING ORDER OF
THESE THREE MAJOR GROUPS IS A LITTLE BIT UNCLEAR
STILL, BUT IT'S
PRETTY CLEAR THAT THEY ARE PARAPHYLETIC AND
THAT THE LIVERWORTS
SHOWN HERE ARE THE EARLIEST LINEAGE TO BRANCH
OFF AND ARE SISTER
TO ALL THE OTHER LAND PLANTS. SO ARE THERE
ANY QUESTIONS ABOUT
THAT? OKAY. SO ONE OF THE THINGS WHEN WE LOOK
TO THE
BRYOPHYTES THAT YOU SEE RIGHT AWAY IS THEY
HAVE SOME INTERESTING
FEATURES THAT MAKE THEM PRETTY WELL ADAPTED
TO LAND. I MEAN
THEY'RE A VERY SUCCESSFUL GROUP. YOU FIND
THEM ON ALL THE
CONTINENTS. AND THEY OCCUR IN A WIDE VARIETY
OF HABITATS,
TEMPERATE AND TROPICAL. ONE THING YOU SEE
IS THAT THEIR SPORES
ARE RESISTANT TO DESICCATION TO SOME EXTENT,
THAT IS THEY DON'T
DRY OUT READILY. SO THEY CAN DISPERSE SPORES
AND THE SPORES CAN
TRAVEL LONG DISTANCES AND WITHSTAND SOME ENVIRONMENTAL
EXTREMES.
BUT ONE OF THE COOLEST THINGS ABOUT THE BRYOPHYTES
AND SOMETHING
THAT'S ONLY BECOME REALLY APPRECIATED IN THE
LAST FEW YEARS,
WELL, IT'S BEEN KNOWN FOR A LONG TIME BUT
IT'S BEEN STUDIED MORE
INTENSIVELY, IS THAT EVEN THEIR MAIN BODY,
THEIR, THE MAIN PLANT
BODY, THE GAMETOPHYTE IN THIS CASE -- WE'LL
GET TO THE LIFE CYCLE
IN A MOMENT -- IS DESICCATION TOLERANT. AND
SO NOT ONLY CAN THE
SPORES WITHSTAND DESICCATION BUT THE ACTUAL
VEGETATIVE BODY OF
THE PLANT CAN DRY OUT ESSENTIALLY COMPLETELY
AND THE BRYOPHYTES
THAT AT LEAST OCCUR IN SEASONALLY DRY ENVIRONMENTS
OR PERENNIALLY
PRETTY DRY ENVIRONMENTS. AND THEY LOOK FOR
ALL PRACTICAL
PURPOSES TO BE LIFELESS WHEN THEY'RE IN THAT
STATE. YOU CAN'T
DETECT ANY METABOLIC ACTIVITY. BUT ALL YOU
HAVE TO DO IS ADD
WATER AND THEY'RE RIGHT BACK, THEY REHYDRATE
VERY, VERY QUICKLY.
AND THEY'RE PHOTOSYNTHESIZING AGAIN IN NO
TIME. SO THIS IS
SOMETHING THAT'S BEEN REALLY INTERESTING.
AND A LOT OF CROP
SCIENTISTS, FOR EXAMPLE, REALLY WANT TO UNDERSTAND
THIS AND SEE
IF THEY CAN GET GENES FROM BRYOPHYTES INTO
CROPS BECAUSE THE
VASCULAR PLANTS, AS SUCCESSFUL AS THEY'VE
BEEN ON LAND, MOSTLY
DON'T HAVE THIS CAPABILITY. THEY HAVE A LOT
OF WAYS OF
PREVENTING THEMSELVES FROM DRYING OUT. YOU
KNOW THEY HAVE GREAT
CONDUCTING TISSUE AND ROOT SYSTEMS, THICK
CUTICLES, THESE WAXY
COVERINGS, BUT ONCE THEY ACTUALLY DO DRY OUT,
MOST OF THEM ARE
TOAST. THEY'RE NOT GOING TO REVIVE. THERE
ARE SOME THAT WILL,
AND I'LL SHOW YOU A COUPLE. BUT THIS IS SOMETHING
THAT THE
BRYOPHYTES HAVE DOWN. THEY DON'T HAVE ROOT
SYSTEMS. THEY DON'T
HAVE, YOU KNOW, DESICCATION RESISTANT LEAVES,
BUT THEY SURVIVE
DESICCATION OR DRYING OUT REALLY WELL. OKAY,
SO THE LIFE CYCLE
OF BRYOPHYTES IS INTERESTING. AND REMEMBER
THAT THE CLOSEST
RELATIVES OF THE LAND PLANTS ARE ALGAE THAT
DIDN'T HAVE AN
ALTERNATION OF GENERATIONS. THEY JUST HAD
A HAPLOID ORGANISM
AND THE ONLY DIPLOID STAGE WAS THE ZYGOTE.
NOW WHAT YOU SEE IN
THE BRYOPHYTES AND PRESUMABLY THE ANCESTOR
OF ALL THE MODERN LAND
PLANTS IS THAT THE DOMINANT GENERATION IS
THE GAMETOPHYTE, THE
HAPLOID GENERATION, WHICH MAKES A LOT OF SENSE
CONSIDERING THAT
THEIR CLOSEST RELATIVES ONLY HAD A HAPLOID
GENERATION. THESE
HAVE A DOMINANT HAPLOID GENERATION. AND THE
SPOROPHYTE
GENERATION WHICH IS SHOWN HERE IN THIS PINK
PART OF THE LIFE
CYCLE IS A PARASITE ON THE GAMETOPHYTE, ON
THE MATERNAL
GAMETOPHYTE. SO THE SPOROPHYTE IS AN EXTREMELY
SMALL AND
EPHEMERAL TYPICALLY PRETTY SHORT-LIVED ORGANISM
THAT'S PARASITIC
ON THE MORE LONG, TYPICALLY MORE, OFTEN MORE
LONG-LIVED
GAMETOPHYTE. AND IT BASICALLY IS PRETTY MUCH
AN ORGANISM THAT
PRODUCES SPORES BY MEIOSIS AND IT DOESN'T
HAVE A LOT MORE GOING
FOR IT. IT'S, IT'S BEEN INTERJECTED INTO THIS
LIFE CYCLE. I
MEAN WE KNOW THAT THE, THAT A HAPLOID ORGANISM
WITHOUT A DIPLOID
GENERATION WAS ANCESTRAL TO ALL THE LAND PLANTS.
AND WE
BASICALLY HAD THE INTERJECTION OF A SPOROPHYTE
GENERATION HERE
THAT IS PARASITIC ON THE GAMETOPHYTE. OKAY,
SO THE SPOROPHYTE
DOES PRODUCE SPORES. AND THESE SPORES AS I
MENTIONED ARE
SOMEWHAT RESISTANT TO DESICCATION. THEY'RE
COVERED WITH A
SUBSTANCE CALLED SPOROPOLLENIN THAT MAKES
THEM RESISTANT. AND IT
ALSO IS PRESENT IN THE ZYGOTES OF THE CLOSELY
RELATED GREEN
ALGAE, THE CHAROPHYTES. BUT IT'S, THESE ARE
LAND DISPERSED
SPORES. AND THEY GERMINATE. MITOSES OCCUR.
WE GET A
FILAMENOUS GAMETOPHYTE INITIALLY IN THIS MOSSES.
THIS IS A MOSS
LIFE CYCLE HERE. AND EVENTUALLY WE GET THE
MATURE GAMETOPHYTES
FORMING WHICH LOOK LEAFY. AND AT THEIR APEX
WE HAVE GAMETANGIA
PRODUCED. REMEMBER THESE ARE THE SAC-LIKE
STRUCTURES THAT BEAR
THE GAMETES ON GAMETOPHYTES. AND IN A LOT
OF MOSSES LIKE THE ONE
REPRESENTED HERE, WE HAVE UNISEXUAL GAMETOPHYTES.
THERE ARE TWO
DIFFERENT TYPES OF GAMETOPHYTES, ONE THAT
PRODUCES SPERM, ONE
THAT PRODUCES EGGS. BUT SOME OF, SOME OF THE
MOSSES HAVE
BISEXUAL GAMETOPHYTES OR HERMAPHRODITIC GAMETOPHYTES
THAT PRODUCE
BOTH GAMET-, BOTH TYPES OF GAMETANGIA. AND
WE CALL THOSE
ANTHERIDIA. SINGULAR WOULD BE THE ANTHERIDIUM
WHICH PRODUCES
THE SPERM. AND THE ARCHEGONIA OR THE ARCHEGONIUM
IS SINGULAR,
THAT'S THE TYPE OF GAMETANGIA THAT PRODUCES
AN EGG. AND SO ONE
OF THINGS THAT PRETTY MUCH LOCKS THE MOSSES
INTO AT LEAST
SEASONALLY WET ENVIRONMENTS TO SOME EXTENT
IF THEY'RE GOING TO BE
SEXUALLY REPRODUCING IS THAT THEY HAVE FREE-SWIMMING
SPERM. AND
THE SPERM HAS TO LEAVE THE ANTHERIDIUM AND
SWIM TO THE NECK OF
THE ARCHEGONIUM AND SWIM DOWN THE CANAL OF
THE ARCHEGONIUM WHICH
IS THE FLASK-SHAPED GAMETANGIUM WITH AN OPENING
AT THE TIP AND
THEN A LONG NECK. AND THEN AT THE BASE IT'S
SWOLLEN AND THERE'S
AN EGG THERE. THAT'S A TYPICAL SHAPE OF AN
ARCHEGONIUM. AND
THE SPERM HAVE TO SWIM DOWN THERE TO FERTILIZE
THE EGG. BUT NOT
ONLY DOES THE FEMALE GAMETANGIUM PRODUCE A
GAMETE, THE EGG, BUT
IT'S ALSO WHERE FERTILIZATION OCCURS AND WHERE
THE EMBRYO
DEVELOPS. SO IT'S ANALOGOUS IN A LOT OF WAYS
TO FEMALE
REPRODUCTIVE TRACKS IN ANIMALS, BUT IT'S COMPLETELY
INDEPENDENT
EVOLUTION OF THOSE, OF THESE FEATURES. AND
SO WE SEE A
FERTILIZATION OCCURRING HERE. THE ZYGOTE DOWN
AT THE BASE OF
THE ARCHEGONIUM, DIPLOID NOW. AND THEN THIS
UNDERGOES MITOSES
TO FORM AN EMBRYO. NOW AN EMBRYO IN PLANTS
BASICALLY JUST
REFERS TO AN IMMATURE SPOROPHYTE THAT'S AT
THE STAGE WHERE THERE
CAN BE A RESTING STAGE. AND IT'S ELABORATED
TO A GREATER OR
LESSER EXTENT IN DIFFERENT GROUPS OF LAND
PLANTS. BUT THEY ALL
HAVE EMBRYOS. AND SO ALL THE LAND PLANTS,
THAT IS THE
BRYOPHYTES PLUS THE VASCULAR PLANTS ARE OFTEN
CALLED EMBRYOPHYTES
OR EMBRYO-PRODUCING PLANTS. AND THE EMBRYO
BECOMES REALLY
IMPORTANT WHEN WE GET TO THE SEED PLANTS.
TALK ABOUT THEM
SHORTLY. BUT HERE'S THE YOUNG SPOROPHYTE THEN
DEVELOPING. AND
AS I MENTIONED, IT'S PARASITIC ON THE GAMETOPHYTE,
THE MATERNAL
GAMETOPHYTE. SO IT HAS A FOOT HERE, WHAT THEY
CALL A FOOT
THAT'S, IT'S ACTUALLY EMBEDDED IN THE TIP
OF THE GAMETANGIUM OR
IN THE TIP OF THE GAMETOPHYTE HERE. AND IT
ALSO HAS A STALK AND
MOSSES WHICH WE CALL THE SETA. AND AT THE
TIP OF IT IS
BASICALLY JUST THE SPORANGIUM, WHICH IS SOME,
WHICH THE MOSS
SPECIALISTS, THE BRYOLOGISTS CALL A CAPSULE.
AND HERE YOU CAN
SEE THE SPORANGIUM OR THE CAPSULE MAGNIFIED.
SEE THE TIP OF IT MAGNIFIED USING SCANNING
ELECTRON MICROSCOPY TO
SHOW THIS ELABORATE STRUCTURE AT THE TIP CALLED
A PERISTOME.
AND THE MAIN POINT HERE IS THAT THE MOSSES
CAN REGULATE THEIR
SPORE DISPERSAL BY MEANS OF THIS SPECIALIZED
STRUCTURE THAT
RESPONDS TO ATMOSPHERIC HUMIDITY SUCH THAT
SPORES WILL TEND TO BE
RELEASED WHEN IT'S DRY OUT. SO IT'S MORE EASY
TO DISPERSE
SPORES INTO THE ENVIRONMENT TO GET THEM AWAY
FROM THE PARENT
GAMETOPHYTE OR AND THE PARENT SPOROPHYTE HERE
IF, IF IT'S DRY, IF
WE HAVE DRY, A DRY CLIMATE. AND UNDER WET
CONDITIONS IT WOULD BE
ENCLOSED. SO THE SPORES HAVE SOME, SOME REGULATION
OF THEIR
SPORE DISPERSAL THAT'S A NICE ADAPTATION TO
LAND. WE DON'T SEE
THIS STRUCTURE IN THE LIVERWORTS OR THE HORNWORTS,
THE OTHER TWO
GROUPS OF BRYOPHYTES. ALSO SOME OF THE MOSSES
HAVE THE ABILITY
TO CONDUCT WATER AND NUTRIENTS IN THEIR TISSUES
BY MEANS OF
SPECIALIZED CONDUCTING CELLS THAT DON'T APPEAR
TO BE HOMOLOGOUS
WITH THOSE IN VASCULAR PLANTS. AND THEY'RE
NOT STRONGLY
REINFORCED STRUCTURALLY SO THEY DON'T ALLOW
MOSSES TO GET VERY
LARGE. THE LARGEST BRYOPHYTES ARE TYPICALLY
ONLY ABOUT
15 CENTIMETERS TALL, SO UNDER A FOOT TALL.
NOT VERY BIG PLANTS.
SOME OF THE MOSSES CAN GET UP TO A COUPLE
OF METERS TALL, BUT
THOSE ARE REAL EXCEPTIONS. OKAY, SO JUST TO,
SO ARE THERE
QUESTIONS ABOUT THE LIFE CYCLE OF BRYOPHYTES?
OR SOME OF THESE?
YEAH?
STUDENT: [INAUDIBLE].
PROFESSOR: YEAH, THEY HAVE A SIMILAR LIFE
CYCLE. IN THE
LIVERWORTS, THERE ARE SOME LEAFY LIVERWORTS
THAT HAVE THIS KIND
OF LEAFY APPEARANCE. THE LIFE CYCLE'S PRETTY
MUCH THE SAME
EXCEPT THAT MOST OF THE LIVERWORTS AND HORNWORTS
DON'T HAVE AN
ELONGATED STALK THAT BEARS THE CAPSULE. SO
THE MOSSES GET THEIR
CAPSULE UP AWAY FROM THE GAMETOPHYTE PRETTY
WELL. AND SOME OF
THE LIVERWORTS DO ACTUALLY HAVE A STALK, BUT
THEY, THEY
BASICALLY, WHEN THE SPORES ARE READY TO DISPERSE,
THE CAPSULE
JUST COMPLETELY OPENS UP AND ALL THE SPORES
ARE RELEASED. THEY
DON'T HAVE THIS REGULATION OF SPORE DISPERSAL.
BUT THE GENERAL
STEPS OF THE CYCLE ARE THE SAME. THE GAMETOPHYTE
IS DOMINANT.
AND THE SPOROPHYTE, IF ANYTHING, IS EVEN LESS
CONSPICIOUS. AND
THE LIVERWORTS DEFINITELY. I'LL SHOW YOU A
HORNWORT SPOROPHYTE
IN A MOMENT. THOUGH HERE ARE THE THREE MAJOR
GROUPS OF
BRYOPHYTES JUST BRIEFLY. THE MOSSES, AGAIN
WORLDWIDE, ABOUT
9,000 SPECIES, REALLY PRETTY DIVERSE. PROBABLY
A LOT MORE
SPECIES THAN ARE RECOGNIZED BECAUSE MOSSES
SEEM TO EVOLVE FAIRLY
QUICKLY. I MEAN, I SHOULD SAY THEIR MORPHOLOGY
EVOLVES REALLY
SLOWLY BUT IT'S CLEAR THAT THEY'RE SPECIATING
OR DIVERSIFYING
MUCH MORE RAPIDLY THAN THEY'RE CHANGING IN
CONSPICUOUS WAYS
MORPHOLOGICALLY AND THAT'S CLEAR FROM MOLECULAR
DATA. SO
THEY'RE PROBABLY A MORE DIVERSE GROUP THAN
WE RECOGNIZE. BUT
THEY HAVE THIS GREEN GAMETOPHYTE. IT DOESN'T
LOOK VERY GREEN IN
THIS SHOT BUT THE, TRUST ME, THESE ARE PHYTOSYNTHETIC,
THIS
DARKER AREA. HERE YOU CAN SEE A SHOOT, A GAMETOPHYTE
HERE
THAT'S GREEN. AND HERE'S THE SPOROPHYTE WITH
THE LONG SETA
EMBEDDED IN THE TIP OF THE GAMETOPHYTE. THE
SPORANGIUM OR
CAPSULE, AND THERE'S THE LITTLE PERISTOME
AT THE TIP THAT
REGULATES SPORE DISPERSAL. OKAY, NOW THE LIVERWORTS
ARE, THERE
ARE ABOUT 6,000 SPECIES RECOGNIZED. IT'S STILL
A PRETTY DIVERSE
GROUP. ALSO FOUND WORLDWIDE. AND THEY HAVE
A VARIETY OF
DIFFERENT FORMS. THE ONES YOU MOST COMMONLY
ENCOUNTER, AND ARE
EASILY RECOGNIZABLE IS LIVERWORTS, HAVE THESE
WHAT ARE CALLED
PHALLOID BODIES WHICH ARE BASICALLY JUST FLATTENED
BODIES THAT
LIE FLAT ON SUBSTRATE LIKE SOIL AND CAN BECOME
LOBED LIKE THIS.
AND THE, AS I MENTIONED, THE SPOROPHYTE IS
PRETTY MUCH EMBEDDED
USUALLY INSIDE THE GAMETOPHYTE, ALTHOUGH SOMETIMES
ON A STALK.
BUT THE STALK IS PRETTY FRAGILE BY COMPARISON
WITH THE ONE THAT
WE DID IN MOSSES IF THERE IS ONE. AND THE
HORNWORTS ARE A
PRETTY LOW DIVERSITY GROUP. THERE ARE JUST
A COUPLE HUNDRED
SPECIES OF THESE. AND THEY ALSO HAVE A PHALLOID
BODY LIKE SOME
OF THE LIVERWORTS THAT'S JUST BASICALLY LYING
FLAT ON SUBSTRATE.
AND HERE YOU CAN SEE THE SPOROPHYTES OF HORNWORTS
WHICH ARE
PHOTOSYNTHETIC. AND THEY ACTUALLY HAVE STOMATA
WHICH ARE PORES
THAT REGULATE GAS EXCHANGE WHICH IS INTERESTING.
AND THEY ALSO
HAVE BASICALLY THIS WHOLE ELONGATED HORN-SHAPED
STRUCTURE, WHICH
IS THE BASIS OF THE NAME HORNWORT, IS A CAPSULE.
IT'S JUST AN
ELONGATED SPORANGIUM. IT DOESN'T HAVE A STALK.
IT SPLITS OPEN
AT MATURITY. AND IT'S UNCLEAR WHETHER THE
HORNWORTS ARE THE
CLOSEST RELATIVES OF THE VASCULAR PLANTS OR
THE MOSSES. THERE'S
SOME UNCERTAINTY ABOUT THAT. BUT ANYWAYS,
THERE'S SOME
CONSIDERABLE DIVERSITY IN THE BRYOPHYTES.
AND THESE THREE
GROUPS ARE DEFINITELY NATURAL GROUPS. AND
WORT, YOU'LL SEE THE
NAME WORT USED A LOT IN BOTANY. IT'S JUST
AN ARCHAIC TERM FOR
AN HERB, BASICALLY A NON-WOODY PLANT. SO THAT'S
WHAT THE BASIS
FOR WORT IS. OKAY, SO THOSE ARE THE THREE
MAJOR GROUPS OF
BRYOPHYTES. AND I SHOULD MENTION THAT THEY
BEGAN TO DIVERSIFY
FROM A COMMON ANCESTOR, OOPS, PRIOR TO THE
ORIGIN OF THE VASCULAR
PLANTS. REMEMBER THEY'RE A PARAPHYLETIC GROUP.
ALL RIGHT, SO
ECONOMICALLY AND ECOLOGICALLY THE MOSSES ARE
REALLY IMPORTANT.
AND ALTHOUGH THEY DON'T PRODUCE FOOD ITEMS
LIKE VASCULAR PLANTS
FOR US, THEY ARE IMPORTANT IN MANY WAYS. SOME
OF THE MOST
CONSPICUOUSLY IMPORTANT MOSSES -- AND MOSSES
ARE WHERE WE FIND A
LOT OF ECONOMICALLY IMPORTANT BRYOPHYTES
-- ARE THE PEAT MOSSES,
MEMBERS OF THE GENUS SPHAGNUM. IT'S A VERY
DISTINCTIVE MOSS
GROUP. AND THESE ARE OFTEN FOUND IN BOGGY
ENVIRONMENTS,
SATURATING ENVIRONMENTS. AND THEY IMPART ACIDITY,
LOW PH, AND
CERTAIN CHEMICAL PROPERTIES TO THESE BOGS
DUE TO THESE PHENOLIC
COMPOUNDS THEY PRODUCE THAT RESULT IN VERY
LOW RATES OF
DECOMPOSITION IN THESE BOG ENVIRONMENTS. AND
SO THE CARBON
THAT'S FIXED BY THE, BY THE, BY THE PEAT MOSS
AND OTHER
PHOTOSYNTHETIC ORGANISMS IN THESE SITUATIONS,
IN THESE
ENVIRONMENTS WILL TEND NOT TO DECAY RAPIDLY
AND WILL TEND TO BE
DEPOSITED AND REMAIN IN THE SOIL ENVIRONMENT
OR REMAIN, RAIN OUT
OF THE ATMOSPHERE. AND SO BRYOPHYTES ARE REALLY
IMPORTANT FOR
FIXING CARBON AND KEEPING IT OUT OF THE ATMOSPHERE.
AND
UNFORTUNATELY NOW, WELL, THE PEAT HAS ACCUMULATED
OVER THE AGES
TO SUCH AN EXTENT, ESPECIALLY IN SOME NORTHERN
CLIMATES WHERE WE
HAVE COOL TEMPERATURES AND ANAEROBIC CONDITIONS
-- THAT'S
TYPICALLY WHERE WE FIND SPHAGNUM ARE IN COOL
ENVIRONMENTS -- THAT
NOW THIS IS BEING EXTENSIVELY USED AS FUEL.
AND HERE YOU CAN
SEE, THIS IS ONE OF THESE INDUSTRIAL PEAT
HARVESTING OPERATIONS
IN THE U.K. AND SO A LOT OF THIS CARBON IS
BEING RETURNED BACK TO
THE ATMOSPHERE. BUT EVEN MORE DISCONCERTING
IS THAT A LOT OF THE
PEAT THAT'S BEEN DEPOSITED IN SOILS OVER THE
YEARS, A LOT OF
THESE PEAT ENVIRONMENTS THAT ARE STILL INTACT
IN NORTHERN
CLIMATES ARE STARTING TO DRY OUT WITH GLOBAL
CLIMATE CHANGE AND
RATES OF RESPIRATION ARE INCREASING AND THIS
CARBON'S BEING
RETURNED TO THE ATMOSPHERE. SO THERE'S A REAL
CONCERN ABOUT,
ABOUT SOME POSITIVE FEEDBACK LOOPS THAT MIGHT
RESULT IN A LOT OF
CARBON RETURNING TO THE ATMOSPHERE FROM THESE
KINDS OF
ENVIRONMENTS. IN ANY CASE PEAT MOSS IS ALSO
USEFUL
ECONOMICALLY. IT'S, HOLDS WATER REALLY WELL.
AND THE ACIDITY
OF IT, AND AS I MENTIONED THESE PHENOLICS,
MAKE IT AN
ANTIMICROBIAL ENVIRONMENT THAT'S GOOD FOR,
SAY, WRAPPING UP PLANT
CUTTINGS OR ROOTS FOR SHIPMENT. IT'S ALSO
GOOD AS A SOIL
CONDITIONER, ET CETERA. SO THERE ARE A LOT
OF USES FOR PEAT
MOSS. THERE ARE SOME MOSSES TOO THAT ARE MEDICINALLY
IMPORTANT.
IT'S A MINORITY, BUT IN SOME ASIAN MEDICINAL
TRADITIONS THERE ARE
SOME USEFUL MOSES THAT ARE BEING ACTIVELY
STUDIED. NOW ANOTHER
REALLY THING IMPORTANT SCIENTIFICALLY ABOUT
THESE PEAT BOG
ENVIRONMENTS AND BOGGY ENVIRONMENTS IN GENERAL
IS THAT THEIR
ANAEROBIC CONDITIONS -- THE LACK OF OXYGEN,
THE COOL ENVIRONMENT,
THE LOW PH -- HAS NOT ONLY LEAD TO THESE BIG
CARBON DEPOSITS BUT
ALSO PRESERVATION OF FOSSILS. AND A LOT OF
WHAT WE KNOW ABOUT
THE LAST SEVERAL THOUSAND YEARS OF HISTORY
FROM THE FOSSIL
PERSPECTIVE COMES FROM THESE KINDS OF ENVIRONMENTS.
AND NOT
ONLY PLANT REMAINS ARE PRESERVED IN THESE
SITUATIONS BUT ALSO
ANIMAL REMAINS ARE WELL PRESERVED, INCLUDING
HUMAN REMAINS. AND
IN NORTHERN EUROPE, THERE ARE THESE SO-CALLED
"BOG PEOPLE" THAT
HAVE BEEN EXCAVATED, USUALLY INADVERTENTLY
FROM BOG ENVIRONMENTS.
AND SOME OF THESE INDIVIDUALS LIKE THIS ONE
LOOK LIKE THEY'RE
SLEEPING. THEY SHOW NO DECOMPOSITION. YOU
CAN MAKE OUT THEIR
FACIAL FEATURES PERFECTLY. AND THEY'RE BASICALLY
JUST DEEPLY
STAINED BY THE PHENOLICS. THIS IS A LEVEL
OF PRESERVATION FOR
CORPSES THOUSANDS OF YEARS OLD THAT YOU CAN'T
SEE IN ANY OTHER
CONDITIONS, ANY OTHER SITUATIONS. THERE'S
OVER A THOUSAND OF
THESE PEOPLE THAT HAVE BEEN FOUND. AND YOU
CAN SEE THE ROPE
AROUND THIS PERSON'S NECK. THESE PEOPLE ALMOST
INADVERTENTLY, I
MEAN ALMOST ALWAYS APPEAR TO HAVE BEEN EXECUTED.
AND THEY MAY
HAVE BEEN RITUAL SACRIFICES. THEY MAY HAVE
BEEN EXECUTED
CRIMINALS. IT'S UNCLEAR BUT IN ANY CASE THERE'S
A LOT THAT CAN
BE LEARNED ABOUT. THESE ACTUALLY DATE BACK
TO THE IRON AGE, SO
THERE'S A LOT OF IMPORTANT HUMAN REMAINS THAT
HAVE BEEN FOUND IN
THESE SITUATIONS FOR ARCHEOLOGISTS. OKAY.
SO ALSO ANOTHER
THING THAT PEAT MOSS USED TO BE REALLY IMPORTANT
FOR, HERE YOU
CAN SEE SPHAGNUM MOSS FOR THE WOUNDED ON THE
FRONT BEING
HARVESTED UP IN CANADA, BRITISH COLUMBIA,
IN PRINCE RUPERT.
PEAT MOSS WAS EXTENSIVELY COLLECTED AND SHIPPED
TO THE FRONT
DURING WORLD WAR I TO USE AS STERILE BANDAGING
FOR SOLDIERS THAT
WERE INVOLVED IN TRENCH WARFARE IN THESE REALLY
UNSANITARY
CONDITIONS. AND IT SAVED A LOT OF LIVES AT
A TIME WHEN
ANTIBIOTICS, PENICILLIN IN PARTICULAR, WASN'T
AVAILABLE. THOUGH
THAT'S NOT SUCH A COMMON USE ANYMORE OF COURSE,
BUT THAT'S AN
INTERESTING HISTORICAL FOOTNOTE. OKAY, SO
NOW WE'RE GOING TO
MOVE ON TO VASCULAR PLANTS, WHICH AS I MENTIONED
THESE ARE THE
ORGANISMS THAT DOMINATE THE TERRESTRIAL ENVIRONMENT
TODAY AND
THAT HAVE EXTENSIVE CONDUCTING TISSUE TO CONDUCT
BOTH WATER AND
NUTRIENTS IN THEIR PLANT BODY. THEY ALSO HAVE
WELL-DEVELOPED
ROOT SYSTEMS FOR CONDUCTING WATER AND WELL-DEVELOPED
CUTICLES,
THAT IS WAXY COVERINGS ON THEIR SPOROPHYTE
GENERATION. WE SHOW
A NUMBER OF IMPORTANT FEATURES FOR SURVIVAL
ON LAND. AND ONE OF
THE MOST INTERESTING FOSSIL FINDINGS ABOUT
ANCIENT VASCULAR
PLANTS WHICH ARE A MONOPHYLETIC GROUP IS THAT
THE EARLIEST
VASCULAR PLANTS APPEAR VERY DIFFERENT FROM
OUR MODERN VASCULAR
PLANTS. AND THESE ARISE ABOUT 50 MILLION YEARS
AFTER THE
BRYOPHYTES FIRST APPEAR. AND THESE THINGS
ARE ONLY ABOUT THE
SIZE OF A MATCHSTICK. THESE ARE REALLY SMALL.
AND THEY DON'T
HAVE MUCH IN THE WAY OF CONDUCTING TISSUE.
THEY ALSO DON'T HAVE
ANY LEAVES. THIS IS, THIS ARTIST'S RENDITION
IS ACTUALLY
INACCURATE. YOU CAN, THIS IS, THESE SHOULD'T
BE, THIS SHOULDN'T
SHOW LEAVES HERE. THESE ACTUALLY AREN'T THERE
IN THE FOSSILS.
THERE ARE NO LEAVES. THERE ARE NO ROOTS. AND
THEY HAVE
DICHOTOMOUS BRANCHING WHICH MEANS THERE'S
NO APICAL DOMINANCE OF
ANY PARTICULAR BRANCH. THE APEX OF THE SHOOT
JUST SPLITS INTO
TWO EQUAL BRANCHES AND YOU GET THIS Y-SHAPED
BRANCHING THROUGHOUT
THE PLANT. AND THE TIPS OF THE BRANCHES ARE
TERMINATED BY THESE
REPRODUCTIVE BODIES, EITHER BY A SPORANGIUM
IN THE CASE OF A
SPOROPHYTE OR A GAMETANGIUM IN THE CASE OF
A GAMETOPHYTE. AND
THE GAMETOPHYTE GENERATION AND THE SPOROPHYTE
GENERATION, THE
HAPLOID AND THE DIPLOID GENERATIONS ARE VERY,
VERY SIMILAR
MORPHOLOGICALLY. SO WE'VE GONE FROM A SPORE
OR GAMETOPHYTE
DOMINANT GENERATION, I SHOULD SAY GAMETOPHYTE
DOMINANT LIFE CYCLE
AND THE BRYOPHYTES, TO A LIFE CYCLE WHERE
THE GAMETOPHYTE AND THE
SPOROPHYTE SHARE DOMINANCE WHERE THEY ESSENTIALLY
ARE ON EQUAL
FOOTING AS FAR AS THE DEGREE OF ELABORATION
OF THESE TWO
GENERATIONS. THOUGH THAT'S A, A VERY SIMPLE
VASCULAR PLANT
ORGANIZATION. AND THERE ARE NO MEMBERS OF
THIS GROUP LEFT
TODAY. THEY'RE EXTINCT. RHYNIOPHYTE IS THE
NAME, NAMED AFTER
THE RHYNIE CHERT WHERE THEY WERE FOUND IN
THE U.K. BUT THESE
AREN'T AROUND ANYMORE, SO WE WON'T BE SEEING
THESE. THE MODERN
VASCULAR PLANTS INCLUDE THOSE, THE FOUR GROUPS
THAT I MENTIONED
EARLIER HERE. HERE YOU CAN SEE VASCULAR PLANTS,
THE LYCOPHYTES,
WHICH OFTEN HAVE BEEN CALLED THE FERN ALLIES.
THE TRUE FERNS
AND RELATIVES AND THEN THE SEED PLANTS OF
WHICH THERE ARE
GYMNOSPERMS AND ANGIOSPERMS. WE'LL BE TALKING
ABOUT THESE A
LOT. SO FIRST IT'S EASIEST TO INTRODUCE YOU
TO TWO OF THESE
LINEAGES WHICH WE CALL THE FREE-SPORING VASCULAR
PLANTS. AND
THESE REALLY SHOULD BE IN QUOTES BECAUSE THIS
IS NOT A
MONOPHYLETIC GROUP. BUT IT INCLUDES TWO MONOPHYLETIC
GROUPS,
THE FERNS AND RELATIVES, AND THE LYCOPHYTES.
LYCOPHYTES HAVE
OFTEN BEEN THOUGHT TO BE VERY, VERY CLOSELY
RELATED TO THE FERNS.
THAT'S WHY THEY'RE CALLED FERN ALLIES COMMONLY.
BUT, IN FACT,
THE FERNS AND RELATIVES ARE MORE CLOSELY RELATED
TO THE SEED
PLANTS THAN THEY ARE TO THE LYCOPHYTES. AND
THIS HAS BEEN
REINFORCED BY MANY LINES OF EVIDENCE. THIS
IS A BULLETPROOF
FINDING AT THIS POINT. THE LYCOPHYTES ARE
SISTER TO ALL THE
OTHER VASCULAR PLANTS. AND THE LYCOPHYTES,
THESE SO-CALLED FERN
ALLIES PLUS THE FERNS, THEY BOTH FREELY DISPERSE
THEIR SPORES
INTO THE ENVIRONMENT. SO THEY DON'T HAVE SEEDS.
THESE ARE THE
SEEDLESS VASCULAR PLANTS AS OPPOSED TO THIS
VASCULAR PLANTS THAT
HAVE SEEDS, THE SEED PLANTS HERE. WELL THE
ABSENCE OF SEEDS IS
A PRIMITIVE OR ANCESTRAL FEATURE, SO IT SHOULDN'T
BE A SURPRISE
THAT THESE AREN'T A MONOPHYLETIC GROUP TAKEN
TOGETHER. BUT
THESE ARE TWO WELL-SUPPORTED CLADES, THESE
TWO GROUPS. AND HERE
THERE ARE, THE SEEDLESS VASCULAR PLANTS. LYCOPHYTES
ON THE
RIGHT. AND FERNS, HORSETAILS AND WHISK FERNS,
WHICH ARE ALL
BASICALLY THE FERN GROUP, ON THE LEFT. NOW
THE LYCOPHYTES WHICH
ARE SISTER TO ALL THE OTHER VASCULAR PLANTS
ARE INTERESTING
BECAUSE THERE ARE BASICALLY THREE MAJOR GROUPS
THAT ARE STILL
ALIVE. TWO OF THEM ARE SHOWN HERE. AND YOU
MIGHT AT THESE AND
SAY, WAIT A MINUTE, HE MIXED UP THE SLIDES.
THOSE ARE MOSSES.
WELL, THEY LOOK LIKE MOSSES. BUT THESE ARE
SPOROPHYTES, NOT
GAMETOPHYTES. SO THE DOMINANT GENERATION IN
ALL THE MODERN
VASCULAR PLANTS, INCLUDING THE LYCOPHYTES
IS THE SPOROPHYTE
GENERATION. THE GAMETOPHYTE GENERATION IS
HIGHLY REDUCED. SO
WE'VE GONE FROM ONLY HAVING A GAMETOPHYTE
GENERATION, IN THE CASE
OF THE FRESHWATER GREEN ALGAE THAT ARE CLOSELY
RELATED TO LAND
PLANTS, TO HAVING A GAMETOPHYTE DOMINANT ALTERNATION
OF
GENERATIONS WITH A PARASITIC SPOROPHYTE IN
THE BRYOPHYTES.
THOUGH THE SHARING OF DOMINANCE IN THE FIRST
VASCULAR PLANTS THAT
ARE NOW EXTINCT, SHARING OF DOMINANCE BETWEEN
THE GAMETOPHYTE AND
THE SPOROPHYTE. AND IN ALL THE MODERN VASCULAR
PLANTS THE
SPOROPHYTE IS DOMINATE. IT'S THE MAJOR PHOTOSYNTHETIC
ORGANISM,
THE BIG BRANCHING ORGANISM. AND THE GAMETOPHYTE
IS HIGHLY
REDUCED. THOUGH IN LYCOPHYTES HERE WE SEE,
ANOTHER WAY YOU CAN
TELL THESE AREN'T MOSSES, IF YOU LOOK CLOSELY
YOU SEE THAT THERE
ARE ACTUALLY, WELL, IT'S HARD TO MAKE OUT,
BUT THERE ARE CONES ON
THESE, ACTUAL STROBILI. SO IN A LOT OF THE
VASCULAR PLANTS WE
HAVE WHAT ARE CALLED CONES OR A STROBILUS
OR STROBILI, PLURAL,
WHICH ARE BASICALLY JUST A STRUCTURE MADE
UP OF MODIFIED LEAVES
THAT ARE IN ASSOCIATION WITH SPORANGIA. SO
IT'S A STRUCTURE
THAT BEARS SPORANGIA. AND THESE INCLUDE, IN
THIS PARTICULAR
GROUP WHAT ARE CALLED THE SPIKE MOSSES. THESE
ARE THE CLUB
MOSES. THESE ARE NOT MOSSES THOUGH. THEY'RE,
THEY ARE VASCULAR
PLANTS. IN THIS GROUP WE HAVE DESICCATION
TOLERANCE IN SOME OF
THEM. THEY CAN DRY OUT COMPLETELY AND REVIVE.
SO SOME OF THESE
EARLY BRANCHING LINEAGES OF VASCULAR PLANTS
DO HAVE THIS ABILITY
TO DESICCATE AND REVIVE. BUT IT'S VERY LIMITED
WITHIN THE
VASCULAR PLANTS IN GENERAL. OKAY, SO THE LYCOPHYTES
ARE
WIDESPREAD. THERE ARE ONLY ABOUT 1200 SPECIES
WORLDWIDE. IT'S
NOT A VERY DIVERSE GROUP. BUT IT USED TO BE
REALLY DIVERSE,
AND I'LL SHOW YOU SOME ANCIENT LYCOPHYTES
IN A MOMENT. BACK IN
THE CARBONIFEROUS PERIOD, IN THE PALEOZOIC
THEY WERE REALLY BIG
TREES. NOW THEY'RE JUST SMALL PLANTS THAT,
YOU KNOW, DON'T
TYPICALLY GET MORE THAN ABOUT YEA BIG. SO
THAT'S A, IT'S NOT A
PARTICULARLY CONSPICUOUS GROUP OF PLANTS EVEN
THOUGH THEY'RE
FOUND FROM TROPICAL TO TEMPERATE ENVIRONMENTS.
OKAY, THE FERNS
AND RELATIVES ARE MUCH MORE DIVERSE. THERE
ARE ABOUT 12,000
SPECIES OF THESE. ABOUT TEN TIMES MORE THAN
THERE ARE OF THE
LYCOPHYTES. AND PROBABLY A LOT OF UNDESCRIBED
DIVERSITY TOO.
NOW WE SINGLE OUT THE HORSETAILS HERE AND
THE WHISK FERNS HERE
BECAUSE IT WAS ONLY FAIRLY RECENTLY, WITHIN
THE LAST TEN, 15
YEARS THAT IT WAS REALIZED THAT THESE ARE
NOT, THAT THESE ARE
ACTUALLY FERNS. THESE DON'T LOOK TOO FERN-LIKE.
THEIR STEMS,
THEY HAVE AERIAL STEMS THAT ARE PHOTOSYNTHETIC
AND IMPREGNATED
WITH SILICA, THE HORSETAILS. THESE WHORLED
BRANCHES, WITH MINI
BRANCHES THAT ARE NODE, IT'S A VERY BIZARRE
LOOKING PLANT.
THERE ARE ONLY ABOUT A DOZEN SPECIES WORLDWIDE.
BUT THEY'RE WIDE
SPREAD IN NORTHERN TEMPERATE AREAS. IN ANY
CASE, THIS IS A GROUP
THAT WAS THOUGHT TO REPRESENT A COMPLETELY
DIFFERENT LINEAGE, BUT
IN FACT TURNS OUT TO BE A FERN GROUP. AND
THIS THING MAY LOOK
FAMILIAR AS SIMILAR TO THAT EARLIEST VASCULAR
PLANT THAT I SHOWED
YOU WITH THAT Y-SHAPED BRANCHING AND AND NO
LEAVES. AND IT
DOESN'T HAVE ROOTS EITHER. IT'S ONE OF THE
FEW VASCULAR PLANTS
THAT DOESN'T HAVE ROOTS. AND IT WAS THOUGHT
TO BE ONE OF THE
LAST SURVIVING REMNANTS OF THAT EARLIEST GROUP
OF VASCULAR PLANTS
UNTIL MOLECULAR DATA CAME ALONG AND SHOWED
THAT IT'S JUST A
HIGHLY MODIFIED FERN. SO THE GUY THAT ACTUALLY
USED TO PUSH THE
IDEA THAT THIS WAS THE LAST OF THE RHYNIOPHYTES
WHEN HE, HE WAS
ACTUALLY PRESENT WHEN THE MOLECULAR DATA WERE
PRESENTED SHOWING
THAT THE WHISK FERNS ARE FERNS AND NOT ANCIENT
RHYNIOPHYTES.
AND HE STOOD UP AND SAID, YOU KNOW HE WAS
AN OLD MAN AT POINT
POINT, HE STOOD UP AND SAID, YOU JUST RUINED
MY LIFE, YOU KNOW,
TO THE GUY THAT MADE THAT FINDING. SO IT WAS
A PRETTY DRAMATIC
MOMENT AND, FOR THE SPEAKER WHO WAS JUST A
YOUNG GRADUATE
STUDENT. AND THE GUY THAT SAID THAT, YOU KNOW
THAT HE WRECKED
HIS LIFE, WAS ONE OF THE, WAS CONSIDERED THE
WORLD AUTHORITY ON
SEEDLESS VASCULAR PLANTS. OKAY, SO THE LIFE
CYCLE OF FERNS --
YEAH, SO BASICALLY YOU CAN'T GET TOO ATTACHED
TO YOUR IDEAS IN
SCIENCE. THEY'RE ALWAYS SUBJECT TO BEING OVERTURNED
WITH
ADDITIONAL DATA. SO LIFE CYCLE OF FERNS IS
SIMILAR TO WHAT WE
SAW IN THE MOSSES. BUT AS I MENTIONED THE
HAPLOID GENERATION IS
RELATIVELY REDUCED, AND THE SPOROPHYTE GENERATION
IS DOMINANT IN
TERMS OF BEING THE, THE CONSPICUOUS AND TYPICALLY
MUCH MORE
LONG-LIVED ORGANISM. HERE YOU CAN SEE THE
SPOROPHYTE GENERATION
IN THE LOWER HALF. THE HAPLOID GENERATION
IN THE UPPER HALF.
SO AGAIN, MEIOSIS RESULTING IN SPORES, HAPLOID
SPORES. AND HERE
YOU CAN SEE A TYPICAL FERN GAMETOPHYTE. AND
THIS IS USUALLY AN
EXTREMELY TINY ORGANISM THAT YOU WOULD EASILY
OVERLOOK UNLESS
YOU'RE DOWN ON YOUR HANDS AND KNEES DIGGING
AROUND IN THE SOIL.
AND OFTENTIMES THE FERN GAMETOPHYTE IS HEART-SHAPED
LIKE THIS.
THAT'S NOT ALWAYS TRUE. AND THEY'RE OFTEN
PHOTOSYNTHETIC. SOME
OF THEM ARE ACTUALLY FOUND UNDERGROUND AND
THEY DON'T
PHOTOSYNTHESIZE AT ALL. THEY'RE IN ASSOCIATION
WITH MYCORRHIZAL
FUNGI THAT I MENTIONED EARLIER AND GAIN THEIR
NUTRITION THAT WAY.
BUT THEY'RE TINY ORGANISMS. BUT THEY DO PRODUCE
GAMETANGIA.
AND THEY'RE COMMONLY IN THE CASE OF FERNS,
THEY'RE COMMONLY
BISEXUAL OR HERMAPHRODITIC, PRODUCING BOTH
ANTHERIDIA, THE MALE
GAMETANGIUM OR ARCHEGONIA, THE FEMALE GAMETANGIA.
SO WE HAVE
SPERM WHICH, AND AGAIN IN THE FERNS, EVEN
THOUGH THIS IS A REALLY
WIDELY, WIDESPREAD AND DIVERSE GROUP OF PLANTS,
THEY HAVE
FREE-SWIMMING SPERM. THE SPERM HAVE TO SWIM
THROUGH THE OPEN
ENVIRONMENT TO THE NECK OF THE ARCHEGONIUM
AND SWIM DOWN THE NECK
CANAL TO THE, THE CANAL DOWN TO THE EGG AND
FERTILIZE THE EGG.
NOW THERE ARE FERNS THAT YOU FIND IN DESERT
ENVIRONMENTS. AND
SOME OF THESE ARE DESICCATION TOLERANT. THEIR
LEAVES CAN TRY
UP. IN FACT, THAT'S COMMON IN FERNS THAT OCCUR
IN DESERT-LIKE
ENVIRONMENTS. BUT IN GENERAL THOSE DESERT
FERNS ARE STRICTLY
ASEXUAL IN THEIR REPRODUCTION. THIS IS A REALLY
LIMITING BIOLOGY
FOR BEING ABLE TO HAVE SEXUAL REPRODUCTION
IN DRY ENVIRONMENTS.
OKAY, SO THEN WE HAVE FERTILIZATION DOWN INSIDE
THE ARCHEGONIUM
AGAIN LIKE IN THE MOSSES. WE GET A DEVELOPMENT
OF AN EMBRYO
AGAIN. AND HERE'S THE YOUNG SPOROPHYTE, GERMINATING
OUT OF THE
ARCHEGONIUM. AND IT'S ACTUALLY PARASITIC ON
THE GAMETOPHYTE
INITIALLY. BUT THAT DOESN'T LAST LONG. IT
DEVELOPS ITS OWN
ROOT SYSTEM. THE GAMETOPHYTE DOESN'T HAVE
A ROOT ASSIGNMENT.
IT JUST HAS RHIZOIDS, THESE FILAMENTS OF CELLS
THAT ASSOCIATE
WITH THE UPPER SUBSTRATE BUT ARE NOT REALLY
PARTICULARLY
IMPORTANT IN CONDUCTION. BUT THE SPOROPHYTE
DOES HAVE A GOOD
ROOT SYSTEM AS YOU CAN SEE HERE. AND THE SPOROPHYTE
OF FERNS
TYPICALLY HAS ITS STEM UNDERGROUND AS A HORIZONTAL
STEM OR A
RHIZOME. A RHIZOME IS JUST A HORIZONTAL UNDERGROUND
STEM. AND
STEMS PRODUCE LEAVES AS WELL AS IN THIS CASE
ADVENTITIOUS ROOTS
OR ROOTS THAT FORM WHERE THEY NORMALLY WOULDN'T
FROM THE SIDE OF
THE STEM. AND THE LEAVES EMERGE FROM THE GROUND.
AND THE MAIN
FERN BODY THAT WE SEE ABOVE GROUND ARE THE
LEAVES TYPICALLY.
THERE ARE SOME TREE FERNS THAT PRODUCE LONG
STEMS, AERIAL STEMS
THAT CAN GET UP TO SEVERAL METERS IN HEIGHT,
BUT THEY'RE A
MINORITY OF THE FERNS. AND ALSO THERE ARE
THOSE HORSETAILS I
MENTIONED WHICH HAVE AERIAL STEMS THAT ARE
PRETTY BIZARRE THINGS
THAT WERE ONLY RECENTLY RECOGNIZED AS FERNS.
NOW THE SPORANGIA
OF FERNS ARE TYPICALLY, BUT NOT ALWAYS, BUT
TYPICALLY ON THE
UNDERSIDE OF THE LEAF. OR SHELTERED ON THE
UNDERSIDE OF THE
LEAF IN THESE LITTLE CLUSTERS CALLED SORI.
SINGULAR WOULD BE A
SORUS. HERE'S JUST ONE OF SPORANGIA ASSOCIATED
WITH EACH ONE OF
THE SORI. AND IN FERNS THERE'S OFTEN A MECHANISM
THAT ALLOWS FOR
FORCEFUL EJECTION OF THE, OF THE SPORES. AND
MOST FERNS HAVE
THIS CATAPULT-LIKE EJECTION SYSTEM WHERE THE
SPORANGIUM BURSTS
OPEN IN A PARTICULAR WAY AS IT DRIES OUT AND
IT FORCEFULLY
CATAPULTS THESE SPORES. SO THE SPORES ARE
EJECTED AWAY FROM
THE, THE PARENT PLANT. SO THAT'S A NICE DISPERSAL
MECHANISM.
AND HERE YOU CAN SEE THE UNDERSIDE OF A FERN
LEAF. THIS IS A
SWORD FERN WHICH YOU FIND OUT IN REDWOOD FORESTS,
UNDERSTORIES
TYPICALLY. AND HERE YOU CAN SEE INDIVIDUAL
SORI, THESE CIRCULAR
LITTLE BROWN STRUCTURES. HERE'S ONE OF THOSE
ENLARGED. AND YOU
CAN SEE EACH ONE OF THEM IS ASSOCIATED WITH
LARGE NUMBERS OF
SPORANGIA, SO THIS, FOR EXAMPLE, IS A SPORANGIUM,
NOT A SPORE.
EACH ONE OF THESE CONTAINS DOZENS OF SPORES.
SO THERE ARE A
LARGE NUMBER OF SPORES ASSOCIATED WITH EACH
ONE OF THESE
SPORANGIA. IT'S PROTECTED SOMETIMES BY A SHIELD-LIKE
STRUCTURE
HERE WHICH IS AN INDUSIUM. NOT ALL FERNS HAVE
THIS. BUT IT
SERVES TO PROTECT THE DEVELOPING SPORANGIA.
AND IT WITHERS AWAY
WHEN THE SPORES ARE READY TO DISPERSE. IT
GETS OUT OF THE WAY
OF THE DISPERSAL MECHANISM. SO THE SHAPE AND
SIZE AND LOCATION
OF THESE SO-CALLED SORI IS DIAGNOSTIC FOR
DIFFERENT TAXA OF
FERNS. SO THIS IS SOMETHING THAT IF YOU WANT
TO IDENTIFY FERNS,
YOU USUALLY ARE HAVING TO LOOK FOR THEIR SPORANGIA
AND HOW
THEY'RE ARRANGED ON THE LEAVES. OKAY, SO,
WE'RE AT THE POINT
NOW WHERE IT'S REALLY IMPORTANT TO INTRODUCE
THIS CONCEPT OF
HETEROSPORY WHICH JUST MEANS BASICALLY OTHER
SPORES, WHERE
THERE'S MORE THAN ONE TYPE OF SPORE AS OPPOSED
TO HOMOSPORY WHERE
THERE'S ONLY ONE TYPE OF SPORE. AND THE FERN
THAT WE JUST LOOKED
AT, THAT LIFE CYCLE IS HOMOSPOROUS. REMEMBER
THERE WAS JUST ONE
TYPE OF SPORE THAT GAVE RISE TO ONE TYPE OF
GAMETOPHYTE THAT BORE
BOTH TYPES OF GAMETANGIA, BOTH, IT PRODUCED
BOTH SPERM AND EGGS
ON THE SAME INDIVIDUAL. I SHOULD MENTION THAT
FERNS HAVE
DIFFERENTIAL TIMING OF SPERM PRODUCTION AND
EGG PRODUCTION ON THE
SAME GAMETOPHYTE THAT TENDS TO LIMIT SELFING.
OTHERWISE THERE'D
BE POTENTIALLY A LOT OF INBREEDING. BUT THERE
ARE A LOT OF
PLANTS THAT HAVE UNISEXUAL GAMETOPHYTES. AND
I SHOWED YOU A
CASE OF A MOSS THAT DID THAT. IN THE CASE
OF MOSSES WE DON'T
HAVE REALLY DISTINCTIVE SPORE SIZE DIFFERENCES
LIKE WE SEE IN THE
VASCULAR PLANTS. FOR EXAMPLE, SELAGINELLA
SHOWN HERE WHERE WE
HAVE HETEROSPORY, LEADING TO UNISEXUAL GAMETOPHYTES.
THOUGH
SOME OF THE LYCOPHYTES AND A MINORITY OF THE
FERNS, NAMELY THE
WATER FERNS, PRODUCE TWO TYPES OF SPORES.
THIS IS ACTUALLY A
LYCOPHYTE CONE THAT'S BEEN SLICED DOWN THE
MIDDLE LONGITUDINALLY,
RIGHT THROUGH THE MIDDLE OF THE SPORANGIA
HERE. ON ONE SIDE
IT'S PRODUCING MICROSPORANGIA WITH ONE TYPE
OF SPORE, THE
MICROSPORES. AND ON THE OTHER SIDE IT'S PRODUCING
MEGASPORANGIA
WITH MEGASPORES WHICH ARE LARGER OBVIOUSLY.
YOU CAN SEE THERE'S
ONLY FOUR PRODUCTS OF MEIOSIS IN ONE OF THESE.
THE FOUR PRODUCTS
OF MEIOSIS ARE THE ONLY SPORES IN ONE OF THESE
SPORANGIA WHEREAS
THERE ARE LARGE NUMBERS OF MICROSPORES HERE.
THOUGH THE
MICROSPORES GERMINATE TO BECOME MALE GAMETOPHYTES
THAT PRODUCE
SPERM, THE MEGASPORES GERMINATE TO BECOME
MEGAGAMETOPHYTES,
FEMALE GAMETOPHYTES THAT PRODUCE EGGS. AND
THAT'S WHAT I'VE
INDICATED HERE. THE HOMOSPORY, THE PRESENCE
OF ONE TYPE OF
SPORE, IS ANCESTRAL IN BOTH THE LYCOPHYTES
AND THE FERNS. AND
HETEROSPORY IS DERIVED IN BOTH GROUPS INDEPENDENTLY.
AND IN
BOTH CASES WHAT WE SEE IS THAT THE GAMETOPHYTES
THAT DEVELOP FROM
THESE DIFFERENT SPORES HAVE ALL OF THEIR DEVELOPMENT
OCCURRING
INSIDE THE SPORE WALL. SO THEY'RE PROTECTED
INSIDE THE SPORE
WALL. AND IT'S ONLY LATE IN THEIR DEVELOPMENT
THAT THEY EMERGE
FROM THE SPORE WALL. SO THERE'S SOME ADDITIONAL
PROTECTION
AFFORDED THESE HETEROSPOROUS GAMETOPHYTES
IN BOTH THE FERNS AND
THE, THE LYCOPHYTES. THOUGH HETEROSPORY MAY
HAVE ARISEN IN PART
AS A MEANS OF PROMOTING OUTCROSSING BECAUSE
YOU CAN'T SELF WITH
YOURSELF OBVIOUSLY IF YOU'RE ONLY PRODUCING
ONE TYPE OF GAMETE.
BUT IT ALSO MAY HAVE BEEN IMPORTANT FOR PROTECTION
OF THE
GAMETOPHYE GENERATION, THAT VULNERABLE GAMETOPHYTE
GENERATION MAY
BE MORE READILY PROTECTED IN THESE PARTICULAR
TYPE, IN THESE
HETEROSPOROUS LIFE CYCLE. AND WE'LL SEE THIS
TAKEN TO A REAL
EXTREME IN THE SEED PLANTS. AND THAT'S WHY
I'M BOTHERING TO
MENTION IT. IT MIGHT SEEM LIKE AN ESOTERIC
ASIDE RIGHT NOW, BUT
THE SEED PLANTS, ALL OF THEM ARE HETEROSPOROUS,
AND THE EVOLUTION
OF THE SEED WAS, WAS POSSIBLE BECAUSE OF HETEROSPORY.
THOUGH
GETTING BACK TO THE LYCOPHYTES AND FERNS,
EVEN THOUGH TODAY
THEY'RE FAIRLY LOW STATURE PLANTS FOR THE
MOST PART, IF WE GO
BACK TO THE TIME WHEN THE SEED PLANTS WERE
JUST BEGINNING TO
EVOLVE, BACK IN THE LATE PALEOZOIC, ABOUT
300 TO 350 MILLION
YEARS AGO, THE LYCOPHYTES WERE ABSOLUTELY
IMMENSE. HERE'S A
6-FOOT TALL PERSON FOR COMPARISON. HERE'S
A TREE LYCOPHYTE.
AND HERE'S A HORSETAIL, BASICALLY A TREE HORSETAIL.
AND THESE
THINGS DOMINATED THE SO-CALLED COAL FORESTS
OF THE CARBONIFEROUS,
WHICH ARE THE BASIS FOR OUR EXTENSIVE COAL
DEPOSITS WORLDWIDE.
AND THIS WAS A TIME WHEN THERE WAS VERY LOW
TOPOGRAPHY ON EARTH
FOR THE MOST PART. AND TEMPERATURES AT THE
BEGINNING OF THIS
PERIOD WERE VERY WARM AND WET. AND THERE WERE
BOGGY
ENVIRONMENTS WHERE FOSSILIZATION WOULD HAVE
BEEN PROMOTED. ALSO
THESE TREE LYCOPHYTES AND TREE FERNS HAD A
LOT OF LIGNIN IN THEIR
TISSUES WHICH IS ALSO FOUND IN WOOD. BUT PRIMARILY
IN THEIR
BARK, THEY DIDN'T HAVE VERY MUCH WOOD. AND
THIS ALLOWED THEM TO
FOSSILIZE EASILY BECAUSE LIGNIN'S VERY DIFFICULT
TO DECOMPOSE AND
THERE MAY NOT HAVE EVEN BEEN THE APPROPRIATE
DECOMPOSERS AT THIS
TIME. OKAY, SO WE'LL GET INTO SEED PLANTS
NEXT TIME. AND
YOU'LL START TO SEE THESE IN LAB THIS WEEK.