Sherlock Holmes - Full Movie Released Winter [2011]
FREE on Anton Pictures YouTube Channel
God's Game - Full Movie - Comedy Mockumetary
FREE on Anton Pictures youTube Channel
Director of Photography
George Anton
BORN INTO MAFIA
Directed by Vitaliy Versace
Singer..Don't speak to me, Is so hard to resist
when you talk to me
Don't reach for me
I know that you care, but when it comes up
to loving, you are unaware
Don't you know you are a perfect drug
Inside drives me blind
with one look from you
Hi Dad.
Hi son, you're here.
I told you I will be here.
Is that the same woman that I saw at
our house last night?
Yes, That's her.
She thinks she's in love with me.
Don't you know you are the perfect drug.
Are you serious? Isn't she to young for you
dad?
That's enough Ivan. I did not asked you here
for that.
And what that would be?
If you stop with the sarcasm, we can get to
the point.
there are two things I need you to do for
me.
What is it?
Ivan, I don't know what got into you in the
last few months. You are totally different
person, and is not good.
I have this friend and i want you to go talk
with her. Maybe she can help.
You are sending me to a shrink?
She is not a shrink, she is a very educated
woman. She is the best pshichologist in Moscow.
She is very good.
But I don't have any problems. Why would I
need a shrink?
Oh yes you do. I need you to stay focused.
Not to do things that are below your station.
Soon you will be my replacement.
You need to act like it.
Fine I will go and see your highly recommended
shrink. It won't change anything.
What else do you want from me?
I won't do it!
Yes you are!
(applause)
Hi honey. What is wrong? You look worried.
It is Ivan. He is changing by the minute.
I don't know what to do about it.
He does not seem like he cares.
I'm worried about him.
Oh, I wish I could help.
He is a story
Enough with my words. Tell me how have you
been doing?
Oh, I don't have enough words to tell you.
It's
I'm so grateful for everything that you did
for me Alex. It is also wonderful.
I didn't even dream that one day I will be
sitting in one of the most expensive restaurants.
My pleasure.
Give my beautiful lady a drink.
Yes Sir, What can I get you madam?
Same thing like Alex is having.
Yes madam, I'll get it right away.
Thank You.
You are welcome.
Hi Ivan. Have a sit. How are you doing today?
Good. Thank You.
Ivan, I worked with a lot of people that worked
with your father.
They all have problems. They all can't sleep
and they come to me because they have problems.
Whatever I have said in this room, Whatever
they said in this room, stays in this room.
So don't be afraid to open up and tell me
what is bothering you.
Oh, I'm not afraid.
Ivan. Your father told me you are believing
in God and you talk to God? Do you want to
tell me a little bit about it?
What's so hard to understand that i believe
in God. What's wrong with you people?
Are you feeling angry Ivan?
No. I'm not angry.
Do you want to talk about your feelings?
Oh, do you want to know how I feel? I feel
like I want to run. I want to run away and
never come back.
Ivan. You have everything. Everything that
a kid can wish for.
Maybe you are right. I have everything, except
that I don't have love. My father is killing
people, you know that, and you feel so calm.
Ivan, just .. Let's make appointment for next
week.
I won't see you next week.
I'm moving to United States. I want to start
a new life.
Hey, hey Ivan
Here is the book you are looking for man.
Thank you Sergei.
You are a good friend Sergei.
Of course man.
Friends forever.
Forever man.
We know each other since we were kids man.
Yeah, that's why I have to tell you something.
Something important.
Tell me what.
I'm tired of this Mafia. Is not for me.
So what are you gonna do? How are you gone
get out of this?
I'm moving to United States.
Are you crazy? Your father won't let you do
this in a million years.
If he is not gonna allow me, I'm just gonna
run.
I wonder if you can pull this off. You know,
I was wondering about the same thing too.
Come with me then. Let's go together to America.
That would be so great. Move to America. Get
a new place. Florida maybe!
I have something better!
What?
Hollywood.
Wow, Sunny California!
maybe we can see some movie stars there too.
I have friends there, we can stay at Jacob's
house.
Who is Jacob?
He is a kid I have met online. He is a good
guy.
He invited me over at his house.
You know what man? Let's do it.
Let's do it.
I asked you to take care of that situation
for you and you let me down.
I'm not like you. I can't just pull the trigger
and kill somebody for $5000, I'm not going
to do it.
I built up this whole business, my whole life
for you. For you!
And you are just gonna live me like this?
I did not ask for. Because of your business,
mom is dead. Died!
I don't have a mom. I just have a dad who's
too busy killing people, not hug his son or
love his family.
I'm sick of this. I don't want to do this.
Why are you bringing up this old stuff. This
is got nothing to do with anything.
I sent you to the best schools in Moscow.
I gave you the best education you could possibly
get.
You've done everything you wanted. You've
done everything you wanted to to.
All I asked is to help me out in a situation
but you wouldn't even do that.
Is not the help, is just to shoot somebody,
come on. I know you do this for whole your
life, I just can't go and shoot somebody.
Is just crazy.
You know two years ago I found God. I'm going
every Sunday to Church.
I'm praying. I'm happy. Why do you want me
to kill somebody. This is crazy. You use keep
doing your thing if you think is right.
I'm just gonna.. just do your business
I'm not gonna do this. I'm gonna stay away
from this.
This business is taking you to Los Angeles.
From where do you think you get all the money
from? Do you think it just grows on trees?
I did not ask for this. I did not ask for
you, I did not ask for mom, I'm your son and
..
is just crazy, it just happened this. My mother
died because of this shit and rest of the
stuff, you know?
I can't deal with this, you know? Mom told
me, I never told you this, but Mom told me
before when I was a kid.
I still remember when I was 10 years old.
She told me, she was praying with me one night
and she told me.
"I hope you are not gonna grow up like your
Dad." I'm not gonna be like you.
I'll be something different like a Doctor
or a Lawyer. Something that people used to
look up to and say:
"That's a good man, he is helping people.
Not shooting people." Unbelievable.
This business is our life. Ok? You were groomed
to take over the family business.
I don't have anybody else I can come on. I
can't count on my brother. i don't trust him
too. He is doing some crazy stuff behind your
back.
I see him with different people from different
groups of the town. Your competitors in this
thing. i don't like him too.
I don't like what you guys do, but I'm not
gonna mix in this and not gonna tell you what
to do.
Is just You know who to trust, just don't
count on me. I'm not gonna do it.
I can not trust my brother. You are the only
one I can trust. This is when i need you most.
I ned you now. I don't need you in Los Angeles.
I'm not gonna do it Dad, If you want to pull
the gun and shoot me right here. I'm not gonna
do it.
Bible and God said DON"T KILL. I'm not gonna
kill anybody for money. Is not good.
My brother, he is a scumbag. Is nobody I can
trust but you. I need you watching my back.
Do you know how many times a day somebody
tries to kill me?
Dad, that's why i told you to live this business
and start something else, retire and give
up this.
He has been with you 15 years in this business.
Twenty, I don't even know.
He doesn't have a problem to shoot somebody.
You need that kind of people. You don't need
somebody like me who can't even shoot a guy.
Retire! You don't just retire. You don't just
get out of this, just say "I'm done and that's
it." It doesn't work like that.
That's why I don't want to jump in. Because
if I jump in, there is no way out.
I want normal family, I want normal life.
I want to have wife, children, drive safe.
Not thinking somebody is going to kill me.
But you are already in. You can't get out.
You can't back out now. You are past that
point of no return. This is it. Ivan!
This is it! This is the life. This is what
you were born into.
This is what i groomed you for all these years.
You can do this. I need you. Please. Tell
me you will stay.
Dad. I'm just gonna run away from Russia,
just go somewhere and start a new life.
Hopefully nobody is gonna find me somewhere
and I'm gonna be happy and not hear again
about this Mafia thing.
Stop the car. I'l walk from here.
Are you sure?
Yeah, I'm sure. I'll call you sometimes.
Tom, LA. Tom, how are you? Listen.
My son is flying to LA tomorrow.
Can you look after him? Thank you.
I knew I can count on you.
Sergei! Sergei
YOU ARE NOT GOING TO AMERICA
Told you not to bother me. I need some time alone.
I know Sir. It's your brother.
He is here to see you.
What do you want Demitry? I'm not exactly
in the mood to talk with you right now.
Would you like something?
Ivan plane just took off.
I know that. Is there anything else?
Actually no. How could you?!
What?
Do you want Ivan to take over your place?
He is my son. What did you expect?
I work for you for over 15 years and this
is how you repay?
Oh, please. You really didn't expect me to
give you my empire, did you?
But Ivan he couldn't even kill a fly. Why
do you expect him to take over your business?
Huh? He is a coward. Don't you see that?
Don't talk about my son like that, or I'll
kill you!
That's why I'm here. To take what was mine
long time ago.
This!
-screaming-
Don't be stupid guys. I'm in charge here now.
Hey, do you want to go to the airport?
Why, what's at the airport?
Do you remember the russian guy I've met,
like, two months ago on the internet?
Yeah, what about him?
He is coming into town.
What is your mom going to say about this?
Hey, she is cool. She said he can move with us.
Dog, are you coming or what?
Ok, allright.
Let's go.
So where is this russian friend of yours anyway?
Just be cool. He will be here any minute.
Alright?
So we are just gonna stand here and wait all
day or what?
He is coming, just be cool.
Why do you have to be like that? Dude? You
have such an attitude.
Sorry man.
Here he comes, right there.
Nice to meet you.
So how is the LA. It is awesome.
Look at the weather.
So we get your luggage?
I don't have a luggage.
A russian with no luggage.
What are the chances of that.
Hold on second. I see somebody who
Hello Ivan, my name is Tom. Your father called
me and ask me to help you out for a few days.
I'm sorry I couldn't get you
a car in such short notice.
Here are the keys to my car.
You can use it for a few days.
There are enough money in
the trunk to cover all the expenses.
So who is that guy?
I don't know.
All right, thanks.
You got it.
Hey guys, I've got a car.
Are you going to get your car?
I'm just gonna live my car here man.
Are you sure? Let's go.
So drive .. watch the stuff!. there are
people in there man!
Mrs Marshal.
Mom, this is Ivan.
Oh, Hi Ivan. Welcome to America. I know you
are going to enjoy staying in our home.
Let's all have some tea.
I'll get the tea.
Demitry, is jake. Yeah. LA. I know. I understand
Sir. We're doing the best we can.
How was your flight? That was pretty long
huh? Yeah, it was 14 hours long.
Is it cold out here all the time. No man,
it is not just like in the movies. Is same
thing like in USA, you know.
We have winter, we have four seasons basically.
Yeah.
What's the temperature?
Well, right now is cold man, it's i think
20 degrees below zero.
But because is January man. Same thing like
in NYC. Basically where I grew up is same
thing like in New York city.
Wow, I only have spring clothes and summer
clothes so yeah
Somebody has to take you shopping, maybe my
son Hehehehe
I  understand. I know.. You don't need
to come here. I'll handle this. I want to
be a part of the family. I can handle this.
We don't know where Ivan is yet.
Do you have a sister or something?
No man, I'm the only son. My mom died when
I was ten. My dad has his own crazy business
and I'm not into supporting so I kinda
of walked away.
I did not know your mother died.
Yeah, she died man. I was ten years old.
That sucks.
But we are working .. We have a lead You
don't need to come out here Sir,  I understand.
I unders.. I'll
That's why I'm kid of jealous man. You have
a good mom and is cool.
You don't have to be jealous! There is enough
of me to go around.
Thank you. Yeah, she is like the neighborhood
mom. All my friends come one, hang out, kick
it.
It's cool. Thank you for letting him.. let
me stay here with you guys. I appreciate that.
I know I met you just for two months online
and it was really col.
i was basically having a bad day, and i went
online two months ago and I've met Jacob.
We had a short online conversation, he told
me about Hollywood, LA.
It's just I had to run away from all this
and start a new life.
I admire you for your courage.
Thank You.
I did not have a clue. I'd probably, no
I would've not had the courage to come so
far by myself.
But, you know.
I'll pick you up at the airpot Sir.  Until
you get here I'll. Hello?
I couldn't imagine, like, leaving the United
States to go live in another country, it's
just like, near, No  You now me like
not knowing what the area is, or  is kind
of scary.
Yeah, I took english in school so, I know
a little bit. I speak little bit english.
Is my first day in LA, in United States, It's
cool.
I'm glad that I understand you guys. If I
would start speaking Russian, nobody would
probably understand anything.
In school do you have to learn english? Or
is it like, you can take other language like
Spanish or something like that?
Same thing.
You have a choice, German, French or English.
I took English so, I just took English.
Did they encourage you to select English?
Yeah, because English is first language in
the world.
I was in a private school. My father has a
lot of money and connections. so I was
I just jot tied of that. I had the best education
basically. Is not about that. After my mom
died, I missed love.
It was not enough love from my dad, he was
always busy and that kind of stuff, so.
He got you that fat car?
That's my uncles.
That's actually Tom's car. He knows my father.
They used to do a lot of business together,
so. He is kind of, kind of like my dad so
I don't want anything from them
But for first days, couple days, I'll take
their help, but then I just wanna be independent.
I don't want anything of this, I just run
away from this but is keep following me.
Because of my dad's connection even in this
country, so is good.
Well, as long as you are in my household,
you've got a cool mom.
Thank You.
I told you she was cool.
Let me show you your room.
Thank You, the tea is good.
Smells good.
Oh, That's my home made vegetable soup. Come
on.
Look at that shit, he is getting her number.
He's been in LA for 5 hours, I've been here
for 5 months and I can't get a girl. That's
sad. ha ha ha ha
Dude she is hot! That's crazy!
He is one lucky son of a gun, that's all I
know.
I'll call you.
Got her number.
What's her name?
Celine.
Do you have to look at the paper?
Yeah. Come on dude. It just happen two seconds
ago. She's hot.
Let' go. I've got to call her.
Do you guys got a dollar?
Dude. Get a job.
What did he just say to you?
He mistakend me with somebody else.
Hi Celine. This is Ivan. Remember me?
Yes. From Russia.
I would like to take you out.
Tomorrow, at 11. That is perfect.
I'll see you tomorrow. Thank You
Bye Bye.
YES!
I'm sorry I'm late.
Thank you for going out with me.
You look beautiful. Thank You.
I see something special in you.
I see something special in your too.
Good, I like that.
So
What did you use to do in Paris?
I used to model.
For how long have you been in LA?
Six months.
What brought you to LA?
I just wanted to turn the page. Start a new
life.
That's funny, because that is why I came to
LA.
That's good.
Why do you think I'm so special?
I don't know, I feel like you are special,
like nobody else I know.
Beautiful, smart.
Thank You.
I'm just very happy that I've met you.
Me too.
Happy for us.
I had a good day.
Thank You. Me too. I'm happy that you enjoyed.
In long time I did not had such a good day.
Me too.
I enjoy you. Thank You. That means a lot to
me.
Oh, My, God
Hey, it is the guy from the airport.
Hey guys, where is Ivan at? He is out on a
date or something.
Oh shit!
What's going on?
His uncle killed his father so he can take
over the family business.
Now he wants Ivan dead too.
What's the family business?
He never mentioned it to you?
His father is the head of the Russian Mob.
What?! He never mentioned the Mafia!
I knew there was something fishy about him.
He did not say anything to me. Did he say
anything to you?
No, he didn't.
Look, we do not have time for this. We need
to find Ivan and we need to find him now.
He is in trouble.
What kind of trouble. I don't understand.
What is going on?
Let's find Ivan, let's find him now.
What are you talking Russian Mafia? Man, I
just want to play basketball. Don't get me
involved in this crap.
I'm not getting you involved.
I made a promise to his father a while back
I'll watch for him, and that's what I'm gonna
do.
Well, I don't know how that involves me, so
find Ivan yourself.
Look, Ivan's problem can become your problem,
real quick.
We need to really help him now. Don't be like
this. He is our friend.
The next time we see Ivan, he could be dead.
We need to find him now.
Get out of here. I'll keep them busy!
Call the police!
Looking for me?
Get your ass up!
Demitry, welcome to the States!
Don't screw around. This guy is crazy.
He is here to kill his nephew.
Do you think he's got a problem killing you?
I've made arrangements to get your clothes
and your choice of transportation.
So, what does it seem to be the problem here?
Why do I have to come out here
and take care of things myself?
Tony, get in the car!
Not in the front sit. Get in the back!
Where the hell do you find these guys?
What's wrong with you?
He is too dumb to pay him it any less. Yes...
So what's your plan?
My plan is  Well first of all I want to
explain myself to you.
We had a problem catching Ivan because Tom
was protecting him.
By who?
Tom.
I understand that you are upset
but we took care of Tom.
Tom was protecting them,
hiding them all over the city.
We have a guy in the back right here, that
might know where Ivan might be.
But he is not giving us the information.
He is not being friendly.
Let's tell him we don't have to friendly either
and let's get some information out of him.
All right. Let's go.
Have this stab on side.
Tony, give me your gun.
My gun?
Yes, your gun.
You are ready.
Please, today. Let's go.
By all means you came so far.
Show me how the russians do it.
Wakey, wakee. Do you know who we are.
Do you know what we're doing here.
Do you remember me?
I guess.
Listen to me. We are not playing around.
Listen to him!
Listen to me. We're here about your friend
Ivan.
Where is he?
I don't know!
You don't know?
Your friend Ivan. Where is he.
We saw you plying basketball with him
where is he?
I don't know.
Tony. One more time.
Do you see this gun at your throat? The last
thing you are going to hear
is me pulling the trigger. Where is he?
Your friend Ivan, you know what I'm talking about!
Do you like the air? Do you like the air to
clean up your brain? Do you hear me know?
A minute ago you did not know what is all
about, now you know. Look at that man right there.
Do you see him? See him? He came over
all the way from Russia to find you.
Now listen, I've seen you in the neighborhood
and I don't want to hurt you
Are you trying to say something to me?
I don't.
You don't what?
Point the gun?
Look at Him! See that man right there.
I didn't do anythin
He's from Moscow, he came here to find you,
but you want to talk with me.
Look at me. You're not gonna talk are you?
I don't know.
let me introduce you to my friend, Demitry.
Demitry!
I tried to save you kid but you don't want
to listen.
Just let me go.
So you're gonna tell us where Ivan is?
What's gonna be kid?
Do you want to get out of here alive?
He's staying at Jacob's, he's staying at Jacob's!
At Jacob's?
Yes.
Oh, why you just didn't say so.
So he's at jacob's huh?
Nice knowing you kid.
Wait, I thought you are going to let me go!
So do you know where to find this Jacob kid, right?
Jacob, jacob Hey Tony, jacob kid, the black kid.
The one you were chasing. The one he got away?
Yeah. Where is he?
Well, we have to find him.
Find him! I gave you the responsibility of
the address book. Where is he?
I don't know where he is.
It is very important as soon as you know where
Ivan is, I need to take care of it.
This is personal. Right?
All right man.
Go on the phone, call who you need.
We need to find that kid right now.
Listen, when we spoke on the phone last fall
you were suppose to be the man in LA. Take
care of everything. Every time you have a
problem, I can't come from Moscow all the
way here to make sure it is all OK.
You need to be in charge of that.
Alright, I'll take care of it.
I won't let you down.
I promised you, that you are going to have
a shot at it and I'm gonna keep my word.
But every time you have a little problem,
you need to be the man who solves these things
out.
OK. Thank You.
Tony. Let's go!
I missed you so much.
Thank you for coming.
You did not change yet. What happened.
No, I did not change yet. I didn't go home.
Listen, I know we didn't know each other that
long but i fell in love with you.
I feel like you are very special person. I'm
very happy that I've met you.
Last night I was thinking about you.
How beautiful you are, how good you smell
and beautiful lips and eyes and.. perfect,
you are perfect. I fell in love with you and
i have something for you.
I hope this is not gonna be a shock, but,
would you marry me?
Wow! This is a big surprise. I don't know
what to say, I mean, I love you too but
I barely met you.
I'll take that as a yes.
This is a beautiful ring.
It is a big surprise.
I love you.
I love you too.
Trying to run from me? I got you now Jacob!
Nice work!
What's wrong man?
What were my instructions?  What were
my instructions?!
We were suppose to get information and shoot
his ass.
What information did you get?
He wasn't gonna talk anyways.
He never had a chance because you
put a bullet in his brain
before he had a chance to say anything!
Just tell him something else happened alright.
We'll tell him that he tried something so
we had to put a bullet in his ass. It's done.
We can't go back. It's over.
You gonna want me to tell Demitry that? You
are going to tell him.
Fine. If I'll have to, I'll tell him
It is just It takes like  wow
I was expecting to come here, I was alone,
no friends and suddenly I've met you.
You are a great man and you know, I feel for
you and it's happy. It's something amazing
what happened to me.
I think, I think we are going to be very happy
family. We can have a good time together.
I think so too. I'm so happy. Where do you
think we will live?
I don't know. We will talk. As long as we
are happy, that's important.
I'm agreeing with you. It is just, you know.
I'm new here and everything is crazy. And
you know, I have to get used to everything.
Get it step by step. You know.
Me too. I've been in Los Angeles for two days,
but we're  i think this is the best.
You came from Paris, I came from Moscow and
we met and it is very cool.
Isn't that strange that we've met after
you know, you came more that 12 hours in the
plane, get here wow! It is something amazing.
It is the best thing, you know.
People are suppose to meet each other. Suppose
to meet people they love. It just happened
to us.
Surprised.
You kind of remind me of my mom. You look
beautiful and you are an awesome person.
I've never met anybody like you, so open.
We've got good time and is awesome.
This is the most important.
I think is great. I would like to meet your
family, maybe they will come here.
Because you know, if we wanna marry. You know.
Then.
I would like to know the members of your family,
most of your family. I think is important.
Yeah, met too. I don't have much family. My
mom died when I was ten and I have...
I have my dad left and he is in Moscow.
Maybe he will come. I think he will come when
he will find out I'm getting married.
I think he is gonna love you.
He is very busy with his job. I don't approve
what he is doing with his job. I think he
is gonna love you, as a daughter. He always
wanted a girl. I'm the only one son in the
family so to have a daughter. He is gonna
have a daughter. Beautiful.
Thank You. I'm sorry what happened to your
mom. You had to grow up alone with your father.
You don't have your grandma helping you.
I don't know, is just...
I'm sad when I hear that because, it wasn't
easy for you.
Yeah, you are right it wasn't easy. Maybe
this is why I've made this move so fast just
to get married because, I missed us for the
last 11 years. I'm 21 and you are 20 and we
are happy. So is really cool. I just have
basically, like I've got my mom back.
I've got with the person that I'll spend my
life with. That is more than mom.
I'e got the person that I will spend my life
with it.
Well, we are both young and hopefully we will
get along together well, because we need more
experience. But I'm so happy to be here, I
have only you here. It is amazing.
You are amazing. That's what happened to me.
I'm gonna pray to God that our marriage is
gonna last forever and we are going to spend
to death and die in the same day.
Wow! I hope so too, in the dame day!
1:00:00.799,1:00:03.069
You are going to have a good time.
I promise you. I'll treat you like a queen.
Uncle!
Ivan, are you alright? Your father asked me
if you are OK.
I'm OK, I'm gonna just use the restroom.
I'll ask Jacob's mom to make us some tea.
I don't think she is in any condition to fix
us tea.
Ivan what are you doing? Come back! I just
want to talk with you.
Celine!
Hey baby. I had a nightmare.
I'm sorry.
I dreamed that my uncle came from Moscow
and killed all my friends and killed you and we've
got married and...
So what's wrong that we've got married?
It is not that is just all my friends died,
and you...
Don't worry, I'm here.
I've got a call.
That's from Moscow.
Take it.
Hello. What?
What happened?
Somebody called me from Moscow. One of my
uncles said that my dad got shot two days
ago
What! I'm so sorry. Oh, poor you.
When I've got the news that my father died
is like my dream became alive.
Where is Tony? Who's Tony?
The guy from the airport.
That guy.
He took the Escalade to the shop.
Had to get fixed.
Can he handle that?
I don't know. He's gonna probably crush the
damn thing.
I'm out. Demitry,
What did you got?
Full house. Nobody is that lucky.
OK boys, that's enough.
Don't we have anything else to do?
Demitry, a little bit more poker
won't kill you. A little bit?
We're playing for one or two hours!
What else we're gonna do?
We have people to kill. Let't get to work.
Work? We don't work. We don't have jobs.
Our only job, is you.
Don't you ever speak to me like that.
Or what?
You are messing with the wrong person.
If I was you I would watch my back.
You are going to come to our country, my city,
and tell me what to do?
You guy, think I would give you a loaded gun?
Do you believe this guy? Call Tony.
Tony!  Yeah. Come on in.
We have a mess to clean.
Thank you Jake for not betraying me
and taking care of Demitry.
Are you kidding? It was fun.
Demitry thought he can come here
and tell us what to do?
But he was wrong.
Now I can see I can trust you Jake. I'm gonna
let you run the area that you wanted so bad.
So you are going to put me in charge of LA?
You deserve it. After Demitry took out Alexander,
we became independent.
Now nobody can tell us what to do.
Except for me.
Are you having a good time?
Yes, I am Jacob.
Baby, do you know what day is today?
It is our anniversary!
I can't believe I forgot about it.
I've got you something.
Oh, That is so sweet.
I love you baby.
Thank You for Watching
BORN INTO MAFIA
Subtitle Translation and
Adaptation
ANTON PICTURES
Please Subscribe