[MUSIC - ENDLESS BOOGIE,
"PACK YOUR BAGS"]
JEAN ADAMSON: We're Vinegar
Hill House.
This is Sam, one
of the owners.
I'm Jean.
We're going with Andrew from
the Rockaway Taco, Brian a
chef at the restaurant, and
Chris Parachini from Roberto's
over to Hotel Delmano
in Williamsburg.
It was part of my plan
to eventually
open up my own place.
Once this space became
available, just owning a
restaurant became what
I wanted to do.
We're going over there because
our friend, Zeb, is going to
hook us up with some oysters
and some nice cocktails.
I went to the French
Culinary Institute.
I moved here in '97
to do that.
And then worked at Tribeca
Grill, just to kind of get me
through school, because I was
going to school at night.
And then I started working
at Balthazar.
And I became a sous chef there
after about two years.
And then just kind of worked my
way through everything in
Keith McNally land.
Finally was at Freemans
and then here.
SAM BUFFA: Hey, what do you
guys want to drink?
JEAN ADAMSON: The
Tres Hombres.
Do you still have that?
ZEB STUART: Three amigos.
JEAN ADAMSON: Oh,
Three Amigos.
ZEB STUART: Yeah, it's
our house-- yeah,
you should get that.
SAM BUFFA: Should we
start with that?
ZEB STUART: It's a can
of beer, sangrita,
and a tequila shot.
It's nice.
SAM BUFFA: Yeah.
ZEB STUART: It's a very
fancy cocktail
SAM BUFFA: It's a very
fancy cocktail.
JEAN ADAMSON: My intention was
basically to bring some people
that had either been here at
the restaurant with us,
because Andrew Field from
Rockaway Taco, Chris Parachini
from Roberta's, had both
initially helped me out of
that time, when things were
bad before Brian got here.
SAM BUFFA: Cheers.
ANDREW FIELD: Cheers.
JEAN ADAMSON: I mean, the
restaurant was a fucking shit
show from the beginning.
We had one cook that had
never cooked before,
myself, and my mom.
Chris came over.
We started drinking at 7:30.
CHRIS PARACHINI: Got it done.
JEAN ADAMSON: And then
basically, six months into it,
I was like, I've got--
I need some help.
And I had a couple of
interviews, one with Brian.
And I knew, like, right when
he walked in the door.
I was like, [SNAPS],
that's it.
He's the one.
I asked him to make something
with coleslaw.
It was good.
-Wow.
ZEB STUART: He's going to
explain to us what we got
here.
-This is the Kumamoto.
It comes from California.
And this is the [INAUDIBLE]
from Washington state.
And you have Beausoleil
from New Brunswick.
And this [INAUDIBLE]
from Rhode Island.
-Nice.
Awesome.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
SAM BUFFA: Vinegar Hill is
like a five block by five
block little area where there's
no other restaurant.
ZEB STUART: You guys had
balls to do that.
You know what I mean ?
I thought about it, but I didn't
have the balls to open
a place there.
SAM BUFFA: Hard place to get
to, hard place to leave.
ZEB STUART: Hard to get
to, but hard to leave.
Hotel California.
SAM BUFFA: Yeah, exactly.
-We're going to Pies
'n' Thighs.
-I want to eat some chicken.
-Let's get some chicken.
JEAN ADAMSON: No, let's
get the big salad.
-I'll get the big
chicken salad.
JEAN ADAMSON: Don't bump
me with your dick.
Can we get just three fried
chicken boxes, two extra
biscuits, and all your sides.
One of all the sides.
-Done.
ANDREW FIELD: Cheers
to the pies.
-Cheers to the pies.
ANDREW FIELD: Pies and thighs.
-Cheers.
[MUSIC - ENDLESS BOOGIE]
SAM BUFFA: I was just trying
to keep up with the pace.
It's like, we're a restaurant in
Brooklyn, but you're doing
Manhattan numbers.
But I think in Manhattan, it's
the rent that kills you.
Like, right from the start, it's
the rent, and it's the
size of the space.
And then it's all the people
around you that are going to--
JEAN ADAMSON: It's not cool.
It's like, of course you can
get a space on Avenue A
between 1st and 2nd.
And then you just have
a space on Avenue A
between 1st and 2nd.
We have a space that's in a
beautiful neighborhood.
It's about creating that--
SAM BUFFA: Your own world.
JEAN ADAMSON: --your
own world.
And you can't do that
in Manhattan.
-Not anymore.
SAM BUFFA: No, we missed
that boat.
So we went out to Brooklyn.
JEAN ADAMSON: Originally, the
idea was that this was a place
made by hand with a
group of friends.
Kind of spinning off of
Woodstock, that kind of 1970's
communal vibe.
So that's where the oven
came into play.
We're like, OK, cool.
Let's make everything in
cast iron in the oven.
BRIAN LETH: I think first and
foremost, everything here is
always very satisfying.
People are coming here to eat
certain dishes they might have
read about, that are usually on
the menu in one permutation
or another.
And then as far as people in the
neighborhood, we try and
run specials pretty
frequently.
So there's usually something new
or something you might not
have seen before unless
you come here a
couple days a week.
JEAN ADAMSON: In that sense, it
was just kind of like the
food was just supposed to
be homey and comforting.
We have a couple of dishes of
mine that stay on the menu.
But Brian's always offset that
in a more technical way but
still have that seeming
comfort,
delicious vibe to them.
We're hippies, man.
ANDREW FIELD: But in the
newer [INAUDIBLE].
JEAN ADAMSON: Brian is a
sophisticated hippie.
ANDREW FIELD: We're all
sophisticated hippies.
SAM BUFFA: I think we should
take pie to go.
-Pie to go.
JEAN ADAMSON: We want chocolate
peanut butter,
concord grape--
-Sounds great.
JEAN ADAMSON: --and
sweet potato.
SAM BUFFA: We're going to
eat that in the car.
It's going to be awesome.
ANDREW FIELD: Let's
go make some pies.
Pizza.
JEAN ADAMSON: Oh my god, I'm
scared I hope I do good.
Everyone's in a pizza
cook off.
We have 40 pies we're making.
I'm making the the
[INAUDIBLE].
-What's that?
JEAN ADAMSON: Eye of the bull.
Ham, I think it's [INAUDIBLE].
My pizza is going
to be amazing!
It's a bunch of thing that I
don't know what they are.
ANDREW FIELD: Where are we?
-What is this?
JEAN ADAMSON: What
is this place?
ANDREW FIELD: What
JEAN ADAMSON: We're at
Vinegar Hill House.
Let's go.
ANDREW FIELD: All
right, let's go.
JEAN ADAMSON: We just
invited everybody.
We told the whole staff
to come back and--
BRIAN LETH: And bring
their friends.
JEAN ADAMSON: --bring
We just kind of wanted it to
just be like a bunch of
friends coming back, as if it
turned into a house party.
I've got to change.
-Change?
JEAN ADAMSON: Well yeah, I'm
not going to wear this.
We just wanted to do something
different, because we were
like, well, let's do something
that we don't normally make at
the restaurant.
Because Brian works here a ton,
and who wants to come
back here--
not that it's not delicious--
and eat a huge pork chop
or chicken or whatever.
And so we knew that those
guys were coming.
And they'd both had experience
in the oven.
And so we're like, let's
just bring that to
the table and see.
I thought that it turned out
really community based.
Everyone's doing everything.
And I thought it
was really fun.
Serve it with a steak knife.
Ooh, we need some crushed red.
Hey, go deliver this pizza
to that guy right there.
Chris Field, pizza number one.
[MUSIC - ENDLESS BOOGIE]
-Maybe we should get
Chris in there.
JEAN ADAMSON: Oh, Chris knows
he has to come in here.
-Chris, Chris, let's go man!
-Whoo!
-Can I have an egg on it?
My favorite.
-Yes.
-I volunteer to try that one.
JEAN ADAMSON: I want
to taste it.
-Cauliflower and onions
and parsley.
JEAN ADAMSON: It's
already cut.
-I don't eat pizza.
JEAN ADAMSON: What?
You don't eat pizza?
You're not an American.
-I'm not an American.
I'm an immigrant.
I'm not an immigrant.
ANDREW FIELD: Cauliflower
and onions.
Cauliflower and onions.
Get in there.
Grab it!
Yes!
See that?
Doesn't stand a chance!
SAM BUFFA: So we're back here
with Justin and Sammy, two of
the other partners here.
And Jean just made some pizza,
and we're going to have a pie.
JUSTIN GALLAGHER: Just going
to cut the whole thing up.
SAMMY STEWART: I already know
I'm going to be cheering for
Jean's pizza.
SAM BUFFA: Here's Jean's.
Awesome.
JEAN ADAMSON: I think it was a
shit show once we got back
here, but a pretty fun one.
Right?
BRIAN LETH: Yeah, it was nice.
JEAN ADAMSON: The shots
were good, too.
BRIAN LETH: Shots?
JEAN ADAMSON: I did
a couple shots.
BRIAN LETH: Oh.
JEAN ADAMSON: Anyway,
the point of the
whole thing, right?
Cheers.
-Cheers.
SAM BUFFA: Salud.
-Ride the wave.
-Ride the wave!
JEAN ADAMSON: Ride the wave!
[MUSIC - ENDLESS BOOGIE]