When you think about certain things, that
you usually don't think about, it may make
sense to you intellectually. But your habits
are established prior to the intellect, prior
to what you call logic and reason. And so
you have feelings about things, feelings and
pride, you know? Like my son was number 1
in his class and all that sorta thing, if
you study your irrelevant subjects, as a fashion
designer, or an interior decorater. or a lawyer,
it wouldn't make any difference to me. And
there was another 10 in his class, all know
nothing in his class, it wouldn't make very
much difference. What makes the difference
is whether or not you can relate, and whether
or not they read up on subjects the class
may not be interested in. I don't care if
you're a liberated female and you walk around
asking, your friends what they think of me
- they don't buy it at all - so you dumb
the view point, I would say you're a tremendous
insufficiency. And a lot of people go a lot
of places, and they sit down and they listen
to ideas, and they won't make a decision.
They'll turn to the person next to them and
say "what do you think of that guy?" you know?
and they forget it. And so a lot of people
are not habituated, to what you call 'think
for themselves,' or evaluate the system and
say "well I don't know enough about it -
I accept some of the things, and some things
I reject." So just remember that prior to
reading books on semantics, and Vedlesm, and
social phenomena, and social psychology, you
get habits established at home. Your brother,
your father, your dad, you have all those
things, and you have social habits. The guy
says "birthday card" you know - and you do
those things, and then you read all the books
on semantics and you go "what the hell's a
birthday card?" - "Happy new year?" - You
don't control the new year. You know - if
you sat up in a clowd and you arranged the
weather and the sea and the climate - and
then I'd know - you say "you're gunna have
a good new year," - he says "how's that?"
- you say "there's a batch of lenses back
there, and things you need - they're all back
there for you." That promises a better new
year. And then John says "you know there's
a lot of matt trucks in town, you can't know
that you're gunna have a happy new year."
You might. You might build something fantastic
with the lenses, so the glasses may snap and
and can blind you life. You can't know those
things. Alls you can know is under certain
conditions, and precautions, you can deminish
the possibility of accidents. But they are
with us, those things are with us. And so,
our earlier habits establish our emotional
set, and our emotional set is dominant, over
your knowledge of semantics, reason, problem
solving, in school - problem solving - you
know, you see 2 people in an argument, and
they're fighting, physically. Ya say - would
you move in and try to say - "listen you fellas,
ya know, why don't you sit and reason together?"
you know, "would you mind your own business?"
What would you do? And a person says - a person
writes down, well this is what I would do,
well actually, when you're involved with somebody,
emotionally, and somebody walks over and says
something, do you listen to what the other
person says objectively? Or do you tend to
take sides with the person you're familiar
with? and the person you know? Somehow, whenever
my kid got into an argument with somebody
else, he always seemed to be right. That's
what I mean, we have that kind of prejudice
condition in ourselves. And it takes a long
time to undo that. You have to have a set
about people, and it's a hard set to come
by. You can get along with people so long
as you get along with them, and in certain
areas you won't get along with them, and that's
a fact. And certain areas some people don't
want to change, because they can't afford
it emotionally. Is there anybody that doesn't
know what that means? They can't afford to
change emotionally. You know, if my girlfriend
put her arm around me, and I say "what's the
matter? You insecure?" You know, and if I
put my arm around her and she says "are you
insecure?" So you don't touch, even though
you want to touch, if you want to touch, "are
you insecure?" Do we put our arms around other
people, because they put their arms around
us and say "yes, I do feel that way" you know,
do we enquire this constant reassurance? And
I would say 1 measure of concern of another
person for any other person, is the services
they attend to render that other person. If
you were studying botany, and the guy that
liked you tried to facilitate that, and get
you the equipment you couldn't get and try
to - if you wanted to go in the other room
and paint, and the person will say "well,
you know, fine" and they sit here and they
read a book, but they don't bother you for
doing it. That would be more important to
me than putting your arms around one another,
it'd be much more important to share in that
general area. Is that locked? To me, it'd
be much more important to do that. But if
you did that, suppose you did that to a person,
suppose you were very extensional to the person,
but no sweet nothings, you'd lose contact
with that person, because their habits of
thought - in other words, if you - if a person
trips and falls, and you help them up, bandage
their knee, and then head off. They say "oh
thank you very much" - "I'm sure you'd do
the same for me, I don't need that" you know
- "there's something odd about that character."
And so, reading on semantics and then applying
at this kind of intellectual sanity, may not
come off right. You may see in the behavior
of other people that you're talking to, a
kind of an alien look. Do you know what I
mean? And they antagonise you, because here
you are trying to provide them with some information
that you feel may be relevant to their lifestyle.
And they turn around and say "that sounds
communist" or whatever the hell they say.
They say things like that "why don't you go
back to Russia?" Here the guy dropped a package
- "could you help me put everything together?"
He says "what are you a communist?" Ya see,
I see it in that sense. They can't always
put things together. And so the way they look
at you when you're talking to them, causes
what I thought you could call it 'unconscious
resentment' or what you would call, seemingly
just speak to the person and it seems to bounce
off their ears, they don't seem to understand,
and then you plead with them. Says "I didn't
mean anything harmful by that, I only attempted
to assist" - he says "I didn't ask you, mind
your own fucking business." Y'know. "What
are you interested in music?" - "What are
you? An FBI agent?" Y'know. They don't always
like to answer to other people. And so, a
lot of people are very private, and the reason
that they are is because, when you tell me
that your kid brother was in a mental institution
for 3 years - y'know - "I'm sorry to hear
that, is he well?" When I get mad at you
- a person says "you notice something occasionally?"
- "Her kid brother was in a hospital for
3 years," and I use it against you, and then
your friend says, "I didn't know your kid
was" - "how'd you find out?" - "Fresco" because
when I get mad at you, I might say, "not that
I've got anything against it, but her farther
was criminally insane. Murdered 9 children."
- "I knew that when she puts coffee down
on the table she shakes a little bit." So,
the point is, people that have any kind of
resentment against you, will notice that your
eyes buldge when somebody's talking. They
will see that. They see it. They have need
to see it. And so, being rational is a tough
project, you launch a batch of crap at people
John, hurl it out - then they go *fart sound*
and you say "I see." But if you say "try to
help the goddamn bastard and look what the
hell I get, he damages my car." That's looking
for justice. So what you're supposed to do
is just throw it out. "Women's lib? Oh shit,
y'know? How did this get here?" - y'know
- "how are you Fresco?" - "I don't like that
much liberation. Besides women are naturally
weaker." Ya know, the whole idea is that,
they don't want a package, they don't need
it. And also when a female picks up a gun
and hits a moving target continuously, y'know,
a guy says "A lot of male arm on her" - y'know
- it's not a god damn thing, not a god damn
thing. A female on the motorcycle in a barrel
is probably a lesbian - ya know what I mean?
You know, it's easier for them to understand.
To become liberated, the need a lot of shades
of grey, and even if a person is a lesbian,
so what? You know what I mean? Cause everybody,
everybody has a certain amount of dualistic
behavior. Sometimes I see a guy that I haven't
seen in a long time and I wanna put my arms
around him, I'm glad to see him. But I don't
wanna kiss his cheek because I wasn't brought
up in Turkey. My farther does that, he kisses
a guy on both cheeks and hugs - and they walk
around brothers - walking around with their
arms around eachother in Turkey. And they
weep, if a Turk hears that another guy had
a little trouble they take out their hankerchiefs
and they weep. And their political leaders
when they get up and make a speech, "we're
losing land and territory of Turkey" and they
weep, they really weep. And they weep like
that, and nobody looks at them as [unknown
word]. And this is a pattern. Now, infact
a lot of men that [unknown word] the junior
feelings about something, sometimes are conditioned
not to weep. But they weep in here, which
is pretty rough, sometimes it's better to
weep. Sometimes it's better to physically
weep. But it's a sign of weakness. See? And
you wouldn't rather scream it, if your brother
was run over by a matt truck. They would remember
that. See? If you don't seem to remember the
fact that you were very close to the person
and you couldn't handle it. You didn't any
tools for handling that situation emotionally.
Remember that people are not gunna sit back
and say you know I'd like to understand her
behavior from her point of view. Or his behavior
from his point of view. They don't do that.
Nor do they really Jacque, so whenever you
yack at people, you're yacking at them in
given culture, in the middle ages. And all
the reinforces are not in your hands. But
if you had a yacht, or something where you
hoard all those boys together to work with
and yelled, and said "hey, we're all going
out this Sunday." And say "gosh anybody that
can get a yacht like that has gotta be darn
smart." He says "what do you think?" You say
"well, I'm a member of the John Burts society"
Y'say "where can I get [unknown]? he's got
a yacht, he's got an [unknown], he must know
something." But here you are, you know, peddling
pencils on a corner and talking about the
insufficiency of congress. And they figured
"jesus christ, how come he's peddling pencils
on a corner?" You see? And so, the idea Joe
is that people don't want to listen. They
don't have any need for it, and you, or John
or me sometimes we don't symbolise anything
that they wouldn't want to look up to. They
do that with very famous people - "what kind
of coffee do you drink? How many cups of coffee
do you drink a day? Do you ever drink tea?
Do you have sleepless nights?" And so normal
people, try to get next to famous people,
or rich people, or important people, cause
they feel a little bit like get on, you know,
and they'll get in with that crowd, and get
the extensionality of that system. So here
you've got hell of a lot of insecure rats,
running round, trying to make contact with
rats that know where the pile of food is.
And the rat says "yeh! There's a pile of food!"
and the guy says "gee it's 800 feet high,
I haven't had anything to eat for 3 days."
A guy says "see that fence around the pile?
It's private property. There's also a proximaty
mechanism on the fence, with a security guard.
But an act of human kindness should be committed
most royal - the guy gives him a sandwich
or half a sandwich. So the idea in our culture
is that the rules of the game are set so that
male and female have antagonisms inherant
in the culture. Is there anybody disagrees
with that? The culture produces automatically,
those antagonistic feelings. And also, you
can see it - if you wanna take the time out
- children growing up. "hey" you know "what
are you playing with the girls for?" I'm talking
about when you're 4 or 5 years old. That kind
of thing, you know "momma, he likes my sister"
I didn't know why, why older guys want to
go out with girls, you can't have any fun
with a girl, you know, you throw your ball,
they can't even catch it. And they won't go
off the high board, *moaning sound* what the
hell are you hanging around with girls for?
And so, they are right in their set the way
they're brought up, the values are different.
Now if a girl climbs a tree - the other girls
- you know "she's an odd one" if you have
a collection of snakes, when you're young,
you know, your girlfriends, you know, they
have a reaction. But it isn't typically female,
it's typically cultural. There any girls here
that collected snakes of any kind, or ever
had any snakes? Any girls here that ever picked
up a frog? Slimey frog? You pick up a frog?
Snakes - did you Linda? - Yeah but [unknown]
Alright, right out of the pond. Have you?
Have I? I have but I wouldn't - Are you conditioned
against that kind of thing? Yeah, I don't
like snakes or frogs. Whether it's poisonous
or non-poisonous? According to your conditioning?
Do you realise that? Oh, very small - Ok
- picking up snakes - do you believe you can
change in that area if you wanted, if you
had need to? Yeah but I don't choose to. You
don't choose to? Ok, that's your problem with
other people - you may say things to them,
and they don't choose to, meaning that forces
that act upon them force that decision. Is
that right? You know, if you go out with a
guy - if a girl goes out with a guy, and she
likes the guy, she wants to go to bed with
him, and she puts her arm around him, she
tries opening his fly and reaches for him,
you know? The guy is - the guy doesn't feel
comfortable, because it doesn't fit the pattern,
it's far afield of the pattern. He says "there
must be something wrong with her" see? And
so - but if a guy does it, "that's how men
are" you know what I mean? "You know how men
are. Everybody knows that." So, what you're
dealing with's a set of patterns they're all
established, the patterns are established.
You know, if you squeze your girlfriend's
butt while she's getting into a car, it's
alright. But if I were in a supermarket and
my girlfriend was reaching for my balls, you
know? I'd say you know "not here!" Because
I can't sit around like that and the supervisor
says "alright, [unknown]." Whereas the people
in the supermarket - "notice that guy with
the captains hat and the beard" if they see
you on the radio once or anything like that,
it doesn't take very long especially - and
so, in the world today if you wanna make contact
with people you have to simulate certain values
on the outside, I mean, you have to wear that
mask. Now I don't think people are gunna turn
around and say "how liberated are you?" and
you say - you go like that, and you fart
- no, now a girl that does that especially
a respectable girl, you know, from a good
home, that's not too liberating, that's sick.
The difference between sickness and liberation
with clothes, alright John there's your major
problem. Major problem is that people don't
choose to change because they don't see the
extensionality of the system.