We actually just got
back to the States.
We spent some time down in
Colombia, where we found out
that some of the locals--
they fuck donkeys.
We're on the Caribbean here
in Cartagena, Colombia.
The city basically looks like
it was constructed from the
daydreams of frustrated
nine-to-fivers.
You can picture some fat guy in
a cubicle going, goddamn, I
just wish I was on a beach
somewhere that was more
beautiful than any beach I've
ever seen in a city with
absolutely beautiful
architecture and filled with
gorgeous women.
That's Cartagena.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
RYAN DUFFY: Some of our friends
had been telling us
that on the northern coast of
Colombia, people fuck donkeys.
Foolishly, we basically
said, we'll believe
that when we see it.
So we flew down to Cartagena
and figured we'd do some
investigating of our own.
ANASTASIA MALONEY: It's a
really macho culture.
And they really value
the chase here.
Colombian men think the chase
is incredibly important.
I'm from London.
I'm a freelance journalist
here.
I've been living here
for five years.
And I'm married to
a Colombian.
Colombian men think they're the
best dancers in the world
because they've never had anyone
to tell them otherwise.
People used to talk, and they
used to say, oh, the
Costonians are--
all they do is party,
they drink, and--
the joke was--
they fuck donkeys.
No one actually said,
I've done it.
They'd always said, oh no, my
friends have done it, and it's
quite common that you lived on a
farm, you'll see people with
their own special donkey.
And yes, it's something
that you do.
It's totally cultural
and it's normal.
It's just a different
way of seeing sex.
It's just a different way
of looking at it.
RYAN DUFFY: Right.
FEMALE SPEAKER:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
MALE SPEAKER: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
RYAN DUFFY: We're here in
Turbaco, which is just a
little bit outside
of Cartagena.
We're getting a tour
of the land from
our new friends here.
And then we're going to
go see about this
donkey fucking thing.
So when we got back from
Colombia, we were so freaked
out and so totally confused by
what we'd seen and what you're
about to see that we felt like
we really had to go see a sex
therapist, if only so we didn't
spend the next two
weeks of our lives crying
in the fetal position.
So we're here in the offices
of Dr. Hani Miletski.
She is the author of this book,
which is Understanding
Bestiality and Zoophilia.
Could you break down what's
bestiality, what's zoophilia?
What are the differences
in terms?
HANI MILETSKI: There's
really very different
things, those two.
Bestiality is sex
with animals.
That's the act.
And zoophilia is more about
feelings, about attraction.
When somebody uses "zoophile,"
it's sort of like a sexual
orientation in a way, while
bestiality is sort of like
using the animal as a form
of masturbation.
Bestiality has been going on
throughout history in every
culture, basically.
In my book, I even mention
an agriculture society in
northern Colombia
called Cagaba.
And in that society, it is an
ancient pre-Colombian belief.
"Adolescent males will not
achieve competence in marriage
unless they practice intercourse
with donkeys."
[MUSIC PLAYING]
RYAN DUFFY: Colombia is very
religious and super Catholic.
So a lot of these girls are not
having sex until they're
married or whatever it is.
All of which is fine, but all
of which leaves our friend
over here and various other
14-year-olds with basically a
six-year long case
of blue balls.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
MALE SPEAKER: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
FEMALE SPEAKER:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
RYAN DUFFY: What's
with the whole
initiation thing, anyway?
You're not going to find that
in the States, right?
You get initiated together.
It's 13-year-old boys and girls
in rec rooms groping
each other and it's awkward and
terrible, but they're of
the same species.
So what's keeping that
from happening here?
ANASTASIA MALONEY: There comes
a certain age of 12, 13, 14,
and if they hadn't had a sexual
experience, they hadn't
had sex, then they're
not a man.
I mean, they just can't
go around saying
that they're a virgin.
RYAN DUFFY: So in junior high,
a lot of credibility is based
on how many people you've made
out with and all that stuff.
So we're trying to sort out here
which one of these two
little guys--
both of them are 14-- have
fucked more donkeys.
MALE SPEAKER: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
FEMALE SPEAKER:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
MALE SPEAKER: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
RYAN DUFFY: Oh my god.
RYAN DUFFY: We heard a lot of
different reasoning from the
folks we spoke to down there.
And it ran the gamut between
really practical reasons to
stuff that we found a little
more far-fetched, like, oh, it
enlarges the size
of the penis.
HANI MILETSKI: I have heard
that there are other
civilizations who believe that
having sex with an animal,
specifically donkey--
I mean, that's what
I came across--
will enlarge penises.
Like Muslim countries, fathers
will encourage their sons to
have sex with a donkey so that
their penises will grow and
that they will learn to
be better lovers.
MALE SPEAKER: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
RYAN DUFFY: We're about a 35
minute cab ride outside of
Cartagena, which is a beautiful
Caribbean city where
I'd say-- a rough estimate--
every other girl is a fucking
10, give or take.
And the ugly girls are sevens.
And we are here, 35 minutes
from there, and our friend
here is going to
fuck a donkey.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
RYAN DUFFY: So after talking to
all these folks in Turbaco,
hearing all their stories,
pretty much thought that we'd
heard and seen it all.
Little did we know that our
cab driver was so happy to
help and eager to share this
part of the culture with us,
that we were about to see
a whole lot more.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
RYAN DUFFY: So Martin took
us out to this field.
And the sun was setting and
there were all kinds of trees
and a couple little lakes, and
it was quite beautiful.
MARTIN: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
HANI MILETSKI: What I'm hearing
from people who had
sex with animals and then they
want to have sex with humans,
how different it is for them--
that they're not equipped with
the knowledge of what to do
when-- they call it "mind
games." That with people you
have to play mind games and you
have to figure out what
they want, while the animals,
it's like it's right there.
And then, if you try
to translate
that to humans, it's--
humans are a lot more
complicated.
On top of the fact that
sometimes it feels different.
Especially, I hear from men who
had sex with female dogs
that the female dogs
are a lot tighter.
And they say, after you had
sex with a female dog, you
don't want to have sex
with a woman anymore.
MARTIN: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
HANI MILETSKI: And even when it
comes to zoophilia, I mean
like sexual orientation, there's
different degrees.
Somebody may be completely
straight and somebody may be
completely gay, but there's all
these different shades in
the middle.
And I think Martin is somewhere
in the middle,
because he has a wife and I'm
assuming he has sex with her,
but because he was talking
about, fantasizing about,
women, I would assume that
he's not completely zoo.
He's somewhere in between.
MARTIN: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
RYAN DUFFY: So Martin is
back there preparing.
He's getting himself
aroused and
preparing to fuck the donkey.
So he's going to give
us a shout when
he's ready to mount.
There's nothing good.
It's walking behind a tree
to find a-- oh no.
Oh no.
It's like the surprise you knew
was coming and you didn't
want to be there.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
RYAN DUFFY: Really
not into it, man.
It's one of those careful what
you ask for situations where I
thought it was going to be
really funny, and now I'm so
bummed and there's not
enough fucking
rum in all of Colombia.
We were told a variety
of reasons that
this might be happening.
We were told it's a
gender role thing.
We were told it has to do
with the predominant
Catholicism in Colombia.
Even an economic reason
was suggested to us.
There's a million things.
I'm not going to wrap this up
in any tidy package, because
it doesn't exist.
I watched a man fuck a donkey,
and it probably changed me for
the rest of my life.
But the reality probably is that
there are probably people
fucking animals all over
the fucking place.
And it's certainly not
distinctly a Colombian thing.
Now I definitely think it's
safe to say that we really
have seen it all.
Way too damn much, in fact.
Even now, back in New York,
everywhere I look, I keep
seeing these Colombian
donkeys.
[MUSIC PLAYING]