beautiful Del Rey--
oh, not counting Lana Del Rey.
Don't tell her.
OLGA KAY: [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
That was me speaking Russian.
Tonight is International Comedy
Night, presented by
Comedy Gives Back.
You're going to see--
[AUDIENCE CHEERING]
OLGA KAY: Yeah, yeah!
BETH HOYT: All right, yeah.
It's live.
OLGA KAY: You're going to see
some of the best international
stand-ups from all over
the United States.
BETH HOYT: Oh my gosh, man.
There is so much stuff going
on this whole week.
People are ready to bust down
the doors to get involved.
OLGA KAY: Yeah, I'm actually
scared, all right, because I
called my mother back
in Russia just to
be on the safe side.
I'm just kidding.
My mom doesn't have a phone.
BETH HOYT: It's an international
joke.
That's not all.
Don't forget to check out all
of the live events at
youtube.com/comedyweek.
I mean, it's all so funny,
I'm scared of it.
We're very scared.
OLGA KAY: It's terrible,
hilarious, and lots of
frightening stuff.
BETH HOYT: Right.
Also, last night's comedy show,
it's been uploaded and
can be streamed on the Comedy
Week page, so check that out.
OLGA KAY: Yeah, please.
And hey, don't forget that every
day, we have multiple
Comedy Week videos
being posted.
So go check out videos
from Improv
Everywhere, Rhett and Link--
I'm in it-- and the new video
from Tim and Eric, "Goatee,"
which also can be seen on
youtube.com/comedyweek.
BETH HOYT: Oh my god, we have
to get out of here and let
this show happen.
OLGA KAY: Yeah, you're right.
I'm going to go first
all right?
BETH HOYT: Yeah, OK.
Oh, she's showing off.
I can do that, too.
We're going to be right back
tomorrow, but right now it's
time for our international
stand-up show.
ROVE MCMANUS: Thank you,
thank you very much.
Thank you.
Welcome to Comedy
Week on YouTube.
How is everybody here in
the house tonight?
Welcome, wherever you are
watching around the world.
Thank you for pausing whatever
hilarious Psy video clip you
had to put aside to
be here tonight.
Thank you.
We are live, so everybody in
the audience, please, watch
yourselves.
I know when it's live, you
go, they can't stop me.
You just want to yell "titties"
or something, but
rein it in.
Grow up.
I know it's YouTube.
This is where we all first saw
the two girls and the one cup.
But, at the same time, there's
a lot of innocent, overweight
Japanese cats just trying
to jump in and out of
their boxes in peace.
Have some dignity.
I am your host for this evening,
wherever you are
watching this.
[AUDIENCE CHEERING]
ROVE MCMANUS: That's great.
Thank you, thank you.
Thank you for pretending
to know who I am.
That's very--
yes, your laughter
gives you away.
My name is Rove McManus.
I am an Australian comedian
and talk show host.
This is very exciting
for me to be here.
For those of you who don't know
me, yes, Rove, I realize
it's a bit of a weird name.
At least I thought so 'til I
moved here to Los Angeles.
Did you know there's a person
who lives in this city called
Zooey Deschanel?
That's the name of a person.
I'm like, whooey with
the what now?
That can't be a real
thing, surely.
But what I've also discovered
is that, in this city
especially, celebrities
love a crazy name.
I fit right in here.
Normally what happens is, the
celebrities, they'll pair up
to get themselves a really cool
celebrity fun nickname--
like Brad Pitt and Angelina
Jolie are Brangelina, Ben
Affleck and Jennifer Garner
are Bennifer.
And Keith Urban and Nicole
Kidman are Keyhole, I think.
Listen, could we--
might have to research
that, yes--
OK, cool.
I'm--
yep--
I'm being told I don't
have an earpiece.
Good.
But it's now even gone
even further, where--
I don't know if you've noticed,
but the celebrities
are so bang up for a crazy name,
they're giving all their
kids crazy names.
Yes, says the audience.
I've noticed, too.
Yeah, observant.
Because that's how you
all talk to me.
You've suddenly become very
well-spoken British.
I'm a YouTube audience member.
I cannot be trusted with
a real candle,
however, but still.
Ah, ah.
But, yeah.
Crazy baby names, like Beyonce
might be having another one.
Blue Ivy was her first.
That was great.
Other great names out there,
thank you celebrities--
Apple, Shiloh, Suri, Banjo,
Moon Unit, that's a name.
My favorite, though, I think,
would be Nicolas Cage, the
actor Nicolas Cage, as opposed
to the mechanic Nicolas Cage.
I don't know why I needed
to bring that up,
but there you go.
But Nicolas Cage named
his son Kal-El.
K-A-L hyphen E-L. Does anybody
in the room tonight know the
significance of that name?
Yes, yell it out.
Yell out.
AUDIENCE: Superman.
ROVE MCMANUS: Superman,
yes, yes.
Be proud, nerd.
He's into Superman.
Yell it out, my friend.
Sure.
You may as well yell it out
because if you know this,
you're not getting laid
tonight, so be proud.
Get it out there.
For those of you who don't
know-- and you probably will
in the next couple of months
with the movie coming--
Kal-El is Superman's birth
name, from his
home planet of Krypton.
Well done, Nicolas Cage.
You've just come up with the
perfect way to make sure that
your son comes home from school
with his underpants on
the outside as well.
Genius.
Well, ladies and gentlemen, you
have plenty of fantastic
acts coming up tonight.
You have logged on to a
wonderful show, Comedy Week
here on YouTube, international
night.
One more round of applause
as we get into it.
Our first performer tonight,
ladies and
gentlemen, Daniel Kinno.
DANIEL KINNO: Thank you.
Give a go for Rove one
more time, your host.
Thank you.
It's good to be back
in America.
I just got back from Canada.
Funny already, all right.
I was in Winnipeg, Canada.
When I was there, somebody
goes, are you
nervous to be here?
It's the murder capital
of Canada.
Murder capital of Canada.
I got all scared,
I Googled it--
35 people a year.
That is adorable.
I live in Los Angeles.
35 people got killed in my
apartment building last year.
We didn't even call the cops.
So I kept reading.
They don't kill each other as
much as we do in Canada.
Only 500 people get murdered
in Canada a year.
America, 20,000.
We're number one, yay.
Pew, pew, pew pew.
So they got us beat there.
But here's something odd-- and
this is true-- their suicide
rate in Canada is four times
their murder rate.
2,000 people kill themselves
every year.
That's weird, right?
How does that even work?
Somebody breaks into
your house in the
middle of the night.
You're like, oh my god, are you
think about killing me?
Me, too, me too.
What a coinkydink.
Don't even waste your bullets,
I already got
the sleeping pills.
Well, it's either that or they
have the dumbest cops in the
world in Canada.
They think everything's
a fucking suicide.
They show up at a crime scene,
get off their horses or
whatever they do,
I don't know.
Hey, what happened here?
Oh my god, this is the worst
suicide I've ever seen.
This guy must have
been so sad.
He broke into his own house,
tied himself to this chair,
and then shot himself in the
back of the head five times.
Some people just don't want
to live, I guess, eh?
Let's go get some free
health care.
More for the rest of us.
I was just in Ch--
that's a weird laugh.
I was reading an article
today about China.
Did you guys know this?
China has the fastest-growing
number of
millionaires in the world.
Did you know that?
Yeah.
It's got to be bittersweet
for them.
No one in China can pronounce
the word "millionaire."
There's a lot of L's and R's,
that's all I'm saying.
Relax.
I've done that joke in China.
They hate it there, too.
Your instincts are in
the right place.
But that's true. "Time Magazine"
said that they spend
so much time and money in
America that the entire mail
order bride trend is
now reversing.
Because it used to be, American
guys would go China,
get a wife, then bring
her back to America.
Now Chinese millionaires
are coming over here
to pick up our sluts.
That's messed up.
Those are our sluts.
We can't even hide these
girls from the Chinese
millionaires, right?
They all have Chinese
shit tattooed
right above their asses.
If you have one here, relax.
I'm sure you're not a slut.
I'm sure you're into strength
and courage.
I did that joke one time.
A girl came up to me
after the show.
She goes, you're an asshole.
I'm spiritual.
Yeah, you sound like it.
That's a whole lot of
enlightenment coming out of
your mouth right there.
Just because you put a Chinese
symbol above your asscrack
doesn't bring you closer
to Buddha, OK?
It brings you closer
to my hotel room.
There's nothing spiritual
about that experience?
It's more of a Catholic
thing, really.
People get touchy
about Catholics.
Don't worry.
Catholics get touchy, too.
It's all good.
I knew that Catholics were
up to no good, right.
They have a room in the church
called the rectory.
What did you think was going
to happen to you?
I'm never a following a horny
old guy into a rectory.
Can we just stay here in the
hand job-ory until my parents
pick me up?
Then I can go to the shrink-ory,
pretend this shit
never happened.
Tell you a little bit
about myself.
I was born in Russia.
A lot of people don't believe
me when I say that because I
don't sound like a James
Bond villain.
I did my best to lose the accent
because girls say they
like accents--
not the Russian one.
That is not a sexy accent.
You never see a Russian
lover in a movie.
[RUSSIAN ACCENT]
Hello, how are you?
You are a pretty
female person.
Would you like to drink vodka
and then complete me?
But that's true.
I was born in Russia
in a small town
right outside of Chernobyl.
People find that odd.
They always go, Daniel, growing
up near Chernobyl, did
that affect you in any way?
And it did.
I have a giant penis.
Unfortunately, it's right
above my tiny vagina.
That's a radiation joke.
That's not a dick joke.
Google Chernobyl.
It'll be funnier.
I Google everything now.
Google's amazing.
It's unnecessary for you to
learn how to spell the word
"unnecessary." You can throw
a U, two N's, and a C into
Google, it goes, did you mean
"unnecessary?" Yes, I did.
Thank you.
Let's move this along.
I don't know how people did
anything before the internet.
They went to the moon
before the internet.
How did they even
know there was a
moon before the internet?
Some places still
don't have it.
That weirds me out.
I was checking into a hotel a
couple weeks ago, and I go, is
there internet in my room?
And the guy looks at me and he
goes, no, but there is a phone
in your room.
There's a phone in my pants,
and it has internet.
All right, guys,
that's my time.
Thank you very much.
CAT: My wife's in heat.
Let me tell you something.
There's nothing worse than
being married when
your wife's in heat.
You know that voice, right?
She's always like, Mr.
Sprinkles, I'm in heat.
Let's have sex.
And I'm like, I don't want
to fuck Garfield.
ROVE MCMANUS: You'll have to
excuse our studio audience
while they go, did I just see
what I thought I just saw?
You're probably all thinking
the same thing.
All right, we are moving
hastily along.
As wonderful as that cat in a
suit was, I'm going to bring
on our next performer, a man
I have had the pleasure of
performing with on
many an occasion.
I think he's fantastic.
I know you will, too.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Matt Kirshen.
MATT KIRSHEN: Thank you.
Thank you.
ROVE MCMANUS: Hey.
MATT KIRSHEN: Thank you.
Rove McManus, ladies
and gentlemen.
It's Rove.
Rove, yeah.
This is exciting.
Geez, I didn't--
if you'd told me as a kid
growing up in 1980s London
that one day I would be on
youtube.com, I wouldn't've
believed you.
I'd be like, no way.
No kid like me gets
on youtube.com.
Maybe President Barack Obama
gets on youtube.com, but not a
little Englishman like me.
So thank you.
Thank you, people here.
Thank you, viewers at home, for
taking time out of your
lazy masturbation to flick
over to my tab.
It's what I'd be doing if I
was watching this at home.
I'd have both going
at the same time.
One eye on me, one on the porn--
get mixed up in your
head, good things happen.
Somewhere an association's
being made, and
I appreciate that.
So this just happened
to me the other day.
I still haven't processed it.
Because I work nights,
this is my job.
So I finish work, and then
I do normal things.
So I do things like grocery
shopping in the
middle of the night.
I'll do it at 2:00 in the
morning when it's just me and
drunks, all right, and the
occasional nurse and the
occasional drunk nurse.
I love that.
I love a drunk nurse, not even
for any creepy reasons.
It's just like, nurses have
the best stories, and if
they're drunk, they share.
Nurses have stories that would
put a sea captain to shame.
Stories with lines in it like,
no, you have to understand.
It was a full-sized umbrella.
But I was just in this 24 hour
store, just buying normal
groceries at 2:00 in
the morning, like
bread, milk, cereal.
And I put my basket of food next
to the register, and I
went to get a couple
more things.
And I came back,
and it's gone.
My basket's gone.
So I'm looking for the
overzealous employee who's
putting everything back.
And then I see the most
confused-looking drunk man
leaving with my stuff.
He bought my things.
He bought my--
I don't even know if
that's a crime.
I don't know.
If anyone at home knows,
comment in.
I don't know what
the legality--
I think until you pay
for something, it
belongs to the store.
And then he paid for
it, so it's his.
But I selected it.
I put all the work in.
I got like a week's worth
of food, and he just
waltzed off with it.
I couldn't even be mad at him,
either, because he was so
drunk and so baffled.
Because from his point of view,
that's just the world's
most convenient convenience
store.
He's just staggered in,
hammered, and the guy's like,
what do you want?
He's like, this.
Thank you.
Thank you, convenience store.
I'll be back here every night.
This is wonderful.
I don't remember having a cat.
Either that, or he was so drunk,
he'd forgotten that he
hadn't already gone to the
effort of selecting
everything.
Have you ever done that thing
where you're really drunk and
your brain just starts
to do useful things?
Am I the only one
who does that?
Who's just hammered and
thinking, well, I'm
slaughtered.
Everything's fun, so I might as
well get some chores done.
You wake up the next morning and
all the bathroom tiles are
clean, but you've vomited
in the freezer.
It's a trade-off.
The entire apartment's
vacuumed, but
you've killed a man.
It's give and take.
Gee, Daniel going straight in
with the Catholic stuff, at a
time that we have a
new pope, as well.
Of all the times to
be doing that.
The pope is barely out of--
I don't know where
popes come from.
He says that-- first
Latin-American pope, as well.
First pope from Latin America.
[AUDIENCE CHEERING]
MATT KIRSHEN: I know.
Yeah, it's pretty cool, right?
I mean, don't worry.
He's still white and hates gays,
so they kept it safe on
that front.
They kept the light-skinned
homophobe theme
that's working so well.
It's an exciting time
for gay rights.
We had the debate in the UK.
It got passed by Parliament.
The conservative prime minister
voted for gay
marriage, which is remarkable.
That's never happened before.
Not everyone was for it.
One guy in the middle of the
debate actually said the
words, Adam and Eve,
not Adam and Steve.
He said that, out loud, knowing
that other people were
listening, as well, knowing
that his words were being
recorded and everything.
He thought that was a
good thing to say.
That's on a par with, if it
was a debate about whether
women should have equal pay in
the workplace, and he'd just
stood up and gone, girls smell,
and sat down again.
That's the same level
of sophistication.
He is my second-favorite
homophobe.
I know it's weird to have
them ranked, but I do.
My number one is,
and I think will
always be, Michele Bachmann.
She has to be because she's the
only one I know who's that
homophobic while being married
to such an obviously gay man.
He's so gay.
I know I'm like libeling someone
on a livestreaming
thing right now, but he's so--
if he's not gay, he's putting
a lot of effort
into appearing gay.
He is really-- have you seen?
You're on YouTube right now.
Don't do it right-- open up
another tab next to my one,
and YouTube "Marcus Bachmann
interview."
He is ridiculous.
I know not everyone who sounds
like that is gay, and not
everyone who's gay
sounds like that.
But the two of them
are absurd.
In the modern era when people
are becoming so much more
accepting, they exist.
Last year I was in San Francisco
during Pride
weekend, and I would urge any
of you to go there, whatever
your sexuality.
I was there as a straight guy
with my girlfriend, and it's
one of the best celebrations
on Earth of
humanity and sexuality.
It's just a massive
party where the
only theme is tolerance.
And walking through the middle
of this park, around which a
lot of the events are centered,
were these two guys.
And they were in great physical
shape, which we could
clearly tell because all they
were wearing were shoes and
matching cock rings.
I hope intentionally,
by the way.
I hope that was planned between
the two of them.
I'd hate to think they rocked up
independently and like, oh,
you as well.
Oh, well, there's no time to
go home and change, either.
This is embarrassing.
But they were walking through
the middle of the park
together, and it was hilarious
and it was wonderful and it
was fantastic.
And it was absurdly gay, but
still not as gay as Marcus
Bachmann's voice.
Thank you very much for
listening to my
part of this evening.
Take care.
I appreciate it.
I've been Matt Kirshen.
Bye!
ROVE MCMANUS: Matt Kirshen.
MATT KIRSHEN: Thank you.
Yeah.
Later, Matt and I are going
to go to Six Flags with an
oversized coat.
He's going to get
on my shoulders.
X2, here we come.
It's a roller coaster, for
those of you not in the
Angeleno way.
And I don't know what
that means.
As I say "Angeleno way," it
suddenly means you're pregnant
with a Californian.
Could be a thing,
you don't know.
Look it up.
This is one of the things I have
found having moved here
to the States from Australia,
is adjusting a little bit.
And, for the most part, it's not
too difficult, but one of
the things I have kind of
struggled with is tipping.
Because we don't tip
as readily as you
do here in the States.
Yeah, at cafes and stuff,
sure, we'll do it there.
But I had an experience when I
first arrived where I was in
the men's room.
I don't know how it is for the
women, but sometimes in the
men's room, there's a guy, like
an attendant, there--
right guys?
Yes.
He's got cologne and little
hand towels and a bowl of
mints, because that's what you
want when you've just been to
the toilet.
Candy.
How many times have you found
yourself in the situation
going, I just took a dump.
I could really go with
some M&Ms right now.
But he's there with the
towels and everything.
And I don't mean to brag,
YouTube people, but I've been
able to go to the toilet
by myself since
about the age of three.
And so I wasn't sure
of what to do.
So I did what I needed
to do, and then went
past, washed my hands.
The guy gave me a towel.
I was like, thank you.
I dried my hands, then walked
out but didn't tip.
Oh, yes.
I learned a very valuable lesson
that day, because let
me tell you something.
There is no worse look than
you leaving the men's room
with another guy chasing
you demanding payment.
Trap for young players.
It is indeed a pleasure to
welcome our next act, ladies
and gentlemen.
You have seen him on "Conan."
You have seen him on "Jimmy
Kimmel Live." You have seen him
on "Cougar Town." He's a
MILF, the absolutely brilliant
Rob Delaney.
ROB DELANEY: Thank you, sir.
Thank you.
Hello, everybody.
Nice to see you all.
In keeping with the
international theme, I want to
tell you a story.
I recently did a show in
Belfast, in Northern Ireland,
and it's calmed down
in recent years.
It's not as scary anymore.
But the city's covered with
murals back from when it was
going through its Troubles.
And you can hire a cab and get
a ride around and look at all
the murals.
Some of them are really
beautiful, some of them are
sad, like hunger strikers and
stuff, but it's just sort of
how they healed and
dealt with it.
Anyway, I got a cab
driver, and he was
showing me all the murals.
And as he was about to finish,
he said, now I'm going to take
you, and I'm going to
show you the most
powerful mural we've got.
It's my favorite mural.
By I need to tell you, as an
American, there's a symbol on
this mural that you're not
going to understand.
So you'll look at it, sort of
absorb it, let it wash over
you, and then I'll explain
the symbol to you.
So I was excited to learn
about a new symbol.
He pulled around the corner, and
there was this seven-story
tall painting of a British
paramilitary soldier, just
firing tear gas canisters
into a pile of kids.
It was upsetting.
But then in front of it was this
ancient Irish symbol that
he had mentioned.
And what it was, it was a giant
red circle with a slash
through it.
And so I was like, uh-oh.
Uh-oh.
Oh, OK.
And I decided to mess
with him a little.
I was like, OK, so what you're
saying is, you take a thing,
and then you mural up a
building, and then you put
this symbol on it, and the
symbol kind of means you
should do that some more?
And he's like, no, for
goodness' sake.
What I meant-- no, the symbol,
I knew you wouldn't
know what it is.
You take a great red, ruby red
circle and you then circle the
entire building with it.
And then from the northwest to
the southeast, you bisect it
with a mighty red slash.
And what we're saying is,
none for me and mine.
No, none of that.
And I was like, OK, I get it.
So basically you draw something
or whatever, you
take a picture, and then you put
this around there and it's
saying, yeah, a few
more of those?
And he's like, no, for
goodness' sake!
Get the wax out of your American
ears, for god's sake!
And anyway, now you guys know
what that symbol is, too.
So I just wanted to share
that with you guys.
It's my favorite thing that's
happened to me in the last
five years.
Since this is live on the
internet, I want to talk about
internet filth and porn.
I grew up in the '80s.
And when I wanted to masturbate,
I had to write a
letter to a friend's older
brother who lived in
Pennsylvania.
And he would mail me back the
coordinates of where he had
buried a cigar box 11
years ago with a
rain-damaged Playboy.
I would have to take a map, and
I'd have to get a friend.
And we'd have to bring like
victuals and dry goods and
hike though the woods.
We would get there just as the
sun was setting, and we'd dig
it up, there'd be no
more daylight.
So we'd have to jerk off
together just because that's
all the time that was left.
But now with the internet,
it's just filth.
You open your computer, and you
open your AOL homepage,
it's a gaping butthole.
It's just total filth.
Why is it so gross?
I'm just so glad that I grew up
in an age where, when I was
younger, I would have to
jerk off to poetry.
I used to jerk off to
the written word.
You should try it.
But now it just is garbage.
And people are fucking
each other in
their butts a lot online.
And I don't understand that.
And I'm not speaking
out of school here.
I tried it.
When I was in college, I had a
girlfriend, and we were like,
hey, I heard people buttfuck.
And it wasn't even me.
I wasn't like, it's
my birthday.
Can I?
Literally, it might have
even been her idea.
I don't remember.
I didn't have a hankering
for it.
And so we were going
to do it, right?
So we're having normal
penis-vagina sex, and then
she's like, yeah, go ahead.
So I take it out and I
just, like, started.
And she was like, oh, god, no.
And I was like, oh,
I'm so sorry.
We'll never do it again.
I'm very sorry.
I want you to enjoy
what we do.
Let's go get a falafel.
And she was like, [GRUNTS].
And she goes, no, you need
to know what it was like.
And I was like, what it--
it seems awful.
I believe you.
She was like, no, you
need to know.
And I was like, what
does that mean?
I backed up against the wall.
I thought Navy SEALs were going
to burst out of the
building and be like,
time to learn.
And so, anyway, what she did
is, she went to her dresser
and she got just a tiny little
vibrator, a wee little
itsy-bitsy one, a tiny one like
you'd use on the bus,
like nothing.
So then we started messing
around again.
And then she took it and touched
it to my surprisingly
cute little butthole, and
then she went, push.
And I immediately was like
throwing up, almost, sobbing,
racked with sobs.
So anyway, I get it.
I understand that there are
people in the world who don't
want a big hard penis going in
out of their butthole, and I'm
among them.
I am one of those people.
So I'm just saying you're the
boss of your own butthole, OK?
Remember that.
So if your boyfriend is like,
it's Arbor Day, be like, N. So
you don't have to let
him to do it.
Look, if you want me to fuck
you in your butt, I'll fuck
you in your butt.
I'm not a monster.
But I'm saying you're the
boss of your butt.
You decide what goes in
and out of there.
Another thing for you youngsters
out there, that
same older brother--
the friend's older brother who
I called and had to get the
coordinates for the cigar box
to dig up the porn-- he also
taught us what blow jobs were.
He didn't do a tutelage session,
but he mentioned that
he got a blow job.
And we were like, what's that?
He's like, when the
penis goes.
And I was like, shut up.
I want one.
And so anyway, he was like, yeah
but they got to swallow.
They can't spit.
And I was like, what
does that matter?
And he was like, [GRUNTS].
Anyway, decades later, finally
a Samaritan put my penis in
her mouth, and I realized
that if you suck my
dick, you're a hero.
You can take it, you can spit
it in your hand, and you can
break my jaw, and I will
drive to the florist--
I'll get my jaw wired shut-- buy
you flowers, come, and be
like, thank you so much.
I love you.
Spit, swallow, it's up to you.
I don't care.
I mean literally, you could suck
my dick, and then when
you're done you could peel
off an expensive "Mission
Impossible" style mask and
reveal that you're not a
beautiful young woman, you're
Pat Sajak from "Wheel of
Fortune." And I would
like, Pat, let
me take you to brunch.
I'm Rob Delaney.
Thank you very much.
ROVE MCMANUS: Rob Delaney,
the king of regular
penis-vagina sex.
Another thing I need to point
out to you is, when I first
arrived here--
I think this is going very
well tonight, by the way.
Don't you think?
It's really cool to get asked
to do something like this,
especially because when I first
arrived here in Los
Angeles, Hollywood itself, they
said if you want to make
it in this town, you're
going to have to sleep
your way to the top.
I did that.
But the problem was, no one
told me it had to be with
someone in the industry who
can further your career.
So I just ended up nailing some
homeless guy in an alleyway.
But to his credit, he said he
would put some calls in, so.
Although, it was a banana he had
in his hand at the time.
So anyway, the night
is still young.
Fingers crossed.
Ladies and gentlemen,
our next performer.
Please welcome him now, one of
the best, Mr. Jeremy Hotz.
JEREMY HOTZ: Hi.
Thank you.
Thanks.
OK, stop.
Hi, how are you?
This is my face.
Sorry.
It's just we can't all be good
looking, but I still have the
odd sexual experience.
This is my lucky shirt.
Do you know what that means?
I got laid while I was
wearing this shirt.
And she loved this shirt because
when we were doing it,
she said, whatever you do, don't
take off that shirt.
I like women.
They're way better-looking
than us.
They are.
But everything in the
world's designed to
make them even more.
We can't compete.
You're a good-looking guy, but
this is the best you're ever
going to look.
Look at her, man.
Because women wear the makeup,
and they're already pretty.
You can't wear makeup.
Did you ever see a woman without
her makeup for the
first time and just think,
who the fuck is that guy?
See, even the women have to
give me that one because
they've all seen one of their
friends and thought, Jane's
looking a lot like
Dave lately.
This is ridiculous.
Women cheat, man.
Their underwear is way
better than ours.
It is.
Are you a boob man
or an ass man?
AUDIENCE: I like both.
JEREMY HOTZ: You like both,
you greedy bastard?
Leave some for somebody else.
He likes both.
You ever been startled
by boobs?
You've been fooled
haven't you?
Oh yeah, because you see giant
boobs on a woman and then she
takes off her bra and it's two
little gingerbread man eyes
staring at you.
You think, shit,
I've been had.
It's true.
Women have underwear
that fixes stuff.
Victoria's Secret should
just be called "Lies."
Our underwear is garbage,
isn't it?
It comes with a fly for
no apparent reason.
Ladies, we don't use the fly.
We pull it down and flip
it over the top.
And if we're at a urinal and
the guy next to us is using
his fly, we punch him
in the fucking face.
But it's not all
gloom and doom.
I'm just saying, ladies, if
you've got a guy that loves
you, stay with him because
he's trying, isn't he?
Seriously, it's gross, man.
We know it's tough to be
a woman, it really is.
You have the period.
Good lord.
You just bleed.
You don't fall down
or nothing.
It just happens.
But we didn't invent it, so quit
fucking yelling at us.
And we have balls.
They're not particularly
attractive.
Come on, ladies, you
don't like balls.
You don't.
You're like, I'll deal with that
long thing, but I don't
want those bouncing all
over my forehead.
These are nasty, aren't they?
If it was reversed, ladies,
and you had balls, you
couldn't handle it.
It'd be like carrying
a purse that never
matched your outfit.
They're horrible.
Do you know this, ladies?
We have the unique ability
of being able to
sit on our own balls.
Do you know this?
Your guy'll never
tell you that.
You just see this look on his
face at a restaurant.
What happened?
I don't want to talk about it.
Tell me.
I sat on my ball, are
you satisfied?
Sat on your ball?
That's ridiculous.
How fucking uncoordinated
are you?
I'm just saying, they're
nasty, man.
You gotta find the right person
who puts up with your
bullshit, man.
You can't live your whole
life by yourself.
You don't want to die alone.
Get a dog like I did, man.
Seriously, check it out.
Here he is.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
He's 17.
I rescued him.
I got him out of someone's
backyard.
I just opened a fence, picked
him up, and ran
away like an asshole.
I took him to Petco
to be groomed.
What a shit place that is.
I said a trim.
They shaved him almost
totally bald.
He comes waddling out, I don't
even recognize him.
But I took him because
he seemed to know me.
You know how embarrassing it
is walking a bald dog in my
neighborhood?
Cats try and fuck him.
I'm not a big cat guy.
I don't like them.
You never buy a cat, do you?
They just show up on your stoop,
and you hear, [YOWLS].
You're like maybe I
better let it in.
Thus begins a 25 year commitment
with the most
standoffish bullshit animal
on the face of the planet.
You ever call your cat?
Oh, yeah, they're right on it.
They get up and walk in the
complete opposite direction,
lift their tail, and show
you their asshole.
How rude is that?
I feed you, you miserable
animal.
Don't flip me off with
your hole, gee.
Just get a dog, man.
Dogs are the best.
He's 17 now, man, like I said.
You never know.
If you've got an old dog,
you don't know.
They go old like your grandpa.
Your grandpa's nuts, right?
OK, let me explain it.
You ever see your grandpa just
staring at the wall?
Your mom comes downstairs and
goes, leave grandpa alone.
The TV used to be
on that wall.
That's the way your dog is.
He sleeps so soundly, man.
I poke him, and if he opens his
eyes, I go, well, I guess
we're going for a
walk right now.
Because he's old, man.
He's so old.
But dogs are fantastic, man.
Listen, honestly speaking,
are you guys dating?
Yeah, yeah yeah, yeah.
And you love her, right?
Do you have a dog?
AUDIENCE: We don't.
JEREMY HOTZ: You don't.
Man, have you ever had
a dog in your life?
Yeah, yeah.
Remember when you used to go
outside and the dog would lie
by the door until you
fucking came home?
She has never done that.
And if she does, get the hell
out of that relationship.
You were great.
Thank you so much.
CAT: Great to be here,
everybody.
As you know, my name is
Professor Boyfriend.
Hey, what do you want?
My owner's a lonely fat chick.
Oh, what are you guys aww-ing?
You're not the ones who have
to sit in her lap.
ROVE MCMANUS: Seriously,
you're all
seeing that too, right?
That's not just me just going,
wow, something just kicked in.
I'm going to give a press
conference now.
I'm hoping each performer, as
they come out now, are getting
more and more--
we've gone from microphones
to stands.
The next person might
have a podium.
And we just build a--
I don't know what.
Some huge-- it'll be like Best
Buy at the end of this, but
with people in here.
Aww, what?
Best Buy, what have they
done to anybody?
Nothing.
They've given us wonderful
audio-visual memories for
years, and then I just feel the
need to kick them for no
apparent reason.
Hey, look at that thing!
We're back.
Ladies and gentlemen, our next
performer, you may know him
from the wonderful sketch
group Dead Kevin.
Any Dead Kevin fans
in the house?
Even just fans of people who
hate a guy called Kevin and
love that idea, ladies and
gentlemen, please welcome
Ahmed Bharoocha.
AHMED BHAROOCHA: Thanks, guys.
Keep it going for
Rove, everybody.
He took the mic stand back.
It's BYO mic stand.
This is crazy.
YouTube is becoming like
television now.
The only difference is, they
still give the opportunity to
the viewer at home to attach
their hateful thoughts to the
bottom of this video.
Parents, read your children's
YouTube comments.
Recently, I went to a bar and
I went to the bathroom.
In the bathroom, they
had two urinals.
One of the urinals was filled
with ice, which I thought was
kind of weird, so I went
to the other urinal.
And as I was going to the
bathroom, I started
looking at that ice.
I was like, hmm.
It would be really fun
to melt that ice.
So I stopped myself, went over
to the other urinal, and I
started melting the ice.
And I thought I was alone, but
a voice just comes from the
stall and he's like, couldn't
resist the ice, could you?
I was like, who is that?
What kind of perverted
science experiment
did I just walk into?
He's like, that's
three for ice.
I feel like it's not cool
to like things anymore.
You can't enjoy anything.
You have to like everything
ironically or hate it.
The cool people, like hipsters,
hipsters have become
the two old guys from
the Muppets.
At first glance, you're like,
wow, these guys really hate
the Muppets.
But then on closer inspection,
you're like, hey, these guys
bought season tickets
to the Muppets.
They keep coming back.
[IMPERSONATING STATLER
AND WALDORF]
Why do we keep coming here?
Because we're dead inside.
I basically grew up
in your typical
all-American household.
My mother's an Irish Catholic
woman, my father is a
Pakistani Muslim.
See you guys later.
You know, baseball, apple pie,
gulab jamun, things like that.
A lot of people ask if my
parents fought because of
their religions, different
religions.
They didn't fight because
they loved each other.
It's crazy to fight
over religion.
You can't prove who's right.
Every religion has the
same credentials.
It's like, how do you know
your religion's right?
Oh, it says it in this book.
But it says it in my book.
Yeah, but my book says
your book's not true.
So does my book.
But my dad told me
my book was true.
But so did my dad.
It's just a guess,
just a guess.
But it's the only guess
that people will
murder each other over.
There's no one killing each
other over how many jelly
beans are in a jar.
We say it's 67.
We say it's 87.
52.
It's all part of the
same jelly bean.
We think the jelly bean
hates gay people.
There is no jelly bean.
There might be a jelly bean.
I'm a jelly bean.
Let's kill him.
We're all jelly beans.
Let's kill ourselves.
I think the jelly
bean's a woman.
That's ridiculous.
Who said that?
Yeah, shut the hell up.
I found out that there's
people that
don't believe in dinosaurs.
They think that the devil put
dinosaur bones in the
earth to trick us.
That is the lamest, nerdiest
devil ever.
Is this just some science
fiction nerd devil?
Like, hey Lucifer.
What's on the agenda
for tonight?
Murder, genocide, plague?
Ah, no.
Actually a much more
diabolical scheme.
I've created a prehistoric
reptilian species.
I'm going to take their bones
and bury them deep down in the
earth, as to suggest
an alternate
timeline than in the Bible.
And then we'll hope that one
day, someone comes along, digs
them up, and questions
God's existence.
Huh?
And if that doesn't work,
we still have the gays.
Hey, guys, you've
been fantastic.
Thank you very much.
ROVE MCMANUS: Another round of
applause for Ahmed, everybody.
I'm collecting the set.
Seriously, one day, we will look
back at this moment when
there are no microphones left
in the world, and I'll be
sitting here laughing, going,
they all said I was mad!
Who is laughing now?
Me, with my booming voice!
Ladies and gentlemen, it is
indeed a pleasure to welcome
our next performer
on the stage.
Not only a very gifted stand-up
comedian, but one of
the stars of one of my favorite
shows on television,
"Parks and Recreation."
Ladies and gentlemen,
give it up for Retta.
RETTA: Hi.
How's everybody doing?
So I'm the black girl.
It's OK, I'm used to it.
I've been this way a
long fucking time.
So I'm here to talk
about race.
That's cool.
We're all a little racist.
What I can't stand is when
people are boldly racist.
I prefer old school racism,
where you talk shit about me
behind my back or behind
closed doors.
Now, old school racism is
not to be confused with
old-fashioned racism, OK?
These are two very
different things.
Old school racism is passive,
while old-fashioned racism, a
lot more aggressive.
A lot more in your face.
It was all the rage in the
'50s and '60s with its
high-powered fire hoses and
its public hangings.
Yeah.
That's the kind of racism I
don't prefer because, quite
frankly, I don't like
to get my hair wet.
So I accept that we're all a
little racist, and I include
myself in that.
I still make generalizations
about you people.
For example, I still believe
that white people can't really
feel cold, which is why you can
wear shorts and flip-flops
in 40 degree weather.
As a black woman who turns on
her heat in September, I find
this to be a bit peculiar.
But as an old school racist,
I keep that shit to myself.
It's only during high-stress
situations that I find that my
racism rears its ugly head.
Like when I've been in line at
the DMV for an hour and the
blonde in front of me insists
on flipping her hair forward
and back, forward and back until
it brushes across my
face and sticks to
my lip gloss.
That is a situation where a
white girl might find herself
getting snatched by
a black woman.
Or at the airport when the
ticket agent announces that
they will begin boarding first
class and the executive
platinum frequent flyer business
traveler bumps and
pushes past me because he
assumes I'm flying animal
class with rest of the plebs.
Excuse you, John J McAllister
the Third.
I'm assigned to seat
2D, bitch.
Recognize.
But my racism is most evident
when I'm driving because I
have an obscene and unrelenting
case of road rage.
I am what you might call a
psycho bitch behind the wheel,
who's also a little racist.
But I'm here to tell you that
it is a new-- what-- fucking
day, people.
It is a new fucking day.
Because I was in my car,
headed towards a light,
towards an intersection.
Now, there's another young
lady headed towards--
I'm traveling east to west.
She's traveling north
to south.
Now she, too, would like
to move east to west.
So my light is about to turn
yellow, so all she has to do
is wait 10 seconds for
the right of way.
But instead of waiting the 10
seconds for her rightful turn,
she takes it upon herself to
risk my life and property by
gunning it and making the
turn just as I enter the
intersection.
This little entitled bitch--
I think at this point
we all know what
I was really thinking--
this little entitled white
bitch cuts me off.
So I immediately go to my "angry
black woman who has no
patience for entitled white
bitches" place, right?
So now I'm about to gun it so I
can pull up next to her and
give her the "bitch, do you know
who the fuck you just cut
off?" face, right?
I am looking to intimidate the
shit out of her when I notice
that she's got an Obama hope
sticker on her bumper.
And that's when I said,
you know what?
I'm going to let this one go.
Yeah.
I'm going to give you a pass on
this one, Marcy, because it
is a new-- what-- fucking day.
Just know that this type of shit
did not fly during the
Bush administration.
Yeah, I'd have lit
your ass up.
Know this.
Because normally I'd want to
strangle this trick, but it
was the Obama hope sticker that
convinced me to Barack
the choke and let
that bitch go.
That's my time.
Thank you guys for
paying attention.
ROVE MCMANUS: To Retta.
Oh, she's going to take it.
That's professional.
Let any aspiring comics out
there, either in the room or
watching this at home right
now, whenever you leave
anywhere, take your microphone
stand with you.
What were you doing with a
microphone stand there the
first place?
You need to question
your attitude.
Ladies and gentlemen, our
final performer of the
evening, are you ready?
Are you ready?
Oh my god, one of my favorites,
the host of one of
my favorite podcasts, "Walking
the Room," ladies and
gentlemen, Greg Behrendt.
GREG BEHRENDT: Hello,
hello, hello, hello.
Nice to see you.
Wow, this is exciting, guys.
Top line in the old YouTube
show, shit, at 50?
That shit is awesome.
Yeah, I'm 50 years old.
Well, you look awesome.
Yeah, I fucking iron my neck.
I look amazing, man.
I've had a pretty good career.
I've made some mistakes.
I'm not going to lie to you.
I had an audition for "Saturday
Night Live" years ago.
When I say audition,
it didn't happen.
I was standing outside 30 Rock
doing an imitation that I do.
I do voices, I do characters.
Yeah.
I've hid that, but I do them.
I do characters pretty
good, Bill Cosby
explaining the Holocaust.
They put the Jews
on the train.
Like, it's not a great
imitation, but HoloCosby is an
awesome t-shirt.
I'm going to make that t-shirt
later, if I feel like it, put
that little Michael Jordan
mustache on him.
He's got the patent
on that now.
How are you guys?
This is really--
[AUDIENCE CHEERING]
GREG BEHRENDT: I mean,
it's dope.
This is exciting.
I've had a pretty good life.
I have a family.
I've got a beautiful--
two daughters, beautiful.
One of them's nice, daughters.
Not nice, they're both nice,
just one likes me.
The other one doesn't like--
the younger.
The older one likes me.
11, she likes me.
The older daughter
likes me a lot.
Like, she thinks I'm
the sun and moon.
She really--
well, she's not a
genius, either.
She's not a bright person.
Doesn't make her a bad person,
she's just not a genius.
As a parent, I wouldn't be a
good guy if I pretended she
was smarter.
She's going to be the president
of nothing.
That doesn't make her not--
she's lovely.
She's a lovely person.
Do you know what she wanted
for her 11th birthday?
You know what's at the
top of her list?
She wanted a hug.
How about that?
You know what her second
favorite thing in
the whole world is?
Cartwheels.
If she could cartwheel
into a hug, she
would turn into a rainbow.
She's just not a genius,
that's all.
She's not a thinker,
She's just not a person who
puts things together.
Let me give you an example, just
so you don't think I'm
being a dick.
We're on an airplane.
She has a 7-Up in a can.
Flight attendant comes over and
says, would you like to
have a cup of ice with that?
She says, yes, I would.
Flight attendant puts
down a cup of ice.
My daughter looks at the cup,
looks at the can, and
takes a cube and--
she's really pretty.
Like, she's super--
she's gorgeous.
She's a very, very pretty--
she's just not a thinker.
Now let me explain my
younger one to you.
She's more complex.
She's seven.
She has an imaginary friend
that hates her.
Hang on.
And she don't give a fuck.
How weird is that?
She has a friend that she made
up with her mind that
doesn't like her.
And she's like, go
fuck yourself.
She already knows human beings
are going to be disappointing.
She was walking through the
house the other day on an
imaginary phone like
this, not talking.
I go, what are you doing?
She goes, I'm on hold.
That's weird.
And the other one is really--
I'm not comparing them because
they're both lovely.
They're both beautiful.
But the other one sort of fell
out of my wife's vagina with
big brown hair and beestung
lips and beautiful eyes.
And the little one came out with
the-- you know like when
the babies have hair--
barely any, like you've got to
push all three together and
put a bow in it so
that everyone
knows, oh, it's a chick.
Like, it's not a chick, but
you have to do that.
And then she has no depth
perception, so she had to have
these glasses.
And then all of her teeth came
through one hole at the front,
so she has to have this thing
called an expander where you
have to twist--
it's like an iron maiden
for your mouth.
And you put a key in there and
turn it at night so that her
teeth spread.
And then we've given
her a lisp.
She didn't have a lisp, but we
put plastic in our mouth so
now she talks.
It just has to be like this,
she doesn't have a choice.
And then when she's done
talking, she has to go and
suck it back in because her
mouth is filled with spit.
How about that?
Seven.
Maybe she's cynical.
She's kind of a punk.
I walked past her room
the other day.
She was talking to her friend,
telling what I did for living,
and she goes, yeah, I
think he's a clown.
First off, you're right.
But they take care
of each other.
That's the kind of cool thing,
because the older one, she's
excited by outside.
Like, oh my god, outdoors.
Everything is exciting to her.
And the younger one
is cynical.
They'll date at some point,
which will be exciting but
weird at the same time.
Because I live in a house
with just girls.
There's just nothing but
vagina at my house.
I don't have it in boxes.
What I'm saying is that
there's a lot
of women in my house.
And I'll probably be psyched
when they start dating, you
know what I mean?
I'll probably freak the dude
out that comes over because
I'll be excited there's
a man in the house, do
you know what I mean?
He'll knock on the door
with his fucking face.
And I'll be like, get in here!
What do you want to do?
Jerk off?
Watch a game?
Put a Tapout shirt on?
We can do that.
Hang on, my muffins are ready.
And then I'll go to
get muffins and
explain my apron to him.
The point is.
And then the older one will--
she'll date, and she'll get her
heart broken because she's
open hearted.
And she'll give her heart
to a dude, and he'll
fucking fuck it up.
But then she'll have her little
sister there to take
care of her, to watch
out for her.
And I sort of like to imagine
the scene, like a John Hughes
type movie where they're at high
school together because
they're only three
years apart.
True, that's my older daughter,
she gets her heart
broken and she runs off
down the hall, crying.
And then she goes to the
bathroom and she's in tears.
But then she notices her
reflection in the mirror, and
she's delighted by
reflections.
And then my little one will just
walk over to this dude
that's standing by the locker,
put out her cigarette, and go,
[LISPING]
if you fuck with my sister
again, fuck with my sister
again, I will kill you.
My imaginary friends hate me.
[SUCKING UP SALIVA]
My name's Greg Behrendt.
Thank you all very much.
ROVE MCMANUS: Greg Behrendt!
That's how you do it.
It is, it is, so I'm thinking.
That is it, ladies
and gentlemen.
That is our show.
Did you enjoy yourselves?
Yeah, you did.
It was free.
And for you at home it was
free, too, unless you pay
yourself to go into your own
house, in which case
that make no sense.
Coming up, it is comedy week,
of course, on YouTube.
This time tomorrow there will
be live improv, thank you to
the UCB people, on this stage.
So be sure to be part of that.
Yes, nice.
Good reaction.
That's the one to have.
A round of applause
for yourselves.
You guys have been
a great crowd.
Thank you to YouTube.
Thank you to Comedy Gives Back
for organizing tonight.
We are fighting malaria,
people, one annoying
mosquito at a time.
We are doing it.
Thanks very much
for having me.
Thanks to all our comics.
For you watching, I'm
Rove McManus.
Say hi to your mum for me.
Goodnight, everybody.
Thank you.
ANNOUNCER: This week on Comedy
Week Live, it's a
week full of laughs.
Tuesday night, get ready for a
show full of comedy based on
your own YouTube videos,
with UCB Comedy.
Wednesday, check out the hottest
up and comers in the
YouTube stand-up show.
Thursday, College Humor goes
from dusk 'til dawn with their
all-nighter.
And Friday night, we close it
out big, first with Set List
Live: Stand-up Without a Net,
and then the big music show,
featuring all your favorite
musical comedy acts, including
the godfather of them all,
Weird Al Yankovic.
All this week on Comedy
Week Live.