SHANE SMITH: So we go
see [INAUDIBLE].
Thank you, North Korea,
you blew our minds.
But time is ticking, we got into
North Korea and all I'm
going to have is footage of
monuments and libraries.
We're bummed.
I have the shits.
I don't know what the fuck
I'm eating half the time.
We're very tired.
We're going to go out getting
drunk with our guides tonight.
Hopefully they'll let
us shoot more.
I look like a used
car salesman from
Boca Raton or something.
What does anyone do at
Pyongyang at night?
There's nothing.
There's zero to do.
But in our hotel there's
a karaoke place.
And the only people who go to
karaoke are foreigners,
generals, and high-ranking
party officials.
MALE SPEAKER: Check,
check, check.
1, 2.
[INAUDIBLE]
1, 2, 1, 2.
SHANE SMITH: So we get drunk.
We meet these generals, we're
partying with them, and we're
like how do you get anything
done here?
How do we go see these
film studios?
And they were very cautious.
They said look, I'm not going to
stick my neck out and tell
you anything.
But here's a word of advice--
dress like us, pay your respects
to Kim Il-sung at the
statue, and see what happens.
So we're like, OK, let's
go get some clothes.
Problem is, you can't.
You can't go to a store, you
can't even handle the money.
So we had to find a tailor
and say hey, can
you make us a suit?
And by the way, we need
it in five hours.
What we want to do is we want
to get North Korean-like
clothes and a badge,
and go and pay
respects to Kim Il-sung.
MR. KIM: You say that
[INAUDIBLE]
Kim Il-sung.
You don't say--
SHANE SMITH: Kim Jong-Il.
MR. KIM: The Chairman
Kim Jong-Il, or
Great Leader Kim Jong-Il.
We only say it like that.
So please say it like that,
Great Leader Kim Jong-Il,
General Kim Jong-Il, and
Chairman Kim Jong-Il.
SHANE SMITH: And what
about Kim Il-sung?
Great leader?
MR. KIM: President
Kim Il-sung.
SHANE SMITH: President
OK.
Can we go to where he lies in
state, the Kim Il-sung Palace?
Great Leader Kim
Il-sung Palace?
MR. KIM: Great Leader Kim
Jong-Il, General Kim Jong-Il,
Chairman Kim Jong-Il.
SHANE SMITH: President
Kim Il-sung.
MR. KIM: Yeah.
SHANE SMITH: OK.
Now, does Kim Jong-Il
have a son?
MALE SPEAKER: Chairman.
MR. KIM: General Kim Jong-Il.
SHANE SMITH: Oh, General
Kim Jong-Il.
Does he have a son?
MR. KIM: I don't know.
We only respect our General
Kim Jong-Il.
SHANE SMITH: I'm going
to respect them both.
I'm going to leave flowers.
MR. KIM: That's a good
idea, that's perfect.
We are friends now.
SHANE SMITH: We're friends.
MR. KIM: If you respect to--
SHANE SMITH: We'll
be best friends.
MR. KIM: With your hearts.
Respect our General Kim Jong-Il
and President Kim
Il-sung with your hearts,
we'll be best friends.
SHANE SMITH: Good.
MR. KIM: [INAUDIBLE]
SHANE SMITH: I'm excited.
I can't wait.
I want like this, but lighter.
Yeah, yeah, perfect.
We're going to look like
that when we're done.
We're about to go pay our
respects to the Great Leader
Kim Il-sung, Eternal
President.
Let's go [? do it. ?]
After that, everything
changed.
Smiles all around.
What do you want to do?
Where you want to go?
And finally, they let
us go see the
North Korean film studios.
SHANE SMITH: Thank you.
So we're at the film studios in
Pyongyang in North Korea.
This is the Great Leader
Kim Il-sung
behind us with the cameras.
Let's go and check
out how they make
films in North Korea.
MR. PAK:
[SPEAKING KOREAN]
SHANE SMITH: General Kim Jong-Il
made a film of the
Great Leader Kim Il-sung?
He made a film?
[SPEAKING KOREAN]
SHANE SMITH: OK.
Shall we go inside?
So we're in the film
studio now.
We're being introduced by a
very amazing picture of
General Kim Jong-Il.
He's directing a mega-picture
of the war.
[WHISPERING]
It's totally insane.
I shouldn't say it's
totally insane.
It's totally insane.