[THEME MUSIC PLAYING]
STEVE SPANGLER: I'm Steve
Spangler, and I'm all about
making science fun.
For the last 20 years, I've
been teaching ways to turn
ordinary science experiments
into unforgettable learning
experiences.
I have an amazing team who will
do whatever it takes to
affect the way people
think about science.
And to do that, I live
by one motto--
make it big, do it right,
give it class.
Just finished that great
Thanksgiving meal.
Boy, am I full.
So the deal is this-- there's
lots of toothpicks around.
And if you're like 80 years old,
you know what this is,
but if you're a little kid you
don't even know why they even
use toothpicks.
For science experiments.
Here's what you're going to do--
you're going to bend some
toothpicks like this, and you're
going to form them into
the shape of a star.
This is what we want our little
project to look like,
but the toothpicks actually have
to start out on a plate
like this right here.
And without touching it, you
turn it from this into this.
How do you do that?
I'll show you.
Watch.
It didn't work.
Since that last strategy clearly
did not work, we're
making another one.
So notice how you break it just
like this, not all the
way through.
This completes a last little
piece right here.
So the object is to go from
here and to make it
open up as a star.
Believe it or not, the
secret is a straw.
And you're going to put the
straw down in some water, and
put your finger in the end,
and pick up just a
little bit of water.
You don't want much at all--
just a couple drops.
It goes right into the
middle-- watch.
It's not that the water just
pushed out the toothpicks, but
instead the toothpicks
absorbed the water.
And when it absorbs the water,
the little capillaries that
make up the wood literally
went from this to
pushing back out again.
And in doing so, it literally
just pushed those pieces out
to form the little star.
So you might want to practice
and try some different
things-- some different kinds
of liquid, maybe different
kinds and styles of toothpick
to be able to
get your best burst.
But once you've got it, hoard
the toothpicks, because you're
going to want to
do it forever.
It's pretty cool.
This little trick is going to
teach all those people who
give you more silverware
than you need at your
fancy little dinner.
You know how they always
give you two forks?
Well, snag one of them, because
you're going to need
two of them at the very
end of the meal.
And you're going to need
to have a water glass.
And a toothpick.
So here's what the
challenge is.
You need to balance these forks
on the rim of the glass,
using just this toothpick.
And you can't break
the glass, and you
can't use Gorilla Glue.
That's pretty much everything.
Well, and magnets.
And you can't use duct tape--
for sure not duct tape.
You can't use Elmer's glue,
Superglue, c-clamps, radiator
hose clamps--
any other things like that.
That's what you can't use.
You just can use the
toothpick and this.
And your brain.
So here's the secret.
You're going to jam
these little tines
together, like that.
So this is what you're looking
for, this little system.
And then it's going to take a
little work, but you're going
to try to get the toothpick
in through both sides.
I've got an opening here at the
top that you can just work
the toothpick in a little bit
more, and you've got it.
So here's what we're
going to try to do.
We're going to try to rest this
on the edge of the glass.
The trick here is to get the
center of gravity down below
that balance point
right there.
So the object here is to balance
it on the glass.
It's going to go to
the very edge.
And you've got it.
A lot of people think
it's done.
No, it's not done, because
now we introduce
the element of fire.
Watch.
See, you burn this part here,
and you burn this part over
here, and here comes
pending disaster.
You'll notice that the stick
stopped burning the moment it
got to the glass.
That's because the glass-- the
rim of the glass absorbed that
heat energy away from the wood
and caused it to go out.
Same thing with the
metal over here.
It absorbs that heat energy.
So it just naturally goes out,
burns everything to the very
end, because the real support is
only at that one point, and
you have a system that is
in perfect balance.
And a trick that's guaranteed
to amaze your friends.
It's pretty good.
So this one, you're going to
need to have some money-- a
couple nickels.
So clear an area on the table,
put the nickel on the table,
put the other nickel so it's
perpendicular, like this.
And of course, the theme
today, toothpicks--
so you're going to
need to have that
toothpick right there.
You're going to try to balance
the toothpick right on the
edge like that.
I can kick it over just
a little bit more.
Balance it just like that.
Now, the object is to move the
toothpick, but you can't touch
the toothpick.
And the problem is, it's so
precariously balanced that
just breathing on it would move
it, so that's where the
cup comes in.
Because now you cover the whole
thing with the cup, and
now, without touching the glass,
the object is to move
the toothpick.
How would you do it?
The secret--
a balloon.
Blow it up.
Now you're not going to pop
the balloon and cause that
burst to move it.
You're actually going to use
something as simple as static
electricity.
So you're just going to build
up some static electricity
here-- that's about right.
Now we're going to take that
over and get it close to the
toothpick, and watch.
So you're just trying to
discharge the electrons in the
balloon, and these electrons
literally are able to push
that stick around, and to move
it in such a way until it
finally discharges.
But it totally looks like
magic, doesn't it?
And very cool how you can move
it even under the glass.
Now, even with the glass
off, you can try it.
Try different kinds
of glasses.
See whether or not plastic is
the only thing that you can
use, or whether or not
an actual glass
container will work.
It's ridiculously cool, and it
almost looks like magic.
Secret?
Electrons.
[HIGH-PITCHED NOISE]
STEVE SPANGLER: It's the sound
that annoyed every mom in the
world, unless your mom was the
cool mom that actually taught
you how to do this.
My mom.
So listen to this.
[HIGH-PITCHED NOISE]
STEVE SPANGLER: It's
very, very cool.
The way that this works
is stick and slide.
Not every cup works.
Like for example, this
cup here doesn't work
very well at all.
Even with water inside--
[SCREECHING NOISE]
STEVE SPANGLER: --you just get
this screeching thing.
Not as good as this thin-walled
glass here.
[HIGH-PITCHED NOISE]
STEVE SPANGLER: The secret
is stick and slide.
Your finger sticks and then
slides, and that stick and
slide creates a vibration.
[HIGH-PITCHED NOISE]
STEVE SPANGLER: Vibration
creates a sound.
Here's what I'm going to ask you
do, is find two glasses.
Start with them identical.
That's usually not hard, since
you buy them in a set, right?
And try to get them so they're
exactly the same sound.
We're going to try to make
this so it's sympathetic.
We'd like to have the vibration
from one go
to the other one.
In comes the toothpick.
Balance a toothpick on the rim
of the glass that you're not
going to vibrate.
Take the other glass.
Vibrate it.
Get it close, but not close
enough to touch, and see
whether or not you can transfer
the vibration.
Watch.
[HIGH-PITCHED NOISE]
STEVE SPANGLER: See?
If you start to transfer that
vibration, you get movement in
the toothpick.
That's what you're
looking for.
You're looking for
that vibration.
[GASP]
Forwards, and sometimes going
the opposite direction can
make it go opposite.
Guaranteed not to amaze your
friends, but to annoy
everybody at the table.
[HIGH-PITCHED NOISE]
STEVE SPANGLER: OK, somebody
will be amazed.
If you look this up online,
you're going to find a lot of
people doing this, but the
directions they have are you
have to have identical glasses,
identical amounts of water--
[HIGH-PITCHED NOISE]
STEVE SPANGLER: --and that's how
the vibration moves from
one glass to the next.
However, a little
experimentation, which now
turns this into a real
experiment and not just a
table trick, is to find
two different glasses.
So for example, look at this.
Two different style
of wine glasses--
one a little shorter, and
one a little bit bigger.
That means that it had different
amounts of water--
[HIGH-PITCHED NOISE]
STEVE SPANGLER: --to give
you the same sound.
Listen.
[HIGH-PITCHED NOISE]
STEVE SPANGLER: Pretty close.
Let's see whether or not
we can cause the
toothpick to move.
Watch.
[HIGH-PITCHED NOISE]
STEVE SPANGLER: See, it will
still move, because it's not
about the volume of the water
or the size of the glass.
It's about the frequency of the
tone that you're creating.
That energy is literally
transferring from one
container to the next.
Look at that toothpick move.
It's all because we tried to
experiment and prove something
wrong that somebody said
was an absolute.
This is beautiful.
So what do you do at the
end of any good meal?
Sit here and pick your teeth?
No.
Even though you've just amazed
everyone with your little
toothpick tricks, you
offer to clean up.
But you always start with the
tablecloth, because that's
what's dirty first.
So you just take the tablecloth
like this, and--
perfect.
Now you can wipe your mouth,
and you're ready to go.
All right, you want
to learn how to do
the tablecloth trick.
It's actually very cool, and
one of the secrets is
selecting the right
tablecloth.
Now most tablecloths that people
use are nice, and they
don't work.
And the reason they don't work
is because they have a hem.
Look at this one here.
There's no hem.
See, I just literally
cut the edges off.
This means that it gets to be a
little frayed after a while,
and it's not very pretty.
But this is exactly what we
want, because we don't want
there to be any bump or anything
that would interrupt
the flow of the cloth.
When you learn how to do the
tablecloth trick, you're
learning about the laws of
inertia, or the tendency of an
object to stay at rest until
a force acts upon it.
Thanks, Newton.
It starts with a little
bit of practice.
You start this way.
Now, I've got a piece of cloth
here that's probably 1 meter
by 1 meter, so almost
a yard by a yard.
You're going to practice doing
this-- you lay it out on the
table, and your hands, I
think, are the secret.
Because you hold the
cloth like this.
I actually fold it up a little
bit in my hands and hang it
over the edge like this.
I never go above the table.
I'm going to start
below the table.
It forces me to pull
straight down.
You pull straight down
to your toes.
So you can hear the
whipping sound.
Listen to this, listen.
[WHIPPING SOUND]
STEVE SPANGLER: That's what
you're looking for.
Practice that a couple times.
All right, a hundred times,
I don't care.
But if you don't practice
this, you're going to be
ruining some dishes.
Second thing--
the dishes.
Notice how this is smooth
on the bottom.
You're going to run to garage
sales and try to find dishes
that are smooth here
on the bottom.
If they're rough or they have--
the more expensive they
are, probably the more rough
they're going to be, with a
little edge, and you
don't want those.
So this nice and smooth will
be perfect, because we want
very little friction between
the cloth and the dishes.
So that when you're pulling the
cloth out from underneath,
then it slides very easily.
So find dishes that have no
little things that will grab
on the bottom, and this'll
be perfect.
Third part, the glasses.
I like to call these the
convincer, because glasses by
themselves are perfect,
especially when you take water
and you fill these with water.
What you're actually doing,
believe it or not, is making
it easier on yourself, because
you're increasing the mass.
See, once you increase the
mass, you increase the
inertia, or the tendency of an
object to stay at rest until
some sort of force
acts upon it.
The force here-- gravity
pulling down.
Of course, the table below,
supporting it, so there's no
movement at all.
And hopefully, we can slip
the tablecloth right out.
Other things you're going to
need-- forks, of course, find
a knife, spoon.
The only thing that you
don't want to use--
wineglasses.
See, they're too heavy on the
top, and so a wineglass can
fairly easily tip over.
You might find one that works
well, but for me, this seems
to be the perfect setup.
Remember, straight down, and
notice that I didn't put a lot
of the tablecloth over there.
As I'm practicing, I'm going
to set this off to the side
like this and allow the edge
to sneak out first.
It just makes it a little bit
easier as you're starting.
Right straight down to your
toes, watch this--
three, two--
it's that easy.
The best part of learning the
tablecloth trick is you can
come up with your
own variations.
So here, take a look at this.
Everybody's seen the standard
whip the tablecloth off, and
you've got a couple dishes.
Let's try this.
Here's the glass here.
Here's the plate, glasses.
And now you take another plate
on top of the glass like this.
And now the glass goes on top.
This is going to be hard
enough-- don't get crazy.
All right, here we go.
Three, two, one--
awesome.
[THEME MUSIC PLAYING]
STEVE SPANGLER: Well, now you
have everything you need to
ensure that Aunt Gertrude never
invites you over to her
house for Thanksgiving again.
Because who likes to go
to her house anyway?
So, Happy Halloween.
DIRECTOR: Cut!
STEVE SPANGLER: No--
You know what's fun to do?
Maybe you don't like going
to Thanksgiving dinner.
So here's what you do-- glue all
the plates secretly to the
tablecloth, and when
you whip it off--
that's a surprise.
You know the best part
of doing this stuff?
It's because you never have to
sit at the adult table again,
because who likes to sit
at the adult table?
Especially next to Uncle Bob.
Uncle Bob's always going--
[SNORING SOUNDS]
and then you've got Clyde over
there, who's always telling
war stories. "You know, back
when I was a kid--" You don't
want to sit at that table.
You want to sit at the fun
table, the kids' table.
Problem with sitting
at the kids' table?
Boogers.