It's a good move.
How many types of messages do
you send, and how do you
decide what message you send?
Great question.
So I can share a little
bit of stats.
At this point, we do send
hundreds of thousands of
messages each month.
That might sound like a lot,
but for example, one search
engine named Blekko estimated
that a million spam pages are
created every hour.
So the web is very large, so
it shouldn't be a surprise
that some percentage
of it is spam.
And as a result, we do spend a
lot of time finding that spam.
And since we automatically
send messages and
notifications when we find it,
there are a lot, hundreds of
thousands of notifications that
we send out each month.
There's a lot of different
categories of spam.
They're covered in our
Webmaster Guidelines,
everything from cloaking to
scraping to sneaky JavaScript
redirects, paid links,
all sorts of stuff.
But all of those boil down to
roughly about 10 different
messages that we send.
So hidden text, keyword
stuffing, gibberish, all that
would go into one message
that we send out.
I can share some stats from
earlier this year, from
January and February.
Out of the hundreds of thousands
of messages that we
sent over that time period,
roughly 90% of those were for
what we call Black Hat.
That's pure, egregious spam,
clear cut, anybody
sufficiently tech savvy would
probably be able to recognize
that it's spam.
It's the stuff that you think
of as traditional junk that
you just don't want to show up
in your results because it is
very clearly spam.
About 4% of the messages were
because the content had little
or no added value, and so it's
not ranking as highly in our
search results.
About 3% of the messages
that we sent
were related to hacking.
So hacking is a big attack
as far as Black Hats.
And even though it's illegal,
there's a lot of people that
do that-- trying to promote
their pharmacy pills or
whatever, that sort of thing.
So about 3% of those messages
were related to hacking.
Something like 2% of the
messages that we sent out were
related to link buying,
and about 1% were
related to link selling.
So overall between 2% and 3%
related to links and link spam
overall about buying
and selling links.
So that gives you a broad idea
of the sorts of categories
that we send things out for
and the rough number of
messages that we send
out each month.