THOMAS MORTON: The area around
Maraba is all cleared pasture.
The only leftover signs of the
rainforest are the castanero
nut trees, which farmers leave
standing because they're
protected by law, and babassu,
which is the first thing that
grows back when farmland
is left unused.
Even though 20 years ago Maraba
was in the middle of
the jungle, these days it looks
like Texas, and the
people act like it's Texas.
Everybody's truck is huge.
Everybody's cowboy
hat is huge.
Domestic violence
is very popular.
And far and away the biggest
show in town is the city
cattle expo and rodeo.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
This is the culture
of the Ruralistas.
It's basically cowboy culture.
And it's what's taking
over the Amazon.
[BLOWING HORN]
[SPEAKING PORTUGUESE]
THOMAS MORTON: Giovanni Queiroz
is a representative
for the state of Para and one
of the leaders of the
Ruralistas in Congress.
People are worried that
deforestation is
happening too rapidly.
Do you feel the same
thing down here?
[SPEAKING PORTUGUESE]
[MUSIC PLAYING AND ANNOUNCER]
THOMAS MORTON: What
do you personally
think about the activists?
Do you think they
have a point?
[SPEAKING PORTUGUESE]
[MUSIC PLAYING AND ANNOUNCER]
[COWS MOOING]
MALE SPEAKER: About 75% of the
clear land is occupied by
pasture where people
raise cattle.
This is the deforestation
rates.
And these peaks, they are
associated with the increase
of price of agriculture
commodities, especially beef.
In these areas, you have a
lot of very bad pasture.
Because they opened, but they
don't have a proper
management.
So the efficiency of these
cattle ranges is quite low.
There is little amount of
cattle in the huge area.
THOMAS MORTON: All this land
we're in right now it, which
just looks kind of like crummy
pastureland, well, this
actually used to be the forest
like 30 years ago.
This is what happens 30 years
later when the land's no good
for farming.
It isn't worth raising
cattle on.
It's a waste.
It's kind of like
crack farming.
You get like two or three years
of good stuff, then you
have to go find your next fix.
MALE SPEAKER: Sometimes people
say, well, we need to occupy
the Amazon to generate wealth.
But this wealth is generated
only when you have forest.
And after that, you have
actually more poor people than
you had before.
It's very important to note that
about 42% of the Amazon
biome is under some form
of protection.
It's quite dangerous now because
people want to harvest
anything that is left.
For example, a lot of loggers
they go into indigenous lands.
It's not their land.
They are not allowed
to go there.
But they go there and harvest.
THOMAS MORTON: We're just
now entering a protected
indigenous land.
And we're going to visit a
village of Kayapo people.
They lead traditional lives,
and they basically have to
fight off illegal loggers and
settlers to keep their ways.
James Cameron called them
"the real Avatars."
[SPEAKING PORTUGUESE]
THOMAS MORTON: We just got
to the Kayapo village.
It looks like everybody
is in that hut.
Felipe said it was the warrior
hut, which is like the center
of every Kayapo village.
They're watching
a soccer game.
Today's Brazil versus
Paraguay.
It's a big game.
Once the game was over,
they invited us in to
explain why we'd come.
First of all, I'd like
to thank you all
for welcoming us.
We just spent three hours kind
of explaining ourselves to the
men in the community.
And I think they think
we're on their level.
Everybody's really nice.
Tomorrow we're going
to party with them.
Tonight we're sleeping
in hammocks.
[KAYAPO TRIBE SINGING]
THOMAS MORTON: The wake-up
call's kind of intense.
[KAYAPO TRIBE SINGING]
THOMAS MORTON: What's nice about
this village is they've
kind of picked and chosen the
little aspects of whatever
Western culture technology
that worked for them and
blended it into their
everyday lives.
It kind of puts the lie to this
exoticized version we get
in America that our influence
is going to corrupt them and
destroy something that should be
left exactly the same as it
was for 1,000 years.
These people haven't been
the same as they
were for 1,000 years.
And it's kind of like
the rainforest, too.
You don't have to keep
it exactly as it is.
You just got to not destroy
the whole thing.
[KAYAPO WOMEN SINGING]
THOMAS MORTON: And now we're
supposed to go get dressed for
a party because they complained
that we look naked.
[KAYAPO TRIBE SINGING]
[SPEAKING KAYAPO]
[KAYAPO TRIBE CHANTING
AND SINGING]
THOMAS MORTON: We spoke with all
the different members of
the tribe about what's going on
in their little stretch of
the Amazon.
[SPEAKING KAYAPO]
THOMAS MORTON: We talked
to the men.
We talked to the women.
We talked to the elders.
We talked to the chief.
We talked to the young guys.
They all told us roughly
the same thing.
[SPEAKING KAYAPO]
THOMAS MORTON: Like Ze Claudio
and Maria, the Kayapo aren't
just conservationists or
tree-hugger types.
They make their living off the
rainforest, and they're
fighting to preserve
that way of life.
The problem is, their way of
life is terminally at odds
with people like the
Ruralistas' vision of progress.
[SPEAKING KAYAPO]
[KAYAPO TRIBE CHANTING
AND SINGING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[SPEAKING KAYAPO]
THOMAS MORTON: The only outlet
interested in publishing
Felipe's interview with Ze
Claudio was the Brazilian
edition of VICE.
[SPEAKING KAYAPO]
THOMAS MORTON: Ze Claudio and
Maria's story might have faded
into the woodwork, like that
of so many other murdered
activists, if not for one
major coincidence.
The same day as Ze Claudio and
Maria were murdered, the Lower
House of Brazil's Congress was
voting on controversial
changes to the country's
Forest Code.
The Ruralistas had pushed for
revisions which would loosen
federal regulations on logging
in the Amazon.
The measure passed.
But right before the vote, the
deputy of the Brazilian Green
Party stood up and read part
of Felipe's article to
announce their deaths.
We're in the congressional
offices right now in Brasilia.
We're going to go meet with
Deputy Sarney Filho.
He's a Green Party member.
And he's the guy who stood up
on the floor of Congress the
day that Ze Claudio and Maria
were murdered and read from
the VICE blog, an interview
with him about him being
threatened, and he got booed
by the Ruralista block.
THOMAS MORTON: This place
beats the shit
out of American Congress.
It looks kind of like
Miami Beach in 1962.
I think my grandma
had this carpet.
Thank you, Deputy, for taking
your time to talk to us.
Can you tell me what's going on
with the Forest Code right
now, with the new provisions
for it?
[SPEAKING PORTUGUESE]
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE]
THOMAS MORTON: This is the
Lower House of Brazilian
Congress, kind of like
the House of
Representatives in the US.
And this is where Deputy Sarney
Filho read Felipe's
article about Ze Claudio
and Maria the day
that they were murdered.
[SPEAKING PORTUGUESE]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
THOMAS MORTON: As soon as Felipe
heard the news about
the murder, he flew
back to Maraba.
He joined Baixista, the family,
and more than 4,000
people who came together to take
part in Ze Claudio and
Maria's funeral.
[SPEAKING PORTUGUESE]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[APPLAUSE AND CHEERING]
[SINGING IN PORTUGUESE]
[SPEAKING KAYAPO]
[SINGING PORTUGUESE]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
THOMAS MORTON: The same day as
the funeral, word came down
from the settlement
of another murder.
And man named Erivelton dos
Santos had been missing for
several days.
After discovering his abandoned
motorcycle under a
cloud of vultures, federal
police led a search party into
the jungle.
[SPEAKING PORTUGUESE]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[SINGING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
THOMAS MORTON: It's not clear
whether Erivelton actually
witnessed anything or if his
death was even related to Ze
Claudio and Maria's.
Nevertheless, his murder
escalated the
tension in the region.
In the days following Ze
Claudio and Maria's
assassination, alternate
theories for their death
started cropping up in the local
press and rumor mill.
A lot of people tried to claim
they'd just been killed over
an interpersonal dispute, a
fight between neighbors.
However, one thing was clear
from the scene of the crime.
Whoever killed Ze Claudio
and Maria had not
acted on their own.
After being shot, one of Ze
Claudio's ears was cut off as
proof of his death, a telltale
sign of a murder for hire.
[SPEAKING PORTUGUESE]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
THOMAS MORTON: Is it reasonable
to expect that
there will actually be justice
or any sort of
action in this case?
[SPEAKING PORTUGUESE]
THOMAS MORTON: Two months
after the murder, police
announced three suspects
to the deaths of
Ze Claudio and Maria.
According to police, a small
farmer named Ze Rodriguez had
ordered the assassination, which
was carried out by his
brother, Lyndon Johnson Silva,
and another man, Alberto Lopes
de Nascimento.
The immediate reason for
the murder was a
dispute over land.
Ze Rodriguez had tried to
illegally purchase lots inside
the settlement, and Ze Claudio
had stopped him.
The state police launched a
joint man hunt with the
federal police involving
more than 65 officers.
After a 40-day search, Ze
Rodriguez and his brother were
found hiding in a shack over
100 miles away from the
settlement.
They were still carrying
the murder weapons.
The third guy was found
a few days later.
While the killers capture is
a good start, they're still
awaiting trial and a long way
from being convicted.
At the same time, it's very
likely there were bigger
interests behind the murder
involving people who may never
be held accountable.
[SPEAKING PORTUGUESE]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
THOMAS MORTON: Ze Claudio and
Maria's story is fairly
exceptional, both in the
attention it's received and in
the fact that this attention
may lead to
some measure of justice.
MALE SPEAKER: Maria is here
and Ze Claudio is here.
THOMAS MORTON: Their story
however is not unique.
The same struggle is played
out every day across the
Amazon between those who want to
use the forest sustainably
and those in search of profits,
and ultimately, by
the very forces that
shape Brazil's
economy and social structure.
[SPEAKING PORTUGUESE]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
THOMAS MORTON: Oh, wow.
[SPEAKING PORTUGUESE]
[MUSIC PLAYING]