SAMIR KRIM: That was
a fun cruise.
Like, we would just go from
Bastille, which is on the
other side of town, and we would
just ride, you know?
All along the Seine.
Come skate that spot, then go
skate that spot, then go skate
the museum.
And in the day, you just went
through the whole city.
This is Rue des Saints Peres.
It's a cool spot we used to hang
out, back then when they
didn't put this bar.
It used to be just
manual pads.
You go from the top, and
you just go down.
You don't even have to push.
Just manual, trick, manual,
trick, and then [INAUDIBLE]
at the end.
SAMIR KRIM: No.
See?
There's no one now, because
you've got to have a little
pop to skate the thing.
It's dead now.
It's so bad, because in the
middle of Paris here was a
cool hangout spot.
And you're in the nice
neighborhood.
This is actually the
Medical University.
The girl's still coming out.
It's very funny.
-Do Parisian girls
like skaters?
SAMIR KRIM: I don't know.
They don't like Joseph,
though.
I don't think it's nice to pick
up girls with the line,
hey, I skate.
It's just like a hobby
here, you know?
You skate.
That's a hobby.
That's it.
Maybe like 10 people here in
France live out of skating,
but the rest is just
for fun, you know?
JOSEPH BIAIS: [SPEAKING FRENCH]
SAMIR KRIM: He always picks on
me for not skating around, and
just sticking [INAUDIBLE].
And I'm like, yo, when I was
your age, me and my friends,
we used to just skate all around
the city, cruising,
finding new spots.
I'm older now.
I'm like 10 years older than
him, and if I go out for
skating, it's like,
I got two hours.
So I'm just going to go to a
spot, meet up with the boys,
and just skate, you know?
He's always like, yo,
let's go cruise.
And I'm like, I did that.
We did that.
JOSEPH BIAIS: [SPEAKING FRENCH]
SAMIR KRIM: He's always like,
oh, you used to skate there.
You used to skate there.
Like, yeah.
JOSEPH BIAIS: [SPEAKING FRENCH]
SAMIR KRIM: He always skates
with different people.
Like, anyone is in town, he
will go skate with him.
That's what's cool with him.
In it for the right reasons.
We're in Bastille right now.
Bastille is center
of the city.
It's my center of the city.
That's where I grew up.
I grew up like a block from
here, and it's really like my
neighborhood here.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
It became actually one real spot
here in Paris, because it
was one of the first ledge
spots we really had
downtown, you know?
-Who was the first person
you saw skate here?
SAMIR KRIM: I think the
first one is these
guys from Mad Circle--
Scott Johnston, Rene Matthyssen,
and I think Rob
[INAUDIBLE] was there too.
I was going out of school, and
every night after school, I
would meet up my friends here.
I think I showed up early, like
around 5:00 or something,
and I'm just here alone with
those guys, and the skating.
It was just crazy.
And then one day, they put those
anti-skate things to
keep us away from here.
JOSEPH BIAIS: [SPEAKING FRENCH]
SAMIR KRIM: [SPEAKING FRENCH]
SAMIR KRIM: There's
a lot to skate.
Like, these little gaps, this
ledge, the little manual pad
right there.
It's a generation
thing, you know?
It's like, there's always a new
spot, new group of people,
then it's going to be the
next one, and then--
so we're just at that time.
That timing.
It was us skating here.
There's a lot of memories
when I come here.
I just remember a
lot of things--
the people that skate here
with us, the stories that
happened to us, you know?
One day, one guy just shot
himself right there.
We were trying to go to the
phone, and trying to call the
police and stuff, and
the guy is just--
he missed himself, you know?
He's just on the floor
like that, with a
little bit of blood.
JOSEPH BIAIS: So where I live,
the train station is just in
front of my house.
So I just have to walk for 20
seconds, take the train, and I
am in the center of Paris.
-Did you tell your parents the
first time you were going to
skate here?
JOSEPH BIAIS: No.
I didn't tell them, because they
were afraid about that,
because I was young,
and alone, and very
far from the house.
They don't really like it.
So the first time I went with
a couple of friends, and we
skated the city.
SAMIR KRIM: Yeah, that's what
skating's all about, right?
Pushing the limit.
Everyone's like, don't
go further than this.
I remember the first time we
went to Bercy was such an
expedition for us.
My mom was like,
never go there.
I think a lot of people from
Europe come here to just film
lines because it looks
good in their video.
It's a famous spot, so people
are like, all right, I had a
line at that Bercy spot, or I
jumped on the [INAUDIBLE].
JOSEPH BIAIS: Maybe it's the
most easy spot to find,
because everybody knows
the name is Bercy.
SAMIR KRIM: It's easy
to find too.
The subway's right there.
You go, and then it's it.
You see the skaters, and
they're right there.
Ledges all around.
This gap for the people that
want to jump or die.
We didn't start skating that
until the mid-'90s.
I remember like when we came
here and put the first wax on
this ledge, because before,
skating was just, like, little
ledge, little curb.
Just trying to ollie it.
And you know, by the end of the
'90s, skating was a lot of
ledge, so it became
a paradise for us.
We'd come here every day, stay
here all day, all night.
-Perfect.
We were filming for a video
in '95 or something.
We just came here.
[INAUDIBLE], and just broke my
ankle, and I never skated that
thing again.
JOSEPH BIAIS: [SPEAKING FRENCH]
SAMIR KRIM: Go, go, go.
Jump.
They think like some
guy [INAUDIBLE].
How fuckin' crazy is that?
-Who's the real French
street skater?
SAMIR KRIM: For me,
Stephane was.
Everywhere you go, you see
Stephane Larance skating.
He was so good.
He could do everything.
I'm talking 12 years ago, 15
years ago, he was all the way
on top of everything.
I saw him skate here, skate at
the dome, skate everywhere.
Skate the wave.
He would just skate
everything.
He was very, very good.
JOSEPH BIAIS: Stephane was
the most famous Parisian.
skater.
Because I'm not from Paris, I am
from the suburbs, and when
I was very young, I used to come
in Paris and have a one
hour train journey
to come here.
And so I was coming to the dome
and saying, oh, there's
Stephane Larance.
STEPHANE LARANCE: We're at
the dome, one of the
main spots in Paris.
It's pretty cool, because you
can just come no matter the
weather or the time.
There will always
be skaters here.
It's really crazy because it's
all marble and it's pretty
smooth and open space.
And people just let us skate.
There was always a big
scene in Paris.
And I met one guy that
was a skater that
was skating at Trocadero.
Then we became friends, and he
took me to skate with the guys
at Trocadero.
Then I just came here
every week.
We just came down,
and they were--
actually, there was nothing
here but marble--
like, pieces of marble
everywhere.
And we were just looking at this
platform up there, and we
just thought that they were
building a skate spot for us.
-So when they were finishing
down below, this is where you
guys skated?
STEPHANE LARANCE: Yeah,
this is where we
were skating, yeah.
The ledge and the stair were
just going in circles all day.
Some of the best skate memories
have been here.
-Is there a certain trick that
you saw on this ledge that you
were like, man, I can't believe
someone did that.
STEPHANE LARANCE: Yeah.
Flo.
Gnarly Crook.
Flo just killed this spot.
And this spot used
to be so smooth.
It's so good now.
It's all cracked everywhere.
The spot has had too
much success.
If you come here in the
summertimes, so
many skaters here.
-Has it ever been a problem
skating here?
STEPHANE LARANCE: Yeah.
There's always problems.
But every two years or
something, they just try to
get the skaters out of here, and
it just lasts for like a
month or two.
And then, since everybody just
come and skate here anyway,
they just sort of give up.
And so they just let us skate.
-So this was the
big double set.
STEPHANE LARANCE: Yeah.
Pretty big double set.
We've been skating this spot for
a long time, but not a lot
of tricks have been done.
Only a few manage to skate it,
because it takes a lot of
energy to push, then to fall,
then to go back and to push
and to fall.
It's even bigger when
you try to skate it.
It's really big.
"FRENCH" FRED MORTAGNE:
I spent about 15
million hours here.
'94 to, I don't know, '97, '96,
we've been here all the
time filming.
That's where I pretty much
learned filming.
Yeah, this spot is the
main plaza in Lyon.
When they finally finished
it in '94, it
was like, oh, paradise.
When they finished the plaza,
that was the turning point
where skateboarding went back
to the street in Lyon.
Watching the first 411s, there
was virtually all the
skateboard community in 411.
Each new issue, I was like, I'm
sure there's going to be
some French guys.
And they never came.
And I was like, ahh!
So maybe I have to do it.
I'm filming.
Maybe I'll just send footage,
and maybe they want to use it.
And that's what happened.
411 people like Steve Douglas,
I sent him all the VHS videos
from here, and then he was like,
oh, it's really good.
You should send stuff for
411 And then J.B.,
oh, it's really good.
And the second time I
sent a video, J.B.
Had improved a lot.
He was skating really well.
And then they were like,
oh, that's it.
We want [INAUDIBLE].
So I was like, oh, videos
are important.
So that was the first thing that
pushed me to keep going.
And we were doing it for a
purpose, not just for fun.
But it was helping people,
so that was good.
That was a good thing.
As you can see, it's in really
bad condition right now.
I think they redid
the place twice--
completely renewed the ledges.
But they get fucked up really
quick, and then only the other
ones they're really strong.
-What kind of stuff has been
done on this thing?
I mean, again, it seems like
everything I see here is from
J.B., but--
"FRENCH" FRED MORTAGNE: Oh,
Jeremie was skating this thing
in a different way.
It's the only one that I know
that he will lead from one
side to the other straight.
That's pretty difficult.
Yeah, Jeremie is the one who's
been doing all the best stuff,
because there's the crack
at the bottom.
We used to put cement so it
smoothed, but now people got
used to skating it this way.
So when you're not a local, it's
not easy to skate without
the cement.
But Jeremie is like, oh,
it doesn't matter.
JEREMIE DACLIN: When
we were 17, I got
interviewed by French TV.
They were saying, how do
you see your future?
And I said, I don't see myself
skating when I'm 20 years old,
because it's kind of
lame or whatever.
But I'm 35 and I'm
still skating.
I was riding for Flip when they
moved to America, and I
didn't really want to do it.
So I thought the best solution
was to start a Euro company
that can pay riders so they
can stay in Europe.
Lots of good riders were riding
in Europe, and they
weren't even getting paid.
And if they wanted
to get paid, they
had to move to America.
Nowadays, you can be pro
and live in Europe.
Before, it was impossible.
SEB CURTIS: I was driving back
to Scotland with my folks, and
I bought a couple of magazines
just for the
road back in the car.
And I remember, I think it
probably was about '96, and I
didn't really know anything
about French
skateboarding at that time.
And I was just looking through
this French magazine--
it was like, I thought this guy
was fucking killing it.
And it was Jeremie that was
doing a frontside lipslide
down a handrail or something
like that.
And I think the actual interview
in it was, if I
remember correctly, he was going
on about how he didn't
want to move to the States.
And he was going on about how
many rippers there are in
France, and you can
still do it here.
And he was even saying
it then.
If you ask the older dudes that
kind of stopped skating
now, used to skate back in the
day, all the stories, like,
Jeremie did this.
Jeremie did that.
Way back in the day.
The shit he's done is
pretty ridiculous.
It definitely played a
big part in European
skateboarding.
JEREMIE DACLIN: Foch.
Because it's the train station
stop, and it's where we are.
-How far is it from
the Hotel de Vile?
JEREMIE DACLIN: It's across
the bridge from the river.
-Who's the first person
to skate this spot?
JEREMIE DACLIN: I
think it was me.
First I did ollie [INAUDIBLE]
on it, and then 50/50 on it.
-When's the last time
you skated here?
JEREMIE DACLIN: I mean,
really skated?
A long time ago.
But I come here every day to
skate the mini ramp, because
there's also a mini ramp.
And every time there's some
skaters who are coming to Lyon
they want to see it.
JEREMIE DACLIN: I really want
to see a lipslide on it, but
you need to be goofy
foot to do it.
And yeah.
JEREMIE DACLIN: There's one, but
you'll see it in the next
Cliche video.
HUGO LIARD: We are here
at the mini ramp.
It's our mini ramp.
We built it.
Really famous, because actually,
it was the first
place of the film "Lumiere."
They start the cinema--
the movie.
It was here.
They filmed the door
in front of there.
People come and squat, they
start to build some places,
and start to do some
art stuff.
And then we come, and we start
to do some skate stuff.
I am living here.
I built my house here.
We tried to build something
different.
Until the wall fall, we're
gonna stay here.
JULIEN "JU JU" BACHELIER:
Welcome to
Hugo's place and Vincent.
HUGO LIARD: So yeah.
This guy here, Vincent,
this guy.
Everywhere here, they're
playing music.
They built the house six years
ago, and then after, one year
ago, I came here, and
said yeah, it's
possible to build it.
So I built it.
It's perfect.
And I have internet,
and a kitchen.
Perfect.
VINCENT GUILLERMIN:
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
HUGO LIARD: You can go inside.
-What's inside?
HUGO LIARD: It's my house.
I built all this.
There was nothing, and then my
friend was living here, he
tells me one night,
yeah, maybe it's
possible to build something.
It's possible to make it.
I was like, yeah.
Check the wood, check this
carpet, you know?
There's enough to
do something.
Every night, six months, I built
everything, and now I'm
living here.
It's all the stuff I have, and
the stuff I bring here.
So I was like, start to
put everything here.
[INAUDIBLE].
It's all the stuff
I have with me.
-[SPEAKING FRENCH]
HUGO LIARD: No, that's the
first American board
I saw in the shop.
-[SPEAKING FRENCH]
HUGO LIARD: In a sport shop--
I'm like, this is an American
skateboard.
At the beginning, we just made
some t-shirts with a marker,
like erase the logo, and
on it, like, fuck, it's
our logo, you know?
Like, fuck, we put the logo on
the other logo, and that's it.
Wow, it's a crew.
A lot of skateboarders do
it-- oh, it's my crew.
So we started a crew, and
just made 50 t-shirts,
and then 100 boards.
And next year, it was like,
wow, we sell it?
OK, maybe we do 200 this year.
We will see.
JULIAN DYKMANS: Yeah, the
company wasn't even existing.
It wasn't official.
We just put some money.
It wasn't an official company,
so it's all black market.
HUGO LIARD: For three years.
JULIAN DYKMANS: We just
wanted to do our own
thing, and we had all--
I was riding for Consolidated,
and he was riding for, was it
[INAUDIBLE]
at that point?
Kind of the European guys
on the American brands.
You would go, show up, and
skate, and nobody was around,
and everybody had their
own problems.
You don't even know why you're
going there and stuff.
And you're from Europe, and then
you're just like, well,
actually, we can do our little
own thing, and it's more fun,
because it's your thing.
HUGO LIARD: That's a good
contrast with Cliche.
For me I used to come here and
skate a lot with the Cliche
guy, because they were the only
ones who really moved
their ass for skate--
like move, travel, in
a van, cut some
fence, and skate something.
But the style was different,
so kids were like, I don't
know-- rock and roll,
all of this.
Some kids were happy to see
something different.
And from the beginning,
it was just, fuck it.
Fuck everything.
Fuck all the company.
Fuck the consuming stuff.
And at the end, we're in
the business world.
And we try to keep the spirit we
had at the beginning, too.
JULIAN DYKMANS: No,
it's not hard.
It somehow comes naturally,
I guess.
You always crash test those guys
on the tour, and it fits
perfectly or it doesn't
at all, actually.
JULIEN "JU JU" BACHELIER:
Much more than
money, it's like a family.
All people get involved
in [INAUDIBLE]
is like, just friendship.
And the thing is, we go on the
road with a backpack with the
boards, and we just enjoy,
and try to skate, try
to have a good time.
And I think it's the best
treasure you can have
[INAUDIBLE]
skateboarding.
That's the roots of
SAM PARTAIX: I skate for Antiz
since maybe four years right
now, and that's really,
really good.
Because for me, when I was a kid
I was dreaming when I saw
Hugo and Ju Ju on the magazine,
I was all, crazy
skateboarder.
A photographer called me and he
just said, you have to come
with me, skate a bit in Lyon.
And I met this guy, and it was
really, really fun and good.
And they told me, yeah, if you
want, skate for Antiz.
Then I was ahh, so good.
So [INAUDIBLE] you can
not go inside.
It's private.
-What's going on in there?
SAM PARTAIX: Huh?
-What's going on inside?
SAM PARTAIX: Skating, cheating,
enjoying life.
WILFRIED AGNES:
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
BASTIEN DUVREDIER:
ALEXIS JAUZION: I was in
Marseille, south east France
the first big bowl
we got in France.
It's famous pretty much because
of the bowl riders
contest that Quicksilver
organized a few
years ago for us.
It's a real historical place,
compared to what has been
done, which legends
of skateboarding
have skated that spot.
US pros used to come more in
Europe, because there was
still a lot of World Cups
taking place in Europe.
So they came along to promote
their brands and stuff.
And most of the time, when they
were in France, they were
always managing to get two or
three or four free days for
just checking Marseilles.
So there's a list
of crazy names--
like, really good names
of skateboarding
that have skated here.
The incredible transfer of John
Cardiel with a broken
board, backside 360.
Still the craziest trick
that has ever been
done in this spot.
Omar Hassan is the only one for
the moment I've seen doing
McTwist in the big bowl.
But after that, years after
years, the local skaters that
were also entering the bowl
riders, they knew how to take
the lines, and which kind
of transfer they can do.
It's kind of perfect.
What people designed
almost 20 years ago
is still real skateable.
MAT BEGUE: When they did all the
metro stuff in Marseille
in 1991, all the ground they
took out from the town, they
used it to make all these
beaches you see here.
Before, the sea was against
the street.
So they decided to build
a Californian
way of life, seashore.
And we had the luck to have Jean
Pierre Collinet, who is
the architect of the bowl.
And he was a passionate
skateboarder, and 100%
skateboarder, and he
helped having this.
There has always been skating
in Marseilles, but the bowl
really connected people.
SAM PARTAIX: [SPEAKING FRENCH]
MEHDI SALAH: [SPEAKING FRENCH]
BASTIEN DUVREDIER: You
have a lot of--
I don't know the word.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
MEHDI SALAH: The gang.
BASTIEN DUVREDIER:
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
MEHDI SALAH: [SPEAKING FRENCH]
-So where are we going?
BASTIEN DUVREDIER:
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
MEHDI SALAH: [SPEAKING FRENCH]
HUGO LIARD: [SPEAKING FRENCH]