is a particular term
which actually means
a dealing with intuition.
In the theistic tradition
there is a notion of
clinging into a word.
A certain act is regarded as
displeasing to our
divine principles.
A certain act is regarded as
pleasing for the divine whatever.
In the tradition of
non-theism, however
it is very direct
that the case history is not
particularly important.
What is actually important
is here and now.
Now is definitely now.
We try to experience what is
available there, on the spot.
There's no point in thinking
that a past did exist
that we could have now.
This is now.
This very moment.
Nothing mystical, just now,
very simple, straight forward.
And from that nowness, however
arises a sense of
intelligence, always
that you are constantly
interacting with reality
one by one, spot by
spot, constantly.
We actually experience
fantastic precision, always.
But we are threatened by the now
so we jump to the
past or the future.
Paying attention to the materials
that exist in our life
all these choices take
place all the time
but none of them are regarded
as bad or good per se.
Everything we experience are
unconditional experience.
They don't come along
with a label by saying
"This is regarded as
bad" or "This is good".
We experience them but we don't
actually pay heed to them properly.
We don't actually regard that
as we are going somewhere.
We regard that as a hassle
waiting to be dead.
[Echoed: waiting to be dead]
That's a problem. And that is not
trusting the nowness properly
that what is actually
experienced now
possesses a lot of
powerful things.
It is so powerful
that we can't face it.
Therefore, we have to borrow from the
past, invite the future, all the time
and maybe that's why
we seek religion.
Maybe that's why we
march in the street.
complain to society.
Maybe that's why we vote
for the presidents.
It is quite ironical and
very funny, indeed.
ZEITGEIST
(J. Maxwell)
The more you
begin to investigate
what we think we understand,
where we came from
what we think we're doing
the more you begin to
see we've been lied to.
We've been lied to by every institution.
What makes you think
for one minute, that the
religious institution
is the only one that's
never been touched?
The religious institutions of this
world are at the bottom of the dirt.
The religious institutions
in this world are put there
by the same people who gave you your
government, your corrupt education
who set up your international
banking cartels.
We have been misled away from
the true and divine presence
in the universe that
men have called God.
I don't know what God is
but I know what He isn't.
And unless and until you are
prepared to look at the whole truth
wherever it may go,
whoever it may lead to
the more you educate yourself,
the more you understand
where things come from, the
more obvious things become
and you begin to see lies everywhere.
You have to know the truth
and seek the truth and the
truth will set you free.
They must find it difficult...
Those who have taken
authority as the truth
rather than truth
as the authority.
G. Massey, Egyptologist
(G. Carlin)
Because I have to
tell you the truth, folks.
When it comes to bullshit
big time, major league bullshit
you have to stand in awe of the
all-time champion of false promises
and exaggerated
claims: religion!
Think about it.
Religion has actually convinced people
that there's an invisible
man living in the sky
who watches everything you do,
every minute of every day.
And the invisible man has a
special list of ten things
he does not want you to do.
And if you do any of these ten
things, he has a special place
full of fire and smoke and
burning and torture and anguish
where He will send you to live
and suffer and burn and choke
and scream and cry forever and
ever until the end of time!
But He loves you.
[Laughter and applause]
He loves you.
He loves you and He needs money!
He always needs money!
He's all-powerful, all-perfect,
all-knowing, and all-wise;
somehow, just can't
handle money!
Religion takes in
billions of dollars
they pay no taxes and they
always need a little more.
Now, you talk about a
good bullshit story.
Holy shit!
PART I:
The Greatest Story Ever Told
(P. Joseph)
This is the sun.
As far back as 10,000 BC
history is abundant with carvings and
writings reflecting people's respect
and adoration for this object.
And it is simple to understand
why, as every morning
the sun would rise, bringing
vision, warmth and security
saving man from the cold, blind,
predator-filled darkness of night.
Without it, the cultures understood,
the crops would not grow
and life on the planet
would not survive.
These realities made the sun the
most adored object of all time.
Likewise, they were also
very aware of the stars.
The tracking of the stars allowed them
to recognize and anticipate events
which occurred over
long periods of time
such as eclipses and full moons.
They in turn cataloged
celestial groups
into what we know today
as constellations.
This is the cross of the Zodiac
one of the oldest conceptual
images in human history.
It reflects the sun as
it figuratively passes
through the 12 major constellations
over the course of a year.
It also reflects the 12 months
of the year, the four seasons
and the solstices and equinoxes.
The term Zodiac relates to
the fact that constellations
were anthropomorphized or
personified as figures or animals.
In other words, the early civilizations
did not just follow the sun and stars
they personified them
with elaborate myths
involving their movements
and relationships.
The sun, with its life-giving
and saving qualities
was personified as a representative
of the unseen creator or God.
God's Sun: the Light of the world,
the Savior of human kind.
Likewise, the 12 constellations represented
places of travel for God's Sun
and were identified by names, usually
representing elements of nature
that happened during
that period of time.
For example, Aquarius the water
bearer, who brings the spring rains.
This is Horus. He is the Sun God
of Egypt of around 3000 BC.
He is the sun,
anthropomorphized and his life
is a series of allegorical myths
involving the sun's movement in the sky.
From the ancient
hieroglyphics in Egypt
we know much about
this solar messiah.
For instance, Horus, being
the sun or the light
had an enemy known as Set
who was the personification
of the darkness or night
and metaphorically
speaking, every morning
Horus would win the battle against
Set, while in the evening
Set would conquer Horus and
send him into the underworld.
It is important to note that 'dark vs.
light' or 'good vs. evil'
is one of the most ubiquitous
mythological dualities ever known
and is still expressed on
many levels to this day.
Broadly speaking, the story
of Horus is as follows:
Horus was born on December 25th of the Virgin Isis
- Mary
His birth was accompanied
by a star in the east
and upon his birth he was
adored by three kings.
At the age of 12, he was a
prodigal child teacher.
At the age of 30 he was baptized
by a figure known as Anup
and thus began his ministry.
Horus had 12 disciples he traveled about with
performing miracles such as healing
the sick and walking on water.
Horus was known by many gestural
names such as The Truth
The Light, God's Anointed
Son, The Good Shepherd
The Lamb of God and many others.
After being betrayed by
Typhon, Horus was crucified
buried for 3 days and
thus, resurrected.
These attributes of Horus,
whether original or not
seem to permeate in many cultures
of the world for many other gods
are found to have the same
general mythological structure.
Attis of Phrygia, born of the
Virgin Nana on December 25th
crucified, placed in a tomb and
after three days, was resurrected.
Krishna of India, born
of the Virgin Devaki
with a star in the east
signaling his coming.
He performed miracles with his
disciples and upon his death
was resurrected.
Dionysus of Greece, born of
a virgin on December 25th
was a traveling teacher who performed
miracles such as turning water into wine.
He was referred to as The King of
Kings, God's only begotten son
the Alpha and Omega and many others.
Upon his death
he was resurrected.
Mithra of Persia, born of
a virgin on December 25th
had 12 disciples and
performed miracles
upon his death was buried for
3 days and thus resurrected.
He was also referred to as the
truth, the light and many others.
Interestingly, the sacred day of
worship of Mithra was Sunday.
The fact of the matter is
there are numerous saviors
from different periods
from all over the world
which subscribe to these
general characteristics.
The question remains:
why these attributes?
Why the virgin birth
on December 25th?
Why dead for 3 days and the
inevitable resurrection?
Why 12 disciples or followers?
To find out, let's examine the
most recent of the solar messiahs.
Jesus Christ was born of the Virgin
Mary on December 25th in Bethlehem.
His birth was announced by a star in
the east which Three Kings or Magi
followed to locate and
adore the new savior.
He was a child teacher at 12.
At the age of 30 he was baptized
by John the Baptist and
thus began his ministry.
Jesus had 12 disciples which he
traveled about with performing miracles
such as healing the sick, walking
on water, raising the dead.
He was also known as the King of Kings,
the Son of God, the Light of the World
the Alpha and Omega, the
Lamb of God and many others.
After being betrayed by his
disciple Judas and sold
for 30 pieces of silver, he was
crucified, placed in a tomb
and after 3 days was resurrected
and ascended into heaven.
First of all, the birth sequence
is completely astrological.
The star in the east is Sirius, the
brightest star in the night sky
which on December 24th aligns with the
3 brightest stars in Orion's belt.
These 3 bright stars in the
Orion's belt are called today
what they were called in ancient
times 'The Three Kings'.
And the Three Kings and the
brightest star, Sirius
all point to the place of the
sunrise on December 25th.
This is why the Three Kings
follow the star in the east
in order to locate the sunrise,
the birth of the Sun.
The Virgin Mary is the constellation
Virgo also known as Virgo the Virgin.
Virgo in Latin means Virgin.
Virgo was also referred
to as the House of Bread
and the representation of Virgo is
a virgin holding a sheaf of wheat.
This house of bread and
its symbol of wheat
represents August and September,
the time of harvest.
In turn, Bethlehem literally
translates to "house of bread".
Bethlehem is thus a reference
to the constellation Virgo
a place in the sky,
not on earth.
There's another very
interesting phenomenon
that occurs around December
25th or the winter solstice.
From the summer solstice
to the winter solstice
the days become
shorter and colder.
And from the perspective
of the northern hemisphere
the Sun appears to move south and
gets smaller and more scarce.
The shortening of the days
and expiration of the crops
when approaching the winter solstice
symbolized the process of death
to the ancients.
It was the death of the Sun.
And by December 22nd the Sun's
demise was fully realized.
For the Sun having moved south
continually for six months
makes it to its lowest
point in the sky.
Here a curious thing occurs:
The Sun stops moving south, at
least perceivably, for three days.
And during this three day pause,
the Sun resides in the vicinity
of the Southern Cross,
or Crux constellation.
And after this time
on December 25th
the Sun moves one
degree, this time north
foreshadowing longer
days, warmth and spring.
And thus it was said:
The Son died on a cross
was dead for three days, only to
be resurrected or born again.
This is why Jesus and
numerous other Sun gods
share the crucifixion, three-day
death and resurrection concept.
It is the Sun's transition period
before it shifts its direction back
into the northern hemisphere,
bringing spring and thus salvation.
However, they did not celebrate
the resurrection of the Sun
until the spring
equinox or Easter.
This is because at the spring equinox,
the Sun officially overpowers
the evil darkness as daytime
thereafter becomes longer in duration
than the night and the revitalizing
conditions of spring emerge.
Probably the most obvious of
all the astrological symbolism
around Jesus regards
the 12 disciples.
They are simply the 12
constellations of the zodiac
which Jesus, being the
Sun, travels about with.
In fact, the number 12 is
replete throughout the Bible.
Coming back to the cross of the zodiac,
the figurative life of the Sun
this was not just an
artistic expression
or tool to track the
Sun's movement.
It was also a pagan
spiritual symbol
the shorthand of which
looked like this.
This is not a symbol
of Christianity.
It is a pagan adaptation of
the cross of the zodiac.
This is why Jesus in earlier
cult art is always shown
with his head on the cross
for Jesus is the Sun.
The Son of God, the Light of
the World, the risen Savior
who will come again as
it does every morning
of the glory of God, who defends
against the works of darkness
as he is born again
every morning
and can be seen
coming in the clouds
up in heaven
with his crown of
thorns or sun rays.
Of the many astrological/astronomical
metaphors in the Bible
one of the most important
has to do with the ages.
Throughout the scriptures, there are
numerous references to the age.
In order to understand this, we need
to be familiar with the phenomenon
known as the precession
of the equinoxes.
The ancient Egyptians, along
with cultures long before them
recognized that approximately
every 2150 years
the sunrise on the morning
of the spring equinox
would occur at a different
sign of the zodiac.
This has to do with a
slow angular wobble
that the Earth maintains
as it rotates on its axis.
It is called a precession because
the constellations go backwards
rather than through the
normal yearly cycle.
The amount of time it takes for the
precession to go through all 12 signs
is roughly 25,765 years.
This is also called
the great year
and ancient societies
were very aware of this
and they referred to each
2150 year period as an age.
From 4300 BC
- 2150 BC, it was the age of Taurus, the Bull.
From 2150 BC
- 1 AD, it was the age of Aries, the Ram.
And from 1 AD
- 2150 AD, it is the age of Pisces
the age we are still
in to this day.
And in and around 2150 we
will enter the new age
the age of Aquarius.
The Bible reflects broadly
speaking a symbolic movement
through three ages while
foreshadowing a fourth.
In the Old Testament when
Moses comes down Mount Sinai
with the Ten Commandments,
he is very upset
to see his people worshiping
a golden bull calf.
In fact, he shattered the stone
tablets and instructed his people
to kill each other in order
to purify themselves.
Most Biblical scholars will attribute this
anger to the fact that the Israelites
were worshiping a false idol
or something to that effect.
The reality is, the golden
bull is Taurus the Bull
and Moses represents the
new age of Aries the Ram.
This is why Jews even today
still blow the ram's horn.
Moses represents the
new age of Aries
and upon the new age everyone
must shed the old age.
Other deities mark these
transitions as well such as Mithra
a pre-Christian god who kills
the bull in the same symbology.
Jesus is the figure who ushers
in the age following Aries
the Age of Pisces
or the two fish.
Fish symbolism is very
abundant in the New Testament.
Jesus feeds 5,000 people
with bread and two fish.
When he begins his ministry
walking along Galilee
he befriends two fishermen
who follow him.
And I think we have all seen the "Jesus
fish" on the back of people's cars.
Little do they know
what it actually means.
It is a pagan
astrological symbolism
for the Sun's kingdom
during the age of Pisces.
Also, Jesus' assumed birth date is
essentially the start of this age.
At Luke 22:10 when Jesus
is asked by his disciples
where the last Passover would be
Jesus replies "Behold, when
ye are entered into the city
there shall a man meet you
bearing a pitcher of water
follow him into the house
where he entereth in."
This scripture is by far
one of the most revealing
of all the astrological
references.
The man bearing a pitcher
of water is Aquarius
the water-bearer, who is
always pictured as a man
pouring out a pitcher of water.
He represents the
age after Pisces
and when the Sun (God's Sun)
leaves the Age of Pisces (Jesus)
it will go into the House of
Aquarius, as Aquarius follows Pisces
in the precession
of the equinoxes.
All Jesus is saying is that
after the Age of Pisces
will come the Age of Aquarius.
We have all heard about the "End
Times" and the end of the world.
The cartoonish depictions in
the Book of Revelation aside
the main source of this idea
comes from Matthew 28:20
where Jesus says "I will be with
you even to the end of the world."
However, in the King James Version,
'world' is a mistranslation
among many mistranslations.
The actual word being used is
'aeon', which means 'age'.
"I will be with you even
to the end of the age."
which is true, as Jesus' Solar
Piscean personification will end
when the Sun enters
the Age of Aquarius.
The entire concept of End Times
and the end of the world
is a misinterpreted
astrological allegory.
Let's tell that to the approximately
100 million people in America
who believe the end of
the world is coming.
Furthermore, the character
of Jesus being a literary
and astrological hybrid is most
explicitly a plagiarization
of the Egyptian Sun-god Horus.
For example, inscribed
about 3500 years ago
on the walls of the
Temple of Luxor in Egypt
are images of the enunciation
the miracle
conception, the birth
and the adoration of Horus.
The images begin with Thoth
announcing to the Virgin Isis
that she will conceive Horus
then Kneph, the holy ghost,
impregnating the virgin
and then the virgin birth
and the adoration.
This is exactly the story of
Jesus' miracle conception.
The literary similarities
between the Egyptian religion
and the Christian
religion are staggering.
And the plagiarism
is continuous.
The story of Noah and Noah's Arc
is taken directly from tradition.
The concept of The Great Flood is
ubiquitous throughout the ancient world
with over 200 different cited claims
in different periods and times.
However, one need look no further
for a pre-Christian source
than the Epic of Gilgamesh,
written in 2600 BC.
This story talks of a great
flood commanded by God
an ark with saved animals
upon it and even the release
and return of a dove, all held in
common with the Biblical story
among many other similarities.
And then there is the
plagiarized story of Moses.
Upon Moses' birth, it is said that
he was placed in a reed basket
and set adrift in a river in
order to avoid infanticide.
He was later rescued by a daughter of
royalty and raised by her as a Prince.
This baby in a basket
story was lifted directly
from the myth of Sargon of
Akkad of around 2250 BC.
Sargon was born, placed in a reed
basket in order to avoid infanticide
and set adrift in a river.
He was in turn rescued and raised
by Akki, a royal mid-wife.
Furthermore, Moses is
known as the Law Giver
the giver of the Ten
Commandments, the Mosaic Law.
However, the idea of a Law being
passed from God to a prophet
up on a mountain is
also a very old motif.
Moses is just another law giver
in a long line of law givers
in mythological history.
In India, Manou was
the great law giver.
In Crete, Minos
ascended Mount Dicta
where Zeus gave him
the sacred laws.
While in Egypt there was Mises,
who carried stone tablets
and upon them the laws
of God were written.
Manou. Minos. Mises. Moses.
And as far as the Ten Commandments,
they are taken outright
from Spell 125 in the
Egyptian Book of the Dead.
What the Book of the Dead phrased "I have
not stolen" became "Thou shall not steal".
"I have not killed" became
"Thou shall not kill".
"I have not told lies" became "Thou
shall not bear false witness"
and so forth.
In fact, the Egyptian religion is
likely the primary foundational basis
for the Judeo-Christian
theology.
Baptism, afterlife, final
judgment, virgin birth
death and resurrection, crucifixion,
the Ark of the Covenant
circumcision, saviors,
Holy Communion
Great Flood, Easter,
Christmas, Passover
and many more, are all
attributes of Egyptian ideas
long pre-dating
Christianity and Judaism.
Justin Martyr, one of the first Christian
historians and defenders, wrote:
"When we say that he,
Jesus Christ, our teacher
was produced without sexual
union, was crucified and died
and rose again, and
ascended into Heaven
we propound nothing different
from what you believe
regarding those who you
esteem Sons of Jupiter."
In a different writing,
Justin Martyr said:
"He was born of a virgin,
accept this in common
with what you believe
of Perseus."
It's obvious that Justin
and other early Christians
knew how similar Christianity
was to the pagan religions.
However, Justin had a solution.
As far as he was concerned,
the Devil did it.
The Devil had the foresight
to come before Christ
and create his characteristics
in the pagan world.
(B. Hicks)
Fundamentalist
Christianity, fascinating!
These people actually believe
the world is 12,000 years old.
I actually asked one of these
guys "OK, dinosaur fossils?"
He says "Dinosaur fossils?
God put those here
to test our faith!"
[Laughter]
"I think God put you here
to test my faith, dude!"
(P. Joseph)
The Bible is nothing more than
an astro-theological literary hybrid,
just like nearly all
religious myths before it.
In fact, the aspect of transference
of one character's attributes
to a new character can be
found within the book itself.
In the Old Testament there's
the story of Joseph.
Joseph was a
prototype for Jesus.
Joseph was born of a miracle birth.
Jesus was born of a miracle birth.
Joseph was of 12 brothers.
Jesus had 12 disciples.
Joseph was sold for
20 pieces of silver.
Jesus was sold for
30 pieces of silver.
Brother Judah suggests
the sale of Joseph.
Disciple Judas suggests
the sale of Jesus.
Joseph began his work
at the age of 30.
Jesus began his work
The parallels go on and on.
Furthermore, is there any non-Biblical
historical evidence of any person
living with the name
Jesus, the Son of Mary
who traveled about with 12
followers, healing people?
There are numerous historians who
lived in and around the Mediterranean
either during or soon after
the assumed life of Jesus.
How many of these historians
document this figure? Not one.
However, to be fair, that
doesn't mean defenders
of the historical Jesus
haven't claimed the contrary.
Four historians are typically
referenced to justify Jesus' existence.
Pliny the younger, Suetonius and
Tacitus are the first three.
Each one of their entries consists
of only a few sentences at best
and only refer to 'Christus' or the
Christ, which in fact is not a name
but a title.
It means 'The Anointed One'.
The fourth source is
Josephus and this source
has been proven to be a forgery
for hundreds of years.
Sadly, it is still
cited as truth.
You would think that a guy
who rose from the dead
and ascended into Heaven
for all eyes to see
and performed the wealth of
miracles acclaimed to him
would have made it into
the historical record.
It didn't because once
the evidence is weighed
there are very high odds that
the figure known as Jesus
did not even exist.
"The Christian religion is a
parody on the worship of the sun
in which they put a man called
Christ in the place of the sun
pay him the adoration
originally paid to the sun."
Thomas Paine (1737-1809)
(J. Maxwell)
We don't want to be
unkind, but we want to be factual.
We don't want to
cause hurt feelings
but we want to be
academically correct
in what we understand
and know to be true.
Christianity just is
not based on truth.
We find that Christianity was in
fact nothing more than a Roman story
developed politically.
(P. Joseph)
The reality is,
Jesus was the Solar Deity
of the Gnostic Christian sect
and like all other pagan gods,
he was a mythical figure.
It was the political establishment
that sought to historize
the Jesus figure for
social control.
In 325 AD in Rome, Emperor Constantine
convened the Council of Nicea.
It was during this meeting
that the politically motivated
Christian Doctrines
were established
and thus began a long history of
religious bloodshed and spiritual fraud.
And for over the next
1000 years, the Vatican
maintained a political
stranglehold on all of Europe
leading to such joyous
periods as the Dark Ages
along with enlightening events such
as the Crusades and the Inquisition.
Christianity, along with all
other related theologies
is a historical fraud.
These religions now serve to detach
the species from the natural world
and likewise, each other.
They support blind
submission to authority.
They reduce human
responsibility to the effect
that 'God' controls everything
and in turn awful crimes
can be justified in the
name of a divine pursuit.
And most critically, it empowers
the political establishment
who have been using the myth to
manipulate and control societies.
The religious myth is one of the
most powerful devices ever created
and serves as the psychological soil
upon which other myths can flourish.
(D. Griffin)
A myth is an idea that,
while widely believed, is false.
In a deeper sense, in
the religious sense
a myth serves as an orienting and
mobilizing story for a people.
The focus is not on the story's relation
to reality but on its function.
A story cannot function, unless
it is believed to be true
in the community or the nation.
It is not a matter of debate if
some people have the bad taste
to raise the question of the
truth of the sacred story.
The keepers of the faith do not
enter into debate with them.
They ignore them or denounce
them as blasphemers.
It is wrong, blasphemous and
sinful for you to suggest, imply
or help other people
come to the conclusion
that the US government killed
3,000 of its own citizens.
Part II:
All the World's a Stage
(Man on phone)
As if a
demolition team set off...
when you see demolitions
of these old buildings.
(Series of 3 reporters)
It looks like
one of those scenes
of an old building being
purposely blown up.
Anybody who's ever watched a
building being demolished
on purpose knows that if you're
going to do this you have to get
at the under-infrastructure of
a building and bring it down.
The way the structure is
collapsing, this was the result
of something that was planned.
It's not accidental
that the 1st tower just happened
to collapse and then the 2nd tower
just happened to collapse
in exactly the same way.
How they accomplished
this, we don't know.
(Fireman Casaliggi)
The building
collapsed to dust.
You don't find a desk,
you don't find a chair
you don't find a
telephone or a computer.
The biggest piece of
a telephone I found
was half of the keypad and
it was about this big.
- What happened to the concrete?
- The concrete was pulverized.
From river to river there was dust
powder, two or three inches thick.
The concrete was
just pulverized!
(Man on phone)
...reminiscent of those
pictures we've all seen too much
on TV before when a building
was deliberately destroyed
by well-placed dynamite
to knock it down.
- It's as if they had detonators...
- Yes, detonators
-...planned to take down the
building, boom, boom...
I heard a 2nd explosion.
There was a
heavy-duty explosion.
There was a secondary explosion
and then a subsequent collapse.
...explosion blew and then
it knocked everybody over.
To me it sounded
like an explosion.
It sounded like
gun-fire, bang-bang!
And then all of a sudden
three big explosions.
... and we heard big
explosion coming down.
... and then the entire top
of the building just blew up.
- We saw some kind of explosion.
- By the force of the explosions... - big explosion...
It blew us back into the 8th floor.
- We got to the lobby, there was a big explosion.
The lobby looked as if a
bomb had exploded there.
(Series of 7 witnesses)
Huge explosion,
now raining debris...
There's been a huge explosion!!!
Huge explosion that we
all heard and felt.
We just witnessed some kind
of follow up explosion...
We heard a very loud (It blasted!
) explosion...
Smoke and secondary
explosion in Tower One...
That is another bomb going off.
He thinks that there were actually devices
that were planted in the building...
planted in the building...
The 9/11 Myth
19 hijackers, directed by Osama bin
Laden, took over 4 commercial jets
and, while evading the Air Defense System
(NORAD), hit 75% of their targets.
In turn, World Trade
Towers 1, 2 & 7 collapsed
due to structural failure through
fire in a 'pancake' fashion
while the plane that hit the
Pentagon vaporized upon impact
as did the plane that
crashed in Shanksville.
The 911 Commission found that there were
no warnings for this act of terrorism
while multiple government failures
prevented adequate defense.
'no warnings'
(C. Rice)
I don't think
anybody could have predicted
that they would try to use
an airplane as a missile
a hijacked airplane
as a missile.
Nobody in our government at least, and
I don't think the prior government
could have envisioned flying
airplanes into buildings.
No specific threat involving
domestic operations
involving what happened obviously,
the cities, airliners and so on.
There were no warning
signs that I'm aware of.
USAToday reports that in the 2 years
before the attacks on September 11th
NORAD conducted exercises using
hijacked airliners as weapons.
And one target was the
World Trade Center.
Cover of FEMA response
manual, 1997.
Operation "Mascal", Oct.
2000, simulated a plane crash into the Pentagon.
(Journalist)
In confidential documents
from the Philippines obtained by CNN
the plan was clear: He will board
any American commercial aircraft
control its cockpit, and dive
it at the CIA headquarters.
Other buildings targeted included the
Pentagon and World Trade Center.
The Federal Aviation Administration
(FAA) received 52 warnings
about Al-Qaeda in the
six months before 9/11
and did not
apparently heed them.
(Journalist)
The Pentagon reportedly
does not want the public to hear
next week's Senate
Testimony about the former
secret intelligence unit,
known as 'Able Danger'
And it identified Mohammed Atta
and three other 9/11 terrorists
as members of an Al-Qaeda
cell in Brooklyn, New York
more than a year
before the attacks.
And we found two of the three cells
which conducted the 9/11 attacks.
(Journalist)
Lt Colonel Anthony Shaffer,
the first member of 'Able Danger'
to go public, has now been told in writing
by the Defense Intelligence Agency
that it can't speak to members of Congress
or their staff without prior approval.
This is an attempt to
prevent the American people
from knowing the facts about how
we could have prevented 9/11
and people are
covering it up today.
(Journalist)
Security and
counter-terrorism was blinking red
in the words of George Tenet, that
the warnings of an imminent attack
were so severe that something
dramatic should have been done.
It was unparalleled. Instead, our
president went on a month-long vacation.
19 Hijackers
(M. Meacher)
The head of Pakistani
intelligence (ISI) Mahmood Ahmed
requested Omar Sheikh to wire
$100,000 to Mohammed Atta
who was the lead hijacker.
(2 journalists)
Hijacker Mohammed Atta
received wire transfers via Pakistan.
The man sending
the money to Atta
is believed to be Ahmed
Omar Saeed Sheikh.
Omar Sheikh admitted
he was supported
by the Pakistani Government's
intelligence service, the ISI.
No inquiry was ever made as to why
General Ahmad ordered $100,000
to be sent to Mohamed Atta.
On the morning of September 11, government
officials were having breakfast
with General Ahmad
in Washington.
The 911 Commission deemed the
financing of the attacks
was 'of little practical significance'
in their official report.
(Journalist)
As hard as this is to believe,
that two of the alleged terrorists
involved in what
happened on Tuesday
may have attended schools run by U.
S. military.
Evidence was also
apparently planted.
The passport of one
of the hijackers
on Flight 11 was allegedly
found in the rubble.
The hijacker's passport
was found blocks
from the World Trade Center crash
site, if you can believe that.
The 9/11 hijackers
are alive and well
that's according to the chief
of Japan's Democratic Party
who says 9/11 is a hoax.
Several of these 19
men are still alive.
"I couldn't believe it when
the FBI put me on their list.
They gave my name and my date of
birth but I'm not a suicide bomber.
I am alive.
I have no idea how to fly a plane."
At least 7 of the hijackers
are still alive.
The FBI has to this day
not revised their list.
At least 5 hijackers are reported as
linked to US Military Institutions.
Osama B. Laden
Of course we're after Saddam
Hussein, I mean bin Laden, he's...
(Journalist)
In the early 80s bin
Laden worked with operatives
from US Intelligence, the Pakistani
military and Arab states.
January 2001.
The Bush Administration orders the FBI
and intelligence agencies
to back off investigations
involving the bin Laden family
including two of Osama
bin Laden's relatives
who were living, guess where?
In Falls Church, Virginia
right next to CIA headquarters.
When he was already America's
'most wanted criminal'
he reportedly spent two weeks in
the American hospital in Dubai
was treated by an American doctor
and visited by the local CIA agent.
We have not seen one piece of
evidence that links Osama bin Laden
directly to the planning
stages of September 11th.
(D. Griffin)
This failure to provide
proof was later said to be unnecessary
because bin Laden, in a video
allegedly found in Afghanistan
admitted responsibility
for the attacks.
"I have carefully examined
the Pentagon's translation
which is very problematic.
At the most important pieces where it is held
to prove the guilt of bin Laden, it
is not identical with the Arabic."
Arabist Dr. Abdel EIM Husseini
"The American translators who listened
to the tapes and transcribed them
apparently wrote a lot of things
in that they wanted to hear
but cannot be heard, no matter how
many times you listen to the tapes."
Gernot Rotter, Prof.
of Islamic Studies at University of Hamburg
In 1976, Osama's older
brother Saleem bin Laden
hired a man in Texas by
the name of Jim Bath
to handle all the investments in the
United States for the bin Laden family.
Jim Bath also happens to be a
personal, almost life-long friend
and former international guard
pilot, with George W. Bush.
The connections between the
Bushes and the bin Ladens
become much more clear when
George Herbert Walker Bush
made trips to Saudi Arabia in
1998 and 2000 to meet with
the bin Laden family on behalf of a
company called the Carlyle Group.
On the morning of 9/11, the Carlyle
Group was having a conference
in Washington, which included Osama's
older brother, Shafig bin Laden.
The Carlyle Group is linked to the
world's largest defense contractors
which continue to reap massive profits
off of the post 9/11 'War on Terrorism'
and Afghan/Iraq Wars.
Pentagon
(Reporter)
How could anyone
fly a 60 ton, 125 foot wide
44 foot tall plane through
this obstacle course?
(D. Griffin)
The aircraft before striking
the Pentagon reportedly executed
a 270 degree downward spiral
and yet Hani Hanjour was
known as a terrible pilot
who could not safely fly
even a small plane.
"He didn't care about the fact that
he couldn't get through the course."
"I am still to this day amazed that he
could have flown into the Pentagon... "
- AZ Flight school employee (New
York Times Report 5/4/2002)
(Reporter) No seats,
no luggage, no bodies.
Nothing but bricks
and limestone.
(D. Avery)
The official explanation is
that the intense heat from the jet fuel
vaporized the entire plane.
Flight 77 had two Rolls Royce engines
made of steel and titanium
alloy and weighed 6 tons each.
It is scientifically impossible
that 12 tons of steel
and titanium was
vaporized by jet fuel.
We're also told that the bodies
were able to be identified
either by the fingerprints
or by their DNA.
So what kind of fire can vaporize
aluminum and tempered steel
and yet leave human
bodies intact?
(Reporter)
From my close-up inspection
there's no evidence of a plane
having crashed anywhere
near the Pentagon
and the only pieces
left that you can see
are small enough that you
can pick up in your hand.
(D. Griffin)
Shortly after the
strike, government agents
picked up debris and
carried it off.
The entire lawn was covered
with dirt and gravel
so that any remaining forensic
evidence was literally covered up.
The videos from security
cameras which would show
what really hit the Pentagon
were immediately confiscated
by agents of the FBI
and the Department of Justice has to
this day refused to release them.
If these videos would prove that the
Pentagon was really hit by a 757
most of us would assume the
Government would release them.
[Request Denied]
Shanksville
- It looks like there's nothing there
except for a hole in the ground.
- Basically that's right, the only
thing you could see from where we were
was a big gouge in the earth
and some broken trees.
You could see some people working,
walking around in the area
but from where we could see
there wasn't much left.
- Any large pieces of debris at all?
- No, there was nothing.
Nothing that you could distinguish
that a plane had crashed there.
Commercial plane
crash in Nigeria
Flight 93 "Crash" in Shanksville
The FBI and state police here have
confirmed that they have cordoned off
a second area about 6 to 8 miles
away from the crater here.
This is apparently
another debris site.
Why would debris be
located 6 miles away?
Could that have blown that far away?
Seems highly unlikely.
World Trade Towers 1, 2 & 7
(D. Griffin)
Pancake theory,
according to which the fires
while not melting the steel,
heated it up sufficiently
to cause the floors weakened
by the airplane strikes
to break loose from the steel columns
and this started a chain reaction.
- So, you would expect then from that
theory, which is the official theory
to see a whole stack of floors
piled up on top of each other
and then a spindle of core
columns standing too.
- The core of each of the Twin Towers
consisted of 47 massive steel columns.
If the floors had broken loose
from them, these columns
would have still been sticking up
into the air, a thousand feet.
The plane did not cut
all those core columns.
We designed the buildings to take
the impact of the Boeing 707
hitting the building
at any location.
The building probably could sustain
multiple impacts of jetliners.
- ...that the plane flew straight into the building.
- Straight through, right.
- So you're saying that the building
was actually designed to cope
with a hole like that and then still survive?
- Yes, it was.
- If you would drop,
say a billiard ball
from the top of the World Trade
Center, 110 floors up there
it would have taken 8 to 10
seconds to hit the ground
encountering no
resistance whatsoever.
(D. Avery)
The Twin Towers came
down in nearly free fall speed.
200,000 tons of steel shatters and
explodes outwards over 500 feet.
- This means that floors
shattered at an average rate
of about ten floors per second.
- There is no scenario for a pancake
effect of buildings falling
that allows them to fall
at a rate of free fall.
Now what can do that?
What can move mass out of the way?
Explosives.
47 huge steel columns going up the
core that are interconnected.
How do you get them to fail
simultaneously so the core disappeared?
It looks like those
core columns were cut.
(Controlled demolition expert)
We do this by cutting the beam
at an angle.
World Trade Center core
column after the collapse.
Notice the 'cut' shape and the melted...
or 'molten metal'.
(S. Jones)
I started looking
at the molten metal.
All three buildings, both towers in
the rubble, in the basement areas
and Building 7, there were
these pools of molten metal.
For well over 6 weeks
after the collapse
hot spots of 2000°F were
documented in the debris.
That is 500°F hotter
than jet fuel can burn
in the most controlled
conditions.
You'd get down below and
you'd see molten steel
molten steel running
down the channel rails
like you were in a foundry
like lava of a volcano.
(D. Avery)
The molten steel was
found 3, 4 and 5 weeks later
when the rubble was
being removed.
He said that molten steel was also
found underneath World Trade Center 7.
So I'm looking through the official reports.
What do they say
about the molten metal?
They say nothing.
Wait a minute.
This is important evidence.
Where did that come from?
(S. Jones)
Thermite is so hot that
it will just cut through steel
through structural steel, for example,
like a knife through butter.
The products are molten
iron and aluminum oxide
which goes off
primarily as a dust.
You know, those
enormous dust clouds?
You can imagine, when you assemble
these chemicals on a large scale.
- So, professor Niels Harrit,
you examined the rubble
that came from the World Trade Center.
What did you find in it?
- In there, we find remains
of what we characterize
as a thermitic material.
This is very energetic material
which can be used
either for melting iron
or it can be designed
as an explosive.
The evidence for controlled
demolition is overwhelming.
I told you that the thermite
reaction produced molten iron.
Molten iron was in pools of
molten iron in the rubble
and the point is that the
thermite kept on reacting.
This was the witches' brew
of thermite chemistry.
Molten metal pools under both
towers after they collapsed
and Building 7, which
wasn't even hit by a jet.
(Reporter)
Part of the
problem is that most people
simply don't know
much about Building 7
due to the extraordinary secrecy
surrounding this collapse.
(Reporter)
This was a
47-story skyscraper.
This building fell at 5:25.
(D. Griffin)
It was not hit
by a plane.
This building had fires
on only 2 or 3 floors.
- ... and it was brought down by what
we know was a controlled demolition.
- Demolitions look just like
that, kink in the middle
and then that building just comes
straight down almost at free fall speed.
In 2005, The National Institute
of Standards and Technology
released its report
on WTC Towers 1 & 2.
The 10,000 page report does not
address the actual collapse.
In 2008, The National Institute
of Standards and Technology
released its report
on WTC Tower 7.
They did not analyze
one piece of steel
or test a controlled
demolition hypothesis.
Rather, they built a computer
model with a predisposition
that it was a
'fire-induced' collapse.
The parameters used
have not been released.
While admitting there was a period of
'free fall' for 2.25 sec (8 floors)
they provide no explanation
as to how this is possible
since their 'progressive
collapse' theory is based
on systemic collisions
and triggered failures.
The Law of Conservation of
Momentum simply cannot allow
for a 'progressive'
movement through resistance
at the rate of 'free fall'.
Did we review the
sub-basement explosions
which occurred moments
before the first plane hit?
Our office was on the B1 level.
As I was talking to a supervisor at 8.46
and all of a sudden we hear
- BOOM!
(William Rodriguez, 20
year employee of the WTC)
An explosion so hard
that pushed us upwards.
And it came from the basement, between
the B2 level and the B3 level.
And when I went to verbalize, we hear
- BOOM!
The impact of the
plane on the top.
(Reporter)
It would appear as if there's
more smoke coming from the ground...
I was down at the basement, came down,
all of a sudden the elevator blew up.
And as we were coming out, we passed a lobby.
There was no lobby
so I believe the bomb
hit the lobby first
and couple of seconds,
then the first plane hit.
As I'm walking by the main freight
car of the building in the corridor
that's when I got blown.
I mean, the impact of the
explosion threw me to the floor
and that's when everything
started happening.
All of a sudden a big
impact happened again
and all the ceiling tiles and
light fixtures were falling down.
You have to go clear across the
hall from 1 to 2 World Trade Center
and then all of a sudden it
happened all over again.
Something else hit us to the floor.
Right in the basement, you felt it.
Walls were caving in,
everything that was going on...
I know people that got
killed in the basement.
broken legs in the basement.
People got reconstructive surgery
because the walls hit them in the face.
NORAD (North American
Aerospace Defense Command)
According to standard operating
procedure, if an FAA flight control
notices anything that
suggests a possible hijacking
controllers are to contact their superior.
If the problem cannot be fixed
within about a minute, the
superior should ask NORAD
the North American Aerospace
Command to send up
or scramble jet fighters to
find out what is going on.
NORAD then issues
a scramble order
to the nearest air force
base with fighters on alert.
Although interceptions usually
occur within 10 or so minutes
in this case 80 or so
minutes had elapsed
before fighters
were even airborne.
(Reporter)
It's a
mind-bending anomaly.
Not a single US Air Force interceptor
turns a wheel until it's too late.
There are no jets at all.
What if they were so confused, and
had been so deliberately confused
that they couldn't respond?
The reason that they didn't know where to
go was because a number of conflicting
and overlapping war game
exercises were taking place
that involved the insertion
of false radar blips
on the radar screens in the
north-east air defense sector.
(FAA)
"Hi, Boston Center TMU,
we have a problem here.
We have a hijacked aircraft
headed towards New York
we need someone to scramble some F-16s
or something up there to help us out."
(NORAD)
"Is this real
world or exercise?"
There was another exercise,
"Vigilant Warrior"
which was in fact according
to a NORAD source
a live-fly hijack drill being
conducted at the same time.
With only 8 available
fighter aircraft
and they have to be
dispatched in pairs
they were dealing with as many as 22
possible hijacks on the day of 9/11
and they couldn't separate the war game
exercises from the actual hijacks.
In 2000, NORAD had 67 intercepts.
100% accuracy.
On 9/11 they failed
4 times in one day.
In at least one of the many war
games going on the morning of 9/11
planes being flown into
buildings was a scenario.
9/11 Commission
Page 172: "The US Government
has not been able to determine
the origin of the money
used for the 9/11 attacks.
Ultimately, the question is of
little practical significance."
The American authorities
have not managed to trace
the source of the funding
and then the most amazingly
disingenuous statement: "Ultimately,
is it of little consequence".
It is of massive consequence!
Doesn't it matter
who paid for 9/11?
(D. Griffin)
The collapse of
Building 7 has been recognized
as especially
difficult to explain.
The 9/11 Commission Report implicitly
admitted that it could not explain
the collapse of this building
by not even mentioning it.
- Mr. President, why are you and
the Vice President insisting on
appearing together before
the 9/11 Commission?
- Because the 9/11 Commission
wants to ask us questions.
That's why we are meeting and I
look forward to meeting with them
and answering their questions.
- The question was, why are you appearing
together rather than separately
which was their request?
- Because it's a good chance for
both of us to answer questions
that the 9/11 Commission is
looking forward to asking us
and I am looking forward to
answering them. Let's see.
- Do you think they should be able to
stand up and speak their own words?
- They should go under oath.
In public!
When Bush and Cheney met with the
9/11 Commission, they did so
only on their own terms:
They appeared together.
They were not under oath.
No press or family members
were allowed to attend.
No recording of any
kind was allowed.
- Don't you think that the families
deserve to have a transcript
or to be able to see...
- Adam, you asked me that question yesterday
and got the same answer.
- The final report was
a unanimous report.
That means that if there was a single
commissioner who had any objection
about anything, that fact would
be dropped from the report.
- We have found out that he not
only served on the transition team
of the Bush Administration
that he was a person
who wrote a draft memo
for the setup of the Bush Administration's
National Security Council
that he was an individual who
wrote the preemptive war strategy
that was eventually used
for the war on Iraq
that he's a close friend
of Condoleezza Rice's.
We want him to resign.
There is literally nothing
in the 9/11 Report
that the Bush Administration
did not approve of.
(D. Griffin)
We can understand
therefore why the Commission
under Zelikow's leadership would
have ignored all the evidence
that would point to the truth
that 9/11 was a false
flag operation
intended to authorize
the doctrines and funds
needed for a new level of
imperial mobilization.
Terrorism
Terrorism: 1) Systematic
use of terror
manifesting itself in violence or
intimidation, for generating fear.
Armed with knives. Armed with chemical,
biological and nuclear weapons.
Fanatics. Terrorists. September 11th.
September 11th. Killers.
September 11th. Terrorists.
Al Qaeda, Terrorists.
Nuclear weapons. Terror.
9/11. Terror. Evil.
September 11th. September 11th.
The terrorists. War and danger.
September 11th. Terrorism.
Global terrorism. Terrorism. Terrorist
Terrorist. (Repeated 5 times)
Terrorists. Terrorism.
September 11th. Global terrorism.
Terrorism. Terrorism. Terrorists.
September 11th. World terrorism.
Terrorism. September 11th.
Global Terrorism.
September the 11th. Terrorist.
Terrorist. Terrorist. Terrorist.
Weapons of mass destruction.
September 11th.
September the 11th. The evil terrorists.
Terrorists. Terrorists Know!
(Journalist)
Terrorism.
The words are hypnotically repeated:
Terrorism. Terrorists.
Terrorist threat.
And of course, "believed
to be linked to al-Qaeda".
But, it's the so-called
'War on Terrorism'
that's in our faces
practically 24/7
as the inescapable focus
of our existence.
(D. Rumsfeld)
One day our grandchildren
will look back on this time and ask
"How was the War on Terror won?"
The entire US ruling
class, ruling elite
comes to see terrorism
as the preferred means
indeed the only means to
provide social cohesion
to provide an enemy image for the
society, to keep it together.
According to neocon theory from
Carl Schmitt, you have to have
an enemy image in order
to have a society.
A very dangerous thing because now it
means that the entire social order
the political parties, intellectual
life, politics in general
are all based on a
monstrous myth.
[Echoed: monstrous myth]
Terrorism: 2) Technique
used by governments
to manipulate public opinion
in order to further an agenda.
Look, what the CIA has
done in this country
what they have done to
us is unbelievable.
Look at the terrorist
acts that have occurred.
The CIA is behind most
if not all of them.
We had the Marine barracks,
their embassy in Kenya.
We had Pan Am 103.
We had the USS Cole.
We had Oklahoma City.
We had the World Trade Center in 1993.
...that helped the terrorists to blow up
the World Trade Center the first time.
They built the bomb.
They got the driver's license.
The informer Emad A. Salem, a 43-year-old
former Egyptian Army officer
was given the assignment
to put the bomb together
and he went to his
FBI supervisor
and he said "We're going to put
a dummy bomb in here, right?"
and the FBI supervisor said "No,
we're going to put a real bomb."
(Journalist)
FBI agents might
have been able to prevent
last February's deadly explosion
at New York's World Trade Center.
They discussed secretly substituting
harmless powder for the explosives
but they didn't, according to the
FBI's own informant Emad Salem.
Unbeknownst to the
FBI at the time
Salem recorded many of his
conversations with his handlers.
Unfortunately for them, there
were only six people killed
not enough to pass
the legislation.
So, what happened
is two years later
April 19, 1995 down
comes Oklahoma City
the Murrah Building,
168 people killed.
One year later, the anti-terror
legislation, which takes away
many of our constitutional rights
and civil liberties, is passed.
Madrid, 2004
7/7/2005 London: 3 trains and a bus
were bombed, killing 56 people.
That morning, an "anti-terror
exercise" just happened
to be taking place as
well, dealing with...
THE EXACT SAME BOMBING SCENARIO
AT THE EXACT SAME TRAIN STATIONS
AT THE EXACT SAME TIME.
- ... because at half past 9 this morning,
we were actually running an exercise
for a company of over a thousand people
in London based on simultaneous bombs
going off precisely at the railway
stations where it happened this morning
so I still have the hairs on the
back of my neck standing upright!
- To get this straight, you were running
an exercise to see how you would cope
with this and it happened while you
were running the exercise? - Precisely!
Yeah... That's right. The exact same
bombing at the exact same train stations
at virtually the same time.
[We're] supposed to believe it
was some kind of coincidence
that there was also an anti-terrorist
drill going on on 7/7.
And again, just like on 9/11
they were talking about
attacks on the same targets
the same kind of tube stations
at exactly the same time
as the actual attack happened
providing some kind of
cover for what must be
operations orchestrated
in some way by the State.
(J. Maxwell)
I am
absolutely appalled
at how much people in this
country do not think.
We are given to understand
that a guy out there
up in the mountains
financed the most elaborate
attack on this country.
(A. Jones)
Do you think
some people in a cave
were able to have
NORAD stand down?
Do you think that
people in a cave
were able to have
all of this happen?
(J. Maxwell)
And when I think
about how many Americans
were killed in New York City
and believing as I do that
this thing was a set-up job
this is a textbook
operation that Nazis used
and they've used it
over and over again.
America has been suckered
in one more time.
("Network" 1976)
I don't have
to tell you things are bad.
Everybody knows things are bad.
The dollar buys a nickel's worth.
Banks are going bust.
Shopkeepers keep a gun
under the counter.
Punks are running wild in the street.
There's nobody anywhere
who seems to know what to do
and there's no end to it.
We know the air is unfit to breathe
and our food is unfit to eat.
We sit watching our TVs while
some local newscaster tells us
that today we had 15 homicides
and 63 violent crimes
as if that's the way it's supposed to be!
We know things are bad.
Worse than bad, they're crazy!
It's like everything everywhere is going
crazy, so we don't go out anymore.
We sit in the house and slowly the world
we're living in is getting smaller
and all we say is "Please, at least
leave us alone in our living rooms.
Let me have my toaster and my
TV, my steel-belted radials
and I won't say anything.
Just leave us alone!"
Well I'm not going to leave you alone.
I want you to get mad!
I don't want you to protest,
I don't want you to riot.
I don't want you to write to your
Congressman because I wouldn't know
what to tell you to write.
I don't know what to do about the depression
and the inflation and the Russians
and the crime in the street.
All I know is that first
you've got to get mad!
You've got to say "I'm a
human being, goddamn it!
My life has value!"
(Man on phone)
There's smoke, real bad!
105, two tower.
It's real bad, it's
black, it's arid.
My wife thinks I'm all right.
I called and said I was leaving the building.
I was fine, and then BANG!
Three of us - two
broken windows.
Oh God!
(Charles Lindbergh, 1941)
When hostilities
commenced in Europe in 1939
it was realized that the American people
had no intention of entering the war.
But they believed that this country
could be enticed into the war
in very much the same way that it
was enticed into the last one.
They planned, first, to prepare
the United States for foreign war
under the guise of
American defense.
Second, to involve us in the war
step by step, without
our realization.
Third, to create a
series of incidents
which would force us into
the actual conflict.
These plans were, of course,
to be covered and assisted
by the full power of
their propaganda.
Our theaters soon became
filled with plays
portraying the glory of war.
News reels lost all
semblance of objectivity
and they have used the war
to justify the restriction
of congressional power
and the assumption of
dictatorial procedures
on the part of the President
and his appointees.
A fear campaign was inaugurated.
We cannot allow the natural
passions and prejudices
of other peoples, to lead
our country to destruction.
Part III:
Don't Mind The Men
Behind The Curtain
"Behind the ostensible government sits
enthroned an invisible government
owing no allegiance and
acknowledging no responsibility
to the people."
- Theodore Roosevelt
"The real menace of our republic
is the invisible government...
The little coterie of powerful international
bankers virtually runs the US government
for their own selfish purposes.
" John F. Hylan
"The real truth of the matter is that a
financial element in the large centers
has owned the government since the days of Andrew Jackson."
- Franklin D. Roosevelt
(P. Joseph)
1775, the American
Revolutionary War began
as the American colonies
sought to detach from England
and its oppressive monarchy.
Though many reasons are
cited for the revolution
one in particular sticks
out as a prime cause:
that King George llI
of England outlawed
the interest-free
independent currency
the colonies were
producing themselves
in turn forcing them to borrow money
from the Central Bank of England
immediately creating economic
hardship and despair.
In the words of Peter Cooper,
former vice-president
of the New York Board of Currency:
"After Franklin had explained
to the British government as
the real cause of prosperity
they immediately passed laws forbidding
the payment of taxes in that money.
This produced such great inconvenience
and misery to the people
that it was the principal
cause of the revolution."
In 1783, America won its
independence from England.
However, its battle against
the central bank concept
and the corrupt, power-hungry
mentality associated with it
had just begun.
So what is a central bank?
A central bank is an institution
that issues and regulates the
currency of an entire nation.
Based on historical precedent,
the typical powers inherent
in central banking practice include
the control of interest rates
and the expansion and contraction
of the money supply itself.
The Central Bank does not simply
issue money to the government.
It loans it to them
with interest.
Then, through the mechanisms of increasing
and decreasing the supply of money
the Central Bank essentially regulates
the value of the currency issued.
It is critical to understand that
the entire structure of this system
can only produce one thing
in the long run: debt.
It doesn't take a lot of ingenuity
to figure this scam out
for nearly every single dollar
produced by both the Central Bank
and its regulated commercial
banks is loaned at interest.
That means every dollar
produced is actually the dollar
plus a certain percentage of
debt based on that dollar.
And since the banking system has
the monopoly of the production
of the currency and they
loan each dollar out
with an immediate
debt attached to it
where does the money to pay
for the debt come from?
It can only come
from the banks again
which means the banking system
has to perpetually increase
its money supply to temporarily
cover the outstanding debt created
which in turn, since that new
money is loaned out at interest
creates even more debt!
The end result of this system
is essentially slavery
for it is technically impossible for
a government and thus the public
to ever come out of the
self-generating debt.
"And I sincerely believe...
that banking establishments are
more dangerous than
standing armies;
and that the principle of spending
money to be paid by posterity
under the name of funding, is but
swindling futurity on a large scale"
Letter from Thomas Jefferson
to John Taylor (May 28, 1816)
"Banking was conceived in
iniquity and was born in sin.
The bankers own the Earth...
If you wish to remain the slaves of bankers
and pay the cost of your own slavery,
let them continue to create money."
Sir Josiah Stamp, University
of Texas speech, 1927
By the early 20th century, the US
had already implemented and removed
a few central banking systems,
which were maneuvered into place
by ruthless banking interests.
At this time, the dominant families
in the banking and business world
were the Rockefellers, the Morgans,
the Warburgs, the Rothschilds.
In the early 1900's, they
sought to push once again
legislation to create
another central bank.
However, they knew the
government and public
were very weary of
such an institution.
They needed to create an incident
to affect public opinion.
JP Morgan, publicly considered a
financial luminary at the time
exploited his mass influence
by reportedly creating rumors
that prominent banks in New York
were insolvent, or bankrupt.
Morgan knew this would trigger mass
hysteria and a systemic crisis.
And it did. The public, in
fear of losing their deposits
immediately began
mass withdrawals.
Consequently, the banks were
forced to call in their loans
causing the recipients
to sell their property
and thus a spiral of bankruptcies,
repossessions, and turmoil emerged.
Putting the pieces together years later,
Congressman Charles Lindbergh wrote:
"The King Bankers put in motion,
in 1907, a great scheme.
They had gambled and
speculated on Wall Street
until so many watered stocks and
bonds had been manufactured...
The King Bankers knew the
condition and informed
the favored of their
friends what was to come.
There was to be a panic in the fall
of 1907 that would be advertised
as the result of our bad
banking and currency laws."
The Panic of 1907 led to a
Congressional investigation
headed by Senator Nelson Aldrich
who had intimate ties
to the financial powers
and later became part of Rockefeller
family through marriage.
The Commission led by Aldrich
recommended a Central Bank
should be implemented so a panic
like 1907 could never happen again.
This was the spark that the bankers
needed to initiate their plan
and in 1910 a secret meeting
was held at JP Morgan estate
on Jekyll Island off
the coast of Georgia.
It was there where the
Central Banking Bill
called 'The Federal
Reserve Act' was written.
This legislation was written
by bankers, not lawmakers.
This meeting was so secretive,
so concealed from government
and public knowledge that most
of the figures who attended
disguised their names when
in route to the island.
After this bill was constructed,
it was then handed over
to their political frontman, Senator
Nelson Aldrich, to push through Congress.
In 1913, with heavy political
sponsorship by the bankers
Woodrow Wilson became President,
having already agreed to sign
the Federal Reserve Act in
exchange for campaign support.
A few days before Christmas,
when much of Congress
was at home with their families, the
Federal Reserve Act was voted in
and Wilson made it law.
The night before its passage,
Congressman Charles Lindbergh pleaded:
"This act establishes the most
gigantic trust on Earth...
When the President signs this
act, the invisible government
by the money power
will be legalized."
The public was told that
the Federal Reserve System
was an economic stabilizer and
inflation and economic crisis
were a thing of the past.
As history has shown, nothing
was further from the truth.
The fact is the bankers now
had a streamlined machine
for economic manipulation.
(From the movie 'Frankenstein'
,1931) It's alive!
For example, from 1914 to 1919, the FED
substantially increased the money supply
resulting in extensive loans
to small banks and the public.
Then in 1920, the FED deliberately
contracted credit in an extreme way
thus resulting in banks having to
call in large numbers of loans
and just like 1907, bank runs, bankruptcy
and systemic collapse occurred.
Numerous competitive banks outside of
the Federal Reserve System collapsed
further consolidating the monopoly
of the money trust cartel.
Privy to this scheme, Congressman
Charles Lindbergh pronounced:
"Under the Federal Reserve Act,
panics are scientifically created.
The present panic is the first
scientifically created one
worked out as we figure a
mathematical equation."
However, the panic of
1920 was just a warm-up.
From 1921 to 1929 the FED again
increased the money supply
resulting once again in extensive
loans to the public and banks.
There was also a fairly new type
of loan in the stock market:
the Broker Call Loan.
Very simply
this loan allowed an investor
to put down only a fraction
of the stock's value, with the
rest being loaned from the broker.
This method was very popular
in the roaring '20s
as everyone seemed to be
making money in the market.
However, there was a
catch to this loan.
It could be called in at any time,
and had to be paid within 24 hours.
and the typical result was the selling
of the stock purchased with that loan.
A few months before
October in 1929
JD Rockefeller, Bernard
Baruck, and other insiders
quietly exited the market, knowing the
bubble created was about to burst.
On October 24th, 1929, the financiers
who furnished the call loans
started calling
them in, in mass.
This sparked an instantaneous massive
sell-off in the already inflated market
as sell orders and margin calls
were systemically triggered.
That then lead to mass bank runs,
eventually collapsing thousands of banks
enabling the large banks to buy up
the now failed ones at a discount.
But it didn't stop there.
Rather than expanding the money
supply in order to recover
from this economic collapse,
the FED actually contracted it
fueling one of the largest
depressions in American history.
Outraged, Congressman Louis
McFadden then Chairman
of the House Banking Committee
filed petition for impeachment
against the Federal
Reserve Board, stating:
"Mr. Chairman, we
have in this country
one of the most corrupt institutions
the world has ever known.
I refer to the Federal Reserve Board
and the Federal Reserve banks.
This evil institution has
impoverished and ruined the people
of the United States...
and has practically bankrupted our government.
It has done this through the defects
of the law under which it operates.
Through the maladministration of that
law by the Federal Reserve Board
and through the corrupt practices of
the moneyed vultures who control it."
Having reduced the
society to squalor
it was then decided that the
gold standard should be removed.
In order to do this, they needed to
acquire the remaining gold in the system.
Under the pretense of helping
to end the depression
came the 1933 gold seizure.
Under the threat of imprisonment
for 10 years, everyone in America
was required to turn in all
gold bullion to the Treasury
essentially robbing the public of what
little real wealth they had left.
At the end of 1933, the gold
standard was abolished.
If you look at a dollar bill before
1933, it says it is redeemable in gold.
You look at the dollar bill today,
it says it is legal tender
which means it is backed
by absolutely nothing.
The only thing that gives our
money value is the public faith
and how much of it
is in circulation.
Therefore, the power to
regulate the money supply
is also the power to
regulate its value
which is also the power to manipulate
and control entire economies.
"Whoever controls the volume
of money in any country
is absolute master of all
industry and commerce."
James A. Garfield, 20th
president of the United States
It is important to
clearly understand:
The Federal Reserve is
a private corporation.
It is about as 'federal'
as Federal Express.
It makes its own policies and
is under little regulation
by the US government.
It is a private bank
that loans all the currency
at interest to the government
completely consistent with
the central banking model
that the country sought to escape
from when it declared independence
in the American
Revolutionary War.
Going back to 1913, the Federal
Reserve Act was not the only bill
pushed through Congress for the
vested financial interests.
They also pushed its partner:
the federal income tax.
First of all, the federal income
tax is completely unconstitutional
as it is a direct,
unapportioned tax.
And the required number of
states needed in order to ratify
the amendment to allow the
income tax was never legally met
and this has even been cited
in modern court cases.
"If you were to go back and try to
find and review the ratification
of the 16th amendment...
you would find that a sufficient number of states
never ratified that amendment."
- US District Court Judge JC Fox, 2003
Second, at the present day, roughly
25% of the average worker's income
is taken from them via this tax.
That means you work 3 months
out of the year to fulfill
this tax obligation and
where does that money go?
According to the Grace
Commission Report of the '80s:
"100% of what is collected is
absorbed solely by interest
on the federal debt and by
federal government contributions
to transfer payments. In other words,
all individual income tax revenues
are gone before one nickel
is spent on the services
which taxpayers expect
from their government."
Today, the money Americans make
working 3 months out of the year
goes almost entirely
to the interest fees
charged for the
debt-based fiat currency.
The fact is, the Federal Income Tax
exists to feed the Federal Reserve
federal government money machine
making sure the interest
payments are always there.
And 3) Even with the government claim
as to the legality of the income tax
there is evidently
no clear statute.
No law in existence that
requires you to pay this tax.
(Former IRS agent)
I really expected
that of course there's a law
that you can point
to in the law book
a code, that requires you to file tax return.
Of course there is!
I was at that point where I
couldn't find the statute
that clearly made
a person liable
at least not me and
most people I know
and I had no choice in my
mind except to resign.
Based on the research that I
did throughout the year 2000
and that I'm still doing, I
have not found that law!
I've asked Congress, we've asked
a lot of people in the IRS
the IRS Commissioners' helpers.
They can't answer
because if they answer, the
American people are going to know
that this whole
thing is a fraud.
I haven't filed a federal
income tax return since I left.
I have not filed a tax
return since 1999.
(Joseph)
Now, the control of the economy
and the manipulation of society
for the vested financial powers is
only a part of the game being played.
Another level is the
business of war.
Since the inception of the
Federal Reserve in 1913
a number of large and small
wars have commenced.
The three most pronounced
might be World War I
World War 2 and Vietnam.
World War 1: In 1914
European wars broke out
centered around
England and Germany.
The American public wanted
nothing to do with the war.
In turn, president Woodrow Wilson
publicly declared neutrality.
However, under the surface,
evidence now shows
that the financial powers
behind the Administration
were looking for any excuse
it could to enter it.
It is important to understand that
one of the most lucrative things
that can happen for
the bankers is war
for it forces the country to
borrow even more money at interest
not to mention the profits generated through
the financing of military productions.
In the words of two-time
Congressional Medal of Honor winner
Smedley D. Butler "War is a racket.
It always has been.
It is possibly the oldest,
easily the most profitable
and surely the most vicious.
It is the only one international in scope
and it is the only one in which the
profits are reckoned in dollars
and the losses of lives."
Woodrow Wilson's top adviser and
mentor was Colonel Edward House
a man found to have
intimate connections
with the financial
interests of the time.
In a conversation between
Colonel House, Wilson's adviser
and Sir Edward Grey, the
Foreign Secretary of England
regarding America and
the war, Grey inquired:
"What will America do if
Germans sink an ocean liner
with American passengers on board?
" House responded:
"I believe that a flame of indignation
would sweep the United States
and that by itself would be
sufficient to carry us into war."
On May 7th 1915, a ship
called the 'Lusitania'
was sent where German military
vessels were known to be.
As likely expected, German
U-boats torpedoed the ship
exploding stored munitions,
killing 1200 people.
To further understand the obvious
anticipation of this setup
the German Embassy actually put
advertisements in the New York Times
telling people that if they boarded the
Lusitania they did so at their own risk
as such a ship sailing from America
to England through the war zone
would be liable to destruction.
In turn and as anticipated,
the sinking of the Lusitania
created a wave of anger among
the American population
and America entered the
war a short time after.
Major General
Smedley D. Butler summarizes
the monetary reality
of World War I:
"Looking back, Woodrow Wilson was
re-elected president in 1916 on a platform
that he had "kept us out of war".
Yet, five months later he asked Congress
to declare war on Germany...
The 4 million young men
who put on uniforms and marched
or sailed away were not asked
whether they wanted to go
forth to suffer and die.
Then what caused our government to
change its mind so suddenly? Money.
An Allied Commission...
came over shortly before the war declaration
and called on the President, who
summoned a group of advisers.
The head of the Commission spoke.
Stripped of its diplomatic language
this is what he told the President
and his group: "There is no use
kidding ourselves any longer.
The cause of the Allies is lost.
We now owe you American bankers,
American munitions makers
American manufacturers, American
speculators, American exporters
5 or so billion dollars.
If we lose (and without the help
of the US we must lose), we,
England, France and Italy
cannot pay back this money...
and Germany won't."
It has been estimated by statisticians,
economists and researchers
that the war yielded $16 billion in profits.
That is how the 21,000 billionaires
and millionaires got that way.
This $16 billion profits is not to be sneezed at.
It is quite a tidy sum.
And it went to very few."
World War II
On December 7th 1941, Japan attacked
the American fleet at Pearl Harbor
triggering US entry
into that war.
President Franklin D.
Roosevelt declared the attack was:
'a day that will live in infamy'.
A day of infamy indeed
but not because of the alleged
surprise attack on Pearl Harbor.
After 60 years of surfacing
information it is clear
that not only was the attack
known well in advance
it was outright
wanted and provoked.
In a journal entry by Roosevelt's
Secretary of War Henry Stimson
dated November 25th, 1941,
he documented a conversation
he had with Roosevelt: "The question
was how we should maneuver them
into firing the first shot...
" and in Congressional testimony
he later added: "It was
desirable to make sure
the Japanese be the ones to do this
so that there should remain no doubt
as to who were the aggressors."
In the months leading up to
the attack on Pearl Harbor
Roosevelt had done almost
everything in his power
to anger the Japanese, showing
a posture of aggression.
He halted all of Japan's
imports of American petroleum.
He froze all the Japanese
assets in the United States.
He made public loans to Nationalist
China and supplied military aid
to the British, both enemies
of Japan in the war
which, by the way, was in complete
violation of international war rules.
With numerous Japanese
codes broken in advance
revealing the plan to attack,
on December 7th 1941
Japan was allowed to attack Pearl
Harbor killing 2400 soldiers.
Before Pearl Harbor, 83% of the
American public wanted nothing to do
with the war. After Pearl Harbor
one million men
volunteered for that war.
It is important to note, Nazi Germany's
war effort was largely supported
by two organizations, one of
which was called IG Farben.
IG Farben produced 84%
of Germany's explosives.
One of the unspoken
partners of IG Farben
was JD Rockefeller's Standard
Oil Company in America.
The German Air Force could not
operate without a special additive
patented by Rockefeller's
Standard Oil.
The drastic bombing of London
by Nazi Germany for example
was made possible by a $20 million
sale of fuel to IG Farben
by the Rockefeller's
Standard Oil Company.
This is just one small point on the
topic of how American businesses
funded both sides
of World War II.
One other treasonous
organization worth mentioning
is the Union Banking
Corporation of New York City.
Not only did they finance numerous
aspects of Hitler's rise to power
along with actual
materials during the war
it was also a Nazi money laundering
bank, which was eventually exposed
for having millions of dollars
of Nazi money in its vaults.
The Union Banking Corporation of
New York was eventually seized
for violations of the
Trading with the Enemy Act.
Guess who the director and Vice
President of the Union Bank was?
Prescott Bush, the father and
grandfather of former US President
George W.
Bush and George HW Bush.
Vietnam: United States official
escalation and entry in the Vietnam War
came after an alleged incident
involving two US destroyers
being attacked by North Vietnamese
PT boats in the Gulf of Tonkin.
This was known as the
Gulf of Tonkin Incident.
This situation was the catalystic
pretext for massive troop deployment
and full fledged warfare.
One problem, however
the attack on the US destroyers
by Vietnamese PT boats
never happened.
Former Secretary of Defense Robert
McNamara stated years later
that the Gulf of Tonkin
incident was a 'mistake'
while declassified documents
released years later show
that it was a farce, manipulated
for the purposes of war
and once in the war, it
was business as usual.
In October 1966, President Lyndon
Johnson lifted trade restrictions
on the Soviet Block knowing
full well that the Soviets
were providing upwards of 80% of
North Vietnam's war supplies.
Consequently, the Rockefeller
interests financed factories
in the Soviet Union, which the
Soviets used to manufacture
military equipment and
send it to North Vietnam.
However, the funding of
both sides in this conflict
was only one side of the coin.
In 1985, Vietnam's Rules of
Engagement were declassified.
This detailed what American troops were
and were not allow to do in the war.
It included such absurdities as: North
Vietnamese anti-aircraft missile systems
could not be bombed until they were
known to be fully operational.
No enemy could be pursued
once they crossed
the border of Laos or Cambodia.
Most revealing of all, the most
critical strategic targets
were not allow to be attacked, unless
initiated by high military officials.
Apart from these illogical limitations,
North Vietnam was informed
of these restrictions and therefore
could base entire strategies
around the limitations
of the American Forces.
This is why the war went on for so
long and the bottom line is this:
The Vietnam War was never meant
to be won, just sustained.
This war for profit and resources
resulted in 58,000 American deaths
and 3 million dead Vietnamese.
Where are we now?
September 11th was the jump-start
for a hegemonic agenda
enabling the possibility of
constant global warfare.
It was a staged war pretext no different
than the sinking of the Lusitania
the provoking of Pearl Harbor
and the Gulf of Tonkin lie.
If 9/11 wasn't a
planned war pretext
it would be an
exception to the rule.
It has been used to launch
two unprovoked illegal wars:
one against Iraq and one
against Afghanistan.
However, 9/11 was the pretext
for another war as well.
The war against you.
The Patriot Act
Homeland Security, the
Military Tribunals Act
and other legislations are
all completely designed
to destroy your civil liberties
and protect those in power.
Currently in the United States,
unannounced to most Americans
your home can be searched without a
warrant, without you being home.
You can in turn be detained indefinitely
with no charges revealed to you
no access to a lawyer
and legally tortured.
All under the suspicion that
you might be a 'terrorist'.
If you need a painted picture
of what is happening
let's recognize how
history repeats itself.
In February 1933, Hitler
staged the false flag attack
burning down his own German
parliament building the Reichstag
blaming it on
communist terrorists.
Within the next few weeks
he passed the Enabling Act
which completely eradicated
the German constitution
destroying people's liberties.
He then led a series of preemptive
wars, all justified as necessary
to maintaining
'homeland security'.
An evil exists that threatens
every man, woman and child
of this great nation.
We must take steps to ensure
our domestic security and
protect our homeland.
George W. Bush?
Adolf Hitler
when announcing the
Gestapo to the people.
On the matter of communism
and its front organizations
should not obscure the issues!
Our enemy is a radical
network of terrorists
and every government
that supports them.
(P.Joseph)
It's time to wake up.
The people in power go out
of their way to make sure
you are perpetually
mislead and manipulated.
The majorities'
perception of reality
especially in the political
arena is not their own.
It is shrewdly imposed upon them
without them even knowing it.
For example, the public at large
now believes the invasions of Iraq
and the Middle East, along
with the resulting instability
are the consequences of political
and military mistakes.
What the public fails to see is that
the destabilization of the Middle East
is exactly what the
Western interests want.
This war is to be sustained, so
the region can be divided up
domination of the oil maintained,
continual profits reaped
for defense contractors,
and most obviously
permanent military bases established
to be used as a launching pads
against other oil bearing,
non-conforming countries, such as Iran.
For further implication that the
Middle East destabilization
is purely intentional, in 2005,
two elite British SAS officers
were arrested by Iraqi police
after being caught driving around
in their car shooting at civilians
while dressed up as Arabs.
After being arrested and
taken to a jail in Basra
the British army immediately
demanded the release of these men.
When the Basra government
refused, British tanks came in
and physically broke out the
men from the Basra prison.
(L. LaRouche)
If you wish to
destroy an area, how do you do it?
There are two ways: You can
go in there and bomb it
but that is not very efficient.
What you do is you try to get the
people in that area to kill each other
and to destroy there own
territory, their own farms.
And that's what has
been done in that area.
The way in which you destroy
an opponent is by getting him
to destroy himself by dividing
his ranks against one another.
Then you feed both sides, you
have agents feeding both sides
inflaming both sides.
And they kill each other off.
It's time that some of us
woke up to this reality.
To understand that people who try to
maintain empires and create empires
do it by manipulating the people
they are trying to conquer.
(P. Joseph)
You might want to ask
yourself why the entire culture
is utterly saturated with mass
media entertainment from all sides
while the educational
system in America continues
its stupefying downward slide
since the US government
decided to take over
and subsidize the
public school system.
(J. Maxwell)
What your
government pays for, it gets.
When we understand that, then
we look at government financed
institutions of education and
see the kind of students
and the kind of education
that is being turned out
by these government-financed
schools
logic will tell you that if what is
being turned out in those schools
was not in accord with what the state
and the federal government wanted
then it would change it.
The bottom line is that the government
is getting what they have ordered.
They do not want your
children to be educated.
They do not want you
to think too much.
That is why our
country and our world
has become so proliferated
with entertainments
mass media, television shows
amusement parks, drugs, alcohol
and every kind of entertainment, to
keep the human mind entertained.
So that you don't get in the
way of important people
by doing too much thinking.
You had better wake up and
understand that there are people
who are guiding your life
and you don't even know it.
We are in a lot of trouble!
Because you people
and 62 million other Americans
are listening to me right now.
Because less than 3 percent
of you people read books.
Because less than 15 percent
of you read newspapers.
Because the only truth you know
is what you get over this tube.
Right now there is a whole, an entire
generation that never knew anything
that didn't come
out of this tube.
This tube is the gospel,
the ultimate revelation.
This tube can make or break
presidents, popes, prime ministers.
This tube is the most awesome goddamn
force in the whole godless world
and woe is us if it ever falls in
the hands of the wrong people.
And when the largest
company in the world
controls the most awesome
goddamn propaganda force
in the whole godless world
who knows what shit
will be peddled for
truth on this network.
So you listen to me.
Listen to me:
Television is not the truth.
Television is a goddamned
amusement park.
Television is a circus, a carnival,
a traveling troop of acrobats
story tellers, dancers, singers,
jugglers, sideshow freaks
lion tamers and
football players.
We are in the boredom
killing business!
But you people sit there day
after day, night after night
all ages, colors, creeds...
We are all you know!
You're beginning to believe the
illusions we are spinning here.
You are beginning to think
the tube is reality
and that your own
lives are unreal.
You do whatever the tube tells you.
You dress like the tube
eat like the tube, raise
your children like the tube
you even think like the tube.
This is mass madness, you maniacs!
In God's name you people
are the real thing.
We are the illusion!
(P. Joseph)
The last thing the
power establishment wants
is a conscious informed public
capable of critical thinking.
This is why a continually
fraudulent zeitgeist is output
via religion, the mass media,
and the educational system.
It is in their interest to keep
you in a distracted naive bubble.
And they are doing a
damn good job of it.
This is Aaron Russo, a filmmaker
and former politician.
To his left is Nicholas Rockefeller
of the Council on Foreign Relations.
After maintaining a close friendship
with Nicholas Rockefeller
Aaron eventually ended the relationship,
appalled by what he had learned.
(A. Russo)
I got a call one day
from an attorney woman I knew
and she said "Would you like to
meet one of the Rockefellers?"
And I said "Sure, I'd love to."
And we became friends
and he began to divulge
a lot of things to me
so he said to me one night:
"There's going to be an event,
Aaron, and out of that event
you're going to see, we're
going to go into Afghanistan
so we can run pipelines from the Caspian Sea.
We are going to go into Iraq
to take the oil and establish
a base in the Middle East
and we are going to go into
Venezuela and get rid of Chavez."
The first two they have accomplished,
Chavez they didn't accomplish.
And he said "You are going
to see guys going into caves
looking for people they are
never going to find. "
He was laughing about the fact
that you have this war on terror
and there is no real enemy,
he was talking about
how by having this war on
terror you can never win it
because it is an eternal war.
So you can always keep taking
peoples liberties away.
And I said "How are you going to
convince people that this war is real?"
And he said "By the media, which can
convince everybody that it's real. "
You just keep talking about things, you
keep saying them over and over again
and eventually
people believe it.
You created the Federal
Reserve in 1913 through lies.
You create 9/11, which
is another lie.
Through 9/11, then you are
fighting a war on terror
and all the sudden you go into
Iraq, which was another lie
and now they are
going to do Iran.
It's all one thing leading to
another, leading to another...
I would say to him "What are you doing this for?
What's the point of this thing?
You have all the money
you would ever want.
You have all the power. You're hurting people.
It's not a good thing."
And he would say "What do you
care about the people for?
Take care of yourself and
take care of your family."
And then I said "So what are
the ultimate goals here?"
He said "The ultimate goal is
to get everyone in this world
chipped with an RFID chip.
And have all money be on those chips
and everything on those chips
and if anybody wants to protest
what we do, or violate what we want
we just turn off their chip."
(P. Joseph)
How far will
the sickness of power go?
To what lengths will
those in control go
in order to maintain and
preserve their positions?
We have a Florida family who are
really pioneers in a brave new world.
They have volunteered
to be the first ever
to have microchip identification
devices implanted into their bodies.
After 9/11, I was really concerned
with the security of my family.
I wouldn't mind having something
planted permanently in my arm
that would identify me.
(P. Joseph)
George Orwell in his famed and
possibly prophetic work '1984', stated:
"Power is not a means,
it is an end.
The object of persecution
is persecution.
The object of torture is torture.
The object of power is power."
Today, symptoms of a surveillance
society continue to grow
as irrational fears
of invisible enemies
coupled with rising economic
instability spread across the globe.
It is under this guise of security
that we can foreshadow a world
where everyone is tracked,
everyone is on camera
and everyone is subordinated.
The most incredible
aspect of all:
Such totalitarianism would likely
not be forced upon the people.
Rather, the people
will demand it.
For the social manipulation of society
through the generation of fear
and division has completely
inhibited the culture.
Religion, patriotism,
race, wealth
class and every other form of
arbitrary separatist identification
and thus conceit has served to
create a controlled population
utterly malleable in
the hands of the few.
'Divide and Conquer'
is the motto
and as long as people continue
to see themselves as separate
from everything else, they lend
themselves to being completely enslaved.
However, if the people ever realized the
truth of their relationship to nature
and the truth of their personal
power to affect change
the entire manufactured
zeitgeist that's preyed upon
would collapse like
a house of cards.
(R. Alpert)
The whole
system that we live in
drills into us that we're
powerless, that we're weak
that our society is evil,
that it's crime ridden, etc.
It's all a big, fat lie!
We are powerful, beautiful,
extraordinary.
There is no reason why we cannot
understand who we truly are
where we are going.
There is no reason why the average individual
cannot be fully empowered, we
are incredibly powerful beings.
- I think I spent
30 years of my life
the first 30, trying to become something.
I wanted to become good at things
I wanted to become good at
tennis, school and grades
and everything I viewed
in that perspective:
I'm not OK the way I am, but
if I got good at things...
I realized that I
had the game wrong.
The game was to find out
what I already was.
(R. Albert)
Now, in our
culture we have been trained
for individual differences
to stand out.
You look at each person
and the immediate hit is:
brighter, dumber, older,
younger, richer, poorer
and we make all these
dimensional distinctions
put them into categories
and treat them that way.
And we get so that we only see
others as separate from ourselves
in the ways in which
they are separate.
And one of the dramatic
characteristics of experience
is being with another
person and suddenly seeing
the ways in which they are like
you, not different from you.
And experiencing the fact,
that which is essence in you
and which is essence
in me, is indeed one.
The understanding that there is no other.
It is all one.
I wasn't born Richard Albert, I
was just born as a human being
and then I learned this
whole business of who I am
and whether I'm good or
bad, achieving or not
all that's learned
along the way.
"When the power of love
overcomes the love of power
the world will know peace."
- Sri Chinmoy Ghose
(C. Sagan)
The old appeals to racial,
sexual and religious chauvinism
to rabid nationalist fervor,
are beginning not to work.
A new consciousness is
developing which sees the Earth
as a single organism
and recognizes
that an organism at war
with itself is doomed.
- Bill Hicks used to finish
his shows with this:
"Life's like a ride
in an amusement park
and when you go on it
you think it's real
because that's how
powerful our minds are.
The ride goes up and
down and round and round
it has thrills and chills and
it's very brightly colored.
And it's very loud and
it's fun for a while.
Some have been on the ride for a long
time and they begin to question:
Is this real?
Or is this just a ride?
And other people have remembered
and they come back to us
and they say: 'Hey, don't
worry, don't be afraid ever
because this is just a ride."
And we kill those people.
Shut him up I have got a lot
invested in this ride, shut him up!
Look at my furrows of worry...
Look at my big bank account and my family.
This has to be real.
It's just a ride. But we will kill those
good guys who try and tell us that.
Have you ever notice that?
And let the demons run amok...
But it doesn't matter,
because it is just a ride
and we can change
it anytime we want.
It is only a choice. No effort, no
work, no job, no savings of money.
Just a choice right now.
Between fear and love.
The Revolution is Now
For detailed sources, explanations
and further information
regarding the content in this
film, please download the free
"Companion Source Guide" from www.
ZeitgeistTheFilm.com