JAKE BROWN: I think he actually
just came up with it
the day before he was going
to do it or something.
Or maybe that night, like,
he was partying.
And then he just randomly
went and did it.
LIZARD KING: I'm just fucking
super wasted, talking shit,
saying that I'd go there
and do it and fucking--
MALE SPEAKER: What,
did you run into
him at a bar or something?
LIZARD KING: Yeah, I was down
in Hensley's bar down south.
One night, I was just talking
shit to all those fools.
And the next thing I know, PLG
fucking pulls up at like 10:00
in the morning and drove
me to Bob's house.
It's just, like, still high as
fuck on ecstasy, just sitting
there, like, what the fuck?
I think I maybe slept for
30 minutes or something.
MALE SPEAKER: So they just
thought you were
claiming it, so?
LIZARD KING: Yeah, I pretty
much got fucking put in my
place, like, all right,
here it is.
Fucking, let's put your mouth
where your fucking shit is.
PIERRE LUC GAGNON: I set him up
with a board and some pads.
At first he was claiming he
was going to do it without
pads, but we were kind of like,
dude, you've been up all
night, take it easy.
Maybe you should just warm up
with kneepads, at least, and
then when you get comfortable,
take your pads off.
LIZARD KING: Dude, when I got
there, Bob's like, it's
nothing, dude, try it.
Check it out.
He goes up, no pads, nothing,
just grabs his board, drops
in, jumps the gap, and just
lands on his butt, looking at
me, talking at me.
He's like dude, it's easy.
You got it, like sliding
on his ass.
MALE SPEAKER: Any quotes, Bob?
BOB: He's making it right now.
No big deal.
It's Lizard King.
MALE SPEAKER: Do
it first shot.
You fucking got it.
BOB: All right.
LIZARD KING: Slash drove
me up to the top.
And we got up there and looking
down, I was fucking
shitting myself.
PIERRE LUC GAGNON: And it was
pretty crazy, because he was
super hung over.
And before he even tried,
he threw up.
He was puking, because he was
kind of like nervous and hung
over at the same time.
LIZARD KING: Fucking
scared shitless.
MALE SPEAKER: How far was
the gap that you made?
LIZARD KING: I think
it's like 50 feet,
or 55 feet, or something.
Dude, yeah, it's nuts.
And the way it's built, too,
it's like a step-up.
You know what I mean?
So the whole time you're rolling
up to it, it looks
like you're going to just
fucking run into a green
plywood wall.
Like, if you hit that, you
just fall into a net.
And the net is sketchy
as fuck.
PIERRE LUC GAGNON: I mean, for
me, jumping down 15 stairs is
way gnarlier than jumping
the mega ramp.
So I was like, yeah, if he can
do shit like that, he can
definitely do the mega ramp.
I've seen guys do back flips
over the mega ramp, just like
looping out because they'd
be in the backseat.
This guy John Schultes, used to
be a pro skater, he got so
scared he was like
leaning back.
And he did a perfect back
flip into a knee slide.
It's like the most insane
footage you've ever seen.
So yeah, I was telling Lizard
all those stories.
And he was pretty
hyped on them.
Then tried it maybe, like, 5 to
10 more tries, and pulled
it, like full pull.
[CHEERING]
MALE SPEAKER: That was a make.
PIERRE LUC GAGNON: Dude, that
was the fastest, probably
fastest make I've ever seen.
[CHEERING]
PIERRE LUC GAGNON: Congrats.
LIZARD KING: Wow, that
shit is so tight.
PIERRE LUC GAGNON: After I took
him out to the mega ramp,
we were drinking
this one night.
And he was, like, dude, I'm
fucking getting "PLG" tattooed
on my wrist.
And I'm like, yeah right,
you're just drunk.
I was like, yeah,
whatever Lizard.
Then the text came in that
said, I told you, son.
And it was like the ghettoist
tattoo of just like
"PLG" on his wrist.
Thrasher did the little
feature on it.
The article kind of ended, it
was like, oh yeah, it'd be mad
passion if PL would get
a Lizard tattoo.
LIZARD KING: PLG got a big ass
lizard right here holding a
flag that says "passion"
on it.
[LAUGH].
PIERRE LUC GAGNON: It's like
one of his board graphics,
actually, so.
MALE SPEAKER: [LAUGH].
MALE SPEAKER: And then
you have a Laced one?
LIZARD KING: Yeah,
because I was
partying with Jake Browning.
It was like, we stayed
at his house.
I just got all fucked up.
Did a bunch of coke, and a bunch
of ecstasy, and shit,
and had some dude come over
and give me that one.
[LAUGH].
MALE SPEAKER: Wait, what's
Laced, is that your company?
JAKE BROWN: Yeah.
MALE SPEAKER: What is it?
JAKE BROWN: It's a clothing
thing me, Smolik,
and Sheffey are doing.
We'd been drinking all night
or whatever and then he's
like, I'm down, I'm going to
go get a Laced tattoo.
We're like, yeah, right, all
right, see you tomorrow.
He shows up the next day, he's
like, check it out, fool.
[LAUGH].
Like, dude, this fool's
beat us to the market
shit on our own shit.
[LAUGH].
He's a fireball, man,
just hanging out
with the dude, he's--
you never know what's going
to happen next.
He's like, 100%.
PIERRE LUC GAGNON: There was
a contest when I was at the
Harmony Festival.
And it's this big hippy fest.
Just like people taking
shrooms, and
doing acid, and shit.
And Lizard was going
to judge a contest.
And next thing you know,
Lizard's nowhere to be found,
just tripping all weekend.
He ended up trying to judge a
contest, but all I remember
hearing was Neil Hendrix telling
me that Lizard fell
asleep halfway through
the contest.
He was judging, and then halfway
through, he was like,
that was fucking gnarly,
and just fell asleep.