So sofrito's the base. It's chopped white
onions and a little bit of celery. And then
I want to add the risotto rice. I'm using
arborio rice, you can use carnaroli. A handful
per person.
Now while that's doing that, here I've got
some dried porchini. So what I'm going to
do is get a bit of my stock. So I'm just going
to give them a couple of minutes.
So my rice is sounding a little hot, and what
I'm going to do and you could use white wine
at this stage, but I'm going to use vermouth
which is absolutely fantastic.
Now as soon as that's gone in we want to stop
the frying and we want to go into risotto
mode adding small ladles of stock every minute
or so and giving it a little stir up.
Literally after a minute, right, beautiful
porchini and look in there. I mean already
chicken stock and dried mushroom taste is
incredible.
In with the mushroom stock. Now here, look.
Here on the board just chop them up and straight
in every last bit.
All I have to do now is keep adding stock
and stirring it. Massaging out all the starch
until it's ready.
Now while that's just finishing off, here
I've got some lovely wild mushrooms. I've
got the girolle, pied de mouton, chanterelle,
with the mushrooms, what I want to do is I
want to put them dry in and around this screaming
hot griddle pan.
Risotto is done. What I need to do definitely
while it's hot is get a knob of butter. I
want a nice handful of Parmesan, going to
mix this up. Beat that up. Lid, let it chill
out. Whilst that off the heat, let's have
a little look over here.
These mushrooms should be toasted. I'm going
to get these mushrooms, I'm going to pick
some nice herbs. I love chervill, very, very
nice. I've got some parsley, tarragon. Most
of that in there, leave a bit for garnish.
Now, tiny bit of oil. Now let's get a lemon.
Squeeze half that lemon into there, while
these are nice and warm and while the risotto
is resting. Let's plate it up. Lovely.
Just spoon this on beautiful risotto. Beautiful
look at that. And then we get a little handful
of our beautiful mushrooms and we just splay
them all over the top like that.
Then I get get a little knob of butter and
put that in the middle there and it will start
to melt. Now just give it a tiny, tiny little
grate.
Look at that.