ROY STAFFORD: All
part of the job.
HARRY STAFFORD: The first race
of this season at Jerez, I got
a really good start.
I got second into the
first corner.
ROY STAFFORD: He was in a bunch
of four or five riders
at the front and the
next group were
very, very close behind.
He made a slight mistake
at the hairpin.
Nearly high sided, and then
another rider hit him, which
consequently injured him,
breaking his collarbone and
having a severe concussion.
All I could see was what was on
the monitor, and I just saw
number 24 rider crashed.
And I was hoping that it said
then afterwards, rider okay,
but it didn't.
He was very expertly
attended to.
The concussion was the worst.
He had two small blood clots on
the front right-hand lobe
of his brain.
This is what they were
concerned about.
I hadn't slept from Saturday
night, and I
was absolutely shattered.
But when your little boy is
in the hospital, and he's
injured, and he might need
you at any time,
you can't go to sleep.
The bike came over his
shoulder, broke his
collarbone, went up here--
this is Dunlop rubber--
and then glanced off.
So consequently, the helmet
cracked here, because of the
side pressure.
This is the first time I've seen
it since the crash and
it's the first time Harry had
seen it since the crash.
So whether it's brought back
any memories, I don't know.
But I wouldn't have thought so,
because you can't really
remember much.
HARRY STAFFORD: I can't remember
the lights going out
or anything.
Everything was a blank from
near enough a week.
And then the last two days in
hospital, I just barely
remember that.
I just remember pulling
up to the grid.
That's it.
So--
ROY STAFFORD: Yeah, it's taken
him two months to fully
recuperate.
But this was on the advice
of Red Bull.
HARRY STAFFORD: If you crash
and it affects you and you
don't want to ride, then
you shouldn't ride.
But I love riding, so I want
to get back on the bike as
soon as possible.
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYING]
ROY STAFFORD: I worry about him
all the time, but there's
not a lot you can do about it.
He wants to race motorcycles
and that's it.
The minute he says he doesn't
want to do it anymore, I shall
say, OK, mate.
Finished, no problem.
But hopefully I'll never
have to say that.
[MOTORCYCLE ENGINE REVVING]
ROY STAFFORD: No.
HARRY STAFFORD: My mom is really
nervous because she
thinks there's something
wrong with me now,
because I keep on crashing.
But when you get to ride at this
level, and you have to
push hard to ride with the
front, you start crashing.
And Gusto tells me that whenever
you crash, you learn
from the crash so you know
not to do it next time.
I learn a lot.
[MOTORCYCLE ENGINE REVVING]
DANNY WALKER: He's down at about
20, and he was 10 for a
little while, and he
just hasn't gotten
comfortable with it.
So I'm hoping-- he's got about
6 minutes left, so we'll see
how things turn around
here for him.
Hope he can find something
he's comfortable with.
DANNY WALKER: He did?
See?
He was trying, and
he just crashed.
HAYDEN GILLIM: I just
shot off the track.
My hands are beat
up a little bit.
Some purple, but that's
about it.
My leathers got beat
up more than I did.
DANNY WALKER: Hayden doesn't do
anything just a little bit.
He's got to do it big.
Go big or go home.
HAYDEN GILLIM: This is the
first time I crashed.
[INAUDIBLE]
Cup.
The Rookies.
I've only crashed
twice on the US.
ROY STAFFORD: You did a 45 flat
and then a 44.6, which is
absolutely fantastic.
All right?
HARRY STAFFORD: You start
getting better and better and
better, and you just think,
oh yeah, I can make it.
You can go for the next step,
you can just keep on going up.
When you're riding, you should
be happy all the time.
If you're sad, then you
don't do very well.
MATHEW SCHOLTZ: For now
I got like third,
so I'm pretty happy.
MATHEW SCHOLTZ: What happened?
MATHEW SCHOLTZ: Really?
JAKE GAGNE: I think I got sixth
out of both qualifying,
so six on the grid tomorrow.
I'm not too sure about that
second row, so I'm pretty
happy with it.
Just got to get a good
start tomorrow.
We'll see how it goes.
STURLA FAGERHAUG: Yeah, and
I'm going to beat him.
At least try.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
ROY STAFFORD: We don't
do holidays.
We don't like doing holidays.
This is our holiday, at
the race circuit.
I know it probably sounds
sad, but it's true.
What you have to remember is,
racing is a very, very, very,
small circle.
There are not many
people that race.
We are all a family, because we
all have a common interest.
HAYDEN GILLIM: Our van that we
have has a horrible AC system,
so we drove yesterday back from
here to the hotel with
the side door open.
MATHEW SCHOLTZ: We took 100 and
what, like 60 kilometers?
Hayden's hanging out, both feet
outside, sliding and stuff.
It was just crazy.
And the end we saw pretty
hot German chicks.
HAYDEN GILLIM: We were lifting
up our shirts and trying to
see if they would do it.
MATHEW SCHOLTZ: We were trying
to flirt with them, but we
weren't so good.
HAYDEN GILLIM: In the rain,
it's two things for me--
either win or crash trying.
So far, it's crashed.
All right, now I'm
pretty happy.
If it stays like this for the
rest of the day, this is going
to be good.
DANNY WALKER: They keep telling
themselves that, I
hate the rain, I don't like
the rain, I hate the rain.
And guess what?
They're going to hate the rain,
they're not going to
like the rain.
So Bradley's going to tell me
that he loves the rain.
Right Benny?
I love the rain.
No, can't even say it.
Go on, say it.
Didn't hurt, did it?
Everything has to
slow way down.
Any of your actions that you
have have a gigantic reaction.
So if you brake really quick,
or get on the gas really
quick, or turn too hard, it
usually ends up being a, I
don't like the rain, I don't
like it at all, doesn't it?
BENNY SOLIS: I've been in the
rain three times and every
time I crashed, so we'll see.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
COLLEEN SCHOLTZ: Last year,
Mathew did three races in the
wix, and he did very well.
And we put it down to his
motocross experience, riding
in the mud and everything
in South Africa.
HARRY STAFFORD: If you're
aggressive with the bike, the
bike can be aggressive back,
and that's when you crash.
It throws you off.
It's like the bike's got
an emotion, just
the same as a person.
It can only take so much,
and then it snaps.
[MOTORCYCLE ENGINE REVVING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
DANNY WALKER: We hadn't had a
chance to ride the bike after
it got crashed, and you just
never can tell, you know,
little things.
We started it a couple times but
without actually going out
and doing a lap, you have no
idea what's going to happen.
So we had a slight problem, and
we think we got it fixed,
and he's ready to make up some
points this weekend.
It's Christmas time
for Hayden.
He likes the rain.
PETER CLIFFORD: Not a
wonderful start from
Fagerhaug, but not too
disastrous, he has made some
disastrous starts.
But into the first corner,
I think it's Kornfeil who
probably leads.
Kent is there in about fourth
place, the white helmet, he
drifts a bit wide.
Out of the picture already
has gone Kornfeil.
Fagerhaug and Brown go
past Kristiansson.
So Fagerhaug now takes it down
to a 1.9 second advantage, and
he's really got Kornfeil
in his sights.
And Fagerhaug goes down,
Fagerhaug goes down and out.
Well, it's an absolute disaster
for the cup leader.
And we're just saying that
before the race that really
Sturla had it all to lose.
He went into this race
with a handsome
40 plus point advantage.
High sided, out of the
race, goes Fagerhaug.
Fastest man on the track,
though, is Hayden Gillim in
sixth place.
He's riding brilliantly in these
tricky wet conditions.
Hayden Gillim in the black
helmet has passed the white
helmet of Danny Kent, and Gillim
now is right there in
the battle for the last
rostrum position.
PETER CLIFFORD: There is Hayden
Gillim, he's now on his
own, though.
Gillim on his own.
So what has happened to Scholtz
and Kristiansson, has
he just ridden away from them?
Ah, no it's Gillim who had the
fall and he's on his own
because he's just got himself
back into action.
DANNY WALKER: Ooh.
Ooh.
That close.
It's called racing, otherwise
it'd be a parade.
You'd just nod and wave.
ROY STAFFORD: Hey,
he's up to 11th.
Yeah, he's riding OK, he's
riding within himself, he's
riding according to the
conditions, not doing anything
stupid, opting out.
PETER CLIFFORD: It's
Kent and Scholtz.
Scholtz goes up the inside
on the brakes
into the tight section.
Here comes Jakub Kornfeil around
the last climbing left
hander, out on to the start and
finish to win his first
Rookies Cup Race.
And down goes Danny Kent, out of
the last corner, down goes
Danny Kent.
And it's Scholtz that
takes second place.
And across the line
comes Jake Gagne.
He didn't expect
that, I'm sure.
[BAND PLAYING]
JAKE GAGNE: Everybody kept going
down, and going down, it
was really slippery.
So I just sat back and let
everybody else scratch,
because I already was too far
back at the beginning, so I
just let everybody go down
and ended up third.
So it's good.
COLLEEN SCHOLTZ: I am
proud of Mathew.
He started eighth on the grid
and worked his way up to
second, and I'm very
pleased for him.
COLLEEN SCHOLTZ:
Nerve wracking.
[LAUGHS].
Especially as you can see him
going, and you just keep
thinking in your head, keep
it smooth, you can
do it, keep it smooth.
ROY STAFFORD: Well, it was
absolutely bang on.
He started from 15th
on the grid.
Rode his own race, rode nice
and steady, quite within
himself, to the track
conditions.
And dash me, he come
home ninth.
So I'm well happy with that.
HAYDEN GILLIM: These
guys are idiots.
HAYDEN GILLIM: I got
a black eye.
STURLA FAGERHAUG: I got some
ice on my lower back, yeah.
I landed straight on my
back, so I'm feeling
a bit of pain there.
HAYDEN GILLIM: I landed
on my head.
HAYDEN GILLIM: Yeah, it is.
GUSTL AUINGER: It
was a race like
professional racers are racing.
And someone was very
lucky today, and
some were not so lucky.
But I'm proud of my boys.
They did a great, great job.
ROY STAFFORD: Well, people often
will say to you, how the
hell can you let your child race
around a circuit at 130
mile an hour, putting
them in danger.
But what they don't
realize is, these
children want to do this.
It is their life,
their passion.
And they are not
forced at all.
Not at all.