Lightning flickers somewhere in Earth's atmosphere
dozens of times every second. Most of these
electrical flashes remain in the clouds, with
only about a fifth of them reaching low enough
to strike trees, buildings or the ground.
Yet lightning bolts in the clouds deliver
a unique and powerful punch of their own.
They're directly linked to events that produce
some of the highest-energy radiation naturally
found on Earth: terrestrial gamma-ray flashes,
or TGFs for short.
Thanks to recent work by NASA's Fermi Gamma-ray
Space Telescope, scientists have come a few
steps closer to understanding these extraordinary
outbursts. When lightning flashes high in
the clouds, its energy may alter the strong
electric fields near the top of the storm.
About a thousand times each day, this sudden
change triggers an upward surge of high-speed
electrons. Reaching speeds nearly as fast
as light, these accelerated electrons give
off gamma rays when they're deflected by air
molecules. TGFs happen quickly and randomly,
so even catching them by satellite has been
difficult.
But new results from the Gamma-ray Burst Monitor
on Fermi are giving scientists fresh insights.
Last year the GBM team showed that TGFs well
away from Fermi produced beams of charged
particles that could travel along Earth's
magnetic field and hit the satellite. Now,
thanks to advancements in data processing,
Fermi's GBM is better at detecting TGFs than
ever before. As a result, scientists have
discovered that radio signals once thought
to be produced by the lightning that triggers
a TGF are in fact broadcast by TGFs themselves.
Each lightning stroke creates a burst of Very
Low Frequency radio waves. Through the World
Wide Lightning Location Network, scientists
use this unique radio signal to track electrical
activity around the globe. For some time,
scientists have know that TGFs were associated
with strong radio signals, so it was natural
to think that these radio signals were produced
by the lightning stroke that triggered the
TGFs.
Here's one instance that highlights why the
GBM team now questions this interpretation.
It's August 2009 and Fermi is flying over
thunderstorms off Mexico's West Coast. Each
symbol marks the location of a lightning The
highlighted circle shows how much of Earth's
surface
Fermi can see at any given moment. Just as
the satellite passes over the storms, a TGF
occurs. There's no other lightning near that
position when Fermi detected the TGF. hundreds
of TGFs and comparing them to radio-based
lightning locations, the GBM team concludes
that both the gamma-ray and the the strong
radio emission comes from the TGF. The team
also finds that weaker radio bursts ocurring
up to several thousandths of a second before
or after a TGF actually represent the individual
lightning stroke associated with it.
The GBM findings confirm a theory published
in 2011 that the same avalanche of speedy
electrons that creates a TGFs gamma rays also
produce strong Very Low Frequency radio signals.
With this knowledge, scientists can pair the
Fermi TGF sample with the more precise radio
positions from the World Wide Lightning Location
Network.
This will clarify weather patterns associated
with TGFs and usher in new studies, perhaps
helping scientists determine which types of
thunderstorms produce some Earth's highest-energy
natural light.