nonsense charges
things that are at most of my relation
of copyright law
and why we should terms of service
uh... but should not be criminal let
alone a felony
do you know this officer precourt
justice a very serious crime
the gifted you off too
one year in prison
you sort of a dangerous weapon
in yet your maxim of ten years in prison
cabinet secretaries members of congress
say more
if you go out for supreme court justice
or the attorney general the united
states with a weapon
in get up to ten years
passports was facing fifteen years
now i know it's multiple counts
above his the trip but they always do
follow that one time that i think you
were hiding in
that account
another time that was a free
administrator that's another town and
it's another town we had all these
together we had fifty years why
we wanted to meet you will a bully you
will pressure you wanna break you
because you do not banned all our power
to do not banned or power we will break
it
number two
uh...
threatening the president might dot it's
really serious right
they epic five years in prison
five years in prison protecting the
president
fifty years providing terms of service
practically dick
contract yet with a private organization
doesn't know it work for us they work
for the corporation thread but in this
case is mental disease or
people are criminal charges also told
george is a guest at par
no only spreading aids
killed outright
max of ten years in prison
welcome are selling child pornography
read that's gotta be much wars yeah well
it is worse
maxim of twenty years in prison
uh... fifty years transports possible
bank robber twenty years
or bank robbery endangering others
maximum twenty five is a grim
you are all bank with a shotgun
you get twenty five years in prison
you couple
possibly hacked in it's not even hacking
into something 'cause he had a contract
with them
he didn't break into their system he was
already in their system
you want to terms of service
for this cat
private contractor you have fifteen
years he was facing they had already
bankrupted m with all that money that
had gone to as a case
do you know that there is a crime called
selling slaves is showing that happens
actually there's sex slaves that art
before sleep kidnapped
brought into sex slavery itself
selling slaves just that
maxim of twenty years in prison
passwords facing
fifty years in prison
helping terrace developed and no clear
watch apt to be more right
walang
twenty years in prison
twenty years in prison for helping out
here develop a nuclear weapon
but whatevs forested face up to fifty
years in prison
you know what's criminal
what our government is doing to its
citizens
that's what's criminal
and by the way
one of the things that he was charged
with was wire fraud
you know was not charged with the wire
fraud
hsbc
did why fraud
money-laundering which the government
says they did
with the largest drug cartels in the
world
and without a doubt
and with a wrong
for that they face a fine
but the prosecution the justice
department is so concerned about as
toward came and said
on sorry
and there's nothing we can do it if we
prosecuted any of those banking
executives that might indeed to the bank
which might endanger the global economy
so you can do wire fraud well the
largest drug cartels a terrace in the
world
but don't you bill by a later time
service
with a private corporation
does that mean i will come to get you
because you are dangerous
you're a danger to them because you have
something they do not have
you've actually access information they
do not want you to access
because you have a skill but they have
not been able to neutralize yet so they
try to neutralize you flawless or
justice department did aris words is
sickening is grotesque and now he is
dead at least partly because of it and i
would say largely because of it i'd hope
they're proud