the Pulitzer Center and National Geographic,
has been covering that for the past year.
We have explored how the composition of our
society is changing. We are becoming a more
urban population. Mega-cities, those with
more than 10 million residents, are booming.
In 1975, there were only three such places.
Now there are more than 21. Fred de Sam Lazaro
reported from New Delhi last December. FRED
DE SAM LAZARO: Jyoti Sharma, a conservation
activist who runs a small aid agency, says
the city is simply overwhelmed. JYOTI SHARMA,
water activist: Every year, we get an additional
.5 to .7 million people. That's the net addition
to the city. FRED DE SAM LAZARO: Seven hundred
thousand people every year? JYOTI SHARMA:
Seven hundred thousand people, yes. A majority
of this growth is of people who are poor.
And they typically come and settle in these
kind of settlements. Only 27 percent of the
city is actually a planned city. The rest
of it has just grown like this. And you cannot
stop them from coming, because that's the
only place they will get some livelihood from.
HARI SREENIVASAN: Babies born today enter
a world where 13 percent of the population
doesn't have access to clean drinking water.
That was the subject of Steve Sapienza's report
in march from Dhaka, Bangladesh. STEVE SAPIENZA:
If you want to see the human toll exacted
by unsafe water and poor sanitation in Dhaka,
you come here. This is the overflow tent at
the short-stay unit at Dhaka's main cholera
and diarrhea hospital. This man arrived at
the hospital with no vital signs. After 15
minutes of trying to revive him, his wife
is given the news. The staff reports cholera
as the cause of death. HARI SREENIVASAN: But
while the overall number continues to rise,
in places like Brazil, family sizes are shrinking.
In August, Fred de Sam Lazaro outlined some
of the forces changing fertility rates there.
FRED DE SAM LAZARO: Eighty percent of women
of childbearing age use contraception. At
the same time, a robust economy has needed
their labor. Today, women make up 40 percent
of the country's work force up and down the
economic ladder. The majority of college graduates
in Brazil are women. HARI SREENIVASAN: To
see many more images, you can download the
National Geographic 7 Billion app for the
iPad. For more now on what a seven billion-person
world might mean, we are joined by Azza Karam,
a senior adviser at the U.N.'s Population
Fund, and Dennis Dimick. He is the executive
editor of environment at National Geographic
magazine, our partner in world population
coverage. So, Dennis, let me start with you.
What are the implications of a 7 billion-person
world? You have been looking at these stories
all year. DENNIS DIMICK, National Geographic
magazine: Well, I think the idea that 7 billion
is really just a spot on a trajectory that
we're all on. And if it's laid out, we were
at 6 billion just a few years ago, and by
2025, we will be at 8 billion. So, really,
what it is, it really gives us an opportunity
not so much just to talk about 7 billion,
but what does that mean and what are the kind
of challenges that we all face as we go forward
to try to fulfill the needs of everybody on
the planet? HARI SREENIVASAN: Now, Azza Karam,
it's a nice round number that gets our attention.
So now you have it. What should we be focused
on? AZZA KARAM, United Nations Population
Fund: We should be focused both on the challenges
that this represents, as well as on the opportunities,
because there is no way that it is only a
litany of challenges. It certainly is a matter
of access to resources. More people means
more pressure on already rare resources, from
the air we breathe, the water we drink, the
food we eat. It literally is a great deal
more demand than there may well be supply.
But at the same time, we have to balance that
perspective by looking at the opportunities
that 7 billion presents in terms of the most
amazing amount of human power that this Earth
has ever seen, and especially given the technology
that is being evolving as we speak, especially
communication technologies, but also the technologies
of the better use of resources that we're
all trying to harvest. The fact that there
will be 1.8 billion of that 7 billion is young
people, which is a remarkable potential, as
we're seeing every day unfold in terms its
of new strategies for seeking demand. And
one of the challenges and also an opportunity
is the fact that we have a lot more women
who will be hard-pressed as heads of households
to make ends meet, but, at the same time,
a lot more women in the labor force who are
in positions of decision-making. So I think
we need to make sure we keep that balanced
perspective all the time. HARI SREENIVASAN:
Dennis, as one of the stories we profiled
showed, the rate of population growth isn't
the same all over the world. In fact, the
U.N. says that 42 percent of the population
on Earth is not replacing itself generation
after generation -- 40 percent is and maybe
a little bit more. And then there is another
18 percent that's rapidly growing. What are
these disparities about? DENNIS DIMICK: So,
what we see in large measure is, in northern
latitude countries -- in fact, we're seeing
-- across Europe and Japan, we're actually
seeing a fertility rate -- that's the number
of children born per women that reach childbearing
age -- is actually less than replacement.
And so we are seeing aging populations across
Europe and in Japan. So we don't have the
young people coming into the society that
do things like work and pay the taxes and
help pay for the pensions, for example. And
then in, largely in southern countries, for
example, most of the largest potential growth
we're going to see is in Africa and in Southern
Asia, where the populations are getting younger.
HARI SREENIVASAN: Ms. Karam, what does it
mean when we have these sort of lopsided societies,
when certain countries are going to have much
older populations without the young to support
them? AZZA KARAM: Well, it basically means
what we're seeing evolve right now, which
is migration patterns from the areas where
there seems to be too many people, if one
can say that, to areas where there is obviously
a need for labor, because there is a serious
shortage of that labor. That is only one of
many implications, which is this migration
trend. You are also going to see different
kinds of pressures being exerted by governments,
unfortunately, on women to either try to encourage
them to have more children. But what is infinitely
more effective, I think -- and that's one
of the reasons why the United Nations Population
Fund has been leading a 7 Billion Actions
campaign globally -- what is a great deal
more effective is to show how women can become
very important agents of change in their societies.
But in order to do so, they need access to
good health care, access to education, equitable
access to all kinds of resources. But we also
know that investing in health care, especially
maternal health and education about sexuality
and reproductive health, can be -- can save
lives and it can save a great deal of money.
So it's very cost-effective to do this. HARI
SREENIVASAN: Dennis, on your site, there's
a story that says a baby born today in the
U.S. or perhaps in a Western nation has a
50/50 chance of living to be 100 years old.
What sorts of resource strains -- or what
sorts of resources do we have to have to sustain
a population that can live that long? DENNIS
DIMICK: Well, I think that's one point that
we have tried to make in our series, also,
is that this discussion of population is really
not just about numbers of people, but it's
also the resources that each of us use. And
if you look in the United States, for example,
we use many, many times much more resources
per person than say a person in Bangladesh
or other country that doesn't have advantage
of, say, things like electricity. A quarter
of the world's population doesn't even have
electricity, like we take advantage of every
day. HARI SREENIVASAN: Ms. Karam, what are
those correlations that you're seeing between
the levels of education for a woman and the
population growth in those countries? AZZA
KARAM: Well, we know for a fact that the statistics
indicate that women who have more access to
population and who are better educated are
actually women who choose to have smaller
families, certainly smaller compared to generations
before them. So there is a very strong correlation
between education and choosing or the ability
to make choices about the size and the number
of our families. But there's an even more
important point I think that we have to make,
which is that, effectively, there are over
200 million women who would want to have access
to family planning facilities and care and
who cannot have that access. And one of the
things that the United Nations Population
Fund and many partners around the world is
engaging in is trying to ensure that there
is an awareness that we have to make sure
that not only knowledge and education, but
also access and information about family planning
and reproductive health care and access to
services, all manner of reproductive health
services, needs to be made available for women
around the world and for families. HARI SREENIVASAN:
All right. Azza Karam from the United Nations
Population Fund and Dennis Dimick from National
Geographic magazine, thanks so much for your
time. DENNIS DIMICK: Thank you. AZZA KARAM:
Thank you. urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:smarttags
PersonName urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:smarttags
place urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:smarttags
City urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:smarttags
PlaceName urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:smarttags
PlaceType urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:smarttags
country-region JEFFREY BROWN: Hari Sreenivasan
takes the story from there Normal Microsoft
Office Word JEFFREY BROWN: Hari Sreenivasan
takes the story from there Title Microsoft
Office Word Document MSWordDoc Word.Document.8