You got to pay attention
to that stuff.
All right, [INAUDIBLE].
-Ready?
GRIME: Yeah, man.
Let's put some stencil on you.
God, I really tweaked out
on that little city.
Fuck, it's like way nicer
than I thought.
I can't believe I have to
fucking match that.
Fuck, why did I do that?
It's way too much work.
Shit, shit, shit, shit.
Did I really do it that it
looks that good somehow?
It looks that good?
And why did I put that
much work into it?
Now I have to do it again.
I can do it again though.
I can do it again.
I can manage it.
CIV: When you're dealing with
people who are their harshest
critics, the work's going
to be amazing.
And I think Grime's been
pushing himself
so hard for so long.
We spoke about it
a long time ago.
And I said to him, do you think
if you didn't have the
accident when you were a kid
that you would push yourself
as hard as you do?
Are you trying to prove
something because of the burns
and because of the accident?
And he's like, of course I am.
I make myself push myself more
because of what happened.
And he's super honest about it
and that made sense to me.
No one is going to be able to
work as hard as him unless
they're him.
And I'm not speaking for
him, this is my own
perception of it.
You don't have this insane
hurdle that he
deals with every day.
So the way he gets over that
hurdle is by crushing
everybody in tattooing.
GRIME: I don't think there's a
lot of difference between my
work and a lot of people's work
besides I think I'm able
to get my personality through
in a lot of my work.
They probably think
I'm kind of crazy.
That's probably what I think.
CHRIS O'DONNELL: Everybody
across the board has complete
respect for Grime.
Whether you love his style, or
just kind of like it, or don't
like it all, you can
appreciate the work
that went into it.
GRIME: There's only so much that
I could seek for outside
[INAUDIBLE].
I'm not so insecure that I'm
going to get rattled by some
people going I don't know.
I don't know if he's
that good, or I
don't like his tattoos.
Not to say if everybody in the
world thinks my tattoos suck
and I think they're great, I'm
going to be walking around
thinking I'm king shit
of turd island.
But if I can get reward out of
it, then for me then it's
nice, you know?
HENRY LEWIS: We have people
coming from all over the world
mainly to see Grime, because
that's his spot.
And the guy's been consistent
ever since I've met him.
He's always been a
cool cat and he's
always spoke his mind.
But he hasn't been Mr. Tattoo
Ego Tattatude guy, so I
appreciate that.
-What is the name
of your shop?
GRIME: Skull and Sword.
-Who works there?
GRIME: Me, Yutaro Sakai,
Henry Lewis, and Lango.
They seek, I think, along
the same lines as I do.
They're not trying to
be on a TV show,
or be fucking whatever.
They're trying to do work.
They want to improve
their work-- that's
important to them.
They're not interested in being
a famous tattoo person.
They seek satisfaction
from the work itself.
HENRY LEWIS: Every day is like
there's something new to be
learned from anyone.
It's funny, we have this dynamic
in the shop where
Grime and Yutaro are the
older cats and on the
more technical side.
And they're a little quieter
than we are.
And then Lango and I, we
control the back room.
We're a little loud and mad--
personally expressive.
But that dynamic in the shop
just works really well with
each other.
Because everyone has something
to bring to the table, no
matter what.
He's a little quieter until you
rouse him a little, he's
like right with all the boys.
GRIME: What happened?
What happened to the girl that
you were thinking was probably
really good marrying material
because she doesn't do coke?
Remember her?
That was amazing.
CIV: I think when Grime and I
first met we connected on a
wise ass level, because we
didn't know each other at all.
I had these sunglasses on that
I thought were super cool and
I thought, break the ice.
And I just like, dude, stop
sweating my sunglasses.
I was like, do you want
to try them on?
And without missing a beat he
goes no, thanks, I don't have
any fucking ears, so how
would I try them on?
So I was like aw, man.
And he just started cracking
up and the other
dudes started laughing.
He's like you see his face?
See his face?
I fucking got him.
And I was like, oh my
God, this guy's a
complete dick, got it.
All right, cool.
So then that was kind of how
it was, which was back and
forth breaking each other's
balls kind of a thing.
You guys have a wide angle lens
enough for Grime's hairdo?
HENRY LEWIS: I think people
are in love with his
personality more than anything
and then the work is like an
extra bonus.
No two pieces are the
exact same, ever--
that's ill.
Like every day is
something new.
YUTARO SAKAI: His technique
is amazing.
And also, after he's been
tattooing for 17-18 years and
he's still managed to
progress every time.
That's incredible, I think.
CHRIS O'DONNELL: A lot of the
guys that work with him can't
help but be influenced by his
work, working with him on a
daily basis.
He has his own look.
So the shop has got a certain
look that's unique to itself.
I think a big part of what makes
up their look is detail
and effects and then
drawing skill.
And the ability to do
something unique.
And the desire to create
something unique and not just
adapt to what's come
before them.
LANGO OLIVEIRA: There's a lot
of good tattooers out there.
But not a lot of people push
stuff to the limit and he's
been doing that for
a long time.
GRIME: I definitely could
express myself in certain ways
because I have a lot of freedom
with my clients.
And I'm really fortunate
they let me just
push some of the stuff.
Like, they say I want
a skull on my back.
Then I get to go, OK, well,
what do I want that
thing to look like?
Or what are we going
to do with it?
You can try to create expression
or something,
whatever it is--
an idea or a look.
And to me that's very satisfying
to be able to do
that and to see it.
Even though most of the time I
don't really like looking at
my tattoos afterwards.
It's like a hypercritical
eye or something.
Sometimes it's just having
expectation of seeing
something that's not fully
finished yet, and wanting it
to look better.
CIV: When Grime's tattooing you,
if he starts with single
needle stuff it's the most evil,
brutal shit and he's
kind of like laughing
about it.
So it's like you're
kind of thinking
what's wrong with him?
He works feverishly to a point
where you think there's a gun
to his head for some reason.
You don't know why he's trying
to work so fast and so crazy
and kind of talking
to himself.
Because if you know him, it's
just 10,000 things are going
around in his head.
It's like a hornet's nest in
there, so his hands are just
keeping up.
I was actually talking to my
girlfriend on the way here.
She said something like Grime's
style is really weird.
And I said, it is?
She's like, it's beautiful,
but it's weird.
It's his thing.
I'd say Grime's stuff
is tweaky.
Everything is so tweaked out
and so overdone, but with
enough restraint where it
doesn't fuck it up.
HENRY LEWIS: He had this piece
in the "Iron Will" book, and
it was like a vampire woman.
There was no line work
in her bottom jaw.
And her bottom jaw was like this
big black gaspy mouth.
And for some reason-- like, it's
something new, but you
could tell it was based
off a traditional.
Or he did like a snake and a
bell, and then the snake's
made out of this really
weird smoke and dots--
that type of stuff.
That's coming from his head,
that's his style.
And that's the type of stuff
I like that pushes me.
CHRIS O'DONNELL: To me he seemed
very almost angry at
the idea of the status quo.
Like conforming to a style
or not putting
your mark on something.
Like it had to be unique or it
wasn't worth doing at all.
He's very almost obsessive about
getting away from any
kind of mediocre quality.
GRIME: I think about
art a lot.
I think about what I want
tattoos to look like.
I think about the things I like
and don't in tattooing,
in my own work or
other people's
work, and I apply those.
I think about that
stuff a lot.
I try to execute in a way so
that I can get the most amount
of visual pleasure from my work,
both in impact and the
dynamic aspect--
those are really important
to me.
I have pieces that
I actually like.
Tomorrow, the guy I'm tattooing,
he's got a sleeve I
really like.
It's kind of older now, but
I still really like it.
I wouldn't do the same one
again, but overall I really
like the tattoo.
It moves really well
on his arm.
I like the way it looks.
I like the colors.
I mean, not to sound too full
of myself, I don't think it
looks like anyone else's work.
To me that's very important--
I don't want my work to look
like other people's work.
I want it to look
like what I did.
If I can't distinguish my work
from two other guys, well
maybe they should just
do the tattoos.
What am I here for?
To me there's some of that
involved in tattooing.
I want to look at work that
I've done and go oh, wow,
that's cool.
I created that.
I put a lot of energy
into that.
I put a lot of conception
And wow, look, it kind
of came together.
It kind of gelled together after
all that work and all
that thought and everything
else.
Because we don't have a lot.
The tattoos go away.
It's nice to see them sometimes
and then to have a
good photo is sometimes nice.
We'll have tracings that you
think I should throw way.
Besides that, I don't have
much of tattooing.