in film or on TV, but
you're probably not
used to seeing him in a
suit and tie appearing
before a congressional
committee to testify
about a serious subject,
like Alzheimer's disease.
Seth has a very personal
connection to the disease
through his own family.
SETH ROGEN: After forgetting
who she and her loved ones were,
my mother-in-law, a
teacher for 35 years,
then forgot how to speak, feed
herself, dress herself, and go
to the bathroom herself,
all by the age of 60.
JACOB SOBOROFF: How
disappointing is it that only 2
of the 18 senators
on the committee
showed up for Rogen's testimony.
SETH ROGEN: Americans
whisper the word
Alzheimer's because their
government whispers the word
Alzheimer's.
And although a whisper is
better than the silence
that the Alzheimer's community
has been facing for decades,
it's still not enough.
It needs to be yelled
and screamed to the point
that it finally gets the
attention and the funding
that it deserves and needs.
JACOB SOBOROFF: His presentation
was certainly informative,
but, as you probably
expect, he was
able to bring levity
to what is otherwise
a very, very serious subject.
SETH ROGEN: That's right.
The situation is so
dire that it caused
me, a lazy, self-involved,
generally self-medicated
man-child, to start an
entire charity organization.
JACOB SOBOROFF:
Rogen and his wife,
Lauren, have created what's
called Hilarity for Charity.
It's an organization
that raises money,
it raises awareness, and holds
a star studded annual event.
Last year they made
half a million bucks.
You've probably seen Seth and
his wife talking about this.
They have been everywhere
from Larry King
to HuffPost Live, where
I actually had a chance
to sit down with
Lauren last year.
LAUREN MILLER: I'm
incredibly lucky to have
such a wonderful, supportive
husband who was been not just
good to Alzheimer's
personally, with my own family,
but he's able to bring an
awareness to the disease
that it unfortunately
doesn't have.
JACOB SOBOROFF:
It really is cool
when someone like this,
someone so famous, so funny,
can use their celebrity to bring
such a big spotlight on such
an important subject.
Chances are you or somebody
you know has been affected
by Alzheimer's.
Even Charlie McDonnell
has a touching story.
CHARLIE MCDONNEL:
Alzheimer's is something
that has affected me personally.
My granddad, Joe,
had Alzheimer's,
and unfortunately passed away.
Seeing him go through what
he did was hard for me.
And that's just me.
I can't even imagine what it
must have been like for him.
JACOB SOBOROFF: There
are a ton of great videos
out there to find out
more about Alzheimer's,
about current research,
about treatments,
and some really wonderful
personal stories.
We put together a playlist
for you with much, much more.
And you know what?
Get involved.
Go to hilarityforcharity.org,
or go down into the description.
All the links you
need are right there.
SETH ROGEN: I don't know if
you know who I am, at all.
You told me you never saw
"Knocked Up," Chairman, so--
TOM HARKIN: I will wager
this is the first time
in any congressional
hearing in history
that the words "knocked
up" have ever been--
SETH ROGEN: Oi, you're not gonna
like the rest of this, then.