general strike began.
Someone said about a million
people were turning up.
Further emboldening the strikers
was the presence of a
lot of stray dogs marching
in support.
MALE SPEAKER: [SPEAKING GREEK]
NARRATOR: They started early,
with crowds meeting around the
city at 10:30 and slowly
converging on Syntagma Square.
The vibes were good, unified
and peaceful.
MALE SPEAKER: [SPEAKING GREEK]
NARRATOR: Thanks to the guys
protecting Parliament, there
was nothing for the crowd to
do but pick a fight with a
cageful of riot police.
[SHOUTING]
That was the first and mildest
tear-gassing of the day.
By the way, that stuff they're
dousing themselves in is
called Maalox.
It's supposed to counteract
the gas.
MALE SPEAKER: [SPEAKING GREEK]
[CHANTING IN GREEK]
NARRATOR: Back outside
Parliament, it
was all kicking off.
We kept venturing into the
Square, only to get gassed
with the rest of the crowd.
[EXPLOSIONS]
[COUGHING]
NARRATOR: That's the sound of
our camera guy coughing blood.
[COUGHING]
[EXPLOSION]
[SCREAMS]
MALE SPEAKER: [SPEAKING GREEK]
[EXPLOSION]
NARRATOR: By 5 o'clock, after
more than four hours of
running battles around
Parliament, the people started
to disperse.
We might have felt like the
world was ending, but
according to the conversations
around us, the
day had been tame.
Everyone was saving themselves
for day two.