Should we interview
Shane Smith more?
SHANE SMITH: Here?
SPIKE JONZE: Yeah, right here.
SHANE SMITH: OK.
SPIKE JONZE: You know, I always
think that a lot of
what "Vice" has done has
happened because of your sheer
will of it.
You've willed it to be through
your force of life.
And--
SHANE SMITH: Yeah,
I think that too.
[LAUGHTER]
SPIKE JONZE: You know, it's part
having a vision, part PT
Barnum hyping it, and sort
of willing everyone to
go along with you.
SHANE SMITH: Yeah, when you're
starting out, you have to
definitely be louder noise
than the other guys.
SPIKE JONZE: You freak me out.
SHANE SMITH: No, I'm
the only one that
doesn't freak you out.
See, you've forgotten.
SPIKE JONZE: Oh, that's right.
You don't freak me
out anymore.
SHANE SMITH: I used
to freak you out?
SPIKE JONZE: No.
SHANE SMITH: See, I could
interview you.
So how did I freak you out?
SPIKE JONZE: I would say you
never freaked me out, but I
would say you've calmed down a
lot since I've known you in
the last eight years.
You're calmer.
SHANE SMITH: I was too--
SPIKE JONZE: You had, like, this
gusto, which both made
everything happen, but
also sometimes--
here's where you
freaked me out.
It's because whenever you'd
tell me what was going on,
you'd be like people
are freaking out
over what we're doing.
We just put the new issue, and
people are freaking out.
We're starting a new magazine
in Croatia.
People are freaking out.
We just wrote this script and
people are freaking out.
And like, everything
was on 10.
People were freaking out
about everything.
And this was like
eight years ago.
So, you know, you were
a younger man.
SHANE SMITH: Yeah, well know,
I probably had to sell it a
lot more because we weren't
as established.
So I had to be, like, always,
like, pumping it, pumping it.
And for sure, you're right.
So I was probably selling
Vice with my head nod.
People are freaking out!
Spike!
SPIKE JONZE: How do you think
you've mellowed out in the
last 8 or 10 years?
SHANE SMITH: You know, the
truth of it is, I always
thought I was going to die
because, when I was young, I
was in kind of a quasi gang.
There was 12 of us.
And then by the time I was
18, nine had died.
So I would just get wasted,
and get into fights, and
screw, and smash things, and--
I didn't care.
And I would always be like,
we have to do it now, and
fucking let's go!
Because I didn't there would
be a lot of time.
So I think that when
you realize--
I realized my mortality
was a good thing.
Because I'm like, first of all,
I'm going to be around
for a few years, hopefully.
And we can take our time.
We can enjoy it.
And I didn't have to
drink every day.
I didn't have to eat five steaks
everyday, although you
wouldn't know it.
I don't have to coke
all night.
I don't have to fuck 20 women.
And when that sort
of switched, then
you're like, OK, now.
Now what do I really
want to do?
So I want to work.
I want to put my indelible mark
on the cultural fabric
because I'm an egotist still.
I don't want to just be a guy
know for business or making
"Vice." I want to write
books, and make films,
and make the biggest--
I want to be like Tom Freston
and you, rolled into one.
I want to do a lot of stuff.
But I want to do it my
way and be happy.
And also enjoy traveling to
places like this, which is the
most beautiful place on
Earth, and crying.
SPIKE JONZE: And crying?
SHANE SMITH: Yeah.
SPIKE JONZE: Come
here, let's cry.
Come cry with me.
It's OK.
SHANE SMITH: See, [INAUDIBLE]
that's a good interview.
You're getting up there.
That's--
SPIKE JONZE: We're getting
there, we're not they're yet.
We're not there yet.
MALE SPEAKER: No one has
shit their pants.
SPIKE JONZE: Yeah,
then we're there.
Ah, yes.
Woo.
So Shane, so this game goes, I
give you a subject, and you
give me something profound, and
quick, and mindblowing.
And if I don't like it,
I cut your neck off.
SHANE SMITH: OK.
SPIKE JONZE: OK.
How about, tell me
about self-doubt.
SHANE SMITH: Oof.
I think my hyperbole was a
blanket again self-doubt.
I think everybody
has self-doubt.
And you mask it in
different ways.
Tattoos hide self-doubt.
Muscles hides the self-doubt.
Fashion hides self-doubt.
We put on outfits and personas
to mask our self-doubt.
And for me, I had to push
it to the back of my
sub-consciousness because
failure couldn't be an option.
Uh-oh, there it goes.
SPIKE JONZE: This is the
effect he's had on
[INAUDIBLE].
SHANE SMITH: I'm so
scintillating.
SPIKE JONZE: So drugs.
SHANE SMITH: Drugs.
Drugs, look, I think that the
whole world is drugged on one
thing or another.
SPIKE JONZE: What drugs were
you ever addicted to?
SHANE SMITH: So cigarettes.
Cigarettes was the hardest
thing I ever had to quit.
They're insidious.
Alcohol, there's a quote from
Napoleon which is a conquest
has made me, and conquest
must sustain me.
And so I used to say, alcohol
has made, and alcohol must
sustain me.
Because everything I did, my
hilarity, my lunacy, all the
stories, all the crazy things
I did was all just
booze-fueled.
SPIKE JONZE: Did you go through
a period where you had
to be the Shane Smith
character?
SPIKE JONZE: Correct, yes.
Describe that Shane
Smith character.
SHANE SMITH: Sort of the poor
man's Hemingway, sort of bon
vivant storyteller drunk.
Let's have 14 bottles of wine at
dinner, roast suckling pig,
and a story about chopping
off a dude's head in
the desert or something.
Like, adventurer.
I was never really addicted
to anything except for
cigarettes and booze.
And I probably did too
much cocaine for a
little period of time.
SPIKE JONZE: Yeah,
you did, a lot.
SHANE SMITH: How do you know?
SPIKE JONZE: Because I
remember seeing you.
SHANE SMITH: I used to
do coke off knives.
SPIKE JONZE: Off [INAUDIBLE]?
SHANE SMITH: Off knives,
yeah, any kind of knife
SPIKE JONZE: This is--
SHANE SMITH: Whoa,
don't-- fuck.
No, no, no, no, no.
That's not a fun game.
[INAUDIBLE]
We're going to put this back
in the area where it's
supposed to go.
SPIKE JONZE: OK, good job
with the sound bites.
SHANE SMITH: Oh, thanks.
Again
SPIKE JONZE: What do you think,
like, how she we end
this thing?
SHANE SMITH: We should go
swimming and end it as
the sun goes down.
SPIKE JONZE: OK, that
sounds good.
Making love on the beach?
SHANE SMITH: Yeah.
SPIKE JONZE: OK, got it.
Oh, wow let's go down there.
(SINGING) A salaam aleikum.
A salaam aleikum.
What does it say?