ordinary science experiments
into unforgettable learning
experiences.
I have an amazing team who will
do whatever it takes to
affect the way people
think about science.
And do that, I live
by one motto.
Make it big.
Do it right.
Give it class.
So let's find out simple
things that
will float and sink.
Dennis, it's time to
play float or sink.
Do you want to pick something?
That's perfect.
Dust remover.
I wonder-- rocket science--
what do you think?
DENNIS: Floats.
STEVE SPANGLER: Oh, you might
want to think it again.
DENNIS: Sinks.
STEVE SPANGLER: See, always
trust your first thing.
See, that's why he didn't
do well in school.
Float or sink?
What do you think?
MALE SPEAKER: Well, it's
going to sink.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK, let's
check and see.
No, you're wrong.
It floats.
You're fired.
Why don't we test this?
Your stapler, float or sink?
DENNIS: Sink.
Definitely sink.
STEVE SPANGLER: Are you sure?
You want to change?
DENNIS: Sink.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK.
Here we go.
Nope, it floats.
DENNIS: No, it doesn't.
STEVE SPANGLER: Oh
wait, it sinks.
All right, so it sinks.
All right, so you
won that one.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Sink.
STEVE SPANGLER: All right.
Let's check and see
how smart she is.
All of her pens.
Some float and some sink.
FEMALE SPEAKER: And some are
ruined and some are--
STEVE SPANGLER: I'm sorry.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Watered down.
STEVE SPANGLER: Look.
The amazing thing is
all the pens float.
But the scissors sink.
Isn't that an interesting
thing to have happen?
All right.
I want you to get
back to work.
Enjoy your day working at
Steve Spangler Science.
FEMALE SPEAKER: I love my job.
STEVE SPANGLER:And
this is great.
There you go.
FEMALE SPEAKER: You
know what--
STEVE SPANGLER: There you go.
Hey, let's see how iPhone
float or sink.
STEVE SPANGLER: Renee, what
would float or sink?
Let's see her hand.
It sinks.
Notice how it sinks very low.
MALE SPEAKER: Get a
piece of her car.
STEVE SPANGLER: Yes.
MALE SPEAKER: Pull off
a piece of her car.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK,
there you go.
Hey!
FEMALE SPEAKER: I'm
just kidding.
STEVE SPANGLER: I got
to get out of here.
Oh, that's perfect!
Here, can I have that?
Thanks, Higginsworth.
This is going to be perfect.
This is perfect Diet Coke ready
in our tank of floating
and sinking wonders and
mysteries of the universe.
Float or sink?
Let's see.
Here we go.
Yes.
It's a floater.
If you're a science person, you
can't just sit there and
say, well, it just floats
and I don't know why.
So I took all my lunch money,
and now I'm going to test all
of these cans.
There we go.
Ready?
That's a sinker.
All right.
And a floater goes over here.
Here we go.
Two sinkers.
Got it?
All right, here we go.
And here we go.
And this one is a--
look at this.
All right, here we go.
Sink and sink.
All right, so this is it.
These are the sinkers
right here.
These are the floaters
over here.
It's our job to figure out the
difference between the sinkers
and the floaters.
I know exactly what
you're thinking.
The scientific way would be to
first of all look at the
volume of each can, because
we'll need to see if the
amount in each can
is the same.
That means we need to take a
look at the amount right here.
Let's line them up.
Take a look at this.
355, 355, 355.
If you're metrically challenged,
that's 12 ounces.
Stick with metrics.
355.
Now let's take a look at
the ones that floated.
There's one.
Here's one.
And here's this guy here.
It's the same, 355.
Each one of these has
the same amount of
liquid that's inside.
And we can only speculate that
the volume of the can is
exactly the same, because look,
they're identical all
the way across.
It must be what's inside the
can that makes all the
difference.
Time to look at the label.
Let's move this out of the way
and analyze cans from each of
the two groups.
Float goes over here.
The sink goes over here.
And these--
Here's something that Americans
haven't read in a
long time, judging
from waistline.
140 calories in this one,
0 calories in this one.
But that doesn't really mean
anything until you go down a
little bit further.
The only noticeable difference,
in the one that
sinks, it's 39 grams
of carbohydrates.
The noticeable difference, the
one that floats, 0 grams of
carbohydrates.
But what does that
really mean?
Carbohydrates mean sugar,
a lot of sugar.
And the average American
consumes nearly 50 gallons of
this sugar-packed soda
every single year.
That's a lot of sugar.
And if you think about it,
there should be a weight
difference between the cans
because if density equals mass
divided by volume, and the
volume is the same on both of
them, it means the amount of
stuff in each of those cans
must be different.
It's time to weigh it.
All right, take a
look at this.
389 grams for the
one that sinks.
And the diet, 370 grams.
That's nearly 20 grams.
And it's all sugar.
But what does that
really look like?
A packet of sugar, that's
easy enough.
How many packets of sugar are
in that can of regular soda?
Well, of course, there's
more than one.
How about this 1, 2.
Keep going, 3.
And I got a bunch of them.
Just stop me when we're ready.
4, 5, 6-- no, keep going--
7, 8, 9, 10-- no, keep going--
11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 17,
18 packets of sugar.
Nutritionists say the equivalent
of sugar in that
can of soda is nearly
18 packets of sugar.
Now, let's say you go home and
on your way home, you're
thirsty, so you go get one of
those bladder busting cups
that's 60 ounces.
That's nearly 100
packs of sugar.
So let's say that you just
wanted one of these a day.
365 days, what could
that do to you?
Well, after 365 days, you've
eaten the equivalent of 3,650
teaspoons of sugar.
That's 32 pounds, or 14.5
kilograms of sugar.
All this talk of sugar
is making me hungry.
And who doesn't like
a gummy bear?
You ever heard of a kid being
all hyped up on sugar?
Well, my question is so how
much energy is in just one
tiny little gummy bear?
Let's go figure it out.
Well, this is where we
need safety glasses.
And we're also going to need
a strong oxidizer.
This is where we're using
this oxidizer here
called potassium chlorate.
And this is the part where I
have to tell you don't try
this at home.
Try it at a chemistry
teacher's home.
Wait until you get to college.
I don't care.
Just don't try it at home.
Potassium chlorate has oxygen
molecules that we can liberate
fairly easily with some heat
and an organic material.
And potassium chlorate has a
fairly high melting point.
That's why we're going to
need to use some fire.
You can see that it's
finally melting.
And it's just about ready
for some gummy bears.
So let's see how much energy
we can release by simply
dropping three of
the gummy bears
into our strong oxidizer.
Watch.
There's a tremendous amount of
energy being release in just
three gummy bears.
The strong oxidizer touches
the organic,
which is the sugar.
In fact, we're just figuring out
how much energy is trapped
in three gummy bears.
What remains from this smoky
mess is just a small amount of
carbon that's at the bottom
of the beaker.
Well, the producers at the Ellen
DeGeneres Show liked
that experiment.
But they wanted to know what
would happen if we took it to
an extreme level.
And I'd never seen anybody
do it in a
five liter flask before.
The question was just how much
smoke would it produce.
They weren't worried
about that.
And trust me, there was
a tremendous number of
firefighters that
were on the set.
Take a look.
Have you ever heard somebody
talk about a sugar high?
They say kids have
a sugar high?
So I have gummy bears.
So these are little
gummy bears.
And they're packed
with energy.
So when you get them to a kid,
of course, they're crazy.
So here's what I have here
is I have this liquid.
It's not just gummy bears you
feed to a kid that is crazy.
It's just candy in general.
I have a liquid here that's
full of oxygen.
And it's a great oxidizer.
So what I'm going to do is take
some of the gummy bears
and I'm going to drop
them down inside.
And I'm going to show you how to
release the energy from the
gummy bears.
ELLEN DEGENERES: What's
the liquid in there?
STEVE SPANGLER: It's
an oxidizer.
It's called potassium
chlorate.
It's an oxidizer.
So you stand back just
a little bit.
You're perfect right there.
OK, ready?
So I'm going to drop them
in here like this.
So watch this.
Oh, beautiful.
Look at the energy
that comes out.
Isn't that amazing?
ELLEN DEGENERES:
That's amazing.
STEVE SPANGLER: That glow.
ELLEN DEGENERES: Wow.
STEVE SPANGLER: Wow.
It never does that at home.
ELLEN DEGENERES:
And the noise!
STEVE SPANGLER: Do you
hear it howling?
So we call it screaming
gummy bears.
And the fumes are only slightly
toxic, which is nice.
ELLEN DEGENERES: Oh,
that's nice.
So I'm glad I'm not wearing--
STEVE SPANGLER: No, it's fine.
And the nice thing about
this is that it
smells like a campfire.
Well, in order to make candy,
believe it or not, you need to
know something about the
chemistry of sucrose.
And this is a simple
sucrose molecule.
Take a look.
The black here represents
carbon.
There are 12 of the carbons.
There are 22 hydrogens, which
are the white ones.
And there are 11 oxygens
that you see here.
And the difference between
somebody who really knows how
to make candy and somebody like
me who's just cooking
sugar is that the chef knows how
long to cook that sugar so
that they can literally just
make the water molecules start
to evaporate.
While we're not going to cook
that molecule, there is a way,
using some chemistry, that we
can make all those water
molecules come right off.
For this demonstration, we're
going to need to have some
gloves and some powdered
sugar.
Into the beaker it goes.
And that's the perfect amount.
And the reason for the safety
glasses and the gloves, this
bad stuff right here,
sulfuric acid.
If you read the label,
you would think that
sulfuric acid is strong.
Is says 18 molar, which
indicates the
strength of the acid.
However, chemically speaking,
it's a fairly weak acid.
The real danger around sulfuric
acid, believe it or
not, is when it gets in
contact with water.
And since we know that there's
water there in sugar, it
should be an easy way for
us to pull it out.
So here's what happens.
We take the sulfuric
acid and pour the
sulfuric acid into here.
And now we mix it around.
Watch what happens as it
starts to turn black.
We mix it around like this and
really get it mixed up.
It starts to become very, very,
very hot as we mix it.
And now watch what happens
when it takes off.
What you see coming off is all
of that water vapor, some
fumes, and of course we have
the black carbon remaining
from that simple
sugar molecule.
Higginsworth, you're
a good friend.
Thanks for letting me
have your soda.
You take that and buy
whatever you want.
HIGGINSWORTH: Thanks, Steve.
STEVE SPANGLER: You're
a good guy.
Little does Higginsworth know
that his body is going to
change with all that sugar.
It's going to transform
into something
that looks like this.
Well, if you enjoyed this week's
episode, go ahead and
click the Subscribe
button here.
And you'll be the first to know
when a brand new episode
appears each week.
This button right here will
show you some more cool
science experiments that we
do outside of the show.
This button right here will
take you to last week's
episode, just in case
you missed it.
And you want to see the stuff
that you shouldn't see, that's
the bloopers and the outtakes,
well, just click this one
right over here.
If you want to hear me stop
talking through the magic of
television, just click this
button right here.
Go ahead.
Click it and I'll stop.