NOAH SALASNEK: I definitely
skateboarded before I ever
snowboarded.
I probably started skateboarding
when I was six
years old, I believe.
My older brother actually,
when I was young, was my
mentor for skateboarding.
But as I got older, and got into
it, and progressed, some
of the prominent pros at the
time, obviously Tony Hawk, and
some of the vert skaters,
as I was a vert
skater at the time mainly.
One of my first sponsors
was a shop sponsor,
Marin Surf and Skate.
And that kind of gave me a
stepping stone to enter some
contests and get some
visibility.
I started getting in magazines,
and traveling a
little more, and I got picked
up by H-Street later on.
Yeah, I was in a couple
different H-Street videos.
The first one I was not in, I
think it was "Shackle Me Not"
was the name of it.
But that was the one that
got so much notoriety.
And then I got on H-Street and
I was in the following "Hokus
Pokus" video the next year,
I believe, and had a
good part in that.
Mack Dawg had actually
got me on.
I was friends with Mack
Dawg and he was
making videos for H-Street.
This was before the videos
were a big craze.
The Bones Brigade videos were
like the only thing.
So H-Street came out
with a great video
inspired by Mack Dawg.
And he actually got me on
the team and got me
introduced to them.
MIKE MCENTIRE: Well because
of "Sick Boys," Mike
Ternasky saw that.
He was pretty hyped on it.
I think the main thing
he liked about it
was the Super 8 filming.
He didn't know much about film
and he wanted to have that
look in "Hokus Pokus." So that
was the main reason why I got
hired for that gig and it
worked out pretty well.
NOAH SALASNEK: It's all history
there because I
started shooting with Mack Dawg
with snowboarding too and
kind of gave him a career, and
in return, he's helped my
career too.
So it's been pretty cool.
The reason I turned pro was I
had just competed the year
prior in three different events
to get to the nationals.
And I went there, qualified in
the street, and for the vert
contest as well, which was
my forte, a vert skater.
And I ended up winning a street
contest the day before
the vert contest.
And everyone was like, you're
going to turn pro.
And I'm like, what
do you mean?
They're like, dude, you won
the biggest event, amateur
event, you're going
to get a board.
I'm like, really?
And I was like, I don't
know about that.
And then I did horrible on the
vert contest because I was
just stoked on that I won
the street thing.
And sure enough, I did turn pro
and for a few years had my
own board with H-Street and Life
Skateboards at the time.
And I did pretty well.
I wish I would've hung on to
that career a little more now
that I look back and juggled
both, kind of
like Shawn White does.
I feel he's kind of a
new school of me.
He's really powerful on vert,
and doing well in
competitions, and killing in
snowboarding, obviously.
So he's someone who has kind of
taken a step farther than
what I did, I feel like.
MIKE RANQUET: About the same
time I met him snowboarding
through Roach, he was
already coming up in
NorCal skate scene.
And man, that guy
was so talented.
And when you see someone on a
vert ramp that size do a 6
foot ollie, like over
your head frontside
ollies, it's like wow.
And yeah, I knew if he got into
snowboarding, he would
help change things.
He was a much better
skater than me.
He was a pro.
He had a pro model deservedly,
not because he was like
"snowboarder." It wasn't like
a token type thing.
He was a legit gnarly
pro vert skater.
NOAH SALASNEK: I guess it was
around a seven to eight year
career that I had in
skateboarding before I
actually stepped away and
focused more on snowboarding
in my early 20s, I would say.
And not that I let my stating
go, but definitely the
competitive side I did.
And I still skateboarded for
fun, but I really focused on
the snow and made that my main
profession, I could say.
So I think I started
snowboarding when I was 18.
And it was kind of a cross
between my skiing and my
skateboarding.
I was like, wow, snowboarding
looks so cool to me.
And so I got into it way
later than actually
skating, for sure.
CHRIS ROACH: Yeah, when I first
met him he was already a
professional skateboarder.
I think him and AV were both
professional and they were
just getting into
snowboarding.
And once I saw them skating,
I was like, holy.
They were already
ripping skaters.
If we went somewhere together,
I could watch them skate and
try to learn from them.
And it was nice not to be the
only one around having that.
And they were pushing
snowboarding like they were
skateboarding.
NOAH SALASNEK: When I started
snowboarding, I saw people
like Chris and a few other pro
snowboarders on the hill when
I was actually learning,
I guess.
And this was probably in the,
I don't know, late '80s.
And I saw people like Chris just
ripping down the hill.
And I was like, wow, these
guys are really good.
And it just kind of motivated
me to ride more and
aspire to be that.
MIKE RANQUET: Noah has a lot
more to do with things than
maybe people know or maybe
even he knows.
Noah with Mack Dawg for
sure helped turn
that tide, like 100%.
BRAD KREMER: I think in "Hokus
Pokus" there was a couple
snowboarding shots of Noah.
And Dawger just was totally
against the whole snowboard
scene and stuff.
MIKE MCENTIRE: Well,
snowboarding was pretty
hurting, I thought.
And it actually was
pretty harsh.
Like early snowboarding, guys
didn't really understand
anything about style at all.
There was a few people that did,
like Terry Kidwell and
Craig Kelly, and they were
like doing it right.
But for the most part, your
average people that you would
see, they'd just suck.
Man, I can't even describe
how lame it looked.
I was over it.
We went up there and there was
all these dudes in hard boots
and tights basically,
like Day-Glo stuff.
And it just looked so stupid.
And I was filming skating, like
Danny Way, and Hensley,
and Noah, and those
guys, and all the
CBS guys in San Francisco.
Like the contrast between those
snowboarder dudes that I
saw and stating, I just
thought it was stupid.
Anyways, Noah wanted that shot,
so we went and got it.
But then I started snowboarding
with him and I
enjoyed it a lot.
And then him and Roach were
going off doing stuff.
And they made snowboarding
look good.
So that's why I started
shooting it.
CHRIS ROACH: When we were riding
together, like every
day it was something new.
Every single day we were
changing what was going to
happen with snowboarding.
And I remember those two years,
or whatever was going
on when we were doing that, that
snowboarding was going
into a new direction.
And it was nice to be
a part of that.
And I think Noah was one of
the guys who was in the
forefront of that.
And there would be no stopping
it at that point.
SHAWN FARMER: I don't know what
it was with those two,
but it was obvious--
I still feel like that whole
look still came from Terry
Kidwell, and like Palmer, and
then Craig Kelly, and Roach
was always there
too, and Salas.
But I don't even see it
today really, hardly.
You just don't see it.
It was just like I don't know
why those dudes got it and
like a lot of people didn't.
But it was really
cool looking.
They like rode together.
That was part of why they
are the way they are.
JAMIE LYNN: Noah had more of
like a technicality to him and
did more spin-oriented tricks
where Chris would kick out a
big grasser and Noah would
do like a backside seven.
Both sick, equally impressive
tricks, but just you could
tell that one was kind of a
technician and the other one
was kind of like laid back and
cruising, but also on point.
NOAH SALASNEK: No, if anything
he was more proficient.
He was the better rider.
I was trying to aspire to
be calmer like he is.
He's really calm on his board.
And I think I had that arm
movement that's so famous.
God, I don't know where
that came from.
But, yeah, I lost that.
And part of that I can
contribute to Roach.
A calm style, he's always had
that, and very fluid.
And I think I developed my style
more over the years,
whereas he actually just had
style, just hands down.
People might have said I have,
but I think that I worked on
it a little more,
I worked for it.
They either say you have
style or you don't.
You can work at it a little bit
and get some style if you
ride it enough.
CHRIS ROACH: I don't think our
styles were mimicking each
other at all.
I think if you look at it, we
don't ride alike at all, but
we did a lot of the same tricks
and stuff because we
fucking hung out every day.
And it was like, that was sick,
how about I try it?
JP WALKER: He was one of the
first guys that I was super
hyped on in snowboarding.
Like the first video I ever saw
was "Critical Condition"
and he had like a really sick
part in that video.
It wasn't like a part, but
he was like in the video.
And he was, I felt, one of the
guys that just kind of have
like a sick style.
Like Chris Roach is in the video
too, but he didn't have
much footage in it because
he got hurt.
And I was just stoked
on Salasnek's style.
I mean I had long blonde
hair and a goatee.
I looked just like him besides
maybe a dip in the mouth.
Like I totally tried to model
myself after him for so long.
NOAH SALASNEK: Well, I think
with Mack Dawg, growing up I
had a relationship with him.
We got along really well.
So I'd say he was the easiest
best person to film with.
And then with snowboarding, I
met Faultline Films and they
were pretty cool people,
I'd have to say.
They were my first real
snowboard film company that I
worked with legitimate.
Got some recognition
one year on that.
I had this offer from H-Street
to make a snowboard.
And I said, hey, let's do one.
They put my name on a board.
And unfortunately, one of the
owners had got in an accident
and passed away.
And the other owner of H-Street
did not want anything
to do with snowboarding and I
was kind of left in limbo.
And I ended up going to a trade
show with a resume and
going to Tom Sims
in the booth.
And they had new backers
and kind of worked
out a deal with them.
It was kind of a good
timing type thing.
But yeah, it was unfortunate
because I think H-Street could
have done something in
snowboarding had
Mike Ternasky lived.
But anyway, it was sad and it
was unfortunate, but I did
work it out with Sims and
ride for them for
seven or eight years.
TOM SIMS: I mean Noah was just
a really easygoing, likable
guy, and you couldn't help
but like the guy.
He was so low-key that when
you did seem him in a
half-pipe competition, you're
almost like, gosh, it almost
seems like it's a different
guy because he was so
technically advanced
on his tricks.
The other snowboarders could
appreciate what Noah was doing
and quite often the
judges didn't.
CHRIS ROACH: I think what
set Noah and I apart
was that, for me--
I mean I gave a shit, I did
contests and stuff, but I
never did well in them.
And Noah would go in there and
his head was always together.
He always did well
in contests.
I mean, he could go to any
contest and, fuck, he was
going to be top three
no matter what.
I'd go there and even if we
are the same rider and I
should be up there, I'd get
fucking 10th and be like,
yeah, I got 10th.
And he wasn't stoked, man.
He wanted to win everything.
And that's cool, man.
He had a lot of heart
and passion for it.
CIRCE WALLACE: I feel like
Noah took it farther.
I think Noah was technically
more capable.
Chris really, he was a little
bit of an underachiever, where
Noah wasn't.
He wanted it all the way.
And yeah, I think he
made more money.
NOAH SALASNEK: Just after riding
for Sims for the first
year, and getting the response
we had, and having a pro
model, and coming into money
being young, and just being so
adamant about my career and
snowboarding at the time, I
just focused on that.
I bought a house in Tahoe and
really when after it.
I made that decision, my
professional career to be a
snowboarding.
And financially it worked
out at the time and so
I stuck with it.
TOM SIMS: The Noah Salasnek
board when we first came out
with it was one of the
most progressive
snowboards we ever made.
And it was so cool.
One of the ones had
a skateboard
graphic on the bottom.
It just showed that so many of
the Sims team riders had solid
skateboarding backgrounds.
And I had a skateboarding
background before I got into
snowboarding.
And so, that connection
was very much a part
of what Sims was.
NOAH SALASNEK: Well my first
graphic with Sims, I had
always wanted to do like
a skateboard base.
And that's what we
ended up doing.
The top sheet was kind
of totally unrelated.
It had kind of like
a hobo with a dog.
It kind of looked like
me, I suppose, with
the goatee and stuff.
But nonetheless, the base had
the independent looking trucks
and wheels and stuff.
So that was my idea then.
And that board did pretty
well, actually.
And it's funny because Hetzel
came out with one even though
he heard that I had done that.
And he did it, I think, the same
year even though he knew
that I had done that,
which I don't know
why he would do that.
But whatever, I don't think he
sold half as many boards as I
did that year.
So what do I care?
I'm just playing, I'm
friends with Hetzel.
But that was pretty funny.
I think Palmer was the one who
told him he should do it.
Because Palmer was pissed that
I got on Sims and I'm getting
a board right away.
He's ridden for them for
years and now he's
getting his first board.
So he's like Hetz, make your
skateboard base, that's cool.
Noah, do it too.
So he thought he'd get the last
laugh, but my board did
well that year, so
that was cool.
KEVIN ENGLISH: It's funny, I
forget what Standard movie it
is with Salasnek.
There's like a part where he's
riding an old Sims board, I
don't know what it was, like
Sims half-pipe or something,
where he's kind of
wearing like the
color-blocked pants and stuff.
It was also the year that
he came out with his
skateboard pro model.
So half the shots he was the
little character that was on
his boards and then the other
shots he was kind of like the
late '80s snowboarder guy.
But it was like his
season was mixed.
I don't know how that really
went down, but you could
definitely see a distinct style
change right there.
And then I think snowboarding
kind of followed Noah with it.
NOAH SALASNEK: I think working
with Standard and having that
"TB 2" part come out was one
of my better parts and
definitely gave me a good push
and motivated me to film with
them further for "TB 3" and "4."
But yeah, I think it was
one of my better parts.
And I think it was, again,
good timing.
The time it came out was kind
of early back in the day.
Yeah, I'm proud of that
part, absolutely.
MIKE HATCHETT: When we picked
a crew for "TB 2," it was
basically just a combination of
my brother and I and Mack
Dawg sitting down and saying,
who's the best 10 or 12 guys
we want to shoot?
Noah was my bro from Tahoe.
We knew he ripped and was
potentially one of the best
guys in the world.
And then there was the whole big
mountain guys that I was
more friends with.
So it was a combination of
Mack Dawg's freestyle
background and him picking
those guys and having the
connections, and then me being
connected with my brother and
the big mountain scene, and
just kind of shuffling the
deck and going here's the hand
we want to play right here.
And some of it came to do
with Faultline too.
Some of the guys who worked with
Faultline for years were
getting a little fed up
with it and wanted
to go in a new direction.
So the timing was good for us.
For Noah and Terrier, those
guys just wanted to try
something new.
So when they heard that Mack
Dawg and I want to go out on
our own, they were all pretty
stoked because I think they
had realized the vision.
MIKE MCENTIRE: As a filmmaker
back then, I wasn't interested
in filming anyone snowboarding
until they had learned a bunch
of new stuff every year.
So what did mean for us?
Well, at the beginning of the
year we're riding powder every
day while everyone's learning
their stuff.
I didn't even start filming
until spring.
So I had met up with the
Hatchetts in Squaw and just
riding with them stuff.
And I know Mike was pretty
frustrated about his situation
over at Faultline.
And he was hitting me up.
I was making these pretty
low-budget films.
He was like, why don't you get
a 16 millimeter camera and
let's do this, dude.
And I thought about
it and I wanted to
move up into 16 anyways.
Because I was just shooting
Super 8 and Hi8 and stuff.
And so I got a camera, like a
1960 Airflex of this super old
guy who used it maybe once.
It was like brand new.
And then I got out there and
we started doing our thing.
We made Standard Films.
And I came up with the name when
I was taking a leak at
some gas station.
There was a Standard
urinal there.
And I'm like, sick, Standard.
So that was how I came
up with that name.
And it was a lot of fun, man.
There was a good time in
snowboarding back then, a lot
of progression.
And it was super easy back
then because nothing
much had been done.
So it was good stuff.
NOAH SALASNEK: The only
difference is Standard is
going to meet at 5:00 AM at the
gas station and Artie and
them might meet you at 9:15.
So you get to sleep in a
little more when you're
working with Faultline maybe.
But other than that, they're
both professional on site and
they're both motivated,
dedicated, good filmers.
You know you're going
to get the shot.
That's why I like filming
with them.
If I'm going to go risk my life
or hike some peak and do
some line, I want to guarantee
that it gets in the can, and
you can get that working
with people like that,
professionals.
MIKE HATCHETT: I guess what Mack
Dawg and I and my brother
wanted to prove is we wanted
to make the best snowboard
video that ever had been made.
And I don't want to say that
sounding arrogantly or cocky
in any way, but we just thought
that the movies that
were out there were good,
but they weren't great.
We wanted to focus on just
snowboarding itself and the
characters, the riders,
themselves and not so much of
the storytelling
and narration.
We were over the Faultline
narration, we went here, and
we did this, and we did that.
And again, not to dis on Jerry
and Artie because Faultline is
a great film company, and the
contribution they made in
snowboarding was amazing.
But yeah, we wanted to get away
from that and more just
like this is dope snowboarding,
here's some good
music, here's Noah Salasnek,
watch him rip.
[PUNK MUSIC PLAYING]
NOAH SALASNEK: I think there
was a cool shot of Granite
Chief Peak where I do like two
turns and pop like a 30, 40
foot cliff maybe max, and land
it pretty good, and do a
couple turns out.
And I was on like a race board,
but no one probably
knows, like a 170.
But it was pretty cool
because I was able
to stomp the landing.
But what they don't know, or
maybe it's in the slam
section, I went back up and
tried it again and ended up
tumbling and just tomahawking
at like 30 miles an hour.
It was one of my worst
beat-downs.
I think it did make the slam
section, actually.
But when I stomped it was pretty
rewarding for sure.
So that stands out in my mind
JEREMY JONES: Noah's was the
first style that really kind
of drew me in.
And that's when it was really
like, oh, I get it now.
Because before it was Damian in
hard boots like going down
the fingers at Tahoe or getting
dropped off in a
helicopter.
And to me as a kid, it was
something that was just what
those guys did.
It was nothing I could
ever imagine doing.
And then when these other guys
went to that level, I could
grasp that and it made sense.
And then all a sudden, it was me
and my buddies, like we're
doing what they're doing, and
we could do this one day.
JP WALKER: Maybe the year
before, like somebody did like
a late backside 180.
And then Noah's part came out
the year later and had like
late switch backside 3's and
all this crazy stuff.
So I was all about that
and doing butters.
Like butters was just like the
only thing for a while that
mattered, just butter from the
top of the lift to the bottom.
And he was super good at it.
And it was sick because I
remember he had like shots
where he'd butter up to cornices
and spin off of them
and all kinds of stuff
like that.
So I was just like goateed
up and buttering it up.
NOAH SALASNEK: I don't know who
started the whole little
butter thing.
I know we got kind of into the
nose pressing and tail
pressing and trying
blunt slides or
whatever they're called.
I mean everyone's got a
different name for them.
But yeah, there was a little
era everyone went through.
They were trying to press the
nose and spin out of this and
that and went through
a little phase.
But it's pretty cool.
I've been known to sit back on
my tail and snap a 180 out of
it now and again.
So it's still pretty fun to
dabble in, little nose press
or butters or whatever.
MIKE HATCHETT: And kind of
what's cool about filming back
"TB 2," "3," "4," there wasn't
like today it's almost, OK,
we're going to go to this
knoll and build this gap
that's been filmed 20
gazillion times.
We're going to hit this log, or
I'm going to back lip this
rail, or I'm going to do a front
side through this kink,
or I'm going to do a switch
back 1260, whatever.
You're going to do this trick
and it's a set-up shot.
You're sitting sideways, you
point it, you do your trick,
you land just far enough for
the shot, and you're done.
We'd just go out and look up
at something and go, let's
just ride it, let's
just film that.
Watch Noah's part from "TB 4,"
his opening shot, you can just
see the spontaneous riding
in that shot.
It's just slashing front 3's.
He just cruised it.
JP WALKER: The one thing that
stood out to me was he had
this backside 720 tail grab.
I think it was like somewhere
in Tahoe, like a spot, maybe
it was like at Mount Rose or
something, it was like a
cornice gap thing.
And it was just like the best
backside 720 to ever go down,
I felt like, in the history
of snowboarding.
I remember it was just like so
good, and tail grab, and I was
pretty hyped on that.
SHAWN FARMER: I mean Salasnek
for a while was just crushing
every one, I think, out there,
on overall just riding.
And he was throwing tail
grab 7's and 9's.
I know 7's.
I think 9's too.
And just crazy stuff and like
super smooth style.
I've always looked up to him
always thought he was just one
of the best for sure, timeless.