If you're walking the
red carpet this Sunday,
I've got a good idea for you.
Great dress, fantastic
shoes, and a parachute.
Roberta Mancino is
an Italian model
and a professional daredevil.
She set up her red carpet event
on the cliffs of Italy's Monte
Brento.
[ITALIAN ELECTRONIC MUSIC]
We've got a playlist of
other insane base jumpers
for you after the show.
Come si dice complete
crazy people?
CARLY: A little over year ago,
British journalist Ben Cook
set out to conquer
the world of YouTube
even though he had never
uploaded a video before.
And in the process he created
my favorite web series
of all time.
It's an in-depth
look at the world
of online video from someone who
started as a complete outsider.
And the finale I've been waiting
super long for is finally here.
BEN COOK: The great
thing about online video
is that there is infinite
space for people to create in,
and so there will
always be people
who are doing it in new
and interesting ways.
CARLY: There's also a bunch
of cheeky humor in there,
like my main man Tom
Scott playing God.
TOM SCOTT: Who's going to hell?
OK, let's see.
Anyone who thinks Gangnam
Style is still a thing.
It isn't.
Charlie the Unicorn, of
course, and the Vlogbrothers.
MALE SPEAKER: The Vlogbrothers
are going to hell?
TOM SCOTT: I'm just
messing with you.
Only Hank.
CARLY: I say grab your cats
and giant glass of iced tea
and enjoy the entire
series on Ben's channel.
JACOB: What's James
Murphy been up
to since he left
LCD Sound System?
Our friends at "The Wall Street
Journal" tracked him down.
ARABY WILLIAMS: I made a
video about James Murphy
and his "Hope for the Sounds
of the New York City Subway"
with my colleague Hannah Karp.
I hope you like it.
JAMES MURPHY: I started
noticing that the subway sounds
quite brutal.
Why don't we just
make it a nice sound?
Just make it pleasant.
The more people going
through, the more times
the turnstile gets turned, if
you have different notes that
are all in agreement,
it would make music.
It's just an opportunity to have
something beautiful in a place
where something beautiful
seems impossible.
JACOB: This video's been getting
shared a ton by New Yorkers
and music fans everywhere.
Let's get this thing
pushed through.
Go sign James Murphy's
petition at subwaysymphony.org.
SHANNON COFFEY: Hey,
YouTube Nation, Shannon here
from Random Ass Girly Channel.
I want to share the official
video for the song "Killing,"
by We Are Shining and Eliza
Doolittle, because it's insane.
Have you ever seen someone
just dancing in a music video?
Yeah.
But have you seen
someone dancing
while they get knives
thrown at them?
[POP MUSIC]
SHANNON COFFEY: There's dancing
and knives put together.
What else could you
want from a music video?
And the song is
really good, too.
JACOB: The sriracha
apocalypse is upon us.
Residents of
Irwindale, California,
are claiming that the odors
from a sriracha factory
are burning their
eyes and their lungs,
and they're pushing
to shut it down.
If you're a little behind
in your sriracha chemistry,
you're in luck.
The American Chemical
Society dissects
what makes this hot sauce hot
and what makes it so good.
NARRATOR: These two molecules
trigger the TrpV1 receptor
protein in our
mouths, thus causing
the spicy hot sensation.
Then the body responds
to capsaicin's burn
by releasing a pain-killing
endorphin rush kind of like one
a jogger feels after a long run.
JACOB: The public
hearing is today
and the fate of the
world's greatest hot sauce
hangs in the balance.
Get informed.
Share this video with a
sriracha lover in your life.
A lot of people argue over what
pop-up storybook, animated,
love songs, zombie ukulele
music video is the best one,
and finally there's an
answer to that question.
DEANNE SMITH: I wrote a song
called "Apocalypse," kind
of about love, and I got my
buddy Beck Hill to animate it
because I think she has
a really unique style.
You're going to see what I mean.
[SINGING "APOCALYPSE"]
JACOB: If you've made or
found a video that you
want to see right
here on the show,
film yourself talking about
it just like DeAnne did
and post it with the
hashtag YouTubenation.
Now plays us out, Fidlar.
[MUSIC - FIDLAR LA, "NO WAVES"]