-Some kids, they want to grow
up to be president.
Some kids want to be
a doctor, you know?
I just wanted to be bad.
-Let's just get that fucking
cash and go on spring break.
-They kicked me out of school.
I thought that was great.
-Freeze, motherfuckers!
Give me all your money now!
-Shit.
That was the best thing
in the world.
-Spring break, bitches.
-I'm about making money.
-This is the fucking
American Dream.
-I'll always remember
this trip.
-This is the way it's
going to be forever.
-Now let me guess.
Spring breakers?
-Somebody loves y'all.
-Why are you here?
-Come on, y'all.
Why you acting suspicious?
Get in.
-You're going to be
our chauffeur?
-Yeah.
You can play Beyonce.
-I don't know these people.
And I don't know this guy.
I want to go home.
-And then you're going to be
back right where you started.
And you'll be thinking,
hmm, maybe I missed
something out there.
-I knew y'all's special from
the moment I saw you.
You're my motherfucking
soul mates.
Let's cause some trouble now.
-Spring break, bitches!
[GUNSHOTS]
[CHEERING]
-Sit down, motherfucker,
sit down!
[INAUDIBLE]
belong to me.
-Y'all want to die tonight?
-You're fucking scared,
aren't you?
-What if we just used
you to come here?
-Spring break forever, bitches.