Let me hear fucking more!
[APPLAUSE]
KENNY POWERS: All right, cool!
OK.
OK, OK, shut the fuck up!
I have a dream, a wet dream, and
today you get the pleasure
of witnessing my dream
come true.
The way I see it, there's three
things an athlete needs
to succeed.
Talent, strippers, and most
importantly, speed.
Because speed is what takes an
athlete to the next level.
Today, it's time to unleash my
greatest creation ever, my
magnum fucking opus, Blades!
[APPLAUSE]
[MUSIC]
KENNY POWERS: Witness and
behold the world's most
advanced running shoe.
He's doing the running
man, get it?
That's hilarious.
Look how nimble he is.
OK, running man, that's cool.
You're overdoing it now.
You're making yourself
look stupid.
Get the fuck out of here.
Now, let me give you a
sneak peek into the
brilliant mind of me.
Yo, word.
Welcome to the K-Swiss
R and double D lab.
Double D for development,
and also for huge tits.
Come on in.
Cool science, dog.
In order to create a shoe that
will make an athlete run
faster than fuck, I not
only watch how fast
this cheetah runs.
I watch how that motherfucker
kills.
Suck it, slow ass animal.
What's up?
Me and my smart as hell
scientists here have developed
what I like to call speed
activated technology.
Run slow and the blades will
become soft and pillowy, like
these awesome things.
Or, flip the fucking
turbo switch and
blades will react quickly.
Like a spring loaded shotgun for
your fucking feet parts.
Nice work, dickheads.
But next level technology like
this doesn't mean jack shit if
it doesn't translate to peak
performance on game day.
That's why I enlisted
the help of all pro
linebacker Patrick Willis.
PATRICK WILLIS: Aah!
KENNY POWERS: See if he can run
this motherfucker through
some tests.
Fuck that wildebeest up!
PATRICK WILLIS: [YELLING]
Aah!
KENNY POWERS: Willis, that
is fucking bad ass!
That is how I invented Blades.
[APPLAUSE]
KENNY POWERS: As for the name,
I got to give credit where
credit is due.
To a Chinese man by
the name of Bruce.
Ni Hao, player.
You're fucking blown
up these days.
You got like a bagillion
Facebook fans.
BRUCE LEE: Definitely,
definitely.
[LAUGHING]
KENNY POWERS: Whoa, whoa.
Don't get cocky on me
there kimosabe.
BRUCE LEE: I meant that
as a joke, of course.
[LAUGHTER]
KENNY POWERS: All right,
time for serious.
Remember that time when me and
you were fucking around in
your dojo playing with swords
and shit and those derelicts
tried to step to us?
BRUCE LEE: Violence man.
[LAUGHTER]
KENNY POWERS: Oh yeah,
that was violence.
Well while you were busy tearing
them a new asshole, I
saw something.
You see these motherfuckers?
These little scratches on your
titties, they were the
inspiration for the
name Blades.
BRUCE LEE: And it's a
heck of a name, man.
KENNY POWERS: Yeah, no shit.
I came up with it.
BRUCE LEE: All type of knowledge
ultimately means
self knowledge.
Now you put water into a cup,
it becomes the cup--.
KENNY POWERS: OK,
how about this?
How about instead of doing all
this poetry shit, we just go
fuck some dudes up with
this blade, huh?
BRUCE LEE: [LAUGHTER]
KENNY POWERS: [LAUGHTER]
Woo!
[APPLAUSE]
KENNY POWERS: Yep,
that was me.
That exchange was
completely real.
But all this blood, sweat, and
innovation doesn't mean a
goddamn thing if we don't
get feet in the shoes.
So we're making Saturday
morning commercials
specifically for the soft little
minds of children.
Let's get these kids fucking
hooked on speed!
All right ladies, let's see
what these blades can do.
Fuck yeah, Blades!
Woo!
Speed!
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha!
You just shit your pants, nerd.
Blades!
Woo!
Aw shit, evil dude.
Run fast or die, hombre.
Speed!
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha!
Take that, fuckers!
Blades, go buy them.
[APPLAUSE]
[MUSIC]
[ASTRONAUT BREATHING]
KENNY POWERS: Walking on the--
fuck.
Walking on the moon was the
greatest thing that man had
ever done, until now.
I've basically taken all the
fastest shit I've ever seen--
bionic missiles, fucking
Bruce Lee, cheetahs--
and I've combined them together
to make the best shoe
you've ever seen.
You may applaud now.
[APPLAUSE]
KENNY POWERS: Oh yeah, water on
the moon feels just right.
What do you ladies say we
take a trip to Uranus?
You get it?
MALE SPEAKER 2: Blades.