BIOLOGY. SO I'M THE FIRST OF THREE LECTURERS
AS YOU PROBABLY ARE A WAY. DURING THE REGULAR
SEMESTER, DURING THE REGULAR YEAR WE HAVE
THIS COURSE DIVIDED INTO THREE MODULES.
AND THIS YEAR, ECOLOGY IS GOING FIRST, FOLLOWED
BY THE EVOLUTION MODULE WITH DR. JOHN HUELSENBECK
AND THEN THE BOTANY MODULE WITH DR. BRUCE
BALDWIN. THESE MODULES CAN REALLY GO IN
ANY ORDER. THIS IS THE FIRST TIME THAT ECOLOGY
IS GOING FIRST IN SOME YEARS, IF IT'S EVER
GONE FIRST. AND SO WE DON'T HAVE MUCH TO
BUILD ON IN THE  ECOLOGY SECTION IN TERMS
OF BASIC BIOLOGY ANOTHER EXCEPT FOR WHAT
YOU BRING IN FROM YOUR PREVIOUS EDUCATION.
SO I WILL, I CAN'T INTRODUCE ABSOLUTELY
EVERY TERM AND EVERY CONCEPT AS WE GO. I
NEED TO ASSUME SOME THINGS ABOUT YOUR KNOWLEDGE.
AND YOU'LL NEED TO DRAW ON YOUR ENTIRE STORE
OF KNOWLEDGE. I'LL BE MENTIONING FAR-FLUNG
COUNTRIES PART ONE OR THE OCCASIONAL ORGANISM
LIKE AN URCHIN. AND I MIGHT JUST ASSUME
THAT EITHER YOU'VE HEARD OF THAT COUNTRY OR
THAT ORGANISM OR THAT YOU WILL TAP IT INTO
GOOGLE AND YOU WILL CHECK ON IT. BUT I WILL
TRY TO SPEAK SLOWLY AND CLEARLY AS POSSIBLE.
THIS COURSE IS DIFFICULT, CERTAINLY. WE
DON'T APOLOGIZE FOR THAT. IT'S HARD BUT WE
SHOULD APOLOGIZE IF IT'S CONFUSING,
UNCLEAR OR DISORGANIZED. HERE WE ARE, THEY
SAY THE GREATEST PUBLIC UNIVERSITY IN THE
WORLD. SO WE'RE NOT GOING TO APOLOGIZE IF
IT'S HARD. BUT IT'S OUR RESPONSIBILITY TO
MAKE IT CLEAR FOR YOU. I'LL PRIMARILY USE
THE BOARD JUST FOR WRITING TERMS. OUTLINING
POINTS. BUT REALLY I'M FOCUSED ON MY SLIDES.
IN THE PRESENTATION. AND I WILL GIVE YOU
A SUBSET OF THESE SLIDES AS A PDF FILE.
THAT WILL GO ON TO BSPACE AFTER THE LECTURES.
ONE OF THE GOALS IN BIO 1B IS TO HELP DEVELOP
YOU AS GOOD NOTETAKERS. AND THAT, THAT MEANS
COMING TO CLASS AND TAKING NOTES WITH AN OLD
FASHIONED PEN OR PENCIL. SO REALLY TRY TO
DO THAT. IT DOES EARLY IN THE DAY. AND IT
WILL BE A STRUGGLE SOMETIMES TO KEEP AWAKE.
BUT THERE ARE GOING TO BE ELEMENTS OF LECTURES
THAT ARE NOT ON THE WEBCAST. PARTICULARLY
VIDEOS THAT I SHOW AND ANY COMMENTS I MAKE
DURING CERTAIN VIDEOS. AND IT'S JUST A FACT
OF BIO 1B THAT STUDENTS WHO COME TO LECTURE
PERFORM BETTER. THEY GET HIGHER GRADES.
SO TRY YOUR BEST. OF COURSE, YOU'RE NOT GOING
TO MAKE EVERY ONE. LET ME JUST COMMENT ON
A COUPLE OF OTHER COURSE LOGISTICAL MATTERS.
I DON'T WANT TO SPEND ANYMORE TIME ON THIS.
WE HAVE TOO MAN LOGISTICAL THINGS TO DO.
BUT I SHOULD POINT OUT THAT YOUR BOOK, THE
EIGHTH EDITION OF CAMPBELL, IS THE ONE OF
THIS SHADE OF MAROON AND BLACK. AND IT'S
AVAILABLE AT THE LOCAL STORES. I THINK NED'S
IS THE ONLY ONE STOCKING THE BOOK RIGHT NOW
WITH SUCH THAT YOU CAN USE THIS 10 PERCENT
OFF COUPON. YOU CAN ALSO FIND IT AT VARIOUS
OTHER PLACES, INCLUDING ON-LINE. THE EIGHTH
EDITION IS WHAT  WE'RE USING. IT BEHOOVES
YOU TO USE THE EIGHTH. I'VE GIVEN ONLY THE
READING ASSIGNMENTS ON THE COURSE WEBSITES.
BUT ON THE PDF I JUST PUT UP THIS MORNING
ON BSPACE I DO PROVIDE A CONVERSION FOR THE
SEVENTH EDITION. WHICH SOME OF YOU MIGHT
CARRY FROM OTHER COURSES. THEY'RE NOT THE
SAME BOOK.
AND I THINK YOU CAN GET AWAY WITH IT BUT
YOU DO YOURSELF A SMALL DISSERVICE BY USING
THE OLD EDITION. IF IT'S OKAY WITH YOU,
IT'S OKAY WITH ME. I'LL PROVIDE THE CONVERSIONS
FOR THAT ON B SPACE. IT'S UP THERE ALREADY.
MAKE SURE YOU GET IN THE SWING OF BSPACE IF
YOU'VE NEVER USED IT BEFORE BY MONDAY. NO
LABS NEXT WEEK. AS MIKE MENTIONED. YOU DO
HAVE YOUR DISCUSSION SECTIONS. AND THEN
A WEEK OFF DISCUSSION AND LAB. AND THE FOLLOWING
WEEK DISCUSSIONS AND LABS START FULL FORCE.
WE'RE EASING INTO THE SEMESTER NICELY. WE
DON'T NEED TO HIT THE GROUND RUNNING TOO FAST
HERE.
TODAY I'M FOCUSED ON BY WAY OF INTRODUCING
WHAT ECOLOGY IS, I'M REALLY FOCUSED ON THE
HISTORY OF ECOLOGY. I LIKE TO INTRODUCE
TOPICS FROM A HISTORICAL PERSPECTIVE WHEN
POSSIBLE. I'M REALLY DOING THAT TODAY, REACHING
BACK TO LOOK AT THE ROOTS OF ECOLOGY IN
ORDER TO GIVE YOU AN IDEA WHAT ECOLOGY IS
AND ECOLOGISTS DO.
I DIDN'T HAVE MUCH KNOWLEDGE OR AWARENESS
OF ECOLOGY WHEN I GOT TO COLLEGE. PARTLY
THAT'S BECAUSE ECOLOGY HAS REALLY TAKEN
OFF SINCE I WAS IN COLLEGE. ECOLOGY HAS BEEN
FOLLOWING AN EXPONTENTIAL GROWTH CURVE. AND
THERE'S A LOT MORE AWARENESS OF ECOLOGY
BECAUSE OF ENVIRONMENTAL PROBLEMS THAT WE
FACE. BUT THERE'S A, THERE'S JUST AN EXPANSION
WITHIN THE SCIENCE ITSELF THAT IS REAL,
THAT HAS OCCURRED OVER THE LAST  MANY
YEARS, MY HIGH SCHOOL BIOLOGY CLASSES MAY
NOT HAVE BEEN UP TO SNUFF. THAT MIGHT BE PART
OF IT TOO. I DON'T KNOW. I'M NOT SURE.
BUT SOME OF YOU, FOR SOME OF YOU ECOLOGY WILL
BE A NEW FIELD OF STUDY. AND WHAT I WANTED
TO DO TODAY IS TRY TO GIVE YOU A SENSE OF
WHAT IT IS. SO WE'LL BE LOOKING INTO ITS ROOTS.
IN BASIC NATURAL HISTORY OBSERVATION, AND
WE'LL BE LOOKING AT SOME EXAMPLES OF NATURAL
HISTORY AND HOW IT FED THE ECOLOGICAL CONTINUES
TRADITION AND HOW IT CONTINUES TO FEED ECOLOGY
TODAY. WE'LL LOOK AT SOME EXEMPLARS OF THAT
NATURAL HISTORY TRADITION AND START TO APPROACH
DEFINITIONS OF ECOLOGY AS WE GET INTO THE
20TH CENTURY. AND TRY TO, WE'LL TRY TO SHOW
THAT ECOLOGY IS AN INTEGRATIVE DISCIPLINE.
IT INTEGRATES FIELD WORK LABORATORY WORK
WITH THEORETICAL AND MODELING WORK. AND
FINALLY WE'LL DRAW A DISTINCTION BETWEEN ECOLOGY
AND ENVIRONMENTALISM. WITH A COUPLE OF EXAMPLES.
NATURAL HISTORY. IT'S KIND OF OLD FASHIONED
IN SOME CONTEXT THESE DAYS, THE IDEA OF
NATURAL HISTORY. BUT AT BERKELEY IT'S STILL
TAKEN VERY SERIOUSLY. NATURAL HISTORY DEFINE
AS THE STUDY OF NATURE AND NATURAL PHENOMENON
USUALLY BASED ON OBSERVATION AND DESCRIPTION.
WE STILL HAVE COURSES IN NATURAL HISTORY HERE
IN THIS DEPARTMENT.
NATURAL HISTORY IS OFTEN DEPENDENT ON VERY
SIMPLE AND PATIENT OBSERVATION OF NATURAL
PHENOMENA. SITTING IN THE FIELD AND WATCHING
AN ORGANISM PERFORM A CERTAIN BEHAVIOR,
DESCRIBING A PLANT IN ITS GROWTH, IN THE LABORATORY.
ITS MORPHOLOGY AND ITS MORPHOLOGICAL CHANGES
THROUGH TIME. NATURAL HISTORY IS NOT LIMITED
TO THE STUDY OF BIOLOGICAL PHENOMENA TO
THE STUDY OF LIVING PHENOMENON. WITH ONE WORD,
INTERESTED IN THE TIDES AND THEIR INFLUENCE
ON THE GEOLOGY OF THE BAY, THAT WOULD BE A
STUDY IN NATURAL HISTORY. IT ENCOMPASSES THE
FULL RANGE OF NATURAL PHENOMENON, WHETHER
PHYSICAL OR CHEMICAL OR BIOLOGICAL. BUT
GENERALLY WHEN USING THE TERM IN BIOLOGY,
WE'RE SPEAKING ABOUT A DESCRIPTIVE AND OBSERVATION-BASED
STUDY OF ORGANISMS AND THEIR RELATIONSHIP
TO THE ENVIRONMENT. WE ARE FORTUNATE TO BE
LIVING IN THE MOST DIVERSE STATE IN THE COUNTRY
IN TERMS OF ITS BIOLOGY. AND HERE IN NORTHERN
CALIFORNIA AROUND THE BAY WE ARE VERY FORTUNATE
WITH AN AMAZING LOCAL ECOSYSTEM IN TERMS OF
ITS DIVERSITY AND A RICH HISTORY AND A LOT
OF RESOURCES FOR ITS STUDY, LOCALLY. AND
IF ONE WHERE STUDYING, ZOOPLANKTON OR SHARKS
OR BLUE HERONS ON THE BAY, BY OBSERVATION
AND DOCUMENTATION OF THOSE OBSERVATIONS,
WHETHER PHOTOGRAPHIC, WRITTEN, OR EVEN WITHOUT
FORMAL DOCUMENTATION AT ALL, ONE IS CONDUCTING
A NATURAL HISTORY. BUT THE BEST NATURAL
HISTORY DOES INVOLVE CLEAR DOCUMENTATION AND
A CAREFUL RECORDING OF OBSERVATIONS.
IN TRYING TO ELUCIDATE THE IDEA A LITTLE BETTER,
WE'RE GOING TO GO WAY BACK TO SOME 30,000,
32,000 YEARS AGO. KA HERE, WE'LL JUST NOTE
IT NOW BECAUSE I'LL BE COMING BACK TO IT
EVENTUALLY. I'LL HAVE TO ERASE THIS NOW.
WE'LL BE WORKING VERY CONSISTENTLY AT THE
INTERFACE OF PRESENT TIME AND PAST TIME
AT THE INTERFACE OF PALEO AND NEO, OF THE
OLD AND THE NEW. AND THIS IS JUST ONE OF THOSE
CASES WHERE I SHOULD ELUCIDATE BECAUSE YOU
MAY NOT HAVE THE INFORMATION AT YOUR DISPOSAL
ALREADY. WHAT I MEAN BY THE IDEA OF KA, ALL
I'M MEANING IS THOUSANDS OF  YEARS.
K STANDING FOR KILO AND A ATOM. YOU MIGHT
SEE MY USE CAPITAL MA, MEGA ANUM, MILLIONS
OF YEARS. I HAVE PARTICULAR INTERESTS IN
PALEONTOLOGY. AND WE'LL BE USING THE HISTORICAL
RECORD CONSISTENTLY THROUGHOUT THE COURSE.
THERE YOU GO FOR THOSE IN TV LAND. WATCHING
AT HOME. OKAY. KA, THOUSANDS OF YEARS. MA,
MILLIONS OF YEARS. OKAY. SO CHAUVET CAVE
IN SOUTHERN FRANCE WAS DISCOVERED IN THE MID
90'S IN 1994. BY SPELUNKERS, BY CAVE ENTHUSIASTS,
NOT SCIENTISTS, WHO WENT INTO THE DEEP RECESSES
OF ONE OF THESE CAVE SYSTEMS AND DISCOVERED
FABULOUS GALLERIES OF ROCK ART ON THE WALLS
OF THESE CAVES. NOW MANY SITES LIKE THIS
WERE KNOWN IN EUROPE. AND MANY SITES AROUND
THE WORLD DOCUMENT THE ARTISTIC ACTIVITIES
OF HUMANS OVER TENS OF THOUSANDS OF YEARS
IN AUSTRALIA AND AFRICA. HERE IN THESE CAVES
OF WESTERN EUROPE YOU HAVE EXQUISITE PRESERVATION
OF THE
PAINTINGS ON THESE WALLS AS A RESULT OF THE
UNIQUE ENVIRONMENTS OF THOSE CAVE SYSTEMS.
SO HERE AT CHAUVET, WHEN THE CAVE EXPLORERS
BROUGHT ATTENTION TO THIS DISCOVERY AND
SCIENTISTS WENT IN, THEY OBSERVED SOME PAINTINGS
SUCH AS THIS. PANELS ON THE WALL AND ALSO
ON THE WALLS YOU GET A SENSE OF SCALE ON
THAT GUYS'S HEAD OF THE HORSES, SOMETHING
RELATED TO  HORSES. SOMETHING IN THE FAMILY.
YOU RECOGNIZE THEM AS SOMETHING HORSE LIKE.
MAYBE ZEBRA LIKE, SOMETHING LIKE THAT. REMEMBER
THIS IS WESTERN EUROPE. 30 TO 32,000 YEARS
AGO. SOMETHING IN THERE. YOU NOT ONLY HAVE
THESE PANELS OF ILLUSTRATION, YOU HAVE ON
THE FLOOR OF THESE CAVES, YOU HAVE BONES.
YOU HAVE FOSSIL BONES. SO YOU CAN START TO
INTERPRET YOUR PAINTINGS WITH REFERENCE TO
THE BONES AND TEETH. IN SOME CASES FECES,
THE SCAT, THE POO OF THESE ORGANISMS. ALL
OF  THESE THINGS YOU USE TO RECONSTRUCT
YOUR KNOWLEDGE OF WHAT THESE THINGS ARE
AND WHAT THE PEOPLE WHO PAINTED THESE THINGS
WERE DOING. POSSIBLY THINKING. THE BIG PANEL
LIKE THIS YOU CAN SEE SOMETHING LIKE A RHINOCEROS
HERE. PRETTY CLEAR RHINO FORM, MAYBE INDICATING
THE MOVEMENT OF THE HORNS THERE. ELEPHANT
LIKE FORMS HERE. WHAT ARE THESE BACK HERE?
FIND MAYBE A BABY ELEPHANT THERE. WHAT'S
THAT? IT'S A BEAR. RIGHT? YOU RECOGNIZE IT
AS A BEAR.
IT'S GOT THE LITTLE EARS, IT'S GOT THE SHORT
MUZZLE. IT'S GOT THE LITTLE FACE. IT'S A
BEAR. DARN IT. YOU RECOGNIZE IT BECAUSE IT'S
SO WELL DEPICTED. IT CAPTURES THE FEATURES
OF THAT ORGANISM SO WELL THAT IT'S JUST
WITH A FEW STROKES NOT ONLY WHAT KIND OF ANIMAL
IT IS, GENERALLY SPEAKING, BUT SOMETHING
ABOUT WHAT IT'S DOING. THIS IS AN INDIVIDUAL,
THE PERSON WHO PAINTED THIS HAS MADE CLEAR
NATURAL HISTORY OBSERVATIONS DURING THEIR
LIFETIME. THERE'S NO BEAR POSING FOR THIS
PICTURE. THEY'RE GOING ON THEIR MEMORY AND
EXPERIENCES OF BEARS. AND THESE ARE NOT BEARS
THAT ARE ALIVE TODAY. THESE ARE DIFFERENT
SPECIES OF BEAR. THEY'RE CAVE BEARS, VERY
COMMON DURING THIS PERIOD IN WESTERN EUROPE.
MORE VEGETARIAN MAYBE THAN SOME OF THE BIG
BEARS TODAY. BUT A BEAR NONETHELESS, A MEMBER
OF THE BEAR FAMILY. WHAT ARE THOSE? THAT
WERE CREEPING UP BEHIND THE BABY ELEPHANT?
LIONS. LIONS IN FRANCE? YEAH. MAYBE A SUBSPECIES
OF THE LIVING LION. TAXONOMY IS ALWAYS CONTROVERSIAL.
THE TAXONOMY, THE NAMING OF THESE CREATURES.
AT WHAT LEVEL WE RANK THEM. BUT THEY'RE CLEARLY
LIONS. AND TAKING EVERYTHING INTO CONTEXT
IT LOOKS LIKE THEY'RE IN A HUNT. AND YOU
CAN EVEN LEARN SOMETHING ABOUT THE BEHAVIOR
OF  THESE EXTINCT POPULATIONS OF LIONS
FROM THESE PAINTINGS BECAUSE THEY'RE SO CAREFULLY
DOCUMENTED. THEY TURN OUT NOT TO HAVE A BIG
SHAGGY MANE. THEY DON'T HAVE A BIG MALE
KING OF THE BEASTS LION'S
MANE. IN SOME CASES IT LOOKS LIKE THE MALES
ARE IN THE LEAD BECAUSE THE  ONES IN THE
FRONT HAVE TESTICLES. PERHAPS UNLIKE THE LIONS
TODAY, MAYBE THE MALES TOOK MORE OF A LEAD
IN THESE PACK HUNTING STRATEGIES WHERE IT
TENDS TO BE A FEMALE LED STRATEGY TODAY. YOU
CAN ACTUALLY LEARN SOMETHING ABOUT BIOLOGY
OF THESE CREATURES AS A RESULT OF THE
CAREFUL DOCUMENTATION AND DEPICTION OF THESE
ORGANISMS BY THESE ARTISTS. ANOTHER POINT
WHERE I SHOULD JUST STOP AND IT WOULD BE
GREAT TO BE BUILDING ON THE EVOLUTION SECTION
IN DISCUSSING SOME OF THIS, BUT I SHOULD
STOP AND NOTE THE STRUCTURE OF THESE NAMES.
THIS IS JUST A COMMON NAME. THAT'S OUR ENGLISH
NAME. IT'S NOT STANDARDIZED. WE CALL THESE
THINGS CAVE LIONS. BUT IN FRENCH THEY'LL CALL
THEM SOMETHING ELSE AND IN JAPANESE THEY'LL
CALL THEM SOMETHING ELSE. WE STANDARDIZED
OUR NAME FOR THIS ORGANISM BY USING THE LATIN
NAME, WHICH WE ITALICIZE, RIGHT? IT'S A GOOD
PLACE TO INTRODUCE THIS HERE BECAUSE I'M
GOING TO TALK ABOUT LINNAEUS IN A SECOND.
LINNAEUS, RIGHT? SORRY, I'M GOING TO HAVE
TO GO TO THE BOARD.
THIS IS MAYBE A NAME YOU RECALL FROM A PREVIOUS
COURSE, LINNEAUS, CAROLUS LINNAEUS. I BELIEVE
HE WAS BORN LIME. BUT HE LATINIZED EVEN
HIS OWN NAME. SO WE KNOW HIM AS LINNAEUS.
FAMOUS FOR ADVANCING A SYSTEM OF NOMENCLATURE.
THE BINOMIAL SYSTEM OF NOMENCLATURE
TO BRING ORGANIZATION TO OUR NAMING OF BIOLOGICAL
ORGANISMS. WHAT HE DID WAS SUGGEST THAT WE
USE A BINOMEN,
A TWO-PART NAME SUCH AS URSUS SPELAEUS. SO
THAT EACH KIND OF ORGANISM,
EACH SPECIES OF ORGANISM WOULD HAVE A TWO-PART
NAME LIKE THIS.
COMPRISED OF A GENOUS AND A SPECIES. THE GENOUS
THAT WE CAPITALIZE THAT GOES FIRST FOLLOWED
BY THE SPECIFIC EPITHET THAT GOES SECOND
THAT'S NOT CAPITALIZED. IF YOU'RE WRITING
IT ON THE BOARD OR ON PAPER YOU SHOULD UNDERLINE
IT. IF TYPING IT YOU SHOULD ITALICIZE IT.
IF YOU EVER SEE A NAME SUCH AS THIS WITH
A CAPITAL ON THE FIRST WORD AND A LOW CASE
ON THE SECOND WORD IN ITALICS, YOU'RE PROBABLY
DEALING WITH A LATIN NAME, A FORMAL SCIENTIFIC
NAME.
A BINOMEN THAT REPRESENTS A PARTICULAR SPECIES,
A PARTICULAR KIND OF ORGANISM. AND YOU NEED
TO KNOW THIS, IF NOTHING ELSE BY THE END
OF BIO 1B, JUST KNOW THAT. KNOW THAT'S HOW
YOU WRITE A LATIN NAME BECAUSE YOU SEE IT
IN THE NEWSPAPER ALL THE TIME. THEY'LL CAPITALIZE
BOTH WORD. IT JUST LOOKS AWKWARD AND IT
LOOKS AMATEURISH. AFTER GETTING THROUGH BIO
1B YOU WON'T MAKE THAT MISTAKE. OKAY. SO
BY WAY OF INTRODUCING LINNAEUS A LITTLE BIT
THERE, LET'S LOOK AT LINNAEUS'S ROLE IN THE
HISTORY OF ECOLOGY. I BRING UP A COUPLE
OF PEOPLE HERE IN PART BECAUSE I DON'T THINK
THEY GET THE CREDIT THEY DESERVE IN THE HISTORY
OF ECOLOGY. LINNAEUS'S IDEAS WERE VERY INTERESTING
ACTUALLY. BUT IT SHOULD BE NOTED THAT THESE
WERE, THE WRITINGS WE ATTRIBUTE TO LINNAEUS
WERE NOT JUST LINNAEUS'S. THE HISTORIANS HAVE
SHOWN THAT MANY OF HIS WRITINGS, ALTHOUGH
PRODUCED UNDER HIS MENTORSHIP, WERE PRODUCED
BY SOMETHING LIKE GRADUATE STUDENTS. THEN
THEIR NAMES FELL OFF THE WORK OVER TIME
AND WE ATTRIBUTE THEM ALL TO LINNAEUS. THAT'S
SOMETHING THAT'S BEEN HAPPENING FOR A LONG
TIME. LESS AND LESS AS SCIENCE CONTINUES.
BUT A VERY COMMON THING IN THE PAST. SO
WE DON'T KNOW WHO WROTE THE ECONOMY OF NATURE
SPECIFICALLY. IT WAS PROBABLY LINNAEUS
AND ONE OF HIS STUDENTS IN SOME COMBINATION.
BUT LINNAEUS IS THE MENTOR IN THIS PROCESS.
AND THIS BRIEF ESSAY ON THE ECONOMY OF NATURE
WAS TRANSLATED INTO ENGLISH AND WAS READ.
IT CAN BE VERY HARD TO FIND A COPY OF THIS
ESSAY. AND THE OTHER ESSAYS OF RELEVANCE
THAT LINNAEUS WROTE TODAY. BUT WE HAVE ONE
OF THE BEST LIBRARIES IN THE WORLD HERE,
IN THIS VERY BUILDING. AND YOU CAN FIND
SOME TRANSLATIONS FROM THE 1800S OF THESE
ESSAYS AND YOU SHOULD GO TAKE A LOOK FOR
FUN. MAYBE NOT DURING THE SEMESTER, YOU'RE
TOO BUSY. BUT AFTER STUDYING SOME ECOLOGY
YOU'LL SEE JUST HOW HOW FOUNDATIONAL SOME
OF THESE IDEAS WERE OF LINNAEUS'S. HE SPOKE
OF AN ECONOMY OF NATURE. A SYSTEM OF ORGANISMAL
RELATIONSHIPS OF CHECKS AND BALANCES IN NATURE
THAT GIVE RISE TO THE PATTERNS WE SEE TODAY.
AND HIS PHRASE WAS TAKEN UP AS WE'LL SEE
IN ENGLAND BY DARWIN AND OTHERS, THIS ECONOMY
OF NATURE, THIS IDEA AND THIS PHRASE ECONOMY
OF NATURE. AS AN EXAMPLAR OF THE NATURAL
HISTORY TRADITION, WE CAN FOCUS ON A COUPLE
INDIVIDUALS, INCLUDING GILBERT WHITE, WHO
WAS VERY WIDELY READ. HIS ONE BOOK IN PARTICULAR,
THE NATURAL HISTORY OF SELBOURNE. IT HAS
BEEN READ BY COUNTLESS INDIVIDUALS SINCE
IT WAS WRITTEN IN THE 1700S. HE WROTE ABOUT
THE NATURAL PHENOMENA OF HIS LOCAL AREA, INCLUDING,
FOR EXAMPLE, THE BIRDS THAT LIVED IN HIS
LOCAL AREA. WHERE SCIENTISTS WERE BUSY STUDYING
SPECIMENS IN MUSEUMS THAT WERE
BROUGHT INTO MUSEUMS DESCRIBING DIFFERENCES.
GILBERT WHITE WAS OUT ON THE LAWN WATCHING
BIRDS AND DESCRIBING THEIR ACTIVITIES. AND
HE  KNEW, HE COULD DISTINGUISH CERTAIN
SPECIES OF BIRDS BASED ON THEIR CALLS, BASED
ON THEIR TIMES OF MIGRATION THAT SCIENTISTS
BASED ON MUSEUM SPECIMENS COULD NOT DISTINGUISH
BECAUSE THEY DID NOT HAVE THAT LIVING INFORMATION
ABOUT THESE CREATURES. HE DOCUMENTED ALL
THESE THINGS VERY CAREFULLY, WROTE THEM DOWN
AND MADE CONTRIBUTIONS TO SCIENCE AS A RESULT
OF HIS PATIENT FIELD OBSERVATIONS. OR HERE
IN AMERICA SOMEONE ALSO WHO DOESN'T GET MUCH
CREDIT FOR HIS WORK AT THE END OF HIS LIFE,
HENRY DAVID THOREAU. YOU MAY KNOW THOREAU
AS MAN OF LETTERS, HAVING WRITTEN WALDEN,
POLITICAL SCIENCE WITH CIVIL DISOBEDIENCE
OR SOMETHING LIKE THIS. BUT THOREAU WAS ALSO
A VERY ACCOMPLISHED NATURALIST. WORKING
IN NEW ENGLAND, HE WAS AT HARVARD. HE WASN'T
REALLY INTERESTED IN CLASSROOM LEARNING
THOUGH. FOCUSED ON LIFE IN THE FIELD AND
OBSERVATIONS OF ORGANISMS AND NATURAL PHENOMENA
IN THE FIELD. AND MORE AND MORE TOWARD THE
END OF HIS LIFE, IN THE LAST COUPLE YEARS
OF HIS LIFE HE WAS MAKING VERY IMPORTANT
STRIDES IN A VERY CONCRETE ECOLOGICAL FRAMEWORK
BUT HIS JOURNALS FOR THIS TIME, HE DIED
SUDDENLY. AND HIS JOURNALS FOR THIS TIME
WEREN'T PUBLISHED, DIDN'T COME TO LIGHT UNTIL
MAYBE 20 YEARS AGO. HE HAD NO INFLUENCE
ON THE HISTORY OF ECOLOGY, DON'T GET MY
WRONG. BUT HE IS A GREAT EXEMPLAR OF A NATURAL
HISTORY APPROACH, OF PATIENT DESCRIPTION
OF NATURAL PHENOMENA. HE, I WAS A GSI IN
THIS COURSE, I WAS A GRADUATE STUDENT HERE,
GOT MY DEGREE IN THIS DEPARTMENT. AND I
WAS A GSI FOR THIS COURSE. BACK THEN WE
LEARNED THAT THOREAU COINED THE WORD ECOLOGY.
AND IN RETROSPECT, IT'S UNDERSTANDABLE THAT
HISTORIANS MADE THAT  MISTAKE TO ATTRIBUTE
TO THOREAU, THE COINING OF THE WORD ECOLOGY.
BUT, IN FACT, HIS HANDWRITING WAS JUST TERRIBLE
AND A HISTORIAN
MISTOOK THE WORD GEOLOGY IN HIS JOURNALS FOR
THE WORD ECOLOGY.
AND QUITE QUICKLY IT MADE IT INTO THE OXFORD
DICTIONARY AND
THEN INTO A NEW YORK TIMES BOOK REVIEW. AND
BEFORE YOU KNEW IT EVERYONE WAS SAYING,
OH MY GOSH, THOREAU COINED THE WORD ECOLOGY.
BUT AGAIN IT WAS AN EASY MISTAKE TO MAKE BASED
ON THOREAU'S WORK. THOREAU WAS INTERESTED
IN ALL NATURAL PHENOMENON. BUT PLANTS, HE
WAS A VERY GOOD BOTANIST. HE WAS A VERY
KEEN OBSERVER OF PLANTS. HE WOULD FOLLOW
PLANTS ACROSS THE SEASONS. THE ONE THAT LIVED
ON SO-AND-SO'S YARD JUST BELOW THE OAKS
BEFORE THE FIRST HILL, HE WOULD REVISIT
A PARTICULAR PLANT OVER THE COURSE OF THE
SEASONS TO CHECK ON IT, TO CHECK ON ITS
STATUS, TO CHECK ON IT'S STATUS IN ITS LIFE
HISTORY,
YOU KNOW, ITS STAGE OF GROWTH. ITS FLOWERING
TIMES. IT'S THE TIME OF ITS SETTING SEED.
AND HE RECORDED ALL THESE THINGS IN GREAT
DETAIL. DOCUMENTED CAREFULLY THE DAYS ON WHICH
HE WAS MAKING THE OBSERVATIONS. ANY CONTEXTUAL
INFORMATION OF RELEVANCE. AND HIS NOTES
WERE SO GOOD THAT SCIENTISTS JUST RECENTLY
COULD GO BACK TO THEM AND LOOK AT THE FLOWERING
TIMES OF THESE VARIOUS PLANTS IN THAT REGION
AND COMPARE THEM WITH THE FLOWERING TIMES
OF THE SAME SPECIES OF PLANTS TODAY AND
INTERPRET THE CHANGES IN LIGHT OF CLIMATIC
CHANGE. RELYING OR THOREAU'S CAREFUL NATURAL
HISTORY OBSERVATIONS, EXTRACTING THE DATA
FROM THEM, AND USING IT TO PROVIDE INSIGHT
INTO THE ROLE OF CLIMATE IN STRUCTURING PLANT
GROWTH OVER THE PAST HUNDRED YEARS OR MORE.
DATA, THERE'S THE DEFINITION OF DATA FOR
YOU. AS YOU RECALL DATA IS THE FLORAL FORM
OF THE WORD SO TRY TO SAY DATA ARE. DATA THEY
ARE. THE SINGULAR IS DATUM. RIGHT? WE ALL
STUMBLE ON THAT ONCE IN A WHILE. BUT THERE
YOU GO.  THOREAU WAS READING DARWIN
BUT DARWIN WASN'T READING THOREAU. NO ONE
WAS READING THOREAU AT THAT TIME. BUT THOREAU
READ DARWIN AND LIKED HIM QUITE A LOT. WE'VE
ALL HEARD OF CHARLES DARWIN WHO PUBLISHED
HIS GREAT WORK ON THE ORIGIN OF SPECIES
IN 1859. IN MANY WAYS DARWIN IS THE MOST
IMPORTANT QUOTE UNQUOTE ECOLOGIST OF THIS
ERA. WE TEND TO BOW TO THE FEET OF DARWIN.
DARWIN THE GREAT IN BIOLOGY FOR HIS INSIGHTS
INTO EVOLUTION. AND WE DO SO RIGHTLY. AN
EXTRAORDINARY BODY OF WORK. BASED ON CREATIVE
INSIGHT AND CAREFUL STUDY AT HOME, IN THE
LAB,
IN THE GREENHOUSE AND IN THE FIELD ON HIS
TRAVELS. DARWIN DESERVES A LOT OF CREDIT FOR
HIS ROLE IN THE HISTORY OF ECOLOGY. THIS
COULD BE ILLUSTRATED IN MANY WAYS, AND I'M
TAKING A VERY BROAD BRUSHSTROKE APPROACH TO
THIS HISTORY.
THIS IS ONE WAY TO THINK ABOUT DARWIN'S INTELLECTUAL
CONTRIBUTION HERE WITH HIS METAPHOR OF A
TANGLED BANK. AND HERE'S A QUOTE THAT YOU
CAN READ ON YOUR TIME. WHERE HE REFERS TO
THIS RICH NETWORK OF INTERACTIONS IN A TANGLED
BANK. MAYBE SOMETHING LIKE THIS THAT HE
HAD IN MIND IN THIS PICTURE HERE, WHERE ALL
THE ORGANISMS ARE INTERACTING ONE WITH THE
NEXT, THE PLANTS WITH THEIR ROOTS IN THE SOIL
WITH THE EARTH WORMS MOVING THROUGH IT AND
AERATING THAT SOIL AND PROVIDING A MEDIUM
OF GROWTH FOR THOSE PLANTS WITH THE BIRDS
HAWKING INSECTS OFF OF THE BRANCHES OF THOSE
PLANTS AND THEN DEFECATING AND RETURNING SOME
NITROGEN TO THE SOIL, SOME OF WHICH MAKES
IT INTO THE WATERWAYS AND OTHERS TAKEN BACK
UP IN THE PLANTS. THIS NETWORK OF INTERACTIONS
REALLY IS WHAT ECOLOGISTS STUDY. ECOLOGISTS
STUDY THE INTERACTIONS OF ORGANISMS IN RELATION
TO THEIR ENVIRONMENTS. AND DARWIN DID THIS
AS WELL AS ANYBODY. SO SOON AFTER DARWIN'S
GREAT WORK, A GERMAN NAMED ERNST HAECKEL
COINED THE WORD ECOLOGY. HERE'S HAECKEL IN
HIS YOUNGER YEARS IN THE CANARY  ISLANDS
WITH A FIELD ASSISTANT. WE DON'T THINK OF
HIM AS A GREAT FIELD BIOLOGIST.
HE WAS AN ARTIST AND A THINKER. BUT HE IS
RESPONSIBLE FOR GIVING US THIS TERM. HE WAS
A GREAT COINER OF TERMS. HE DERIVED THE
WORD ECOLOGY FROM THESE TWO ROOTS,  OIKOS
AND LOGOS. THE STUDY OF THE HOME. WHAT DOES
HE MEAN BY HOME? OR HOUSE? WHAT DOES IT MEAN
TO STUDY THE HOUSE? WHAT IS THE HOUSE? HABITAT.
YEAH. THE STUDY OF THE HABITAT OF ORGANISMS
OR THE PLACE OF DWELLING, PLACE OF LIVING,
THE ENVIRONMENT OF ORGANISMS. HE DEFINED
IT AS THE COMPREHENSIVE SCIENCE OF THE RELATIONSHIP
OF THE ORGANISM TO THE ENVIRONMENT. THAT'S
THE DEFINITION. QUITE THE DEFINITION IN MANY
WAYS IN 1869. ONE OF HIS PAINT THERE OF
MOSSES AND VARIOUS BRYOPHYTES, QUITE A GREAT
ARTIST. LET'S JUMP TO THE 20TH CENTURY.
ECOLOGY IS NOT REALLY TAKING ITS ROOTS YET
AS A FORMAL SCIENTIFIC DISCIPLINE. THAT
DIDN'T REALLY START HAPPENING UNTIL THE 1960S.
BUT YOU ARE STARTING TO GET IN THE '20S
POSITIONS IN ECOLOGY AT UNIVERSITIES OR IN
GOVERNMENTAL CONTEXTS. CHARLES ELTON WAS A
VERY CLEAR THINKING FIELD ECOLOGIST FROM
THIS EARLY PERIOD. HERE HE IS AT OXFORD.
THERE HE IS GOING OFF ON HIS MOTOR BIKE WITH
A BUNCH OF LIVE TRAPS TO STUDY MICE, SETTING
OFF FOR THE FIELD. HE DID VERY EXTENSIVE
WORK IN THE ARCTIC, THE FAR NORTH. AND THIS
IS AN EXAMPLE OF A FOOD WEB HE CONSTRUCTED
BASED ON DATA COLLECTED IN THE FIELD. FOOD
WEBS BEING A VERY IMPORTANT PART OF ECOLOGICAL
SCIENCE, THE STUDIES OF THE INTERRELATIONSHIPS
OF ORGANISMS ON THE BASIS OF THEIR DIETARY
HABITS. AND HE OPENED ONE OF HIS MOST FAMOUS
BOOKS BY SAYING ECOLOGY IS A NEW NAME
FOR A VERY OLD SUBJECT. IT SIMPLY MEANS
SCIENTIFIC NATURAL HISTORY. SCIENTIFIC, MEANING
IN THIS CONTEXT, SYSTEMATIC, MAYBE QUANTITATIVE
BASED ON NOT ONLY DESCRIPTION BUT NUMERICAL
DESCRIPTION, QUANTIFICATION. BASING OUR
OBSERVATIONS IN COUNTING AND NUMBERS AND MATH.
BRINGING A MORE SOPHISTICATED METHOD TO
OUR APPROACH THAT COULD RENDER IT MORE SCIENTIFIC.
I'LL TALK MORE ABOUT GAUSE, A RUSSIAN BIOLOGIST
LATER. BUT JUST BRING HIM IN HERE I WILL
TO HIGHLIGHT THAT THIS PURSUIT IS NOT ENTIRELY
ONE OF THE FIELD BUT IT INVOLVED EXPERIMENTS
IN THE LABORATORY. THE LABORATORY IS WHERE
EXPERIMENTS MAKE CONTRIBUTIONS TO ECOLOGY
IN VERY IMPORTANT WAYS. HE WAS STUDYING
PARAMESIA, MAKING FORMAL EXPERIMENTS AND
DEEPLY INFLUENCING THE FIELD. WE'LL GET
TO HIS IDEAS ON COMPETITIVE EXCLUSION LATER.
AND TODAY YOU DON'T EVEN NEED TO DO LABORATORY
EXPERIMENTS OR GO INTO THE FIELD. YOU COULD
MODEL SYSTEMS ON THE COMPUTER, SIMULATION
MODELING AND MAKE CONTRIBUTIONS TO ECOLOGICAL
SCIENCE. BUT ECOLOGY A IS AT ITS BEST WHEN
IT INTEGRATES THESE APPROACHES. BEST WHEN
THE MODELS ARE BASED ON EMPIRICAL DATA FROM
THE FIELD OR FROM THE LAB. AND THESE THREE
COMPONENTS, FIELD, LAB AND THEORY REINFORCE
AND SUPPORT EACH OTHER. SO LET'S GET INTO
MORE MODERN DEFINITIONS OF ECOLOGY AND SOME
THAT HAVE BEEN VERY INFLUENTIAL. IN THE '60S,
AN AUSTRALIAN ECOLOGIST DEFINED ECOLOGY
AS THE SCIENTIFIC STUDY OF THE DISTRIBUTION
AND ABUNDANCE OF ORGANISMS. DISTRIBUTION AND
ABUNDANCE, SPATIAL DISTRIBUTION AND ABUNDANCE,
THE NUMBERS, HOW  MANY ARE THERE, OR
WHAT IS THEIR DENSITY. THE DENSITY OF ORGANISMS.
THE BIO MASS, HOW MUCH DO THEY ALL WEIGH?
DISTRIBUTION AND ABUNDANCE. BUT THAT'S A
LITTLE STATIC. THAT'S A LITTLE NARROW AS A
DEFINITION. IT CERTAINLY DOESN'T ENCOMPASS
THE FULL RANGE OF ECOLOGY, A LITTLE BIT
BETTER IS A DEFINITION THAT YOU HEAR QUITE
A LOT IN AN ECOLOGY COURSE IN AN UNDERGRADUATE
ECOLOGY COURSE. BY CHARLES KREBS. IT'S THE
SCIENTIFIC INTERACTION AND ABUNDANCE OF ORGANISMS.
SO YOU CAN USE THAT AS A WORKING DEFINITION.
AND IF YOU WANT YOU CAN USE ONE OF THE OLDER
DEFINITIONS THAT I'VE GIVEN YOU IF YOU WANT.
HOPEFULLY YOU'RE GETTING A BETTER SENSE OF
WHAT ECOLOGY IS. LET ME GIVE YOU AN EXAMPLE
OF WHAT DISTRIBUTION AND ABUNDANCE. A DISTRIBUTION
AND ABUNDANCE. THE CATTLE EGRET IS A FINE
LITTLE BIRD THAT USED TO LIVE ONLY IN THE
OLD WORLD IN AFRICA. THERE'S ONE RIDING ON
THE BACK OF A WILDEBEAST OR SOMETHING. IN
THEIR BREEDING PLUMAGE THEY HAVE THESE NICE
ORANGE YELLOW PLUMES ON THE BACK OF THEIR
HEADS. THEY TEND TO USE BIG MAMMALS
TO FOLLOW BIG MAMMALS AS THEY MOVE AROUND
AND THEY PICK UP INSECTS. ANYTHING THAT'S
FLUSHED BY THE MAMMALS AS THEY WALK. AS THE
HOOVES AND FEET DISTURB  THE GROUND, GRASS
HOPERS AND A LIZARD MIGHT GET PARTIALLY STEPPED
ON AND THE BIRD WILL GO IN AND PICK IT UP.
IT FORMS THIS RELATIONSHIP WITH THESE OTHER
MAMMALS. THIS WAS AN  AFRICAN BIRD, A WELL-KNOWN
AFRICAN BIRD. IN THE 1930S A SMALL FLOCK OF
THESE GUYS FLEW ACROSS THE ATLANTIC AND
LANDED IN SOUTH AMERICA. AN INCREDIBLE DISPERSAL
EVENT THAT WAS APPARENTLY VERY WELL DOCUMENTED.
THE ARRIVAL OF THIS FALL FLOCK. FROM THAT
POINT OF ARRIVAL IN SOUTH AMERICA IN 1937
THEY'VE EXPANDED THROUGHOUT THE NEW WORLD.
THINK ABOUT HOW THAT DISPERSAL EVENT EFFECTED
THE DISTRIBUTION AND ABUNDANCE OF CATTLE
EGRETS. IT EFFECTED IT QUITE A LOT ACROSS
THE  GLOBE IN TERMS OF THEIR RANGE
AND THEIR OVERALL NUMBERS ON A GLOBAL SCALE.
LET'S TAKE ANOTHER EXAMPLE OF DISTRIBUTION
AND ABUNDANCE, THAT'S AUSTRALIA AND THAT'S
A KANGAROO. AND IT SHOWS THE LIMITS OF RANGE
OF THESE RED KANGAROOS, MACROPUS RUFUS. AND
THE HOTTER AREAS HERE ARE THE AREAS OF GREATER
DENSITY IN TERMS OF NUMBER OF KANGAROOS
PER SQUARE KILOMETER. AS DESCRIBED HERE.
THE LIMITS OF THE RANGE TEND TO CORRELATE
WITH WHAT? WHO KNOWS THE LANDSCAPE THERE
A LITTLE BIT? WHAT ARE THOSE LIMITS? YEAH,
DRY AREAS.
THE LIMITS OF THE OCCUPIED AREAS ARE THE DRYEST.
THOSE COASTAL AREAS ARE MUCH WETTER AND MAYBE
LESS VARIABLE IN THEIR ARIDITY. FOR SOME
REASON, THE KANGAROOS ARE OCCUPYING PRIMARILY
THE DRYEST AREAS. THE ARID AND SEMI-ARID
AREAS. WHY?
I'D LIKE YOU TO CONSIDER WHY AFTER WATCHING
A VIDEO THAT I'LL PROVIDE FOR YOU EITHER AT
THE END HERE TODAY OR I'LL GIVE YOU AS A
STREAM ON-LINE. I DON'T WANT TO TAKE THE
TIME TO DO IT RIGHT NOW.
ECOLOGY IS NOT ENVIRONMENTISMALISM. THE TWO
HAVE BECOME SO CLOSELY RELATED THAT IN THE
PUBLIC'S EYE, IF YOU SAY YOU'RE AN ECOLOGIST
THEY MIGHT THINK THAT YOU ARE AN ENVIRONMENTALIST.
AND THEY MAY BE RIGHT BECAUSE IN ECOLOGISTS
BECAUSE AS A RESULT OF THEIR STUDIES ARE
LEAD TO INTERACTION POLITICAL CONTEXT IN TERMS
OF WANTING TO MAKE CHANGES THAT SUPPORT A
HEALTHY ENVIRONMENT. BUT THE TWO FIELDS
ARE NOT SYNONOMOUS, THEY'RE NOT EQUIVALENT.
ECOLOGY WE'LL SPEAK OF AS A SCIENTIFIC STUDY
OF ORGANISMS AND THEIR INTERRELATIONSHIPS.
ENVIRONMENTALISM WE'LL THINK OF MORE AS A
SOCIOPOLITICAL MOVEMENT TOWARD CREATING
HEALTH AND SUSTAINING HEALTH ECOSYSTEMS.
LET'S USE RACHEL CARSON AS AN EXAMPLE OF A
BIOLOGIST AND AN ECOLOGIST WORKING IN THE
FIELD AND STUDYING ORGANISMS, WHO WAS LEAD
BY HER STUDIES TO DRAW ATTENTION TO THE
ROLE OF PESTICIDES IN THE DECLINE OF BIRD
POPULATIONS. PESTICIDES, PARTICULARLY DDT,
AT THIS TIME WERE CAUSING THE THINNING OF
EGGSHELLS AS A RESULT OF GETTING INTO THE
FOOD CHAINS AND MAKING THEIR WAY INTO THE
TISSUES OF BIRD THAT THEN LAID EGGS. THE
SHELLS OF THESE EGGS WERE THINNED TO THE POINT
WHERE THEY WERE CRACKING AND MANY BIRDS WERE
HAVING TROUBLE SURVIVING. HER BOOK, SILENT
SPRING, DREW ATTENTION TO THIS PHENOMENON.
AND SILENT SPRING, A REFERENCE TO JUST HOW
QUIET IT HAD GOTTEN IN THE SPRINGS THAT
USED TO BE RICH WITH BIRD SONG. AND THIS
WAS ONE OF THE MAJOR CATALYSTS FOR THE ENVIRONMENTAL
MOVEMENT. THIS IS AN ECOLOGIST WHO CATALOGED
SOCIOPOLITICAL ACTION AS A RESULT OF HER
SCIENTIFIC WORK. SO THEY ARE CLOSELY RELATED
BUT THEY'RE NOT THE SAME THING. JUST FINISHING
THE DISCUSSION OF THIS EARLY PERIOD, THIS
IMAGE ALONE IS THOUGHT BY HISTORIANS TO HAVE
BEEN ONE OF MAJOR FACTORS IN THE LAUNCHING
OF THE ENVIRONMENTAL MOVEMENT, WHENR HUMAN
BEINGS SAW EARTH FROM SPACE FOR THE FIRST
TIME. A SPINNING AMD FRAGILE APPEARING BLUE
PLANET AGAINST THE DARK RECESSS OF SPACE.
THAT IMAGE ALONE FOR MANY PEOPLE TRIGGERED
AN AWARENESS OF OUR GLOBE AS A SINGLE AND
FRAGILE HOME. YOU GUYS HAVE HUNG IN THERE
WELL. PLEASE TRY TO COME BACK ON MONDAY.
HAVE A GREAT WEEKEND.