of Browns Ferry Unit Number 1 represents the
first nuclear reactor to come online in the
United States in more than a decade. (Applause.)
This is a demonstration that one is capable
of doing a job on time and on budget. And
I congratulate you all for your hard work,
and thank you for the contribution you're
making to the United States of America.
I'm going to talk a little bit about nuclear
power today, and there's no better place to
do it here than with a group of folks who
understand the great benefits of nuclear power
to our country. I believe that it is essential
that we have a comprehensive energy policy
to be able to deal with the challenges we're
going to face in the 21st century, whether
that be energy independence or economic security
or good environmental policy. And at the core
of such policy must be electricity generated
from nuclear power. (Applause.)
I'm also here to nudge Congress along. They're
working on a bill -- (laughter) -- that I
hope that they can get to my desk, that is
a good bill, a balanced bill, a reasonable
approach to making sure we continue to be
wise about how we use energy in the United
States.
I do want to thank Bill for his leadership,
and I thank the members of the board of the
TVA. I thank Tom Kilgore for taking time to
visit today. He's led me on a tour with R.G.
Jones. Some of you may have heard of R.G.
(Applause.) R.G. and I discovered we're both
60. (Laughter.) We were born in 1946, which
is a fine year to be born, at least as far
as R.G. and I are concerned. (Laughter.) I
reminded him 60 is not as old as it used to
sound -- until I climbed up all those stairs
to get to the control room. (Laughter.) I
also want to thank Brian O'Grady, the Vice
President here. (Applause.)
Put a good man who understands nuclear power
as the head of the Energy Department, Sam
Bodman. He's with us today. Mr. Secretary,
thank you for traveling with us. Appreciate
you coming. (Applause.) Also with us is Dr.
Dale Klein, Chairman of the U.S. Nuclear Regulatory
Commission. It's an important position. It's
a position that's going to expedite the regulations
so we can get more plants up and running.
And I'll talk a little bit about his intentions
and our intentions to help increase nuclear
power here in the United States.
I'm traveling with a fine United States Senator,
in Jeff Sessions. (Applause.) As well as the
Congressman from this district, a man awfully
proud of the work you do here, and that's
Bud Cramer. (Applause.) Finally, we let a
fellow from Mobile tag along with us, Congressman
Jo Bonner. Appreciate you coming, Congressman.
(Applause.)
I thank all the employees who work at this
plant. Thanks for what you're doing. Thanks
for being skillful. Thanks for working hard.
Thanks for helping the country.
The world is seeing the promise and potential
of the peaceful use of nuclear energy. I emphasize
that word, peaceful use, because one of my
predecessors, Dwight David Eisenhower, in
1953 called on the world's scientists and
engineers to find a way to produce peaceful
power from atomic energy that would serve
the needs, rather than the fears, of mankind.
That's exactly what we're doing here. You're
serving the needs, rather than the fears,
of mankind. You're helping implement the vision
of President Dwight David Eisenhower.
Nuclear power is America's third leading source
of electricity. It provides nearly 20 percent
of our country's electricity. I don't know
if a lot of our citizens understand that,
but nuclear power is a key component of economic
vitality, because it provides 20 percent of
the electricity.
Interestingly enough, nuclear power provides
78 percent of electricity for France, provides
50 percent for Sweden, 30 percent for the
entire European Union. China has nine nuclear
reactors in operation and has ambitious plans
to build many more over the next two decades.
Nuclear power is prevalent and it's recognized
as a necessary power source, not only here
in the United States, but around the world.
Nuclear power is clean. It's clean, domestic
energy. There is a lot of discussion about
the environment, as there should be. We certainly
want to leave the environment better for the
next generation that comes along. There's
a lot of discussion about greenhouse gases,
which I believe is a serious problem.
And therefore, I remind those who share my
concern about greenhouse gases that nuclear
energy produces no greenhouse gases. If you
are interested in cleaning up the air, then
you ought to be an advocate for nuclear power.
(Applause.) Without nuclear power here in
the United States, there would be nearly 700
million additional tons of carbon dioxide
in the atmosphere every year. There is no
single solution to climate change, but there
can be no solution without nuclear power.
Nuclear power is safe. The nuclear sector
is one of the safest industries in the United
States. Advances in science and engineering
and plant design have made nuclear plants
even safer than the last generation of plants.
In other words, technology has advanced, knowledge
has advanced, engineering has advanced. This
is a safe plant and the people in the United
States must understand that.
They've also got to understand that NRC inspectors
are stationed full time at these plants to
provide daily inspections, and I appreciate
the NRC inspectors who are with us today.
In other words, we go extra steps to be able
to say to the American people, this is a safe
place to work and it's a safe facility to
have in the area of the country in which you
live.
Nuclear power is affordable and it is reliable.
Once a nuclear plant is constructed, fuel
and operating costs are low. The cost of electricity
from a nuclear power plant is stable. It is
predictable. The cost of electricity from
a plant like this doesn't fluctuate the way
plants fired by natural gas can fluctuate.
The flow of power is not intermittent like
the wind. This is a reliable source of low-cost
energy.
We need nuclear power to play a greater role
in our future. That's what I want to share
with you and the American people, as we talk
about a comprehensive energy strategy, a comprehensive
energy plan, nuclear power has got to be a
really important part of our future.
Nuclear power is the only large-scale emissions-free
power source that is currently able to meet
the growing need for electricity. As our economy
grows, with additional demands for power and
electricity, nuclear power can handle those
needs.
In order to keep pace with our nuclear energy
needs, experts believe it will be necessary
to build an average of three new plants per
year starting in 2015. In other words, it's
one thing to talk about nuclear power; it's
another thing to have -- understand the strategy
necessary.
So we are going to need three plants starting
in 2015. And as we tackle climate change,
it may be necessary to have even more plants.
Here's the problem: Our country has not ordered
a new nuclear power plant since the 1970s,
partially as a result of constant litigation
and overly complex regulations. So we're working
to overcome those obstacles. I appreciate
the fact that the TVA is making decisions
to move forward nuclear power. It's time for
our country to start building nuclear power
plants again. That's what I want to share
with you. (Applause.)
One thing to restart one, and I congratulate
you. It's another thing to build the new ones.
And that's what we ought to have happen if
we're interested in a comprehensive, sound,
wise energy policy that is environmentally
friendly. The federal government is helping
to expand the safe use of nuclear power in
some important ways. First, we've set up what's
called the Nuclear Power 2010 initiative.
We launched the nuclear power initiative,
which is a partnership between industry and
the U.S. government, to reduce regulatory
and other barriers to the development of new
nuclear power plants. That's why we set it
up. We want to start building plants, and
we recognize that there have been some regulatory
burdens that prevent the construction of new
plants or at least discourage the construction
of new plants.
The 2008 budget I submitted would double the
requested funding for this initiative to $114
million. In other words, it takes money to
get this initiative moving. And we're asking
Congress to spend money on it in order to
help us put in a comprehensive energy strategy.
It makes sense. It's just a common sense strategy.
The Nuclear Regulatory Commission is working
to improve and streamline the regulatory process
to help accelerate the construction of nuclear
plants. Under the old system, the permitting
process was slow. Some of the older hands
here might remember that. It was cumbersome,
because it limited builders to completing
only one step at a time before moving on.
You could only do one thing, and then there
would be regulatory deals, and another thing
-- and it just took a long time. And when
something takes a long time to build, that
discourages capital and discourages people
from moving forward. Plus you could get sued
all the time. That would discourage people,
as well.
The Nuclear Regulatory Commission is implementing
a more efficient review process that allows
builders to complete several steps at a time
without compromising safety. They took a good
look at the problems, they said we need more
nuclear power, and so we're going to streamline
the process. The Nuclear Regulatory Commission
now expects 20 applications for combined construction
and operating licenses for up to 30 new reactors.
In other words, we're beginning to make some
progress. Things are beginning to change.
Attitudes are changing, and so is the regulatory
process, which has enabled me to tell you
we've got 20 applications for up to 30 new
reactors. That is good news for the American
consumer. (Applause.)
We think that we ought to -- America ought
to -- should be able to start construction
on additional nuclear plants by the end of
this decade. That's not all that far away.
So I've got the Chairman of the NRC here.
I want him to hear what I just said. (Laughter.)
He's doing some good work. He's got more work
to do.
I signed an energy bill in 2005 that included
important incentives to support the development
of nuclear power, including federal risk insurance
for builders of new nuclear plants, loan guarantee
eligibility and production tax credits. In
other words, to get this industry started,
put some incentives out there for people that
would be spending the money to get the plants
going.
We're working to settle the issue of storage
for nuclear waste. That's an issue. More than
55,000 metric tons of spent nuclear fuel and
high-level waste are stored at a hundred sites
in 39 states. I've submitted a budget of $495
million to continue progress on licensing
Yucca Mountain as a repository for spent fuel.
There's also another idea that I want you
to -- I know you know about it, but I want
Americans and Congress to consider. We ought
to do something about reprocessing. We ought
to bring that technology to bear. (Applause.)
We ought to bring new technologies to bear
to help us all deal with the spent fuel. So
we proposed a global nuclear energy partnership
to work with nations with advanced civilian
nuclear energy programs, such as France, Japan,
China, and Russia. And the reason why we proposed
this partnership is we want to use technologies,
new technologies -- develop and use technologies
that effectively and safely recycle spent
nuclear fuel.
Reprocessing spent uranium fuel for use in
advanced reactors will allow us to extract
more energy and has the potential to reduce
storage requirements for nuclear waste by
up to 90 percent. I am confident that we can
have the technological breakthroughs necessary
to deal with the fuel. Congress needs to spend
the money in order to do the research. And
when we do, we will be able to answer a lot
of the charges of our critics that say, what
are you going to do with the fuel?
Well, here's a good answer: Recycle it, reburn
it and reduce the amount of the problem. And
that's what the United States needs to be
doing. (Applause.)
Nuclear power is part of a broader strategy.
I want to spend a little time on the broader
strategy before we all pass out in here. (Laughter.)
There's enough hot air in the room as there
is. (Laughter.)
We're too dependent on oil. And you know,
in 1985, about 27 percent of our oil came
from other countries; today, about 60 percent
does. And that's a dependency that creates
economic and national security problems for
us.
On the national security side, our dependence
on oil leaves us more vulnerable to hostile
regimes and terrorists. If you can blow up
oil facilities overseas, it will affect the
price of oil here at home. When you're dependent
on something and somebody disrupts the supply
on which you're dependent, it will affect
you. It effects international politics, to
a certain extent, to be dependent on oil.
When the price of oil goes up for whatever
reason overseas, it affects the price of gasoline
here in northern Alabama. So there is an economic
issue for being dependent on oil. And, of
course, when oil is burned as a fuel, it effects
the environment. So we've got to change our
dependency.
One way to do so is to spend some of your
money on new technologies that will change
how we live in positive ways. So we spent
$12 billion since I've been the President
to develop cleaner, cheaper and more reliable
energy sources. I think that's a wise use
of your money -- to encourage research and
development on new ways to drive your cars,
for example.
One such example is -- that we're spending
your money on is for clean coal technologies.
We've got to do something to make sure that
when we have electricity generated by coal
that we can say to future generations of Americans
that we're going to protect the environment,
as well. We've got a lot of coal. If you want
to be less dependent on foreign sources of
oil, you ought to use the energy sources you've
got here at home. Not all electricity is going
to be generated as a result of nuclear power.
We're going to be burning coal. And so we
are spending a lot of money, and I believe
that we'll have emission-free coal plants
that will capture and remove virtually all
air pollutants and greenhouse gases from burning
coal. That's what the experts tell me.
So some of your money, some of your hard-earned
money is going to encourage that kind of research.
I think it's worth it. And I know it's necessary
if we want to be less dependent on oil and
be good about how we deal with the environment.
And we're also spending money to help others
research wind and solar power. That's a nice
alternative. It's certainly not going to -- wind
power is not going to be nearly as effective
and efficient as nuclear power, but it can
be a part of the mix.
If you want to affect dependency on oil, then
we've got to figure out how to use -- put
different power sources in our cars. Gasoline
is oil. You know, so when you say I'm using
gasoline, you really are using oil. Because
that's how -- that's where gasoline comes
from. And so one idea that we're working on
is to encourage ethanol, which works. See,
if you're driving your automobile based upon
something a farmer grows here in northern
Alabama, as opposed to something that's as
a result of buying from overseas -- makes
sense to me.
You've got your farmer growing something that
powers your automobile, I think it puts us
in a much better position economically, from
a national security perspective. And we're
spending a fair amount of your money to make
sure that we can use something other than
corn from which to make ethanol. If you're
a hog farmer, you're getting tired of seeing
the corn prices go up. If you're a corn farmer,
it's a nice feeling to see the prices go up.
(Laughter.)
But we believe we can come up with technologies
that will enable us to use wood chips to make
ethanol that you can put in your automobiles
to help us become less dependent on oil, or
switchgrasses. That would be nice for some
of the people from my state. Switchgrass grows
in a nice dry environment. I understand you're
dry here, by the way. The senator and the
congressmen are working hard on me about the
drought that you've got here. (Laughter.)
But some parts of our country need to -- have
got dry country and they can grow some switchgrass.
The whole idea is to come up with different
ways to power our automobiles. And along those
lines, I think it's not going to be long before
you're going to be able to drive an automobile
with new battery technologies that you can
just plug in to your garage. And your automobile
won't look like a golf cart. It will be a
normal size pickup truck. (Laughter and applause.)
So I laid out a goal that said we're going
to reduce our gasoline usage by 20 percent
over 10 years as a part of our energy diversification
strategy. And I think we can achieve that.
I also know we need to change our fuel economy
standards just like we did for trucks, and
I want to work with Congress to do that as
well.
In other words, it's part of a comprehensive
strategy. I call it the 20-10 goal. And I
commend Congress for pursuing the framework
for the 20-10 proposal. It's a promising start.
However, as bills get written, it's being
frustrated by special interests and, of course,
all the politics that takes place in Washington,
D.C.
The current plan being debated in the Senate
falls far short of the ambitious goal I laid
out. But it's a realistic goal. It's a necessary
goal if we want to become less dependent on
oil from overseas. The Senate's proposed fuel
mandate, for example, calls for just a 10
percent reduction in gasoline usage by 2017.
We can do much better than that. We really
can. We've got to be optimistic about what
America can do when we put our mind to doing
something.
And so I urge the Congress to be realistic
about the bills they're talking about and
get it done. Get it to my desk so we can all
say we've done a good job of representing
the people.
By the way, as we talk about these new technologies,
we're still going to need oil and gas. And
we can explore for oil and gas in environmentally
friendly ways. I strongly believe that we
ought to open up more outer continental shelf
area, as well as ANWR in Alaska. You know,
there's a big debate about whether or not
you can drill and find oil and gas that's
good for you without ruining the environment.
I'm telling you we can. Technologies have
changed. (Applause.)
By the way, when they're debating the bill
up there, they've also got to fill up -- add
to the strategic petroleum reserve. If you're
worried about a terrorist attack which could
affect the price of oil, we ought to have
oil in the ground that we can use to protect
the American consumer. And they need to expand
the petroleum reserve against natural disasters,
protection against natural disasters, as well
as a potential attack.
By the way, the Supreme Court -- I don't know
if you follow the Supreme Court at all, but
they've ruled that the EPA must take action
under the Clean Air Act regarding greenhouse
gas emissions from motor vehicles. That's
what the Court said. And when the Court says
something, then the executive branch of government
says, okay, you said it, now we'll listen.
We'll do what you asked us to do.
And so I directed the EPA and the Department
of Transportation, Energy, and Agriculture
to take the first steps toward regulations
that would cut gasoline consumption and greenhouse
gases using the plan I just described to you.
So Congress can pass the law, which I hope
they do, but if they don't, we're moving forward
because the Supreme Court told us to move
forward. And either way, in either case, we're
going to become less dependent on oil, and
that's good for the United States of America.
(Applause.)
So I appreciate you letting me come by and
talk a little energy. You live it, I'm talking
it. (Laughter.) I thank you for what you're
doing for the country. I thank you for your
hard work, I thank you for your skill, I thank
you for your prayers. I thank you for being
good Americans.
And may God bless you. And may God bless our
country. Thank you all. (Applause.)