Ed Ricketts, sailed down the coast of California
and Mexico to the Sea of Cortez.
"The abundance of life here gives one an exuberance,"
they wrote, "a feeling of fullness and richness."
Their stated purpose was to document the creatures
that inhabit shallow waters and tide pools
on the margins of the Sea of Cortez.
But it became much more.
In these mysterious, phosphorescent waters
they sought an understanding of mankind's
relationship to the natural world, and a wellspring
of hope for a world headed toward war.
Looking beyond the events of the day, the
two friends foresaw our rising impact on the
oceans, and the devastating impact that over
fishing would have on this rich sea.
And yet, in their journey, they encountered
a periodic cooling of the eastern Pacific
Ocean known as La Ni–a that can still set
off an explosion of life.
Can the story of their journey inspire new
efforts to preserve the Sea of Cortez?
Down along the shores of western Mexico, the
wind blows hot and dry.
Beyond these barren landscapes, cold currents
rush up from the deep, and the ocean literally
boils with life.
Following their journey down to the Sea of
Cortez in March of 1940, John Steinbeck and
Ed Ricketts searched for a way to describe
what they saw.
"Trying to remember this place," they wrote,
"is like trying to re-create a dream. It is
fierce and hostile and sullen. The stone mountains
pile up to the sky and there is little fresh
water. But we know we must go back if we live,
and we don't know why."
The Sea of Cortez is one of the most diverse
marine ecosystems on the planet. It's shaped
by the cool waters of the California Current
flowing into the warm tropics, and by a complex
undersea terrain that rises up along a chain
of islands and seamounts.
It was the shorelines, between the desert
and the deep, that drew John Steinbeck, the
author, and Ed Ricketts, a marine biologist
and expert on coastal ecosystems.
Ricketts' book, "Between Pacific Tides," is
a classic study of the inter-tidal zones of
the California coastline... and the myriad
creatures that live in shallow pools, clinging
to rocks to sift the rich nutrients carried
in by the tides.
Steinbeck and Ricketts sought to extend this
work to the Sea of Cortez and to explore ideas
at the core of their friendship.
They shared a belief that man's fate, like
that of the animals they saw, is linked to
the health of the natural world.
Ricketts is said to have inspired some of
Steinbeck's most memorable characters, including
Doc in Cannery Row, and the preacher Jim Casy
in The Grapes of Wrath, published a year before
their voyage.
Set against the backdrop of drought and economic
depression, the book describes the dustbowl
conditions that gripped the American heartland
in the 1930s.
"Now the wind grew strong and hard and it
worked at the rain crust in the corn fields.
Little by little the sky was darkened by the
mixing dust, and carried away. The wind grew
stronger. The rain crust broke and the dust
lifted up out of the fields and drove gray
plumes into the air like sluggish smoke."
In most years, southerly winds carry moisture
into the midsection of the country from the
Gulf of Mexico.
In the 1930s, according to a recent NASA study,
those winds were diverted by a build up of
warm water in the Western Atlantic, and by
a periodic cooling of the Eastern Pacific
known as La Ni–a.
This combination robbed the region of rain.
By the time Steinbeck and Ricketts began their
journey, the historic backdrop had shifted
to war. Fighting had engulfed Europe and was
spreading to the western Pacific.
While the United States was still officially
neutral, American companies had begun supplying
arms to the allied effort.
In early 1940, John Steinbeck used money he
earned from "The Grapes of Wrath" to hire
a sardine boat called the Western Flyer.
From Monterrey, California, he, his wife Carol,
Ed Ricketts and a four-man crew headed south,
charting a course along the Mexican coastline.
By all accounts, the journey was filled with
adventure, camaraderie, and a sense of wonder
at the diversity of living things they encountered.
Over a six-week period, the two friends wrote
journal entries, took notes on conversations,
and catalogued specimens they collected on
the way.
They compiled these writings into a book:
"Sea of Cortez, A Leisurely Journal of Travel
and Research," later changed to "The Log From
the Sea of Cortez." The work amounts to a
search for a way to understand nature, and
humanity at large, in a world steadily coming
apart at the seams.
The crew had little to go on in advance of
the journey, for the sparsely populated coastlines
of Baja California had not been studied or
mapped in detail.
"From the information available," the book
says, "a few facts did emerge. The Sea of
Cortez, or the Gulf of California, is a long,
narrow, highly dangerous body of water. It
is subject to sudden and vicious storms of
great intensity."
One book they had read contained accounts
of "ships broken up and scattered, of wrecks
and wayward currents; of 50 miles of sea more
dreaded than any other."
In fact, their route along the coastlines
of Baja California was an obstacle course
of islands and outcroppings.
All along the way, erosion and bone rattling
earthquakes have exposed layers of ancient
bedrock and volcanic flows, offering a window
into the events that long ago shaped the region.
Beginning around 25 million years ago, a giant
section of the Earth's crust, known as the
Pacific Ocean plate, began sliding past and
pulling away from North America.
Deep underground, the friction of rock grinding
against rock fueled the rise of mountains
and volcanoes that now define these rugged
coastlines.
Meanwhile, along a fault line that reaches
north through California, a gash nearly 10,000
feet deep opened in the Earth, now known as
the Gulf of California Rift zone.
From the north, the Sea of Cortez is fed by
melting snow that flows down from the Rocky
Mountains and through the Grand Canyon, and
from the south, by powerful tides that surge
in from the Pacific.
On their way down from Monterrey, the crew
of the Western Flyer passed by a wide diversity
of coastal habitats.
Below the surface, are kelp beds common in
northern waters, and coral reefs that recall
the tropics.
Vast sea grass meadows, and tangled mangrove
swamps, and a network of tidepools and rocky
shallows, teeming with life.
In the sheer density of living things, they
may well have witnessed the extraordinary
flipside of the climatic conditions that created
the Dustbowl.
During the onset of La Ni–a, every three
to six years, strong equatorial winds begin
to blow off the coast of South America, pushing
warm surface waters away, while drawing cold,
nutrient-rich waters up from the deep.
That can fuel an explosion of microscopic
plankton, and in turn, a vast natural melting
pot of marine life.
The two friends interpreted what they saw
using the emerging science of ecology. Ricketts
had been exposed to it in his studies at the
University of Chicago and Steinbeck at Stanford
University's Hopkins Marine Lab.
The idea is that an ecosystem is governed
by complex inter-dependencies between species
and their environments. Scientists have expanded
this notion to include evolution, nutrient
cycling, food webs, and more.
A central idea that appealed to Steinbeck
and Ricketts is that the sum of individual
animals adds up to a greater whole.
Take, for instance, a school of small fish
under attack by a band of sailfish. For individuals
to survive, they must literally come together
as one.
"Their functions in the school," they wrote,
"are in some as yet unknown way as controlled
as though the school were one unit. We cannot
conceive of this intricacy until we are able
to think of the school as an animal itself,
reacting with all its cells to stimuli which
perhaps might not influence one fish at all."
Steinbeck and Rickett's stated mission was
to explore how individuals function within
a group, and how a school or a reef or a tide
pool fits within the greater marine ecosystem.
Rather than find species that were rare or
undiscovered, they set out to document what
was there, then to contemplate its connections
to the wider world.
While the purpose of the trip was to produce
a scientific record, the book they wrote,
according to the scholar Richard Astro, is
a "celebration of this holistic vision, depicted
in terms more mystical and intuitive than
scientific."
This vision came together in their description
of a shore visit to Puerto Escondido, a cove
that today hosts a small marina.
There, some local residents invited them on
a hunt for big-horn sheep.
The hike took them along hillsides lined with
plants adapted to long periods of dryness.
While they never saw any wild sheep, the trek
gave them a chance to look back down at the
Sea and to reflect on the mountains and the
world that envelop it.
They marveled at tiny desert springs, isolated
within the waterless landscape, that were
somehow filled with life.
Likewise, in the ocean, they noted the remarkable
collaboration between invertebrates in the
tasks of gathering food and moving around.
Mysteries like these, they believed, would
yield only to the most expansive view of individual
organisms in relation to countless others,
all nested within the folds of an ocean, a
desert, and a planet.
Many of the great thinkers, they remind us
later in the book, "discovered and reaffirmed
with astonishment the knowledge that all things
are one thing and that one thing is all things
- plankton, a shimmering phosphorescence on
the sea and the spinning planets and an expanding
universe, all bound together by the elastic
string of time."
"It is advisable," they wrote, "to look from
the tide pool to the stars and then back to
the tide pool again."
Within this all-embracing view, they believed,
humans are uniquely capable of understanding
the whole of nature and affecting it.
As isolated and pristine as the Sea of Cortez
might have seemed in 1940, it was still subject
to the intrusions of the wider world.
The two friends reported shrimp boats, for
example, dredging up the sea bottom, "rapidly
destroying the species so that it may never
come back, and with the species destroying
the ecological balance of the whole region.
That isn't very important in the world. And
thousands of miles away the great bombs are
falling and the stars are not moved thereby."
"None of it is important," they wrote, "or
all of it is."
The book they wrote was published over a year
after their journey ended, on December 5th
1941. Two days later, on December 7th, Japanese
bombers descended on Pearl Harbor.
The book was lost in the news of the day,
in a nation and a world moving rapidly toward
World War.
John Steinbeck went on to serve as a war correspondent,
then returned to his literary career.
Ed Ricketts too served in the war as a medical
lab technician for the Army.
He then returned to doing science, with groundbreaking
studies on the sardine fishery in Monterrey
Bay that linked fishing practices to declining
harvests.
In 1948, the two friends were planning another
trip -- to study marine life in the Pacific
Northwest. Tragically, Ed Ricketts was killed
when his car was hit by a passenger train.
The book he authored with John Steinbeck would
echo down the years as commentary on the events
that had shaken the world, and on the world
that would emerge in the aftermath.
Many of Baja California's landscapes and coastlines
are still the way they were before humans
settled there.
But its waters have become the center of a
thriving tourist and sport fishing industry,
and a magnet for large-scale commercial fishing.
Scientists at Scripps Institution of Oceanography
recently conducted a comprehensive survey
of wildlife in the Sea of Cortez. Comparing
what they saw against past surveys, they identified
a series of mounting threats.
Unsustainable water use practices in the Colorado
River basin have damaged many of the estuaries
at its mouth, threatening shrimp and other
fisheries.
Industrial fishing methods have wreaked havoc
on a variety of fish populations.
An example is the deployment of gillnets,
curtains that stretch across miles of ocean
and trap whatever happens to come by.
Another is long-line fishing, in which fishermen
deploy hundreds of baited hooks from lines
of buoys.
These methods have all but eliminated oceanic
predators such as sharks and tuna.
They've decimated some non-target species
such as manta rays.
With many of the traditional fisheries depleted,
the report warns of a practice known as "fishing
down the food web." Teams of divers pick through
the reefs for invertebrates, or lone fish
hiding among the rocks at night. They take
anything they can get.
On their visit to the rocky southern tip of
Baja California, Cabo San Lucas, John Steinbeck
and Ed Ricketts reveled in the diversity of
living things: "the incredible beauty of the
tide pools," "the brilliant colors," "the
swarming species."
Those same tide pools today are covered over
with sand trucked in for the construction
of condos and vacation resorts.
Cabo San Lucas has become a major tourist
destination, with accommodations for over
a million visitors per year in resorts and
hotel chains.
The human presence has introduced a major
new dynamic to the Sea of Cortez that can
be difficult to unravel.
Since the year 2002, the entire eastern pacific
coast, up to Alaska and including the Sea
of Cortez, has experienced the rapid spread
of Humboldt squid. Moving up from the deep
in large numbers, these ferocious hunters
go after a wide variety of prey.
Their overall impact on the food web is largely
unknown. In the Sea of Cortez, they are targets
for fishermen who ride out at night, often
hauling in tons of squid per trip to bring
to market.
A recent study blames the spread of these
squid on a combination of factors, from warming
ocean temperatures, to reduced competition
for food, and the decline of predatory species
like sharks.
The disappearance of sharks is in stark evidence
at a seamount near the Bay of La Paz.
Known as El Bajo, it was once a top destination
for divers hoping to observe the gathering
of hammerhead sharks.
This seamount still attracts a rich array
of sea life.
Today, the big hammerhead schools are a rare
sight.
That's because few things have changed in
the Sea of Cortez as dramatically as the value
of its sharks.
It has exploded in recent years, mainly to
supply the Asian market for shark fin soup.
Traditionally served at weddings in China,
it can fetch up to $100 per bowl.
About half the world trade in shark fins goes
through the port of Hong Kong, a trade estimated
at 38 million sharks annually, that may well
be much higher.
The oceans today are literally being swept
of sharks.
Because they congregate in large numbers,
hammerheads are especially vulnerable.
There's money to be made in a big haul, such
as this one filmed in the Sea of Cortez in
the year 2000.
A fishing boat had encircled a school at a
seamount. With nets designed to haul in large
numbers of tuna, it scooped up dozens of hammerhead
sharks.
Whether for subsistence or industrial-scale
business, fishing is an opportunistic pursuit.
Fishermen take what's there or what they are
able to bring to shore.
Overfishing in the Sea of Cortez is part of
a larger global problem. According to UN estimates,
80% of oceanic fish stocks around the world
are now considered fully or over-exploited.
John Steinbeck and Ed Ricketts had sought
hope, amid a rising tide of war, by crafting
a holistic view of man and nature. In doing
so, they helped supply the philosophical underpinnings
of a broad movement to protect Earth's natural
environments.
That movement is beginning to take hold in
the Sea of Cortez, offering glimmers of hope.
There are new regulations, for example, governing
drift-net and long-line fishing. Some critics
say they don't go far enough. Others say they
are at least a start.
If nothing else, in the Sea of Cortez today,
more divers, sport fishermen, and boaters
are out keeping a watch on things. With the
aid of a Mexican navy diver, this group has
come out to remove a drift net, one step in
restoring a reef to its natural state.
Some places like this are now part of a growing
network of preserves and protected areas,
a hedge against the rising impact of development.
Sailing along the southern tip of Baja, Steinbeck
and Ricketts were struck by the natural desolation
of the shorelines, "dry with strange flat
mountains and rocks torn by dryness, and the
heat shimmer hung over the land even in March."
Here, they visited a reef called Cabo Pulmo,
where swift ocean currents bring in a torrent
of sea life.
In the 1990s, these reefs were considered
overfished and damaged by pollution. Biologists
and local fishermen came together to fight
for and win protected status for Cabo Pulmo.
Today, no fishing is allowed.
The reefs of Cabo Pulmo have since become
a Mecca for divers and a source of large,
mature fish for local fishermen outside the
reserve.
In their visit to Cabo Pulmo, the scientists
at Scripps Institution of Oceanography found
that the sheer weight, or biomass, of fish
here is at least four times that of similar
unprotected reefs. That includes species up
and down the food chain, from plankton feeders
to predators, bottom dwellers to ocean fliers.
Moving north and into the Sea of Cortez, the
crew of the Western Flyer passed by a chain
of volcanic islands, the largest of which
is called Espiritu Santo.
In the year 1535, the Spanish Explorer, Hernan
Cortes, named it Isla de las Perlas, Island
of the Pearls, after rich pearl oyster beds
on its western side.
On the northern end of this chain, a tiny
marine reserve runs down the steep sides of
a group of small islands called Los Islotes.
The islands deflect deep currents that flow
into the Gulf, sending them to the surface.
These nutrient-laden waters fuel an explosion
of microscopic plants and animals.
They in turn draw vast walls of anchovies,
sardines, and other baitfish.
Moving with currents that swirl around it,
these schools wrap the island in a ribbon
of silver.
Large numbers of bait fish help support a
community of predators.
Reserves like this protect wild creatures
from overfishing, but not from a larger cycle
of awakening and dying that defines the Sea
of Cortez.
John Steinbeck and Ed Ricketts sailed into
the cool, rich waters of La Ni–a.
Inevitably, they give way to the warm waters
of El Ni–o.
This climatic shift brings rain to the Baja
Peninsula, along with glimmers of green.
Washing down hillsides and gullies, the rains
deliver a flood of nutrients to shallow lagoons
and mangrove swamps.
Within the protective shelter of mangrove
roots, young yellow snappers and other fish
can now grow and mature.
Out at sea, El Ni–o is a time of scarcity.
The influx of warm water stifles the upwelling
of nutrients. The Sea of Cortez can then grow
fallow, turning clear and lifeless.
That can wreak havoc on some critical habitats,
including dense forests of sargassum, or brown
algae, that grow along the shorelines.
A wide variety of fish use them as a refuge
in their early stages of development. Then,
when wind and waves pull patches of sargassum
from the shore, these fish hitch a ride out
to their ocean habitats.
As sargassum dwindles during El Ni–o, so
do a range of fish populations.
Many ocean creatures are known to travel widely
in pursuit of food supplies that shift with
the seasons or with the climate.
Pacific white-sided dolphins, traveling in
groups up to 100 or more range from the tip
of Baja California in the South to the Bering
Sea near the Arctic in the north .
One study showed that with the onset of warm
El Ni–o waters, these highly mobile predators
adapted by migrating out to cooler seas and
by changing their diet.
Another ocean predator, the Magnificent Frigate
bird, has a strategy that allows it to stay
put in times of scarcity.
Gathering in colonies atop mangrove forests,
it has the longest nesting cycle of any bird.
A frigate male attracts a mate by inflating
a huge red sack on its chest. Once a pair
is made, the couple puts its all into raising
a single chick, incubating, then feeding it
for about a year and even longer in lean El
Ni–o years.
The colony is a busy place as couples take
turns flying out over the ocean in search
of food.
Because frigates lack the oils in their feathers
that would allow them to land on the water,
they stay in flight for days or weeks at a
time, riding wind currents to conserve energy.
Frigates are known to snag flying fish out
of the air, or to steal fish caught by other
birds.
Soaring high above the ocean, they watch for
signs of activity on the surface. If predators
force small fish to the surface, frigates
can swoop down to skillfully pluck them out.
In time, as the warm waters of El Ni–o fade,
the productivity of the Sea of Cortez begins
to rise again.
With the return of La Ni–a, the wind blows
again across the barren shorelines.
Cold water rises up from the deep, laden with
nutrients, and the sea grows cloudy with plankton.
Life returns with a flourish.
John Steinbeck and Ed Ricketts celebrated
the rush of living organisms.
"The sea here swarms with life," they wrote.
"We could see the splashing of great schools
of tuna in the distance where they beat the
water to spray in their millions."
They also noted great schools of giant manta
rays. One crew member tried repeatedly, but
without success, to haul one onto the boat.
While mantas are scarce in the Sea of Cortez
today, their smaller cousins, the mobulas,
are not.
Hundreds swim together in glorious flying
formation, at times rising to the surface
to feed on a dense layer of plankton.
The recent period of La Ni–a shows how productive
the Sea of Cortez can be and offers a glimpse
of what's at stake in efforts to preserve
it for the future.
The abundance of food at the surface has also
drawn the largest fish in the ocean, the whale
shark.
Moving slowly along, they take in big gulps
of water, then filter out zooplankton, krill,
larvae, and even small fish.
At up to 30 tons and 20 meters in length,
adult whale sharks have few natural predators.
They can live up to 70 years, churning along
in plankton-rich seas.
With plankton filling the water column, the
drama of life and death in the Sea of Cortez
reaches a fever pitch.
Predators and prey come together amid the
tangled ruins of a sunken ship.
Out along the Pacific coastline of Baja, the
cool water of La Ni–a has spurred a rarely
seen migration of countless young mola molas.
These so-called ocean sunfish can grow to
three meters long and weigh several tons.
Along the way, parasites hitch a ride.
When that happens, fish swims up along side
bird hoping there's a mutual advantage.
Just on shore, the season has brought a bumper
crop of young sea lions. They are born with
their eyes open and are able to swim soon
after.
While pups may nurse on shore for up to a
year, they begin to eat fish within a few
months.
Along the Pacific coast, just beyond the Sea
of Cortez, the young ones hang out within
the protective shelter of the rocky shoreline.
Here, they learn to interact with other sea
lions, to vocalize, to swim, and hunt.
Being a young sea lion is all about riding
the currents and waves and investigating the
myriad creatures that live in shallow water.
This one finds itself in a game of hide and
seek with a giant damsel fish. The fish is
most likely just defending its territory.
At every turn fish out-maneuvers mammal. But
the sea lion is becoming more and more determined.
In the end, there's only so much frustration
a sea lion will endure.
If you can't eat the fish, you can always
eat sand. It could be to gain extra ballast
for deep dives or to help with digestion.
No one really knows.
When the urge to scratch strikes, a rock with
barnacles is always within reach.
As these young sea lions grow, so do their
appetites. As adults, sea lions move out into
the ocean to forage, sometimes traveling hundreds
of miles.
To observe their full potential as hunters,
you have to follow them out to sea. Near a
seamount, a group of sea lions encounters
a school of small fish. The fish instinctively
pull together, forming a bait ball.
Out here, in the blue water, schools of fish
are targets for predators endowed with blazing
speed and lightning reflexes. Striped marlin
join the attack from below, pinning the school
on the surface.
With their ability to quickly accelerate,
and swim in tight circles, striped marlin
are the dive-bombers of the sea.
The bait ball avoids the agile predators by
turning, dodging, dispersing and coming back
together.
The predators begin to outlast the prey and
pick them off one by one.
Divers report seeing marlin use their bills
to stun their prey, then circle back around
to pick up their prize.
In a survey of fish found in the stomachs
of Marlin caught by fishermen, over half bore
deep marks or cuts.
Another predator now joins the hunt. A Brydes
whale roars in from out of the blue.
In the Sea of Cortez, the strongest reason
for hope may well lie in the hidden treasures
of the sea itself.
In tandem with the shifting climate, the ocean
releases its stores of wealth from places
unknown to people yet well known to creatures
that ply its depths.
Down along a seamount near the mouth of the
Sea of Cortez is a sight that many hope will
one day become commonplace again.
Vague shapes appear in the gray and murky
deep. Perhaps in response to a change in temperature,
or to an ocean flooded with nutrients, a school
of hammerhead sharks suddenly arrives.
To these sharks, equipped to read the magnetic
contours of the sea floor, islands and seamounts
may serve as landmarks, or gathering spots,
for mating and feeding.
John Steinbeck often portrayed his characters
at the lowest points of their lives, struggling
to gain a fresh start against larger forces
at work in the world.
That may well be the case for these sharks
and for the phosphorescent waters of the Sea
of Cortez. John Steinbeck and Ed Ricketts
believed that humanity, with its unique ability
to see the whole, would find a way to preserve
natural scenes like this.
"In spite of overwhelming evidence to the
contrary," they wrote, "the trait of hope
still controls the future, and man, not a
species but a triumphant race, will approach
perfection, and tearing himself free, will
march up the stars and take his place where,
because of his power and virtue, he belongs."
The two friends knew that even their own footprint
would change the Sea of Cortez in small ways,
as they entered its tide pools to collect
specimens, sailed through its channels, or
docked on its shores.
In the years since, mankind's impact on this
already dynamic ecosystem has steadily grown.
And yet more and more of us are coming here,
not to harvest its treasures, but to experience
the sense of discovery, the mystical connection
to the ocean and the earth that the two friends
shared.
On their journey to the Sea of Cortez, they
had lost, they wrote, "the fear and contagion
of war and economic uncertainty. The matters
of great importance we had left were not important."
What they had found instead was the fulfillment
of joining a vital continuum, linking the
humble microcosm of the tide pools to a sea
teeming with life, to the Earth, and to the
universe beyond.
??