Narrator: On this episode of
Wicked Tuna.
Paul: Yo, the white boat.
You're too close.
Pirate: This is bad.
Ralph: The googans that come out
on the weekends don't really
have a clue of what's going on.
Bill: He's hooked up.
Get the hell out of the way.
Dave: We're on, again.
We were able to hook up with
this guy parked five feet away
from us.
That's why we're the best.
Bill: Yeah, we're really
struggling man.
Tuna.com hooking up allthe time
is really starting to piss us
off.
Donna: I'll kill you.
Narrator: Fishing is a hard
life.
Ralph: There's gonna be
confrontation.
Narrator: And harder
with blufin stocks depleted.
In Gloucester, Massachusetts,
there's a special
breed of fisherman.
For generations, they've used
rod and reel to catch the
elusive bluefin tuna.
Jay: Yeah, baby!
Narrator: They depend on these
fish for their survival.
The competition is brutal.
Scott: You miserable prick.
Narrator: This is Wicked Tuna.
Dave: It's great to be on top.
It's great to make all the
money.
But with that, nobody likes a
winner.
Marciano: For me the money
doesn't fall out of the sky, it
comes out of the sea.
Bill: This gets harder as you
get older.
But I'm keeping up with the
young guns.
Get out of the way.
Ralph: If it's on my mind you're
gonna hear about it.
And if you did something
to me, I'm gonna
do something back to you.
Ralph: All right, Pirate.
We're gonna start the boat.
Let's rock and roll.
Cabin lights are off.
You ready?
Pirate: Yeah.
Ralph: Here we go.
All right, Pirate, we're
gonna go check out the bay
today.
From what
we hear there's been some
fish caught close to the
beach here at Cape Cod Bay so
we're gonna give
that a chance.
I hate to fish
on the weekends,
'cause there's so many idiots
and googans out there,
it turns the ocean
into a parking lot.
But the weather outlook for
the upcoming week is pretty
(bleep), so I guess we have
no option but to fish this
weekend.
Pirate: These are the types
of bait we're using, is, uh,
whiting right here.
You get our butterfish,
squid, uh, herring.
And what we're doing to it
is I've add some live bait.
A little bit of a flush to
help you out on catching the
fish.
'Cause that little bit
of movement like that,
the fish might see
that, and, whoosh!
Go at it, instead of having
just kind of like a little
bait fluttering around or
something like that, so.
Hopefully a fish makes
a mistake and eats
one of the baits for us.
Paul: You (bleep) dirt bag.
What are the odds of that
boat being on our numbers?
What are the
(bleep) odds of it?
Dave: There's definitely a
problem with fishing on the
weekends.
I come out here this morning.
And this scumbag is sitting
right on my numbers to within
50 feet.
So.
Yeah, I mean everybody, when
we're fishing we have certain
numbers we like to fish.
Coordinates,
latitude, longitude,
time differentials.
But these weekend warriors,
they follow the boats that
catch fish, steal
our coordinates,
and it's just absolutely
(bleep) disrespectful.
Paul: Weekend warriors.
The reason why we don't
like 'em next to us,
it's because if we hook-up,
they don't know enough to
clear their lines,
drop their anchor.
They have no clue.
You're gonna break 'em off.
Sandro: That's a
big (bleep) boat.
Dave: I was fishing
there every single day.
I went in, I offloaded
a fish, came back out,
and there he is
sitting on my numbers.
Paul: Just go up
to him and say,
"I've been here for
three (bleep) years."
Tell him, "I'm
getting in this spot."
Dave: He'll move.
Can he anchor on my numbers?
Absolutely.
That's his right to do so.
This is battle of
the turf right here.
I'm gonna get it closer.
Let me see.
Wait, I might even
get closer to him.
Hold on.
Sandro, I want to get
closer to this guy.
Dave: Let it go.
Paul: Time to get the
(bleep) out of here.
Dave: I basically anchored
right off his, uh,
starboard bow, threw
the anchor there,
and drifted back.
Got tight on the anchor, and
I was literally two or three
boat lengths away from 'em.
(Bleep).
Paul: Right in 'em.
Hi.
Dave: If he was
smart he'd move.
And if has something to say,
he can come to the dock and
say it to my face later.
If you're gonna be a
man, go toe to toe.
Sandro: Heard about a
bunch of fights on sea,
but I've never
actually seen one, so.
Paul: See it a lot.
Sandro: What's that?
Dave: See a lot of
fights out here.
Paul: Dude, one guy (bleep)
backed up to the guy in the
middle of the ocean,
jumped on his boat,
punched the (bleep) out
of him, knocked him out,
got back on his
boat and drove away.
Dave: He's gotta deal with
it, or he's gotta move.
Marciano: We're
in New England.
We're late in the season.
It's November, 'cause this
time of year the weather's
very unstable.
We're gonna lose
the next two days,
possibly even three days,
because there's gonna be too
much wind for us to
come out here and fish.
So I had to try this weekend.
Middle Bank's gonna be mobbed
this weekend with the weekend
warriors, the part-timers
and the ferryboats.
We're gonna go up to one of
my secret spots up on, uh,
Jeffreys Ledge.
And we're gonna
just find some fish.
Ralph: Yo, it's
unbelievable here today.
Now we got this guy anchoring
up next to us here now?
Gonna (bleep) have all these
guys all over you today.
It's gonna be ridiculous.
Cut their lines
off with the fish.
Teach 'em a lesson.
Giant tuna fishing we
have the commercial guys,
we have the sport guys, and
then we have the googans.
Come on, what's the
matter with you guys?
Why you driving around?
Get the (bleep) out of here.
The googans are kind of like
sport guys, in small boats.
Come on.
Slow down.
That's an idiot for you.
That come out on the weekends
and don't really have a clue
what's going on.
Pirate: Waaaaah.
Ralph: Yo, you're too close.
Hey!
Yo!
The white boat!
Rules are, you usually, you
give a boat a quarter of a
mile.
When there's a boat
20 yards from you,
and they don't realize what
happens is the tide is gonna
turn.
Everybody swings, and you
know, on the next tide,
you're float or balloon
is in his anchor line.
And if you get a
bite, you're gonna
lose the fish right off.
Hey, little white boat.
Come in.
Come on, pick me up on 69,
you want to talk on the
radio?
Come on.
Yeah, you can't stay there.
My balloons are going
under your anchor line.
You just got out here.
We're here since
4:30 this morning.
You can't just drop
there like that.
Man: What do you mean,
you're under my anchor line?
Ralph: The balloons are
going towards your boat.
If I get a bite, I'm
under your anchor line.
I don't want to
deal with that.
Man: Wah.
Wah.
Ralph: They're over there
with orange pants like they
know what they're doing.
They should require a test
before you get a pair of
orange pants.
On the weekends, you want
to get your own spot,
protect it, fight the other
boats off from getting too
close to you, which probably
means you're gonna be yelling
and screaming and
cursing a lot.
But, it usually pays off.
Why don't you just wind your
lines up and go somewhere
else?
Man: Why don't you
mind your business?
Ralph: No, this is
my (bleep) business.
This ain't your
(bleep) business.
Go to work!
This is what I do
to feed my family,
and you're (bleep) with me!
Man: How am I doing that?
Ralph: Well, because you're
drifting right down the side
of my boat.
You're fishing where
everybody's (bleep) anchored.
You're an (bleep).
Man: No, that's you.
Ralph: Yeah, I'm an (bleep)?
We're gonna get off the
anchor and go (bleep) chase
'em off.
Donna: Where the
hell are you going?
Bill: I don't
know where to go.
We got a late start today.
We heard there was a
biting on Cape Cod,
but we're having a hard
time finding a spot.
Between all the other
fishermen and the googans,
it's like a parking
lot out there.
I'm trying to get in that
line, that line of boats,
'cause that's where
the bites were.
Donna: Need to get
further that way.
Bill: That's not easy to do.
Donna: You need to get
in the line that way.
That, you can
see the pattern.
What the (bleep) is he doing?
Scott: Go yell
at him, will ya?
Donna: Oh, I can be
very vocal, yeah.
Definitely.
I let him know if I
don't like something.
Listen, listen.
Bill: What?
I'm gonna pull in back there.
Donna: You need to go, do you
see where the hookups are?
Bing, bing, bing, bing, bing.
Bill: I know, but I
can't get in there.
Donna: Yeah you can.
Bill: If he wasn't there
I could get in there.
Donna: Who, Pete?
Go around Pete.
Bill: I can't go around him.
Where am I going
to put the anchor?
I can't drop it while
he's fighting a fish.
Donna: Some days when what
he's doing might not be
working, I'd like him to
try something else and he's
stubborn and we get into it
a little bit on the boat.
Bill: No, they're all
in front of the nets.
That's where they are.
Donna: Well, what's his face.
Bill: The nets don't go.
They're not
perfectly lined up.
I went over there.
There's no place to anchor.
Donna: That's the line that
they caught the fish in.
Bill: Listen, Pete's anchor.
Donna: Yeah, it's over here.
Bill: No, that's
Frankie's anchor.
Donna: I'm just telling you.
That's where the line is.
We haven't had a lot of luck,
uh, so far this season.
Uh, we've lost a lot of fish.
A lot of big fish.
If we don't catch
some fish pretty soon,
I'm not gonna be able
to pay my mortgage.
You know, this whole thing
is really driving me crazy.
It's hard enough
to deal with, uh,
the challenges of
catching these fish.
Never mind having to deal
with all these googans.
Bill: (Bleep).
Dave: Unbelievable.
These guys are still anchored
on our (bleep) numbers.
But whatever.
We can't let it get to us.
The bottom line is that we
got to catch fish before the
storm comes in this weekend.
Paul: Get some bait for the
hooks see if we can catch a
couple here.
This is a good day.
It's nice.
It's dark today.
Perfect.
Sandro: We're on, we're
on, we're on, we're on!
Paul: Yeah.
Start it up!
Get the engine, Dave!
Dave: I'll get the engine!
Paul: We just hooked up.
Nice!
Sandro: (Bleep) tuna.
Good, good, good, good.
Paul: Good job, buddy.
Dave: Ready for a swap?
Sandro: Yeah, go ahead.
Dave: We're hooked
up right now,
but this guy's so (bleep)
close to us, if our
lines hit his lines,
they're gonna
break right away.
There's so much pressure when
you have a 300-pound fish on,
anything can break the line.
Dave: Swivel.
Forward, forward, forward!
Color.
Right here, Paul.
Right here.
Don't miss, Paul.
Got one.
Paul: Yeah.
We got him.
Dave: Yeah, even though
this guy stole our spot,
we hooked up and he didn't.
Yeah, you know we
know what we're doing.
And there's a reason why
we're one of the best.
Paul: You're unreal!
Sandro: Oh, God.
Dave: Hey, you guys think you
can give me a little room?
Paul: That's way too close!
Dave: Go down there a
little bit, come on!
You guys gotta be (bleep) me!
(Bleep) unbelievable.
Paul: He's done.
We just gotta bury the
(bleep) out of him now with
this ice and the buckets.
Dave: Good job, boys.
Dave: Yeah, that's a three,
400 pound fish there, maybe.
That'll bring us between, you
know, three, 4,000 dollars.
Pretty good day.
Paul: He's already
ready to ship now.
Ha, ha, ha.
Dude, he's all done.
Donna: You know,
this is like torture.
I got no fish to work with.
But I see other
guys hooking up.
The boat's got the plague
or something, I don't know.
This'll make you quit
this, right here.
Bill: You'll be fine.
Donna: Yeah?
Don't count on it.
I've about had it
with this (bleep).
Come on fish,
give me a chance!
I'll kill you!
I'll give you a
run for the money.
Bill: She's a
beautiful or what.
Her teeth are grinding.
Donna: Aaah!
I'm so irritated.
Ralph: Hey, Billy.
Are you there?
Bill: Dot Com got
one first thing.
Ralph: Really?
Bill: Yeah, big one.
Ralph: Holy cow.
What the (bleep) he doing?
I can't get a bite over here.
So I get stuck listening
about Tuna.com catching
another fish, and I can't get
a line in the water with all
these (bleep)
googans around here.
It's ridiculous.
(Bleep) Tuna.com.
I can't worry about him.
Have to worry about
catching one myself.
I'll talk to you
later, Billy.
Marciano: Well
here we are today.
We're out on Jeffreys Ledge.
We're about 25 miles from
where we left those guys on
Middle Bank.
Nothing's going on at Middle
Bank because there's nothing
but (bleep) weekend
warriors down there,
making it real hard to fish.
So I decided just to
roll the dice today.
Come up here and do something
I wouldn't normally do.
We're off on our own.
Nobody's followed
us here yet.
We've seen fish before we
even got ready to fishing.
Now I've got a few rods out.
We're waiting for 'em
to come through again.
See if we can get
a rod to bend.
Jay: Bend!
Why?
Come on.
Just please sing to me.
Marciano: What are you doing?
Jay: Waiting.
Marciano: Chum to me.
What's that on your face?
It looks like chum to me.
We have been protecting the
stocks of bluefin tuna in
this country for better
than 20 years, all right?
We've come a long way from
lowest levels ever recorded.
We set limits.
We set boundaries.
We're not like a lot
of other countries,
who don't have
all those limits.
Jay, clean up this
(bleep) mess, too,
(bleep) Christ's sakes.
All right, here
they come, Jay.
They're coming up
from the bottom.
They're racing right up.
Any minute now, that
rod's gonna bend.
Jay: Shark, right here!
Ah yeah, he's
frickin' hauling!
Zipping all around!
Oh, he's big.
We don't want him to
bite the hook or nothing.
We just want him to
get the hell away.
Look at him!
I could touch him!
Those blue sharks
got big mouths.
Marciano: For a brief moment
we got a little excited.
We thought we were on
a, on to a tuna fish.
But it was just a blue shark.
Gonna get some fresh baits
out and see if we can get the
target species,
the bluefin tunas.
Dave: Yeah, we had a problem
with that googan parked right
next to us.
But we friggin' showed them,
and nobody else caught
anything so we're
doing great.
We got a 300
pounder in the back,
but considering it was over
all 300 dollars for fuel,
bait, food, and a
fish back there,
eh, probably 3,000 dollars.
So, it's a pretty good
profitable day, 2,500
dollars in the
pocket, and we had a
good time doing it.
So, I'm happy.
Man: So the tuna gods have
been good to you again, huh?
They've been doing real good
with the price on these,
Dave.
Dave: Have they really?
Man: On these smaller fish.
Dave: Really?
Man: They've been doing
real good with the price.
Dave: Whatever, I'll take it.
Man: Yeah, they've been doing
like 18 dollars a pound.
Dave: Really?
Man: Yeah, for
these little ones.
Dave: Hey, Paul.
Paul: Yeah.
Dave: He said these little
fish have been paying like 18
dollars a pound.
Paul: Really?
All right.
Dave: Double what we said.
That might be four or 5,000.
I'll take that.
Yeah, as it turned out it
was a high quality fish,
and better quality the
meat the higher the value.
It sounds like we may
get between five and
6,000 or something.
That was a good day.
Marciano: So we spent the
night on Jeffreys Ledge,
away from all the dumbass
weekend warriors.
Jay is still down below
getting a little beauty
sleep.
I'm gonna see if I can catch
a tuna while he's down there.
We're gonna roll the
dice one more time,
and see what happens.
Oh, but there's a big fish.
There's a big fish now
marking on the screen.
That's the one we want.
We're scraping the proverbial
bottom of the barrel with
last sexy herring.
Last roll of the
dice right here.
The fish we just
marked was a big fish.
We get that little
puppy to bite, we could,
we're gonna come out
of this day just fine.
Just fine.
OK, let's take a look.
Oh, hey there.
That's like a (bleep) shark.
Ah ha!
All right, now I'm
getting aggravated.
That was my last
(bleep) herring.
You can tell it's a shark
just by the way it's
fighting.
It's real lazy.
Real blah, blah, blah.
(Bleep) shark.
There he goes.
All right.
Well that was just a plain
old-fashioned kick in the
nuts.
Bill: I heard that Dot
Com hooked up yesterday.
Even with a guy parked on the
spot he still managed to get
a bite.
I'm curious to find out if it
had anything to do with his
fishing gear.
Joe: What's up, Billy?
Bill: Hey, Joe.
Joe: What's happening?
Bill: How's it going buddy?
Good.
Hi, Johnny.
Johnny: What's going on?
So you guys making
any money out there?
Bill: We haven't caught any
fish in a couple of weeks,
and we're really not making
any money right now.
And you know, but the time
you give the crew the money
and you pay the expenses,
there's not much left.
Johnny: Right.
Bill: Really isn't.
Joe: Yeah.
Bill: What, what's
Dot Com buying?
Johnny: Joe, I wouldn't
tell 'em too much.
Joe: Yeah.
Bill: Why not?
Johnny: We can't, we can't
tell you because when people
come in to ask what you're
using I don't tell 'em.
Bill: You don't?
Johnny: No.
Absolutely not.
Bill: You're not gonna
tell me anything, then.
Joe: You get nothing.
Bill: I get nothing.
Bill: Tell me the story.
Joe: What?
What story?
There's no stories, Billy.
There's nothing.
Bill: What if we
take you fishing?
Still no story.
Joe: You get nothing.
You get nothing.
Bill: I tried to get some
information from the tackle
store, but they were
completely unhelpful.
Thanks for nothing.
Joe: Yeah.
You're welcome.
Bill: I'll see you later.
Joe: See you.
Dave: We're just getting
here, down to Cape Cod Bay,
there's maybe 20,
25 boats here.
There's gonna be a
lot more after noon,
it's been a late bite, so
this fleet will probably
double in size.
Just looking for a spot to
throw the anchor and get
lines in the water
and sit and wait.
Paul: You could actually get
anywhere by yourself if you
want, on the other side.
Dave: Oh, you want to
drop it right here or
you want to move around?
Paul: We just want a
nice big spot behind us.
Dave: There's gonna be a
million more boats coming,
too.
Where do you wanna go?
Say it now.
Paul: I want to get
away from the boats.
Just go this way a little.
It's so nice being away
from the (bleep) (bleep).
Dave: I got a good
feeling about today.
Paul: Good.
Dave: Nice big fatty.
Paul: Nah, we want
a (bleep) big boy.
Dave: If you want to
catch a world record tuna,
where is it?
Paul: Right here.
Dave: This is the spot.
Paul: This is the spot.
Ralph: Nobody wants to spend
a portion their life on a
boat and not be productive.
We all have families.
We all have bills to pay.
You know, boat insurance.
And, you know, there's so
many things on your mind when
you're sitting
there, you know,
it just manifests to a point
where if you don't gain
control of it, it's
counterproductive.
I want to get nasty
with some tuna fish.
Pirate: Two days solid
fishing, not even a bite.
Ralph: The suffering through
all that (bleep) yesterday,
you would think the man
upstairs would grant us a
fish today.
Oh, marking one.
Fish under the boat, Pirate.
Fish on!
Pirate: I'll take a second.
Ralph: Get the other
line, get the other line!
Pirate: Right now we
got one on the line,
it looks like it's
gonna be a big one.
Ralph: This is what
it's all about.
Ready, Pirate?
Pirate: Yeah.
Ralph: That's it.
I call this dancing
with giants.
He's pulling the boat
backwards right now.
Pirate: And he's doing
a good job of it, too.
He's got head up towards
the bow a little bit now.
Ralph: Nice and
steady, all right?
Don't (bleep) with
his brain too much.
He's coming up,
he's coming up.
Path of least
resistance is up.
That means he's
getting tired.
You need a break?
Pirate: Yeah.
Whoo.
Ralph: Come to papa.
You got a plane
ticket to Japan.
Pirate: As soon as he said
that, I shrugged my head,
don't ever do that.
It's bad karma.
You're gonna jinx yourself.
Ralph: A (bleep) bent rod,
that's what it's all about.
Tight lines and blue gold.
I got a plane ticket
for you, buddy.
Pirate: You want
me to jump back on?
I got it, I got it, I got it.
Should be seeing
color pretty soon.
Ralph: Coming up.
Pirate: I know I
gotcha, I can see.
Ralph: Coming up.
Pirate: Coming
up the elevator.
All of a sudden I see
the line getting closer,
I see the color coming up.
Wow, he's acting
stupid right now.
Oh!
Ralph: It's (bleep) gone!
Pirate: It's just gone!
I don't know what happened.
The line just, it, it
snapped, something.
I don't know.
Ralph: (Bleep) Over the
course of your career,
you know, you know that
they're not dead until
they're in the boat.
Pulled the hook.
Sometimes you just get a
little too cocky, you know?
I mean I was sending that
fish to Japan and he told me,
no, he's not.
He's staying.
And he wound up staying.
I'm miserable.
But it'll go away,
we'll get another one.
Pirate: That guy Dave on
Tuna.com is so lucky.
We're out there struggling,
and he seems to be able to
catch fish every
five minutes.
Dave: Nobody else has
been catching anything.
But I have a feeling
we're gonna score again.
You smell 'em?
Right here.
Paul: Come on, baby.
Make a mistake.
Every single day we go out,
we're looking for multiple
fish, and a nice
quality fish.
And a big fish.
Dave: Oh, man.
My back.
I've got to do it this way.
If I get pulled over, you
guys come and get me?
After you get the fish.
Two there.
Paul: Yeah, two of them.
45 feet.
Everywhere.
They're just wherever the
chum is that's where they
are.
Dave: Yeah, just
zigging and zagging.
Paul: Yeah.
Dave: Still smell 'em.
You guys smell 'em?
Still there.
Holy (bleep)
jumbos right there.
Here we go.
We're on.
Make sure the anchor's
disconnected.
Paul: We're fine.
Dave: Okay.
Let's go.
You can pop.
How's the anchor?
You guys alright
on the anchor?
Paul: We're way away, Dave,
the anchor's (bleep) half a
mile in front of us.
Dave: I'm just checking,
Paul, (bleep) relax.
Forward.
Another 8,000-dollar
fish coming in, baby.
This is what it's all about.
I don't have much more to go.
Good color.
I don't know where Paul is.
We were fighting a fish.
Sandro was the wheelman.
I was on a fish,
and Paul was gone.
I just got to
keep him sliding.
Good color.
You're gonna miss the white.
Paul: Dave!
Dave: What?
Sandro: It's sicko,
he's pooping.
Paul: Yeah, I was taking
a (bleep) on the bucket.
Yeah.
Dave: Hurry up.
I'm gonna have
to, I got color.
The most opportune time
to harpoon the fish,
he's downstairs.
I don't know what
he was doing.
I guess he really had to go.
Paul: I had a bran
muffin and some Wheaties.
So I had to go
to the bathroom.
Dave: You better
pinch that loaf fast.
Paul: Ha, ha.
Ha, ha, ha.
Sandro: Ha, ha,
ha, ha, ha, ha.
Paul: What?
Dave: That's gross!
Sandro: It's gonna cut
right through the poop.
It's gonna cut right
through the poop.
Paul: Aw, you're
touching it right now.
Dave: Oh.
Swivel.
Good color.
Paul, faster!
Bring it around!
Paul: Yeah.
Dave: Go, go, go.
Back, back, back.
Got one.
Good button.
Stay there.
Got neutral,
neutral, neutral.
Get the other gaff.
Other gaff quick.
Paul: Other gaff?
Dave: Quick before he kicks.
Got it.
Paul: Dude, he's got
beautiful shape.
Like the little
fat kid in school.
Come here, you.
He's bigger than we thought.
Dave: That's
(bleep) beautiful.
That's a five,
600-pounder right there.
We're gonna make five, six
grand on that, no problem.
Bill: Ralph.
Can you hear me?
Ralph: Yeah, go ahead.
Bill: Did you hear?
Dot Com hooked up again.
Ralph: Dave's got two?
Ralph: Pretty frustrating to
watch Tuna Dave on the Dot
Com have two fish
this weekend.
And nobody else
is doing anything.
Bill: Tuna.com hooking up
all over the place is really
starting to piss me off.
Ralph: Yeah.
The guy works hard.
We just got to
work harder, Billy.
Dot Com is still finding ways
to catch, so we will too.
Bill: All right.
Ralph: I drive out to a spot
that I've been fishing for
two weeks, and there's some
(bleep) on my numbers.
Pirate: Someone is
sitting on our spot.
Ralph: There's gonna be a
confrontation here right now.
I'm fishing the same set
of numbers for two (bleep)
weeks!
Man: Ralphie, I been
fishing here for a month.
Ralph: (Bleep)!
(Bleep) (bleep)!
(Bleep)!
(Bleep).
Pirate: This is bad.
If you were fishing
in a certain numbers,
you would expect someone else
to respect your numbers.
Ralph: (Bleep) low life,
that's what he is.
Go ahead, put your lines out!
I'm gonna cut 'em all off!
I'm a very vocal guy.
I like to yell and
scream at people.
It's the challenge, it's
the competitiveness,
it's the aggressiveness,
it's the environment.
And when people do that
to me I just lose my mind.
Are you gonna move or
you're not gonna move?
You're not gonna move?
(Bleep).
All right.
Go ahead, put your baits out,
I'll ride right over them.
Pirate: Sometimes we have
some incidents where I think
that the Captain's gonna blow
a head gasket when he gets
that wound up.
Man: Hey, it's time for you
to go back to Georges Bank.
Ralph: I'll see you at
the dock, you (bleep).
Bill: We haven't seen
nothing for a long time.
Scott: You know, it's an
expensive operation to run
that boat.
You know, fuel, bait,
food, slip fees.
These are bills.
These are real time
bills you have to pay.
The stakes are extremely
high for Bill and Donna.
I've heard them say to me,
"If we don't catch some fish,
I'm gonna have to
sell the boat."
Scott: We marking some fish
now at around 100 feet.
Donna has a good
chum slick going.
And I'm gonna put my mackerel
in the middle of it.
Bill: There he is
again, 70 feet.
80 feet.
He ain't leaving.
Donna: We're just praying
that he makes a mistake.
Come on, make a mistake.
Make a mistake.
Bill: Here he comes.
70 feet.
Come on, come back.
Back again.
60 feet.
Come back, come
back, come back.
Oh, right under the boat.
Both screens.
We basically use the
sonar to locate the fish,
and that tells us that
they're under the boat,
and then you have
to go to work.
50 feet.
Big mark.
Oh, real big.
Coming up more.
Coming up higher.
40 feet.
Donna: Come on, you (bleep).
We're on!
Scott: Take the (bleep)
thing, don't look at it.
Holy (bleep), hurry up!
Donna: Bring him up, Scott,
come on, bring him up.
Bring him the (bleep) up.
Yeah, baby, we're on.
Bill: Go get him, Scott.
Hey!
He's hooked up!
Get the hell out of the way!
Donna: And then the
googans show up.
Bill: Watch that, watch that
(bleep) be in the (bleep) way
now.
These other guys that
come now, they just,
they don't know any better.
It's not even respect.
It's they don't
know any better.
Yeah.
We're going right for
his (bleep) anchor.
Donna: Get the (bleep)
out of the way!
Bill: It's a battle.
It's a battle you have to
deal with and it happens all
the time now.
He's (bleep) my line.
Hey!
Meathead!
Bill: They have no etiquette.
They don't care.
They don't know.
I don't know what it is.
Scott: Look where
his line is.
He's in our (bleep) fish.
Bill: He's hooked up!
Get the (bleep)
out of the way!
Scott: Here it comes, Billy.
Get ready with a knife.
Bill: Oh, the (bleep) hook!
You (bleep) (bleep).
This (bleep) guy.
If we get caught in
his (bleep) anchor,
I'm gonna (bleep)
lose my mind.
Bill: Hey!
Go some other (bleep) place.
Scott: You get this (bleep)
googan who parks right next
to you.
Only bad things can happen.
He runs over our line.
The line's gonna break.
And we're gonna lose tens
of thousands of dollars.
Coming up.
Bill: Get the (bleep)
out of the way!
Scott: You know, I'd like
to scream and yell at this
(bleep), and he doesn't think
he's doing anything wrong
because he has no idea.
'Cause he's, he's a googan.
Bill: You gotta try to stop
him from going down there.
Scott: Forget it.
He's gone.
Bill: Huh?
Donna: (Bleep).
The line broke.
Bill: Are you sure?
Scott: Yeah.
Donna: Yeah.
Scott: I saw it pop.
Bill: The main line broke.
The guy's line got
caught in our line,
chafed the main line.
Eventually the line
popped and we lost him.
And then when we pulled
it in to check it,
the main line was chafed.
And I know where
that came from.
There's no if, ands
or buts about it.
So the guy basically cost
us five or 10,000 dollars.
Well, put it on, put it out.
Scott: What happened
to us, you know.
Bill: It's always been a
battle, but today it's worse.
That's worse
than the weather.
It's worse than the fish.
It's worse than the dogfish.
They don't get it.
It's a sad thing.
Scott: What they don't
realize is the effort.
The effort it takes to reel
one of these things in.
To lose it like
that, that hurts.
Bill: If they allowed
guns out here,
there'd be a lot
of dead people.
Ralph: What happened to you?
Broke a main line and
then you broke a hook?
Bill: The googan
guy in the boat,
thought he was hooked up.
He's tugging on the thing,
and pulling my rod around
while I'm fighting the fish.
And I think that it
chafed the main line.
It is what it is, you know.
It's how my year
has been going.
Ralph: Yeah, it's just you're
on the you're on the bottom
of the turn,
Billy, that's all.
You'll be back on top again.
Takes a while to get
around the curve.
Bill: Yeah, I know.
Ralph: How many times in your
career do you hit the bottom?
Couple.
Bill: Oh, yeah.
And that's the way it
is, buddy, thank you.
Not much I can do about
it, you know what I mean?
Even when I get the
bite, I don't get 'em.
All I know is if I lose a
fish on a googan again today,
ah, I'm going to jail.
Ralph: All right.
Wish 'em up.
Let's go.
Bend the rod.
Marciano: We're wrapping
it up here for the day.
Buh-dee-buh-dee-buh-dee,
that's all folks.
We didn't get nothing today.
You know?
And I tried a little
something different,
I came out here,
we came a long way.
We spent probably close to
200 dollars on fuel today.
Maybe threw another 100 bucks
worth of bait over the side.
And now we came up
empty, you know?
So that's another 300
bucks onto our total.
But it was important that
I try this, you know?
I know Bounty Hunter
didn't get any.
And I know Ralph:
didn't get any today.
But I think it
was a good gamble.
We blew 300 bucks
on a recon trip.
I'm not thrilled with that.
But I'm okay with that.
Dave: You know, we hooked up
and we had a bunch of other
fish under the boat.
Paul: Marking like
a whore right now.
Dave: Sometimes
you could hook two,
you could hook three.
Yeah, you could make 15,000
dollars, boom, boom, boom,
but you really gotta keep
your (bleep) together.
Paul: If you don't pay
attention and you get back on
'em right now.
Dave: Day's over.
Paul: we'll lose him and then
that's it, for the day.
If you don't (bleep)
hustle your balls off,
you're not gonna
catch another one.
Sandro: Watch how
quick we hook up again.
Speed, speed.
Paul: A lot of whole herring
in the water I'm throwing.
Dave: Okay.
Paul: Here he comes, baby.
Here he comes, two of 'em.
60 feet!
70 feet!
Bang!
Dave: Sandro, keep throwing.
You keep doing
your job, buddy.
Paul: Three of 'em!
Whoo!
Dave: Come on, eat
it right there.
I dare you.
Got direct sunlight going
all across the lines,
the glare right off the
line, they see everything.
These fish aren't 1,000
pounds 'cause they're stupid.
They've been
around the block.
They'll come up, look at a
bait and in the last two or
three feet, they'll
just turn away.
Sandro: Oh, they're big boys.
Paul: Was it big?
Was it really?
Sandro: Oh, yeah.
Paul: Yes, (bleep).
Dave: There he is.
We got him.
Throw it up.
Paul: Go, baby.
Dave: Go, go, go.
Paul: Oh, yeah, let's
go forward there.
Paul: Hold on, you're
good, you're good.
He's going around here.
He's pissed.
Dave: We're on.
Again.
Forward, left.
Forward left fast.
Fast, go!
The other way, all
right, all right.
That a way.
Paul: We're on.
Yeah, let him, let
him do his thing.
Hopefully we'll get to
use this right here.
You never can tell.
Sandro: Anything can happen.
Not just (bleep).
Paul: Yeah.
Actually, the first
one, (bleep) happened.
Sandro: Yeah,
(bleep) has happened.
Dave: Very close.
Neutral!
Gonna get a shot.
Forward, forward.
Reverse, reverse,
hard reverse.
Neutral.
Good job, good job, good job.
Paul: Keep going, keep going.
Dave: Do the.
Paul: Turn him.
Dave: You're okay.
Paul: Alright.
Dave: Hard reverse,
hard reverse.
Paul: Go forward.
Dave: Don't miss!
Paul: Oh, I (bleep) missed!
Dave: You gotta
be (bleep) me.
Paul: Can't throw at
the mono or I'll cut it.
Dave: Forward, forward,
come on, forward Right.
Forward right, Sandro!
Come on!
Sandro: (Bleep) bring
the wheel around, Dave.
Easy.
Relax.
Paul: Take it easy.
Dave: Get ready
to throw here.
Same as before.
Paul: Go forward, Sandro.
Now back up.
Got him!
Right in the back!
Dave: Go!
Forward, forward!
Paul: The (bleep) fish
was like forty feet away.
I (bleep) launched
it and nailed him!
Phoosh!
Paul: Got him
right in the back!
That's good, that's good.
You did good, Sandro.
Dave: Yeah, you did well.
Got one.
There we go.
Go ahead.
That was the best feeling
in the world there,
catching two big slobs.
That's a lot of fish.
Paul: He is big (bleep), huh?
Dave: Mm-hmm.
Yeah, this fish is gonna
weigh between eight,
900 pounds.
We get nine grand
for this fish.
Thank you for the paycheck.
Paul: Aren't they so
(bleep) beautiful though?
Look how gorgeous they are.
Dave: Amazing.
I studied fluid dynamics, and
if you look at this fish,
and look at a raindrop
falling out of the sky,
they'd look exactly alike.
Perfectly hydro-dynamically
designed.
Even the eyeball is
perfectly smooth.
Nothing.
Not a bump, nothing.
Second fastest
fish in the world.
Put him to bed.
Paul: The boat's
got a big fish hole.
This one was way too
big to put down there,
so we left it on
top of the deck.
It was like over
11 feet long.
So what we did, we had
this big packing bag,
that's what they ship
the tunas to Japan in,
in the coffin.
Just (bleep) burrito
him, and fill 'em.
Done.
We pack it with ice.
Oh, yeah.
(Bleep) ice cubes coming
out of his mouth, dude.
Dave: See 'ya.
Paul: Ha ha.
All right!
Yeah.
Dave: Yeah, bitch.
Ralph: You know nobody likes
to go fishing everyday and
not catch anything, you know?
You know, mates get on
the boat to make money.
If they don't make money,
they don't get paid and
they're not happy.
Captain's not happy 'cause
I keep dishing out a couple
hundred dollars to leave
the dock every day.
It was a good day on the
bite category but bad on the
killing category.
We didn't kill anything.
Tomorrow may be another day.
Maybe we'll get him tomorrow.
Maybe not.
You never know how these
losing streaks go.
Bill: Lowman bridge
Bounty Hunter.
Man: Come back.
Bill: Good afternoon
captain, Bounty Hunter,
on the harbor side,
whenever you get a chance.
Thank you very much.
We didn't catch (bleep).
We lost a giant to a googan.
And Tuna.com caught everyone
that swam by his boat.
All I want is for
somebody to beat that guy,
and I don't even
care if it's me.
Dave: Where do you want it?
Yeah, I'm getting ready to
meet with the buyers right
now.
We got two jumbos on
the boat, and I'm just,
I'm excited to see
how much they weigh.
Man: Good, here we go.
Up we go.
Dave, I think you're
gonna wear out my winch,
keep pulling in
all these big ones.
Yeah, look at the
strain on that.
That's when you
know it's a fat one.
Uh-oh.
You might have to
take the head off.
Oh no.
That's as high
as she goes up.
Paul: Yeah, just
bring him down,
I'll cut it right there.
Man: Yeah, Yeah.
Dave: That's a
pretty fish, though.
Get one with me
and Paul up there.
Paul: Get us right in there.
Sandro: Yep.
Paul: Pull that fin down.
Will it come out?
Yeah.
Dave: This is probably a
10, 12, 13,000-dollar day.
So, yeah, awesome day.
Doesn't get any
better than that.
Paul: Yeah.
Wait 'til you see
the ones I got.
Dave: I mean we fished
fishing close again.
Expenses are
absolutely nothing.
Two or three hundred
dollars a day at best.
Do you know how much money
we're gonna make this year?
A lot.