Yo, what up?
This is Nas, and this is like a
crazy party, a crazy thing I
remember from back
in the days.
I used to live in the projects,
and we were always
trying to throw parties
in the neighborhood.
Usually a girl whose parents
were out of town, that was
always the place.
We were throwing one party
one night for some girl.
We had the speakers, drinks,
no lights on, sweaty.
There'd be a party going on.
This older guy we know who's
known as the brawler, he's
just looking for a fight,
drinking beer all the time.
The brawler is a little drunk,
and he does something that
pisses the girl off, and they
get into an argument.
Next thing you know, we see
him dragging her sofa out.
And they can't really
stop him.
He's moving stuff and knocking
shit over, pulling out tables
and chairs, and things
off the wall.
And we're kind of in the
corner like why?
Why is this happening?
It's like, people are
holding her back.
She's acting like she
wants to attack him.
So next thing you know, the
girl's entire apartment is
sitting out in the hallway.
He's got this little smirk on
his face, and the girl is
going crazy.
She just grabs a chair and
clocks the brawler.
We got a few laughs.
She never threw a party
out there again.
Actually, I think she
moved after that.
And that was some crazy ass
shit from back in the days
around the way.