[CHATTERING]
DIRECTOR (OFFSCREEN):
[INAUDIBLE]
[STARTING PITCHES GIVEN
BY KEYBOARD]
[MUSIC - "SI HEI LWLI MABI"]
INTERVIEWER (OFFSCREEN): How
old were you when started
taking drugs?
AMY PROTHEROE (OFFSCREEN): When
I first started taking
dope and Valium and things
like that, I was 12.
CORNELIUS COLLINS (OFFSCREEN):
I was 11 when I started
smoking dope, then Valium
and eggs and speed.
AMY PROTHEROE (OFFSCREEN):
When I started taking
heroin I was 14.
My mother started
giving it to me.
CORNELIUS COLLINS (OFFSCREEN): I
was 15 when I started taking
heroin and crack.
I was dealing by the time
I was 16 with my father.
AMY PROTHEROE (OFFSCREEN): I
was homeless when I was 12.
And when I was 14, I went back
to live with my mother, and
within three months of going
back to my mother, I was
taking heroin.
She sent me to work in a
parlour-- do you know a
massage parlour--
when I was 14, wasn't it?
CORNELIUS COLLINS (OFFSCREEN):
It was not a parlour.
It was a fucking whore house,
not a massage parlour.
AMY PROTHEROE (OFFSCREEN):
Yeah.
When I was 14, she sent me
to work in one of them.
CORNELIUS COLLINS (OFFSCREEN):
That's the posh word
for them, isn't it?
AMY PROTHEROE (OFFSCREEN): And
all the money that I was
earning, I was giving to
her and her boyfriend.
CORNELIUS COLLINS (OFFSCREEN):
That's because people like us
grow up with parents who are
selling drugs and doing drugs,
you learn where you live.
AMY PROTHEROE (OFFSCREEN):
You end up copying.
CORNELIUS COLLINS (OFFSCREEN):
Right.
You end up kind of doing what
your parents did, because you
think that's what's the norm.
That's what normality
is to you.
AMY PROTHEROE: Oh, oh.
Amy Protheroe loves Cornelius
Collins forever, 2008.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: It's just a
little reminder to the world
that she loves me.
AMY PROTHEROE: He's my baby.
I loves him.
We've been together nearly
four years, haven't we?
CORNELIUS COLLINS: Yeah.
Well, three years, 9 months.
AMY PROTHEROE: I lied about my
age when I got with him.
I told him I was 16.
I was only 15.
I wrote that.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: She did
it when I was in jail.
INTERVIEWER (OFFSCREEN): 2008,
October last year.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: Yeah.
AMY PROTHEROE: I was
on suicide watch.
24/7, they made sure someone
was with me all the time,
because I was depressed.
I used to sleep with his red Gap
jumper and cuddle into it.
I never washed it.
I'd smell him, yeah?
CORNELIUS COLLINS: Don't--
hey.
AMY PROTHEROE: But we've had
some hard times, haven't we?
We've had a lot of trouble.
We recently lost a baby.
Didn't we, Corneil?
We recently lost our baby.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: Sort me
out with a glug of that.
AMY PROTHEROE: Didn't we?
CORNELIUS COLLINS: Let's talk
about better things, Amy.
AMY PROTHEROE: No, wait.
But I'm explaining, that's how
we went downhill so rapidly.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: Well,
whatever, innit.
AMY PROTHEROE: I was eight and
a half months pregnant.
My baby was born stillborn.
I had a little boy.
And after that happened, we just
started drinking really
heavily, didn't we, babes?
Because we never
used to drink.
You hated drinking,
didn't you?
CORNELIUS COLLINS: Yep.
I did.
AMY PROTHEROE: We started off
drinking a little bit, and
then when the baby died, that
was it, our heads went.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: Give us a
glug on that, babes, please.
AMY PROTHEROE: I don't
want to, shove off.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: No, man.
Oh, this one's fucking dirty.
[INAUDIBLE].
ANDREW WILLIAMSON: Lighter?
The lighter?
Where's that filter?
You're a dozy fucker.
Lighter.
It's like talking to
the fucking wall
with you lot, man.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: Haven't
got a lighter.
ANDREW WILLIAMSON: Amy, have
you got a lighter?
[WHISTLES]
ANDREW WILLIAMSON: Yeah, that's
nice as fuck, that is.
Lovely gear, that is.
[WHISTLES]
ANDREW WILLIAMSON (OFFSCREEN):
I wish I'd said
this when I was sober.
I'm having to maintain myself on
a seriously addictive drug.
Just make sure you
wait for me.
I'll come into town
with you, innit?
CORNELIUS COLLINS: We'll
meet you round the
back of the YM, yeah?
DEREK JAMES: I heard a
definition many years ago
about the difference a North
Walian and a South Walian.
And the difference was between
belt and braces.
The South Walian always wore
a belt slung under his beer
belly, and was a roistering,
boisterous taffy.
Whereas a North Walian always
wore braces and hunched them
forward as if he were forever
plodding uphill.
Most of the coal that was mined
in the Swansea area and
up the Swansea Valley
was used in Swansea
for the metal refining.
Swansea was then, at one time,
the major metal refining
center for the entire world.
That's an example from the old
days, when children were
underground.
And it was only about 1840- odd
that they raised the age
of children working
underground to 12.
But no, Mrs. Thatcher
shut the lot down.
It's awful when you think that
the amount of skill and the
amount of knowledge that was
here, the knowledge base that
they had, and it all
just withered away.
Employment after the heavy
industry went as not good.
There was a short period in the
'60s when there was quite
a lot of work around.
But that declined all through
the '70s and the '80s, until
the late '90s.
Yeah, that's played a part in
the present drug problem, I
think, in Swansea, and
the alcoholism.
Of course, the system under
which we live--
the capitalist system--
is so competitive.
And it's a continual stress
on the individual.
And younger people, I feel, who
can't get into the stream
and compete and can't get
work just lose heart.
And then they descend into a
drug culture, which is almost
a subculture now.
DANIELLE GRAY: (SINGING)
Swansea, oh
Swansea, Swansea City.
Living on the lamppost
until the day I die.
(SPEAKING) Something like
that, isn't it?
JOSIE: My name's Josie.
DANIELLE GRAY: My name
is Danielle Gray
and I'm from Swansea.
We're stepsisters.
JOSIE: We're stepsisters.
DANIELLE GRAY: That we are.
INTERVIEWER (OFFSCREEN):
Stepsisters.
DANIELLE GRAY: There's 12
of us all together.
INTERVIEWER (OFFSCREEN):
Right.
DANIELLE GRAY: There's me,
Rachel, Ciaran, Becca, Teagan,
Gemma, Emma, then it's Ryan,
Reagan, Brandon,
and Timmy and Teagan.
And my daughter's named
Courtney-Lee--
28th of the fifth--
it's a bit faded
at the moment.
JOSIE: "Dad", I put there.
DANIELLE GRAY: They're prison
tattoos, they are.
JOSIE: I got "Mum" there.
DANIELLE GRAY: You've
got her ex-missus
named Leanne up there.
That's fucked it off.
JOSIE: Fucked off.
My ex-girlfriend's name there.
I've got my ex-boyfriend's
name--
DANIELLE GRAY: On that
side, isn't it?
Yeah, Mark.
I got a daughter.
She's three years old now.
And if you look there, I got a
Cesarean, from there to there.
I sees her every Tuesday between
10:00 and 12:00.
She's brilliant.
She goes, Mummy, Dani,
where's my daddy?
I goes, working away.
But he was in prison.
He came out the other day.
No, she doesn't want to
see him and that.
Two days ago, my mother was a
bit drunk, and she hit me.
I hit her back.
And she bit my nose from
there to there.
INTERVIEWER (OFFSCREEN): What
happened to your face there?
JOSIE: Oh, I was jumped
by two girls, I was.
INTERVIEWER (OFFSCREEN):
Right.
In Swansea?
DANIELLE GRAY: Yeah.
It's gone down.
Rough area.
JOSIE: Rough, yeah.
DANIELLE GRAY: Real
rough area.
INTERVIEWER (OFFSCREEN): Why?
JOSIE: Because of the drugs.
DANIELLE GRAY: But now you've
got kids at ages 12 and 13--
JOSIE: Taking heroin.
DANIELLE GRAY: They're
taking heroin.
JOSIE: There's dealers
selling it to them--
DANIELLE GRAY: Exactly.
JOSIE: And they don't really
care about them, as long as
they get their money.
DANIELLE GRAY: They won't care
if a 12-year-old or an 11
goes, oh, have you got
a bag and that?
Oh, yeah, have you
got a tenner?
Yeah, here's a bag and that.
Do you know what I mean?
JOSIE: They just don't care.
DANIELLE GRAY: No.
They should have more respect.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: Right, you've
got SANDS, which is for
over-18s, and Sandpit, down in
Nash House, for under-18s.
This is a drug agency.
They offer counseling.
They can help you get on
opiate prescribing--
methadone, Subutex, Suboxone
Needle exchange.
They do a men's day on a
Wednesday, when you go in and
have some toast and tea, and
just have a chat with all the
boys in there.
JOHN FRITH: Thanks, Lynn.
Is everybody here?
This is another counseling
room, which we'd
call a family room.
First point of call would
normally be the needle
exchange, where we'd
first engage with--
INTERVIEWER (OFFSCREEN):
Why's that?
JOHN FRITH: A lot of them would
actually come here and
be asking for clean needles.
And so we've got the
cookers, then.
This is the most popular
type of needle.
So this is a 1 mil syringe.
You hear about people drawing
up water from puddles.
We have got water ampules as
well, which you can put in the
cooker and mix with
the heroin.
People will still use whether
we were here or not.
Where there's a way,
they'll find a way.
You can actually inject into
your anus, where there's lots
of blood vessels close
to the surface.
People are beginning to
inject crack now.
Most people are still
actually smoking it.
ANDREW WILLIAMSON: This is how
complicated it is to get
drugs, but this is
to get crack.
Basically, I've got
to get there.
I'll ring him on the way--
say I'm in a taxi.
I meet him by a certain shop.
Hello?
Yeah?
Righto.
No, I will.
I will comply.
At 11:30.
And what's the time now?
Righto.
Right.
OK.
OK, I'll be there at 11:30.
[INAUDIBLE].
My drug worker, that was.
I got a phone call about my
medication, because I'm banned
from the building, due
to an incident.
I've got to meet the lady
outside there at half past 11.
And she'll go through
things with me.
And it's involving my methadone
prescription, it is.
I'm on my way up in a taxi
now, mate, yeah?
I've got to be back by the
YMCA at ha;f past 11.
So, step on it, driver, as
they say in the films.
Yeah, I take crack
recreationally.
It's not something I make
a habit of doing.
It's not physically addictive,
so it's--
INTERVIEWER (OFFSCREEN):
You don't think so?
ANDREW WILLIAMSON: Well,
textbook, it's
not physically addictive.
I have come off it before.
And I have vomited blood.
I drank 60 mil of methadone.
And then an hour later, I
injected 2 mil of Subutex.
And I tell you what, it was one
of the worst cold turkeys
I've ever been through
in my entire life.
Any users who watch this
program, never ever do that.
I don't want to be vulgar,
yeah, but you could have
fitted a watermelon up my
asshole, that's how disg--
it came out of me like piss.
And I laid on my bed with my
eyes like 50 pence pieces--
the old 50 pence pieces.
I'm there now, yeah.
INTERVIEWER (OFFSCREEN):
You all right?
ANDREW WILLIAMSON: Yeah,
safe, sorted.
INTERVIEWER (OFFSCREEN): Good.
ANDREW WILLIAMSON:
That's the crack.
Kim, it's Andrew, it is.
Right, love, I'm going to be
about 10 minutes later, is
that all right?
Yeah, I know, I know.
But I've got to pick up a
counter payment from the job
center, see?
Yeah, no.
This won't happen again.
This is a one off.
Yeah, I know, love,
but please.
I promise you I'll be 10
minutes, at the most, late.
Yeah, no.
I didn't realize I was going to
get a phone call saying to
be at the job center.
I got a phone call after
I spoke to you,
you know what I mean?
I didn't realize this
was going to happen.
OK, my love, I'll be there.
OK, thanks.
Bye.
ooh.
She weren't happy.
She bought it.
Oh, Jesus.
Christ.
Ah, Shit.
I haven't got a lighter.
Fucking Frank [INAUDIBLE].
Right, this is the wire wool.
You've got to burn this first to
get the toxicity out of it.
[ACCOMPANIST PLAYS CHOIR'S
BEGINNING PITCHES OFFSCREEN]
[DUNVANT MALE VOICE CHOIR
SINGING "SI HEI LWLI MADI"]
ANDREW WILLIAMSON: The good
thing about a glass pipe is
residue collects, and you
can clean it out.
And what you clean out is better
than what you smoked
the first time round.
One more pipe, boys,
and we're away.
Fuck it.
Aw, I left your lighter,
didn't I?
Ah, for fuck's sake.
If it was better stuff, I'd
still be rushing my tits off,
you know what I mean?
I'd still be--
[PANTING]
[WHISTLES]
[DEEP EXHALATION]
ANDREW WILLIAMSON: It's a bit
of a double-edged sword, me
arriving late.
She might have someone--
I was wondering, they might have
someone waiting there to
maybe arrest me for the theft
of the magazines.
Ah, come on, mate.
Please.
Get out of the fucking way.
Oh my god, what's
this traffic?
It's driving me nuts.
Well, mate, I'm going to
get out and run, yeah?
LEE DENNIS: Well, we've known
each other years.
I mean, we always used to bump
into each other and talk.
RACHEL REES: We used to have
a nice chat, didn't we?
LEE DENNIS: I mean, she's
a tidy girl, like.
RACHEL REES: My ex was giving
me a few hidings here and
there, like.
Dennis is there.
Have a chat with Dennis-- this,
that, and the other.
Tidy guy.
And that's how we
clicked, really.
LEE DENNIS: I mean, I've
always had a little
soft spot for her.
RACHEL REES: We'll see how it
goes from here now, isn't it?
LEE DENNIS: Yeah.
RACHEL REES: Just take it day by
day and help each other out
as much as we can.
Yeah?
LEE DENNIS: February 27,
I got out of jail.
But when I moved in here,
it was stinking.
This is my bedroom.
I'm gonna put my
bed down here.
Put the bed down here--
I got my bedside cabinet--
and lay the carpet and put my
wardrobes down here and my
chest of drawers behind
the door.
RACHEL REES: You can't put
it in your ear, can he?
LEE DENNIS: It's all
right like that.
That's my first ever Swansea
City tattoo--
the proudest ever.
I've been to a few prisons, as
well, and I always wear it
with pride, always walk around
with my top off.
And I want to get clean.
I'm starting treatment now on
the 26th of this month.
Because I tattooed myself in
jail, I had test results done.
I had a letter then from
the nurse, saying come
down and see me.
I need to see you urgently.
And when I went down, she says,
I'm very sorry, but you
have got hep C. I'm gonna
try a cupboard, put a
cupboard up on here.
I'm gonna paint the ceiling.
I'm gonna paint that.
It'll probably be tomorrow.
And look, there's
bits of blood.
When you're cooking up
and that, you draw
the blood into yourself.
And when you draw so much in,
there's a little bit of blood
left in, and they
just squirt it.
There was some on
here as well.
I put a bit on there.
My stereo's in my mum's it is.
INTERVIEWER (OFFSCREEN): Why?
What kind of music
do you like?
LEE DENNIS: I like all different
types of music.
I got loads of music here.
R&B, Garage, R&B, Fleetwood
Mac Seven Wonders--
if I live to see the
Seven Wonders.
RACHEL REES: There
was an abscess.
I had to go in for an operation
on that, because I
missed there.
You know, basically, my
veins are kaput now.
That's going into
another abscess.
That one's not too bad.
If I wasn't on the heroin, I'd
cry my eyes out for my kids
now, you know?
Don't get me wrong, I love
them all to bits, but you
know, I can't really see them
while I'm in this predicament.
LEE DENNIS: This is gonna
go up in my bedroom.
RACHEL REES: Other
way round, babes.
LEE DENNIS: Is that all right?
RACHEL REES: The other
way, babes.
LEE DENNIS: (SINGING) When I was
just a little boy, I asked
my mother, what shall I be?
Shall I be Swansea?
Shall I be scum?
This is what she said to me.
Take your father's gun, and
shoot the Cardiff scum.
Forever will be, my son.
You'll always be Swansea.
Who are we?
Jack Army!
LEE ANDERSON: Lee Anderson, in
Swansea, like, in a shared
flat, with smackheads,
down and outs.
CLINT RYAN JONES: Aye.
All right?
This is Clint, the old
famous Clinty.
This is a friend's bedsit,
as they call it.
He said I could stay here for a
couple of days, so I've made
myself a room.
[FARTING]
LEE ANDERSON: Oh, had to
come out, didn't it?
CLINT RYAN JONES: I started a
program now with methadone.
It's done me a world of good.
For some people, it'll
make them worse.
And then they have a
heroin habit on top
of a methadone habit.
LEE ANDERSON: It's people
like Clint are stupid.
They think it's the answer.
But it's not.
INTERVIEWER (OFFSCREEN):
You disagree with him?
CLINT RYAN JONES: It's going
again in a minute.
[FARTING]
CLINT RYAN JONES: Right.
Better out than in, isn't it?
You know what I mean?
Because I went off the heroin,
and when I get to that point
when it's making me better, I'll
stop using heroin, and
then eventually, in a couple of
months, gradually come off
the methadone.
And I'll be a brand new, squeaky
clean person again.
LEE ANDERSON: With
rotten teeth.
KRISTIAN EVANS: I've been on
it since I can remember--
14, which is the best
part of my life.
CLINT RYAN JONES: Anyway,
I'm just doing about
my day to day thing.
Come on, let's go down
the shop now.
KRISTIAN EVANS: Is it?
LEE ANDERSON (OFFSCREEN):
Come along if you want.
KRISTIAN EVANS: Hm?
Well, if it's all about him--
he's a fucking idiot.
CLINT RYAN JONES: Before I had
the bedsit, this is where we
used to go up to have a dig.
"Dig up" means inject your
heroin and what have you.
Bish, bash, bosh.
LEE ANDERSON: Look,
there's pin tops.
Look, there, where
he's standing.
CLINT RYAN JONES: This is where
we used to go for a
pipe, down here.
This is where we used to go.
LEE ANDERSON: We started--
we get the needles from there.
KRISTIAN EVANS: It's
our fault why the
needles are down there.
LEE ANDERSON: Yeah.
People should clean up.
KRISTIAN EVANS: They
give us things--
CLINT RYAN JONES: Hang on, let
me put this camera right now.
Hang on.
It's not our fault the needles
are down there.
We clean up what
we used to use.
KRISTIAN EVANS: Yeah, yeah.
CLINT RYAN JONES: Months ago,
when I used to come here, I
always used to take my doings
with me and put them in the
same bin and take them back
to the drug project.
The dirty smackheads that are
around that leave needles
about then and what have you--
we are the clean smackheads,
the user.
We are users, not smackheads.
Whoa, watch you don't sit on
any fucking needles, mate.
KRISTIAN EVANS: I would have
thought the heroin
consumption--
considering that 90% of heroin
comes from Afghanistan, how
much has come into the country,
considering a our
British troops--
CLINT RYAN JONES: But it's
not all about fucking
Afghanistan, really.
Why are we using it, you know?
KRISTIAN EVANS: Yes, I know.
But the documentary's
about how there's
been such an increase.
CLINT RYAN JONES: Yeah, but
they want to know about
Swansea and things--
why are we using it so much?
And basically, at the
end of the day--
KRISTIAN EVANS: Well, I wasn't
talking about that.
CLINT RYAN JONES: Why?
Because there's boredom.
KRISTIAN EVANS: I think that
a lot of heroin addicts are
using the actual, "oh, I'm
addicted to heroin" to get
away with the way that they're
looking, the way that they
talk to people, and the
actual way that
they live their lifestyle.
I like to think that I've
proven them all wrong.
I've been a heroin addict since
I was 18 years of age,
which is nearly 10 years.
Yeah, I'm well known around town
for shoplifting to fund
for my habit.
But fingers crossed, that if
someone walked past me in the
street, they wouldn't
think that I was a
dodgy-looking bastard--
excuse my French--
and consider me to look like a
typical smackhead like you see
off Trainspotting, you know?
I can't see any reason why I
can't turn my life around.
LEE ANDERSON: [INAUDIBLE].
[INAUDIBLE].
CLINT RYAN JONES: OK, we
having a dig, are we?
MAN (OFFSCREEN): Yeah.
CLINT RYAN JONES: Positive
mental attitude, as I put
underneath.
You know, I wake up in the bed
in the morning, and I thought,
I see the sign that's
on the wall.
So I look and I think, right.
PMA, PMA--
Positive Mental Attitude.
So, at the end of the day,
positive mental attitude.
Right, what am I going
to do today?
Straight to the chemist--
they'll have my methadone--
positive mental attitude.
There's one.
Number two, go and score
a fucking bag.
Positive mental attitude,
yeah?
My spelling's not too
good, though.
Sorry.
I just want to be part of my
kids and my ex-wife, you know?
I just want the chance
to be a daddy, yeah?
I love my babies.
I said to myself, PMA.
I'm going to stop using any type
of drug before I get in
touch with my children ever
again, because it wouldn't be
fair on my children if I
was to go, oh, that's
my daddy, that is.
Ah, but your daddy's a junkie.
CORNELIUS COLLINS (OFFSCREEN):
My old man's never been on the
streets, homeless.
He's just been a junkie and a
drug dealer most of his life,
and a burglar, and in
and out of jail.
He's not selling drugs at the
moment or committing crime,
but he's still using drugs.
SEAN COLLINS: Please
don't litter or
urinate on the stairs.
They want to put with that "or
use needles." That's for them
to have a boot, smoke the heroin
on the foil That's
probably two days,
between three.
INTERVIEWER (OFFSCREEN): So how
many do you drink a day?
SEAN COLLINS: About 12 each.
About 12 each, yeah.
Come on.
Come on, Celine.
LIBBY COLLINS (OFFSCREEN): No,
you can't have a joint.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Of course we can.
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah, you can.
LIBBY COLLINS (OFFSCREEN):
Where's my can, then?
Hang on, let me have a can.
CARLO: Can you just get one
between me and you?
LIBBY COLLINS: Why?
Dad.
SEAN COLLINS (OFFSCREEN):
I put it on top of
there, right by you.
LIBBY COLLINS: Four cans, Dad!
CORNELIUS COLLINS:
Yeah, no, it is.
Sorry, I've picked yours up.
LIBBY COLLINS: Dad, come here.
Dad, just come here a sec.
It's in your hand.
SEAN COLLINS: It's not.
I just opened it.
LIBBY COLLINS: Yeah, and you've
got one in the fridge.
Come here.
SEAN COLLINS: No, I haven't.
LIBBY COLLINS: Yes, you have.
That one in the fridge
is yours, Daddy.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: That's Carlo,
my sister's boyfriend.
This is my sister, Libby.
LIBBY COLLINS: Hi.
CORNELIUS COLLINS (OFFSCREEN):
My old man, Sean.
Dad's mate, Darren.
And my missus, Amy, who
you've met already.
CARLO: Well, I've known her for
years, but we recently got
to meet on the streets, yeah?
LIBBY COLLINS: Yeah, we
met drinking in town.
CARLO: In town.
Drinking in town.
INTERVIEWER (OFFSCREEN):
In the last four years,
everyone's said there's been a
lot more heroin in Swansea.
Is that true?
LIBBY COLLINS: Oh, yeah.
SEAN COLLINS: Lots of it.
You've got to go back
from the '60s.
You've got to take it from
the '60s, really.
You could do chemists,
and it'd be amazing.
You know, it's be wooden--
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Morphine and--
SEAN COLLINS: Shut up.
Shh.
Shut up.
LIBBY COLLINS (OFFSCREEN):
People of these days, they're
just growing up--
CARLO (OFFSCREEN): They're
growing up around it.
Yeah.
LIBBY COLLINS (OFFSCREEN):
Everybody's doing gear,
because everybody's doing it.
You know, people just don't care
now, because their mother
or their father or their
brother or their
cousin is doing it.
They're all doing it.
SEAN COLLINS: It don't make no
difference about your mother
or your father--
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Of course it do.
SEAN COLLINS: It's about you.
It's about you.
It's your brain.
LIBBY COLLINS (OFFSCREEN):
Look at kids now.
10, 20 years ago, it
was different.
Look at them now.
SEAN COLLINS: And yet my--
LIBBY COLLINS (OFFSCREEN):
[INAUDIBLE]
No, hang on.
I'm not saying it's the parents'
responsibility.
What I'm saying is, if you're
round people doing it.
If your mother and your father,
your aunt and your
uncle, or anybody that's around
you 24/7 is on heroin,
obviously, you're going
to take it.
I'm not blaming you
or Mammy, Dad.
I'm just saying, I got sucked
into the wrong circle.
DARREN: [INAUDIBLE].
SEAN COLLINS: Right.
Hang on, now.
How did you get sucked
into it?
I never used in front of you.
Your mother never used
in front of you.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: Right.
As a kid, I did catch you dosed
up on the toilet with
the works in your arms.
Shit like that.
Yeah?
SEAN COLLINS: Yeah.
CORNELIUS COLLINS:
Right, started
smoking fags and drinking.
Then I went to smoking dope.
Then I went to smoking
dope with you.
Seeing you smoking dope once
I'd started smoking dope.
But that's part of
it, isn't it?
Drink and drugs.
That's the circle you're in.
LIBBY COLLINS (OFFSCREEN): He
shouldn't have been should he?
CORNELIUS COLLINS: Not now,
I've got an abscess.
SEAN COLLINS: I know.
I've never laid a
finger on him.
I think once I hit
you, didn't I?
One time.
LIBBY COLLINS (OFFSCREEN):
Don't get into this now.
Speak to these questions.
SEAN COLLINS: And that
was in another house.
AMY PROTHEROE: How long was
you homeless for, Carlo?
CARLO: I'm lucky
at the moment.
I've got a girlfriend with
a flat at the moment.
So god knows what's gonna happen
if she kicks me out.
LIBBY COLLINS: Well, if you were
a bit nicer, you wouldn't
be worrying, would you, love?
CORNELIUS COLLINS: How many
times have you been into detox
and rehab and whatever?
SEAN COLLINS: Detox.
I've been to detox about--
CORNELIUS COLLINS:
10, 12 times?
SEAN COLLINS: 10, 12 times.
I didn't stay that long.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: My mother
and father split up--
AMY PROTHEROE: Ask if his
mother got clean.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: When I 13.
My mother got clean.
I stayed with Dad.
[INAUDIBLE].
SEAN COLLINS: Not my
fault, I said.
Look at her, sticking
her oar in.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: In and out
of detox, rehab, whatever.
LIBBY COLLINS (OFFSCREEN): Mammy
and Daddy fought fucking
and got clean for 8 weeks.
SEAN COLLINS: It'll be
like Jeremy Kyle now.
CORNELIUS COLLINS:
I just pissed a
whole day on that one.
SEAN COLLINS: Let me tell
you something now.
She's one bitch.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: Ah, Dad,
give it up now, will you?
Don't speak about
her like that.
It's not nice.
SEAN COLLINS: All right,
she's not a bitch.
I didn't mean to insult
dogs, sorry.
AMY PROTHEROE: It's
a long story.
SEAN COLLINS: No, it's not.
It's a short story.
If I have a minute with my son,
Amy seems to think that
that little bit of love in that
minute, she's losing.
She won't allow us about
five minutes together.
AMY PROTHEROE: You're the
same, though, Sean.
SEAN COLLINS: Quiet.
Hurry up, because you've got
one minute now, right?
[MUSIC - DUNVANT MALE
VOICE CHOIR SINGING]
SEAN COLLINS: I used to
beat you when you
were a little baby.
LIBBY COLLINS: Shut up, Dad.
SEAN COLLINS: All I'm
saying is the truth.
She's one evil person.
[ALL CHATTERING]
LIBBY COLLINS: Come on,
then, sit up here.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: Cheese.
It's a chaotic family
I got, isn't it?
LIBBY COLLINS: There'll
be no chaos.
Excuse me, you've got
a loving family.
[CHOIR SINGING]
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN): In the
old days, the way to get
out of a situation was boxing.
If you wanted to earn a bit of
money, you wanted to become a
professional, you wanted to
get a bit of money, people
went into boxing.
So it was physical.
The working environment
was more physical.
Now we look around, and
there's no jobs
left for the kids.
And, same as anything else, they
want to make a few bob.
And then you've got the people
who've got these drugs.
Right, OK, go and sell these.
Take them into schoolyards,
where, I know from personal
experience, 11 year olds have
been given cannabis and things
in schoolyards.
And it comes down to an economic
climate, if you like.
That person will grow up to be
18, 19, perhaps meet a girl,
get married--
drug problem is still there.
The children see the parents
with a drug problem, and it's
just a never-ending circle.
When the factories closed down
and the docks closed down, and
you've got the coal tippers
gone from the docks.
BP closed down.
Then the steel company
cut back.
And then you got all the
building firms that were
pulling out.
Depression can do a lot of
things to a lot of people.
I can understand why these kids
get so depressed and turn
to something like drugs,
alcohol, whatever.
It's a sad indictment of our
society that at 30 years of
age, you're on the
rubbish heap.
MALE SPEAKER: It's not that
the city was changed.
It's the people that's changed
It's all about derelict
warehouses on the back
of the strand
down there, for instance.
They're now about to be taken
over by a lap dancing company.
So, showing your knickers off
in a club for a couple of
quid-- that's OK, is it?
I don't think so.
All I can say is only a total
idiot would pay money at the
door to go in and watch
crap like that.
And if I had a grandchild--
and I've got a couple of
granddaughters, actually,
well, three--
I would hammer them with that.
FEMALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN): This
is just basically my job
at the moment, which
is really good.
It's good fun, pouring alcohol
down each other's necks,
getting wet, breathing
fire, stripping off.
Like, trying something different
and wearing really
sexy, beautiful clothes.
FEMALE SPEAKER: My
parents know.
Yeah, they think
it's brilliant.
It gives me confidence.
I wasn't normally a
confident person.
It's given me a world
of confidence.
I really enjoy it.
FEMALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Yeah, my
parents think it's awesome.
My nan actually thinks
it's amazing.
She said if she was like 60
years younger, she'd do it.
But, yeah, she's a
bit old to do it.
But they love it.
FEMALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN): My
mum wants to come do it too.
She wants to come and dance
around the poles.
FEMALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN): I
think they're actually proud
of the fact that we're going
out there, and we're
independent females who can do
this kind of thing and just be
amazingly proud of it.
We have a really good time.
[DOG BARKING]
MALE SPEAKER: I've been living
here for 12 years.
INTERVIEWER (OFFSCREEN): Yeah,
and how old are you now?
MALE SPEAKER: 13.
INTERVIEWER (OFFSCREEN): OK.
And how old are you?
MALE SPEAKER: 14.
MALE SPEAKER: Prostitutes
all the way down there.
MALE SPEAKER: In those
flats there.
MALE SPEAKER: Goofy as hell.
They've got [INAUDIBLE]
all over-- one girl,
all over her teeth.
She hadn't got none.
They were false.
Loads of boys speak about
her and that--
like loads of junkies
and all that.
INTERVIEWER (OFFSCREEN): What
do they do, the junkies?
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Inject
themselves on the street.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN): Couple
of them died the other
day up there, didn't they?
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
A boy, he took Valium,
isn't it?
And he died then.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN): No,
I don't like the Muslims.
INTERVIEWER (OFFSCREEN):
You don't like them.
Why not?
MALE SPEAKER: Because
they wouldn't like
it if we all emigrated.
They wouldn't like it if we all
emigrated over to their
countries, so why should they
come over to our country?
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah, and they
comes down here, works, gets
the money, and then
goes back to their
country and spends it.
They don't spend it here.
TAHA IDRIS: When somebody has
got no job, no income, et
cetera, and you go and tell
them, have you seen the people
out there, the black people
taking our jobs?
People tend to believe
that sort of thing.
Swansea's a very
peaceful place.
You know, it has always been
a very peaceful place.
I've lived here for almost 40
years, and I can honestly say
that there has never been
any major discord.
The only time I've ever seen a
big protest, demonstration in
Swansea, where people actually
joined in thousands, was
protesting against the killing
of Kala Kawa Karim, or
anything of that nature.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Hey!
Who is it?
Who are you?
TAHA IDRIS: Goodness me.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Abdul!
TAHA IDRIS: Why?
INTERVIEWER (OFFSCREEN): Why?
TAHA IDRIS: Yeah,
come on through.
INTERVIEWER (OFFSCREEN):
Who are you?
FEMALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Abdul!
INTERVIEWER (OFFSCREEN):
"Abdul."
TAHA IDRIS: There we are.
That's what happens.
You get used to it, honestly.
You get used to it.
And you start thinking, well,
if there is that sort of
attitudes around, you can't
do anything about it.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: A mosque?
Fuck.
Are you taking the piss, man?
Why do they want to
open another--
a wosque-- a mosque, when
there's one opposite?
There's one across the road.
AMY PROTHEROE: I got arrested
for being racist, right?
But he said something
behind my back.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: He called
her white trash, so she
slapped him and smashed
a window.
He says to her, show me your
tits, and I'll give you free
kebab meat.
Cheeky cunt, innit he?
MALE SPEAKER: Fuck off.
ALL CHANTING: Nazi scum,
off our streets!
MALE SPEAKER: What, then?
What, then?
POLICE OFFICER: I want
your full name.
[CHANTING AND SHOUTING]
MALE SPEAKER: Just
charge forward.
Give it some of that.
MALE SPEAKER: Swansea's
a good town.
It's a good town.
As long everybody gets on.
If you don't get on, well, you
can't make it, can you?
I say there's enough room in
the world for everybody, as
long as somebody gives
some space.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: Hey, hey.
What's happening, boys?
Oh, a lot of old bill
about, isn't it?
Fucking filth everywhere, man.
Oh, they're doing a--
There's my old man, look!
AMY PROTHEROE: There he is.
That's his--
CORNELIUS COLLINS:
Mr. Collins.
SEAN COLLINS: How's it going?
All right?
How's things?
CORNELIUS COLLINS: Remember
this one, do ya?
SEAN COLLINS: Where's the bin?
CORNELIUS COLLINS: You
all right, man?
Yeah?
SEAN COLLINS: Well, I went to
that BNP thing, and I thought,
well, it's a load of fucking--
what's going on?
But we do need the jobs
for our boys.
And most of them are
illegal immigrants.
There's no black on
the Union Jack.
There is no white on the
Stars and Stripes.
AMY PROTHEROE: [INAUDIBLE].
CORNELIUS COLLINS: Oy, it'd be
nice if we was working again,
Dad, wouldn't it?
SEAN COLLINS: Yeah.
Get him off the drugs.
AMY PROTHEROE: Oh, look what he
bought me for my birthday.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: I'm trying
to get back on The
Big Issue, I am.
SEAN COLLINS: I don't want
them two to get married.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: Why?
SEAN COLLINS: Would you?
Too many--
CORNELIUS COLLINS:
We're in love.
SEAN COLLINS: Yeah, right.
CORNELIUS COLLINS:
We're in love.
SEAN COLLINS: I really
don't want my son
to marry this girl.
CORNELIUS COLLINS:
Come on, then.
SEAN COLLINS: She drags
him down, man.
Since he's been with
her, it's like he's
gone into the gutter.
She drags him down, man.
I don't know why he loves her.
Love is blind, so they say.
I don't know.
And it's a sad thing.
I'm really sorry
for my son now.
I'm sorry for her, for
what happened-- what
she said, you know?
That she was abused and that.
AMY PROTHEROE: He's not
just my boyfriend.
He's my soulmate, my best
friend, and he's
the love of my life.
SEAN COLLINS: I loves him.
He loves me.
I loves him.
AMY PROTHEROE: I
loves him, too.
Sean, why don't we
get on, darling?
SEAN COLLINS: What
do you reckon?
AMY PROTHEROE: We
do and we don't.
SEAN COLLINS: You're
a bitch, man.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: Shut
it, you, you cunt.
SEAN COLLINS: Well,
you asked me why.
I'm telling the truth.
You are a bitch.
Eh?
You are a bitch, you know.
INTERVIEWER (OFFSCREEN): He
pulled your hair out?
AMY PROTHEROE: Yeah.
And he smashed the phone up.
SEAN COLLINS (OFFSREEN):
I did, yes.
I shouldn't have, but I did.
I am very sorry.
You know that, don't you?
CORNELIUS COLLINS:
The Collins clan.
CLINT RYAN JONES: Hello.
How are you?
INTERVIEWER (OFFSCREEN):
CLINT RYAN JONES: All
right, thank you.
INTERVIEWER (OFFSCREEN):
Good to see you.
CLINT RYAN JONES:
I've cleaned up.
I'm clean.
INTERVIEWER (OFFSCREEN):
You are?
CLINT RYAN JONES:
Yeah, I'm clean.
I've sorted my head out since
the last time you've seen me.
I went on a detox.
And then, that didn't
work for me.
I relapsed.
And then they put me on
a methadone program.
Ah, that's better, isn't it?
I've come a long way since you
last seen me, you know?
INTERVIEWER (OFFSCREEN): Yeah.
CLINT RYAN JONES: It's nice to
see you fellows, anyway.
INTERVIEWER (OFFSCREEN): Yeah.
You too, man.
You too.
Positive mental attitude.
CLINT RYAN JONES: Yeah.
PMA.
INTERVIEWER (OFFSCREEN): Yeah.
CLINT RYAN JONES:
It does work.
CLINT RYAN JONES (OFFSCREEN):
I've really
improved and things.
I'm much happier.
Like, I want to go back to
college and study social--
is it care?
I'm saving up now for my
daughter, for when I get to
see her, to give her a load
of presents and things.
Because I don't want to be
dependent on methadone.
No, no way.
Liquid handcuffs,
they call it.
That's what they call it--
liquid handcuffs, because
you've got to stay in the area
to take that liquid every day
to stop you from being ill.
It's impossible.
It's every other door around
here is selling it.
Or if they haven't got it, you
know, it's only down around
the corner have got it.
You know, it's easy to get
a hold of-- so easy
to get a hold of.
It is.
It's getting really worse.
It's getting terrible.
INTERVIEWER (OFFSCREEN): Why?
Because of the demand?
CLINT RYAN JONES: Well, It's
not so much as that.
It's the money that's being
made off it, you know?
People are making thousands
upon thousands
of pounds off it.
I'm ashamed to say I
used to sell it.
I used to make, easy,
1,500 pounds a day.
And I'd still be living
like a scruff.
I'd do a snowball,
as they call it--
mix heroin with crack and
have one hell of a
fantastic head on.
But you've still got to wake
up to the same shit the
following day, you know?
I've turned my life around
now, and I've
sorted myself out.
And I wouldn't dare touch
another bag of it in my life.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: Hey, cat.
Guess what we done yesterday?
INTERVIEWER (OFFSCREEN): What
happened yesterday?
CORNELIUS COLLINS: Lost
our fucking money.
Amy gets paid on a Wednesday.
I get paid on Thursday.
She's coming.
Said she had the car.
There she is.
She's crying.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: Amy, would
you be nice and not hit me?
AMY PROTHEROE: [INAUDIBLE].
You poured cider all
over my hair, man.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: What?
Why?
Amy, why?
Because you fucking--
AMY PROTHEROE: You
fucked my mother.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: I didn't
fuck your mother.
Amy.
AMY PROTHEROE: I'm homeless.
[INAUDIBLE].
Look what you've done.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: Look
what I've done.
Hold on.
Right, Amy?
It's either do that, right,
or hit you back?
What do you want me to do?
Do you want a punch?
Or do you want a fucking
dribble of
cider chucked at you?
I'm not having it, Amy.
Amy, your mother and Fogey
yesterday, right, told me and
you you're lucky I haven't
fucking hit you.
That's what they said.
You're lucky you haven't
had a fucking hiding.
Do you know if you weren't
my girlfriend--
AMY PROTHEROE: You
fucked my mother.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: Amy,
fuck off, right?
AMY PROTHEROE: He's always
abandoning me.
I've fucked my own mother.
Her lips are long, man.
Don't they sag down a bit?
CORNELIUS COLLINS (OFFSCREEN):
I know you've fucked your own
mother, Amy.
You've told me, man.
AMY PROTHEROE: Don't they
sag down a bit?
CORNELIUS COLLINS: Fuck off.
You knows I wouldn't
shag your mother.
Would you risk shagging your
girlfriend's mother when your
girlfriend's on the settee,
you're out in the kitchen
looking for cider with your
girlfriend's mother.
And her boyfriend--
no, her mother's boyfriend--
is upstairs, who's fucking
loopy, who's been to jail for
kidnapping and smashing
people's toes off.
And he's fucking psycho
to the max.
Would you risk shagging
his missus
downstairs while he's upstairs?
Would you?
INTERVIEWER (OFFSCREEN):
I wouldn't.
CORNELIUS COLLINS:
Would you, Adam?
INTERVIEWER (OFFSCREEN):
Mm-mm.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: Would do?
INTERVIEWER (OFFSCREEN): No.
CORNELIUS COLLINS:
So fuck you.
I wouldn't neither.
You knows I don't
like violence.
like fighting.
So am I gonna risk having
my fucking hand
chopped off with an axe?
AMY PROTHEROE: [INAUDIBLE].
CORNELIUS COLLINS:
Not my problem.
I'll give you one glass
and that's it.
I'm not having you take
a piss ut of me.
Telling me I shagged your
fucking mother.
How are you so insecure?
AMY PROTHEROE: Corneil, I paid
the money [INAUDIBLE].
CORNELIUS COLLINS: Why don't
you go do a punter?
Quicker than begging,
isn't it?
AMY PROTHEROE: I had
to beg for the 17
pounds my mother robbed.
And I'm only allowed
to have one.
Can I have the cider?
It's just gonna make me ill.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: Fucking
fill your glass
up, and shut up.
You're being dopey.
AMY PROTHEROE: [INAUDIBLE].
CORNELIUS COLLINS: Oh, well
fuck off then, if
you're gonna go.
I just don't know why
you're being nasty.
AMY PROTHEROE: Fill
it up, will you?
Fuck's sake.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: Look at
the way you're talking.
Get off my-- hey.
Kick my glass on the floor.
Get all dirt all over it.
Thanks.
I'm in agony, right?
Yesterday, she punched me four
times in the bollocks.
And she's fucked my other--
she's fucked my only decent
bollock up.
One's fucked already from 11
years ago, as she knows, and
she's gonna fucking punch
me four times.
And I've got a pain in my
stomach at the moment.
My bollocks are fucking
killing.
AMY PROTHEROE (OFFSCREEN):
You're fucking lying.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: I'm lying?
Right.
Did you know I had a fucking
dodgy bollock, then?
AMY PROTHEROE (OFFSCREEN):
Yeah.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: Was is much
bigger than the other one?
AMY PROTHEROE (OFFSCREEN):
Don't know.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: Fuck off.
You don't know.
AMY PROTHEROE: Why can't
you give me some cider?
CORNELIUS COLLINS (OFFSREEN):
I just gave you a glass.
AMY PROTHEROE: I want you
to give me some more.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: All right,
[INAUDIBLE], huh?
Are you going to
knock it over?
AMY PROTHEROE: [INAUDIBLE].
CORNELIUS COLLINS
(OFFSREEN): Amy.
AMY PROTHEROE: [INAUDIBLE].
CORNELIUS COLLINS: What
AMY PROTHEROE (OFFSCREEN):
[INAUDIBLE]
CORNELIUS COLLINS: Oh, phwor.
Poor little Amy.
LEE DENNIS (OFFSCREEN): I feel
a lot better in myself.
I mean I've been clean
now a good few weeks.
There's a few boys on the
bikes by here, look.
[ENGINES REVVING]
LEE DENNIS (OFFSCREEN):
Little kids, eh?
Some mad times we used to
have up here as kids--
setting cars on fire.
Good boy.
The rabbits and the hares and
that-- many times we'd come up
here, early hours of the
morning, and you could see
eyes running everywhere.
We used to try to chasing them
in a stolen car and try
killing them and stuff
you know what I mean?
Off our face, drunk and stuff,
Many times, the farmer used to
come out with his rice gun and
shoot us with his rice--
rice cartridges.
And they used to sting like
hell, especially if they catch
you on the arse, like.
You know, I wish I'd stuck with
the old crowd, instead of
all the heroin users
and stuff.
Years ago, I could count a good
few friends on my hand.
But now, they disowned me, type
of thing, for the heroin.
If I'd known how bad heroin was,
I wouldn't have tried it.
It's a bad drug.
It' a dirty drug.
But it's a nice drug as well.
It's a nice feeling off it.
Now, I wake up in the morning, I
go down to get my methadone,
I drink my methadone, and I try
to keep myself occupied
then by going over to my
sister's or my mum's That I
made when I was in
prison before.
INTERVIEWER (OFFSCREEN):
You did?
LEE DENNIS: Yeah, Gypsy caravan
out of matches.
Nodding head--
when I put my reggae on, his
head rocks back and forth.
Drug testing kit that I done
yesterday, which is a negative.
They test you for heroin
and crack cocaine.
And there's two lines--
negative.
Now I just want to be normal
now, try and get myself a
decent job.
INTERVIEWER (OFFSCREEN):
When you look back on
it, how do you feel?
LEE DENNIS: Tell you
the truth, man, I
think I'm an asshole.
Put my family through so
much shit and trouble.
Many a times, I said I've love
to move away and that, but
really, I won't.
I don't know.
It's my hometown, and all my
family are in Swansea.
I don't think I've
ever move away.
AMY PROTHEROE: If I didn't have
Corneil, I think I would
have killed myself by now.
He's what keeps me going.
You're my rock, aren't you?
CORNELIUS COLLINS: Oh, baby.
AMY PROTHEROE: He's my rock.
Well, we loves each other
to bits, don't we?
CORNELIUS COLLINS:
We do, yeah.
AMY PROTHEROE: Yeah.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: We
love each other.
AMY PROTHEROE: We're engaged.
He got me an engagement
ring for my
18th birthday, remember?
CORNELIUS COLLINS: Just found
a bottle of wine.
That is when I had Student of
the Year award in Swansea
College, Tychoch College, for
NVQ Level 1 business studies.
Or was it level 2?
I can't remember now.
Level 2, I think it was.
No, GNVQ Foundation Level 1.
And I look like I
got lipstick on.
AMY PROTHEROE: He done a
catering course, business
studies course.
CORNELIUS COLLINS:
What's that say?
AMY PROTHEROE: Have
you got fucking
lip balm on or something?
CORNELIUS COLLINS: Don't I look
like I got lipstick on?
I look weird, don't I, man?
AMY PROTHEROE: I love you.
See, look at that.
Look at all that--
all stale blood.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: See
this bit here?
That was all up the wall.
It was a shit hole.
AMY PROTHEROE: Look
at my pillow case.
[INAUDIBLE].
There's blood on it.
He got me all of my shampoos.
These shampoos-- he didn't
get me cheap ones.
He got me that.
He got me perfume.
CORNELIUS COLLINS:
Do you like that?
From Next, but I didn't actually
have it in Next.
It was three or four quid in
one of the charity shops.
AMY PROTHEROE: He
bought me that.
I haven't worn it yet.
Look, al the tags
are still on it.
CORNELIUS COLLINS (OFFSCREEN):
Knickers
AMY PROTHEROE: My pajama set--
my Minnie Mouse.
I'd love to be pretty.
CORNELIUS COLLINS (OFFSCREEN):
You are pretty.
AMY PROTHEROE: Me?
I looks like a fucking dog.
CORNELIUS COLLINS (OFFSCREEN):
Shut up, twat.
AMY PROTHEROE: I'm fat.
Look at the size of me.
Look how fat I am.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: She's
not fat, is she?
AMY PROTHEROE: Aren't I fat?
My ass is huge.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: You're
more of a twat than fat.
[INAUDIBLE].
Turn around and show
them your feet.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: No, I
don't want to do that.
AMY PROTHEROE: Don't
be a big baby.
Turn around.
If you love me, you will.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: Stop it.
AMY PROTHEROE: [INAUDIBLE].
Look, look.
They're not well, are they?
Lift your foot up.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: No way.
Stop it, man.
It's embarrassing.
AMY PROTHEROE: Please.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: The red's
burning right there.
It's all burning.
AMY PROTHEROE (OFFSCREEN):
He's been crying.
Every time he walks, it's like
he's just been bum raped.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: It's
called trench foot.
They used to get in the war.
Yeah, I bought the trainers.
Was it me that bought
the trainers?
AMY PROTHEROE: Yeah.
CORNELIUS COLLINS: She woke
up, and somebody had taken
them off her fucking
feet, man.
AMY PROTHEROE: My
little zebra.
What's he do now?
How do you do it?
[COWBOY-LIKE SHOUTING
FROM TOY]
CORNELIUS COLLINS (OFFSCREEN):
Woohoo.
AMY PROTHEROE: My mother
sent me to live
with this bloke, right?
He was 31 and I was 13.
He used to make me sleep with
his friends and that.
They used to know what
was going on.
They used to watch
him beat me up.
And they used to watch
him send me to the
bedroom with other men.
And my mother did nothing,
because he used to give her 50
pounds' worth of heroin
for free.
I had to have sex with
my mother and
her partner as well.
So it hasn't been a really
good life, but--
it's tough, isn't it?
CORNELIUS COLLINS (OFFSCREEN):
Let's talk about
something else, Amy.
AMY PROTHEROE: The first time
his father ever hit me, his
father misplaced 20 pounds.
And we didn't have it.
I had my maternity grant.
I was six months pregnant.
His father threw me on the
floor, ripped my hair out,
slapped me in the face, spat on
my face, and within three
weeks, the baby died.
[MUSIC - DUNVANT MALE
VOICE CHOIR SINGING
"SI HEI LWLI MABI"]
FEMALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Are you ready, boys?
CLINT RYAN JONES: This is the
one now, "Don't Do Drugs."
Some of my friends
sang some of it.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
FEMALE SINGER (OFFSCREEN): I was
sitting on a log And along
came a frog.
He said, do you want
to smoke some pot?
I said, I'd rather not.
He said he slung hash, come
on and give me your cash.
You mean you want my money?
You must be trying
to be funny.
I don't do drugs.
CLINT RYAN JONES: I relapsed
a fortnight ago.
So I went to put a needle
in, and I missed.
And it went in to an abscess.
I've lost my wife,
my three kids.
Now, all I want in life is to
be a family and to be loved.
I've never been loved.
I've never had a mother or
father that loved me.
Basically, I was abused.
Instead of having a cutch,
I'd be fucking
punched around, you know?
But I am going to be the best
daddy going when I get to the
stage I can say, fuck it.
I don't want no more.
That was me demonstrating on the
very last fucking bag I'll
ever do in my whole
entire life.
I missed a bit.
But there's the fucking hole it
left me with, which isn't a
fucking pleasurable sight,
as you can see.
Mums, dads, don't turn your
back on your children.
Always be there.
Give them plenty of love
and attention.
Once chance you have
of living.
Don't blow it.
That's all for now.
Nice one.
Clint Ryan Jones.
Thank you.
CLINT RYAN JONES: Clean and
serene for 30 days.
Clean and serene
for six months.
INTERVIEWER (OFFSCREEN):
How did you get
the six months one?
CLINT RYAN JONES: Because I
was clean for six months.
INTERVIEWER (OFFSCREEN): When?
CLINT RYAN JONES: When was
I clean for six months?
No, three months I
was clean for.
They gave me the
wrong keyring.
[MUSIC - DUNVANT MALE
VOICE CHOIR]