journal of course
there to a scientist
tremendously conservative or they
clearly think it's a really their
corporate us they love uh... all the
multinational corporations and protect
them and the establishment so in this
case alike
extra u_s_ citizens of plus a pro
stylish banquet allotted i'll get your
empl
uh... here's a wall street journal quote
gear rental credit for theatrical timing
as a snowstorm to settle on a washington
the filibuster fill their attention void
on twitter and cable t_v_
it's always reasoning match the
showmanship
people
of the area is supposed to go
uh... all right so what is your best of
your argument i'm curious
well here's what they see
calm down center
how awesome we do mean is that
uh... mister holder is right
even if he doesn't explain the low very
well u_s_ government cannot randomly
target america citizens on u_s_ soil or
anywhere else
what it can do under the laws of war is
target than enemy combatant
anywhere anytime
including on u_s_ soil
this includes and u_s_ citizen who is
also
an enemy combatant and all of that
his that's the wall street journal being
smug and say
up all quote
yourselves so i read for a number is
there is other sister
and would you rate and there are even
though i
well when i killing u_s_ citizens work
ily enemy combatants who are u_s_
citizens
but wait a minute you schwantz that's
the whole point
who gets to the side of their an enemy
combatant
okay so if i'm the president
and i decided you are an enemy combatant
kenai execute you
unlike not everyday probably wouldn't
probably
we don't do that in this country or we
weren't we didn't use to do that in this
country they give the executive branch
that authority to just the claire people
guilty
you know that so they should do that so
we are the magna carta the kings would
say autograph power wrong
intended for robert
and then
he would be executed without a trial
without anything
hitting a citizen
meetings as i declared it a bit
outlawing your dog
in a wall street journal on these
republican knuckle heads want to go back
to that time and by the way so the
democratic not collapse
so they when when paul says
undermines all western civilization he's
absolutely right for the wall street
journal snickers with sharply execute
them
well of course and i want her comes
walmart or john mccain
hooters ones this stuff he says
i watch some of that quote debate on
quote yesterday i don't think that same
quoting but
bailey says i saw carcinoma better
teleflora voice some of this
uh... some concern
we just totally unfounded really john
white
but let's say that the user jane fonda's
name
does a book certain memories with me and
i must say that she is not my favorite
american
as reported mission
uh... could we kill her during the
vietnam war
uh... but i also believe that as
audiences it was miss pond acted within
our constitutional rights
and is somehow say the someone who
disagrees with american policy and even
demonstrates against it
is somehow member of an organization
which makes that individual an enemy
combatant assembly false someone falls
well how do you know john
you've never seen any of the evidence
so we killed on or all of locking
sixteen-year-old son
how do you know he was there any combat
in fact we ask the united states
government why did you kill 'em they say
we're not gonna say about but when it
was not purpose or was it an accident
when i can say anything about
so you can execute sixty or u_s_
citizens
and not tell us
what u_s_ senate executed them
on what evidence let alone on what legal
principle
and what do you want it or not
but don't worry distrust the wall street
journal and john mccain
effing second because i want to get out
more
then they can
we executed without any due process
so he wrote some republicans the
so-called conservatives
including the one thing
angry with obon administration on this
extreme
on her door unconstitutional executive
power over your services
of course who's going to rework them
here comes the canes laptop
lindsey graham william lindsay
to my republican colleagues are in
memory of you coming down here
suggesting that president bush was gonna
kill anybody with a draft
are only remember the harshest critics
of the
uh... for our president bush on the
democratic side they had a drone program
back then
so what is it
all of a sudden
that this trial program
has gotten every republican so spina
whether we ought to hear
people are astonished that president
obama center mccain is doing many of the
things that president bush did
i'm not a scottish i congratulated
or having the good judgment understand
where war
though i agree with the first part you
know the bombs are being hypocrites
because they didn't someone from doing
any of this
but then the second was like
this is the one thing lizzie grams below
will probably have some bad briefly
right
he's also ya bums the woodwork
forthrightly l mama until one or more
than one there were resolved on please
vote for me
but on this what all he has great
judgment
lindsey graham
was that attorney in the military
that was his job an attorney
and here is turns around and says
well president says he's a man he come
back
well then obviously edits
no it's not his
that's why we have trials
that's why it's a democracy but lindsey
graham john mccain and wrestle war
mongers
i've totally forgotten that
thank god that ran paul stood up to them
and the republican establishment and the
democratic establishment
they've all fergan
but the constitution sposed to be about
and they're also smart mode
they're not gonna give these guys and i
deleted poets
that you and i might get put on a list
of some point somebody without power
might get put on a list they've gotta go
on a list right
but you'd given executive or anybody
unlimited power
tick tock
ticked off
only a matter of time
before they start abusing that power
there are any sort of museum abroad
there is a wall street journal article
ironically given their editorial says
here
where they explain
and the c_i_a_ and then a little
caterpillar the drone program
and uh... they realize ever while they
were just using
subleasing interest rates
they had no idea who they were killing
and risk ratings so much blow back from
the local populations that they decide
to go radon test aloo you know a bit
you know what this continued until
people that they don't know have
but not quite as much as before
but exactly power would never corrupt
right
if they're asking for a list one day all
watch them
goal
how
but you know was intrigued
that they can i mean the president
can put anybody honest killers
as long as he calls an enemy combatant
there is no check on him
you've got a big damn sure you're not an
enemy combatant