Jazeera International
Documentary Festival, which
was taking place in one of the
oldest buildings in Doha--
the Sheraton.
And while it was a nice place,
in a Logan's Run sort of way,
I wanted to get out and see what
else Doha had to offer in
the categories of food,
sports and culture.
Qatar is a tiny little country
jutting out from Saudi Arabia.
Thanks to its plentiful natural
gas reserves, it is
the wealthiest nation
on earth.
What is your name?
JASON MOJICA: Nasam Bashir.
A friend of mine told
me about a shawarma
place called Mara Mara.
JASON MOJICA: OK,
can we go there?
NASAM BASHIR: Yeah.
JASON MOJICA: Are we going
to be stuck in traffic?
JASON MOJICA: We drove out to
Old Airport Road to a place
that I'm almost positive
was not the place
my friend had suggested.
But you know, sometimes you just
gotta go with the flow--
especially when the
meter's running.
A friend of mine told
me that this is the
best shawarma in Doha.
Is it true?
Of course it's true.
JASON MOJICA: In my experience
it's the Lebanese who make the
best shawarma on the planet,
so I was a bit skeptical.
Hey, hey.
What?
JASON MOJICA: Beef?
MALE SPEAKER: Yes.
JASON MOJICA: I was shocked.
It was probably the best
shawarma I'd ever had--
ever.
Holy shit, that is good.
I can't stop swearing,
it's so good.
It's so good.
It's amazing.
Nope, definitely not the place
my friend recommended.
It had been nearly 24 hours
since I'd had a drink, and
that needed to change.
But that was something easier
said than done.
So here in Doha, just to get a
simple drink, you actually
have to join a club and present
your passport and get
an ID card made.
But in a country where a drink
can be hard to find, it's
worth the trouble.
Now, you could go to one
of the expense tourist
hotels for $20 beers.
But I wanted to see where some
of the zillion foreign workers
who made Doha function
hang out.
Sometimes, though, you have to
be careful what you ask for.
The only women were
on the stage.
But the real talent was on the
dance floor, where men dance
with other men, and it really
wasn't gay at all.
No, really, not at all.
[DANCE MUSIC PLAYING]
We're going to go try
and see some camels.
This city looks like
a chess set
designed by retarded children.
Now, it wasn't just camel racing
that had drawn us out
into the desert, but
the promise of
camels jockeyed by robots.
[ARABIC]
robot jockey?
[SPEAKING ARABIC]
JASON MOJICA: There's a race?
Is there a race today?
[SPEAKING ARABIC]
JASON MOJICA: No races today?
Is there a coaching practice?
JASON MOJICA: We certainly
weren't going to let a
knowledgeable local stand in the
way of finding robot camel
jockeys, so we pressed on.
Holy shit, these camels
are tied to sandbags.
Hi, camel.
So we came here to see some
camel racing, because we were
told that it was a crazy, crazy
scene, and that the
camels were raced by robots.
And if you have camels and
robots in the same sentence, I
get very, very excited.
And we've only found the camels,
and there are no
robots anywhere.
What kind of future is this?
You all right?
You ready?
I don't know that he's
much happier than me.
Oh!
OK.
All right, so Doha isn't
the most exciting
place in the world.
But I'd happily trade the quote
unquote "excitement" of
a place like Egypt for the
blandness of Doha.
That is, so long as they keep
making the best fucking
shawarma I have ever
had in my life.
[CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING]