fifty
million
i thought for sure the million for sure
it is a fifty bucks and i was like you
know what you got ron beloved no like
probably do it for free but yap
can fate
all not let's put that into a little bit
of perspective just that
compared to what the other people made
uh... chris hamesha represented jeremy
ryder margaret cho bill would be between
two and three million
and then that the other big two stars
uh... seminar jackson's character hanson
maybe between
four and six million
so he's still made more than all of them
were combined to just be in that little
suit and had to do all the tricks you
know why
the cease-fire
he's it's just because i mean schooler
than the rest of the things you know
course right now
crafted actually free market here next
it does make some sense and i'll tell
you one
it looked as you look at his people go
through the member because he probably
had a blast through it will live in
got anything like institute in little
rock
and what's what why it's so interesting
about this up
because almost other characters
didn't necessarily since the four
candidate
comic book character rested but they
could have been plagued by different
actors at that point week-and-a-half
enable really 'cause
there was an established
ready
it we have hoped movie with a couple
nuns
but it's a little blockbusters wrist
iron man isn't absolute golden
blockbuster
and it's robert downey so it is always
in order give him in the movie any time
in a movie
they had to pay a king's ransom yeah so
and that's why he had
more leverage than other star right now
this also has to do with that he got
bonuses and other compensation
and there's all kind of risks when you
have a good guys got quite a history of
drug use and showing up late and all
that has a
but he's kinda clean himself up for
fifty million bucks i would clean myself
up to out yeah yeah i mean for fifty
million bucks if i get on crackdown
perhaps
exactly is there much is there anything
you would do for a very very job
for fifty million box that you would not
be distracted by
this is just plain act that you know yet
apparently being a lawyer
that would be mademoiselle who did it
and yeah i was coming out when you take
fifty million orbit that was so painful
if they said you were to give you fifty
million dollars we want your soul 'cause
that's what they take great right
could you go back crude you do it work
for corporate law firm honestly itp one
hundred-percent depends on the timeframe
you're saying one year unlike all
corporate you dot darn larry
to is usually a good way to use it
is so precious terrible as this is that
uh... lit
if you say
twenty years
and i look people might think i might
ask for say no but i gotta held onto
them
i mean that's because you only live once
you all but i was there
well you take twenty beloved
pc years that i have a big that left
you made me do this whole question job
but what was the fifty billion worth
danny was supported four react animated
you lost the twenty prime years of your
life in the course make mike
but i guess what the main part of this
articles about them
is the amount of money that is being
played on you know we're paying now what
would you pay to go to movies like
twelve thirteen bucks if not more
three-d_ it's like
seventeen box around in l_a_ insanity
and i hadn't even been to the movies in
l_a_ in l_a_ like over there's a super
special
freedom of religion in israel or
pressure the
and you know and the in the middle of
something and so singer it around in
general area and so heritage address
that in oregon
so by british citizen and you know some
lady comes and anyway
it's not anticipated exaggeration aside
seventeen dollars ninety dollars you
like
for pricing what about what you had a
lot less threatening a resort or well
we've it's digital production and then a
three-d_ sound about our blah but
clearly
fifty million
for robert downey junior i hope you guys
are happy when you're pain than mine
yep so and look at the fighting is the
vendors like
let responding are right enough you know
uh... thomas roberts from msnbc
middletown
back at him you
uh... i know i know
nobody's looked at as well the person be
in mainstream media
so and i've been a mess of aidid
bizarre reason for me it but it is
obvious why have
whenever i see the other anchors
especially msnbc anchor that italy's
unlike
with are excellent
uh... that's a little bit
but there's something kinda grow every
time i see it you know the movie contact
had time to the c_n_n_ people deep
impact that the media it's kinda msnbc
has
and it's like and find it very
frightening because then it shows how
much here
is involved in
actually work what we do anything to
take that mask away and it's kinda
disturbing you know you're absolutely
right and that's exactly why i would
definitely noite at you're right but i
think i might add that the other side of
the reader of bsnl
what he really unavailable for
adventures ok soviet please