Okay beautiful pastry. the old school rule
is half fat to flour. So, we've got 600 grams
of flour here. Plain flour, you can sift it
if you like. A nice pinch of salt goes in
just to get a bit of seasoning happening there.
Of course the classic in the old pies would
be to use lard or butter. I'm using butter
which is brilliant, it's nice and it's sweet
and it gives wonderful colour to pastry. So
I've got 150 grams of butter going in and
then to make the fat, half fat to flour I'm
going to add 150 of cheddar cheese. Bust it
up in your hand, grate it if you like but
the whole point of this is that you have a
beautiful golden, rich, sweet, crumbly pastry
right but with this wonderful nuggets of cheese
in there.
So we're going to use the rubbing in method
so just with your thumb and forefingers so
just spend a couple of minutes rubbing this.
So if we're going to make our own pastry do
it by hand because you get this amazing crumble
that you simply can't replicate by a factory
made pastry.
yes you can go and buy shortcrust pastry from
a supermarket it will be very good. This is
amazing. You can actually make it in a food
processor and just pulse it, It will be very
good but it won't be very good as this.
Just two minutes rubbing this flour together.
Can you see how the flour has gone from chalky
white to a sort of yellow colour, it's little
bit heavier now. So once you've rubbed it
in like this, I'm going to add about 250 grams
of cold water.
We really don't want to over work this. This
recipe is going back to roots, a little bit
of love, care and attention. Also it's about
kind of under kneading it. You always think
that you've got to knead it like bread, you
don't. You've got to literally scrunch the
dough. See what I'm doing I'm just packing
it and pressing it together to make this because
you don't want to work the gluten in the flour
because that makes it hard and little bit
like eating the bottom of your shoes. So we
want to just push it together and that's the
key. So guys I've pretty much just pressed
that pastry together. That's what it looks
like. Beautiful. If you want to see where
this pastry ends up, click the link. Take
a look at my beautiful Aussie meat pie. Go
and have a look!