-What do you think, Dave?
DAVE HATCHETT: I think it's
time to go off, off the
Richter scale, that is.
If you flash a line 15, 20 years
ago, and it's a big,
gnarly line in Alaska or
wherever, and you flash it
clean, what's the difference
between then and
20 years from now?
You could put it in a segment
today, and a lot of the riders
would love to have that
in their part if they
rode it that well.
MIKE HATCHETT: I can go back
to "TB5" and watch a movie.
And I'm not trying to sound
arrogant or whatever on the
filmmaking point of it,
but I can put in
"TB5" Alaska footage.
And I can put in Alaska footage
from this year, and I
can be like, I don't
see a difference.
In fact, I think the stuff from
'95 is almost better.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
DAVE DOWNING: Yeah,
"TB5," Johan part
was the one for sure.
It still is.
You look back at that part, and
if he filmed that right
now, it'd still be a
groundbreaking part
right now, I think.
And that's pretty cool to
witness that firsthand, see it
with my own eyes.
JEREMY JONES: He's like
a wild animal.
He'd get to the top and just
be like, cameramen, media,
this is Johan.
I'm dropping in 10 seconds.
And cameramen are
just scrambling.
No back and forth.
That would be the only
communication
you'd hear from Johan.
And then he'd go do something
that no one's ever done before
on a snowboard.
And half of his best riding
probably wasn't on film,
because he didn't feel like
waiting for cameramen.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
EIKI HELGASON: Yeah, this was
the first Standard movies from
one to six just a
few weeks ago.
And man, the riders there were
just standing it for the
sketchiest jumps and bigger then
than they're doing today.
It's so sick.
I got so pumped just
seeing back flips
off the biggest cliffs.
And front flips.
They're standing it.
I like that.
JEREMY JONES: Noah's descent
in "TB5" on Super Spines is
hands down--
changed what that dream run
was in big mountain
riding in one line.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
DAVE HATCHETT: Definitely my
most famous first descent is
the Mendenhall Towers.
And that was in Juno.
We had a heli, and we were like,
we want to go there, we
want to go there.
And we just started pointing
at the mountains, which are
all basically now the runs that
are right off the road.
But at that point,
they were all--
a good portion of them
were first descents.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
JEREMY JONES: I would say both
of those descents, the Super
Spines descent and the
Mendenhall Towers descent--
before those guys did that, no
one thought that you could
ever ski or snowboard down
something like that.
It just shattered the ceiling
and was like, we were all
looking over this way, they go
and do this, and we're like,
OK, that's what we should
be looking at.
JIM RIPPEY: And as I would talk
to people who would watch
the videos--
it's usually those one or two
shots where you almost kill
yourself and you're just
totally, totally going for it
that they remember.
LONNIE KAUK: Yeah, "TB4"
was the one.
Like, you see Rippey
doing that big old
back flip off of there.
And it was just like
next level.
You're like, I want
to be that dude
snowboarding in the video.
JIM RIPPEY: We got out
of the helicopter.
Terje saw something he wanted to
do, some turns down below.
And I didn't really
see anything.
So I kind of walked over to
the ridge, and I saw this
perfect cliff.
I've always loved jumping off
cliffs, because what you get
when you jump off a cliff is,
you get that acceleration
experience where you're going
from going really slow and
just feel that drop rate.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
TERJE HAAKONSEN: If I remember,
we did a run right
next to it, like first time I
went on a big mountain that
was that long and that
steep for that long.
And what I remember is just
doing airs on the way down on
small, little bumps.
And you would just fly for so
long, because it was so steep.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
JIM RIPPEY: I remember him being
like, this is sketchy,
this is sketchy.
Like, of course it's sketchy.
We're flying around in a
helicopter looking over these
crazy peaks.
TERJE HAAKONSEN: The whole
intensity level when you go
first is obviously a little
higher because what's going to
happen and stuff.
We tore airs up there,
too, and Jim.
I'm like, yeah, sure,
you could go first.
And then Mike on the radio,
Terje, you're going first, and
you're going now.
I'm like, OK.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
DAVE HATCHETT: This
looks so easy.
You're like, I could do that.
But you don't really realize,
or maybe you do, what could
happen if something
went wrong.
And that's when you watch the
bail segments, and you watch
Tom tumble through rocks, or
some of Jeremy's close calls.
And you really, really realize
what could happen if you hook
an edge in the chute
or a rock line.
And all it takes is one tumble
onto a rock, and you're toast.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
LONNIE KAUK: They'll show a
video, and people will just be
like, oh, dude, I would've done
that, or I would've went
there, I would've done that.
You're like, dude, you got no
idea what it looks like when
you're riding down that.
Like, dude, you're either scared
as shit, or you just
forget where you're at.
And it freaks you out.
And then everybody's
like, oh, dude,
you're just riding along.
It doesn't mean anything.
It's like, dude, you have no
idea what it takes to freaking
do that stuff.
It's gnarly.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
JEREMY JONES: The thing with
riding these serious lines is
crew is everything.
And Mike and Dave are some of
the best, most experienced
guys in the mountains
in the world.
So when I'm on a line and need
to get advice, I can call up
the cameramen and they're giving
me world-class, on
point feedback.
MIKE HATCHETT: Even me, I'll
let my guard down, just not
thinking, hey, is that guy in
the right spot to respond to a
rescue or whatever?
You see people, and there's just
three dudes on the slope
at the same time, and that
guy's in the way of the
[? abbey, ?] and there's some
guy standing on the cornice,
and that guy's snowmobiling
here, and just no one--
they're just like, dude, what
if something happens?
Is anyone ready?
Is anyone even paying
attention here?
JIM RIPPEY: They take the
back country seriously.
They assess the snow
conditions.
And Mike is always taking that
very serious, way more serious
than I did.
There was a lot of times where
Mike and I would almost butt
heads, because I'm like,
let me do this.
And he'd be like, no,
it's not safe.
JEREMY JONES: watch a kid be
lining up a gap or something.
And I've seen them time and
again be like, you know what,
I haven't seen enough out of you
that tells me that you're
going to make that gap.
You came up short on this jump,
you overshot this jump,
and there's a five
foot sweet spot.
And if you don't get it, you're
going to hurt yourself.
I'm not shooting it.
DAVE HATCHETT: I've definitely
seen and witnessed a lot of
really close calls with me
filming other riders with
trees that have been way
too close for comfort.
TOM BURT: We were trying this
follow-cam shot through this
little slot rock.
But it had a little wave in it,
it's a wind wave, but it
was almost like a kicker.
DAVE HATCHETT: We saw a little
wind drift at the bottom, and
we threw snowballs at it.
And it seemed soft.
The snowballs disappeared,
and we all agreed it
looked like it was OK.
There was a tree kind of in the
fall line to the right.
But we all thought, oh, we'll
just hit that little snow
drift, and we'll just
ride right over it.
TOM BURT: And so
I went through.
And I don't want to
hit that lip.
I got bucked, but when
he hit it, he was
trying to save the camera.
And he got whipped around
and lost his edge.
And then he slid down the
hill and slammed this
tree that was there.
DAVE HATCHETT: He must have
missed the tree by two to six
inches, maybe.
I just grazed the tree with the
tail of my snowboard, kind
of sliding butt-first
down the hill.
Luckily, that's how I
hit it, tail first.
And it was actually enough
force to break my femur.
And it broke my femur
and my hip.
So of course, I was completely
out that year.
And it was definitely a
pretty big blow to me.
Physically, it was an insane
injury to come back from.
And after that, I wanted to come
back, and I wanted to do
everything I was doing before.
But by the time I came back
from the injury, it was
another year and then another
year after that to even be
100% again.
And at that point, I was a
couple years older, and I just
kind of realized some things.
And I kind of lost the
desire after that.
I would say that, in a sense,
breaking my femur put an end
to my snowboard career.
So definitely, trees don't
move when you hit them.
[MUSIC PLAYING]