NICK SWARDSON: Hey this is Nick
Swardson, and this is
probably the craziest
party that I
remember from my childhood.
I was 14 years old and I hung
out with a lot of the shady
and the shady crowd.
We had Starter jackets
and silver
chains and hats on sideways.
So there was this one kid who
was like extra shitty.
He was crashing in this
abandoned house--
like super old, like the
yard was all cruddy.
One night we're like, let's just
fucking break in there
and like we'll throw
a big-ass party.
So we go into this place,
we get a fucking bunch
of bottles of booze.
And we're partying and we're
boozing, we're just pounding
vodka, whatever the hell we
can get our hands on.
Anything that was breakable,
we would break.
We would break light bulbs,
threw the bathtub down the
stairs, we were graffiti-ing So
we just totally decimated
this house.
And then everybody was like
starting to pass out.
So this kid decides to go up on
the top floor and throw a
Molotov cocktail.
So he lights a Molotov
cocktail, throws
it against the wall.
Of course has no plan on how
to put the fucking fire out
that he just set.
So he ran downstairs and was
screaming, and we were all
like hung over and fucking
fucked up.
He was like, we got to get
the fuck out of here.
So we all escape out
of this house, and
it's totally torched.
The next day there was cops
everywhere just around the
neighborhood.
We looked out the window, we
were smoking weed which made
it even more paranoid.
And I turned to my buddy, I go,
we got to get the fuck out
of here, man.
The cops are going to come,
they're going to find us.
So I took off my Starter jacket,
I took off my chains,
took off my hat.
I put on a Polo shirt that I
found in his closet and I put
on these tiny little
tennis shorts.
And I grabbed a tennis racquet,
and I walked out the
back of his door and walked in
through this whole sea of
police and they're all
staring at me.
I'm walking with my tennis
racquet, and I look like this
nice kid from the '80s.
The city bus pulls up and I jump
on it and I take it home
like 10 blocks to my house.
And I called my friend and I
was like, I made it home.
And just as I talked to him on
the phone, the cops broke in
the door and they were
all arrested.
I was the only one
that got away.
Yep.