DANNY LOZANO: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
BORJA SANTIAGO:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
IGNACIO: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
DANNY LOZANO: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
BORJA SANTIAGO:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
DANNY LOZANO: For sure, it's the
oldest store in Madrid, if
not even Spain, I don't know.
But it's super old.
The thing is that it looks
exactly the same now as it did
25 years ago.
But that's what gives
it its beauty.
JOSE ANTONIO MUNEZ:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
IGNACIO: I think that we must
begin with some boards that
are really, really old school.
These are the boards I was
talking to you before.
these are the Sancheskis.
These were the first
Spanish brand of
skate, as you can see.
I love this deck because this
one, it was the first pro
model deck of a Spanish guy.
It was Ricardo Damborenea.
He was a really, really
good skater.
And he still skates.
He has skated with
us every weekend.
And now he's dedicating most
of his time to slalom.
This one is another Sancheski.
You can see it's a bit weird.
This one, it was [INAUDIBLE]
with both feet like this,
really near the feet.
My name is Ignacio.
I'm the son of the founder
of Caribbean.
His name is Jose Antonio.
And in 1975, he opened
Caribbean.
And this was the first
skate shop in Spain.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]?
JOSE ANTONIO MUNEZ:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
IGNACIO: '75.
JOSE ANTONIO MUNEZ: 1975.
IGNACIO: 1975, when we
opened the shop.
JOSE ANTONIO MUNEZ:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
IGNACIO: These are
the new ones.
JOSE ANTONIO MUNEZ:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
IGNACIO: This is Barcelona?
JOSE ANTONIO MUNEZ:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
IGNACIO: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
JOSE ANTONIO MUNEZ:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
IGNACIO: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
JOSE ANTONIO MUNEZ:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
DAVID SANCHEZ:
DANNY LOZANO: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
ALAIN SAAVEDRA:
ARMANDO SANTOS:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
ALAIN GOIKOETXEA:
JAVIER MENDIZABAL:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
ALAIN GOIKOETXEA:
SERGIO MARTIN:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
-[SPEAKING SPANISH]