War planes and rockets crossing paths in the
sky. Right now that`s part of daily life for
people living in parts of Israel and Gaza.
The signs of the fight maybe in the air, but
the impact is on the ground. This is an office
building in Gaza that`s been used by some
media organizations. It was hit by an Israeli
air strike on Monday. Israel said Palestinian
militants were hiding in there. Israel`s targets
include government buildings, police stations
and the homes of Hamas officials. That`s the
terrorist group that took control of the government
of Gaza in 2007. Israel has launched strikes
against more than 1300 sites since the fighting
started.
The rockets are flying in both directions.
In Gaza, militants from Hamas are launching
them into Israel. More than 1000 rockets have
been fired from Gaza since the start of the
conflict. On Monday, one of those hit a school
in southern Israel. It`s been closed since
the fighting began.
Now, CNN reporters are in Gaza and Israel
covering this conflict, and at times doing
their job can put them near the fighting.
Now, you are about to see how they react in
those situations. First, Anderson Cooper in
Gaza, then Frederick Pleitgen in Israel.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
ANDERSON COOPER, CNN CORRESPONDENT: One family,
also two media centers built ....
(explosion)
Wow.
Well, that was a rather large explosion. That
occurred -- if you just look out here - I
can`t actually see where the impact (no sound)
that was, it`s actually set off a number of
fire alarms. But that was probably the largest
explosion that we`ve heard just in the past
-- really, in the past hour. There have been
a number of explosions in the last hour or
two. But that one - that one was pretty loud.
FREDERIK PLELTGEN, CNN CORRESPONDENT: OK,
we have an alarm going off right now. I`m
going to have to seek cover. We are going
to go over here. Let`s take the camera off
the tripod, though.
All right. Seems like something impacted in
the distance, not sure how far away. OK, the
alarm stopped.
So, it seems the impact was quite away in
the distance, I would say, a couple of miles,
probably, in the distance. There, over in
the sky, you probably won`t be able to see
it here, there is an interceptor missile taking
off right now, that is the Iron Dome interceptor,
right? If you just saw the flash in the sky,
that was a rocket coming out of Gaza that
was just intercepted right now.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
LANCE: Now, you heard Fred Pleitgen mention
the Iron Dome. It`s Israeli Defense System
that shoots down rockets coming in from Gaza,
so far it`s intercepted about 30 percent of
those rockets. Frederik has more on this technology
and how it works.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
PLELTGEN: This video shows an Iron Dome missile
intercepting a rocket fired from Gaza at Tel
Aviv on Sunday.
The defense system had just been installed
in Israel`s largest city a few hours earlier.
Several days into the conflict, it`s already
clear: the Iron Dome is having a big impact
picking off hundreds of rockets.
I got a tour of the Israel aircraft industry`s
plant that assembles the air defense system.
DR. ISRAEL OZNOWICH: Deployment is the matter
of minutes.
PLELTGEN: Dr. Israel Oznowich is one of those
in charge. One key element is an advanced
radar.
OZNOWICH: The radar such as locates, tracks
and intercepts and guides the intercepting
missiles within several seconds, few seconds
within the launching time.
PLELTGEN: It`s extremely hard to shoot down
short distance rockets like the ones coming
out of Gaza, in part because they are not
in the air for older radar systems to lock
onto them.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
AUNG SAN SUU KYI, DEMOCRACY ADVOCATE: I would
like to say how happy I am to receive President
Obama in my country and in my house. The friendship
between our two countries is of long standing.
The United States has been staunch in its
support of the democracy movement in Burma,
and we are confident that this support will
continue through the difficult years that
lie ahead.
I say difficult, because the most difficult
time in any transition is when we think that
success is in site.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
LANCE: There was some history happening right
there, in that video. President Obama was
visiting the home of Aung San Suu Kyi, that
home is in Myanmar and Barack Obama is the
first American president to go there. It was
the middle stop on his trip to Asia. He went
there after visiting in Thailand and before
going to a conference in Cambodia. Myanmar,
which used to be knows as Burma, was the big
focus of this trip. For decades, it was closed
off from the rest of the world, denied political
freedoms and people who pushed for democracy
like Suu Kyi were punished. The country has
started making some reforms and during the
president`s visit he said, also some changes
could lead to incredible opportunities for
Myanmar and its people.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: It`s time for the "Shoutout."
In the economic world, what color is associated
with profits? If you think you know it, then
shout it out. Is it green? Blue? Red? Or Black?
You`ve got three seconds, go!
When a company is making a profit, it`s said
to be in the black. That`s your answer and
that`s your "Shoutout."
(END VIDEO CLIP)
LANCE: That`s why this Friday is called Black
Friday, the day after Thanksgiving officially
takes off the holiday shopping season. It`s
one of the busiest shopping days of the entire
year, and it`s when stores make enough sales
to hopefully put themselves in the black.
Some stores aren`t waiting for Black Friday
to start Black Friday. Wal-Mart, Sears, Target
and Toys R Us are some of the stores that
are open on Thanksgiving evening. That might
sound good to shoppers, but not to some of
the employees who work there. They`ve started
petitions against the early openings, so that
workers can spend Thanksgiving with their
own families. Some Wal-Mart employees are
planning to protest by walking off the job
on Black Friday.
And before they sit down for Thanksgiving,
or head out shopping on Black Friday, a lot
of people have to get where they are going
for the holiday. According to AAA, more than
43 million Americans are expected to travel
at least 50 miles for Thanksgiving. Most of
those will be going by car, but more than
3 million will be traveling by plane. So,
if you are heading to the airport, don`t expect
to see too many empty seats on your flights.
So, let`s talk about college for a minute.
There is still some time before applications
are due at most schools, but how do you pick
which college to apply to?
There is a lot to consider, there is location,
what programs are offered, how much it costs,
and how are you going to pay for it.
Those last two are what Christine Romans looks
at in this report.
(BEIGN VIDEOTAPE)
CHRISTIANE ROMANS, CNN CORRESPONDENT: At this
college fare high school junior Veronica Woodley
is exploring her options.
VERONICA WOODLEY, HIGH SCHOOL JUNIOR: Finding
schools that had premed and I can major in
biology to become a dermatologist. And to
also minor in Spanish.
ROMANS: Picking the right college is a high
stakes decision with a high price tag. Average
tuition for a year at a public college is
more than $22000 for in-state students. A
private college, more than $43,000. Community
colleges cost $15,000 a year. Not all kids
borrow for college, but those who do, graduate
with $27,000 in debt on average. With a price
tag like that college choice is a careful
investment that depends on the student`s talents
and finances.
Most important, you have to graduate from
school in four years, no more five years,
and you have to pick the right school. If
you haven`t saved any money, you can`t pick
the super expensive school and graduate five
years later.
For students like Veronica and her mom Kathy,
it`s an exciting time. And a lesson in high
finance. They are crunching the numbers and
considering all the options.
WOODLEY: I mean on scholarships, financial
aid, and then - I work, but my mom - -I think
like my mom will do most of they paying, but
I mean I will help her out, of course.
Christine Romans, CNN, New York.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
LANCE: Thanksgiving is only two days away,
and we ask you to tell us what you are thankful
for. And you definitely didn`t hesitate with
sharing with us.
Betsaida said she is thankful for the holidays,
family and friends, as well as Thanksgiving
day, because it reminds us of what we are
most thankful for.
Ms. Risley`s reading class told us they are
thankful for good health, a safe home and
family members, plus they are grateful to
the soldiers who keep us safe and for living
in the USA.
Victoria is thankful for this country as well,
and how it`s prospering even during the tough
time. Sarah is thankful her great grandmother
is still alive and will be turning 90 year
old. Happy birthday, Grandma.
Ronnie is being raised to be a young man,
thanks to his mom, and he`s also thankful
for his great education and good grades.
While we all could probably agree with Peri
on this one, who is thankful for everything
that makes us smile. And so many of you wrote
that you are thankful for your family, your
friends and even for CNN STUDENT NEWS. But
we are definitely grateful for all of you,
too. And we are also thankful for the people
who sent an I-report on this topic, so if
you go to the spotlight section on our home
page, you`ll find a link to watch those. But
before we go, we are going to check out this
cardboard village. They young people who you
see putting it together, right there, they
are planning to camp out there overnight.
This was in Colorado, and yes, it`s going
to be cold, but that was the point: they were
trying to raise awareness about homelessness
by facing some of the challenges that the
homeless regularly deal with. It`s a good
cause and a good story to wrap up our week.
CNN STUDENT NEWS returns on Monday, and we
hope you all have a very happy Thanksgiving.
Until then, I`m Natisha Lance.