PATRICK O'DELL: Hi.
Welcome back to the Epicly
Later'd Show.
This episode, we have
Kevin "Spanky" Long.
Kevin's skating is really
spontaneous.
I don't think he feels that kind
of pressure that other
skaters feel.
He's going to just ride some
spot and just try something
until he lands it.
He's doing a trick because, I
think, he's having fun, and
you can see that in the rest of
his life, too, the way he
lives and stuff.
Everything's just right
now, like everything's
right in the present.
So today, we're going to go into
Spanky's apartment, and
you can see for yourself
how he lives.
KEVIN "SPANKY" LONG: Well, I
was just gonna kind of like
get a couch, maybe some pictures
or something, maybe
get a bed, like a proper bed.
I don't know.
The girls are working on it.
PATRICK O'DELL: Where'd
you get this giraffe?
KEVIN "SPANKY" LONG:
I got that from the
Fairfax swap meet.
That's Reginald.
PATRICK O'DELL: What?
KEVIN "SPANKY" LONG: His name.
PATRICK O'DELL: Reginald?
KEVIN "SPANKY" LONG: Yeah.
This is the original
pizza of trust.
PATRICK O'DELL: How long's
that been there?
KEVIN "SPANKY" LONG: How long
you think it's been here?
Like month and a half?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Month
and a half.
PATRICK O'DELL: Your dad tries
to give you furniture?
KEVIN "SPANKY" LONG: Yeah.
My dad's like constantly working
on a million different
projects at once.
Like he gets these ideas, and
then he's like, I want an old
bus, and I'm going to make it
all nice, and then we're going
to go on family trips and
stuff with the bus.
But it's like all this kind
of stuff, like that.
It's my great-grandfather's
chair.
He was a barber.
I guess he still has all the
books and stuff that my
great-grandpa had, like with the
styles and cuts, and the
scissors and everything.
But he was afraid that I was
going to spill wine all over
everything.
JON LONG: The revelation
is, I mean, it's just
in the blood, man.
It's something to
do with Irish.
I mean, it's an innate
fuckin' thing.
He's ADD like his old man.
It's just part of it.
They used to put a block of wood
under my chair because I
was so tiny, and they
thought that was
going to calm me down.
No way.
I was frickin' off the wall.
I was--
whew.
And so, I would take him to,
like, Safeway, and skate with
JT or his other buddies.
He's going, dad, I got to
land this trick, I got
to land this trick.
Like, that's fine, but mom's
cooking dinner, so
we got to get home.
And he'd just go, I got to land
this trick, and I'd call
home and say, hey, we're going
to be a little late.
And he would sit there
and sweat and work
at doing this trick.
And then he would make the
trick, and then I'm like, OK,
we're out of here, we're going,
you did it, finally.
And he says, I got
to do it again.
And that's Kevin.
PATRICK O'DELL: You got to
tell me what happened.
KEVIN "SPANKY" LONG: Well,
I lost the keys, and my
motorcycle's parked
in front of it.
And I had to get some
shit out, so--
PATRICK O'DELL: How'd
you lose the key?
KEVIN "SPANKY" LONG: Well, the
keys were like in my bag.
I usually carry around a
little bag like this.
PATRICK O'DELL: That's
like your purse?
KEVIN "SPANKY" LONG:
Yeah, sort of.
But I mean, it's just a black
bag with my stuff.
PATRICK O'DELL: I mean, what
happened to the keys?
That's a good plan, you know.
KEVIN "SPANKY" LONG: Yeah, it
didn't fail until one of the
bags blew out.
It was like a thinner one like
this, and with those you got
to double bag sometimes.
CHRIS SHONTING: Oh, the
little man purse?
The little deli bag, bodega.
He usually carries it, but then
I've seen him kind of
like progress into strapping
it around his neck.
I guess it's literally like one
of those situations if his
head wasn't screwed on either,
he'd lose that, but now he's
got a bag around his neck.
ATIBA JEFFERSON: If I could pick
a lifestyle like that, I
would go with his, because it's
got be so stress-free.
I mean, think about it,
how many times he
will flake on something.
Spur of the moment, you could
get the dude to go do
something knowing he probably
has prior engagements.
But like, Spanky, let's go jam
at the house, you know
instantly, he's flaking
on someone for dinner.
And that's wha6t's funny.
When you meet someone that's a
little kid, you always picture
them as a little kid.
And I hate to say it, the dude's
22 and he's still a
little kid.
PATRICK O'DELL: How long have
you known Spanky for?
TERRY KENNEDY: Years.
Like, I met him, Paul, Mikey,
all like going to the valley,
so five years.
From knowing him when
he was sponsored.
It was like [INAUDIBLE]
ATIBA JEFFERSON: I totally
remember it.
It was like, I remember
the Gap.
I was shooting photos.
It was that Santa Monica Blue
Gap, the Pawn Gap, and Mikey
Taylor's trying a gnarly flip.
But anyways, there was this kid,
and he's sitting there,
and he's frontside flipping
it, like, good style and
everything.
And I was like, yeah,
what's his name?
And they're like, Spanky.
KEVIN "SPANKY" LONG:
He is spaced.
ANDREW REYNOLDS: It's
different now.
Like, now, he's kind
of grown up.
We became really good friends.
But back then, it was, like,
I'm this druggie guy, and
you're like a little kid, so we
really don't have much in
common, you know what I mean?
It was different back then.
JAVIER NUNEZ: Spanky, though,
it's funny how Spanky turned
out, because I'm,
like, how old?
Like I said, I would be smoking,
drinking, and he'd
just be wildin' out, blazin'
bitches, and fuckin', they
would just look at me,
like, oh damn.
Because they wasn't really
doing none of that shit.
They was just young--
PATRICK O'DELL: Spanky
and Paul?
JAVIER NUNEZ: --always talking
about skating.
Yeah, Spanky, Paul, Mikey,
Devon, Cal, all them cats.
KEVIN "SPANKY" LONG: 6:23 in
the morning, and we've been
skating all night long.
MALE SPEAKER: Hook him up!
Give a little bit.
Oh!
Uh, uh, uh!
MALE SPEAKER: Give him a hug,
give him a tight squeeze.
FEMALE SPEAKER: What's
wrong, you scared?
You a virgin?
KEVIN "SPANKY" LONG:
I'm not scared.
JAVIER NUNEZ: I've seen Spanky
in the [INAUDIBLE]
getting twisted.
I'm like, ah, I got you a
drink, what you want?
Because it's funny, just like,
people grow up, you know?
ANDREW REYNOLDS: I guess City
Star's kind of falling apart,
and he had some offers to ride
for Toy Machine or something
like that, and I just kind of
told him, like, you should
just ride for us, you know?
It's way better.
And he knew what was right.
PATRICK O'DELL: You had to
convince him for a while,
though, right?
ANDREW REYNOLDS: Yeah.
KEVIN "SPANKY" LONG: I was going
on that Baker tour to
Australia, but I wasn't
riding for Baker yet.
I was trying to figure out if
I was going ride for them or
Toy Machine.
Like, the whole time we were
staying at Dustin's house, and
that pretty much pressured me
on the going on Baker, which
I'm glad I did.
But he was just torturing me the
whole time, like, making
me feel really bad for even
questioning riding for Baker.
What the fuck is wrong
with you, man?
Like, you know how Dustin is
just like, you're stayin' in
my house, like, what's
the question here?
Like, you ride for us.
And basically, like, by the end
of it, I heard, like, "you
ride for us" so many times, it
was like, all right, I can't
say no to that.
Especially to a young lad who's
never been on a skate
tour with people he's looked
up to, and he's basically
calling them a fucking
asshole.
ROBIN FLEMING: Yeah he went from
being a baby to being a
full-blown, jaded,
fucking hipster.
But he also doesn't take
this whole thing that
seriously, you know?
He, I think, recognizes it, and
is really grateful, which
is refreshing.
So it's a free life with a lot
of wonderful travel and great
opportunities to hang out with
another amazing bros, and
travel the world with
your friends.
He could lose everything
and he wouldn't know.
He doesn't care.
And that's what's
good about him.
He cares about the
right things.