BEN LASHES: Brad O'Farrell
kind of
started this whole thing.
BRAD O'FARRELL: Oh
yeah, I guess.
BEN LASHES: The internet,
he started the internet.
BRAD O'FARRELL: My name is Brad
O'Farrell, and I posted
the first Keyboard Cat video
and started the meme of
mashing up Keyboard Cat to fail
videos so he's playing
people off.
So the actual video of the cat
was filmed in 1985, I think.
And I was born in 1986, so
I didn't film the video.
The original video was made by
a guy named Charlie Schmidt.
And he's an artist who does
lots of different mediums.
He's kind of like
an old hippie.
It sounds mean that I said that,
but that's very much
what he is.
CHARLIE SCHMIDT: You're not
getting anything done on this
spray paint thing.
Look at this mess.
If you want to see weird,
just be it.
BRAD O'FARRELL: Completely
unrelated to Keyboard Cat, he
has a nose that he can move
like an elephant.
He can move it in directions,
and he used to be in Japanese
commercials and stuff.
And he has an agent
for his nose.
And that was his job
at some point.
I can't remember exactly
how I came across it.
I was looking at a lot of
videos at the time.
Every day, my job was
to look at videos.
So somebody sent it to me,
but I can't remember
who sent it to me.
The first video that I made was
just a fail video of a guy
trying to go up an escalator on
a wheelchair, and then he
tumbles backwards.
And then Keyboard Cat
plays him off.
-You OK, man?
-Yeah.
BEN LASHES: So that's when all
of a sudden this video that no
one had cared about started
exploding, going viral, and
turning his life upside
down a little bit.
BRAD O'FARRELL: And I was
originally going to do a
series of them, so I sort of
made it into a template of--
I can easily repeat this
template later, like a
knock-knock joke
type template.
BEN LASHES: And why it
was smart and why it
caught on so well was--
so much about the internet
that's about shocking people
as much as you can.
BRAD O'FARRELL: Then I saw
people starting unprompted
doing parodies.
I was like, whoa.
BEN LASHES: A lot of these
videos that it got put with,
you almost don't know if
it's right to laugh.
It could be the most awful thing
that you've ever seen,
and if you put Keyboard
Cat at the end of it,
then you can smile.
BRAD O'FARRELL: When it was
happening, I was like, yeah.
I was talking to people about
that all the time.
Because something I did was on
MTV Movie Awards, and Bill
O'Reilly said that Keyboard
Cat was a patriot.
I just wanted to talk about
it, because it was an
interesting thing that was
going on in my life.
BEN LASHES: About a year and a
half into it, we'd already
done a Wonderful Pistachios
commercial.
-Keyboard Cat does
it purrrfectly.
BEN LASHES: Movie trailer from
"Exit Through the Gift Shop,"
but he did it with all cats and
he called it "Exit Through
the Pet Shop." Still getting
some cool deals coming across
that was making Keyboard
Cat a household name.
BRAD O'FARRELL: Most of the
stuff that's popular on
YouTube isn't bloggers trying
really hard to be popular.
It's a baby biting
another baby.
-Charlie, that really hurt.
Charlie bit me.
BRAD O'FARRELL: You know, all
these people that do things on
the internet, there's two
different categories.
There's some people who ended
up doing internet stuff, and
they don't know how they got
there, Like "David After the
Dentist," where the little boy
was at the dentist, and then
he was on drugs.
And he's in the car, and he's
like, is this real life?
-Stay in your seat.
-[SCREAMING]
I don't feel tired.
-You don't?
-Uh uh.
BRAD O'FARRELL: You ever
seen Tron Guy?
He's this guy in a latex Tron
costume, but he's really old
and fat and has a pot belly.
TRON GUY: I will never
again be anonymous.
And one of these days,
somebody's going to come up
with a way to synthesize
3D images from
pictures on the internet.
And 3D models of me are going
to float around known space
until there isn't any more.
BRAD O'FARRELL: You know "Where
the Hell is Matt," the
guy who dances all
over the world?
His wife is somebody
at Google.
I've met him like eight times
and never on purpose.
I'll be traveling to a place,
and he'll just happen to be
also in that place, because
we both go to
internet videos things.
People I've met on the internet
and at internet
conferences and stuff is like
an alternate set of high
school alumni friends, where you
just follow where everyone
is and you vaguely
keep in touch.
Do you guys know about meme
characters at all?
So Scumbag Steve is
one of those.
It's a photo of a guy in
a really obnoxious hat.
And he just looks
like a douche.
And people caption it stuff
like, borrows your lighter and
never gives it back.
Your girlfriend's drunk,
I'll take her home--
stuff like that.
He turned out to be
a real person.
BLAKE BOSTON: Yo, what's up?
This is Blake Boston
aka Scumbag Steve.
[MUSIC PLAYING - BLAKE BOSTON,
"SCUMBAG STEVE OVERTURE"]
BLAKE BOSTON: Scumbag Steve is
that guy you do not want
around, all right?
He'll steal your lighter, he'll
steal your girlfriend,
he'll steal anything
that you have.
You have him sleep over
at your house,
he's taking your mama.
BRAD O'FARRELL: He's also not
a scumbag at all, but he has
the demeanor of a scumbag.
He talks and makes jokes like
he's a scumbag, but he's
actually super nice.
[MUSIC PLAYING - BLAKE BOSTON,
"SCUMBAG STEVE OVERTURE"]
BRAD O'FARRELL: I think I've run
out of things really with
Keyboard Cat.
I'm sort of just sick of doing
stuff related to Keyboard Cat.
I don't care about it that
much anymore, but it's
interesting that it happened
to me at some point.
[MUSIC PLAYING]