CARL AZUZ, CNN ANCHOR: As we kick off this
Tuesday edition of CNN STUDENT NEWS, we are
going to take off reporting on a trip of the
new U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry. This
is his first trip overseas since he became
secretary. And that kind of travel is something
Kerry can expect a lot of: visiting other
countries and working with their leaders is
one of the biggest parts of his new job. The
Secretary of State is the president`s top
advisor on foreign policy. The president comes
up with his own policies when it comes to
how the U.S. interacts with other nations,
then it`s the secretary`s responsibility to
carry those policies out.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
JOHN KERRY, U.S. SECRETARY OF STATE: In today`s
global world, there is no longer anything
foreign about foreign policy. More than every
before, the decisions that we make from the
safety of our shores don`t just ripple outward.
They also create a current right here, in
America.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Secretary Kerry will probably take a
lot of trips to other countries, but this
one is getting some deeper attention.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
NICHOLAS BURNS, FORMER STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:
First trips by an American Secretary of State
overseas are watched very closely. There`s
a lot of symbolism attached to them. People
look for clues as to which region is most
important for the United States.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: The last Secretary of State, Hillary
Clinton headed east for her first trip. Experts
say that showed President Obama`s focus on
Asia. Secretary Kerry is heading to nine countries
on his eleven day trip: England, Germany,
France, Italy, Turkey, Egypt, Saudi Arabia,
the United Arab Emirates and Qatar. In Europe,
he`ll be talking with America`s traditional
allies, he`ll also be rallying their support
in the ongoing dispute over Iran`s controversial
nuclear program. And for any next steps to
help the opposition groups fighting the Syrian
government.
Sometimes severe weather alerts can be a little
confusing. Is a watch worse than a warning?
How serious is an advisory? Well, National
Weather Service`s message in Amarillo, Texas
yesterday was pretty clear.
Do not travel. All caps. You could see why.
A blizzard, one that the weather service called
historic, hit the Texas panhandle. This thing
was dropping snow at a rate of two to three
inches per hour. Officials said, nearly all
the roads in the panhandle were impossible.
The National Guard was being called out to
help drivers who got stranded. Even snow plows
had to be pulled off the roads because of
whiteout conditions in Texas and Oklahoma.
A whiteout is a blizzard that you just can`t
see through. Driving in one, incredibly dangerous.
Yesterday we talked about homeless man who
returned a woman`s diamond ring that she accidentally
dropped in his collection cup. Quick reaction
on that from our blog: Chandler says, "The
value is on what`s important. It`s the significance
of the object. I wouldn`t return $100 bill,
but I would look for the owner of a cell phone
despite it being worth $40."
Patrick would keep whatever he found, "even
if giving it back is generous, I still have
to support my life and survive."
Serenity says, you never know what something
means to someone. "I would try to return a
piece of jewelry, but if it`s a $10 bill,
there`s little chance of finding a legit owner."
Teachers, we want to hear from you, too. It`s
cnnstudentnews.com. Please, take a moment
to tell us what you thought of today`s show.
February 26th 2012, exactly one year ago,
two strangers met in Sanford, Florida. One
died that night, the other is on trial for
second degree murder. What happened caused
outrage on both sides and led the protests
across the country. Trayvon Martin was 17.
He was walking home from a convenience store.
He was unarmed. George Zimmerman was 29. He
was a neighborhood watch captain, he was carrying
a gun. We know there was some kind of confrontation
between them, and we know that Zimmerman shot
and killed Martin. Attorneys for Martin`s
family say he was racially profiled and shot
"in cold blood".. Zimmerman said he shot in
self-defense after Martin attacked him. When
police were called out to the scene, they
did not arrest Zimmerman, they said they didn`t
have enough evidence to disproof his story.
As news of the incident spread, people held
rallies and protests across the country. Eventually,
Zimmerman was arrested and charged with second
degree murder. The cases don`t go to trial
immediately. His lawyers are building their
defense right now as prosecutors plan their
legal strategy. The trial, the state of Florida
versus George Zimmerman is scheduled to start
in June.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today`s "Shoutout" goes
out to Mr. Ball`s young adult class at Liberty
School in Saline, Michigan. What part of a
plant produced pollen? You know what to do.
So, it the anther, petal, pistil or sepal?
You`ve got three seconds, go!
Those pollen grains that could wreak havoc
on allergies are produced in the anther. The
male part of the plant. That`s your answer
and that`s your "Shoutout"
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Whether or not you believe in the perfunctory
prognostications of Punxsutawney Phil who
said spring is coming early this year, there`s
something in the air we can count on every
year. Yes, pollen as in excuse (ph) me while
I sneeze again. You can blame men for this
one, at least the male components of plants.
They produce countless grains of the stuff
that fertilizes other plants, but also sometimes
winds up planted in our nooses. Here is the
fun part: and by fun I mean terrible: in some
parts of the U.S. pollen sneezing is staring
early this year. Tree pollen is supposed to
pick in March, grass pollen in the following
weeks, but regions from the nation`s capital
to north Texas saw pollen counts spike in
February. What does that mean? Well researchers
count the number of pollen grains in a cubic
meter of air. A count of 120 or more is considered
"high", but in recent years, the south east
has seen counts in the thousands. If you are
not allergic, you`ll notice the pollen on
your yellow car, which didn`t start out yellow.
If you are allergic, you`ll know by the coughing,
sneezing wheezing, sniffling, allergic suffering
that pollen brings you. The worst times for
pollen are dawn and dusk, so you want to try
to be indoors then. The best - right after
it rains, when the air is clearer. Here`s
hoping your pollen season isn`t appalling.
Something else you can count on around this
time every year - spring training. Games don`t
officially count until the end of March, but
the next several weeks are a big deal to the
guys trying to make the team. The fans showing
up at the ball part in the cities that host
the annual events. Mark McKey (ph) covers
the basis on the spring tradition for the
boys of summer.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: You could say it`s like
a car. You got to get it warmed up before
you get it out there on the open road, and
that`s what baseball teams do in the spring.
It`s an annual right of spring were Major
League teams make their way to Florida and
Arizona to get ready for the 162 game regular
season. In Florida, they play what`s known
as the Great Fruit League. And that, of course,
mainly teams on the East Coast with some Midwest
teams thrown in. The Cactus League, that`s
the spring training sites in Arizona, and
mainly West Coast teams are a part of that
league.
It usually takes pitchers a lot, an extra
four to five weeks to get ready for the actual
start of the regular season. So, when you
have the pitchers in there, working on their
arms, they need somebody to catch the balls,
and that`s where the catchers also report
earlier than a lot of the position players
do.
A lot of Minor League players show up and
try to prove themselves to the Major League
coaches and managers that they belong on the
team. If they don`t make the Major League
roster, then they go back to the Minor League
to hone their craft.
If the Major League player gets injured, or
he has to go on the disabled list, a lot of
those Minor League players will come up from
those teams and actually make the big roster.
So, there`s a lot riding on the spring training
weeks for these Minor League players.
Fans will come to spring training, and want
to see these stars, these superstars players.
And you have to remember in spring training,
it is a warm-up period, you will see a lot
of the stars of the future on these teams,
a lot of the Minor League players that want
to make the rosters. You will see superstars
sprinkled into these games, the spring training
games, but you`re not going to be necessarily
guaranteed to see your favorite player, you
have to hope for the best.
Baseball being America`s pastime, spring training
has taken on a life of its own. It`s a wonderful
opportunity for fans to get close up to the
game, and to the players who play the game.
Autograph opportunities, even conversation
with players along the sidelines, commonly
seeing spring training sites all throughout
the south, if you`re able to take this in,
and you have a favorite team. That would certainly
make a point of heading to spring training
one of these years.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Sticking to sports to wrap things up,
a shot you just got to see.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
(CHEERS AND APPLAUSE)
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Ashlee Arnau just hit a front flip half-court
shot. We`re not the only one impressed by
this cheerleader`s amazing fit. The Harlem
Globetrotter asked Ashley to show them how
it`s done. If you think her trick shock was
a one time fluke ...
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
GLOBETROTTER: Yes.
(CHEERS AND APPLAUSE)
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: But then, the Globetrotter in this Youtube
video then tries to recreate Ashlee`s achievement.
His form still needs a little work, maybe,
but at least he made the shot. If you can
put it all together, the crowd might flip
out. But if they`ve already seen Ashlee`s
performance, they know the real score. That
used up the remainder of our time. For CNN
STUDENT NEWS, I`m Carl Azuz. We`ll see you
tomorrow.