But actually I'm a professional
idiot with
decades of experience.
On your marks, get
set, Shoenice.
And I just open up my throat
and just something happens,
and I just know.
It's like Evel Knievel jumping
over them 20 buses.
He knows he can die.
But once he gets over it,
it's epic for life.
Here's to you.
People must think I'm nuts.
I'm in the right place
at the right time to
do whatever I want.
I don't want to be president
of the United States.
I'll save the world from the
number one YouTube channel.
It's a nice day today.
A nice day to go swimming.
Maybe we'll go swimming
later on.
All I do is travel around
the world, you know?
My family threw me out
two years ago.
Because they just didn't
understand my YouTube career
and what it's all about.
It always seems like I stay in
a hotel near a cemetery.
I don't know why.
But like the last four hotels
I've been in, I come out in
the morning, and it's daylight,
there's a cemetery.
I don't know if God's trying
to tell me something.
But either way, Lake George,
New York, just
spreading the word.
We had a great house,
great family.
My father and mom had me
and my two brothers.
Really good times.
And then just things started
changing in the house.
My father wasn't home
every night.
And eventually there was
a for sale sign out.
And we went from a nice,
everybody had their own
bedroom, to like a one-bedroom
with my mom who literally just
started drinking from
all the problems.
It's been about 35 years.
Nothing's changed.
We just bounced from apartment
to apartment.
Because me and my brothers were
so crazy that literally
landlords would just say, you're
a great lady, but your
kids are psycho.
What's going on, buddy?
MIKE: How you doing?
SHOENICE: I used to live
here as a kid.
Now I'm famous on YouTube, so
we're doing a documentary
about my life.
My name's Chris, by the way.
Nice to meet you.
You own this property?
SHOENICE: Yeah, we played
around the garage.
I just always remember
we weren't
supposed to go somewhere.
And finally the landlord, maybe
it's the one who owned
it, and just said listen, you
got three great sons, but
they're animals.
You got to move out.
We weren't bad kids, but we just
spray painted the sides
of people's houses.
We don't know why.
We were only seven.
But never did anything bad.
It was nice meeting you.
All right.
Take it easy, man.
Oh, the old neighborhood--
never changes.
As far back as I can remember,
I just was always the kid on
the playground or outside
in the yard.
And just everybody in the
neighborhood knew I would eat
crazy things.
So I was eating grass at first,
and I'd swallow pebbles.
Then my home economics class,
I just started eating the
salt, the baking soda.
And actually, it became such
a trending thing in home
economics that they always
knew that our group would
never be able to finish
the cake or
the muffins or whatever.
Because I already ate half
the ingredients.
And then it became just like
something that I knew I could
make money off of.
I got three guys from England
that don't believe I can drink
three bottles of Budweiser with
the tops on them in under
a minute with no hands.
On your mark, get
set, Shoenice!
So I was in a high school with
gangs and the principal got
his ear half cut-off.
So I knew it was time to go.
My mom said, if you want to quit
high school, you have to
join the Army.
And I said, no problem.
So I joined the Army.
I did my basic training.
I did all this other stuff.
Eventually, Baghdad was
being bombed in 1991.
I'm watching it with
my roommates.
Wow, man, they're
tearing shit up.
The phone rings.
Is this Christopher Thomas
Schewe, 097 B, B, B, B, B?
So I knew once they said my
social security number they
were coming off the IOR list.
So I went out there.
I was food supply.
I basically just fed all the
troops food and water as they
came through.
One day there was a sandstorm.
And I found these two little
kids buried in
this little sand dune.
I gave them some ravioli and
Dinty Moore beef stew.
You could see just the energy
come back in them, too.
And just things like that are
why I want to make sure no kid
goes to bed hungry anymore
in the world.
Now the YouTube community has
allowed me to take that next
level into what I've always
believed in-- stopping global
hunger for good.
I'm going to explain to you
something, to everybody, and
this is the way it is.
My mom told me that someday,
Chris, you're
going to save the world.
And she knew it, too, because
that's what I'm going to do.
Actually, my son signed me
up for YouTube when he
was eight years old.
I didn't even know that you
could have a YouTube channel.
So he was actually the one
that signed me up.
And then he said, Dad, the only
way you're really going
to let people know
that you're on
YouTube is to join Facebook.
So once I posted a YouTube in,
and there was 40 views the
next day, I was sold.
I just knew that was the best
advertising for whatever you
wanted to sell or believe in.
When I first did YouTube,
I just did a joke.
It builds up, and people were
suggesting, why don't you do
what you did in high school
at the cafeteria table?
You used to take the toilet
paper, the napkins, and you'd
eat it all.
I go, OK, I'll do that.
So I did a three-part series
where I ate a whole roll of
1,000 sheets of toilet paper
in like 10 minutes.
That literally is
what blew me up.
And all my eating stunts after
Elmer's glue were all requests
from my fans.
Go to my buddy Nathan's
diner, Wakin' Bacon.
I was just here the other day.
I set a new challenge
for his menu.
Hey, there's my buddy Ian!
We know everybody in the town.
How you doing, Ian?
I'm going to come have
some breakfast.
How you doing?
IAN: Awesome.
SHOENICE: All right.
What are you looking at?
[INAUDIBLE]
a [INAUDIBLE] drive by.
We just kid around.
The town knows us around here
that we don't play games.
Hey everyone, Shoenice again.
Well, basically this
is my first
interview as a famous YouTuber--
glazed420, otherwise
known as Ian.
Dude's no joke.
Helped me out a lot,
he's my friend.
IAN: And then I found out that
he was in [INAUDIBLE]
or something.
He's walking down Lake
George, the road.
And I'm like Shoenice!
And then we basically
immediately hit it off.
I have a separate YouTube.
It's called glazed420.
I do things like working out,
because I do calisthenics.
So I'll do like a minute
and a half handstand.
I'll do a bunch of pull-ups.
I do a bunch of goofy videos.
I have one that's pretty viral
where I'm getting tased by a
cop at a fish show.
The video went viral-- has
about 40,000 views.
SHOENICE: I can't
do it anymore!
I can't do it!
I can't do it, Ian!
Thank you.
Took the breath right
out of me.
I might have looked like a
little bitch, but you do it.
Oh my God, my room keys
are in my pants, bro.
JIM: I've known Chris
for years.
On and off for 11 years.
And he just recently started
staying at the motel and
telling me of his success
on YouTube.
People just living
at the hotel, it
don't happen too often.
We're against it.
But Chris can stay here
any time right now.
Because he'll bring a smile
to my face when I'm
having a bad day.
You can't go wrong with that.
IAN: With Shoenice, his style on
YouTube, he likes it to be
very simple.
He doesn't want any intro with
the letterheads and all that.
He wants it simple and
down to the point.
SHOENICE: All right, all right.
I'm ready.
Let's eat some glue today.
Hey, everyone.
Shoenice again.
Well, basically, you're probably
wondering why I'm
wearing a microphone
right now.
Well, the Vice documentary crew,
they actually showed up
here today.
And they're videotaping
me right now.
And we got my man Dan.
He's got a bottle of wood glue,
and he's going to open
up the top and he's going
to pour it in my mouth.
Somebody's actually
testing it out.
DAN: Yeah.
SHOENICE: It's glue.
I love you, bro.
On your mark, get set, don't
kill me, Shoenice.
All right, keep going, bro.
Uh huh, all right, go.
Oh man, is it almost done?
DAN: Uh uh.
SHOENICE: Oh, God.
Oh man, not in the face, bro!
Now [INAUDIBLE] is going
to want my job!
I got to go out later!
Hold on.
It's coming out of
my nose, hold on.
Water's for pussies,
but glue isn't.
All right, man.
Let's finish this up, bro.
OK, I'd say it's good enough.
I'd say that's good
enough, don't you?
DAN: Yeah.
SHOENICE: Time.
Time.
Thank you.
Bomb.
That's how we do
a Shoenice vid.
I'm going to go clean
myself up.
How you doing?
Either way, basically what I
do is medicinal marijuana.
I've got Crohn's disease.
So either way, this is what I do
for my medications instead
of spending thousands of dollars
on medicines that give
you more side effects than the
actual Crohn's disease.
And I've been in remission
for 25 years just smoking
something that comes
out of the ground.
So either way, how you doing?
A lot of people probably don't
like me smoking weed and doing
videos for teenage kids.
But I'd rather see a kid
smoke a tree than get
wrapped around one.
Let's get rid of the alcohol,
you know what I mean?
But then the prisons would
be only about 30% full.
This is one of my secrets.
Cranberry juice solves
all problems.
All right, all right, let's get
this loaded up to YouTube.
Vice documentary on location.
When I started YouTube, I never
had an enemy in my life.
So I don't know what
it was like to
be like a Rush Limbaugh.
Like all these people
just hate you.
A lot of people argue
between each other
on my comment boards.
I mean, I'll go back the next
day, and they've literally
argued for hours on end over
the most stupidest things.
Let me just get a feel for what
the people are saying in
the comment board.
I don't think it's going to be
anything other than oh my God,
this is incredible.
Bad ass, you.
This is the only time I'm going
to say first is best,
love the behind the
scenes, Shoenice.
Vice has sunk to a new low.
Blah, whatever.
These are just people that fight
over first, actually.
You look so fucking
baked, haha.
Awesome, haha, it sounds like
you're really enjoying it.
I just think that there's a lot
of people out there that
are just jealous of me.
They want to sit at home
and to do what they do.
I get bottles of liquor
sent to me.
And I get drunk, and
I get paid for it.
It's fun to troll.
IAN: Don't feed the troll.
Don't feed the troll.
But that's what I'm saying.
SHOENICE: Trolling means you
say or do things to get a
negative reaction
out of someone.
You're just trying to say
something just to get them
irked, you know what I mean?
You want one of these?
-Sure.
SHOENICE: You want to eat one?
-Yeah.
SHOENICE: Really?
SHOENICE: You're going
to eat one.
-Yeah.
SHOENICE: You're going
to eat one with me?
I'm not opening it.
Oh, you got sugar porn
on your lap.
I'm going like this.
-Oh, no!
OK.
SHOENICE: Well you can't
eat them-- it keeps
all the sugar together.
Some people have made these
fake rest in peace videos.
Like, my brother died trying
to-- and it hurts me.
I'm saving a billion children
before my heart stops beating.
So if we lose one to a tampon
stunt, I just call collateral
damage to be honest with you.
Everybody tries to impersonate
their heroes sometime.
And I just have over 5,000
parody vids of people either
hating me, imitating me--
-Shoenice here again.
SHOENICE: Attempting
my stunts.
Just shouting me out.
Or literally they just want
to find me and kill me.
I don't understand.
-Shoenice is a fake,
everybody.
I just want you guys
to know that.
SHOENICE: I took all the beer
out of my fridge on the 4th of
July, and I went straight
for six years.
And then I started
doing YouTube.
I was still straight.
My ex-wife couldn't
handle the fame.
So she's like, you've
got to go, and I
moved out to the garage.
You can see how I have
some garage vids.
And then I just eventually
just left the property.
And I knew I wasn't putting
my son to bed that
night, so time to drink.
On your mark, get set.
Everclear.
Because that's the only reason
why I put the bottle down, is
for family.
So without them, I was
chaotic again.
I was homeless for a while.
I did Matchbook stunts.
On your mark, get
set, Shoenice!
Hard!
-Look at his tongue.
-I'm all ready.
SHOENICE: Ha ha, hee
haw, bitches!
Every bar banned me.
I mean, I literally couldn't
go anywhere.
Hello, everybody.
Shut up.
This is Shoenice22.
I'm going to eat a tampon
in under a minute, bro.
I've always been used to
living under a roof.
So when I was like thrown out,
there was nothing I could do.
I couldn't get to my bank
account or whatever.
But I had that specialty of just
freaking out people on
the street.
And I could go into a bar flat
broke, and I'd walk out with
$400 drunk as a skunk
an hour later.
So it worked for me, but there's
people out there that
don't have my talent,
you know?
I met this hotel owner that was
rehabbing all these hotels.
He actually fed me, gave me
a place to do my laundry.
JIM: Yeah, he borrowed my
car, went to the store.
And comes back and it's full of
gas, and gave me money, and
this and that.
I mean, he's got a big heart.
He likes to make people
happy, I guess.
SHOENICE: Basically, I'm
going to save the
whole country of Africa.
So we're going to
start practicing
doing donation drive-bys.
These people never seen us
before behind us, and we're
going to go surprise this one
lady with a $20 bill.
-You're not a--
SHOENICE: I'm serious.
I make money off of Google.
I know what it's like
to be homeless.
I'm not saying you are,
but what we do
is we help out people.
All I had was a $20 on me, but
this guy Ian, my cameraman, is
very friendly.
-Is this going to be on TV?
SHOENICE: I've been on "Tosh.0,"
"World's Dumbest." I
mean, I'm just a crazy fella.
Hey, we were so poor growing
up, my mom used to say, you
better finish everything
on your plate.
There's people right now
starving in the living room.
Get it?
I think my mom was just a woman
that just was too young
to have three sons on her own.
Eventually alcohol took over.
And literally it would
be like she would go
out on a Friday night.
She wouldn't want to, you know,
forget about her kids.
But she would go into
a blackout.
Obviously, go somewhere
other than her home.
And then the neighbors were
wondering when she'd pull in
like the next afternoon.
I always was able to suffice
when we didn't
have food in the house.
If you didn't have a Miracle
Whip sandwich, I'd just take
some sheets off the
toilet paper roll.
I think I still do
it to this day.
It fills your belly.
But my father eventually came
and got us, and times went on.
See, I don't like to hang
out with drunk people.
My mother was a chronic
alcoholic.
She was a great lady.
But when I found her dead at 56
on the living room floor, I
knew she was out
of her misery.
Because she lived
off of vodka.
I guess that's where I get
my liquor slamming
stunts from, you know?
My mom always had that big
bottle of vodka, right
underneath the kitchen sink
next to the dish soap.
I thought it was normal to
go to eighth grade in
a blackout by lunch.
I mean, we just used to take
the whole glass of vodka to
the bus stop.
We'd all pass it around
and go to school.
But it'll catch up
to you someday.
It'll catch up to me.
They sent me a bottle of Devil's
Springs, 160 proof--
30 proof less.
Now, what I'm going to
do is talk to you
before I slam this bottle.
Nothing's fake about this.
I just have a really crazy
tolerance for liquor.
The Devil's Springs was
kind of freaky--
160 proof.
My friends were there.
I kind of like was lethargic
and passing out, and they
couldn't wake me up.
So I woke up actually with
a tube down my throat.
It's the only time I've ever
had my stomach pumped.
And to be honest with
you, I was mad.
Because I didn't have insurance,
and I knew that
tube down my throat was about
a $400 procedure.
Alcohol leads to bad stuff.
The only two times I ever smoked
crack in my life was
when I was drunk.
I would never even think about
walking down the street
looking for a bump at 4:00 in
the morning going like this.
IAN: When Shoenice chugs bottles
of liquor, I feel
concerned for his health.
I don't want to see the guy end
up dying from one of his
drinking stunts.
And I showed my concern, and a
bunch of people on Facebook
and YouTube have showed
the concern.
So he did one stunt with a
bottle of Everclear to end all
the drinking stunts.
He defeats death in a way.
You know what I mean?
Because some of this stuff,
normal people
would die from it.
And it's just like people
like that about
death-defying things.
And like wow, he must be
some kind of mutant.
There's something special about
Shoenice where he can
handle that kind of stuff.
JIM: It's hard for anybody to
hear, but then there's smokers
and stuff like that.
Life is full of choices, and
he's making a choice.
And do I agree with it?
No.
But it's getting him somewhere,
isn't it?
Would I do it?
No.
But people do anything
for money, they say.
So if he's getting a little
money out of it, that's why
he's eating glue, and tampons,
and everything else.
SHOENICE: And what I do is I'm
basically trying to figure out
who can really handle being
a part of my revolution.
I got Muslims hanging out with
whites from southern Alabama.
I mean, I've literally had
people coming and going
Shoenice, you saved
me from a suicide.
You brought us back together
as a couple.
And it's just, you're in our
lives now, don't never leave.
Stop all the craziness,
because you
will save the world.
So I mean, I'm a lot of
people's higher power.
I'm their antidepressant.
It's just like, where's
it going to lead to?
It scares me sometimes.
SHOENICE: I'm hoping I can stop
global hunger in three
years because I'm
getting tired.
But if I die, I know
that there'll be
people that carry on.
I'll be a better martyr and a
better human on this planet,
that's a guarantee.
Shoenice!
Na, ha, ha, hee haw, bitches!
I own this town!
You heard me.
Trying to play dead
in the cemetery.
All right.
It's a nice day.
[BEEP]
SHOENICE: Hi, Aaron,
it's Shoenice.
Great job on the documentary.
I loved everything.
One thing I would like to take
back that I said though, is
that if a child died imitating
one of my stunts on YouTube it
would be collateral damage
towards my revolution.
Actually, I would like
to take that back.
It would be devastating to me
just for me to even think that
I had any possibility in the
way of somebody dying.
So, yeah, I appreciate you
doing my life story.
It should help me out a lot
with my hunger campaign.
But that was just the one thing
I really wish I could
stick my foot in my mouth
on is that comment about
collateral damage for a teenage
kid to die imitating
one of my stunts.
Because that would literally
break my heart.
OK.
Thanks, Aaron.
But if you keep it in, that's
no problem either.
Documentary's a documentary.
Ba, ha, ha, ha, hee haw.
Thank you.