Right now.
Lunchtime upper decker.
Who doesn't like that?
You know?
I'm like no, really, that's
not a good idea.
Stop me.
Somebody got to stop me.
[MUSIC - TiDUS, DELANCY]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
EDDIE HUANG: Yo, I'm going to
drop the ill disclaimer on you
here, the "Midsummer Night's
Dream." If we shadows have
offended, blame vice.
Because we're here, since
there's a cheap ride from San
Francisco to LA.
Two episodes, one plane flight,
you already know.
The saving grace is that I'm
introducing you to my dude Roy
Choi, and we're going
to East LA.
Which is actually a very
charming, ill, Mexican
neighborhood, and we're going to
have the best tacos you've
ever seen at Guisados.
EDDIE HUANG: What's up Roy?
ROY CHOI: What's up man?
EDDIE HUANG: What's good?
How's it going?
ROY CHOI: Good, welcome to
East LA, Boyle Heights.
EDDIE HUANG: This is
not Hollywood kid.
ROY CHOI: It's not Hollywood,
but it is the
real LA, you know?
EDDIE HUANG: Definitely.
I've been to LA a few times, and
really it's suspect to me.
You know what I'm saying?
Everyone I come visit is
just trying to show me
another pool deck.
You know?
Another roof deck.
ROY CHOI: This is
the real deal.
This is East LA man.
EDDIE HUANG: Oh wow.
ROY CHOI: This is a piece of
culture you don't see much on
the east coast.
Because you don't get a lot of
the same immigration to New
York from the states of Mexico
that you get here.
So this is chicharon.
EDDIE HUANG: Just so you all
know, usually I give you a lot
of the food technical aspects.
But this is Chef vs. Chef, Spy
vs. Spy today man, I'm going
to leave it to Roy, you
know what I mean?
This is his town.
It's always ill to
meet other Jedis.
And Roy is definitely
Jedi master.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
EDDIE HUANG: So what
are we getting Roy?
ROY CHOI: You got to
get anything here.
The cochinita pibil,
the mole poblano.
I don't meat anymore, so I'm
going to get some of the
veggie stuff.
EDDIE HUANG: For real?
ROY CHOI: Yeah.
Armando, you got to give
him some of your best.
Probably the cochinita right?
ARMANDO: The cochinita.
And today's special, we have
costillas in mole negro.
ROY CHOI: That's probably
good for him.
ARMANDO: OK.
EDDIE HUANG: Thank
you so much.
Where do you live in LA?
ROY CHOI: In Korean town.
EDDIE HUANG: OK, did you
grow up out there?
ROY CHOI: I moved
around a lot.
My parents came in
the early '70s.
For any Asian immigrant
at that time you
couldn't get a job.
Because you were looked at
as a brown, slanty-eyed,
dark-haired motherfucker.
EDDIE HUANG: Yeah, you washed
clothes or you cooked food, or
you drove cars.
ROY CHOI: Washed clothes,
or cooked
food, or you're a janitor.
Or, with the Koreans coming in
the early days here in LA, you
opened your own business.
During my main period of
elementary school, I was
mainly in the restaurant.
That's where a lot of my whole
understanding and love
of food came from.
EDDIE HUANG: I came back to
food after doing the law,
trying to be a journalist,
doing all these things.
Because I realized that I would
be given a fair shake in
food, but I wouldn't be given
a fair shake at a lot of
other-- people expect us
to be good at food.
ROY CHOI: For me, a lot of my
cousins are really smart and
do really well, and I was
always the black sheep.
You know?
Like fuck man, I can't
sit in this
laboratory and split cells.
I just can't do that.
And then it started to wear on
my whole consciousness of like
I'm a fucking loser,
I'm a failure.
EDDIE HUANG: Because you didn't
fit this model minority
stereotype thing.
ROY CHOI: I didn't fit that, and
then I think it took this
whole generation through the
'80s and '90s for us to mutate
and evolve.
And now it's just coming into
fruition where we're doing it
with expression in
our own ways.
This is homemade masa for
tamales and tortillas.
Come on in.
Especially for you
East Coast guys.
This stuff is new to y'all.
ARMANDO: This is dried corn,
it comes in a dry state.
And it doesn't actually boil
and it doesn't cook.
We just steep it.
After it's rinsed it goes into
the hopper right behind you.
[SNEEZES]
EDDIE HUANG: I'm sorry.
Man, the smell and flavor
is so strong,
I'm sneezing in here.
ARMANDO: Take this
ground corn.
At this point we can take this
and add lard, shortening, to
it, and make masa for tamales.
At this point it's good
for tortillas.
EDDIE HUANG: Delicious.
You don't usually see
this process.
ROY CHOI: You don't.
This is the west coast pizza
dough right here.
[LAUGHTER]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
ARMANDO: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
ROY CHOI: Amazing.
EDDIE HUANG: Hot sauce?
ARMANDO: Yeah, hot sauce.
EDDIE HUANG: Yeah, let's
get some on the side.
ROY CHOI: The thing
about Guisados, is
guisados means a stew.
This is a stewed style
of taco, but I
think you'll enjoy.
EDDIE HUANG: No, I
tell you what.
Unless it's a high heat broiled,
I really think
proteins should be
slow-roasted, braised, something.
Something to get the glutamates
out in a slower way.
ROY CHOI: This is kind of like
the LA vibe right here.
When you're eating, there ain't
nowhere else to go.
There's no before,
there's no after.
It's just right now.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
EDDIE HUANG: I've never had a
tortilla like this, this good.
Anywhere outside of East LA,
in America you don't see
tortillas like this.
You know, I grew
up in Orlando.
A lot of Mexicans in Orlando.
They made great tortillas, but
they were the white ones, the
flat, that are more flimsy.
This is toothsome, this
is like al dente.
You know?
ROY CHOI: Yeah.
This fucking salsa
is so spicy.
EDDIE HUANG: Mm.
ROY CHOI: Hell yeah, right?
Oh man.
EDDIE HUANG: Oh yeah.
That chili sauce is en fuego,
I'm not doing that.
My ass would be on
fire by 7:00 PM.
ROY CHOI: The last two
generations of American kids,
you wake up and you have
fucking Pop Tarts.
And then at lunch, you have
a fucking Hot Pocket.
You know?
And then at dinner,
you're having
fucking Hamburger Helper.
And none of that shit is at a
table, none of that shit is
with other people.
On a daily fucking basis,
that shit is just
fucking like corrosive.
EDDIE HUANG: There's people
who eat microwave
meals or Pop Tarts.
There's us who eat homemade.
We all do what we do because of
the environments we grew up
in, and we just want people
to get the whole spectrum.
And you make your
own decision.
ROY CHOI: I want to make food
as cool as Monsters and Red
Bulls and Pop Tarts.
I want to make it as
cool as the McRib.
So that way food is a part
of their life, and
they can make a choice.
EDDIE HUANG: Much
respect, kid.
Much fucking respect.
ROY CHOI: Yeah you got to
pay homage, definitely.
EDDIE HUANG: I really don't hang
out with that many chefs.
And Roy is one of those
people that transcends
being a chef to me.
He understands things in and
outside of the plate.
He takes it beyond, and he's
really trying to tell a story
with his food, with his actions,
with his business.
And I really relate
to that a lot man.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
EDDIE HUANG: Next up on
"Fresh Off the Boat"
PETER: Back then the guy riding
shotgun had a shotgun.
I say the person sitting
in the passenger
seat now is my kid.
And I don't need nobody
shooting at me
because of old beefs.
EDDIE HUANG: Yeah.