SHANE SMITH: We met some crazy
characters yesterday.
I think the reason why they are
so eccentric is because
it's so oppressive here.
It's so stark and heavy, and
they're worried about the
secret police, the FSB coming to
get them, that they hide in
their eccentricities.
They're crazy guys with crazy
hair and big long beards.
In America, it's like
sort of Hollywood
and then indie films.
Here, it's crazy people making
crazy films based on very
far-out intellectual theory.
We're here to shoot
a film today.
And this is where we're going
to shoot today, which is an
old style in this
block of flats.
It's really stark, and cold,
and gray, and oppressive.
It reeks vaguely of shit,
people picking garbage.
And you say this is the most
expensive city on Earth.
ANDRE SILVESTROV:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
SHANE SMITH: Right.
ANDRE SILVESTROV:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
SHANE SMITH: I wanted to
understand exactly how
Alcho-Cinema was a subset of
Parallel Cinema, but they sort
of just grabbed me and
threw me in the room.
What am I interviewing
them about?
We were just, OK, here we go.
[TOASTING IN RUSSIAN]
SHANE SMITH: OK, you're
the leader.
How are you?
Nice to meet you.
Oh, thank you very much.
Oh, nice to meet you.
We came here to shoot an
Alcho-Cinema film.
They brought all of the
characters, set up the set.
They had a director.
They had a producer,
everybody--
no cameras.
It's kind of amazing.
[CHANTING IN RUSSIAN]
SHANE SMITH: What
are you doing?
What are you protesting?
MALE SPEAKER: We here drink
for the crisis.
Stop the crisis!
SHANE SMITH: Stop the crisis.
Stop the crisis.
MALE SPEAKER: We are against the
crisis, and we don't want
it anymore.
Stop the crisis!
MALE SPEAKERS: Stop
the crisis!
SHANE SMITH: Stop the crisis.
You have to drink vodka then
pickle, vodka then pickle,
vodka then fish, which, by the
way, made the room reek.
Because there's only pickled
fish, some sort of meat,
smoked cheese, pickled garlic.
That with lots of booze,
cigarettes, and the BO of
eight stinky men, it
was like a wall.
And that's what Alcho-Cinema
seems to be--
an excuse to get wasted.
I've had so much vodka in about
14 minutes that I'm
pouring with sweat right now.
SHANE SMITH: Capitalists.
SHANE SMITH: Death to
the capitalists.
Bitches.
What's amazing about it is, it's
not about communism, or
capitalism, or socialism,
or anything else.
Because they don't know
what it's about.
They don't know what
a global crisis is.
Russia was closed for so long
that this is all new to them.
It's like what the
fuck is going on?
We don't know what's going
on, but we're against it.
So we're going to protest it,
because protesting leads to
social change.
I guess so.
Not where we're from.
[MALE SPEAKER:
[SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN]
SHANE SMITH: So the more and
more people we met, the more
difficult we were finding
pegging down Parallel Cinema
and what it was.
We knew there was a lot
of booze involved.
There's a lot of crazy
characters.
But everyone said oh, you have
to go see Yvgeni Yufit.
He's still making films, and he
was the founding father of
the St. Petersburg division
of Parallel Cinema.
So we went to St. Petersburg
to check
out what he was doing.
We're on an old Soviet train
going towards St. Petersburg.
It's about 6:00 in
the morning.
I'm very tired.
I've heard about Yvgeni's
films and
they're pretty crazy.
I'm a little bit nervous.
Now where's this here?
Is that St. Petersburg?
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah, it's
St. Petersburg.
SHANE SMITH: We're going here.
So we arrived at St. Petersburg,
and it was a
really surrealistic scene
because there were just Army
guys everywhere and packs of
wild dogs roaming throughout
the train station.
We're here in St. Petersburg
after the
long trip from Moscow.
Yvgeni's got an exhibition here
at the Russian Museum of
Ethnography.
And we're going to go meet him
and check out some of his
artwork, and then, hopefully,
make a film with him, which
means I have to lie down with
thousands of naked bodies and
maybe have sex with them.
Inside--
it's an old palace of
Peter the Great's--
is this massive
floor-to-ceiling, beautiful,
pink marble room,
priceless room.
Hello?
Hello.
YVGENI YUFIT: Hello.
SHANE SMITH: Yvgeni Yufit?
YVGENI YUFIT: Yes.
SHANE SMITH: Pleasure
to meet you.
YVGENI YUFIT: Nice
SHANE SMITH: When we asked
Yvgeni about his paintings, he
explained that they were
inspired by a true event in
Russian history where the
military experimented with
making super soldiers by
breeding men with apes.
And if you think that sounds
fucked up, wait
until you see his films.
Now, Yvgeni's sub-strata of
Parallel Cinema is called
Necrorealism.
Now, during the socialist
realism period, you couldn't
show death, you couldn't show
bums, you couldn't show
unhappiness.
So Yvgeni just puts all of
that into his films.
Were you ever worried that you
would get in trouble from the
state when you were
making your films?
YVGENI YUFIT: [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
SHANE SMITH: So he asked us,
actually, hey, do you want to
make a movie?
And we said we'd like to do
that more than anything.
YVGENI YUFIT:
SHANE SMITH: Perfect.
YVGENI YUFIT: OK, thank you.
SHANE SMITH: Where Yvgeni took
us next was one of the most
amazing things I've ever seen.
It's the old headquarters of
the Soviet Documentary
Filmmaking Union.
Looks like it's straight
out of the '30s.
And it's just this huge old
building with floor-to-ceiling
old stock, old footage, just
racks of 35-mm cameras, and
nobody else, just Yvgeni.
He has the keys.
YVGENI YUFIT: Like
machine gun.
SHANE SMITH: Yeah, it's the
Kalashnikov of cameras.
[RUSSIAN OPERA MUSIC PLAYING]
MALE SPEAKER: That's
a tradition.
[CHUCKLES]
Live Stoli!
SHANE SMITH: Hey, thanks.
MALE SPEAKER: Broken seal!
SHANE SMITH: This place is
fucked for sending me here.
[RUSSIAN OPERA MUSIC PLAYING]
We're going down into the
pit of hell here.
[RUSSIAN OPERA MUSIC
PLAYING CRESCENDO]