this is CNN STUDENT NEWS.
We are going to start things off today in
Egypt. The country is going through some problems,
some political unrest right now. People are
angry with Egypt`s president and their protesting
against him. If that sounds familiar, it should:
nearly two years ago, Egypt was part of what
some called the Arab Spring: the series of
uprisings across the Middle East and Northern
Africa. That led to Egypt`s long time leader
being forced out of power. Egypt held its
first free elections after that, and Mohamed
Morsi was elected president. We reported on
Monday that Morsi announced that any decisions
he makes can`t be reviewed or overturned.
He says he is trying to protect Egypt as it
build its new government. The protesters say,
President Morsi is grabbing up power, kind
of like a dictator. Some of those protests
have turned violent. Hundreds of people have
been injured, at least one person was killed.
We are going to hop across the Atlantic and
head to Washington, D.C, specifically to the
White House for a meeting between a president
and a president-elect. Enrique Pena Nieto
was elected Mexico`s president back in July.
Now, he`s officially going to become president,
to take office on Saturday. Yesterday, he
was in Washington, D.C. for a meeting with
U.S. President Obama.
Immigration, security and the drug war in
Mexico have been some of the biggest issues
for these two countries recently. They were
expected to come up in yesterday`s meeting,
too, but President Elect P said he wants the
relationship between the U.S. and Mexico to
go beyond that. He said one of his biggest
goals is to strengthen the economic ties between
the neighboring nations. The U.S. is Mexico`s
biggest trading partner, sharing billions
of dollars in imports and exports.
A lot of the action in our next story is happening
at the U.S. Capitol. That`s where members
of Congress are considering the fiscal cliff
and how to avoid going over it. Now, really,
what this comes down to, is debt. The U.S.
government has it: trillions of dollars worth.
It`s got to try to find ways to reduce that
debt, and that`s where the fiscal cliff comes
in. Now, it`s not an actual cliff, it`s an
economic one. And it involves two main things:
one, how the government takes in money through
taxes and two, how it spends money.
If the country goes over this fiscal cliff,
taxes will go up for everyone, plus government
spending cuts will automatically go into a
fact. That would effect the military, national
parks and other government services. If Congress
and the president can agree on ways to cut
government debt, then the country won`t go
over the cliff. They`ve been working on that
for a while, both sides have presented ideas,
there was even the special super committee
in Congress that tried to come up with ways
to reduce the debt. So far, though, no deal.
And the deadline now is January, First. If
a deal is not reached by then, that`s when
the U.S. would go over this fiscal cliff.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Is this legit? Salmonella
is a type of virus.
This one is not true. Salmonella are bacteria
that can cause food poisoning and other health
problems.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Back in June, 41 people in 20 U.S. states
got sick because of a salmonella outbreak.
Officials with the FDA, the Food and Drug
Administration, traced this outbreak to a
peanut butter plant in New Mexico. On Monday,
regulators shut it down. Back in 2011, new
food safety laws gave the FDA the power to
shut facilities down. This is the first time
it`s done it. And an FDA report found the
conditions at the plant might have led to
the products there being contaminated with
salmonella. A spokeswoman for the company
that owns this plant says it`s working with
officials to get the proper health and safety
procedures in place.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today`s "Shoutout" goes
out to coach Cochran`s, coach Julian`s and
Mrs. McClanahan`s classes at Winfield High
School in Winfield, West Virginia.
What Central American country is highlighted
on this map?
You know what to do. Is it Costa Rica, Guatemala,
Honduras or Nicaragua? You`ve got three seconds,
go!
That`s Guatemala, a country that`s home to
more than 14 million people. That`s your answer
and that`s your "Shoutout."
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: A German fashion designer who lives
in Guatemala came up with an idea to help
clean up the country: stuff trash inside empty
plastic bottles. After a hurricane ripped
through her village, she realized her bottles
could be used to rebuild. That`s when the
ecobrick was born.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: I`m Susanna Heise (ph),
I`m the founder of the Pura Vida Movement.
We are here in like Atitlan (ph), and this
is in Guatemala in Central America. And this
is called the most beautiful lake on earth.
In the `60s, this new material plastic came.
That was totally new for them, plastic is
also -- it`s not a bad material, it helped
them a lot. But nobody told them like, look,
this is not a leaf, this is not going to decompose.
This is going to stay here for 20, 30, 50,
100, 500 years.
CHRIS BARRY, FMR. PEACE CORP VOLUNTEER: The
trash problem is affecting these communities
in several ways. Tourism is a big issue. Cyanobacteria
blows up in the lake. Tourists are no longer
allowed to swim, and that region is very much
dependent on tourism.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: This is the Pura Vida,
famous Pura Vida wall, built out of 1,000
ecobricks. And these ecobricks have been (inaudible)
by many children, kindergarten children.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: It is trash and it is
a container for trash. And when it`s filled
with trash, it has sufficient integrity to
be a building block.
BARRY: And you use those as a basic building
material, and you are also -- are able to
clean up the community and teach about environment
education and importance of maintaining a
clean environment around you, trash management,
all that kind of good stuff.
GERSON GUITZ, HUG IT FORWARD: We are building
a two-classroom school in a community in Pachai
(ph). This school serves about 200 kids. As
you can see, it takes about 6,000 bottles
to finish a whole construction, and this is
the last square that we are making right now.
And we are tying all the bottles, all the
bottles have to be the same height.
BARRY: People are really catching on to the
idea. Projects are growing in El Salvador,
Guyana, I`ve heard of a similar type building
in Thailand.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: It makes me so glad that
the idea of the (inaudible) is spreading from
like Atitlan towards all Guatemala, towards
the whole world. That`ll be a part of the
solution and not a part of the problem anymore.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: All around Indianapolis, people are
showing their support for Chuck Pagano. He
is the head coach of the NFL`s Indianapolis
Colts and he`s fighting cancer. A team cheerleader
offered to shave her head if the team`s mascot
could raise $10,000 for cancer research. He
raised $22,000. The cheerleader says she was
happy to lose her locks for the cause.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
MEGAN M., COLTS CHEERLEADER: I wasn`t freaked
out. I was just so excited and proud of our
city for pulling together for a great cause.
The cheers were deafening, it was just phenomenal,
I was able to have another cheerleader join
me at the last minute and be able to hold
her hand while we both went through this process.
It was just absolutely phenomenal, and, you
know, everyone hopes to make an impact in
their life, and I was just lucky enough that
Blue (ph) came up with this idea and we were
able to do something really good.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Yesterday, we told you about the college
basketball record set by Jack Taylor. Most
of you think, he is a basketball star. On
our blog, Haylie wrote, "Taylor deserves the
new record because if you have skill, you
should be able to shine!"
Brandon says "It`s unusual for anyone to score
that many points. Plus, he had the help of
his coach and the team to get him the ball
to make those shots."
And Ashley argues, "If Taylor`s team members
thought of him as a ball hog, they wouldn`t
have continuously passed the ball to him."
Brennan believes that scoring 138 points would
not make him a hero because he basically embarrassed
the other team, and that beat down could turn
those other players off to basketball.
Mark says, that while Taylor`s skills are
exceptional, "his teammates deserve more credit
for things like playing great defense and
hustling down the floor."
And from Olivia, "I do think he was a ball
hog, but does that term always have to be
negative? He did his job and what he was told
to do. He is a star and the ball hog, and
there is nothing wrong with that.
Remember, when you were a kid, and you would
sit in the cart at the grocery store, that
was kind of fun, right? This is the grownup
version. It`s 12 feet long, 9 feet tall. That
guy must need a lot of groceries.
This is just a publicity stunt, the super-sized
cart draws lots of lookers and shoppers, or
at least that`s the plan. The store`s owner
spent two years and tens of thousands of dollars
building it. He admits, he`s better with food
than four wheelers. So, it`s possible he had
to work out some buggies, probably needed
a detailed map to figure it all out, that`s
when you call on a cartographer.
It`s time for us to hit the road, for CNN
STUDENT NEWS, I`m Carl Azuz. See you later.