but in any given case i think
uh... on in prosecutors around the
country being responsible
should speak to regulators she speak
experts 'cause if i bring a case against
institution a
the result of bring that case to
something
there's some huge economic effectively
creates a ripple effect so the subway
counterparties and other financial
institutions or other companies that had
nothing to do with this are affected
badly
so factor we need to know and understand
so in other words they are too big a
jail
uh... if i an expert comes it tim burger
and tells me i hate look this will cause
a ripple effect and it will hurt the
global economy
if you do the job
and you're s
bankers who are
criminal fraud or criminal money laundry
it as a test be seated
uh... that could hurt the economy so
back down do not do your job
waitressing so
hair colour with in for the senate
judiciary committee yesterday may ask
you about that the same eric holder who
earlier was saying i can drop a drone on
you for your regular citizen padhai
trials truck stinkin trials i don't need
i'm right
and is executed
but what does the bankers this is what
he said is that
i'm concerned that
the size of some of these institutions
becomes so large that it does become
difficult for us to uh... to prosecute
them when we are hit with
indications that give you prosecute if
you do bring a criminal charge uh... it
will have a negative impact when the
national economy press given the world
economy
and i think that is a function of the
fact that some of these institutions
have become
too large
and mainstream
in actual senate testimony isis
well you have tended to large but what
can we do so it'll hurt the global
economy so we're not going to do our job
get out of jail free card here you go
use exactly like
not only do we not prosecute for pass
crimes weren't telling you right here in
public
we're not gonna prosecutor enterprise
how bad i toss
now do they feel same way about regular
citizens was interesting 'cause
their goal was also asked about their
sports where they pursue the case
against them
he'd even violate the law
they claim you buy a lady determine
service contract in a private contract
he had that he downloaded documents too
fast
you know he didn't even make them public
spoke booked his name crime was
downloading documents too fast
they threatened in japan
thirty five years in jail
do you think that was appropriate to
turn into older
uh... doesn't try to use
odd that the government would uh...
indict someone for crimes
that put carry penalties of up to thirty
five years in prison
and million dollar fines and then offer
my three or four months
prison sentence
well i think that's a good good use of
prosecutorial discretion to look at the
the conduct
regardless of what the statutory maximum
sworn to fashion a sentence that was
consistent with but what the nature of
the the conduct was i think that what
those prosecutors did in offering three
four zero two six was consistent with
with that conduct three don't consider
this a case of prosecutorial re-try
misconduct
no i don't look at what necessarily was
charged as much as what was offered in
terms of um...
how the case might have been resolved
isn't that amazing
no it was good prosecutorial discretion
to charge a guy who didn't actually
break the law
with a possible thirty five-year
sentence
and at the same time on the same day he
just said
on wall prosecute
any bankers
remember hsbc did money-laundering for
the mexican drug cartels needed money
laundering for al-qaeda
you got a lot of rock as well as your
time bakery or free to go that is
brilliant prosecutorial discretion but
if you are every citizen
a new download documents all too fast
and we call you how active s
all we need put you in jail for thirty
five years
ways as well we probably would have put
him in for laughs well are you not
merciful you see that right there is a
perfect microcosm of what's wrong with
our justice system because we don't have
one
is to polina consistent
no justice for us
and the bankers get what ever they want
anarchic turned gel our top law
enforcement officer goes out and tells
the senators of this country i will not
prosecute the buyers