and they are radar blame the right wing
and wonder who you fix it
listen to what he says he'll be able yes
sir
i dare say that if you are a moslem you
can
you can be pretty certain you can rest
assured
that everybody
in the media
will circle the wagons
and say this is not
because of islam
this is a loan
bad actors lol wharf
but this is not what a
says anything about islam is is no way
says anything about muslims is just the
law or not
and they were mind us that the vast
majority of people
denounced this kind of terrorist the
vast majority of muslim so if you're a
moslem then it turns out to be a moslem
bomber
you will be
in no way associated with it
skies a king a projection and that's all
he does
after every right wing extractor you
know it's a guy who shoots up a charge a
guy was gonna go to shoot up tides
foundation the list goes on and on
rush limbaugh comes out of this how long
lol patel all they can do is work that
is bad
suggestible asides theirs
and the judge the whole right wing based
on
so he now projects that are to moslems
and who will be doing the opposite by
the way if it is one muslim what will
rush limbaugh's
e islam yeah no i did let me know
straddling ty cobb but it's all of islam
white rush it is a christian
them i love the state's all christians
it has a right wing of my life is
falling wing as they can
nor at fault was somewhat my leather set
no your head would blow up
and the reality is fiction
dominici their waives a right wing of
course is not all right wingers
it really forty percent of the country
is guilty
because some idiot right winger would
get it now that doesn't mean that the
department of homeland security should
have more people tried it tracked right
wing
extremists
dubbed forty percent of the country they
consistently boats
right way
the barbed wire stories out of one
person driving them
that's mental
four should be increased so that we go
after extremists of any help
in the same loved ones and there's a lot
of muslim what date
rush limbaugh apparently decided the
media upper deck of muslims when in fact
what
we should be invading ran the muslim
countries
bud we're at about eleven
the level of his stupidity is
tiring i'm exhausted try to correct as
dumbass
skimming we do a one more time
however folks if you are a conservative
had to do that
and it turns out that whoever did this
is you there
or has a
mentioned connection to conservatives
everybody in the media will unite to
denounce your whole group
and believe me that's what they're all
hoping for
reminded what i do again up
i looked
i listen i read
i see the things people the institutions
i believe in under assault against i
come here and defend them
uh... purely in a defensive posture
today
trial that last part was very proud
why did it as a posture in the figures
which airs on the right winger
why would you care at that picture was
right wingers are all connected to you
why would you be a defensive posture
posse figured perhaps a disconnect
now look i don't know we don't have that
information yet but apparently rushes
word about so he's already in a
defensive posture said look he regains
he gets up he breeze room fairly heavily
he goes to the bathroom several times
and any comes out defends right wingers
whether extremis or otherwise
brush your spot if it is an extremist
right wingers who say they don't
represent us
they have an ideology that is extreme
for example some fundamentalist muslims
bubonic stare terrorist their extremist
are fundamentalists they're not like the
rest the muslim issue rational people
uh... can understand the stuff fairly
easily
but rush limbaugh if adam point where he
cannot put into a box yet salute
computer has broken down he's like i
want to blame all muslims
but whatever it is a right winger than i
do not want them blaming us
does not compute does not compute
i want to defend all of us but attack
all of them how do i go do it without
being able to put it into using black
and white buckets
i am de beers
says they're breaking that i am no
longer eating reading and upping