That's your signal that
you can try that
experiment at home.
Everything else off limits.
Look, I've already given you
homework and the show hasn't
even started.
Well, it's Monday and for
me that means 9News.
This is the local TV station
that I work for and many of
you have maybe seen the segments
over the years that
we've done with 9News.
I thought this would be a
perfect opportunity to give
you kind of a behind the scenes
view of what it looks
like as we prep for one
of the segments.
And actually what it looks like
from beginning to end.
Today, microwave science.
So this is the best part of
getting ready for 9News is
that you get to go to the
playroom and actually kind of
work out some of the details.
This is the secret hallway that
leads to the playroom.
This is a place that
not even--
I mean, our employees don't
even know about.
It's secret and this is the--
what the [BLEEP].
Hey!
Hey, get out of here!
We're shooting and--
[CROWD GROANING]
STEVE: Just get out of here.
Go on.
Get out of here.
MALE SPEAKER: Sorry, it fell
out and I picked it up.
STEVE: How do you even know
about this place?
MALE SPEAKER: I don't know.
I need to get back--
STEVE: Make people get out.
All right, so the challenge
is something fun
to do in the microwave.
I mean, there's easy things
like, for example, there's--
we grab a soap.
So if you take Ivory soap, for
example, and you put it in the
microwave, as long as it's
fresh Ivory soap--
I do it enough so there's stuff
on hand-- as long as
it's fresh Ivory soap.
Ivory soap is the soap that
floats, and so we should be
able to put that in the
microwave and have it puff up
into these great clouds.
This is a simple thing
that people can do,
so we can try that.
There's other things
that we can try.
If you use a light bulb,
for example.
If you take a regular light
bulb and you put a regular
light bulb in the microwave--
well, that would be bad because
of the metal, but the
secret is you put it in
there with some water.
And the energy from the
microwave actually heats up
the tungsten and
starts to glow.
So we can try that.
And then, I've been saving these
for a long time, so that
you can see this.
Here it is.
OK, I've been saving these
for a long time.
Look at this.
Empty chip bags.
So if you take an empty chip
bag, made out of this foil
kind of material, stick that
in the microwave--
I'll have to look at the notes
again-- but you stick that in
the microwave, it will heat it
up enough that it will shrink
and you get a little miniature
bag out of the deal.
So out of all these things
there should be something
today, for the afternoon
spot to be able to do.
Let's go find a microwave.
Here's one of these cool things
with these chip bags.
Found this online.
So one of our researchers found
it online of people
doing this so don't
do this at home.
Find a friend's microwave
and do it in
their microwave, right?
So find the plastic chip bags,
and use the ones that have
what looks like little
foil that's inside.
And again, if you have any
concern about ruining your
microwave, then I guess
don't do this.
So this goes here like this.
This goes here.
All right, so now you don't
want to do this for a long
time, so we're just going to set
it for like a minute, but
we're going to turn
it off right away.
So this goes in here
like this.
And let's do quick minute.
All right, we're ready.
So we're going to turn
it off once you see
the sparks come in.
So watch this.
It's going to heat it up.
Bam.
It's really cool.
Watch this.
Bam, look at that.
Look what it does.
Now you have to be very careful,
because it's hot.
And there's some cool
science behind this.
It's the science of polymers,
of course.
When these chip bags are made,
they're made out of long
chains of molecules.
So these polymers are stretched
out, heated, and
then they're cooled quickly,
so it retains this kind of
shape that you have here.
Once we heat it get back up
again, which I think you could
do the same thing with just an
industrial like heat gun, one
of those things, it would shrink
it back down as well.
But here in the microwave,
that's
exactly what's happening.
So you're hitting it with a lot
of power, it releases it,
and allows those molecules to
go back to their original
state, which is a relaxed state,
and you've got it.
So it's kind of cool to see
the difference there.
It's just a matter now of
whether or not this passes the
safety test with my producer.
She might say no to this, of
telling people at home to do
this with chip bags.
I think it's OK though.
That's pretty cool went it's
been online quite a bit.
All right, here's one that I
learned a long, long time ago.
You have to have a
glass of water.
Here's the glass of water.
Got it?
And to the glass of water we
are going to put a regular
light bulb in the
glass of water.
So here's the light bulb.
Got it?
And I know you're not supposed
to put things that are metal
in the microwave, so to make
it so we don't get that
sparking, we're going to put
this down inside like this.
So now, you see how the light
bulb is submerged
there in the water?
I think that's exactly
what we need.
So now, this whole thing goes
into the microwave.
OK, so now watch the
filament insight.
So when we start this, watch
the filament inside.
See how it starts to glow?
It's that awesome?
And there it is.
Here is our light bulb
like we had before.
So the energy from the microwave
excites that
tungsten filament that we have
inside, enough to be able to
give off light.
If you do it for too long,
then it cracks and you'll
probably ruin your
microwave anyway.
But that's very, very cool to
be able to see what it looks
like inside when you stick
it in the microwave.
You just have to watch it
really, really carefully.
So cool.
All right, perfect.
There's two.
This is one of my favorites.
It starts with a mistake that
happened years ago, as the
legend goes, that Ivory soap
is the soap that floats.
And it's the soap that floats
because, supposedly, a long
time ago the person who was
manning the whipping device
that made the soap in the
factory, left it during a
lunch break, and they came
back and the volume was
overflowing and what they'd
done is they'd whipped air
into the soap.
And so what they found is when
they formed it into the bar--
Ivory is the soap-- here
watch this-- it's
the soap that floats.
So Ivory floats.
I guess that's a good thing.
If you're taking a bath, I
guess, it floats to the top.
It also is very, very
interesting.
Now, if we use those little air
pockets that are inside
now, to be able to stick that
in the microwave and watch
what happens to the
expanding air.
So watch this.
What I like to do is
to break it up into
smaller chunks like this.
So break it up.
That's pretty good.
It just gives it a little
bit more surface area.
OK.
This will make everybody on this
floor very happy because
when you cook this, it has this
beautiful smell to it
that causes everybody
to come out.
Here we go.
So this goes inside.
You just kind of have to watch
the cool things that happen
inside as it's moving around.
Ready?
So watch this.
So take a look at what
happens inside.
As it starts to heat up, those
little pockets of air--
of course the molecules move
away from each other--
and it starts to expand and you
start to see some movement.
Oh, yeah, take a look.
If you just stick the whole bar
inside, it'll work, but I
found that when you break into
smaller pieces you get much
better clouds.
Oh, that's great.
Here, watch this.
Nice.
Look at that.
These small little pieces
produce these
great results here.
So look at the air that's
fluffed into it and
pops back out again.
It's hot at this point.
You have to be careful,
but this is what
it looks like here.
This is easy to do.
This will be perfect, and we can
do it in their microwave,
and there shouldn't be any
problem with this at all.
Now it's my job go sell the
ideas that work, minus the
grapes, to my producer.
So I'll let her know about the
chips and the light bulb, and,
of course, the soap.
And I get the OK, and we write
the segment, and we're done.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
All right, it's not as exciting
as all three of them,
but I can do it.
All right, the expanding soap
is what we're going to do.
OK, see you this
afternoon, bye.
All right, so here's
how it works.
Everything is set.
We're about 30 minutes to air.
This is live, so we don't
do live-to-tape.
Got everything that you
need, hopefully.
Sneak in the building, tell the
producer that you're here,
set, and you're ready to go.
Today's different because I
just have no idea where
they're shooting.
And you'll notice that we have
this just in case the
microwave doesn't work, we can
at least show what happens.
TV tricks.
So this is the control
room here at 9News,
and Bob is the director.
And my producer is Jessica,
right over there, and she's
the one that told me that I have
to do something different
today, so we can't
be in the studio.
We have to be some
other place.
This is normally where
I bring guests and my
boys and those things.
If they do a good job, look,
they get to go to
vending land over here.
So this now is the set
for today's segment.
So I'm assuming that we're using
a microwave here and
we're just going to stay in here
and do the spot this way.
So it's definitely impromptu
from what we normally do.
I think it will be fine.
NEWSCASTER: You're not
miked so this is us.
STEVE: No, so this is us.
I'll use both hands, so I'll
grab this, and I, at the end,
will hold this for you.
The reveal is over there,
if I ask you to grab it.
NEWSCASTER: Oh, cool.
All right.
Steve's very cool science
experiment today is another
one of those in which he warns
you, do not do this at your
home, do this at a
friend's home.
STEVE: Because you're in
the kitchen, right?
Why do you want to mess
up your microwave.
NEWSCASTER: That's
right, exactly.
STEVE: That's exactly right.
Do you smell that smell?
NEWSCASTER: I do.
STEVE: It's not eggs, it's
not, no, it's Ivory soap.
NEWSCASTER: Oh, it's soap.
STEVE: So this is it.
So you're going to
need Ivory soap.
NEWSCASTER: What a cool-- that
was a cool science experiment.
STEVE: Isn't it kind of fun?
Kind of fun.
NEWSCASTER: Once again,
at a friend's
house, not your house.
All right, Science Guy.
All this information available
at stevespanglerscience.com on
the On-Air tab.
STEVE: Got it.
NEWSCASTER: Look for
Spangler Science.
OK, it's 4 o'clock, and
9News continues.
We'll be right back.
STEVE: Just take that
to Miss Kobrick, OK?
She'll love that for her little
bath on Saturday.
NEWSCASTER: That was cool.
STEVE: Three and a half minutes
later, I'm done and
what do I do?
No, I don't go to the trailer,
not to the green room, fresh
fruit and--
I'm dusting the floor now
because we've spilled all over
the place, and we've got another
shot back here in
about two and a half minutes.
Hard part about doing live TV is
I never know what it really
looks like until the very
end and I grab the tape.
Because you never know how it
mixes down and what the camera
shots look like.
And in this particular case,
there's just one shot there.
So we'll see how the whole
thing kind of played, but
that's the only thing they've
allowed us to do is the soap
in the microwave, because they
were fearful that kids would
try to put the light bulb
in the microwave and
it would blow up.
And the chips would be a
problem, so if you happen to
see that earlier in the show,
you didn't see it, if you know
what I mean.
Just the Ivory soap trick.