Pasta compomodori. It's
basic, basic tomato sauce. The basis of lots of Italian recipes. It is classic.
We are going to show you two different directions
One is gonna be arrabiata and
then the other one is tuna and capers
Onions and garlic and tinned tomatoes are your base
Ems, you're on the onions. I'm going to chop the garlic
My trick with garlic is I put a bit of salt on it and it releases all the juices
Look at all that moisture
That's the salt that's released that. It makes it really easy to crush
with a flat blade. A nice glug of olive oil. Heat it up
Ready? Yup
We've got a lovely mix of different sized onions in there. Authentic.
In theory you'd have them all diced nice and fine. Garlic wants to go in a little bit later because
you don't want it to burn, the garlic
cooks much quicker than the onion's. Ems
will you open the tin of tomatoes. Make sure they're chopped
Mum's shown us how to do this.
It just saves you pulling them out and chopping them. There we go nice chopped tomatoes
Look at that!
Because there's a lot of liquid in there we also cheat with the stock.
Crumble that stock in and it will dissolve
Trust me!
It does the job, it really does.
There's some bigger chunks of tomatoes there. Just bash it down with your spoon
Put some salt and pepper in them
and then pepper anchino, which is cayenne pepper. Not enough to make it spicy.
It should just give it a little heat
That is a classic tomato sauce. I'm just going to have a little taste. I'll have a little taste too please.
Leave it to simmer as it is, for about 15 minutes but that's pretty much
the same time as your pasta's going to cook
Mum would literally make this in vats
Do you want to come and have a little look?
This is where she stores all the essentials
Italian tuna, Italian pasta. Here we go.
Come September they'll
probably be 15 of these and these are brilliant because they're
like little bricks, they're perfect for two people. You can pop that straight into
a pan
from frozen, ten minutes on the heat? Mum's going to hate the fact that we're in here. Don't tell her!
Come on, take a look at our pasta store cupboard  essentials video.
Just click on the link below
So we're going to split this sauce and show you arrabiata, which is
spicy, a bit like a pesto, really versatile. Let's put our pasta in because that's
going to take ten minutes
So this pasta that we're using here is fusilli.
All those little twists
really mop up the sauce, and you'll have gooey tomato sauce running
through that pasta.
Chop up some pancetta now
So that's nice and warm
You don't need any oil
because this pancetta will just, it's got enough fat in it
If you say you're arrabiata you're cross, you're angry, they call it that because it's
fiery and
spicy
You don't want to get rid of that fat because it's full of
flavour and saltiness and it's
really good
Look at those bits
Nice and crispy and delicious
If you're going to have an arrabiatta you want it nice and hot. Half a teaspoon of chilli flakes
As you can see it's quite meaty
thick sauce now.
Just before I put the pasta in there I'm going to add a little bit of the pasta water.
Come on Em's. I'm ready. We want 50/50 yeah?
Marry the pasta on the heat.
Always
This one's your spicy Arrabiata
And then the other one is really simple
we loved it as kids
tuna and capers
My tuna's gone in
Capers will give it a little bit of saltiness
and it goes really really well with
the fish
After our swimming lessons when we were kids, instead of going to the fish and chip shop like everyone else,
we went home for a plate of pasta with tuna
I want a drizzle of olive oil
I'm going, I'm not waiting for you.
I want parmesan on mine too.
Yup, really good
Chilli?
Yup, it's got a hit. It's good.
Ohhh, everytime
You can try some of mine