ANTHONY STRONG: Ironically, I'm
at my happiest when I show
up here at the crack of dawn
after leaving work at 1:00,
1:30 in the morning.
And I'm in the kitchen and I'm
surrounding by all my cooks
and all the food.
And we have a list a mile long
to get through, problems,
around every corner.
It is so much fun to attack
something like that.
It's such a beautiful process.
My name is Anthony Strong.
I'm the executive chef for
Locanda Osteria and Bar, in
San Francisco, in the Mission.
I guess my interest in food
started when I was a kid
growing up in Iowa.
And I'd weed my grandmother's
tomato garden.
And then she'd make me BLTs with
bacon made at the Dubuque
meat packing company nearby,
where the whole family worked
at some point.
I moved to New York, worked at
Le Bernardin, and then moved
out here because I just really,
really wanted to cook
in San Francisco.
I just fell in love with it.
It was exactly everything
I was looking for.
As a cook, I think it's
important to have a certain
set of parameters that are
guiding your cooking.
We're trying to give a Roman
restaurant and food experience
through the lens of
the Bay Area--
slightly interpreting dishes,
but really making it feel
Roman to the core.
Last night, we went out to Lers
Ros, which is my favorite
Thai food in the city.
Do want to meet us there,
or should I swing by
and pick you up?
My conundrum with Lers Ros is
that the menu is so huge, and
I haven't been able to dig all
of the way through it yet
because I keep finding favorite
dishes that I want to
order over and over and over.
Sweet.
So far, we've got deep-fried
quail in garlic sauce.
We've got grilled pork shoulder,
and we've got
chilled duck salad with lime
and peppercorn dressing.
And spicy and sour soup soup,
with pork spare ribs.
KAREN ROGERS: No.
ANTHONY STRONG: This
is so good.
And they chopped the thing
up, deep fried it.
KAREN ROGERS: And we're all
having some of it, right?
ANTHONY STRONG: Oh, yeah.
KAREN ROGERS: This one.
ANTHONY STRONG: Guys, I'd
like to introduce
everybody to Caleb.
[LAUGHTER]
ANTHONY STRONG: Caleb is the
gentlemen lovingly drinking
soup broth out of the spoon.
CALEB ZIGAS: This is awesome.
ANTHONY STRONG: Caleb
runs La Cocina.
They are some of the
biggest heroes of
the local food scene.
It's a non-profit business
incubator, basically, geared
towards Mexican women.
And basically, they start food
businesses with their clients,
rent out kitchen space, and give
them all the guidance and
infrastructure and assistance
that they need to start their
cookie shop, taco truck,
restaurant, catering business.
La Cocina has given
birth to so many
businesses in the Bay Area.
And they are very
important to us.
CALEB ZIGAS: San Francisco has
a customer base that wants
that kind of authentic food.
And that we've been lucky
enough to find really
talented, driven women who can
bring that kind of food in a
way that people want.
So, I think San Francisco's
a place for it to start.
I think it has a lot
of meaning here.
And I think there are other
places where it would make a
lot of sense, too.
ANTHONY STRONG: And they're
some of the best
cooks I've ever met--
CALEB ZIGAS: The best.
ANTHONY STRONG: --in my life.
We are going to Suppenkuche,
the most badass German food
and beer in the city.
The one thing that I miss about
New York, and I crave in
San Francisco, is late-night
dining.
I love late-night
dining scenes.
I love having a bunch of cooks,
restaurant people, from
around the city coming in and
digging the food and drinking
and having a good time.
So we've got weinerschnitzel
and roasted potatoes.
And then over here, we've got
jaegerschnitzel, which is a
weinerschnitzel covered in
mushroom gravy with spaetzle.
We have this, which is already
kind of destroyed.
It's their house-made pretzle,
with this insanely dense
cheese stuff.
I don't really know
what that is.
But it's absolutely incredible
with beer, sausages and mash,
and grilled lamb chops.
RUSSEL OLSON: [INAUDIBLE]
ANTHONY STRONG: Thank
you, sir.
ANTHONY STRONG: Now say "prost"
and make eye contact.
KAREN ROGERS: Prost.
ANTHONY STRONG: Prost
ASHLEY BELLVIEW: Prost.
MALE SPEAKER 1: Prost.
MALE SPEAKER 2: Prost.
ANTHONY STRONG: I love
San Francisco.
It's a great place
to be a cook.
I love it.
We just basically survive on
vegetables and hippy love.
We have drum circles pretty
much every night.
ZACK SWELME: We have to
before a service.
ANTHONY STRONG: And that's
what San Francisco
is really all about.
It's great.
What I love about being a cook
in San Francisco is that
there's such a great
democratization of the food
culture here, and the
food community.
You're able to get an insane
tasting menu, beautifully,
beautifully prepared
multi-course dinners, and then
you can walk two blocks away and
get one of the best tacos
of your life for $2, or a
burrito that's the size of
your arm, and it is absolutely
delicious, and made by people
who are loving what they do.
We're going to Locanda, in the
Mission, the restaurant that,
apparently, I run.
We're going to make BLTs
because I want a BLT.
Is that cool?
Hey, welcome to Locanda.
KAREN ROGERS: [LAUGH]
ANTHONY STRONG: BLTs
a la Locanda.
Being a kid from the Midwest
and a very working-class
background, I've never
really believed in
anything like luck.
It's always been very important
to me from the start
to pound the pavement
and pay dues.
And I've always believed that
the harder you work, the more
luck you have.
Create your own luck.
In the restaurant and cooking
world, it's cool that there's
space for so many of us.
And we can all be
so different.
I love the fact that there are
people that are great at being
on TV, and looking and talking
great, and shooting from the
hip with the question
and answer thing.
And I love and respect
those people.
And I also am really
appreciative of the fact that
there's space for guys like me
that are just really good at
getting underneath the
dishwasher during a Friday
night service and fixing it.
[LAUGH]
I'm definitely invigorated by
how competitive and ruthless
the restaurant industry is, and
how tough it is to make a
plate of pasta happen
on somebody's plate.
And then how tough it is
to make a buck on it.
It's a blast.
It's a constant challenge.
And I wouldn't trade
it for anything.