ads and that's what about the intense
they respect problems
they arent trade yeast co communities or
we can all walk
t to one another
can be spread out
well into my old side note it's coming
into town
in fact safeguards on skype its patrick
assess of course is a republican agenda
twenty one
well the building is a conspiracy theory
but it's a real book
it deals with probably rights in our
food source ideals of their ability to
bring his food employees agricultural
methods
uh... sounds very serious
of impose explains fitzpatrick along
with her son of while roland
the bill sponsor argued that the u_n_ is
pushing the sustainability plan
to take away property rights
uh... there we go
all right so what is again that we want
well those are resolution passed by the
united nations
back in nineteen ninety two it's not
like an admin recently in their patting
your dad eleven ninety two
it was not grant a fly by the united
states senate
and does not contain the force of law
and the united states
in other words passing a bill as they're
planning in missouri to say that you
cannot local
problem and cannot enforce
it's hard
totally in well then
this is not along the united states of
america of course they can enforce it
it doesn't exist as a law here
it was a resolution
is a resident you see kirk intervarsity
alive
but he did a great skit we did this show
on a lark forty years later you guys are
still coming conventions overt
with
it will also send out a witness for the
planet
news has a lot of public are probably
right because not all
that movie ticket senator ted cruise
united states and abroad experts
has about one site
talk about how that homes and other
engine that's what i want to go to jail
anyway this is repeating what's right
this lunatic is fiercely theory and this
is not going to pass legislation
missouri right now
cells are observances photo dot it
one hundred and ten to forty
favor it has passed
there will be no problems of misery
raha tha
we four hundred gender twenty-one
no resolution spare i'll tell you that
navistar was said in the governor's
center but
can imagine
a hundred antenna forty past
what do you have a lot next bigfoot
happen ok dark
of cap exceeded ford has a lot more
possible
the united nations landing black
helicopters in the middle of missouri
and forcing everyone in the harbor dolls
just leaving you can't get any crazier
we move on to kansas
where they are are trying similar things
standards of this had t
had already proposed legislation
yesterday on the twenty one last year
last year he said quote
or actually twenty eleven i should be
correct or years ago
this resolution informs policy makers of
the aggressive
environmental social engineering in
global political control
but is it yet but what he
so kansas is way ahead in this area on
the spot
that's not all
but i was going to a eleven and he wants
update so that same say senator comes
then per se rat
that separates them
that he would like to ban
sustainability
his legislation would ban kansas state
local governments
from spending public funds unsustainable
develop
if i will take them to think about of
buddy that's
we will not be sustainable and guests
everything will immediately pair
you will not be able to develop anything
that last past seven days
what does it mean the band all
sustainable development
which was looking at the but they
couldn't get any crazier
happened can you accidentally break the
law
home and i'm really sorry man that
nothing sustain itself like two weeks
mcbride that bad it we can share
now you think that's bad
you know who that the same republican
lawmakers in kansas
part of this would have a twenty-one
nonsense
fought that biking to work or biking in
general
was part of the u_n_ intend that
they try to pass a law let me quote here
that bypass were radical
and destructive to the american way of
life
this is a lot of the major political
parties
in the largest and most powerful nation
on earth
be afraid
the very afraid