EDDIE HUANG: That's fresh.
They've got some shallots
in there.
EDDIE HUANG: Oh, he's crazy.
Oh, this is the food?
-[SPEAKING CHINESE]
-Sorry.
EDDIE HUANG: Yo, Otto just gets
really upset anytime you
touch anything on
the school bus.
So we're not going to touch
anything else on Otto's school
bus over here.
Finesse, finesse.
OTTO: [SPEAKING CHINESE]
EDDIE HUANG: Oh,
he's finessing.
[THEME MUSIC PLAYING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
EDDIE HUANG: So you see this
short, fat Chinaman?
Clearly, I don't like to eat
breakfast and get my
metabolism going
in the morning.
But my man's here, Huckleberry
Finn up in this bitch, was
like you've got to have
breakfast in Taiwan, right?
It's not all some IHOP shit,
not some Waffle House shit.
We about to go to the
best soy milk joint.
Fresh, hot soy milk for
that ass, right now.
No photos, no photos,
the God is here.
The name of this place is
World's Greatest Soy Milk.
But, it's so good, and this
neighborhood is Yung Ho, that
it is now known as
Yung Ho Doujiang.
It's the most official, the
best, it's like Cali Kush--
Yung Ho Doujiang.
These are staple items at
a Taiwanese breakfast.
So we got the whole spread
so you guys can see
what's really good.
This is what we came for--
hot, sweet soy milk.
You got to see my eyes
eating, this is mean.
This soy milk is fucking mean.
They're the only people that
roast their soy beans before
making the soy milk.
They roast their soybeans
like coffee.
This is amazing.
This is a beef in a sobe,
which is like a pancake.
Well, I'm going to open this
up for you so you can see.
Look at those pickled mustard
greens with a
little chili in there.
And then this is beef
shank lu goda.
And when we say "lu" it means
braised, and specifically
braised with five-spice.
This is the egg pancake.
It is a fried dough bottom, so
it's like a Sicilian pizza.
Then topped with a egg-- like,
this is just straight murder
on a plate.
It is so good, this
is retarded.
I wake up, eat this, drink this,
I run 20 miles in soft
sand and have a career
longer than cannabis.
This is mi jung, and this is
peanut and sticky rice
breakfast soup.
This is shaobing youtiao.
You have the fried cruller
on the inside, it's
the Taiwanese churro.
I'm going to dip this in here.
This really compliments
the flavor of
this shaobing youtiao.
It's a churro on the inside, a
pancake on the outside, and it
tastes like peanut
butter and jelly.
Like, un-motherfucking
defeated.
Uh, so good!
It's so good.
Peanut butter jelly time.
Oh, pretty Indian!
Pretty Indian!
DAVID: This is hella
good, man.
-[SPEAKING CHINESE]
EDDIE HUANG: [SPEAKING CHINESE]
Yo, why am I speaking
Chinese to you?
I always speak Chinese
to this dude.
Number one soy milk champion.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
EDDIE HUANG: We are at sunny
Normal University and I'm your
abnormal guy.
I'm very, very curious to find
out who goes to Normal
University.
I have no idea what cosplay
is, but looking at the
turnout, either fucking Justin
Bieber is here or Jeremy Lin's
about to jump off the roof.
I hope one of those
things happens.
What up, Biebs?
I fucking love you!
[MUSIC PLAYING]
EDDIE HUANG: This kind of looks
like the AVN Awards,
except everyone looks
like Asa Akira.
Yo, peep game.
EDDIE HUANG: Oh!
Don't shoot up the skirt?
-Yeah.
EDDIE HUANG: Oh!
Yo, let's get some
upskirt here.
Do some upskirt here.
Oh, more upskirt.
Go upskirt.
I don't know if I want to
be Taiwanese anymore.
So a lot of your favorite
fashionistas didn't get invited.
Anna Wintour, we're
sorry, boo.
Invitations get lost
in the mail.
Today is a single man cosplay
fashion show for your boy.
We gonna see what the
game's been missing.
This one is rocking the
fall 2012 chainsaw--
we like that a lot.
Oh, oh, oh, the movement!
Killing the game!
Next we have a musical number
that just might be the
must-have item of
winter 2012--
the steel lotus groin.
Oh, Taiwan girl-next-door,
maybe?
I think Forell might
like this shorty--
it's kind of his thing.
Oh, model minority--
very studious.
Two is better than one.
One's got the Laotian sword,
execution-style.
This one got a little gut-- you
know the kid likes that.
Two girls, one gun.
All right, hang on, hang on.
Oh, she is finessing
that chainsaw, B!
Oh, these shorties
are mad jealous.
They're like peeping the
chainsaw game here.
And they're literally just like,
look at this bitch, she
thinks she's really some shit
with that chainsaw.
Let's show you how
it's really done.
Two for one, ah.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
EDDIE HUANG: So your boy just
received the ill King Jaffe
Joffer treatment--
one man cosplay fashion show.
And what could be better?
We're going to go eat
out of some toilets.
Lot of people have shot at this
restaurant, Modern Toilet.
I really wanted to see
it for myself.
We're going to sit on
this shorty's face.
She seems real nice.
Hey, [INAUDIBLE], look at this
dude's ill collar pop.
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
My neckroll ma.
-Neckroll?
EDDIE HUANG: No.
Oh.
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
All the ladies back home, if
you're lucky enough, I could
bring you here.
Did you ever think that this
could happen to you?
Oh, most official.
This is like a day in the life
of a toilet in your mizow.
That's disgusting.
From what I can gather as an
outsider in this country, I
think this is like Red
Lobster in Taiwan.
Because this is where
you take people for
Valentine's Day or prom.
Um, send the chef
my compliments.
Oh, that's not cool.
Should we send this
back, dude?
I thought German sausage, it's
like a giant footlong sausage.
This is kind of like shorty took
the pants down and dude
came with sliced sausage meat.
It's like, oh yeah, you're
gonna fuck me up tonight.
Mm, let me see that shit.
Asian homies out there, don't
let your shrubbery look bigger
than your weaponry, all right?
Even if this is what you're
trying to fucking lay
the game down with.
You can make it look better
without your fucking giant
whack-a-mole bush.
Remove it and it's like oh, I'm
still really not going to
have very much fun but
he's a nice guy.
See that Asian sausage--
it's not big, but it's
pretty flavorful.
This is now my favorite
Taiwanese restaurant.
You know why?
It is a satire and a parody
of all cuisines not
Taiwanese or Chinese.
What are they putting
in the toilets?
Japanese, Indian curry, Italian
food, German food.
And they're like, yo, your
food is such hot trash,
non-Taiwanese, Chinese
countries.
We're going to help you out.
We're going to put it in
its proper home so it's
appreciated the way it should
be-- in a fucking toilet.
Modern Toilet, to the gods.
Out of here, number one.
Mad subliminal.
Extra subliminal.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
EDDIE HUANG: This was like the
Jekyll and Hyde day, because
breakfast was the most official
Taiwanese breakfast
I've ever had.
Like, everything there
was on smash.
And I even liked when the chef
punched our cameraman in the
face because he was protecting
his recipe.
He didn't want people to see.
Cosplay--
yeah, cosplay was
a lot of fun.
It's like going to Comic-Con.
You look at it and you think
people are cornballs.
Sometimes you got to be like not
so fucking cool and just
have a good time, and
I had a great time.
And that toilet restaurant,
same thing.
It's not always about
what's in the
toilet, it's the toilet.
The whole experience of eating
out of toilets is some wild,
funny shit, you know?
This episode I think really
shows people don't judge a
toilet by its cover.
"Fresh Off the Boat," Taiwan.
Eddie Huang, we out.
On the next episode of
"Fresh Off the Boat."
[SPEAKING CHINESE]