Simple fact.
I mean, you're not going to
pull it out straight out.
That's in there.
You're going to lean on that.
You're not going to do it.
That's how deep it goes in.
And that's a Bowie.
That against any man
would've been dead.
He'd have been dead already.
That's a lot of knife
coming on you.
I have two sides.
I have no middle ground.
I am pure light and
pure darkness.
I cry for people
in the streets.
I hate poverty.
I hate children that
don't eat.
It drives me crazy.
It breaks my heart to
see children suffer.
I love people.
Walk on the wrong way--
yeah, I'm one dark bastard.
I didn't choose when
I got attacked.
The only thing experts agree
on is-- with a black
bear, you never run.
A black bear, you
never play dead.
A black bear, you always
show aggression.
This is 100% of the time.
Not so with a grizzly.
Your best chance, if it's a
female, you see the cub or
not, yeah, play dead.
Whether it was my
martial arts.
Whether it's just--
I'm one pissy son of a bitch.
I don't know.
I don't know anything about
grizzlies back then.
I'm still a teenager,
you know?
And I can feel the sense
for days, you know?
It's quiet.
It's a stillness.
I look at this grizzly.
And then he just moves in
on me-- just smash,
right in the chest.
All of sudden, something
hits me.
One of my senseis said, there
will come a time in an
individual's life where
anger supersedes fear.
And that's when you
stand or fall.
And it was beautiful,
it really was.
Just let the knapsack go, looked
at this animal, and
said, piss on you.
It ain't going to happen.
I had my Bowie, and
I had a machete.
And I walked up to him.
I said, man, your fighting
prowess is 50 times mine.
But pal, I'm good enough to
stick both these in you.
And he just gave me that look,
and his head kind of
went back and forth.
And he turned 180 degrees,
and he was just gone.
I just watched him walk off.
And it was almost a-- oh man,
the stillness, the quiet was
unbelievable.
You see, that's the
wilderness.
That's what brings us.
You can get those-- it's like,
wow, OK, this is cool.
This is what it's all about.
So I wanted to learn more
about this bear.
I wanted to know why.
I went back to college.
I had quit in grade 10.
So I had to go upgrading
all over again.
And what I found out, there was
not a damn thing known on
the grizzly.
You can't get close enough
to study them.
They'd kill you.
Well, I'm watching RoboCop.
And I'm telling you, halfway
through that movie, it just
all came together.
I just looked at that
and said, that's it.
You give me the time
and the money, I'm
going to build a suit.
That's how it all started.
1987-88, I watched Robocop, I
started building the bear
suits for grizzly
bear research.
I am the world's foremost
authority on deterrent sprays
sold to the public.
So I started building it-- the
Mark III, the Mark IV.
It's all soft material
for flexibility.
You learn a lot, 25
years at this.
I mean, I've got 25 years ahead
of anybody out there.
And by the time I got to the
M VII, you're looking at
$150,000, straight titanium.
Again, only about 20%
flexibility, 135 pounds.
But I only need to be able to
stand there, raise the arm.
There's a trigger device that
sends off the spray.
That's the research I do--
and in aggressive behavioral
research, what happens
afterwards, if it gets
through, what
does the bear do.
[INDISTINCT SHOUTING]
Troy goes to McMaster
University.
That's our MIT.
And I go to doctors
in physics.
So I present the problem to
them, and they love it.
Wow, that's brilliant.
Wow, how do we simulate the
power of a grizzly?
OK, let's break this down.
After two days' research, they
look at me, and they say, OK,
here's what you've got to do.
If you can handle that pickup
truck, dead impact, at 50
kilometers an hour--
got no problem with a bear.
Well, they see that and
assume, what an idiot.
Jumped in the suit-- no, buddy,
that's four years.
That's five suits, starting at
3 kilometers an hour, pop.
8 kilometers an hour, pop.
15 kilometers an hour, pop.
All the way up to 50
before I got there.
Do you know why I never
broke a bone?
Do you know why I've never
sustained so much as a
concussion?
Because I know what I'm doing.
People, this isn't
a big reach.
I don't want to get hurt.
So you're talking three years
and another four suits later
before we got to the M VI.
And that's how it does it.