design combined with visionary
technical solutions.
Our latest car, the Agera R, is
built in the old hangers of
a former Swedish fighter
jet squadron.
Their symbol, a ghost, is now
proudly painted on the back of
every Koenigsegg.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHRISTIAN VON KOENIGSEGG: So
now I'm going to show you
something which we are working
on for the future, which I
personally find very, very
interesting in many aspects.
So what this is, this is what
we call an actuator.
It's a Free Valve actuator.
Most of you who are familiar
with combustion engines and
especially car engines know
that there are camshafts
involved to move the valves
inside the cylinder head.
And these valves, they have been
controlled by camshafts
for the last 150 years or
something like that.
But it's very restrictive,
really, especially if you have
multi-cylinders and you want
to have a rev range to go
through with efficiency and
power because, when you have a
camshaft, you basically look
at all the cylinders in the
same line to do, pretty
much, the same thing.
There are coming systems now
which give some flexibility.
You can tweak the angle a little
bit, compared to the
crank of the engine.
And you can slide them sideways,
like Audi is doing
to shut off cylinders now.
So it's getting better and
better, but it's still very,
very restrictive.
You can think of the camshaft
like a broom, pretty much.
You hold it in your hands and
you push all the valves
simultaneously with
this broomstick.
What the Free Valve system
does is that each valve
becomes individual.
So if you think of the valves
like keys on the piano,
suddenly, instead of pushing all
the keys at the same time
with a broomstick, you can
actually play the keys with
your fingers, which is
the Free Valve idea.
And then, of course, the
engine can perform in a
completely different way than
being forced into a preset
pattern of combustion.
So what we're going to show
you here is this is like a
small cut out of a
cylinder head.
Here we have one valve.
Normally, there are two intake
valves and two exhaust valves.
And here is just a small
rig to run one of
these Free Valve actuators.
So basically, here you
have the valve.
Here you have the actuator.
It goes into it like this.
This is lubricated by engine
oil and pressurized by
pressurized air, which acts
like an air hammer
to move this out.
Then the engine oil makes sure
it stays stable and can lock
it in different positions.
And then air spring or a metal
spring pushes it back.
So we have individual control
over each valve, which brings
great benefit to the combustion
cycles in the engine.
So it's actually a snowballing
effect.
The engine becomes lighter,
smaller, cheaper, cleaner.
It can change the look of
the car in the end.
So it's a very, very interesting
technology that
I'm sure, one way or the
other, will conquer the
cylinder heads of the world.
So here we'll go into a little
bit of details how it works.
Urban, who is partly responsible
for this
development, will show you a
little bit what it looks like.
URBAN CARLSON: It's a very
simple control system.
We have one signal
for each valve.
And when we tell it to open,
it opens with a few
milliseconds delay.
And when we tell it to close,
it closes with, again, a few
milliseconds delay.
This it can do at very
high speeds, up to
20,000 RPM, if necessary.
CHRISTIAN VON KOENIGSEGG: The
same size of actuator is
actually good for a small
motorcycle engine revving
15,000 RPM and a truck engine
revving 2,500 RPM.
Because the motorcycle valve is
very light, so it takes the
same energy to drive it
backwards and forwards at
15,000 RPM as it takes to drive
a huge, heavy truck
valve backwards and forwards
at 2,500 RPM.
So it's very neat that the same
actuator basically covers
the need for all different
engine sizes.
So now we're running at
what kind of RPM here?
URBAN CARLSON: Well, here's
a little bit over idle.
CHRISTIAN VON KOENIGSEGG:
This is actually the
movement of the valve.
So you can see it
goes quickly up.
And then it stays flat.
It's like having a square
camshaft profile to make the
engine breathe really well.
If you would have a square
camshaft profile, it would
break immediately, because it
would jump off the edges and
would start hitting
the valve stem.
And it wouldn't work.
But with the Free Valve system,
you can actually open
any way you like and open really
fast, stay open flat,
and then drop down.
Here it's possible to see the
valve sequence as well.
That is a smooth curve, so it
doesn't hit the valve so you
create noise and wear.
URBAN CARLSON: This
is 3,000 RPM.
And you can see still a square
form of the valve curve.
This is 9,000 RPM.
CHRISTIAN VON KOENIGSEGG: So
this might just look like an
old Saab to you all.
And in fact, it is, apart
from one aspect.
That aspect is what you
see that's red here.
And that's the cylinder head,
which has been modified to
accommodate our Cargine
Free Valve system.
So basically what we've done
here is we've taken the
cylinder head apart, machined
out all the mountings and so
on for the camshafts, and
installed 16 Cargine Free
Valve actuators.
And then we have designed
a special valve cover.
Or it's not really
a valve cover.
It's more a lid containing
pressurized air channels and
pressurized oil channels
coming from
the engine oil side.
You can see the height of
this black cover here.
That's the same height as
the standard cylinder
head used to be.
So even when we retrofit it,
when it's not optimized for
space, it's anyway lower than
the standard cylinder head.
So the engine actually shrinks
and becomes lighter.
If we would have made a cylinder
head from scratch,
instead of retrofitting into an
existing cylinder head, it
would also become much narrower
and even lower.
And this whole section here,
which is a cover for where the
chain drive and for the camshaft
used to sit, would
disappear completely.
So the engine would also
become a lot shorter.
Basically, when you go from
a camshaft to Cargine Free
Valves, the size of a
four-cylinder engine becomes
just a little bit bigger
than the size of a
three-cylinder engine.
And then, of course, if you
cut away one cylinder to
maintain the power and torque
level you used to have in your
four-cylinder engine, then it
becomes really much smaller.
So this car here has been
running with Cargine Free
Valve system, winter
and summer, for the
last 2 and 1/2 years.
We've accumulated almost 60,000
kilometers, without any
failure whatsoever to the
Free Valve system.
It's just been upgraded with
our latest generation,
actuator generation 5, on both
the intake an exhaust side of
the engine.
And it's been tested at the
testing institute, called AVL,
with up to 20% improvement in
fuel efficiency so far.
And that's just the starting
point, I would say.
This is more a test field to
run for durability and for
cold starts, even in the winter,
down to minus 20
degrees Celsius.
But it's really exciting.
And it's, I think, one of the
few cars in the world that is
running with no camshaft
whatsoever.
When it's fully optimized, we're
expecting to have 30%
less fuel consumption, 30%
more torque, and 30% more
power, and, in an
average driving
cycle, 50% less emissions.
And that's without connecting
it to the possibility, which
is very interesting, which
is an air tank.
Given this valve technology, we
can actually recoup energy
while engine braking, by using
the engine as an air pump,
pumping up a tank with air,
getting air pressure there,
and then driving off only on
that air, using the engine as
a compressor or, let's
say, an air engine.
That compressed air can also
be used for boosting the
engine while using fuel to
have a really big, quick
spooling turbo which
consumes no energy.
So instead of storing energy
in the battery and like a
battery, we're using an
empty tank of air.
So that's the next step
of this technology.
But already, without that, it's
a huge benefit, compared
to normal camshafts.
This technology is not
yet in Koenigsegg.
And it's something, of
course, we might plan
to do for the future.
It will be another three, four
years out, before it's in any
production car.
And hopefully, the Koenigsegg
could be one of the first.
[MUSIC PLAYING]