My name is Dr. Tierney Thys
I am a National Geographic Explorer,
marine biologist and filmmaker.
My work has taken me all over the world ocean.
From coral reefs in the tropics
And the kelp forests off California
to the frigid waters of Antarctica.
I've studied life in the sea from some of the biggest fishes
to some of the tiniest organisms in the drifting world of plankton.
From this time underwater,
I've come to see our planet through a new lens.
We live on a water planet where 99%
of the available living space lies in the ocean.
All the water in our bodies,
our eyes, our skin, our blood
once resided in the ocean and will return one day to the sea.
Water is the one element
that connects us all so deeply-so profoundly.
Here is where life began nearly 4 billion years ago and it's been honing
its survival tactics ever since.
We've explored less than 5% of this ancient realm.
And now we're entering a true golden age of discovery in the ocean.
Nearly 50% of the oxygen we breathe comes from hidden world of ocean microbes.
Their intricate processes are crucial for life on Earth.
I am constantly in awe of the ingenuity and tenacity of ocean life.
How it manages to withstand the relentless
and powerful energy of the waves,
Extreme changes in temperature
How so much diversity can thrive with nothing to latch on to,
nowhere to hide.
It's in these salty waters that I know the most profound secrets
of the biological world still lie.
If we can take care of the ocean and the life within,
we can unlock the keys to so many more discoveries
discoveries in science,
medicine, food,
energy...
our own survival.
As a biologist, explorer, filmmaker and mother,
the ocean is the greatest gift I could ever ask for.