FRANK GERWER: Pretty good.
Fine.
MALE SPEAKER 2: Did you
get some of last
night's action, Matt?
It's like night and
day, right?
That's all it is.
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
MALE SPEAKER: It's [INAUDIBLE]
night and day.
FRANK GERWER:
[SING-SONG FASHION]
John, come on.
It's early time.
John.
Get up.
You're going to miss English.
[SOUND OF SKATEBOARDS]
PATRICK O'DELL: Hey, what's
this park called?
He didn't know.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Reedsport.
PATRICK O'DELL: Reedsport.
Oh, Reedsport.
We're at Reedsport skate
park in Oregon.
CROWD: Yeah!
Yeah!
[WHISTLING AND CLAPPING]
PATRICK O'DELL: Pretty
gnarly skate park.
I guess it's the second
day of skating.
The third day of the tour.
I guess we're going to go pick
up Spike Jonze from the
airport in a little while.
He decided to fly in, I guess.
CROWD: [CHEERS]
CROWD: [CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
MALE SPEAKER: That was like
reaching for the stars dude.
CROWD: [CHEERS]
MALE SPEAKER: Wow.
MALE SPEAKER: That wasn't the
bottom of the pole either.
MALE SPEAKER: Uh uh.
MALE SPEAKER: Patrick, Patrick,
flip of the day?
P-STONE: Gees.
MALE SPEAKER: I don't have to
say anything about that.
That speaks for itself.
ROBBIE RUSSO: Gnarly.
MALE SPEAKER: How'd you
get on Anti-Hero?
ROBBIE RUSSO: I went to skate of
the year when they won one.
And then I talked to Darren,
one of the guys, and Retta
hooked me up with it.
MALE SPEAKER: Retta?
ROBBIE RUSSO: Yeah.
MALE SPEAKER: Retta's got
ins at Anti-Hero?
ROBBIE RUSSO: Yeah, Retta
helped me out.
MALE SPEAKER: What about
the Girl guys?
How long have you known them?
I just met them like
a couple days ago.
Practically met them, yeah.
MALE SPEAKER: You know
all there names yet?
ROBBIE RUSSO: No.
MALE SPEAKER: What's
that guy's name?
ROBBIE RUSSO: Alex.
MALE SPEAKER: Alex.
What's the guy filming?
ROBBIE RUSSO: Uh, Gabe.
No, Erin.
MALE SPEAKER: The guy
in the blue shirt.
ROBBIE RUSSO: Rick Howard.
MALE SPEAKER: What's the guy in
the blue shirt all the way
back there?
ROBBIE RUSSO: Mike Carol.
MALE SPEAKER: What did
you call him before?
ROBBIE RUSSO: Mark Johnson.
MALE SPEAKER: Have you been
to Oregon before?
ROBBIE RUSSO: Yeah.
MALE SPEAKER: Oh, so you've
been to this park before?
ROBBIE RUSSO: I been to this
one, but none of the ones we
hit up earlier.
MALE SPEAKER: Are you bummed
you didn't do the--
ROBBIE RUSSO: Yeah.
I wanted to do it but
the cops came.
They just told us we had
to leave and stuff.
Next time though, for sure.
I'm just going to do it.
MALE SPEAKER: Fucking Robbie.
MALE SPEAKER: How much
money is on the line?
MALE SPEAKER: Robbie's
got hot hands.
Two bucks.
MALE SPEAKER: So tell
me, do you have
homework on this trip?
ROBBIE RUSSO: Yeah, journal.
I got to right in a journal
every day what I did.
MALE SPEAKER: Have you been
keeping up on that?
ROBBIE RUSSO: Yeah.
MALE SPEAKER: Let me get
this little kid out
the game right here.
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah,
knock him out.
PATRICK O'DELL: We just
got done at the park.
It's the end of the
second day.
We're going to pick
up Spike Jonze.
I think that's kind of cool
because its been real
Anti-Hero heavy so far
with the tents
and Anti-Hero lifestyle.
Adding Spike Jonze into the
mix might make it a little
more Girl skateboards.
He's probably got the
gnarliest tent ever.
SPIKE JONZE: How's it going?
MALE SPEAKER: How are you?
SPIKE JONZE: I totally
spaced out.
MALE SPEAKER: So you don't
know who we are?
SPIKE JONZE: [LAUGHTER]
MALE SPEAKER: We came for you.
SPIKE JONZE: How pretty
is this place?
MALE SPEAKER: It's nice.
SPIKE JONZE: It's insane.
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah,
you got your tent?
SPIKE JONZE: I think Brink might
have me hooked up, but I
think Eric's not coming
in until Monday, so
I can use his stuff.
MALE SPEAKER: So what made you
decide to come on the trip?
SPIKE JONZE: Just to
get out of town.
Works been stressful.
And just get out on the
road with the guys.
And plus, I haven't been
on a trip with
those guys in a while.
In plus, if they're going out
with the Anti-Hero guys, which
sounds like a one time thing.
How often is that
going to happen?
I think the last time I went
camping was for a Girl camping
trip, and it was messy.
MALE SPEAKER: What do
you mean messy?
SPIKE JONZE: Just drunken
beyond drunken.
MALE SPEAKER: Cover your eyes.
MALE SPEAKER: Dude, seriously?
Come on.
Really [INAUDIBLE].
MALE SPEAKER: Really.
MALE SPEAKER: Tony, you're
the guy now?
MALE SPEAKER: Oh, you're
doing good though.
[LAUGHTER]
MALE SPEAKER: Gravity is what
holds us to the Earth for
Christ sake.
CROWD: Whoa.
[LAUGHTER]
MALE SPEAKER: I told
you Johnny.
Hot cut.
MALE SPEAKER: Whoa, hot cut.
MALE SPEAKER: As hot
as a hot cut.
MALE SPEAKER: Don't half-ass
a hot cut.
MALE SPEAKER: Spit on it.
MALE SPEAKER: I told you it's
a little hot in there.
I wasn't kidding.
MALE SPEAKER: Give
him a hot cut.
[INAUDIBLE]
MALE SPEAKER: Stand on the
edge of the hot cut?
[INAUDIBLE]
MALE SPEAKER: Danger zone.
MALE SPEAKER: Oh man, trademark
it and label it.
MALE SPEAKER: You got
combat shoes on.
MALE SPEAKER: Oh shh,
my sock's on fire!
[LAUGHTER]
MALE SPEAKER: Hot cut.
MALE SPEAKER: That's the cut.
MALE SPEAKER: German.
[LAUGHTER]
MALE SPEAKER: Nice [INAUDIBLE]
right there.
MALE SPEAKER: All right,
clear house.
Go in fan zone.
Watch out, P.
MALE SPEAKER: Why don't
you just put it out?
MALE SPEAKER: I did.
One handed, one-handed.
MALE SPEAKER: One-handed with
the hand on, right?
MALE SPEAKER: One-handed and go
back and fourth and the air
flow is way better.
[LAUGHTER]
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
MALE SPEAKER: That fucker's
stoked, man.
MALE SPEAKER: Bush box wins.
MALE SPEAKER: Fuck you, dude.
MALE SPEAKER: Watch it go
out in like two seconds.
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah, we didn't
need that blanket.
MALE SPEAKER: Look at
that thing going.
That's how they used to do
it int the old west.
Yep.
MALE SPEAKER: We still
got three left to go.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
[LAUGHTER]
MALE SPEAKER: Forest Rangers are
going to be [INAUDIBLE].
[INAUDIBLE]
MALE SPEAKER: The whole
[INAUDIBLE].
MALE SPEAKER: The tent?
MALE SPEAKER: I got a tent.
I ain't setting that shit up.
It's in there.
I'm set, dude.
Look at that.
Double blankets, a mat under
there, two pillows, that neck
pillow, and the old skull.
MALE SPEAKER: Nice.
Can you lay in there all
the way straight?
ROBBIE RUSSO: I think so.
I got to do the--
MALE SPEAKER: He likes being
in the fetal position.
It's still normal for him.
[INAUDIBLE]
ROBBIE RUSSO: Fucking warm.
MALE SPEAKER: Hey, let me
check out your journal.
ROBBIE RUSSO: Robert Torres.
It's the same, Russo.
MALE SPEAKER: You
in ninth grade?
ROBBIE RUSSO: Yeah.
MALE SPEAKER: Read it to us.
ROBBIE RUSSO: Got
picked up it--
in the morning.
MALE SPEAKER: Got picked
up it, in the morning.
ROBBIE RUSSO: It morning.
In.
MALE SPEAKER: You want me to
help you with this shit?
ROBBIE RUSSO: Yeah, dude.
MALE SPEAKER: You wrote this.
ROBBIE RUSSO: In the morning
and called everybody
to wake them up.
MALE SPEAKER: Who?
MALE SPEAKER: No, that's
not what it says.
It says I got picked
up in the morning--
ROBBIE RUSSO: In the morning.
MALE SPEAKER: In the morn--
more.
ROBBIE RUSSO: That's
I-N-G right there.
Morning.
MALE SPEAKER: That's E.
That's not right.
ROBBIE RUSSO: [LAUGHTER]
MALE SPEAKER: And then--
ROBBIE RUSSO: Then got picked
up, woke up in the morning.
The other rod instead of road.
MALE SPEAKER: Then we
got on the rod.
ROBBIE RUSSO: Got on the road.
Stopped at Ch-, Chipo--.
MALE SPEAKER: You're
writing this.
You should know what
you're spelling.
ROBBIE RUSSO: Dude, I don't know
how to spell for shit.
MALE SPEAKER: I know, but
you should know how
to read your spelling.
ROBBIE RUSSO: No,
please that's--
MALE SPEAKER: What is that?
ROBBIE RUSSO: I don't
even know.
[LAUGHTER]
MALE SPEAKER: All right, we're
going to work on your
spelling, dude, all right?
ROBBIE RUSSO: I know.
I suck at it.
MALE SPEAKER: If you don't do
that fucking channel tomorrow
morning, we're going to
work on your spelling.
MALE SPEAKER: We need
to get you a tutor.
ROBBIE RUSSO: The channel--
[LAUGHTER]
MALE SPEAKER: I'll tutor you.
That shit's ri-- come on now.
ROBBIE RUSSO: I just get mixed
up and I fucking can't spell.
MALE SPEAKER: So next time you
get mixed up-- are you
confident when you're
writing this?
ROBBIE RUSSO: Yeah.
No, I'll stop and I'll be--.
MALE SPEAKER: You try to figure
it out when you're
writing it?
ROBBIE RUSSO: Yeah,
it's too hard.
MALE SPEAKER: So next
time your trying to
write it, ask someone--
MALE SPEAKER: Holler, holler.
MALE SPEAKER: --how you
spell something.
Well, either way.
MALE SPEAKER: We'll help you
with the spelling at the end
of it, and then we
can rewrite it.
ROBBIE RUSSO: Rewrite
the whole thing?
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah,
you type it up.
MALE SPEAKER: No, we got to
figure this out though, before
then end of the trip,
all right?
ROBBIE RUSSO: Mm hm.
MALE SPEAKER: When you
hand that in, A+.
MALE SPEAKER: Robbie, so wait.
Who's on your shirt?
ROBBIE RUSSO: Guy Mariano.
MALE SPEAKER: Are you sure?
ROBBIE RUSSO: No its Gonz.
MALE SPEAKER: Gonz, what's
his first name?
MALE SPEAKER: What's
ROBBIE RUSSO: Guy.
I don't know.
MALE SPEAKER: What's
his last name?
ROBBIE RUSSO: Mariano.
MALE SPEAKER: All right.
ROBBIE RUSSO: I forgot what
the fuck we did though.
MALE SPEAKER: You didn't do
anything over the fucking
little skidoo.
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
It was somebody who jumped,
and there was you.
MALE SPEAKER: Rick
McCrank did.
MALE SPEAKER: Yep.
ROBBIE RUSSO: I know.
I put that.
MALE SPEAKER: [INAUDIBLE] did.
MALE SPEAKER: Yep, Marano did.