Mayday, this is UNSC FFG 201 Forward Unto Dawn requesting immediate evac.
Survivors aboard, prioritization code Victor 05-3-00
Mayday, this is UNSC FFG 201 Forward Unto Dawn requesting immediate evac. Survivors aboard…
Halo 4: Forward Unto Dawn Part I
Locking onto frequency, tracking the coordinates.
Play it again, please.
Mayday mayday mayday. This is UNSC FFG 201 Forward Unto Dawn requesting immediate evac. Survivors aboard…
We have a lock.
It's him! -Initiating protocol 117-alpha. All stations on deck!
Shall I play it again, sir?
Sir?
Commander Lasky?
Cryopods opening.
Lasky? You okay?
Are you alright?
Lasky, let's go!
Hastati Squad, four minutes to the rendezvous point.
Copy, Vickers. Timer four minutes.
Will you be able to shoot with those hands?
We'll find out.
Come on! -Axios!
Move it!
Tchatkova, checkpoint.
Chen, checkpoint.
50 seconds
Go!
Where are you guys?
RV in 15 seconds.
Ready?
I'll see you at the party.
Sully!
We have to leave him!
Lasky, what the hell? -Come on!
Lasky!
Ten seconds!
Lasky, hurry it up!
Landing in 3-2-1
Enemy inbound. They'll be on us in 35 seconds.
Fresh mags in your weapons, prepare to attack.
Whst?
Our objective is to neutralise the insurrectionists and acquire the target. We move on my mark.
30 seconds.
We should flank them a force a surrender.
They're too close to flank! Innies never surrender.
Dimah and I could circle around, there's still time.
We can make it.
25 seconds
Guys.
It's our best move.
20 seconds
No, we're sticking to my plan. ON MY MARK.
It won't work.
You're not in charge anymore, Lasky.
Tom, just do what he says.
15 seconds.
Those are my orders.
I don't care.
10 seconds
5 seconds
Axios!
Lasky!
Hastati Squad leader on the field. Exercise paused.
Let me guess, Lasky. You ignored orders.
Just another strategic casualty, sir.
Unacceptable.
Game over.
Shoulder your weapon, cadet. Your little escapade kept Hastati Squad from achieving its objective.
Again.
Exercise complete. Zero wins, Hastati defaults.
Shit.
Robot tagged you?
Once with two meters. Twice from one.
I'm still numb from all the stun rounds.
I'm always numb
Hastati, hold arms!
General Black, sir!
Let me remind you cadets: This academy bears the name of the Roman general Gnaeus Domitius Corbulo.
Because he represents honour, valour, allegiance.
General Corbulo was to take his own life in the name of the empire.
Corbulo did not hesitate nor question.
He loyally obeyed, screaming "Axios!" as he fell upon his own sword.
Axios. I AM WORTHY.
But I'm afraid, cadets, today you have proven to be anything but.
We are at war with insurrectionists. Terrorists who would like nothing more than to see all of us dead.
Had this been an actual Firefight the rebels would have likely killed every member of Hastati Squad.
Every single one of you at this academy was sent here because your parents are the upper eschelon of the United Nations Space Command.
Because all of you are its future, and I expect you to act like it.
Understood, sir!
Well what are you waiting for? Lead them on tour, Orenski.
Axios!
Hastati, right turn!
Double ???
Corbulo Academy of Military Science Circinus-IV
Sully, do you ever stop talking?
No, seriously. I'm on to something, here.
The comms are messed up and I'm decoding something kick-ass.
ONI's hiding stuff from us, I'm positive. They've got secrets, man.
Stop stepping on our dicks, Lasky.
Hey, ease up, Gingerbread.
No, Sully. Vickers is right. My combat score sucked because of you.
Don't bother, JJ. He's gone soft. He's an Innie-lover now.
Dimah, that order didn't make any sense.
Doesn't have to make sense. Just follow it.
I'm trying to survive here, okay?
You need to respect the chain of command. The UNSC isn't the enemy. The Innies are.
Spoken like a true believer.
Yeah, well. At least I believe in something these days.
Cadet Thomas Lasky report to Colonel Mehaffey's office immediately.
No, we're sticking to my plan. ON MY MARK.
It won't work.
You're not in charge anymore, Lasky.
Tom, just do what he says.
15 seconds
They're my orders.
I don't care.
Pause.
You don't care? You do realise your helmets transmit everything.
No excuse, sir.
You continue pulling down your squad, you're going to end up with a lot of enemies.
Yes, sir!
I served under your mother and I know what she's like. And I sure as hell don't need to tell you that Colonel Lasky's not going to
allow a son of hers to leave this academy without a diploma.
I wouldn't know what my mother thinks, sir. I never see her.
It's been a long war. Your mother holds a lot of hands.
So I'm told, sir.
You know, Thomas, I've seen a lot of cadets come through here. Many have suffered like you.
Pain like that can't be forgotten. But you can learn how to tolerate it.
I'll do my best, sir.
That will be all.
How long have you had those blisters?
It's been on and off for a few weeks, but these are from yesterday.
Any other symptoms?
It's getting hard to breathe.
Okay. Let's keep an eye on it. Cryo training can take its toll.
You really shouldn't be looking at that stuff, Sully.
Score.
"Your academic performance is exemplary. But your combat scores are disappointing."
Hey, little bro. Hello from Jericho 7. It's day 131 of deployment. So, I gotta show you something.
Mom's gonna flip when she sees this. But whatever.
It's still a little raw. But we got a big drop on an innie stronghold next week, wanted to get it done before then. Anyways--
So you haven't been court-marshalled yet, then?
I'm not apologizing.
yes you are.
At least I believe in something.
I do believe in something.
Yeah, so do I.
Like what?
Just not in stupid orders that lead to needless violence.
Negotiating isn't an option anymore, Tom.
So we're brainwashing kids and then sending them in to exterminate a bunch of overtaxed farmers.
Farmers? That's who you think they are? You have no idea what the innies are like.
I have a pretty good idea.
Well then, you should know how much they hate us and that they're not going to stop fighting until we're all dead.
Can you blame them?
Yeah. I can. I blame them for a lot of things.
And you should, too.
I'm staying safe, doing my job. I just want you to do your job.
Oh, an by the way, nice check mate, bro.
Yet again.
Okay. New game. It's your move.
And hang in there. I know it's tough with mom being gone all the time. Being alone.
She loves you, so do I.
Miss you, buddy.
I miss you, too.
Lights out, doors closing.