SUROOSH ALVI: From what we were
seeing and hearing, the
secular society that was the
hallmark of Saddam Hussein's
Iraq has largely been replaced
with religious conservatism.
Mix that with Western-inspired
youth culture, and there are
going to be problems.
Subcultures in Iraq
are under attack.
For example, the Iraqi
equivalent of emo kids are
being targeted.
And in one of the biggest
stories out of Iraq since the
US has left, a number of them
were supposedly killed.
-[SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: However, there
wasn't a lot of concrete
evidence supporting
these stories.
And some people thought that the
case of these emo killings
was just scare mongering
to keep kids from
straying from tradition.
We went to meet with Dog Faced
Corpse and Fatalogy, two local
metal bands, to get their
opinion on it.
Oh, yeah.
Great.
Thanks buddy.
Cheers.
Shukran.
So this emo story, is it like
legit or is it bullshit?
Did it actually happen?
-It did not.
-No, it's true, man.
-It's true?
-Yeah, it's true.
SUROOSH ALVI: See?
There's still like--
Well, you're saying it happened,
and you're saying it
didn't.
-Yeah, it's happening.
-The media exaggerates
the things.
I think it's bullshit.
As you know, they think that
emos are metal heads are
satanists as this everything.
[SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: So they had to
turn the freezer off to plug
in the amp.
Across the street there's
a religious cleric.
It's the month of Muharram.
And he gets pretty pissed
off apparently.
So yeah, they're a bit freaked
out about playing right now.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
SUROOSH ALVI: Dog Faced Corpse,
where does the name
come from?
-[SPEAKING ARABIC]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
-Sounds good?
SUROOSH ALVI: Yeah, man.
Thanks for doing that.
I know that the religious cleric
is probably not too
happy right now.
It's Muharram and everything.
Or yeah, maybe he's out there.
It was pretty clear that no
matter what kind of music
you're playing--
rap, emo, metal, or
even classical--
you could get killed.
But in terms of oppression,
the group that has it the
absolute worst is the gay
community in Iraq.
What is the situation
like here for you?
ALI AL-HAFEZ: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: During Saddam
Hussein's time, you were
persecuted for being gay.
And now you live in fear of
being persecuted as well.
So it was bad before
and it's still bad.
ALI AL-HAFEZ: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
These are my friends.
[SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: That's you?
ALI AL-HAFEZ: Yeah.
SUROOSH ALVI: Yeah.
That's a good look for you.
ALI AL-HAFEZ: That's me.
Sorry.
Why?
Excuse me, cat.
SUROOSH ALVI: I assume it's a
very underground kind of world
that you have.
ALI AL-HAFEZ: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: Even though they
might be part of the same
group that's persecuting
you guys.
ALI AL-HAFEZ: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: Wow.
That's crazy.
And are you getting help from
the gay rights organizations
in the West?
No?
Not yet?
ALI AL-HAFEZ: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
-[SPEAKING ARABIC]