Delocated mastermind,
Jon Glaser.
THOBEY CAMPION: Cheers
by the way.
JON GLASER: Cheers.
And cheers on this one.
I gave mine wings real quick.
I hope everyone notices that.
Let's get it for both cameras.
Wings.
[MAKING AIRPLANE NOISES]
JON GLASER: I'm just going to
be doing that the whole
interview, so everyone
get used to that.
If you're not cool with that, I
advise to stop watching now.
THOBEY CAMPION: It'll be pretty
helpful for the editors.
[VIDEO PLAYING]
-Don't worry.
Your friends are right
here, John.
-No, you guys don't count.
You're professional
relationships.
-I'm a professional
relationship?
-David, I have to hang
out with you.
All right?
I'm obligated to.
I can't just call you up and
be all like, "was-sup bra?
Let's go grab a couple
o' fa-laff sandies.
Wash 'em down with some
ice cold 'ronas.
Check out some tush."
You're my son.
I can't be all like,
"was-sup bra?
Da
bra." -I get it.
[END VIDEO PLAYBACK]
[MAKING AIRPLANE NOISES]
THOBEY CAMPION: I feel like a
shithead for just drinking
beers normally.
JON GLASER: Make your wings.
Make some wings and
have some fun.
Here's what you should do.
You should make wings and then
after this interview post a
link on the site, like,
show us your wings.
And then get people
to send in photos.
THOBEY CAMPION: What's
interesting about your career
to me is that you're almost more
accomplished as, I mean
you're definitely more
accomplished as a writer than
someone who's in front
of the camera.
Was it inevitable that you
would go into writing?
JON GLASER: I never thought
I would, honestly.
I love David Rakoff's book Fraud
just because that's how
I've always envisioned myself.
I'm not a writer.
And I still don't feel
like I necessarily am
even though I do.
But it's not something I
envision doing at all.
And even when I got The Dana
Carvey Show job I felt like,
this will be cool for
now and I'm still
going to pursue acting.
But it's the greatest thing
that ever happened to me,
getting that job and opening
up a whole other
world of just jobs.
And a second career or
even a first career.
But I still feel like I'm an
actor, a better actor than I
am a writer but I
love doing both.
And especially jobs where I can
do both, like Conan, or my
own show now.
THOBEY CAMPION: That was
kind of the dream
job at Conan, right?
JON GLASER: Conan was like
the dream job, at
least at the time.
Doing Delocated is the ultimate,
but Conan was really
just the best job.
So much fun.
Just a great group of people
that work there.
But also getting to write
and perform and do your
own stuff or not.
To also not perform was great.
You know, you're writing
for another
person, of course, Conan.
But the nature of the show,
doing all the sketchy bits and
getting to be in them,
it was awesome.
Really fun.
THOBEY CAMPION: So, one of
the ideas we had for--
JON GLASER: What's the
better idea you have?
THOBEY CAMPION: --It was
to go and get tattoos.
JON GLASER: Well, we'll see.
I doubt I'm going to get a
tattoo but I will be happy to
watch you get a tattoo and--
THOBEY CAMPION: Help me.
JON GLASER: --give input, and
give suggestions, and make it
a really good one.
THOBEY CAMPION: Great, great.
I'm excited for it.
JON GLASER: But I agree with you
that perhaps these flying
bottles will be a part.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
THOBEY CAMPION: We were thinking
that or that bird,
which is actually kind of an
amazing, it's just a really
angry pheasant.
JON GLASER: Jesus Christ,
this thing?
This one is nice because he
certainly looks like he's
angry but you're right he
also could be like, hey
ladies, how we doin'?
Right?
He's like, that's
what he's doing.
THOBEY CAMPION: What's up?
JON GLASER: He just
looks angry.
But once you get to know him you
know that's just his face.
[LAUGHTER]
THOBEY CAMPION: That's his
normal body structure.
JON GLASER: Yeah, hey guys.
These guys are all psyched.
This is the still photo and
they're all kind of like
looking nervous but in the next
photo, they're all like,
oh yeah, Larry's here.
THOBEY CAMPION: [INAUDIBLE]
[VIDEO PLAYBACK]
-Yeah.
So what happens from here?
We get some ninja dudes to
follow me around, or what?
-The less you know,
the better.
-Let's do that.
That's smarter.
Call of the day, right there.
All right, I'm gonna take off.
I'm out-skies.
So, sayonara.
And I'll see ya "ta-ma-ra."
[END VIDEO PLAYBACK]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
JON GLASER: Very excited to
not get a tattoo here.
THOBEY CAMPION: What's
up guys?
Thobey.
MALE SPEAKER: Nice to
meet you, Thobey.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
THOBEY CAMPION: Nice
to meet you.
This is Jon.
CHUCK: Chuck.
Nice to meet you.
JON GLASER: Nice to meet you.
THOBEY CAMPION: We've been
doing some light
brainstorming already.
But none of them are as
well-thought-out or as
beautiful as these.
I'm still into the whole hawk
or falcon from the bar.
CHUCK: These are kind of like
the more [INAUDIBLE] ideas.
Some of them will kind of
get the juices flowing.
THOBEY CAMPION: What's battling
that snake right there?
CHUCK: That's a good question.
Or you get the lady in
the bottle, have
it say mom, or something.
THOBEY CAMPION: Jon.
CHUCK: Jon, yeah.
THOBEY CAMPION: I do like
the party hawk idea.
JON GLASER: Party hawk
is pretty good.
To me, the funniest thing is,
you don't know if this bird is
coming in for the kill or if
he's coming in, to put his
arms around his buddies.
MALE SPEAKER: 'Cause that
face is good too.
That looks like an angry face or
it could easily be a really
intense, what's up man?
THOBEY CAMPION: Yeah, that guy's
kinda got it going on.
I like that guy.
CHUCK: OK.
That's cool.
JON GLASER: Here's the three
party bird's buddies.
One, two, three.
THOBEY CAMPION: All
right, cool.
Let's do it.
CHUCK: You wanna do it?
THOBEY CAMPION: Yeah.
CHUCK: Yeah?
Chris?
THOBEY CAMPION: So now you're
into your third season as
executive producer and
star of the Adult
Swim TV show, Delocated.
Where did the idea come from
for the character?
JON GLASER: The original idea,
I had done an incarnation of
this character, before I got
hired at Conan, which is an
impressionist who is in the
witness protection program,
who really still wanted to
perform and get himself out
there so he wore a ski mask
and altered his voice.
And the joke was that
the impressions
all sounded the same.
It was that stupid voice.
You know, when you hear someone
on the news doing a
hidden identity interview.
But so, it was just really
as dumb as can be.
Really shitty impressions.
Super hackey comedy.
But he was very confident
in it.
So I like that archetype
of just this
smug, confident dick.
THOBEY CAMPION: Yeah,
he's a dickhead.
JON GLASER: Yeah,
real asshole.
[VIDEO PLAYBACK]
-What the [BLEEP]
are you doing in there, man?
-What are you talking about?
-I'm trying to grandpa my
granddaughter, that's what.
This is my weekend, TB.
Just stay outta grandpa time.
[END VIDEO PLAYBACK]
THOBEY CAMPION (OFFSCREEN): You
know, the other thing that
struck me right off the bat, was
you've essentially limited
your vocal and facial range to
your eyes and mouth and a very
small spectrum of vocal
inflection.
JON GLASER: Basically, I think
the key to it actually is the
mask we have.
Because the eye holes
are really big, as
is the mouth hole.
So I still feel like you get a
sense of a face and you do get
a sense of expression with
the eyes and the mouth.
So I don't think you
lose too much.
And for me it was never
an issue, like the ski
mask and the voice.
I always looked at it as, this
is just how he looks and this
is how he talks.
Like that's his face.
That's his voice.
THOBEY CAMPION: And what's in
store for season three?
JON GLASER: My character just
decides to play pro-ball.
And he dedicates himself to
trying out for teams, working
on his dunks, shoots about
1,000 free throws a day.
So if you like basketball, and
if you like the art of
training for basketball, you're
gonna love season three.
THOBEY CAMPION: So it's part
of the structural--
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
JON GLASER: You gotta learn
to go to your left.
You gotta learn to
go to your left.
And if you're a lefty,
you gotta learn
to go to your right.
Use your opposite hand.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
CHUCK: Sorry, but you wanna
continue the interview but you
wanna stand up and then I'll
put the stencil on you?
THOBEY CAMPION: Yeah.
CHUCK: Is that all right?
JON GLASER: Here we go.
THOBEY CAMPION: All right.
JON GLASER: Buddies.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
JON GLASER: Yeah.
Oh, you have to shave.
THOBEY CAMPION: It's my favorite
part of the tattoo.
JON GLASER: Fuck,
that's awesome.
CHUCK: That's a bird of prey.
It's an eagle, right?
This is what makes
you a man today.
JON GLASER: We don't
know what it is.
That's the tattoo.
Is it an eagle?
Is it a hawk?
Is it a falcon?
That's fucking cool.
CHUCK: What do you
think, though?
It that the right spot for it?
JON GLASER: My input is that,
looking real good.
Now what I'm going to do, and
I'm going to give you guys,
this is for free, I'm gonna
give you guys a hotshot.
I'm gonna say looking good and
what would be nice is if you
could frame it and shoot
right through this
signal and see the bird.
Looking good.
THOBEY CAMPION: It makes
my skinny arm
look fucking bad ass.
JON GLASER: This is a
pretty good tattoo.
Buddies?
That should be a sports bar.
Buddies, question mark.
Where you walk in like, Hmm,
what's going to happen.
Fuck, man.
CHUCK: Are you still good for
the interview, right?
THOBEY CAMPION: Yeah,
I'm all right.
CHUCK: There we go.
[TATTOO GUN BUZZING]
THOBEY CAMPION: There was a
great article that was talking
about the accessibility
of the show.
In comparison to the
general slate of
programming on Adult Swim.
Which I think is hilarious
considering the main
character--
they're calling it accessible
and the main character is
wearing a mask.
JON GLASER: It mirrors the most
traditional sitcom as far
as accessibility goes.
And it's 30 minutes also, which
allows it to be a little
more expanded and breathe a
little bit as opposed to the
shorter form shows they do
predominantly, which are just
shorter, faster, and tighter,
and crazier.
But I also agree, for good
and not for bad.
This is pretty painful, right?
THOBEY CAMPION: When,
I talk to you--
JON GLASER: I'm watching your
face and I'm seeing--
THOBEY CAMPION: When I talk
to you, I forget about it.
And when I look down,
it hits me.
CHUCK: How's it looking?
All right?
Everybody good?
I'm doing a little thing.
His talons are doing
the thing.
JON GLASER: Wanna get this?
So that is supposed to be the
talon-claw version of this.
MALE SPEAKER: We're going
to have to tattoo
some dots right there.
CHUCK: That could've gone
horribly wrong by the way.
JON GLASER: It went
horribly right.
THOBEY CAMPION: Is your
son a fan of the show?
JON GLASER: He's not even six.
So he knows what the show
is and he's come
to visit the set.
He gets into it.
And he's pretty funny.
THOBEY CAMPION: Does he
get the concept of it?
JON GLASER: I don't know
if he gets the concept
but he enjoys it.
They made these great billboards
for the show.
And it was me in my underwear
and the ski mask and we took
him into the city to show it to
him and take some pictures.
And we showed him these
billboards.
And said, who's that?
And he said, Daddy.
That was his reaction to a
guy in a ski mask and his
underwear on a billboard,
with these dead eyes.
Daddy!
It was really cute
and hilarious.
Very funny.
CHUCK: Yeah, it looks
good, huh?
Like that shading.
THOBEY CAMPION: How do you
do those lines like that?
CHUCK: It's all whip
shading actually.
THOBEY CAMPION: Whip shading?
CHUCK: Yep.
Whipping it.
Whipping it out.
THOBEY CAMPION: Is it basically
skipping over my
skin right now?
CHUCK: Yeah.
JON GLASER: Buddies?
[LAUGHTER]
MALE SPEAKER: Hey, buddies.
JON GLASER: Just cut to
a month from now.
Hi, so, my girlfriend and I were
sitting at the bar and we
just wanted to ask you
about your tattoo of
the eagle and buddies?
THOBEY CAMPION: Well, I met
this guy, Jon Glaser.
JON GLASER: Buddies?
That's awesome man, that's
really funny.
THOBEY CAMPION: You did
a great job with
the creative direction.
And good luck on season
three of Delocated.
JON GLASER: Thanks very much.
THOBEY CAMPION: Cheers, man.
JON GLASER: It turned
out awesome.
THOBEY CAMPION: Buddies?
JON GLASER: Buddies?
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYING]