A couple people I want to thank.
In particular, your CEO
Steve Roell is here.
Steve.
(applause)
And sitting next to him, one of
my favorite people and one of
the finest senators
in the country,
Carl Levin is in the house.
(applause)
So I just had a chance to
see what you guys are doing
in this plant.
It is very impressive.
Elizabeth was
giving me the tour,
and she was very
patient with me,
and I think I understood
about half of what she said.
(laughter)
At a time when Americans are
rightly focused on our economy,
when Americans are asking
about what's our path forward,
all of you here at Johnson
Controls are providing a
powerful answer.
This is one of the most advanced
factories in the world.
You're helping America lead
in a growing new industry.
You're showing us how we can
come back from the worst
recession that we've had in
generations and start making
things here in America that
are sold all around the world.
And that's why I'm here today.
I've said it before; I will say
it again: You cannot bet against
the American worker.
(applause)
Don't bet against
American ingenuity.
(applause)
The reason a plant like this
exists is because we are a
country of unmatched
freedom, where groundbreaking
ideas flourish.
We've got the finest
universities,
the finest technical schools,
the most creative scientists,
the best entrepreneurs -- all of
which is why we are home to the
world's most dynamic and
successful businesses,
large and small.
(applause)
And that's why even in
these difficult times,
there is not a single country
on Earth that wouldn't trade
places with us.
Not one.
We've got to remember that.
But we also know that we face
some tough challenges right now.
You know what they are.
You live them every day
-- in your communities,
in your families.
You know too many people
who are out of work,
or struggling to get by with
fewer shifts or fewer customers.
Paychecks aren't big enough.
Costs are too high.
And even though the economy has
started growing again since the
recession started in
2007, the fact is,
it's not growing fast enough.
Now, some of what we're facing
today has to do with events
beyond our control.
As the economy was improving and
improving through 2009, 2010,
the beginning of this year,
suddenly it was hit with the
unrest in the Middle East
that helped send gas prices
through the roof.
Europe is dealing with all sorts
of financial turmoil that is
lapping up on our shores.
Japan's tragic earthquake hurt
economies around the globe,
including ours, cut off some
supply chains that were very
important to us.
And all of this has further
challenged our economy.
And as we've seen, it's playing
out in the stock market,
wild swings, up and down,
and it makes folks nervous,
and it affects the savings of
families all across America.
Now, challenges like these
-- earthquakes, revolutions --
those are things
we can't control.
But what we can control is our
response to these challenges.
What we can control is
what happens in Washington.
Unfortunately, what we've seen
in Washington the last few
months has been the worst
kind of partisanship,
the worst kind of gridlock --
and that gridlock has undermined
public confidence and impeded
our efforts to take the steps we
need for our economy.
It's made things worse
instead of better.
So what I want to say to
you, Johnson Controls,
is: There is nothing
wrong with our country.
There is something
wrong with our politics.
(applause)
There's something wrong with our
politics that we need to fix.
We know there are things we can
do right now that will help
accelerate growth
and job creation --
that will support the work going
on here at Johnson Controls,
here in Michigan, and
all across America.
We can do some things right now
that will make a difference.
We know there are things we have
to do to erase a legacy of debt
that hangs over the economy.
But time and again, we've seen
partisan brinksmanship get in
the way -- as if winning the
next election is more important
than fulfilling our
responsibilities to you and to
our country.
This downgrade you've been
reading about could have been
entirely avoided if there had
been a willingness to compromise
in Congress.
(applause)
See, it didn't happen because we
don't have the capacity to pay
our bills -- it happened because
Washington doesn't have the
capacity to come together
and get things done.
It was a self-inflicted wound.
(applause)
That's why people
are frustrated.
Maybe you hear it in my voice
-- that's why I'm frustrated.
Because you deserve better.
You guys deserve better.
(applause)
All of you, from the CEO
down, are working hard,
taking care of your kids or
your parents -- maybe both.
You're living within your means.
You may be trying to save for
your child's college education
or saving for retirement.
You're donating to the
church or the food pantry.
You're trying to
help the community.
You're doing your part.
You're living up to
your responsibilities.
It's time for Washington
to do the same --
to match your resolve,
and to match your decency,
and to show the same sense
of honor and discipline.
That is not too much to ask.
That's what the American
people are looking for.
(applause)
And if that can happen,
we know what's possible.
We know what we can achieve.
Look at this factory.
Look what's happening
in Holland, Michigan.
Every day, hundreds of people
are going to work on the
technologies that are helping
us to fight our way out of
this recession.
Every day, you're building
high-tech batteries so that we
lead the world in
manufacturing the best cars and
the best trucks.
And that just doesn't
mean jobs in Michigan.
You're buying equipment and
parts from suppliers in Florida
and New Mexico and Ohio
and Wisconsin and all
across America.
So let's think about it --
what made this possible?
The most important part is you:
your drive, your work ethic,
your ingenuity, your management.
The grit and optimism that says,
"We've got an idea for a new
battery technology or a
new manufacturing process,
and we're going to take that
leap and we're going to make
an investment.
And we're going to hire some
folks and we're going to
see it through."
That's what made it possible.
But what also made this possible
are the actions that we took
together, as a nation,
through our government --
the fact that we were willing to
invest in the research and the
technology that holds so much
promise for jobs and growth;
the fact that we helped create
together the conditions where
businesses like
this can prosper.
That's why we're
investing in clean energy.
That's why I brought together
the world's largest auto
companies who agreed,
for the first time,
to nearly double the distance
their cars can go on a
gallon of gas.
(applause)
That's going to save
consumers thousands of dollars
at the pump.
It's going to cut our
dependence on foreign oil.
It's going to promote
innovation and jobs,
and it's going to mean more
groundbreakings and more jobs
posting for companies
like Johnson Controls.
And that's how America will
lead the world in automotive
innovation and production
and exports in this country.
Think about it.
That's what we got
done -- and by the way,
we didn't go through
Congress to do it.
(laughter and applause)
But we did use the
tools of government --
us working together --
to help make it happen.
Now, there are more steps that
we can take to help this economy
growing faster.
There are things we can do right
now that will put more money in
your pockets; will help
businesses sell more products
around the world; will put
people to work in Michigan and
across the country.
And to get these things
done, we do need Congress.
They're common-sense ideas that
have been supported in the past
by Democrats and Republicans,
things that are supported by
Carl Levin.
The only thing keeping
us back is our politics.
The only thing preventing these
bills from being passed is the
refusal of some folks in
Congress to put the country
ahead of party.
There are some in Congress right
now who would rather see their
opponents lose than
see America win.
And that has to stop.
It's got to stop.
We're supposed to all
be on the same team,
especially when we're
going through tough times.
We can't afford to play
games -- not right now,
not when the stakes are
so high for our economy.
And if you agree with me --
it doesn't matter if you're a
Democrat or a Republican
or an independent --
you've got to let Congress know.
You've got to tell them you've
had enough of the theatrics.
You've had enough
of the politics.
Stop sending out press releases.
Start passing some bills
that we all know will help our
economy right now.
That's what they need to do --
they've got to hear from you.
(applause)
Let me be specific -- I'll
give you some examples.
You've got to tell them to
extend the payroll tax cut,
so middle-class families
will continue to have more
money to spend.
We passed this in December.
The average family received
$1,000 from that tax cut,
and you need to get it
again, because the economy
is still weak.
It's going to help
you make ends meet,
but it's also going to mean
more customers for businesses.
It will increase demand.
It's right for the economy, and
I would sign that bill today if
it came to my desk.
(applause)
Tell Congress to get past their
differences and send me a road
construction bill --
(applause)
-- so that companies can put
tens of thousands of people to
work right now building our
roads and bridges and airports
and seaports.
(applause)
I mean, think about it.
America used to have the
best stuff -- best roads,
best airports, best seaports.
We're slipping behind because
we're not investing in it,
because of politics
and gridlock.
Do you want to put
people to work right now
rebuilding America?
You've got to send that
message to Congress.
(applause)
Send a message to Congress to
come to an agreement on trade
deals that will level the
playing field and open markets
to our businesses -- so we can
sell more goods to countries
around the world.
(applause)
We've got a lot of Americans
driving Kias and Hyundais.
I want folks in Korea driving
Fords and Chevys and Chryslers.
(applause)
I'd like to see that.
I want to see billions of
dollars' more products sold
around the world stamped with
three words: "Made in America."
(applause)
"Made in America."
Those trade bills are teed
up; they're ready to go.
Let's get it done.
Tell Congress we need to
reform the patent system,
so entrepreneurs like the ones
who developed some of the
technology here can turn their
ideas into businesses more
quickly; so companies like this
one can better compete against
companies around the world.
We shouldn't make it so
difficult for somebody with a
good idea to translate
that into a business.
Tell Congress we've got hundreds
of thousands of bright,
talented, skilled Americans who
are returning home from Iraq
and Afghanistan.
And I've proposed connecting
those veterans looking for work
with businesses that
need their skills.
You've got 24-year-olds and
25-year-olds that are leading
platoons and handling equipment
that's worth tens or hundreds of
billions of dollars, and they
come back here and they can't
find a job?
Let's put them to work.
These are things we
can do right now.
(applause)
These are things I've
already proposed,
we've worked out the glitches,
the legislation is drafted --
let's get it done.
Now, given the weaknesses
of the economy,
we need to do even
more than that.
And over the coming weeks, I'm
going to be putting out more
proposals, week by week, that
will help businesses hire and
put people back to work.
And I'm going to keep at it
until every single American who
wants a job can find one.
Now, we do have to
pay for these things.
And in order to pay
for these things,
Congress has to finish the job
of reducing the nation's budget
deficit in a sensible,
responsible way.
Not just with more cuts
this year or next year --
those cuts would weaken the
economy more than it already is,
and we've already cut a trillion
dollars in what's called
discretionary spending.
What we need is a long-term plan
to get our nation's finances
in order.
That's the only way we can
invest in places like this.
That's how we can fund the
research at the Department
of Energy.
That's how we can fund the
community college that trained
folks to be able to work here.
That's how we can fund the
infrastructure and the
technology that will
help us win the future --
by doing what you
do, what families do.
Think about it: When things are
tight you cut out those things
you cannot afford,
even if it's tough,
to pay for the things
that really matter.
You don't cut out the
college fund for your kids.
You stop maybe
going out as often.
You don't stop taking care of
your parent who needs care.
You cut back on some of
the things that you don't
really need.
The same principle
applies to government.
And by the way, in
your own families,
I'm assuming you don't just keep
all the stuff you like and tell
your spouse, you got to get
rid of all the stuff she likes
or he likes.
(laughter)
That wouldn't work
in my household.
You don't just cut out the stuff
that's important to you and --
or keep all the stuff that's
important to you and cut out the
stuff that's important
for your kids.
The same is true for us
as an American family.
We can't ask the
people in this room --
working families,
middle-class families --
to bear the entire burden.
We're not going to balance
our budgets on the back of
middle-class and working
people in this country.
Everybody has got
to do their part.
(applause)
Everybody has got
to do their part.
Everybody has got to chip in.
That's fair.
You learn it in kindergarten.
That's what all this fuss was
about in Washington: Are we
going to deal with our
deficit in a way that's fair?
And that means closing tax
loopholes for billionaires
before we cut college
loans for young people.
(applause)
That means ending government
subsidies for oil and gas
companies that are doing very
well before you cut health care
for seniors.
(applause)
It means making sure that the
biggest corporations pay their
fair share in taxes before
we gut the investments in
technology and clean energy that
made this factory a reality.
Now, that's just common sense.
It should have
bipartisan support.
These are things we
could be doing right now.
That's how we can jumpstart
this economy and speed up the
recovery and get
more folks working --
while making sure that we
get our fiscal house in order.
We can do both.
And I'll be laying out more
proposals in the days ahead.
And I'm going to keep after
every idea and every serious
proposal to help us
grow this economy --
until everybody who
wants a job can find one.
But I want everybody
to understand here,
the problem is not that
we don't have answers.
The problem is, is that folks
are playing political games.
And we've got a long way to go.
We didn't get into
this mess overnight,
and it's going to take
time to get us out.
That's the truth.
But that's no
excuse for inaction.
It's time to put
aside ultimatums.
It's time to stop drawing
lines in the sand.
You know, in the aftermath of
this whole debt ceiling debacle,
and when the market's going
up and down like they are,
there's been a lot of talk in
Washington right now that I
should call Congress back early.
The last thing we need is
Congress spending more time
arguing in D.C.
(applause)
What I figure is, they need
to spend more time out here
listening to you and
hearing how fed up you are.
(applause)
That's why I'm here.
That's why I'll be traveling to
a lot of communities like this
one over the next week.
That's what Congress
should be doing --
go back home, listen to
people's frustrations with all
the gridlock.
Listen to how frustrated folks
are with the constant bickering
and the unwillingness to
compromise and the desire to
score points, even if it's at
the expense of our country.
And if they're
listening hard enough,
maybe they'll come back to
Washington ready to compromise
and ready to create jobs and
ready to reduce our deficit --
ready to do what you
sent them there to do.
You know, America voted
for divided government.
And that makes it tough.
You got one party controlling
the House of Representatives,
another party
controlling the Senate.
So they voted for -- you
voted for divided government.
But you didn't vote for
dysfunctional government.
You didn't vote for a
do-nothing government.
You didn't vote for a government
where folks are just looking out
for special interests.
You didn't vote for a government
that is beholden to lobbyists.
We've got a lot of work to do,
and the only way we will get it
done is if everybody,
Democrats and Republicans,
find a way to put
country ahead of party.
That's what I'm fighting for.
I'm here to enlist
you in that fight.
You've got to hold
everybody accountable,
because if we can come together
and find common ground,
there is no stopping the
United States of America.
There is no holding us back.
(applause)
We can strengthen this economy,
and we can put our nation
back to work.
And we can lead the world
in growing industries.
And we will make it through
these economic storms and reach
calmer waters stronger
than we were before.
Thank you very much, everybody.
God bless you.
Thank you.
(applause)