Permanent observer -- or non-member observer
state -- now they might not sound like much
of a difference between those two terms, but
if you ask some Palestinian officials, the
difference is huge. Yesterday, the United
Nations voted to upgrade the status of the
Palestinian Authority. Palestinian officials
had been pushing for this. They think it will
give them some leverage in negotiating with
Israel, but Israel and the United States have
been against this upgrade, they argue that
it won`t have much of an effect on efforts
to create a Middle East peace deal.
When you hear about drones, unmanned aircraft
you might think about them flying over Afghanistan.
These are remote controlled vehicles, and
they are used a lot by the U.S. military in
the fight against terrorism. But drones could
start popping up in the skies over the United
States. Lisa Sylvester looks at the capabilities
and the concerns that might come along for
the ride.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
LISA SYLVESTER, CNN CORRESPONDENT: Right now,
only groups with special FAA permission, like
the U.S. Customs and Border Protection can
operate drones in the United States, but that
is going to change: Congress has asked the
Federal Aviation Administration to find a
safe way to expand the use of drones, or unmanned
aerial systems domestically.
BEN WIITTES, BROOKINGS INSTITUTION: The bottom
line is that by 2015, the FAA has to have
a comprehensive plan to open the air space
to both public and private UAS.
SYLVESTER: Think of the potential from crop
dusting to news traffic reports to surveilling
land to monitoring forest fires.
There is a big industry pushing the federal
government to open up the skies arguing these
unmanned air craft systems are safer and less
expensive.
SYLVESTER: Unmanned aerial vehicles or drones
can be as large as a fighter jet or only just
a couple of feet long, and people have actually
been flying unmanned vehicles or even model
airplanes for years, but with certain restrictions.
They can`t fly them above 400 feet, or in
certain areas like airports without running
into problems with FAA.
That brings us to one of the problems the
FAA is trying to solve: how to ensure safety
if the sky suddenly become a lot more crowded.
KEVIN HIATT, FIGHT SAFETY FOUNDATION: Some
of the larger concerns are the construction
of the aircraft. Who`s piloting them? The
actual bandwidth. Also, taking a look at some
of those social issues, which we`ve all started
to look into as far as privacy.
SYLVESTER: It`s the privacy peace that Representative
Edward Markey is most concerned about: could
prying paparazzi hound celebrities? When can
drones be used by law enforcement to gather
evidence? And what about the information gathered
by the drones?
REP. EDWARD MARKEY, (D ), MASSACHUSETTS: Is
it possible that this is just going to be
a rampant, eyes in the sky gathering information
about Americans with no rules, whatsoever.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: During the 2012 U.S. presidential election,
Barack Obama and Mitt Romney only came face
to face four times: they had their three debates
and a fundraising dinner. On election night,
President Obama suggested another get together:
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
BARACK OBAMA, PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES
OF AMERICA: In the weeks ahead, I also look
forward to sitting down with Governor Romney
to talk about where we can work together to
move this country forward.
AUDIENCE: Yes!
(applause)
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: That meeting happened yesterday. The
former opponents got together for lunch at
the White House. Now, we don`t know exactly
what was sad, there were no news media allowed.
But a White House statement said President
Obama and Governor Romney talked about America`s
role in the world. And they promised to stay
in touch with each other.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: See, if you can I.D. me.
I was born in Germany in 1879. In my early
life, I worked in the Swiss patent office.
But I`m known as a famous physicist. And in
1921 I won the Nobel Prize for physics.
I`m Albert Einstein. And you`ve probably heard
about my theory of relativity.
AZUZ: When a Nobel prize came up with the
theory of relativity, it`s no wonder that
a lot of people think of Einstein as a genius.
And that`s why there is a lot interest in
the organ that did Einstein`s thinking: his
brain. Some photographs were published recently
that show Einstein`s brain after he died.
Scientists were eager to get a look and see
if there were any clues to the famous Germans
genius. Doctor Sanjay Gupta has more on this.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
DR. SANJAY GUPTA, CNN CORRESPONDENT: Let me
just say as a starting point. You know, for
the last nearly half century now, people have
been fascinated with trying to figure out
what it was about Einstein brain that might
be different. And let`s take a look at these
images. Here, it`s a good place to start,
specifically looking at all those ridges and
valleys on the brain. These convolutions that
are sort of -- they develop as the brain is
developing as someone ages.
What do we know about his brain is that he
had more of these ridges and valleys. And
the reason that`s significant is you just
think about that -- as the result of those
increased ridges and valleys and convolutions,
you get more surface area. You get more neurons
and you have more capacity for different parts
of the brain to talk to each other.
It doesn`t necessarily means someone`s going
to be more intelligent, I think it`s best
to say that they have the capacity for higher
intelligence because of that increased surface
area neurons.
There is also a couple of other things that
people really honed in on, again, in terms
of differences. Take a look at this image
over here. That`s frontal lobe area, and in
most people whose brains have been examined
that area of the brain is fused, but if you
look at that red line there, that`s an area
of the brain of Albert Einstein where it was
actually split. This is an executive area
of the brain. This is where you implement
things, get things done. He had a higher executive
sort of capability there.
Again, it doesn`t necessarily correlate directly
with intelligence, but it does correlate with
this idea that if you have significant thoughts,
to be able to do something with those could
be -- you could have a greater capacity for
that.
A lot of people ask, you know, what does it
mean for us? Could my brain be like Einstein?
There is more (inaudible) things that he was
born with. There are certain areas of the
brain like look at this area over here that`s
sort of upside down a horse shoe. That`s an
area of the brain that`s responsible typically
for motor control of the hand. In this case,
the left hand. And now you`d look at that
area and you realize it, because it`s bigger
like that, it`s typically associated with
someone who`s very good with their hands.
In this case, Einstein was a musician, played
the violin.
But that is not something that people are
born with. That is something that develops.
And that gives us a little bit of an insight
into other parts of his brain as well that
may have increased in size, may have increased
in capacity as a result of all the work that
he was doing. It`s fascinating stuff. Back
to you.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
HIILLARY CLINTON, U.S. SECRETARY OF STATE:
Make no mistake about it - - HIV may well
be with us into the future, but the disease
that it causes, need not be.
We can reach a point where virtually no children
are born with the virus and as these children
become teenagers and adults, they are at a
far lower risk of becoming infected than they
are today.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: You heard Secretary Clinton mention
the disease that HIV causes. She`s talking
about AIDS, which stands for acquired immunodeficiency
syndrome. Tomorrow, December First is world
AIDS day. It`s the time to support the millions
of people living with these disease and honor
those who have lost their lives to it.
Around 34 million people around the world
have AIDS. New cases are recorded every year.
But the number of new cases is decreasing.
And yesterday, Secretary Clinton announced
a plan that aims to get rid of AIDS, but focuses
on preventing the spread of the disease and
improving treatment for people who have it.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
CLINTON: Thank you all very much.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: "CNN Heroes": ordinary people doing
extraordinary things to make a difference
in their communities. We know who this year`s
top ten are on Sunday night and all-star tribute
honors them and announces the hero of the
year. A special program starts at 8 p.m. Eastern
on CNN. Then the CNN "Heroes " tribute as
it 9 Eastern, 6 central. It`s this Sunday,
so check it out.
When you step off an airplane you might hope
to be greeted by a friendly face. Not this
one. It`s what visitors to Wellington, New
Zealand are coming face to face with for a
few months, though. Gollum can be a larger
than life character in the "Lord of the Rings"
and the "Hobbit" movies. And at this airport,
he`s just larger than a life. The 43 foot
sculpture -- it`s 43 feet high, and it`s part
of a publicity campaign, but it`s only going
to be up for a while. So we don`t think this
kind of thing is going to be habitual. Now,
I don`t think anybody is going to make the
mistake of calling it cute, although some
might see it as precious. Calling it that,
though, would take some Gollum. We know these
puns will get a ringing endorsement for some
of you , but we really only have two options:
more, door -- we`re just going to baggins
them. Those of you who follow the "Lord of
the Rings" are like OK, OK, the rest of you
like. So we`re just going to end in there.
We`ll see you next Monday with more news and
more puns. Bye now.