dish, I think there's something
wrong with her.
That's what dating is.
It's figuring out what's wrong
with the other person and
going into each other's
neuroses.
But how else are you supposed
to find love?
My name is Harry, and
I have been a loser
for most of my life.
I thought I was done with my
awkward phase when "Vice"
hired me to write about
politics, culture, and other
important world affairs,
which should make me
cool, but it doesn't.
I'm still just a weird kid
who creeps people out.
This is "All Around Losing
with Harry Cheadle."
I don't know what's wrong
with me exactly.
But lately--
and by lately, I mean
the past few years--
I've been having trouble
meeting women.
I mean, I can meet women OK.
I just have trouble going from
the hi, my name is Harry
stage, to the let me
get a condom stage.
So I'm on my way to talk to
Blake Eastman, who teaches
people who are afraid of other
people, like me, to figure out
how to date.
Hey, Blake.
BLAKE EASTMAN: Hey, Harry.
How are you?
Nice to meet you.
HARRY CHEADLE: Nice
to meet you.
Are you ready to teach me how to
use my body so I don't come
off like a weirdo?
BLAKE EASTMAN: Yeah.
All right, let's go.
HARRY CHEADLE: All right.
I mean, more broadly, I just
want to know how to talk to
girls I've just met.
I go on a lot of online
dates, you know?
So there's that moment, where
you meet someone.
And you're trying to figure out
do I want to have sex with
this person?
Do they want to have
sex with me?
And, you know, I feel like
they can pick up on my
nervousness.
BLAKE EASTMAN: I think it's an
indication of anxiety for the
most part, or what's called
soothing gestures, or
pacifying gestures,
or self-rubbing.
Basically, they rub themselves
to calm themselves down.
HARRY CHEADLE: OK.
BLAKE EASTMAN: The biggest
one men do on a
first date is this.
HARRY CHEADLE: Oh, this.
BLAKE EASTMAN: I guarantee
you do this.
HARRY CHEADLE: This.
Yeah.
BLAKE EASTMAN: Do you go out on
dates with anxious people?
HARRY CHEADLE: Sometimes, you
know, because I go on online
dates, so the people who are
online dates can get kind of
weird sometimes.
BLAKE EASTMAN: You know
the online pool is
contaminated, right?
HARRY CHEADLE: Ha, ha, ha.
Yeah, that's a good idea.
BLAKE EASTMAN: I would challenge
you to get the hell
off online dating, man.
HARRY CHEADLE: I'm thinking
about doing this
speed dating event.
It's like three-minute
interactions.
It's going to be like 20--
BLAKE EASTMAN: --how many?
20 three-minute interactions?
HARRY CHEADLE: Yeah,
like in an hour.
I think that's what it is.
It's something like that.
So what kind of advice
do you want to give
me to, like, make--
BLAKE EASTMAN: OK, so movement
really works.
If you go, literally,
like five or six
minutes before a date--
I mean, get there like
10 minutes early--
and go to the bathroom, or go
wherever, and just start
throwing as many punches or
jumping up and down--
HARRY CHEADLE: Like
literally, like--
BLAKE EASTMAN: You know,
I have no idea.
Literally, it will lower
cortisol levels and increase
testosterone levels
as you move.
So for example, get
on the floor.
HARRY CHEADLE: What
do you mean?
BLAKE EASTMAN: Push ups.
HARRY CHEADLE: Push ups?
BLAKE EASTMAN: Yeah,
do push ups.
HARRY CHEADLE: OK.
All right, I'll do
some push ups.
How many push ups do
you want me to do?
BLAKE EASTMAN: Your
push ups are bad.
HARRY CHEADLE: My push ups?
Well, I haven't done
push ups that much.
BLAKE EASTMAN: Chest up.
Chest up.
HARRY CHEADLE: Chest up?
BLAKE EASTMAN: Yeah.
All right, good.
Get up now.
Now jump up and down.
HARRY CHEADLE: Just like this?
BLAKE EASTMAN: Yeah,
but see, even your
jumping's not confident.
Like if you're gonna jump,
start jumping.
Get excited about it,
or something like--
HARRY CHEADLE: --like I'm
excited about jumping, right?
BLAKE EASTMAN: Yeah, I still
feel that you're
awkward right now.
HARRY CHEADLE: Yeah, I feel
that I'm awkward--
BLAKE EASTMAN: --because
you feel awkward.
HARRY CHEADLE: Yeah.
BLAKE EASTMAN: Right.
HARRY CHEADLE: Blake filmed me
to demonstrate just how bad I
was at standing around, then
showed me some videos of his
body language students.
Some of it was too subtle for
me to understand, but I did
like his technique.
I'm going to start videotaping
my friends for later analysis.
BLAKE EASTMAN: Have
a go at it.
HARRY CHEADLE: Yeah.
Thanks to you.
BLAKE EASTMAN: No problem.
HARRY CHEADLE: Thanks
for doing this.
So I feel I learned a lot from
Blake about communicating and
using my hands to get
my point across and
interact with people.
But I want to try it
out in the field.
So I'm here in The Watering
Hole, a bar and restaurant in
Manhattan, where I'm going to
go on some speed dating.
And I'm going to meet 15 girls
in about 45 minutes.
And that just seems
like a bad idea.
But I need to try this out.
And I need to figure
out if girls like
me, if I like girls--
I know I like girls--
and I'm going to deal with my
nervousness in two ways.
I'm going to do those exercises
Blake taught me.
And I'm going to get drunk.
MAYRA PERDOMO: Hi.
How are you?
HARRY CHEADLE: Hi.
I'm good.
I'm Harry.
I'm here for the speed dating
thing, the On Speed Dating.
MAYRA PERDOMO: Yes, Harry.
HARRY CHEADLE: Yeah.
MAYRA PERDOMO: Is this
your first time
speed dating with us?
HARRY CHEADLE: It is, yeah.
I have no idea of
how this works.
MAYRA PERDOMO: You're
going to have fun.
Don't worry about it.
HARRY CHEADLE: OK.
All right.
MAYRA PERDOMO: But if you'd
like, we're just having
everybody hang out at the bar.
HARRY CHEADLE: I didn't remember
exactly why Blake
told me to exercise before
going on a date.
Something to do with
the hormones?
Maybe women are naturally drawn
to men who are a little
out of breath?
In any case, punching the air in
front of a mirror does make
you feel like a cool, tough guy
who is ready to throw down
at a moment's notice.
This looks like the kind
of place where you
fall in love, right?
I'm sure plenty of people have
started relationships here.
Christ.
[BELL RINGING]
MAYRA PERDOMO: So for all of
you that haven't done this
before, it's very,
very simple.
What we're going to do is
everybody's going to have a
three-minute date.
I hope you guys all find love.
And thank you, again,
for coming.
[BELL RINGING]
HARRY CHEADLE: Hey.
MICHELLE: Hi.
Hey.
GERALDINE: Hi.
- Hi.
HARRY CHEADLE: How
are you doing?
I'm Harry.
ISABEL: I'm Isabel.
HARRY CHEADLE: Hey, I'm Harry.
NICKEE: Harry--
- How are you?
HARRY CHEADLE: How are you?
I'm Harry.
- How are you?
HARRY CHEADLE: I'm
good, I'm Harry.
- Eric, nice to meet you.
HARRY CHEADLE: No, no, Harry.
Yeah.
- Oh, Harry.
HARRY CHEADLE: Yeah.
No.
It's a confusing name.
I'm Harry.
KAITLIN: Kaitlin, nice
to meet you.
HARRY CHEADLE: Kaitlin,
nice to meet you.
AGNES: Hi, I'm Agnes.
Nice to meet you.
HARRY CHEADLE: Nice
to meet you.
I'm Harry.
AGNES: How are you?
HARRY CHEADLE: I'm good.
AGNES: How's it going?
HARRY CHEADLE: Good, good.
Yeah.
AGNES: Good.
HARRY CHEADLE: How are you?
AGNES: I'm good, fantastic.
HARRY CHEADLE: I'm a
shy guy naturally.
Yeah, is that coming across?
I feel like this is like
everyone's New Year's
resolution.
- Ha, ha, ha.
Totally.
HARRY CHEADLE: It's like they're
either at the gym, or
they're here.
I like your earrings.
They're very nice.
But they're very
big and round.
ANGELIQUE: Basically.
HARRY CHEADLE: You work
with Chris Brown.
ANGELIQUE: I'm doing a
Rihanna impression.
HARRY CHEADLE: Oh, yeah, yeah.
That's like representing--
GERALDINE: --yeah--
HARRY CHEADLE: --Stalin
or something.
GERALDINE: Yeah.
- Are you looking for
a relationship?
Are you looking for marriage?
HARRY CHEADLE: Oh, God, no.
Not marriage.
Well, yeah, maybe divorce.
You're not looking to get
married and have kids?
- Well, not tomorrow.
HARRY CHEADLE: OK, good.
Look, thank God.
Because I'm not up for
anything like that.
You love surgery.
- Yes.
HARRY CHEADLE: And you love
cutting dogs open, basically.
- Yeah, I like to.
HARRY CHEADLE: I like
your earrings.
They're very dangly and big.
NICKEE: Thank you.
[BELL RINGING]
HARRY CHEADLE: Well, that bell,
it's very nervewracking,
isn't it?
- It is.
Meeting new people is sometimes
nervous for me.
And then, like, the
bell goes off.
And like, oh, God,
what's happening?
NICKEE: Oh, it's over.
HARRY CHEADLE: Fuck meeting
new people.
I don't need this.
I could be more enthusiastic,
I guess.
By the end of the speed dates,
I felt like a slightly drunk,
squeezed-out dishrag.
I'd be surprised if any of my
dates liked me, because I sure
hated myself.
Well, that wears you out.
Jesus.
So it turns out that meeting
15 people for three minutes
each in 45 minutes is kind
of stressful and
kind of not that helpful.
I was trying to do everything
Blake taught me.
I was trying to be positive
with my body language.
But the truth is that when
you're meeting people, you
think about where your feet are
or where their feet are,
or where your hands are supposed
to be, or if they're
supposed to be waving around.
You're thinking about
the person.
Sometimes it just doesn't
work out.
You're just not compatible.
But I think that's OK.
You know, it's OK, actually, not
to like that many people
and to wait around for the
people that you like.
[MUSIC PLAYING]