and human systems.
A lot of people think
that programming
is exactly the same in
people and robotics.
It is not.
The major difference is
that you can design a robot
to walk over, pick up an object
and put it in another place
but before the robot moves
if you put the object in a place
the robot was going to put it in
it will still walk over and
grab nothing in particular.
Do you understand that?
That's programmed.
The difference between
human systems and robots
is that it's not linear.
That means that the robot can do certain
things that you program into it
and if you look at that
under a microscope
you can see magnetic domains that
will make the robot walk over
to a given area and
sit in a chair.
If you pull the chair away
the robot will walk over and
sit on nothing and fall over.
That's programmed.
The human system differs considerably.
When you work on a human being
or a chimpanzee or any animal....
(I'll work with the
chimp this time)
Put the chimp in a big box
and in that box are rods sticking
out at different lengths
with a cue (a circle, a
triangle, different patterns)
and you don't have to teach it anything.
It'll walk in
and sooner or later, it'll
touch those things.
When it touches one of them
water will come forth,
touches another one, food.
It touches another one and a
soft bed comes out of the wall.
If the animal is put there
for a long enough time
it will use those
rods appropriately.
Any animal has a
range of behavior.
When put in an environment, it
doesn't respond like a robot.
It looks at the environment and
seeks reinforcement: food.
If the leaves are circular
where the food is
it will go to the
circular leaves.
That's called
'associative memory'.
Programmed computers have
no associative memory.
They follow a pattern.
If you look at a
phonograph record
with a microscope,
you'll see zigzags
cut in the vinyl record.
Those zigzags are representations
of the voice of a person.
While the record is playing
if it's somebody
singing 'Caruso'
it can't deviate
from those patterns.
Robots that are programmed can't
deviate from those programs
unless you have
path alongside it
and you show variations, instead
of a circle a slight ellipse.
The animal will touch that thing
thinking it's a circle because
they're not that critical
and it gets burned slightly
so it will never touch
that one again.
That's what the animal has
that the robot doesn't have.
If the robot touches something
and it doesn't reinforce it...
How do you reinforce a robot?
If he gets stung, that
wouldn't bother him at all
but a robot can learn to
respond to different figures.
When he sees a triangle, presses
a button, he gets lubricated
but he doesn't feel good
when he gets lubricated
so there's no reason
to retain that action.
It's only when a human
touches something
and they feel good touching
it, that they repeat it.
A robot cannot touch something
and say "Hey, that feels good."
They can reach out,
do that and pull back
but they can't make anything of it.
Do you understand that?
The reason I say "Do
you understand that?"
is because there's so
much conflict today
about robots and people:
Will robots take over?
Not if they're programmed
not to take over.
If they're programmed to take
over, they can only shoot
a guy in a certain uniform.
If the guy stays put
in a given area
the robot can walk over,
unless you condition the robot
with the eyes to follow anything
that moves and shoot it.
Is a robot an assassin?
No, it's programmed to shoot.
That's quite different.
Human beings have
some people believe, 10
to 15 billion neurons.
A robot has hundreds of thousands
of associative sets, not billions.
If you learn that a
cup gives you water
anything that looks like a
cup might support water.
We can deviate from
our programming.
Our programming appears
rigid, but alongside of it
is associative memory: I
touched that and I felt pain.
I touched the other thing and I
didn't feel pain. I got something.
A robot never looks at a thing
and says "That's interesting!"
If you were to float in
midair in front of a robot
it wouldn't say "Now
that is interesting!"
It can't do that, it can only
do what it's programmed to do.
A man can see things
and be programmed and compare
it to something else.
Is that very clear, or do you
want to question anything there?
That's a major difference
between programmed behavior
and human programming.
Humans have a lot of associations
prior to programming
so the other associations, if
it reminds him of the other
he can deviate.
That's why people walk
out of here when I speak
with different interpretations.
(Roxanne) Kurzweil talks about
using nanotechnology and
implanting something in the head
like a second brain
that may be so fast
that it could take over the
other brain in the person.
This is something he's raised.
- You can do that
but it doesn't give them
leverage to wonder about that.
I've never seen that happen.
A man could say that.
A man could look at
an event, and say
"That's strange, the way that
paper holds up that speaker."
A robot does not do that.
It looks at the speaker.
It doesn't even look at it and
say "That looks like a speaker."
Unless you put a speaker in
front of the robot and say
"That's a speaker" so when its eye
sees it, it says "That's a speaker."
When you turn it sideways, it
doesn't know what that is.
When you turn it sideways and
say "That's also a speaker"
and you rotate the speaker
in many positions
so the robot has
associations with the shape
in different positions,
he can call it a speaker.
If you call an orange an orange,
but if you cut it in half
it can't call it an orange.
It doesn't say "It looks like half an orange.
" Do you understand that?
(Roxanne) This thing that Kurzweil
is putting out like 'singularity'
is when you start to implant
things in people's heads
that have so many more
calculating ability, or...
- If it is not connected
to the other neurons
it won't do anything.
-It couldn't take over? -No
unless it's connected.
(Joel) He's proposing that
it is connected somehow.
There is some interface between...
-If there is an interface
organic neurons respond
to certain rate of speed.
Anything beyond that
rate, it can't respond.
Electronic systems travel
almost at the speed of light.
Neural associations
are relatively slow.
If you try to speed up
digestion of food in a human
the digestive acids
flow at a certain rate.
If you were to triple the
rate, it might digest
portions of the intestines.
Do you understand what I mean?
For instance, let's take a bear
and put it in a room this size
with a bunch of objects sticking
out (they have to stick out)
40 of them.
A bear might learn how to use
12 of them but not 40.
It won't remember 40.
It doesn't have the neuronal
amount to remember...
A bear could remember
because when a bear walks through an
environment "This bush has berries."
He remembers where the bush is
"This area has animals
that I can eat."
A bear can build up maybe
thousands of associations
but first you have to study
the range of the animal.
How many levers an
animal can remember
will tell you what its
outside response will be.
If you find a bear that can
learn to work 47 levers
(a little beyond that or a
little less if that's true)
then you know what the bear can
respond to in the environment:
40 different systems.
A human can generate
associations
with thousands of things
in the environment.
If a human learns
to eat certain food
and he has to climb
a tree to get it
if you put that food at the base of
the tree he won't climb the tree.
A robot will.
Do you understand that?
If you program a robot to
climb a tree to get the apple
it'll do that.
If you put the apple on the
ground, the robot goes "Ha!
That simplifies things."
No, unless you build in
something special in the robot
to handle unforeseen variables
and that's what people
don't know how to do yet.
They don't know how to program a
robot to say "What have we here?"
because the words "What have we here?
" don't mean anything to a robot.
It means something
to a human being.
(Roxanne) The roboticists and
Kurzweil are bringing up
when the robot does become
connected to the environment
and does have enough
information that it would
surpass and overtake people.
- No, a robot does not
ask questions.
A robot does not say
"I've been here before.
I've seen that before."
They don't have enough
neurons to build
all kinds of associations.
(Roxanne) Do you think it's
possible that they can do that
if they use biological....
-If it's programmed, no.
But if a robot is
self-programming
then the reason for
a robot's actions
are very different
than human systems.
When a human puts something
into his mouth, it tastes good
while if a robot does it, nothing.
There's no reward.
What's a reward to a robot?
Sitting down does it say
"Whew, I'm so tired
and now I feel better.
" He doesn't feel.
When he sits down,
he doesn't say
"It's good to have a
chair in my area."
He doesn't give a shit about those things.
If the light gets so bright
that the eyes of the robot turn
off, he says "I can't see"
(if you wire him that way) but
he doesn't turn down the light
unless you wire it that way.
He turns down the light
when it gets bright
not because it's bright, but
because he has senses
that turn off the light.
Do you understand
that difference?
(Roxanne) You were explaining
this last night in terms of
humans have to have
experience to react...
Yes, that means a robot
doesn't seek experience.
A robot doesn't want to know why some
tires wear out faster than others.
He doesn't take a microscope
and look at the rubber
under a microscope.
A robot is not equipped that way.
They don't have
pleasure and pain.
If they had pleasure and pain
they would have preferences.
Do you understand?
If a robot cuts
wood with a rotary saw:
All the wood is shoved in there
automatically; he cuts it.
If you put a human in
there, he'll cut him too.
He doesn't think "That's a person,
I don't want to cut that."
The robot cannot do anything
unless it's programmed to do it.
It could be programmed to cut wood
but it will cut anything else
shoved in there.
If you interfere with its programming
it doesn't say "Wait a while, you're
interfering with the programming!"
If radar picks up fog
in San Francisco
the airplane might fly
above the weather.
The airplane moves up based
on what's out there.
If it's fog, it moves up, but it
doesn't move up to avoid the fog!
That's human projection.
A robot moves up because
there was fog ahead.
Its senses bounce back
and give it a thing
that controls the elevators
and makes it move up.
If it's raining, the robot
may open an umbrella
above itself.
But when the raindrops hit the umbrella
they make contact
with two terminals
so there's a flow across.
That opens the umbrella.
But the robot says "It's raining.
I'm going to get wet. I'll open it."
No, none of that.
Do you understand that?
I'm talking about
robotics today.
When people say "Do you think
robots will take over?"
There's no basis for it if they're
programmed a certain way.