And finally,
my moo shu pork.
Whoo-hoo!
Oh, there you have
it, gentlemen.
Our entire dinner
unpacked by robot.
And it only took 28 minutes.
Impressive,
but we must be cautious.
Why?
Today, it's a Chinese food
retrieval robot.
Tomorrow,
it travels back in time
and tries to kill Sarah Connor.
I don't think that's
going to happen, Sheldon.
No one ever does.
That's why it happens.
Hey. Is the food here?
Ooh. What's that?
That, dear lady,
is the Wolowitz
Programmable Hand,
designed
for extravehicular repairs
on the International
Space Station.
Ah, cool.
Ask me to pass the soy sauce.
Oh, does that come up much
on the space station?
Mostly with Asian
and Jewish astronauts.
All right. Pass the soy sauce.
Coming up.
So how's work?
Oh, it's not bad.
Kind of hungry.
Yeah, we all are.
Just wait.
You realize, Penny,
that the technology
that went into this arm
will one day make
unskilled food servers
such as yourself obsolete.
Really?
They're going to make a robot
that spits on your hamburger?
I thought you
broke up with her.
Why is she here?
Okay, here we go.
Passing the soy sauce.
Put out your hand.
Oh!
That's amazing.
I wouldn't say amazing.
At best,
it's a modest leap forward
from the basic technology
that gave us
Country Bear Jamboree.
Hey, Sheldon?
Yes?
Peace?
No, not peace.
Hang on.
♪ Our whole universe
was in a hot, dense state ♪
♪ Then nearly 14 billion years
ago expansion started... Wait! ♪
♪ The Earth began to cool ♪
♪ The autotrophs began to drool,
Neanderthals developed tools ♪
♪ We built the Wall ♪
♪ We built the pyramids ♪
♪ Math, Science, History,
unraveling the mystery ♪
♪ That all started
with a big bang ♪
♪ Bang! ♪