and its stupid design and talk
about ERV's with Dr.
Jean Lightner - you're watching
Genesis Week
[music]
Welcome! To this episode of
Genesis Week, the
weekly program of creationary
commentary on news,
views and events pertaining to
the origins
controversy, made possible by
the supporters of
CORE Ottawa, Citizens for
Origins Research and
Education, and now carried on
the Christianima
network - christianima.com -
Christian cinema at
its finest. Excellence in pirate
broadcasting, we
took over my best friend's
garage for our studio
today so we could continue to
bring you the
information the anticreationists
don't want you to
see or hear, and giving glory to
our Creator while
doing it. The Bible does NOT say
"Put on therefore,
as the elect of God, holy and
beloved, bowels of
mercies, kindness, numbness of
mind..." No! God
gave you a brain, we here at
Genesis Week presume
it's because He wants you to use
it! Remember if
you get lost in cyberspace, you
can just punch in
wazooloo.com or genesisweek.com
and you can find
us, and also subscribe to our
youtube channel to
get extras like CrEvo rants and
full interviews
with our guests. I'm your host,
Ian Juby.
You'll recall a few episodes
back I discussed a
NATURE interview with Dr. Steven
Benner who
described DNA as a "Stupid
design." Well nature had
a couple of papers out this past
week on the
marvels of DNA and its design.
The first one was
from researchers at the Max
Planck Institute of
Biochemistry who detailed a
ring-like protein which
holds the DNA into its compact
bundles. Now at
first, you may say "Who cares?"
But you need to
understand the significance of
this bundling. Your
DNA would be about 2 meters
long, yet it is so
tightly and carefully wound up
that it fits into
chromosomes only 1 or 2
MILLIONTHS of a meter. If
you took all of the DNA in your
body, unwound all
the strands and laid them end to
end, they could go
to the moon and back over
100,000 times. And yet,
the complex bundling and
packaging system is so
efficient, that all the DNA in
your body can fit
in a teaspoon.
Anyone who has ever packaged the
good old string of
christmas lights knows the
importance of packaging
the light strings properly, or -
it costs you an
incredible amount of work. So
now compare your DNA
to a string of christmas lights
thousands of miles
long, and you can quickly see
the importance of
keeping it very carefully
bundled when it's not in
use! This is why there are all
of these complex
bundling systems involved with
the DNA. There are
molecular machines who very
carefully and
meticulously bundle the DNA.
Guess where the plans
for those machines comes from?
You guessed it
- the DNA.
When it comes to DNA, life is on
the line. While
you need to have all these
systems for keeping DNA
controlled and tightly wound up,
cell division must
take place. So the DNA must be
unwound, a second
copy made, and the copies
properly and evenly
distributed to the two cells
dividing off. That's
where these ring proteins come
in. These are only
ONE of many, many required
complex tools and parts
for handling the very important
DNA. So which came
first: The rings which hold the
DNA together, or
the DNA which contains the plans
for the rings
which are needed to hold the DNA
together? Or the
machines which read the DNA and
make the rings? Or
the machines which install the
rings, very
carefully and methodically wind
and unwind the DNA?
The plans for those machines
come from the DNA, but
still yet other machines make
those machines, based
on plans from the DNA. The plans
for ALL of these
machines comes from the DNA -
including the
machines that make the DNA. So
which one came
first? It's a nonsense question
to ask which came
first, because the correct
answer is they all came
about at the same time! Like any
factory, these
different systems were DESIGNED.
What an incredible
designer - our best minds and
technology cannot
produce even crude renditions of
these system. All
of our best minds - all of our
most incredible
intelligence pales in comparison
to the astonishing
intelligence and design that
went into DNA and the
machines that read it. Our
Creator is truly
an awesome God!
But wait - wait - DNA was
supposed to be a stupid
design right? Not according the
researchers
attempting to use DNA in place
of hard drive
storage! Publishing their paper
in the journal -
NATURE, Goldman et al., used
synthetic DNA as a
man-made digital storage medium
- using DNA instead
of a hard drive, CD ROM, or
flash stick.
Effectively, that is what your
DNA is - think of it
like the hard drives that store
the program on how
to build you.
So Goldman et al took that
concept and ran with it:
they made a strand of DNA which
contained digitally
encoded files: They recorded all
of Shakespeare's
sonnets, a PDF copy of Watson
and Crick's original
paper describing the structure
of DNA, a JPG
photograph of the research
institute that produced
the synthetic DNA, a 26 second
MP3 of Martin Luther
King's "I have a dream" speech,
and the code that
was used to convert all of those
digital files into
a DNA sequence! All of this was
recorded onto what
can only be described as a speck
of dust, which the
researchers are confident can be
stored in cool,
dry locations, preserving the
digital data for tens
of thousands of years!
This truly is some marvelous
engineering on their
part, but obviously DNA is not a
stupid design,
seeing as how the researchers
went to great lengths
extoling the benefits of digital
storage on DNA,
and its reliability.
What's even more remarkable is
when you look at how
DNA is actually used in biology,
as it relates to
digital storage. For example,
imagine reading
information off of your hard
drive. You start at
sector 1 and read your file. If
your hard drive was
written like DNA is, you could
also start in the
middle of sector 1, read through
until the middle
of sector 2, and get OTHER
information - that's
right, completely different
information is
superimposed on the letters on
the hard drive of
sector 1. It would be like
having this line of
instructions being the first
three steps of
assembling a machine:
Our first two instructions
actually overlap and are
superimposed upon each other.
You can decipher the
instructions if you know where
to start and stop:
So you provide more instructions
with fewer letters
- your instructions take LESS
SPACE. And that is
how the DNA is written. A lot of
imformation is
actually superimposed upon other
strings of letters
in the DNA!
As has now been discovered,
other portions of the
DNA direct the reading of other
portions of the DNA
so that, in our example
sentence, we can extract a
third step in the assembly
instructions. The
numbers on the end dictate how
to extract the third
assembly instruction from
seemingly random places
in the original information, by
telling us to
collect the specific words by
their position
in the string:
Yet in the DNA, that extra
directing information -
those seemingly meaningless
numbers, make up some
98% of your DNA! It was called
"junk DNA" because
it didn't seem to do anything
directly! We are only
now beginning to unravel how the
"junk DNA" is used
- and it's mind bogglingly
complex!
Our best computer programmers on
earth would be
hard pressed to write programs
with overlapping
lines of code, other sections of
code which direct
how to retrieve more
instructions from random
locations in the overall code,
etc... and if a
computer programmer did such a
thing, we'd call
them a genius. We certainly
wouldn't say their code
was a stupid design - unless we
were ignorant of
what they were doing.
So here we see Goldman et. al.
using DNA to do
exactly what it does in nature:
Communicate and
transmit information. No one is
suggesting that
this man-made DNA happened by
unguided processes.
Everyone is acknowledging it was
intelligently
assembled. So why is it then
that some would
suggest that OUR DNA was NOT
intelligently
assembled? I'll tell you why -
philosophical
reasons only. No one has ever
seen DNA assemble
itself and compile information
out of nothingness.
Information has only ever been
observed to come
from information. That's a
scientific fact. In fact
I would dare say that DNA has
only ever been
observed to arise from DNA!
Think about it.
Intelligence has only ever been
observed to come
from intelligence, therefore the
intelligence that
went into the incredible design
of our DNA is the
ultimate in intelligence,
because after decades of
mind-bogglingly complex research
and study, we
STILL haven't found out the
entirety of how our
computer program, our DNA, is
used.
That ultimate intelligence is, I
would suggest,
Christ Jesus, our Creator. His
incredible
intelligence in baffling the
pharisees, saducees
and those attempting to trap him
in His words, that
intelligence He showed was only
a scratch on the
surface of his ultimate
intelligence.
Speaking of alleged "junk DNA" -
ERV's were in the
news again this past week.
Researchers from the
University of Massachusetts
published a paper in
the journal Retrovirology,
showing that an ERV
played a role in the production
of our stem cells.
Stem cells are found in various
places throughout
the body and are crucial to
development, as stem
cells can turn into pretty much
any cell that your
body needs. The researchers
claimed this ERV was
"millions of years old," and
notice what the
researchers said in their
interview with
ScienceDaily:
I know, I know what you're
thinking - Come on Ian -
what on earth is an ERV? To help
us understand this
technical subject, Dr. Jean
Lightner has joined me
via skype. Dr. Lightner obtained
her bachelor's
degree in agriculture, earned a
masters and DVM in
Veterinarian medicine, all from
Ohio State
University. She is an excellent
communicator and
I'm thrilled to have her join me
today  welcome
to the show Dr. Lightner.
>>Why thank you Ian
>>So let's start off with that
question  - just
what is an ERV and how does it
relate to
the creation/evolution debate?
>>An ERV is an endogenous
retrovirus. In order to
understand what that is, we
should probably talk
about what a retrovirus is.
There are several
different kinds of viruses, all
pretty much contain
a protein outside, a coat, and
inside they have a
nucleic acid, either DNA or RNA.
>>RNA is one half of the DNA
ladder.
>>Essentially. Retroviruses have
RNA on the inside.
When they infect a cell the RNA
is injected into
the host cell. Then it does
something very
interesting. Usually we think of
DNA being
transcribed into RNA which is
translated into
proteins. However, with the RNA
from the
retrovirus, it does something
kind of backwards.
The RNA is used as a template to
make new DNA that
then becomes part of the host
DNA. This is reverse
transcription, which is where
the retro term comes
from. So a retrovirus is
something outside a cell
which infects a cell. The RNA is
reverse
transcribed back into DNA. Then
when the host
transcribes its own DNA it will
copy the virus DNA
as well. Then it will make new
viruses. Then you
will have a whole bunch of new
viruses to go and
infect other cells.
There are some specific features
of a retrovirus
sequence that help us to
identify it. For example
on either end are long terminal
repeats (LTRs).
This is repetitive DNA. In
between are several
specific genes. When we started
looking at sequence
data from the DNA of various
creatures, such as
humans or animals, we found
patterns that looked
like the result of retrovirus
infections. However,
these sequences are part of the
DNA that is passed
down from parent to offspring.
It is these
sequences which are called
endogenous retroviruses
(ERVs).
>>OK. So can you briefly clarify
how we know the
difference between a retrovirus
and endogenous
retrovirus (ERV)?
>>With a regular retroviral
infection, some of the
cells in the body are infected,
but these cells do
not pass information on to the
offspring. With an
endogenous retroviral sequence,
it appears similar
to a retroviral sequence but it
is found in all
cells of the body and is passed
on to the
offspring. Many of these
sequences have patterns in
them that look like damage from
an ancient
infection because they do not
code for all the
necessary components to make an
active virus. Often
there are many copies of them,
which makes it look
like they have spread in the DNA
in the past.
>>So how does it relate to
the creation/evolution debate?
>>If we assume that these ERV
sequences are really
from a past infection in the
germ line and if we
assume that the retroviral
sequences are inserted
essentially randomly, then when
we find an ERV
sequence that is very similar in
the same position
in two different animals it
would make sense that
this came from an infection that
happened in one
of their ancestors.
So evolutionists were really
excited when they
found out that humans and other
primates share
similar ERV sequences in the
same position. To them
that was proof that humans and
other primate had to
share a common ancestor. It
seemed they were best
explained as an infection in a
common ancestor.
>>Now I like the way Dr. Joseph
Mastropaolo put it:
I mean typically a virus infects
a specific type of
cell or area in the DNA, so you
and I getting the
same flu does not make us
relatives
>>True enough. And that is a
good point, perhaps
those sequences got there
independently in
humans and primates.
>>What are some of the problems
with this thinking
that ERV's are, in fact,
evidence of viral infection and
more importantly,
evidence of evolution?
>>As I mentioned, ERVs were
believed to be junk
DNA. If ERVs were left over from
an ancient viral
infection, they certainly
wouldn’t be expected to
carry out important functions.
The problem is that more recent
research has shown
that these portions of DNA are
transcribed at
specific times in specific
tissues. They appear to
be important in a number of
different ways.
There is an excellent
creationist article
highlighting this. In 2009 Dr.
Liu and Dr. Soper
published an interesting article
in the Answers
Research Journal entitled: The
Natural History of
Retroviruses: Exogenization vs
Endogenization. In
it, they cite research
documenting ERVs directly
coding for proteins, and others
associated with
gene regulation, DNA repair and
recombination, and
transduction (making copies onto
RNA and then
reverse transcribing them
somewhere else in
the DNA).
Basically, they hypothesize that
things actually
went the other direction.
Retroviruses appeared
when these mobile elements
within the
genome escaped.
>>So in other words ERV's
weren't caused by virus
genes, but rather virus genes
came from ERV's?
>>It appears so. One of the
biggest problems for
the earlier claims that these
are evidence for
evolution is that ERVs have been
shown to have
essential roles in reproduction
and development.
So how did the primate ancestor
reproduce while it
was waiting for the germline
retroviral infection?
>>Ya  like it brings whole new
meaning to
“Honey, I don't have a
headache.” This is a
critical point  this is the
reproductive system.
So effectively, without this
alleged ERV, no
reproduction, therefore,
extinction of the species.
>>It would seem so. Instead of
these sequences
being the result of an ancient
infection, it seems
more logical that they were
created for a purpose.
The article by Liu and Soper
make a good
case for this.
I mentioned earlier two
assumptions. The first is
that these sequences were the
result of germline
infections in the distant past.
We have just
discussed why this may not be
the case. The second
is that they insert essentially
randomly. A more
recent article by Santoni et al.
challenges this.
Not only did they find a human
ERV associated with
an essential part of
development, but they also
found that the placement of
these sequences were
associated with certain
epigenetic markers.
>>For the sake of the viewers,
if I may interrupt,
epigenetics is sort of the
controlling of genes
with other genetic “switches,”
which are called
epigenetic markers. So just
think of epigenetic
markers as switches that turn on
or off certain
portions of the DNA. Sorry Jean
- I just had to
throw something in to make
myself look smart. Carry
on with what you were saying.
>>In this case the epigenetic
marker was a specific
histone. Histones are special
proteins the DNA is
wrapped around that affect how
exposed the section
of DNA is so it can be
translated. So the Santoni
et al paper indicates that this
type of ERV in
humans is less randomly arranged
than
we had thought.
Sometimes the word random can
just mean we don’t
understand yet why the pattern
is there.
Now there are times where ERVs
are associated with
disease. In fact, we often
discover the problems
associated with something before
we really
understand the importance of
that something. This
was true of bacteria. Because
they were found to be
associated with disease, many
had assumed they were
always bad. It turns out this is
not the case. Most
are not harmful. In fact many
are essential for
life on earth. It looks like the
same may be true
of ERVs and other mobile genetic
elements.
>>Well that is fascinating Dr.
Lightner, I really
appreciate your taking the time
to be on the show
today, I know the viewers will
appreciate it too,
so for all of us, thank you for
being with us
and sharing today.
>>Okay - thank you for having
me.
>>Stick around, we'll be right
back after this
break that is so short, your
viruses won't even
have a chance to get you
infected!
This show sponsored in part by
Canada's first
permanent Creation Museum, in
the heart of
Alberta's dinosaur beds, the Big
Valley Creation
Science Museum. bvcsm.com
And by Genesis Park.com where
you can pre-order
your own beautiful hard covered
copy of the
Chronicles of Dinosauria, the
history and mystery
of dinosaurs and man.
[funny music]
Funny, fast and furious! Ian's
CrEvo Rants cover a
multitude of topics in an easy
to understand,
comical way. Complicated subject
that normally make
your brain hurt, hurt a lot less
when
Ian explains them...
while wearing his
anti-government mind reading
equipment. Have questions about
Carbon 14 dating?
Natural selection,
thermodynamics, or...
what on earth is he doing there?
Three volumes of rants on DVD,
take your pick for
$15 each plus S&H or order all
three as a package
and save yourself ten bucks!
Order on line today
at Ian's bookstore.
[scary, dramatic music]
Wahoo! Mail for me?
[sound of a geiger counter
detecting a
lot of radiation]
Hmmm...I wonder what it tastes
like?
[drinking sounds]
[scary, dramatic music]
In response to last week's
discussion about the
population problem, YouTuber
Kiwifrogg wrote in:
Thanks for writing in! Several
people brought up
similar points, but you need to
remember several
things: First of all, cremation
is a modern
phenomena. Secondly, as I
mentioned briefly,
Neanderthal graves have been
found, complete with
burial artifacts - so it's not a
western ideal to
bury a single plot with grave
artifacts. Lastly,
you also need to remember the
astronomical numbers
of bodies we're talking about
here - I was
exceedingly conservative for the
sake of argument,
and as several viewers pointed
out, I still only
dealt with 200,000 years of
people, not the two
MILLION years of alleged human
ancestors right
through to Homo Habilis and the
like. Besides
which, none of that was my main
point: to assume
deep time and explain away the
missing bodies is
arguing from absence of
evidence.
lunchbox420wb wrote in:
Actually, I got it from a
Messianic Rabbi on
YouTube by the name of Steven
DeNoon. He pointed it
out in scripture and I went and
looked - and he's
right! The word "bush" that is
used there in Exodus
is the word Sen-eh which
according to
Strong's concordance is
a bush, thorny bush
the burning bush of Moses
perhaps a blackberry bush
And of course we see the
representation of the Holy
Spirit there as well in the form
of fire, and we
are told that this was all
"God." So you can see
the three parts represented in
one,
in that passage.
Thanks everyone for writing in,
keep'em coming -
you can send in your comments,
questions, letter
bombs and random hate mail to
comments@genesisweek.com, or
send us a tweet
@genesisweek, or head to
Genesisweek.com which is
our YouTube channel, and leave a
comment under the
most recent show. And while
you're there, please
subscribe to our youtube channel
and remember you
can share the show with all your
friends on
twitfaceplus using the
convenient "share" button
below the video. I'm your host,
Ian Juby, signing
off for now and reminding you of
those words of
warning and comfort from our
Creator, the Lord
Jesus Christ, who said "I am the
way, the truth,
and the life - no man comes to
the Father but
through me" See you week.
We need your support to keep
this program on the
air. Please pray for us, and if
you wish to
financially support the program,
Canadians can make
a tax-deductible donation to
CORE Ottawa, CORE
Ottawa, Kanata North Post Office
Box 72075, Ottawa,
ON. Canada, K2K 2P4
While we cannot offer tax
deductable receipts
outside of Canada, donors
wishing to financially
support the program can do so on
line at
ianjuby.org/donations.html and
thank you for your
support.
[music]