[SPEAKING GREEK]
[EXPLOSION]
[COUGHING]
Yeah, we all know Greece
is messed up, but how
did it get this bad?
In 2009, national debt
threateners turned Greece into
a failed state.
Decades of endemic economic
corruption had finally caught
up with the place.
Their position was now so
volatile, it threatened the
entire future of the Euro.
Europe scrabbled together
billion-dollar bailouts, but
they came with orders of
austerity, demands of huge
cutbacks in public spending and
services, which have left
the Greek people hopeless
and jobless.
[SPEAKING GREEK]
In October, another series of
austerity measures were
announced for the country.
A two-day general strike
was called.
So we flew to Athens, bought
a bunch of gas masks, and
wandered into a fight at the
center of a European tragedy.
A lot of Greek people told us,
Athens is going to burn.
[CAR HONKING]
We met Adam, a young protester
who asked us not to identify
him due to his history of
violent clashes with police.
This is Syntagma Square, where
Greek Parliament stands.
In June 2011, as Greece face
bankruptcy, violent battles
took place here between police
and protesters, as the prime
minister, George Papandreou
forced an austerity bill
through Parliament.
Between the Square and the
Parliament, the desperadoes
would be standing.
They're the normal people,
protesting for the first time.
The more militant members of
the march kind of dismissed
them as moobs.
The students will be marching
from the university library,
presumably with a hilarious
banner or two.
The Communists will be
starting from here.
There are loads of
indistinguishable Communist
subgroups called things like
PAME, but no one really
understands the difference
between them.
This is Exarcheia,
which the media
describes as a rebel lair.
It's from this sector of squats
and occupied buildings
that the anarchists will
start their day.
The union workers will
begin from here,
marching through Exarcheia.
Anarchists hate them, so
there'll probability be a
fight en route.
Everybody's heading for Syntagma
Square, where the
police will be waiting,
defending Parliament with
sticks and gas.
This is Michael, a young student
who recently spent two
months occupying Syntagma
Square.
[SPEAKING GREEK]
On the other side of Syntagma
Square, a van had been
trundling along the streets with
megaphones blaring the
revolutionary slogans of PAME,
the workers' militant front.
They were happy to
give us a ride.
[SPEAKING GREEK]
Greece's economic shit storm has
landed in the middle of a
country with a long history of
getting rid of regimes they
really don't like.
They did it to Mussolini
in 1940.
Then there was a coup
d'etat in 1967 and a
student uprising in 1973.
You can see why the Greek
authorities might be nervous
of their people.
Maybe that's why they employ one
of the most hated police
forces in all of Europe, one
with a reputation for
brutality and widely rumored
connections to the local
fascist organizations.
Depending on who you ask,
Greece's tradition of violent
anarchist activism is either the
cause of police brutality
or a natural revolutionary
reaction to authoritarian
oppression.
In the river district of his
Exarcheia sits a huge occupied
university building.
Most journalists aren't
allowed in.
But two young anarchists agreed
to take us there.
They thought our gas masks were
pretty funny, though.
[SPEAKING GREEK]
[EXPLOSION]
[CLAPPING AND CHEERING]