EDDY MORETTI: No, I'm
not smoking crack.
No, they're not smoking crack.
I don't think they're
smoking crack.
NOREEN: I'm Noreen [INAUDIBLE]
from Anzac.
I come around here.
Um, my mom stays in here.
LLOYD LEONARD CAMPBELL: I'm
Lloyd Leonard [INAUDIBLE]
Campbell.
EDDY MORETTI: Is it okay
that we film you guys?
LLOYD LEONARD CAMPBELL:
You sure the hell can.
Because if somebody doesn't say
nothing, how does people
understand how the
homeless live.
You are the first ones that
ever come and got
a report from here.
And we've been here for many
years, but nobody--
SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
We had no problems.
LLOYD LEONARD CAMPBELL: --seems
to care about us.
And yous guys are the first ones
that seem to want to know
how we live.
SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN): OK,
you will light that--
don't burn him.
MALE SPEAKER 1: No, I'm
not going to burn him.
EDDY MORETTI: That
was hot, though.
SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Don't burn him, no.
EDDY MORETTI: Did I--
I burned my beard, didn't I?
SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN): Oh yeah.
[LAUGHTER]
MALE SPEAKER 1: No, you didn't,
because I have a lot
of respect for you.
[LAUGHTER]
MALE SPEAKER: I wouldn't
let that happen to you.
NOREEN: Mom, there she is.
Are you cold?
MALE SPEAKER 1: That's an
elderly lady sleeping--
SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
It's a big mess.
MALE SPEAKER 1: --in the
wintertime without a home.
NOREEN'S MOM: [INAUDIBLE]
I'm so weak, I just
want to lay down.
SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN): SPCA.
EDDY MORETTI: That's OK.
Yeah sure, we'll get you
something to eat.
What would you like to eat?
NOREEN'S MOM: Anything.
I was never fussy.
EDDY MORETTI: You were
not fussy, right.
MALE SPEAKER 1: She hasn't
ate for 24 hours.
We talk about equally--
like, equally in humane
society--
EDDY MORETTI: Right.
MALE SPEAKER 1: But look
where we're at.
EDDY MORETTI: Did you ever
work on the oil--
for the oil companies?
MALE SPEAKER 1: Yeah.
EDDY MORETTI: You did?
How was that?
MALE SPEAKER 1: Could I
be able to say, like,
there's a lot of--
EDDY MORETTI: Racism?
MALE SPEAKER 1: Yeah.
SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
I have worked.
MALE SPEAKER 1: I didn't want
to use those words, but--
SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
I worked at--
MALE SPEAKER 1: It is.
A lot of racism.
EDDY MORETTI: Like white
people don't--
MALE SPEAKER 1: --recognize
us, because--
like, I got fired from a
job, where five guys I
trained got me fired.
And I trained them
how to push dirt.
EDDY MORETTI: When
was it better?
Was it better before?
MALE SPEAKER 1: Oh, boy.
SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN): Not much.
MALE SPEAKER 1: Oh.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Mostly
trapping.
SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Mostly trapping?
Fishing?
SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN): Fishing.
MALE SPEAKER 1: Fishing.
FEMALE SPEAKER 1: But you
can't eat it no more.
EDDY MORETTI: Why can't you
eat the fish no more?
MALE SPEAKER 1: Because--
FEMALE SPEAKER 1: Because
it's polluted.
MALE SPEAKER 1: It's
chemicals.
FEMALE SPEAKER 1: [INAUDIBLE]
MALE SPEAKER 1: They sink
in [INAUDIBLE] and--
EDDY MORETTI: Do they look--
FEMALE SPEAKER 1: They're
all polluted.
EDDY MORETTI: --funny,
the fish now?
Do they look different?
SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
No, I don't know.
MALE SPEAKER 1: Yeah, they do.
They have some-- they
have some--
EDDY MORETTI: --markings
on them?
MALE SPEAKER 1: You
could tell.
EDDY MORETTI: You could
tell they're not--
MALE SPEAKER 1: You could
tell the difference.
Like, we don't have to be
educated to tell the
difference, OK?
LLOYD LEONARD CAMPBELL:
This water,
this water, it's polluted.
You go and get fish, we don't
know if we can eat that.
Because the oil company's down
at the other end, and all that
waste is going into the water.
We've seen it.
And I respect your company
for coming
down here and checking--
NOREEN'S MOM: I thank you
so much for supper.
LLOYD LEONARD CAMPBELL:
--to see how we
live and what we do.
[LAUGHTER]
[MOTOR RUNNING]
SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Come by the fire.
MALE SPEAKER 1: This is
Happy New Year's.
SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN): It is.
Happy New Year, right here.
EDDY MORETTI: It's Happy
New Year by the river.
MALE SPEAKER 1: Yeah, this is
New Year's by the river.
EDDY MORETTI: It's
a barbecue party,
although it's fried chicken.
It's a fried chicken party.
NOREEN'S MOM: Thank
you so much.
How could I--
I appreciate my--
EDDY MORETTI: Just
shake my hand.
NOREEN'S MOM: Could
I make moccasins?
EDDY MORETTI: 8 1/2, 9.
NOREEN'S MOM: 8 and 1/2, OK.
EDDY MORETTI: Nine.
NOREEN'S MOM: Where do you
want me putting them?
EDDY MORETTI: I don't know.
I'll have to come back to
get them, or you can--
NOREEN'S MOM: I've
got deer hide.
EDDY MORETTI: Yeah.
NOREEN'S MOM: And I do a lot--
my daughter helps me do that.
EDDY MORETTI: Deer
hide moccasins.
Yeah, I'd love a pair.
NOREEN'S MOM: And you, too?
EDDY MORETTI: She'd love--
yeah.
FEMALE SPEAKER 2: I would
love some moccasins.
NOREEN'S MOM: OK.
FEMALE SPEAKER 2: Get
stuck in the snow.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
[WHEELS SPINNING]
EDDY MORETTI: So Lou, you helped
us out of the snow, and
now you're giving us
a tour of the town.
LOU: This is, uh yeah,
the rush hour.
EDDY MORETTI: Rush hour traffic
Thursday night.
LOU: Thursday night.
EDDY MORETTI: Holy fucking shit,
it's pickup after pickup
after truck.
LOU: Yeah.
EDDY MORETTI: Do you think this
boom is going to last a
long time, or do you
think it's gonna--
LOU: Who knows?
Last time they said it was
supposed to last a long time,
and then all of the sudden,
it just died.
EDDY MORETTI: What if 50% of
the people left, suddenly?
You'd have all these
empty apartments,
and rent would be--
LOU: That happened before.
EDDY MORETTI: Really?
LOU: Oh, yeah.
EDDY MORETTI: Homes for--
LOU: People did throw
their keys on the
table and walk away.
EDDY MORETTI: No?
LOU: Oh yeah, that
happened before.
There's nothing up here.
If you want to see a doctor,
you might as well fly back
home and go and see a doctor.
EDDY MORETTI: It's true, though,
there are a lot of
people here for only
six doctors.
It's a bit insane.
Right?
LOU: Yeah.
EDDY MORETTI: But you're not
going to move or anything?
LOU: No, I wouldn't move.
EDDY MORETTI: You're
staying here.
LOU: It's home.
EDDY MORETTI: It's home.
LOU: Once you're here, where
else can you go?
It's an oil town, and it's
always gonna be.
EDDY MORETTI: This used to
be called the "Bridge to
Nowhere," because in the '80s
they just stopped building it
when the bust happened.
This place has gone through
two or three
boom and bust cycles.
LOU: That was our
last project.
EDDY MORETTI: And this
thing flows up to--
LOU: Fort Chip.
EDDY MORETTI: --Fort Chip.
LOU: Right around the corner,
right over here, that's Steep
Bank River, right over there.
Well it's not a very good river
to be riding sleds on,
that's for sure.
Yeah.
EDDY MORETTI: Do you eat the
fish out of this river?
LOU: No, not now.
[LAUGHTER]
LOU: Years ago, yeah,
but not no more.
EDDY MORETTI: We're in the
middle of nowhere, and you
can't eat the fish.
OK, let's go look at this close
and read this thing,
"the first thing you notice
about the wood bison is its
majestic appearance, and
rightly so." What
they've done is--
this is reclaimed land.
So, and this is, like, they've
made it into a park.
It's called Wood Bison Park,
I think, and they're
very proud of it.
And they put a herd
of bison back in.
There's a few over here.
The most interesting thing about
this park is if you look
over there, that's Suncor
spewing out pollution.
LOU: And this stuff, here,
it's not snow.
That's what they call,
"sinkered snow."
EDDY MORETTI: What's
sinkered snow?
LOU: Basically it's
humidity from what
you see, right there.
EDDY MORETTI: Yeah.
LOU: It creates its
own weather, so it
creates its own snow.
EDDY MORETTI: This plant
produces its own weather.
This is fake snow.
This is condensation from
all of that polluted
steam that's rising.
And if you look at it,
it just looks weird.
It doesn't look like
proper snow.
It's all freaky.
It's polluted--
it's pollution.
It's fake snow.
[GASP]
EDDY MORETTI: I can't
feel my fingers.
FEMALE SPEAKER 2: Me neither,
me neither.
EDDY MORETTI: OK.
GEORGE POITRAS: We don't
disagree with development.
We don't disagree that
energy is required
throughout the world.
We disagree when the President
of the United States, though,
suggests, at any expense, that
his solution to the United
States' energy crisis should
come from the oil sands versus
Saudi Arabia, now.
Because like anywhere, we
will, still, be the
inhabitants of the
land once the
resources have been exploited.
EDDY MORETTI: So this is it--
Fort Chip--
GEORGE POITRAS: Yeah.
EDDY MORETTI: Fort Chipewyan,
oldest settled community in
Alberta, 1788.
They came up over the northern
part of Canada, and--
GEORGE POITRAS: Yeah.
EDDY MORETTI: --settled here.
Anthropologists trace these
communities back 12,000 years?
GEORGE POITRAS: About
12,000 years, yeah.
EDDY MORETTI: Wow.
PAT MARCEL: If we could survive,
you know, almost on a
daily basis, we didn't
destroy anything--
we've been here 10,000
years, and look
for the Indian footprint.
You won't see it.
I never said I was against
development, but it's got to
be sustainable development.
Everything has to fit
in a certain way
to make things work.
If you throw something out of
balance, something's out of
kilter, right away.
Things go wrong.
We've got cancer rates.
We've got arsenic in moose.
That's only the start.
That's only in 60 years.
Everybody will dispute that.
Each level of government that
comes here will dispute that.
But we know.
We're the people
who are dying.
We should know who's dying,
here, and of what.
If I'm put in a corner,
you know,
I'm going to do something.
And that's what I started to
feel like, you know, like I'm
being pushed.
SIMON DYER: There are five
First Nations in the Fort
McMurray area.
Two of the most impacted by oil
sands development are the
Mikisew Cree First Nation and
the Athabasca Chipewyan First
Nation, who live downstream of
Fort McMurray in the community
of Fort Chipewyan.
And they obviously have been a
lot of concerns about use of
the Athabasca River-- still
being able to fish, still
being able to eat the fish,
still being able to get out on
the land and trap and pass
on their traditions.
Fort McKay First Nation, which
is, actually, right in the oil
sands area-- they, actually,
have, obviously, oil sands on
the reserve lands, and they're,
actually, developing
a portion of those in
partnership with Shell
LINDSAY TELFER: You know, it's
kind of-- they got the raw end
of the stick.
They're, sort of, screwed
both ways.
So why not get some money.
Right, like--
EDDY MORETTI: That's
short thinking.
You shouldn't be thinking
like that.
LINDSAY TELFER: I,
totally, agree.
I'm not-- you know-- but I try
to understand where they're
coming from.
Their community is surrounded
by these mines.
Their land is just
being taken away.
And I think that they're
starting to realize, as well,
that they're getting a bit of
a raw end of the stick.
The Treaty 8 First Nations have
just called for a class
environmental social impact
assessment in the region.
EDDY MORETTI: Hasn't there
been one already?
LINDSAY TELFER: No.
The mercury levels in moose
meat have skyrocketed.
And so now they're at-- can
we eat moose anymore.
Can they-- you know,
caribou have been
pushed out of the region.
And so they're not there.
And so the subsistence lifestyle
of many of the
northern First Nations is
rapidly disappearing.
If you want to destroy a
culture, then all you need to
do is lock up their food.
And that's what she sees these
processes as doing-- is
locking up their food to force
them into buying into what
they see as the "white
man world."
EDDY MORETTI: We were up in Fort
Chipewyan the other day.
We flew up there, and we were
talking to the chief there.
What's the water quality
like there?
Are you concerned at all about
contamination in the water.
I mean--
MELISSA BLAKE: We test water
quality, so I would suggest
that the testing that's done is
probably giving assurances
to residents that whatever
you drink is appropriate.
EDDY MORETTI: If you knew that
people wouldn't drink the
water from the rivers, would
that be enough for you to--
MELISSA BLAKE: I still won't.
EDDY MORETTI: No.
MELISSA BLAKE: I put it through
a filtering system.
EDDY MORETTI: Right.
MELISSA BLAKE: That's what gives
me my assurance that
when it comes out of my
tap, I can drink it.
So nobody is going to go back to
the belief that they could
ever take water from a stream,
probably, and--
EDDY MORETTI: Which was shocking
to me, because I'm
living in New York for about a
decade, and I thought this far
north, we're eating snow and
drinking from the river.
MELISSA BLAKE: Why would
anybody anywhere?
EDDY MORETTI: Returning to the
land as some kind of idyllic
idea is, probably--
those days are gone, right?
MELISSA BLAKE: I
wouldn't know.
PAT MARCEL: Yeah, and it
has been a concern
for a good many years.
They just dumped all the
dioxins and [INAUDIBLE]
directly into the Athabasca.
And people are wondering how
come we're getting sick, here,
and dying of rare cancers.
But they dump 4,000
other chemicals
every day in the Athabasca.
GEORGE POITRAS: Even 20 years
ago, you could go in the
river, which a lot of our people
do for cultural and
other reasons.
They were able to scoop water
from the river and drink it
without any concern about
contaminants in the water.
Today, nobody would
drink the water.
You couldn't.
EDDY MORETTI: Really?
GEORGE POITRAS: Nobody would
drink the water.
SIMON DYER: If we just look at
the mining perspective, all
these oil sands mines
are either side of
the Athabasca River.
So oil sands companies, oil
sands mines, basically,
extract water directly from
the Athabasca River.
The typical oil sands mine takes
between 2 and 1/2 and 4
barrels of water to extract
one barrel of bitumen.
Because the process, of course,
pollutes that water so
much, it's, largely, not,
actually, returned to the
Athabasca River.
The vast majority of
it gets dumped into
these tailings ponds.
So these are, basically, oily
lagoons full of waste water
and suspended hydrocarbons.
The working hypothesis is that,
you know, the portion of
that tailings is thickened,
and incorporated into the
terrestrial reclaimed
landscape.
LINDSAY TELFER: We're starting
to get more information on the
health effects.
I mean, the thing with health
effects is that it's long
term, right.
They often come after too much
development, and so what we're
seeing, now, are some very clear
signs that there are
downstream health effects.
EDDY MORETTI: Who's
being affected?
LINDSAY TELFER: The First
Nations communities.
PAT MARCEL: This is a
huge experiment, and
I warned the companies.
I said, "what looks bad in
eastern Canada, might look
even worse here." Because you're
not only going to kill
the river, you're going
to kill First Nations.
This thing's out of control--
produce, produce, produce,
you know.
And that's where we're going.
Why the mad rush to take
all this oil out?
Take your time.
Develop safely.
Make sure it's sustainable.
Instead of taking it all
out in 40 years,
make it last 200 years.
So it doesn't stop, because
man is greedy.
Man can have a handful of money,
more than what he needs
to survive, but he'll
still want more.
SIMON DYER: We need to
communicate what's going on in
the oil sands.
We need to ensure that
this gets better,
rapidly better, quickly.
We need to ensure there
is a moratorium
until we improve that.
And we need to use this
as a stepping
stone to change things.
America, of course, uses
more than 20 million
barrels of oil a day.
LINDSAY TELFER: Obviously
there's been no plan.
That's why it spiraled
out of control.
Our communities have spiraled
Development spiraled
out of control.
PAT MARCEL: I never said I was
against development, but it's
got to be sustainable
development.
So at this fast pace--
you know, development
right now--
we are losing our youth.
ANTHONY: It's absolutely
crazy.
The infrastructure's
not meant for this.
RALPH KLEIN: At some
point, they will
say enough is enough.
We've reached our limits.
There is no room to move.
LINDSAY TELFER: The growing
emissions of the oil sands are
enough to prevent Canada,
single-handedly, from meeting
our Kyoto commitments.
The reality is Canada signed
and ratified Kyoto.
EDDY MORETTI: Mhm.
LINDSAY TELFER: It's
international law.
Whether we like it or not, we
have an obligation to meet it.
The conservative governments
have been backtracking and
backtracking, trying to figure
out a way to get us out of it.
Basically, they said
it's impossible.
They won't do it.
It will trash our economy,
none of which is true.
We can do it.
It won't trash our economy.
Suncor, one of the biggest oil
sands operators, came out just
this week and said, "eh, it
won't trash our economy."
RALPH KLEIN: These oil
companies know--
EDDY MORETTI: Mhm.
RALPH KLEIN: --that they are
going to have to curtail their
emissions of greenhouse gases.
EDDY MORETTI: And eventually
start bringing them down.
RALPH KLEIN: By the year 2020.
EDDY MORETTI: Right
RALPH KLEIN: OK it's a longer
period of time.
It's not 2010 as the
Kyoto protocol--
EDDY MORETTI: --demands
or dictates.
RALPH KLEIN: --dictates.
EDDY MORETTI: Right.
RALPH KLEIN: It's a longer
period of time, but it is
legislated.
SIMON DYER: Canada could meet
its Kyoto commitments by using
a combination of regulations
and incentives
to make this happen.
EDDY MORETTI: Right.
SIMON DYER: For the cost of a
couple of dollars on the cost
of a barrel of oil, companies
could be completely carbon
neutral-- that's have a net zero
greenhouse gas emission
footprint-- because you know,
it's most efficient when you
have large point sources.
And that's what the
oil sands are.
So we have solutions out there,
but we're choosing not
to use them.
LINDSAY TELFER: Alberta,
southern Alberta has the
strongest possibility for solar
and wind in Canada.
Yet we don't have-- we don't
put any money towards it.
And in fact, we capped our wind
energy production at 900
megawatts--
EDDY MORETTI: Smart.
LINDSAY TELFER: --so we couldn't
build anymore.
EDDY MORETTI: Brilliant.
LINDSAY TELFER: So I mean, we
need to be creating that
environment for innovation
within the province.
And I think people want
to see us going there.
I don't think that they want to
see us putting all our eggs
in the oil sands basket.
The community is saying, "no
more." And if the government
doesn't respond, then there's
going to be--
I think that there's going
to be some uprising.
And my question to the Alberta
government has always been, do
we really want to be the final
frontier of a dying resource.
Or do we, actually, want
to be the innovators
of something new.
And I think that we've got the
innovation and the technical
ability and the know-how in this
province to, actually, be
leaders of a new energy
frontier.