And they need to discuss
your mental challenges.
- I have to go to
a fund-raiser meeting.
Why do you think I have to go?
- Fund-raiser meeting?
- Mm-Hmm.
I can't stand these stupid meetings.
And those women get on my nerves.
- How come?
- Because all they do is
nitpick and gossip
And criticize.
And every time I go to one
of these things,
Somehow I end up running another event.
And then all they do
is sit around and say no
To everything I suggest.
And then they wait till the last minute
And look at me like I'm crazy.
Well, I'll tell you what.
They're gonna
have to find another fool.
- I'll tell you what.
Why don't I go with you?
- You don't have to do that.
- Well, yes, I do.
I've seen you mad.
I'm not gonna let you
run around that room
Snatching off wigs and weaves
"Ahh, Ahh!"
Screaming at the top of your voice,
And running up on the roof,
talking about,
"you'll never take me alive!"
And then the police
have to surround the place
With guns and megaphones.
And then they arrest you.
And then I end up a single father.
That's not why I got married.
- Aw, honey.
That's very nice.
What about the kids?
Do you think we need a sitter?
- No.
By the time I was 15,
My mother was leaving me alone
with food, keys, bus fare,
And a couple of blank
post-dated checks
Just in case something came up.
- All right, Lindsey.
You can handle things around here.
But if you want to get paid,
You're actually gonna have
to watch your brother.
- Why would you pay her to watch me
When you can cut a deal with me
to watch myself for free?
- Because we don't negotiate
with terrorists.
sync by dr.jackson
www.addic7ed.com
- Okay, guys, we'll see you
about 10:00 P.M.
- Nick!
- What?
You're not supposed to tell them
What time we're actually coming back.
You're supposed to tell them
an hour later.
This way, when we come home early,
We can catch them in the act.
- In the act of what?
- Whatever they were doing
When they thought we weren't
coming home for an hour.
- Ooh, that's a good idea.
- Okay.
- Actually, guys, we'll see you
about 11:00.
- 11:00?
Got it.
- Kevin.
- I know, I know.
Behave, clean up the dishes,
Do my homework,
and don't set Lindsey on fire.
- Bye.
- Bye, guys.
- Okay, so here's the deal.
I'm going over to Kelly's,
And I'll be back in about an hour.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
What about my dinner?
Here's ten bucks.
Go to up-and-down burger.
It's just a few blocks.
- Whoa, whoa, hey.
Make it $20.
$10 for the burger
and $10 for my sides.
- How much to make you shut up forever?
- Leave and never come back.
- Never gonna happen, bro.
Nice try.
- Okay, take your seats, people.
We're back, we're back, we're back.
Okay, people.
As you know, we are here tonight
To discuss the annual
baby got buck dinner.
- My idea.
Said they hated it.
It was a great idea, so thank you.
It was a huge success last year.
We were able to get books
For the entire fourth grade class.
- It was a great idea, baby.
- As you know, we are going to
need a volunteer chair person.
- What they need is a volunteer sucka.
Ain't gonna be me.
- Okay, I do understand.
It takes a lot of time.
But when you see those kids
coming in to school
Knowing how much work their
parents are doing for them,
It is always worth it.
- Not to me.
- Mm-mm.
- Okay, so I see nobody wants
to volunteer.
- That's 'cause nobody is stupid.
- I have a suggestion.
- She got a suggestion.
- Since last year's event
Was such a huge success...
- Because of me.
- I nominate
Suzanne Kingston-persons.
- What?
- Suzanne, would you?
- Of course I would.
Yay!
- You would?
- Yay, yeah!
- Man, I'll be glad
when I can babysit myself.
Then I won't have to deal
with my stupid sister.
- Don't take it for granted.
Sometimes I wish I had a stupid
sister who hated me
And left me to fend for myself.
You got it good, man.
Aw, man, nothing.
- Yeah, that's usually what that
sound means.
- No, I mean I didn't win the prize.
These are big bonus cups.
When you finish your drink,
The cup reveals a prize at the bottom.
Finish yours and see if you won.
- Oh, okay.
Oh, oh, brain freeze.
Brain freeze.
Ah, ah, I hate those!
- Dude, you won.
- Dude, quit lying!
Let me see that.
$500?
Wait, wait, wait.
$500...
Five... what?
Hit it!
- Kevin, you know you're not
supposed to have people over.
- Oh, well, I would like to thank you
For leaving me home alone,
Because now I have $500.
What?
- How?
I can't believe this.
- I know.
I can't wait to tell mom and dad.
- No, you can't.
- Why not?
- Allow me.
You can't tell your parents,
Because you weren't supposed
To be out of the house.
If you show them the cup,
They'll know you went out.
That's okay.
I won't tell them.
I'll just go get my money.
- Yeah.
- Yeah!
- Nope, you can't do that either.
- Why?
- It says right here in order
to claim the prize
You have to be at least 18 or older.
- So how are we supposed
to cash the cup in?
- Do you trust me?
- No.
- Let me rephrase that.
Do you want your money?
- Yeah.
- Then you're gonna have to trust me.
- Ha ha!
You didn't think we'd be back
so early, did you?
- Actually, we did.
Mom always comes home an hour
early from meetings.
- Then how come you guys
are sitting on the couch
Watching tv, eating popcorn?
- Because we wanted popcorn?
- Come on.
Watch your tone.
- Now go to bed.
And next time, don't y'all
be trying to outsmart people.
- You're right.
I don't know what we were thinking.
- Can't believe I'm in charge
of this committee again.
- Baby, all you had
to say was "no."
- How do I look standing there
saying "no"
In a room full of people
who are clapping for me,
Including my husband?
- You look like someone
who doesn't want to do it.
- Fine, make fun of me.
- Baby, let me help you with this.
- What are you gonna do?
Go back in your time machine
And not clap when they pick me?
- No, I was thinking I could do it.
You're kidding, right?
Those women are a nightmare.
They will suck you in,
set you up, and spit you out.
- It can't be no worse than what
your kids try to do to me.
Hey, I played football.
I ran a business.
I ain't scared of no moms
and a fund-raiser. Shoot.
- Okay, homey.
But don't come crying back to me
When you get played like a boy band.
Yeah!
- I don't do it like that.
I don't do it like that.
You got to have the swagger.
- So what happened with Suzanne?
Is she okay?
- Oh, she's fine.
She just didn't realize
how swamped she was with work
Before you asked her to chair
the event again.
- Oh, well, if you are anything
at all like her,
I imagine we are in excellent hands.
- Okay, you guys ready to get to work?
- I just want to say,
what you're doing is fantastic.
It's nice to see a dad step up
for a change.
- And it's good to break up
Some of the female energy.
- Kind of like a security guard
at a shoe sale.
- Tell me, Nick.
How did Suzanne convince you
To come down here in her place?
- Well, she didn't.
I volunteered.
Oh!
- That's amazing.
I can barely get my husband
to read a report card.
- Send it to ESPN.
Have them put it on the ticker.
- My husband doesn't even know
where the children go to school.
- Let me tell you something, honey.
Take the tv remote.
Put it in heir backpacks.
He'll find 'em.
- Can we not talk about husbands?
The only reason I don't kill
mine is because I am too lazy
To row his dead body
out to sea and dump it.
- Is that why Suzanne keeps trying
To get me to go on that cruise?
I finally figured that out.
You know what?
I just have to be honest with you guys.
Suzanne said you would be rough on me,
But, you know, you're all right.
- Now, why would she say
something like that?
- We love her.
- If anything,
she's kind of tough on us.
- I know what you mean.
Suzanne does not play.
- You know what?
- We do.
- Ooh, Carol!
- Drinks, anyone?
- Carol, what are you doing?
Oh, my goodness.
Pta stands
for "pass the alcohol."
- So let me see if I've got this right.
You're gonna take the cup
and give it to your friend Eric.
- Eric, right.
- And he's gonna take it
To the place and cash it in.
- Right, then he takes 20 bucks,
and gives the rest to us.
- You mean me.
- No, us.
You need me to cash it in, so it's us.
- But it's my cup.
I bought it
When you left me in the house
by myself.
- Which I'm prepared
to tell mom and dad
If you don't share your money with me.
- So you would tell mom and dad
that you left me alone
Just so I don't get the money,
Even though you know
you'd get in trouble?
- Yeah, they'll forgive me.
- You just took evil
to a whole new level.
- Hey.
I thought you had a school thing
this afternoon.
- I sent Nick in my place.
- Why would you send Nick down there?
You hate those women.
They hate me.
And I was ambushed.
We have another fund-raiser,
And they nominated me
to be chairperson.
- Fund-raising is easy.
You put on a nice dress,
find a man of means,
And tell him what he has to pay for.
- That may work with a trip to Vegas,
But you can't use that on your kids.
- Okay.
So Nick is there.
- Mm-Hmm.
- Hmm.
- "Hmm" what?
- I just, you know, okay.
I don't want to overstep my boundaries,
But I have a question for you.
- What?
- Are you crazy?
These women hate you,
Which means they can't be
trusted around your husband.
- I'm not worried about Nick.
- Well, you should be,
because you and I both know
Men are stupid.
- Nick is not stupid.
- I love you.
Yes, he is.
- Gigi!
- I'm sorry, but you throw a man
In a room with a bunch of women,
He can't help but try to be liked,
Even by women who hate you.
And they know that.
- You're overreacting.
And trust me.
I can handle my man.
And the good news is,
after a hard day's work here,
I don't have to see them.
- Ow, ow!
- Hey, everybody!
- Hey, baby!
Hi, Suzanne.
- Hi!
hi.
- Wow!
Nick, you didn't tell me
all the ladies were coming by.
- Well, it just kind of happened.
Pop!
- You know, we ran over our time
at the school,
But we were on such a role,
I said, "let's just go to their house.
And you have a lovely home.
- Mm-Hmm.
- And Nick is so great.
He said it would be no problem.
- He did?
Mm-Hmm.
- Your husband is quite
The idea man, Suzanne
We love having him on the committee.
- Adore.
- Is that so?
- We are already moving so much
faster than last year.
- Oh, it's amazing.
- Your husband is such a doll.
- Oh, he is, isn't he?
Nick, can I show you something
I brought home from work?
- Oh, can it wait?
We're almost done here.
- Not really.
It kind of has something
to do with your health.
- Okay, well,
Keep it moving.
Bend it;
don't break it.
We'll be right back.
- Nick, you know I can't stand
those women.
Why would you have them here?
- We got caught up.
- I mean, everyone has something
going on at their houses.
- They were lying.
They're just trying to get
in our business.
I can't believe you fell for that.
- Fell for what?
You're being paranoid.
Those ladies are out there
trying to figure out a way
To make money for the kids.
You said they were gossips,
But they haven't said anything
but nice things about you.
They love my ideas,
And you know, this might be shocking,
But I think they're quite nice.
- The only reason they're being
nice to you
Is so that they can get at me.
- Is it possible that they could
just like me?
- No!
Because they know that I don't
like them.
And they know that if they're
nice to you,
You're gonna come back
and tell me how nice they are.
And it's gonna get under my skin
like it is right now.
- You guys almost finished?
- Aw, yes, Melissa.
Nick will be right back out.
Thanks so much.
- I was just telling the ladies
it's so nice
That Nick is such a great husband,
Especially since you work
And can't be with your kids
like you want to.
- It is.
I'm blessed.
- By the way,
your kitchen is so...Charming.
- You see what I mean?
- No!
Look, baby,
If I thought for one minute
That those ladies had
anything against you,
Believe me, they would be out of here
Faster than you could say,
"backstab."
- Backstab.
- Oh, look.
You know what?
You don't like them.
I understand it.
But I just cannot go out there
and kick them out of here.
- You could.
You won't, but you could.
- You know what, sweetheart?
If it means that much to you,
I'm just gonna go out there,
and I'm gonna end the meeting.
- Thank you.
- All right, here's the cup.
- There's been a change
in the agreement.
I want $100.
- $100?
- Either that, or find somebody else.
- $40.
$75.
- $50.
And if you don't do it,
we'll get a homeless guy.
- Fine.
- We'll meet you tomorrow night.
- Okay, that it?
- One more thing?
- What?
- Keep your mouth shut.
- Get your finger off me.
- I'm sorry.
- What is wrong with you, man?
Get in the house.
- Baby, I'm sorry that those
ladies don't like you.
But I can't help it if they like me.
- For the last time,
they don't like you.
They're doing it to annoy me.
- Prove it.
- Okay, you want me to prove it?
I'll prove it.
What is this idea you have
That the ladies think is so wonderful?
- Well, I suggested the
fund-raiser be '80s funk themed.
Huh?
- And what does that mean, exactly?
- You know,
Shoulder pads, space suits, codpieces.
Ow!
- And where are you supposed to
get these codpieces,
At a cameo yard sale?
- I don't know.
A costume store?
- In the spring?
Who do you know that carries
costumes in the spring
Or are you just gonna make
your space suits
Out of aluminum foil?
- No.
- Nick, these ladies couldn't
plan a bottle opening.
They don't know a good idea
from a bad idea
When they hear one.
- Well, my next idea
was a Mardi Gras party.
- Mardi gras?
- Mm-Hmm.
- Okay, when's the party?
- April.
- A mardi gras party in April?
- Sure.
Why not?
- Because mardi gras is in February.
- It's a mardi gras party.
Not mardi gras.
- Okay, what day in April?
- April 15th.
- Tax day?
You're seriously going to plan
a fund-raiser
On the day people
have to file their taxes?
- Well, not anymore.
So you guys don't think
It's weird celebrating
mardi gras in April?
- Oh, no, not at all, Nick.
It's a theme party.
- I have Easter themed parties
in September all the time.
- But we're scheduling it for tax day.
- All the better.
People will want to celebrate.
- It can be a mardi tax day party.
- Ladies, no.
These are all bad ideas.
- Oh, Nick, Nick.
It doesn't really matter.
We'll make it work.
We'll figure it out.
- We're just glad you're here.
- Right.
Things are so much better
than last year.
- You mean when Suzanne was here?
- Well...
- I hear you.
It's okay.
So you do agree that
these ideas are bad?
- A little.
- A lot.
- Okay.
Here's another idea.
You're probably gonna hate it.
But I think it's gonna work.
- We're all ears.
- Can you hear me now?
- Suzanne, terrific.
- Oh, Carol, just zip it.
You're trying to play me
like the quick pick.
You put on a bigger show
than lady gaga at the grammy's.
- I don't know
what you're talking about.
- "I don't know
what you're talking about."
That's because you're so fake
You don't know you have
a real problem on your hands.
- Suzanne...
- Oh, you want some?
Here you go.
- Melissa, your kids are stupid.
- That's crossing the line.
- No, no, that's telling the truth.
Crossing the line
is asking your husband
Why he's always down at the math class
Talking to the 22-year-old
teacher's aid.
That's right.
Tap out.
- That was uncalled for.
- Oh, you got something
you want to say, Theresa?
- I think we should go.
- Oh, give that woman a hand,
Because that is the first good idea
That she has had in her whole life.
Kick rocks.
Bye-bye.
- See, I don't need y'all
to plan nothing.
Don't, don't, 'cause I got
vaseline in my purse, Carol.
You better turn that around.
I'll snap your fingers right off.
- Okay, here's your cut.
$440.
- Say what?
Did he just say...
yeah, I think he did. Yeah.
- Okay, we agreed on $450.
That's ten bucks short.
- Transaction fee.
- You're not even a bank.
- Dude, everybody charges
transaction fees.
It's like taxes.
You can't get around them.
- Just take the money, Kevin.
- Fine.
Oh, I can't believe it.
I'm rich!
Hit it!
- Ah, I'll just
roll around in it naked.
- I know!
- Let me get my cut first.
- Baby, baby.
That was exactly what I was
trying to avoid
By me taking over for you.
The only thing missing
Was you on the roof
with a wig and a weave
Screaming at the police.
"Ahh!
You'll never take me alive!"
"I'm still alive!"
"Ahh!"
Okay, I'm trying to tell you.
Look, the joke is still on you though.
- Oh, really?
And how is that?
- Well, you are chairman
of yet another committee.
- Darn it.
Well, I'm not doing it again next year.
You can count on that.
- Until they call your name.
"stop it."
- Stop.
Hey, you realize something?
- No, what?
- It's quiet.
- Too quiet.
- Just remember, no buying
any big-ticket items.
No cars, no houses,
No nothing.
Don't spend it on dames, booze.
Stay away from the ponies.
- The ponies?
- Got to lay low for a while.
Start doing stuff like that,
They're likely to tip off the feds.
- What year do you think this is?
- Oh, Eric,
Dude, you better get out of here.
- No worries.
It's only 9:00.
And mom and dad said they won't
be home until 11:00,
Which means we have
about another hour...
- Aha!
- You'll never take me alive, coppers!
- Freeze!
- It worked.
- Mm-Hmm.
Sync by dr.jackson
www.addic7ed.com