-And you'll never walk alone.
-You'll never--
-Walk alone.
-It's the most famous football
song in the world.
[MUSIC-GERRY MARSDEN, "YOU'LL
NEVER WALK ALONE"]
GERRY MARSDEN: I was livin' in
New York doing the Ed Sullivan
Show and the Liverpool
team were
playing around the Americas.
So I said to Ed, there's a
soccer team in here from
England called Liverpool.
Get them on stage, and we'll
sing "Walk Alone" with me.
He said, OK.
So we got the whole team on the
stage, and we sang "Walk
Alone" on the Ed
Sullivan Show.
Coming off, Bill Shankly said
to me, "Teddy, my son.
I've given you a team, but
you've given us a song."
[MUSIC-GERRY MARSDEN, "YOU'LL
NEVER WALK ALONE"]
GERRY MARSDEN: This way in.
We'll go through here.
That's the Shankly Memorial.
How are you?
My name is Gerry Marsden from
Gerry and the Pacemakers, and
you have the pleasure of being
in Liverpool Football Club's
magnificent ground
called Anfield.
Not many people get in here.
In fact, through them
doors there, my team
walk in like gods.
Look at these names
on the wall.
Look.
Look at them.
They're wonderful.
God himself, Mr. Bill
Shankly, what a man.
He used to come to my
house for dinner.
This is the European Kop.
Everybody tries to win it.
We won it so many times,
we give them back.
Look at this sign.
This is Anfield.
Those other teams would come
and see it and go, uh-oh.
The holy of holies.
Look at this ground.
I mean, when you look at
it, you get frightened.
Nevermind playing on it.
Can you imagine coming here to
play Liverpool on that field?
Your heart does that.
JAMES MCKENNA: Football's much
more than entertainment.
It's part of who you are.
My first picture in my dad's
arms when I was born was with
a Liverpool scarf on.
It's stuff that instills
in you.
It's part of you, and
it always has been.
You don't ask people the
question, what do you do?
You ask them, who
do you support?
Liverpool at the time, they used
to play the Top 10, and
"You'll Never Walk Alone" was
number one, and they used to
just sing along.
Probably also just
liking the song.
GERRY MARSDEN: Once I came to
the game one day, and they all
sang at the Kop, and I thought
the Kop is singing our song.
Wow.
I was over the moon.
Then when it went out of the Top
10, and that weekend, the
Kop shouted, where's our song?
Where's our song?
So we had to put it back on.
And from that day to this,
every home match, we play
"You'll Never Walk Alone."
You all know the words.
You can all help just a bit,
if you don't mind.
JAMES MCKENNA: But it's when you
think of what's gone on at
Liverpool, our history, our dark
times, our joyous times,
that the words seemed to fit.
It was like it was
meant to be.
It was like that song was meant
to fit the Liverpool
Football Club.
[MUSIC-GERRY MARSDEN, "YOU'LL
NEVER WALK ALONE"]
GERRY MARSDEN: When you walk
through a storm, hold your
head up high.
Don't be afraid of the dark.
And that's all great.
That's what made this song.
And also what made this song is
the build up-- the way it
goes up to a great sound, and
that's what gets everybody
going as it builds and
builds and builds.
And the end is just wonderful.
And that's why I think the
Kop picked it all up.
Easy to sing.
At the end, give it
a bit of rally.
And thank God it worked.
[MUSIC-GERRY MARSDEN, "YOU'LL
NEVER WALK ALONE"]
JAMES MCKENNA: You can go abroad
now and probably within
a few minutes, you'll meet
someone who likes Liverpool,
has a Liverpool [INAUDIBLE], or
is from Liverpool, and it
shows you won't be alone.
You will always meet someone.
There will always be them
stories in our history to live
on as well.
[MUSIC-GERRY MARSDEN, "YOU'LL
NEVER WALK ALONE"]
GERRY MARSDEN: When they said
we're going to put Walk Alone
on top of the Shankly
gates, I said, what?
It was such a wonderful thing
not only for me, but for my
kids and the kid's kids.
I still love looking at
it when I come up.
You'll Never Walk Alone.
It is, it's tremendous.
-You'll never walk alone.