Here we have Gucci Mane.
He's exactly like
what you would
imagine him to be, amazing.
He was in his element in the
strip club, for sure, had his
game face on.
We lit the whole club with these
insane red and green
neon filters and gels.
And everyone was super high.
That's a lot of Gucci's crew
in the movie, and I think a
lot in real life.
You got Gucci's real life
manager on the side, Coach K,
holding a pistol.
That's a serious
OG right there.
Here we go with Franco, again
Franco and strippers, we had
to throw some money.
This is Dangeruss, a rapper
from Saint Petersburg.
I put him together with Franco
before the movie.
They hung out.
And he was kind of a
character study.
These guys in here are pretty
much the real deal.
These dudes are legit.
So I think Franco got a lot
for his performance.
The actual location had these
amazing neons, these purple
[INAUDIBLE]
candy-colored lights.
There's a palette I thought
coincided with that world.
The colors of nail polish became
fluorescent colors.
Benoit would shoot in these
super vibrant filters.
So we would pick a look, almost
like in this weird
magical realism, or this kind
of idea that things are just
the real world, except pushed
it into something hyper
extreme, hyper beautiful.
[HOUSE MUSIC]