Narrator: On this
episode of Wicked Tuna.
Dave: And he's
gonna (bleep) us.
Paul: He's used to being
the number one boat.
Kevin: There's only room
for one Number One in this
group.
Dave: I want to be on top.
Paul: It was like someone
(bleep) flicked a switch.
Dave: (Bleep) them,
(bleep) them all.
Kevin: I know he's a
little jealous right now.
Dave's been humbled.
Humbled and hobbled.
Dave: I want the (bleep)
biggest one in the fleet
this year.
Marciano: Holy (bleep).
Bill: Oh, my God.
He's right under the boat.
Marciano: Any rod
can go any minute.
Scott: It's all right, I'll
play this game all night.
That's huge.
This is a monster.
Paul: The biggest one, ever.
Kevin: Oh, my god.
Narrator: Fishing
is a hard life.
Ralph: There's gonna
be confrontation.
Narrator: And harder with
bluefin stocks depleted.
In Gloucester,
Massachusetts,
there's a special
breed of fisherman.
For generations, they've
used rod and reel to catch
the elusive bluefin tuna.
Jay: Yeah, baby!
Narrator: They depend
on these fish for their
survival.
The competition is brutal.
Scott: You miserable prick.
Narrator: This
is Wicked Tuna.
Dave: It's great
to be on top.
It's great to make
all the money.
But with that, nobody
likes a winner.
Marciano: For me the money
doesn't fall out of the sky,
it comes out of the sea.
Bill: This gets harder
as you get older.
But I'm keeping up
with the young guns.
Get out of the way!
Ralph: If it's on my mind
you're gonna hear about it.
And if you did
something to me,
I'm gonna do
something back to you.
Dave: Sandro,
keep throwing 'em.
You keep doing
your job, buddy.
Come on, we got
the fish here.
Paul: Still there.
Two of 'em right now.
Dave: Keep it on.
Keep it, I like it,
gets them frenzied up.
You know what you're seeing
right now on the Tuna.com?
Three good fishermen at
the top of their game,
catching fish
and kicking ass.
Two of 'em right
now under the boat.
All big (bleep)
chum feeding fish.
One of us, sometimes two of
us, sometimes three of us,
are always in the back of
that boat working non-stop.
And that's what we do,
work hard and catch fish.
So we got a bite the
other day, right there.
Paul: They're coming
in hot right now.
They're hot.
Dave: They're hot.
I'm gonna get him in.
Here we go.
Bill: Alright, Charlie.
You have avoided
me long enough.
It's time to jump on
and go for a ride.
This year, we are pretty
much in the hole.
You know it's getting
late in the season now.
You still have
to catch them.
Come on.
Say some prayers,
do something.
Do a voodoo or do
something good.
There you go.
Now you're talking.
I'm telling you,
they're coming.
You watch.
Kevin: We're gonna go
kill one here shortly.
I grew up fishing.
I was one of those kids
that, uh, you know,
I'd skip school and grab a,
a trout rod and sneak down
to the lake.
I caught my first
giant when I was 18.
Once I caught that first
big fish, I, I was hooked.
It, obviously, it's fun.
It's a challenge.
But it's all
about the money.
Sandro: What's he doing?
What the hell, what's
he doing right there?
Dave: Anchored.
Sandro: Right there?
Dave: He's, yeah.
I don't know why he's
not in his other spot.
Kevin anchored way
too (bleep) close.
We steam out of
Gloucester Harbor.
We're fishing.
An hour goes by.
And we look out the window,
and see this boat steaming
right at us and, uh, I
realize its Kevin on the
Christina.
He's been around
a long time.
He's a very
experienced fisherman.
He knows better than
to anchor that close.
And he's gonna (bleep) us.
He's gonna saw us right off
and our day is gonna be
over.
And there's no reason for
him to be sitting right on
top of our anchor.
He knows I've been catching
fish there every day.
So he wanted to be close
to us because we were
definitely pulling up quite
a few fish out of there.
Now he's gonna hook up and
he's gonna (bleep) go right
through our anchor.
Paul: Of course.
Sandro: I can't believe he's
setting up right there.
Dave: I don't
understand that.
And if he hooks up
he's gonna say, "Dave,
you gotta get
off your anchor."
And we're gonna
miss the bite.
Paul: Uh-huh.
Kevin: Dave's
got this thing.
If anybody anchors within
a mile of the Dot Com,
he goes, he comes unglued.
Unglued.
So I said, "You know what?
I'm gonna torture him
a little bit today."
Shut my radio off.
And I anchored
right on top of him.
His theory is, everybody
knows Dave's catching fish,
so they all want to
anchor on top of him.
For me, I just anchored on
top of him to torture him.
Dave: Kevin, keep in mind,
you're pretty close to my
anchor right off the port.
You copy?
Because he anchored
up so close to us,
if he hooks up and makes
us get off the anchor,
I'm gonna be
(bleep) furious.
Kevin: He'll be beatin'
himself against the side of
the boat.
Sammy: That is a
weird looking boat.
Kevin: It is a
He was pointing at
us a minute ago.
Dot Com coming unglued.
Dave's been on
top for a while.
But it's definitely
all gonna change.
Somebody's gonna catch
one bigger than his.
Marciano: On the
starboard side,
we got Dave in the Tuna.com.
On the port side, we got
Kevin on the Christina.
And then on the
port side of Kevin,
we have Bounty Hunter.
We're all right
in a row here.
These guys have
been seeing fish.
We're gonna see if we can
snag one right out from in
between them all.
Paul: We got one in the
chum at 35 feet, Dave.
Dave: All right.
Paul: Dude, look
how long he is.
Sandro: He is
(bleep) long, dude.
Holy (bleep).
Paul: Look at how
big he is, Dave!
Dave: Is it really?
Holy (bleep).
Paul: Oh, Dave, right here.
These fish are eating chum.
Dave: I'm gonna get him in.
Bill: Oh, my God, he's
right under the boat, yeah,
a big fish, though.
Real big.
Donna: Come on, come on,
come on, come on, come on,
come on.
Bill: How far up?
Scott: He came up
to a hundred feet.
Bill: Here he comes.
Come on baby, come on.
Come on.
Donna: Come on.
Bill: 50 feet.
Here he comes.
Marciano: There we go.
He's coming to life now.
Let's see holy (bleep),
that's a big one, Jay.
Jay: Get your rig on,
I'll put this guy down.
Marciano: I'll be damned if
I'm gonna let somebody else
land this fish.
Jay: 10!
That's a big one.
Marciano: Come on,
baby, you're all mine.
Blair: Ah, that's a big one.
There he is.
He's turning.
Kevin: There he is.
Oh.
I'm looking at the
fish finder, Sammy.
He's right up in the chum.
He's, I know he's big.
We're on, we're on.
Scott, you take the rod.
I'm on the wheel.
Get out of my way.
Blair: Real
tight, real tight.
Scott: Easy.
Kevin: Come on,
stay with him.
Stay with him.
Come on.
Blair: He's coming.
All right, take it easy.
Take it easy.
Kevin: That fish took the
line right out of Scott's
hands, and we hooked up.
Come on, come
on, stay on him.
He's taking line, guys.
Scott: Jesus, Kevin,
he's pulling hard.
Kevin: Make it crank.
There you go.
He's pulling away from us.
Scott: Easy, easy.
Kevin: He took off,
and he kept going.
Scott: Forward!
Forward!
Kevin: And he burned rubber.
Scott: Okay, back
up, back up, back up.
Kevin: Just put some
good pressure on him.
Take him now.
Scott: Hold on, I can't
see him well enough.
Yeah, he's coming around,
he's on his side.
Kevin: I can see him
on the fish finder.
So we're slowly
gaining on him.
If we get him up to 50 feet
or so, he'd see the boat,
he'd go right back
to the bottom.
Blair: Oh, no.
Kevin: He still there?
Scott: I don't
think so, hold on.
Yeah, he's there.
He's there.
Blair: Yep, he's circling.
Scott: Move forward
just a little bit.
Kevin: So we're slowly
gaining on him.
And you're looking down on
the water, I'm like, "Jeez,
this is a big fish."
Blair: He's coming around.
Stop.
Under the boat.
Don't, leave it in neutral.
Swivel's coming.
Under the boat.
Get ready for
the reverse, Kev.
Kevin: I don't like that.
Scott: I don't either.
Blair: Forward,
forward, forward.
Scott: Hold on.
Man: He's on this side.
There he is, he's up on
top, he's coming down.
He's coming right at us.
Yep, he's still there.
He's coming up,
he's coming up,
just come back a little bit.
He's coming up.
You gotta blast him.
Blair: Alright, alright,
alright, bring him up.
Scott: He's coming
up, he's coming up.
Coming up, coming,
coming, coming.
Kevin: Ready to let go?
Scott: No Kevin, no?
Scott: There he is.
Kevin: This is a monster.
Oh my God.
Kevin: Still going?
Scott: Yep.
It's all right, I'll play
this game all night.
Kevin: He started
circling, under the boat,
like he knew what to do.
He was trying to
cut himself off.
Probably a 30 year old fish.
It's not his first rodeo,
he had been hooked before.
Scott: He just took back
everything I grabbed.
Blair: Pure power right there.
Kevin: Still going?
I can't let him
go under the boat.
He wasn't ready to die.
Take him now.
Got him.
Scott: Come on,
get the tail rope.
Get the tail rope.
Kevin: He's pulling
away from us.
Man: Put it in
reverse, reverse.
Come on, pull it ahead.
Kevin: Got him.
That is a beast, my boys.
Scott: Where'd
you come from?
Kevin: Whoo!
All right.
Scott: That's above
average, Rich.
Kevin: That's
why we do this.
Blair: That is gonna
be all of 900 pounds.
Kevin: That's my
grander right there.
I gotta give you a hug.
Whoo hoo.
Scott: Let's get
him in the boat.
Kevin: We open the door
and we slid him in.
Pull.
Pull!
(Bleep), look at that boy!
And we were all in awe.
I said, this is the biggest
one I've ever caught.
Ohh!
I think we need
a bigger boat.
If anybody was to catch
that, it's a trophy.
I'm gonna call it an
eleven hundred pound fish.
This is gonna cash in
between 10 and 15 grand.
That's all that it's all
about, the big fish.
You know, people talk about
the glorious and the big
ones.
You know, it's not
in the numbers.
Dave: Come in.
You guys there?
Hey, where you guys at?
Come in.
They're not answering.
Bill: It was a big boy.
It was jumbo.
And, uh, we couldn't
time it just right.
Hey, good going.
Big one?
Kevin: Oh yeah,
she's a beast.
A thousand pounds at least.
Bill: Woo.
Awesome.
Real good.
Good going.
Donna: Good job, Kevin.
Kevin: Thanks a lot, Bill.
Bill: Yeah, we had him
here a minute ago and, uh,
couldn't get him hooked.
Pretty big, pretty big
mark too, you know.
Kevin: Yeah, we had this guy
up to the boat like two or
three times then he'd just
go right to the bottom.
We were getting ready to
leave and dumped a bunch of
chum and he showed up.
Dave: Come in.
You guys there?
Bill: Good going, Kevin.
At least it wasn't Dave.
Dave: He still
ain't gonna answer.
I give up.
Marciano: Kevin, that guy
in the Christina, yeah,
that guy.
You know we heard he had an
eleven hundred pound fish.
On the one hand, it's
like good for Kevin.
But on the other
hand, you know,
that's a bigger fish than
we've caught in this season.
We're still in the game.
We know how to catch
twelve hundred pounders,
and we're gonna
do one today.
Dave: Hey, you there, Kevin?
Kevin: Yo.
Come in.
Dave: How was it?
How big was he?
Kevin: Ah, he's in the boat.
118 inches.
Paul: Nice.
Dave: That's a
nice 118 inches.
That's.
Paul: That's a
big fish, dude.
Dave: That's a
big fish there.
Paul: That's as long
as the stern, dude.
Dave: 118 inches
is a big fish.
Paul: 10 feet long.
Dave: That's a big boy.
I'd like to see a
couple more of those.
Good for him.
Paul: He was (bleep)
beside himself.
We were very envious of him.
That was a big (bleep).
Rick: That is the biggest
fish that we've seen all
year.
That's huge.
Kevin: I've fished with
Blair for probably 20 years,
and we both gave the nod.
We knew it, we knew it
was, this was a slammer.
He made a turn, came by the
boat, and we, we all said,
"Holy (bleep)," and it's
something that we've fished
our whole lives to catch a
fish of that, of that size.
Rick: Far and few of these
fish come across the boards.
And we're looking at a,
you know, a 15,000
dollar fish right now.
15,000, 18,000 dollar fish.
That's.
Kevin: It's like
catching three, right?
Rick: Right, it's
like catching three.
A sizable fish like this,
and the beauty and the
quality of this fish, I, I
feel that you can do real
well.
Think you'll really raise
the bar at the auction.
This, this, this is a fish
that we certainly want to
get to Tokyo as
soon as possible.
Bill: Oh, yeah,
that's a big boy.
Ohh!
Donna: Ooh, hoo, hoo.
Nice job, Kev!
That was worth
waiting for, Kev.
Rick: It's a
thousand pound fish.
Biggest fish I've
seen all year.
Sammy: Big fish,
with a little hook.
I told these guys
earlier in the day,
"Elephants eat peanuts."
Man: Okay.
Easy.
This is just gonna fit.
Rick: Kevin,
congratulations.
That's the biggest fish of
the year, dressed weight,
here at Compass Seafood.
Great job.
Man: Biggest by 400 pounds.
Rick: Word will travel real
quick about this fish being
landed tonight throughout
town and it'll get everyone
hot and hungry again, to go
back out and try to catch
one of these giants.
Kevin: All right.
I'll buy.
Who flies?
Dave: We're just gonna
spend the night here.
It's such a perfect night.
Winds are five knots, so the
radar running for the night.
I'll fish a couple
more hours anyway,
and wrap it up, and,
uh, wait for sunup.
That's the game plan.
Paul: Now, Dave is obsessed
with beating Kevin.
It was like someone
(bleep) flicked a switch.
He turned into this (bleep)
crazed (bleep) robot.
Dave: Oh, we gotta
catch a (bleep) fish.
Paul: He was like, "I don't
even want an 800-pounder.
I want a 1.200-pounder or
I don't even want one."
Dave: We're long overdue,
it's, uh, it's time.
It's time for it
to happen for us.
Hopefully, tomorrow
will be the day.
Dave: Out here in day two.
Just got word from Kevin
his fish was 1,075 pounds.
That's a, that's
a big ass fish,
that's all I could
say about that.
Paul: Dave wants to get a
bigger fish than Kevin.
He couldn't even sleep.
And then when we get up,
he was (bleep) exhausted,
'cause he stayed
awake all that night.
Dave: Definitely under
pressure to get one today
after Kevin got that one.
Can't come home
empty handed now,
he'll be rubbing
it in my face.
Paul: It was really hard for
Dave 'cause he's used to
being the number one boat.
And now Kevin got this
thousand fifty pounder,
and it just made him twitch.
I made him freak out.
Dave: All I know is I want
to get the biggest fish out
of this group this year.
Paul: We just need
'em to make a mistake.
Dave: (Bleep) them,
(bleep) them all.
Everybody's
giving me (bleep),
but I want the (bleep)
biggest one in the fleet
this year.
And we're gonna
(bleep) get him.
Paul: That was cool to see
him amped up like that.
That's what you want.
You want the guy that's
running the boat to (bleep)
be amped up like that.
You want to give him
a kick in the (bleep).
Dave: I want to be on top.
And we're gonna
(bleep) get him.
Marciano: All we've been
doing at this point is
surviving this season.
We keep, we get a few, and
then we fish for a while and
don't get more.
We get a few and then we
don't that's just survival
mode for us.
We're not really getting
ahead at that level.
What really needs to happen
is we need to go right back
out there now after landing,
and keep catching those
fish.
And that's how I get
ahead of the game.
Steve: You got a, a charter
this weekend, Dave, or?
Marciano: Yeah, the, the
last one coming up for the
season, yeah.
We'll take the, uh, little
bit of extra bling.
Come on, it's like a kid in
a candy store here, right?
I keep wandering around.
My wife hates it
when I go here.
You know, I finally
get desperate.
I finally agree to
do a few charters.
You guys want to go fishing?
Put, put some
money in my hand?
I'll take you out
fishing for the day.
Okay.
Steve: We'll worry about the
tab later and we'll just
take care of this, then?
Marciano: Yeah, all right.
Steve: 18 once, twice.
11.
19, nine, nine, 10 once.
10 twice.
Marciano: Here's
the painful part.
Steve: $117.94.
Marciano: Remember,
if my wife stops
in, I only spent 17.
Steve: I think, sure,
wanna pay her tab?
Marciano: Oh, man, come on.
You're killing me.
What is her tab?
Steve: It's $487.50.
Marciano: Who, wha-, what?
Steve: Four hundred and
eighty seven dollars and
fifty cents.
Just, 487's good
for me, buddy.
Marciano: That's it.
You get it all.
Steve: I get it all, huh?
Marciano: I get nothing.
Steve: Thanks, buddy.
Marciano: I get receipts.
And I thought tuna
fishing was expensive.
Kevin: Dave and myself
are very competitive.
I know he's a little
jealous right now.
He's been humbled.
Humbled and hobbled.
There's not a day in my life
with Dave that we don't
compete one way or another.
Size matters.
Sandro: The (bleep) you
gotta do to catch tuna.
It's ridiculous.
Paul: That's right.
Dave: Now we're
gonna pretty much,
pretty much kind of fish the
same way today as we did
yesterday and all
the other days.
Only nothing,
nothing different.
You just got to be in the
right place at the right
time, and have the right
fish here, that's all.
Paul: Hopefully
we can get lucky.
Dave: Exactly.
Kevin had a beauty,
no doubt about it.
Paul: The biggest one ever.
Dave: That's his, that's
his biggest fish, for sure.
Paul: I haven't caught a
(bleep) eleven hundred
pounder in 25 years.
I haven't caught a thousand
pounder in 20 years.
Dave: Hey, you there, Kev?
Kevin: Yeah, come in.
Dave: That thing had to be
fat as, fat as it was, uh,
as long.
Kevin: Could barely, barely
fit through the door.
Dave: Really?
Yeah, it's gonna be a few
years before you beat that
one.
That was your first, first
grander plus, in 27 years.
Sandro, his first fish,
was eleven hundred.
Kevin: Unbelievable.
Dave: All right, well, I'm
gonna go back to work.
Kevin: Hey, hey.
Dave: I was just
saying to Kevin,
it took him 27 years
to catch his first
1,000-pounder.
Sandro comes out
with me on his,
one of his first maiden
voyages on this boat and,
uh, his first giant tuna
was eleven hundred pounds.
So, quite a big disparity.
27 years to catch the first
one and Sandro catches one
eleven hundred
pounds the first day.
Yeah, man, I want a bigger
one now than I have all year
because Kevin got one.
Kevin: So the
drama continues.
Davy.
There's a lot of jealousy.
I mean, that's
the bottom line.
If you're catching fish,
and the other guy isn't,
he can't help
but be jealous.
Dave is absolutely sour.
Scott: Beside himself.
Kevin: About not having
a bigger fish than us.
Size matters, Davy boy.
Kevin: He didn't break the
thousand mark this year.
And we got one.
Yeah, you still there Dave?
Come in.
Dave: Well yeah, only did
see on fish there and that
was at, uh, first light.
And that was it.
Marciano: We were sitting
there at prime time and
we're hoping them big, fat
slobs come back through and
cooperate.
Dave: Got to do something.
I'm getting kind of burned
out just (bleep) sitting in
one spot.
Nothing happening, you know?
Should be doing
better than this.
Marciano: Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, I hear you.
Dave: Oh, man.
Well, I'm gonna fish
through this tide here.
I'll be out of here
shortly thereafter.
Good luck.
I'll chat with you
in a few minutes.
Marciano: Standing by.
Kevin gets lucky, gets a
wicked slob, (bleep) yeah,
I want to catch a
bigger fish than him.
All right, so we got Davy
Dot Com up ahead of us.
Now, Wilson, I want you to
be paying attention up here
while I'm back there
getting these rigs out,
make damn sure you let me
know if you start to see a
few fish.
It's gonna hurt him a lot
more than it's gonna hurt
me.
There's a bunch
of fish here.
Any rod could go any minute.
There he is.
We're on!
We definitely got a tuna
fish on the line here.
Let's just hope he makes the
grade to be a sellable fish.
The legal limit is
73 inches or greater.
Let me have a good
look at you, son.
He's awful close.
Nah, he's not a keeper.
Right species.
Wrong size.
Gonna do a quick
release job here.
There he is.
You know?
So that's it.
We got a short.
Again, not what
we're here to target.
But, uh, it would be illegal
for me to sell that fish.
He's too short.
The legal limit for a giant
bluefin tuna is 73 inches or
greater.
That fish there
falls into the, uh,
small medium bluefin
tuna category.
Jay: You know, it's
a disappointment;
no meat for the boat.
But, uh, at least we know
the tuna are biting.
Just not the big tuna.
Marciano: Well we just
(bleep) haven't been having
a good year.
I (bleep) pissing
money away,
(bleep) hand over fist.
It just, you know, this
has been the worst (bleep)
season I've ever
(bleep) had doing this.
Jay: Yeah.
Right now it just sucks.
It feels like we can't
do anything right.
Enough is enough.
Captain decides to go home.
You know, we're gonna come
out tomorrow and put the
hooks back in the
water and hopefully,
we can get that right bite.
Get that week's check.
You know?
Get that thousand
pounder, hopefully.
The Hard Merchandise
will be on the fish.
Dave: Good morning.
Sandro: Yo.
Dave: Yeah, let's get
out of here quick.
Uh, catch a couple
fish hopefully, and,
we got to beat Kevin.
Sandro: Be the biggest fin.
Dave: You ready?
Sandro: Let's get it done.
Dave: Come on.
One big jumbo today.
Sandro: Yeah, right.
Dave: 1,038 whatever it is.
Sandro: Thousand
thirty-eight.
Paul: And you
know what Kevin?
Back the (bleep) up.
Here we come.
Jay: Who wants a nice
gourmet breakfast?
Anybody up for a
Man: Yeah, I'd love
one, yeah, yeah.
Marciano: The season
wasn't going well.
I had to do something.
So I had an opportunity
to grab this charter.
Jay: Remember, nice and slow
so you don't rip it out of
his mouth.
Marciano: The whole idea of
a charter is these guys are
hiring me for the
opportunity to come out and
catch a few fish.
It's not something
I normally do.
Call me a slut, but they
offered me money for me to
take 'em out fishing.
I'll do what I got to do.
Yeah, you can whip a
few flounders up there,
though white side up.
Man: Like that?
Marciano: Yeah.
And then we'll do
these flounders first,
and then I'll do the cod.
You know, it's nice
to have the charter.
Its guaranteed income.
Especially when tuna
fishing's slow.
But then sometimes it's a
little frustrating 'cause
that pulls me away
from the tuna game,
right during prime time.
You know, guys are looking
to catch some good eatin'
fish for supper.
You know?
We have these beautiful cod
and haddock up here in New
England.
It's usually pretty easy to
go out and get a handful of
cod and make
these guys happy.
Jay: What we got here, we
got some nice big clams.
You got to make sure your
baits got that black gook
the haddock and cod and
pollock they like to suck on
that.
The more nastier it is, the
faster it's gonna work,
and the faster you're gonna
hook that little fish.
Marciano: I desperately
need this trip.
This will give me a paycheck
and Jay a paycheck to keep
us in the tuna game
a little bit longer.
Dave: There'll be a bit
here in the next few days.
Do you think so, Paul?
Paul: I hope so.
I hope it's this afternoon
will determine what's going
on.
The last few days have
really been bad luck.
But, it happens.
Sandro: I would love
an 800 pounder.
Paul: Could, there's
always that chance,
we've done really
good here this year.
Dave: We're gonna
stay until dark,
I don't care how
hard it blows.
Especially with Kevin
getting that fish.
It's imperative we come home
with something, anyway.
I'm getting a
little burned out.
Getting a little burned
out to say the least.
Paul: Yep.
Dave: Man, I'd love to see
something happen here,
I really would.
We caught a lot of
fish here this year.
But it's not
happening right now.
We'll blame it on Sandro.
Paul: Yep.
Just (bleep) everything up.
Dave: It's all his fault.
Right, Sandro?
Sandro: (Bleep).
Paul: Aah.
Dave: Look, aah, you can't.
Paul: He can't even
hold his, chum.
Paul: You got one?
Dave: You got one?
Crank it.
Something's on there.
Paul: Something's going.
You got him; don't
let him slack out.
Dave: Crank, that's
tuna coming up.
Paul: Yep.
That's a tuna.
Dave: It's what
it's all about.
Paul: Keep him
tight there, rookie.
Dave: Crank, crank.
Come on.
Always want to stay
ahead of the competition.
Just by one.
We're on the cliff,
right Sandro?
Sandro: Yeah.
Bend that rod.
This is what it's
all about again.
Crank, crank, come on.
The competition continues.
Sandro, stay on him.
Stay on him.
Here he comes.
I almost got color.
Grab that rope?
Dave: Yeah, bitch.
Aah, looks small,
maybe a small tuna.
Small tuna or bluedog.
Paul: I don't know; a seven
hundred pounder does the
same thing.
Dave: A little French fry.
Paul: A (bleep) baby.
Dave: Come on.
Going on?
There he is.
Little rat.
Paul: Throw it back.
We don't want those
little (bleep).
Small fish.
It's just like a streak of
bad luck, that, it happens.
Dave was pissed.
(Bleep)!
What the (Bleep)!
Dave: Ah, not a (bleep) rat.
Damnit a rat.
Oh, man.
Now what we want.
Sandro: Look at
those huge fins.
Look at that, it's giant.
That fish there one day will
be a thousand-plus pounds.
Look at the belly on him.
Paul: Look how fat he is.
Sandro: Alright,
you can let go.
Dave: Good-bye.
Paul: Yeah.
Dave: Not even
close actually,
we could've used
him for bait.
Real small.
They got to be 73 inches.
Those are the regs.
We follow 'em, so does
everybody else, pretty much.
And, uh, let him go.
Come back, get
him another day.
Get him in another, what?
Maybe five, six years?
Paul: You give back to
you save the stocks.
Keep the fishery alive.
You don't want to kill
every little fish.
You've gotta give back
to the sea, you know?
It's good karma, too.
God damn it.
Dave: Definitely a
lot of fish around.
Both the little ones
and the big ones.
Unfortunately we can't
get the big ones to bite.
I'm very competitive
in nature.
You know, especially
with Kevin,
and he's got us beat right
now and I want to beat him.
I want to beat him
in the worst way.
Donna: You want to put
the live guy in, or?
Bill: Yeah, I was actually
thinking about it.
Donna: Once in a while I
have dreams that are really
whacked out about fishing.
Dreamt one time that I was
tuna fishing off my front
porch in a puddle, and
actually hooked up.
Yeah.
Rod was bent over.
It was great.
Scott: What
the hell is wrong with you?
Donna: I told you, I'm
whacked out, I'm sick.
Bill: I can't
make it happen.
They just won't
get under the boat.
Dave: I know.
I feel for you, I do.
We're rooting for you.
Bill: You're a lying
sack of (bleep).
Dave: Keep plugging away.
I don't, I don't know.
Donna: Again, getting to the
point where this is not a
good habit to be in.
Glad that Christina
got a fish.
But, doesn't do me any good.
I'm sure the mood on the
Christina is a whole lot
better than the mood on the
Bounty Hunter right now.
Kevin: We caught a big fish.
It was almost eleven hundred
pounds and it could turn out
to be the biggest
fish of the season.
We're hot right now.
We're here to do it again.
I know the big
fish are feeding.
And I know what
they're biting on.
I think the best part of the
whole thing is knowing that
it's killing Dave.
Dave: Yeah, let her go.
You're good.
Let's go with the
fourth bridle.
Hopefully we can
get something here.
Paul: Kevin, we're
coming for you.
We're gonna kick your
(bleep) (bleep),
so watch the (bleep) out!
Dave: Day's not over.
Day's not over.
Marciano: Today we've got
a charter aboard the boat,
and it's a
double-edged sword.
On the one hand, fifteen
hundred bucks is a pretty
good chunk of change.
On the other hand, I could
be out tuna fishing.
And I could catch a fish
that's worth 10,000 dollars.
We're doing a little bit
of cod fishing right now.
So what we're
going to do is,
we're gonna hope we can do
a little of both here today
for these guys.
While we're out there
with this charter,
I'm gonna throw the tuna
rod over just for a little
while, just to
see what happens.
That movie The
Perfect Storm,
I knew a few of those
guys on that boat.
In particular,
that guy Sully.
Now the interesting thing
about that, is, uh,
I was just about
to go on that trip.
That very trip that wound up
being that boat's last trip.
Just two days
before we left,
I got the opportunity for a
full-time job on a day boat.
So I went with
the full-time job.
Like that kid Sully, we were
down in the Crow's Nest
having a few beers and he
loaned me some money that
night.
He loaned me a few hundred
bucks, and to this day,
I still owe him that money.
If it wasn't for me getting
that full-time day job,
you know, I'd be with the
rest of those guys on the
Andrea Gail.
And I wouldn't
have any kids.
Man: Not to mention, you
wouldn't be cutting that
flounder right now.
Marciano: Yeah.
Jay: Hey, Dave?
Marciano: Yeah?
Jay: That boat's on
a fish over there.
That guy.
I just watched
him do a circle.
Marciano: Oh, yeah?
Kevin: Stay on him.
Which way?
I need one guy
talking to me.
Scott: Good.
Good.
Blair: There, good.
Scott: Ah, Jesus,
pulling hard.
Kevin: One more circle
then I'm coming back.
Scott: All right, that's
good, right there.
Bill: You've got
to be (bleep) me.
Scott: Kevin on Christina
the hug boat, he, uh,
was here five
minutes, he hooked up,
and he's off fighting
the fish right now.
Bill: How can that be?
How, how can that be?
Donna: It be.
Scott: I'm trying to
stay on top of this fish.
Gonna keep the
pressure on him,
and slowly bring him up.
Kevin: Dad, get
the small harpoon.
Get the small harpoon.
I'm gonna come back.
Tell me when I can
come back, Scott.
Scott: Back, back, back,
back, back, back back.
Kevin: Keep him coming,
keep him coming.
Keep him coming.
All right, we got him.
Sammy: I got the gaff.
Kevin: Gaff.
Tail, tail wrap.
Then we're gonna go watch
the Patriots, boys.
All right, now
we're roped up.
Man: I'm on it.
Get on it.
Kevin: Nice
angling, my friend.
Let's go guys.
Pull.
Man: It's a whale!
Kevin: Told you they
grow when they come in.
Ooh, that's, uh, that
might be a grander.
Man: It might be, it might
be another thousand pounder.
Kevin: Right there,
that's what you do.
108.
Dave: Holy (bleep).
Oh, there he is!
We're on!
We're on, we're
on, we're on!
Paul: Yeah!
Dave: Yeah, (bleep).
Go!
This is the one.
This is the one that's
gonna beat Kevin.
Might be a grander.
This is it, guys.
Paul: This is the one
that's gonna beat Kevin.
Dave: Come on,
Sandro, come on.
Paul: This is it, guys.
Dave: Whoa!
Dave: Kevin just put
another one on the boat.
Sandro, stay on him.
Stay on him.
I know there's a lot more
money swimming under the
boat right now that
we're gonna catch.
Paul: This might
be a grander!
Dave: Come on,
Sandro, come on!
This is the one!
This might be him.
This is it, guys.
God damn it, another
(bleep) baby.
Paul: Oh, there
goes this line.
Dave: Man, I don't have
time for this today.
Paul: Another (bleep) baby.
Dave: Let it go.
Let it go for another day.
Little rats.
Sandro: A baby.
Dave: Ready?
Kevin: Let him go,
it's just a baby!
It's a baby!
Come on, 144 inches
over here, Davy.
Paul: Kevin, he
was being cocky.
He's like, look at
that (bleep) thing,
look how little it is.
Kevin: Hundred and forty
four inches, Dave.
Paul: I felt like (bleep)
going over there and cutting
his off.
Dave: I know I'm never gonna
hear the end of Kevin's
fish.
He'll find some way
to stick it to me.
Kevin: I've said it to Dave,
and I said it to him earlier
today.
I said, "Size matters, Dave.
And you know it."
There's only room for one
Number One in this group,
and sorry, buddy.
It's right here.
Came in early because,
uh, couple reasons.
Boat's full.
Which is a good thing.
We pretty much went through
all the tackle that we had,
and, you know, I'm
just, I'm just beat.
I'm beat.
We couldn't have
hit that one better.
Man: We need
those dots back.
Kevin: Yeah,
we're out of dots.
That's another
reason we came in.
We had no dots,
we're out of dots.
Man 1: Close to 800.
Seven and change.
Big fish.
Man 2: Here's your receipt.
Good job.
Kevin: Thanks.
Man 2: Good job.
Kevin: I'm hanging on with
the biggest fish out of the
group here, so.
Uh, I don't think, uh,
delicate Dave's gonna beat
it.
Man: See you, guys.
Kevin: It's been
a good week,
but the Pats are
playing tonight.
I'd like to see this game.
Jay: This is how
the rig's gotta be.
It's gotta be right on
the bottom, like that.
Man 1: Yeah.
Jay: Keep it tight.
Marciano: Guys
are hooking up.
I can see their
bent rods from here.
But I got to sit here and
tell fishing stories.
I might shift in
a minute, guys.
I don't see us getting
much good here.
We'll give it a
few more minutes.
Man 2: I'm good for
one minute.
Ask my wife.
Ha ha ha.
Man 3: That is so stupid.
Jay: Oh, we're on,
we're on, we're on!
We're on!
Dave!
Jay: Um, about
a 300-pounder!
Man 2: Go, Dave, come on!
Jay: We got you, Dave!
Man 3: Marciano, he's
bringing him in.
Jay: He's coming
right at us.
There he is.
Man 3: There we go.
Man 2: Let's get him!
Man 3: Let's go!
Jay: I saw his tail.
Right there, right there!
My (bleep) heart's out
of my chest right now.
Marciano: This I think is
about a 400-pound fish.
So we know he's gonna be at
least five grand for me.
Man 2: Come on!
Man 3: Yeah, come
on, Dave, here we go!
Marciano: Watch what I'm
doing, alright guys?
We'll give you a
little time on the rod?
Man: Yep.
Marciano: You saw
how we did it, right?
You pull with one,
reel in the other.
You know, for me, now we're
hooked up to an eight or
eight or 10,000 dollar fish.
I did have a
little, you know,
anxiety letting these
guys get in on the game,
fight the fish for
a little while.
You gotta keep that
rod bent for me though.
Jay: Nice and easy Johnny!
Man: The Tuna God,
thatta boy, Johnny boy.
You're the man!
Marciano: It's not gonna be
very exciting for them if
Jay and I just
bring the fish in.
Who's gonna pay
you to do that?
Well if they get
a taste of this,
they're gonna want to
come back and do more.
All right, watch the tip.
While you guys are fighting
this fish, watch the tip.
That's the key.
The part that bothers me
a little bit about this
situation, you can
lose one so easily.
And now I gotta have six
cherries on the rod,
so they can all
get a little turn?
You know, that's the
potential for making six new
guy mistakes which
could cost me this
8,000-dollar fish?
Eventually, and
we got to land that fish.
All 800 pounds of him.
Broke the (bleep)
tail strap.
Jay: Oh, my goodness.
Wow.
It is a big (bleep) fish.
He's way bigger.
Marciano: It was a thrill
for them to see such a big,
beautiful fish up
close and personal.
Now we got him.
Man 3: Jesus,
feel that derma.
Marciano: Hard, huh?
Man: Say thank you.
Feel it, feel it.
Man: Whoa.
Oh my God.
Look at that
frigging football.
Dave: Kevin got a big
thousand pounder now and
we're here to catch a big
fish and it didn't happen.
Paul: Dave's been beside
himself that Kevin got that
big fish.
Dave: I want to
beat his (bleep).
That's what's
important here,
it's not about the
dollars anymore,
it's about the biggest fish.
Paul: I said, "Don't worry.
We'll get one
bigger than Kevin's.
You just wait."
Dave: We deserve
to be on top.
I mean, we're working
hardest at it.
I'm not gonna sleep until
I get a bigger fish than
Kevin.
Paul: You know what Kevin?
We're (bleep) coming
for you, dude.
Marciano: This morning, I
wasn't too thrilled about
this trip.
But I gotta admit, it was
fun to have an audience
cheering me on.
Tail's up, man.
That's what it's all
about right there.
A couple of you
kneel down in front of him
so we can get everybody
in, even the whole fish.
I love it when a
plan comes together.
As a rule of thumb, I don't
like people on my boat.
But this is a great
bunch of guys.
'Cause this is the
part we get paid for.
We don't get paid
for the head.
for the tail.
We get paid for the meat.
Man 2: You know what
I got to tell you?
You made sure that each of
us got to take a little
turn.
Marciano: Yeah?
Man 2: Reeling that fish in.
I know it was a lot
of money for you.
And, we, you know, we're all
rookies, and everything.
Marciano: Right.
Man 2: But the fact that you
thought of enough to make
sure we all it
meant a lot to us.
Marciano: Good, good.
I'm glad you enjoyed it.
That's what it's all about.
Man 2: Thank you very much.
Man 4: Best Captain on
the planet, right there.
Man 1: Right there,
buddy, right there.
Man 4: Captain
Dave Marciano.
The best.
Not just because I'm
married to your sister.
Jay: What, what
about the best crew?
Nothing about the crew?
Man: Who's he?
Jay: Who's this guy?
Man 2: I thought
he worked here.
Thank you, fellas.
Great trip.