in the past few years, and each time I learn
the news, I react not as a president, but
as anybody else would, as a parent. And that
was especially true today.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
CARL AZUZ, CNN ANCHOR: President Obama speaking
last Friday about a shooting at Sandy Hook
elementary school in Newtown, Connecticut.
We`re going to be focusing exclusively on
that story today.
There are a lot of questions about what happened
on Friday. Right now, there aren`t very many
answers. As people struggle to understand
this tragedy, they are mourning the victims
who lost their lives and looking for ways
to honor those victims and support their families.
President Obama ordered the flag at the U.S.
Capitol building and at all U.S. Government
buildings to be lowered to half-staff on Friday.
Governors across the country asked for flags
in their states to be lowered as well. Messages
of sympathy for the shooting victims came
in from all over the world. A lot of people
shared similar thoughts on social media.
In the community of Newtown where this happened,
services and candle-light vigils like this
one had been going on since Friday night.
There has been an emotional reaction to the
shooting, as you might expect, and you could
see some of that emotion from President Obama
when he talked about it on Friday.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
OBAMA: I know there is not a parent in America
who doesn`t feel the same overwhelming grief
that I do. The majority of those who died
today were children, beautiful little kids
between the ages of 5 and 10 years old. They
had their entire lives ahead of them - birthdays,
graduations, weddings, kids of their own.
Among the fallen were also teachers, men and
women who devoted their lives to helping our
children fulfill their dreams. So our hearts
are broken today for the parents and grandparents,
sisters and brothers of these little children,
and for the families of the adults who were
lost.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: 26 people from Sandy Hook elementary
were killed on Friday. Earlier this year,
the principal put in a new security system.
It locks the doors at 9:30, and it requires
visitors to be identified and then buzzed
in. Officials say the alleged shooter, 20-year-old
Adam Lanza, used a gun to force his way into
the building, a gun authorities say belonged
to his mother, whom he`s also accused of shooting.
Around 9:30 Friday morning, witnesses reported
hearing gunshots inside Sandy Hook elementary.
Police say the gunman opened fire in two classrooms
after killing the principal and school psychologist
in the hallway. Officials said the shooter
eventually took his own life. The attack claimed
the lives of 20 students, all 6- or 7-year-olds,
and six adults, and left the community of
Newtown, Connecticut in shock.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Just a tragic, tragic
situation for the teachers, the principals,
and those angels, that`s all I keep thinking
about is those angels.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: When things happen to
your children, and to other people`s children,
I can`t look at my children`s faces now without
seeing the faces of every one of their schoolmates.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: The shooting at Sandy Hook elementary
is a story of violence and tragedy. It`s also
a story of heroism. Certainly the police and
emergency workers who responded to this attack,
but especially the teachers and administrators
at Sandy Hook and their actions last Friday.
When one kindergarten teacher heard shots,
she locked her classroom door, took her students
to a safe area in the back of the room, and
read to them in order to keep them calm. A
first-grade teacher ushered her students into
the class bathroom and then keep them there
until the police came to evacuate them. Another
first-grade teacher moved her students into
a corner away from the door. When the gunman
came into the room, the teacher stood in front
of the students, protecting them while sacrificing
her life.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
GOV. DANNEL MALLOY, D-CONNECTICUT: In this
time of troubles and travails, when the unthinkable
happens in our very midst, our faith is tested.
Not just in the religious sense, not just
necessarily our faith in God, but our faith
in community and who we are and what we collectively
are. And it`s in so many ways permissible
to have those thoughts and those doubts about
who we are and what we are and what community
represents, but then we turn to understand,
as we turn around this room, and recognizes
our friends and our neighbors, those we have
done things for and those who have done things
for us. This is a great and beautiful community,
located in a great and beautiful state and
a great and beautiful nation.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: There are a number of organizations
that are working to help the community of
Newtown. Some are fund raising, some are offering
counseling and other services to families.
Some are collecting messages of support. CNN
has a list of several of these organizations
as part of our impact your world program.
It offers some ideas on how you cane make
a difference to those in need. You`ll find
the link in the spotlight section at CNNstudentnews.com.
We also have a blog posted at cnnstudentnews.com,
where you can talk about this if you`d like.
From those of your viewers on Facebook, here
are a few of the comments posted yesterday
afternoon. From Tessa, "The country needs
to come together to help the families that
were hurt and affected by the shooting. We
need to put the focus on them and helping
them recover, put the focus on prayer and
recovery."
From Kate, "these precious angels will forever
be missed and never forgotten."
From Carlos, "when will things like this ever
stop?"
From Seth, "This is a horrible tragedy, but
we must now begin to heal and ensure that
something like this never happens again."
From Kelsey, "I`m proud of all the brave teachers
who risked their lives to save those poor
little kids."
From Chris, who is a teacher. "No student
or teacher should have to fear going to school.
My heart goes out to everyone in that community."
And from Alicia, "I think the whole nation`s
thoughts, prayers and love should go straight
to the families affected by this tragedy."
Alicia, I could not agree more. I join everyone
who is praying for this community and for
all of you around the world who`ve been affected
by this. We know many of you still have a
lot of questions. We have a lot of questions.
But we`ll continue searching for answers in
the days ahead.