-I don't know what
they think we do.
I think people think we
might sell drugs.
I don't know what they think.
But they don't realize
we work our ass off
all day, every day.
We wear suits and go
to work all day.
And do this gnarly ass shit.
Seriously, people go to
school their whole
lives and do this shit.
[HIP HOP MUSIC]
-Why don't you guys talk
about that more?
-It's just not--
-I just don't.
I don't know.
-You're not allowed to
tell your alter ego?
-It's not that.
It's just I keep certain
things private.
-It's nobody else's
really business.
I keep those things separate.
-If you know me,
you know that.
-One of our best friends
worked, got
this job as an attorney.
I referred my sister.
She had a case.
I referred her to him, which
made him $10,000.
-It made him 10 racks,
boom, rock that.
-He liked us.
He knew what we were
capable of.
So one day, I'll never forget,
it was a Thursday.
He called us.
He was like, I'll hire
you guys right now.
I'm like, don't fuck
with this.
-He said quit your job, and
show up tomorrow morning.
And we did.
-That's what we did.
-And the rest is history
10 years ago.
So we got in there, not
knowing shit about--
-He didn't teach
us shit at all.
--legal shit at all.
We just paid attention and
learned, and figured out, how
do you make money
doing this shit?
-We're good.
-Wat we do is all
insurance money.
-We're living good.
You see we're living good.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
-And he knew you guys had only
graduated eighth grade?
-Yeah.
-I don't think he knew that.
-I don't even think
he knew it.
He didn't give a shit.
At the time, we didn't
wear suits.
We wore fucking--
-This.
-LRG gear.
We were super into LRG
back in the day.
-So when did the suits
come into play?
-When we started getting a
little more serious about it,
and realizing--
-It makes things easier.
-Because we go sign
these people up.
And they're looking at us like,
wait a second, you guys
look kind of crazy.
But we talk our way out of it.
And they love us.
It made it easier when we
started wearing suits.
-With us, we can deal with the
most ghetto mother fuckers.
I can speak their fucking
language, and break it down to
them.
-And then super conservative
people, I can put this act on,
and tell them--
-You guys would be so
tripped up if you
guys saw us in action.
-It's always both of
yous guys going?
-And he likes that.
That's the thing.
When we first got
hired he liked.
-He aid I like the fact
that it's four eyes.
-It's four hands.
It's better.
-It's two brains.
-That's good.
-It's true, though.
Together, we're a fucking
powerhouse.
We kill shit.
And every fucking god damn
day that we work there--
-I've come to realize, we
don't talk about it or
anything, but we work
60 hours a week.
-Really?
-Yeah.
You think I'm living like this
from fucking what, getting
into "Rolling Stone?" No.
We work our fucking
ass of every day.
And what sucks, what's crazy
is we go to New York.
We go to LA.
Go film "Spring Breakers," and
do all this amazing shit.
And then have to come back.
-To reality.
-To reality and work.
-So you're trying to
piece that out?
-Yeah.
-Do you think with this movie
about to come out, that your
life will permanently
be changed?
-I hope so.
I hope some good opportunities
come up.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
-Bikinis and big booties,
y'all, that's
what life is about.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
-There's one scene where
Franco introduces us.
-He says--
-He said they do everything
together.
They eat, [INAUDIBLE].
-He says all this whole line.
He says they double
penetrate bitches.
-And as he's saying all this
stuff, it's flashing back to
this party scene.
And it shows Selena's
face, and she's--
-Freaked out.
-For her to be in "Spring
Breakers" is nuts.
Her part in "Spring Breakers"
is the chillest one.
-The safe one.
You saw it.
-She's still guilty
by association.
She has tits.
-What do you think it's
going to do for
Selena Gomez's image?
-They're trying to move out of
that Disney shit and get real
serious acting rolls.
Selena Gomez is going to be a
huge star for the rest of her
life.
-But she's still--
-She's a star, bro.
She's going to be a star for
the rest of her life.
-But she still want
to be portrayed
as a serious actress.
She knew fuck with Harmony
Korine, and a movie like--
-Street cred.
-He had to get on the
phone with Bieber.
She was talking to Bieber.
I was like let me talk
to that fool.
She was like, all right, here.
-How'd it go?
-I think Bieber's amazing,
personally.
-A lot of people hate on him,
I think, that's music and
shit, all that.
Do I like his music, no?
Do I like his personality?
He seems amazing.
-Anybody doing something
successful in their lives and
they're passionate about it,
how can you hate on that?
You can't.
-What was it like working with
those little Disney girls,
being two dirts?
-We'd just show up--
-I don't give a fuck
who they are.
-You've got to understand,
you know how we are.
-You know How we act.
So we went up to them.
Yo.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
-ATL Twins.
We're like yeah, what's up?
How are you doing?
-Ashley Benson is cool.
Vanessa Hudgens is cool.
They're all cool.
Selena's cool.
But you understand--
-They're from different
worlds.
-She's got such a
fan base, bro.
She's so protected
and watched.
She can't just do that.
You know what I mean?
When we first got on set,
Ashley and Vanessa
were cool as fuck.
And we immediately
did a photo.
And she's got a fuckload
of Instagram followers.
-So she posts the photo like
on set today with the ATL
Twins and links us up.
Our Instagram starts going
ham, like this is gross.
Later that day, we get a photo
with Selena, and we post it on
our Instagram.
And shit was going ham.
All of a sudden--
-We're gone.
-Suspended.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
-I got pissed.
-We were drunk, too, and we
got super heated about it.
-I started Tweeting, fuck you
Selena Gomez fans, you fucking
psychos.
-Impersonators.
-You fucked my fucking
Instagram up.
And they just--
-We fucked up, dog.
-Thousands of mentions.
-Name some big time people,
Selena Gomez has
the biggest fan base.
-Period.
-We told Selena, yo, your fans
are fucking attacking us.
-She was like, yeah, don't
fuck with my fans.
They're loyal.
-It's an army, I would say,
of anywhere from 5
to 10 million people.
-I tweet, we are under attack.
-Please help us.
We're under attack from
Selena Gomez fans.
-Nonstop, bomb, bomb,
going off.
-We apologize.
-I apologize.
-We are sorry.
-We did not mean to--
just please--
-Leave us alone.
-And we surrendered.
-You want to try to call her
right now, on speaker phone?
See what happens.
-Sure.
-What do you think?
Two rings and ignore?
-I say she doesn't answer.
-She's not going to answer.
-I'm going to go with
a no answer.
-The number you dialed is
not a working number.
-Changed it.
-Ah, changed.
-What's the goal?
-The goal is to be like
Justin Bieber, yo.
Make money like that fool.
-I want to be a millionaire
for real.
I want to make just millions.
-I want to fuck celebrity
chicks.
-When people say fame, yeah, I
want to be fucking famous.
I want to fucking be like
balling, living in Hollywood,
fucking living that life.
You know what I'm saying?
[MUSIC PLAYING]