Ah.
Where's the bathroom?
Oh, man we got--
holy shit.
Peep the shitter.
Bang.
Shower next to the toilet.
You could technically take a
shit and shower at the same
damn time, future.
Take a shit, take a shower at
the same damn time, at the
same damn time.
Lounging.
Yo, man, I feel like
Najeh Davenport.
I just took a shit
in that closet.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Yo, what's up?
FREDDY LIM: Hi.
EDDIE HUANG: How's it going?
How you doing?
FREDDY LIM: Great.
EDDIE HUANG: Should we
close this door since
we're going to scream?
FREDDY LIM: Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, going to be noisy.
EDDIE HUANG: Hi, how are you?
FREDDY LIM: He is
one of the hot
shot teachers of screaming.
EDDIE HUANG: Do your parents
know you have this?
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
DU-BU KUO:
EDDIE HUANG:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
DU-BU KUO:
FREDDY LIM: So where is yours?
EDDIE HUANG: I have one here.
It's like a Chinese astronaut.
See?
FREDDY LIM: Oh, that's great.
DU-BU KUO: Oh, cool.
EDDIE HUANG: See,
Asian astronaut.
We can go in outer
space too, guys.
FREDDY LIM: Yeah.
And one of the funny part is
that because metal is getting
more and more popular in
Taiwan-- so most of the kids,
if they want to learn screaming,
they go to music
class to learn.
EDDIE HUANG: Very Asian
of these kids.
FREDDY LIM: Yeah.
So now today the first class for
you is to learn one of the
hit songs that most of
the kids will learn.
EDDIE HUANG: This is a hit
mother fucking record here.
This is a hit record?
FREDDY LIM: Yeah, that our--
EDDIE HUANG: All right.
FREDDY LIM: Vultures fly,
circling the dark skies
plucking carrion from
the ground.
EDDIE HUANG: What's carrion?
FREDDY LIM: That's like--
EDDIE HUANG: Like,
extra luggage?
FREDDY LIM:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
EDDIE HUANG:
FREDDY LIM:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
EDDIE HUANG: Ah, OK, cool.
Vultures fly, circling the
dark skies plucking
carrion from the--
FREDDY LIM: You need to
add some distortion.
Vultures fly-- that's loud.
But you need distortion.
EDDIE HUANG: Oh, I
need to distort.
FREDDY LIM: Vultures fly.
EDDIE HUANG: OK.
Vultures fly, circling the dark
skies plucking carrion
from the ground.
FREDDY LIM: Yeah, that's it.
EDDIE HUANG: Yo, so how did
I lose my voice so fast?
FREDDY LIM: You used
too much throat.
You need to use your
stomach and chest.
EDDIE HUANG: Really,
mega, mega pause.
Don't use the throats, kids.
So right now we're in Gongguan,
and I'm with our
fixer, George, all right?
So George is showing
me around.
In this neighborhood there's a
lot of like what Taiwanese
people call [FOREIGN LANGUAGE],
like
little snacks.
And this area is known for it.
So this is a traditional
Taiwanese dish called
[FOREIGN LANGUAGE].
It's made with bonito, like
dried fish from Japan.
This is amazing.
I'm not sharing shit, so I'm
going to combine these two
soup spoons.
It's a very good example of
like cross utilization of
ingredients from Japan and
Taiwan together, because
Taiwan was occupied
by the Japanese.
And see these oysters in here?
Oysters.
You see the intestine
right there.
I like it because it's somewhere
in between noodle
soup and porridge.
It's a little thick.
You could kind of
just drink it.
You don't even need
chop sticks.
This is a very popular treat.
This is one of my favorite
hot pot foods.
Pig's blood cake, all right?
It's sticky rice and
pig's blood.
Then they dip it in
sweet chili sauce.
And then they roll it in crushed
peanuts and cilantro.
Check it out.
So, yo, there's a giant line
here, but this woman is a huge
VICE fan, going to hook it up.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
-[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
EDDIE HUANG: This is
[FOREIGN LANGUAGE], pan fried dumplings.
This one I got with cabbage
and pork, super
crispy on the bottom.
Nice and chewy, nice
chewsome feel.
Delicious flavor.
It doesn't need the soy sauce.
Eat it without soy sauce.
Let's fucking kill it.
Let's get some metal make
up and eat with Freddy.
All right, so, I'm here.
I'm in Freddy's crib.
I've got my heart pillow.
I've got my white wine.
I got my pink tissue box.
I'm ready for some really
heavy hardcore
metal shit right now.
Enjoy.
Have some sauvignon blanc.
FREDDY LIM: The make up in
metal culture, there are
different kind of make ups
in different countries.
Yeah, like Scandinavian
kind of--
EDDIE HUANG: Are there
always dudes putting
it on you like this?
With oink near my knee
and this white wine
and this heart pillow?
This is not helping any Asian
stereotypes right now.
I might have just set us back
like 10 years, like worse than
Wiliam Hung.
Yo, you look like you got the
Lebron logo on his head.
He has that on his shoe, but
now it's on your head.
FREDDY LIM:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE].
EDDIE HUANG: I'm not going to
bug out when I see this.
Yo, son, I look like Mike Tyson
raped the legion of doom
and had kids.
This is horrible.
It looks like the technique
on the fish got a
little fucked up.
FREDDY LIM:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
EDDIE HUANG: He told me-- he
said that a lot of your songs
is about Taiwanese
independence.
[MUSIC - CHTHONIC, "TAKAO"]
FREDDY LIM: Not really.
I think it's all related
to the history.
Sometimes I don't really
consider it to be called
Taiwanese independence, because
we are independent.
So it's more like we should be
normalized, because we are not
a member in the UN.
We don't act like
a normal state.
EDDIE HUANG: Do you feel that
it's a more symbolic thing or
it's an actual in practice will
change your life on a day
to day like realistic basis?
I'm just curious.
FREDDY LIM:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
-[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
EDDIE HUANG:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
BRIAN:
EDDIE HUANG:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
BRIAN:
EDDIE HUANG:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
BRIAN:
FREDDY LIM:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
-[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
FREDDY LIM:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
EDDIE HUANG: I love SARS.
FREDDY LIM:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
EDDIE HUANG: I don't think
anyone should be under
anyone's control.
I don't even like having
a producer.
But then it's also--
let me ask you this.
You leave one job, but if you're
not economically or
personally sufficient,
you trade it for
another job, right?
FREDDY LIM: Yeah.
EDDIE HUANG: And you're
constantly trading masters.
Do you think Taiwan can be
independent on it's own
without China, without America,
without Japan, you know?
Because if you need America to
get away from out from under
China, then isn't that
your new master?
I don't know.
I'm just asking questions.
FREDDY LIM: I really like
speaking all these kind of
things with this make up.
EDDIE HUANG: Extra
appropriate.
FREDDY LIM: That's great.
EDDIE HUANG: Just in the last
60 years Chinese people have
emigrated so many places.
Taiwanese people have emigrated
so many places.
And the identities are very,
very complicated, the
political identities
even more so.
And just on this shoot, our
fixers feel one way.
Freddy feels one way.
I'm kind of stuck in the
middle just trying to
represent both sides.
It's very, very interesting how
many angles there are to
this topic.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
BRIAN:
-[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
FREDDY LIM: So I just play?
-Just play a song.
-[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
EDDIE HUANG: Got him.
On the next episode of "Fresh
Off The Boat"-- yo, this
"Fresh off the Boat,
Taiwan" with Eddie
Huang, mother fucker.
This is the single man cos
play fashion show.
We going to see what the
game's been missing.