GRACE HONIGSBERG: Hello,
I'm Grace.
I live here at Hidden Pastures
Alpaca farm with 65 alpacas in
the back yard.
PAUL HONIGSBERG: Hi, my name
is Paul Honigsberg.
I live here at Hidden
Pastures.
I like these alpacas a lot.
ANTHONY: Hi, I'm Anthony,
and I'm Paul's friend.
I'm nine years old, and
I come here a lot.
I know a lot about
alpacas too.
KAYLE DEFRANK: Hi, I'm
Kayla DeFrank.
I come here a lot.
I basically know my way around
here blindfolded.
GRACE HONIGSBERG: This
is something
called fiber on them.
And if you see the inside
of it, it's very crimpy.
That's ideal in an alpaca.
NATALIE BURGER: These alpacas
were shorn in April, so they
probably only have about an
inch of fleece right now.
At full fleece, they'll have
four to six inches of fleece,
and they'll be shearing
5 to 15 pounds of
fleece off their bodies.
I love to send my fleece to a
mill to make it into yarn, and
then I sell yarn at the various
yarn shops in the
area, as well as we go to
different farmers markets with
an alpaca just to let people
know what an alpaca is and
what a wonderful product
they do create.
KAYLE DEFRANK: Alpaca socks in
the winter are extremely warm.
I usually sleep with them
because they just keep my body
heated instead of, I'm
cold, I'm cold.
-Who's this little guy?
GRACE HONIGSBERG: This is a
girl, her name is Jewel.
She's about six months,
half a year old.
KAYLE DEFRANK: This
is Neptune's baby.
There's her mom, Neptune.
This baby has blue eyes,
which means she's
deaf and can't hear.
She's very adorable and fuzzy.
-And how old is she?
KAYLE DEFRANK: Four days old.
-Four days.
GRACE HONIGSBERG: This
one's Terror.
He's the terror of the group,
but he bothers everyone else
in the herd.
He doesn't have a name yet,
but he's very cute.
They make a humming noise,
which is what Charisma is
making to her baby.
They also make a clicking noise,
that distinct click.
KAYLE DEFRANK: And when the
male is breeding with the
female, he "orkles"?
GRACE HONIGSBERG: Orgles.
KAYLE DEFRANK: Orgles.
-What does that sound like?
KAYLE DEFRANK: You can't
make the noise.
[ORGLING]
GRACE HONIGSBERG: This
is baby Cassia.
She's got very exotic
marks on her head.
They come in 22 natural
colors.
They are very sweet animals.
They're just around you.
They're not trying to
hurt me in any way.
KAYLE DEFRANK: They're not
trying to run away from us
because they think
we're a threat.
They're just being peaceful.
GRACE HONIGSBERG: Yes, they're
very peaceful animals.
-And they can't bite you?
GRACE HONIGSBERG: They cannot.
TOGETHER: They only
have bottom teeth.
[MUSIC PLAYING]