and beginning I was like
to be doing hearing when I leave with
their way out commanders like walk out
the door
it's kinda hard to believe that's over
like everyone says the
the days go by slow in the weeks go by
fast and
proved to be pretty true grazing
and I don't necessarily mean that in a
bad way but they're just
there so much your always going you're
always tired you're always hungry euro
is trying to figure something out what
you think
figured out they had something to it and
it's just constantly had something new
that you're doing
I mean I'll just just is and it's not
like
crazy and same way but there's no break
you just what you really feel like
I need to stop any breakdown they just
pushing it a little more than you
realize you can do and it just
doesn't stop don't come here expecting
hidden in the back just for mine you
have to do
review asking for want leadership
afternoon
before I was like oh great about our
country awesome Comerica
and that I like I'm apart a bit like
caring savon 25 means more as well i
mean
I like I'm there to help protect our
country to an
is a definite just means more looking
back at it now
doesn't feel like it was that long and
you're in like three
in the first few weeks you know
is
in
the the first night was really crazy
no screening Allen and I can only do
anything you want to do this there's
on it faces of yeah
me like it's not getting yell that or
intimidated wire rampant
unique see hot for
3 you one getting through the first
night stressful
it's the first night here confused
scared
nervous
different emotions run into their remind
everybody get upstairs and
I felt like picking out a little bit
have
slowing your yelling at come here feel
bound opening a pandora's shaping
just can't think that way do thanks a
fight on the very day that feedback
effect her
every moment fermionic on his top
you are in
if we were to get them off the bus
assure them and hold their hand we're
not setting a precedent
or not setting structure we're not
saying I'm in charge
I say you do we're not just doing it to
be mean
not just doing it because we think we
have always power its
focus direct it has a purpose yet to
demand their attention
to command the situation you have to
bring them
in let let him know what I am the alpha
dog I'm in charge
I'm gonna tell you what to do in your
gonna listen to it you don't want to
you're going to
member to do what I say when I tell you
doing the man what are you doing is
understood
deviations that's why don't you look
down because you told was a mi
to be told does not because it does
because you don't stop understood
by the elevators amor teacher it's a
control thing you gotta get 'em
wrapped in quick all the way to lose if
you don't set that standard
said that President you're not gonna
have that word is on it you don't get
that strong good
product the indoor tracks we were to mir
stop
top efforts were you working about still
he's our he's our world and we're lucky
to be living
very home if I can say pic he decides
when the Sun comes up
goes down credo so
classic stop for small seaside house
you now strap to cover stuff
pick it up firsters
right is this a game see time
planes are my answers military trying to
break this down
you hear all the stories from brands
like just play the game your birthright
abrasive
just but there's a lot more to
that surgical team is see carries
sound contractors from house Tuesday
well
like its mind to nearly like the level
system
and the expectations he has and
he's not comes if we do
here right on over
to your right tried under I understand
just trying to make us the best they can
possibly Vegas
the sooner that we get everything is he
you know the less headaches uni
experience personally
slightly and I whole Soho
them
you do that
up you see
there's two elements
day for two days your four elements
that's why we have four
the dorm chief is in turn charge
the entire flight said I relay a message
how complicated it might be to the dorms
stuff
decide adorn chief
or break it down using giving the albany
is
only enough information piece by piece
at a time
to get them to start moving trainees in
the oil feed them or
to get the task of master wing man
go through a meter from me other than
that
there should be no talk seizes goes
trainees a lot of it is really to try it
encourage that the wing man concept that
they have
that you know they want they want you to
use the people who are around you to try
to figure things out getting
completed on your own without having let
me tell you what to do every single day
every second even though they are
telling us what to do every single
second
same stairs with your force on others
you needed sure that you
practice yourself stymie family here
switch pre-trial hours your profile
have the capabilities qualities needed
million honestly he's shown me that a
lot for
the key is how p
you've got kids that come here
down for instance far is musicals
schools
on but I'm not going to expect anybody
you know I'm not stop it I don't want
them secure don't
by the way you got this on they need to
be answered in with
in this process it's awesome on weddings
own leaders and one cheese figure out
how to do conflict resolution
because I'll come to the rescue of time
because if something's happening
I'm not mom I'm not there to be like
your bad you can be doing this
you talk to that person me he
3 guys smoke finance its no
20 guys in the shower has shower heads
in the spring of
role trying to figure out how to make it
work thing is just
its worse is forced on us that we will
we will figure it's not just about me
it's about the country
spin it's been
minor taps play
now from my side there's a lot I mean
I'm your part in this amazing
history in such a minimal
using the level frustrate in on the
future
you never know
they will get out the bed the same in
which I get out this is a person sees
be purpose for the day the way it was a
girl these represent
what they expect to get other day 57
trains while
as dress savon she's last
no less than 10 minutes
the fact that you mean to live on so
many more
everything is ok so quick
it 33 will but it just makes you realise
a lot things thing
it makes it easier for me at least
to it I'm not focusing on things
my cell phone or Facebook anything like
that just it makes it easier for me to
focus on them
telling susannah I so many mistakes way
looking at life then get accept them get
out
hearings
liked you always have your
you urges you know top-notch physically
fit
secure themselves selling the best for
their daily regimen that's on that
they come here thinkin their August
p.m. yet shape
they're gonna do it for me who'd
as they don't CST come here not the
neighborhood
subversives you don't realize they're
not just hurting themselves facet for PT
field
here
I think it's getting
caveat shapes what's in it and if I feel
my body
was from hostile
weeks degrees here
here
he hit save and hit
not just for C
visit old
forest alertness ready yes
sixty from 04 mild
long time down in
few in my brain
something since where QB nutrition when
you sleep
when your body is gone through the sky
stress
T streams
you're not busy it's hard
of
his cat
mystery times gorecki
just a little obvious fun of
expired
on another time 50
there are a lot of
of a female I'm in our fight
personalities that are having a hard
time with it so there's little if
conflict butting heads someone younger
people who were
you know though like really into
themselves I mean all the surrender
ourselves but
I might go and do what's best for the
group in
a lot I have a hard time doing haha I
no that they're not can be able to do it
but I'm forcing them to get into that
met my said I have talking back and
forth any usually comes from one point
where
up you down mean we can't do this or
I stepped in because I know things are
going south and certain words certain
things get said
you know that's my turning onto re: it's
time to have the talk
now before I go off might change it it
starts with you
you gotta be mile
you stand up right now be a big girl you
put on table
see how you are now you got beef
get up right now
some you are as tough as you think you
are that's for damn sure
it was a house divided in many ways a
house divided
I love people who care to people who
didn't hear on there was a house divided
people who
got it in didn't get it jens that's
where
as an EMT i you gotta step in any way
just because
we sit around gonna be and we who are
still together
our conversations only ok up where so
way out we you know blew him me or
whatever you feel like we do
we have we know a
yeah I'll smart will Hermes my
anybody else I will call the name since
I wanna put names from Connie
job for you have talked crates to Indian
this
stop happy yesterday we came in the door
by mean it was only while over now why
you timid in the shower but it was so
funny
health yeah I wanted this yup did that
happen before but I've never seen
never you're so worried bout
everybody else you're so works with you
think that I pick on you
you follow your hair and new york also
we get my
loan approval for not be able to see it
still all
will get that you're not the only one
different if you
let a situation like that go with you
let a trainee you know
just keep going up you give them lookout
this is a personal everybody it's not
you
you need to call even setting like its
it's so fragile you're on the fifth
you're trying to defuse the situation at
the time
I'm still in control not lei pursue just
to the blind I'm so emotional and she
wanted your point across for same time
I care went to see you plane all this if
it was winds but you have to want to
fight
you know other scents like right you
Park solution I'll just keep or fall
word
this is a breaking bad habits and if
that comes to its
I'm gonna shut down not be late in your
own pockets shut your mouth with salt
interject what only forty jet so which
is it
of City I said you're not the only one
over it other individuals they have a
problem
with when I talk to them address what
they're doing wrong
because again you are so worried about
your feelings
it's not my job to make you feel good my
job is to train use that when you got to
do your job
you don't get somebody else killed on
I went through and I mean it point the
ones that were sitting in the corner
like this
was like and what you up say that what's
your
he said percent right now for example
too long to detail I was where
now not toward tired
sleep
shot with his legs sneezed
I'm me everybody some
so that way you yeah for okay Heights
now its I'm
you're dealing with the site with free
in you know people's you guys get
careful with it
is far is getting trees to certain
emotions and back in forth
he you just can't leave him you needed
your gotta get thru of two different
stages of
shower or something my boyfriend nope
pair no there's there's so many things
that weren't
do everyone's won't you seen at home the
comic
be there's a line were all her
without children and no of world
you like she said there's finding
Trimline are you going to be a very and
this is where my insert joke
turns out also hey y'all
say but
so in its point is you can't rewrite it
to it's almost like
over fighting it's going going going you
can
popping and Rick this is it
word walking out the door this which is
going from here
backed game on Mon and that's the whole
point we talking about
David you like is that door a here
weekend
we can let loose out there scheme or if
you take the advice
you do now what you all put out on the
table
there's no stopping you
really not yes have peace march
on you don't doesn't look that bad
as and drop the subtle compliments
his you stirred up less today
it's very dark process kit you let up
too soon
don't never fights with and if you want
to try
Danny yes you it deteriorates and
to be used no
for out
well we started with a fast one festoon
second
tree have a pair them specified school
in order to
around the fence self
I
the usual six
getting trainees used to hate it here
and i won personal personal protection
they wanna get
rough and tough to tell you
with 10 points that way it will to be
able to go out there
literally let their hair down but those
football helmets on
and his daughter petitions them a lot of
confidence
reassures films
faced with a friend somebody 1
back go thoroughly trained for myself he
became one
to 34 taking all that Anna
Jess first 18 conduct criteria training
day
you're gonna need to know in order to
keep wife sustained until
trained medical personnel
see bernie is dozen 4-3 victory series
is a chemical biological radiological
explosives ago to a class A shares
quit
have DC gas chamber you can ask of
blessed
ass and we find forms
as it was hard to tell their introduced
to the fresh air side with Cassidy
hey clear
the worst part is trying to open your
eyes after work 12
blanket of the rise and it was
goes alright
of of sufficient skills funds for
themselves
savings bonds can actually be going to
CPR and temperatures to you at all that
stuff
put together being displayed how to set
up an area
how defend themselves out a Fender bass
in all common it's at the beast
is it related
there's to be limited mandolins vision
required
all tools
they've learned his office bus for 1
of level
guard and to go to see
areas near there shaking off a should do
it right no longer
washes unit which scenario saying okay
this which declined it switched Iran's
disputed
Albany final
good
their time I Y making you know that
right now it would even do wrong
but it it we just we learn to do things
better
better r fi and I rather fight just
having instructor team that we day
everything he did had a reason behind
at the time miss seems stupid to us or
may have seen
meaningless or whatever but the bag now
edges as automakers better and better
get better at in my career for a hater
I really did I when I first met her I
was like
dang it we had a female CIA because of I
soaked but I've always heard the horror
stories
that name like and look up to her so
much
it have to call out about something it
was necessary she's
I some she really is awesome she's just
the prime example but what
you want to be an airman cell and he's a
beast everything she does
i really wanna be like her you in him
we have a mentor we r structure have our
a father figure for sale on
I disciplinarian I'll someone's very
stern very strict
words whose very meticulous
am really the really knows
you
his measure of well
chairman
%um yes could
day
this my last life
this my last last night this Nadia I was
just things
now this this my last night far as being
at Force Base filters resort
of have
instructor said Norte is
a mentor yep
first here guy and then you're gonna end
up loving them
my first two weeks years ago there's no
im ever gonna like an easy
they're absolutely terrible now like I I
wouldn't trade her and guys for anything
even other really intense and
so sometimes like this kid everyone
looks up to him whenever in the dayroom
a everyone's is locked on listen to what
he has to say
is what every says it you help us out
everything
gonna be in and its yes gonna be
important every says gonna be important
in the beginning when you have a week
def no one here
as soon as their fun she's just so
awesome
so was assessed wake we carry
and we what's been a student here dnt
for that's gonna be
determining factor go
but it's nice to have I
this isn't over yet great pace ring so
nice to work with
now
i think im is a Mother's Day card I
think I don't know cuz they know I'm a
your positive approach in your attention
to detail make a real difference in
0:28:03.289,1193:02:47.295
mom
everything you do
positive approach and so we're going
these days
this is the first 1 I've ever had as a
mom I guess
its first from other days maybe stuff to
capitalize on it but
poets for Mother's Day I think in a way
it was also there
way it kinda given me their little
feedback thank you I guess
even now I don't need to thank you for
it really i kno
I can tell when I can tell change that
they appreciate
are on sorry I think you're just being
girls
we'll all have to sit there you know
when I have time back to work is there
something you don't speak
stuff like that you don't
given there's a time and a place I if
that were to happen like that for spring
training area Oak Hill now and I'm
you know would say you ever get on a
personal level with the trainee but
you're on a level
more understanding more stay and a I
think there's more over time and place
for it which
the now entering it doesn't bother me
that that they would
show their appreciation said he
certainly governor
forces were hits
with you'd
who felt guilty sometimes because
how much time you giving us eyesight
Derek East those and I said
I can see what you're sacrificing
you that some you know I'll we saw
and I want your wife
to for work both you sacrifice
for all start
I let trainings taken off like flights
look good
March take most of the dorms stop thing
here
cock is let the March let them get a
distance away
if
yes this there's no
I life with and
I was using amazing all sizes of
during the gulf
your flight
the car
won the PGA masses on your phone's
summer them
make some the mall last hope you'll
asked
life but has moved the
some you will never see each other again
these things are going up that have
opportunity to thank you was that's life
there
the
nerve your