EVAN GREGORY: The Gregory
Brothers are mostly known for
online videos that we do,
and those videos are the
realization of a Utopian vision
in which we uncover
hidden songs from within the
speech of ordinary people.
ANTOINE DODSON: Well, obviously
we have a rapist in
Lincoln Park.
[MUSIC - ANTOINE DODSON,
"BED INTRUDER SONG"]
EVAN GREGORY: We started in a
musical background and had
toured together with
my brothers.
ANDREW GREGORY: I don't know, we
toured a lot as a band, but
in a very small-scale way.
We were playing to crowds
of anywhere
between 0 and 200 people.
MICHAEL GREGORY: Nobody
likes a regular band.
SARAH GREGORY: We were
definitely pursuing the arts
in very traditional
ways when we first
started working together.
But then, once your imagination
gets a little
crazier and crazier, there's
stuff that you can only
produce using technology.
MALE SPEAKER: Senator
Obama, two minutes.
[MUSIC - MICHAEL GREGORY,
"DEBATE HIGHLIGHTS"]
SARAH GREGORY: Back in the 2008
presidential election,
Michael made a video out of the
first debate between Obama
and McCain.
And he wanted to write a song
basically about the issues
that he knew were going to be
coming up in that debate.
[MUSIC - MICHAEL GREGORY,
"DEBATE HIGHLIGHTS"]
SARAH GREGORY: So he
successfully made that video
and just thought it would be
way more fun if we could
somehow get the candidates
to sing along with us.
[MUSIC - THE GREGORY BROTHERS,
"AUTO-TUNE THE NEWS"]
EVAN GREGORY: We took some
technology that we had a grasp
of, the pitch correction
technology that includes
Auto-Tune, and used it to modify
their voices so that it
sounds like they're
singing with us.
And then we could create duets
and melodies that we're
actually participating
in together.
And that became "Auto-Tune
the News."
[MUSIC - THE GREGORY BROTHERS,
"AUTO-TUNE THE NEWS"]
SARAH GREGORY: We spent about
a year auto-tuning the news.
And then realized that we
shouldn't limit our quest for
music to just news
and politics.
[MUSIC - THE GREGORY BROTHERS,
"REALITY HITS YOU HARD BRO"]
"CAN'T HUG EVERY CAT"]
SARAH GREGORY: So then we just
started calling it Songify
because that's essentially what
we're doing, we're just
finding songs out
in the universe.
EVAN GREGORY: Where
are we, Andrew?
ANDREW GREGORY: Well, as you
might notice, our office is
very spacious.
Why you might ask?
Because it used to
be a horse barn.
EVAN GREGORY: This is where all
the audio magic happens,
where we try to summon various
types of sonic wizardry to
coax songs out of those places
in the universe that,
heretofore, have been dark,
songless corners.
We are trained musically but
not in the art of video
editing, so we just kind of
accrued those skills by
saying, let's try this
in the video.
I don't know how.
OK, let's figure it out, and
let's do the next thing.
Nearly everything that we shoot
for our videos is done
on a green screen.
Let's say, if we needed
a floating head.
ANDREW GREGORY: Or arms
waving around, we'll
still use the sheet.
EVAN GREGORY: But we upgraded
this year and
just painted the walls.
It's like, why hang the sheet?
Just paint the wall, man.
ANDREW GREGORY: So let's
take you back to the
area where we edit.
Hey, Sarah.
SARAH GREGORY: Hi guys.
ANDREW GREGORY: We run After
Effects stuff and Final Cut
stuff in tandem to sort of put
the videos together while the
audio is being made.
EVAN GREGORY: That's
a gold record.
ANDREW GREGORY: That single, it
just went gold in January.
I mean, something like "Friday,"
Rebecca Black's
"Friday," has gotten watched
a lot more than the "Bed
Intruder Song." But people
are not as excited about
downloading "Friday"
for $0.99.
EVAN GREGORY: Little-known
fact, you have to buy the
plaque for yourself once you
get it certified gold.
But we got-- we got
a couple of them
and sent one to Antoine.
So he's got one hanging
in his house, too.
ANDREW GREGORY: And,
unfortunately, solid, pure
gold does not come cheap.
MALE SPEAKER: Do your moms
understand what you actually
do for a living?
MICHAEL GREGORY: She
understands, but she still
says "YouTubes," plural.
[MUSIC - THE GREGORY BROTHERS,
"WINNING"]
EVAN GREGORY: Once the number of
views exceeds the number of
moms related to video producers,
then you feel like
you're beginning to hit your
stride as an auteur.
We have found success on
YouTube, if only by the metric
of we all left our day
jobs to just do this.
[MUSIC - THE GREGORY BROTHERS,
"WINNING"]
SARAH GREGORY: We're getting
into comedy, and we're doing
more writing.
ANDREW GREGORY: We're in the
middle of a development deal
with Comedy Central, which
is really cool.
EVAN GREGORY: That's pointless
to plug, since no one could
actually watch it right now.
If it was about to air on TV,
then we would be like plugging
it like silly.
[MUSIC - THE GREGORY BROTHERS,
"WINNING"]
EVAN GREGORY: But it is true
that a lot of doors have been
opened to us based on our
videos being seen a lot.
ANDREW GREGORY: Basically,
YouTube actually works.
That's a huge--
MICHAEL GREGORY: YouTube
actually works.
ANDREW GREGORY: It
MICHAEL GREGORY: It's
just so egalitarian.
It doesn't matter if it's a very
grainy footage of a bunny
making a weird sound or
whether it's very high
definition footage of Newt
Gingrich giving a speech that
he later regrets.
[MUSIC - THE GREGORY BROTHERS,
"GET MONEY, TURN GAY"]
ANDREW GREGORY: The desire of
the American workforce to not
be working while on the clock
is just really impressive.
[MUSIC - THE GREGORY BROTHERS,
"GET MONEY, TURN GAY"]
MICHAEL GREGORY: They
don't need solitaire
anymore, they have cats.
[MUSIC - THE GREGORY BROTHERS,
"GET MONEY, TURN GAY"]
[MUSIC PLAYING]