SAUL: You got any whiskey?
KIRBY STAR: Ah la la!
EDDY MORETTI: Hi, Roman.
ROMAN COPPOLA: Hey.
EDDY MORETTI: Thanks
for sitting down.
ROMAN COPPOLA: It's
my pleasure.
EDDY MORETTI: OK.
Where did the inspiration for
"Charles Swan III" come from?
ROMAN COPPOLA: It came
from a few places.
I had done "CQ," which is a
film I'm very proud of.
But the main character is very
internalized, and he's not a
very outgoing or
dynamic person.
Having done that, it would be
fun to do a contrasting kind
of character study, and just
have a character just balls
out, just showy and flashy and
full of verve and panache.
EDDY MORETTI: So Charles
is kind of--
he's just been dumped.
And he and the people around
him like Saul, the business
manager, and Jason's character,
they all represent
parts of a man's relationship
with women and
perspective on love.
ROMAN COPPOLA: Yeah.
EDDY MORETTI: And Saul's
character has this amazing
line, something like, desire
is as close as I'm going to
get to happiness.
SAUL: I want to be free to lay
whatever girl who might be
interested in an old, balding
business manager.
CHARLES SWAN III: You
ever stop wanting
the sexy young ones?
SAUL: Mm.
Desire is about as close to
happiness as I'm going to get.
EDDY MORETTI: How do you feel
about that perspective on love
and desire?
ROMAN COPPOLA: Well, the movie
doesn't have any answers or
definitive statements.
It's sort of an exploration
of those notions.
And it speaks to this thing of
there's a beautiful thing when
people come together
that is so joyous.
And there's the difficulty of
maintaining a relationship.
It's just a fact of life
from time immemorial.
IVANA: I can't believe this
is how you treat me!
[SOBBING]
EDDY MORETTI: Your first film,
"CQ," was set in the
'60s more or less.
And this film is set
in the '70s.
Do you draw inspiration
from those periods?
And what's wrong with today?
ROMAN COPPOLA: I am someone
who is nostalgic, I guess.
And a lot of the things that I'm
drawn to in my adult life
are things that I have a
connection with as a kid.
I think both "CQ" and this
recent film, "Charles Swan,"
they were both set in a time
that was very vibrant and very
vivid to me as a kid.
-Not these two turkeys again.
What did they do this time?
CHARLES SWAN III: Just
pour your phone
number into my coffee.
KIRBY STAR: Look at me.
Don't break eye contact.
It's bad luck.
CHARLES SWAN III: Well, if I
can't get your phone number,
then you should take mine.
-Go hot.
-Coordinates 3-2-niner.
-Prepare to fire.
-Roger.
Standing by.
-And fire!
ROMAN COPPOLA: Those impressions
that you have, at
least for me, really, really
resonate and are very
interesting.
And in terms of "Charles Swan,"
I wanted to tell a
story in this kind of visual
style from the mid-'70s
graphic design.
It's so playful.
It's fun.
It's sexy.
It's kind of carefree.
I don't think I'm too obsessed
in an unhealthy way, but I'm
just drawn to that.
EDDY MORETTI: It does feel like
a lot of these scenes
were heard before they were
written, at least.
ROMAN COPPOLA: Definitely.
EDDY MORETTI: Does music
really inspire you?
ROMAN COPPOLA: It does.
My tastes are kind of narrow in
that when I was preparing
this movie, I listened pretty
much exclusively, and that's
not an exaggeration, to
Liam Hayes' music.
EDDY MORETTI: Right.
ROMAN COPPOLA: That was the
soundtrack of that time.
When I heard "Whose Blues,"
which is the lead track on
"Fed," which appears in the
film, that had all the DNA of
this movie in that song.
EDDY MORETTI: Oh, wow.
ROMAN COPPOLA: Because it's
the sequence where he's
gathering all the stuff
up, the shoes,
putting them in the bag.
And there's this kind of
melancholy, very intimate
sound that the music
expresses.
Very internalized.
[MUSIC --
LIAM HAYES, "WHOSE BLUES"]
ROMAN COPPOLA: And then
there's a transition.
And in the movie, the garage
door opens, the car pulls out,
and it's like--
[MUSIC --
LIAM HAYES, "WHOSE BLUES"]
ROMAN COPPOLA: And that's the
other side of this movie.
And that song, to me--
when I heard that, I was like,
oh, I want to make the movie
for that song.
And I think my work doing music
videos probably relates
to that somehow.
And the movie is a bunch of
little episodes and little
moments and glimpses.
And I tried to tell a story in
a kind of kaleidoscopic way
that was more--
you had a very free-form style
that was able to go anywhere.
And the state of mind that you
can get into when you're in a
break-up situation can be very
confusing and distressing.
Your emotions can go-- you can
still be in love, you can hate
someone, and all these kind of
contrasting things that you're
sort of flailing around.
I thought it would be fun to
portray that state of mind in
the form of a movie.
-OK.
It looks like about 70% of your
brain, this whole region
here, is concerned pretty much
exclusively with sex.
You're using about 20% of what
remains on your desire for
power and money.
This small section here is
used to deal with bodily
functions and also manage
your affairs.
CHARLES SWAN III: Affairs?
ROMAN COPPOLA: I like diversity,
and so you want
to--and I think "CQ" has this,
maybe to a fault, where I like
black and white, I like
action scenes, I
like dramatic scenes.
I like so many things, I just
try to put it all in there.
And so I'm kind of like
that in my work.
I like the scene-- like the
Western scene has a lot of
cuts and B camera.
CHARLES SWAN III: Ivana,
can't we just talk?
[GROANING]
I'm hit.
ROMAN COPPOLA: And then another
scene just takes its
time to let a scene play.
[MACHINE BEEPING]
-Do-do, do-do.
CHARLES SWAN III: Go ahead
and unplug it.
I don't want to live.
EDDY MORETTI: The film is
visually gorgeous, and the
script is excellent.
The writing's great.
And you've been recognized
as a great writer.
Where did the written word come
for you in the history of
your career?
ROMAN COPPOLA: It's interesting,
because I don't
really see myself as a writer.
So when I've written things,
in the case of my film, I'm
really writing more
as a filmmaker.
Like, oh, I want to
make this movie.
And so I'm not really thinking
about the word.
In fact, a lot of times when I
was directing on the set, I
wasn't even referring to the
script, because I was
operating the camera.
I didn't even have it.
And then I would go home and
say, oh shit, I forgot to do
something, because
I wasn't paying
attention to the script.
So the script to me is not
precious or any kind of goal
unto itself.
EDDY MORETTI: Why
Charlie Sheen?
And how did that work out?
ROMAN COPPOLA: I wrote the
thing without thinking of
Charlie at all.
It was just something I was
working on and cooking up.
And I had a sense
of this guy--
a certain age, handsome, a
little getting into that next
chapter of life.
And then as I was just finishing
the writing, it so
happened that a mutual friend
put us together on the phone.
I had known Charlie as a boy
during "Apocalypse Now." We
were kids together.
And that friendship we had
over those months in the
Philippines, he was my pal.
He was my buddy.
And I think anyone who has a
friend from that age, it just
doesn't go away.
So I had that sense of
camaraderie with him, or
friendship.
And I realized that he would
be great for this movie.
So I approached him.
And this is all prior to the
very public kind of stuff.
And he was interested but a
little trepidatious in that it
was a challenging role, and he
had to do a lot of stuff--
dance, speak Spanish, do it.
EDDY MORETTI: He nails it.
ROMAN COPPOLA: Yeah.
And all that stuff.
So he was sort of
pushing back.
And during all that kind of
public stuff, I just never
wavered in my belief that he
would do a fantastic job.
And I think he does.
And I thought it was kind of
outrageous that there's this
kind of presumption about--
you read something in a tabloid
and sort of don't
understand.
So he's my friend, and so I
defend him in that regard.
But also, he's my colleague and
a very talented one and a
very loyal one.
So I feel that loyalty
towards him.
So anyway, I'm very proud
of his performance.
EDDY MORETTI: His farewell
speech to her is like the
oddest and strangest farewell
speech, because he's not
begging to be with her.
It's almost like he's nostalgic
about the idea of
their love and sad about the
fact that they won't be in
love anymore.
CHARLES SWAN III: You know,
Ivana, I was thinking.
It's kind of a sad thought.
I'll meet someone, and
it won't be you.
And I'll fall in love with her,
and I'll have kids and a
happy family.
And I won't love you
like this anymore.
And I'll miss it.
And I'll miss you.
EDDY MORETTI: Where did that
particular speech come from,
writing-wise?
ROMAN COPPOLA: I was involved
with a break-up that just kind
of was over.
And there was no scene
like that.
So in a way, it probably--
being honest, was a little bit
of a chance to write the scene
that never happened.
CHARLES SWAN III: Goodbye.
EDDY MORETTI: You're not dark.
Your world view on life and love
and the inevitability of
heartbreak and failure and
re-loving someone new seems to
be almost something that you
embrace and celebrate.
And ultimately, the film, it
ends with this amazing, I'm
going to throw the whole,
everything including the
kitchen sink at this last
scene, where all of the
characters are there.
And it's a celebration.
Everyone turns to the camera and
does that awesome farewell
to the audience.
CHARLES SWAN III: I'm Charlie
Sheen, and I played
Charles Swan III.
KIRBY STAR: I'm Jason
Schwartzman, and
I play Kirby Star!
IVANA: I'm Katheryn Winnick,
and I play Ivana.
SAUL: I'm Bill Murray.
I play Saul.
IZZY: I'm Patricia Arquette.
I play Izzy.
LIAM HAYES: I'm Liam Hayes,
and I wrote the music.
ROMAN COPPOLA: I'm glad
that you feel that
way about the ending.
I recognize the things that are
dark and unpleasant and
cause suffering at
the same time.
That's no reason to get down.
There's so many beautiful
things to celebrate.
[MUSIC PLAYING]