The first thing we are talking about today
is the civil war in Syria. Now, there are
some signs that the conflict might be changing
a bit. The fighting in the Middle Eastern
nation has been going on for 20 months now.
It started because some Syrians wanted changes
to their government. Like for their president
to step down. Different rebel groups have
been fighting against the government. This
weekend, they officially formed a single coalition,
and some analysts think that a unified opposition
can have a better chance for victory. It`s
been estimated that more than 35,000 people
have been killed since the Civil War started,
more than 400,000 have left their homes because
of the fighting. And that includes two brothers
that Arwa Damon met for her next report. Teachers,
this is a personal account about the war.
We suggest that you preview it. The younger
brother who is 11 years old, was wounded in
Iraq at attack. He lost one of his legs, that`s
when his older brother, who is 21, made a
promise that led them out of their home country.
Here is their story.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
ARWA DAMON, CNN CORRESPONDENT: Like many other
boys his age, 11-year old Abdurrahman (ph)
wanted to be a professional soccer player
when he grow up. But like so many others in
his homeland of Syria, the violence shattered
his dream.
OMAR, BROTHER: After he woke up as just, we
were just saying, I was crying. I cannot (ph)
control myself. He said please don`t cry.
If you love me, don`t cry.
DAMON: And that is when Omar made Abdurrahman
a promise, that he would walk again.
OMAR: He started to hang onto that idea. So
I`m going out, and he kept saying to me, when
are we - when are we leaving? Yeah, because
once - every time they are fighting, jets
come, he says, when are we leaving? We should
leave.
DAMON: Omar is now an expert at changing his
brother`s bandages. He started to save money
for a prosthetic, but realized that it was
going to take too much time. He began asking
around, and a group of visiting Egyptian doctors
told him about the Global Medical Relief Fund,
a small U.S. NGO, dedicated to helping children
badly injured in disaster and war zones.
Its founder Alyssa Montante (ph) was quick
to respond. But first, the brothers had to
get to Turkey. A car drove them as close to
the border as it could, the driver`s last
words "You are on your own now." Omar`s arms
were aching as he carried his brother and
their three bags across the muddy field. The
brothers eventually made their way to Ankara
in Turkey. But the boys don`t have passports.
Their visas to the U.S. were denied, and now
they are waiting to see if the State Department
will grant them humanitarian parole.
OMAR: The most important thing that he is
learning at this time, I think, it`s to be
aware of everything, I mean to grow up his
mind, I mean. He`s not a child anymore.
DAMON: Arwa Damon, CNN, Ankara.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: Next up, a natural disaster in Venice,
Italy. Severe flooding has led to the deaths
of several people there, 200 Italians have
reportedly been forced out of their homes.
Venice is in Northern Italy, it`s a major
seaport and a popular tourist destination.
It`s famous for its canals. So you might usually
think of people riding down the street it
boats, but this is anything but usual. Two
big weather systems combined together and
drenched the city. Earlier this week, 70 percent
of Venice was under water. It was the city`s
sixth highest water level in 140 years.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today`s first "Shoutout"
goes out to Mr. Toijala`s social studies classes
at Lakeland Union High School in Minocqua,
Wisconsin.
Which should be this part of the executive
branch of the U.S. government? You know what
to do, is it the Library of Congress, U.S.
Copyright Office, Cabinet or U.S. Supreme
Court? You`ve got three seconds, go!
The executive branch includes the cabinet,
advisors to the president. That`s your answer
and that`s your "Shoutout."
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: But you are going to expect to see some
changes in President Obama`s cabinet in the
days ahead. When a president is reelected.
Some of the advisors from the first term stay
on, others don`t. It`s up to the president
to decide who stays and who goes. Now, the
vice president is considered part of the cabinet,
but the other members are not elected. They
are nominated by the president and confirmed
by the Senate, including the vice president,
there are 16 members of the cabinet, you see
eight of those positions here, and here are
the remaining eight positions. One interesting
thing about the cabinet: the word "cabinet"
doesn`t actually appear in the U.S. Constitution.
But the concept does. Article II, Section
2 says "[the president] may require the opinion
in writing, of the principal Officer in each
of the executive departments, upon any Subject
relating to the Duties of their respective
Offices ..." It doesn`t say what departments
or how many of them there should be. The first
U.S. president had four cabinet members, more
were added over the years.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Time for a "Shoutout
Extra Credit." Ohms, amperes, coulombs are
associated with what? You know what to do?
Is it sound, electricity, pressure or temperature?
Put another three seconds on the clock and
go.
You might get a charge from knowing that these
options are all associated with electricity.
That`s your answer and that`s your "Shoutout
Extra Credit."
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: "Motor Trends" magazine names a car
of the year. And this year, for the first
time, the winner is all electric. It`s the
Tesla model S, and according to representatives
from the magazine, the voting wasn`t close.
The luxury car didn`t win just because it`s
electric. "Motor Trends" said it won in part
because of its performance. Zero to 60 in
four seconds, and because it`s one of the
most efficient cars ever tested, averaging
nearly 75 miles per gallon or the electric
equivalent of that. Only a couple of hundred
have been sold, they ain`t cheap, the Tesla
averages between $50,000 and $100,000.
Our next story today comes from Port St. Lucy,
Florida. High school student there has cerebral
palsy. It`s a medical disorder that effects
movement, posture or muscle tone. His fellow
students nominated him to the homecoming court.
But if you are worried we just spoiled the
ending of that story, no, we`ll let WPBF`s
Randy Gillenhal (ph) take it from here.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: It`s homecoming football
at Centennial High School. And watching from
the stands, sits senior Hakam Daley in his
wheelchair. Hakam has cerebral palsy. His
caretaker Chris, a football coach, helps him
get in and out of the car and carries his
book bag at school.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Going through a crowded
hallway can be tough.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Live hasn`t always been
easy for Hakam. Put up for adoption, he`s
been in and out of foster homes for most of
his life, but one thing he does have, is a
big smile and lots of friends who nominated
him to be homecoming king.
HAKAM DALEY, HIGH SCHOOL SENIOR: When I heard
the message, my -- I -- I had no words to
describe. I was so happy.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Go, Eagles!
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Kayla Donohue was the cheerleader,
and one of Hakam`s good friends. She secretly
rallied up the senior class and got them to
put his name on the homecoming court.
KAYLA DONOHUE, STUDENT: It just showed how
well as the group we can come together and
make such a special person have such a special
experience that he is going to remember for
the rest of his life.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Hakam lines up with the
other nominees: football stars and popular
kids. He`ll have to roll his wheelchair out
onto the field.
DALEY: I feel nervous, very nervous, it`s
going to be exciting. I know that God is with
me.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: But as they call his name,
he`s got a surprise for everybody in the crowd.
Hakam takes his first steps walking publicly
for the very first time. And when they announced
the winner, the homecoming king, the students
here have a surprise right back.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Homecoming king is Hakam.
AUDIENCE: (cheering)
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: He`s a great guy, he deserves
this more than anybody else I know. So it
just made me so proud.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Surrounded by cheerleaders
and flashing cameras, Hakam Daley is the most
popular kid at his high school.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: What a story! Today`s before we go,
segment is explosive. Now, like a lot of you
, I like a good firework show. The government
of Kuwait really likes a good firework show.
Hopefully, the country`s people do too, this
one went on for a while. 77,282 individual
fireworks. Yes, that is a new record and one
that cost $15 million to set. The country
was celebrating the 50th anniversary of its
constitution, obviously, that`s an event they
don`t take lightly, that extinguishes all
the time we have for today. We will be back
with more illuminating stories tomorrow. So
I hope to see you all then. Bye now.