[CHEERING]
MASARU OGASAWARA:
[SPEAKING JAPANESE]
In Japan, it's pretty common
when the customers come into
the restaurant [JAPANESE].
Something like that.
But I want to give the customer
a good impression, so
we just sing that only
one time together.
[SINGING IN JAPANESE]
MASARU OGASAWARA: It means
"Welcome to our restaurant."
Some people hate greetings
because it's so noisy, loud.
But it's pretty important.
When I come to Toronto, I'm
not sure about that we are
being so successful.
So at the beginning, I really
want to say, thank you so much
for coming to this
small restaurant.
I love greetings.
I love the shouting.
It's totally different from
the other Japanese
restaurants.
It's our style.
It's Guu style.
It's my style.
Hi.
This is Masaru Ogasawara.
I'm a operational manager
at the Guu Toronto.
And kind of the executive
chef too.
I don't eat sushi every
single day.
But I can go to Izakaya
every single day.
Izakaya is the Japanese
style pubs.
Every Japanese people, after
work, they go to the Izakaya
and having the beer.
Izakaya is the not so high-end
dining restaurant.
We don't serve any sushi.
But our tapas dishes
is pretty good.
Our price is a pretty low, but
some Japanese restaurants
overprice the dishes, is
so we are pretty honest
to serving our food.
I'm proud to be Japanese, so I
want to serve the real taste
Japanese dish for
Torontonians.
We serve a lot of dishes.
So something, they
don't like it.
Something, they love it.
So I think it's a good
experience for Izakaya dining.
-[SPEAKING JAPANESE]
-Nice order.
MASARU OGASAWARA: At our
restaurant, Kakimayo is that
most popular dish.
Kakimayo is the baked Pacific
oyster with white sauce,
spinach, mayo, with cheese
on the top too.
I serve the Kakimayo
on their shells.
Customers see those.
They like our presentation.
Everybody order the dishes.
Ikapiri is the deep fried squid
legs with spicy ketchup
sauce, with some hint of deep
friend garlic tips.
We just deep fry slightly and
we toss the [INAUDIBLE]
like a spicy ketchup.
[INAUDIBLE]
dishes [INAUDIBLE]
popular food.
Yeah.
I'm pretty proud of it.
-Here we go, guys.
[JAPANESE].
[CHEERING]
MASARU OGASAWARA:
I went out with
Natsuhiko, Kenta, and Yumeho.
Kenta has been working together
for three lives.
He's a nice manager.
Natsuhiko, I was working with
him almost seven years.
He's my best friend.
And Yumeho is the
administrator.
We are working with
[INAUDIBLE].
They are my friends.
Kind of my family.
KENTA: [CLEARS THROAT]
MASARU OGASAWARA: [INAUDIBLE].
Let's go to get spaghetti
now, OK?
-OK.
MASARU OGASAWARA: Yeah.
Let's go to Enoteca.
Enoteca sociale.
[SPEAKING JAPANESE]
[CHEERING]
NATSUHIKO: [SPEAKING JAPANESE]
KENTA: Yeah.
MASARU OGASAWARA: Actually, my
dad used to own the Italian
restaurant in Japan.
Japanese Italian food
is pretty good.
So, yeah.
Sometimes better than authentic
Italian food, I guess.
Yeah.
KENTA: [SPEAKING JAPANESE]
MASARU OGASAWARA: Here,
you go, sir.
KENTA: Thank you, sir.
MASARU OGASAWARA: Here
you go, lady.
Here you go, gentleman.
CHRIS JACKSON: How are
you guys doing?
Come on in.
Chris.
Great to see you guys again.
LUCA GATTI: Hi, I'm Luca
from Enoteca Sociale.
And we're just about to cook the
crew from Guu some bites.
You guys like everything?
Perfect.
We'll feed you all night.
MASARU OGASAWARA:
I need a beer.
You need a beer too?
LUCA GATTI: The cuisine in this
restaurant is Roman food
with a little Toronto flair.
What we do differently from a
lot of Italian restaurants in
the city is we use
not very many
ingredients in our dishes.
But the little ingredients that
we do use, we treat them
with extreme care so they all
stand out quite nice.
Treating the ingredients very
simply can be a challenge,
because you can't really hide
behind certain spices and
certain flavors.
You have to make sure the
ingredients that you source
are the best ingredients
as possible.
We're lucky here in Ontario.
We have some great
local farmers
that do amazing things.
So I always make sure to support
the local farmers that
are willing to go out
of their way and
grow an amazing product.
All right.
Main course time.
The main purpose of this
dish is to have a
lot of fun with it.
The chicken is completely
deboned except for the wings.
This way, it's super easy
for the customers to
tear right into it.
Just finish it with a knife
directly in the middle of it,
and she's done.
-[SPEAKING JAPANESE]
KENTA: Wow, it's so crispy.
MASARU OGASAWARA: Oh.
ALL: Wow.
MASARU OGASAWARA: So good.
-That's not an easy thing.
MASARU OGASAWARA:
[SPEAKING JAPANESE]
KENTA: [SPEAKING JAPANESE]
MASARU OGASAWARA:
[SPEAKING JAPANESE]
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
MASARU OGASAWARA: What's that?
LUCA GATTI: That's a sticky,
sticky [INAUDIBLE] for you
with house made vanilla
ice cream.
There you go, guys.
Enjoy
MASARU OGASAWARA: Looks good.
Thank you.
[LAUGHING]
MASARU OGASAWARA: It was such a
good time for us, having to
know Toronto more.
We just came to Toronto
like, three years ago.
So I'm not Torontonian yet.
Let's go to the next
place, OK?
Yeah.
Let's go.
It's time for drinks.
-[SPEAKING JAPANESE]
MASARU OGASAWARA: I want to be
a Torontonian in the future,
so I have to hang around
more with my friends.
-[SPEAKING JAPANESE]
[ALL LAUGHING]
MASARU OGASAWARA: I don't know
so many bars in Toronto, so my
friends told me the
secret bar.
[SPEAKING JAPANESE]
MASARU OGASAWARA: Hi there.
What's up?
-[INAUDIBLE]
MASARU OGASAWARA: Just
for four people.
-Yeah.
Sure
MASARU OGASAWARA: Thank you.
So I have never been
there before.
The place is pretty gorgeous.
I ideally want to
go back there.
Yeah.
Nice to meet you.
Masaru.
ROBIN KAUFMAN: Nice
to meet you.
MASARU OGASAWARA: The bartender,
he's nice guy.
So I trust him 100%.
He's moving pretty fast.
He put a lot of ingredients.
[SPEAKING JAPANESE]
ROBIN KAUFMAN: A pink sea salt
and a grapefruit twist.
NATSUHIKO: Pink sea salt.
MASARU OGASAWARA:
Pink sea salt.
Everybody loves his cocktails.
-[SPEAKING JAPANESE]
MASARU OGASAWARA: Thank
you so much.
[SPEAKING  JAPANESE]
NATSUHIKO: Woah.
MASARU OGASAWARA:
[SPEAKING JAPANESE]
I tried two of them.
Two of them was pretty good.
ROBIN KAUFMAN: Agave, lime
juice, orange bitters and a
twist of [INAUDIBLE].
MASARU OGASAWARA: Mmm.
ROBIN KAUFMAN: But
lots of alcohol.
Enjoy.
MASARU OGASAWARA: So good.
Let's go to munchies.
Let's go back to our
own restaurant, OK?
NATSUHIKO: All right.
Thank you, Robin.
MASARU OGASAWARA: Thank
you, Robin.
-Bye, Robin.
MASARU OGASAWARA:
Next up, man.
Go back to Guu Isakaya.
Let's go have some snacks.
I love you guys.
KENTA: Me too.
MASARU OGASAWARA: You too?
[LAUGHING]
Actually, I guess three
years ago, I just come
here alone, by myself.
And then Nats came here
one month later.
Three years ago,
just two of us.
But right now, over 100 people,
100 staff working at
the Guu restaurant at
the [INAUDIBLE].
[INAUDIBLE]
our workers at the Guu,
they don't have
the family in Canada.
So it means that we are
kind of family.
Guu family.
He's my brother.
He's already my brother.
Here's my sister.
I love you guys so much.
NATSUHIKO: Aw.
MASARU OGASAWARA: Please
don't leave me.
[SPEAKING JAPANESE]
MASARU OGASAWARA:
Go, go, go.
[INAUDIBLE].
Go!
Kenta, what are you going
to be making?
-Ochazuke.
MASARU OGASAWARA: Ochazuke?
-Yeah.
MASARU OGASAWARA:
What is that?
Ochazuke?
Yeah, it's kind of Japanese
kind of congee.
Chop the scallion with egg.
Oh, looks good, man.
I'm still hungry.
I'm still munchy.
Seeing The meal's
so good, Kenta.
So good.
Especially like, after drinking,
we need some of
those soup dishes.
[INAUDIBLE]
Kenta.
It's so good.
Do we eat this one a lot?
No [JAPANESE].
You have to eat more.
You did.
But even though we ate the
ochazuke, I feel some hangover.
[LAUGHS]
Kenta feels more hungover,
actually.
KENTA: [SINGING IN JAPANESE]