10 minutes.
It's going to be good.
I'm Steve Spangler, and I'm all
about making science fun.
For the last 20 years, I've
been teaching ways to turn
ordinary science experiments
into unforgettable learning
experiences.
I have an amazing team who will
do whatever it takes to
affect the way people
think about science.
And do that, I live
by one motto--
"Make it big, do it right,
give it class."
[MUSIC PLAYING]
STEVE MEER: This is Edge
of Space Sciences.
And today's flight is
flight number 175.
LARRY NOBLE: OK, we have a PVC
nozzle, which has been turned
on a lathe.
It's specially designed.
It fits in the balloon
and neck.
So when this bag starts lifting
off the ground, we
know we have sufficient helium
in the balloon to lift the
entire payload string to
the edge of space.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
MALE SPEAKER: Are you ready
to get started?
All right.
Well, we're going to bring him
up right now and introduce to
you Steve Spangler.
[CROWD CHEERING]
STEVE SPANGLER: Welcome,
everybody.
You know, meteorologists have
the coolest tools nowadays.
They've got all this tracking
device and everything else.
But believe it or not, a long
time ago, all they had was a
simple balloon.
So here is what a weather
balloon looks like.
Kids, you want one of these
for your birthday.
Just ask mom and
dad, all right?
[CHEERING]
STEVE SPANGLER: Say, mom and
dad, can I please have a
weather balloon and about
$500 of helium?
It'll be awesome, right?
The mere fact that I just
unrolled this means that they
probably can't launch this.
We'll only use it for teaching
purposes, because that balloon
is so delicate.
I told you early on that we
partnered up with Edge of
Space Science.
Kathy is on the field right now
with our team from Edge of
Space Science.
They're going to tell us a
little bit about the weather
balloon that we got permission
to launch today.
Kathy, tell us all about it.
KATHY SABINE: Hey, Steve.
I've got Steve Meer with
me, and he is with
Edge of Space Science.
And this is a one of a kind
event that you all are going
to be witnessing today,
isn't it?
STEVE MEER: First time we've
ever launched out of a stadium
like this with so many people
watching, so we're very
excited to be here.
KATHY SABINE: Is this
the biggest weather
balloon ever made?
STEVE MEER: No, this is
actually kind of a
small one for us.
This is what we call
1,200 grams.
And it's got about 230 feet of
helium in it when it leaves.
When it gets up to the edge of
space, it'll be about half the
size of a school bus.
KATHY SABINE: My colleagues
are holding pieces of this
weather balloon.
Steve, can you kind of help
me show the kids what
we have behind us?
STEVE MEER: Sure.
So the first thing we
have is a parachute.
And so when the balloon breaks,
it'll all come down
under the parachute.
It's about 5 feet in diameter.
Then we come down to this
payload right here, the green
and orange one.
This is the tracking and
telemetry receiver.
This sends us information about
where the balloon is so
we can find it.
And if we need to abort the
mission for some reason, we
can send it a radio signal,
and it'll cut the balloon
away, and it'll come back
under the parachute.
KATHY SABINE: We've got
Amelia down here.
What's she holding?
STEVE MEER: So Amelia's holding
what we call the batmobile.
The batmobile has two
cameras in it--
one that'll point down and
one that points up.
And then these long rods provide
inertia so it doesn't
spin too much under the thing.
So hopefully on the website
later today, you'll be able to
see some cool video.
KATHY SABINE: All right.
Marty Coniglio's holding
an orange box, Steve.
STEVE MEER: So this orange
box is another camera.
This camera is also
a high-def camera.
And it's going to take video
out to the side.
In fact, it's taping
us as we speak.
And then again, the inertia
rods to keep it
from spinning so much.
So Parker has probably the
most important job here,
because this is the main
tracking and relay beacon.
So this gives us the
latitude and the
longitude and the altitude.
And it also serves as a relay
point for all the trackers on
the ground to talk through, so
we know exactly where the
balloon is at all times.
KATHY SABINE: Now, Steve, I
understand you had to get
special permission, and we have
to get a special window
in sending this balloon
up today.
STEVE MEER: We very much want
to stay out of the way of
everything in the air
that could suck
it into their engines.
So we're on a kind of
a deadline here.
And it's about time.
KATHY SABINE: All right.
I'm going to let you
take over, then.
STEVE MEER: OK, let's go--
STEVE SPANGLER: Hey, Steve,
Kathy, there's two things.
Would you show us the flags
that are on there?
We have a Colorado
Rockies flag.
This is what we're going to
bring back to 9NEWS today,
hopefully for the
4 o'clock show.
Everybody on the weather team
signed that flag, so that
we've got to be able to
get that one back.
And then we put a scientist
on board.
Never before has this scientist
ever gone to the
edge of space.
Ladies and gentlemen, it's
Beaker right there in the
middle of the line.
[CHEERING]
STEVE SPANGLER: And you have to
know that there's tracking
devices on here.
And we're going to learn
something about it right now.
Let me introduce to you the
president of Edge of Space
Sciences organization.
It's Rob Wright.
Nice round of applause
for Rob.
All right, Rob, how do
you know where it's
going to come down?
I mean, what kind of tracking
do you have to let it know
where it's coming down?
ROB WRIGHT: The National Weather
Service compiles a lot
of information about the
upper-level winds.
And what we do is we gather that
information, we base that
information on how fast our
balloon is going up in the
air, and what level
it's going to hit
those directional winds.
And when we graph all that out,
it shows us a nice line
of where it's going to
go direction-wise.
STEVE SPANGLER: All right.
So here we go with
a prediction.
Ready?
You have to do a prediction for
a science hypothesis, but
this guy's on the line with
his organization.
I want you to look right
into that camera.
Tell us where it's going to
come down, because that's
where the chase team from 9NEWS
and the Spangler Effect,
we're all going.
ROB WRIGHT: Hm, thank.
All right.
STEVE SPANGLER: All right,
look right into the
camera and tell them.
ROB WRIGHT: We're going to land
just north of Wiggins, I
say about 10 miles.
STEVE SPANGLER: Wow.
All right?
So 10 miles north of Wiggins.
We've got a track team that's
starting their way there so
that they can see this
all the way through.
Nice round of applause
for Rob, would ya?
From Edge of Space Science.
Here's what had to happen.
In all seriousness, you don't
normally launch from the
middle of Denver.
The FAA has given us permission
for this window of
opportunity.
It means that air traffic right
now for jets has been
diverted around Denver for the
next 10 minutes so that you
can see a launch.
I think that's pretty cool.
So say thanks to the Edge
of Space Science people.
[CHEERING]
STEVE SPANGLER: Kathy and
Steve, are you ready?
STEVE MEER: OK.
We're good.
STEVE SPANGLER: We're going
to a countdown from 10.
Are you ready?
Here we go.
10 9, 8, 7, 6, 5, 4,
3, 2, 1, let go!
Here it goes.
There's Beaker.
I love it.
Look at him go.
Wow.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
SPEAKER: 93,715.
93,715 was max.
[INAUDIBLE].
ROB WRIGHT: Made it
up to 93,000 feet.
It's currently at 92,800 feet.
STEVE SPANGLER: I think
you can call off
the tracking team.
I think we see it in the sky.
So we'll just head
towards that.
SPEAKER: Oh, OK.
You're all good.
STEVE SPANGLER: See these
guys over here?
These are the mart guys.
We've just got a car
and a [INAUDIBLE].
That's all we have.
And some gummy bears
and some chips.
All right.
We're here.
I don't know where we are.
All I know is there's a whole
bunch of people, and it's
supposed to be in that
field somewhere.
And I understand the farmer's
not going to shoot us.
So we can climb over
the fence.
We're going to go find
the payload.
Beep, beep, beep, beep,
beep, beep.
All right, so what
does this do?
DOUG: This is a directional
antenna.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK.
DOUG: OK.
And so what it does is it
receives the signal really
well here and not
very well there.
So you can hear it, right?
STEVE SPANGLER: Right.
DOUG: So when it's pointed at
the payload, now I know which
way I'm walking.
If I point it over here, I'm
not walking that way.
STEVE SPANGLER: Oh,
how cool is that?
There it is.
Look at this.
It's from the end of the
Spangler Effect.
We have nothing.
No Spangler Effect anymore.
This is our flag.
S-- that's as much
as we have left.
While the logos may not have
lasted, look at this--
Beaker made the flight.
And he actually looks good.
Doesn't look like there's
any problem at all.
He made the flight.
Popped at 93,000 feet, and
he's back down again.
Edge of space--
I can hardly wait to see the
video of him just flopping
around up here like this.
This is really cool.
At 11 o'clock today,
we launched this
massive weather balloon.
We had a wonderful payload.
And here we are at
about 3 o'clock.
We finally have tracked it
15 miles north of Snyder.
The payload's intact.
Looks like we have our GoPro
cameras that will
grab all of our video.
Of course, the scientist
is here.
Beaker made it back.
I have no idea what
this guy saw.
And our flag from 9NEWS all
signed has come back as well.
Success--
this is the whole process,
the scientific process.
And it takes a team of really,
really smart people to teach
us how to do this.
I just want to get kids
excited about science.
It's fun.
Well, if you enjoyed this week's
episode, go ahead and
click the Subscribe button here,
and you'll be the first
to know when a brand new episode
appears each week.
This button right here will
show you some more cool
science experiments that we
do outside of the show.
This button right here will
take you to last week's
episode just in case
you missed it.
And if you want to see the stuff
that you shouldn't see--
that's the bloopers and the
outtakes-- well, just click
this one right over here.
And if you want to hear me
stop talking, through the
magic of television, just click
this button right here.
Go ahead.
Click it, and I'll stop.