It's growing up poor,
teaching yourself,
playing from the heart.
I don't think the
sound that was
created in here was planned.
DONNIE FRITZ: The key word
to me about Muscle
Shoals, it's a groove.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
IAN SVENONIUS: Here we are.
We're in Muscle Shoals,
Alabama.
Muscle Shoals is known
for a lot of things.
It's known for Reynolds Wrap.
And it's known for
being a swamp.
But it's mostly known
for American music.
The studios Muscle Shoals Sound
and Fame have produced,
you know, Wilson Pickett
records, Percy Sledge records,
Rolling Stones, and everything
up to Lynard Skynard, the
Osmond's, and the
group Alabama.
We wanted to explore what made
this region such a fertile
musical region.
We're talking to the people who
have worked here, who've
established Muscle Shoals,
put it on the map.
And we're going to talk to the
young people who are trying to
make their own way.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
IAN SVENONIUS: So much music now
is based on the music that
was made here.
What are the central ingredients
of that sound?
DOC DAILEY: When I think of the
Muscle Shoals sound, like,
from the old recording era, I
think more of an R&B feel.
But that's kind of what
I think about.
I think it's probably more
of a recording legacy.
You know, we had all the great
session players here and
studios back in the day--
white guys playing soul music.
RICK HALL: We all started
out as pickers.
We all had our own bands
and we all played gigs.
And the odds were against us.
We're recording in a town of
5,000 people where you only
have four good guitar players.
You only have three
good song writers.
It's a dry county.
You can't buy booze
or even beer here.
And the thing we have going
for us in spite of all of
that, we were cutting hit
records because we worked
harder, longer, and were more
driven, and felt the pressure
to be competitive
with the world.
DONNIE FRITZ: We were just
kids and learning.
But it was a young business.
It'd only been like three or
four years since Elvis and all
these guys from Memphis
started.
SCOTT BOYER: Yeah.
IAN SVENONIUS: First of all,
I want to asked how you got
started, how you got the job?
DAVID HOOD: Well, I started
hanging around Fame which was
just down the street
from the store.
I was working at my father's
tire store.
And my first union scale
recording session was a hit, a
gold record.
And I had to start learning
how to play
the base after that.
RICK HALL: We started out
with a little funky
demonstration studio.
We stapled egg cartons
on the walls.
And that was in Florence,
Alabama, that's where Fame got
its name, of course, Florence,
Alabama Music Enterprises.
DAVID HOOD: This is the
legendary Rick Hall who
produced Arthur Alexander and
the first hits that were from
around here.
He would find a song or an
artist and go in and record
that artist with that song.
And then he'd go shop
it and try to get it
played on the radio.
RICK HALL: I went on a tour.
We called it the Great
Vodka Tour.
And any black station that had
a tower, I'd take them a
bottle of vodka, or a bottle
of gin, or whatever.
Then we left town and we're
driving down the highway.
And we took a swig a vodka.
And said, hey.
They're playing our record.
IAN SVENONIUS: Yeah.
RICK HALL: It also started
out with black music.
IAN SVENONIUS: Yeah.
RICK HALL: And I want
to make that clear.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
IAN SVENONIUS: Wilson
Pickett came in.
This was after he was in
the Falcons and was--
DAVID HOOD: Yes.
They recorded "Midnight Hour"
at Stax in Memphis.
And it was their
first big hit.
And Jim Stewart, who owned Stax,
said, well, look, we're
not going to let you guys come
back in here and record
anymore stuff.
I want everything to be for
Stax that's recorded here.
And so Jerry Wexler started
looking for
another place to record.
And that's when he
brought Pickett.
What really got Muscle Shoals
music happening was Jerry
Wexler bringing Wilson
Pickett and then
later on, Aretha Franklin.
RICK HALL: It's a little strange
when you are a white
cracker from the State of
Alabama and you become known
as a producer who produced
only blacks acts.
So when you get to the Rolling
Stones, and Otis Redding, and
on and on, you start to
make your mark and
the word gets out.
Wait a minute?
What's going on down in Muscle
Shoals, Alabama?
[MUSIC PLAYING]
IAN SVENONIUS: What makes this
area so musical or whatever?
Or do you think it's anymore
musical than any other places?
DOC DAILEY: Oh, it's definitely
more musical than
other places.
IAN SVENONIUS: Is
it the water?
DOC DAILEY: That's what they
talk about, the singing river.
IAN SVENONIUS: Really?
The river?
That's interesting.
DOC DAILEY: Yes.
That's what they say.
There's supposedly an Indian
legend that there's a lady in
the river that sings.
And you can actually hear her.
IAN SVENONIUS: Does
she sing well?
DOC DAILEY: I've never
heard her.
[LAUGHTER]
RICK HALL: People started
migrating here from other
areas of the country, from
California, from Los Angeles,
from New Orleans,
and everywhere.
DAVID HOOD: I think that they
came here because they had
heard a record or something,
a hit that was recorded.
And they came because they
wanted a hit too.
RICK HALL: So it's not where
you're at, it's the
determination you have.
New York didn't want me and Los
Angeles didn't want me.
So it was either Muscle
Shoals, or nothing.
I just decided to plant myself
here and said, look,
I'm going to do it.
I don't care if it was Wilson
Pickett, or Clarence Carter,
or Aretha Franklin, or Mack
Davis, or Elvis Presley,
whoever it was, if I was
producing the record, the
record became my record.
And what you heard
on the record was
what I wanted to hear.
TRAVIS WAMMACK: Back then, we
were an exclusive for Fame.
And we were punching the
clock from 9:00 to
I think 5:00 everyday.
And you had to be busy.
You had to be writing or doing
something, you know.
IAN SVENONIUS: The Fame Rhythm
Section moved over to Muscle
Shoals, started their
own thing.
Did you see that as like a
threat to what you were doing
or were you excited that this
was becoming, like, growth of
a new music center?
RICK HALL: Well, I was certainly
proud of the fact
that I felt like a teacher
of a bunch of guys
that were making it.
And I was dumb enough not to
know that they were to almost
put me out of business.
DAVID HOOD: The Muscle Shoals
Rhythm Section were the rhythm
section at Fame before we left
and started Muscle Shoals
Sound Studios.
And so when we left, Rick was a
little pissed off at us for
leaving him.
But he went right ahead and cut
hit records without us.
RICK HALL: They was so good at
what they had done, and they
had learned so well that they
were kicking my ass.
DAVID HOOD: When Rick started
having his success as a
result, me, guys I work with,
all of the sudden people
thought that we were
experts almost.
And so you think, well,
maybe I am.
DONNIE FRITZ: Well, just one
thing led to another.
And it just build up
to what it became.
But it was those early days of
young people learning as we
went along, you know.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
JAMIE BARRIER: The Fame,
like, Ben Tanner
used to work in there.
And he let us come
in at night.
And we wrote songs and we
had killer microphones.
It recorded it perfect.
If I go to my brother's house,
this real sassy record player,
you can, like, hear the earth
being ripped apart, you know?
It's was just, like, I thought
it was awesome.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
JAMIE BARRIER: Florence,
Alabama is so--
it's such a corpse.
It's real easy to kick it.
Here it's a wasteland of
abandoned massive buildings.
The potential, if you want to
do it, is, like, unlimited.
It's just a matter of,
well, I'd rather sit
on the couch tonight.
And, like, watch television
or getting up and
doing it, you know.
That's like your main battle.
It's hard to make a living off
of art anywhere in any town--
anywhere.
I worked at Subway
for seven years.
I'm, like, I put this many hours
into this job and do it
for myself I can
make ends meet.
Yeah, this is the Black
Owl Trading Company
in Florence, Alabama.
I mean, we record bands.
We have touring bands.
And we do screen printing
in there.
And that's the printing wheel.
And this is our old
heat machine.
I listen to reggae records all
day long and screen print.
It's pretty cool.
It's been good.
We used to get a lot of
harassment from the police.
But we quit having a lot of the
high school bands play,
which sucks.
But most of those bands were,
like, hardcore or metal.
Like, we weren't
into the music.
But we would do it just to,
like, just to give them the
place to play.
The way I learned to do music is
like the DC discord style.
Putting out your own record,
record it yourself for cheap,
put out a zine, load
up the van.
I absolutely love that.
You know what I mean?
If that's what making it
is, that's what I want.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
DOC DAILEY: And there's a lot of
the older guys that'll tell
you a lot of good stories.
That's for sure.
But I think the industry has
just changed so much that
right now it's the wild west
as far as I can tell.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
JD MCCORKLE: In Florence there's
not really, like, a
music venue.
There's bars and they have,
like, a PA system set up.
A big hold back is a
law called 49/51.
You can't have more revenue
coming in from alcohol than
you do food.
It has to be in a
49-51% ratio.
JAMIE BARRIER: I'm like the only
guy that, I don't care
about that law.
All you got to do is clear
furniture out of the room.
You know what I'm saying?
The lousiest nights I ever
have are in bars anyway.
That's just me.
The best times I have are, like,
in those weird kind of
shows in the laundry room.
IAN SVENONIUS: So yeah, what's
it like being in a group here?
DOC DAILEY: Travel a
lot if you want to
really play, you know.
It's not your ideal place.
You know, bands try to tour
through here and we can't find
shows for them.
And people are really beating
down the door to come
through here now.
But you just can't fill the
place on a Monday night or
Tuesday night.
People would rather go and watch
someone cover a song by
a guy that might be playing
down the street,
you know, the original.
IAN SVENONIUS: Yeah,
yeah, yeah.
Yeah.
DAVID HOOD: We play on a
Wednesday night, which in the
South, that's church night.
I'm wondered sometimes if Elvis
Presley couldn't show up
and draw five people
or something.
It's just the people.
It's not a really big scene
around here like it is in a
larger city.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
DOC DAILEY: Everybody growing up
around here, their parents
know some session guys.
And everybody grew
up with guitar in
their house and pianos.
It's hard to find someone
down here that
doesn't play a guitar.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
IAN SVENONIUS: I think of the
Muscle Shoals thing as kind of
this meeting point of
all these songs.
DAVID HOOD: I think so, too.
And I think it was the players,
and engineers, and
people that created that
sound probably more
than anything else.
SCOTT BOYER: The heart and soul
that the people around
here play with has always been
my favorite thing about music
from the Shoals, you know.
DONNIE FRITZ: How this can
happen in a little bitty town
in North Alabama, you know.
SCOTT BOYER: Yeah.
I don't know whether to call it
magic or not, but there's
been something going
on here that
doesn't go on other places.
RICK HALL: The main thing is,
it's all about music.
And it all starts with a song.
And we can't forget that.
[APPLAUSE AND CHEERING]
MALE SPEAKER: One,
two, three, four.
[MUSIC PLAYING]