working and we're going to work...
we're going to work the back from the
floor.
Kind of brushing her off right now. Just
starting showing you some other things to do.
Just kind of get the contact going.
and of course when they're working the
back we're going to need to apply the oil.
So, we're going to start by
putting some oil on.
Here on the back you want enough oil to
be able to have a nice
slide
to your hands,
but not too much
you still want enough..
enough mobility to work the muscle.
And if you get too much of a slipperiness to it it's hard to maintain
that part of it
We're gonna go all the way down to the
to the hip
area here where there's
muscle attachments that come down from the
top and from the bottom up.
This is quite a place of stability through here.
It's been a
few weeks since I've
worked her back so i can feel that
there's been some
i guess from sitting room whatever it is
that she does carry there's a little
bit of tension
coming up through the back.
Now, because of it being positioned on the
floor things change
a little bit with the routine.
So, normally I start at the head with myself being at the head, but instead I'm just
gonna start
up in this area and
take my fingers on either side of the
vertebrae
and work down.
Ok, that way you could see where I am on
here,
which is right next to the vertebrae
working it downward...
I'm doing two right close in
and i'll tell you when you do this you
can feel
a lot of what's going on
down in the spine.
We're not taking a whole lot of pressure
just enough pressure to where the
muscle is letting you in and not enough
pressure to where it's pushing
back at you.
Then you move a little farther away from
the spine
and sometimes you'll see
it's not a straight line.
You have to go with where the tissue is. Always
follow the anatomy
and then down
on the edge
there's a lot of different structures
that come into play so just
keep on the focus
when working the erector spinae.
Ok, and then you can work it back up
... the neck is turned
so you can't really
get a real good straight shot at that
but if you're working a person from the floor you
can get that neck when you're doing neck
unwinding.
You might want to wait until the end to do
that part, have them turn over last.
And okay, now we're just going to start in with this
shoulder area.
And if you're on the floor it's a little bit trickier.
I'm gonna put one leg up...
get a little bit better leverage.
I'm leaning against my knee here.
And here what I'm going along is the trapezius muscle. Just
one little band at a time.
And moving down, now the scapula,
which is the shoulder blade
is right here.
Here's the scapula.
So you're gonna hit a bony surface, so
i'd just work up to that surface and
take it right to the edge
similar to
how i did the clavicle.
You're right on the edge of it, a little bit underneath... and following this
down the trapezius muscle coming to a point
down here.
Okay now starting at the point of the trapezius muscle,
trapezius is
somewhat of a "V" shape and then
up like a trapeze.
And then
pushing inward kind of
stroking his toward the
vertebrae
and there's a little bit of a circular motion, not much.
Now, here I'm going along the
scapula. Let me see if I can get a better sort of vision for you.
Here's the scapula
right here
you can go underneath it by picking
up the shoulder slightly
working underneath it.
If you feel a little snapping thing
or crunchy kind of feelings
that's been referred to as crepitus.
I don't know if people really know what
crepitus is...
It feels to me like it's just a really
tight tight area that's not getting a
lot of fluid in it.
And I have
been able to see crepitus change.
and then i'm going to be a flat on the scapula.
And just working the muscle
the weight of the muscle school you can
feel there kind of an upward
and they curve into the
arm socket.
so it's really about
knowing the anatomy and just following the anatomy
and then knowing the pressure not to be too
deep with the pressure and then along the side
here
getting along side the scapula here... the scapula is here. Coming down you're working right up
up
alongside of it and kind of up under
under it a little bit which can be
lifted under here
as well.
Where there is a little bit of a scapula pick up here
it's mostly
muscle through here.
Sometimes this is very ticklish
for people, so
you can usually get through
tickling..
ticklishness
if you go slowly into it.
And just work with it. Eventually, it won't have that tickly response.
Now, working all the way down
we're going to be doing upward
movements
along the hip.
Thumb, one right after the other.
It's moving ever so slightly
until you're all the way to the edge.
Running your thumbs down
and then you can
go up the vertebrae
on one side.
And again you can't get all the way to the
head so just take it as far as you can.
Lighten it up and kind of touch that area of the head.
And then we're going to do the
middle part of the
long muscle,
the erector spinae.
It's the muscle that holds the spine up
in an upright position.
It holds the spine erect.
It does need abdominal muscles to
support it properly
which is why core exercising is
important.
That's another reason why movement is so
important
and the free flow movement from what
i have done is
much more beneficial than
rigid movement because sometimes you can
unwind yourself
going through
more of a free type of movement than
something that's
in a straight line,
than the more linear type of movement. Now
I'm doing a cross fiber friction up the
erector muscle and
kinda getting underneath it. You kind of slip your finger underneath it and
kind of stretch it to the side, kind of pull it aside. It feels real good to have that done.
And up we go.
Okay and then
you can go to the other side
...
So, now on the second side I'm gonna just repeat it. I'm gonna go a little quicker at
this.
This stretching down. Remember we stretch down
and I start at the vertebrae.
Kind of follow the.. now here's the scapula.
Let's show you the scapula again
where we are.
There is the scapula.
right here it comes down to a little point.
It actually lifted up quite a bit.
And that's the scapula, so that's...
Now, you can get under it and shake it. I didn't really do much of that
on the other side, but
if you have your one hand underneath
and you're right on the shoulder
uh... not the socket, but above the shoulder toward more mid-line of the shoulder and just
rock it back and forth while you let your other hand slide up underneath
in the sub-scapularis area
you.. it's a very nice feeling to loosen up the scapulas that way.
So that's.. I didn't show much on that side, but I'll show more on this side and of course you can
apply it on both sides.
And then of course getting the muscles on top of the scapula
working them a little bit more.
You can work a little more petrissage, where you are
really moving that around
giving a little more range of motion to
uh... the muscles.
They don't really have range of motion but
they can move a little more on there when they are relaxed they can have a little more movement.
Okay
So then we can take it and bring
ourselves back up through the
trapezius muscle and this muscle is really.. on this side it's  much
much tighter
than the other side and i know that's
because of
different things that Corrina does
with her arms and posture so if
you are right dominant
the muscular feeling
much more work that the right side of her body takes on
so the muscles are a little
more developed as well as a little bit
tighter
you're never going to find true complete
symmetry in
most people. You might find it in one or two but usually people do have a
lack of symmetry somewhere in the body.
It's not a problem as long as it's not too
out of balance.
You do want to try to keep both sides of your body
as balanced as possible.
And then we are done with the hip again. Working that.
That's an important part to feel. Sometimes you will feel little bumpies
in there
and just be gentle when you go over them and work on them
don't put too much pressure. Don't try to beat them out just
work them
slowly,
on winding them,
spreading them
kind of thing
and then we just work up the back
and up again.
This is the same thing going up
the muscle is a
strap of muscle so you just want to go to three different
places on that muscle and another little
thing you can do.. I'm not doing the exact same thing on each side. I'm getting some different
ideas.
It's very different working from the
floor
than it is
from the table.
So, things change quite a bit.
But you still do want to keep some kind of
symmetry of what you're doing so you're
covering the same things.
In this video I'm just demonstrating
different things that you can do from the floor
and working that up again through the
vertebrae.
And then you can come back down the
umm...
with your fingers on each side
and doing a little
vertebral
vibration
which is very very nice.
Takes a little
practice though for the therapist to do
or the person working, so
how I started was I would just put the other hand on top
fingers on either side and just
rock it back and forth
to start with and then when you get
really you can also vibrate it down like this but that's a little
harder
to do. It takes a little bit more practice.
That's a very nice one as well
and then something that's real nice to end with
is if you just place the palm of your hand
across the spine and very slowly. You first...
you just interface with it, so you feel like there is this interfacing
and you will feel a bit of energy between
your hand
and the vertebrae if you're not pushing
too hard
so if your on them
even if your light just lighten it more, lighten it more
lighten it more
so that you're
feeling as if there's just a little tiny
paper-thin
area that you're touching the body
with
and then very slowly move
the hand up.
Now this
really turns out to be a little more
energetic
but oftentimes I feel
people's muscles relaxing out from under
my hands when I go real slowly
at this
there's something about this particular
thing that relaxes the muscles in a way
that i feel a tremendous amount of work
coming out of a lot of
backs
as they're
relaxing more
just like coming up
this uh... spine
very lightly
and more of an energetic kind of
move.
And you just take that all the way up
very slowly
And you can do this once or twice, I usually try to do things in threes and
then at the neck you''ll just
take your thumb around and
just complete it out, now because the neck is turned sideways
and because of the nature of this being
more energetic I'm
flattening the palm
and just completing it more energetically
up through the base of the skull
and then letting it come off.
And then you can go up just regular.
But that's a very very very nice
thing to do and then you can just wrap
the body
and we'll wrap it from this side and then pulling it down
stretching it that way.
Okay
there we have it.
A few more ideas for you if you are working from the floor. Thank you so much this is
Athena Jezik.