(male voice-over).
Live from the
Buzzard Auditorium
on the campus of
Eastern Illinois University,
it's "Issues and Attitudes".
(Dr. Janice Collins).
Good evening.
Good evening and welcome to
"Issues and Attitudes", a town
hall meeting just for you
to ask certain questions,
serious questions
about a serious topic.
I'm your host and moderator
tonight, Dr. Janice Collins.
Welcome to everyone,
thank you for coming.
The earthquake in Japan has
reminded us all that disaster
can strike us at any time
and in many ways that
we can hardly imagine.
And while we in central
Illinois may not be at risk
for a tsunami, we do share
one thing in common with
our friends in Japan.
We depend on nuclear power to
generate a substantial portion
of our electrical power.
And with the benefits
there comes risk.
According to the Nuclear
Energy Institute,
almost 48 percent of
Illinois' electricity
is generated by nuclear power.
Illinois is home to 10 active
nuclear power plants with
at least 4 with the same design
as the Fukushima plant that was
damaged by the
earthquake, tsunami,
and the power outage
that resulted.
Most of the plants operate
in the northern portion
of the state but on the
Clinton--as far as the
Clinton nuclear power plant
that's located less than 80
miles away from Charleston--it
must be noted that it's 80
miles away from Charleston
and it does not have the
same design as the
Fukushima plants.
We are here tonight to discuss
what are the realistic risks of
the radiation release from a
nuclear power plant in Illinois
and are we prepared to handle
the emergency that could result.
Joining me to help facilitate
this conversation and to help
answer your questions we are
joined by Mr. Jonathon Monken,
the Director of the Illinois
Emergency Management Agency,
and the IEMA is the agency
responsible for coordinating
the state's emergency
response for a
wide assortment of
potential situations.
Good evening and thank
you for joining us.
(Mr. Jonathon Monken).
Good evening, my pleasure,
thanks for having me.
(Dr. Collins).
Dr. Steven Daniels,
Chair of the Physics Department
and full professor at
Eastern Illinois University
who is well versed
in how nuclear power is
generated and the effects
that radiation can have on
humans and the environment.
We want to thank you
graciously for agreeing
to assist us at
the last minute.
Thank you so much.
(Dr. Steven Daniels).
Thank you.
(Dr. Collins).
Mr. Cameron Craig is a
well-known geology professor at
Eastern Illinois University who
is an expert on weather
and the environment.
Good evening and thank
you for joining us.
(Mr. Cameron Craig).
Good evening, thank you.
(Dr. Collins).
And then finally
we'd also like to welcome,
in our audience,
Mr. Pat Goodwin, the
Charleston Fire Chief
and the person responsible for
developing and overseeing
the city's emergency
response team.
Thank you, sir, for joining us.
Welcome to everyone,
welcome to us all.
Let's go ahead and get
started, this is a huge topic.
I guess I first want to ask,
the first question is, well,
I could ask are we safe but
to make sure that we have an
understanding, can you describe
just for the audience and
for the listeners and the
viewers how the Fukushima plant
was designed and how
the problem evolved
so we're all on the same page
before we begin the discussion.
(Mr. Monken).
Basically what we've seen--
and information is
limited unfortunately,
as far as how much detail
we're getting from Japan at
this point to find out exactly
what the significant damage
was, what the critical damage
was that ultimately caused it.
But as you mentioned,
there are some similarities
in the designs.
Really what you're looking at is
just the inner containment
facility is what's similar,
which is the GE Mark 1.
So the overall plant
itself, there are actually
some very significant
differences.
Ultimately, over the course of
the last 30 or 40 years that
these nuclear power plants in
Illinois have been operational,
there have been significant
upgrades that have been made
to the facilities, multiple
alterations and expansions
that have happened, that have
really changed the system here
that you would find in the
plants as compared to
what you saw in Japan.
But ultimately, based on the
information that we have
available, what we've
seen is that it
really wasn't the earthquake
that ultimately caused
the situation that they have
at the Fukushima plant.
It actually withstood that
earthquake fairly well.
Ultimately, the problem
was the following tsunami
as you mentioned before.
Now obviously the magnitude of
both instances, both emergencies
was far beyond anything
that they had planned on.
But ultimately what
the tsunami did was,
it knocked out the back-up
power supplies to the plant.
As ironic as this sounds,
a nuclear power plant
needs electricity in
order to function,
so it cannot run by itself.
So ultimately what happened is,
the system shut down by itself
as it's supposed to do.
The reactor shut itself
down in response to
the initial earthquake.
Ultimately what happened is when
the tsunami came in, a 40-foot
tidal wave basically wiped out
their back-up diesel generators.
And that's something that all
the power plants in the state of
Illinois have, you have a
redundant back-up diesel
generating system to
make sure that the plant
never fully loses power.
Well in this case it actually
knocked out all of the
backup power and, arguably
just as significant,
it knocked out all of
the backup fuel.
Whereas in Illinois we
have all of our fuel,
basically the diesel fuel
is stored underground,
there it was stored
above ground.
And when the tsunami came in it
knocked out the generators and
all of the fuel, and they
were ultimately unable to
restore power directly to the
plant in order to get the
coolant flowing through what's
called the spent fuel pool.
So after the draining rods are
used for power generation
they are removed
from the core and
placed in what is called
a spent fuel pool.
That's incredibly hot.
And as it happens--and the
really, really unfortunate
timing is--those spent fuel rods
had just been removed within
months of this disaster
happening, and those
take somewhere between 12
and 15 years to cool down.
So they'd only been out
for a couple of months.
If you can't get coolant
through the spent fuel pool,
that's actually where we're
getting radiation from,
not the inner core, but
these spent rods that
were already used
for electricity.
(Dr. Collins).
Okay, and thank you
for that explanation.
Spinning off of just the last
part of the radiation, talk a
little bit about the effects of
the radiation, containing the
radiation, because at the very
beginning when it first happened
the reports were we don't
have to worry about it.
We're all the way in Illinois,
but we're starting to see, we've
already seen the creeping in of
certain elements of radiation in
our water and our plants
and our air supply.
Can you tell me a little bit
about radiation, what that
means, but also what does that
mean for our environment and
for the humans here.
(Dr. Daniels).
Radiation, the deal is that
we get radiation all the time.
It's coming from cosmic rays
it's coming from background in
the soil, it's coming
from everywhere.
We get a little bit all the time
but nonetheless, the sense is
that any radiation is still
going to harm the body.
It has some damage to cells
almost no matter what.
So the question is how
much can you take.
When we're talking about
these trace amounts we're
talking about amounts that are
lower than the background,
or basically around
the background level.
We're not talking about
amounts that are going
to be significantly dangerous.
However, if the coolant
and the waste fuel,
that stuff is very hot, and it
is hot enough that it would
be a significant danger
to a person right there.
But here we are halfway around
the world, it's going to be much
dilute by the time it
gets here, if any of it.
Even though it has gotten here
it's at much lower levels,
so the danger to humans at this
point is probably pretty low,
at least in Illinois.
(Dr. Collins).
Okay, so that's good.
Yes, professor.
(Mr. Craig).
When you talk about the
atmospheric concepts
here that, you know,
Fukushima creates its own heat
and so it creates its
own low pressure.
And so all that radiation gets
into the upper atmosphere and
is carried by the jet
stream over North America.
Over time it is dispersed so
it's not as concentrated,
so it does eventually
fall from the sky.
It's like, you know, we have
dust storms in the Great Plains.
The dust gets picked up,
carried by the jet stream, and
lands here in the Midwest, so
it is the same kind of thing,
but it's minute, it's
very traceable.
(Mr. Monken).
And if I may add to that,
ultimately what we
found is obviously,
we have detection systems
throughout the state of
Illinois that ultimately,
that's how we identify
and we take these samples
on a regular basis,
whether there is a
disaster globally or not.
In this particular case what
we've identified as an isotope
is iodine 131.
And iodine 131 is not, obviously
in large quantities or heavy
doses or things like that,
it's 10 percent gamma and
gamma is what you need
to be concerned with.
Ultimately that's where you have
the biggest risk involved, but
what we have detected here--as
you mentioned we've detected it
on grass, we've detected it in
the air--what we have detected
is more than 2,000 times
below the level at which
there would be any
amount of concern.
And ultimately as an isotope it
only has a half-life of 8 days
which is good because it's
not really persistent,
it's something that will
go away very quickly.
(Dr. Collins).
Okay, so then are you
saying that we don't, because
it's so small and it's diluted
in its travel, we don't have to
worry about these
levels rising?
(Mr. Monken).
Certainly not,
unless there was actually
an additional source of
radiation or something
more significant.
All radiological disasters
from this perspective are
rated on a scale
of one to seven.
So what we've seen at Fukushima
is something similar to what we
saw at Three Mile Island
three decades ago,
which is a level five.
Something bigger than that is
something like Chernobyl,
which is a level seven, where
actually the inner core of a
nuclear power plant
is exposed, which
is fortunately, thankfully,
not what we saw at Fukushima.
(Mr. Craig).
And distance is a big deal, too.
When you consider Chernobyl
that's half a world away,
you know, as far as the jet
stream is concerned, because of
the westerly winds, everything
comes from the west,
and so it gets
diluted over time.
(Dr. Collins).
Okay, okay, great.
That's really interesting
and an absolute easy way
to understand it.
I wish we had it during our news
breaks and our news packages.
We could all put that in one
one-and-a-half-minute
package there.
Let's, you know, we're dealing
with the unknown.
I want to move a little bit
toward "what if", okay.
I want to understand and ask how
do you prepare for the unknown,
because things are happening and
occurring that are not natural.
Whether it's man-made,
whether it's just nature,
it's unpredictable.
So I want to know and ask, how
do you prepare for the unknown.
Are we prepared for
even an earthquake?
If something were to
happen with our plants,
since we have so many,
are we still protected?
Let's say the unknown, the
unthinkable, the impossible
actually happens, as we
continue to see globally.
So I'll ask the first question.
Are we prepared for the unknown,
and if so, how are we prepared?
(Mr. Monken).
I guess what you
probably did with
that comment is
you completely encapsulated
what my entire job entails.
[panel laughter].
So thank you for doing an
excellent job of really
articulating what it is that I
actually am charged to do for
the state of Illinois,
which is prepare for
those types of things that
you can't prepare for.
So really the mandate
for IEMA is to cover,
it's just like FEMA, I mean,
that's what we do at the
state level is we cover,
as we describe it, everything
from terrorists to tornadoes
and everything in between,
so any type of disaster,
whether it's man-made
or it's natural.
So as you mentioned, there are
many things that can actually
threaten the state of Illinois,
and something that people don't
often realize is that we
actually sit very close
to a major fault line.
In this case, it's
the New Madrid fault
and the Wabash fault.
And as it happens, for the last
two-and-a-half years, we've
been preparing for what's called
a national level exercise.
It's run by FEMA and at this
point, includes nine states
participating in it and we're
actually simulating a
7.7-magnitude earthquake on
the New Madrid fault line.
(Dr. Collins).
And this is 250 miles
away, that's where we are?
(Mr. Monken).
That's correct.
Yeah, we're about 250 miles
away from the epicenter.
New Madrid, Missouri is
technically the center of mass,
if you will, for that
particular fault line.
And those are the types of
things that we have to consider.
Now, as you mentioned
before, there's actually
6 nuclear power plants with 11
active reactors, as far as the
nuclear power generation
in the state of Illinois.
The closest one to a fault line
is actually the one that you
mentioned which is Clinton,
which is about 250 miles
from that fault line.
And that's obviously why
we're exercising the way
we're exercising now is to
simulate what would be the
impact of something like that.
Ultimately what we have to do is
we have to try and come up with
the most unexpected things
that you can imagine,
I mean, that's really
what we're designed for.
So that's why we continue to
plan, rehearse, drill, and we
try and look at things that
either haven't happened before
or, when you look at the case
of the New Madrid fault line,
we're actually on the 200th
anniversary of the last
major earthquake on
that fault line,
which was in 1811 and 1812, and
it was powerful enough that
it actually reversed the flow
of the Mississippi River and
rang church bells in Boston.
That's a pretty significant
earthquake if you're looking at
the impact and obviously I won't
get too far into the science
because I'm not the
expert--as you mentioned,
there's no "Dr." at the
beginning of my name.
[panel laughter].
But Japan in one respect was
fortunate simply because you're
really talking about whether or
not this magnitude of earthquake
travels through rock versus
what you see here in Illinois,
which is much looser soil.
(Dr. Collins).
That can be a challenge,
right, that could be
one of the challenges.
(Mr. Monken).
Right, and I would say that
we are as prepared as
we could possibly be
for those types of events.
We actually drill every six
months at each of the power
plants, so we rotate through
between the six power plants.
So basically, what it comes out
to is every six months we're
doing a nuclear response
exercise at one of those plants.
(Dr. Collins).
Okay.
(Mr. Craig).
You said 7 magnitude
on the Richter scale.
Why is that the
magic number?
(Mr. Monken).
Ultimately, that was the
closest estimate that we had of
what happened in 1811 and 1812,
is they estimated between
a 7 and an 8 magnitude
on the Richter scale,
which obviously
is only one dimension of
what you have to consider
when you look at an earthquake.
What you're really looking for
is the g-force of the actual
impact of the earthquake,
or the ground speed.
And that's what was so
significant in Japan,
why it resulted in such a
humongous tsunami is that
the g-forces created by
the earthquake were
orders of magnitude beyond
anything in recorded history.
So that's ultimately what
created the biggest problem.
So you can have a 7.7-magnitude
earthquake that actually doesn't
do a whole lot of damage, or you
can actually have something
like you did in New Zealand
where you have a 6.2-magnitude
earthquake that does horrific
damage because that was
the second most powerful
earthquake in recorded history.
(Mr. Craig).
So in preparation for a 9,
would there be any, you know,
because there's been some
concern that some of
the reactors here in
the United States are
at 7, but we have 9.
(Dr. Daniels).
It's my understanding that
Fukushima was designed for 8,
and all the Japanese ones are
designed for 8 because that
was the biggest recorded,
so they were covered according
to what might have worked,
but then something comes along
that's even bigger than that.
(Mr. Monken).
That's exactly right.
They were designed to withstand
a magnitude of 8.0 earthquake
and a 30-foot tsunami,
so what they got was
a 42-foot tsunami and
a 9.0 earthquake.
(Dr. Daniels).
An important point is that
the difference between 8
and 9 is a factor of 10.
One's 10 times stronger.
The 9 is 10 times stronger
than the 8, so that's a lot.
(Mr. Craig).
And on top of that, the
tsunami--33-foot--they
had prepared.
Over 30 years they built walls
to protect themselves from
tsunamis but because of the
tectonics, that whole coast line
dropped 3 meters and so it
allowed water to spill over.
(Dr. Collins).
Okay, so even though--and I want
to ask this question, then I'm
going to ask Chief Goodwin
if he will, to step to the
mic because I did want
to ask you--or have the mic
brought to him--but I did want
to ask about the local response
in the next question or so.
So am I to understand that
because we're not under the
threat of a tsunami, even though
we have reactors that have the
same design, that we really
don't have the same concern
because we really don't have to
worry about the tsunami?
So we can handle an earthquake,
but because the tsunami that you
said was really what pushed it
over, we're still okay, we're
going to be okay?
(Mr. Monken).
I would tell you no matter what,
I mean, I can tell you that each
of the plants here in Illinois
were designed basically
to withstand the threats
that are most
significant to them.
So earthquakes is certainly
one, but obviously some of
the distance involved
helps insulate those,
and there's a reason why Clinton
is the farthest south that any
nuclear power plant was
constructed in Illinois.
But obviously, we have other
things to be concerned with.
We have floods as an
issue--there's a plant in
Quad Cities right along
the Mississippi River.
Tornadoes are
obviously a concern.
In Virginia, we just saw that
within the last 36 hours they
actually had a tornado wipe out
power to that power plant and
they're operating on backup
diesel generators right now.
So you bring up a good point
that even if we don't have
an earthquake of the magnitude,
or let's say we do but we don't
have a tsunami threat, I
think what this has taught
a lot of people, especially
in my line of work, is that
you absolutely have to
kind of throw out the book
on what you think is the
worst-case scenario.
So in my conversations with the
governor, talking about this
because this is obviously
something significant
in his mind, is you
actually have to start
playing the "what if"
game, just like you said.
What if there was an earthquake
and a flood and a tornado,
and they all happened
simultaneously?
Those are the types of
preparations that you have to
make in order to insure that all
those plants are safe and that
we have a response that
fits those types of needs.
(Dr. Collins).
Okay, and let's move to then,
from the state to the local.
Chief Goodwin, I
wanted to ask you,
let's say the unthinkable
does happen.
What do we have in place?
Do we have procedures and
processes in place so that
we're ready for the unknown
because you also, sir, have to
prepare for the unknown
as well, correct?
We've prepared as
much as we can.
You say the unknown,
what is the unknown?
We can prepare for
what we can do.
We've got the NIMS
training throughout
the city and throughout
the county, which is
the National Incident Management
System, so we're all on the
same page on the incident.
Charleston and Coles County and
most of Illinois belongs to a
MABAS organization--that's a
Mutual Aid Box Alarm System.
It started in northern Illinois
years ago, it's covered the
state of Illinois, Missouri,
Wisconsin, and Indiana now.
It's the same system that
when we went to New Orleans,
when they needed help,
Illinois sent a task force
down--that's through MABAS.
Charleston here, mainly composed
of Charleston firefighters and
Mattoon firefighters, have the
technical rescue teams and
also the HAZMAT team
for this part of Illinois.
We cover a huge part of
southern and central Illinois.
With that, we are prepared
as much as we can,
we have some highly
trained individuals.
You talk about the dispense of
the technical rescue and HAZMAT.
All Charleston fire and
police vehicles have
radiation detectors in them
that are going any time the
vehicles are on the streets.
You talk about the radiation,
there's two to four millirads in
the background just driving
around towns now so it's out
there but we're prepared
as much as we can be.
With the MABAS though,
we can call in resources.
We have potentially four
states at our hand.
With one phone call I can
request whatever resources
I need, with one phone call they
will deploy them and have them
here within a few hours.
(Dr. Collins).
Great, great answer.
Good, very complete answer.
What I'd like to do is take a
short break.
We've talked a little bit about
how it all started in Japan.
There are other areas that we
may have to consider that are
a little closer to us than Japan
and the effects of if something
happened there--would we
really be ready for all of this?
So I want to take a short break
and we'll be right back with
questions from the audience and
continue our discussion on the
nuclear reaction and
safety of Illinois.
[no dialogue].
(Dr. Collins).
Okay, great, thank you so much.
Welcome back, welcome
back, everyone.
I wanted to ask one
quick question
before we go to the audience.
When we talk about nuclear
safety, I wanted to ask
how is it outlined basically?
Can you tell us a little bit
more about that, please?
(Mr. Monken).
Sure, yeah, the Illinois
Department of Nuclear Safety
has actually been around
for several decades and it
was beefed up significantly
following the Three Mile Island
incident because those types
of questions, the questions
that we're asking right now,
those were questions that
were raised at that time.
And there was a significant
investment made by the state of
Illinois to really develop what
is now really the premier
nuclear safety program
in the country.
So we have several systems
that are actually
unique to Illinois that no
one else actually has.
One of them is called a
resident inspector program,
where our department actually
has third-party independent
radiological inspectors that
actually work at each of these
plants, so we actually have
a triple redundant system.
The company that
owns them, Exelon,
they have their own
resident inspectors.
The NRC, the Nuclear Regulatory
Commission, they have them.
What's unique to Illinois is we
actually have a third tier of
inspectors that actually
work for IEMA and
conduct inspections
at those plants.
We also have something called
the remote monitoring system.
We take data from more than a
thousand sensors in each of the
plants, and we can actually
collect and interpret all that
data in real time, so we will
actually know if there is an
incident inside the plant before
the company actually knows it.
And all of this is centered
around a program called REAC,
which is actual physical
location in the
State Emergency Operations
Center that collects all this
data 24 hours a day, 7 days
a week in real time and
actually represents it
graphically for our personnel.
And the last thing is an actual
part of the remote monitoring
system, is gaseous
detectors that are
actually surrounding each
of the power plants.
So, at a radius of 2 miles
around each of the plants,
they collect--24 hours
a day, 7 days a week--
they collect data so we can
actually tell if there is a
radiological leak or
a leak of radiation
from any of the plants.
We can tell which direction it's
going, how significant it is,
what types of isotopes
we're looking at,
which is very unique.
There's no one else in the
country that has that.
(Dr. Collins).
Great points, good to know.
And also I think it's important
for us to mention that Exelon is
the owner of these
reactors, correct?
(Mr. Monken).
That's right.
(Dr. Collins).
All of them, so I think that's
important in your
narrative there.
Thank you so much.
We're going to take a
question from the audience,
or a statement.
Sir if you would step
straight to the mic and pull
the mic down a little bit so we
can hear what you're saying.
(Dr. Alan Baharlou).
I can hold it.
(Dr. Collins).
Okay.
[laughter].
(Dr. Baharlou).
I'm Alan Baharlou.
I'm a geochemist.
First of all, yes, New Madrid
moved 200 years ago and
because of that the tension
is building around it.
[unclear audio].
And it just moved like
the San Andreas fault.
And that would be
devastating--shock, travel.
It's there at any moment.
Two, all this nuclear waste that
we have has, Steve knows,
plutonium and plutonium radiates
alpha and alpha penetrates
anything--you need only one
atom.
It goes through the body, goes
through the membrane of the
cell, goes through the nucleus
and damages the regulatory gene.
The regulatory gene goes berserk
and that's what cancer is.
It's not like solar radiation,
radiation from your lamp.
Steve knows, highly
penetrative.
You only need one atom.
You cannot see it, cannot taste
it, you cannot smell it.
And all of this nuclear waste,
which is now stored at the
nuclear power plant in the pool,
we don't know where to take it,
where to dispose of it.
There is a place, Yucca
Mountain, supposedly.
If that ever happens, all this
waste will travel to American
highways from east to west.
All you need is one accident.
So, in other words and the
fourth, an airplane could crash
in any of these nuclear power
plants, so I don't want us
to be pessimistic but I'll
finish my statement.
When Einstein discovered
E=MC2--that statement- he said,
the unleashed power of the
atom has changed everything
except our way of thinking,
thus we drift toward
unparalleled catastrophe.
(Dr. Collins).
Okay, thank you sir.
So, Dr. Daniels, you were
called out by name,
we're going to let
you respond to that.
(Dr. Daniels).
Okay, well first of all,
there are three main types of
radiation that we consider.
There's alpha, beta and gamma.
The alpha particle is basically
helium with high energy.
The beta particle is
basically an electron
and the gamma particle is a
photon with high energy.
The alpha particles
will basically be
stopped by a piece of paper.
Because they are so
massive and so large,
they're very easy to stop.
However, if they get inside your
body, they get stopped by your
body and, therefore, they can do
significant damage that way.
So it's when you ingest
alpha emitters that
that can have the
most damage there.
The beta emitters can go a few
centimeters, a few tenths of a
centimeter, so they would
go inside your skin.
They can actually start to harm
your body, but it's the gammas
that actually go through you and
can impact deep tissue.
(Dr. Collins).
Now, okay, I'm not a physicist
or any of those "icists."
I just wanted to ask though, is
that one of the reasons why our
first point of attack or defense
was in the air, in the water
supply, in the plants--things
that we can ingest--is that why
we've been looking and
monitoring those particular
elements every six
months, as you say?
(Mr. Monken).
Absolutely, I mean, really,
that's the best way to tell
and a lot of times--and you
can certainly expand on this
quite a bit--there can be
significant inconsistencies
just in areas of the state.
Northern Illinois versus
southern Illinois--it's a large
geographic area.
So when we take air samples
from northern Illinois and air
samples from southern Illinois
or grass samples--and
we also do milk, we do fish, we
do water, all of these types of
things--we test them
on a regular basis.
This is something we did long
before anything happened to
Japan, but that's why you
have to test all areas
of the state--because there are
a lot of environmental factors
that could actually cause
certain things to go to certain
places where you
wouldn't see it.
But that's exactly why we
test it because that's
the air you breathe, it's
the grass you walk on,
it's the fish that you eat, it's
the milk that you drink--those
are the types of things that
we need to be able to check.
(Dr. Collins).
Okay, well, let me ask this.
From an environmental
point of view then,
because one of the things that
we haven't been able to control,
one of the things that we
haven't been able to say is
"this is what we have in place
and this is how we can measure".
Are the elements that can
actually drive up these levels,
such as the wind, the
water, the river--I mean,
maybe I'm looking at it a
little differently, but I'm
looking at it critically now
and I have this question.
Since we're sitting on the
Mahomet Aquifer, right--the
largest body of fresh water in
the country--could any release
reach that source of water and
what would be the effect?
(Mr. Craig).
Yeah, if you have a meltdown
it's definitely going to
cause a serious issue.
If you have a leak in the
suppression containment then it
gets into the water system and
then we're all drinking it,
but it's not just us that
is going to be impacted,
it's going to be all vegetation
from the ground level.
Atmospherically, you have
heat that's billowing should
a disaster occur and then what
happens is--we're
surrounded by winds.
(Dr. Collins).
Absolutely, with flat.
(Mr. Craig).
And so all that radiation
would transfer quickly,
especially with storms.
And so radiation gets
into the clouds, you
have a huge storm system
that naturally occurs,
but then it starts dumping the
precipitation back into the soil
and so contaminating it doubly.
(Dr. Collins).
So that's my concern.
When you say that, and we're
looking at a flat terrain here,
and we can't really
control the wind.
So then, therefore, I'm looking
at, if that's the case, are we
prepared or do we have filters
in place of some sort or how are
we preparing or
protecting ourselves?
(Mr. Craig).
The big question is
how much education has there
been to educate the community.
That's the big question.
I haven't heard anything,
I didn't even know that
Illinois had nuclear power
plants until Fukushima.
(Dr. Collins).
Really?
(Mr. Craig).
Yeah.
(Dr. Collins).
Okay, well I guess it may
not come up in regular
conversation until
something like that happens.
(Mr. Craig).
You're right until something
actually does
happen, so.
(Dr. Collins).
Yeah but that's good to
know though, it's
important to know.
(Mr. Monken).
I think you're absolutely right.
What it comes down to is
education and we run into this,
it doesn't matter what
type of natural disaster
you're talking about.
Whether you're talking about
earthquakes--which people in
Illinois typically just don't
understand, or how to respond
to them or what they would do
in the case of an earthquake.
The last thing you should do
in an earthquake is run out of
a building because you have
to worry about the debris.
That's something that a lot
of people just don't realize
because people in Illinois
aren't used to it.
But really I think the
educational piece is very
important to understand what
types of radiation there are,
how it is naturally occurring.
You know radiation is released
from the soil when it rains--you
know those types of things--but
I think the last part of it is
information is the most critical
piece of what you're looking at.
So if you look at a plant like
Fukushima, they don't have a
system of sensors that are
actually around each of the
plants like we do in Illinois.
That is, we designed that system
specifically because of what
happened at Three Mile Island.
They didn't know how much
radiation, they didn't know
which way it was headed,
they didn't know, you know,
they could look at the wind
currents but they didn't
understand exactly where
the radiation was going.
And that's why we have the
system of sensors that we do
and that's why we take the
samples that we do on a regular
basis to make sure if we
can detect the patterns,
we can detect the intensity
level, the saturation level,
all those types of things,
which I think is the
most important part of
responding to them.
(Dr. Collins).
Okay, thank you,
Dr. Daniels you wanted to say.
(Dr. Daniels).
If I can give a little
perspective here, I was
about 80 miles downwind
of Three Mile Island
when it happened.
And the first thing we did was
we put a detector out the
window--a radiation
detector--and over
the next three days the detector
went from background level
to twice background
level and stayed there
for about two weeks.
Now how much danger is that,
just to put it in perspective,
walking past the radiology
department in a hospital was
more radiation than that--
(Dr. Collins).
Oh wow.
(Dr. Daniels).
--for the average person
and taking airplane flights you
get more radiation than that.
(Dr. Collins).
Something else to
worry about now, airplane
flights, oh my goodness.
(Dr. Daniels).
Well the point is
that the background
level is fairly low and
when something as major as
Three Mile Island happens
even at that, it wasn't
really contaminating all
the atmosphere,
everywhere, all the time.
It was a fairly major event but
at the same level it didn't
really impact even 80 miles
away, it didn't change the
way people had to
worry about radiation.
[Dr. Baharlou].
Could you please explain
half-life and dose limit,
[unclear audio].
(Dr. Collins).
So he's asking about half-life
for the listeners and
the viewers out there
in the audience and
the TV audience.
He wants you to explain, Dr.
Daniels, half-life.
(Dr. Daniels).
Okay, so a radioactive
material will give off so much
radiation as in terms of a rate,
maybe some number
of decays per second.
Over time that material will
disappear, if you start with
say a thousand grams
of something and
it decays well it's
going away and it takes
exactly one-half life for half
of that material to go away.
But the interesting thing is
that then now you have 500 grams
of the material and you
wait one-half life
for that to go away too.
It doesn't all go away
in two half lives,
it only half goes away
at any given half life.
(Dr. Baharlou).
Would you give an example
of half-life of Uranium?
(Dr. Daniels).
Half-life of Uranium--
I believe it's in the
millions of years.
(Dr. Baharlou).
404.5 million years so again,
as I said, unleashed power of
the atom has changed everything.
This is not like any other
thing, it's there for eternity
so we have to be
concerned about that
and would you also
speak about dose limit.
(Dr. Collins).
Okay and what I'm
going to ask you, sir, those
are great questions and
I'd love for everyone
to make sure that they
see you, so if you have a string
of questions please feel free to
go to the microphone
so we can have that.
(Dr. Collins).
Okay very good,
I just wanted to make sure,
very good thank you, okay.
Dr. Daniels, please.
(Dr. Daniels).
Well this is probably
more like John's specialty
than mine but again
we measure how much
radiation you take in and
the more radiation you get, the
more dangerous it's going to be.
But typically the IEMA and the
NRC have set limits of how much
the public can get and how much
workers in the industry can get
and various levels
that that can be and
they're in the
millirem I believe.
(Mr. Monken).
That's right.
(Dr. Daniels).
So I'll let you talk about that.
(Mr. Monken).
Absolutely, yeah so
the maximum as I
mentioned before
when we had detected the iodine
131, which is what everybody
has been picking up as a result
of the disaster in Fukushima.
Ultimately we're looking at it
is in the millirem so we're at
the point, what we're detecting
right now is one-two thousandth
of the level that would be
necessary to actually have
an impact on public health
in any way, shape or form.
It would actually cross the
threshold of the dose level
that the Nuclear Regulatory
Commission would say
you have something to
be concerned about.
So certainly not to be
taken lightly by any
stretch of the imagination.
That being said it's
also important from an
educational perspective to
understand the orders in
magnitude of where we are.
It took us about two-and-a-half
days of testing one sample to
actually detect the iodine 131
and you'll probably vouch for
the fact that you would never
put a sample in something
for two-and-a-half
days to find it.
If it's not detectable
and something you can do
within a few hours it's
something that's at such a
low level that you wouldn't
even be concerned about.
(Dr. Collins).
Okay great, thank you gentlemen.
We have a question from the
audience, ma'am if you would
just step right up to the mic,
there you go.
(Female Speaker).
Yes, my name is [unclear audio]
I'm an EIU staff and a current
mother of two EIU students.
I got a question
regarding to information
that I did receive
a while back,
The gentleman here said
that the radiation is
dissipated as it travels from
Japan to the United States.
What about the merchandise that
is coming currently from Japan
such as vehicles, which I've
been told that plutonium could
get into the vehicles and
the seats and everywhere
and that stays there
for a very long time.
We have a lot of merchandise
coming currently from Japan.
How do you prevent all that
merchandise and how does
corporate America deal
with that loss of money.
What are they doing with that
merchandise supposed to
arrive in the United States and
it's already contaminated with
plutonium and other chemicals?
(Dr. Collins).
That's a great question,
it is global isn't it.
We have to look at things
outside of state lines.
(Mr. Craig).
One of the things is that,
I buy rice, big bags of rice
and I've been concerned.
The first thing that comes
to mind is how long ago
was this harvested and how long
did it sit in a warehouse and
I'm guessing that it's okay
but the production of rice is
probably going to be a
critical factor in the future
especially with other
vegetation that we eat.
But as far as products
are concerned I--
(Mr. Monken).
Yeah, I can tell you
ultimately and this
is actually kind of
interesting because there
is a reason why all hazards
cover everything from
man-made to natural.
In the post 9/11 world we
actually have a much better
developed system of radiation
detection as it applies
to customs and
border protection.
So if you're looking at Japan
as an example, they actually
import 60 percent of all the
food the country consumes,
simply because there's
not enough space and
there's 123 million people.
So the exports from a
food perspective are
actually extremely low from
Japan as it stands anyway.
That being said, ultimately
there are some very, very
significant systems in place to
detect even small trace amounts
of radiation on any passenger
plane, on any cargo plane,
on any ship, or any vehicle
that crosses an
international border.
So nothing can really get into
the United States even with
minor trace levels of radiation
without being detected
immediately upon arrival.
So people don't actually even
realize that planes that you're
flying, if someone flies from
Narita to O'Hare, you don't even
realize that that plane
is actually scanned
for trace levels of radiation
as it comes into the airport.
(Dr. Collins).
Even with that though
there has to be or
there appears even
when the news first broke
we saw a dip in the Dow
and so there's going to be an
economic effect globally.
Are we prepared for
something like that?
Let's say it's great, we can
detect certain small levels on
planes and modes
of transportation,
but it can have an effect in the
way that our state is right now,
it could really affect us harder
and deeper and more intensely
than an earthquake if
we're not very careful.
What do you think
about that assessment?
(Mr. Monken).
I think it's a
fantastic question simply
because right now even the
estimated economic impact,
it's the world's third largest
economy and you're talking
about an estimated
economic impact of at
least $330 billion.
That's just what Japan needs
in order to recover, that says
nothing to the fact about the
total net value lost in world
markets and things like
that when you have
that type of impact.
You can even strike it close
to home--Caterpillar,
which is headquartered
in Peoria, Illinois,
has five facilities in Japan.
The question is whether or not
they can export what they
continue to export because
that's actually the regional hub
for Southeast Asia.
So the economic impact I think
is going to be measured in a
dollar figure that I don't
think any of us could possibly
wrap our minds around.
(Dr. Collins).
Ok, yeah.
Well, okay, thank you
for those responses.
I wanted to ask a question about
the reactors--I wanted to come
back to that for just a moment.
Because I believe in the
research it shows that they're
close to 25 years
old, approximately.
(Mr. Monken).
Actually, older.
(Dr. Collins).
Older, okay.
So my question, my
follow-up question is
have there been measures
for improvement as far as
they're getting a little old?
Have we started taking steps
to improve the defense?
(Mr. Monken).
Yes, as I mentioned before
briefly but I'll kind of
expand on right now,
you mentioned the similarities
between the designs of some of
the plants that we have here
in Illinois--specifically,
you're talking about the two
reactors located at the Dresden
plant and two reactors located
at the Quad Cities plant.
And the similarities
are really most direct
when you're looking at the
inner containment facility,
which is the GE mark-1.
The rest of the facility has
changed drastically over the
course of time,
because ultimately
significant improvements
have been made
to each of those facilities
as technology has increased.
So as the technology continues
to get better, which
to a certain extent, we're kind
of in the middle of what some
people would refer to as a
nuclear renaissance as far as
the efficiency of nuclear power,
the capability to produce it--
all those types of things--but
there hasn't been a nuclear
power plant commission in the
United States in over 20 years.
So what you're looking at is
plants like the Quad Cities
and Dresden--Dresden just
celebrated 40 years this year,
so it's a 40-year-old
reactor right now.
That being said, over that
span of time, significant
improvements have been made to
the facility to make it more
efficient, to make it better at
what it does, to make it safer
--all of those things have
been done over time.
Now the Nuclear Regulatory
Commission had basically,
when they commissioned a
new plant they gave them
a license for 40 years.
That 40-year license expired
at Dresden this last year
and was renewed for
an additional 20.
The expectation is that
the Quad Cities will get
an additional 20 years
next year, but really
the youngest power plant in the
state of Illinois is at Clinton.
So, as it happens, the
closest one to us is the
youngest facility in the state
of Illinois, but youngest is
kind of a dubious honor
at this point because
really you're talking
it's over 30 years old.
So really you're
looking at a lot of plants now
that have been on line for
several decades.
(Dr. Collins).
We've talked to Chief Goodwin
and asked his
opinion and all the
wonderful measures that he has
in place that appear to be,
that can be effective if
something were to happen.
Let's make it even simpler.
If we were to have to power
down a plant, are we prepared
for that and what measures
would have to be in place
--are they in place if we just
needed to quickly power down?
We see a lot of travesties that
have occurred because the
safety elements didn't
take on because they
weren't able to power
down very quickly.
So where are we in that
since we have 10?
Where are we as far as the
powering down element?
(Mr. Monken).
Sure, yeah, ultimately
the plants themselves are
actually designed to respond
to an emergency by shutting
down, but saying it's
shutting down is definitely not
flipping the light switch.
[panel laughter].
I can tell you that it is
significantly more complicated
than that process.
(Dr. Collins).
And how long of a process is it?
(Mr. Monken).
It's a very long process really
in a lot of respects because
what you're looking at is
you've got whether or not it's
actually actively functioning
as a reactor as versus
whether or not there's still
radioactivity coming from
the inner core and the
spent fuel pool and that's
kind of two different things.
So if you look at the earthquake
that we had in Illinois
just a couple years ago, which
was a very low magnitude,
that actually caused the plants
to shut down simply because if
there's seismic activity
in the immediate area,
they'll automatically
shut down right away.
But what we're talking about
too is, you know like I said,
it's not like flipping
off the light switch.
The other thing you need to be
concerned with--and this is what
they saw in Japan--is, as I
mentioned before, when you pull
that spent nuclear fuel out,
which is something that was
raised, and very, very
accurately raised
by the audience, when you pull
those spent fuel rods out,
they're still radioactive
--very, very radioactive.
And it takes a significant
amount of time for them to
ultimately cool down where
the atomic reactions are not
happening with the frequency
or at the rate that puts out
the heat and radioactivity that
actually causes the problem.
That takes 12 to 15 years.
(Dr. Collins).
Wow.
(Mr. Monken).
To put it in perspective,
when they have a
spent fuel pool
ultimately before it can
actually be transferred to
a low-level nuclear waste
site, it takes about
12 to 15 years cooling
down in water in order
to actually slow down the
reactions enough that you're
taking away the harmful reaction
that you're getting.
The first step though is making
sure that the plant itself is
shut down because there are
other issues that you can run
into if the plant is still fully
functioning at the time.
(Mr. Craig).
How much of the shut down
process is automated
versus human-controlled?
(Mr. Monken).
Really, the human element
is kind of the redundant
element to it.
Most of it happens
automatically,
and it's designed that
way to make sure that
under no circumstances is it
possible for--it cannot solely
rely on human error as
you accurately identified.
The point is there is an
automatic system that's in place
and then there's multiple
redundant human systems
that are in place.
So you have the individuals who
are physically at the plant,
then you also have agencies like
IEMA who are actually monitoring
those plants, that
actually have the
capability to do
something as well.
So ultimately it's, you know, if
you look at an aircraft, the
only way you can actually
fly an aircraft is that it
actually has to have six
redundant autopilot systems
on a commercial
passenger airliner.
We take a very similar model.
You have to have multiple layers
of redundant capability to
shut down those plants
to make sure that
under no circumstances
could it basically run wild.
(Dr. Collins).
Okay, what I would like to do
is have Dr. Daniels make his
comment then we're going to
take a short break to come back
with some closing statements.
And I had one more serious
question to ask before we have
the closing statements,
but Dr. Daniels--
(Dr. Daniels).
I have another question.
Going forward you have new fuel
coming in all the time and it
takes 15 years to get
rid of a piece of fuel.
How much do they change over
the rods and, therefore,
how much is piling up?
(Mr. Monken).
A lot of it just depends on,
right now what you're looking at
is, you're looking at roughly
over 9,000 pounds of low-level
nuclear waste that's
being stored somewhere in
the state of Illinois
right now at each
of the plants.
So, it's distributed between
each of the plants,
even if it's inactive like
the Zion plant that's
on the north shore of Chicago.
So it's a great question because
that's a national concern.
That's not just an
Illinois concern,
that's a national concern
because ultimately you
cannot use those nuclear
rods into perpetuity.
At some point, the level of
the reaction is going to drop
to the point where it's not
efficient as a power source.
So it's a constant process and
it varies from plant to plant
as far as how long they
run one set of rods
and then how long it's been
since they've been taken out.
I mean, at any one of
the plants you can see
the spent nuclear fuel
pools contain rods that
have been out for varying
lengths of time.
The real question that has to be
asked at a national level is the
Yucca Mountain facility
was supposed to be the
solution for low-level
nuclear waste nationally.
Unfortunately, it's not open, so
what's happening now is each of
the states are
continuing to store low-level
nuclear waste on site at
each of the power plants.
That's what Illinois
has to do right now,
until a permanent
solution is reached.
(Dr. Collins).
Okay.
[audience member speaking].
(Dr. Collins).
Hold that thought one moment.
Hold that one moment, sir.
We're going to come back
with that question.
We're going to take
a quick break with
"Issues and Attitudes:
Nuclear Safety in Illinois".
[no dialogue].
(Dr. Collins).
Great, welcome back to
"Issues and Attitudes:
Nuclear Safety in Illinois".
The final question before we
have our closing statements--
I wanted to ask
about the "what if".
We've been talking
a lot hypothetically
because we have to.
We're fortunate that we haven't
had some of the tragedies that
have occurred in
other countries.
But I want to ask about, we've
talked about the environment,
we've talked about air supply,
we've talked about water supply.
What about the actual evacuation
of movement of people?
And what do they do,
and what can they do?
Not necessarily what can they
do on an individual basis,
but do we have plans and
measures in place to actually
get the word out to the
people, educate the audience
and actually get
them out safely?
(Mr. Monken).
I would say
the closer you live to
a nuclear power plant,
the more you actually know
about this process because
there's actually a requirement
placed on how much information
we need to put out,
and it's actually a
shared responsibility
with Exelon who,
as you mentioned earlier,
owns the plants.
But ultimately, I think
you're hitting on
the critical piece here which
is there are a lot of factors
that we cannot control
that we have to monitor.
The human element is
the only factor that
we actually can control, which
is the evacuation plans
and everything else that we have
because it can be probably
even more easily
carried by people
than it can be by, really,
natural elements.
(Mr. Craig).
You know, most of the residents
here In Illinois are not used
to evacuation on mass.
If I can ask the audience
a simple question,
how many of you know
what to do in a tornado?
Okay, how many of you know
what to do in an earthquake?
What do you know how to
do for a nuclear reaction?
Yeah, one.
But, that was my key point.
We all know about tornadoes but
a nuclear reaction or disaster,
we don't.
(Dr. Collins).
Okay, that is a different--
(Male speaker)
[unclear audio].
(Dr. Collins).
Okay, sir, I'm sorry.
If you'd like to ask--we can't
hear you at all because you're
in the audience--If you'd like
to stand to the microphone,
if we have time we'll get
to that before we close.
That would be fine, but
we just can't hear you.
(Mr. Monken).
That evacuation plan is actually
what we spend the most amount
of time actually practicing and
the Chief hit the nail
on the head, which is,
through the mutual aid systems
that we have throughout
the state of Illinois, that's
exactly what we drill.
It's what we would
need to do because
you can only educate
the public so much.
At a certain point it actually
takes the involvement of your
public safety entities, whether
it's fire, EMT, or police.
Those are the people that we
train on a regular basis
and we have very, very
detailed evacuation plans for
every area of the state.
(Dr. Collins).
Okay, thank you.
And let's move to
Chief Goodwin,
who has offered some really
valuable information.
I wanted him to have a moment
to make a closing statement,
sir, before we move on.
(Mr. Goodwin).
We have a specialized team
for this part of the state
as far as HAZMAT and
technical rescue but as
far as HAZMAT, if we do
get into the nuclear side of
it, my second phone call is
going to be to IEMA
for their assistance
because they're the
experts in it.
But as far as the evacuation,
we talked about that.
Charleston, we have an
evacuation plan in place,
so we try to prepare
for everything.
What's going to
happen, who knows,
but we try to prepare for
the worst that we know of.
(Dr. Collins).
Thank you, sir.
Dr. Daniels.
(Dr. Daniels).
Radiation is something that
you can't see, you can't
smell, you can't feel,
but the key to
protecting yourself and
understanding the whole thing is
learning and education and we
need to understand, have the
masses understand, exactly what
the dangers are and
exactly how bad they are
or how not so bad they are.
(Dr. Collins).
Okay, great, thank you.
Professor Craig.
(Mr. Craig).
Nuclear plants are necessary and
they're very efficient--more
efficient than wind power and
solar panels and so it's
necessary, but again education
and understanding what to do
in the event of a
situation is needed.
(Dr. Collins).
Great and Mr. Monken.
(Mr. Monken).
Really what I'd like to
really just kind of say about
what we have in Illinois is
that I think the citizens of
Illinois should be extremely
proud of the system that
we actually have here.
In many respects, it's unique
nationally and unique globally.
Representatives from 22
countries, including Japan,
have been to
Illinois to see how
we do our nuclear
safety program.
While it is really the best in
the country-- incredibly well
developed and really better than
anything anyone else has--
we always have to
see these disasters
as an opportunity to
improve our plans.
There's never a finish line.
There's never a point at which
we are done making our plans--
how we're going to evacuate
people, what types of
scenarios we need to be prepared
for--and that's what these types
of events, that's why they're
so important to us is that
we have to take a look
back, rework our plans and
make sure that everything is
as accurate as it can be.
(Dr. Collins).
Okay, that's wonderful.
I wanted to also add to the
education aspect--it is
important to be educated and I'm
so happy, happy and pleased
to see everyone here who wanted
to come out and ask questions
and hear some of the answers
and actually continue
and participate
in the dialogue.
I also want to mention
April 28, right?
IEMA is having the Great
Central U.S. Shakeout--
getting prepared
for earthquakes.
That's going to be going on.
60,000 Illinois residents
have already registered to
participate in an
earthquake drill,
so we're really
pleased about that.
So that's one part of
getting educated.
Another part of getting educated
is having guests such as
Professor Craig--thank you
so much for being here;
Mr. Monken--thank
you so much;
Dr. Daniels and Chief Goodwin,
thank you so much
for being here.
[unclear audio].
(Dr. Collins).
You're watching "Issues
and Attitudes", thank you
everyone, for coming,
"Nuclear Safety in Illinois".
Have a great evening
and goodnight.
♪ [music playing--
no dialogue] ♪♪.