Life is just unreal, just
the way it works.
That's exactly what I'm thinking
about every time I
cut something open.
When I start taking stuff out,
I look at the inner workings.
And I'm just amazed by it.
I think it's so beautiful.
A carrot!
A carrot?
Ugh.
[UPBEAT MUSIC]
Fashion and taxidermy were two
very separate things that I
was really interested in.
The love of anatomy got me into
fashion, because I saw
clothes as wearable sculptures
that people could wear to
either express themselves or
turn into a different person.
This to me is what fashion is.
It's not really trends.
It's just more about crazy
self-expression and becoming
who you want to be.
I think the first mouse that I
did that came out well, I was
so excited.
I was just, like, shit.
I'm going to do this
so much more now.
I'm going to fucking do it.
I'm going to do it.
Whenever I go hiking, I've
always got a little cooler and
Tupperware and Ziploc
bags and gloves.
And more often than not I'll
find something on a hike.
And then when it's the season
to trap, I'll go trapping.
So a friend called me, and told
me about a lot of pests
that were on his property, and
just gave me the invitation to
come up there and trap.
We set the traps really early in
the morning, before all the
animals wake up.
I always had this connection to
the outdoors and science,
and always seen the two
as one and the same.
We got something.
I think it's actually even
better for women to hunt.
Because I think--
not to be stereotypical
or sexist--
but I think women are
more intuitive.
They're just a little quieter.
So this guy is small, so
he'll fall right out.
We have stuff to prove,
but there's kind
of nothing to prove.
Chippy.
With guys it's like, I got
to prove that I can
shoot this big gun.
And I got to prove I can catch,
like, 45,000 minks this
season, and all this stuff.
Whereas a women would just be
like, I caught a chipmunk and
I'm going to put a cherry in its
hands and make taxidermy
out of it and just be happy.
I grew up in Miami, Florida.
My parents were pretty
conservative.
My mom was a biology teacher,
which had a huge influence on
my love of nature, my
love of anatomy.
My dad was an accountant.
And I think he always wanted
me to be a doctor, or a
lawyer, or something.
And when he found out I wanted
to be artist, he was like,
well you better be really
fucking good.
Or else I'll have said
I told you so.
My family is pretty traditional
Hindu in that
they're nonviolent.
They don't hunt.
They don't kill animals.
And they're vegetarian.
Whoo!
Fuck.
Oh, so we caught a woodchuck.
He's dead.
And he's going to turn
into a piece of art.
So pumped.
Such an adrenaline rush.
We have to go to the general
store and get a bigger cooler.
Yeah, I'm OK with killing
something and eating it.
And I'm actually feeling better
about killing something
and making art out of
it and eating it.
Because it seems so
much more natural.
It seems so much more real.
And it's super satisfying when
you finally do get to get your
hands on something
and take it down.
It's a huge accomplishment.
So end of the trapping day, and
I got one big one, which
is the biggest thing I'll
have mounted, ever.
And one little one, which
is still pretty awesome,
because he's cute.
What I'm going to do right now
is skin him, take his guts
out, and all that.
So what I'm going to do is just
make a cut right down the
back, all the way down here,
and just take it apart.
I did a lot of dissection
in high school.
And I was always the kid who
was so ready to dissect
whatever it was.
And this time was dissecting
a mouse.
I had never dissected
a mouse before.
I was always really curious
about their anatomy and stuff.
Because you hear that
thing about, their
bones are like rubber.
They just squeeze
into whatever.
And I read a bit about
taxidermy.
I got some books.
And then got an X-acto knife
and some Borax, and
just went at it.
I cut this open and was so
amazed by its tiny bones, the
little world inside its body.
It's just fucking fantastic.
He's heavy, oh my god.
Putting him down.
There's that tension and
excitement there.
But then there's also the thing,
the feeling of, I've
got to keep my hands steady
so I don't fuck this up.
It's deeply reflective when
you cut something open.
You see all of its
inner workings.
And every time I'm just amazed
by this anatomy, and seeing
the structure of an animal.
You're dealing with death.
And death is not pretty.
It's not fun.
There's nothing really
light-hearted about it.
What it does is take something
that's ended, for whatever
reason, and give it a second
life, give it a new
way to enjoy it.
I think it's a lot more healthy
if we remember it.
Not to dwell on it, but to
remember and to memorialize,
and to face the reality that is
that things and people and
stuff dies.
[MUSIC PLAYING]