RICHARD FREEMAN: We're here on
the banks of the River Lea,
where something has been
attacking and killing full
grown Canada geese, which
are big, powerful birds.
It's interesting that at the
time of the Olympics, we have
an Olympic monster
in the river.
Richard.
MIKE WELLS: Hello, Richard,
Mike Wells.
Hi.
RICHARD FREEMAN: Nice
to meet you.
MIKE WELLS: Thanks for coming
to discuss the great Olympic
monster of the River Lea.
RICHARD FREEMAN: Yes,
well, fascinating.
So what was it you
saw, and when?
MIKE WELLS: We were sat on the
back deck of my boat, and
there were a group
of Canada geese.
And there was one goose
a little bit
separated from the group.
Suddenly, this goose
went vertically
down into the water.
Me and Steve kind of looked at
each other in amazement, and
we were kind of looking to
see if it reappeared.
RICHARD FREEMAN: There have
been a number of theories
about what the creature in the
River Lea is, some of them
more fanciful than others.
Some people have suggested
crocodiles and alligators.
These are tropical reptiles.
And they are formidable beasts,
they can kill full
grown tigers, but they're not
going to be found in the
middle of London.
It's far too cold.
Same with pythons.
I investigated a very similar
case in Lancashire in 2002.
Witnesses there said there was
something the size of a car
swimming around, attacking
full grown swans.
And I was saying to my
colleague, there is no way a
big predator can live
in this lake.
There's no way.
Half an hour later, I was eating
my words, because I saw
it come to the surface no more
than six feet away from me,
and it was an 8 foot
long wels catfish.
[THREATENING MEOW-LIKE ROAR]
RICHARD FREEMAN: Whether it is
still on this stretch of the
river or not, I don't know.
The river starts in Luton, and
it ends up in the Thames, so
the creature could
be anywhere.
It's a tradition to give
monsters names.
The Loch Ness monster
is called Nessie.
The monster of Loch Morag
is called Morag.
The monster of Lake Okanagan
in Canada is Ogopogo.
So I would like to take this
opportunity to officially call
the Olympic monster of the
River Lea Old Greg.
[VAGUELY THREATENING MOO]
FEMALE SPEAKER: So another
fallacy of the Green Games is
what's actually happening to
places like Leyton Marshes,
which is, if you've ever been
there, it's one of those parts
of London that makes you think
that you're not actually in
London, if you ignore
the pile up.
So when they started digging all
this green land up, they
suddenly went, oh, there's a
reason why there's been mounds
of earth and piles of
earth on top of it.
It's because there's a lot of
asbestos from the buildings
from before the Second
World War.
Oh, dear, this is a problem.
And the other thing they've done
to that now is because
it's a greenfield site-- don't
know if you know what a
greenfield site is, but it's
a patch of land that hasn't
actually been developed on--
once you've put a temporary
structure like a basketball
court on there, it suddenly
become a Brownfield site.
So it sets this legal precedent,
which then means
you can then sell that land
and the sky above it for
further regeneration.
[WHISTLING AND DRUMMING]
CAROLINE DAY: It's been
very hard for us to
make our voice known.
That's why we're here today.
That's why we have to come, and
we have to make a racket.
It's not because we
haven't exhausted
every legitimate channel.
Because we have, and we have
not been listened to.
[WHISTLING AND DRUMMING]
CLAIRE WEISS: In Waltham Forest,
we have really done
badly in terms of legacy
from the Olympic Games.
We've seen how much damage has
been done to the lands on
Leyton Marsh.
They have dug up what was under
there, the contents of a
landfill site.
And we believe the whole thing
is too high a price to pay for
five weeks of games into our
countryside in one of the
poorest parts of the capital.
MALE SPEAKER: The whole
thing all along is
mirror image language.
It's the opposite
of what it says.
So you see a big sign saying,
improving the image of
construction, when you're
ripping some building down and
digging a major hole
in the ground.
So it actually means improving
the image of destruction, and
regeneration generally
means degeneration.
What is this?
This is two, three weeks worth
of sports day stuff that is
supposed to totally reinvent
500, 1,000 years of London
history, and just brush
it aside for a
corporate sports day.
LIZ SCOTT: The word Olympic
didn't come into the games
here until 1636.
The games were started
in 1612.
Because the Olympic games had
stayed here since the 1600s,
the Olympics Commission came
here to learn about the
Olympic Games.
So that is really special.
JAMES WISEMAN: One second, I'm
just going to put my phone on
silent, and in my
little man bag.
All right.
OK.
So it was a much bigger
event 400 years ago.
They had things like horse
racing going on.
There was wrestling, which we
still do a little bit of.
One of the most popular events
involved a person holding a
pig and attempting to sing
at the same time.
Well, it's a piglet, really,
rather than a pig, but if you
imagine the piglet, it's going
to wriggle quite a lot, and so
you've got to try and
hold it while
singing at the same time.
Climbing the greasy pole, where
women would scramble to
get to the top of a greasy
pole and retrieve some
petticoats from the top,
which they then won.
PETE "BUZZSAW" HOLLAND: When you
learn swordsmanship with a
traditional English backsword
such as this, which is the
steel sword, obviously when
you're training to sword
fight, it's a very dangerous
art and skill to learn.
So traditionally, people
would use a wooden
waster, use the cudgel.
PHILLIP PITT: Basically, you're
out to hit anywhere.
Try to be careful of, obviously,
the groin area.
It's quite painful.
I got my kneecap split open
with a steel a couple of
months ago.
That wasn't pleasant.
Very serious, drew blood.
PETE "BUZZSAW" HOLLAND:
Originally, opposed to
fighting for a prize bag of
money, you would fight for a
good hat with a good cockade
of feathers.
If at the end of the day that
you won and you became
champion, just wearing the hat
around the local community was
such a symbol of kudos,
if you like.
JED "JOKER" PASCOE: It was
super 16th century, 17th
century bling.
[CHEERING]
JAMES WISEMAN: Shin kicking is
probably the most popular
event for spectators.
Personally, I don't see why
they couldn't have shin
kicking in the Olympics.
There's certainly some other
sports in the Olympics which I
think you could quite
easily replace.
Probably synchronized
swimming could be
replaced with shin kicking.
I think people just like
watching people get hurt.
MALE SPEAKER: I like this
because it is a community
event, whereas the hardest sport
lover in the middle of
London is going to be hard
pushed to feel it's really on
their store step as
a community event.
JAMES WISEMAN: This
has always been
about being very inclusive.
Doesn't matter who you are.
Again, in terms of the sports,
anybody can enter the sports.
There's no us and them.
There's no corporate sponsors
and VIP's box and all that.
It's all everybody's
in it together.
MALE SPEAKER: You've got the
manager franchises, Coca-Cola
and McDonald's.
And this is an eco
green games.
Dow Chemicals have been
responsible for horrors in
India, are doing the wrap that
goes around the Olympic
stadium, making it look
like a wedding cake.
Everything is just turned
on its head.
Everything is absurd, and
quite ridiculous.
MEREDITH ALEXANDER: When London
bid to host the Games,
we promised the world that
we would have the most
sustainable Games ever.
And until January, I was a
member of something called the
Commission for a Sustainable
London 2012.
We were asked to look at the
deal that the London Games
organizers had with
Dow Chemical.
And the more I looked into it,
the more compelling evidence
was presented to me by
organizations like Amnesty
International and the Bhopal
Medical Appeal to show that
Dow Chemical bears
responsibility for this tragedy.
In the end, I wasn't able to
feel comfortable being part of
a body that defended Dow
Chemical and claimed that it
was a sustainable company.
COLIN TOOGOOD: On the night of
the 2nd, 3rd December, 1984,
there was a huge gas leak from
a pesticide factory, Union
Carbide owned pesticide
factory in Bhopal.
This was a factory that was in
a very poor state, and it's
true to say that even the
safety systems had been
switched off.
So unfortunately, the
people there didn't
stand much of a chance.
The gas was incredibly
poisonous.
In the first 72 hours,
there was 7,000 to
10,000 people killed.
Now, we accept that Dow never
owned or operated the plant,
as we are so often told in the
media, but they did acquire
Union Carbide out right.
And they have a very strange
relationship with Union
Carbide, which is one of
not just ownership.
They're effectively
one and the same.
High level executives from one
sit on the board of the other.
MEREDITH ALEXANDER: Dow
Chemical in Bhopal is
responsible for a situation
that is seeing generation
after generation of children
born with the most appalling
birth defects.
The tragic irony of them
sponsoring the Paralympics is
pretty overwhelming,
to be frank.
MALE SPEAKER: Sponsors
like BP--
these large people who've been
associated with all kinds of
forms of pollution--
are actually now wearing the
green jacket of being the eco
heroes rescuing this wonderful
park land that we're going to
be handed back.
MEREDITH ALEXANDER: Rio Tinto
is providing the medals that
actually go around the
athlete's neck.
These are one of the most iconic
images of the Games.
But unfortunately, the metal
comes from mines that are
really environmentally
problematic.
And the local communities are
fighting to get those mines
either closed down or run
more responsibly.
BENNY WENDA: My name
is Benny Wenda.
I am from West Papua.
I am also ex political prisoner
and independent
leader, and now I'm
living in exile.
Rio Tinto is a part of the
problem in West Papua.
Even the human rights
violations, our mountain been
destroyed, our river polluted.
These companies are indirectly
or directly support Indonesia
committed genocide my people.
Rio Tinto need to admit it.
Their gold is the blood
of my people.