PRESIDENT OBAMA: --who
now have served either
in Iraq or Afghanistan.
All of them have done
extraordinary work,
and it is our moral
obligation to make sure--
RANDALL: Look at this bird.
Thanks for the treat, stupid!
"Hey, come back here,"
says the honey badger.
Birds don't care.
And you know what?
The jackals do it, too.
Look at these little dogs--
TED WILLIAMS: --listen to one
of our area radio announcers.
And I went as a field
trip to go meet the guy,
and he looked nothing
like what he sounded like.
So--
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[MUSIC - THE GREGORY
BROTHERS, "WINNING"]
[MUSIC - MARIA ARAGON,
"BORN THIS WAY"]
[MUSIC - M.I.A., "PAPER PLANES"]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[SYMPHONY MUSIC PLAYING]
MALE SPEAKER: --and it looks
like the tsunami has engulfed
several cities in
Miyagi Prefecture.
Live footage of Miyagi
as the tsunami--
[BABIES TALKING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
PRINCE WILLIAM: --in
sickness and in health.
ARCHBISHOP OF CANTERBURY:
To love and to cherish.
PRINCE WILLIAM: To
love and to cherish.
ARCHBISHOP OF CANTERBURY:
Till death us do part.
PRINCE WILLIAM: Till
death us do part.
ARCHBISHOP OF CANTERBURY:
According to God's holy law.
PRINCE WILLIAM: According
to God's holy law.
MALE SPEAKER: --so
all Jax and Stryker
are going to find is you
dead, the robotics gone,
and my men waiting.
[MUSIC_-_NYAN_CAT]
[OLD TIME PIANO MUSIC PLAYING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[SHOUTING]
[DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
MALE SPEAKER: So you know,
I went to the fridge,
and I opened up the meat drawer.
You know what the
meat drawer is, right?
DOG: Yeah.
What was in there?
MALE SPEAKER: Well, I'll
tell you what was in there.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
RAY WILLIAM JOHNSON: My
kid is an honor student,
which is nice-- nice-- nice.
You know, guys, I
did a little research
and looked up the "Blue
Book" value of this car,
and it's approximately
two packs of menthols
and one bag of beef jerky--
[APPLAUSE]
CONAN O'BRIEN: You now
have a crushing advantage
over 8% of the workforce.
[LAUGHTER]
CONAN O'BRIEN: I'm talking
about dropout losers
like Bill Gates, Steve Jobs--
[MUSIC PLAYING]
MALE SPEAKER: We
can stick around.
[MUSIC_-_JANE'S_ADDICTION]
[MUSIC AND SHOUTING]
HARRY POTTER: Let's finish
this the way we started.
Together!
[MUSIC AND SHOUTING]
[DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
MALE SPEAKER: Take two.
Two for one.
HARLEY MORENSTEIN:
OK, I'll take two.
I'll take four.
MALE SPEAKER:
HARLEY MORENSTEIN: No.
MALE SPEAKER: Oh my god,
that's an awesome thing.
MALE SPEAKER: Here you go.
Apple pies for all the children.
MALE SPEAKER: Just waiting
for the page to load.
Hey, there we go!
A million subscribers!
Ahh!
Thank you so much.
COMPUTER VOICE: Congratulations.
[INAUDIBLE] for reaching
1 million subscribers--
[MUSIC - ADELE,
"ROLLING IN THE DEEP"]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
MALE SPEAKER: What?
MALE SPEAKER: Can I
tell you something?
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
MALE SPEAKER: Will
you love me, period?
MALE SPEAKER: Yes.
MALE SPEAKER: Like you'll
always love me as long as I'm--
MALE SPEAKER: Don't worry.
MALE SPEAKER: I can do "Mrs.
Doubtfire," [INAUDIBLE].
Oh, it's perfectly all right.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Let's see,
take a series of photos.
I was doing that wrong.
MALE SPEAKER: That's OK.
FEMALE SPEAKER: And you can
email these to selected media,
but why can't-- why
won't it take a picture?
MALE SPEAKER: --gets better.
They touched hearts, drew tears,
and brought smiles to faces.
You never know when your
story can change a life
or when it can change the world.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
MARK BLOCK: Mark Block here.
Since January, I've
had the privilege
of being the chief
of staff to Herman
Cain and the chief
operating officer--
[MUSIC PLAYING]
STEVE JOBS: --decided to
put me up for adoption.
She felt very
strongly that I should
be adopted by college
graduates, so everything was all
set for me to be adopted
at birth by a lawyer.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[MUSIC - KARMIN,
"LOOK AT ME NOW"]
LADY GAGA: --that poor boy.
[LAUGHTER]
FEMALE SPEAKER: There's also
so many fan remixes and remakes
of your songs on YouTube.
I was wondering if you
have a favorite there.
I know there's Maria, the
young girl, I think really--
[YELLING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
MALE SPEAKER: Dad, I'm gay.
MALE SPEAKER: I
still love you, son.
[MUSIC - FLO RIDA,
"GOOD FEELING"]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
FEMALE SPEAKER: --or the
next president of Egypt
will be chosen by the people.
[MUSIC PLAYING]