[APPLAUSE]
SPANDY ANDY: Tonight is UCB
comedy, hot improve from the
best comedians.
BETH HOYT: That is hot,
muy caliente.
It was good, right?
I love every one on the show.
This is exciting.
Oh, boy.
NATHAN BARNATT: And--
BETH HOYT: Whoa!
NATHAN BARNATT: Be sure to
check out Comedy Week
countdown videos starting
tomorrow.
BETH HOYT: Oh, yeah.
Wow!
That's a kick.
SPANDY ANDY: Not to mention, you
should always be checking
out our live events at
youtube.com/comedyweek.
As well, tonight's live Adam
Carolla podcast, with special
guest, Ray William Johnson.
NATHAN BARNATT: And last night's
international comedy
show is up in its entirety.
[APPLAUSE]
BETH HOYT: That's a very
impressive hip flexor.
It's so--
NATHAN BARNATT: Let's
keep it rolling.
BETH HOYT: Wow.
Yeah, I mean, wow.
I'm from [? France-uh. ?]
That joke doesn't work
as well because we
have the kicking thing.
But that's--
NATHAN BARNATT: Oh, I think
I know what you're saying.
BETH HOYT: That's OK.
We got there.
That was just--
that's quite a lot of balancing,
dexterity you--
NATHAN BARNATT: You
noticed my wood.
BETH HOYT: Your wood is
right in my face.
Getting real close to my face.
NATHAN BARNATT: Plus we keep
on churning out Comedy Week
videos, which can be seen
at H-T-T-P W dot dot
youtubecomedy.com/comedyweek.
BETH HOYT: Thank you for letting
everyone know that.
Man, when they churn it out,
it's like that Play-Doh
machine you guys know we had
as kids, with like the--
spaghetti comes out?
I miss being a kid so bad.
I so miss it.
I want to be a kid again.
I just want to be there.
NATHAN BARNATT: OK, you
are on ecstasy, Beth.
BETH HOYT: OK, you're a narc.
You're such a narc, seriously.
Join us again tomorrow
for more.
Without further a-dude--
yeah.
OK.
NATHAN BARNATT: That
was pretty good.
That was pretty good.
BETH HOYT: Just trying.
Thank you.
Let's commence with
UCB comedy.
[APPLAUSE]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
JOE WENGERT: Thanks
a lot, guys.
Welcome to UCB Comedy, live
from the YouTube space.
How you guys feeling tonight?
We're here tonight as a
part of Comedy Week.
I don't know about you guys.
I can't believe it's Comedy
Week already.
The year went by so quickly.
JON GABRUS: I feel like it was
just drama week weeks ago.
JOE WENGERT: I know.
I just took down all my Comedy
Week decorations, and now here
we are celebrating
it once again.
We're performers from the
Upright Citizens Brigade
theatre in Los Angeles.
And what we're going to be
doing tonight for you is
improv comedy.
We're going to be watching
real YouTube videos.
And that's going to serve as
the inspiration for comedy
scenes that we're going to
make up on the spot.
They've never been
seen before.
And they will never
be seen again.
I mean, you can go back
and rewatch it again.
But in theory, we're not
going to do them again.
Are you guys excited
about that?
[APPLAUSE]
Improv is all about the ensemble
and about the group,
so now let's take some time
to introduce ourselves
individually as performers.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Hi, I'm
Mike Leffingwell.
TONI RAMOS: Hey, guys.
I'm Toni Ramos.
JOE WENGERT: Hi, everybody.
I was already talking.
My name's Joe Wengert.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: Hi,
Drew DiFonzo Marks.
JON GABRUS: One guy loved it.
I am Jon Gabrus.
MALE SPEAKER: Oh, my god.
ALLAN MCLEOD: And I'm
the last one.
I'm Allan McLeod.
How's it going?
[APPLAUSE]
JOE WENGERT: OK.
Now that you know our first
and last names,
it's time to do improv.
Let's roll the first
YouTube clip.
CRAZYPUERTORRICAN99: Cartoon
Network, you have
fucking done it again.
I am sick of it.
Cartoon Network, I am
just sick of this.
OK.
You cancel "Young Justice" and
"Green Lantern," the only
reason to watch Cartoon
Network right now.
OK?
And this happened before.
"Toonami--" you know
"Toonami." That got canceled
for low ratings.
OK.
But this was the only thing
that was worth watching on
Cartoon Network.
They just-- why do
they do that?
Hell, Boomerang has
better shows.
Disney Channel has now better
shows, and that
has a lot to say.
Cartoon Network, what
the fuck is wrong?
You guys just can't
keep doing this.
"Toonami," childhood ruined.
"DC Nation--" "DC Nation"
is a one hour block.
It should be more.
This could have been the new
"Toonami," but just with
superhero shows.
They could have had
three hours.
Like they could have had two
hours of the new shows and
like one hour of the
classics, like
"Teen Titans," or "Batman--
The Animated Series," "Justice
League Unlimited." But OK, to
do this again?
Nah.
I'm just sick and tired
of this shit.
You know what, Cartoon
Network?
The only think I'm watching
right now is Adult Swim.
And that's because of "Toonami."
It's only because
of "Toonami," and I only
watch it on Saturdays.
Get that through your
fucking skulls and
just stop doing this.
That's all.
Stay cool.
Bang.
[APPLAUSE]
JOE WENGERT: OK.
So, we all watched that video
for the first time with the
rest of you, right now.
And we're going to use that
video as the inspiration for
some improvised scenes.
[APPLAUSE]
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Excuse me.
Are you the manager of
this McDonald's?
TONI RAMOS: Uh, yes sir, I am.
How can I help you?
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Oh,
you can help me by
answering this question.
TONI RAMOS: OK, great.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Where
the fuck is the McRib?
Where is it?
TONI RAMOS: Sir, the McRib
is a limited time thing.
It's in the month of
June, so it'll be
coming up in a few weeks.
If you can come--
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Oh, OK.
Hey, yeah, yeah.
No, I got a great idea.
Why don't we only have sunshine
in the month of June,
and it's total darkness
for the other 11
months of the year?
Why are you fucking America?
DREW DIFONZO MARKS:
Hi, can I get a
number four, super sized?
And instead of a soft drink,
can I get a Shamrock shake?
TONI RAMOS: Oh, sorry.
We don't have Shamrock shakes.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS:
Go fuck yourself.
TONI RAMOS: It's been
a rough day, sir.
ALLAN MCLEOD: I've been
looking around
the Playland area.
TONI RAMOS: Oh, great.
Yeah.
Did you lose a kid?
Or are you--
ALLAN MCLEOD: I think you
guys lost Grimace.
Where the fuck is Grimace?
Where's my big purple man?
TONI RAMOS: Sir, that's
just an action figure.
He's not like a real
guy running around.
He's just like a--
ALLAN MCLEOD: What?
What's wrong with you?
JOE WENGERT: OK.
Toni, we've heard your
complaints, and--
TONI RAMOS: I mean,
they are rough.
So many guys have told me to
go fuck myself, that I'm an
idiot, threw out the C-word.
JOE WENGERT: Look,
these products
are seasonal products.
There's no way that
we can offer them
throughout the year.
The best that I can do for you
is give you this handgun, OK?
If someone is especially irate
about the fact that they can't
get a specific--
JON GABRUS: I'll have--
TONI RAMOS: Pow.
JON GABRUS: Come on!
Ow.
JOE WENGERT: I need the
gun back, because--
[APPLAUSE]
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: So it's
a lovely apartment.
JON GABRUS: I noticed.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: Thank you.
So honestly, it's in
a great school
district, hardwood floors.
Second floor--
I'll take you up there.
JON GABRUS: Great.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: Now, these
three katana swords are on the
wall at all times.
JON GABRUS: Yeah, I was just--
I was going to ask about it.
Because I have kids, bunch
of crazy, fucking kids.
And I can't have them playing
with katana blades or
whatever that is.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: They are
part of the apartment.
They are non-negotiable.
Did you call your own
kids fucking crazy?
JON GABRUS: When you see these
monsters, you'll know what I'm
talking about.
One kid eats wood
by the pound.
I can't-- it's a fucking
nightmare.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS:
That's crazy.
JON GABRUS: Thank you.
See?
I'm not like using that like,
oh, my crazy kids.
Like I think there's serious
mental issues.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: Sure.
I'm a father myself.
JON GABRUS: Oh.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: Yeah.
JON GABRUS: I would never
have guessed.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS:
One of my kids?
Bonkers.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Dad,
are you done?
JON GABRUS: No, we're not--
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: We're
running out of
oxygen in the car.
JON GABRUS: Mike, you're not
in the car anymore, so your
oxygen should be fine.
And that is my good doorstop.
God damn it, Mike.
You took this from my--
I use this doorstop
to hold my door.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Mom lets
me eat doorstops.
JON GABRUS: Well then you
can eat it on the
weekend when you go visit.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Oh, I will.
I will.
JON GABRUS: Sit down
right there.
Thank you.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS:
So you have kids.
OK.
So it seems like this
is a big apartment.
It might be good.
JON GABRUS: Yeah, it might be.
Are those blades sharp?
I got to-- this is a
hard for me to--
that seems like a very specific
thing to have in an
apartment that is
non-negotiable.
I feel like, once I move in and
you're not around, I could
take the katana blade.
Just like I lived in an
apartment where the landlord
said, you can't go
on the roof.
The second he left I went up on
the roof and smoked weed.
So I feel like the second you
leave, I'm going to put those
katanas in a drawer or
I'm going to play
with them by myself.
ALLAN MCLEOD: Daddy.
JON GABRUS: Oh, no.
What is it, Bruno?
ALLAN MCLEOD: I pooped
nails again.
Nails came out of my butt.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: I thought
my kids were crazy.
JON GABRUS: No, my kids
are genuinely crazy.
They eat things that
aren't food.
ALLAN MCLEOD: Dad, I got
a nail in my eye.
If I'd had wood, it might
have stopped it.
JON GABRUS: It's not how it--
are you pooping in your
brother's eyes again?
ALLAN MCLEOD: Yeah.
JON GABRUS: Please, Bruno,
none of that.
And what do we say?
It's I made boom-boom
with nails.
Trying to teach them
better language.
ALLAN MCLEOD: Nice swords.
JON GABRUS: OK.
You've got a point
there, Mike.
Insane fucking child
likes swords.
Shit nails.
Do you know how you
shit nails?
Do you see how casual
he was about it?
That would ruin most people.
My kids have--
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: It's
a jarring experience
for me to see that.
JON GABRUS: My kids are like
fucking cartoon sharks.
They swallow everything.
I swear.
You know how cartoons
sharks do that.
Is that not a casual
expression here?
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: Here?
JON GABRUS: Yeah,
where are we?
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: We're
in this apartment.
JON GABRUS: Yeah.
Yeah, all right.
JOE WENGERT: Dad?
Daddy?
JON GABRUS: One at
a time they come.
What is it?
JOE WENGERT: I finished
my math worksheet.
I need you to check
over my answers.
JON GABRUS: Get out of
here, you sick fuck.
You're a fucking nightmare.
JOE WENGERT: I need you
to check my answers.
JON GABRUS: No.
No.
JOE WENGERT: How do I know
if they're right or not?
JON GABRUS: Go clean up your
brother's nail shit.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: Sir, I do
not mean to get involved, but
that just seemed like a
child crying for help.
JON GABRUS: But his pants didn't
even match his shirt.
He's a wacky little kid.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: That's
not enough of a reason.
Look, are your kids--
JON GABRUS: I lump all my kids
together a little bit.
Some of them are better
than others, OK?
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: OK.
JON GABRUS: But you know, by the
time the third one comes
around, you're a little worked
up from your first two.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: And they're
all just out there in
the car by themselves?
JON GABRUS: Yeah.
Do we have to keep this like,
awful, awful brown color that
we have everywhere?
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: God, no.
JON GABRUS: I can repaint, but
I can't move the katanas.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: That's
the one thing.
ALLAN MCLEOD: OK, everybody.
[APPLAUSE]
ALLAN MCLEOD: So, you know,
we've been having a lot of
programming issues here, people
not a big fan of what
we're doing at the
Hallmark Channel.
So we brought into a new
kid to be the CEO of
the Hallmark Channel.
You know, because kids,
they have moms.
They overhear a lot of stuff
their moms like.
That's the thinking behind
me hiring a child.
JON GABRUS: I'm standing right
here, Mr. [INAUDIBLE].
ALLAN MCLEOD: Oh, yeah.
JON GABRUS: Hi.
My name's Danny.
I run the Hallmark
Channel now.
And we're gonna, my first
idea, my first idea is--
aw, I have a nervous boner.
I have a nervous boner.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: That is a
huge boner for a little boy.
JON GABRUS: Thank you.
Thank you so much.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: That
was not a compliment.
It's more bewilderment.
JON GABRUS: It's a compliment
for me.
JOE WENGERT: Is your nervous
boner a programming idea?
JON GABRUS: Yeah.
Of course.
That's why I did it.
We're going to have a two-hour
boner block on Thursdays.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Rob Lowe
could play the boner.
JON GABRUS: Yeah.
Who's that?
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Oh, he's an
actor that does a lot of
Hallmark movies.
JON GABRUS: Oh, all right.
ALLAN MCLEOD: He's
a great guy.
I'll call him.
JON GABRUS: Cool.
I'm a kid.
So I'm not going to know
that reference.
Um, my other idea was
we could have no
commercials and free pizza.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: Boss?
I got to call bullshit here.
ALLAN MCLEOD: Whoa.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: Because I
got a boner in a meeting last
week, and you told me
was inappropriate.
ALLAN MCLEOD: Because
you're an adult man.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: Yeah, it
was a confident boner.
ALLAN MCLEOD: Well, this is a
nervous child's boner, OK?
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: I'm just
pissed because his
is bigger than mine.
JOE WENGERT: Maybe we need,
like, to have a meeting so we
know which boners are OK and
which boners are sort of
outside the lines.
JON GABRUS: I guess as your new
CEO of Hallmark Channel, I
might as well have
that meeting now?
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Well you know
what would help me a lot?
Is a lot of times, I'm not cc:ed
on the company email, so
I only had like a half chub at
the Friday meeting last week.
Because I wasn't ready.
I didn't know it was going on.
And I was even also like,
are they appropriate?
Is it inappropriate?
ALLAN MCLEOD: Well, we all
emailed each other about that.
And we're going to have
to let you go.
The half chub is not
appropriate.
At least get it all the way
up or nothing at all.
JON GABRUS: Right?
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Guys?
I can't have my marriage and my
job end the same week for
the same reason.
ALLAN MCLEOD: Change is good.
Embrace it.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: All right.
Good luck, kid.
You're gonna need it.
Slam!
ALLAN MCLEOD: He always
does that.
Every time he leaves, he closes
the door, he says slam.
That was another reason.
We can't fire him on
those grounds.
JON GABRUS: I can't believe we
fired such an awesome dude.
OK, idea number three, now just
try to get this through
your thick, fucking skull, OK?
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: What
was idea number two?
JON GABRUS: Idea number
two was no
commercials and free pizza.
You don't remember it because
you were too busy thinking
about your own boner.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS:
He's right.
JON GABRUS: All right.
Let's table the boners
for now.
What we're talking about is free
pizza, no commercials.
Because commercials suck,
pizza is awesome.
So how can we capitalize
on that?
ALLAN MCLEOD: Pizza
commercials.
JON GABRUS: All right.
JOE WENGERT: Only commercials
for pizza?
ALLAN MCLEOD: Why not?
I'm trying to-- we
have to have--
JON GABRUS: We're just
spit-balling here
TONI RAMOS: I know we're
tabling the boner talk.
But what about--
I feel weird saying this
in front of a kid.
But getting wet, or moist, or
maybe laughing too hard, or
hitting the edge of
a desk and wetting
yourself a little bit--
does that count as like
a boner time?
JON GABRUS: Are those things
that could happen to people?
TONI RAMOS: To women who
have had children, yes.
Yes, it can.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: They
can hit a table and wet
themselves?
TONI RAMOS: If you
hit a part, yes.
Yes, it can.
If you hit a table too hard,
it blows out a little bit.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: Sweetheart,
now, close your eyes?
TONI RAMOS: OK.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS:
Now, hold on.
I rearranged the furniture
a little bit.
TONI RAMOS: Why would
you do that?
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: Hold on.
It's OK.
Just keep walking.
I got you something.
TONI RAMOS: Oh!
Oh.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS:
Did you come?
What happened?
TONI RAMOS: Whoa, definitely
didn't come.
[APPLAUSE]
JON GABRUS: Mr. Smith,
I wanted to talk to
you about your son.
I ran all the tests
that I could.
And I feel like the only real
answer left to this issue is
that I don't think
he can blink.
I don't think he--
the reason his eyes are drying
out so rapidly is that he
doesn't know how to blink.
ALLAN MCLEOD: That's not usually
a thing you have to
teach somebody.
JON GABRUS: Yeah, no shit.
And that's why I'm
freaking out, OK?
I'm a doctor.
I'm a doctor of eyes, as we call
it in the medical term,
an eye doctor.
And now I've got this.
I've never seen this before.
Blinking is something we
instinctually do--
I did like the, [SNAP].
You didn't blink either.
ALLAN MCLEOD: Uh, I just--
I didn't want to
miss anything.
JON GABRUS: [LAUGHING]
Are you--
a strange man just threw a punch
in your face, and you
didn't even react at all.
ALLAN MCLEOD: Do it
again, I'll blink.
I'll blink.
JON GABRUS: You didn't blink.
ALLAN MCLEOD: Oh, wait!
Wait!
JON GABRUS: Shit,
it's hereditary.
It got to be on the
Y chromosome.
ALLAN MCLEOD: Yeah, it's
probably on the Y chromosome.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Dr. Douglas?
JON GABRUS: [LAUGHING]
Uh-huh.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Sorry
to interrupt.
Your wife just called
and left a message.
She wants you to call her as
soon as you get a chance.
Thanks.
Bye.
ALLAN MCLEOD: Your secretary--
JON GABRUS: I'm just now
noticing that my secretary
I've had for the last
18 years might never
have blinked before.
ALLAN MCLEOD: Gosh--
JON GABRUS: I'm always
looking right here.
ALLAN MCLEOD: OK, OK.
I get that.
JON GABRUS: I got you right
in the center there.
My bad.
I didn't mean to touch
a stranger.
You didn't react at
all, again, dude.
ALLAN MCLEOD: Well, what
do you expect, my
pecs to blink now?
Look, I'm working on it.
My son stares at me creepily
all the time,
even when he's asleep.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: Daddy?
Daddy?
ALLAN MCLEOD: No, it's me son.
Yes.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: I know.
I've just been waiting a long
time for this optometry
appointment.
ALLAN MCLEOD: We're going to
get you those glasses.
JON GABRUS: That's very cute,
but we're called eye doctors.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: Why do
I need an eye doctor?
What's wrong with my eyes?
[INAUDIBLE] do anything.
JON GABRUS: There's nothing
technically
wrong with your eyes.
It's more your lid.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS:
The thing above my
eyes that does nothing?
JON GABRUS: Well,
yeah, for most--
holy shit, you're really
creeping me out.
That's some Michael
Caine shit.
[LAUGHS]
Did you just fake blink
after I swung at you
to try to fit in?
ALLAN MCLEOD: Yeah, why don't
you bust my balls about it?
JON GABRUS: I feel like
my soul is being--
JOE WENGERT: Dr. Gabrus, we
heard about your complaint.
And there's nothing that we can
really do except to give
you this handgun.
So if you feel intimidated
by any of your
patients or their parents--
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: So you're
going to do this to make my
eyes react in any way at all?
JON GABRUS: Yeah.
What's wrong with you, kid?
Why aren't you afraid of
a fucking gun, man?
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: Fire
it in the air near me.
See if anything happens
at all.
Not a thing.
ALLAN MCLEOD: [YELLING]
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: Oh!
Daddy!
Daddy, no!
I'd cry, but I can't
close my eyes.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL:
I heard a shot.
What's going on?
JON GABRUS: Jesus Christ, all
of you, get out of here.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Your wife said
the recycling's going to
get picked up on Thursday
this week.
JON GABRUS: Thursday?
No.
Sorry, I'm losing--
I'm cracking up here.
All right.
You see, I'm just
an eye doctor.
Are you blinking all now
from being shot?
ALLAN MCLEOD: This is
years of blinks
flashing before my eyes.
JON GABRUS: That's literally
what's happening.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: Teach me
how to do that with those
above eye muscles.
JON GABRUS: Teach you
how to blink?
ALLAN MCLEOD: Son.
JON GABRUS: That was the--
DREW DIFONZO MARKS:
Yes, Daddy.
JON GABRUS: I got the message.
ALLAN MCLEOD: Take my lids.
Take my lids.
Yes, peel them.
Peel them.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS:
This is so gross.
ALLAN MCLEOD: Attach my
lids to my son's eyes.
JON GABRUS: I honestly don't
think that's the issue.
ALLAN MCLEOD: You've
got to try.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: But,
Daddy, I have eyelids.
I just don't know
how to use them.
ALLAN MCLEOD: Maybe you
need double lids.
More lids, please.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL:
Jon, wake up!
Wake up, Jon.
Wake up!
JON GABRUS: Oh!
[GASPING]
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: You were
talking in your sleep.
JON GABRUS: Oh, no.
Oh, no.
Is it Thursday?
The recycling, oh, my
god, the recycling--
oh, fuck.
I was supposed to put it out.
No.
Wait.
That wasn't the thrust
of my dream.
That's all I remember.
Oh, fuck.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: What
a weird boner.
JON GABRUS: It's
a normal boner.
[APPLAUSE]
JOE WENGERT: So we've narrowed
down the names for the
Saturday morning cartoon block
down to two names.
We're either going to call it
Saturday Morning Fun Time or
Toonami, to sort of evoke the
name of a natural disaster
that would kill--
DREW DIFONZO MARKS:
Oh, I got it.
JOE WENGERT: --maybe
millions of people.
So Saturday Morning Fun Time.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS:
Or Toonami.
JOE WENGERT: Or Toonami.
Also--
I'm sorry.
There was a third option that
I keep blanking about.
Cartoon 9/11 was another
[INTERPOSING VOICES].
So one of those three--
and I can't figure out which
ones to eliminate because
they're all very good.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: Good's
a subjective term.
You've kind of pointed out the
only problem with it, saying
that it invokes a natural
disaster.
JOE WENGERT: Yeah, it's a
little too on the nose.
Cartoon Fun Time is just like,
the kids are going to be like,
this is insulting to us.
Let us decide if it's
fun or not.
And we know it's cartoons.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: Honestly,
Joe, I would say the second
and the third ones are just
borderline offensive, OK?
Like those children could have
had family members that died
in the tsunami or many parents
that were in 9/11, OK?
And that's just going to really
harsh-- not make them
want to watch.
Fun time is fun for everybody.
JOE WENGERT: This way, they'll
sort of deal with their
issues, I feel like, in a fun
environment with their
favorite characters.
JON GABRUS: Hey, boss, I came
up with a few others.
I should probably read them to
you, because I wrote them in
such sloppy handwriting.
Japanese Internment Cartoons.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: You had
to go out of your way
to think that up.
That's just going
for offensive.
JON GABRUS: The Funenburg
Trials.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: At least
there's an attempt at wordplay
in that one.
JON GABRUS: And this one
is just called Lynch.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: It's
just offensive.
And no one would even know
that's a cartoon show.
JON GABRUS: Ahh!
All right.
I'll take these back, put
them in the oven for
a little bit longer.
Ovens!
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: No.
No, I know where you're
going with that.
JON GABRUS: OK, fair enough.
Sorry, boss.
I tried.
We got to find something better
than Saturday Fun Time.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: Look, I'm
not saying Saturday Fun Time
is perfect, but something
like Action Packed
Hour, or Fun Zone.
Or Animation--
JOE WENGERT: Action
Packed Hour?
DREW DIFONZO MARKS:
Action Pack Hour.
JOE WENGERT: OK, that's
very rude of you.
OK?
DREW DIFONZO MARKS:
How is that rude?
JOE WENGERT: You want to know--
you think that kids are
going to want to tune into
something that's going to
remind them of car crashes
and buildings imploding?
Two actions?
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: I think
9/11 Hour is a little more
buildings imploding than
Action Pack Hour.
JOE WENGERT: Well, most of the
cartoons are going to be
airing between 9:00
AM and 11:00 AM.
I don't understand what the
problem is with that.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: That's
a stretch at best.
JOE WENGERT: What?
DREW DIFONZO MARKS:
That's a stretch.
JOE WENGERT: Nobody's watching
the 8 o'clock cartoons.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: Look,
I'm just saying--
even if that reference went over
the kids heads, let's say
the kids are too young for 9/11,
the parents are going to
be up, you know, making
breakfast for the kids.
And they're going to watch it.
And adults will be
offended by it.
It's just something--
JOE WENGERT: Those adults need
to find something better to do
with their time, I think, than
watch cartoons all morning.
Take care--
take care of your kids.
Focus on your career
and your future.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: All right.
Let me just run a little
test by you.
You tell me which of these
you think is better.
And I'm just going to go with
the line of logic I think
you're using.
OK, let's go with Animation
Station--
JOE WENGERT: Love it.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: Or
just, Holocaust Hour.
JOE WENGERT: Super love it.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: No!
JOE WENGERT: Wow.
Now, I got a dilemma again.
I don't know which
one to take.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: No.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Excuse me.
I'm sorry to interrupt.
I just had an idea, kind
of a brainstorm.
Hitler had some pretty
good ideas.
I'm sorry, I don't actually
work for this company.
I'm just looking
for a bathroom.
Is there one on this floor?
I'll find it.
JOE WENGERT: Yeah, you just go
down the hall, three doors
down to your right.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Thank you.
JOE WENGERT: You're welcome.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Slam.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: He
always does that.
Look, the cartoons themselves
are G rated, OK?
All right?
They're for all audiences.
Some of them have smart jokes,
because the parents will be
watching, too.
So the material itself
is not--
is geared towards kids.
You want to make sure the title
of the hour is as well.
ALLAN MCLEOD: Guys, guys.
Did you guys hear the news?
DREW DIFONZO MARKS:
What happened?
ALLAN MCLEOD: 1,000 people
just died in a Fun Time
Animation Station accident.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: All
right, fuck it.
Let's go with Holocaust hour.
JON GABRUS: Thank you guys.
That's our first show.
[APPLAUSE]
JOE WENGERT: OK.
Right now, we're going to bring
out another performer.
He's also a performer from
the UCB Theatre.
And he's got a show coming
on Comedy Central called
"Review." Let's give
a warm welcome
to Andy Daly, everybody.
[APPLAUSE]
ANDY DALY: Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Yeah.
That's a good round
of applause.
MALE SPEAKER: Standing
ovation--
[INAUDIBLE] that.
ANDY DALY: That son of a
bitch just cut me off.
Hey, fuck you, you
piece of shit.
Fuck you.
INTERN: Oh, this is amazing.
ANDY DALY: This guy just
fucked with the wrong
motherfucker.
INTERN: Fuck, yeah,
Mr. MacNeil.
ANDY DALY: Motherfucker,
you just fucked
with the wrong guy.
INTERN: I got your back,
Mr. MacNeil.
ANDY DALY: What the fuck
is the matter with you?
I'm trying to fucking
drive here.
You blow through that
stop sign like that.
You don't fucking do
that to people.
You got a stop sign?
You stop at the fucking
white line.
INTERN: Mr. MacNeil.
ANDY DALY: Oh, yeah.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
OK.
Hey, asshole.
It looks like something
happened to
your fucking taillight.
What the fuck happened to your
sideview mirror, asshole?
Looks like your blind
spot just got a
little bigger, fuckwit.
What are you going
to do about it?
MALE SPEAKER: You forgot
about something.
Oh.
You forgot one more thing.
Hey!
You ever been in a smash off?
You are now.
ANDY DALY: Smash off!
INTERN: No, no, no.
Mr. MacNeil, no.
No, Mr. MacNeil.
Stop, Mr. MacNeil!
That's my fucking car.
Please, Mr. MacNeil!
Please!
Fucking stop him.
That's my car.
Somebody help me!
[INAUDIBLE]
ANDY DALY: Fuck you.
What are you going to
do now, asshole?
MALE SPEAKER: I will end you.
[APPLAUSE]
ANDY DALY: What the fuck was
that, you may well wonder?
Often, when a clip is shown in
a context like this, it's
explained first and
then shown.
But we'll do it the other way
around where it's shown in
total mystery and then
explained afterward.
I have a show premiering on
Comedy Central soon called
"Review," in which I play
character named Forrest, who
is a critic who reviews not
movies, or food, or books, but
life experiences.
So what's it like to steal,
what's it like to be a racist,
or what's it like to experience
road rage?
And so, as you're now beginning
to piece together
what you just saw,
in that piece--
here's what I would have said.
The character has borrowed his
intern's car to go experience
what it's like to
have road rage.
And the intern comes
along for the ride.
And here is what happens.
So, yeah, right?
[APPLAUSE]
In retrospect it's enjoyable.
So that's it for that.
Now, will you do some
improvising?
JOE WENGERT: Yeah, we're
going to watch
another YouTube video.
And we're going to improvise
off that.
ANDY DALY: Maybe we should
improvise first and then watch
the video that the improvising
is inspired by.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
ROB MENARD: You little
rascals.
You try to control the whole
world for your own benefit
without regard to the needs of
others or future generations.
You demand that we seek your
permission and pay your fees
to exercise our rights or
suffer being beaten with
sticks and shocked with tasers,
which incidentally,
you force us to buy.
You steal our wealth, you tax
our wages, our income, our
transactions.
You're burdening us and our
kids with a debt which can
never be repaid, so that you can
build bombs that you drop
on people on the other side of
the planet while you're safely
sipping champagne well out of
range, so you can eventually
do the same thing to them.
And you got us calling
that freedom.
You've raped the earth,
devastated diversity,
monopolized money.
You poison the air we breathe
and the water we drink.
You made organic food a thing
by ladening the food supply
with chemicals.
And you deny us our rights to
the point of jailing us for
the plants we grow.
You claim to be protecting us
from criminals and enemies by
calling us criminals, acting
like one yourself, and then
needlessly creating enemies
in our name
and with our resources.
You have denied the entire
planet peace in abundance in
order to fulfill your own
psychotic wanton greed and
lust for power.
Then you claim to be the
protector of our rights, but
then you abandon the biggest
and reject the best.
Oh, god, you use deception when
you craft your statutes.
You call them laws to justify
your aggression.
And you cloak it all up in
a great big flag of false
constitutionality.
You rely on fear.
Oh, man, you're experts at it.
You use fear to create
division.
And then ignorance--
you rely on ignorance
to insure obedience.
You've completely perverted
democracy buying politicians,
obstructed justice hijacking
the courts.
You caused us to lose faith
in our own institutions.
And best of all, you hindered
our spiritual growth and the
development of our
consciousness.
In short you've been very,
very, very naughty.
And we know it.
ANDY DALY: So I watched your
online dating video.
I just had some pointers, just
as like an online video dating
consultant.
It's my job to help people get
the most out of the service.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: That's
what I want.
ANDY DALY: And attract a mate
who's really going to be good
for you but also be someone
that exists.
You know what I mean?
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Well, I
believe there's somebody out
there for everybody.
ANDY DALY: I don't know.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Is it
the shirt choice?
Because I was in my head about,
like, do I just wear a
solid color?
Or should I do a pattern?
ANDY DALY: It was interesting
to me that the hat seemed to
be made out of the material
that the shirt was.
That suggests a certain
self-sufficiency.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: It used to be
a hoodie, and then I made
it more economical.
ANDY DALY: I think
I understand.
I would say that there is
somebody out there for the
best version of everyone,
right?
And that's what we want
to put out there.
So your video was, let
me actually ask you.
How long did you feel it was?
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Oh, god.
I mean this, can't be right.
But it must have been like
45 seconds or something.
Just like, it just flew by.
ANDY DALY: Fascinating.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL:
Like, a minute?
ANDY DALY: That's fascinating
that you would say that.
It was three hours and
25 minutes long.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL:
Was it really?
ANDY DALY: It really was.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Once you
just deep dive into your
heart, it's like,
[MAKES SOUND EFFECT].
ANDY DALY: Yeah.
It was--
it covered a wide range of
topics, questionable
interpretations of
history, science?
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Yeah, I mean,
I feel like I just kind
of want to put myself out
there as much as--
cast a wide net.
And then just kind of see what
kind of woman fish jumps into
the net and is like, take
me out of the water
where I can't breathe.
ANDY DALY: That doesn't
sound great.
JON GABRUS: I've watched
your video five times.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Really?
JON GABRUS: Yeah.
You seem amazing.
I agree with everything.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Oh,
yeah, yeah, yeah.
JON GABRUS: Soup to
nuts, all of it--
you're a genius.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: So you believe
that the Declaration
of Independence was actually
signed by dogs.
JON GABRUS: Yeah.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: That the
framers of the Constitution--
JON GABRUS: Were dogs.
They were dogs, and
they had dogs.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: That
we came from dogs.
JON GABRUS: We were all
originally dogs.
Yeah, I think that was the most
important message that
you had there.
Because I always have dreams
at night that I'm a Boston
terrier, urinating on
various things.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Oh!
I have a dream almost--
at least once a week where
I'm a various thing
getting peed on.
JON GABRUS: Me, too.
I only sleep once a week
for two hours.
So I have the dreams that--
well, I can't go to sleep.
Because just like in your video,
you said everyone's pod
casting your nightmares out to
various enemies and insurgents
and stuff like that.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Yeah, and
the second you close your
eyes, that's where they start
targeting the lasers at you.
And then, boom, you're going
to get blown up.
JON GABRUS: That's great.
Can I-- can I have
more napkins?
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Yeah,
yeah, yeah.
You have to get some roughage.
Absolutely.
JON GABRUS: Look, so, I think
this is going well.
If you wanna--
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: I
have to be honest.
I'm not totally feeling it.
I'm so sorry.
You're are an amazing girl.
I like you.
[APPLAUSE]
ALLAN MCLEOD: Yes, yes.
The missile will fly 5,000 miles
or so and blow up the
whole continent.
But I have a question.
Where's the room where
I drink my champagne?
Is it around here?
I didn't see the
champagne room.
I'd like to enjoy some
champagne as I
watch the world die.
TONI RAMOS: I could fashion
a champagne room for you.
I wasn't prepared for this.
ALLAN MCLEOD: Yes, you seem
more like a brainy science
geek who toys with missiles
and that sort of thing.
TONI RAMOS: Yes, I'm not
used to human contact.
I am just so thrilled
that you are around.
I could--
I have a bunch of Mountain Dew
or Red Bull I could mix
together for some sort
of champagne--
ALLAN MCLEOD: That's not the
ingredients for champagne.
That's not the ingredients.
TONI RAMOS: OK.
All right.
ALLAN MCLEOD: Really should hire
more wine connoisseurs or
something here at the factory,
at the missile factory.
Because I mean, who's funding
these sorts of operations?
People like me who wear furs and
expensive jewelry and like
to drink champagne
while people burn
up for no good reason.
TONI RAMOS: Oh, god.
Oh, gosh.
ALLAN MCLEOD: What are you
looking on the ground?
There's no rooms down there.
I want my champagne room.
JOE WENGERT: I'm afraid I have
some other bad news.
I just went to the area where
the lunch was set up.
And there are no caviar.
There are no king crab legs.
Can I please have the name of
your supervisor so that we can
complain to them now before
the world is destroyed?
Because we are very unhappy
with the job
that you've done here.
And you are going to perish
along with everyone else in
the world, but I want it to go
down on your record that you
are bad at what you do.
ALLAN MCLEOD: Very bad.
TONI RAMOS: I mean, we only
have mere minutes.
I have some jerky.
His name is Hank, if that's what
you're still looking for.
ALLAN MCLEOD: Jerky's
name is Hank.
TONI RAMOS: I have jerky.
My boss's name is Hank.
Please don't tell him.
I'm going to get fired.
JOE WENGERT: You thought we
wanted to snack on some jerky?
TONI RAMOS: It's all I have.
ALLAN MCLEOD: Benedict, what
kind of missile factory silo
is this place?
You're the one that found
them on the internet.
What--
JOE WENGERT: Their Yelp reviews
were off the charts.
TONI RAMOS: Thank you.
[APPLAUSE]
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: Excuse me.
Officer?
I'd like to turn myself in.
JON GABRUS: Sure.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS:
I raped the earth.
JON GABRUS: I don't have
time for any of this.
I got to do--
I got to file--
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: I did it.
I've been doing it for years and
I just woke up today, and
I realized I'm not
driving a Prius.
I'm an earth rapist.
I've been following the earth
back to its car at night, and
getting into my gas guzzling
shit of a car
and raping this planet.
Take me away.
JON GABRUS: I'm going to just
take you way for the way you
just talked to a police
officer, for starters.
Raping the earth?
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: Yeah.
JON GABRUS: Well, so what do you
call it, if unbeknownst to
the earth, you dig a little
hole, fuck it, and
then come in it?
DREW DIFONZO MARKS:
I don't, man.
Is that hole some fucking
asphalt that's eating away at
our nutrients?
Or is it a compost--
JON GABRUS: You don't
fuck asphalt.
You want mud or something
like that.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: Look,
man, you can rape the
planet how you want.
I'll rape the planet
how I want.
You can fuck it and
I can destroy it.
But my carbon footprint
is unforgivable.
I've been raping this
earth like it was a
fucking frat party.
Now, take me away.
I deserve it.
JON GABRUS: All right, man.
I'm going to take your prison,
where there's going to be gas
guzzling, or whatever
you refer to it.
ALLAN MCLEOD: All right.
Well, we ran the rape kit tests
on the earth like you
forced us to do.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS:
How bad is it?
ALLAN MCLEOD: I mean,
it's pretty normal--
there's some grass in it, some
bits of dirt and soil--
DREW DIFONZO MARKS:
I'm a monster.
ALLAN MCLEOD: There's no
evidence that you--
we can only arrest you if you
physically raped the earth.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: Now, did
you do a rape kit on the
general environment's area, on
this whole where that cop came
over and fucked it?
ALLAN MCLEOD: We did both--
JON GABRUS: [INAUDIBLE]
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: Hey, you
rape the earth your way.
I'll rape it my way.
ALLAN MCLEOD: Hey,
don't worry.
The earth was asking for it.
He's OK.
He's [INAUDIBLE] me.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: The earth
was asking for it?
Why?
Because of its shiny
blue oceans?
JON GABRUS: I mean, it's
covered in 70% water.
ALLAN MCLEOD: I mean, come on.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: That's
water that we need.
ALLAN MCLEOD: It's so wet.
It's so wet.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: Oh, so
it's just asking for it?
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: All
right, officers,
officers, get in here.
MALE SPEAKER: All right.
ANDY DALY: What?
MALE SPEAKER: Here's this?
ANDY DALY: I'm busy being
a police officer.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: We
need to have a
little sensitivity training.
It's come to my attention that
a number of you have been
making comments out when you're
interviewing suspects
about raping the earth, and how
the earth is asking for
it, and look at the way it's
dressed, and if it didn't want
to be raped it should have
stayed at Pangaea.
So from now on we just to look
at the earth as not an
acceptable thing to
talk about raping.
All right?
JON GABRUS: No matter--
OK.
Got it.
So like--
OK.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: No.
Let's put anything out there.
I want to know where
your heads are at.
All right?
ALLAN MCLEOD: It spread apart
from Pangaea, like you said.
It spread out.
JON GABRUS: I mean, if I'm
busting a couple of guys who
are smoking a blunt in their
car, why can't I bring up that
I think raping the
earth is OK?
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: How would that
even come up just in the
process of arresting
them for that?
JON GABRUS: You know,
you see something.
You're like, oh that's
from the earth.
Speaking of earth, you ever
seen the way it rotates,
taking 24 hours?
Yeah, you're showing it
off, motherfucker.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Kowalski,
you're having to do a lot of
work to bring rape
earth into that
conversation, I feel like.
ANDY DALY: Why is the earth
going out alone at night?
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Well,
technically, it's not going
out alone at night because it's
part of the solar system.
But even so, like would you say
that was OK for a woman?
Like would you say your mother
can't go out alone at night?
ANDY DALY: She cannot.
She's got a bad hip.
She needs help.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Right, but
you would never say to a
citizen that it would be OK to
rape your mother because she
has a bad hip, or because
she's going
out at night, right?
ANDY DALY: Certainly not.
[WHISPERS]
Yes, I would.
JOE WENGERT: I think what he's
saying is, why can't the earth
sync up with some of the other
planets, in terms of having
their orbits happen at the same
time so they're not out
there in space on their own?
ANDY DALY: That is exactly
what I am saying.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Are you
drawing a parallel between
earth's and other planets'
orbits and women's
menstruations?
JON GABRUS: What?
ANDY DALY: Whoa.
JON GABRUS: Whoa.
Slow it down, creepo.
No one was saying that.
JOE WENGERT: I'm saying that
they should hang out together.
I mean, earth and the other
planets don't have a problem
all going to the bathroom
together.
ANDY DALY: [LAUGHS]
JOE WENGERT: That didn't
make any sense.
No.
I realize now that
I think about it.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: All right.
I don't you feel uncomfortable,
Lewalski, but I
want to get a female perspective
here, all right?
JON GABRUS: Well why don't
we ask Darren?
He's part earth.
What do women have
to do with this?
ALLAN MCLEOD: He's a
herm-earth-rodite.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: What is he?
ALLAN MCLEOD: I always
mispronounce it.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS:
Say it again.
ALLAN MCLEOD: Herm-earth-rodite.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS:
Herm-earth-rodite?
ALLAN MCLEOD: Herm-earth-rodite.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: I'm
a herm-earth-rodite.
JON GABRUS: Yeah.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
with both a penis and
a layer of crust.
[APPLAUSE]
JOE WENGERT: Hey, Dean Ramos?
I'm sorry to bother you.
But I'm supposed to be teaching
an intro to art
history class in Williams
lecture hall and Ted Nugent's
down there.
And he's just in front of the
white board making some
YouTube videos.
TONI RAMOS: Ah, shit.
JOE WENGERT: And I can't get Ted
Nugent out of the lecture
hall by myself.
He's got a couple of
crossbows with him.
TONI RAMOS: Well, I'll
help you out.
Let's go.
JON GABRUS: And I know--
TONI RAMOS: Ted?
JON GABRUS: Dean.
TONI RAMOS: Yeah.
We need the room, all right?
JON GABRUS: But I have
the room til 4:30.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL:
I know you do.
JON GABRUS: I've signed
in with the activities
coordinator.
I have the room til 4:30.
JOE WENGERT: He does?
TONI RAMOS: He does.
But just give us five
minutes early out so
he can set up, please.
I know you're doing your rants
and the world needs to know
about them.
But give us--
JON GABRUS: I mean, I shaved
this flavor savor perfectly
for my big debut.
TONI RAMOS: What flavor
are you saving?
JON GABRUS: Venison and other
meats that I hunt myself.
Look, if you want the
room, square--
it's all yours.
JOE WENGERT: I just feel like
you could record your YouTube
videos from essentially
anywhere at all.
And you keep choosing--
JON GABRUS: But this is where
I keep my laptop.
JOE WENGERT: You're using
laptops wrong.
You could take laptops
anywhere.
You don't have to
keep them in--
JON GABRUS: But this is
where the outlet is
that I plug my laptop.
What don't you understand
about the
world around you, professor?
You could just call yourself
professor in
this world and teach.
You know who teaches?
I teach, to the masses, the
real word-- the word
of our Lord, me.
ALLAN MCLEOD: What's
going on in here?
I've got the room at 4:30.
That's right, me.
Jesse, The Body, Ventura--
former senator,
conspiracy-monger.
JON GABRUS: We knew by the
confidence and swagger in
which you entered the
room that you could
only be Jesse Ventura.
Good to see you again,
The Body.
ALLAN MCLEOD: Good to see you.
JON GABRUS: The Mind.
TONI RAMOS: You guys, I must
have overbooked the room.
So if we could just have
Professor Wengert come in,
just for this Wednesday, not a
big deal, and then you guys
can get back again.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Yeah
you did overbook it.
Because Randy Quaid
signed up there.
And I want to talk about how
the Hollywood hit mafia is
trying to assassinate
us celebrities.
I've been in Canada the
last four years.
This is the first time I came
down, just to make this video.
TONI RAMOS: You guys can
go in the hallway.
I'll show you.
Let me unplug the--
[SCREAMING]
JON GABRUS: Oh, no!
I didn't even save my files.
TONI RAMOS: No.
No, trust me.
I got it.
It's not a big deal.
Here we go, closing it down.
JON GABRUS: But I'm not in
the mainframe anymore.
TONI RAMOS: No, it'll work.
Trust me.
JON GABRUS: Mainframe
is everywhere.
TONI RAMOS: All right.
All right.
JON GABRUS: That's my
mainframe thing.
TONI RAMOS: That's your
mainframe thing?
Great.
Awesome.
All right.
So, guys, if you want
to follow me.
Mr. Wengert, if you
want to get your
class prepped and ready.
JOE WENGERT: Great.
Thank you again.
TONI RAMOS: Absolutely.
JOE WENGERT: You need help
with some of that stuff?
JON GABRUS: If you're going to
carry the laptop, I think I
can get all the guns.
I'll be all right.
ALLAN MCLEOD: I got to
get all my weights.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: And I left
all my "Christmas Vacation"
shit in here.
[APPLAUSE]
ANDY DALY: Hi.
How you doing?
I just want to let you know.
This produce over here,
this is all organic.
OK?
And then over here, it's just
full of chemicals that will
definitely shut your system
down like that.
I'm talking about immediate
organ failure.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: Wow.
You guys have really
changed the way
Trader Joe's is organized.
ANDY DALY: Yeah.
We just drew it-- you know,
everything used
to be mixed in together.
Now, we just got
it real clear.
Organic, you can eat
that and live.
Not organic--
immediate organ failure,
death upon ingestion.
And it's a little more expensive
for the organic.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: How
much are we talking?
Because I'm on a budget.
ANDY DALY: Typically like
25-- oh, hang on.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS:
Oh, my god!
TONI RAMOS: [GAGGING]
ANDY DALY: Just want
to explain to you.
Over here is organic.
Oh.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: Am I allowed
to just freely sample
like she did?
ANDY DALY: No.
I mean--
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: All right.
What I--
ANDY DALY: Yeah, that was
not supposed to happen.
Normally--
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Great,
I'm going to have
to clean that up.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: OK.
Well, based on this woman's
experience, I clearly see the
cons of eating what I'll just
call, the death food.
ANDY DALY: That's a
fair name for it.
Yeah.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: But
you also said that
this is more expensive.
So I'm torn.
ANDY DALY: It is a little more
expensive, typically a markup
of like 25% or more.
That's got be a better way
to clean up a dead body.
It's really--
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: He's just
hitting that body with a mop.
ANDY DALY: He's just--
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: Yep.
There it goes.
Yep.
ANDY DALY: --trying to
push her with a mop.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: He's
got to push it more.
The body is moving
towards the mop.
ANDY DALY: Yeah.
JON GABRUS: Need help
with this, Tim?
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Yeah,
would you mind?
JON GABRUS: What
happened here?
She hit herself on the corner of
desk, something like that?
JOE WENGERT: All right.
That's the end of
our second set.
[APPLAUSE]
JOE WENGERT: How you
guys feeling?
You're still in it with us?
[APPLAUSE]
JOE WENGERT: We're going to
do one more set of improv.
So we're going to watch one more
YouTube video before we
get into it.
RYKER DUNCAN: Kelsey,
you manipulate me.
You manipulate my mind.
You manipulate my heart.
You tell me how you were the one
that helped me get through
my dad's death, you were there
for me, how I promised my dad
that he would meet the girl of
my future before he dies, and
that you were the one.
And then today, you have the
audacity to go to someone else
after telling me that you were
falling back in love with me.
That shit don't fly with me.
I may have been dating Jess.
I didn't love her and
you knew that.
Use your fucking mind.
Of course, you don't have one.
They're too fucked up with
drugs, and alcohol, and all
the other poisoning.
You go out with someone who
you said raped you.
You keep getting your
heart broke.
Yet you keep going back
to the same guy--
same guys over and
over and over.
At least I don't do that.
Fact is, you want to
manipulate my mind.
You want to manipulate
my heart.
You want try to break me down.
It's not going to happen.
I'm a lot smarter than that.
I'm a lot smarter than a lot of
people give me credit for.
But if you want to try and
destroy me, and go that low,
say, oh I love you, oh, I'm
back in love with you, and
you're not, and it's just
a lie, do me a favor.
You do those drugs, you do that
alcohol, you end up dead,
and you burn.
Burn in hell.
Rest in peace, bitch.
[APPLAUSE]
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: All right,
YouTube employees.
All right, YouTube employees.
ALLAN MCLEOD: What's going
on, I'm excited.
ANDY DALY: Comedy week!
Comedy week!
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: We are
doing Comedy Week.
ANDY DALY: Comedy Week!
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Here's
what we got to do.
We need some funny videos
to inspire some comics.
ANDY DALY: Fuck, yeah!
MIKE LEFFINGWELL:
Just brainstorm.
What's like the funniest topics
you guys can think of?
ANDY DALY: Oh, like the
death of your father.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: OK.
All right, all right, all
right, all right.
All right.
That's a little heavy.
That's a little heavy for
the first one up.
But we're spit-balling.
No wrong answers, all right?
No wrong answers.
TONI RAMOS: A girl that keeps
going back to a guy that says
she's been raped by him.
ANDY DALY: I was hoping you
were going to say rape!
TONI RAMOS: Yes!
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: OK.
TONI RAMOS: It's Comedy Week!
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: It is.
OK.
But also, just think
like generic, like
broadly fun, silly--
ANDY DALY: Like somebody who's
so mentally ill that it's
depressing.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: OK, yeah.
You can objectively maybe
laugh at that.
JOE WENGERT: I have one that
I think is pretty funny.
It's a cat, and you don't
realize this when
you first watch it.
But the owner's holding its paws
out so it looks like it's
playing a keyboard.
And then you find out that cat
raped a bunch of other cats.
JON GABRUS: I was not on board
at first, and then something
piqued my interest
in the middle.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: I had the
exact opposite experience.
I was on board at first, that
sounded like a typical, fun
YouTube kind of thing.
And then--
I don't even know how we get
that information across there.
The cat raped--
JOE WENGERT: It's my cat.
And it has a problem with
raping other cats.
I cannot get it to stop.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: All right,
Drew, you had--
DREW DIFONZO MARKS:
What about this?
What if it's like a montage of a
bunch of different videos of
people getting kicked
in the nuts?
And every time they get kicked
in the nuts it plays like a
weird wacky sound effect,
like boing?
And then we actually pan out and
reveal that this is going
on inside the mind of a man
who is giving his suicidal
video into a video blog before
he puts a gun in his mouth.
Cries and says, this
is for you, Daddy.
And blows his brains out.
ANDY DALY: I like that.
JON GABRUS: I feel like we could
lose all the nut kicks,
and just get to the funny
stuff right off the bat.
ANDY DALY: Can we just
say this for sure?
Let's not show any, any videos
where it doesn't feel like at
the end, that person
either killed
someone else or himself.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL:
I mean, I guess.
I got to be-- so far, I'm
closest on board with that
last one, but really
in protest.
ANDY DALY: And preferably, we
could see the murder weapon in
the shot, if possible--
six or seven of them, swords,
or guns, or what have you.
JON GABRUS: What about that
channel we have on our site
that is all like diatribes that
people are giving right
before they set their cult
leader's house on fire?
You know the one, where the
people are just talking
directly to the camera
as the FBI is coming
in and killing them?
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Yeah,
I did not sign off on
that channel, guys.
JON GABRUS: It's Comedy
Week, chief.
It's comedy.
ANDY DALY: Comedy Week.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Wait.
I'm sorry.
So is it going to be like--
that's an example of
the video we do?
JON GABRUS: Let's use
those videos.
I think those videos
are the best.
They're two camera.
And they're people about
to be murdered, like
police-assisted suicide.
TONI RAMOS: It's like a quick
eight-minute thing and you get
to--there's lots of fun stuff.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Let me give
you guys an example.
Maybe somebody wearing something
kind of interesting,
or like a conversation starter,
doing a voice, or an
impression or something?
ANDY DALY: Like a mustache
they're too depressed to grow
out all the way.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: OK.
Yeah, yeah.
All right.
That's fine.
That's in the ballpark.
ANDY DALY: I think we know
what we're doing.
[APPLAUSE]
JON GABRUS: If you're nervous
at all about giving the
eulogy, I think you'll
be fine.
Just, if you can--
the last one was super intense
when Mom died.
So OK?
Just keep it low key, light,
maybe one anecdote, one joke.
And I'll be up here
to support you.
TONI RAMOS: Thank you.
Thank you so much.
JON GABRUS: And just remember,
not too much.
TONI RAMOS: Thank you all for
coming to my cunt of a
mother's funeral.
She was a real woman.
I loved her so much because
that fat, fucking bitch
wouldn't do anything.
And that's when I learned
to be a real woman.
JON GABRUS: Toni!
Toni.
TONI RAMOS: What's up?
It went all black and then
I just started going.
JON GABRUS: The services will
continue in a moment.
This always happens
at funerals.
You went a little dark.
You used the C-word
TONI RAMOS: Cunt?
JON GABRUS: That's the C-word
I was referring to.
TONI RAMOS: I didn't know
if it was cancer.
JON GABRUS: Yeah.
ALLAN MCLEOD: Boo.
Let's do the eulogy some more.
Boo.
JON GABRUS: Sir, could
you take the Solo
cup off your mouth?
We couldn't hear you.
ALLAN MCLEOD: Boo.
JON GABRUS: I think he wants
more of the eulogy.
Just light, light.
ALLAN MCLEOD: Tell
a funny story.
JON GABRUS: Thank you, sir.
TONI RAMOS: Uncle Jimmy--
a funny story.
When I was five, I started
ballet and have
continued on since.
And the first day of ballet
class, I remember, I got out
of the car.
I was so excited.
My mom grabbed my face.
And she took her cigarette
with her shaky hand.
And she burned my cheek.
And she said, you
fucking dance.
Dance, little baby, dance.
Mama's gonna go get drunk.
Mama's gonna get drunk and--
JON GABRUS: All right.
All right!
Toni!
Toni, I let you hang
out there.
I thought that story was
going to take a--
TONI RAMOS: It got so black.
And then I got dizzy and then
I didn't know what happened.
JON GABRUS: Well, what happened
was you told the
dance, you baby, dance story.
TONI RAMOS: Oh, my mom.
JON GABRUS: I know,
she was so--
TONI RAMOS: That was my first
burn she gave me.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: Boo,
we want more eulogy.
Not clearly videos stolen
from Comedy Week.
JOE WENGERT: Hey, Tina?
Can I ask you a question?
DREW DIFONZO MARKS: Sure.
JOE WENGERT: I heard that you,
uh, you passed around a
birthday card for Jerry's
birthday.
But you didn't come by and
ask me to sign it.
And I just wanted to let
you know that shit
don't fly with me.
If we are going to celebrate
someone's birthday in this
office, I better to be an
integral part of that
celebration.
Because if I find out
about it, that shit
don't fly with me.
DREW DIFONZO MARKS:
Tuck, two things--
number one, I am so sorry.
And number two, you are doing
great for your first week as
an intern here.
JOE WENGERT: I know I've
only been here a week.
But Jerry and I have shared
a couple of fun moments.
And I would have very easily
been able to reference one of
those moments into a message
on his birthday card that
would have made his
birthday brighter.
But then what do I find?
I got a fucking knife stuck
in my back by you, Tina.
ALLAN MCLEOD: Hey, man.
I'm sorry.
I forgot to give you the paper
clips back earlier.
I borrowed them.
I used a lot of them.
But I meant to give them back
to you sooner than now.
But anyway, sorry
about that, man.
Been a real busy day.
JOE WENGERT: You used a bunch
of my paper clips?
ALLAN MCLEOD: Yeah, but--
JOE WENGERT: I'm confused.
I though you were just going to
borrow them, and you said
you'd be right back with them.
ALLAN MCLEOD: Yeah, yeah.
Well, when they've all been
processed I'll-- if it's an
important to you I'll try to
gather those paper clips back
and return them to you.
JOE WENGERT: It's just that my
whole thing is you're going to
come over here, and take my
supplies and tell me that one
thing's going to happen
with them.
And then I come to find out that
a completely different
thing has happened with them.
And also, you're giving
me a timetable.
And then you might as well just
not even bother to do
that because it doesn't
mean a fucking thing.
That shit don't fly
with me, OK?
ANDY DALY: Hey, you
know, it Friday.
I think we're all just
going to knock
off around 3:00 today.
I know we talked about staying
until 4:30 or 5:00.
We're all going to
leave at 3:00.
Cool?
JOE WENGERT: I might need to
sit down for this one.
ANDY DALY: What's up?
No, we're all just going
to head out at 3:00.
Just going to take off
a little early.
JON GABRUS: Here's your chair.
Here's your chair.
JOE WENGERT: Thank you.
JON GABRUS: You're
welcome, please.
ANDY DALY: Just because Monday's
a holiday, figured
give everybody a jump on the--
JOE WENGERT: When I got up
this morning, I said, I'm
going to go in.
Get into the office around 9
o'clock like I normally do.
ANDY DALY: Yeah,
that was great.
We saw you at 9:00.
Great.
JOE WENGERT: And I was like,
maybe I'll hang out with my
buddies tonight.
Maybe I'll go out and hang
out with the gang.
ANDY DALY: That sounds great.
JOE WENGERT: And I said you know
what, I'll just send them
all an email.
Maybe we'll meet up later.
What time am I going to
put in the email?
Well, clearly I'll put
around 5 o'clock.
Because I know that the work
day here ends around 5
o'clock, at the earliest,
4:30.
And if for some godforsaken
reason, the powers that be
decide that we're going
to just shirk our
responsibilities and fuck off
at 3 o'clock, I, as an
employee, will be made aware
of such a decision.
But that hasn't happened.
So I know that the day ahead
of me is going to be smooth
sailing with what I normally
expect, working from 9 o'clock
til 5:00 PM.
ANDY DALY: You can
stay til 5:00.
JOE WENGERT: Oh, OK.
No problem.
[APPLAUSE]
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Here
we are in hell.
It's every bit as horrible
as I would have imagined.
What did you do to get here?
ALLAN MCLEOD: I had some
of that alcohol.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Yeah?
ALLAN MCLEOD: Yeah.
I had some of that alcohol.
JON GABRUS: Welcome
to hell, boys.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL:
Are you, uh--
JON GABRUS: Yeah, I'm one of the
devil's sidekicks, if you
can call me that.
I funnel his diarrhea
every day.
It's part of the hell gig.
Look, ah--
ALLAN MCLEOD: Out
of-- out of him?
Or into him?
JON GABRUS: Yeah, out of
him into my mouth.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Really?
JON GABRUS: Like, beer funnel.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Because I
would think a sidekick would
be like a position of like,
you're a step above the people
that are prisoners here.
JON GABRUS: And of course as you
know, it's part of hell.
You should probably know this.
But "Toonami" is cancelled.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Come on.
ALLAN MCLEOD: This
really is hell!
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: What
are they going
to show in its place?
JON GABRUS: There's a couple
of different programs they
might be airing.
There might be the John
Wayne Crazy hour.
It's a pun on Gacey.
Give me a second.
I'm trying to think of some.
ALLAN MCLEOD: You shouldn't have
to think of--I mean, they
already exist.
JON GABRUS: Yeah, yeah.
They all-- but you know, also,
I've had a steady diet of the
devil's diarrhea for the last
infinity amount of years.
So if you can cut me a
little slack here.
There is the, it's the Child
Abuse Power Hour, or like that
Power Child Abuse Hour.
I don't remember the exact--
ALLAN MCLEOD: Well, I
like those names.
JON GABRUS: But more
importantly, the worst part
about hell is that "Toonami"
has been canceled.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Look, I'm not
100% sure I belong here.
The only thing that I ever did
in my life was I broke up with
my boyfriend.
And I'm going through
everything.
He was really upset.
Like, he was really,
really mad.
JON GABRUS: Why did you
break up with him?
Was it because--
MIKE LEFFINGWELL:
He was crazy.
He was like a crazy guy.
He was really weird.
He was totally different from
the point that I met him until
the point when I decided
to break up with him.
JON GABRUS: You broke up with
him because he raped you, and
that was like a known thing
around the school?
ALLAN MCLEOD: We're dealing
with like hell-type stuff
here, so we're assuming it was
a pretty severe breakup.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: Yeah, sorry.
Wait, wait.
If he raped me, then I
would go to hell for
breaking up with him?
JON GABRUS: Well, I'm
not saying that.
ALLAN MCLEOD: You might have
been asking for it.
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: I'm
not a planet.
ALLAN MCLEOD: That's
too far in hell?
JON GABRUS: In hell, that's
a little touchy.
ALLAN MCLEOD: That's
crossing the line?
MIKE LEFFINGWELL: No, just,
nothing happened specifically.
I just broke up with him.
Because I was like,
I don't want to be
involved with this guy.
He's just weird.
JON GABRUS: OK.
I'm really sorry I
came over here.
JOE WENGERT: I was going to
run out and grab lunch for
everybody down here in hell.
I was going to go
to McDonald's.
Do you guys want McRibs?
ALLAN MCLEOD: McRib is back?
JOE WENGERT: Just kidding.
There's no McRibs
ever in hell.
[YELLING]
DREW DIFONZO MARKS:
That's our show!
[APPLAUSE]
ALLAN MCLEOD: Good
night everybody.
Thanks for watching.
Appreciate it.
JOE WENGERT: Guys,
thanks a lot for
watching UCB Comedy Live.
Please come back tomorrow night
for stand-up night at
the same YouTube,
wherever you're
watching this on the internet.
Thanks a lot.
[ROCK MUSIC]
ANNOUNCER: Tomorrow night on
Comedy Week Live, it's all the
fun of a comedy club with none
of the chicken fingers.
Tune in for stand up from Jim
Hamilton, Iliza Shlesinger,
Brody Stevens, Ron Funches, Todd
Womack, Kyle Dunnigan,
and Sean Patton.
Tomorrow on Comedy Week Live.
[MUSIC PLAYING]