FEMALE SPEAKER: On the 1st of
May, the small Swedish town of
Eskilstuna, one hour west
of Stockholm, went
from this to this.
[HEAVY METAL MUSIC]
The extreme right groups
Svenskarnas Parti and
Forbundet Nationell Ungdom
had chosen the sacred
international labor movement day
and the city of Eskilstuna
to spread their xenophobic
agenda, Swedish jobs for
Swedish workers.
This is did not go down well
with the left-wing kids, who
won't stand for extreme right
marches on their streets,
especially not on May
Day, which is a
huge deal in Sweden.
They founded the organization
First of May for All and began
planning a massive counter
demonstration.
We met up with them
as they started
gathering in the city center.
[SPEAKING SWEDISH]
FEMALE SPEAKER: While more and
more people joined Kim and his
friends in the
counter-demonstration, the
nationalists started
gathering at their
assigned meeting points.
Despite supporters coming from
Norway and Germany, the
turnout wasn't exactly
massive.
[SPEAKING SWEDISH]
FEMALE SPEAKER: The counter
demonstration soon gained some
unexpected momentum.
They managed to form a blockade,
preventing half of
the nationalists from
joining their peers.
The blocked nationalists
eventually managed to break
away, marching straight into
a park where families were
having picnics.
Some kids from the
counter-demonstration
followed, throwing bottles
and rocks at them.
The nationalists got pissed
off and trashed some poor
guy's car in the process.
When the nationalists finally
began their march, hundreds of
people, everyone from thugs,
dogs, grannies, to the Black
Bloc stormed the streets
to form a blockade.
[CHANTING IN SWEDISH]
FEMALE SPEAKER: Then some
troublemakers started throwing
rocks at the nationalists, and
it all erupted into violent
riots, sending at least eight
people to hospital with
cracked skulls.
After about an hour-long stand
off, the nationalists started
marching, protected
by the police.
But they were forced to take
an alternative route.
The kids from the
counter-demonstration started
running, taking a shortcut to
form another blockade further
up the street.
But they were chased away by
the riot police and their
angry dogs.
This process kept repeating
itself all afternoon.
Like ferrets on speed, the
counter-demonstration had
become a living organism that
just wouldn't budge until the
nationalists had gone home.
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYING]
[SHOUTING]
[HORN SOUNDING]
[SPEAKING SWEDISH]
FEMALE SPEAKER: The police lost
control over the city and
had to call in reinforcements
from Stockholm and other
nearby areas.
Realizing they wouldn't reach
their destination, the extreme
right groups decided to hold
their speeches from the back
of a rental truck, but only
the nationalists gathered.
The police a few booing counter
demonstrators could hear them.
At 6:00 PM, their demonstration
permit ended,
and the police escorted
the nationalists
back to their cars.
By then, extra police forces
from Stockholm and the
surrounding areas had arrived
and began mass searching the
counter-demonstrators and
forcing them into buses.
Some of them broke away to
bid the nationalists
a final, fond farewell.
[CHANTING IN SWEDISH]
[PUNK MUSIC PLAYING]