I say it's over, unless there are
other questions that you have
which you don't understand.
This is the application of relativity,
that all things are relative.
You can't know exactly
the way things work.
You can only know
what you can receive.
There's a gadget
that scientists use
to see if there's an
electromagnetic field here.
They also have a gadget
they lower from an airplane
(like a big disk) with an electric
current going around in a circle.
There's a lot of
iron under the land
and it slows up the
electric current.
Instead of going around
geologically looking for iron
the airplane drops this down,
and it flies over the Earth
and it tells you
where the iron is
(do you understand?
) by a current moving around in a coil.
It's called a magnetometer.
That's how they know.
In the old days they used to
dig down, find metals and say
"This is a good place for it!"
Nowadays, with a prism,
a certain type of prism
arranged in a certain way,
if you aim it at a star.
It tells us there's no
oxygen on that star
no nitrogen, no water.
The prism, the color bands, tell
you what there is on that planet.
It was discovered accidentally
when the Germans made airplanes
that were lighter and stronger.
They didn't know what it was made of.
They heat the metal
so it's bright white hot and
run it through a prism.
They get a color band,
and the color band says:
2% magnesium, 1% carbon, cobalt
(you know what I mean?).
It's called spectral analysis.
We can turn a spectrum
on anything today
and if we heat it so it's white hot,
we can tell what it contains.
That's how they knew
there's no air on the moon
before they ever went there,
but normal people [ask]
"How did they know there's no air on the moon?
They've never been there!"
There are other ways, but they
don't know about spectroscopes.
Do you know about
spectral analysis?
A lot of people don't know about
those things, so they [say]:
"How the hell do they know?
My opinion is just as good as theirs!"
They don't look into it and
say "How do they know?"
They speculate, you
know what I mean?
That's why we have so
much trouble with people
because they do not have a common
way of seeking information.
They say "If you ask me, I think my
opinion's just as good as yours."
Good.
People want to
feel equal to you.
They say "That's your opinion,
now I'm going to give you mine."
They think one opinion
is as good as another
and that's valid amongst people that
don't know how to check things out.
They should say "I wonder how they
know there's no water on the moon"
but wondering that, they don't
go to their computer and say
"How do people know that?"
I don't know if your
computer will handle that
but your computer will
tell you every phase
of metals with a memory.
If you put in
'metals with a memory' or you put
in 'materials with a memory'
you'll get more than
metals with a memory.
If you put in 'What is memory?'
(you know what I mean?
) That's another question altogether.
We don't ask those questions
because we're not brought
up to ask such questions.
We're brought up [with]: If you
get money you can buy anything;
a Rolls-Royce, or a big
house with 40 rooms.
Most aims are for money, not
scientific instruments.
If you wonder why do people
only think of making money?
[It's] because they can buy any
car, any house, pay off people.
Money is a symbol and it can
get you anything you want.
If you study chemistry, you
might learn about chemicals
but you can't afford to
live in a nice house.
That's why people
are money-oriented.
Not because they're
bad or greedy.
[It's] because money gives
them what they want
and without it they can't
have what they want.
Is that real clear?
It's rewarding to people.
If helping people is rewarding
you instead of money
that's different, but
you'll be abused by it.
You'll have to drive a
car that breaks down
because you don't have the money to
buy a car that doesn't break down.
A brand new Mercedes will last
longer than the average car
but you can't afford that.
If you use magnetic braking,
it will last longer
but you can't afford it.
People with money ask "What's
the best braking system?
I'll take two.
" You know what I mean?
"How do I make my house fireproof?
" "You do this. You do that"
and they can afford it.
Without money, you're
pissed off by people
sleeping in the street.
You're broke.
Everybody says "This
guy is a bum!"
I've met, what they call 'bums'
that were so well read, that they
didn't want any part of the system.
They lived in poverty.
I think I told you about the guy in Haiti
with a shirt made of
nothing but patches.
I couldn't tell which
was the real shirt
because it was so patched up.
He was well informed
in semantics.
The shirt he wore looked like a
guy put a hand grenade in it
and blew it up.
There were holes all over it
and torn, and he still buttoned
it up because that's all he had.
He loved to read, and he
was very well informed
in what he read
but he was pissed
on by everybody.
I talked to him for hours.
He was bright as hell
but he couldn't identify with
being part of the world.
So, they were considered bums
and I consider politicians, bums
and people that
design bombers, bums
and the people that made
the atom bombs, dangerous
because they gave it to people who
were not wise enough to use them.
They couldn't take that into account,
but they loved the challenge
of solving the problem.
Even the Bible says "Cast
ye not pearl before swine."
You know what that means?
If you give a pig a pearl
it doesn't say "Gee
that's great, thank you!"
If you give an atom bomb
to an undeveloped country
they'll blast the hell out of
people they disagree with.
They'll poison the Earth.
They don't care about that.
They're not wise
enough to use it.
That's what "Cast ye not pearl
before swine" means to me.
Don't give people atom bombs.
Don't give people bombers
unless they learn to
live together in peace!
You give them airplanes,
spectroscopes and things like that
so they can educate kids
in spectral analysis
and magnetometers, and all the
things they don't know exist.
They will not make
their own conclusions.
They'll say "Let's put a spectrometer
on that and try to find out."
They don't even think that way today.
They think
"Man will always be greedy,
no matter what you do."
You can say that man
has always been greedy
due to scarcity or fear of loss.
A man can have a million
dollars and still steal
because he wants to
secure his position.
He wants to make damn sure
that even if the banks fail
he has money buried
under the mattress
or under the ground in a
trunk in the backyard.
People are insecure because
they've known banks to fail
and all their money that they
put in the banks is gone
because the bankers called
other bankers and said "Hey!
We're going to sell out.
We're going to close down in three months.
Take your money out" to their
friends in the banking business.
They did that first, so
there was nothing left
even though a guy worked all his
life and saved up $800,000.
When the bank failed, they were
lined up outside the banks
demanding their money.
The banks said "We don't have it"
and the people killed
themselves because they felt
they'd let their families down.
So people that don't
put money in the banks
they have a locker in banks
where you can put cash
and it gets no interest
but that can't be touched by the banks.
They can't invest it.
In that way came a
form of security.
If you put a million dollars
in the bank, if you did that
and you get interest, you get
about $50,000 a year in interest
so you don't have to
worry about anything.
You can live on $50,000 a year as
long as your million stays there.
And that puts it on the
back of other people.
[Roxanne]
- We should... I should go down and... - Yes, OK.
That was the last portion of a
talk on the subject of relativity
and he covers some other
things in there, as well.
If you'd like to
hear more of that
as well as other
lectures in audio format
please go to the twitter
page that we just set up
where we will post links to more
new material including answers
to questions and more
current update briefs.
I'll put a link to
the twitter below.
In addition to the
Venus Project tours
which are given on
scheduled Saturdays
Jacque continues to give
new lectures almost daily
in which he covers all areas of
social designs, human behavior
and more in depth issues that are
important to consider and understand
when learning about this
direction and way of thinking.
We're also doing our best to get
these talks edited and released
onto DVD and expect to have
about 15 to 20 new lectures
available as soon as we can.
If you check on thevenusproject.
com, you go to the store
check that out.
In the next hopefully few weeks
there will be some new
material available there.
Thanks for watching, and
also The Venus Project
is appreciative of
everybody that's out there
in the trenches talking about
these ideas that are not so easy
to talk about with
'normal people'.
As Jacque always says "We
have a tough job ahead of us
but I'd rather have a tough job
than to go along with this system."
Thanks! sub-like-favorite-friend
Twitter: @frescotweets