I'm wondering, what's
your plan as far as
summer loving goes?
MALE SPEAKER 1: As
far as what?
MALE SPEAKER 2: Summer living?
XIA HWANG: Summer loving.
MALE SPEAKER 2: Somewhere
loving?
Or somewhere--
XIA HWANG: Summer.
Summer.
FEMALE SPEAKER 1: Summer
is the worst period
to find a good guy.
MALE SPEAKER 3: Girls in NYC are
a little bit more guarded.
You walk down the street and you
try to talk to one, they
think you're a psycho
or something.
MALE SPEAKER 3: In general,
I live and love.
So I love all humans.
So I get to be in love
all the time.
XIA HWANG: Where do you think is
the sexiest place in Paris?
MALE SPEAKER 5: My home.
XIA HWANG: Do you mind to
tell us your location?
MALE SPEAKER 5: No.
XIA HWANG: Men who wear
shorts, do you
think they're sexy?
FEMALE SPEAKER 2: No.
XIA HWANG: What about
flip-flops?
FEMALE SPEAKER 2: Flip-flops?
XIA HWANG: Do you think French
people are into Asian girls?
MALE SPEAKER 5: No.
MALE SPEAKER 3: I definitely
like certain things.
I like light skin.
I like half-black, half-white.
I like Latin girls.
But then again, Scarlett
Johansson is awesome.
When I get some more external
power, I'm totally going to
take you on a date.
XIA HWANG: Do you think you'll
bring God to the
bedroom with you?
MALE SPEAKER 5: I don't
leave God anywhere.
I make love.
I don't fuck anymore.
XIA HWANG: If you can take a
girl that you love on a date
in the summer, where would
you like to bring her to?
MALE SPEAKER 2: In the summer,
somewhere nice.
First, I'd like to
know her first.
Because you can't just take
any girl anywhere, right?
MALE SPEAKER 3: The woods.
A lot more fun.
Tie each other to trees.
It's all fun and games.
Just don't do it during
hunting season.
XIA HWANG: Are you afraid that
when that's happening you hear
people shooting guns?
MALE SPEAKER 3: The gunshots
don't bother me.
I'm a gun owner.
XIA HWANG: How can a girl
catches your eye?
MALE SPEAKER 2: Catch my eye?
One girl?
Be alone.