INTERVIEWER: Damn.
Lucky.
Wait, tell me about
this place.
DYLAN RIEDER: I don't want to
reveal too much information.
INTERVIEWER: You've gotta
tell me something, Bro.
DYLAN RIEDER: It's just
a private facility me
and some guys got.
I designed the [INAUDIBLE]
corner,
that was my main piece.
INTERVIEWER: And we're
not supposed to
be filming in here?
DYLAN RIEDER: I don't think
we're supposed to
be filming in here.
Whatever, I pay rent, so.
I might get yelled
at for this.
But, whatever, my life.
PATRICK O'DELL: What's up?
Welcome back to Epicly
Later'd.
This episode's about Dylan
Rieder whose hands down one of
the best pros out right now.
He just came out with a part
on gravis, just him as the
whole video, and it's amazing.
I guess the only reason he made
it is because he wasn't
really that satisfied with the
Alien Workshop part that came
out a year ago.
Dylan's amazing, I hope
you enjoy the episode.
DYLAN RIEDER: I grew up in
Westminster, a little north of
Huntington Beach, kind of like
Korean, Mexican town, a lot of
pool halls, a lot of pho.
I don't think anybody's really
from Westminster, none of whom
that skates.
Just Huntington Beach, Dells
from Huntington Beach.
I think, Templeton's
from Huntington.
Like you ever been to that murdy
park down there, it's
like a little ashtray park, I
think Templeton designed it.
INTERVIEWER: Yeah,
the famous one.
DYLAN RIEDER: No, I think in
Huntington Park's the famous
one over by the high school.
Then there's another one before
that, that was smaller,
before Huntington Park.
But we used to go there,
because we were too
intimidated to go to Huntington
Park, because
that's where Andrew went and all
those those Warren Avenue
crew dudes, at the time.
I was like 11, maybe 10.
I remember seeing like Andrew
at Huntington Park for the
first time, I was pretty
star struck.
Saw Penny there a couple times
when I was little.
That old Penny footage
there is awesome.
He rips that place.
It's not there anymore, they
took it out, demolished it to
extend the football fucking
field, which is stupid.
INTERVIEWER: So how
old are you now?
DYLAN RIEDER: 21.
INTERVIEWER: OK, that seems like
you'd be real young when
that was going on.
DYLAN RIEDER: Yeah,
I was super young.
Such a little shit head.
MARK OBLOW: I first met Dylan,
I was doing a photo shoot for
Quicksilver for their
youth campaign.
I would shoot whoever
they would bring.
They would bring models,
or whatever.
And then at that point Dylan
actually had come in, like
they picked him as a
little boy model.
And he had come in like that
like, and they're like, oh, we
brought a little skater guy,
and I was super anti.
I was like, [PHEW], totally
get away from me.
We shot some photos, and then
they needed action photos.
So then I sent Tim to go shoot
some stuff with Ortiz, because
I was like, I ain't even going
to waste my fucking time.
I talked to Ortiz later, and I
was like, hey, how'd that go?
And Ortiz was like, Dude,
he's pretty gnarly.
And I'm like, what
do you mean?
What was he pretty gnarly?
He's actually like, Smith Grind
this rail and he kick
flipped down these stairs.
And I was just like, what?
Get the fuck out of
here, whatever.
So then, Damn Am comes around,
he basically is like, can I
come enter the Damn Am?
Can I enter under Quicksilver?
And I'm like, yeah go for it,
whatever, it's totally cool.
And then next thing you know,
he won the contest.
And I was just like,
what the fuck?
From that point on, he basically
went on pretty much
every single trip that I
did for Quicksilver.
These are the fucked up ones.
Like this, this was the
first Miami trip.
That was his first
trip with us.
That was with Janoski, and
Donny Barley, and Reece.
But like that was--
INTERVIEWER: He's got braces?
MARK OBLOW: Yeah,
he's got braces.
He was such a little,
like, little guy.
The old team right there.
GREG HUNT: I mean, that's
something I even, like, I
skate with him all the
time and I forget.
Like when he was like 12, he
was going on trips with the
Quicksilver guys, like Reece,
Stefan, and he was just like
the little kid with
men, you know.
And then also with Osiris, I
think he went on like a bunch
of trips with Jerry,
and all those guys.
So he's got like some
pretty deep roots.
Like, once in a while I'll see
these old photos, be like, Oh
yeah, were like, one of
those little kids.
Misled Youth, or whatever,
was his favorite video.
And like, he had like super skin
tight pants, he was like
13 years old, he's like one of
those kids, like lip sliding
15-stair hand rails,
or something.
Going out with his buddies at
night, like lighting stuff up
like a bunch of like
15-year-old kids.
Like trying to skate like most
gigantic hand rail and almost
killing themselves, you know.
MARK OBLOW: Jerry has a portrait
of him somewhere.
And it's just like this portrait
of this baby, it's
like Dylan, it's like
this baby face.
JERRY HSU: I first met Dylan
when I rode for Osiris.
And I think Chris Pastras was
our team manager at the time,
and I don't know where
he found him.
I think he went to like a
contest or something, and just
found this kid, and just brought
him on some trips.
That's how I'd first met him,
I'd never heard of him, or
seen photos of him, or
anything like that.
But I just trust Chris, because
he had good taste.
Me and Louie on tour we would
kind of try to take care of
him and make sure he
didn't get into too
much trouble or anything.
He was so young.
He was really quiet.
He never said anything.
He was just this really quiet
kid, with like braces.
It's funny, like he
was really shy.
Girls always wanted to
talk to him, and
like hug him and stuff.
He was just like this adorable
little kid, and like he was
just so shy, and like he didn't
really-- and it was all
really new to him, just being
sponsored and traveling.
You could tell he was
a mature kid.
He wasn't like just some spaz.
Like normally kids at that age
you can tell that they don't
really know how to skate yet.
I mean, maybe they could do hard
tricks, but they can't
really skate.
But Dylan could skate
everything, and like skate
really well.
Like, we liked him
a lot right away.
We really liked his skating.
DYLAN RIEDER: When Osiris came
out with the Subject to Change
video, I shared a part
with "the Butcher".
I was excited, it was the first
video I was filming for.
I was like 15, 14.
When I was that age all I really
did was like skate
rails and stuff.
GREG HUNT: He kind of got
labeled as like a little rail
kid, because that's all he was
really skating was rails.
Once again, seeing a little
kid in the beginning.
He thinks one way,
and then he gets
influenced by someone else.
He really got influenced with
Tony T and those guys.
And Tony was, I think, a big
influence with him, and so was
Donnie Barley.
And those guys, what kind of
set them apart, was their
being able to skate tranny.
It really hit him, and I think
the way he looked at skating
bowls, and skating tranny.
And, like I actually made him
enter the first contest.
And he did pretty bad.
And then he went back the second
year, and he actually
got 13th place, which is pretty
gnarly for Marseilles.
This was actually that one
he rode in Marseilles.
That was the one where
he got 13th place.
That was pretty gnarly,
stoked on out.
INTERVIEWER: That was
an Am contest?
MARK OBLOW: No, it was pro.
It was pro, that was when he
did, and that was before
anyone, I mean, I saw doing
them was the no-comply
tail-side reverts.
He did that in there,
in one of his runs.
And then he did like, there was
a wall, a vert wall, and
he did like, kick flip front
side wall rides, and kick flip
backside wall rides, but like
super high and popping.
He was skating more
like, doing more
technical and flip stuff.
It was good, I think, it was
just good for him to like
break out of the little
rail kid deal.
JERRY HSU: After all the Osiris
stuff, I would just
kind of see him around.
I didn't see him for years,
and then he just grew up.
I guess I feel kind
of like proud.
It's not like I played like
a big part in his life, or
anything, but it was just cool
to see him go from like a
little kid to just like a full
blown, like totally well
respected skater.
INTERVIEWER: Are you psyched
to be in another episode?
DYLAN RIEDER: Yeah, I feel like
it's good that I make my
cameo every three or
four episodes.
That's good.
INTERVIEWER: You're in the
[INAUDIBLE] for no reason.
DYLAN RIEDER: Yeah like--
INTERVIEWER: [INAUDIBLE]
occasionally pan over to you
[INAUDIBLE]
DYLAN RIEDER: Yeah, Yeah, I
don't know, that day I just
felt like being in an episode.