Oh!
[LAUGHING].
That's what Mike was
talking about.
[LAUGHING].
FEMALE SPEAKER: Kick your ass.
LIZARD KING: Ha ha!
Did you just see that?
DON NGUYEN: Can't stand still.
He just has to keep
moving and shit.
Yeah, he's always been the
same-- super fucking hyper.
ANDREW REYNOLDS: Like, out
of everybody on a tour or
something like that, he's
probably up first--
him and Antwuan, but Antwuan's
mellow-- but he's up first and
just jumping and punching near
your face and stuff first
thing from like 8:00 all day
long, until he goes to bed.
I don't know where
he gets it from.
He's just hyped up.
LIZARD KING: [SINGING]
DON NGUYEN: There was 26 fools
rolling in three vans.
MALE SPEAKER: That was nuts.
DON NGUYEN: The sessions that
were going down were
in-fucking-sane.
MALE SPEAKER: Is there like
sober van and wastoid van?
DON NGUYEN: Yeah, there's like
the boss van, the fucking
syrup van, and then our van was
just like, whatever man.
MALE SPEAKER: Do you ever give
Lizard or Antwuan talks about
their drinking, or drugs,
or anything?
JIM GRECO: Yep.
To each his own.
Everybody's different.
Like Dustin, Dustin Dollin, he's
fueled by the alcohol.
But yet it destroys his body,
so that's where it gets him.
But he's invincible
on the alcohol.
Lizard is similar.
Lizard's similar, but he
rips drunk or sober.
He's got a little bit more
common sense than Dustin.
LIZARD KING: Oh,
you're on acid?
He's like, go skate the bowl.
What do you mean, go
skate the bowl?
I'm like, I can't skate
the bowl right now.
I don't want to skate
I'm fucked up.
He's like, no, try it.
Let's go test it out.
Went outside, we walked inside,
went to the bowl,
shredded the fuck out
of the bowl, right?
I came back, turned to
him, and was like,
skating on acid is tight.
It's the best shit ever.
JIM GRECO: I just tell him how
it was like for me about
drinking and shit.
That it affects you.
Choices you're making now.
And just to be careful and try
to figure out in your head
what you want to do before
you ruin your chances.
LIZARD KING: He's always
like, dude, I'm
going to pray for you.
I mean, I know you don't want me
to, but I'm going to do it.
He's not into the whole
Satan thing.
I think he thinks of me as a
jinx, maybe, or something.
He's just a nutcase, kind of.
I mean, all of us are
nutcases, but--
MALE SPEAKER: When you're on
death wish, do any of the
other pros like Andrew--
like, some of the older dudes,
do they ever give you pep
talks or coach talks?
LIZARD KING: Yeah, yeah.
Sometimes like how if I got
sober, how much better I'd be
at skating, and fucking--
a bunch of shit, and how I'm
a drug addict and shit.
I think it's pretty funny.
That's all we do, pretty much,
shit is pretty funny.
But then the older guys are
all sober and shit.
Well, not all off them,
but, I mean, Shane,
Drew, fucking Jim.
It's kind of weird.
And the best part is they'll
still put footage out that's
really old of them, but it's
of them partying and shit,
just to make the part
more hijinks
and exciting or something.
MALE SPEAKER: You think you'll
eventually quit drinking and
be like those dudes?
Go into that rag?
LIZARD KING: Me?
Fuck, I don't know.
I probably should.
But I'm kind of like, I
like being a pile of
shit, though, you know?
We should make another cruiser
board that's like
a AA meeting directory.
MALE SPEAKER: [LAUGH].
And when you get sober, you
get the sobriety cruiser.
It's like the AA book.
[LAUGHTER].
LIZARD KING: Isn't that
like, 8 o'clock,
Tuesday, fucking pep talk.
That would be fucking
hilarious.