SAM: Timothy DeLaGhetto.
PETER: Taryn Southern.
SAM: Brock Baker.
PETER: Megan Batoon.
SAM: We just did a collab with
VitalyzdTV, the biggest prank
guy in YouTube.
PETER: It was really
cool because it
was the first time he acted
in a scripted comedy thing,
and we got to be a part of that.
MALE SPEAKER: A-P-P-L-E.
MALE SPEAKER: Correct.
[CHEERING]
FEMALE SPEAKER:
What are you doing
with your life that's so great?
MALE SPEAKER: I just made
$5,000 tonight, spelling.
MALE SPEAKER: Oh, whoopity doo.
MALE SPEAKER: Going up against
the Martini brothers tonight.
They've never lost a battle.
MALE SPEAKER: B.
MALE SPEAKER: A.
MALE SPEAKER: N.
MALE SPEAKERS: Banana.
MALE SPEAKER: Correct.
SAM: And it turns out, we
share the same sense of humor
with Vitaly.
PETER: And we're both hardcore
freestyling street spellers.
SAM: Please go watch our other
videos, "Tinder the Movie"
and "Darth Vader in Love."
PETER: And if Vitaly hasn't
died filming one of his pranks,
he's probably going to put
up something next week.
SAM: Dude, he hasn't put
out anything in a while.
PETER: He might be dead.
SAM: Oh my god.