FREDDY CORBIN: I tell them the
story, you know, well, I did
my brother's funeral here, and
I got married, and I'm having
a baby, so I'm kind of coming
back for good juju for his
birth and stuff like that.
And they just got it.
They're way into thinking
like that.
You know what I mean?
So they just totally got it.
We were trying to figure
out a place to tattoo.
They told them what I was doing,
and asked them if it
was OK if I tattooed
at the temple.
They really dug the intention
of what we were doing.
They were just dumbfounded, why
would you come here and
tattoo us for free?
Now, the temple would literally
only fit a few
people in there.
But we would do a puja every
morning, build an altar donate
fruit to the sadhus,
the Brahmin
priests that are monastic.
My friend, Vinnie, that I was
telling you about, made a big
flower mandala.
We decorated the whole temple
with flowers and
marigolds and stuff.
It was really beautiful.
It was really magical.
So I just drew up this piece of
flash, any of these seven
designs for free.
I wrote it out in Hindi that
there was no charge.
It was only symbols.
It was religious symbols.
So there was a Tibetan om, a
Hindu om, a Buddhist om, a
cross, and a swastika with a--
The swastikas over there usually
has four dots in them,
one for each element.
And it's funny because I did
tons of crosses, and I didn't
do one swastika, which I thought
was kind of unusual.
But they were like, since World
War II, we don't really
push the swastika so much.
It's all over our religious
artwork.
It's all over our buildings and
our clothes, but, at the
same time, they get that it
kind of hurts people's
feelings, in a way, which I
thought was pretty cool.
There was probably 50 guys
hanging out, and everybody's
like, oh, me, me, me, me,
me first, me first.
So we were basically trying
to figure out how are
we going to do this?
And are we going to
give them tickets?
So my friend, Little Mary,
was really good.
She had a great idea.
She's like, just take a Sharpie
and just draw a number
on them and sign it.
So I would basically just
write number one,
cross, and sign it.
Number two, om, sign it.
Dustin, my apprentice,
was just on point.
He was right there next to me,
handing me a clean set up as
soon as I--
I'd take a smoke break every
four or five or whatever, but
we worked pretty labor
intensively because we were
tattooing under the
light of day.
MALE SPEAKER: Were you the
only guy tattooing?
FREDDY CORBIN: Yeah.
Going into the night, I
had a head lamp on.
So we only had a little bit
after dark to do it before
they had to do the closing
ceremony and lock
the doors and stuff.
Then we'd go in back
and smoke hash with
the priests and stuff.
It was really awesome.
A really sweet thing when I was
there the first time, I
met this two really cool kids.
It was Raj and Raju,
they're brothers.
So Raj wanted to be
the first one.
He's like, Freddy, can
I be the first one?
Of course, of course.
And just perfect for India
because no rules apply.
I had the seven that you could
only get, but at the bottom,
there was a little pyramid
with an eye,
and he wanted that.
So the first thing I did was
break the rules of only
getting the seven and then
everybody was like,
well, can I get it?
And I was like, no,
no, no, only Raj.
Only Raj.
So I tattooed a cross on his
younger brother's neck and it
looked pretty cool.
I mean, it was on his neck, he's
like 16 years old now.
And my cut off point
was 15 years old.
So there was a lot of kids there
wanting to get tattooed,
and I'd say, I can't
touch you, your
parents would get mad.
I have no parents.
I am alone in the world.
They give you this shtick.
You know half the time
it's true, maybe.
I don't know.
There was a deaf
kid named Raul.
He was deaf and dumb.
And he obviously couldn't speak
or hear, and the older
guys would let him
hang around.
But you'd see other guys kind
of fucking with him a little
bit, like teasing
him and stuff.
He was young, so
he kept saying,
I want to get tattooed.
I was like, no, no, no, no.
And so after the first night,
I went to dinner with Dustin
and Vinnie, and fortunately,
they
brought it to my attention.
They said this poor kid is
already missing out on so much
in life, like not being
able to hear or speak.
Other people are mocking him
and teasing him and stuff.
This is just like one more
cool thing that's coming
through town that he doesn't
get to participate in.
And I immediately wanted
to tattoo him, but I'm
like he's so young.
You know what mean?
I know he was 11.
I got Raul, the 11-year-old,
tattooed, and he got an S and
an I with two periods
after them.
Still to this day, nobody knows
what that stands for.
So I said OK, we'll
go to your house.
I'll tattoo you and Raj again.
I'll tattoo Sunny.
He's like, maybe my mom
wants to get tattooed.
I started getting nervous as
we're going to the house
because I'm going
to meet his mom.
And I just tattooed
her kid's neck.
You know what I mean?
So I'm like, was it OK
with your mom that
you guys got tattooed?
Oh no.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
It's totally cool.
I don't know if they're just
telling me that because they
want to get me there--
it's really cool or whatever.
So we show up at the house and
the first thing I said after
nice to meet you, was I really
hope it's OK that I tattooed
your sons' necks.
And she was like, oh,
we're Christians.
I was like, oh, killer, OK.
Like no problem.