MALE SPEAKER: What led
you to join PJAK?
BARAN BERITAN:
[SPEAKING KURDISH]
MALE SPEAKER: Apo is like
the Kurdish Mao.
Really, he is the Kurdish Mao,
since all he did was basically
take Mao's Little Red Book and
tweak a couple points to make
it more "Kurdy." So Apoism is
an essentially a grassroots
socialist movement that promotes
full gender equality
and guerrilla warfare, hearts
and minds, 1,000
blossoms, et cetera--
but for Kurds.
Apo is the political father
of both the PKK and PJAK.
Like with most good leftists,
feminism is a
staple of Apoist thought.
PJAK likes to claim that roughly
50% of their fighting
forces is women--
which is pretty progressive in
general, but completely insane
for the Middle East.
BARAN BERITAN:
[SPEAKING KURDISH]
RUKEN: [SPEAKING KURDISH]
MALE SPEAKER: Kurdish society
seems to put such a strong
emphasis on the family.
Do women in PJAK, are they able
to have families and be
part of that too?
Or is that something
you have to give
up to become a soldier?
RUKEN: [SPEAKING KURDISH]
MALE SPEAKER: The conventional
view of liberated women is a
bunch of crew-cut, masculated
butchies--
basically women acting
like men.
But aside from the uniforms and
in spite of the strictures
against motherhood and fucking,
the female PJAK
fighters we'd seen so far
all preserved a sense of
femininity that went well with
their Kalashnikov in a kind of
Leila Khaled meets the Viet Cong
sniper from Full Metal
Jacket way.
RUKEN: [SPEAKING KURDISH]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
MALE SPEAKER: While everything
sounded good, we were well
aware that we were still at a
press event, and everybody's
answers felt extremely
well-rehearsed.
So we were a little anxious to
get up in PJAK's friends, the
mountains, and see how well
all this translated to the
actual battlefield.