[ALARM]
JACK: Hey.
EMILY: Morning.
[TV]
JACK: What?
What's wrong?
[TV]
[HIP-HOP MUSIC]
[GROWLING]
[SCREAMING]
JACK: [MUTTERING WORRIEDLY]
Uh--
[MUTTERING TO SELF]
[GRUNTING]
JACK: Emily.
Hey.
Emily.
Em.
Hey.
Can you hear me?
You OK?
Come on.
[MOANING]
JACK: Oh, God.
You're OK.
EMILY: Jack.
JACK: I'm so sorry.
EMILY: What the fuck, Jack?
JACK: It was a surprise.
I didn't mean that to happen.
EMILY: What do you mean?
JACK: There's a-- a picnic
up there for you.
A surprise for you for
your birthday.
I didn't think--
I was just being an idiot.
I thought you would
go the other way
where the picnic was.
I didn't think you would
go over the cliff.
[MOANING]
JACK: Can you feel your legs?
Em?
Your legs.
Can you feel them?
EMILY: Yes, Jack.
I can feel my fucking legs.
JACK: Thank God.
[MOANING]
JACK: That was amazing.
You-- you rode off the cliff.
I can't believe you
survived that.
EMILY: God.
You're so stupid.
JACK: You were so mad
at me this morning.
[MOANING]
JACK: You thought I'd forgotten
your birthday,
didn't you?
[MOANING]
JACK: I'm sorry about
your bike too.
I'll get you a new bike.
[MOANING]
JACK: I got you this--
I got this amazing suit.
It's so realistic.
Look.
[MOANING]
JACK: See?
It's pretty good, huh?
I'm very scary.
[LAUGHTER]
[GROWLING]
JACK: I'm gonna eat you.
[LAUGHTER]
[GROWLING]
[GUNSHOT]
[MOANING]
[WHIMPERING]
RANGER: Hey, you all right?
RANGER: Can you hear me?
[SCREAMING]
RANGER: Is it dead?
[MUSIC - IONE SKYE,
"BEAUTIFUL FLIRT"]