STEVE SPANGLER: Yes, you do.
You're smart, and you
like science.
And I got your favorite
demonstration, the bed of nails.
BARBIE: [MOCK FEMALE VOICE]
No, not the bed of nails.
STEVE SPANGLER: No, you
really like it.
Watch this.
No, don't lay down that way.
That'll hurt you.
So you have to lay
down this way.
Ready?
BARBIE: [MOCK FEMALE VOICE]
Ohh.
STEVE SPANGLER: No.
It didn't really hurt because
the pressure is distributed
all over your back.
BARBIE: [MOCK FEMALE VOICE]
No, that's a lie.
It totally hurt.
STEVE SPANGLER: No.
It'll be fine because I have
a new thing for you to do.
Watch this, Barbie.
You're going to love this.
It's the Barbie bowling ball.
BARBIE: [MOCK FEMALE VOICE]
No, not the Barbie
bowling ball.
STEVE SPANGLER: Yes.
It's only 10 pounds.
But dropped from here, it's not
going to hurt you at all.
Watch.
[BOOM BOOM]
STEVE SPANGLER: Oopsie.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
STEVE SPANGLER: I'm Steve
Spangler, and I'm all about
making science fun.
For the last 20 years, I've
been teaching ways to turn
ordinary science experiments
into unforgettable learning
experiences.
I have an amazing team who will
do whatever it takes to
affect the way people
think about science.
And to do that, I live by one
motto, make it big, do it
right, give it class.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
STEVE SPANGLER: You
guessed it.
Today is all about bed of
nails and pressure.
I'm going to show you all the
secrets of the bed of nails--
how they crush the cinder block,
how you can make your
own bed of nails at home, and
how we use the coolest bed of
nails I've ever seen on
over 700 teachers in
less than 24 hours.
So if you're going to make your
own bed of nails, you're
going to need some nails.
We wanted good-looking nails
here for our bed of nails.
And we have 98 of them to be
exact to correspond with the
98 holes that are in the board
that you see right here.
Now we have this as a kit.
It's like a CNC machine
did this.
It's spaced out perfectly.
But you could easily make
this in the shop as a
simple little project.
But before you load up the thing
with all of the nails,
try just one.
See here's what makes this
demonstration cool--
is if you start with just one
nail get to see the effect of
all of that pressure, the
amount of force per a
particular, area exerted
on this balloon.
And all the pressure as I push
down will be exerted on the
tip of that nail.
What happens.
[POP]
STEVE SPANGLER: No surprise.
It pops because all of that
pressure was on just a small
amount of that balloon.
What if we try two nails?
Watch this.
[POP]
STEVE SPANGLER: It still pops.
But I got to push a little
bit more than I do
on the first one.
What if we do four nails?
See, every time I add a
nail, it looks worse.
But in fact I'm just spreading
that weight out
over a bigger area.
[POP]
STEVE SPANGLER: And I
had to push harder.
You guessed it.
It's time for 98 nails.
Go.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
STEVE SPANGLER: Last nail.
Looks good.
Just push down.
[BANG, BANG, BANG]
STEVE SPANGLER: Perfect.
And there's your bed of nails.
See, doesn't this look
so much worse?
98 sharp nails.
It looks bad.
But I'm actually now spreading
that pressure, or that weight,
distributing that pressure
across 98 points instead of
the one or two points that
was there before.
It looks bad, but it's going to
be better for the balloon.
Don't make the mistake of
pushing the balloon down with
your hand as hard as you can
because you can see just a
small amount is perfectly
fine.
But if you push harder, then
this is going to pop, and,
finally you're going to
impale your hands.
Not a good idea.
That's why we have these
guideposts that
go on either side.
And now there's a safety piece
that goes at the top that'll
now protect your hand.
Time for Mr. Balloon to meet
his fate because it
goes down like this.
The safety panel goes on
top here like this.
And now we're ready to go.
You start pushing and watch.
As you get closer and closer and
closer, you can actually
see the tips of the nails
working their
way into the rubber.
A tremendous amount of
pressure goes in.
Look at this.
That's a lot of pressure.
Yet when you pull it back out
again, the balloon is
perfectly fine with small,
little indentations right on
the surface.
This time we use a clear balloon
because this time I
want you to see the nails
actually being forced up and
into the surface
of the balloon.
Watch.
Look right down here.
As I increase the pressure,
look at those nails being
pushed into the balloon.
Again, the secret is
distributing that pressure
over all of the nails.
And that force is being
distributed.
You can put a tremendous
amount of
pressure until finally--
[POP]
STEVE SPANGLER: --it pops.
That's the reason we have
the safety shield.
You want it bigger?
This is bigger.
2,000 nails in our
new bed of nails.
It's bigger.
It's scarier.
But it still works on the same
principle of a distribution of
the weight on all the nails.
And it even passes
the balloon test.
Watch.
You have to always
remember that the
bed of nails is dangerous.
If you just let it sit here on
the floor unattended, somebody
could walk on it.
It can be very, very
dangerous.
And so you need to have
a cover for it.
And that's what these are for.
See, these thin pieces of wood
cover the nails so that nobody
accidentally trips and
falls on it as well.
And now we're ready
for Higgensworth.
Oh, there is one more thing.
We have a little fake blood.
All right.
So just a little fake blood
here like this.
We just throw a little
bit here like this.
Ahh, that's perfect.
We have to have some splatter
marks here.
This will freak him out
when we reveal it.
And we'll say, no, it's OK.
Ever since we fixed the problem,
it's perfectly fine.
Well, ladies and gentlemen, boys
and girls, children of
all ages, it's come to the time
of the show you've all
been waiting for.
That's right.
That's where we do
the bed of nails.
And who better to lay on the
bed of nails than our own--
you know him, you love him, the
master, the dangerous, the
disastrous, it's Higgensworth.
Where is he?
Higgens?
Higgensworth?
I'll get him.
Hey, it's going to be OK.
Come here.
Higgensworth, come here.
HIGGENSWORTH: I'm getting
tired of this [BEEP].
STEVE SPANGLER: So I got
everything worked out, all the
bugs worked out.
This is going to be great.
You're going to like this.
HIGGENSWORTH: I've heard
that before.
STEVE SPANGLER: And when
they see this, they're
going to love you.
Drum roll please.
HIGGENSWORTH: Brrrrrrr.
STEVE SPANGLER: Little
bit more enthusiasm.
HIGGENSWORTH: Brrrrrrrrr.
STEVE SPANGLER: Watch this.
Drrrrr-rup.
2,000 nails.
Look at this Higgensworth.
These are two--
HIGGENSWORTH: [BEEP]
is that?
STEVE SPANGLER: That's find.
Don't worry about it.
It's just a little thing.
You're going to be
perfectly fine.
This is a carny stunt that's
been done for hundreds and
hundreds of years, maybe
thousands of--
who knows.
I don't-- maybe Egyptians
did this.
Maybe they didn't.
I don't know.
But today you're going
to lay on this, and
it's going to be awesome.
They're going to love you.
HIGGENSWORTH: All right.
STEVE SPANGLER: I would do it
myself, but I have to talk and
explain what's working.
So that's why I'm asking you
to be the star of the show.
HIGGENSWORTH: That sounds
really important.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK.
Just--
why do you have a pillow?
HIGGENSWORTH: Don't
worry about that.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK.
Just put it here.
OK.
This is going to be great.
Ouch.
OK.
Important if you're doing
this at home--
I mean don't do this at home.
But if you're helping a friend
do it at a friend's home, you
have to help them down
onto the nails.
So you just don't go lay
down on the nails.
So watch.
I'm going to help you,
Higgensworth.
Ready.
So I'm going to hold your
wrist like this.
Now go ahead.
You're just going to sit down.
OK.
HIGGENSWORTH: All right.
STEVE SPANGLER: Ahh.
Perfect.
OK.
Now ready?
And you're just going to kind
of put your hands there and
kind of lay down.
OK.
Your head is going to be
back here like this.
All right here.
I'd better take this hat.
HIGGENSWORTH: Yeah.
Get that off.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK.
Good.
HIGGENSWORTH: All right.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK.
How is that?
HIGGENSWORTH: Pretty good.
STEVE SPANGLER: How
does that feel?
HIGGENSWORTH: Not terrible.
STEVE SPANGLER: Is
that pretty cool?
HIGGENSWORTH: Yeah.
I think we're good.
STEVE SPANGLER: This, ladies and
gentlemen, is the bed of
nails trick.
And it kind of is boring.
You see, it's boring because for
years and years and years
people have done the
bed of nails.
But see, the wow moment
is the moment that the
person touches the nails.
When he sat down here like this
and then he started to
lay back, you knew he wasn't
going to get hurt.
And so all that motion of him
laying down and finally the
ta-dah moment, there is not
ta-dah moment because
all he's doing is--
HIGGENSWORTH: Steve, Steve.
Am I done?
STEVE SPANGLER: No
we got more.
So-- here, just wear this.
HIGGENSWORTH: What
is this for?
STEVE SPANGLER: Don't
worry about it.
It's fine.
HIGGENSWORTH: All right.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK.
Just stay right there.
For years, people have done
this classic stunt.
And Higgensworth is going to
perform the crushing cinder
block trick.
And this is where we take a
cinder block and we put it on
Higgensworth like this.
All right, Higgensworth,
this is a cinder block.
I don't know exactly
where to put it.
Do you want it right here?
HIGGENSWORTH: Yeah.
STEVE SPANGLER: Does
that feel good?
I've never actually done this
before, but I read about it on
the internet.
OK.
I'm just going to smash down.
You're ready?
Here we go.
Drum roll please.
Drum roll.
HIGGENSWORTH: Brrrrrrrrrr.
STEVE SPANGLER: Louder.
Here it goes.
HIGGENSWORTH: Brrrrrrrrr.
[BANG]
STEVE SPANGLER: Look at that.
And he's OK, ladies
and gentlemen.
I remove this from
the Higgensworth.
Look at this.
He's perfectly fine.
You did such a good job.
I think you're going to actually
get a t-shirt for
doing this.
All right.
HIGGENSWORTH: A t-shirt?
STEVE SPANGLER: Yes.
This is the other part
that's important.
Help them back up again.
Otherwise, they get hurt at
the end of the trick.
And then you're not
amazing anymore.
I'm going to help you
Higgensworth.
Are you OK?
OK.
Lift up.
Perfect.
Look at your back.
There's indentations all over
your back, but, see, it's
perfectly fine.
You're fine.
HIGGENSWORTH: I'm good.
STEVE SPANGLER: Turn around.
Ta-dah.
HIGGENSWORTH: I survived.
STEVE SPANGLER: He'll never
actually have kids,
but he did the trick.
It was awesome.
All right.
So I need you to do
it one more time.
So I'm going to have
you just lay down.
HIGGENSWORTH: I don't want
to do it another time.
STEVE SPANGLER: It's fine.
Don't worry about it.
Just--
I'll let you go home
early today.
HIGGENSWORTH: That's fair.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK.
So we're just going to lay
down on it one more time.
I got another idea.
Come on.
Play along.
HIGGENSWORTH: All right.
STEVE SPANGLER: Well, after
the last time Higgensworth
pulled me off to the side
and said, could I
please do it again?
And I said, sure.
Right, Higgensworth?
HIGGENSWORTH: Yep.
STEVE SPANGLER: So here's
what I was thinking.
This a totally a boring
demonstration because the
moment of wow is lost.
Wouldn't it be really
cool if the nails
actually lifted you up.
What if you just got lift--
hey, hey, hey.
What--
what--
No.
I didn't mean lift--
I don't mean the whole
bed of nails lifting.
I just meant if the nails
lifted you up.
Like--
Higgens--
If you were just like
on a bed of nails.
This--
hey--
Higgens, if you're--
it'll be all--
We already did this
with 700 teachers.
Take a look.
How about this.
How about 4,500 nails.
And this is the bed
of nails from the
Oklahoma Museum Network.
And they're nice enough to let
us borrow it so that we can
show teachers the difference
between pressure and support.
FEMALE SPEAKER: There you go.
STEVE SPANGLER: So when
I push the button,
4,500 nails will rise.
FEMALE SPEAKER: [LAUGHTER]
STEVE SPANGLER: Isn't
that weird?
FEMALE SPEAKER: [SCREAMING].
STEVE SPANGLER: You're going to
feel this unusual pressure
that's all over your body.
Isn't that kind of
an unusual piece?
So if you put your fingers here
now, you actually can
feel that you're on the
very tip of the nail.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yes.
STEVE SPANGLER: So your body
is supported on the tip, I
don't know, of about 1,000
nails, somewhere there.
When I let you back down again,
keep your hands there.
You're going to feel the tip of
the nail go into the top of
the table, and it literally
will vanish.
But if I took out half of those
nails, you couldn't lay
on the bed of nails because
the pressure
would be too much.
Isn't that a great sensation?
So as a teacher--
FEMALE SPEAKER: Kind of neat.
STEVE SPANGLER: -- what would
it feel like as a teacher if
we had 100% support in
everything that we do?
It'd be amazing.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Ahhh.
STEVE SPANGLER: Ahh.
Isn't that great?
FEMALE SPEAKER: It
would be awesome.
STEVE SPANGLER: We clicked
your picture
when you had wonder.
All right.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
STEVE SPANGLER: And then I have
a new name tag for you in
five minutes is [INAUDIBLE]--
[MUSIC PLAYING]
HIGGENSWORTH: Thanks, Steve
for the sweet shirt.
STEVE SPANGLER: You survived
the bed of nails.
You did a great job.
HIGGENSWORTH: Thank you.
STEVE SPANGLER: You
did perfect.
You just laid on the nails, and
everything was just fine.
I told you it'd be OK.
HIGGENSWORTH: I guess
you were right.