could do it justice.
FEMALE SPEAKER 2: I'm not sure
that people who are angry
about the Olympics would
be very patriotic.
MALE SPEAKER 3: I think
there's a lot of
dissatisfaction.
MALE SPEAKER 4: It's a complete
overkill for what is
a sporting event.
FEMALE SPEAKER 2: The Olympics
is not about politics.
MALE SPEAKER 5: We're seeing
the biggest mobilization of
troops in the UK since the
end of World War II.
FEMALE SPEAKER 3: Do Londoners
feel safer?
We've now got drones coming
in over the sky.
MALE SPEAKER 6: I'm not afraid
of the army or the police.
The longer you're out,
the better it is.
MALE SPEAKER 7: There's
going to be a
threat of an alien invasion.
The whole area could be sealed
off in a heartbeat.
And then effectively it becomes
a concentration camp.
MALE SPEAKER 4: The security's
predominantly about defending
the interests of the sponsors.
MALE SPEAKER 8: Instead of a
park for the people, we've
actually created a toxic
wilderness for a corporate
sports day.
MALE SPEAKER 9: We should
have a right to
hang around our area.
FEMALE SPEAKER 4: We're
a community.
This is my home.
And I don't see why we should
be kicked out of it.
MALE SPEAKER 10: We're going
to have a lot of rather
useless, rather empty buildings
left in Stratford.
MALE SPEAKER 11: The London I
knew really is dead and gone.
MALE SPEAKER 12: That's
a bit extreme.