BRAD KREMER: He did good
for a long time.
Because he started out--
he was in skateboarding.
Then he transitioned into
snowboarding in the very, very
early days of snowboarding.
And as snowboarding progressed,
he progressed.
But then it got to a point to
where he wasn't this full
freestyle guy.
But because he was so good at
riding the mountain, he all of
the sudden transitioned into
this big mountain guy, and was
up in Alaska doing lines and
stuff that nobody ever
expected him to do.
He was amazing.
It was really cool to see that
transition from just hard core
freestyle guy to big mountain
guy, and to do both of them so
well, better than
almost anybody.
I would definitely say he's
one of the first to bring
freestyle to the backcountry,
to the big mountain.
MIKE HATCHETT: When I first met
Noah, he was definitely
more focused on just freestyle,
and just riding
Squaw, and just ripping
the pipe.
But he started going out with
my brother and I in the
backcountry and just kind of
dabbling around the steeps.
He was a total natural talent.
And then when we took him to
Alaska, that's almost when his
mind just--
I think he started just seeing
the possibilities
of riding up there.
That was the key that unlocked
the door for Noah.
He's just amazing to watch
big mountain riding.
And his ability on big
mountain riding
is top 10 for sure.
JP WALKER: He rode Tahoe
all the time.
So it was just natural for him
to like ride those type of
conditions.
And he did it sick.
Because it seemed like all the
other guys that were just big
mountain riders kind of had a
weird style, or just not as
smooth, like Matt Goodwill,
or Tex, or all those guys.
They were sick for sure, but
then it was just cool to see
somebody that could do both.
I remember he did, like,
these one lines.
I think they were called Super
Spines or something.
He's, like, doing frontside
airs off them.
And it's like the steepest
thing ever.
Like if you fell, you'd
just be dead
probably from rag dolling.
MIKE HATCHETT: We did a
season TB2 at Donner.
And that spring, let's
go to Alaska.
OK, let's go.
We just went up there and
started riding the stuff.
We weren't really thinking
about it really.
And Noah wasn't thinking
about it either.
It wasn't, like, a goal.
I want to charge Super
Spines one day.
I had to basically almost talk
him into that run when he
finally did do that.
Because it was just so
ridiculously gnarly.
But he was ready for it.
And it was the perfect
day to do it.
NOAH SALASNEK: Yeah, I would say
anything that's spined out
is usually, the spines develop
anything over 55 degrees.
So you're on something steep if
there's spines on it, and
if it's powder and
good conditions.
I mean, there's nothing
funner than that.
It's a really amazing feeling.
And the adrenaline you get
from it is just unreal.
MIKE HATCHETT: Also being
goofy foot in
Valdez on the spines.
I know this is a little bit of
a sidebar that might be kind
of a twist for people
to understand.
A lot of the spines up there,
if you're goofy foot, you're
toe edging them.
And the way for the sluffs
run, and the way that the
spines face, you're better off
being a goofy foot on a lot of
the lines up there.
Not to say on the big open
faces like what Johan was
charging and Tom Burt.
I'm just talking steep,
technical spines that are
close together.
When you send a sluff down a
run, you'll have to hop to the
next one to send your
sluff down.
Goofy foot--
Jeremy Jones, Noah Salasnek--
who rips the spines
the hardest?
Those two guys.
And they're goofy foots.
And I think Valdez
and Haynes--
maybe I'm crazy by
saying that.
But I don't know.
Ask Jeremy or Noah
what they think.
But that's my opinion.
NOAH SALASNEK: A lot of on
those spine runs, I would
assess the line.
I like to be able to ride
from left to right.
Because you deal with
this sluff slides up
there, they're called.
And they're basically
mini avalanches.
And they're made from your
turns, being on a steep slope.
Throwing all that snow from
your turns creates these
little avalanches.
And when I saw, like, Super
Spines, for instance, it was
kind of a big face.
But I was able to go diagonal,
knowing all my snow would go
below me and I wouldn't
encounter it again.
So I didn't have to deal
with the sluff.
And you can also jump from
one to the other.
And I've always kind of prided
myself on bunnying from one
spine to the next and kind of
staying on the power line and
out of the channels.
And maybe that's what Mike's
talking about appreciates my
technique on the spines.
Because that's kind of my
approach I guess a little bit.
A lot of times we'll have to
take a Polaroid from the
helicopter on the way up.
Because we haven't been
to this mountain
before or flown by it.
So you get on top and
you can't see
over the edge, really.
Even if you walk down close
to the edge, it
keeps rolling over.
So you really rely on these
Polaroids that you take on the
way up to know where you're at
and to find your line down.
And it's really essential,
in Alaska especially.
-That could be a go.
That could be sick.
-I'm starting here.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
-The first one's a drop.
Second one, you can
poke through.
First one's a mandatory
little niblet.
NOAH SALASNEK: Yeah, sometimes
I'll go to roll over.
And what you think you might
be 30, 40 feet from your
entrance is like 200 or
300 feet in Alaska.
Because everything's so
much bigger up there.
You're like, hey, I'm going
to do that cliff--
30 footer.
And you get next to it and
it's like 60 or 70.
Everything's way bigger
than it looks up
there for some reason.
So it's really easy to get lost
on top of the ridge or
not know where your
entrance is.
And that could be a little
confusing until you get over
and you say-- into that fluid
motion when you're
involved in a line.
But the entrance in the
top 100 feet or 200
feet is just blinding.
It keeps rolling and rolling
and rolling, especially if
you're riding 55 degrees plus.
So it's pretty burly.
And that's the scariest thing,
is being on top, out of your
board before you ride down.
You don't have that edge.
But once I get on my board,
I feel comfortable.
I have my edge, dig in, and just
wait for the cameras to
say "roll," and then get it.
And it's pretty fun, actually.
JAMIE LYNN: My first trip up
to Alaska was with Noah.
And I look back at that as, I'm
so thankful I had someone
as knowledgeable and as
professional and as on it as
he was to show me an
introduction to one of the
biggest arenas of
snowboarding.
Especially with Mike
and Dave Hatchett--
they are the ultimate
mountaineering guides, that
can not only drop into
the craziest
terrain, but allow you--
if something went down, be there
for you and be able to
assist in any kind of situation
that could come up.
It's a tense situation being
up there-- a lot of first
ascents, a lot of unstable
snow conditions.
And the knowledge and
understanding of the mountains
that Noah, in particular,
showcased made me sit a little
bit easier in dropping into a
55 degree slope where you
couldn't even see what you were
dropping into, only by
looking at the Polaroid picture
that you took from the
helicopter on the way up.
We shared a couple first
ascents up in AK that--
runs of a lifetime that
I'll never forget.
NOAH SALASNEK: I was in Alaska
with Jamie one year.
We had a really good trip and
did some incredible lines
together, too.
One of my first ascents--
Blind Faith.
I was with Jamie Lynn.
That was one of my more
notable runs.
And he was pretty stoked and
terrified at the same time, as
was I.
But we got out on this thing and
the guide didn't get out.
The guide got in the
heli and flew away.
We couldn't believe it.
We're like, isn't the guide
supposed to get out with us?
And we're on this thing
together, on a cornice of all
thing entrance line.
But anyway, it was a
pretty sick run.
And he was there for that.
It was cool.
I enjoyed riding powder.
I never thought that would have
been most of my focus and
my career later on, which
it absolutely was.
Not that I had tried
to do that.
It just kind of developed
that way.
I had an opportunity
to go to Alaska.
That was amazing.
So I went back every year.
And it's super enjoyable
as a rider.
It's the best thing to film.
Because they're like,
go ahead.
Ride the mountain.
We'll film you from the heli.
So you just ride the
whole thing.
And the footage that comes out
of there isn't going to be
freestyle-based.
It's going to be some powder.
But yeah, professionally,
I think
freestyle's where it's at.
It's always been the
progression.
It should be the focus, and
it is in most sports.
And it is in snowboarding.
So I think that--
I don't know if it was a
career mistake of mine.
But I don't think it certainly
helped to focus strictly on
powder as much as I did, and
big mountain riding.
I should have done a little
bit more of both, and, of
course, stayed in freestyle
for longer.
I think I would have had a
longer career had I done that,
potentially.
So it's interesting to say.
Because big mountain riding's
pretty gnarly, putting your
life on the line for
first ascents.
But a lot of people don't
ride that kind of
stuff and can't relate.
They can relate to the
parks and the pipes.
And that's the stuff
they want to see.
And I understand that.
And so it's unfortunately
not as marketable.
That's how it is.
JP WALKER: I mean, I didn't
really see it like that.
I just kind of figured he just
got sick of doing it.
Because back then it seemed like
the average time spent
for a top pro was--
like if you had like five video
parts, you had a lot of
video parts under your belt.
So he'd already had, like,
a bunch of parts.
And I just figured he was on to
other things or something.
NOAH SALASNEK: You know, I never
aspire to say or set
goals for myself, like most
people probably do
and should, I believe.
But I really was just motivated
and hungry to ride
and to film.
I wanted to put out these
videos every year.
And they were selling well.
And the boards are
selling well.
And I was just really motivated
to snowboard.
I like snowboarding.
But I would focus on a part
every year and try
to make a good part.
And be aware of what I've shot
so far this season and
try to mix it up.
And then cap it with Alaska
at the end of
year, was always nice.
But definitely made filming a
priority and tried to put out
the best part I could
every year.
It's always hard.
Everyone wants to one up you
every year, or put out a
better part every year.
And that can be tough.
Unfortunately, as I became more
popular, I could say,
worldwide, travel becomes a
little bit of an issue.
I'm not great with travel.
A lot of times it's not all
glory in snowboarding.
I'd go to Japan without my board
and do five or six shop
tours in a week.
Sometimes it can be a burden.
I wasn't cut out for that.
A lot of people are like,
I want to be sponsored.
I want to be pro.
I'm good enough.
Well how professional are you?
It's a lot of marketing involved
and you've got to
present yourself properly and do
a lot of stuff you may not
want to do.
That became old, I think,
year after year.
I just wanted to snowboard.
Because that's who I was--
a snowboarder.
I wanted to ride powder
and go to Alaska.
And I was able to do that, but
you just want to snowboard.
And you're like, I rip.
I'm in a video.
I deserve this.
And you think you're
everything.
And sure, it's a lot of it.
But there's a lot more that
comes with it that you don't
realize when you're young.
--is the start of the beginning
of the end.
Woo.
Thanks.
-Hello.
Hello.
NOAH SALASNEK: Get that thing
off me right now.
-It's been a long day,
a long month.
NOAH SALASNEK: A long couple
of years, to be honest.
-Just a year.
NOAH SALASNEK: Longer.
-How long?
NOAH SALASNEK: 14.
Just kidding.
That thing's not on, right?
-God, I look like shit.
NOAH SALASNEK: Yeah, my last
few years with Sims, my
contract was up.
And I had wanted to break away
from Sims and start this
company with Mack Dawg and
Peter Line called Forum.
And I was into it.
And I went to Sims and said,
I don't want to re-sign.
And they said hey, we
have obligations.
We got you for two more
years if we want you.
Line 36 c clearly states--
I didn't fight them on it.
I signed up again and balked
on the Forum thing,
unfortunately.
And two years later--
I don't know-- they changed
hands again.
Sims had a lot of different
CEOs, a lot of different
manufacturers over the years.
And unfortunately, they didn't
re-sign me after two years.
They kind of left me hanging.
I was like, whoa, I wanted to
break away and do my thing.
Now you're leaving me hanging.
And it was a little late for me
to get in on Forum at that
point, obviously.
So that was really unfortunate
how that played out.
And I really felt let down.
Man, I had done so much for
them over the years, and
kicked me to the curb in late
summer without a contract and
no warning.
It's just kind of crazy.
Some 17-year-old
team manager--
doesn't seem right.
So I was always a little
jaded on that.
I would've appreciated a call
from anybody in the office,
maybe even Tom would have been
cool. "Hey dude, we're not
going to make a board.
Sorry." But no.
They had some kid come out and
tell me they're not going to
re-sign me.
After I begged them to not ride
for them to go to this
other company.
So they really, I think, took
advantage a little bit.
And unfortunately for me, it
didn't pan out that well
afterwards for me.
I would've loved to have
been a part of Forum.
JP WALKER: I think probably he
was being talked to just
because he was such good
friends with Mack Dawg.
And I think I do remember him
talking about that actually.
But like I said, around that
time-- because I think Forum
started, like '96 or '7 as well,
so that was kind of that
same time frame where he was
kind of just trying to fade--
or starting to fade out of
the scene a little bit.
NOAH SALASNEK: Now looking back
on it, I don't know that
I would have been a perfect
piece of that puzzle, because
they were so
freestyle-oriented--
hand rails, and just
kickers, and--
I don't know that they knew
that then either.
They just had this idea.
And they wanted me in.
It was a good crew so far.
I wanted in.
JP WALKER: Back then when
it started there
wasn't that many people.
He was one of the best
freestyle or
jibber dudes, you know?
He wasn't doing , like, crazy
rails and stuff like that.
But he was definitely bonking
and had like that skate style.
And I know he was friends with
Peter Line and stuff.
And then there was only
me, Bjorn, and Chris
Dufficy from there.
So it was like, him and Peter
could've easily spearheaded
that whole thing together.
And who knows which direction
it would've went.
I would have been stoked.
NOAH SALASNEK: Sims-- when I was
growing up snowboarding,
it was like Sims
was the board.
Everyone rode Sims.
They were the best boards,
probably, back then.
It was incredible to think
that I would ride
for them one day.
And when I did, I think
it was such a large
entity in my mind.
The Sims name is just a huge
name in snowboarding.
I was stoked to ride for them.
And I still am to say that
I rode for them.
It just didn't go
well at the end.
And everything works out for a
reason, I feel like, in life.
And I can't complain.
Should'ves and would'ves
will kill you.
And I can sit here all
day and say that.
But again, I have no regrets.
And I've had good experiences
and a great life in
snowboarding for sure.
JAMIE LYNN: I don't think that
opportunity's gone for
someone like Noah.
I really still feel that there's
a lot of people out
there that he's touched in a way
that has made a difference
in their life.
NOAH SALASNEK: I guess
what I've done for
Billabong and Sims--
Billabong, I rode for them,
being the only rider for four
or five years.
I felt I helped develop
a whole brand there.
And with Sims, I felt I brought
them around with
Palmer, brought them
kind of back.
And yeah, I don't know.
A lot of it's my first ascents
and the actual riding that
I've done that I'm really
stoked and proud of.
Not necessarily in my
accomplishments and my
professional part, but
the riding itself.
And the lines that I've done in
Super Spines, and all these
just hairball things--
risked my life.
I'll never forget them.
It was like yesterday I
remember these things.
And it's sick, because
I have that.
And I'll always have that.
And that's pretty sweet.
And that's the best thing I'll
take with me from my
snowboarding is all these
experiences and what I've got
to do over the years.
And it's a blessing that
companies like Billabong and
DC and Dragon, and
people that have
promoted me over the years.
I really appreciate them too.
Because I couldn't have
done it without them.
[RUSTLING AND BREATHING]
NOAH SALASNEK: OK, I'm ready
for 10 seconds You
can count me in.
NOAH SALASNEK: Tell them it's
kind of sticky pile in the
fucking sunlit.
That cliff was beat.
That cliff was just beat.
It was just peppery
takeoff huge.
That snow got jacked.
It's good in the chute though.