And I want to know how much
people know about Dr. King.
So do you know what's
today's holiday?
MALE SPEAKER: Martin
Luther King Day.
Luther King.
FEMALE SPEAKER: It's Martin
Luther King Day.
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah, MLK.
Martin Luther King, yeah.
SHAN: Oh, MLK.
Ahhh.
Do you know what's
today's holiday?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yeah, Martin
Luther King's Day.
Yeah.
SHAN: Do you know what he
stands for, for America?
FEMALE SPEAKER: I don't know.
He--
break, broke, the
abolish, maybe?
MALE SPEAKER: He's just black
guy, and he's work for black
people right?
Yeah.
SHAN: Are you going to do
anything to celebrate?
MALE SPEAKER: Yes.
SHAN: What are you
going to do.
MALE SPEAKER: I'm going to go
south, where it's warm and I
think that's about it.
Get warm.
That's what black people like.
We like to be warm.
So this cold weather shit's
for, like, white people.
SHAN: Are you going to do
anything to celebrate?
MALE SPEAKER: No.
I have to work.
All day.
SHAN: What are you going
to do today?
MALE SPEAKER: I might do the
same thing I did last year,
was I read a little bit about
him when I got home.
And like, that's mostly it.
Just read about him, and
like, what he did.
SHAN: So you read a little
bit about him every year.
So maybe when you're
50, you would know
everything about him.
What do you know
about Dr. King?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Well, he was
leader of the black civil
rights movements here.
MALE SPEAKER: The whites didn't
like him, and so he
protested and he had this speech
that he had a dream for
everybody to be the same,
equal rights.
SHAN: Very, very impressive.
FEMALE SPEAKER: I have a dream
my English teacher came out
and he said, oh, you're
English is so poor.
You have to try more.
MALE SPEAKER: I had a dream that
I was teaching kids and
one of them turned
into my boss.
FEMALE SPEAKER: We're actually
experimenting with dreams at
the moment.
You have to go to this forest
in your dream and then meet
this cat there while a brass
band is playing.
SHAN: So what about, if you were
going to cook one dinner
for Dr. King, what would
you serve him?
Crispy kale.
MALE SPEAKER: Maybe I'd just
have a burrito, right?
Everybody likes Mexican food.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Fish.
SHAN: What type of fish?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Whitefish.
And steamed potatoes.
We call that nursery food.
SHAN: Nursery food?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
It heals everything.
And we'd make him miso
soup as well.
SHAN: What do you think Dr. King
needs to be healed for?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Needs
to be healed for?
Being assassinated, I suppose.
SHAN: Oh, OK.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
[MUSIC PLAYING]