Last time we were talking about computerized
layout planning and the focus of the last
two lectures has been on the development of
process layouts. In today’s class we are
going to talk about the design of product
layouts or assembly lines and the features
that we have there in product layouts. If
you recall, we had talked about the PQ chart
and in that we are identify the range in which
product layouts and process layouts are used.
Let us briefly recall the features of these
different kinds of production systems and
see which kind of layout is relevant under
what circumstances.
For instance when you talk about kinds of
production systems, we can talk about a flow
shop. A flow shop is essentially a production
system in which the same sets of operations
are performed in sequence repetitively. So
what we have is essentially when the operations
are going to be repeated so that the pattern
of flow of the raw materials through the plant
is constant more or less. That particular
configuration is called a flow shop and in
fact such systems even in assembly line could
be used as a flow shop in that sense. On the
other extreme we can talk about a job shop.
Job shop is something with facilities, capable
of producing many different jobs in small
batches. So the difference between a job shop
and a flow shop is essentially in terms of
the variety of products that we are handling.
In a job shop you can handle a variety of
products and because each product might require
different kinds of processing depending upon
its requirements. You have actually general
purpose machines laid out in the job shop
and each product can go to the respective
machine, get the operations done and then
you to the next particular machine for the
new operations. So what really happens in
the job shop is that the flow pattern is quite
complicated and material handling costs are
pretty high. Basically when you are designing
layouts for such job shops you are basically
talking about the design of process layouts.
What we are talking about is designing a process
layout which can accommodate a variety of
products that you make. That is what we saw
when we were dealing with both the systematic
layout planning procedure of Muether and also
the computerized layout planning packages
which are there for handling such types of
systems.
Of course one can have a production system
which is totally distinct and which is a project
that should be a major one time job requiring
sequencing and coordination among interrelated
tasks. Now in a project therefore things are
done once and for all and there is no need
for repeating whatever you are doing. Generally
a project is a one time activity and therefore
whatever layout emerges is actually a layout
dictated by the particular circumstances.
Therefore there are no formal methods of designing
a layout for a project it is actually dictated
by the various activities which have to be
performed in the project, the kind of equipment
that is to be laid and the kind of terrain
in which the project is to be done. So we
are not really talking about layouts when
you are talking about a project for these
reasons. Now it is important to note that
all these different kinds of production systems
that we have talked about essentially require
resources. Let us recall these resources could
be man power machines, materials, money, energy,
information etc.
They have to be provided to the production
system and the production system will generate
to you the desirable goods and services and
also some undesirable goods and services in
the form of pollutions noise scrap etc. The
purpose of a layout is actually to facilitate
this operation which goes on within the black
box. So we should look at a layout as something
which facilitates the production process and
at the same time tries to improve the productivity
of the production system by enlarged. So it
has to be viewed in that integrated concepts
and not a problem nearly in isolation. This
particular diagram which shows a plot of the
product variety versus the quantity in fact
brings out very beautifully the natural domains
of the flow shop, the job shop and the projects.
For instance if your quantities are small
but the variety is large then this particular
domain is the domain of the project and the
job shops primarily on the other hand when
you increase the quantity and also relatively
reduce the variety in fact, what happens here
is that we are talking here about predictable
variety ion a job shop.
The medium level variety and medium level
quantity is actually the domain of the job
shop and when you are talking about the job
shop, you are primarily talking about the
design of process layouts. Whatever we studied
in layout planning was actually applicable
to the job shops that this particular ends
up the spectrum here. On the other hand if
you have a situation where the quantities
are large and the variety of the product is
relatively low, we come to a domain that is
naturally suited for a flow shop or in assembly
line or in mass production in that sense where
we are basically performing the same set of
operations repetitively without much change.
So in such a case you tend to use a layout
which is generally called the product layout
or we will see how assemble lines are designed
for this. So I think this point needs to be
kept in mind and depending upon the natural
requirements of variety and quantity you choose
the type of layout and it could be a process
layout or it could be a product layout as
things are there. We are all familiar with
the concept of mass manufacture, these things
and mass production. However there are a couple
of ideas in mass production or mass manufacture
which are worthy of note. So we will talk
about some of the key ideas which led to mass
manufacture as a viable entity. You probably
know that the first assembly line was set
up be Henry ford for making cars in the United
States.
But this could not have been possible unless
you have number one a logical breakdown of
work which means the entire task is to be
performed is broken down into smaller and
smaller tasks and some group of tasks are
assigned to one particular individual or a
machine. This breakdown of tasks into smaller
task helps in the division of labor to a very
large extent. As a consequence of that suppose
you could know what is the basic advantage
of the division of labor rather than one person
doing all the jobs involved in an assembly,
if there are ten people doing fractions of
those jobs, what is the specific advantage
that you get by engaging a large number of
people? That is one thing you get. Specialization
of labor that means individual people will
now be focusing on individual tasks and as
a consequence they could become more and more
skilled and learning times will tend to draw
depending on the operation time. The real
advantage of the concept of division of labor
depends on what the assembly line is based.
What is that specific concept?
The major advantage of the division of labor
is the fact that it is much more economical
to produce parts when different people do
the jobs. Why is this so? It is because different
tasks involve different degrees of skill.
So what could happen is that there could be
many tasks that can be performed by an unskilled
operator. Other tasks requires skilled operators
and you can buy along skilled operator at
a much cheaper rate as compared to a skilled
operator for whom you will have to pay that
much. However if you have one skilled operator
doing the whole job then even for the unskilled
job which is done you are actually paying
in at a higher rate. That is what it is. So
you are really underutilizing these capabilities.
If you are employing only one person for doing
all the jobs, this particular fact is in fact
responsible for much of the economic advantage
that you get through the division of layout.
Apart from this of course there are other
factors like development of a skill and these
kinds of things. But I think this must not
pay last site off. The second underlying idea
in mass manufacture is that it is possible
to divide the work into workstations. What
is the work station? Work station will be
a set of tasks; you have now broken down the
original work into smaller tasks. Some of
the tasks are grouped together and assigned
to one particular work station. So at one
particular work station maybe the operator
will take part and will be inspected. It will
be a fixed up component on it and then clean
it and compressed and send it to the next
operation. So here we performed a number of
different tasks. So this grouping of what
task set to be performed by the operator defines
the content of workstation. Basically Adam
Smith was responsible for the basic idea of
the division of labor. He wrote a book called
the wealth of nations in 1776 which was basically
concerned with the advantages of the division
of labor. Henry Ford was credited with the
first person who actually put this ideas together
and develop the first circular and of course
assembly lines could not have been possible
but for this very important contribution by
E Whitney. E Whitney is the person who actually
talked about the concept of tolerances and
fits in meeting parts.
So he in fact showed that if you maintain
the tolerances with the certain range you
could have parts which are interchangeable
and replaceable. This is something very fundamental
to the assembly language. For instance if
you look at the assembly of let us say Maruti
cars, the person has to fit the four tyres
on to the on the wheels of this particular
car. He can pick up one particular wheel,
put it on, put the second wheel, put it on
third wheel, and put it on. We can take any
one of the wheels from the bilor wheels which
are lying within. Why is this possible? Because
of the processes standardization that has
taken place which means essentially the dimensions
confirmed to a certain range. Now in fact
in all assembly lines this happens. The automobiles
are being assembled. We will pick up any carburetor
and fit up the carburetor of the car and followed
by fitting up the next carburetor and so on.
So it does not really make a difference which
carburetor was fitted on to the whole thing,
whereas this kind of thing could not be possible
if standardization was not there.
You know jocularly we can say you are all
seen in the Mahabharata and you know during
the war the chariot of particular prince was
broken. The edges couldn’t replace the wheel
by any standard wheel. It has to go to a specific
carpenter. We have to make wheels specifically
designed for that and then put it on. This
is because that, it was not a standardized
kind of operation, each thing was there. So
unless standardization is done you will not
be able to go for this assembly. So these
are three fundamental concepts which are at
the back of mass manufacture. What is an assembly
line? Assembly line is actually a very sequential
progression of the input material that comes
with one particular point and one edge. Then
it goes to the first workstation. This person
it could be a person, it could be a machine,
anything. This workstation performs certain
operation on it. Sense it to the next operator
who performs those operations which are required
and so on. So at the end of the whole thing,
the final assembled product comes out of the
line. What are the specific features you see
in the assembly line? I think one of the immediate
things which come to mind is that this production
is going to be much faster.
As compared to a process layout, why not,
because these machines are more official.
The same machines could as well be used in
the process layout. So the total processing
time for producing a part could be the same.
The only difference comes because in a process
layout it has to go from one department to
another department. So there are waiting times
then there is cost of transfer and then it
is waiting at the new workstation and then
so on.
Once after the pieces finish, it has to gain
rate of the department. So all these loading,
waiting, traveling is involved in the process
layout. But here the part is some operation
is performed in this part, immediately it
goes to the next machine which is waiting
for the path with open arms. It welcomes to
the part and starts performing the operation.
So the element of material handling time involved
has considerably reduced this system. That
is the reason why these systems are much more
efficient in terms of production time. This
is what it is. Here as some of the advantages
of flow line production system which we are
talking about today. The first advantage is
the smooth flow of material from one work
station to the next.
I just like to point out that this flow need
not only be linear.
You could have material flowing like this
and then coming back like this and then going
in this direction and then coming here. So
it is like a serpentine flow
especially when there are constraints on space
you will find that this kind of flow takes
place. If you see for instance any television
assembly unit probably go to LG or some other
place, you will find that the operators are
set like this and then set like this and then
set like this. So they accommodate many more
people and this is also an assembly line.
Moreover the flow could be a straight line.
It could be U shape flow, it could be this
kind of a flow or it could be even be circular
flow. The idea is that depending upon the
space but the crucial thing is that smooth
flow of material from one workstation to the
next takes place. So this is one of the features.
Since work is fed from one station to the
next small in process inventories result.
This is another major advantage because directly
the piece is going from one workstation to
the other. So there is a much need for having
in process inventories between the two stations.
Though of course there could be some times
some inventories between the stations in the
form of buffer stops for some reasons. The
total production time per unit is quite short
for reason that we just mentioned. There is
reduced material handling, little skill required
by the operators. Hence training is simple
short and inexpensive. Why because the operator
is doing very simple kind of things. This
job might be to pick up the piece from here,
operate a foot pedal where it is held and
then take the compressed here. Then probably
release it and send it the next operation.
So he has to do a couple of things which can
probably be landed in half a day. So training
is quite simple and inexpensive unlike the
training for a process layout. In a process
layout you might have a lathe operator. Lathe
operator must have proper training. You should
be able to read the vernier calipers. You
should know how to operate a lathe. You should
be at least an ITI trained person and so on.
Greater problems are there. In the product
layout production planning and control systems
are simple. Less space is occupied by work
in transit for temporary storage, obviously
because we have less. So transit storage so
that kind of space is not really used to appear.
Whereas if you happen to work flow process
layout, work through for instance what you
find is typically pasting are storm all over
the place. So you probably might not have
space to work through the whole thing. You
have to mind your step as you step from one
costing to the other and you know because
of the storage, there is something like this.
It could not happen at least in a product
layout. It could happen only at the end. The
process layout of course, you will have a
where house. All the cars are stopped and
therefore that is a different thing.
Some of the disadvantages of flow line production
are that a breakdown of one machine may lead
to a complete stoppage of the following machines.
Hence maintenance is a challenging job here.
This is a very significant thing because if
you happen to be in charge of an assembly
line, you got to make sure that the line is
running all the time which means that is,
if there is a request, if there is a breakdown
then maintenance staff has to be on the job
constantly doing this job. This is relatively
in flexible with regard to changes in product
design. We cannot keep on changing the product
design here. The pace of the line is determined
by the bottle neck machine line. Balancing
is thus a major problem in design. Obviously
different operations workstations take different
amounts of time to process the part. The overall
phase of the line will be determined by the
source machine. Therefore you would like to
have as far as possible fairly constant times
for all the sections, all the workstations.
This may not be possible for various reasons
but at least that is the intention.
Supervision is general rather than specialized
as the supervision of a line is looking after
diverse machines on a line. Compare this with
supervisor for a process layout. If you have
a supervisor, let us say in the lathe section
that person could probably have spent ten
years in the lathe section and could be familiar
with all the machines. We can probably open
out each machine and assemble it, that kind
of thing because all are lathes and he has
considerable experience. But this could not
happen because you have one lathe, one milling
machine, one some special kind of machine
and so on. So all machines are distinct in
the line and you don’t expect any person
to be specialized of all of them. Generally
high investments are required owing to the
specialized nature of the machines and their
possible duplication in the line. So this
is also possible here. Now having understood
the features of an assembly line, let us see
for instance we want to go for mass production.
Indecently you must understand that this decision
is primarily economic decision. So just for
the sake of argument you might say for instance,
suppose we have three options, we can either
purchase the path that we are interested in
making for ten rupees a piece and just keep
buying it that is it or we can invest 10,000
rupees and set up some general purpose machines
are individual stations as the case maybe.
Then we will be able to make a path on our
own for 5 rupees a piece and the total cost
will then be the fixed cost and the variable
cost could be of this nature. You might say
that I can spend and make a heavier investment
of 20,000 rupees or whatever it is it is.
Then maybe we can produce the part for 2 rupees
50 paisa per piece and it will be like this.
Now through a simple break even and analysis,
for instance you can find out these two quantities
quantity Q1 and quantity Q2 here. This is
very simple for instance in this particular
case what could be the break even quantity
here for this particular situation?
I mean what we are saying is what could be
the break even quantity here this is like
trying to say 10X is = 2000. So what we can
therefore say is that we can directly determine
this quantity. Let us call this quantity as
Q1 and which is that is say 2000 here. Then
you find out the tradeoff between the other
two options that is between the option of
buying at individual stations and the options
of setting of a full assembly line. So what
could be this value 4000 mean?
This Q2 is 4000 of this simple analysis tells
you something very interesting or it says
is that the least cost option is the one which
is shown here. Therefore if you have demand
that happens in the range of up to 2000 rupees,
it is better to be just by the part from outside,
that is the cheapest option here. If you happen
to be in the rage of 2000, your demand happens
to be in the range of 2000 – 4000. The best
thing could be to goal for this intermediate
option because it will be cheaper in this
case and it will be worth wise to set up an
assembly line only if your quantity of production
demand happens to exceed 4000 rupees that
is all. So you can get quantitative answers
to the questions of finding out what could
be the best thing to do under various circumstances.
So in this particular situation we could go
in for assembly line only if it is 4000. What
might happen in real life is suppose your
current demand is 3500 somewhere here whatever
it is, and then obviously you can think of
the feature. You are expecting a growth in
the next year; it might be worth while to
set up an assembly line considering the fact
that you are going to cross this barrier of
4000 in the next year and so on. So these
kinds of decisions actually have to be taken
before you make this decision of trying to
find out whether you should go for mass production
and when you should go for mass production.
So it is essential. Let us now talk about
the design of the assembly line.
What is the objective in the design of an
assembly line? It is basically to minimize
the total idle time or the number of workstations
for a given assembly lines speed. The basic
information that we have at disposing such
a situation is that we are dividing the work
into parts and this division is known as the
precedence diagram. So the precedence diagram
is basically projection of what other parts
have to be, the components of the parts that
have to be done in overall products and in
what particular sequence. Once we have done
this development of tasks, the basic design
of the assembly line is actually done by grouping
the tasks into work stations. Before we do
this exercise we have to know what the feasible
range of cycle times is.
We will see the feasible range of cycle times
through an example. It can be determined very
easily as something which lies between the
maximum time for an operation and some of
the times for all the operations. Then there
are many algorithms available for the line
balancing process. We have a procedure due
to Helgeson and Birnie which is quite commonly
known as the rank positional weight method.
We also have a procedure due to Kilbridge
and Wester which is based on the number of
predecessors that means priorities are decided
based on the number of predecessors. There
is a procedure due to Arcus called COMSOAL
which is a computerized method for sequencing
operations on assembly lines. The basic philosophy
in this procedure is the generation of alternatives
by simulation and once you generate a large
number of alternatives, you evaluate them
and take the one which have you think is best.
Once we have generated a large number of options,
the next stage is choosing the best design.
Choice of the best design obviously depends
upon things like balance delay and ideal time
for the operation should be minimum. So this
is a broad set of picture of assembly line
design procedure. Let us now take an example.
What we have here is a precedence diagram
and the precedence diagram shows that 1, 2,
3 and so on up to 12 are the individual operations
or tasks
We are assuming these tasks cannot be further
divided. This could be like drilling a hole.
So obviously drilling a hole cannot be divided
into drilling one quarter of the hole and
then draw in the next quarter of the hole.
So this is that one particular operation which
is indivisible. So we have divided the entire
tasks in to the twelve operations and this
network diagram shows the precedence requirements
that are operation one has to be performed
first. Then two and four can be performed,
similarly six can be performed only when three
and five are over in that sense. The figures
here refer to the duration of each task. So
the duration of the tasks could be determined
by a time study or whatever other procedures
you have. You know the time required to do
this individual task. From this we would like
to possibly design an assembly line. Let us
see how we can design an assembly line manually
for this operation and then we will compare
it by using the rank positional weight technique.
Now clearly in this particular case we are
going to group these operations. So one thing
is clear, the maximum time that is required
for any operation is seven and the minimum
what is the total time required for all the
operations could be some of the times of all
the operations which is fifty. This clearly
means that any assembly line for this precedence
diagram will have a cycle time which will
range between seven and fifty. This defines
the limit on the cycle time for any design.
In this particular example, the number of
work elements is 12, the cycle time will live
between T max and summation Ti is = 1 to N
so seven is the bottle neck operation.
The operation which takes the longest time
in the cycle time will therefore live between
fifty. Now you talk about the desired cycle
time. A desired cycle time must be somewhere
between these two operations between these
two limits. So let us say about desired cycle
time is ten. How does the desired cycle time
come about? It is based on the market demand.
It depends upon how many you want to produce
per day so cycle time is determined accordingly.
This is something the marketing people would
be actually telling you if there is a demand
for so many cars per day therefore your cycle
time should be search. So we say that the
desired cycle time is ten and we have this,
so this cycle time should be within this range.
Obviously if the cycle time happens to be
more than fifty, what is going to be the implication?
The implication is that you don’t require
an assembly line. Your cycle time happens
to be more than fifty itreally means that
you require a piece that is 60 minutes. What
you can do is you can gain one percent, he
will do all the tasks in 50 minutes and still
have ten minutes free with him. You do not
really heed to set up an assembly line if
you are in this particular range. You can
use that person for ten minutes and you can
do something else. You don’t need here and
on the other hand if your cycle time is less
than seven what are you going to do? Suppose
my demand is search there I need a cycle time
of five or three. On this side you need multiple
lines on this side, you have one line and
beyond this you don’t need any assembly
line. So this gives your clear idea as to
when you need and how many lines.
So let us take for this example a situation
that the desired cycle time is ten. This is
now feasible and it should be between seven
and fifty. Let us now try to find out or design
the line for us.
What we are basically trying to do is our
objective is to group the work elements into
stations so that no stations time exceeds
ten units. That is what we trying to say because
if it exceeds ten units, our cycle time will
be more than ten and we are designing the
line for a cycle time of ten units. How do
we attain this? We could do it by inspection
and no algorithm. Just look at the precedence
diagram and this is the feasible solution
what we can say is I can club these two operations
one and two and this takes five minutes, five
seconds or minutes whatever with the unit
of time five + three, so the workstation one
will take eight units of time.
I should not exceed ten. This is now three
and six, so this takes a time of nine. This
one takes four + five which is nine. This
takes two + four which is six, this takes
six + four which is ten and this takes seven
+ one which is eight. What we are able to
do is by simply grouping parts, now what is
the objective in grouping? In grouping, some
of the time must not exceed ten. So I have
six workstations. What is the workstations
I have exactly defined? What is to be done
at this workstation? I t means the persons
going to sit at workstation one will first
do a operation one and take five minutes and
then do operation four which will take three
minutes thereby taking a total of eight minutes
here and so on for the next operator in the
next operand. So I have a design of an assembly
line which as six operators and we exactly
know what each operator has to do. This is
basically the idea of an assembly line which
we just date by simple common sense logic
which we can do this one. However to evaluate
how good this design is you could need some
performance measures. You can have for instance
if this is the bottle neck operation you can
have two machines here in parallel and each
machine will have a in mean effective time
of only 3.5,in that point of view and then
your bottle neck will be maybe six this will
be six which will be the bottle six as you
can work that way also. Are you can look for
a superior machine which instead of taking
seven minutes we will take etcetera and whatever
is your requirement. So for this particular
example that we just worked out we can calculate
something called the line efficiency. What
is the efficiency of this line and this is
nothing but the summation of all the station
times
Summation of the station times will be nothing
but the total time for all the jobs so you
have fifty divided by K. K is the number of
workstations the number of workstations that
we have got a six into the cycle time of the
line is ten. Notice that the cycle time need
not be always ten because when you are doing
this grouping you are constrained by saying
that it should be less than ten. So just we
have got lesser than here. Suppose this value
and then only eight then our cycle time could
have been nine although we started to design
a line for a cycle time of ten. So we have
here ten and then of course the line efficiency
works out to 83.3 percent. One minus the line
efficiency is called balance delay. It is
a nature of the inefficiency of the operation
really. So it is a nature of the idleness
of the different stations. When we talk about
idleness, what you see out of a total of ten
minutes, this value is idle for two minutes.
This is idle for one minute, one minute, four
minutes. This is not idle at all and this
is idle for two minutes. So we would like
this idle time to be as small as possible
and ideal situation could be, the line is
perfectly balanced that everyone is doing
the same amount of tasks. That is generally
not possible. Why? Because the times are integral
number one and then you have a constraint
and precedence. We cannot group everything
into everything else.
You are not way for instance raise that you
can put something here and make it exactly
two hundred and fifty grams. It is not possible
to do that because you are dealing with these
individual entities which have to be grouped
together. So the balance delay is 16.7 percent
and the smoothness index for this is a is
a term for an assembly line which is nothing
but the this is the idle time ST max, maximum
station time that mean that is the cycle time
minus Sti, which is the station time of the
ith operation and whole square. So it will
be for each operation. So what we have to
look at is this example, idle time here is
two. So two square is four and here it is
nine, so this idle is 14 + 1 + 1 and this
is sixteen because the idle time here is four.
Four four sixteen no idle time here and then
four. So root of twenty six which is 5.09
and closer to zero the better if a line is
perfectly balanced this smoothness index will
be zero. So we try to minimize these smoothness
index so we have got measures of the efficiency
of this design, you got a line which has an
efficiency of 83.3 percent. Balance delay
of 60.7 percent and a smoothness index of
5.09, this is what we have. Now let us see
how we can use one of the standard procedures
available. We will discuss the so called ranked
positional weight method for developing the
line.
We will compare the design with the design
that we had obtained by induction as it is
possible. So the positional weight of a work
element is its own processing time plus the
processing time of all the following work
elements. We define a positional weight for
each element in the precedence diagram by
same, that this is the time of that operation
plus times of all operations which follow
it. The basic idea could be that the total
positional weight will give you an idea, how
much time it will take, at least to go to
the end from that operation that happens to
be the idea. This is used subsequently in
defining your priority for assigning jobs
to workstations that is the only thing. At
each workstation a list of an eligible job
is prepared for the placement. In the rank
positional weight technique, the work element
with the highest positional weight is selected
and that is why it is called ranked positional
weight is selected and is assigned to the
current workstation.
So that is the basic logic of the RPW technique.
Let us try to apply this technique to the
example that we are considering earlier. What
you notice in this precedence diagram is the
same precedence diagram that we have. The
times are shown on top of each operation but
the figures are available in the squares at
the bottom or the positional weights. Let
us look at them. You start calculating the
positional weight from the back. So what do
you see is for operation number twelve the
positional weight is seven because this will
take only seven units of time?
You come to eleven then from eleven, this
is the operation and this is the following
operation for this. So seven plus four eleven
will be the positional weights for this elements.
Similarly thirteen is the positional weight
for this element which is six plus seven;
similarly for nine the positional weight will
be what follows it which is seven plus one
which is eight. When you come to job number
six for instance what happens is it is not
necessarily fifteen plus eight plus fifteen
that will be the positional weight for this,
that the point that you have to get. It is
all that these jobs are successors of this
job. So the time required two plus six plus
seven plus one plus four plus four, the total
time required for all these jobs is twenty
four if you add the five also
and therefore this becomes the positional
weight for this particular job. For job number
three, the positional weight will be simply
whatever follows this plus so twenty four
is the positional weight here twenty four
plus four which is twenty eight. Similarly
here is going to be twenty four plus six which
is thirty. Thirty plus three thirty three
thirty one twenty eight plus three is thirty
one. When you come here obviously it is going
to be some of the all the jobs which come
to plus five. So the total positional weight
is fifty here. So the numbers that we have
computed here can be computed in one run starting
from the back and coming to the front and
getting these particular numbers. Now these
numbers will define and will actually tell
us how to determine then try how to go about
designing the assembly line.
See designing an assembly line is now based
on these numbers and this is how we proceed.
For instance you start with a first basket
which is the first workstation. You open the
first workstation and at the first workstation
this is the only job which is eligible because
it has no precedence relationships. So one
will be put there and the moment you put one,
we have consumed five units of time and two
and four are again candidates for placement.
But out of two and four we will take four
because it is a higher positional weight.
So we will put four here and once we put four
here, one and four will consume a total time
of 8 and we can go up to a maximum time of
ten. There is no other job available at this
junction which can be accommodated within
this. So we close this particular workstation
with work time of 8 units and proceed to the
next station.
When you proceed to the next station, this
has been placed. There are two jobs completing
for placement in this particular work station.
This 1, 2 and 5 and out of these, this one
has a higher positional weight so we take
two and place it first. When you place two,
three can be placed too and five can be placed
but out of the two this will get a priority.
So it can be accommodated because the total
time is going to be only nine, so you can
put this. You keep proceeding in this particular
fashion and you will keep on filling these
buckets. The movement you cannot enter anything
more into this bucket you open the next bucket.
So we are now at the first workstation, the
second one, the third one, the fourth one,
and fifth one and sixth one. So in this design
two we have been able to determine the six
workstations and also the operations which
are to be done at these individual work stations
and these are the cycle times. Since this
has the highest cycle time which is ten that
means this particular line will now operate
for a cycle time of ten, as we have decided
earlier.
So what we can do is we can look up and can
try to evaluate this particular design. We
can see for instance that the evaluation of
the design by the RPW method. Again the balanced
delay in the line efficiency of the same is
because the balance delay and the line efficiency
are determined by the number of workstations.
In this design also you have six workstations
in the previous design and you get six workstations.
So practically what is the minimum number
of workstations? How will you calculate this?
You have fifty which is your total work content
and your cycle time is ten, fifty by ten which
five is.
Ideally you can work with the theoretical
minimum number of workstations are five but
in the two procedures that you have just adopted,
we could not we could have these individual
operations into five workstations. So the
balance delay is 16.7 percent. The line efficiency
is 83.3 percent and this particular case.
However if you look at the smoothness index,
there is an improvement in the smoothness.
The smoothness index is found for this design.
Look at the ideal times here, 2 2 square which
is 4 1 square which is 1 1 square which is
1 3 square which is 9 0 and 3 and 3 squares
which is 9. The square root of this is 4.9
is an improvement on the earlier smoothness
index that we have. It means this is slightly
better balanced line as compare to the previous
one. So we can therefore look at the precedence
diagram and from the precedence diagram depending
upon the RPWs, depending upon the positional
weights, we can determine how to fill up these
individual workstations and come up with design.
Subsequently we can evaluate the design in
terms of the three major parameters, balance,
delay, line efficiency and the smoothness
index for these particular situations. The
question now is what are the possible reasons
for high balance delay? Balance delay measures
the inefficiency line; inefficiency means
the degree of idle time which is there for
the various operators.
Some of the reasons for this are:
1. The wide range of work element times. What
can happen is for instance in your example
the work element times will not be constant
for all the operations. If all the work element
time references in one each or even smaller
than this one, then you could combine them
into getting any operation time. But this
does not happen. Some work element time maybe
only one unit second, work element time might
be 12 units and you have to take it as it
is because the operations are not further
divisible.
2. Another possibility could be a large amount
of inflexible line mechanization. What might
happen in the practical design situation is
that you already have a line and you already
have a great degree of mechanization. So when
you have placed some machines at certain stations
which already perform a certain number of
operations, you are actually constrained by
putting in those operations and that particular
point although might not result in the best
balance delay. This could be another reason.
3. Then indiscriminate choice of cycle times
could also lead to high balance device. What
it means is if you know that in our example
we consider the feasible range of cycle times
was from 7 units to 50 units, a wide range
is in it. So you could attempt to do a line
of cycle time of let us say seven or a cycle
time of ten or a cycle time of fifteen or
cycle time of whatever it is. If you do that
then for different cycle times, you will probably
not get the right time. You might get a high
balance delay. These are at least some of
the reasons why you have high balance delay.
Let us now look at some of the problems and
prospects of mass production. You see for
instance that one of the major problems of
mass production is that the variable work
element times. We have designed the line based
on deterministic times but if an operator
is doing a manual task then it is quite likely
that the task time is normally distributed
with certain mean and certain variance. So
sometimes you operator will take less some
times the operator will take more. Then you
will probably find that there could be starvation
for these subsequent machines in that sense
of the term.
What is done is in order to deal with this
problem sometimes buffers are provided in
between the tasks. What can happen is even
if this fellow is slow, or this machine is
slow, this particular person can keep on operating
from these buffers. So this is the variable
effect of the variable work element time.
In fact this problem of finding out the optimum
buffer is an optimization problem. A problem
which can be determined and then there could
be a breakdown at a workstation. If there
is a breakdown at workstation what will happen?
Since the line is all connected, where there
is a breakdown they will be flooding of parts
and beyond that there will be starving of
parts. All the other machines will be start.
So that is why you have to get back into operation
as early as possible and we said the maintenance
stop has to be very quick.
There could be multi product lines that mean
the same line can produce multiple products
this can happen. For instance in Maruti udyog
the same line can produce a Maruti 800, you
can also produce a Zen because what we do
is we change some operations and something
can be done. So designing multi product lines
means that you can handle the same thing.
We can also talk about modular production
and group technology which is an alternative
to assembly lines. This means that you can
talk about grouping parts in a certain fashion.
So that you can achieve modular production
and cellular manufacturing which will try
to capture the advantages of both product
and process layouts and that is the basic
feature of cellular manufacture and of course
automation and robotics have their role to
play. When you are talking about assembly
lines, many operations can be automated. You
can have robots performing many of the operations.
Typically for instance in automobile manufacturing
you find that robots perform this operation
of spot welding of various sheets and components
and we can also use FMS and CIM systems to
perform and automate and programs and some
of the operations that have to be done. Finally
let us try to summarize what we have tried,
what we have done in this particular class.
We will try to look at the advantages and
disadvantages of assembly lines or products
layouts. We have seen the basic principles
involved in the design of assembly lines.
We found that the basic principles involve
things like division of labor and interchangeability
of parts. Contributions by Adam Smith and
by E Whitney help us operate the assembly
line and then we saw that the assembly the
precedence diagram and market requirements
of the design are the two major inputs you
need for designing an assembly line. So you
need the precedence diagram and the desired
cycle time, the rate you would like to produce
the part at. We could like to do the grouping
of elements in a product layout. This could
be done by various algorithms. We mention
some of them and we actually looked at the
RPW procedure in some detail. We found that
they were measures and efficiency like balance
delay line efficiency and smoothness index
for a line and finally we talked about some
of the emerging concepts which could be in
the nature of multi product lines. The provision
for a buffer automation and worker empowerment
is a very important concept, originally given
by the Japanese which allows the operator
to run the line at his will. That means you
can stop the line when there is a problem.
All the workers get together and they repair
the line and then they go back to the respective
places in from the line. So these are some
of the concepts which are there for productiveness.
I think with this we have been talking mainly
about the strategic aspects of design of a
production system in this course. Now we will
go over to the operational decisions which
are relevant in a production system. We talk
about the problem of forecasting aviate production
planning and planning production system.
Thank you!