food magically appear on my plate. Can you
please recommend a one pot recipe of guaranteed
good grub. Thank you!
One pot cooking's really great because it
saves you time, you can get really amazing
depth of flavour in there. I have a really
good recipe that hopefully Fiona will really
like. A lovely beef and ale stew and there's
loads of variations on it. But I think it's
a good place to start.
In the base of your one pot dish you want
to use two onions, two cloves of garlic, two
carrots, two celery, two bay leaves. All you
want to do is peel and roughly chop them,
put it all in a pan. This is not your one
pot pan, this is a different pan. On the heat,
you can just add it all to the slow cooker.
But to get more flavour. It's better to just
spend. 10 to 15minutes cooking off this base
bit first, and then adding it into here.
In here I've got 400g of stewing beef. So
that will serve about four to six people.
With slow cooking you want to use the cheaper
cuts of meat because they tend to be the cuts
that are tighter so then when you slow cook
it, it kind of breaks it down. The meat kind
of goes ahhh.
I'm going to add flour, this will coat the
beef and also help thicken the sauce. Salt
and pepper's going to go in here too. Just
toss it all around so you get a nice coating
on the beef.
And then I'm also going to add this to my
base ingredients. Just to brown it off for
literally five minutes. You can see it's slightly
coloured, keeps the flavour in. Fiona, you
don't have to do this, but I think it's good
to take this time. You know, 20minutes in
total max. To cook all this off to then put
it in here and then you can leave it for hours
and hours.
This one we're doing is beef and ale which
is a classic. You can do chicken and white
wine, you could do pork and cider, you could
do lamb red wine. So yeah, those are the classic
combinations.
So this is now ready to go in here. So that's
on. Different cookers will have different
settings. You probably want it on sort of
medium because the lower the setting, the
longer the time you can keep it in there for.
I'm going to add, one tin of chopped tomatoes.
And then some ale, 500mls. That all goes in.
Just give it a mix around.
It will all cook off, it won't be sort of
alcoholic. Now, just going to put the lid
on and then that's it! Four, five hours later.
Done.
So, this has been cooking for four to five
hours. If you were coming in from work take
the lid off and then just leave it without
the lid on cooking for like 20minutes. Just
to thicken it up a bit. Just let's the liquid
evaporate slightly. Obviously it's all cooked
and lovely. You can see the meat is starting
to break down a bit, it's thickened up.
Bay leaves, remember to take those out. You
don't want to eat a whole bayleaf.
Let's serve up, I have got for you some mash
and then some nice savoy cabbage.
This is a pretty simple beef and ale stew,
but you can make it more complicated if you
want to. To the base you can add marmalade
or Worcestershire sauce or tomato puree.
This is the perfect one pot recipe. Leave
it, you don't have to worry about it. Perfect.
If you have any questions for Jamie's food
team, drop it in the comments box below or
send us a video response. Alternatively write
and email to foodtube@jamieoliver.com. We
would love to hear all your questions, tips
and suggestions on any of the topics we talk
about.
To get the latest uploads, don't forget to
subscribe. We're here to help you too!