of these men were
gunners on the airplane.
And their job was to sit
behind these guns
and protect the aircraft.
They sat in these Plexiglas
turrets, and these turrets
were scattered through
the airplane;
you can see them
on the front here,
and on the top, and the
back, and the side
and down the bottom,
depending on the aircraft.
And their job was to
protect the bomber from
fighter aircraft attacking it.
That's what
they did.
And so these guns were
strategically placed on the
airplane as a protection
for that aircraft.
But it wasn't just for
that aircraft alone.
What they would do was that
they would fly in formation.
And one airplane's gunners
could also protect the other
aircraft that was flying
along next to them.
And so they would have these
very complex formations
that they would fly in--
all to protect each other.
And as they flew in
formation, they had strength;
you could say there was
strength in their numbers.
But there was also strength
in the way that they were
fitted together in formation.
Now, anyone flying alone
was a sitting duck.
It was just like--well,
you're out there. Sorry.
And sometimes when
we try to establish--
you run into somebody and
you're trying to witness
--they say, "Where do
you get this information?"
"Well,from the Bible." "How
can I know the Bible is true?"
Oh, we quickly grab this
Scripture 2 Timothy 3:16
and we say, "All Scripture
is inspired by God."
And we throw this little piece
of information out there;
and it's like--bing!
Battle's won. Uh-uh.
The guy comes back and says,
"Oh, Scripture? So, all
"Scripture is inspired by
God. Well, I agree with
"that--yeah. The Hindu
Gita, it's inspired by God too;
"let me see, the
Quran, it's Scripture;
"it's inspired by God.
Listen, while we're at it,
"we might as well throw the
Book of Mormon and a few
"other books that we
know about into that.
"All these Scriptures that
different people hold sacred,
"they're inspired by God, too.
It says 'all Scripture,'
doesn't it?"
And your sitting there
and thinking--whew!
How did we get here?
And then you try to
nail the word,
"Well, no, no, no, no.
It means inspired."
"Oh, yeah, I wrote a poem
the other day, and I just,
"oh, I just felt so inspired;
it just flowed; it just came.
That must be Scripture, too."
And you think, oh,
how'd that happen?
We're off on some
sort of rabbit trail.
And then, oh, my! You
get to the word 'God'--
and now who knows where
you are going to end up?
And there in just one
little short sentence,
not a whole verse, you
just feel like you
kinda ran up against a wall.
You know what you have?
You have one little
piece of truth--
flying by itself unprotected.
It's true, it's powerful.
It, indeed, even that little
bit alone, is very potent.
But, the enemy comes
in there and envelopes it
with its ameba there and
wraps itself around
and shoots it down, and when
you are left; you think--
"Oh, where am I supposed to--
where should I begin?"
Well, we want to talk a
little bit about that.
We want to talk about
flying truth in formation.
And I just want
to start out by saying,
that what I want to
present here is not
because I'm sort of
scholar and I sat down
with a long face and I looked
at the Scriptures for a
while and studied it--all of a
sudden, "Oh, I see that!"
The way I began
to see this was, as I was
teaching individuals,
all of a sudden, I would
see something come in
there and grab them.
And I--wow, that's powerful!
Oh, now I see why that's
in the Scripture that way!
It would really have
quite an effect on them.
Now, what I want to show you
here is actually a framework
that is stuck together
in the Scriptures.
And when we fly this together,
it's extremely potent.
When we teach the way
that we're talking about,
you're actually doing this.
Now, when we teach, in a
sense, what we do, is we take
a person--the individual
that is coming to us,
the unbeliever--we take
their framework, and
we have some little tricks of
the trade that we've learned.
We take their framework and
we hang it up and we say,
"We'll just let it
sit over there."
And we teach them this
whole new framework.
Now, there's ways that
we do that. For example,
I was teaching a fellow;
he was a very sharp man.
And as we were going
through the story, beginning
with Creation and working
our way through the Fall
of mankind, and then
eventually, we got to the story
of Noah; and we're developing
it out a little bit--
we just touch on these stories.
He looks at me and says,
"John, you don't
believe this, do you?"
And this is the way
I answered it.
I said, "Well...what I
believe is up to me,
"and what you believe
is entirely up to you.
"We're finding out what
the Bible says about itself.
"And I guess my job is try to
present it as clearly as I can,
"and your job as a
student is to say,
"'I understand it' or
'I don't.'" I said,
"The question here is not
whether I believe it or not,
but the question is, 'Do
you understand it.'"
He said, "Oh, yeah,
I understand it."
I said, "Well,
then lets go on."
And what I did there was I
took his framework and I
kinda hung it up and
I said, "Let's just
leave that there for a while."
Later on, he said,
"John, do you remember that
time where I kinda mocked
you a little bit for the story
of Noah and that stuff?"
I said,
"Yeah, I remember that."
And he said, "You know, I
wasn't believing any of it
"up to that point. To me, it
was just a bunch of myths
and stories. I wasn't
believing any of it."
But he said, "What happened…
as I went on, through the
"story, I began to say,
'You know what?
"'This just couldn't happen.
This had to be planned
from the bottom up.'"
And he said,
"I went back and believed
all of this here that
I had rejected."
Now what we're going to do
is, we're going to take a look
at the different aspects in
God's Word that God has
built right in there to the
architecture of His Word,
that causes a person to come
to a point in saying,
"This just couldn't happen.
This just couldn't happen."
And where the veracity--the
truthfulness of God's Word--
just comes through like an
extremely powerful hammer.
And either a person out
of emotion has to just
reject the Word of God, or
because he's a thinking
person, he says, "You know,
it's gotta be true."
But there's no such thing
as a thinking person
looking at it and saying
intellectually,
"This can't happen."
No, he's got to do it as
an emotional response
to the truth;
it's so powerful.
Let's take a look at it.
First of all,
the prophetic events in the
Scriptures verify the message.
Now how does this work?
I want to just take a look
at the books of Moses.
If you were to take a look at
the lifespan of Moses here,
Moses wrote what we
might want to call some
'must-know' information.
He wrote about the origin
of the universe
--this is critical stuff.
He wrote about the origin of
mankind, about the origin
of evil and sin,
origin of death,
how to escape sorrow,
the source of joy.
He wrote about eternal life.
And this is all critical
information that Moses
either touched on or
developed out quite a bit--
that is either what you
might want to call
'must-know' information.
And he recorded this in the
last third of his lifespan.
And you find this information
in the books Genesis,
Exodus--on through
to Deuteronomy.
And as we look at this
information here,
we can ask ourselves,
"How do we know that
what Moses wrote was right?"
I mean, back in those days
there, the people that lived
in that 40 years of Moses
lifespan, that knew him--
as they were seeing this
material written, they say,
"Well, how do we
know this is right?
"What is, what sort of
reality do we have here
that can verify
this information?"
Well, Moses not only wrote
'must-know' information,
he also wrote
Prophetic information.
And this has some really
severe consequences.
Now listen to this--tell
you a little story here.
I first used this in India
here a couple years ago.
I said, What would happen if
somebody was to
call a press conference?
Now nobody knows this guy,
but he calls this press
conference, and he says,
"Listen, I have some very
"important information
I have to pass on.
"What's going to happen
(now this is Friday)
"what's going to happen is,
on Monday, the Ganges River
is going to turn to blood."
And you can see a little handful
of scattering, smattering
of reporters sitting out
there, and they're write--
"What? Say that again?"
"The Ganges River is
going to turn to blood."
"To blood?" "Yes,
that's what I said.…
That's what you need
to write down."
Well, if it even hit
the newspapers at all,
you know the Saturday
edition--if it even got there
at all--it probably got to page
forty, little column in the
bottom, and it would say,
"Crazy man,"
or "Kook says, 'Ganges river
is going to turn to blood.'"
Well, what if on Monday,
the river actually did
turn to blood? Whoa!
Monday's afternoon edition
--bang--big letters:
"Ganges turned to
blood, forecast by--"
"What was that guy's name?
I didn't even get it down."
It's crazy. But it
would be up there.
And there'd be reprints of
that tiny little column--
"Yep, we did actually say
that this man said that."
Everybody would
be talking about it.
You'd have scientists down
there sampling it, seeing if
it's some sort of reversal
of the red tide.
And political pundits
would be talking about
this--looking wise.
And everybody would
be talking about this.
And there would probably be
a lot of people saying,
"That guy hit it lucky; it's
just some sort of weird
phenomena that he was
going to come up with."
Might be some guy trying to
sell it on Ebay, who knows?
But, what if he called a
second press conference?
That room would be
crowded, wouldn't it?
It would, wouldn't it?
There'd be cameras running.
There's CNN.
Everybody would be there.
They'd all be wanting
to arrange to get him
on their talk show and discuss
this. And let's say, he said,
"Well, on Thursday this
country is going to be
overrun with frogs--
overrun with frogs."
Well, you could imagine the
next day, they'd be saying--
scientists would be saying--
"Frogs don't breed this time
"of year, and they
don't normally have--
that's just ridiculous!"
There would be all sorts
of pundits giving comments
on this, but I can tell you
what-- on Wednesday night, about
11:35, everyone would be
sitting there very, very quiet.
The windows open,
listenting.
11:50. 11:55. Midnight.
Ribbit, ribbit.
Whoa!
And just this noise just
permeates the land as they
all being to sing and croak.
Whoa, I mean, you can
imagine the next morning--
this guy is being hauled in.
The prime minister of the
country wanting to meet with
him and discuss this. And it
would be big, big news.
And if this guy then
said, "Well, listen,
"just wanted you to get
the point here:
"that there's a message
that a particular God
"wants to pass
on to the world.
"And he wants you to know
it's important--he has some
"'must-know' information
that you need to know and
"I've been kinda
appointed his messenger.
And, oh, by the way,
next Friday--lice."
You know what?
Everybody would be
listening very carefully.
And everybody
would be hanging on
not only for the fact that he's
saying next Thursday's lice,
but they would also want to know
this 'must-know' information.
You know why?
Because all of a sudden,
he has incredible credibility
in their eyes.
And the Bible tells us this
happened, didn't it,
to a man named Moses?
And it says that God
exalted him in the eyes
of the people; he was
like a god to Pharaoh.
I mean, it's like, what
Moses said, the people
just breathed it in
like pure oxygen.
It had to be.
And the way the
Scripture's design… it was
this prophetic information was
linked together with the
'must-know' information, and
it's inserted in such a way
that you can't divide it.
And Moses, all the way through
the last 40 years of his life,
we see him saying, "God says
this is going to happen."
And guess what? It happened.
There was 100% accurate
fulfillment of those things
that he said was
going to happen.
It just went down that way.
And so, the people during Moses'
lifespan, if they wanted
to know how this 'must-know'
information was true,
all they had to think is,
"Well, Moses said this
other stuff was going to
happen and it happened
just the way it is; well,
it's gotta be true."
Now, that works for people
in Moses' lifespan,
but what about now?
Well, Moses didn't just give
prophecies during his life span.
He also said things that were
going to happen after he died.
And if we were to take his
lifespan and shrink it down--
like this, into a box--and stick
it right at the end of our
timeline there, and
extend our timeline down
to 2006 AD, and look at
this, we'd see that, yes,
Moses gave prophecies in that
last 40 years of his life;
but he also talked
about issues and events
that would happen right
down to this present day.
And after Moses died, for
those people that were
asking that question--"How do
we know that this is right?"--
they would be able to just
look around and say,
"Well, is it happening
the way that
Moses said it
would happen?"
Now Moses
said that after he died,
the people would be
disobedient, remember that?
And he said, "You're
stiff necked;
you're going to
become disobedient."
And people after would be able
to look around and say,
"Have we done that?"
We can read in the
book of Daniel.
Look what Daniel said:
Daniel was very conscious
that they had rebelled
against the Lord. He labeled
it for what it was.
Daniel was very conscious
of judgment
being played out
on his life.
And so as people of Daniel's
day looked around and said,
"How do we know that this
information is right?
'Well, we are doing exactly
what Moses said we
"would do, we've
become disobedient;
we've rebelled
against the Lord."
Not only that, Moses had
said that because of that,
they would suffer curses.
Remember that? He wrote
that--Deuteronomy.
And so the people would be
able to look around, and
they would see that--"You
know what? Boy, just as
Moses wrote, we're
suffering curses."
Look what Daniel continued
on in his prayer and said:
(This is a continuation
of what we just read.)
The linkage was very clear
in their mind between what
Moses had written and what they
were experiencing in their life.
And so, when they
asked those questions:
"How do we know this is
right?" Well, they could
just look around and see
there's been 100%
accurate fulfillment
of what Moses
said would happen
after he died.
We're living it.
Moses also wrote about the
Messiah--that he would come.
He wrote that the people
would be scattered.
It's interesting
reading those chapters
and reading Josephus
side by side.
It's just incredible--
the detail that's in there.
He wrote that the people
after they were scattered,
they'd be persecuted;
and then also that
they'd be regathered.
And so down through the
centuries, as people would
ask, "You know, how do we
know what Moses wrote here
about the origin of the
universe, about the origin
of mankind, about the
origin of evil and sin,
origin of death, how
to escape sorrow,
the source of joy,
eternal life--
all this critical information,
how do we know it's right?"
Well, all they needed to
do is look around
and they would see what
Moses wrote was being
fulfilled in their
very lifetime.
And they could look back in
history--over a long span--and
they could see, "Yeah,
it's just happened--
the way it played out."
And so, what was happening
there was that 'must-know'
information was being
verified by prophetic events.
And I think it's tragic that
we've come to a point
in our church (I'm talking
about in a global sense),
where people don't want
to talk about prophecy.
You know it's divisive, so
we don't talk about it.
We use little jokes: "I'm not
a 'a-mil,' or 'post-mil' or
'pre-mil'; I'm a
'pan-mil'--it's all going
to pan out in the end."
We do this sort of
thing, you know.
But the thing is: what we're
doing is we're taking one of
the very powerful pieces of
God's architecture in the
Word of God and we're just
throwing it out the window.
Now, I don't think we should
go around and just nail
dates down and be hyper-
dogmatic about some of
some of this stuff. Let's
leave it a little open here.
But let's say we can
use words like,
"It seems to be..."
"It looks like it might...."
And if we disagree,
let's disagree without
being disagreeable.
But lets not stop talking
about prophecy in Scripture.
I've read that 27% of
Scripture is prophecy--
much of which has
been fulfilled.
It's a very potent
airplane of truth
that we want to have
flying in our formation.
Let's go on.
The types reveal and
anchor doctrines--
types that we
find in Scripture.
We're going to look at this area
of what it reveals first.
And what I want us to do
is: I want us to start
by looking at the Passover.
And we know that
the Passover was--
came as a result of
the tenth plague.
Now here's the Israelites:
they're in Egypt;
they've been in
bondage there;
they're slaves
in hard labor.
And God brings these
plagues along to cause
the Pharaoh to release the
Israelites from Egypt.
Now that's not the only reason.
I think there's more there;
we don't have time to go there.
He brought these plagues
along, and the tenth one
was to be the death of the
firstborn, remember that?
And…how many here
are the firstborns?
Put up your hand.
Now, when you heard these
instructions, if you were
back then, you would have
listened very carefully.
You'd be taking
notes. You'd say,
"Hold it, Moses, slow down,
slow down, slow down."
First of all, they
were to take a lamb.
(We're not going to look at
the whole Passover.)
Here's my lamb right here.
I know it's small,
but it's cold in Canada,
and they don't grow big.
So, here's my lamb.
They were told
to take a lamb--
and remember it
had to be a male.
That was the gender--
it had to be a male.
And then it was to be without
blemish--it couldn't have the
wool falling out. It couldn't
have a broken leg
or anything like that.
They were to kill it at
the appointed day
and the appointed hour--
there was a time they
were to do this.
Now think, this is kind
of a strange thing.
Can you imagine the
instructions?
I mean, this is to
prevent the death
of the first-born child.
Why didn't he just say,
"Go and lay in bed
for the full day."?
Why didn't he do that?
No, we're getting
this very elaborate--
and like I said, we're not
going to look at it all.
This is what
they're to do here.
And you're supposed
to kill it;
and when you kill it,
shed its blood.
Don't hit it over the head
with a club. You are to
kill it in such a way that
you shed its blood; and
then you are to take its
blood and you're to apply
it to the doorposts and
the lintel of the house.
So we see this animal to
be killed, and the blood
is to be put on--can
you see it over there?
It's to be put on
the door posts
and the lintel
of the house.
Now, that's what
they are to do.
Then they're to stay in the
house: go inside the door,
stay in the house, and
partake of the animal;
and while they do this, don't
break any of its bones.
Now, you think about that--
what a strange prescription
of events to prevent the
death of the firstborn.
What was going on here?
What we were told--that
if they would do this,
that when the death angel
came, he would pass over
that house in judgment.
He would pass over it.
Now, what was
that all about?
Well, this was a picture;
it was an illustration.
And what it was a
picture of was...
The Passover was a
prophetic picture of
something that was
going on here.
Now, what was it?
It was the picture of the
substitutionary work
of Jesus Christ.
You see, just as they were
asked to take a lamb,
the Scripture tells us that
John the Baptist, upon seeing
Jesus, he says, "Look, the…
Lamb of God that takes away
the sins of the world."
Jesus was called
the Lamb of God.
And just as the Passover
lamb had to a male,
so Jesus was a man.
And just as the Passover lamb
had to be without blemish,
so Jesus was without sin.
And just as the Passover lamb
was kept until the appointed
time and even the
appointed hour,
and then he died, so Jesus
died on the appointed day.
I believe it was the Passover at
the appointed hour--it was
3:00 in the afternoon, the
hour of the evening sacrifice.
Right on schedule.
And then just as the Passover
lamb was not to have its
bones broken, when
Jesus was on the cross,
they didn't break
his bones either.
And just as by staying
inside the house, that was
the only place they could
find safety, it's so only
in Jesus Christ that we find
safety from eternal death.
And just as back in those
days (in the days of Moses)
where the Bible
says that if they did that,
and by faith they
trusted the Lord YHWH,
and believed that His words
were true, and they just
put their confidence that--
yes, you know, maybe the
first born was sitting there
and he's biting his nails,
and he was worrying
away, but he didn't need
to worry--because it was
all taken care of.
When the death angel came,
he passed over that house.
Why? Because judgment
had already come
to rest on the lamb.
In Egypt that night, there was
a death in every household.
There was either the
death of the firstborn,
or there was a death
of the lamb.
But, if they had followed what
God had said, and by faith
just trusted God and his
word, the Bible says that
when the death angel came,
he passed over that house--
wherever judgment
had already come
to rest upon the lamb.
And you see, the
same thing applies to us--
just as the lamb died in
place of the first born,
so the Bible tells us that
Jesus Christ died
in our place: He
was our substitute.
This is talking about the
substitionary work of Christ.
And when God comes in
judgment to judge the world,
His judgment will
pass over us. Why?
Because it's already come
to rest on our Lamb.
The types of Scripture reveal
to us certain doctrines,
like the substitutionary
work of Christ.
It really nails it down
in our mind.
And the interesting thing is,
is that this is something
unique to Scripture.
It's also a form
of prophecy.
And you only find it
in the Scriptures.
You don't find it anywhere
else. You don't find it in the
Quran; you don't find
it in any of the other
scriptures out there.
You can't go to the Gita, or the
Vetas--no, it's not in those.
This is something--the whole
idea of prophetic text
is very, very unique
to the Bible.
And it's extremely powerful.
You know, as we use this in
our teaching, we find you
see people sitting there;
they're just gripped by it.
It's like a riddle.
You know, when someone
gives you a riddle, you
sit there and it's all like--
ah, man, I can't get this.
And then all of a sudden, you
get it and it's like--bing!
And it's like your eyes
pop open, the scales fall
off and it's like--"Ahh!"
"Oh!" And then you're one
of those guys sitting
in the room that's got
it, and all the rest--
the rest are sitting there
and…As we do this, as we
teach, we see people
sit there, and you can
actually see in their
faces when it pops off.
It just--on this last trip
to India, Singapore, and
Korea--I remember when
I was teaching there in Korea.
As I was getting to
this point, all of a sudden
I tied the types together. This
lady started tapping her cheeks.
And she was so excited,
she started going
like this with her hands.
And then she looked down
each side and she
put her hands down.
But you could see
it right in her;
you know, it just
bubbled out the top,
because all of a sudden
they got it. It clicked.
They know what it's all
about. They could see it--
Jesus is my Passover Lamb;
He's my subtistute.
Very very powerful stuff.
Very powerful prophecy.
It's something that we
want to have flying
in our armada of truth.
Types not only reveal, but
they also anchor doctrines.
And what do I
mean by that?
Well, as an example, I'm
going to use accuracy
in expression of
salvation truths--
the accuracy in expression
of salvation truths.
Now, stick with me here.
I want to take you to
the tabernacle, and
I want to specifically
look at the brazen altar.
Now, if you're visually
challenged--and I find
some people just don't relate
to something flat on a screen--
here's a 3D model of the
tabernacle that you can
get from us and it will really
help you in your teaching.
We're looking at the
brazen altar right here.
That's what's in question.
All right?
And what they were told--and
we're just really jumping
forward here--the people back
then (if you look in Leviticus),
it says that they were
to bring an offering.
It had to be from the
herd or the flock--
you couldn't bring a crocodile
or a pig or something like
that--it had to be from the
herd or the flock.
It had to be a male; it had
to be without blemish.
And what they had to do,
they had to bring this
to the brazen altar--they were
going to make an offering there.
I'll set this down
here for a moment.
I want to take
this one here--
it's not brazen--but you
got the idea, OK?
And they were to bring
it to this altar.
And what they were
to do is: they were
to place their hand on the
head of that animal.
Now, what was going on here
I believe, is that what
the Bible communicates is
like the person is
saying, "I deserve to die for
my sin; but I'm putting
"faith that God's word,
what he's given here, is true.
"And it's as though my sin
is being transferred
from me to this animal.
And when that happens, this
animal dies in my place."
What we see here with this
hands on the head, we see
that concept of substitution
being brought out here again.
And it's a very powerful
picture that you
can elaborate on
and deal with.
Now the reason why this is
brought out this way,
I believe, is because once
again, when we get to the
New Testament, we see that…
We're dealing with
a substitution issue here.
And this altar picture
here--what we see going
on here--is actually to help
us understand what went
on the cross, when Jesus
Christ took our sin;
it was transferred
from us on to him.
He became our sin bearer,
and he died in our place.
It's all about substitution.
And I really believe that's the
core issue of the gospel--is
substitution, substitutionary
work of Christ.
Now, when we're expressing
salvation truths,
we want to couch our
vocabulary in that sense;
we want to use vocabulary
that communicates
the substitutionary
work of Christ.
But do we do that
all the time?
Well, you know, what do you
do with something like this?
Now, you're driving down
the road, an unbeliever;
you're totally paganized,
and you see that.
You've heard about this
Jesus guy a little bit.
Is he a medical doctor?
Is he into heart
transplants, or what?
Now, we have a problem here.
And you know, we use all sorts
of little phrases that codify
what it means to
be a Christian.
This is just one of
them, as you know.
But, we have a problem,
because if we go back
to our picture here, here we
are--we're standing here.
And just pretend for a moment:
I've brought my sacrifice
to the brazen altar.
Here we are. I've come and
I'm just very weighed down
with a consciousness
and how sinful I am.
And I come, and I
look at that lamb.
I put my hand on its
head and say,
"I'd like to give
my heart to you."
You know, the lamb looks up
and says, "Well, I'm
not going to be around here
in a few minutes, you know."
Or maybe I bring my sacrifice
and I come to the brazen altar.
And I put my hand
on its head; and I look
at the lamb, and say, "I'd
like to give you my heart,
or I'd like to
give you my life."
The lamb says, "That's very
nice, but once again, I'm not
going to be around
in a few minutes."
It doesn't fit the picture.
You get the idea?
What we need to do is--
we need to run
our terminology
past the altar.
And we need to be sure
that when we do, that it
honestly and sincerely
reflects what's going on here.
And the fact is that I'm
a sinner, weighed down
with the guilt and the weight
of sin. And I desperately
need a substitute, and God has
provided it in Jesus Christ.
We need to run our
terminology past there.
Now, if we do that, we
won't be reflecting
accurately what Jesus
Christ did on the cross,
and we'll get into all
sorts of things.
I really like the way Trevor
McIllwain expressed this;
I just got to
give this to you.
I just can't think of a
better way to say it.
We got to make sure that
we're accurate in expression.
And you know what?
The types that we
find in Scripture help anchor
the way we express it.
Here, look at another thing.
It not only anchors
our expression,
it anchors our content.
You know, I believe that the
Scripture tells us that
Jesus Christ--he died for sins
once for all--and that when
we put our trust in Him, we
are secure in Christ;
we can't lose our salvation.
You come back to
this picture here--
the idea of placing your
hands on the head there.
It was the picture
of identification.
You were identifying
with this substitute.
It was though one's sins
was being transferred
from yourself to
that substitute.
That was the idea.
It was your sins were
being imputed to it.
But if you could lose
your salvation, now think
for a moment here, if you
could lose your salvation,
you would have to somehow
reverse this process.
Now, I don't know
what that would look like,
but I took a guess here.
You don't see this in the
Scriptures. You don't.
We could look at another
part of the tabernacle.
You know, here's the veil,
that was between the
Holy of Holies, where God's
presence symbolically
was exhibited right
there over the top
of that mercy seat--
between the two cherubim,
and the Holy Place. And
that veil--it held man out.
It protected God's holiness.
But we see there that when
Jesus died on the cross,
"It is finished," he bowed his
head, gave up his spirit.
And it says in Luke that
the curtain of the temple
was torn in two
from top to bottom.
And Hebrews explains that what
that was: that was the picture
of the body of the Lord
Jesus Christ being torn
for you and me, so that a
way could be open for us
to enter through that curtain
right into God's presence.
It's an incredibly potent,
powerful picture.
You know, I remember
when I was working
with New Tribes Mission--
this happened a number
of years ago when
my son was just
five or six years of age--
just a little boy.
And I was sitting in a
leadership conference;
I was doing some teaching
there. And they had this
elevated stool that I was
sitting on, so I was kinda
looking down on all the
rest of the leaders there
in this big conference
room--big oval table there,
by the lectern and everything.
And we're sitting there and
talking; all these older men
are sitting there--
very important
individuals.
All of a sudden, the door
bangs open--'Bang!'--and
there stands my son with
a glass of water.
And he just marches right in.
He walks by all these
important older men, and
he walks right up to me
and he holds up
this glass to me.
Now, that's the picture here.
Because the reason was--
why my son had no fear of
coming boldly into their
presence, boldly into my
presence--was because I was
his…father.
And you see, that's what
we have pictured here.
When that was torn, we has
now that have put our faith
in what Jesus Christ
did on the cross,
we enter boldly
into God's presence,
because he's our…father.
Ahh! Powerful, isn't it? It's
great stuff. Great stuff.
But if we could lose
our salvation--
if we could lose our
salvation--somehow
we'd have to be kicked out
of the Holy of Holies,
and then this would
have to be stitched back up.
You know what? We
don't see that illustrated
in Scripture anywhere.
We don't.
And so what we find is that
not only do the types reveal
doctrines in the Scriptures,
they help us understand the
substitutionary work of
Christ, but they also
anchor these doctrines
in such a way
to protect us from
getting into error.
They keep us from
shifting around;
it's like cement when you
start studying those types--
you are just locked right
down to what they are saying.
And, of course, the Scripture
in the New Testament
is so good at
just tying back in
and revealing this is
exactly what was going on.
Well, I want to look at
the third area, and that
has to do with the fact that
stories define the words.
Now, we're really
facing a crisis in our
human language philosophy
here in the world,
and that is in this whole area
that post-modernism--
and I'm sure a lot of you have
studied post-modernism--
you at least know
something about it.
Post-moderns believe that
words no longer have…
well, they've never had
meaning in their thinking.
And that is because
word meaning changes.
At one time, the word 'gay'
meant to be happy and
cheerful, but now
it means to be…
it has a lifestyle connotation.
And so they say words--
the meanings shift.
You can't write
something and expect it
to mean the same thing
50 years later.
Nor can one person
necessarily interpret another
person's writing correctly,
because the meaning
that is attached to words
by another person
would be different
from the one written.
And, there's an aspect
of truthfulness in there.
Satan doesn't just
tell a 100% lie; he mixes
truth in there; you know, he
really muddles it up for us.
So post-moderns says that
words don't have meaning.
So you can't really tell if
something's right or not
because the meaning's
been shifted around.
But the Bible actually uses
stories to define words.
For example, if we were
to look at the word 'grace'
in Scripture, this is
the word that we use;
and we understand it
to a certain extent.
But, we really--it's not
really strong in our minds.
Especially, when you go
out into the paganized culture
that we live in, the word
'grace' doesn't necessarily
have a whole lot of depth
and meaning to it.
But, you can
go into the Scriptures,
and you can tell the story
about the children
of Israel being out in the
wilderness, as God brought
them out of slavery--
horrible slavery.
He brought them out and
he was leading them
to this land that he promised
to them. And as he took
them there, he provided
them with food.
He provided them water; he
provided them with clothes.
They had shoes
that didn't wear out.
He did all this for them, and,
I think, we would all agree
that this was a wonderful
statement of love.
Is that not right? It was.
And the people were so
thankful and appreciative.
No. They grumbled
and complained.
But what you see there is
that God still showed love.
He didn't say, "Oh,
you miserable crowd.
"I'm going
to stop feeding you.
"In fact, just expect to get
food on Tuesdays.
"The rest of the week
you'll go hungry.
"And you'll be
thankful for Tuesdays."
No, he didn't say that.
He didn't say, "Oh, everyone
--barefoot from now on.
You'll be thankful
for those shoes."
No, he just kept providing
them faithfully--
day in and
day out for 40 years.
He continued to
show them love.
And you know what?
I think we would all agree,
that hey, that was undeserved.
He didn't have to do that.
And you know what?
That's the meaning of 'grace'--
it's undeserved love.
The story defines
the word.
And now, when you think of
the word 'grace,' you think
of that story and you
think, "Oh, wow! Boy,
that's a neat God
that's like that."
And we find that all the
way through Scripture.
You know, where I come from--
Canada, we are running
into issues having to do with
this matter of homosexuality.
And in Canada, if you went
back 35-40 years ago,
homosexuality was
considered a crime.
It was considered a
perversion, a sin.
And you could be arrested; you
could be imprisoned; you could
face severe consequences
for having that lifestyle.
But now, here we are in 2006,
and the last government
brought in and said, "Hey, not
only is it OK, but we're going
"to sanction it by
making it legal. You can
get a marriage license,
"and you can become a married
couple, and all the benefits
that go along with that can
be yours, as a homosexual."
Now the word has been
redefined as something
inappropriate to something
that is appropriate.
But what does the Bible do?
Well, the Bible says, "Hold
on, hold on, hold on here."
What it does is that it gives
the definition for sexual
immorality and perversion.
And what does it use?
It uses a story--Sodom
and Gomorrah.
And it says that these serve as
an example to those that are
going to suffer the
punishment of eternal fire.
It calls it sexual immorality
and perversion,
and it anchors it with a story.
And the government of Canada
may want to say,
"It's just fine,"
but the Bible is going to go
on for eternity saying,
"No, and here's a story to
illustrate what we mean by it."
And you can't get
around the story.
The story locks it down;
you can't change it.
You can try to shift the
meaning of it, but you just
can't do that, because the
story has locked the
definition of the term in
place as defined as sin.
And this is all
throughout Scripture.
Now, I'm going
to throw out a word here,
and I want you to respond
to me and tell me the
story that defines
this word.
Here's the word....What's the
story that defines it?
Hmm?
Abraham. There
you are. Yeah.
Abraham defines it.
So, here's the story
and it defines--
gives the definition
for faith.
Now, if you want to know
what faith is and what
it isn't, then what
should you do?
Well, I believe,
you need to go back and
give a real serious study
to the life of Abraham.
And you do that, and you
will find that when you do
that, it will tell you just
what faith is like,
and what it isn't. Now, I may
step on a few toes here in
what I'm going to do here
in a moment; but I'm going
to tell you something,
and when you do that--
there's a real popular
thinking of faith out there
that I don't think is
Scriptural--and what you
won't find, you'll find
that faith is not a gift.
There's no where in
Scripture where God (YHWH)
gave Abraham a
gift of faith.
It's just not there.
Fact, you'll find the faith
that he exhibited is very
much the sort of faith that
you're showing right now
as you sit on these chairs--
hoping that whoever built
this building did a good job
with the structural steel,
and the roof is
going to stay up.
The stories define the words.
And we can actually say
that probably it helps
to stay out of error.
Now, we need to look at those
stories and see how they
define words, how they
are using it and then
that needs to determine
our theology.
Well, the fourth one--this
will be the last one
that we'll look at--
I believe that the Bible
uses word pictures to
anchor doctrines.
Now, what do I mean
by word pictures?
Well, an example of a word
picture would be redemption--
the idea of being redeemed.
We know that the idea of
being redeemed was a word
that came out of the slave
market, remember that?
It had the idea of a
slave that was chained.
So the picture for us is that
we are individuals that
were chained by sin in the
slave market of life.
There we are. There's nothing
we could do to escape.
We're humbled;
we're shamed;
we're stuck.
There's nothing that we
could do to save
ourselves, and yet the
Bible says that Jesus Christ
came and he bought us.
What did he buy us with?
His blood.
He bought us with His blood.
He took us out of the
slave market and he
broke off those chains
and he set us free.
That's the idea.
Redemption.
And it's very,
very powerful--
the whole idea of
this word picture.
And remember, I
said I don't believe that
you can lose your
salvation; but if you could,
somehow in Scripture
you would need a
word picture that says you
could be un-redeemed.
We don't find that.
Or maybe de-redeemed.
I'm not sure which way
you would go there.
But then most people that
believe that, also believe that
you could be re-redeemed.
So what you would have is:
you'd have, here's your slave
sitting there; he's all chained
and tied up. And then
he gets re-deemed; so
he's happy. Then he's
un-redeemed; then he's
re-redeemed; then he's a
slave; then he's
re-redeemed, un-redeemed,
then he's re-redeemed.
You don't find anywhere
where there's word pictures
in the Bible that
illustrate that.
These word pictures really
anchor certain truths.
What about the word 'justified'?
Very, very powerful truth.
I want to just use
a visual aid here
that I think
will help there.
When we teach on
the area of sin,
we talk about sin
as being
about our human dilemma--
if you want to call it.
When Adam and Eve sinned in
the garden, a dilemma
entered into the human
race. And this dilemma that
we face is like a coin
that has two sides.
You can't divide
these issues, really.
The human dilemma on the
one side is that we face
a sin consequence; we face
a penalty or a debt--
whichever way you
want to phrase it--
that we're
going to have to pay.
Now, we not only endure
consequences in our
lifetime with shame and
guilt and suffering and
anger--all those things
that go along with that--
but we also face death,
in a physical sense.
This is all
consequences of sin.
And then the Bible says
we face this thing called
'the second death,' which is
an eternity in the lake of fire.
And we're facing an
eternity of judgment.
And so there's this horrible
consequence to our sin that
we're facing. And as we look
at it, we see that there's just
no way that we can escape
this on our own; we're stuck.
And so we
have something here
that we really don't want--
about our dilemma.
But there's another side to
our dilemma and that is that
there's something
that we need.
If we're going to live in God's
presence for eternity,
or even for briefly, we would
need perfection.
'Without holiness no
man can see God.'
There's--we would need to be
as perfect as he is perfect.
We would have to have a
righteousness that is
equal to his righteousness
just to be in his presence.
And we don't have that.
So, we face this problem:
How can I get this
that I don't have?
And how can I get rid
of this that I have?
You see, it's a two-
sides-of-the-coin dilemma
that we face here.
Now, what I believe we
can do here is: I believe
we can illustrate this with
the doctrine of justification.
Paul, can you come down
and help me here?
And, Shawn, could you
give me a hand?
If you guys could just
face me here. All right.
I believe that what the
Scripture tells us is that when
God first created mankind,
when we were first created…
(Come forward as far
as you can, fellows.)
When God first
created us, we were
created innocent
of all sin. OK?
We didn't know
anything about sin.
All we knew was the
goodness of God.
Back in that garden
of Eden, the Bible talks
about how God was
man's best friend.
He would come and he would
walk with man in the cool
of the day. And it's
illustrated that there was
a friendship, a communion
between God and man.
There was a fellowship. But
then something happened.
The Bible talks about how,
remember how Satan, in the
form of a serpent,
came into the garden,
and he questioned something
that God had said.
God had said, "You see
that tree over there?
"Don't eat of its fruit,
because the day you eat
of it, you will die."
Now, God in his love had
given a whole forest,
a whole, a world of fruit
they could eat from;
but he said, "Just that one;
don't eat of it."
You might want to call it--it
was like a friendship test.
Do you trust me? And every
day they didn't eat of it,
it was like saying,
"Yeah, we do."
But, when Satan came into
the garden, he said,
"Did God really say that?
"Ha! God knows that the
day you eat of it,
why, you're going to be
an enlightened one."
(That's by the way
what a Buddha is.)
OK? "You're going
to be an enghtened one."
Adam and Eve were faced
with this equation here--
and the equation was this:
God said, "Don't eat of the tree
because you will die." Satan
said, "Go ahead eat of it--
the day you eat of it
you'll be enlightened;
you'll be like God."
So they had to weigh
out in their mind--who's
telling us the truth; who
is our real friend?
And you know what?
The Bible tells us that Adam
and Eve trusted a stranger.
They trusted someone
that they didn't know
his identity, and they
didn't know his history.
They knew that God
was good.
They knew his identity,
and they knew his
history; but they
didn't trust him.
They trusted a stranger
and they threw aside--
they cast aside their
innocence. And when
they did that, when they did
that, they took on a sin nature.
They became sinful.
(I knew there was something
difficult about sin, but…)
OK. They took on
a sin nature.
They rebelled against God;
they disobeyed him--
they went his own way. They had
trusted Satan instead of God.
And when that happened,
God set aside
his mantle of
friendship.
He set that aside, and it's
like he put on a cloak--
the cloak of a pure,
perfect judge.
Put on a cloak of a
pure, perfect judge.
There was at that point--
what happened--there was a
separation that occurred
between God and man,
because sinful man could not
live in the presence
of the pure, perfect God.
{You need the gavel, right?
There you are.)
Now, as man stood in God's
courtroom, and as God
looked at man, he said,
"You know what?
"You are guilty of
breaking my law.
Even if it was just that
one rule, you are guilty."
And so, we find that God
declared man guilty
[crack!] in his presence.
OK, that's the verdict
that has come down.
Man is standing there, and
he's facing this two-sides-
of-the-same-coin dilemma.
He has this sin consequence
that he's facing because
he's a guilty sinner.
He's going to have
to pay this forever penalty--
this forever debt.
And he can't be in
God's presence,
he can't come back in his
presence, because he
doesn't have perfection--
he doesn't have that
righteousness that's equal
to God's righteousness.
He's in an awful dilemma. And
that's where man is stuck.
But the story
doesn't stop there.
What we see is that God
set aside his gavel.
He set aside his gavel, and he
came to earth as the pure,
perfect person--came to
earth as Jesus Christ.
So he came to earth.
OK, there you go.
Came to earth in the person
of Jesus Christ.
And for a period of time, for
30-plus years, he walked
on the face of the globe that
man could see the fact
that he was indeed the one
who was the Lamb of God--
that one without blemish.
The one that was entirely
complete and able to take
away the sin of the world.
He didn't just come to
live a good example for
man; he came for the
purpose of taking
man's sin off himself
and on himself.
And that's what he did--
when he went to the cross.
When he went to the
cross, what he did is:
he took the consequences
of sin upon himself.
He took care of this
side of the equation.
What he did on the
cross is: he became
the sin bearer and he paid
that eternal penalty,
that eternal debt. In one
moment in time, as an
infinite God, he took care
of it just like that.
And he was able to do
something on the cross
that we could have
never have done.
If we had tried to
pay for the debt,
we would have gone on for
eternity paying and paying
and paying and paying; but
in one moment in time,
he was able to pay that debt
and he said, "It is finished."
It's all done.
But that's not the
end of the story.
You see, he
took care of the sin
consequences on the cross.
But then as a result
of doing that, he could say
that, "If you believe that
"when I was dying on that
cross, I was taking care
of it for you, I have
something more for you."
Do you believe that Jesus
Christ died in your place?
You do. Well then, you
know what? God says that
if you believe that he
died in your place,
then he wants to
give you a gift.
He wants to clothe you
in his righteousness.
And now, when you stand
in God's courtroom,
and he lifts the gavel
to look at you,
he no longer sees
your sin; but he sees you
clothed in the
righteousness of Christ.
And because he's the
resurrected savior that's
come back to life, when he
stands there and looks at you,
he doesn't say, "I
declare you guilty";
rather, he says, "I declare
you righteous in my eyes."
And that is the meaning of
the word 'justified'--
[crack!] to be
declared righteous.
That's the concept
of justification.
Now, let me ask
you a question.
And this is what I do
with my students.
The devil shows up and he says,
"Hmmm. Well, I'll fix that.
I'll just tear this
righteousness off."
Could he do it?
The Bible tells
us this righteousness
comes from whom? God.
It has come from God.
The devil has no right
meddling with it.
It's something that's
been provided by him.
You can't tear it off.
I remember when I was teaching
this out in India here a couple
years ago--a young man,
his hands pop up
"Can Satan tear that off me?
Could somebody else
rip it off me?"
I said, "Well, God's clothed
you; he's put it there.
Who do you think would be
able to take it off?"
"Oh, only God could."
"Well, he says he's not
going to do that."
What he's done is, taken care
of the other side of the coin--
he's taking care of
the perfection side.
You are going to be able to
live in his presence for
eternity not because of
your righteousness,
but because he provided you
with his righteousness.
And now clothed in
his righteousness,
you are what we call
"In Him"--"In Christ."
He's taken care of all you
need to live with him.
You see, what this
does, it shows us that
when we are justified,
there's no such thing as
being un-justified--
or de-justified.
In which case, we'd have to
be able to be re-justified.
No, there's nothing
like that out there.
What it shows us is that when
we are provided with this,
by God from heaven,
and he declares us
righteous in his eyes,
then that's a final act.
And that's the word picture
we find in Scriptures.
It's very, very powerful.
Thanks, fellows.
As we take advantage of the
architecture of God's Word,
as we teach through the
Scriptures as we have outlined,
it's a very, in many ways, it's
a very condensed outline.
Some have said, "Oh, my,
my, that's a thick book.
I don't know if I could ever get
an unbeliever to read it."
Well, you know what? You'd
be amazed at how it works.
If you're reading it
just to yourself,
you can read it in about
eight hours.
When we teach it and
using the WorkBook and
all the visual aids, we can
teach it in about 15 hours.
And, we find that
there's a lot more people
that you'd imagine that are
quite willing to sit down
and have an objective Bible
presentation given to them.
They want to know
about these things.
And it's because it's a big
thing. And, you know, I
think it's uniquely a very
Western thing, that what
we try to do with the
Gospel is we try to say,
"How little can I get away
with to get the guy saved?"
You know? We just kinda
try and shrink it down.
We want to have the
McDonald's mindset.
You know, when you drive
through the drive through:
"Big Mac, order of fries,
strawberry shake. Quick!
Come on, come on, come on,
come on! Is this not fast food?"
And we want to have
a fast gospel.
And we want to be able to list
little things off there--bang!
But, you know what? In doing
that, we do disservice
to the grandeur and the
greatness of this message.
Generally speaking, in life,
people that are making big
decisions give a
little thought to it.
You know, when you go
out to buy a house,
it's not something
you get up in the morning
and on the way to
work, you buy a house.
You don't do that. No.
You put a lot of thought into
it, and you do some research.
Now, what we have found is that
people are very appreciative
when you sit down and you are
able to explain it through.
And as you do that: as
you go from creation
through to Christ, you
know what you are doing?
What you are doing is
this: you're flying
truths in formation.
Prophetic events are
verifying the message.
Types are revealing and
anchoring the doctrines
in the individual's mind.
Stories are defining the words
for them so that they are making
sure that they're
understanding exactly
what you're talking about
when you're using words like
sin, and God, and righteousness.
And the word pictures are
anchoring those doctrines,
so you have absolutely no
doubt what happened
on the cross and
in the tomb.
And, I believe, that's
what we want to do.
We want to take advantage of
the architecture in the Bible.
We want to have truths flying
in formation so that they
will protect each other.
So that it comes out with
a very powerful statement
and it screams in the face of
the individual: "This is true.
Please believe it."
And, I believe, that
what it means when we
talked about yesterday--
being an ambassador--when it
says it's as though God himself
is speaking through
us, and he's imploring
a lost and dying world:
"Please, please, be
reconciled to me."
If we don't do that, this
is what we're doing,
so often. And what we're
doing is, we're taking an
extrememly powerful
airforce of truth,
and we're leaving most
of it on the ground.
And we're sending off this one
little truth, to fly by itself,
and we're saying,
"Yep, it should do the trick."
When really what
we need to be doing is,
we need to be putting our
whole air force in the air
and saying, "Now listen
folks, when we talk about
"the Scripture being inspired by
God, this is what it means.
This is the face of it."
And when you fly this group of
information together,
as you do that, it just has
a very, very powerful
statement that,
"Yes, it is true."
And that's why we do this.
That's why we're doing it.