Morton, is going to run you
through his favorite YouTube
videos of all time.
Then Shan's going to take to the
streets to talk to people
about their plans
for summer love.
But first up, Hanson O'Haver, a
weird little house plant who
sits in the corner of our
office, is going to talk to
you about his favorite
rapper of all time.
HANSON O'HAVER: Hey.
I'm Hanson O'Haver.
Welcome to This Week in Drake,
VICE's look at what Drake's
been up to lately.
So there were really
two big pieces of
Drake news this week.
The first is that he announced
a tour that's sort of like a
monsters of blog rap tour.
It's with 2 Chainz, formerly
Tity Boi, J Cole, Waka Flocka
and the geographically
confoundingly
named French Montana.
Personally, I'm not really a big
fan of concerts because I
think all the best Drake songs
are kind of sad and about
being lonely.
I think it's sort of weird to
be 2,000 people in the room
feeling alienated.
The other piece of news.
He was in Miami alongside
Birdman, Lil' Wayne and DJ
Khaled filming a video for
"HYFR." Personally, I think
that "HYFR" is probably one of
the worst songs on Take Care
just because the chorus of "hell
yeah, fucking right" is
really dumb to just repeat
that over and over.
Doesn't really do much for me.
And also because in the song,
Drake and Lil' Wayne talk
about fucking the same girls,
and it's kind of weird.
I just think Lil' Wayne's
sort of gross.
But to be fair to Wayne, I knew
this girl in high school
that moved to LA, and I heard
that she sucked his dick, and
nothing bad happened to her.
She's fine and everything.
So if Drake's cool with that,
more power to Drake.
But anyways, the video's
supposed to
be bar mitzvah themed.
I never got a chance to go to a
bar mitzvah, so I hope that
the video will kind of show
me what that's all about.
Take care.
RYAN DUFFY: So just to recap,
Hanson is legitimately
concerned, like really honest
to God worried, about Lil'
Wayne's STDs.
But he's also excited to learn
about a Jewish rite of passage
via a Drake music video.
So up next we've
got What You're
Watching with Thomas Morton.
I was actually a little worried
about this show
because I feel like Thomas, as
much as I love him, is a bit
of a weirdo, and not many
people understand
his sense of humor.
As it turns out, Thomas is a
complete savant when it comes
to hilarious videos
on YouTube.
THOMAS MORTON: Hi.
Welcome to the VICE offices.
As you can see, everybody here
is doing a very good job
looking busy.
They're all at computers though,
which means what
they're actually doing is
basically what you're doing.
Screwing around on
the internet.
I work on a computer too.
I'm no stranger to
YouTube links.
And so I decided to put together
a few of my favorites
from this week.
Come enjoy the cream
of the crap.
Since it's our first week
together, a way of forging a
little bond of intimacy with us,
I figured instead of doing
the week's round up, I would
kind of dig back into the
personal archives and share with
you five of my, maybe not
all-time favorites, but I think
significant YouTube
clips from my own life.
The first one is completely
self-contained and
self-explanatory.
It's an Asian reporter
going down a slide.
REPORTER:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[SHOUTING]
THOMAS MORTON: Look, I'm
not going to try to--
kind of want to make that my
ring tone, to be frank.
The next video is what qualifies
as a griefing video.
It's labeled an epic troll,
which is kind of
like slander and libel.
They're both more or
less the same term.
The audio is piped in, which
makes it even funnier.
And then to emphasize that and
make sure you understand
exactly what swears they're
sputtering,
they've added text.
MALE SPEAKER 1: [BRITISH ACCENT]
Fucking, cock-sucking
prick, yeah.
Fucking play the game properly,
you little shit.
THOMAS MORTON: As a veteran of
many busted NES controllers
and harsh words to my mom in
other rooms, I think it's not
only par for the course,
but it's kind of
like grunting in tennis.
It gives you--
it helps you play better.
MALE SPEAKER 1: [BRITISH ACCENT]
You stupid prick.
MALE SPEAKER 2: You
fuckin' gay bitch.
THOMAS MORTON: So the deal
with this kid is--
I think it's like a 10-year-old
who has a camera
but probably also autism.
So this is just one video from
this kid who has a whole page
that you should subscribe
to immediately.
Because all his videos
are of--
not of him but of what he sees
through the camera, and then
him talking about the camera
and kind of getting angry
about the camera's occasional
non-functionality.
MALE SPEAKER 3: Dang it.
Can't zoom up on this camera.
Wonder if all these people
have ever heard of
the camera I have.
THOMAS MORTON: This is a little
more cerebral fare.
It's a robotic birth simulator
as being demonstrated by a guy
who has clearly been inside a
countless number of vaginas.
He makes Wilt Chamberlain look
like Tiny Tim, basically.
MALE SPEAKER 4: Often junior
doctors can place the first
blade but have a lot of
difficulties to place the
second blade.
THOMAS MORTON: I cannot believe
this hasn't been taken
down and moved to Redtube yet.
MALE SPEAKER 4: And the junior
doctor has to go through the
spheres in order to
place the forceps.
THOMAS MORTON: This last clip
was a favorite of our British
office for a while.
I think because all British
people are racist against
every other country in Europe.
It's a pool girl at--
as evidenced by the bathing
suits-- a Eastern European
party of some sort in the
mother of all K-holes.
[DANCE MUSIC PLAYING]
THOMAS MORTON: Thanks.
Really hope you enjoyed this.
And don't not come back again.
Subscribe to our channel and
keep on YouTubeing in the
YouTube world.
[DANCE MUSIC PLAYING]
RYAN DUFFY: Last up, we sent the
nicest person we have ever
met in our lives, Shan Shan, out
to the streets of New York
to talk about summer love.
Hi, I'm [? Shan ?]
Huang.
I'm with VICE.com.
Today we're here to
find out people's
plans for summer loving.
I'm wondering what's your plan
as far as summer loving goes.
MALE SPEAKER 5: As
far as what?
MALE SPEAKER 6: Summer living?
SHAN HUANG: Summer loving.
MALE SPEAKER 6: Somewhere
loving?
SHAN HUANG: Summer.
Summer.
FEMALE SPEAKER 1: Summer
is the worst period
to find a good guy.
MALE SPEAKER 7: Girls in NYC are
a little bit more guarded.
You walk down the street, you
try to talk to one, they think
you're a psycho or something.
MALE SPEAKER 8: In general,
I live and love.
So I love all humans.
So I get to be in love
all the time.
SHAN HUANG: Where do you think
is the sexiest place in Paris?
MALE SPEAKER 9: My home.
SHAN HUANG: Do you mind to
tell us your location?
MALE SPEAKER 9: No.
SHAN HUANG: Men who
wear shorts.
Do you think they're sexy?
FEMALE SPEAKER 2: No.
SHAN HUANG: What about
flip-flops?
FEMALE SPEAKER 2: Flip-flops?
SHAN HUANG: Do you think
French people
are into Asian girls?
MALE SPEAKER 9: No.
MALE SPEAKER 8: I definitely
like certain things.
I like light skin.
I like half black half white.
I like Latin girls.
But then again, Scarlett
Johannson is awesome.
When I get some more external
power, I'm totally going to
take you on a date.
SHAN HUANG: Do you think
you'll bring God to the
bedroom with you?
MALE SPEAKER 8: I don't
leave God anywhere.
I make love.
I don't fuck anymore.
SHAN HUANG: If you can take a
girl that you love on a date
in the summer, where would
you like to bring her to?
MALE SPEAKER 6: In the summer,
somewhere nice.
First I'd like to
know her first.
Because you can't just take
any girl anywhere.
Right?
MALE SPEAKER 7: The woods.
Lot more fun.
Tie each other to trees.
It's all fun and games.
Just don't do it during
hunting season.
SHAN HUANG: Are you afraid that
while that's happening,
you hear people shooting guns?
MALE SPEAKER 7: The gunshots
don't bother me.
I'm a gun owner.
SHAN HUANG: How can a girl
catches your eye?
MALE SPEAKER 6: Catch my eye?
One girl?
Be alone.
RYAN DUFFY: Hope you enjoyed
this episode of VICE Today.
If you liked it, please
subscribe.
And don't worry.
We're not going to send you
a whole bunch of bullshit.
It's just an easier way to find
out about all the great
shit we're about to do.
Thanks for watching.