[CRYING]
[SINGING]
WADE DAVIS: The first thing you
have to do when you even
begin to try to understand a
phenomenon like the Haitian
zombie, which is just one
thread woven through the
fabric of this amazing culture,
is to sort of
eliminate from your
consciousness all your
preconceptions.
HAMILTON MORRIS: In 1982,
Harvard ethnobotanist Wade
Davis traveled to Port-au-Prince
to investigate
the biological underpinnings
of the Haitian zombie.
As early as 1938, Zora Neale
Hurston found there was a
vodou potion that could induce a
death-like state, though she
concluded the ingredients were
so guarded, no sorcerer would
ever reveal them.
Wade Davis did what Hurston
thought impossible.
And over the course of four
years he gained the trust of
several vodou sorcerers,
uncovering the ingredients of
the secret potion, and
documenting his experience in
the 1985 bestseller "The Serpent
and the Rainbow."
Though Davis is quick to say
he's not a "zombieologist,"
he's still considered the
world's leading authority on
the Haitian Zombie.
WADE DAVIS: Now what
is a zombie?
A zombie, by folk belief,
is the living dead.
It's an individual who has been
brought to his demise by
sorcery, passed through the
grave, or at least passed
through a state of death, and
then somehow magically
resuscitated.
Zombies were almost deemed to
be off-limits for serious
academic research.
But Lamarque Douyon had found
this really extraordinary case
of this man called Clairvius
Narcisse.
What made the case unique is
that Narcisse had been
pronounced dead in the
Schweitzer Hospital.
And his death had been witnessed
by two physicians,
both American trained,
one an American.
There were impeccable records
describing his pathology at
the time of his demise.
18 years later, this man
claiming to be Clairvius
Narcisse turns up in his home
village, claiming that he'd
been made a zombie.
All these lines of evidence
led Lamarque Douyon to go
public in about 1980, '81,
saying that they had found the
first medically-verifiable
instance of a zombie.
That kind of opening brought
everybody back to a series of
reports that had existed in
the folk literature of the
reputed existence of a folk
poison that was said to bring
on a state of apparent death so
profound that it could fool
a physician.
Lamarque Douyon had tried for
some time to secure the
formula of that preparation,
to no avail.
And that's why I was brought
into the investigation.
Schultes, my professor, the
man who sparked the
Psychedelic Movement, he was
very much my mentor.
I was working in the Amazon, and
one day he summoned me to
his fourth-floor aerie at the
botanical museum and asked me
if I wanted to go down to
Haiti for two weeks over
spring break and try to find the
formula of the drug used
to make zombies.
Well naturally, I said, sure.
There are lots of plants and
lots of animals that are
poisonous and that
can kill you.
We weren't just looking for
a toxin that could kill.
We were looking for a toxin that
could bring on a state of
apparent death so profound that
it would bring someone
literally to the edge of death,
a threshold from which
they could then recover.
And I went down to Haiti and was
able to secure the formula
of the preparation.
HAMILTON MORRIS: The preparation
contains a
veritable Whitman's Sampler of
poisons, showcasing the great
diversity of Haiti's medicinal
flora and fauna, spanning two
kingdoms and eight
Linnaean classes.
The potions Davis collected
included such ingredients as
datura stramonium, velvet bean,
cane toad, pufferfish
Hispaniolan boa, bearded
fireworm, tarantula, cashew
leaves, and the bones
of a human child.
To the sorcerer who mixes the
potions, each ingredient
serves a distinct purpose, with
the human bones playing a
role every bit as important as
the psychoactive plants.
But to Davis, two ingredients
held the key to understanding
the phenomenon of
zombification.
The pufferfish contains
a chemical called
tetrodotoxin, or TTX.
If administered in the correct
dose, the victim will find
themselves trapped in a flaccid
paralysis, perfectly
mimicking the appearance
of death.
Upon their exhumation, the
victim is fed a paste of
datura stramonium, which
obliterates their memory,
leaving them in a stupefied,
obedient delirium.
WADE DAVIS: We never could prove
really anything, but we
could show that this was
something that had a kind of
coherence within the worldview
of the Haitian people.
If it could not be absolutely
proven, it was at least so
provocative that it demanded
investigation.
If you eliminate the other
possibilities, you have to
allow the facts to speak
for themselves.
And that's why I was prepared
to say very strongly that I
thought this phenomenon
existed.
HAMILTON MORRIS: In the years
since the publication of
Davis's work, there's been
little formal investigation of
the zombie phenomenon.
Though teams of scientists and
anthropologists have traveled
to Haiti in search of answers,
they often failed to find what
they're looking for.
Some have been fooled in
elaborate hoaxes, or found
that the zombies could be
explained medically, with
conditions such as
schizophrenia.
And others have been imprisoned
or sent home with
nothing at all.
In Haiti, the use of this powder
is a crime on par with
murder, and those who concoct
it do so with the knowledge
that it will be used to
destroy a human life.
In light of all this
uncertainty, I will travel to
Haiti to investigate the zombie
and attempt to collect
poison samples for the first
chemical analysis
in almost 30 years.
My results could support Davis's
theory or redefine our
concept of the Haitian zombie.
Or I could have a
railroad spike
driven through my scrotum.