[CAR ENGINE]
LEO PARENTE: Guys, I need your
help to come up with the
content for a new show.
Here's how I envision
this next show.
IAN WHELAN: OK.
LEO PARENTE: With all the
politics going on in racing,
all the personal agendas,
I want to start the next
"SHAKEDOWN" with this subject.
DRIVE "SHAKEDOWN" is going
to design the ideal North
American racing, the collection
of races and race
cars that will grow racing,
reduce the clutter, motivate
the influx of money,
media, and fans.
So I need your guys' help
to figure out how
we fill that up.
What racing-- was is the
ideal that we want?
MAX SEEGER: Yeah.
IAN WHELAN: Yeah.
LEO PARENTE: You've been through
"SHAKEDOWN." Thank you
for joining the team.
MAX SEEGER: Oh, my pleasure.
LEO PARENTE: But we've
done stuff--
the Michael Johnson thing.
MAX SEEGER: Yes.
LEO PARENTE: Race
of Champions.
MAX SEEGER: That's right.
IAN WHELAN: Right.
LEO PARENTE: And you seem to
have this passion for racing
outside of F1.
IAN WHELAN: Well, I'm mostly
an F1 fan, but I can
appreciate other racing.
And I think that there are
certain things that I like
about F1 that maybe we could
apply to other racing or maybe
things from that past of F1 that
we could apply to other
racing, because I don't
necessarily think F1's at its
peak right now.
LEO PARENTE: So I want to
pretend this is like Hot Tub
Time Machine," where
it's all new.
It's all fresh.
We can start over.
And I know there are some rules
of reality, but we're
going to wipe it clean.
MAX SEEGER: OK.
LEO PARENTE: And I want to focus
on North America only.
Let's not try to chomp off
the world right now.
IAN WHELAN: OK.
LEO PARENTE: And without getting
too much into the
criteria, I think we should talk
a little bit about what
we think racing needs to
accomplish to be more popular,
and then cut through the
elements of the action or the
cars or the venues or the
media or whatever.
MAX SEEGER: Yeah.
LEO PARENTE: Let me start
with just that.
What do you want racing
to be to be better?
IAN WHELAN: Well, I think racing
needs to be a little
bit less opaque.
Right now, I see cars running
around tracks that I can't
tell how they relate to any
real cars on the road.
And I'm saying that
as an F1 fan.
I actually love the crazy
technology of F1.
But I think aside from that
racing, there needs to be--
the lower tiers or the sports
car racing, I need to be able
to relate those cars to
things on the road.
LEO PARENTE: Why?
IAN WHELAN: Why?
Because I think if you're a fan
of Porsches or you're a
fan of Fords--
you're a fan of something,
you want to root for
that kind of thing.
You want to have
an allegiance.
LEO PARENTE: OK.
And I think racing is in that
interesting spot where no one
cares, really, about the soccer
ball, or who made the
baseball bat, or how
it's constructed.
They watch the sport.
But because the tool is so
integral to racing, I guess it
does matter.
Max, you're looking at me.
I know you've got something.
MAX SEEGER: Yeah, yeah.
Well, no, because the thing is,
for me, I understand that
there are a lot of subtle things
happening on the track.
And I appreciate it, totally.
But--
LEO PARENTE: Don't
pander to me.
MAX SEEGER: OK, no, no.
But I don't know if it's
enough for me.
So there are a lot of things
that I'm into where you have
an appreciation of it.
You get really into it.
So I don't see-- unless someone
gets really into or
understands How important it
is to get the tires up to
temp, because there's no such
thing as doing a lap at speed
if the tires aren't
up to temp.
LEO PARENTE: Fuck
Adrian Newey.
MAX SEEGER: Oh, my pleasure.
So for me, I think that getting
an appreciation for
that sort of stuff, maybe
there's a shortcut, maybe
there's not.
LEO PARENTE: So this came
up once before.
For you--
and there is no wrong
answer here.
For you, watching a race car
go fast, it's not enough.
I could watch an R18, e-tron--
whatever the
hell they call it--
around Sebring, and I could
catch the nuances and be
entertained.
But at the end of the day, maybe
you're just watching
highway traffic.
MAX SEEGER: Right.
LEO PARENTE: So there
needs to be more?
MAX SEEGER: Yeah.
I don't want to put it down.
I'm not putting it
down in that--
LEO PARENTE: There are
no disclaimers here.
MAX SEEGER: OK.
Well, and also, just going
fast isn't really enough,
because when I was in Bangkok
for Race of Champions--
LEO PARENTE: Hanging
with Vettel.
MAX SEEGER: Yes.
LEO PARENTE: Yeah,
I heard that.
MAX SEEGER: That's where we
met each other, hung out.
I actually didn't talk to him
at all, so I want to clear
that up right away.
LEO PARENTE: You blew
in his ear.
MAX SEEGER: Yeah.
LEO PARENTE: Webber's
a wanker.
MAX SEEGER: Yes.
LEO PARENTE: Yeah, OK.
MAX SEEGER: That name doesn't
really mean anything to me.
[LAUGHTER]
MAX SEEGER: So a guy goes
out, gets some air
on that first lift.
LEO PARENTE: Oh, it
was that race?
MAX SEEGER: Yes.
LEO PARENTE: The Race of
Champions, the bridge, the
whole thing.
MAX SEEGER: Yeah.
They're setting up.
And I'm rolling.
I get it, because I'm
a professional, OK?
But then they put a
chicane in there.
LEO PARENTE: Yeah, because it
was dangerous, I guess.
MAX SEEGER: Yeah.
And then it sort of got
less exciting for me.
Not that I wanted
someone to get
hurt, but air is important.
LEO PARENTE: Wait a minute.
Let me write that down.
So they took away the thing
that was interesting you.
And then it was time
to go home.
MAX SEEGER: Yeah.
Well, then I had to stay there
up until midnight--
IAN WHELAN: Keep shooting.
MAX SEEGER: Yeah, And keep
shooting against my will.
LEO PARENTE: OK.
So actually, I'm going to use
that as a little bit of a
segue then.
So let's start defining
the action.
Jordan Taylor went on about
to him, racing is passing.
And I just negated watching
a car go fast.
At some point in time,
is it enough?
IAN WHELAN: Yeah.
LEO PARENTE: And you were
talking about jumps.
MAX SEEGER: Right.
LEO PARENTE: God knows
what video game
he's got in his mind.
So let's define action.
What do you want to see
as action in racing?
MAX SEEGER: I think that
I just want to
see pushing the envelope.
And maybe to me, that looks
like one wheel's off the
ground or something like that,
because I don't know if I can
really gauge how fast
something's going.
IAN WHELAN: Yeah, or how
on the edge they are.
MAX SEEGER: Yeah.
IAN WHELAN: If they look like
they're not really on the edge
from the outside.
MAX SEEGER: Yeah.
Maybe it's as simple as facial
expressions of a camera right
at their face, because we're
used to seeing straight out.
But maybe we need to see
some gnarly faces.
IAN WHELAN: That's a
good idea, yeah.
LEO PARENTE: Well, you know,
the old guys used to talk
about how, F1, you could watch
Nuvolari and whoever actually
steer the car.
IAN WHELAN: Right.
LEO PARENTE: And you could
see their movement.
You could see them
working the car.
I like MotoGP because you can
see the rider working.
IAN WHELAN: Right.
MAX SEEGER: Yeah.
LEO PARENTE: Now, Tony Kanaan's
a little tired
because his head is tilted
to the left.
And David Hobbes goes friggin'
ballistic when the car goes
one degree off angle, because
that's an F1 slide--
Kimi excepted.
Are you on that page?
We need to see more of it?
IAN WHELAN: Yeah.
I watch F1 all the time, but I
can't even pick out some of
things they're talking
about when they're--
LEO PARENTE: They're
just making [BLEEP]
up.
IAN WHELAN: They
might be, yeah.
Sometimes, it's like they're
talking about things that are
going on there with--
like you said,
they're off a few degrees.
I can't even tell on TV.
But to them, it's a big deal.
So I feel like we need a
little bit of a closer
connection to what's really
going on in these cars.
LEO PARENTE: So that makes me
think of something else that
we should probably cover
up front as a
little bit of a criteria.
So you guys think I'm deep
into the bubble.
You're a fan, knowledgeable.
MAX SEEGER: I'm around it.
LEO PARENTE: I'm going to be
polite, but you're around it.
You're more of an outsider
looking in.
MAX SEEGER: Yeah.
LEO PARENTE: The nuances
work for the die hard.
But who should we
be looking at?
Are we looking at a
bigger audience?
Or are we looking to make a
generalist more of a disciple?
You know what I'm
trying to say?
MAX SEEGER: Yeah.
IAN WHELAN: I think we need to
have a little bit of both.
Racing needs to expand, probably
for business reasons.
And there's a lot of people who
are casual fans that maybe
if they could learn a little bit
about the sport or find a
way to become more engaged,
they could become a
higher-level fan somehow.
LEO PARENTE: What
do you think?
MAX SEEGER: Maybe I'll tell
this quick story of--
I overheard--
so I skateboard.
LEO PARENTE: Wow.
Really?
MAX SEEGER: Yeah.
Come see if we're--
LEO PARENTE: And that's in
addition to the band you have.
What's the band?
The Price of Bandages?
MAX SEEGER: No.
The what?
LEO PARENTE: I don't know.
MAX SEEGER: The Mayor
of Bad News.
LEO PARENTE: I was close.
MAX SEEGER: Yeah.
LEO PARENTE: Yeah, OK.
Go ahead.
MAX SEEGER: So this kid's
skateboarding.
There is a game called SKATE.
It's like HORSE for
basketball.
So one person does a trick.
The other person does
a trick to match it.
LEO PARENTE: By the way,
I'm old, not dead.
Keep going.
MAX SEEGER: OK.
All right, fair enough.
So there's your, I guess,
dominant stance.
Maybe it's right foot forward.
But you can also do things with
the other way, and that's
called switch.
It's like rediscovering
skateboarding.
So the one kid goes to the other
kid, hey, you don't do
any switch tricks.
And then that kid goes,
switch tricks
don't impress my parents.
Because to them, it looks
like the same thing.
So I feel like maybe that's
why I want to
see more air stuff.
LEO PARENTE: So have you watched
Global Rally Cross?
MAX SEEGER: Accidentally.
[LAUGHTER]
LEO PARENTE: Do you
like that stuff?
MAX SEEGER: I guess so.
I do like those--
the Gymkhana video
in San Francisco.
IAN WHELAN: Right.
That feels like you're on the
edge a little bit, right?
MAX SEEGER: Right.
That feels--
IAN WHELAN: What if there was a
race on that course that Ken
Block drove through
San Francisco?
Wouldn't that be cool?
MAX SEEGER: Yeah.
That would almost--
maybe race tracks
are too sterile.
LEO PARENTE: Funny.
And I missed it.
That's my disclaimer.
But at this last X Game,
they had a new
event called Gymkhana.
And they basically did what
you just described.
And I guess it was like drifting
is, plus I guess
there was a combination of speed
or racing measurement as
well as gymnastic type judging,
did they do the trick
or whatever.
So again, if it is exciting and
interesting, am I drifting
toward it for the kids?
MAX SEEGER: Well, that's--
see, I don't want to
ruin racing for--
LEO PARENTE: Yeah, but
this is the point.
There's no definition of ruining
racing, because I feel
like the traditionalists
are clinging
to traditional things.
Indy Car, for example, thinks
it's an epiphany that instead
of having practice, qualifying,
and the race on
Sunday, they're going to have
two races Saturday and Sunday.
MAX SEEGER: Yeah.
LEO PARENTE:
La-dee-freaking-dah, OK?
That's not a big epiphany.
But if that works to attract
more people because they
actually watch racing versus
cars going round, so be it.
So you're not ruining racing.
We're kind of argument that
racing is a little bit broke
and maybe getting more broke as
no new people come to the
sport because they've
got options.
MAX SEEGER: Yeah.
IAN WHELAN: And we're also
talking about different--
we're talking about a whole
sanctioning body with
different types of
racing under it.
So maybe certain
types of racing
appeal to younger people.
And then it feeds them
up along the
way as they get older.
Maybe they kind of graduate to
the more technical stuff that
is not maybe as wild looking,
but there are other nuances
that they'll pick
up as they grow.
LEO PARENTE: Well, that's
where I was getting to.
And I'm going in my notes.
So under some of the objectives
I scribble out, in
no particular order, one,
the cars are the stars.
I think what the cars are
attract people to watch this
and are probably going to be
leading why we need more than
one just racing series
in this collection.
IAN WHELAN: And that goes back
to what I was saying at the
beginning about relating
to the cars.
I always know there's a place
for the spaceship cars.
I love them.
But I feel like even when we
have cars that look like real
cars, you still can't connect
to them as well.
LEO PARENTE: Yeah.
And the corollary to that is
somewhere along the line, the
drivers have to matter.
Action is key.
We already talked about that.
I think we've got to address
technology, because somewhere
between dumbing it down and spec
cars and all this stuff--
NASCAR--
versus people loving the
technology and making it
relevant, at the end of the
day, we're having the
discussion about what the fans
want, the venues, where this
is, how it's set up.
Everyone loves traditional road
courses, but something
new and different may be
a better way to go.
IAN WHELAN: Yeah.
Like we were talking about,
a street course on some
crazy-looking terrain
in San Francisco.
That looks so cool in a lot of
different types of racing.
I know it's difficult
to do, but--
LEO PARENTE: Well, and that's
the part where we're not
getting way too ahead
of our ourselves.
Is it real or is it virtual?
There will never be a
New York Grand Prix.
But virtually, I can get on the
sim and I can run around
Columbus Circle in a race car.
IAN WHELAN: Yeah.
MAX SEEGER: Yeah.
LEO PARENTE: And then somewhere
along the line,
media has to factor in.
MAX SEEGER: Right.
LEO PARENTE: I love banging on
the TV guys, but-- or even
doing internet, but maybe.
IAN WHELAN: Well, the media
thing connects with the
drivers as stars aspect.
To me, those two things are
related because I think that,
especially in this country, the
media coverage of these
people who are driving these
cars is kind of lacking.
I've watch some of the Sky
Sports coverage in the BBC,
and they do a much better job
of letting you get to know
these guys.
And then you feel more of
a connection to them.
And I think that's important.
When you watch football--
I'm not even a football fan,
but I know that people have
their favorite players, and
you're rooting for these guys.
LEO PARENTE: So I would argue
that the roadmap is out there.
You can take an entity that may
be complex and nuanced but
make it play at a couple
of levels.
IAN WHELAN: Right.
LEO PARENTE: You can make the
personalities matter.
You can break down what's
really going on.
And you can do things.
As much as everyone hates PKs
and all that stuff in soccer,
you can break it down and make
excitement, I guess, if you
have to, as long as you manage
it so it respects the game.
IAN WHELAN: Yeah.
LEO PARENTE: And actually, that
leads to who's going to
run this thing.
And the simplest way that I'd
throw it out is that you've
got to follow the money.
The tools are there.
The manufacturers have the most
money, the most vested
interest, probably sponsors
and probably media.
So there should be
this little Mafia
collective of these people.
They throw their money in, put
the kitty in the game.
That's the money to fund the
type of media that needs to be
done, the type of commitment
that needs to be made, whether
it's a kids' program or a junior
program to bring young
sperm into racing rather
than Rich Dad 101.
And then, they're the ones--
frankly, as a benevolent
dictatorship, they're the ones
that start to make decisions.
But we're playing that role.
That's the role I want
to play right now.
IAN WHELAN: Yeah.
LEO PARENTE: So if that sounded
too serious, I apologize.
But now, it kind of cuts
to, so what racing
series should we have?
IAN WHELAN: Well, for sports
cars, I want to see something
like Can-Am again--
LEO PARENTE: The old--
IAN WHELAN: Yeah.
MAX SEEGER: What is--
LEO PARENTE: Which part?
No rules?
IAN WHELAN: Yeah.
I like the--
MAX SEEGER: What is that?
IAN WHELAN: Can-Am
was a series--
what is it--
up through the '80s.
I know it started '60s.
LEO PARENTE: Yeah.
The good stuff was '70s.
IAN WHELAN: And it was basically
like an unrestricted
racing series.
These guys had--
they could do anything they
wanted, basically.
Were there really
any big rules?
LEO PARENTE: There were
minimal rules.
It was an open formula
with them.
IAN WHELAN: And it was
popular in America.
A lot of European guys came over
to race, and they built
these cars that were
just wild.
They were just completely
wild.
LEO PARENTE: Chaparral put
wings on it for the first
time, aerodynamically.
McLaren, to catch up with
Porsche, for example, were
running 8-liter,
9-liter motors.
IAN WHELAN: Yeah.
LEO PARENTE: Anything went.
LEO PARENTE: If you could
build it within the box,
freaking let it go.
IAN WHELAN: I think you could
have something like that now.
But maybe you just restrict the
amount of engines they can
use per season.
Let them run 21,000 rpms.
I don't care.
Let them put turbos.
Let them run 12 cylinders
on the car.
Anything goes.
I want to see a mix of different
things from the
manufacturers who
can profile--
show off their own technology
in their different ways and
say I know how to do
this better than
you guys over there.
LEO PARENTE: So to that point,
do you think WEC with the P1
cars are close to that, or F1?
IAN WHELAN: Well, the P1 cars
are cool to me, but there's
still not enough of them.
We need a whole field
of those cars.
LEO PARENTE: So the problem's
going to be, not to be neg, is
safety and budget.
IAN WHELAN: Right.
LEO PARENTE: But
that's where--
IAN WHELAN: What's safety?
LEO PARENTE: Well, to your point
much earlier, I don't
think you can negate danger.
You've got to make this
feel special.
If anyone thinks they can just
jump in a car and act like
they can drive with a sim,
then you've lost a
bigger part of this.
Slam any sports guy you want,
including Mr. PED.
We know we can't do those
things, so we watch because
they're gods.
MAX SEEGER: Sure.
LEO PARENTE: And from a race
car standpoint, if it's too
easy to friggin' drive, besides
the fact that it's
probably not appealing, the
drivers will tell you, it's
too easy to frigging drive.
And there's no allure there.
MAX SEEGER: They'll
say that now?
LEO PARENTE: Oh, yeah.
IAN WHELAN: Yeah.
The WEC cars--
I think they're really cool,
but they look like they're
easy to drive.
And I don't know if
they are, but--
LEO PARENTE: Yeah.
I'd have to ask Mich.
IAN WHELAN: I don't know.
From the outside, though--
it goes back to what we were
talking about before.
If you look at these spaceships
going down the road
at ridiculous speeds, it just
seems completely undramatic.
Whereas something like Can-Am,
everything looked like
anything could happen
at any moment.
LEO PARENTE: So his definition
of Can-Am, do you like that
idea of having something
unlimited?
MAX SEEGER: Yeah, that sounds
like-- because I think--
more than like seeing
somebody get air or
something like that.
LEO PARENTE: Go ahead.
MAX SEEGER: Because I
mean maybe that's a
little low com denom.
LEO PARENTE: WRC--
rally--
those cars fly.
MAX SEEGER: But I am that,
because it spoke to me when
that guy got air at
Race of Champions.
But I think creativity, to see
people express themselves
within racing would
be something that
would appeal to me.
IAN WHELAN: Well, that actually
brings up something.
Like the old days of F1, when
you had these constructors who
were building their own cars,
that was amazing.
And there were so many different
things these guys
were doing.
The things I said
about Can-Am--
I want to see similar rules in
F1, like the old days where
you had four cylinder cars going
up against V8s or V6s or
whatever, or V12s.
I know that probably with F1, if
you had that first season,
you'd probably see the next
season, everyone would just
figure out what happened, what
was the best way and they'd
all go that way.
LEO PARENTE: But that
happens anyway.
IAN WHELAN: Right.
LEO PARENTE: So actually, the
creativity, like you were
talking about the F1, what my
mind thought of was "Time
Attack."
IAN WHELAN: Right.
LEO PARENTE: All these kids love
"Time Attack," because
they can be creative.
They can build their own car.
All the racing that I see,
even the amateur stuff,
especially the pro, there's so
many rules and regulations and
limitations.
And to your point, once someone
comes up with a good
idea, they all need to follow
that good idea, so everything
looks alike.
IAN WHELAN: Yeah.
LEO PARENTE: Here's what
I was thinking.
North American racing only, we
probably should have a number
of premier racing series to
satisfy all these various
needs of action and whatever and
technology and tradition.
And I'm going to throw this out,
and then we can kind of
beat it to death.
Everything below that is either
to learn the craft or
is a feeder series and really
shouldn't distract from the
specialness of this.
So honestly, not all
this [BLEEP]
should be on TV, because there's
too much clutter.
So here's my short list.
I think there needs to be a
premier open-wheel series in
North America, Indy
Car evolved.
I would it would be very high
tech, open spec, and be
technologically related
to F1 so
there can be some crossover.
I'd even go so far as to suggest
the Indy 500 should be
part of the F1 season.
IAN WHELAN: It's like
the old days.
LEO PARENTE: Like
IAN WHELAN: And the old Indy
cars actually were all
different and high tech
for the time.
They looked cool.
LEO PARENTE: They
had turbines.
IAN WHELAN: Yeah.
They had all kinds
of crazy stuff.
And you had the F1 drivers
coming over and driving cars
on a one-off basis.
Or, like you said, it was
part of the whole world
championship.
LEO PARENTE: I'm not going to
get caught in the details.
Somewhere along the line,
there should be
a connect the dots.
But Indy Car should be the
fastest cars in North America.
IAN WHELAN: Right.
Right now, I'm not interested
at all, because
they're spec cars.
LEO PARENTE: The next one is,
for me, there should be a
premier production car
racing series.
And that's got to be NASCAR.
And I'm not sure it's all that
broke, having NASCAR.
MAX SEEGER: OK.
LEO PARENTE: What
do you think?
MAX SEEGER: I don't really have
an opinion about NASCAR.
LEO PARENTE: OK.
MAX SEEGER: It's sort
of just there.
LEO PARENTE: Yeah.
IAN WHELAN: Yeah.
MAX SEEGER: Right?
IAN WHELAN: I think they focus
too much on the wrong things
in that series, but that's
a whole other discussion.
MAX SEEGER: But maybe
I could--
I didn't like broccoli
at a certain point.
That's kids and all that.
LEO PARENTE: Got it.
I'm with you.
I got it.
IAN WHELAN: All right.
I don't know if there's anything
that would really get
me too excited about NASCAR.
But I think at the very least,
if the cars were
production-based like they
used to be in NASCAR--
and if you don't have a
rear-wheel drive V8 car in
your lineup, then you don't
get to race in NASCAR.
You're going to fail.
And if you want to homologate
cars like they used to do,
that would be cool, at least.
LEO PARENTE: Well, and then it
makes cool, special edition
cars for sale to the public.
IAN WHELAN: I love--
exactly.
And that could go across
all the boards,
except maybe F1 cars.
But I love the old days with
homologation specials and all
this stuff with racing, because
it gives people a real
connection with the race car.
LEO PARENTE: So my
three were--
MAX SEEGER: Just before you do
that, what is homologation?
LEO PARENTE: Oh, OK.
Sorry.
Go ahead.
IAN WHELAN: It's all right.
Homologation is when there's a
requirement of, OK, you want
to race this car,
this extra-fast,
bigger-displacement monster?
Well, then you have to build 500
or 5,000, whatever, street
cars that the public can
actually buy to say, all
right, this is a real car
that you make and you
want to race it.
LEO PARENTE: So the quick story
is back in '70, '69, the
rules for Le Mans
racing changed.
And the big engines were thrown
out the door, and they
were going to have little
3-liter F1 engines.
But you could raise a 5-liter
production car if you built--
I think the number was 250.
So Porsche literally built 200,
250 Porsche 917's, lined
them all up, had the
sanctioning body
come and see the cars.
So Ferrari--
holy [BLEEP], Porsche
has got a real
race car at five liters.
So Ferrari invited
everyone over.
And the story is they built 100
of the cars, showed them
the 100 cars, set the other
100 over here--
let's go to lunch--
moved the 100 cars to another
warehouse, and after lunch
showed them the 100.
And the guy said, oh, yeah.
200-- you got it.
OK, that's good.
MAX SEEGER: Wow.
LEO PARENTE: Homologation.
Anyway, I digress.
So more road racing for NASCAR,
I mean, honestly, if
Australian V8 supercars have
shown us anything--
IAN WHELAN: Right.
That's a perfect example of
how NASCAR could succeed--
and WTCC, another example.
LEO PARENTE: And I bet you
when I babble that in the
show, there'll be a ton of
commentators saying, yeah,
yeah, yeah.
In my less redneck Southern
drawl, I mean, stop making it
this little--
IAN WHELAN: Good
old boys thing.
LEO PARENTE: In the Walmart
parking lot.
IAN WHELAN: The whole heritage
connection with the
moonshiners and stuff,
come on.
It's been a really long time.
There is real technology and
there is real advanced stuff
going on in these things.
Let's--
LEO PARENTE: Bingo.
IAN WHELAN: --bring it
up to modern day.
LEO PARENTE: Yeah.
Third series, I need sports
car road race.
I think we need a GT class
that can be as
open tech as it is.
Everyone talks about
the Corvettes we
see at these races.
If they took the restrictors
off, how freaking
fast would it be?
IAN WHELAN: Oh, I'm fine with
that as long as it's actually
based on a real chassis.
LEO PARENTE: Bingo.
And I can think if they want
tech in it, they can
have tech in it.
I think there should be
a prototype class, no
offense to the F!
cars.
I know I'm talking
too much, but--
MAX SEEGER: No, no.
IAN WHELAN: No, I think it's
fine if there's prototypes,
Can-Am style, that they're
almost like F1 cars with body
work on them.
LEO PARENTE: Now, I'm going
to drag you into this.
MAX SEEGER: OK.
LEO PARENTE: So all these road
racing cars, what would make
road racing appealing to you?
MAX SEEGER: I guess the thing
that would make it more
relatable for me, if it was
in a place, like you said
earlier, like San Francisco or
something like that, or just
something that's tight, kind
of like a tighter race.
LEO PARENTE: So what if
they had eliminations?
What if it was literally every
weekend was a playoff, and it
took all of the entrants
and cut it
down to the two finalists?
MAX SEEGER: Yeah.
LEO PARENTE: Would that
change your thinking?
MAX SEEGER: I don't know.
IAN WHELAN: I don't think the
manufacturers are going to
like that too much.
LEO PARENTE: It's our
Etch-a-Sketch.
I don't know.
IAN WHELAN: Yeah.
But then, by the end of the
year, you have what we have
now with WEC, which is
two manufacturers--
LEO PARENTE: No, no.
I mean on the weekend.
IAN WHELAN: Oh, OK.
LEO PARENTE: 15 cars show
up in the field.
IAN WHELAN: OK.
LEO PARENTE: Instead of
qualifying, there are a
certain number of elimination
races.
And at the end of the day, maybe
that Sunday, you still
have an elimination race
with everyone in it.
But at the end of the day, we
take the two finalists and
they go head to head,
somehow, some way.
MAX SEEGER: Yeah.
IAN WHELAN: OK.
LEO PARENTE: And I know
everyone's going to--
MAX SEEGER: So this is two
and this is one on one?
LEO PARENTE: Yeah.
At the end of it, that's how
you'd stay interested, that
you watch this bad version
of "American
Idol" happen on a racetrack.
MAX SEEGER: Well, I guess what
would be interesting, maybe,
would be a back story of
the racers with a shot.
Each one gets their lead
up to this race.
IAN WHELAN: That's a--
you mentioned "American Idol."
That's what they do for all
these contestants.
MAX SEEGER: Yeah.
IAN WHELAN: They have a back
story so you feel like you
have a connection with these
people even though you've seen
only a three-minute little
video about them.
MAX SEEGER: Yeah.
LEO PARENTE: And NASCAR actually
tried to get there
with this whole take the gloves
off the drivers and let
them fight with each other and
have that type of conflict in
personality.
IAN WHELAN: That seems contrived
to me, though.
LEO PARENTE: Thank you.
OK.
Because that's the other part--
somewhere in here,
authenticity.
IAN WHELAN: Right.
LEO PARENTE: We're going
too long, and I
apologize for this meeting.
But the other thing
in sports car--
I want a GT class that's just
the traditional, low-tech
grunty cars without all the
driver controls and ABS and
traction controls so that people
can get back to the
roots and enjoy just a real
rough house-type race car.
MAX SEEGER: OK.
And what kind of track
is that on?
IAN WHELAN: On a road course.
LEO PARENTE: Road course.
But to your point, we need to
have something that's rally,
dirt, sliding, jumping.
MAX SEEGER: Yeah.
I feel like I'm coming across
like this adrenaline junkie.
LEO PARENTE: No, no.
But you're not alone.
IAN WHELAN: But you like what
you like, and that's why
you're here.
MAX SEEGER: Yeah, yeah.
LEO PARENTE: Let me tell
you something.
There is hundreds of millions
of dollars--
a billion dollars--
thrown at it, and Indy Car
will run a race on the
weekend, and they'll get what?
Maybe a million people
in the US, of 330
million people, watching.
IAN WHELAN: Yeah.
LEO PARENTE: So don't think
you're the exception.
You're the friggin' norm with
the other 229,999 million.
IAN WHELAN: Right.
And in Europe, rally racing
is very popular.
It's up there.
It's up there with F1.
I don't know the numbers, but
it's big compared to here.
It's not so popular.
MAX SEEGER: Yeah.
LEO PARENTE: So I know
there are rally
events here in America.
And I know the Global RallyCross
has done a pretty
good job of getting
manufacturers engaged thanks
to ESPN and X Game.
But somewhere along the line,
with this dictatorship of all
the OEMs running racing, they
just need to commit to have a
bigger racing rally presence.
And this goes back
to the media.
Whether it's digital or TV, it
just needs to be out there so
that people know these are the
special classes of racing that
define racing.
The last one-- something
for bikes.
IAN WHELAN: I've
watched MotoGP.
And the funny thing about that
is even though I love F1 and I
like MotoGP, I think it's
actually more interesting when
the bikes are more like World
Superbike, where they're a
little bit--
LEO PARENTE: Production based?
IAN WHELAN: --more
production based.
Because motorcycles, even the
regular road-based ones that
you can buy at the dealership,
are so wild with the tech and
stuff, you're already up
there in technology.
So just to be able to actually
have a real connection seems
even more important
in that case.
LEO PARENTE: So we were
on the same page
with production based.
I was going to throw something
out there, and I don't
understand why this is.
Why can't I have a racing
weekend where there's car
racing, and if the track allows
it-- and a lot of
tracks do, like Laguna
Seca's--
why don't they have
the weekend with
bike being one event?
IAN WHELAN: Yeah, why not?
LEO PARENTE: And by the way,
have the cars go to a bike
event and be a support
race to them.
Are the fans all that different
that they don't--
IAN WHELAN: No.
I think there are, obviously,
support races already at
different types of
race events.
But if you had more top-level
racing at one event on one
weekend, that could be pretty
interesting rather than the
gentlemen drivers running
around in their Ferrari
Scuderias and then the F1 cars
come out or whatever.
LEO PARENTE: Does racing
include video games?
Does this whole redesign
involved video games more than
just having licensing?
IAN WHELAN: I think it has to.
I'm not a big video game fan,
but I think that it's
important for the aspect
to bring new
people into the sport.
LEO PARENTE: Should I even
mention it in the show?
IAN WHELAN: I think
you might have to.
MAX SEEGER: Would this affect
video game sales?
Or what are you saying?
LEO PARENTE: No.
Would I integrate video racing
into this redesign of what
racing should be in
North America?
MAX SEEGER: As a competition?
LEO PARENTE: Yeah.
IAN WHELAN: Or just to allow
the fans to play a sim of
these different kinds
of racing so they
can feel more involved.
MAX SEEGER: Right.
LEO PARENTE: And by the way, I
don't know how far it should
go, because in Europe, and I
guess in a little bit of
America, Nissan has their whole
GT Academy looking for
young guys and girls to become
professional racers.
MAX SEEGER: Yeah.
LEO PARENTE: Ordonez--
if I'm pronouncing it right--
he's raced at Le Mans.
He raced at Spa.
Ford has their little online
version of Octane Academy,
trying to find talent.
I don't know what they're going
to do with them, but
they've connected
the dots between
virtual and real racing.
MAX SEEGER: Yeah.
LEO PARENTE: And rather than
just sell more, how could
racing use that to get
more fans into this?
And perish the thought that you
have a competition where I
get to race Vettel or Dale, Jr.
On the sim as part of some
other version of "American
Idol" that keeps
ringing in my head.
MAX SEEGER: Hold
on, one second.
Would it be possible--
LEO PARENTE: Go ahead.
MAX SEEGER: You have your guys
out there on the track.
And then you have some kid in
a virtual car racing them at
the same time.
LEO PARENTE: I don't
see why not.
Someone tried to do
that years ago.
And they were way ahead
of the technology.
MAX SEEGER: How would
that work?
Yeah.
IAN WHELAN: You're using the
video feed from the race or
some sort of telemetry to
show where the cars are.
But you're in the race as
well-- the real race.
That would be cool.
LEO PARENTE: It would never
interfere with the real race,
and just have the sim respect
that if you bumped into one of
the real cars, you bumped
into the car.
IAN WHELAN: Right.
MAX SEEGER: Right.
IAN WHELAN: That would
be really cool.
LEO PARENTE: Would you want--
screw watching.
Would you do that?
MAX SEEGER: No, I
don't think so.
[LAUGHTER]
IAN WHELAN: But it sounds like
a good idea for people.
LEO PARENTE: OK.
Why did JF put you on the
"SHAKEDOWN" team?
I'm kidding.
The only one I haven't figured
out is drag racing.
But guess what?
The news is Ford cut
professional drag racing.
They're dumping John Force.
They're going to just
do grassroots.
But I don't know what to do
about drag racing, and I
can't ignore it.
IAN WHELAN: Well, I don't
know enough about
drag racing, but--
LEO PARENTE: Nor
do I, I guess.
IAN WHELAN: I think, again,
people have more connection to
the cars that they can relate
to when they see a really--
I'm thinking back to the
muscle car days.
When they can see a car going
down the strip and then buy a
car just like that, that's
pretty cool.
So that's all I can
say about it.
I know I'm repeating myself.
MAX SEEGER: All right.
How attended are drag races?
IAN WHELAN: Professional ones?
LEO PARENTE: I haven't been in
a long time, but I know the
races on the West Coast,
they get a big crowd--
100,000.
MAX SEEGER: They do?
Wow.
IAN WHELAN: Wow.
That's a lot.
MAX SEEGER: So it doesn't seem
like there's a problem.
LEO PARENTE: No, no.
To that point, I don't think
there is a problem.
They would argue differently
in terms of sponsorship and
what's going on.
But at the same point in time,
what I don't want to do is
allow clutter to seep
back into this
pushing racing forward.
MAX SEEGER: Yeah.
LEO PARENTE: But I'm the bad
guy who said, oh, yeah.
Drag racing, forgot
about that.
And I'm just throwing it
out there for them.
I want to throw it out there
for the crowd when
they talk about it.
MAX SEEGER: Right now, as it is,
are there any events where
they have this thing that you
were saying, where it's more
like an Olympics kind of
thing, where if you're
watching from home, you watch
the guy in the rings, and then
it goes to--
LEO PARENTE: I think the closest
are Race of Champions
and the X Games.
MAX SEEGER: OK
LEO PARENTE: Yeah.
MAX SEEGER: Do you like that?
Do you think you'd stick around
for the whatever you
don't like event?
IAN WHELAN: Well, this
reminds me--
not to cut you off.
LEO PARENTE: Go ahead.
No.
Someone should.
IAN WHELAN: With all these
different racing types within
the sanctioning body, if we
could encourage the drivers to
cross over more often, that
would be helpful, I think,
because if you start following
a driver and you only like
that one style of racing, you
might open your mind once he
goes over to this other one.
LEO PARENTE: I think that's
necessarily brilliant.
That has to happen.
IAN WHELAN: I feel like that
used to happen more often, not
under one sanctioning
body, but--
LEO PARENTE: Well, and to that
point, this is where I'm going
to put too much pressure
on the manufacturers.
But since they are being allowed
to run this thing,
look at Pat Long.
IAN WHELAN: Yeah.
LEO PARENTE: They shopped Pat
Long around to various teams.
What we're saying is go back to
the old Andretti days, and
this weekend, you're
in the rally car.
IAN WHELAN: Right.
LEO PARENTE: Next weekend,
you're in our open-wheel car.
IAN WHELAN: Right.
LEO PARENTE: Whatever.
LEO PARENTE: Yeah.
I think that would
interest you.
And it would build the
personality of these guys--
and girls.
I keep saying that.
IAN WHELAN: And it would show
how well rounded they are and
their strengths and all
that, weaknesses.
LEO PARENTE: And this week, I'm
watching rally, next week
I'm watching Indy, because
I'm following my guy.
IAN WHELAN: Yeah.
MAX SEEGER: So are we done?
LEO PARENTE: Yeah.
Another five-minute
meeting with Leo.
Thanks.
IAN WHELAN: Yeah.
LEO PARENTE: No.
Yeah, I think we're done.
And I think you gave me
stuff to work on.
MAX SEEGER: Cool.
LEO PARENTE: So let me go
write this damn thing.
IAN WHELAN: All right.
LEO PARENTE: Today, on
"SHAKEDOWN," let's redo racing
and create the ideal North
American racing set, the
collection of racing series,
and race cars to get more
fans, to keep the hard-core
enthusiasts happy, and to
bring in new followers without
dumbing the racing down or
sensationalizing it into
some version of--
I don't know--
Ricky Bobby's Death Race 3000.
So why this show?
Well, frankly, I've had it with
the auto racing politics,
personal agendas, and
nearsighted compromises in
racing that never seem to get
us the best solutions or the
best racing.
And why a North American
racing redo versus
taking on the globe?
Well, I've got to
start somewhere.
This first, then we'll take on
F1 Bernie and/or the FIA.
So today, let's design a series
of North American
series with the cars, the
action, drivers, technology,
the traditions, the tracks, the
format of the racing, and
the media that would make racing
be what you want and
what more people would
want to follow.
And like every "SHAKEDOWN,"
we'll be doing our racing
redesign with your
ideas and input.
We're tipping the North
American auto racing
Etch-a-Sketch and turning the
knob "SHAKEDOWN" way, all with
your input.
So come back, and let's see if
we can out think the Indy Car
people, outsmart the SCCA, and
outfox the Frances of NASCAR
and the United Sports
Car Racing.
[CAR ENGINES REVVING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]