things started today. We`re fortunate that
you sent that in. I`m Carl Azuz. Your Tuesday
edition of CNN STUDENT NEWS is here.
The U.S. presidential election is exactly
three weeks away. Some Americans know whom
they are voting for, others might not have
made up their minds just yet. Now, it might
help some people if they could directly ask
the presidential candidates questions themselves,
and that`s exactly what some people are going
to be able to do tonight. It is the second
U.S. presidential debate. President Barack
Obama and former Massachusetts Governor Mitt
Romney will face off at Hofstra University
in New York. CNN is part of this, too. Candy
Crowley, our chief political correspondent,
is moderating tonight`s event.
You might wonder why there aren`t any third
party candidates, why there aren`t any other
candidates in this debates. The group that
organizes them has rules for who can participate
based on how much support a candidate has.
President Obama and Governor Romney are the
only candidates who meet all of the requirements.
Tonight`s debate will be different from the
one two weeks ago. It`s a town hall format,
that`s why audience members will get to ask
the candidates questions directly.
Athena Jones looks at what makes this format
unique.
Round Two. President Obama and Governor Mitt
Romney face off in their second debate Tuesday,
a town hall moderated by CNN`s Candy Crowley
who says the format presents unique challenges
for the candidates.
CANDY CROWLEY, CNN CORRESPONDENT: Now, the
challenge is that they`ve got to connect,
not just with the people that are looking
into the television, and watching them, but
to the people that are on the stage with them,
some 80 or so undecided voters as chosen by
Gallup. So they have to keep those folks in
mind, it`s a much more intimate and up close
adventure with voters.
JONES: President Obama is under pressure.
After his last turn on the debate stage, he
got bad reviews.
ANA NAVARRO, REPUBLICAN STRATEGIST: One bad
debate is losing a battle. Two bad debates
could very well mean he loses the war.
MARIA CARDONA, DEMOCRATIC STRATEGIST: And
I think you`re going to see a very different
President Obama this time around. He`s got
to be seen as being aggressive, but yet he
can`t be seen as being overly aggressive.
JONES: Romney has enjoyed a post debate bounce
in national polls, and a boost of confidence
on the campaign trail.
MITT ROMNEY, ( R ), PRESIDENTIAL CANDIDATE:
There is more energy and passion people are
getting behind this campaign.
JONES: At a town hall without a podium and
with audience interaction, the candidates`
style and body language can take on added
weight. At the first town hall style presidential
debate in 1992, President George W.H. Bush
repeatedly checked his watch, a sign some
thought that he didn`t want to be there.
Commentators said Bill Clinton walking towards
the audience to answer a question about the
recession highlighted his ability to connect
with voters. One thing that can make it hard
for a candidate to be aggressive is a question
like this.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Can we focus on the issues
and not the personalities and the mud?
JONES: Analysts say the format could be good
for the president.
CARDONA: He will absolutely be able to draw
from that energy, from the energy of the public
and the crowd.
JONES: As for Romney ...
NAVARRO: One of his big challenges during
this entire campaign, has been not being able
to connect with the common man and woman and
child. He`s got to be able to come across
as connecting, he`s got to come across as
genuine, as caring as likable.
CROWLEY: The candidate that makes the connection
with the person asking the question is also
I think making a better connection with the
folks back home.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: On this day in history, in 1793, Marie-Antoinette
was sent to the guillotine and beheaded during
the height of the French Revolution. In 1859,
John Brown led a raid against an armory in
Harpers Ferry, attempting to start a revolt
that would end slavery. It was a major event
leading up to the U.S. Civil War. And in 1995,
the Million Man March took place in Washington,
D.C. The goal is to promote unity and values
among African Americans. It was one of the
largest gatherings of its kind in U.S. history.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
JOHN F. KENNEDY: Good evening, my fellow citizens.
This government, as promised, has maintained
the closest surveillance of the Soviet military
buildup on the island of Cuba. Within the
past week, unmistakable evidence has established
the fact that a series of offensive missile
sites is now in preparation on that imprisoned
island. The purpose of this bases can be non
other than to provide a nuclear strike capability
against the Western Hemisphere.
In U.S. it`s called the Cuban missile crisis.
In the Soviet Union it was knows as the Caribbean
crisis, and in Cuba it was the October crisis.
Whatever it was called, the 13 day standoff
in 1962 brought the U.S. and the Soviet Union
right to the edge of a nuclear war. And it
all started 50 years ago this week. That`s
when U.S. spy planes took pictures of Soviet
missiles at launch sites in Cuba. This missiles
could carry nuclear warheads and if they were
launched, they could hit the U.S. East Coast
in just minutes. President Kennedy`s response
was to launch a naval blockade against Cuba.
It was designed to stop additional Soviet
missiles from getting to the island. Kennedy
and Soviet leader Nikita Khrushchev negotiated
a solution and the Soviet missiles were eventually
returned from Cuba. Omar Lopez had a front
row seat to the Cuban missile crisis. Those
secret Soviet launch sites, one of them was
built on Omar`s family farm. And 50 years
later, he took Patrick Oppmann out to see
the remains of the moment in history.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
PATRICK OPPMANN, CNN CORRESPONDENT: Omar takes
us out to see what`s left of this Soviet camp
by mule.
OMAR LOPEZ, CUBAN FARMER: There were a lot
of them, I can`t remember, if it was five
or six barracks of soldiers.
OPPMANN: Now, nature has retaken the once
sprawling missile base.
So, here in the middle of the jungle of some
of the last visible remnants of the huge Soviet
base that was once here, and we don`t know
what this building was, but it looks like
it was one of the huge hangars that they actually
stored the missiles in, and here are some
of the farmers in the area, have repurposed
this enormous concrete supports and have actually
used them to create a pen to keep their pigs
in.
From here, we continue on foot and find the
missile launch pad with a faded plaque marking
how close the world came to nuclear war.
It was over this area 50 years ago that U.S.
spy planes caught the first glimpse of Soviet
nuclear missiles. The photos they took within
just a few days would catapult much of the
world into a panic.
Omar said a news blackout meant he had no
idea that the missiles like the ones on the
old farm nearly caused the U.S. to invade
Cuba.
LOPEZ (through translator): We were lucky
that wasn`t war, after the atomic bombs and
the sickness that would have come, there wouldn`t
have been a single Cuban left and there would
not have been many of you left either.
OPPMANN: To avoid war, the Soviets removed
the missiles and troops. Patrick Oppmann,
CNN, near San Cristobal, Cuba.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today "Shoutout" goes
out to Mrs. Driggers` class at Spectrum Jr.
- Sr. High School in Stuart, Florida.
Which U.S. state is home to college football
teams named the Bulls, Knights, Seminoles
and Hurricanes?
Here we go. Is it California, Texas, Florida
or Georgia. You`ve got three seconds. Go!
Mrs. Driggers` students probably knew this
one, because it`s their home state of Florida.
That`s your answer and that`s your "Shoutout."
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: So, those were all college teams. Florida
is also home to South Plantation High School`s
Paladins. The team played its homecoming game
last week. And the Paladins third string quarterback
had to pull double duty. That`s because she
-- yes, she -- was also crowned homecoming
queen. Erin Damiglio (ph) didn`t get any playing
time in her team`s win, but she has been on
the field this season, and it`s believed that
when that happened, Erin became the first
female quarterback to play high school football
in Florida. When she was crowned homecoming
queen, she had a teammate by her side, one
of the team`s receivers who said it was an
honor to be there with her, was crowned king.
We`re going to stay on the football field
for our last story, which is from CBS News.
It`s a world record attempt that just might
leave your head spinning. Check this out.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
Thirty one! Thirty two!
Thirty three! Thirty four! Thirty five!
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Get dizzy just watching that. 35 backhand
springs in a row, that`s enough to make anyone
flip out. It`s time for us to spring out of
here. We`ll hit the field again tomorrow with
more CNN STUDENT NEWS. We`ll see you then.