And I've been cooking basically
my whole life, but
I've been cooking professionally
about 28 years.
You guys want to stay and have
a drink, you should.
My name is Paul Kahan, I am
the executive chef, a word
that I've never wanted to
attach to my name but
unfortunately I have to.
I am the executive chef for
Blackbird, Avec, the Publican,
and Big Star.
I don't get to cook as much
as I would like anymore,
unfortunately.
When I do, it's joyous.
I guess I'd say that I am
a motivator, organizer,
conceptualizer, numbers guy,
concept guy, market guy,
forager, food lover, goofball,
political man.
That's phenomenal.
[MUNCHING]
Mmm.
Blackbird is in its 14th year.
First restaurant that
I was part owner of.
I get the question all the time,
what are your favorite
food trends of the year?
Which makes me want
to spit blood.
And I say the same
thing every time.
The only food trend for
us is great food,
great wine, great service.
I remember people telling me
that we're at Blackbird for
the first time in year 10, and
that this is a great new
restaurant.
It feels new.
And that's an amazing
compliment.
[ELEVATED TRAIN]
We're doing a rockumentary
if anyone asks.
Bryce Caron, plays lead guitar,
from Dusseldorf.
We're going to Great Lake Pizza,
up in Andersonville.
It is a really teeny little
pizza place, owned by a
husband and wife,
Nick and Lydia.
Everything organic,
everything local.
First and foremost,
Lydia and Nick are
really, really nice people.
And they're really into
local product, and
great simple food.
I mean, the place is a salad,
three pizzas, cookies or
gelato or both for dessert.
And that's it.
It's really sort of the
direction that my mind goes.
I don't want to have 18 courses
for four hours.
I want to go eat something
that's delicious, drink some
wine, and be with loved ones.
This is Kathryn, Biz 3.
She's been kind enough to take
on the publicity for our
dysfunctional company.
This is David.
David's the chef de cuisine
at Blackbird.
Bryce Caron, pastry
chef at Blackbird.
Laurent, one of our managers
at Big Star.
Ben, manager Big Star.
Probably the most popular guy
in all of Wicker Park in
Chicago as far as I can tell.
You know, honestly I'm not like
a super big go out guy,
I'm kind of over it.
It's a really good thing for
a chef-restaurateur to be.
I did a tasting menu at
a unnamed restaurant
like two years ago.
And after like, course five,
my wife and were looking at
each other.
And it was really good, it's
a great restaurant.
Like can we just get the
fuck out of here?
Buddies visit me from out of
town, this would be the place
of choice, always.
Because it's super accessible,
unpretentious, great food.
Hello?
Good, how are you?
We're going to a Korean
barbecue joint.
Chicago Kalbi.
I normally eat three or
four times a night.
And this is only two, so--
I'm kind of hungry right now.
Look at this article.
Pastrami's second coming.
That's awesome, right?
Oh, man.
My heroes.
How are you?
I love that place.
The people are just, they're
good as gold.
They're so incredibly sweet, so
welcoming, it's inexpensive
and it's just really
pure and simple.
Especially the barbecue
itself.
It's just putting meat on a
grill and putting some kimchi
with it and eating it.
It's great quality.
It's a fun place to go up
with a lot of people.
Good, right?
Killer.
We got one of the weirdest
things ever here.
Steak tartare with
the mountain yam.
It's like steak tartare with
slimy foam over it.
Check it out.
Oh yeah.
It's like a yam and when you
grate it, it turns into slime.
But it's really tasty.
It's off putting, but
it's delicious.
It's not freak factor.
I swear to god I wouldn't
do that.
No.
It has no quality of
cheese about it.
KATHRYN: No boogers?
PAUL KAHAN: No, no boogers.
They gave you a good tip?
All right.
Thank god.
How awesome is that?
The sushi case, let's shut
it down, let's put
baseballs in there.
Really?
Who would you say is the best
baseball player, consistently
over the last 10 years,
in America?
Ichiro.
MALE SPEAKER: Ichiro's
up there.
PAUL KAHAN: He's certainly
Oh my god.
He's the best.
For me?
One of my favorite baseball
players ever.
They're baseball
fanatics there.
Every time Ichiro's in
town, he comes to eat
there, every day.
So he walks into a life-sized
picture of himself.
It's the first time I've ever
had a card in my whole life.
No, I'm very irresponsible.
I'm not that kind of guy.
I'm on the down low man.
I'm not into making
reservations.
Usually we make reservations in
my wife's name, she has a
different last name.
I just do not want to
be fussed over.
I'm a chef, yeah.
Our first restaurant
is Blackbird.
Japanese people like
Blackbird.
Thank you.
You guys are awesome.
Thank you, good night.
Man, I am so in love with her.
How cute is she?
LAURENT LEBEC: Very cute.
This is your other life.
This is what you do.
PAUL KAHAN: Baseball,
baseball.
We came to Publican.
We put out a bunch of
charcuterie that we make in
house here, which I was
pretty pleased with.
Pretty special stuff.
LAURENT LEBEC: Oh my god.
Apricots?
BEN FASMAN: Apricots and
fucking foie gras.
PAUL KAHAN: You know, my
business partners, we
conceptualize based on a food
sound bite, basically.
For the Publican, the
sound bite was
oysters, pork, and beer.
And I'd test it out
with chefs.
They're like, what's your next
restaurant going to be?
And I'd say, oysters,
pork, and beer.
And everyone would be like,
how could that be bad?
We like to take flavors from
all around the world.
From Germany and from Belgium,
we'll do a schnitzel with
Mediterranean flavors
on top of it.
The other concepts are so
tightly defined and we don't
stray outside the flavors
that define the place.
Here it was like, we can
do whatever the hell we
want, if it's good.
[GERMAN ACCENT]
So you get to deal here
with the eggs, Dave.
Eggs are next.
We talk German together
when we're cooking.
It's my Wolfgang
Puck imitation.
Hey, what you doing
there, sonny boy?
BRYCE CARON: I have no idea
what this is, but I'm
excited about it.
PAUL KAHAN: The idea
comes from Tunisia.
MALE SPEAKER: What's
the name of it?
PAUL KAHAN: It's called
Tunisian fricassee.
I have this great buddy
named Lior who has a
spice shop in New York.
He keeps firing me all
these ideas on
Tunisia, and from Lebanon.
And so he have me this recipe,
it's like a Nicoise sandwich.
And I've been just dreaming
about eating it.
It's not a Subway, but--
Come on!
Dude, give them some
fucking beer!
You know, these guys
are drinking Point?
MALE SPEAKER: I'm
drinking Point.
MICHAEL MCAVENA: Everyone else
is drinking cider and Cezanne.
I don't know why these gentlemen
are drinking
[? Point ?].
Well, whatever you guys want.
The bar is yours.
PAUL KAHAN: Get more beer,
the bar is yours.
We have these giant weiss beer
glasses that Michael got.
I call him the beer
boy, my wife gets
mad at me, but he's--
I don't know, in his mid- 20s
and he looks like he's 14.
But he's an incredible beer guy,
and I guess him and David
were hanging out by the bar,
and David talked about the
soda fountain thing called
the suicide.
Where you take one
of everything.
We have 12 beers on tap, so
they filled it up with 12
different beers.
BEN FASMAN: What's in there?
MICHAEL MCAVENA: We made the
first beer suicide, ever, at
the Publican.
BEN FASMAN: What's in there?
MICHAEL MCAVENA: Every single
thing we have on tap.
BEN FASMAN: Come on,
that's disgusting.
I'm going to barf.
LAURENT LEBEC: I'll definitely
take a sip of it.
PAUL KAHAN: And then a drunken
guy, me, started pouring
whiskey in it as we went.
It was really fun, with
all the cooks.
I think they were like, we've
got to get out of here.
MALE SPEAKER: Oh, yeah.
Tasty.
It's pretty good, man.
We should put that on
the brunch menu.
Come on, David.
If you can't finish that,
you're such a pussy.
Pull it back, pull it back.
You got it!
Take it, take it!
[APPLAUSE]
PAUL KAHAN: I think we probably
should have filled it
up again and done it again.
But that's the alcohol still
in my system talking.
MALE SPEAKER: Prost.
Prost.
Come on, Michael.
Come on, man.
It doesn't get any more
fucked up than this.
PAUL KAHAN: That was so wrong.
[THEME  MUSIC]