noticed that the fertility rates in
brazil have decreased significantly in
the past few decades and they want to
know why what's going on and he turned
up in brazil there's been this whole
uh... female empowerment movement right
but it also has a lot to do with the
economy in brazil it has to do with
poverty in brazil and it has to do a
soap operas believe it or not
so it's really interesting live okay so
what happens is that you know when you
watch soap operas in brazil and
the story lines in the soap operas need
to be simplistic rectum or simple it is
the war on the issue happens also easier
predicts
so what happens is when in brazil will
watch the soap operas and
they'll see the small families and
watching it on television
almost glamorizes it so in past decades
you see women in brazil having ten plus
children but then as soap operas become
more and more popular they're watching
them they're saying all it is glamorous
little family i want to have a small
family someone more women we have two
children sometimes only one and after
giving birth del gopher sterilization
while rehab
exultation
maisie how the culture can change how
much pop culture affects overall culture
right and is also amazing the soap
operas have actually done some good in
the world for the first time
unintentionally right i'd like to keep
in mind that this is our just keeping
the storyline simple yet because they
don't want a cast of ten k exactly okay
so they unintentionally have is the fact
but idon't want you guys to think that
is that simplistic obviously other
factors play a role you know the economy
um... there's uh... the tremendous
amount of poverty in brazil people are
are living in these tiny little
apartments so women that you don't
realize look we don't need to have ten
kids you know we're living in this tiny
apartment one or two is enough and after
having two they say the factories close
they literally say that mister added
portuguese and then they go they add
have their sterilization
and of course of the macroeconomic
outlook over on this in a plot of the
whole world this is how many more
reporter in brazil partly because of the
pop culture center
uh... is that in the past the reason you
had ten cases because one he worked
surer amira survive and to that you feel
a lot of form for example the kids
worked on the form some orchids you had
a more productive you could be now again
these are broad simple the notion of the
true now if you do don't work out a form
the ten kids far liability economically
speaking not that that benefit
so obviously at some point you will
start again message ready
handsomely combined all those factors in
the place it's actually a great thing
the brazil's population that is now at a
point where it's not exponentially
growing as it used to be rates actually
lower than the replacement rate okay so
i have before
each family had at or there were two
point out there d six children per
family rain and that has dropped to one
point nine children per family merit
and you know
like historically you would have thought
in brazil wall places you would imagine
that at all
but it's even gone there licking my
ideal world
uh... that we do it we all go uh...
under the replacement rate for quite
some time laid out what happened like
demographically do you think it will
happen but it won't happen for some time
rain
but and because if you look at the
graphs of how
extras in the field believe it's going
to work they think of our population
over the world is going to continue to
increase
uh... and forget it was ten or twelve
billion but in that
ballpark
and then also to decrease right right
and at some point you level up
and you know they need to forge a mobile
hot spot for ninety nine nine a monthly
increase your own personal hot spot
of the information five different about
silicon bloom five and provide product
for film cameras laptops portable gaming
blockaded
no virgins
free come up hello you perhaps mention
the best part itself orgy hot spot
but offered do about it
you gotta get it now t mobile
get more