[GUITAR MUSIC]
ADRI MURGUIA: Despite removing
himself from the society,
Faustino's lifestyle began to
change when civilization
started catching up with him.
Just two years ago, the
government found out he had
guns on his property.
And they cut a deal with him
in which he would exchange
them for solar panels, which
he doesn't really use.
That was only the first in a
series of changes that would
lead him to modify
his lifestyle.
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
ADRI MURGUIA: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
ADRI MURGUIA: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
ADRI MURGUIA: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
ADRI MURGUIA: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
ADRI MURGUIA: Perhaps the
biggest change that has
affected Faustino is the
unlikely friendship with an
outsider whom he's
given permission
to live on his land.
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
MARCOS LANCASTER:
[METAL CLINKING]
ADRI MURGUIA: We're shearing
the sheep.
And then we're going to kill it
because we're going on an
expedition tomorrow
to the Green Lake.
And we need to take food.
So we're taking this guy.
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
ADRI MURGUIA: I've never
seen this before.
And apparently, it's
not quick.
It takes like two minutes after
they slit its throat.
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
ADRI MURGUIA: It's like
bones are coming off.
Skin is coming off.
It's our lunch for tomorrow.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
MARCOS LANCASTER:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
ADRI MURGUIA: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
MARCOS LANCASTER:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
ADRI MURGUIA: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
ADRI MURGUIA: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
ADRI MURGUIA: Watching Faustino
kill the sheep and
the casual nature of the act,
reinforce the modes of
survival of this land.
There was absolutely nothing
for us to eat at the Green
Lake, which was a special place
for him that he hadn't
returned to for many years.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS: