ETHAN FOWLER: So I probably
got to talk loud, right?
-Yeah.
ETHAN FOWLER: OK.
All right, well, like a couple
nights ago, the night before
last, I went to The 500 Club
with a couple friends.
And I just decided to
have a few drinks.
It's a bar on Mission.
And there, through I
don't know how or
why, I met this girl.
A friend of mine said, cut
the crap and why don't
you just make out?
So she says, all right
let's make out.
So we make out.
And we're making out and
everything's great.
And we're hanging out
and drinking.
She got pissed because
I saw this other
girl and then we left.
And the dudes pulled up and
fucking jumped out of the car.
Next thing I know, I just was
getting socked in the face,
looking at the guy like it's
not going to do me any good
punching him.
And I got socked a few times.
I fell.
I just covered my face and they
just kicked the shit out
of me for a little while.
It was good, though, because I
got to make out with a girl.
I don't know.
It's getting purple.
-OK.
I'm going to fade it out.
ETHAN FOWLER: OK.
Fade.
-Fade.
ETHAN FOWLER: Fading fast.
DAVE CARNIE: I don't really
remember how the whole living
thing came up.
I got an apartment
in the Mission.
And he moved in with me.
One day, went down to Guitar
Center and bought a little,
white Fender guitar, one
of those $99 ones.
And so that's what he'd do all
day when I'd go to work.
Is he'd just sit there and just
noodle on the guitar.
And every day I'd come home.
He'd only been playing for
like a week or two.
And I came home one day
and he had learned--
he was like, Dave,
check this out.
And he had learned an entire
Slayer song from start to
finish in one day.
Ethan's got just this
really weird talent.
When he applies himself
to something, he's
like the best at it.
And he's completely natural,
kind of like how he skates.
ETHAN FOWLER: I was hanging
out with Chris a lot.
And we were getting way
into this home brew
recorded music and shit.
The whole Guided By Voices
and Sebadoh deal.
CHRIS PASTRAS: Totally.
I didn't even mention that.
Yeah, we were making music
primarily at the time.
And so that was a huge
inspiration for us.
Like we were just
like, fuck it.
Let's Bucket Brothers it.
Like that was our little
joke band.
We were pressured
to make a video.
And it was like the
winter time.
It was like February.
And there was all this pressure
to follow up "A
Visual Sound." And Jason had
like just recently left, or
told us he was leaving.
And there was like a lot of
pressure there for people and
he didn't really want to
film a video part.
And instead of like combusting,
me and Ethan kind
of looked at each other and were
like, let's just have fun
and go skating.
And put it out in a month.
And just, like, make
the soundtrack.
And drink beer.
And bomb some hills.
So, but I think people were
expecting another "Visual
Sound," and that really bummed
them out-- some people.
But I think like 5, 10 years
later, we all watch the video
and my friends will be
like, dude, "Tincan
Folklore" is rad.
I used to say "Tincan Folklore"
was taped together
with masking tape.
Like, that's how we wanted
it to feel though.
It's like so sketchy.
We did the music ourselves and
filmed it in like a month.
And it was just so budget.
"A Visual Sound," we had
a goal and a vision.
And we had something
really big to say.
And with "Tincan Folklore,"
we had something to say.
It was just was not as big.
It was more just like,
hey, this is fun.
This is skateboarding.
Here's us putting out a video.
It was more messy.
ETHAN FOWLER: And so that was
kind of a whole basis of that,
like a four track skate video
as represented in my part.
Which is me, and Carnie, and
Sean Young just drunk off our
asses at 3:00 in the afternoon,
playing the "Wizard
of Oz" theme.
CHRIS PASTRAS: To me, the things
that got me stoked on
skateboarding are things that
make me want to ride my
skateboard.
And I always kind of felt like,
to me it's more of the
character behind it and the
personalities, and their
style, and the way they carry
themselves on a board.
Gets me way more stoked than
technical videos that are
competitive.
It's interesting, though.
The thing I always liked about
Anti Hero and Stereo was that
very thing.
That people would come up to me
in bars and be like, dude,
Stereo videos, or the Deluxe
videos, or Anti Hero videos.
They were so stoked because it
made them want to skate.
And it made them--
I think Eastern Exposure videos
and some of those
videos did the same thing.
Like, anybody who's sitting on
their couch can get up and be
like, dude, Bobby Puleo found
these amazing spots.
Or man, Ethan Fowler's
got such good style.
And, like, go skate their
town hand rail.
ETHAN FOWLER: Yeah, it wasn't
supposed to be perfect.
I think it's interesting
to watch.
CHRIS PASTRAS: We felt it in
the air when Stereo started
and was going to be on fire.
And you felt it in the
air when its time
was over with Deluxe.
I was 19 when we
started Stereo.
So by the time we hit "Tincan
Folklore," I thought I was
over the hill.
I was like 24.
Everything has its time, man.
I think it couldn't have
kept going like it was.
It's like too rad.
Anything that hits that
high of a point
is bound to go down.
And I don't really
even remember.
I'm trying to think.
I think he left for
Foundation.
There was this whole thing with
Mic-E punching Tod Swank
at the ASR trade show.
TOD SWANK: Mic-E Reyes
was really bummed.
The whole Deluxe guys
were really bummed.
They were telling everybody that
we totally like stole him
from those guys.
At that trade show, hanging
out with Mic-E Reyes, and
Mic-E Reyes has got his
arm around Josh being
all like bros, fun.
Hey, you know.
Hey.
And then he'd just
be like, kick.
Whatever.
I was sitting there talking
to somebody.
And Moishe comes up.
He's all, hey, Tod.
How's it going?
What's up and stuff?
I'm all kind of flinchy
because Mic-E's
lurking around and stuff.
And he's all, what, dude?
Did you think I was going to
punch you or something?
And I'm all, no.
And he was like, phew.
Punched me in the stomach.
Doubled over.
Mic-E Reyes paid him $100 to
come punch me in the stomach.
And I was the guy that called
those guys to forewarn them.
And go, look, you guys need to
take care of your business
because your guy's not
happy and stuff.
And that's what we got.
CHRIS PASTRAS: [INAUDIBLE],
man.
Fuck!
Fuck, man!
ETHAN FOWLER: Let's
put it this way.
Getting on Stereo was like an
extension of my skateboarding
ethic to begin with.
I never thought that, like, I
need to go to this thing to do
this specific thing because
that's the thing to do--
ever.
And I still don't,
and I never will.
And being around people that do
that kind of thing, if I'm
interested in it, I'll do it.
If I'm not, I won't.
The Foundation dudes
offered up.
Well, those are guys that are
actually out there skating,
doing their thing.
I get along with them.
So, all right, I'll do that.
TOD SWANK: I think he was our
longest ever team rider on
Foundation.
I think 10 years he rode for
us straight through.
And super solid and obviously an
amazing skateboarder with a
great style and super--
people are just always
hyped on him.
And he was a powerful and smooth
skateboarder for sure.
ETHAN FOWLER: Foundation
was the rail team.
And so, it was get the dudes
who bust the big rails.
And they were amazing
skaters, still are.
And just like being around that
was all cool looking.
It got me excited.
-Yeah.
ETHAN FOWLER: Lack
of motivation.
-If you'd stayed on Stereo, it
would have been like, whoop,
retirement part.
ETHAN FOWLER: Yeah,
at 19, that's
probably not a good idea.
I mean, you've got to be around
motivated people or be
motivated just for
a little while.
TOD SWANK: He always had fun
ideas and would come and work
on crazy graphics that people
would either love or hate.
The sales people would
hate them.
I can't sell them, or
something like that.
Because it's just too
crazy, or something.
ETHAN FOWLER: Talk
about stick.
Ow!
That was my body.
DAVE CARNIE: It's always weird
to me to see someone skating
who's not dressed for skating.
And Ethan definitely now--
it looks like he should be
picking up a guitar and not a
skateboard.
Just there's a weird kind of
visual disconnect to me, but
he's still that amazing skater
that he always was.
TOD SWANK: I think it was
last part in the last
video that we did.
And there was a debate whether
he should have last part or
Corey should have last part.
ETHAN FOWLER: Man, I tell you.
These kids these days,
they hated that.
-Really?
ETHAN FOWLER: Oh, yeah.
It's great.
I love it.
-They were like, why doesn't
Corey Duffel
have the last part?
ETHAN FOWLER: Yeah, exactly.
I had brought it up as a joke,
just to see what would happen,
like the company response.
Well, it's been a while I've
been on this team.
What say you just chuck
it at the end there?
And then it caused this
like, oh, jeez.
I don't know.
You know, big interoffice memos
and call the skaters.
Hey, is that all right
if Grandpa Ethan
gets the last part?
And so it was just kind of
funny to even have that.
I mean, it wasn't an ego trip.
It was the opposite.
It was like, dude, let's
see what happens.
I want to see what happens
if this even happens.
And it's great because there
was so much shit talking.
Oh, that part sucked.
That dude sucks.
It's probably his
retirement part.
I love hearing shit like that.
-Do you have any stuff
we can look at?
ETHAN FOWLER: I have
lots of stuff.
There's the studio.
That's the guitar.
-Damn, that's a big stack.
ETHAN FOWLER: It's a stack.
It's bigger now.
There's me in my Bill Murray
whiskey advertisement pose.
-You have any skate related
stuff, like
say a stereo board?
ETHAN FOWLER: Uh-uh.
I got nothing like that.
I have the new ones.
I got trippy keyboard and
some ancient amplifiers.
-Do you have a Bummer
High board?
ETHAN FOWLER: I have that.
And that's the bus.
So there's that one and this
one's got a dragon on it.
It's like a sweet warrior
dude down there.
He's going to face the
giant blue dragon.
-So what's Bummer High?
ETHAN FOWLER: I don't know.
It's just an extension
of my ethic.
You ever just get really stoned,
and you're having a
great time, and someone
comes up, and just
completely blows it?
This is dedicated to
all those jerks.
Bummer High is my love
for evil music.
It's about getting stomped
on for just being the
dude that you are.
I want it to be how I see it.
And that's not an egotistical
thing.
It's not driven by that.
It's just I think it's a good
way to go about things.
It's a lot less stressful.
You do what you want.
You do it well.
Or if you don't want to do it
well, don't do it well.
Just do it how you do it.
And that shit shines through
a thousand times brighter.
DAVE CARNIE: Any kid who gets
into skating and wants to be
pro or sponsored to be in the
industry doesn't realize how
you're completely fucking up
what you used to enjoy doing
by yourself and with
your friends.
It happens to most skaters.
I mean, there's a few.
Like Ethan's one who didn't
allow himself to get wrapped
up in the, quote unquote,
"industry." He
just did what he wanted.
And fortunately for him, what he
does is so good that people
can't help but have to
pay attention to it.
Yeah, he's always wanted
to do Bummer High.
He's been talking about
that for years.
Yeah, I don't think Ethan knows
much about what's going
on in skateboarding, which
is kind of the
beauty of it, I guess.
ETHAN FOWLER: Nah.
-Yeah, Spanky was telling me
that you don't know who a lot
of the skaters are.
He's always like, yeah, Ethan
doesn't know much about the--
ETHAN FOWLER: Not really.
I mean, just some dudes
that peak my interest.
-I heard something the other
day, that Josh Harmony
believes that Satan buried
the dinosaur bones.
ETHAN FOWLER: Oh, does he now?
-Yeah.
ETHAN FOWLER: Oof!
-Then you know what?
ETHAN FOWLER: That's
interesting.
-At first, I thought that
was ridiculous.
And then the more I think about
it, I'm like, I want to
start thinking that, too.
ETHAN FOWLER: I'm mean, that
would be cool because I'd like
to see a physical incarnation
of Satan.
That would be pretty sweet.
Because he's probably got a
lot of shit to talk about,
getting kicked out of
heaven and all.
I mean, it'd be pretty
cool to hang out.
-Watch Satan bury
dinosaur bones?
ETHAN FOWLER: We can bury
something before
the tape runs out.
Maybe, like, in future times,
people will think that God
buried this.
OK.
It's time.
And then, see, maybe they'll
think Satan buried that and
that there was no such
thing as computers.
Whatever.
There it is.
Rest well, sweet prince.
Served well.
There's your fucking "SLAP"
forum right there.
Finished.
Oh, watch out.
Shooting range.
-Whoa.
ETHAN FOWLER: You're going to
trip over the invisible line.
-What?
You got guns?
ETHAN FOWLER: Yeah,
a little BB gun.
Come out here and blast
away at the cans.
It's fun.
-Damn.
ETHAN FOWLER: Yeah.
-That's pretty cool.