there were recorded mcconnell's office
so caroline insider
in the mcconnell campaign record of this
strategy sessions
where they're talking about how they
would destroy any political opponent
including actually job first we'll hear
from uh... mitch mcconnell himself
do them out
must be contributing and all of them
bob what about that means hit 'em hit
'em hard that applies ashley judd in
anyone else
so they're being proactive about this
and we have this
his mother chalmers a report on david
corn
several suburban forty seven percent
story during campaign has the tapes from
inside source was which mitch
mcconnell's campaign is very upset about
uh... partly because of what it reveals
about what they were saying about
actually job so uh... on issue or
whether they would use
hard oppression
that she talked about in our book
again sir
so there's an interesting words
accused
joint terrorism or are file
printout nine
so is eco sure to use their depression i
guess ornamental breakdown well
later in the tapes they wind up joking
about different episodes that she had
and a lot
affan laugh and laugh
so i think that was of course quite mad
about this you put out a statement
the decaying depression is a laughing
matter and you know it's a
participants all the structure
specializing in the ritz
uh... my new force these tapes were made
a time when they thought they were
probably gonna run against him
so it now that's not the only thing they
had again so there were used
what they interpreted as her
interpretation
of christianity as
uh... from
so now in reality in our book she talks
record how she's a christian often and
prays often et cetera so that one's very
sketchy and then they were thing you
using things the answer such as her
saying
this you know i have kids and grandkids
of this world and except now is all this
fair game
i say the asme yes politics is
oftentimes dirty advising him running
yes a republican who had mental health
issues
using i would bring it up
tear it up
approve probably bring two-by-four
mckay
so am i surprised that mitch mcconnell
who you-know-what here's a guy who sings
in italy's charismatic person in the
entire world
traumatic isn't always a gobbled right
but he is a legal are among the senate
behavior he got there by accident now we
got there through two things
being really good politics and being in
the wheeling and dealing behind the
scenes
and by being able to have to jobs like
this
and number two by selling out to the
corporations amino you know the largest
cell
a save the leader of the republicans
well those days work for right
and so
he was going to try to bury
accidentally guess what worked actually
jordan said monday
even enter the race
and partly based on some as if they had
already running against our even when
she didn't know about these tapes over
meat being made behind ur back that
they're gonna ask mitch mcconnell about
that the press is
it is a is a spare to use them and the
whole thing though
i remember chair that was recalled to be
fair then use it
they consider using it enemy that they
had internally
that's also different part of the
equation
should you have at least consider that
internally
definitely to be honest with you but a
validation couple doesn't want to answer
that question that's what i hear this
virus back and forth where if you notice
he steadfastly refuses the answer
the question asked
and what is it appropriate for members
of your staff to talk about actually
cares
depression as a
well as you know last month my wife's
ethnicity was attacked by a a left-wing
group in kentucky
and then apparently they also
bug my headquarters
so i think that pretty well
sums up the way the political left is
operating in kentucky
in this transmission yet as i indicated
ob
last month they were attacking my wife
ethnicity
and apparently also unbeknownst to us at
the time they were bugging our
headquarters quite
anek sony and uh...
this is what you get
from the political left in america these
days patch
that finally did it last week they were
attacking my wife ethnicity
and apparently also bugging my
headquarters much like nixon and
watergate that's what the political left
dozens does ride
here's what you're prolly not gonna do
mister kyle office talking std
groups that
however you are determined
now did they actually by this
headquarters no
in fact his own staff look for a bug
going fine
but it's a really clever political
strategies say they bug why cousin
f_b_i_ gets involved and they'll figure
out if it was a
an actual staffer that works for
mcconnell or someone planted a bike
in the middle of that investigation
there are a lot of other josie is a
who's your source now you tell us who
your sources because it was a bug it's
illegal
and hence we got investigated
all that smart
has what it does those two things one
itgroup it tries to find out who
the guy
who's leaking this stuff in the
democrats and liberals as
inside your organization
they're very clever way and number two
ish if the conversation away from
what you're talking about a recession is
that appropriate
when it was an appropriate to possibly
bugger headquarters
now mother jones as we didn't put
bargain headquarters we don't know
anything about bugging
we have a source
or not to reveal that source
turns up in transform pretty clever men
and right now has to do it is gone
and he doesn't have those problems he's
casting himself as the victim here and
he's basically saying batter out
who's next
where i come at me
micah molter