was like $800 a semester.
And to me it was like, what a
waste of my fucking money.
So I dropped out and then I
started working as a sign
painter for Wegmans in upstate
New York, sort of gourmet
grocery store.
And they were looking
for someone to do
hand painted signs.
I had all these countless
amounts of like paint markers
and stuff at my disposal.
So I would just come in and then
I'd spend the rest of the
day drawing friends' tattoos
too at the time.
Like a lot of people were having
friends be like, oh Dan
draws, you know like
draw me that tree.
BERT KRAK: Well we've all
been friends with
Dan for a long time.
I kind of always knew that
eventually we would work
together because he has the same
ideas all of us as far as
what a tattoo should
look like.
He really enjoys painting
and creating new stuff.
We don't want to keep pulling
the same things out of the
same books.
But if we take those same
things and repaint them
ourselves, well then it kind
of does become a different
thing, it becomes our own.
I say this is how we keep
our skills sharp.
STEVE BOLTZ: You know the flash
at Smith Street, there's
certain shops, aesthetics,
obviously that
we're trying to emulate.
The whole idea of it being
crushed in flash is like-- and
that's a more old school
approach to a tattoo shop.
Well there was a shop in China
called Swallow Tattoo, there's
photos of this guy Swallow.
He was a Chinese tattooer
standing in the shop.
And I mean everything is covered
in flash, I mean like
the front of everything, little
spots, like this little
side of the fridge would have
designs all down it,
everything was covered
in flash.
I just think it's such
a good look.
I mean obviously you're
in a tattoo shop, it
should look like that.
You know what I mean?
I think that place is kind of
exactly what we want Smith
Street to look like.
So that anywhere you turn, you
see a tattoo design, and then
are still thinking
about tattoos.
Like tattoo heads get it, or
they understand this is hand
painted Flash, and that there is
sort of tattooing revival.
But like regular people who just
walk into the shop, like
I think to them it's sort
of run of the mill.
And actually we get reggies in
there sometimes and say that,
like this is all hand painted
by the four of us.
And they can't even wrap
their heads around it.
Like what do you mean,
like you painted it?
What do you mean
you painted it?
Like with a brush and paper,
they can't even fathom that.
DAN SANTORO: This whole wall
at this point is 100% us.
Like this set, which actually
turned out to be this entire
row, Eli had done
the first three.
He had done the parrots, the
eagles, and I think the owl.
So he did these little triptychs
of like three
different birds.
And then Steve kind of followed
his lead I think
first, if I'm not mistaken.
Right?
So then he did like these sets
of pin-ups, and then I
followed him, and then
Burt, and so on.
I did the roses, Burt did
the geishas, and Eli did
crosses, and so on.
And then eventually it was like,
oh we might as well just
do the whole row.
If you were actually here to see
how much we talk and argue
about where sheets going to
go, it's just stupid.
And then it will last like that
for a week until someone
does another sheet, and then
everybody sits on the couch,
stares at the wall and says,
All right what's going in
next, or where is this one
going, or whatever.
ELI QUINTERS: I don't know of
any other shops in New York
that do all their own stuff.
Aaron Coleman I know in Arizona,
that shop's all their
own hand-painted stuff.
And I think Black Heart has
recently done a bunch of flash
for their shop as well.
But I mean it's a pretty
rare thing really.
And it's kind of funny when you
think about it, you know
it's been so advantageous
for us to have it.
And it's been so fun to do it,
it's really worked out.
But not a lot of people do it.
It's one of those things.
Tattooing goes through those
stages, sort of coming out of
real big custom lonely stage.
Or it's getting back into people
who are realizing they
can pick something off the
wall and if somebody does
happen to have the same design
it doesn't necessarily mean
anything bad.
You now what I mean?
Like certain designs
are just classic.
STEVE BOLTZ: Oh I have to
have something custom.
You know if it's on the wall
then it's very common and
everybody has that.
I want something
that's unique.
But let's face it, the most
unique tattoos are always the
ones that suck the most.
The best tattoos are the ones
you've seen a million times.
There's strength in that
crawling panther
because you know it.
Whether you have tattoos or
ever been in a tattoo shop
that has power, I
think that it's
recognizeability, it's iconic.
I think it's up to the tattoo
artist to save the customer
from themselves.
In other words, like when I
first got into tattoos and I
knew nothing about them,
I thought the
ugliest shit was so cool.
People come in and they
want something bad.
It's kind of our job to say,
hey, you know what, like, we
can give you something better,
or every other teenage girl
comes in asking for that
tattoo, are you
sure you want that.
ELI QUINTERS: You have to sort
of educate or otherwise you
just come off like a dick.
You're just like, no, you got
to tell them why the design
won't work.
You've got to explain to
them what looks better.
A lot of the customer's hold on
to it and they think about
it, and they apply that
to their next tattoo.
BERT KRAK: I think we want for
our customers to stay focused
on what they see and hear.
I don't really think there's one
design in here that any of
us would be upset
with tattooing.
Well actually there's one design
that we all hate in the
shop, Dan loves it.
That band design.
STEVE BOLTZ: It can be a little
confusing and a little
bit overwhelming to a reggie to
come in there and see all
that flash.
And then a lot of it looking
very classic and then yes,
there's like a sheet painted
on cardboard.
There's sheets in there and
designs in there, that
obviously we think are amazing,
that are very foxy,
very simple, and clunky,
or whatever.
And Dan's sheets are good
examples of that.
He does some really
experimental--
he manages to stay very
traditional and very by the
book, but just completely off
the wall at the same time in
imagery that you might not
necessarily see on every
tattoo sheet.
ELI QUINTERS: And he gets a
little more creative with it,
their very unique, and very
clever, and very like well
thought out.
He's got one design,
the great mother.
It's like a crystal with a
little person inside of it,
and it's so weird,
I've never seen
anything like it anywhere.
But it's so smart, you know what
I mean, the way he used
color in it, the way some of the
color doesn't go all the
way up to the lines.
Dan's much more studied in
the folk arts then I am.
He really enjoys folk
art all across
the board, most cultures.
So I think he really knows how
to make tattoo flash look like
that, look like very genuine
like folk art.
STEVE BOLTZ: We all buy
obviously a lot of books and a
lot of tattoo related books.
And Dan definitely brings in
books that we don't expect,
that have great imagery in
them, that are not tattoo
related all.
And I think also it's
like he's sort of
searching those sources.
Obviously the recycled imagery
we love and is powerful.
But we're also always
constantly
looking for one new design.
DAN SANTORO: I'd really like
to talk about this.
This is a drawing from the
little Korean woman at the
local bodega.
She draws these things on the
sides of cigarette cartons.
I just think they're super cool,
like this little old
Korean woman that just peddles
cigarettes and like it's a
little piece of outsider art in
Carroll Gardens that a lot
of people don't even
pay attention to.
I actually wouldn't mind turning
that in to a sheet of
flash at some point.
BERT KRAK: Dan's process is more
I think where he won't
come to us with it.
He'll start it or finish it
and then present it to us.
I think it was last summer he
started doing these really
loose super kind of folk art
style paintings, that were
totally different for all of us,
none of us had ever really
tried to do anything
like that before.
And I think he really kind of
blew us all way with that.
Just from him doing that it kind
of like helped all of us
to do things a little
bit looser.
The paper wasn't even really
watercolor paper, it was just
some really weird junk that I
would have never even thought
to paint on it.
DAN SANTORO: I don't want to be
too cliche and say, like, I
realize that I didn't really
have to follow rules.
But yeah, once I painted on
cardboard I think everybody at
the shop was kind of like why
are you wasting your time.
Because this is something you
do when you're on the phone,
but you don't spend eight hours
on a painting of it.
So I did it and everybody was
like, wow that actually looks
really cool.
I'm also really influenced
by old game boards.
Really naively painted game
boards that were something
that people just would've
done at home.
This one is--
I love the birds, than I was
just thinking about Sweetheart
of the Rodeo.
So it just kind of has like a
lot of the themes that I think
go with real Americana
painting.
It's funny because tattooing
kind of desensitizes you to
anything other than painting
for the sake of painting.
You know what I mean?
So a lot of these things are
just all the things that give
me a certain feeling.
STEVE BOLTZ: How sick
are those things?
Really off the wall.
But so cool, right?
He doesn't really like let them
hang around or show you,
he does them and then
he takes them home.
They're awesome, they're
so different.
And I think that you could
probably see those somewhere
out of context and not even
think about tattoos, or that a
tattooer did them.