Literally... literally... taking
the grass from its own roots!
Now you've
got your Con-Dem-Nation.
Liberals noshing Tories
like altar boys picking dimps up!
Have we had a national
fucking stroke or what?
Is revolution a word
or was it never?
Anybody watching needs
to know, we cope
better than average with
irony in Chatsworth.
Well, for fuck's sake,
we live in Manchester
and they charge us for water!
I wandered lonely as a clown
Necking mushrooms rarely found
This green and pleasant
land in ancient times...
Yak, yak, yak, yak, yak!
It's not theirs any more.
This is our England now!
Pa-a-arty!
Sync and Corrections by APOLLO
www.addic7ed.com
'When I was little, me mam
used to say "If someone hurt you,
'"hurt 'em back."
'An eye for an eye.
'Tooth for a tooth.
'She said we'd be OK doing that,
'because wherever we went
in the world, whatever we did...
'there'd be an angel
watching over us.
'Well, I don't know
about anyone else's angel,
'but I've always thought mine
must be, like,
'a psycho knobhead one, getting
off on me doing the wrong thing.
'And I'll tell you this for nothing.
'It does my fucking head in.'
(WOMAN GROANS)
(WOMAN PANTS)
Spock! Ha-ha!
Have you seriously no shame, you?
Using pictures of your
babby to get into the
knickers of some
unsuspecting slappers?
Fuck off! I'm not trying to
get into anyone's knickers!
Unlike yous lot,
I'm not desperate and sad
and with bollocks like space
hoppers due to underuse.
Hey, I'm not desperate!
I fucking am. Got blisters, me.
I shagged your mam before
we come out, so I'm sorted.
You don't "shag" me mam.
You "make love" to her.
Stop talking!
What are you doing?
Why would you speak about that?
Tell me again why
we can't fucking kill him?
I think I'm in love.
Where?
Come on. Power in numbers.
So do you work or are you a student,
or what?
Cheeky bastard!
Do I look like a student?
You smell like one.
Going for a tom tit.
If you must know,
I'm a serial killer.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
I've murdered shit loads
o'people, haven't I, Jade?
Buried them beneath the patio.
Huge patio.
Skin them alive, making a suit
out of mi' victims' flesh.
Yeah I've heard of that.
It's kinky.
The suit's not for me.
It's for my dog. So we can go out,
like two mates, instead of me
and woman's best friend.
So, you like dogs?
Just Dalmatians.
Cruella deVille thing.
You are the weirdest person
I have ever met!
(LAUGHS) Well, I certainly
fucking hope so.
DANCE MUSIC
Put it away,
I've just had me dinner.
What did you have?
Move!
Don't say I never give you nothing.
Oh, God, sorry, that was work.
I've got to shoot. I'm on call.
Are you a doctor?
(LAUGHS)
D'you think they'd
let me loose with a
stethoscope and nowhere
decent to warm my hands?
I'm a warden
at some retirement flats.
Black Briar Court. D'you know it?
Old folks' home?
I've got to go back.
You can come if you like.
We could carry on the party there.
Yeah, I do like.
Give me two minutes.
Got a light, mate?
Got a spare cig an' all?
You got anywhere to go?
I don't care how wrecked she is.
As long as she can say "Oh, yes,
Chesney, thank you, Chesney."
Don't expect to lay eyes
on me until the morning.
I'm about to get fucking beastly
with a beautiful girl.
Yeah, where is she,
you fucking hound?
I can't see... She must...
No, not the spaz?!
Fuck off! Must have bolted.
Right, I better...
Argh!
Fuck!
D'you want a Viagra? Never go
anywhere without me little bits.
No rush, is there?
You're the boss.
Must be my guilty
Catholic conscience.
Just so you know,
I'm an aggressive power bottom.
But I will switch
for the right fella.
Outside.
Now.
Can't we just do it in the...
Hold on in there, mate.
Hold on in there.
You'll be all right.
Oh, shit!
FLATLINE TONE
(LAUGHS EVILLY)
Eww.
D'you always laugh like that?
It's really fucking annoying.
Go on... Die.
It'd be hilarious.
You can't say that, you're...
my guardian...
What have you got to go back to?
My life.
Is that what you'd call it?
Scared of your own shadow
before all this.
What you going to be like now?
I'm not scared.
Grab life with both hands,
did you? Eh?
The little sperm that could?
You've been an apology
for a life. An anti-life.
And I'm your anti-angel.
Say hello to your anti.
(LAUGHS)
Fuck off!
He's opened his eyes.
Thank Jesus, Joseph and Mary,
he's going to be all right.
Might be even better. A bang on
the head, new and improved version.
Who done this to you, Micky?
Who was it, lad?
Just let him get his bearings, Mimi.
- She's upset.
- We're all upset.
What happened mate? One minute you
were there, and the next you just...
Bit of a downer to be honest...
Shaping up to be
a cracking night as well.
I... I can't remember. I can't...
What's up with me?
Concussion. Bruised ribs.
You could be brain damaged.
Don't fucking say it,
I'm warning you!
He's my baby.
They left you for dead, kid.
What the fuck were you doing out
in the middle of nowhere, anyway?
I wish I could remember.
Really.
It's all a bit foggy.
When it does come back,
let us know. We'll take care of it.
I know what you're thinking.
You went to bed with Rihanna
and woke up with
a fat pig from Crumpsall.
I wasn't thinking...
You're not fat.
(LAUGHS) Fuck off, I'm just messing
wi' your head, pal.
I'm only in it for the sex,
and I bagged myself a blond. Score.
Shut the door on your way out, yeah?
I'm in Crumpsall?!
# You keep saying
You've got something for me... #
All right, gorgeous?
Step aside, boys.
Show us your tits
and we'll think about it.
Where you heading? Keep you company.
You think?
I know what I'd do to you.
Show her some respect, lads.
All right.
Let's do it right here, then.
Who's first?
# And that's just what they'll do
# One of these days these boots
Are gonna walk over you
# Start walking... #
Fuck.
There he is. Dirty stop-out.
Fuck off.
So who was it then?
That bird in the wheelie?
Yeah, right(!) I shag cripples,
that's what I'm in to.
Fuck! Patty...
I didn't mean anything by it.
Don't apologise to me.
I hate the moaning bastards.
Don't knock the raspberries.
Some of my best customers
are the paralytics.
How can you hate them,
when you're in that?
I wasn't born like this.
I had an accident,
it's different.
Tragedy befell me.
Anyway, it was a girl
in the taxi queue. Not Clem.
Ooo, Clem, is it?
Comes with her own WD-40.
Looked in the mirror lately?
You're no fucking
oil painting, mate.
It's not the fish. It's me.
- Say it!
- Fuck off.
- Admit it!
- I'll admit I shagged your sister.
- Makes two of us.
- Easy!
PHONE BEEPS
Filth.
(LAUGHS) Look at that!
I never text!
It's... pre-historic.
Nah. Need a clear head.
Got an essay to write later.
Yeah, you run along now, schoolie.
I don't give a shit, but if I don't
submit it then I get detention.
Detention? Who cares?
School's school, innit?
You get a detention,
you get a detention.
Shut up!
What are you at school for anyway?
Dunno.
Work hard so you can
spend your life tied to a desk?
Not me, man.
No. I'm a free spirit.
As soon as I'm 18,
I'm out of here.
Work the cruise ships,
see the world. Med, Caribbean.
# She's a burglar
# She broke in to my mind
# She took everything she could find
# She looked into my eyes
# In my front socket
# And just like that
My heart was gone
# She put it in her pocket. #
Mam, I can walk, will you back off?
I'm trying to help you.
You're hurting mi' ribs.
We're all here for you, Micky, love.
I want yous lot to spoil him rotten.
He's had a big shock.
Whatever he wants, we give to him.
That's not ticking, is it?
It smells of strawberries.
Somebody's been
using my washing machine.
Someone's been sat in our chairs.
Someone's been eating my porridge.
All right, breakfast,
it's just breakfast.
Here comes Goldilocks.
Hiya, lads.
Hi, Auntie Mimi.
Thanks for bringing
my case in, boys.
(ALL) Auntie?
Nice gaff.
Relative to what?
I'm sorry.
No sweat.
Seriously, I was out of line.
D'you think you're the first dick
I've met? I'm a big girl.
Fair enough. I deserved that.
You didn't exactly
declare your hand, though, did you?
What?
It never occurred to you
that the chair might come
as a bit of a surprise?
Yeah, that's what I do...
I lure men in with
my able-bodied ruse,
so's they can humiliate
themselves.
That's a good night out for me that.
How I like to spend my time.
I'm not fooled, you know.
You like me.
Right, I'm off.
Nice to see you again, Ruby.
You're looking... all grown up.
Eyes to the front,
roll your tongues back in, lads.
Take care of your brother.
I am really sorry.
That's OK.
God gave you your talents,
and you use them to your advantage.
Just don't take the piss.
I really did need
to use the machine.
My stuff was manky
when I came through the window.
That's what I mean
about taking advantage.
Break into my house again,
I'll have your tits for ash trays.
Understood.
How's your mum, then?
She still hates you.
No change there, then.
Yeah, but why's it illegal?
Fair enough nobody wants
babies with eight fingers
on each hand, but fuck
it if you wear a condom.
She's your first cousin.
We've only got her word for that!
Not seen her in ten years.
You should get a DNA test done.
I mean... it's hard to believe
she's the same species as you lot,
let alone family.
Get to fuck.
OK. A blow job from a cousin.
Now, that has got to be legal.
How they going to test for that?
She ain't my cousin.
But I'm your step-son.
Dad... please, do not shag my cousin.
I'm not scared of you, right?
So why don't you just fuck off?!
Who you talking to?
No-one. I'm just doing
mi' exercises, for my lungs.
Have you gone fucking mental?
There's still lots of places
never been mapped, you know.
Indonesia, Papua New Guinea,
and stuff. Thousands of islands.
Don't you need degrees
for that though?
This is all I need.
Pieces of paper
and diplomas make no difference.
What's she called?
- Who?
- Bird you're looking at.
Who gives a shit about her name?
He only reads it for the articles.
What is it? What's her name?
Read it yourself if it matters
that much to you!
Do I look like a fucking slave?!
Do I?!
No.
Was it a gay thing?
I can say it louder if you like?
It's my own fault.
It was me what went there.
Painted a target
on your head, did you?
I'd help out, but...
I fuck strangers
in alleyways and cars. This...
It's an occupational hazard.
I've fucked strangers
in alleyways and cars.
Never had my head
caved in for my trouble.
It's different.
It shouldn't be.
You can't let this rattle you.
No... clearly.
Need to get out, let no cunt
intimidate you. Be a man.
I am a man.
Well, do it, then.
Oh!
I'm sorry, mate.
Sorry.
Fucking virgin!
He still says it's amnesia.
Ambulance picked him up in Gorton.
- So?
- So who runs Gorton?
Felix Dennehy.
If Felix went for him,
he wouldn't have left the job
half done, would he?
We have to hit somebody.
We can't be seen to do nothing.
Besides... the Dennehys have been
getting a bit previous.
How hard?
Think I might need to
tape it down, lads.
How hard do we hit Big Felix?
Random door in Gorton.
Not important.
All right, Ruby?
Billy.
Uncle Billy.
Step-uncle, if you like.
You going running?
I'm quite fit myself.
That's a fair assessment.
- You know me and Mimi?
- Yeah.
We're quite relaxed about stuff?
Oh.
Well, I will bear that in mind.
Don't shit on your own doorstep,
Billy.
(HE MOUTHS)
Enjoy your detention?
No.
Next time, hand in your homework.
Can I ask you a question, Miss?
Mmm-hmm.
I've got a mate who... can't read.
An adult, well, I mean... older boy.
There are evening classes,
day classes at college too.
He's not really a joiner.
I think he's embarrassed about it.
You're not remotely as dumb as you
try to get away with, are you?
He wants to travel. Work on ships.
Your friend needs to get over
the embarrassment and deal with it,
or his life chances will be limited.
You need qualifications.
Your mate. Frasier Kane.
That boy has more than
just literacy problems, Croker.
Why won't you give anybody a chance?
He's the smartest guy I know.
I seriously doubt that.
Thanks for the advice.
Heaton.
She always were a frustrated cow.
Hated me.
All right, sexy?
# You've got to tease your man... #
WOLF WHISTLE
# You've got to please your man... #
Is that her? Clever Girl.
And the rest. That one'll
never starve, I tell you.
Think she could conquer
the world, that one.
Didn't you at that age?
I was practising blow jobs
on bananas.
I thought it was the best way
to a man's heart.
She's had it hard, the kid.
When our Kenny died
and her ma brought her back
from Australia to Glasgow,
didn't tell a fucking soul.
Cut her off from the family.
Is she Scots then?
Only by misfortune.
Scouse by paternal line.
And what brings her here?
I've asked her half a dozen times,
still haven't got a clue.
Got a light, mate?
Outside.
Now.
You can't let this rattle you.
Can I take that?
You can get a cab closer.
It's got to be this one.
Just for argument's sake, say
you did shag a bird in a wheelie.
In a wheelchair.
Wouldn't it hurt?
Maybe... if you let the brakes off.
Nah, not me, her. I mean,
I'd be scared of breaking something.
Hurting her.
She wouldn't be able
to feel nothing.
Oh, that's a misconception.
In fact, for some of us,
sensation is heightened.
Considerably heightened.
Clem?
Clementine!
Clem!
There's two Rs in sorry.
I'm not a complete idiot.
Weren't enough bricks.
I am. Really.
Wait there.
You robbed those
from someone's garden.
Liberated is the word
you're looking for.
Look, you're forgiven, all right?
Go on about your business
with a clear conscience.
You're not a dick,
just another regular lad.
If I let stuff like that bother me,
I'd really be up shit creek,
wouldn't I?
I don't want to be just another lad.
I want to be your lad.
No means no, Carl.
Am I a man?
Yep. My turn. Am I in a band?
No.
Wayne Rooney.
No way, fuck off!
How did you just guess that?
Because you're a bloke
and I thought like a bloke.
I'm sitting here
with these largely on display,
so I'll assume you're not
thinking about other women.
Which leaves music and football
and you said he wasn't in a band.
Yeah, but... it's still a leap.
You're a Blue, right?
Except you think you're sneaky, so you
tried to double-bluff me and pick a Red.
But if you're going to pick a Red,
you'll pick an ugly one,
cos you hate them that much.
You are good.
And significantly better off
than when I came in.
Thanks.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
You can't use made-up names.
Yeah.
Hiya.
Hey.
Behave yourself.
If you could just retrieve my car
and deliver it to my home...
RUNNING FOOTSTEPS
It's her, intit?
Miss Heaton, detention queen.
Get out of my way.
We're not in school now.
Excuse me.
I don't think so.
You never liked me.
You weren't a very likable boy.
I see not much has changed.
Watch your mouth. You can't hide
behind your desk now, you bitch.
You're not...
You're not a stupid boy.
There are programmes
where you can learn to read.
You can't read?
I'm not a stupid boy! I'm not a boy!
Would you like to see?
Shh!
Stop it.
Let's see how smart you are
with a real man up you.
Get off me!
Frasier!
Boys, help me, please!
Frasier.
Shut the fuck up!
I'll deal with you later.
(SCREAMS)
Shut up! Shut up!
Shh! Shh!
MOBILE PHONE BUTTON TONES
PHONE RINGING
'Black Panther Cabs?'
Yeah. I need a taxi.
'Where's it picking up from,
please?'
Just outside your office.
'All our drivers here
are on their breaks.'
What about the guy
in the black Vectra outside?
'He's not available.'
Right, no worries.
I'll just call another company.
'He'll be right out.'
Where to?
Rusholme.
Lot of rubbish on these streets.
I don't mind the blacks.
They've settled down.
It's the Pakis
I've got a problem with.
Our streets,
our neighbourhoods,
infiltrating us.
Then what?
Semtex in their rucksacks.
That's what this pays for, you know.
Fucking Council Tax.
It all goes on them. Furnished
flats, kitchens, legal appeals.
And don't get me started
on the crack-heads, the whores.
The diseased.
Queers.
Go on then. Do it.
Do it, you cowardly piece of shit.
And if you can't do him,
do yourself.
What's the matter with you?
Stop it!
A lot of rubbish needing swept away,
don't you think?
CRESCENDO OF CAR HORNS
Do it.
Stop here! Please.
You all right?
(YELPS)
(LAUGHS)
A horse enters a pub
and the barman goes,
"What the fuck's wrong with you?"
Mind your own fucking business.
Whoa...
I think you'll find
I was here first.
You invaded my drinking area.
Fundamental principle,
around this stool, right,
this is my personal drinking space.
You've got the rest of the known
universe to be fucking grumpy.
I'm sorry.
I've had a rough couple of days,
you know...
Yes, well...
Well, a problem shared.
I think God's got it in for me.
I can't do right for doing wrong.
How confused are you?
There is no right, there's no wrong.
There is no God. Sorted.
Any gratuities gratefully received.
Maybe.
Know no right, no wrong.
But I'm the one carrying the scars,
aren't I?
It's not accidental, is it?
Was it the good Lord herself who
swung a tire iron at your bonce?
I think not.
You see, I have read
her instruction manual
and one of the very few pearls it
offers us is an eye for an eye.
Fuck all that touchy-feely
New Testament shit,
fucking lentil eater's manifesto.
Someone smites you,
you smite them right back.
What's that going to solve?
Well, if you're standing
up for your people, a lot.
Standing up for my people.
# GEORGE MICHAEL:
FAITH
# Well, I guess it would be nice... #
My people bring artistic pleasure
to millions.
Them the choirs?
Oh, yes.
Can't you tell?
# ..before I give my heart away
# And I know all the games you play,
because I play them too
# Cos I gotta have faith,
# I gotta have faith
# Because I've got to have faith
# I've got to have faith, faith,
faith... #
Where the fuck have you been?
Have you got something to say to me?
No.
Well, get with the programme then,
champ.
I'm not going to
be around for a while.
DISTANT POLICE SIREN
Where are you going?
Let him go.
Aidan, you'd better not talk
to anybody.
If you've got it,
flaunt it, fair enough.
But be responsible with it.
I am responsible.
I was young once myself, you know.
Men might button up the back,
but I don't.
Why are you here, kid?
And no bullshit.
My ma threw me out.
If I call her, she'll confirm that?
I thought you couldn't stand her.
I hope she dies a long, slow
death. I'll still call her though.
I'll get my stuff.
Don't be stupid.
You can stay as long as you like.
I owe that to your dad at least,
God rest his soul.
Your business is your business.
And I won't ask again.
Don't seduce all the lads
at one time though, eh?
(LAUGHS)
# Come on, baby... #
Look at this shit!
# You're going to like it
once you get a taste
# I got a feeling in my heart
# Something good is about to start.
# That's a hot dog, hot dog
# Watch me eat a hot dog
# Hot dog, hot dog
# Come on, let's do the hot dog. #
# E-A-T H-O-T D-O-G, Hot dog. #
What is it you want from me, Carl?
I don't know.
You're stalking a girl...
dressed like a dog,
and you don't know what you want?
Not exactly a man with a plan,
are you?
I want to be with you.
After one conversation in a club?
They say it can
happen at first sight.
Shall I tell you what I think?
I want to strap you on to me
and fuck you till my eyes water.
Take the costume off first?
# FLORENCE AND THE MACHINE
Dog Days
# Happiness... hit her
# Like a train on a tra-a-ack
# Coming towards her
# Stuck still no turning ba-ck
# She hid around corners
# And she hid under beds
# She killed it with kisses
# And from it she fled
# The dog days are over
# The dog days are done
# The horses are comin'
# So you better run
# Run fast for your mother
run fast for your father
# Run for your children
for your sisters and brothers
# Leave all your love
and your longing behind
# You can't carry it with you
if you want to survive
# The dog days are over
# The dog days are done
# Can you hear the horses
# Cos here they come
# Happiness
Hit her
# Like a bullet in the ba-a-ck
# Struck from a great height
# By someone who should have known
better than that
# The dog days are over
# The dog days are done
# Can you hear the horses
# Cos here they come... #
Whoa! What the fuck are you doing?
Give me one good reason why
I shouldn't slice your head off
and kick it down the street.
How did you find me?
I was in your cab.
A lot of rubbish needs swept away.
I thought I recognised you.
No wonder my arse tightened.
Maybe I should just chop that off.
I bet it's shrivelled up
like a walnut whip now, ain't it?
- Show me.
- Fuck off.
Get it out.
You bring your filth in here!
Do it!
On your knees, bitch.
It's not nice, is it?
Everything you know stripped away.
All coming to get you, are we?
Blacks, Pakis, queers!
Anyone who's not you, is that it?
What's your little baby going to
think of that when it arrives?
Don't you talk about my baby.
I really hope you do get a boy.
And I hope it's a faggot.
That way you'll have a lot of cocks
to worry about, not just one.
Please.
Looks like you picked on
the wrong guy.
(FRANK) 'You can go through life
being a cliche,
'doing everything
that's expected of you,
'nose to the grindstone,
live to work, work to live,
'but fuck that, break away
and dance to a different beat.
'Ring the changes and just...
'Live.
'Learn to stand proud,
head held high.
'Fuck your detractors,
what do they know?'
Got a light, mate?
'There's no angels, good or bad.'
Got a spare cig an' all?
'There's only you.
'So be proud and fuck the rest.
'That should be enough.'
So why ain't they been yet,
the police?
He knows who we are.
Did you like it?
I thought you wear a wanted man
this side of Manchester.
Maybe he's just checking up.
He doesn't make social calls.
He's a dangerous man.
I don't appreciate a veto on
who I can serve.
You don't have to do this.
What choice is there? How bad do you
want it? I want him dead.
Still got it in you?
I don't care what happens,
I'll be your witness.
It's not normal weed. What is it?
Some herbal shit.
I think I can solve
something over here.
Sync and Corrections by APOLLO
www.addic7ed.com
OK, empty your pockets.
Oh...
They... must be mine.