I pictured guitar solos and
moshing, not waving around a
buzzing wand.
I'm a big fan of the rock and
roll lifestyle, and loud angry
music in general.
But my problem was I didn't
know how to play an
instrument.
So like a lot of ultra amateur
musicians, I turned to the
avant garde electronica scene
and called Wadih, my friend
from art school, and asked if I
could join his experimental
band, US TM.
He said yes, and that's how
I became a wandist.
My name is Harry, and
I've been a loser
for most of my life.
I thought I was done with my
awkward phase when Vice hired
me to write about politics,
culture, and other important
world affairs, which should
make me cool.
But it doesn't.
I'm still just a weird kid
who creeps people out.
This is All Around Losing
with Harry Cheadle.
[INAUDIBLE]
invited me to his studio to
practice with the other
members of his band, Brian and
Genevieve before we performed.
[RINGING]
Hey, it's Harry.
I'm here to be in the band.
[BUZZER]
It smells a lot like
marijuana.
I don't know how
to get in here.
BRIAN CARROLL: Who is it?
HARRY CHEADLE: Hey,
it's Harry.
It's Harry.
When I got inside, there was
an art school style dance
party going on that
was really sexy.
I remember this kind of party
from back in college.
I dusted off my old
dance moves--
namely the dance move where I
feel really uncomfortable in
my body and stand around hoping
that nobody notices me,
or what I'm doing.
Finally it was time to
play with the band.
So I walked back
to the studio.
Before we began, Genevieve had
to smear some junk on me.
It was spiritual.
What is this you're putting
on my face?
GENEVIEVE BELLEVEAU: This is
going to to help open up
everything from your yoni
up to your [INAUDIBLE]
chakra here.
It looks really good on you.
HARRY CHEADLE: Thank you.
I can't see it.
GENEVIEVE BELLEVEAU: Today
we're going to
teach you the wand.
So just think of that like a
masculine creative force.
[INAUDIBLE]
You can also play
with stopping.
HARRY CHEADLE: Oh.
It's nice you get
a breeze, too.
It's a great way to cool off.
GENEVIEVE BELLEVEAU:
It is nice.
HARRY CHEADLE: And
an instrument.
Since they're musicians, Wadih
and his crew can be as weird
as they want.
They can dress like David
Bowie dancers.
They can glue symbolic stickers
onto your face.
They can even spray you
with rose water
containing moth poop.
So when they hand you a buzzing
child's toy and tell
you to dance with it, you
dance with it, no
matter who's watching.
US TM turned out to be
really popular band.
I felt like I was cooler and
more important than the people
watching me, which I think
is what being in a band
is really all about.
[INAUDIBLE]
fit in with the band.
I want to have the look.
I was wondering if you could
take me shopping.
GENEVIEVE BELLEVEAU: The whole
look that we're working on
right now is retard
Renaissance.
HARRY CHEADLE: Maybe we could
go to a thrift store and you
could make me into a
Renaissance retard?
GENEVIEVE BELLEVEAU: Yes,
I would love to do that.
HARRY CHEADLE: So you're going
to make me look as beautiful
as you guys?
GENEVIEVE BELLEVEAU: Yeah.
We can help you.
We just want you to
find your inner--
HARRY CHEADLE: Retard?
GENEVIEVE BELLEVEAU: By retard
we mean your inner child, your
creative unabashed creativity.
HARRY CHEADLE: I want to
look like I get laid.
GENEVIEVE BELLEVEAU: Let's
think chain mail.
Let's think--
HARRY CHEADLE: Like
that thing?
WADIH SADER: Are these
worn by man?
GENEVIEVE BELLEVEAU:
I don't know.
Cool.
HARRY CHEADLE: I feel like I
looks like a cafeteria worker
with this cap.
GENEVIEVE BELLEVEAU: Yeah,
it's a little lunch lady.
HARRY CHEADLE: Like a lunch
lady for a DD and SM club.
So thanks for all
your help guys.
I think I got it sorted out.
GENEVIEVE BELLEVEAU:
I'm excited to
see what you choose.
It's going to be a
transformation.
[PURRING]
HARRY CHEADLE: Would I be able
to pull off the retard
Renaissance look?
Was I weird enough to be
in a band like this?
Probably not.
But I was going to give it a
shot later that night at a
poetry reading slash performance
art thing that
young people with the
beards and the
jewelery like to go to.
We just drank a pint of whisky
in the loading dock.
So that's pretty
rock and roll.
I got one more thing to
wear, and I'm going to
join them in there.
Was this all an elaborate
practical joke?
Why did I have to put all
the stuff in my mouth?
GENEVIEVE BELLEVEAU: And roll
your eyes up to the ceiling.
HARRY CHEADLE: Whisky
chain mail or not, I
wasn't feeling confident.
Part of the wand had broken, and
I wasn't sure it actually
made noise.
The audience seemed to be taking
this really seriously.
Or maybe they were
in on the joke.
So I tried to keep a straight
face while waving the wand.
At this point, when Genevieve
started sort of writhing on
the floor in her sparkly
see-through outfit, and I ran
the wand over her, it felt like
a combination of a little
kid playing doctor, and
performance art.
But sexier.
[APPLAUSE]
HARRY CHEADLE: And
then it was over.
It wasn't exactly a
Springsteen show.
But no-one was laughing
or making fun of us.
So I guess it went
pretty well.
I learned a lot from
performing.
That you don't actually
need to play an
instrument to be in a band.
That should've been obvious.
You just need to wave
something in
front of your face.
It doesn't really matter what
you're doing as long
as you're on stage.
That's the most important
thing, just be on stage.
And also dress weird.
Dress in chain mail.
TATIANA: I thought that
was really cool.
It was also really sexy.
HARRY CHEADLE: Oh, yeah?
What part was the sexiest
part of it.
TATIANA: Just like
the undulating
base and the wah-wah.
HARRY CHEADLE: No one had
ever called me sexy
or undulating before.
So that was a big step.
Who needs years of practice or
training in an instrument?
It turns out all you need to be
successful as a musician is
a sparkly wand.
I felt really empowered
afterwards, and part of a
scene, just like Yoko Ono.
I was finally a cool band music
playing guy, just like I
always wanted.
So, I told them, keep
your chain mail on.
That's a stupid tagline.
All right, Jesus.