You have to set boundaries.
FAT JEW: The thing is, I do have
to say, I have to blame
you for my small penis.
That's your fault.
SOL: No, that's your mother's
side of the family.
Yes, it is.
FAT JEW: I've seen--
I mean, not to make it weird,
but I've seen your penis.
SOL: Yeah.
FAT JEW: I guess it's probably
been about 10 years, but I saw
your penis about 10 years ago.
SOL: It was cold.
It was the middle of winter.
FAT JEW: You were
in the house.
The heat was on.
And your penis just looked like
a chestnut, like a fat,
little chestnut.
SOL: All right, son.
FAT JEW: That's your fault.
Not to be like, it's
my dad's fault!
But you gave me a small dick.
SOL: OK.
FAT JEW: No?
SOL: No.
I still think you probably--
you know, you did have that
nearsighted problem.
FAT JEW: So now it's
my vision.
SOL: Yeah.
FAT JEW: All right, if you want
to be a jerk about it,
not only your dick was fat like
a chestnut, it was kind
of mangled.
It was not--
you don't have a good-looking
dick.
SOL: Once again--
FAT JEW: You're a nice-looking
guy.
I'm not saying you're not
a nice-looking guy.
I'm saying you don't have
a nice-looking dick.
SOL: OK, but, you know, I hate
to lay this at your mother's
doorstep once again--
FAT JEW: Right.
SOL: --but--
FAT JEW: Don't lay anything
involving my penis at my
mother's doorstep.
That's just--
that's weird.
SOL: Oh, well.
FAT JEW: That's weird.
SOL: Well, most parents would
probably be embarrassed to
even sit here and talk
to you about it.
FAT JEW: Yeah, but you're
kind of an open dude.
SOL: Well, sure.
FAT JEW: You're an open guy.