hopefully these are smart,
clever, responsible pranks.
I think you're going to enjoy
them, especially the thing
with the Starbucks cup.
So I want you to watch the
entire video, and if you want
to do any of these, then post
them as response videos.
Because we'd like to feature
some of your videos here on
the channel, and we'll
send some prizes.
Do we have money
for surprises?
All right.
Yeah, we'll send some prizes.
We'll pick a couple of them.
Why not?
Happy April Fools!
Don't get in trouble.
Here's the deal.
If you can turn lunch into a
science department, that's a
good thing.
Because you don't have to be
in a stuffy laboratory or
anything like that.
This is Sarah.
She has been nice enough to hang
with me today, because
we're going to get ready
for April Fools.
And not you could have to just
do pranks on April Fools.
This is just a reminder that
it's a good time to do pranks.
And you could do some pretty
clever pranks.
That said, this is the part of
the program where I say don't
try this at home.
This is all stuff you can try at
home, I'm just going to ask
you to be responsible.
Because I'm going to show you
how to do some things--
you just have to be in control
of it, so neither
of us get in trouble.
Fair enough?
All right.
Let me dig back a little bit.
Do you remember a
couple episodes
back, we used a polymer.
So I'm going to show you the
behind-the-scenes first, and
then we're going
to prepare it.
And we'll go play the prank
on somebody else.
SARAH: All right.
STEVE SPANGLER: Fair enough?
So a couple episodes back,
we used a diaper.
So we just took a baby
diaper, cut it open,
and dumped it out.
And we got this super absorbent
polymer out of the diaper.
If you buy it from a science
company, it looks like this,
or a jar of a material
called water gel--
actual chemical name is
sodium polyacrylate.
It's just a super absorbent
polymer.
So if you haven't seen it
before, so it's not a complete
surprise to you, watch this.
I'm just going to take some of
the powder and put some of the
polymer in the cup like this.
All right?
It looks a lot like Sweet'N
Low or NutraSweet.
I mean, there's a lot of Sweet'N
Low or NutraSweet, but
again, that's kind of
what it looks like.
OK, now here, you go ahead
and pour the water in.
Ready?
Pour the water in, quickly.
Keep going.
That's it, and now turn the
whole thing upside down.
Isn't that awesome?
SARAH: It's cool.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK.
So, this is the super absorbent
material, and
there's lots of things to be
able to do with the polymer.
But people don't expect
that to happen.
And because it looks like
Splenda, or NutraSweet, or
Sweet'N Low the thought is what
if we took these packets
here, actually dumped the
contents out that you would
normally eat, put the polymer
back inside--
I'll show you how
to seal it up.
Now this is pretty good, because
then somebody has no
suspicion whatsoever.
And I actually have made
some here, so here,
take a look at this.
These are my prepared packets
that I did already.
So I just gotta hide
these, right?
So look at this.
I don't want to mix
the two up.
You really cannot tell that
they've been prepared, and
they have the polymer
that's inside.
If you look very closely, you
can see some of the tape marks
and so forth.
These have not been prepared,
these have been prepared.
And it looks really,
really good.
Right?
All right, so here's
everything that
you're going to need.
I just went and got some of the
Splenda packets and some
of these Sweet'N Low-- it's
perfect, all right?
And so here's what
I'm going to do.
You do yours, Sarah,
like this.
What you do is you're
just going to shake
it down like this.
So you want to shake the actual
Sweet'N Low down all
the way to the bottom
like this.
And then, this one here
has this line that's
perfectly cut on it.
See that little line that goes
across here like that?
SARAH: Yeah.
STEVE SPANGLER: All right, so
now I'm just going to take the
X-acto Knife for that little
sharp piece there, and I'm
just going to cut into
it like this.
And because I put the polymer
down there like that, it's
going to be easy for
me to take it out.
OK?
Try yours.
SARAH: All right.
STEVE SPANGLER: And see
what it looks like.
Good?
SARAH: All right.
STEVE SPANGLER: All right.
So now, just in an empty cup,
just got to dump this out.
So this is the actual
sweetener-- right, the
artificial sweetener.
So dump that out.
Good.
And now we have a packet that's
perfect, right there.
So now this is going to be
perfect for us to dump the
polymer back into.
All right?
Now let's fill this one up.
OK, ready?
Here's yours.
Good.
And so this goes in.
This is perfect.
Now we just have to seal
this back up again.
And I'll just get a piece of
tape like this, pull it off,
and put it across there.
And it's that Scotch Tape
that kind of disappears.
SARAH: Oh wow.
STEVE SPANGLER: And couldn't
see it on the other ones.
SARAH: No I couldn't.
STEVE SPANGLER: Right?
On all of them that
I set out there.
Now these are the gimmick
packets that are over there.
Let me clean this off.
So that's the gimmick packet,
and these are the regular
packets here.
So when I do this to somebody,
I could it just mix these in,
and I would suggest that
you don't put it
in the sugar container.
Because if you put it in
the sugar container,
you're going to forget.
Then you're going to waste
everything and you're going to
think, well that's funny.
But if it's not in your control,
it's not a funny
prank, all right?
You gotta take--
So let me show you.
Here's the move.
Just hold it in your
fingers, like this,
like a magician would.
Just kind of clip it in your
fingers like this.
SARAH: OK.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK?
And just kind of curl your
fingers around--
yeah, like this.
Now turn your hand over.
Nobody really cares.
See, look at you.
See how you're trying
to cover it?
No, you don't have to do that,
because if I really had my
hands here, it'd be like this.
Or if I was holding my drink--
so, here hold your drink.
Nobody even suspects it.
So if you want to show somebody,
you go like this.
You go, oh, here look
at this you.
And you just pick up a bunch
of them, and drop it on the
very top, like that.
Drop it on the top,
and then grab it.
Yeah, that's it.
Nobody really cares.
You're just picking up one,
and you just reach
in and pick it up.
See?
SARAH: Very cool.
STEVE SPANGLER: Now, you're in
control of it the whole time,
and we don't get in trouble.
All right?
So now shake it down
like this.
Oh this is the best part.
OK, so now here, try it.
You just don't want
to do too much.
And tear it open.
SARAH: All right.
STEVE SPANGLER: Good.
And you do it to the waiter.
So when the waiter comes over,
say I think there's really a
problem with the sweetener.
Here watch.
Tear it open in front of
them, and dump it in.
Good job.
Put that off to the side.
Yeah, and now you want to be
careful to get rid of that
here in a second.
So once they're playing with
this, and it's all gelled,
you're going to get rid of that,
because they're going to
want to go back to the packet.
Or you could push
it on the floor.
That's perfect.
All right?
So now, when you pour it in,
you gotta pour it kind of
fast, ready?
Because you don't want
it to all solidify
there on the bottom.
I love the fact that in pure
water, it absorbs about
500-800 times it's weight in
water, but this-- it's a
little bit longer.
SARAH: I love it.
STEVE SPANGLER: This is good.
All right, but just be
responsible about the whole
thing, and it'll
be just great.
Because there's nothing better
than to shake it down, and
stir your spoon, and it stands
straight up in the tea.
Like look at that.
That's awesome.
Why isn't that great as a
great practical joke.
SARAH: Oh my gosh.
STEVE SPANGLER: But we have
people at the office, as you
know, that don't use
the packets.
What do they use
in the morning?
SARAH: They use the
big can-- the jar.
STEVE SPANGLER: Yeah, so our job
is going to be to go back
and to substitute--
even though they work with us,
and they work with us all the
time, they package
it and so forth--
they'll never guess.
So we'll go dump it in, then
we'll take some of the GoPro
cameras and we'll hide them.
And let's just watch in the
morning what happens
when they do their--
and they'll never suspect it.
SARAH: It's going to be great.
STEVE SPANGLER: It's
going to be great.
All right, so there's a couple
things that you need for this
next prank.
You're going to need a super
strong magnet-- a neodymium
magnet and you're going to
need a ball bearing.
And we're at a hardware store,
kind of an obscure little
hardware store, this
will be perfect.
OK?
So you're looking for not
just an ordinary magnet.
This is a neodymium magnet.
It's a super, super strong
rare earth magnet.
Super strong--
I mean it's really, really,
really strong.
Neodymium is a permanent
earth magnet.
Isn't that great?
So we're going to need
that magnet.
All right?
So buy one.
Don't just take it out
of the package.
You bought it.
SARAH: OK.
STEVE SPANGLER: Now we
need a ball bearing.
When you're in these obscure,
tiny, little hardware stores,
you can usually find anything.
That seems to be--
that's probably perfect
size, OK?
That's a ball bearing.
Now why you need a
ball bearing--
the normal person needs
a ball bearing--
I have no idea, but that's the
ball bearing we need, OK?
So now we're set up
for our joke.
We have our neodymium magnet,
and we have our ball bearing.
The last thing that we need is
a can of paint, all right?
So not all cans of paint are the
same, so let me show you.
All right, so we have everything
we need-- the
neodymium magnet, we've got the
ball bearing, and now we
need to have a can of paint.
Now, a long time ago, they made
cans of paint that had
metal ball bearings inside--
that classic sound
that you here.
A lot of them now are marbles,
so it's ceramic.
So you would hope for them--
so you might have to
play into your own.
OK?
So here's what I
want you to do.
I want you to hold the magnet
in this hand, like this.
Got it?
You're going to hold
the ball bearing in
this hand, like this.
And just--
nobody will care, OK?
Because we've got a can
of paint in our hand.
So hopefully, the guy
is going to find you
that's in the aisle.
So when you're walking the
aisle, you want to make sure
you're just making some noise.
Somebody will inevitably come
over and say, may I help you?
All right?
So that's where you pick it up.
Ready?
So you're going like this--
shake.
And as you shake it like this,
if you put his hand on there,
the ball bearing will stick.
Ready?
So shake like this,
see how it sticks?
As soon as they hear that stick,
this hand comes up at
the same time.
So it looks like this.
Oopsie.
Isn't that great?
And so that little dink dink
is great, because now when
they look back up at ya,
you're doing this.
And as long as your hand
is covering the
magnet, it's great.
Isn't that perfect?
And now you reach down, and
you pick it up like this.
You say lucky for you,
I can put it back.
All I'm doing is just smashing
it like this, and pulling this
off at the same time.
So I'm just doing this-- like
this-- and then shaking.
And now you know the paint
trick, all right?
There's a lot of uses for
neodymium magnets, but this is
probably the best one if you
have nothing to do on a
Saturday afternoon and you want
to go to hardware store.
It's just hours of fun at
the hardware store.
Let's go see if it works.
SARAH: OK.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK.
So here's what's great.
It's just right around the
corner, so Sarah and I are
just going to stand there and
ask questions about paint, OK?
SARAH: OK.
[PAINT CAN SHAKING]
STEVE SPANGLER: Oopsie.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
STEVE SPANGLER: Is that
supposed to come out?
MALE SPEAKER STORE CLERK:
It's not supposed to.
[PAINT CAN SHAKING]
STEVE SPANGLER: All right, so
here's another prank you can
do since you already have the
neodymium magnet, try this.
So what did I ask
you to just do?
We pulled up, what did
you have to do?
SARAH: I got you an empty
cup and a lid.
STEVE SPANGLER: So she walks
into Starbucks, and she just
asked may I please have
an empty cup?
And did they ask you
why or anything?
SARAH: Not at all.
No.
STEVE SPANGLER: See?
So it's easy for you
to do, all right?
So now, here's what do.
You take the neodymium
magnet, and you it in
the cup like this.
See how it's here in the cup?
And then--
so see, it just rests in
the bottom, no liquid--
and now you just put
this on top.
So it really looks like
a real drink.
OK?
Because that neodymium magnet
is so strong, watch this.
Look at this.
It just sits there.
Here, it'll go like this.
Here, watch, on the
side of my car.
See, it'll just stay there.
But you don't want to do that,
because nobody would believe
you, all right?
But it's super strong.
There could be a hurricane, and
that cup's not coming off.
So now watch.
So you just set this up here,
like this, and now
here's the best part.
You just drive around, and
wait for the response.
If there's a precious cup of
gold there, they will bump
lights to get to you,
and then watch.
When you're sitting there, you
just have to look over at the
people next to you, and watch.
They'll kind of point up and
everything, and then we have
to mess around with like, we're
calling the police, or
maybe you're drinking, or that
kind of thing, all right?
So let's just drive around
and see how much
attention we attract.
This is what you can do if
you have a little science
knowledge, and you have
no life whatsoever.
That's me.
Not you, that's me.
Here we go.
OK we're in.
So here's the best thing is
that you have no idea-- oy
watch this.
So see how somebody's parking
right next to us?
So see if that attracts
any attention.
Not at all.
Let's see if there's any
concerned citizens as
we go by this way.
[INAUDIBLE].
What?
Nope, I'm good.
I think I'm good.
I have my coffee, right here.
I'm what?
Oh shoot.
Oh my gosh, I'm sorry
about that.
Thank you.
You left it there.
What?
No, I got mine here.
Oh God, sorry.
Man, thank you so much.
Thank you so much.
I appreciate that.
Wow.
Sorry about that.
Thank you.
So this is what you expect, for
them to just kind of look
over, so you know that they're
going to catch it.
I don't think so.
Do I really?
Oh shoot.
Thank you.
Sorry, hard to believe.
Such an idiot.
People really are nice.
FEMALE VOICE: You have a
coffee on your roof!
STEVE SPANGLER: Oh,
it's really hot.
FEMALE VOICE: There's
coffee up there.
STEVE SPANGLER: I
know, it's hot.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
STEVE SPANGLER: And it's
so identifiable.
I've tried all these
different cups.
Red cup-- nobody could
care about.
But Starbucks-- if it's
Starbucks, for some reason--
[HORN HONKING]
STEVE SPANGLER: Oh,
on my roof?
Oh, thanks!
I'll get it.
Now, watch this.
Just jump up there, and
go I don't see where.
Is it on the roof?
It's going to fall?
It's back?
All right.
Oh God, thank you!
Oh.
That was awesome.
He was very nice.
SARAH: Very thorough.
STEVE SPANGLER: He was
very thorough.
SARAH: My cup?
STEVE SPANGLER: Oh shoot.
SARAH: Oh my gosh!
STEVE SPANGLER: Oh my gosh.
Thank you.
SARAH: Thank you so much!
STEVE SPANGLER: It's
really hot.
I'm sorry?
Hi, I ordered a Venti non-fat
tall latte, and
I don't have it.
Oh shoot.
I knew I should have
put it there.
Can I have a lid?
Thank you, I really
appreciate it.
Thanks.
OK bye, thanks.
Did you see him check
out the camera?
That was awesome.
A new pot of coffee's brewing,
and now we just have to mess
with the sugar.
I can do it.
So now we just have to put the
diaper polymer-- the super
absorbent polymer-- it's
actually sodium polyacrylate,
is the chemical name for it.
Putting it in with the sugar,
and the greatest part about
this prank is that they
do it to themselves.
So they'll pour it
in themselves,
and it will gel instantly.
So it should be really,
really good.
Let's see if the hidden camera
picks up anything.
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYING]
MALE SPEAKER 2: This means
I don't trust anything
going on over here.
I'm not going to say anything
about that, I'll just go about
my business, but--
[INAUDIBLE]?
Sounds like this is going to
turn it hard and then--
I knew it!
That's why I knew, I was like,
it's gotta be that.
Should've went with
[INAUDIBLE].
MALE SPEAKER 3: Sugar--
good.
That's not sugar.
[LAUGHTER]
[CENSOR BEEP]
MALE SPEAKER 3:That's why
they put that there!
[LAUGHTER]
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
MALE SPEAKER 3: That's funny!
STEVE SPANGLER: I have
a science office.
All these people know that I do
these kinds of things, and
even after they all know that
this kind of thing has
happened, they still get mad,
because I guess I messed with
their little precious coffee.
All right.
Have fun with the practical
jokes, be responsible, post
some of your videos on the
channel, so that we can show
some of the videos, and feature
some of those as well.
Love to always hear your
comments, and happy April
Fool's Day!
Stay classy San Diego.
Well if you enjoyed this week's
episode, go ahead and
click the subscribe
button here.
You'll be the first to know
when a brand new episode
appears each week.
This button right here will
show you some more cool
science experiments that we
do outside of the show.
This button right here will
take you to last week's
episode, just in case
you missed it.
And if you want to see the stuff
that you shouldn't see--
that's the bloopers and the
outtakes, well just click this
one, right over here.
And if you want to hear me
stop talking, through the
magic of television, just click
this button right here.
Go head.
Click it, and I'll stop.
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYING]