Is there life after death?
Do angels exist?
Can our dreams contain messages
from Heaven?
Can we tap into ancient secrets
of the supernatural?
Are healing miracles real?
Sid Roth has spent over 35 years
researching the strange world of
the supernatural.
Join Sid for this edition of
It's Supernatural!
Sid: Hello.
Sid Roth here.
Welcome to my world where it's
naturally supernatural.
I'm so excited about this show.
My guest is going to teach you
the missing message of Jesus.
It's there.
It is in the Gospels.
But it's missing today, and that
is Jesus came to heal the broken
hearted.
And you see, you can't get
everything God promises to you
if you have a broken heart.
And it's my conviction in a
broken world with a broken
devil, with broken people, how
do you expect to have a healed
heart unless Jesus heals your
heart.
Now have you ever felt that
something is wrong and you don't
know what it is.
What a frustrating feeling.
That's what happened to my
friend John McTernan.
John, what was going on in your
life?
You're a believer.
You're speaking before people.
You're not supposed to have a
problem, but you do.
What's your problem?
John: Sid, it's internal and
it's kind of hard to explain.
But I felt a drag side.
I felt like a car going down the
road on the interstate at 65
miles an hour at all sorts of
power, speed, and yet it was
holding back.
There was a power drain inside
of me.
I could feel it.
I knew something was wrong.
I had brought it before the Lord
for many, many years, and it
just sat there.
It didn't go.
I had no idea what it was.
Sid: Okay.
So one day he's minding his own
business, listening to a radio
program and the light bulb went
on.
What happened?
John: There was a woman being
interviewed about, she was a
psychologist, Christian
psychologist, and she's being
interviewed by her research on
children of divorce and how
every one of them, virtually
every one of them had a broken
heart, and it affected them
where the developed loneliness.
That was an outstanding trait of
a broken heart of a child from a
divorced family.
And it was like, bingo, my
parents were divorced.
I didn't even know them
together.
They were divorced before I
could remember.
And I began to think, and I'm
saying, broken heart, maybe
that's what I have.
And I sought the Lord about it,
and I prayed, and at that point,
I didn't know I had a broken
heart.
And if you, Sid, had come to me
like let's say years before that
and you said, "John, I didn't
know you had a broken heart," I
would go, how?
How would it be broken?
I had no idea at all.
And when I sought the Lord Sid:
You know, I'm reminded the Bible
says, "The heart is the most
deceitful thing."
Here he is a believer with a
broken heart and he's so
programmed to operate with that
broken heart he doesn't even
know it's broken.
John: That's exactly right, Sid.
That's exactly right.
So I knew Luke 4:18.
And in Luke 4:18, that is the
ministry of Jesus Christ.
And we all know that he came to
save us from sin.
Right?
Sid: Of course.
John: But it doesn't end there.
When you look at Luke 4:18, it
says, "And he came to heal the
broken hearted, to deliver the
captives, to open the eyes of
the blind and to set at liberty
them that are bruised."
We stop right at the salvation
message.
But if you look in the Bible,
there's a semi-colon, and right
after it, it says, "The Lord
came to heal the broken
hearted."
Sid: There are many other areas
that some have had a broken
heart of.
I mean, a divorced home, that's
enough.
But there are a lot of other
areas, like what?
John: Sid, rejection, especially
with children.
I have come to see it's much
easier than we realize to break
a child's heart.
Their heart is very tender and
it's very easy to break a
child's heart.
But rejection, death.
Death can really break a heart.
I have found with women,
abortion, devastating with
breaking the heart.
Physical abuse, sexual abuse,
the military with men, women in
the military now also.
But that, what they see and what
happens can break their heart.
We call it like post-stress, you
know, the trauma and much of
that is really a broken heart.
Sid: But you know what?
Just the peer pressure of a
young child going to school and
maybe they're not so pretty, and
maybe they hear someone laughing
at them, they say nothing.
But in a child's mind, that's
enough to do it.
So what was the revelation you
had when you started praying?
John: My mother had remarried.
Now there is no way on my own I
could remember this, because
we're going back now to when I
was six years old.
And my stepfather, I don't
think, I know he didn't do this
to be malicious.
But he approached when I was
about six years old about being
adopted, and I had no idea what
he was talking about.
Sid: You thought he was your
natural father?
John: No, no.
I had, my father would come and
visit me, and he was a good
friend.
I knew him as Joe.
I didn't call him Dad or
anything.
I knew him as Joe.
And my stepfather wanted to
block out my father from coming,
and he talked to me about
adoption.
I had no idea what he was
talking about.
Finally, it dawned on me.
I had like a revelation that Joe
was my father and this man was
my stepfather.
And I remember I said to him...
Child: When my name change, can
I still see Joe?
Man No, you'll have my name.
Child: No.
My name John McTernan.
John: And I knew right then and
there the whole thing opened up.
I understood perfectly at six
years old and I knew if I told
my father he would protect me
from what was going on.
It was a complete revelation,
but it broke my heart.
Sid: Hold that thought.
When we come back, we're going
to find out what God did that so
changed his life, that people
don't even recognize him.
He doesn't even recognize
himself after his heart is
healed by God Himself.
But better than that, how about
having your broken heart healed.
Don't go away.
We'll be right back to
It's Supernatural!
We now return to
Sid: I mean, what a devastating
thing.
A young boy, the one that's been
with him his whole life that he
thinks is his father and he knew
his natural father, but he
didn't know him as "father".
And his father brings him, in
the basement and tells him the
truth.
How old were you?
John: I figured about six.
Sid: At six, what affect did it
have on you?
John: From that moment on I did
not want to live with my mother
and my stepfather.
I wanted to be with my dad.
And it brought in, it developed
that spirit of loneliness was
deep with me.
I had, it was a supernatural
spiritual loneliness.
It brought a feeling of
rejection in.
It actually brought fear into me
because I remember I was afraid
he would try that again.
And I never was, from that day
on, I was never comfortable in
the family.
And it devastated me inside as a
little six year old.
And that was that problem.
It broke my heart at six and it
carried over when I came to
believe in the Lord Jesus
Christ.
Sid: Okay.
You have the revelation that you
have a broken heart.
You now realize when it
happened.
John: Yes.
Sid: You know exactly.
What did you do about it?
John: I cried out to the Lord to
heal my heart.
And Sid, it took me with the
Lord about two or three weeks of
prayer.
And I can remember laying in bed
at night with tears rolling down
out of my eyes with this feeling
of loneliness and emptiness, and
it got to the point where I
realized then that I know why a
spouse will die like within a
year after a spouse passes away.
Sid: I've noticed that pattern.
John: That loneliness, that's
what I actually felt.
It felt like I was dying.
That's how severe it was.
And then I cried out and I said,
"Lord, if I die over this then I
go to be with you, but I'm
staying and I'm believing you're
going to heal my heart."
And literally, I could feel
relief.
It like came like that.
It just came like up and out.
Sid: It sounds easy, John.
John: Well those two weeks,
three weeks leading up to it,
for me, was not easy.
But the Lord delivered.
I began a whole new man.
That emergency brake feeling
came off.
Sid: But what about that fear,
the loneliness, the loneliness
you explained, the rejection,
what about those things?
John: I began to see how I
operated in my life.
One of the healing, one of the
ministries of Jesus Christ is to
open the eyes of the blind.
And all of a sudden I began to
see like now that my heart was
healed actions that I did to
protect that heart, and also the
way I interacted with people
with the fear of rejection and
not wanting to be rejected, and
things I said, and things.
There was a whole complete
revelation and I began to
confess it to the Lord and say,
"Lord, I'm not living with fear
anymore."
I didn't even know it was there.
Sid: I heard a man once say, God
never sets you free of your
friends.
He sets you free of your
enemies.
And he had no idea there was an
enemy called fear.
But this is the amazing thing.
Once the heart is restored then
these other critters that are
enemies, they literally have to
go.
John: That's right.
Sid: It's so wonderful.
But tell me when the Bible talks
about the ministry of Jesus was
to restore the broken hearted,
what does the word "broken" mean
in Hebrew?
John: That's a real good
question.
And it's actually Hebrew and
Greek really mean the same
thing.
It means a violent shattering.
There's the word "violent".
And it's like you have like this
glass here and I took it and I
just didn't drop it, but I threw
it down on the ground.
Sid: There would be no way to
restore that.
John: It splinters apart and
that is what the Bible describes
as a broken heart.
And Sid, there is nothing human
on this earth that can heal a
broken heart.
It can only be, it's
supernatural, it can only be
healed by Jesus Christ.
That's his ministry.
Sid: Tell me about the woman
with ulcerated colitis.
John: Well what happened, Sid,
is when my heart was healed, all
of a sudden I would come in
contact with people and in my
mind I would hear, I would look
at you for example and I'd hear
"broken hearted, broken
hearted".
And I would go up to you very
politely, I just didn't yell at
you.
I'd say, "Excuse me, but I
believe the Lord is telling me
you have a broken heart."
And people would start crying
and it was amazing.
The Lord is putting people
across my path who need to be
ministered to.
So this ministry started to
develop, just happened when I'd
see instant results.
Sometimes the results would take
a while, but instant results.
And this one woman had a
powerful spirit of rejection.
It happened when she was about
five or six years old, just like
you mentioned, rejected by kids,
and all her life this rejection
just continued.
She had two husbands that left
her and they liked divorced her
on a Friday, and then married
another woman on a Monday.
And that, she was just, she had
a like self-hatred of herself.
And when I ministered to her
about the broken heart it was
very hard for her to receive
that God loved her because of
her broken heart.
Even though she believed in the
Lord, I know that this sounds
weird, but that's what happens
with a broken heart.
Jesus was her savior.
But the reality of calling God,
Abba Father, she couldn't do it.
She said, "I can't do it."
It took a couple prayer
sessions.
And she ulcerated colitis where
about four or five years she was
in the final stage of it.
I mean, it was critical.
She was anemic, bleeding
severely.
Finally, she broke through with
Abba Father, her heart was
healed and that point my
ministry, now what I do is if
someone has physical issues,
when I pray with them for a
broken heart, we also pray for
the physical issue.
Because a lot of times the
physical issue is caused by the
broken heart, the fear and
anxiety, and tension.
So we prayed and her ulcerated
intestines were healed right
there on the spot.
Sid: Once the heart is healed,
the emotions get healed.
The physical body gets healed.
John: Yes.
Sid: John has even gone into
mental institutions in hopeless
cases.
One of the most hopeless cases
they had in a mental institution
was her heart was healed, she
was healed.
But I'll tell you what, I want
you to pray a supernatural
prayer with John, because this
is what he found out.
The gift is growing.
The same thing happened with me.
I started laying hands on people
and they got physically healed.
Then I started speaking it, not
even laying hands, and they got
just as healed.
I'll have him pray for you when
we come back.
We'll be right back to
It's Supernatural!
We now return to
Sid: Now we find out in the
Bible amazing supernatural
blessings that God has given to
Abraham.
But there's a tie-in between a
heart being broken and receiving
these supernatural blessings.
There is, like with John, there
is a disconnect and many people
don't understand this.
Explain that.
John: When our heart is healed,
it puts us in a new relationship
with God.
It's like when you have an
earthly father and you're afraid
of him for whatever reason, you
shy back, you're afraid to talk
to him, you're afraid to ask
him.
Well with a broken heart, that
can carry over towards our
attitude.
And God tells us to call him
"Abba Father".
And those attitudes towards an
earthly father, we can project
towards God.
But he's not like that towards
us.
So a broken heart can break the
feeling, or block the feeling of
how much God loves us, how much
He wants to bless us, and also
the ministry of Lord Jesus is to
open the eyes of the blind.
So once our heart is healed,
Sid, it's a progression.
Salvation, healing of the heart,
setting the captives free,
opening the eyes of the blind
and then setting at liberty them
that are bruised, it's a
progression of what God does in
our life.
So when our heart is healed and
we're set free, all of a sudden
there's no blockage between us
and Abba Father, and we believe
that He'll bless us then.
Sid: So very briefly, will you
tell me, I mean, John gets calls
from people that have loved ones
in mental institutions.
Tell me about one.
John: A friend of mine asked me
to minister to his sister who
was believer, and she has been
in and out of the psychiatric
ward for severe depression.
She had been there, she's in her
60's, she had been in there now
for three months.
And didn't know she was in there
Sid: How bad was the depression?
John: The doctor said it was the
worst he's ever seen.
They were thinking of
permanently institutionalizing
her.
When I visited her and I looked
at her, Sid, if you could see
depression, that was her.
I mean, you could like cut it or
touch her with depression.
And there's a Bible right next
to her.
So I began to talk to her and
she said, "I've been prayed over
and so many people prayed over
me, and I've gone to Christian
psychologists."
I said, "Did anyone ever pray
for you for a broken heart?"
And she went like this and she
said, "No, never."
I said, "That's the problem."
Terry was her name.
So we got into her background.
When she was 16 years old she
had a child out of wedlock.
The child died and it ruptured
her family, relationship with
her family that destroyed her
inside, and she went on a path
of rejection and depression into
the psychiatric ward.
So we prayed and she forgave
what happened, she believed the
baby died because of what she
did.
Then she believed God punished
her by taking the baby.
She had a grudge towards God.
She had to forgive herself.
She had to forgive her parents.
When that all came and then we
prayed, Sid, the greatest, for
me personally, I think miracle I
had ever seen, her continence
changed.
She had this glow to the point
where people in the psychiatric
ward were saying to her, "What
happened to you?
You look so different."
My friend said to me, "You did
like a magic act.
His name was John."
I said, "What are you talking
about?"
He said, "That's not my sister."
He goes, "I don't know who she
is."
He goes, "I've never seen
anything like this from the
depression to the joy."
And they released her from the
hospital, and she now is leading
a normal life.
The whole problem was a broken
heart.
Sid: Okay.
Will you pray as God instructs
for those that are watching,
because I know that this is what
you've been crying out to God
for.
John: Yes.
Father, we come before you in
the awesome name of Jesus.
And Lord, we bring the listeners
before you and the key on their
part is forgiveness, to forgive
those that broke their heart,
forgive themselves and maybe
possibly we be reconciled with
you from a grudge.
Father, once that's done, I pray
now that in the name of Jesus
you take that shattered, broken,
splintered heart and put it
together, make it solid, make it
one according to your word, and
bind it with the power and the
love of the Holy Spirit, never
to be broken again.
And bring the healing that comes
with that, Father, the healing
from fear and depression, and
anxiety, and rejection where we
can call you Abba Father and
walk in love with you.
And then, Father, we ask for the
flow as the heart is healed,
Lord, that issues like high
blood pressure, heart problems,
ulcerated colitis, Lord,
fibromyalgia, all sorts of
things that are triggered by the
tension inside, the anxiety
inside, the fear inside, Lord,
that your natural healing virtue
would flow through their bodies,
and they be released and healed
of these diseases and maladies.
In Jesus' name I ask.
Amen.
Sid: Amen.
Now I can tell this.
There is a requirement in the
Kingdom.
It came from our teacher, our
Lord, the Messiah of Israel,
Jesus, the Anointed One.
And this is what he says: "I
will forgive you to the same
degree, the same amount that you
forgive other people."
So how much do you want God to
forgive you, 95 percent?
You say, I don't feel like it.
I don't deserve it.
Doesn't count.
Meaningless.
God says, if you confess your
sins He is just and faithful to
forgive you of all
unrighteousness and
unforgiveness is a sin that
blocks the hand of God.
Unforgiveness is taking the
arsenic you want your enemy to
take.
Stop it.
Come to your senses.
It's an act of your will.
It's not a feeling.
It's not emotion.
So don't tell me you can't do
it.
You can do it.
You want to please the Living
God.
There's no one else that you
need to please.
Please Him.
Tell Him you choose to forgive
that person out loud in Jesus'
name and don't look back.
And I'm going to tell you
something.
Now does it mean you have to
trust them?
Not until they earn it.
But you can forgive them.
I'm telling you, you can,
because I have.
And then ask Jesus to forgive
you of everything you've ever
done and say, "Jesus, I make you
my Lord.
Come inside of me.
Take over my life.
I love you, Lord."
And then I pray that you
experience the tangible presence
of the love of the Living
God, in Jesus' name.
Sid: Next week on
It's Supernatural!
My guest was granted the
privilege to see the God of
Abraham, Isaac and Jacob
speaking to the Messiah of
Israel about the End Times.
♪