I mean, your mother and I
got married
so we could be a family:
Mom, dad, son, daughter.
I'm not saying
that you have to,
but if you want to,
it's cool.
Thanks, Nick.
Uh...
Your mother was supposed
to make me a special breakfast.
Do you know
where it is?
I think maybe we ate it.
There's some cereal
if you want that.
I love cereal.
I don't want cereal.
Why would you
eat my breakfast?
We didn't know
you were coming down.
Since when have
I stayed upstairs all day?
There's always a first time.
♪ Are we there yet? ♪
The Hyphenated Name Episode
S01x01 Original Air Date on June 2, 2010
♪ tell me, tell me, tell me ♪
♪ tell me,
are we there yet? ♪
-- sync, corrected by elderman --
-- for www.addic7ed.Com --
You can't eat that.
Why?
How come?
That's mom's favorite cereal.
It's the only kind she eats.
Good morning,
everybody.
Morning, mom.
Hey, mom.
Good morning, baby.
Why are you
eating my corn flakes?
This was all
that was left.
I made your breakfast.
It's not here.
Freeze.
Where is it?
Where is what?
You want to play?
Really?
Kevin?
In the freezer?
I'm sick of this.
Ooh, no, no, no.
Go, go, go.
I can make you
another breakfast tomorrow,
but I can't make
two more kids,
at least
not by tomorrow morning.
I'm not Octomom.
If I made two new kids,
maybe they wouldn't hate me.
Sweetheart,
they don't hate you.
They love you.
And freezing my food
is how they show it?
Exactly.
Well, what would they do
if they didn't love me?
Poison your food
and then let you eat it.
Why are you
looking at me like that?
Can we talk
for a second?
Nick Persons
wants to talk.
This must be serious.
Go ahead.
You know I love you,
right?
Yes.
What?
Are you gonna be coming to bed
looking like this every night?
What are you
trying to say?
During the day,
you look like Halle Berry,
but at bedtime,
you turn into Tyler Perry.
Nick, we have been married
for six months,
and you are acting like
this is the first time
you've seen me like this.
No, I'm acting like
this is the sixth month
I've seen you like this.
And what about you?
How do you look
when you come to bed?
This is not about me.
Look, Suzanne,
I understand you're upset,
but you need to know this.
It's no different
than me telling you
you have lettuce in your teeth.
Oh, so now I got lettuce
in my teeth?
No.
That's not what I meant.
Oh, no.
I know what you mean.
What you mean is,
"you better look beautiful
all the time, or else."
Well, you know what?
The vows say
for better or for worse.
In the daytime,
it's better.
At nighttime,
it's worse.
You can't have it
both ways.
I'm sorry, okay?
I'm just trying to be honest,
like they tell you to do
on Dr. Phil.
Oh, yeah?
Well, how's that
working out for you?
What's that?
It's just a bill.
They got your name wrong.
It says
"Suzanne Kingston-Persons."
You should call and fix it.
Suzanne Kingston-Persons.
I don't need to call.
That's right.
Suzanne Kingston-Persons.
What's with the hyphen?
You're married now.
It's my name.
Hyphenated.
A hyphen in your name
is a recipe for disaster.
No, a recipe for disaster
is telling your wife
she looks like Tyler Perry.
A hyphen is just
a punctuation mark.
A punctuation mark
that says,
"I don't know
if this will work out,
so I'm gonna keep
my old name just in case."
Remember Rebecca Romijn?
She married John Stamos.
Then she became
Rebecca Romijn hyphen Stamos.
Then what happened?
Divorced.
Well, Nick, my name
is part of my identity, okay?
That's the name
I do business under.
Puff daddy
turned into P. Diddy.
Did people stop dancing?
Huh?
The rock turned into
Dwayne Johnson.
Did people stop smelling
what he was cooking?
If you want everybody
to have the same name so bad,
change yours.
That's not
what a man does.
♪ ♪
what's this?
What not to wear.
Did you bring us anything,
dad?
Dad, huh?
We thought
about what you said.
we'd give it a shot.
Dad.
You think I got something
in these bags for you,
don't u?
Do you?
Dad?
How come when I ask
one of you a question,
the other one answers?
Do we do that?
Dad?
Yeah, you do that.
So what's in the bag?
Dad?
My breakfast.
It's toaster waffles,
and they're already frozen,
so if you want
to get under my skin,
you gonna
have to cook them.
Hey, honey.
You went
to the grocery store.
I just stopped
to get some waffles.
Mmm.
Did you get me
some more corn flakes?
No.
Why?
So just to be clear,
you want me to do things
that make you happy,
but you don't want to do things
that make me happy.
Do you think it's easier for me
to get beautiful for you
or easier for you
to get me a box of corn flakes?
When did you
turn into the riddler?
Really think you should quit
while you're ahead, Nick.
Oh, he's not ahead.
Too bad, Nick.
No more "dad"?
Now it's Nick?
It was a trial period.
Didn't go well.
You see that?
Well, they need time
to adjust,
and obviously,
so do you,
because you don't do everything
you did six months ago either.
Nick.
Shave your legs,
maybe I would.
Hey, hey, man, hey.
Yo.
Who are you?
Hello, honey.
Hey, ma.
Ooh, don't speak.
I heard everything
you had to say yesterday.
Anything else
might ruin it.
Mm.
Mm-mm.
Who was that?
Oh, that.
That was Orlando.
We met in New York.
Oh, I thought you said
you was just
gonna hang out this weekend.
I did, in New York.
Oh, there you go.
Thank you.
He's kind of young,
isn't he?
Now would be a good time
for you to quit
asking questions,
'cause if you keep talking,
I will give you
the answer.
What's wrong?
Who said
something was wrong?
I know my son,
and you're acting funny.
Something happen
with you and Suzanne?
It's nothing.
Suzanne wants to keep her name
and hyphenate it with mine.
Suzanne Kingston-Persons.
Hold that thought.
Oh, hey, Suzanne.
Are you at work?
Oh, girl, I'm sorry.
I must have called your number
by accident.
Okay, bye.
What was all that?
Just had to make sure
she wasn't home
before I started
talking about her.
She's my wife.
Start getting used to it.
I started.
Just not finished.
And what is all this
hyphenated name stuff?
You know, the least she could do
is be proud of the fact
that you gave her
your last name,
seeing as how you married her
and took in those...people.
They're not people.
They're kids.
Anyway,
all I'm saying is,
you don't see Michelle Obama
complaining.
You know what her last name was
before she married Barack?
No.
That's right.
Nobody knows,
and nobody cares.
So what else did you do
in New York?
Boy, I'm your mother.
If you want to hear
about something nasty,
go on the Internet
like everybody else.
Thanks, mom.
Mm-hmm.
Uncle Terrence wants to know
if we can spend the night
this weekend.
He got tickets to a screening
of the new Will Smith movie.
It's already made
$100 million,
and it's not even out yet.
Yeah.
If it's fine with
miss Kingston hyphen Persons,
it's fine with me.
In that case,
mom, can we have some
of Nick's money?
Yes.
Yes, you can.
What?
Kids need money.
Thank you.
Thanks.
Dad.
Nick, can I talk to you
for a moment.
Nick Persons, you should be
ashamed of yourself.
You the one
that wants everybody
to be clear
about their identity.
It's just a name, Nick.
What else do we need to do
to make you feel like
you're a part of this family?
How about treating me
like it?
Just because you're here
doesn't mean we have to forget
everything we ever did.
We have a past.
Deal with it.
Okay.
Cool.
Nick,
what is all this?
This is an autographed
pair of 1992 Air Jordans.
And what is it doing
on my table?
You not letting go
of your past,
so I'm not letting go of mine.
So I got all my stuff
out of storage.
Deal with it.
And who is this?
Oh.
That is Renee.
She was my girlfriend
for the first half of--
I don't--
I don't care
about your tramp ex-girlfriends.
Okay?
I'm here. She's not.
So obviously, I have something
that she doesn't.
Yeah, two last names.
You know what?
Just 'cause
you rip up a photo
doesn't make you right,
sweetheart.
And you better not
try and put it back together.
I'm just cleaning up.
Knock, knock.
Kevin, Lindsey,
front and center.
Hey, Uncle Terrence.
What the heck
is all this stuff?
Mom and Nick
are having an argument.
Yeah.
Go wait in the car.
Okay.
And don't talk
to strangers.
We're just
getting inside the car.
Strangers could be anywhere,
even in your own car.
Okay.
Hey, Nick.
Hey, Terrence.
What's wrong?
You tell me, man.
What's going on
with you and my baby sister?
We're having a fight,
and it's not your business.
Oh, I think it is.
Look, I done seen her
go through one heartbreak,
and I'm not about to stand here
and watch it happen again.
What's that
supposed to mean?
I tell you
what it mean.
As the sole member
of an elite black ops unit,
I got extensive training
in defusing situations
just like this.
I got a policy, bro.
If I can't talk you down,
I got to take you down.
And it won't be pretty.
Suzanne, Terrence
is threatening to kill me again.
Terrence,
don't kill my husband.
That's one.
That's one?
That's one what?
What--what are you writing?
What's that?
Hate it when he does that.
It's a shame that
a beautiful woman like you
sitting here
all by herself--
I am married
with two kids,
and I do not look like this
in the morning.
Good-bye.
Oh, my God.
Men get on my nerves.
They think just because
they have a private plane
and a house in Miami,
you will fly off
on a moment's notice,
like you don't have
anything else to do.
Don't go, then.
Are you crazy?
What else do I have to do?
Who is this,
Malcolm?
Are you kidding?
Malcolm can't afford
his own plane.
That's why I dumped him.
When?
This morning.
And you already have
a new boyfriend?
Mm-hmm.
And his name is...
Angelo.
Mm.
And I told him,
I just don't hop in a plane
with just any old body.
I don't sleep around.
I'm a one-man woman.
You mean,
"one man this morning,
one man this evening" woman.
Suzanne,
I would love
to be like you
and find a wonderful man
I can spend
the rest of my life with,
but the fact of the matter is,
men get on my nerves.
Well, you're better off.
You don't want
to be like me.
Why?
Trouble in paradise?
Maybe.
Nick's all bent out of shape
because I want
to hyphenate my name.
I'd like to say
it's not a problem,
but it is.
Mm-hmm.
Well, you know what?
Let me ask you
one question.
What's that?
Are you crazy?
What?
You are a woman...
With two kids.
Not only did you find a man;
you found a good man
with a good job
who loves you
and loves your kids.
Oh, and he black.
I mean, if the man wants you
to drop your name,
drop it.
You drop it
like the sponsors dropped Tiger.
Well...
Either you like
who you are
or you like who you were.
I can't be both?
Michael Jackson couldn't,
and neither can you.
Mmm.
You gonna finish that?
Whoo!
Let's go.
I got to make it to the airport
in 30 minutes.
Well, who's gonna pay?
Don't worry about it.
I used to date the owner.
Come on.
Well, we'll stop
at a gas station,
'cause you gonna
have to pee.
Man, she's hot.
I can see why Suzanne
tore this up.
Why would you bring this
back into the house, man?
Everybody knows
pictures like this
are why basements
and garages exist.
I was trying
to prove a point.
See, that's why
I avoid relationships.
It's just too much.
Who's right?
Who's wrong?
Whose underwear is this?
Just too complicated.
What do you know
about it anyway?
I mean, the longest you've ever
been with a woman is two weeks.
How you supposed
to get to know a woman
over ten working days?
I don't.
See, that's the difference
between you and me.
I don't care
about who you are.
I only care about
what we do together.
Now, if you want to do
what I want to do,
then we do
what we're gonna do.
Do you?
Hey, man,
hate me if you want.
Who's the one of us
having problems?
Do you think I'm wrong
about Suzanne?
Who cares
what name she uses?
Everybody knows Katie Holmes
is married to Tom Cruise.
Okay, weird example.
Everybody knows beyonce
is married to Jay-Z.
In fact, I heard
he's hyphenating his last name.
So now, if Jigga
doesn't have a problem with it,
why should you?
Yeah, I know.
I'm allowed to say "Jigga,"
right?
Oh, can I keep this?
knock, knock.
How was the movie?
Movie was good.
I like Will Smith.
He funny.
Hey, Nick.
Hey, guys.
You wouldn't believe
all the cool stuff
that happened.
Uncle Terrence took us
on the rooftop of the mall
and showed us where
a crazy gunman
got taken out with a single shot
from a helicopter.
Yep.
When did this happen?
A lot of things happen
that you don't hear about, Dick.
It's because of people like me
people like you
don't know how dangerous
this world really is.
Man, what are you
talking about?
Look, man,
I don't have time,
and I'm not interested
in explaining myself
to somebody that sleeps
under the safety and comfort
that I provide
and then questions
how I provide it.
Why don't you just say
"thank you"?
And let's leave it at that.
Hello, Big Brother.
Hello.
Why don't you guys
go upstairs?
Bring your stuff.
Okay, mom.
All right, mom.
Hop to it.
Bye, Uncle Terrence.
Eat your vegetables.
We will.
Moved all your stuff,
huh?
Y'all patching things up?
No, and stay out of it.
I understand,
little sis.
But if you need
to hide the body,
just let me know.
Yeah, he'll be in the bushes
with a vat of acid.
You don't know that.
I could be anywhere.
I could be over there.
Where?
So is this your way
of saying you're sorry,
you were stupid,
and I was right?
Honey, I'm just trying
to understand
where you coming from with this.
You took back
everything else.
What is your old sofa
still doing here?
Honestly,
I hate our sofa.
I put it in storage.
Well, you better
bring it back out,
'cause I'm not sitting there.
Who knows what strange behinds
have been on that thing?
I bought this sofa when
I started going out with you.
So you never...
Not on this.
Mm.
Nick, I know how important
this is to you,
so if you want me
to change my name,
I'm willing to do it.
The reason I married you
is because I love who you are.
If being
Suzanne Kingston-Persons
makes you that woman,
then I'm okay with that.
Just tell me
what you think I should do.
I want you to do
what you want to do.
If you wanted me to do
what I wanted to do,
we wouldn't have this problem
in the first place.
You're an independent woman.
Make up your independent mind.
What kind of example
are you setting for the kids
if you can't make a decision
on matters affecting our family?
I tried to.
You wouldn't let me.
Fine.
Keep your name.
Don't tell me
what to do!
Oh, forget it.
I'll change mine.
What?
You heard me.
I'll change my name.
Nick Kingston-Persons.
Is that okay with you?
Yes.
I'm gonna go get ready
for bed.
No, no,
don't change.
Keep that on.
For me, please?
My eyes!
Turn it off!
What is wrong with you, man?
What in the world
are you two dog?
Uncle Terrence gave us
these new night vision goggles.
We're trying them out.
You got another pair?
Sure.
Here.
Let me talk to you guys
for a second.
If it's okay with you guys,
I'm gonna be Nick
Kingston-Persons from now on.
Did Uncle Terrence
threaten you again?
Yeah.
But it's because I love you.
I want us to be a family
with one name.
You mean two names.
The same name.
Lindsey Kingston-Persons.
I like it.
Good.
So will it still bother you
if we call you Nick?
No.
Do you have any suggestions
for anything else
that would bother you?
I'll see you in the morning.
I love you guys.
Good night.
Oh, my God.
What is wrong with you, man?
-- sync, corrected by elderman --
-- for www.addic7ed.Com --