REVIEW SESSION IS GOING TO BE ON TUESDAY NIGHT
AT 6:00
O'CLOCK IN 145 DWINELLE. AND, IT WILL NOT
BE WEBCAST.
SO, THAT IF YOU WISH TO COME YOU WILL HAVE
TO COME
BECAUSE YOU WON'T BE ABLE TO PICK IT UP ON
THE
WEBCAST. THE OTHER THING IS, THAT IT IS A
WORKING
SESSION. I DON'T HAVE ANYTHING PREPARED AND
I WILL
TAKE WHATEVER QUESTIONS YOU ASK AND WE WILL
TRY TO
ANSWER THEM. SO, MAKE GOOD USE OF THE TIME.
AT THE
END OF THE LECTURE TODAY AS I MENTIONED I
WILL TALK
A LITTLE BIT MORE ABOUT THE MIDTERM AND I
WILL HAVE
OFFICE HOURS NEXT WEEK ON TUESDAY AND WEDNESDAY
AS
USUAL. AND I WILL BE GLAD TO MEET WITH YOU.
LAST TIME I INTRODUCED YOU TO SOME OF THE
CONCEPTS THAT WERE, THAT WATER MOVEMENT AND
WATER
RELATIONS REVOLVE AROUND. AND WE SAID THAT
THE
MOVEMENT OF WATER IN PLANTS AND INDEED IN
ALL LIVING
SYSTEMS, IS DETERMINED BY THE WATER POTENTIAL.
AND,
WE SAID THAT THE WATER POTENTIAL WAS A ABBREVIATED
BY
THE GREEK LETTER PSI. AND THAT THE WATER POTENTIAL
FOR OUR PURPOSES OF PURE WATER, WE SAID WAS
EQUAL TO
ZERO. PSI EQUALS ZERO FOR PURE WATER. WE ALSO
SAID
THAT WATER POTENTIAL HAS SEVERAL COMPONENTS
WHICH MAKE
IT UP. SO THEN WE SAID THAT PSI EQUALS PSI'S
OF PI
PLUS PSI'S OF P. THESE TWO COMPONENTS WHICH
MAKE UP
THE WATER POTENTIAL WHICH DETERMINE WHICH
WAY THE
WATER MOVES. LAST TIME WHEN WE TALKED ABOUT
THIS WE
ALSO MENTIONED TO YOU THAT THE DRIVING FORCE
FOR WATER
MOVEMENT AND THIS IS PROBABLY THE MOST IMPORTANT
POINT
FROM LAST LECTURE, IN PLANTS IS THE EVAPORATION
OF
WATER, WHICH WE SAID WAS EQUAL TO TRANSPIRATION.
ESSENTIALLY IF YOU REMEMBER OF COLUMN OF WATER
THAT I
ILLUSTRATED TO YOU LAST TIME WITH THE RUBBER
BAND
BEING THE HYDROGEN BONDS AND THE YELLOW BEING
THE
WATER MOLECULES, ESSENTIALLY THE WATER COLUMN
IS
STRETCHED DUE TO TRANSPIRATION AND WATER IS
LITERALLY
PULLED UP THE TREE, PULLED UP THE TREE DUE
TO THIS
STRETCHING. AND THIS IS THE MECHANISM BY WHICH
WATER
IS MOVED UP THE TREE. THIS PULL, WHICH ORIGINATES
AS
A RESULT OF A EVAPORATION AND IS PASSED DOWN
THROUGH
THE HYDROGEN BONDS FROM ONE WATER MOLECULE
TO ANOTHER.
AND WE WILL RETURN TO THIS IDEA IN A MOMENT.
FINALLY,
LAST TIME I ENDED BY TALKING TO YOU ABOUT
A CELL IN
WHICH THE MEMBRANE HAD BEEN PULLED AWAY FROM
THE CELL
DURING WILTING.
AND WE SAID THAT THE MEMBRANE, WHICH IS
INDICATED BY THIS LINE HERE, WAS PULLED AWAY
FROM THE
CELL WHEN WATER IS LOST FROM THE CELL. AT
THIS POINT
WHERE THE MEMBRANE JUST PULLS AWAY
WE SAID THAT PSI'S
OF P EQUALS ZERO.
AND WE GIVE A SPECIAL NAME TO THIS POINT WHERE
PSI'S OF P JUST EQUALS ZERO. WE CALL THIS
INCIPIENT
PLASMOLYSIS. AND I MENTIONED TO YOU LAST
TIME THAT
THERE IS A YOUTUBE URL WHICH IS POSTED ON
YOUR WEB
PAGE WHICH WILL TAKE YOU TO SOME EXAMPLES
OF INCIPIENT
PLASMOLYSIS OR PLASMOLYSIS IN GENERAL. AND
YOU ARE
ALSO GOING TO BE DOING THIS IN THE LAB THE
WEEK AFTER
NEXT. YOU WILL HAVE A CHANCE TO DO IT YOURSELF.
NOW,
WHAT I WANT TO DO TODAY IS TO GIVE YOU SOME
PRACTICE
WITH THE WATER RELATIONS EQUATION THAT WILL
HELP YOU
WITH YOUR EXAMPLES THAT ARE GOING TO BE ON
YOUR
PROBLEM SET. AND I WANT TO BEGIN WITH THE
AN EXAMPLE
THAT WE TALKED ABOUT LAST TIME. WHICH WAS
THE
STOMATA. WANT TO TALK ABOUT THESE. WE SAID
STOMATA WERE THE PORES AND THE GUARD CELLS
THROUGH
WHICH WATER VAPOR ESCAPED AND THROUGH WHICH
CO2 ENTERS
INTO THE PLANT. AND I SAID LAST TIME AND YOU
READ
ABOUT IT IN YOUR BOOK, THAT THE SIZE OF THE
PORE IS
DETERMINED BY HOW MUCH PRESSURE IS INSIDE
OF GUARD
CELLS. THIS SHOULD JUST BE REVIEW FROM LAST
TIME.
AND NOW WHAT I WANT TO TALK ABOUT TODAY
IS, HOW
DOES THIS PRESSURE ARISE IN THE GUARD CELL?
WE SAID
THAT THAT PRESSURE WAS CALLED TURGOR PRESSURE.
WE
WANT TO TALK ABOUT HOW IT ARISES AND HOW IT
IS RELATED
TO WATER. SO, LET'S DRAW A GUARD CELL FOR
US. HERE
IS THE PORE. AND ON EITHER SIDE OF THE PORE
ARE THE
TWO GUARD CELLS. TWO GUARD CELLS. AND THEY'RE,
OF
COURSE, ARE PART OF THE EPIDERMIS ON THE LEAF
SO THEY
ARE SURROUNDED BY OTHER EPIDERMAL CELLS. AND
THE ONE
OTHER THING THAT WE HAVE TO ADD TO THIS, WHICH
IS
IMPLIED, IS THAT EACH OF THE CELLS BECAUSE
THEY ARE
ALIVE, HAVE A MEMBRANE. HAVE A MEMBRANE. LET'S
BEGIN
NOW WITH A SERIES OF STEPS THAT WE WOULD FOLLOW
IN THE
OPENING OF THE PORE. SO, WE ARE GOING TO TALK
ABOUT
OPENING OF THE PORE. THE FIRST STEP WHICH
IS GOING TO
HAVE TO HAPPEN IS THAT WE ARE GOING TO HAVE
TO START
THINKING OF SOME WAY OF BUILDING UP THE PRESSURE
INSIDE OF THE GUARD CELLS TO CAUSE THEM TO
OPEN UP, TO
BOW OUT. SO, WHAT REALLY HAPPENS FIRST OF
ALL, IS
THAT SOLUTES AND THE PARTICULAR SOLUTE THAT
WE WANT TO
TALK ABOUT IS POTASSIUM, IS MOVED ACTIVELY
FROM THE
EPIDERMAL CELL
INTO THE GUARD CELL. AND I WILL JUST
ABBREVIATE GUARD CELL AS GC. THIS RESULTS
IN A MORE
NEGATIVE PSI'S OF PI IN THE GUARD CELL. MORE
NEGATIVE
PSI'S OF PI IN THE GUARD CELL, WHICH RESULTS
IN
A CHANGE IN THE PSI OF THE GUARD CELL. BECOMES
MORE
NEGATIVE.
AND AT THIS POINT THEN, WATER ENTERS THE
GUARD CELL INCREASING TURGOR PRESSURE AND
THE GUARD
CELL OPENS. THE PORE OPENS.
NOW, WHAT I WOULD LIKE TO DO IS TO PUT SOME
NUMBERS TO MAKE A TABLE, TO GIVE YOU SOME
REAL NUMBERS
WITH REGARD TO THE WATER POTENTIAL EQUATION
OF WHAT IS
HAPPENING AS THE POTASSIUM IS MOVING INTO
THE GUARD
CELL. AND, FOR THIS PURPOSE WE ARE GOING TO
MAKE
A TABLE AND THIS TABLE WILL HAVE THREE VALUES.
IT
WILL HAVE PSI, PSI'S OF PI, AND PSI'S OF P.
AND, WE
ARE NOW GOING TO LOOK AT HOW PSI AND PSI'S
OF PI AND
PSI'S OF P CHANGE IN THE GUARD CELL WHEN IT
IS EITHER
OPEN OR CLOSED. SO, IN THIS PARTICULAR CASE
WE WILL
SAY, THIS IS WHEN IT IS OPEN, AND IN THIS
CASE, WE
WILL SAY THIS IS WHEN THE PORE IS CLOSED.
AND THEN WE
WILL DIVIDE EACH OF THESE TWO SITUATIONS INTO
THE
GUARD CELL AND THE EPIDERMAL CELL. GUARD CELL
AND THE
EPIDERMAL CELL. NOW, IF WE WERE TO START TO
PUT SOME
VALUES ON THESE. AND THIS IS WHAT I WANT YOU
TO HAVE
A SENSE OF FROM TODAY'S LECTURE. BECAUSE,
THIS IS
WHAT YOU ARE GOING TO NEED FOR THE WATER RELATIONS
PROBLEMS. WE HAVE TO BEGIN BY HAVING AN UNDERSTANDING
OF WHAT REALISTIC VALUES ARE WITH REGARD TO
THESE
VARIOUS COMPONENTS. PSI, PSI'S OF PI AND PSI'S
OF P.
SO LET'S LOOK FIRST AT THE SITUATION OF WHEN
THE GUARD
CELL IS CLOSED. WHEN THE PORE IS CLOSED. AT
THAT
PARTICULAR POINT THERE WOULD BE RELATIVELY
LOW
PRESSURE INSIDE OF THE CELLS. LOW PRESSURE.
SO
A REASONABLE VALUE WOULD BE 1 FOR THE TURGOR
PRESSURE
INSIDE THE GUARD CELL. NOW, HOW ABOUT THE
TURGOR
PRESSURE IN THE ADJACENT EPIDERMAL CELL. WHAT
WOULD
ITS TURGOR PRESSURE BE? THAT CELL WHICH IS
RIGHT
NEXT TO THE GUARD CELL. WELL, A REASONABLE
VALUE LIKE
BEFORE. THESE ARE 4 BARS OR 4 ATMOSPHERES.
NOW HOW
ABOUT THE SOLUTE POTENTIAL? THE SALTS THAT
ARE
INSIDE THE GUARD CELL. A REASONABLE VALUE
WHEN IT IS
CLOSED MIGHT BE CONCENTRATION 2. AND IN THE
ADJACENT
EPIDERMAL CELL, MAYBE CONCENTRATION 6, BECAUSE
IT HAS
MORE POTASSIUM AT THIS POINT. NOW, LET'S LOOK
AT THE
SITUATION WHEN THE GUARD CELL HAS BEEN OPENED.
THAT
IS, POTASSIUM HAS BEEN ACTIVELY MOVED ACROSS
THE
MEMBRANE FROM THE EPIDERMAL CELL INTO THE
GUARD CELL.
AT THIS POINT WE SAID THE GUARD CELL IS NOW
GOING TO
OPEN THE PORE, SO ITS TURGOR PRESSURE HAS
HAD TO
INCREASE. THIS IS A REASONABLE VALUE FOR THE
TURGOR
PRESSURE. IN THE ADJACENT EPIDERMAL CELL,
BECAUSE WE
HAVE LOST SOME WATER, ITS TURGOR PRESSURE
HAS
DECREASED SOMEWHAT, BUT NOT A LOT. THESE ARE
REASONABLE VALUES. AND NOW IF WE LOOK TO SEE
WHAT HAS
HAPPENED WITH REGARD TO PSI'S OF PI. THAT
IS, THE
SOLUTE POTENTIAL. AS A RESULT OF THE POTASSIUM
BEING
MOVED IN, A REASONABLE VALUE MIGHT BE CONCENTRATION
8.
SO WE HAVE GONE FROM CONCENTRATION 2 TO CONCENTRATION
8. WHERE DOES THIS POTASSIUM COME FROM? WELL,
IT
COMES FROM THE ADJACENT EPIDERMAL CELL. SO,
THE
ADJACENT EPIDERMAL CELL HAS GIVEN UP SOME
OF ITS
POTASSIUM AND IN THE PROCESS HAS NOW BECOME
A LESS
NEGATIVE WITH REGARD TO ITS SOLUTE POTENTIAL.
NOW, WE
HAVE ALL OF THE COMPONENTS WHICH ALLOW US
TO CALCULATE
THE WATER POTENTIAL. AND TO REMIND YOU OF
THE
EQUATION, PSI EQUALS PSI'S OF PI PLUS PSI'S
OF P. SO,
IF WE NOW CALCULATE THE WATER POTENTIAL FOR
EACH OF
THESE COLUMNS, WE HAVE GOT A 5, AND A NEGATIVE
8. THE
OVERALL PSI OF THE GUARD CELL WHEN IT IS OPEN
WOULD BE
CONCENTRATION 3. PRETTY STRAIGHTFORWARD.
AT THE TIME
THE GUARD CELL IS OPEN THE OVERALL PSI FOR
THE
ADJACENT EPIDERMAL CELL WOULD BE 3 AND A NEGATIVE
4,
WOULD BE CONCENTRATION 1. NOW, LET'S LOOK
AT THE
SITUATION WHEN IT IS CLOSED. WHEN IT IS CLOSED
WE
HAVE 1 AND A NEGATIVE 2 GIVE US CONCENTRATION
1. AND
THE ADJACENT EPIDERMAL CELL WOULD BE CONCENTRATION
2.
NOW, LET'S LOOK AT WHAT WE HAVE SHOWN HERE.
FIRST OF
ALL, IN THE CLOSED SITUATION THE MORE NEGATIVE
WATER
POTENTIAL IN THE EPIDERMAL CELL KEEPS THE
WANTING TO BE MOSTLY IN THE ADJACENT EPIDERMAL
CELL.
NOT ON THE GUARD CELL AND HENCE THE TURGOR
PRESSURE IS
LOW. ONCE WE PUMP POTASSIUM FROM THE EPIDERMAL
CELL
INTO THE GUARD CELL AND INCREASE ITS SOLUTE
POTENTIAL
WE NOW CAN AFFECT THE WATER POTENTIAL OF THE
GUARD
CELL WHICH NOW BECOMES MORE NEGATIVE THAN
THE
EPIDERMAL CELL AND WATER NOW FLOWS THIS DIRECTION.
THE MOVEMENT OF WATER THEN CAUSES AN INCREASE
IN THE
TURGOR PRESSURE. AND THIS BASICALLY IS WHAT
HAPPENS
IN THE SITUATION WHERE WE HAVE A OPENING AND
CLOSING
OF A GUARD CELL DUE TO A CHANGE OF TURGOR
PRESSURE.
KEEP IN MIND THAT THE DIRECTION OF MOVEMENT
OF WATER
IS DETERMINED NOT BY THESE INDIVIDUAL COMPONENTS,
NOT
BY PSI'S OF PI OR PSI'S OF P, BUT BY THE WATER
POTENTIAL. THE NUMBER THAT YOU GET BY ADDING
THE
INDIVIDUAL COMPONENT. THIS DETERMINES THE
DIRECTION
THAT WATER MOVES. NOW, LET ME GIVE YOU A FEW
MORE
EXAMPLES OF THIS PARTICULAR SITUATION. HERE
IS
A BEAKER OF WATER. I WOULD LIKE YOU TO THINK
OF THIS
BEAKER OF WATER IN TERMS OF PERHAPS EVEN BEING
A LAKE.
WE CAN ALSO HAVE A LAKE HERE. SO, LET'S SAY
WE HAVE
A LAKE OR A BEAKER OF WATER AND I AM GOING
TO TELL YOU
THAT THE TOTAL AMOUNT OF SOLUTES DISSOLVED
BOTH IN THE
BEAKER AND PERHAPS IN THE LAKE, AS WELL. WE
CAN SAY
THAT PSI'S OF PI FOR THE LAKE MIGHT BE CONCENTRATION
4. AND FOR THE BEAKER WE WILL ALSO SAY PSI'S
OF PI IS
CONCENTRATION 4. JUST TO START OFF WITH.
NOW, YOU
HAVE THE WATER POTENTIAL EQUATION, PSI EQUALS
PSI'S OF
PI PLUS PSI'S OF P. AND IF I ASK YOU AT THIS
POINT,
WHAT THEN WOULD BE THE WATER POTENTIAL OF
THE WATER IN
THIS OPEN BEAKER OR THE WATER IN THE LAKE?
HOW COULD
YOU FIGURE IT OUT BY HAVING ONLY ONE VALUE?
THAT IS,
BY ONLY KNOWING THAT THIS VALUE HERE IS CONCENTRATION
4. AND THE ANSWER IS, THAT IN SITUATIONS WHERE
YOU
HAVE AN OPEN BODY OF WATER WHERE YOU HAVE
NO MEMBRANE
THERE IS NO POSSIBILITY TO BUILD UP TURGOR
PRESSURE IN
AN OPEN BODY. THERE IS NO POSSIBILITY TO BUILD
UP
TURGOR PRESSURE. SO, IN THE ABSENCE OF THE
MEMBRANE
AS YOU HAVE IN A LAKE OR A BEAKER OF WATER,
PSI'S OF
PI EQUALS ZERO. SO, THE WATER POTENTIAL IN
THIS
PARTICULAR CASE OF A LAKE OR THIS BEAKER EQUALS
THE
SOLUTE POTENTIAL. BECAUSE WE DON'T HAVE THIS
MEMBRANE
THAT WILL ALLOW US TO BUILD UP PRESSURE. NOW,
UP
FRONT HERE I HAVE SOME EXAMPLES OF A PLANT
THAT SOME
OF YOU MAKE HAVE SEEN BEFORE OR MAYBE AS
A KID MAY
HAVE TORMENTED A PLANT LIKE THIS. THIS IS
KNOWN AS
A SENSITIVE PLANT. AND THE REASON THAT IT
IS
A SENSITIVE PLANT IS BECAUSE WHEN IT IS TOUCHED,
AND I
DON'T KNOW WHETHER IT WILL DO IT NOW FOR US
BECAUSE IT
IS QUITE SHY. BUT, WHEN IT IS TOUCHED I DON'T
KNOW IF
MATT YOU CAN FOCUS ON THIS, THE LEAVES WILL
CLOSE AND
THEY WILL EVEN COLLAPSE SOMEWHAT. NOW, THIS
CLOSURE
OR THE COLLAPSE OF THE LEAVES PROBABLY SERVES
SOME
TYPE OF A PROTECTIVE MECHANISM AS A WAY OF
REDUCING
THE LEAF SURFACE PERHAPS WHEN AN ANIMAL LANDS
ON THE
LEAF. BUT, IT IS ALSO RELATED TO CHANGES IN
WATER
POTENTIAL. AND I WANT TO JUST BRIEFLY TELL
YOU WHAT
IS GOING ON IN THIS LEAF AND HOW IT IS RELATED
TO
WATER POTENTIAL. AND THEN MAYBE YOU COULD
MAKE
A TABLE LIKE THIS FOR YOURSELF FOR THE LEAF.
SO,
LET'S LOOK AT THE SENSITIVE PLANT. THE FIRST
THING
THAT HAPPENS WITH TOUCH IS THAT IT, YOU STIMULATE
OR
YOU MAKE A SMALL ELECTRIC CURRENT. THIS
CAN ACTUALLY
BE MEASURED ON METERS. IT IS NOT ENOUGH FOR
US TO
PERCEIVE OURSELVES BUT IT IS A SMALL ELECTRIC
CURRENT.
THIS RESULTS IN A MOVEMENT OF OUR SAME ION
THAT WE SAW
ON THE STOMATA, A POTASSIUM FROM THE LEAF
INTO THE
STEM. MOVEMENT OF POTASSIUM FROM THE LEAF
IN THE
STEM. THIS THEN CAUSES THE PSI OF THE LEAF
TO BECOME,
IN THIS CASE, MORE POSITIVE AND WATER LEAVES
THE LEAF
AND GOES TO THE STEM. AND THE LEAF COLLAPSES.
THE LEAF COLLAPSES.
SO, HERE IS AN EXAMPLE OF WATER BEING PRESSURE
OR POSITIVE PRESSURE OF THE WATER HOLDING
THE LEAF UP
AND WHEN YOU CAUSE THAT PRESSURE TO DROP BY
HAVING THE
POTASSIUM GO OUT, YOU CHANGE THE WATER POTENTIAL
AND
THE WATER LEAVES AND THEN THE LEAFLET DROPS.
NOW, LET ME GIVE YOU A SITUATION WHICH IS
A LITTLE MORE COMPLICATED. BUT, ACTUALLY PROBABLY
SUMMARIZES NICELY WHAT WE WILL SAY IN THIS
LECTURE AND
WHAT WE HAVE SAID UP TO THIS POINT ABOUT
WATER. THIS
IS AN UNUSUAL SITUATION, BUT WHAT I WANT YOU
TO THINK
ABOUT. I AM GOING TO DRAW TWO CELLS IN THIS
SITUATION. I AM GOING TO DRAW A PARENCHYMA
CELL. WE
ARE ALSO GOING TO MAKE A TABLE AS WE HAD BEFORE.
AND,
NEXT TO THIS PARENCHYMA CELL I AM GOING TO
PUT A XYLEM
ELEMENT. A XYLEM ELEMENT. AND, FOR THIS PARTICULAR
XYLEM ELEMENT I AM GOING TO SAY THAT THEY
ARE IN
EQUILIBRIUM
WITH REGARD TO PSI. THAT IS, PSI OF THE
XYLEM EQUALS THE PSI OF THE PARENCHYMA. AND
NOW WHAT
I WOULD LIKE TO DO IS TO MAKE A TABLE JUST
AS WE DID
FOR THE STOMATA TO CONSIDER WHAT ARE THE VARIOUS
COMPONENTS THAT ALLOW THESE TWO CELLS TO HAVE
THE SAME
WATER POTENTIAL. SO, ON THIS PARTICULAR ONE,
I THINK
I WILL JUST DO THE WHOLE THING DIFFERENTLY.
ON THIS
PARTICULAR ONE, WE WILL PUT, WE WILL HAVE
THE XYLEM
AND THE PARENCHYMA. AND WE WILL LOOK NOW AT
THE THREE
ELEMENTS WHICH MAKE UP THE WATER POTENTIAL
OF THESE
TWO CELLS. WE WILL LOOK AT PSI, PSI'S OF
PI, AND
PSI'S OF P.
NOW THE FIRST THING I WANT TO ASK YOU AND
THIS
SHOULD BE IN YOUR MIND, IS WHAT IS THE REAL
BASIC
DIFFERENCE BETWEEN THE PARENCHYMA CELL AND
THE XYLEM
CELL, THE VESSEL?
WHAT ABOUT THE XYLEM CELL? XYLEM CELL IS DEAD
COMPARED TO THE PARENCHYMA CELL. THE PARENCHYMA
CELL
HAS THEREFORE, A MEMBRANE. IT IS ALIVE.
SO, THIS CELL IS ALIVE. THIS CELL IS DEAD.
AND YET I TOLD YOU THAT THESE TWO CELLS ARE
IN
EQUILIBRIUM WITH REGARD TO THEIR WATER POTENTIALS.
HOW IS THAT POSSIBLE IF ONE IS ALIVE AND OF
THEM IS
DEAD? ALL EQUILIBRIUM MEANS IS THAT THE WATER
POTENTIALS ARE THE SAME AND THAT THERE IS
NO NET
MOVEMENT OF WATER. SO, LET'S BEGIN BECAUSE
WE SAID
THAT THEY ARE AT EQUILIBRIUM. LET'S BEGIN
BY PUTTING
ON NUMBERS FOR THE WATER POTENTIAL FOR BOTH
THE XYLEM
AND THE PARENCHYMA CELL.
AND A REASONABLE NUMBER FROM BOTH CELLS IS
CONCENTRATION 8. CONCENTRATION 8 BARS FOR
THE WATER
POTENTIAL. NOW, LET'S LOOK AT THE OTHER COMPONENTS
WHICH MAKE THIS UP. FIRST OF ALL, THE PARENCHYMA
CELL
IS ALIVE. SO, BECAUSE IT IS ALIVE, IT IS GOING
TO BE
ABLE TO CONCENTRATE SOME SALTS AND ALSO GOING
ABLE TO HAVE A TURGOR PRESSURE. SO, A REASONABLE
VALUE FOR THE SALTS IN A PARENCHYMA CELL ARE
CONCENTRATION 3. PLUS 3, CONCENTRATION 3,
SORRY.
CONCENTRATION 3 FOR THE SALTS.
I HAVE THIS RIGHT OVER HERE. REASONABLE VALUE,
SORRY. REASONABLE VALUE TO THE SALTS IS CONCENTRATION
11 IN THE PARENCHYMA CELLS. THESE ARE CELLS
NOW WHICH
CAN CONCENTRATE THEIR SOLUTES BECAUSE OF THEIR
MEMBRANE. NOW, THIS IS WHERE THE CHANGE IN
YOUR
PERSPECTIVE HAS TO COME ABOUT. WHAT WOULD
BE
A REASONABLE VALUE FOR THE CONCENTRATION OF
THE SALTS
IN THE XYLEM? WOULD IT BE MORE NEGATIVE
OR LESS
NEGATIVE? LESS NEGATIVE. AND THE REASON IT
IS LESS
NEGATIVE, THAT IS THE CORRECT ANSWER, IS BECAUSE
THE
XYLEM CELL NOT HAVING A MEMBRANE CANNOT CONCENTRATE
SALTS. SO, THE SOLUTES IN THE XYLEM MORE OR
LESS
REFLECT WHAT THE SALT CONCENTRATION IS IN
THE SOIL, IN
THE WATER THAT IS COMING IN. IT CANNOT MAKE
THE SALTS
ANY MORE CONCENTRATED. AND SO FOR THE XYLEM,
A REASONABLE VALUE FOR THE SALT CONCENTRATION
IS, IT
IS NOT PURE, BUT IT IS CERTAINLY NOT AS HIGH
AS
A CELL, BUT CAN CONCENTRATE IT. AND NOW, IF
WE LOOK
AT THE LAST COMPONENT, PSI'S OF P, AND FOR
BOTH THE
PARENCHYMA AND THE XYLEM, BECAUSE WE HAVE
A LIVING
CELL WHICH IS CONCENTRATED SOLUTES WE CAN
NOW DEVELOP
A TURGOR PRESSURE. SO, REASONABLE VALUE FOR
THE
TURGOR PRESSURE WOULD BE 3. POSITIVE 3.
AND NOW, I AM GOING TO ASK YOU TO SWITCH YOUR
THINKING AGAIN. WHAT WOULD BE A REASONABLE
VALUE FOR
PSI'S OF P IN THE XYLEM? THIS CELL IS DEAD.
AND
BECAUSE IT IS DEAD IT CANNOT HAVE A TURGOR
PRESSURE.
AND THIS CELL IS ALSO UNDER TENSION. AND YOU
RECALL
LAST TIME THAT WE SAID PSI'S OF P CAN BE POSITIVE
IN
TERMS OF TURGOR PRESSURE OR NEGATIVE WHEN
THE WATER
COLUMN AS IT IS IN THE XYLEM IS BEING STRETCHED.
SO,
WHAT WOULD BE THE STATE OF PSI'S OF P IN THE
XYLEM?
A REASONABLE VALUE WOULD BE CONCENTRATION
7.5.
CONCENTRATION 7.5. SO, HERE WE HAVE A SITUATION
IN
WHICH WE HAVE A NEGATIVE WATER, A NEGATIVE
PSI'S OF P
IN A CELL DIRECTLY ADJACENT TO ONE WITH A
POSITIVE
PSI'S OF P. BUT, NOW IF YOU ADD THEM TOGETHER
PSI
EQUAL PSI'S OF PI PLUS PSI'S OF P YOU NOTICE
THAT THE
PSI'S COME OUT TO BE THE SAME. THESE CELLS
ARE AT
EQUILIBRIUM WITH REGARD TO THEIR WATER POTENTIAL,
BUT
NOT WITH REGARD TO THE COMPONENTS THAT MAKE
UP THE
WATER POTENTIAL. AND THAT IS WHY THE MOVEMENT
OF
WATER IS DETERMINED BY THIS NUMBER, THE WATER
POTENTIAL NUMBER. AND NOT BY THE NUMBER
WHICH YOU
MIGHT GET ONLY FOR THE TURGOR PRESSURE OR
FOR THE
SOLUTE POTENTIAL. FINALLY, BEFORE MOVING ON
I WANT TO
RETURN TO A PICTURE WHICH WE PUT UP ON THE
BOARD, AND
THAT PICTURE HAD TO DO WITH THE PLUMBING SYSTEM
OF THE
PLANT. JUST TO REVIEW A POINT THAT WE MENTIONED
LAST
TIME. IF WE LOOK AT THE PLUMBING SYSTEM OF
THE PLANT
NOW AND WE PUT ON VALUES FOR PSI, FOR THE
ATMOSPHERE
ON A DRY DAY WHEN THERE IS NOT MUCH WATER
IN THE
ATMOSPHERE, PSI MIGHT EQUAL CONCENTRATION
40. PRETTY
LOW NUMBER. IF WE LOOK AT THE PSI'S OF NOW
THE
TISSUES WHICH MAKE UP THE STEM, THE PSI FOR
THE LEAF
MIGHT EQUAL CONCENTRATION 8, NOT AN UNREASONABLE
VALUE. FOR THE STEM, PSI EQUALS PERHAPS CONCENTRATION
5. AND MAYBE FOR THE ROOTS PSI EQUALS MAYBE
CONCENTRATION 2 OR 3. CONCENTRATION 2 OR 3.
SO, WHAT
I WANT YOU TO NOTICE HERE AND THIS IS AN IMPORTANT
TAKE HOME MESSAGE, IS THAT, I WILL WRITE IT
OUT FOR
YOU. WATER IS MOVING ALONG A GRADIENT OF
INCREASINGLY
NEGATIVE PSI'S. SO IN A PLANT TRANSPIRATION
OCCURS,
WE SAID, BECAUSE OF THE PULL OF THE WATER
MOLECULES.
BECAUSE THIS PULLS THEM UP TO THE TOP, BUT
REALLY IT
OCCURS BECAUSE OF THIS GRADIENT INSIDE GOING
FROM THE
SOIL UP TO THE ATMOSPHERE WITH THE PLANT BEING
THE
SORT OF INTERMEDIATE PATHWAY THAT ALLOWS FOR
TRANSPIRATION TO OCCUR. HAVING TALKED A BIT
ABOUT THE
XYLEM I WANTED TO JUST MENTION TO YOU THE
OTHER
TRANSPORT SYSTEM THAT A NUMBER OF YOU HAVE
ALREADY
ASKED ME ABOUT. AND THAT IS THE PHLOEM. THE
XYLEM,
WHICH WE SAID IS THE PRIMARY TRANSPORT SYSTEM
FOR
WATER. THE PHLOEM IS THE PRIMARY TRANSPORT
SYSTEM FOR
SUGARS, FOR FIXED PHOTOSYNTHATE. I WOULD LIKE
TO JUST
BRIEFLY MENTION TO YOU HOW THE PHLOEM WORKS
AND THEN
WE CAN SPEND SOME TIME LOOKING AT SOME INTERESTING
PICTURES THAT I THINK YOU WILL ENJOY LOOKING
AT. SO,
LET'S LOOK AT THE MAIN ELEMENT OF THE PHLOEM,
WHICH IS
THE SIEVE ELEMENT.
BECAUSE THE XYLEM AND PHLOEM ARE
CLOSELY ASSOCIATED AS YOU REMEMBERED SEEING
IN BASKET
OR BUNDLES, NEXT TO IT WE WOULD HAVE A XYLEM
ELEMENT.
NOW, THE SUGARS ARE NOT MADE IN THE SIEVE
THEY ARE JUST TRANSPORTED IN THE SIEVE ELEMENT
SO THE
LAST COMPONENT WHICH WE HAVE TO PUT ON HERE
IS THE
LEAF CELL WHERE SUGARS ARE MADE. NOW BEFORE
WE GO
THROUGH THE STEPS TO INDICATE TO YOU HOW SUGARS
ARE
MOVED IN THE PHLOEM, I HAVE TO AGAIN POINT
OUT TO YOU
A COUPLE OF THINGS THAT YOU SHOULD BE AWARE
OF. AND
THOSE MAIN ASPECTS ARE THAT THE LEAF CELL
AND THE
SIEVE ELEMENT ARE BOTH ALIVE. BOTH HAVE MEMBRANES.
SO, LET'S NOW CONSIDER THE STEPS THAT ARE
INVOLVED IN
THE MOVEMENT OF SUGARS IN THE PHLOEM AND HOW
THE
PHLOEM WORKS TO TRANSPORT THE SUGARS. THE
FIRST THING
THAT HAPPENS IS THAT THE SUGARS ARE MOVED
INTO THE
PHLOEM.
AND THIS MOVEMENT INTO THE PHLOEM TAKES PLACE
ACROSS A MEMBRANE AND PEOPLE CALL THIS MOVEMENT
LOADING. AND BECAUSE THE PLACE THAT THEY
ARE LOADED
FROM IS A LEAF, THE LEAF IS CALLED A SOURCE.
SO,
SUGARS ARE MOVED INTO THE PHLOEM. WE HAVE
SUGARS,
THEY ARE LOADING. THE NEXT THING THAT HAPPENS
IS THAT
WE NOW HAVE MADE THE PSI OF THE PHLOEM MORE
NEGATIVE.
BECAUSE YOU HAVE MORE SOLUTES THERE NOW. MORE
NEGATIVE. THIS RESULTS IN WATER ENTERING THE
PHLOEM
AT THE TOP, AT THE SOURCE LET'S SAY. AND THE
WATER
COMES FROM THE XYLEM.
SO, IN THIS SITUATION AFTER THE
SUGARS ARE LOADED IN TO THE SIEVE ELEMENT
WE HAVE
WATER MOVING IN BECAUSE OF A CHANGE IN WATER
POTENTIAL.
BECAUSE THE PHLOEM IS ALIVE NOW, WE NOW
HAVE A INCREASE IN PRESSURE AT THE SITE OF
LOADING.
THE SITE OF LOADING.
AND THIS IS REALLY NOW HOW THE PHLOEM WORKS.
WHAT I WOULD LIKE YOU TO THINK ABOUT IS YOUR
GARDEN
HOSE THAT YOU MIGHT HAVE AT HOME. IN THE GARDEN
HOSE,
AT ONE END OF THE HOSE YOU HAVE THE PRESSURE,
WHICH IS
THE MAIN WATER LINE COMING IN. AND AT THE
OTHER END
YOU HAVE AN OPENING OF THE HOSE AND THE WATER
COMES
OUT, SO IF YOU COULD PUT A BLUE DROP OF DYE
IN THE
WATER AT THE PLACE THE HOSE IS ATTACHED TO
THE FAUCET,
YOU WOULD FIND THAT THAT BLUE DROP OF DYE
WOULD MOVE
DOWN. THE MOVEMENT IN THE PHLOEM OCCURS EXACTLY
THE
SAME WAY. THE INCREASE IN PRESSURE ESSENTIALLY
PUSHES
THE SUGARS DOWN AND THIS PUSHING OF THE SUGAR
DOWN IS
KNOWN AS MASS FLOW.
BUT, EVENTUALLY THE PHLOEM SHOULD
JUST CLOG UP. I MEAN YOU ARE JUST GOING TO
BE PUSHING
THE SUGARS DOWN AND EVENTUALLY THE WHOLE PHLOEM
SHOULD
BE FULL OF SUGAR. WELL, THE LAST STEP IN THE
PROCESS
IS THAT AT THE BASE, WHICH I HAVE DRAWN HERE.
AT THE
BASE, WE HAVE UNLOADING.
UNLOADING. AND, YOU COULD
VIEW THAT UNLOADING AT BEING A PARENCHYMA
CELL. IT
MIGHT BE, FOR EXAMPLE, A TUBER, LIKE A POTATO
TUBER,
OR IT MIGHT BE A ROOT, LIKE A BEET ROOT, WHICH
IS VERY
SWEET. THE SUGARS ARE NOW ACTIVELY MOVED ACROSS.
SUGARS MOVE INTO THE ADJACENT CELL. WELL,
AS SOON AS
THAT HAPPENS, THERE IS NO REASON FOR THE WATER
TO STAY
HERE ANY MORE. BECAUSE, THE WATER POTENTIAL
HAS
CHANGED AND THE WATER THEN MOVED BACK INTO
THE XYLEM.
AND THIS IS RESULTED IN A DROP IN THE PRESSURE.
RESULTS IN A REDUCTION OF THE PRESSURE AT
THE BASE.
SO, THE
PHLOEM WORKS BY ESSENTIALLY HAVING A PRESSURE
GRADIENT. PRESSURE IS HIGH AT THE TOP BECAUSE
SUGARS
ARE LOADED IN. WATER COMES IN AT THE TOP.
THAT WATER
CARRIES THE SUGARS DOWN TO THE BOTTOM. THE
SUGARS ARE
REMOVED. THE PRESSURE DROPS. IT IS THE SAME
AS YOUR
GARDEN HOSE. SO, THE PHLOEM IS UNDER PRESSURE.
ALL
OF YOU HAVE ACTUALLY EXPERIENCED THIS PRESSURE
WHETHER
YOU REALIZE IT OR NOT IN THE PHLOEM. IF YOU
CUT A
PLANT FROM THE STEM FOR A SMALL PERIOD OF
TIME THE
PLANT WILL BLEED. THIS BLEEDING IS THE LIQUID
WHICH
IS BEING PUSHED OUT IN THE PHLOEM. BUT, A
WAY THAT
PERHAPS MANY OF YOU HAVE EXPERIENCED THIS,
AND I WILL
SHOW YOU A PICTURE OF THIS IN A MOMENT,
IF WE CAN GET
THE COMPUTER TO WORK, IS THAT IF YOU WALK
DOWN STREETS
ON A WARM SUMMER DAY AND YOUR FEET STICK TO
THE
STREET, YOUR FEET IS STICKING TO MATERIAL
WHICH HAS
ACTUALLY COME OUT OF THE TREES AND HAS BEEN
EXUDED BY
THE TREES AS DROPLETS. AND, IT COLLECTS ON
THE
WINDSHIELDS OF YOUR CAR OR ON THE SIDEWALKS
AND IT IS
REALLY SUGAR. AND THAT IS WHY YOUR FEET STICK
TO IT.
NOW, HOW DOES THAT LIQUID GET OUT? THIS NEXT
SLIDE
WILL SHOW YOU HOW THE LIQUID GETS OUT. SO,
ONE OF THE
THINGS THAT HAPPENS IS THAT APHIDS LIKE TO
FEED ON
PLANTS AND APHIDS ARE VERY GOOD IN THE FACT
THAT THEY
CAN TAKE THEIR STYLET, THE THING THAT ACTUALLY
ALLOWS
THEM TO FEED ON THE PLANTS AND THEY CAN INSERT
IT
DIRECTLY INTO THE PHLOEM. SO HERE IS THE APHID
STYLET
WHICH IS ON THE OUTSIDE. THIS IS A CROSS SECTION
OF
A TREE. YOU ALL SHOULD RECOGNIZE THIS AS THE
BARK.
AND THE APHID IS ABLE, WE ARE NOT SURE HOW
IT IS ABLE
TO DO IT, TO INSERT ITS STYLET AND TO GO
DOWN THROUGH
ALL OF THE OLDER PHLOEM UNTIL IT REACHES THE
NEWEST
AND MOST ACTIVELY TRANSPORTING LAYER OF PHLOEM.
AND
HERE IS THE STYLET INSIDE OF A SIEVE ELEMENT.
NOW,
ONCE IN THIS SIEVE ELEMENT WE SAID THAT THE
MATERIAL
IN THE PHLOEM IS UNDER PRESSURE. AND IT IS
UNDER
PRESSURE BECAUSE OF THIS MASS FLOW. BECAUSE
OF THE
TURGOR PRESSURE. AND SO LIQUID IS ESSENTIALLY
PUMPED
UP THROUGH THE APHID. THE APHID JUST SITS
THERE AND
LET'S THE LIQUID GO THROUGH IT AND THE DROPLET
OF THE
LIQUID EXUDES THROUGH THE APHID AND THIS DROPLET
ACTUALLY CONTAINS THE SUGARS. THE APHID HAS
TAKEN OUT
SOME MATERIAL FROM THE LIQUID AS IT HAS GONE
THROUGH
ITS BODY BUT IT CAN'T TAKE OUT ALL OF THE
SUGARS SO
THE DROPLET WHICH FALLS ON TO THE GROUND OR
ON TO YOUR
WINDSHIELD STILL CONTAINS A LOT OF SUGARS
AND IS
ACTUALLY QUITE NUTRITIOUS. AND FOR THOSE OF
YOU WHO
HAVE A BIBLICAL OR A HISTORICAL BENT, IT IS
THOUGHT
THAT THESE MATERIALS ACTUALLY WERE WHAT
THE ISRAELITES
SUPPOSEDLY CALLED MANA. IT WAS THE SUGAR (INAUDIBLE)
WHICH CAME FROM THE APHIDS. FINALLY IN THE
LAST TEN
OR FIFTEEN MINUTES I WANT TO BRING UP A TOPIC
THAT I
GET MORE QUESTIONS ON FROM YOU THAN ANY OTHER
TOPIC IN
THIS CLASS. PROBABLY BECAUSE IT IS ONE THAT
HAS THE
GREATEST PRACTICAL VALUE, AT LEAST WHAT I
THINK OF IT.
AND THAT QUESTION IS, HERE IS THE PLANT THAT
IS
GROWING IN MY DORM. IT LOOKS REALLY CRUMMY.
WHAT IS
WRONG WITH THIS PLANT? CAN YOU HELP ME FIGURE
OUT
WHAT IS GOING ON SO I CAN MAKE MY PLANTS LOOK
BETTER
AND MY ROOMMATES WON'T THINK SO POORLY OF
ME. ALL
RIGHT? NOW, ASSUMING THAT THE PLANT DOESN'T
HAVE
A DISEASE LIKE A PATHOGEN OR A FUNGAL DISEASE
OR AN
INSECT THAT IS EATING IT. IN MOST CASES WHEN
PLANTS
LOOK BAD, IT IS BECAUSE THEY ARE SUFFERING
FROM
A DEFICIENCY OF SOME ESSENTIAL NUTRIENT OR
MINERAL
THAT THE SOIL PROVIDES. WE SAID WHEN WE TALKED
ABOUT
PLANTS, WE SAID THAT GIVEN WATER, CO2 AND
SUNLIGHT
THAT ALL PLANTS BASICALLY COULD LIVE AS LONG
AS THEY
ARE PROVIDED ONE ADDITIONAL COMPONENT OR COMPONENTS.
AND THOSE COMPONENTS ARE MINERALS FROM THE
SOIL. AND
SO, I WOULD LIKE TO TALK BRIEFLY ABOUT SOME
OF THESE
NUTRIENTS AND MINERALS. MANY OF THEM ARE ONES
THAT
YOU HAVE HEARD OF BEFORE. I WANT TO GIVE YOU
AN
EXAMPLE OF WHAT HAPPENED. LET'S TALK ABOUT
A PLANT
WHICH YOU BUY IN A NURSERY AND THE PLANT LOOKS
REALLY
GOOD FOR A PERIOD OF TIME. AND THEN AS THE
PLANT
GROWS IT STARTS TO SHOW SOME SIGNS OF LOOKING
POORLY.
THOSE POOR SIGNS ARE BECAUSE IT IS PROBABLY
MISSING AN
ESSENTIAL NUTRIENT OR ESSENTIAL MINERAL. NOW
WHAT WE
WANT TO DO IS TO TALK ABOUT WHAT THE ESSENTIAL
NUTRIENTS OR MINERALS ARE THAT THE PLANT GETS
FROM THE
SOIL. AND THE FIRST THING WE SHOULD SAY IS
THAT AN
ESSENTIAL MINERAL OR PROBABLY THE BEST WORD
IS
ELEMENT, AS YOU WILL SEE IN THE CHEMICAL SENSE.
ESSENTIAL ELEMENT, WHEN TOTALLY ABSENT WILL
PREVENT A
PLANT FROM COMPLETING ITS LIFE CYCLE. BUT,
IT IS VERY
RARE THAT AN ELEMENT IS TOTALLY ABSENT. IT
USUALLY IS
PRESENT IN SUBOPTIMAL AMOUNTS. AND THE SUBOPTIMAL
AMOUNT ALLOWS THE PLANT TO GROW BUT THE PLANT
LOOKS
SICK. SO SUBOPTIMAL AMOUNTS
RESULT IN WHAT WE KNOW OF
AS DEFICIENCY DISEASES.
AND THIS IS THE MOST COMMON
SORTS OF THINGS THAT YOU HAVE IN YOUR DORM
PLANTS.
THE ESSENTIAL ELEMENT IS NOT TOTALLY ABSENT
BUT IT IS
PRESENT IN SUBOPTIMAL AMOUNTS AND THE PLANT
JUST CAN'T
MANAGE THAT WELL. LET'S TALK ABOUT WHAT THESE
ESSENTIAL NUTRIENTS OR MINERALS ARE. THERE
AREN'T
THAT MANY, SURPRISINGLY. BUT THEY ARE PROBABLY
BEST
APPROACHED BY ASKING ABOUT THE AMOUNT IN WHICH
THEY
ARE NEEDED. BIOLOGISTS, AND A LOT OF THIS
WORK IN
DESCRIBING AND FINDING OUT WHAT THESE ESSENTIAL
ELEMENTS WERE OR ARE WAS DONE HERE AT BERKELEY
IN THE
30'S AND THE 40'S AND ALSO AT DAVIS BY A MAN
NAMED HOAGLAND. LET'S TALK ABOUT THE ESSENTIAL
ELEMENTS. THEY ARE USUALLY DIVIDED INTO TWO
GROUPS.
THOSE THAT ARE NEEDED IN LARGE AMOUNTS, SUCH
AS 1 TO 4
PERCENT OF THE DRY WEIGHT OF A PLANT. AND
THESE THAT
ARE NEEDED IN SUCH LARGE AMOUNTS ARE KNOWN
AS MACRO
NUTRIENTS.
AND THIS IS CONTRASTED WITH THOSE NEEDED
IN SMALL AMOUNTS. OFTEN THE AMOUNTS ARE VANISHINGLY
SMALL, TINY, TINY AMOUNTS. AND THESE ARE KNOWN
AS
MICRONUTRIENTS.
IN GENERAL, THE MICRONUTRIENTS ARE
ELEMENTS WHICH ARE INVOLVED AS COFACTORS,
COFACTORS ON
MANY ENZYMATIC CREATIONS SOMETIMES INVOLVED
IN
ELECTRON TRANSPORT.
SO THEY ARE NEEDED IN TINY
AMOUNTS BECAUSE THEY ARE RECYCLED, REUSED
OVER AND
OVER AGAIN. LET'S TALK NOW ABOUT WHAT THESE
TWO
CLASSES INCLUDE. AND LET'S FIRST LOOK AT THE
MACRO
NUTRIENTS AND WHAT ELEMENTS ARE CONSIDERED
TO BE NEEDS
IN VERY LARGE AMOUNTS. ASIDE FROM CARBON,
HYDROGEN
AND OXYGEN, WHICH ARE OBVIOUSLY NEEDED FOR
ALL LIVING
SYSTEMS, WE NEED PHOSPHORUS, POTASSIUM,
NITROGEN,
SULFUR, CALCIUM, IRON AND MAGNESIUM. THESE
ARE THE
MACRO NUTRIENTS. THEY ARE NEEDED IN HIGH AMOUNTS.
AND AN EASY WAY OF REMEMBERING THIS, IF YOU
WANT TO
REMEMBER IT, IS "SEE HOPKIN'S CAFE MANAGER"
SEE
HOPKIN'S CAFE MANAGER. THESE ARE THE MACRO
NUTRIENTS.
THIS IS AS OPPOSED TO THE MICRONUTRIENTS WHICH
INCLUDE; COPPER, ZINC, MOLYBDENUM, BORON,
CHLORIDE.
THESE ARE GENERALLY NEEDED IN TINY, TINY AMOUNTS.
AND
IN SOME PLANTS, AS THE EXAMPLE I HAVE UP HERE,
THERE
ARE SOMETIMES OTHER ELEMENTS WHICH ARE NEEDED
SPECIFICALLY FOR THAT PLANT. FOR EXAMPLE,
SOME PLANTS
NEED SILICA OR SILICON. AND THIS IS A GOOD
EXAMPLE UP
HERE OF A PLANT THAT YOU HAVE ALREADY SEEN
IN THE LAB.
THIS IS EQUISETUM OR SCOURING REED. AND THE
REASON IT
FEELS SO GRITTY IS BECAUSE IT HAS INCLUDED
SILICA IN
ITS CELL WALLS. SO SILICA IS NECESSARY FOR
THIS
PLANT. BUT IN GENERAL IT IS NOT A NUTRIENT
NEEDED BY
MOST PLANTS. NOW, THESE MACRO/MICRONUTRIENTS,
AS I
SAID, ARE NEEDED FOR A PLANT TO COMPLETE ITS
LIFE
CYCLE. IF YOU HAVE A PLANT YOU'RE WONDERING,
WHAT
ELEMENT IS MISSING FROM ITS REGIME? WHY IS
THIS
PLANT SUFFERING FROM A DEFICIENCY OR IS IT
SUFFICIENTING FROM A DEFICIENCY DISEASE? WHAT
YOU
WANT TO DO IS TAKE A LOOK AT YOUR PLANT AND
ASK
YOURSELF ARE THE YOUNGEST LEAVES IN BAD SHAPE
OR ARE
THE OLDEST LEAVES IN BAD SHAPE? SO LET'S TAKE
A LOOK
AT A PLANT, WHICH IS GROWING IN A POT HERE,
AND LET'S
JUST SAY WHEN YOU BOUGHT THE PLANT YOU HAD
ONE SET OF
LEAVES ON THE PLANT. SO, WE WILL JUST CALL
THESE
LEAVES 1. NOW YOU HAVE LET THE PLANT GO FOR
SOME TIME
AND NOW YOU HAVE TWO SETS OF LEAVES ON THE
PLANT.
HERE IS THE LEAF 1. THEY ARE THE SAME LEAVES
THAT
WERE PRESENT WHEN YOU BOUGHT IT. NOW WE HAVE
LEAF 2'S
WHICH HAVE BEEN PRODUCED SINCE YOU HAD THE
PLANT. AND
NOW LET'S LET THE PLANT GROW A LITTLE BIT
LONGER. AND
NOW WE HAVE 3 SETS OF LEAVES.
HERE IS OUR FIRST THING
WHICH WAS PRESENT WHEN YOU BOUGHT THE PLANT.
THE
SECOND AND THEN THE THIRD, WHICH WERE PRODUCED
WHEN
YOU HAD THE PLANT IN YOUR DORM ROOM. NOW,
IF YOU HAVE
A PLANT IN YOUR DORM ROOM AND IT IS NOT LOOKING
GOOD
THE FIRST THING YOU WANT TO ASK YOURSELF IS;
WHICH
LEAVES LOOK THE WORST? DO THE OLDER LEAVES
LOOK BAD
OR DO THE NEWER LEAVES LOOK BAD? AND BY DECIDING
WHICH LEAF LOOKS BAD YOU CAN BEGIN TO NARROW
DOWN
WHICH NUTRIENT OR WHICH MINERAL MIGHT BE MISSING
FROM
THE SOIL. NOW, HOW IS THAT USEFUL? AND HOW
IS THAT
EXPLAINED? IT IS EXPLAINED IN THE FOLLOWING
WAY; LET'S SAY YOU HAD A NUTRIENT AND THIS
NUTRIENT RAN OUT OF THE SOIL. IT WAS PRESENT
IN THE
BEGINNING AND AS THE PLANT GREW THE NEWER
LEAVES
STARTED LOOKING BAD. WHAT WE CAN CONCLUDE
THEN IS
THAT THAT NUTRIENT THAT YOU PROVIDED THE PLANT
ONCE IT
IS USED BY THE PLANT IT IS ESSENTIALLY TRAPPED
IN THE
SPACE THAT IT IS USED. IT IS IMMOBILE. IT
IS TRAPPED
IN THE PLACE THAT IT WAS USED. THEREFORE,
AS THE
PLANT CONTINUES TO GROW AND THE NUTRIENT IS
EXHAUSTED
FROM THE SOIL THAT ELEMENT CAN'T MOVE. IT
IS TRAPPED
WHERE IT WAS FIRST PUT. AND THIS IS AN EXAMPLE
OF
CALCIUM. FOR EXAMPLE, ONCE CALCIUM IS USED
BY THE
PLANT IT CAN'T BE MOVED. THIS IS AS OPPOSED
TO
A SITUATION WHERE YOUR PLANT WITH TREE LEAVES,
IF YOU
LOOK AT IT, NOW THE OLDER LEAVES LOOK BAD.
AND THE
NEWER LEAVES LOOK JUST GREAT OR THEY LOOK
BETTER THAN
THE ONES ON THE BOTTOM. IN THIS PARTICULAR
CASE WHAT
THIS IS TELLING YOU IS THAT THIS NUTRIENT
IS MOBILE.
IT IS ABLE TO MOVE FROM THE LEAVES THAT IT
WAS IN
ORIGINALLY TO NEWER LEAVES. IT IS MOBILE.
SO, IN THE
MOBILE CASE THE NEWER LEAVES LOOK BEST.
AND FINALLY
BEFORE I SHOW YOU SOME SLIDES, I WANTED TO
MENTION TO
YOU THAT VERY OFTEN IF YOU GO TO THE STORE
TO BUY FERTILIZER FOR PLANTS YOU WILL FIND
A NUMBER
WRITTEN ON THE FERTILIZER PACKAGE. THE NUMBER
MIGHT
BE 16, 12, 8 OR IT COULD BE 3, 9, 16. THESE
ARE CODES
NOT FOR THE NURSERY TO COMMUNICATE BETWEEN
THEMSELVES
BUT TO TELL YOU WHAT THE RATIO OF CERTAIN
MACRO
NUTRIENTS ARE IN THE FERTILIZER THAT YOU ARE
BUYING.
SO, THESE STAND FOR POTASSIUM, PHOSPHORUS
AND
NITROGEN. THEIR CONCENTRATION IN THE FERTILIZERS.
AND THIS WILL BE AN INDICATION BECAUSE CERTAIN
FERTILIZERS YOU BUY FOR CERTAIN PLANTS DEPENDING
UPON
THE RATIO OF THESE MACRO NUTRIENTS. LET ME
SHOW YOU
NOW SOME SLIDES TO ILLUSTRATE TO YOU THESE
VARIOUS
MINERAL DEFICIENCY SYMPTOMS. THIS IS THE WAY
THESE
EXPERIMENTS ARE RUN. AND YOU ARE GOING TO
DO THIS IN
LAB THE WEEK AFTER NEXT. YOU ARE GOING TO
HAVE
A SERIES OF JARS AND INTO THESE JARS NUTRIENTS
ARE
EITHER ADDED OR THE PLANT IS GROWN IN THE
JAR WITH
A NUTRIENT LACKING. HERE IS THE CONTROL PLANT
OVER
HERE IN A COMPLETE SOLUTION OF MICRO AND MACRO
NUTRIENTS AND THEN WE HAVE DIFFERENT NUTRIENTS
WHICH
ARE MISSING AS WE GO FURTHER DOWN. HERE IS
AN EXAMPLE
OF MINUS POTASSIUM, WHEN POTASSIUM RUNS OUT.
NOTICE
IN THIS PARTICULAR CASE THAT IT IS THE NEWEST
LEAVES
WHICH LOOK GREAT. SO THIS MEANS THAT THIS
NUTRIENT
WHEN IT RAN OUT WAS A MOBILE NUTRIENT. IT
WAS MOVED
UP FROM THE OLDER LEAVES UP TO THE TOP OF
THE PLANT.
HERE IS ANOTHER EXAMPLE OF A NUTRIENT WHICH
IS MOBILE,
MAGNESIUM. IT IS MOVED IN THE OLDEST LEAVES,
WHICH
LOOK BAD, UP TO THE NEWEST LEAVES ON THE TOP.
HERE
ARE NOW PLANTS LACKING CALCIUM. IN THIS PARTICULAR
CASE WE SAID CALCIUM WAS NOT MOBILE, IT IS
IMMOBILE.
SO, THE OLDER LEAVES, THEY DON'T LOOK GREAT
BUT THEY
AT LEAST ARE GREEN. WHEREAS, THE NEWER LEAVES
ARE THE
ONES WHICH SHOW THE EFFECTS FIRST. SO, LOOK
AT YOUR
PLANTS IN THAT WAY. HERE ARE PLANTS NOW WHICH
ARE
MINUS IRON. IRON IS A FUNNY NUTRIENT. IT IS
SAID TO
BE SEMI-MOBILE. SO THAT IF YOU LOOK AT A PLANT
SUFFERING IRON DEFICIENCY, AND THIS IS A
VERY COMMON
TRAIT HERE IN CALIFORNIA, THE VEIN IS GREEN
BUT THE
BLADE ITSELF IS WHITE. NOW HERE IS SOME PROBLEMS
THAT
FARMERS HAVE. IF YOU GROW TOMATOES AND THE
SOIL IS
LOW IN COPPER OR ZINC, THESE TWO MICRONUTRIENTS,
YOU
GREATLY AFFECT THE FORM OF THE PLANT. HERE
IS
BROCCOLI. BROCCOLI GROWN IN SOIL WHICH IS
LACKING OR
VERY LOW IN MOLYBDENUM DOES NOT PRODUCE THE
BROCCOLI
FLOWERS AND IT IS SO CALLED WHIP TAIL BROCCOLI.
HERE
ARE PEAS NOW WHICH ARE GROWN IN SOIL WITH
A TOO LOW OF
LEVEL OF COPPER. REMEMBER COPPER IS A MICRONUTRIENT.
AND IN THIS CASE THE OVULES FAIL TO DEVELOP.
HERE ARE
CARNATIONS NOW GROWN MINUS BORON. THIS IS
A BIG
PROBLEM FOR CALIFORNIA. BECAUSE WE GROW A
LOT OF
CARNATIONS. YOU WANT TO MAKE SURE THAT YOU
HAVE
ENOUGH BORON OR IN THE MEDIUM. HERE ARE APPLES
GROWN
IN A BORON FREE MEDIUM IN WHICH CASE YOU CAN
SEE THE
APPLES ALSO ARE NOT PARTICULARLY GREAT SHAPE.
GRAPES
MINUS BORON, YOU CAN AFFECT THEM. SO, WHAT
I WANT TO
POINT OUT TO YOU IS THAT WE HAVE THESE VARIOUS
DEFICIENCY DISEASES. THEY CAN EASILY BE LOOKED
AT
DEPENDING UPON HOW YOU ANALYZE THE TISSUE.
NOW,
FINALLY WHAT I WANT TO SAY TO YOU ABOUT THE
EXAM IS
THAT THE MIDTERM HAS 35 QUESTIONS ON IT. SO,
MOST OF
THEM ARE WORTH 3 POINTS. THERE ARE 2 POINTS
EACH.
AND I WANT TO JUST TELL YOU THE BIGGEST MISTAKE
THE
STUDENTS MAKE ABOUT THE QUESTIONS. I HAVE
ALREADY
ENCOUNTERED THIS IN TALKING TO SOME OF YOU
ABOUT THE
SAMPLE OF QUESTIONS THAT ARE POSTED ON THE
WEB PAGE.
THE BIGGEST MISTAKE YOU MAKE IS NUMBER 1,
YOU DON'T
READ ALL OF THE ANSWERS FIRST. WE ASK YOU
CHOOSE THE
BEST ANSWER. NOT THE ANSWER WHICH CONTAINS
SOME
CORRECT INFORMATION, BUT THE ANSWER WHICH
CONTAINS ALL
OF THE CORRECT INFORMATION. SO, READ ALL OF
THE
ANSWERS FIRST. SECONDLY, THE OTHER MISTAKE
YOU MAKE
AND IT HAPPENS EVERY YEAR, IS YOU READ TOO
MUCH INTO
THE QUESTION. IF THE QUESTION SAYS; IT IS
A SEED WITH
A POORLY DEVELOPED EMBRYO, YOU KNOW THAT IT
HAS A SEED
COAT. YOU KNOW THAT DOUBLE FERTILIZATION OCCURRED.
DON'T EXPECT TO KNOW WHETHER OR NOT THAT IS
PARTHENOCARPIC OR WHETHER THERE IS SOMETHING
WHICH HAS
HAPPENED TO VIVIPARY. THAT IS NOT STATED IN
THE
QUESTION. ONLY READ WHAT IS IN THE QUESTION.
DON'T
ADD MORE TO THE QUESTION. DON'T READ MORE
INTO THE
QUESTION BECAUSE IF YOU DO, YOU WILL MAKE
IT HARDER
FOR YOURSELF. I THINK THAT THE QUESTIONS ARE
PRETTY
STRAIGHTFORWARD. AND I THINK THAT IF YOU
UNDERSTAND ALTERNATION OF GENERATIONS, IF
YOU ARE ABLE
TO UNDERSTAND THE LIFE CYCLE PRETTY WELL,
HOW THE
ENDODERMIS WORKS, YOU SHOULD DO PRETTY WELL
ON THIS
EXAM. SECONDARY AND PRIMARY GROWTH ARE THE
OTHER
FEATURES WE WILL STRESS. SO, WHAT I WANT YOU
TO DO IS
TO COME TO THE REVIEW SESSION. ARE THEIR QUESTIONS
DECIDED TO TRICK YOU? NOT INTENTIONALLY. I
WANT YOU
TO KNOW THAT. OKAY. SO I WILL SEE YOU GUYS
ALL ON
TUESDAY NIGHT.