LEVI: My name is Levi.
And I am one of the guides in
the Impenetrable Forest.
Now this here Bwindi Forest is
the forest very special for
being a home to critically
endangered mountain gorillas.
Yeah, we are going to start the
gorilla tracking journey.
And which will take us possibly
the whole day into
the Bwindi Impenetrable Forest,
an island within the
communities.
When you look at the map of
Africa, you get Uganda, then
bordering Congo, DRC, that is
the location of Bwindi.
We started in an open place, and
you can see here where we
are going, this is a
primary forest now.
DR. RICHARD CARROLL: Mountain
gorillas only exist on that
patch of habitat in the
mountains of the Virungas.
And they only exist in those
three countries, in just a
real small area.
They're not in zoos.
The zoo population of gorillas
are western lowland gorillas,
for the most part.
So this is it.
Their whole survival rests in
this patch of habitat that's
really isolated on these
mountaintops.
And there's only 720 of them
that exist in the world.
And they're all in this
area And it's
surrounded by a sea of humans.
LEVI: These mountain gorillas,
they are the great apes.
Human beings are also
the great apes.
The behaviors, the way they
behave when you look at them,
it's very, very marvelous.
They behave like people,
like human beings.
DR. RICHARD CARROLL: The first
time that you see a gorilla
through that veil of vegetation,
and he's looking
at you, and you look at him, and
you catch him in the eye,
and it's really clear that
there's a species connection.
We share a good part of our
genes, and you can see so much
of human behavior reflected or
derived from behavior of some
of the great apes.
LEVI: Mountain Gorillas
are 99% vegetarians.
Most of the food they
eat is leaves, bark
of trees, and fruits.
But 1% to make 100% of their
food is the ants.
So they change that diet
by eating ants,
actually to get proteins.
DR. RICHARD CARROLL: Opening
up the forest with coffee
plantations and logging
companies from Yugoslavia and
the French to Spanish to Dutch,
when they came in to
get that very valuable hardwood
out of the forest.
And of course, they're
bringing labor
from around the country.
So the population demographics
changed drastically.
So it's a very dense human
population with agriculture
bordering right up
to the parks.
LEVI: Lifespan of these mountain
gorillas is 50 years,
here in the wild.
But when the people started
settling around, then they
started clearing their
habitat for farming.
And also killing them.
Then they started becoming
very few.
Their numbers started
reducing.
Bwindi has about half of
the world's population,
which is about 340.
DR. RICHARD CARROLL: Bushmeat
refers to the capture and
killing of wild game for
commercial purposes.
They set snares on wildlife
trails that are totally
indiscriminate.
And even gorillas get
caught in them.
It'll tighten around its
hand or foot, and
the hand will atrophy.
So there's a lot of mutilation
and mortality from these
snares that are ubiquitous
around the forest.
And so the real threats right
now are human population
growth, it's the main threat.
Insecurity.
This area has been an
area of political
instability for a long time.
In all three countries,
there's been national
conflicts and regional
conflicts.
Uganda went through years of the
most horrible dictatorship
under Idi Amin, where wildlife
populations were decimated
throughout the country.
Rwanda went through
a genocide.
DRC has been at war since
1993 and before.
Millions of people died
in those wars.
Millions of people displaced.
It goes on to right now.
LEVI: OK, this side where we
are overlooking is Bwindi
Impenetrable Forest.
And as you go to the slope,
on this side is DRC.
And where you see across, you
see the bananas, that's the
village on the Uganda side.
But if you go beyond, then
you are in the DRC.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
LEVI: When we get to the
gorillas, we will have a sound
that we make.
We imitate their vocalization
so that they come down, they
know we are friendly, we have
no problem to them.
And that's Sowendi That
vocalization is [GROWLING ].
Like cause they also
communicate.
They live with families,
headed by silverbacks.
And having only one dominant
silverback, only one lead
male, who leads the
whole family.
DR. RICHARD CARROLL: The first
time I saw mountain gorillas
was in the Bwindi National
Park in Uganda.
And when we got up there, the
silverback gave us a really
great sideways sort of false
charge to let us know that he
was the boss.
Interestingly, that silverback
was missing a hand from a
snare wound.
What you need to do when you're
around gorillas is do
everything you can do
to look submissive.
Slowly go down to the ground,
pretend like you're feeding on
leaves, and sort of act like a
monkey, which comes sort of
naturally to some
of us anyways.
But running is the
wrong thing.
LEVI: If one dominant
silverback
start getting weak--
he's very weak, he cannot
protect the family--
he leaves the powers to the
youngest, who is very strong
enough to defend the family.
But sometime they can fight.
We don't have any evidence
that they have
ever fought to death.
But they can fight and
harm each other.
During the fighting of some
primates, they kill those
babies so that they can now have
the females in the estrus
period and start the mating
process and also
produce their own.
That's how we get new groups,
new families started.
We are communicating
with the trackers.
They are just in front of
us some few meters.
When you see the trackers that
means the gorillas are near.
The guys have already done
a wonderful job of
locating them to us.
MEDI: He has located
the gorillas.
They have started from where
they left them yesterday.
The smell also helps them.
Mostly the smell from the
armpits of the silverback.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
LEVI: When you get to the
gorillas, we branch into the
bush to directly where
the gorillas are.
As I told you that they very,
very closely related to us,
and we are visiting them
everyday, so at times we also
monitor to see maybe they could
get like some germs,
some bacterias, parasites
from human beings.
The jungle here is very dense.
So you may be asking yourselves,
how do we know the
population.
We found the last night
nests, which are here.
And then when we want to know
group categories, we have to
look at the dung.
For the babies it's small.
The juveniles, also
small a bit.
Then adult female also
small somehow.
But for the silverback
it's big.
And as he said that when
trackers are following, they
have got signs they
go looking for.
So for them they were looking
for the feedings like these
ones, which they have
left behind.
DR. RICHARD CARROLL: There's
only 720 of them that
exist in the world.
And they're all in this area.
And there's pressures
for other resources.
With minerals, [INAUDIBLE],
gold, oil and gas, it has huge
threats for the future.
What happened in the Virunga
National Park in DRC, where 10
gorillas were killed was a
combination of an economic and
a political statement.
It wasn't poaching by local
communities for food or for
subsistence.
The tensions are still there
from the conflict between
Rwanda and DRC.
There's many rebel factions
that are hiding
out in those forests.
Supplying charcoal to the
cities, transporting it to do
the population centers was a
multimillion dollar operation
that was helping to support a
lot of these rebel factions
and keep them in business,
allow them to function.
And they were working through
the local population.
It's also a sign the presence of
conservation was getting on
their nerves, so they were not
able to operate with impunity.
So they were making a sign.
You guys care so much about
these mountain gorillas, well
we're gonna make a sign that's
really going to have
an impact on you.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
MEDI: So some gorillas are
going up in the tree.
[GROWLING]
[GORILLA NOISES]
DR. RICHARD CARROLL: Gorillas
really hold a real
fascination, I think,
from history.
All of us grew up with Tarzan
movies and King Kong.
And they've always
held a mystery.
And they're always so close
to humans, but the
image of being so strong.
And often a mistaken image of
them being so ferocious.
[GROWLING]
DR. RICHARD CARROLL: A
silverback gorilla is big.
It weighs 400 pounds and has big
canines and a huge jaw to
defend his harem.
So he's defending his
resources, as well.
That exists in our primate
memory that
carries on to today.
-He's picking his nose.
-He is.
He just ate it.
DR. RICHARD CARROLL: Gorillas
live in pretty low density.
There's aggression between the
silverbacks trying to compete
for females and things
like that.
But there's enough room.
We are in such high population
densities
in a shrinking planet.
Right now with the amount of
people on this planet we need
two planets to support us.
And it's going to lead
to more and more
conflict over resources.
We're producing climate change
that's going to change those
resources and make
them scarcer.
All the time it's more people.
And I felt from the beginning
that if we as humans can't
protect our closest family
relatives then we really will
fail as a species ourselves.
[MUSIC PLAYING]