I'm happy to follow two guys who speak kind
of funny. (Laughter.)
What a pleasure to be here with Ambassador
Mike Moore, former prime minister, who is
a great person and a terrific leader. And
I am so grateful to him for the leadership
of New Zealand, a country I've had a chance
to visit several times beginning way back
when I was in the United States Navy; and
also my friend Bob Carr, and thank you, Mr.
Minister, for being here with us. I told him
today I have not yet been lucky enough to
get down under, but I am sure to get there
very, very soon and I look forward to it.
Really privileged to have these two gentlemen
supporting this endeavor, and I'm particularly
grateful to the Pew Charitable Trust and to
National Geographic. Terry, thank you so much
for making this available tonight. Everybody's
favorite magazine; I think we all grew up
with it and it just stays extraordinary. And
tonight you'll share in a film which will
really underscore the importance of everything
that that magazine tries to impart to all
of us and has stood for all of these years.
I am a child of the ocean in many ways. From
the first moment when I was a kid up at Cape
Cod dipping my toes into Buzzards Bay looking
for clams, literally a three or four year-old
being shown the wonders of the ocean, shrimping
and other things, to a time when we used to
gather mussels in the evening and an hour
later cook them and enjoy an incredible meal.
Today, very difficult to find mussels anywhere
in that area.
So I've watched the transition. I've seen
it. As a senator I was privileged to bring
efforts before the United Nations with Ted
Stevens to end driftnet fishing, and also
to try to work hard to preserve through a
number of fisheries bills - I think I rewrote
the Magnuson Fisheries Act at least three
or four times - as we tried to get the balance
right and protect our fisheries.
I've seen the struggle with respect to invasive
species and I have seen this fragile ecosystem
change before our very eyes, whether it's
a problem of acidification, a problem of pollution
and development, a problem of ice melt and
potential ecosystem collapse, to the rise
of the sea levels, which is happening in various
parts of the world more so than elsewhere,
to the overfishing that takes place in almost
every single fishery on the face of the planet.
We call this beautiful planet that we are
privileged to inhabit for a short period of
time, we call it Earth, but it could well
have been called Ocean because three-quarters
of it is ocean. And the oceans are responsible
in many ways for life because of the cycle
of rain and humidity and all of the protein
and life that comes from the ocean. So we
can't be casual about it. We can't be casual
about it. And it is clear that we have an
enormous challenge ahead of us as we face
the extraordinary excess that we see with
respect to each of those issues that I talked
about: energy policy that results in acidification,
the bleaching of coral, the destruction of
species, the change in the Arctic because
of the ice melt, and the change in the krill,
the population of whales. The entire system
is interdependent, and we toy with that at
our peril.
So it is vital that we've come to this moment
where we begin to see that this is not just
an environmental issue. This is a security
issue. It's an economic security issue. It's
a national security issue. And it is in many
ways a challenge with respect to energy security
and our approach to energy policy, and ultimately
it is a challenge to our commitment to science
and facts and ultimately our basic sense of
faith and what we believe in and our responsibility
as human beings on this planet.
So climate change is coming back in a sense
as a serious international issue because people
are experiencing it firsthand. The science
is screaming at us, literally, demanding that
people in positions of public responsibility
at least exercise the so-called "precautionary
principle" to balance the equities and not
knowing completely the outcomes at least understand
what is happening and take steps to prevent
potential disaster. I've often said to people,
"What is the worst that could happen to you
if you make a decision to put good energy
policy in place and respond to what the science
and the facts are telling us?" Well, the worst
that can happen to you if you would employ
a lot of people in alternative and renewable
and clean energy; you would have less hospitalizations,
cleaner air, more children with less asthma;
and you would create an enormous number of
jobs by moving to those new energy possibilities
and policies and infrastructure. That's the
worst that can happen to you.
What if the other people are wrong and we
are right; what's the worst that can happen?
The destruction of the ecosystem as we live
with it today. So that's really what's on
the line, and I'm here to tell you that, proudly,
President Obama has put this agenda back on
the front burner where it belongs, that he
has in his Inauguration Address and in his
State of the Union Address and in the policies
he's working on now said we are going to try
to exercise leadership because of its imperatives.
So I want to thank the Pew Foundation and
National Geographic for joining in this imperative.
We need to try to pass the Law of the Sea.
We attempted to do that earlier and we will
continue to try to press for that. But most
important when it comes to the Ross Sea and
Antarctica, we're not going to wait for a
crisis before we take action. I think we're
making a smart choice now. We're proud to
join with New Zealand and Australia, two countries
that have an extraordinary understanding of
the sea and commitment to protecting it and
who have been great stewards.
The Ross Sea, as we heard from Karen earlier,
is a natural laboratory. And we disrespect
it at our peril, as we do the rest of the
ocean. The environment there is so extreme,
as we know, that it's difficult to live as
a penguin or a killer whale or a seal, but
they've adapted. And in their adaptation,
we've learned what a remarkably diverse and
productive ecosystem it is. We've learned
from the scientists who go down there at McMurdo
Station and spend those critical months trying
to research it and understand it.
Now, you've probably never asked a waiter
- any of you - for a nice Antarctic tooth
fish, I suspect. You're probably more used
to ordering it as a Chilean sea bass. But
American researchers working in the Ross Sea
have actually discovered that the tooth fish
produces a special antifreeze protein, and
whenever ice crystals form in the fish's cells,
these proteins latch onto them and actually
ferry the ice out of the body. That discovery
has launched a whole new scientific field
of structural biology, and it's helping us
to think now about other adaptations to extreme
environment in new ways. It also has commercial
applications. Think about perhaps fluffier
bread or ice cream that stays frozen without
ice crystals in it. These are real possibilities.
Another group of researchers from my home
state of Massachusetts have done remarkable
work studying the physiology of seals as they
dive in the Ross Sea. And they've actually
learned - they've helped unlock our understanding
of hypoxia, which is a condition that develops
when the body is deprived of oxygen. As a
result of that, they have actually developed
a treatment that has dealt with hypoxic newborns
and saved more than 10,000 babies a year.
That's what we can learn, as well as many,
many other things that we could talk about.
So imagine the possibilities of these discoveries
that await us if we can encourage our innovators
and our inventors to put our shoulder to the
wheel and have the maximum preservation of
the opportunity of that laboratory.
That's why it is so important for the Commission
for the Conservation of Antarctic Marine Living
Resources to approve our proposals to establish
this Marine Protected Area - and you've heard
all the comparisons from Ambassador Mike Moore
about roughly the size of this, that, several
Californias, Alaska. It's extraordinary. It
will be quite simply the largest protected
area in the world.
Now, I know the value of that, and the reason
I know the value of that is I was the author
in the Senate of the Marine Sanctuary called
Stellwagen Bank off our cape. And we have
seen what that preservation has been able
to do. Imagine what this would do as a baseline
study for what happens to the species that
assemble in that area as we preserve a component
of it as a managed fishery and the rest of
it as a baseline laboratory for all of this
research.
We also support the important proposal of
Australia, the EU, and France that they have
developed for protection of East Antarctica.
So my friends, I'd just summarize by saying
this to you: Antarctica is a collection of
superlatives. It is the highest, the coldest,
the windiest, the driest, the most pristine,
and the most remote place on Earth. And it
has beguiled humankind for centuries as people
have sought to understand it. Starting in
the 1700s, explorers struggled to chart its
contours and to cross its desolation without
any guarantee ever of a safe return. And still
today, curiosity and sheer doggedness are
what draw people from all around the world
to explore its southernmost shore.
So we signed the Antarctic Treaty in 1959.
For those who doubt the benefit of treaties,
go look at what we have achieved there, not
to mention so many others. The world has shown
that we can work together to ensure that Antarctica
remains a place devoted to peace and devoted
to expanding the human understanding of this
fragile planet that we live on. This is one
of the last places we could do this, and I
think we owe it to ourselves to make it happen.
So I thank you for coming here tonight. I
noticed coming in here there were a number
of empty wine glasses on the tables, so I
know you didn't waste your time completely
before I got here. (Laughter.) But I hope
this movie will inspire you. I hope the support
of our wonderful friends who understand the
ocean as well as any people on this planet
and who have worked to preserve it, I hope
that will inspire all of you to connect to
the rest of America and the rest of the world
to apply our human responsibility during this
time of stewardship that we have on this fragile
planet.
Thank you for being here tonight. Thank you
most of all for what you're going to do. I'd
just remind you, in the 1970s there wasn't
really an environment movement in America.
We didn't have an EPA. Just think of that.
We had no EPA. And it wasn't until Rachel
Carson wrote her Silent Spring and inspired
people to become activists that people became
aware of Love Canal and Woburn dump and places
which give people cancer and kill citizens.
And all of a sudden, people decided we don't
want to live next to these places, we think
there's a different choice. And 20 million
people came out of their homes on one single
day. April 21st, 1970 was the first Earth
Day. And those 20 million people didn't stop
on that day. They translated that day's action
into political action. They targeted the 12
worst votes in the United States Congress,
labeled them the Dirty Dozen, and kicked seven
of them out of Congress in the 1972 election.
You know what happened? It unleashed a torrent
of activity so that we passed the Clean Air
Act, Safe Drinking Water Act, Marine Mammal
Protection Act, Coastal Zone Management Act,
Safe Drinking Water Act, and even created
the EPA, which Richard Nixon, whose idea it
was not, signed it into law. (Laughter and
applause.)
So folks, that's what being here is all about.
That's what tonight's inspiration is all about.
We can change everybody's attitude about this
because it matters to all of us. Thank you
and God bless. (Applause.)