our discussions with members of LEAP, Law
Enforcement Against Prohibition. These are
police officers who believe that the prohibition
against drugs is failing and the war on drugs
should be stopped and drugs should be legalized.
Now joining us to talk about this, first of
all, is Stephen Downing. Stephen's a retired
deputy chief of police for the Los Angeles
Police Department. He was commander of the
Bureau of Special Investigations. One of those
divisions was the Administrative Narcotics
Division. Thanks for joining us.
Also joining us is Terry Nelson. Terry's law
enforcement career spanned three decades.
It included service in the U.S. Border Patrol,
U.S. Customs Service, and the Department of
Homeland Security, taking him beyond the U.S.
borders into Mexico, Central America, and
South America. In various capacities he acquired
a first-hand knowledge of the war on drugs
through his direct involvement with counternarcotics
missions. Thanks very much for joining us.
TERRY NELSON: Thank you for having me.
JAY: So start with your own story. You're
a Texan. You told me off-camera you're a Republican.
You grew up with these values (I would have
thought) that the war on drugs is a necessity,
and you were involved in fighting it. What
is your thinking in the beginning of your
career? And how does that--your experience
change that thinking?
NELSON: Well, as a young officer, you think
you can make a difference, of course, and
you spend years trying, and then all of a
sudden you realize the futility of what you're
doing 'cause you're not making any progress.
I never really turned against the war on drugs
until I got into command structure and was
working in Central and South America and saw
the total futility of--like, Plan Colombia
was $5.2 billion we spent trying to train
the Colombian police and spraying herbicides
on the coca crop. At the end of five years
of that program, the coca production went
up 25 percent in Colombia. So either we were
spraying fertilizer on it instead of herbicide
or the farmers became much better. And that's
what happened. The more successful we were
in destroying the crops, the more successful
the farmers were, and they tripled the yield
of the coca plant in about three years. So
they made up all the difference and actually
produced 25 percent more cocaine than they
had at the beginning of the drug war. You
see this and you know you're not going to
arrest your way out of the drug war. Arrest
and incarceration will never work. But education,
we believe, will work.
JAY: Okay. So that coin dropped for you, but
you're working with other officers. And in
the command structure, do you talk about these
things? And what kind of pushback do you get?
NELSON: Well, you talk about it somewhat,
but you have to be careful, because everyone
wants to get promoted. That's the whole purpose
of going in, to work your way up the chain,
where you can have more influence on what's
going on.
I spoke out at an interdiction committee meeting
one time with--I called in a triple-PhD from
Washington, D.C., that came down just to tell
us how to do the--he was laying out economic
models and said, if we can just destroy this
much property, this much coke, we can win
this drug war. And I stood up and said, am
I the only SOB in this room that thinks we're
doing this wrong and we should change our
strategy? And everybody applauded until I
was called up in front of the room and he
stuck his finger in my chest and said, Agent
Nelson, you don't make policy, you carry it
out, so you salute smartly and you go back
and sit down [incompr.] Okay. So when I got
out of the service, I decided I was going
to help change that policy, because I could
do it then.
JAY: Stephen, how about you? You're in tough
territory, downtown L.A. Drugs must be one
of the overwhelming things you have to deal
with. You must have bought into this idea
that it was necessary.
STEPHEN DOWNING: Well, as a young 22-year-old
coming in from a rural community, going into
the academy, you listen to what they tell
you and you believe it. And so you buy into--at
that time you were still buying into the residual
of Harry Anslinger, who said that blacks and
browns use marijuana and it makes them rape
white women. And so a lot of the myth-making
was still alive. And you believe it. You go
out on the street.
And in those days, just possession of a tiny
amount of marijuana was a felony. Well, a
felony arrest was a big deal for a young police
officer. And so you did your job. And in those
days, especially in those days, quota systems
were rampant. The measurement of good police
work was not an absence of crime; it was what
did your recap look like at the end of the
day. But as you grow and you go through the
ranks and you study and you become a manager,
you realize that there are more effective
methods for supervising police operations.
And so by the time I was a commander, it was
about the same time that President Nixon announced
the war on drugs, and it was also the same
time that I had just uncovered at the divisional
level the growth of two small gangs. They
were called the Bloods and the Crips. And
they had a membership of less than 100. So
our charge--when Nixon announced the war on
drugs, I took over the narcotic effort, narcotic
enforcement effort. Our strategy, which was
the national strategy--cut the head off the
snake, reduce the flow of drugs into the country,
and reduce drug abuse and drug addiction.
Well, as we started, a big deal when we call
the press for our dog-and-pony shows: one
or two kilos, a few thousand dollars, a few
handguns. Next month, it's a little more than
that. A little more. A little more.
So today you look at it--and there is really
no metric--none--that measures success--all
of the metrics say this is a failure. Those
two small gangs in the 40 years of this drug
war have grown to 33,000 gangs across the
nation with a membership of 1.5 million. When
we started, the cartels were barely heard
of. They were somewhere in South America,
Latin America. Two years ago, the DOJ said
the cartels control drug trafficking with
the help of the gangs in 250 American cities.
This year the DOJ said the drug cartels control
drug trafficking in 1,000 American cities.
So we haven't made a dent in these three strategy
approaches. Addiction, drug abuse, it goes
up and down. The flow of drugs is now warehouses
full. The guns are tens of thousands of war-level
weapons. And the money, even being laundered
by domestic banks, they get a slap on the
hand, there's millions of dollars on pallets.
And cutting the head off the snake, I came
to discover as a police executive who likes
to do a good job and likes to meet his goals
and effectively execute the strategy, that
was a big thing to me, because I finally decided
there's no snake, it's starfish. And when
you cut a starfish in half, you get two starfish.
When you cut it four ways, you get four. And
the only way to kill a starfish is to remove
its nutrient. And in the case of the cartels
and the gangs, the nutrient is money.
They can't function without money. They can't
buy guns, money can't be laundered, and they'll
be out of business. And so prohibition creates
their opportunity for money. And if we take
that black market away, we're going to dry
'em up. And that's what I discovered as a
police executive. And that's why I believe
that the only way to get out from under this--.
And since I've left the department in the
'80s, they just poured more money in, unprecedented
money. They militarized our police. The federal
government bought off our police, in effect,
by providing military equipment, by providing
grants.
This asset-seizure program, it's evil. It's
totally evil. They say they created it to
get the kingpins, but the average seizure's
$15,000, and if a guy wants to get his $15,000
car back, he can't hire a lawyer for that
kind of money. So all of these things that
go into the harm of people, the discussions
about prisons--California in 1980 had a total
prison population of 23,000. Between 1980
and now, we've built 23 prisons, we've hired
thousands of prison guards, we've fired thousands
of teachers. Today our prison population is
163,000. Twenty-five thousand of those are
nonviolent drug offenders, at $65,000 a piece
a year to keep them in jail. That's $1.52
million.
And this year, we told our 23-campus university
system: no more new students. Our community
college student--three weeks ago, demonstrations,
500,000 kids can't get classes. So we're trading
the education of America for a drug war that's
just stacking our prisons with cordwood, destroying
families, destroying neighborhoods, unraveling
our whole social structure.
JAY: So when colleagues of yours, people you
know in law enforcement hear arguments like
this and arguments that you give, I don't
understand how they cannot be persuaded. What
is this sort of moral imperative that seems
to be deep in American political culture that
you got to fight this war on drugs 'cause
somehow it represents the struggle between
good and evil or something?
NELSON: Well, our drug czar recently came
out and said that drug abuse is not a moral
failure. So he actually came out and said
that. And he also said, we're not going to
arrest our way out of the drug war. The issue
is--.
JAY: Who said that?
NELSON: Kerlikowski, the drug czar.
The issue is it's institutionalized. Prison
unions fight us all the time. Police unions
fight us because they don't want it legalized,
because then they're going to lose membership.
As he mentioned earlier, the police make a
tremendous amount of money from the federal
government, not counting--if the police arrest
someone at night, a couple of kids for a few
joints, they take them in and arrest them,
put them in jail, they go back the next day
for a hearing, they get three hours overtime
a piece. It's a money-making machine for them.
They don't want to quit it.
The military-industrial complex does not want
it to end, because if you sell a Sikorsky
helicopter to Colombia for $16 million, that's
nothing. It's going to cost $100 million a
year to put the maintenance contract in place
to keep them flying.
So it's all about the money. In law enforcement,
it's all about the Benjamins. You follow the
money trail, you find the problem. And everybody's
making money off of the current drug war at
the expense of our children's futures, because
when you get arrested for a drug offense,
I don't care if they don't put you in jail;
you've got an arrest record. And when you
go to get a job, you check the box, they see
you've had an arrest, they look and you had
a drug arrest, you're not going to get hired.
You're going to be marginalized the rest of
your life. And that's going to mean you're
not going to pay your fair share of the taxes
that you would have earned if you'd have been
able to get a decent job. And instead of being--contributing
to your society, you actually are a drain
on our society.
And I don't blame the people, other than the
fact that they broke the law. They're in a
position they can't get out of. I mean, once
you've got the arrest record, that monkey's
on your back the rest of your life. Our saying
in LEAP is you can get over an addiction;
you will never get over a conviction, 'cause
it follows you throughout your life.
So it's not just a short-term thing. It ruins
the people for the next 30, 40 years, breaks
up families. One-point-nine million kids go
to bed every night 'cause one of their parents
are in prison. Forty-some-odd percent of the
people that go to prison this year will have
had a family member in prison in front of
them. And 25 percent of the children or the
kids that will go to prison this year come
out of a foster home or an institution.
Well, that tells you right there this is a
hamster wheel. We're destroying the very people
that drug policy claims to want to protect,
which is our children. We're breaking up families.
They're raised in foster home. They've become--one
parent goes to jail, the other parent has
to get a second job. There's no one to monitor
the kids. The evil wheel keeps turning. They're
on the street. They're going to get in trouble.
We all know that. Kids are going to be kids.
We've got to keep our kids safe until they
reach adulthood.
JAY: So some people think that if you legalize,
it leads virtually to anarchy. If it's legal,
everyone's going to go out and do drugs or
way more people are going to run off and do
drugs, and the place is going to go crazy,
and we've got to clamp down on it. I mean,
how do you argue against that?
DOWNING: We legalized alcohol after a horrible
13-year experience where we discovered we
really made some very bad decisions, and that
didn't happen. We retune it and we returned
at that time. We passed a constitutional amendment
to put it into effect, and we passed a constitutional
amendment to get rid of alcohol prohibition,
and we returned the responsibility to the
states, which is provided by our constitution,
demanded by our constitution. And all of the
states, gee, they worked things out, they
controlled and regulated and set up their
systems, and they served as models for each
other, and they would adopt things. So over
time we had regulated and controlled alcohol.
And during the same time, the organized crime
syndicates that were born as a result of alcohol
prohibition, they died. We took their nutrients
away, like I say, and they died out. Now,
we're always going to have some criminal organizations,
but when we announce a war on drugs, zoom--right
back they came. But this time, the bribery
is institutionalized. In Capone's day, they
took the brown bag full of money and handed
it to the politicians or the policemen. These
days, the money comes through our system and
bribes our institutions and our police, especially
because they've militarized our police and
they've diverted them away from what I call
the social contract our police officers have
with their communities, and that's to protect
them from crimes against person and crimes
against property.
A perfect example in Los Angeles two years
ago--you might have read about it. The paper
uncovered the fact that the police laboratory
was backlogged 3,000 rape kids, a three-year
backlog, meaning that women who have been
raped were waiting for their cases to be resolved
because detectives handling their cases did
not have laboratory results. So it was a big
[haz@rA], and they scrambled around and they
found $10 million and said, we're going to
catch this up.
Well, what nobody really said is: how come
they're backlogged? And the reason they're
backlogged is because when a person is arrested
with narcotics, that's a body in custody that's
going to show up in court, and they can't
show up in court until that narcotic has been
analyzed. And so all this dope arrests, 43
million arrests since 1971 in this country,
those are analyzed in our laboratories. And
every time somebody's arrested, the others
are pushed back.
So they cleaned that one up. And this year,
now they've got--they're behind by 4,000 fingerprint
examinations. Fingerprint examinations are
coming off of burglaries, they're coming off
of assaults, they're coming off of robberies,
stores. These are the crimes the police are
supposed to be working with their communities
to solve. But at the same time they're making
all these narcotic arrests, they're angering
people in the communities because they're
jacking the kids up against the walls or sitting
them on the sidewalks, they're draping them
across the hoods of their cars. And 90 percent
of those frisks that are going on are all
about drugs. They're not about the criminal
problems. And so pretty soon you don't have
a community communicating with you, you don't
have a community cooperating with you, because
this drug war has destroyed that cooperation
and it's destroyed respect for the professional
law enforcement.
JAY: Just quickly, what would you like to
see?
NELSON: I would like to see total legalization
of all drugs, which will cure about 80 percent
of our crime and violence issues. Won't do
anything for our drug problem, because that's
a separate issue, and I believe that's a medical
and a social issue that's best handled through
education and treatment instead of arrest
and incarceration.
JAY: Thanks very much.
NELSON: Thank you for having us.
JAY: Thank you very much.
And thank you for joining us on The Real News
Network.