I'm not Immigration to get
the cook up from the basement. Here.
Call it.
- Uhh, ex-con.
- No way.
- What?
- Wannabe cop.
Got "police academy reject"
written all over.
Hey, pal!
Hey, buddy!
- Try "dude".
- Hey, dude!
- You did time in Chino, right?
- No, Lompoc.
I told you. Ex-con. It's the only job
the poor bastards can get. Thank you.
13-A-6-7, you have a 4-59
silent alarm at Centurion
Storage, Alvarado and Marathon.
A-6-7, roger.
13-A-6-7,
cancel that pre-alarm company.
- Must've been a power glitch.
- Wanna take a peek anyway?
Why is it that on these nice
quiet nights you get so restless?
I mean, this is a great opportunity
for us to connect, you know?
We can open up with one another
and really kinda talk. You need a hug?
Shut up.
Uh, you called it.
A-6-7, door open,
Centurion Storage,
Alameda 22nd. Requesting backup.
- Roger, A-6-7.
- Let's go.
- 3-1 en route.
Hey, Charlie, you ever hear
that word, "stealth"?
Shut up.
At least they don't know we're here.
The element of surprise.
- Ready?
- Yeah, I'm ready.
- Go on.
- You're unbelievable.
- Let's split up.
- Okay.
Hank!
A-6-7, shots fired!
Shots fired! Officer needs help!
Hank, taking fire, four to five
suspects on my side.
Hank!
Come in!
Where you at?
I'm in the big room,
off the office.
- Hank!
- I got you!
- It's bulletproof! I'm comin' in!
Charlie! Your six!
- What?
- Your six!
A-6-7,
my partner's down!
Request paramedics.
I have four suspects, armed!
My partner has been hit!
All units, all units, all L.A. units.
Officer down. Officer down.
Impressive shooting,
Montgomery.
You realize, though, you missed
the target in the middle.
Who, the brother?
I wasn't shootin' at him.
- You mind telling me why not?
- He don't look suspicious to me.
Look at 'im. One lone brother,
surrounded by four white guys with guns?
The man is terrified.
What do you want him do?
Tap-dance?
It's all right, brother.
Okay? I got you.
Don't be afraid to call 911.
I keeps it clean, when Herb
Montgomery's on the scene.
What the problem is?
On behalf of the citizens
of Los Angeles,
I present to you
our nation's flag.
McDuff.
Sorry about Charlie, Hank.
He was a good man.
I want in
on the investigation.
Hank, I think it's best
if we let McDuff handle this
in his own way.
It's a complicated situation.
Wh-what's so complicated
about it?
My partner's dead and I just want
the son of a bitch who pulled the trigger.
There was over 800,000 dollars of
stolen computer chips in that storage
and a police warrant
to seize it.
The night before the raid,
somebody blew in there
and cleared it out.
Look, I don't care about
any goddamn computer chips.
I just want the guy
who killed Charlie.
You're a uniform, not a detective.
Stick to your job.
Fine.
You interfere with
an ongoing investigation,
you won't have a job.
Am I clear?
Yeah, fine.
- Hank. They're gonna find 'im.
- Yeah.
When chasing a suspect,
the goal is simply
to maintain visual contact
until a backup force of sufficient size
can arrive to assist in the arrest.
Time!
Nice job, Taylor.
Did you say something,
Montgomery?
Well, you said "Nice job, Taylor",
and I just said:
- You think you can do it better?
- Let me think.
Check me out.
Hey, Taylor,
you think he ready?
- I'll take this one.
- All yours.
Show this boy how it's done.
So you the suspect, man?
What you do?
Doesn't matter.
Oh, so, you could've robbed a bank,
mugged an old lady...
said somethin'
about my mama?
Just chase me,
smartmouth.
Okay,
Mr. White Bank Robber.
You're insane!
And you're resisting arrest.
Don't you run from me.
I'm insane? I'm insane when
it comes to old-lady muggers, huh?
You like robbin' banks, huh?
You said somethin' about my mama?
And I heard you
call me "boy".
That's cowboy to you.
Time!
I see how this works.
The system can't tolerate a black man
who master clear police skills.
I'm the future law enforcement,
and it scares you
cause you're gonna be
out of work, right?
Look, I remember when the
NBA was all white.
You know...
That's a'it. That's a'it.
I'm fine, I'm cool.
Cause y'all losin'
somebody good, yo.
I'm a virtual one-man,
kung-fu SWAT team.
That's a'it.
I got skills! You, bitches!
Hank.
- Don't have to be back up there so soon.
- No, I'm better off.
- Want somebody to ride with you?
- No. It's okay.
Need some help?
You askin' me if I need some help,
or... if I'm stealin' this car?
Okay, fine.
Are you stealin' this car?
Does it look like
I'm stealin' this damn car?
- Little bit.
- Why? Because I'm black?
White man has his hand
in the car,
you probably give him
a good samaritan award, huh?
Figure he's just goin' around
turn off people's lights.
Yeah. All right, could I see
your license and registration, please?
I ain't showin' you
a damn thing, you Nazi.
- Excuse me?
- Hey, man!
This here? This is my car.
Hey, now, I ain't done
nothing wrong.
Now, the way I see it,
- you owe me an apology.
- What did you just call me?
You ain't listening, baby.
We ain't got nothin' to talk about.
Unless it starts
with you saying, "I'm sorry".
You're on
dangerous grounds here, Bob.
I'd be very careful what
comes outta your mouth next.
Oh... You wanna hear what...
what comes outta my mouth next?
You're...
a...
fucking...
pig.
- You're under arrest.
- Oh, no.
I ain't under arrest. You're
under arrest. I'm arresting your ass.
Citizen's arrest. You're under
arrest for legal false arrest.
Now, get your hands up on the car!
And give me those cuffs.
Back off!
I'm warning you.
You're warnin' me? Uh-ha.
You have the right to shut the hell up.
All right, that's it.
Get up against the car!
Don't make me add "resisting arrest"
to the charges.
Now! Up against the car!
Hey, watch my car, okay?
I just had it detailed.
- Just settle down! You understand?
- This is police brutality!
Okay? And you ain't doing nothin'
but compounding your problem.
- I've had enough of your crap!
- I've told you, man. Get off me.
Whoa! Whoa!
- What?
- There's a big-ass bumblebee behind you!
You don't think
I'm gonna fall for that crap, do you?
I'm allergic to bees.
If I get stung...
I'm-a seize up
and die.
What? Just ignore him
and he won't touch you.
- Yeah. All right.
- Look! Right there.
I'm-a tell you...
Help! Help! He's tryin'...
he's tryin' to kill me!
- Help! Help! He's tryin' to kill me!
- Get down! I got him!
Don't kill me!
I got him!
He's tryin' to kill me!
What you are seeing
is a home video
taken earlier today, showing
Los Angeles police officer, Hank Rafferty,
brutally beating an
unidentified black male.
The police are withholding
the name of the victim,
but we have obtained
this photograph
taken after the beating, his face
grotesquely bruised and swollen.
It was a bumblebee.
Police officer Hank Rafferty's
vicious beating of a black suspect
has sparked a swift and angry
response from the black community.
Detective Frank McDuff
had this reaction:
I wanna assure you
that the police department
and the district attorney's office
are treating this matter very seriously.
I urge the people of this city
please, be patient and
trust us to do our jobs.
Clearly, this is
an isolated incident.
- It was a bee.
- Get the hell outta here.
Mr. Montgomery, this
is detective McDuff,
lieutenant Washington and
District Attorney Robert Barton.
- Morning.
- Good morning. Call me.
I'm serious.
Giggler. All right.
Weren't you on TV last night?
Oh, snap, that is you.
- What's up, man?
- What happened to your face?
I was attacked by one
of your deranged officers.
What you think happened?
No, I mean, what happened
to the swelling and the bruises?
Oh, that. That ain't nothin'
but allergies. You know, bee stings.
Come again?
Y'all mind
if I have a seat? Cool.
I mean, y'all gonna
ask a brother all these questions,
you don't even
offer me the seat.
What's happenin'?
All right. Well, um...
While I was being slammed into the car,
having... billy clubs jammed into my neck,
that psychotic storm trooper
y'all call a cop
also allowed this big-ass bumblebee
to nearly sting me to death.
You know what? I'm not even sure
that that bee wasn't one o' his own.
You know, like some anti-Africanized
attack bee, trained to hate black people.
But, you know what?
That's the sort of thing that, uh,
y'all gonna uncover in the course
of your... your-your investigation,
so, ptss, I ain't trippin'.
- Would you excuse us for just a moment?
- Ptss, do your thing, man.
Thank you.
We can't put this guy
on the stand.
- He's unstable. Not to mention that he...
- Yo.
Who's the Planet-of-the-Apes-lookin'
lady in the dress?
- That's my father.
- Handsome man.
I don't believe this.
I don't either. I'm calling off
the pull-am. This is crazy...
Hold, it, hold it.
Look. You like this guy or not,
Hank Rafferty violated his rights
and people of this city
are not gonna look the other way.
We can't go
through this again.
You can drop
the prosecution,
I guarantee you
you got a riot on your hands.
Earl, do you, uh...
you work?
I mean, do you have
a... steady job?
Yes, I work.
I work in security, man.
Ah.
That's just until
I get back in the academy.
- I see.
- Speakin' o' which, you know what?
- Y'all need to investigate them...
- Mr. Montgomery...
all allergies aside,
did officer Rafferty assault you or not?
How many times
I gotta say it?
All right.
Let's get down to business.
Superior Court of the County
of Los Angeles is now in session.
Please be seated.
People of the state of California
versus Henry Rafferty.
Case no. CV-34259.
Honorable Marsha Gailey presiding.
Okay. It's at this time that the bee appeared.
Right here. There it is. It's coming in.
You can't...
You can't really see it
on... the tape, but it... it's there.
Okay.
I'm swatting it
with my... stick.
There I am, stomping on it,
with the heel of my boot.
Kept missin' it.
Not a good angle.
So, Mr. Montgomery,
are you claiming
there was no bumblebee present
at the time of the incident?
No, I'm not.
- There was a bumblebee present, man.
- Oh, good.
And there were birds chirpin'...
There were dogs barking...
Hell, for all I know, there was a chipmunk
in the bushes, humpin' a turtle.
You know, you gotta be careful
with them chipmunks.
They'll-they'll hump anythin'.
This is no laughing matter,
Mr. Montgomery.
Look, man, I came here for justice.
Okay, that man right there?
That man harassed
and choked me.
He used excessive violence
way before there was or
was not a bumblebee, sir.
I know the score.
It's not the first time
I been pulled over for DWB.
- DWB?
- Driving While Black.
- Move to strike!
- Kiss my ass.
Will the defendant
please rise?
The jury has found you
guilty as charged.
You are hereby sentenced to serve
six months in a state penitentiary.
- Murphy.
- Okay, move along.
- Keep it moving.
- Rafferty.
You must be that white cop, huh?
Beat up the black guy.
- What makes you say that?
- Them.
Oh, man.
Hey, ase.
Save your strength.
You're gonna need it.
- You look cute, baby.
- Get goin'.
Look, don't mess with me
or I'll throw your ass in solitary.
All right, let's go.
You're out of the hole.
- Hey, how long have I been in here?
- Three months.
Congratulations.
You are the graduating class
of this third week of August.
Many people don't make it through
both days of intense training.
You are the elite.
Wherever you go, you'll be
part of this special fraternity.
You're equipped with everything
you'll need to do your job:
flashlight...
pepper spray...
and if things get
really nasty...
a coin holster full of quarters,
so you can call the police.
Congratulations.
What do you mean,
you got nothin'?
You had a crime scene,
physical evidence.
- I gave you a goddamn tattoo.
- Which was a ghost.
We couldn't find
anything on it in the database.
Look,
these things take time, Hank.
- Oh, please...
- Holy cow, check it out. Hank Rafferty...
a security guard.
Yeah, nobody throw gum on the ground,
okay? We'd get, like, a... a warning.
District 21 units, additional
on the ADW in progress.
Suspect, male white,
blue jacket, brown pants.
Male black, green shirt, brown pants.
Fled eastbound on foot.
Excuse me.
You ever see that?
4-59. Silent alarm, A & L
Beverages, 18th and Main.
Cancel that. Must have
been a power glitch.
Gotcha.
Where's security?
Freeze!
What are you doin'?
The lights went out,
and I couldn't find a switch.
So I was filing
in the dark.
That's why
I called you here.
Lola...
filing in the dark is a serious offense.
You're in a lot of trouble.
Get up against that wall.
What are you gonna
do to me?
Search you. Make sure you
ain't carrying any concealed weapons.
You finding anything?
- Is this a thong?
- What?
Is this a thong?!
Are you gonna
strip-search me?
No.
I'm-a put on some music.
You gonna
strip-search yourself.
Whoa, whoa, slow it up for me.
Nice and easy. Yeah.
Can't get enough
of your love, babe!
Yo, pass those two.
- Get the motherboard.
- Check those boxes, man.
Got it. Load them up.
Get them out of here.
We have to check the load.
Oh, yeah, Earl.
No. Don't call me Earl.
Call me "officer".
- Oh, okay.
- Yeah, yeah.
Are you gonna give it
to me now, officer?
Hell, yeah.
I'm-a incarcerate you.
You know my style.
I like it wild.
- All right, pass that over here.
- No, I got it.
Freeze!
Hands up!
What was that?
I said "freeze"!
You, behind there!
Wait here. Might get
a little dangerous.
You really playin' this thing
out, aren't you, baby?
Talk to me about a hit
six months ago. Centurion Storage!
Talk to me about a hit six
months ago, Centurion Storage!
- Go to hell.
- We wondered where security was.
Drop the weapon.
You should have run when
you had the chance.
Now you got no chance.
Over there!
There he is! Get 'im!
Somebody shoot them!
- Thanks.
- No sweat.
What the hell
are you doin' here?
I work here!
What the hell you doin' here?
You little punk! I spent six months
in prison because o' you!
Six months? That's all they
gave you, six months?
Damn it, Earl! This
ain't turnin' me on!
- What the hell is that?
- Earl Junior.
Likes to hang out with daddy.
Precious, ain't it?
Get the goods!
Load them up! Now!
- Cover me!
- Hey, man, you ain't my boss.
Well, I say, we work
for the same company.
Since I got seniority,
you cover me.
- Okay, I cover you.
- Go!
No! My car!
No, not my car!
Somebody shoot that monkey!
What did you call me?
Let's go. Now!
Get them in here!
Go, go, go, go!
- Get outta my car!
- Why, cause I'm a black man?
Look, this has nothing to do
with you. It's personal!
You damn right it's personal. White boy
back there called me "monkey". Drive!
- Get out, now!
- Look, man.
I been waiting my whole life
for shit like this to go down. Okay?
If you gonna shoot me,
shoot me.
That's the only way
I'm gettin' out outta this car.
They getting away, man!
Come on! Get, go!
Earl?
Man, this slow-ass...
damn... Flintstone car, man,
we might as well be...
pedaling with our damn feet.
What the hell is wrong
with this piece of junk?
Yeah, I don't know.
You know, I was gonna take it in
for a regular scheduled maintenance,
but, uh, for the past six months
I've been in prison!
Hey, man,
you should've got more time.
Pushin' me into cars and.. and-and
puttin' me in satanic chokeholds.
You were resisting arrest! I was
authorized to use any force...
Hey, hey, look, man! Look.
We could go back and
forth on this all night long, man.
Fortunately, there are courts
to handle this matter.
And according
to the courts,
you were assaulting and battering
me like a hillbilly on his wife.
Yo, yo, yo!
Oh, oh, oh. Shit. This is how
I'm gonna conceal the weapon.
Pull over! Pull over!
Get the van!
- You pull over, buddy!
- No, get the van!
- Drop the gun!
- The van!
- Drop it!
- Get the v... Get...
Damn!
If I would've gotten out
with a wallet in my hand
I'd have bullets
all in my ass!
That's some bullshit, man.
Security guard, huh, Hank?
That's a shame.
- Hey, Washington, how are you doing?
- Better than you.
- You okay, man?
- You know how it is, my brother.
Just a little shaken up,
that's all.
Let me see...
if I got this figured out.
You get out of prison,
pissed with your life,
you decide to pay your old buddy Earl
here a little visit. Things got out of hand,
shots are fired, police respond just
in time to catch Hank trying to get away
with you in his car, probably
holding you at gunpoint. Am I correct?
Amazing.
You are very, very good.
Oh, wait a second. This is crazy.
I di... I wasn't out for revenge.
Shut the hell up, Hank!
Just shut the hell up.
I'm tired of
your goddamn lies.
I got a restraining order
that says
you cannot get within
100 feet of this guy, okay?
So, I don't really give a damn what
you have to say. All I need from you...
is your testimony and his ass
goes back to prison. Tomorrow.
Nothing would make me happier...
than to see this man go back to prison.
Good.
For... for the heartache...
and the trauma.
One time he took the club
and he switched it around
with the handle sticking out
and bop, right there.
Can you see that little cut,
right there? Anyway...
What happens is it makes
me start saying inco-herent...
You know, I'm liable to spurt that out.
Just incoherent shit. Bitch!
I-I-I apologize.
My doctor said that I'm not gettin'
the proper oxygen up through here.
They said pump it and...
and breathe.
And... it's sort of
like that sneaker.
It's a weird exercise.
Anyway, nothing would make me
happier than to see him go back to prison.
- Wait a second here!
- Get back, bitch!
- Shut the hell up, Hank, and I mean it!
- You... The violence.
Let me calm myself.
Unfortunately, certain details
of your story are slightly skewed.
What do you mean,
skewed?
Hank...
did not come back for revenge.
- Thank you.
- He came back to apologize.
- What?
- You went there to apologize?
The man's talking to you.
Yep.
- And you were saying?
- I was...
saying I was sorry.
- For what?
- Beatin' you.
Yeah. My dog. Ooh-ooh-ooh!
That's what I'm talkin' about, man.
Hank was right in the middle
of this very touching apology...
when I discovered that
my warehouse was being robbed.
So Hank and I, we banded together
to apprehend these outlaws.
And we would've had them,
had not your boys come along.
Excuse me?
Deputy Droop-a-long.
Man, they stopped the wrong car.
- You better watch your mouth.
- What you gonna do?
Beat the hell outta me?
Probably blame it on a damn spider.
- What you got?
- The updated report.
We got a 4-59 at the warehouse,
but nothing on a van.
Coroner has two bodies.
D.A. says self-defense,
so, uh, we kick 'em loose.
- The C & L warehouse on 18th?
- Yeah.
Not a cop anymore, Hank,
so stop acting like one.
I'm all too happy to find any reason
to lock your ass up. You understand?
Go find McDuff, tell him
I wanna see him right away.
Oh, yeah, we also encountered
a naked girl upstairs,
- handcuffed to a light fixture.
- Oh, Lola. Lola.
Uh, you think you could hook a brother
up with another restraining order?
Right there, cause I recognize them.
Great.
All my stuff should be
in here too.
What's up?
Right.
I don't believe this.
Where's my bullets?
We don't return
live ammunition.
Well, if you wanna keep the bullets,
why don't you just keep the gun?
- All right.
- Give me my gun, man.
Where's my car?
Impound lot. Twenty blocks up,
seven blocks over.
You expect that man
to walk...
Y'all got a shuttle bus?
You know what?
You upset my partner.
I should set it off up in this...
But you got your boys.
Hank, you believe
his attitude, man?
Man, they probably gonna give you
your car back with no tires.
I like the way you played it
back there, Hank.
Yeah, not lettin' 'em in on our case.
That was smooth.
- This is our bust, right, partner?
- Get the hell away from me!
Hey, Hank!
You know what?
Sooner or later,
your hostility is officially
gonna start
affecting our work.
Now, look, man.
All you got to do is kind of...
What is you running for?
I'm tryin' to talk to you.
Look! I am trying
to remain calm,
because I know that if I hit you,
I will never see the light of day again,
which right now seems
almost worth it. So don't push it!
- You threatenin' me?
- Yeah! Yeah, I'm threatenin' ya!
Well, bring it on.
Bring it on, Hank.
I could have went pro.
I drop bombs on 'em,
drop bombs on 'em.
What? What? Right here,
slip, move, slide...
Can't redial
without a signal.
Oh, bang 'em outta there.
Hey, where you goin',
man?
- Shut up!
- Big Red Truck and Trailer.
Truck and trailer. Yeah, look,
you guys got a call...
uh, yesterday, I think it was, regarding
a white van that you rented out.
We only rent big rigs.
Oh. Yeah, well, maybe
you can help me out.
I'm tryin' to find
a couple of my buddies.
Uh... Uh... I think they rented
a truck from you... yesterday.
- What name is it under?
- No, I don't know their names.
- Listen, pal, we get a lot of people here.
- No, I...
- You listen.
- Give me the phone.
- Where you located?
- Downtown, on Normandie.
South Central?
These were white folks.
Oh, they just left.
Bought extra insurance for Baja.
- Headin' to Mexico?
- I guess.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
The way I see it,
they got a 20-minute head start.
They're probably
headin' down the 405.
What are you doin'?
Stop the car!
National Security!
Stop the damn car!
National Security.
I'm commandeering this vehicle.
- What did I do?
- Oh, student driver, huh?
Well, lesson 12: Man with gun,
get your ass up out the car.
- Go!
- Okay, okay, don't shoot.
And do your homework!
What the problem is?
Hey, man. Do I gotta solve
this crime by myself?
Unbelievable.
Big, red truck.
It's gonna be easy to find.
It's probably gonna say "Big Red"
all along the side of... the truck...
in big, red letters.
Hey, Hank, you know that file
back at Washington's office?
Well, I used my acute peripheral vision
to get a upside-down read.
- Wanna know what I saw?
- What?
On one of them papers
it said "CIA heist".
And?
- That's all I saw, "CIA".
- That's it?
Hey, look, man, I said I got peripheral
vision, not X-ray vision, man. All right?
Now, apparently, we are
caught up in some real live
complex-ass, espionage shit.
This is great,
man, ain't it?
Me and you, man, we're security guards
out here acting like real cops.
- I was a real cop, Earl.
- Well, you must've loved it, huh?
I can't believe
you gave that up.
Yeah. There's Route 1.
Now, just stay on the freeway,
it's a lot faster.
No. No, they wanna keep a low profile.
They're gonna go Route 1.
Stay on the freeway.
No, on the freeway, come on.
- Don't!
- Oh, shit!
- Hey, come on!
- Freeway traffic, man.
- Stay on the freeway.
- We're in the middle of the street.
What are you doing?!
- Let go of the wheel!
- Freeway!
What are you doin',
Hank?!
Oh, shit!
- God! Are you okay?
- Yeah.
- Shit.
- Hey!
Sorry.
Look like somebody was right
about the freeway.
What?
Look at that. You can't tell me
that ain't a big, red truck.
Yeah, yeah.
Gun. Under the seat.
Hank! Hank!
Get off me!
- Hey!
- Shoot 'er, Hank.
Shoot this big bitch, man.
Hank's about to shoot you.
No, I ain't gonna shoot anybody.
Put him down...
in a minute or two.
No hurry.
I don't like nobody
messin' with my rig.
Don't be a pussy, Hank.
Shoot 'er!
You oversized, big-boot,
thick-ass, Jerry Springer-reject ass...
- Earl, come on. Let's go.
- No, man.
Shaq here
owes me an apology.
But then again...
- what your name is?
- Brittany.
Yeah?
Got a ring on every finger
except that lockdown one, huh?
You like to wrestle?
Cause that's my thing. I like to wrestle.
Earl. Earl, come on,
let's go.
Why don't you
give me your number?
And if you're nice, I'll show you
what a real big rig looks like.
Earl, come on!
- I'll call you.
- Let's go, let's go! The truck's leaving.
- I'm with you. Hold on, hold on.
- Come on!
- Think these are our guys?
- How the hell am I supposed to know?
No, wait. Wait.
Oh, wait. No, no.
Sorry.
Earl!
Earl, come on!
Come on, come on!
Swing around!
Oh, my knee!
Oh, shit.
Hey, come on!
Come on, come on.
- You did that on purpose.
- Look.
So that's why the cops
couldn't find the van.
Hey, do you know how
to hot-wire a car?
Oh, cause I'm black, I... automatically
know how to hot-wire a car?
- Hey, look. Do you know how or don't you?
- Yeah.
- But not cause I'm black.
- Do it.
- Move your leg, man. Close your legs.
- Get in there.
- See that?
- All right. Go, go, go, go.
Okay.
See... see how that spark went when
one o' them bumped into each other?
That's cause that red wire
is what gives off all that energy.
- I don't care.
- See how that's sparking there?
Got it?
- How's that? What's that doin'?
- Earl, the windshield wipers are on.
Must be a '94.
Touched the wrong one.
How's that?
- What's that?
- What the hell?
- Turn it off. Turn it off!
- Oh, come on.
Somebody's back in that trailer.
Let's take a look.
Eddie, look out!
- Do it. Come on, come on, come on.
- Yeah.
Go!
Oh, shit! Ooh!
Thanks, Hank.
That's the second time in 20 minutes
you landed us in some shit.
Hey, you messin'
with Earl and Hank!
What the problem is?
You know? What the hell
is in these boxes.
Oh, Hank!
Oh, it stinks.
- Oh, damn!
- Sorry.
Damn, it looks
like Christmas.
Except for these fish guts
and... orange peels.
Please be guns.
What the hell is that?
This is a beer keg.
Doesn't make any sense.
Makes a lot o' sense
when you put together all the pieces.
What pieces?
It's obvious.
The CIA,
they're smuggling alcohol...
into the inner city in an effort
to further subjugate the black man.
Hey, do you actually believe the crap
that comes outta your mouth?
Oh, I'm never really sure
till I'm finished talkin'.
Think they all kegs?
Yeah. Nash.
We got a problem.
Well, what we have here
appears to be
your average, garden-variety,
22-dollars-deposit beer keg
but it's way too light.
- It must be light beer.
- Yeah, way too light.
Couldn't be a pound and a half.
Let's take a peek inside, huh?
Yeah, she's empty all right.
You think maybe there's a double wall?
Something stashed in between, hmm?
Happy to take a look.
Put on the glasses, boys,
or you will go blind.
This torch burns
at 4000 degrees Fahrenheit...
so let's slice open
this can o' peaches.
Incredible.
She's cold as ice.
Gorgeous.
Why don't you
and the keg get a room?
Gentlemen,
what we have here
is an Area 51, high-tech,
aerospace alloy.
Weighs next to nothing,
disperses heat instantaneously
and is resistant to almost
any force in man or nature.
Well, is it worth anything?
Yeah, millions!
Which is exactly why...
I want you two to take this thing
and get the hell out of my shop.
Personally, I don't feel
like dying right now...
and this is exactly the kind o' shit
people get killed over.
Thanks.
We'll stash the van here
till we find out what's what.
- Whose garage is this?
- This guy I know. It doesn't matter.
Nah, nah. This ain't no guy garage.
There ain't a power tool in here.
Let's go.
Hank, this box up here
got your name on it.
This wouldn't happen to be
your girlfriend's house, would it?
Hey, Earl. Could you do me a favor?
Could you stay outta my business?
Oh, well, lookie, lookie, lookie.
Looks like somebody got dissed, huh?
A'it, let me guess, Hank.
Uhh, your girl left because
you beat the shit out of her.
No. Ironically, she left me
because, uh, I was convicted
of beating the shit outta somebody else.
Oh, me? Moi?
Man, go ahead with that, man.
Look, Hank, I'm just saying, man...
I suppose that's what
your attitude is all about? Huh?
Hanky ain't gettin'
no lovin'.
Hey, man, I'll be happy
to go back in there
and straighten this
whole mess out for you.
No, thanks, I think
you've done enough.
Nah, nah, serious, Hank.
I wanna do it, man.
Earl Montgomery is a love-maker,
not a love-taker.
Wait a second.
Let me get this straight.
You-you're telling me you'd go
in there and tell Denise
that I never harassed you,
and I went to jail for no reason?
Absolutely.
But you and I both know
you got exactly what you deserve.
Denise.
I hope they don't think
we're breakin' in.
She's not home.
Damn. Denise got
one fine-looking maid.
- Excuse me?
- Earl...
that is Denise. Hey.
- What do you want, Hank?
- I only wanna talk.
- Oh, you wanna talk?
- Yeah.
Or you wanna lie? Because
there's a difference, you know.
I-I've always been honest
with you, Denise.
Course you were.
You just... forgot to tell me you were
beating up black men on your lunch hour.
Oh, snap. She's witty.
Yeah, yeah. She most definitely
got the upper hand.
Hey, could you be quiet
for a minute? Thanks.
- Look, I told you how...
- I know, I know, the bumblebee did it.
- Yeah.
- You lied to me, Henry.
Lies, lies.
Lies just compound lies.
You know? But you sayin'
the same thing. Do your thing.
I didn't beat anybody, okay?
And I can prove it.
This is the man that I was accused
of assaulting. Okay, Earl.
- Hi.
- You got somethin' you wanna say?
Oh, yeah.
She's black.
You never told me she was black.
Did I or did I not
assault you?
Oh, he beat the hell
outta me, ma'am.
- What?
- Look, I'm not gonna lie to the sister.
No, you're... You son of a bitch!
I'm not gonna take this!
Hey! Get your hands off him.
Stop it. Get out.
- Get out!
- Get out! Just get out!
- Henry, get out!
- You too. Get out! Get!
- But...
- Get!
I think the violence
might kick off out there.
Get out.
Listen, man. Wait.
Why you all salty at me, man?
Look, Hank, kill that noise, man.
Listen, it's not my fault. Okay?
- You told me she was white.
- I did not.
Well, you didn't tell me she was black,
so that's the same thing.
- What difference does it make?
- Makes a big difference.
Look, if I had lied and told her
that you didn't beat me up,
I'd be condoning
interracial relationships.
Which is somethin'
I do not condone.
Okay, that's it. If you're not outta
my face in three seconds...
Whoa! Now, you don't wanna be...
be threatenin' your partner.
I am not your partner!
I had a partner!
I would have taken a bullet for him!
You, I'm having a hard time
not shooting!
All right, hold on! Now, that's it.
Now I'm upset.
You try to leave, I'm-a put
your ass under citizen's arrest.
Okay? And you and I both
know you are in direct violation
of a legal, binding
restraining order.
- You have something in your teeth.
- Where? Here, or here?
Now you can tell people
I hit you.
- Hi.
- Hi, '78 Plymouth Volare, tan.
- Can I have your driver's license?
- Yep.
You... Are you kiddin' me?
I got somethin'
in my teeth?
I'll tell you what it was, Hank.
Trust. And now it's gone.
Earl, what do I have
to do, huh?
Hey, I just came here
to get Earl Jr. Okay?
I don't go nowhere
without my baby.
So why don't you get your jalopy,
and we both go our separate ways.
Hey, that's my car
right over there.
Do you think I could
just have the keys and...?
We're just trying to locate
your paperwork, sir.
Lookie, lookie, lookie.
What do we have here?
How you doin', Miss Doll?
- Fine.
- Oh, yes, you are.
You got a pair of handcuffs
on you I can borrow?
- You hittin' on her?
- Uh, yeah.
What was all that crap
about interracial... couples?
Oh. I am firmly and belligerently
against any interracial coupling...
when the man is white.
Darlin'... can I interest you
in a stick o' gum?
You know, they say five outta five
dentists recommend this shit.
Thanks.
Get your stuff outta my car
and get the hell outta here!
Miss Darling, what do I have
to do to get my car outta here?!
Would you please
just be patient?
Patient.
- Freeze!
- On the ground, now!
Goddamn it. God.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I gave up!
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
No, don't give up. Get in.
- Hank, freeze!
- Get in the back.
- Know what I'm doin'?
- Stealing a police car.
I'm saving your ass, yet again,
despite the fact that you struck me
- yet again.
- Okay. Sorry. Thank you.
God!
- Apology accepted.
- Okay, we're even. Go, go, go!
- Don't hit me no damn more.
- Go, go, go!
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Car!
Forklift.
Forklift, my side.
Forklift!
I got it!
- Yep... you got it.
- Watch out!
Dead end!
Dead end, dead end!
- Hey!
- I see it.
Come to think of it,
you hit me and I didn't kill you?
I'm lettin' you live,
savin' your ass...
- Oh, I'm going straight to heaven.
- Fence!
Chill, Hank. I'm blessed.
What'd you do
this time, Hank?
I don't know.
I'll find out.
You know, for a cop, you sure
get in a hell of a lot of trouble.
Yeah, yeah.
Turn. Turn, turn, turn!
Hey, chopper.
Turn here, turn here!
Turn!
Always loved
the car wash, man.
White, foamy water over you...
Brushes waving in the breeze...
When you a kid in the ghetto,
that's like goin' to Hawaii.
- Hey, they got an APB out on both of us.
- Both of us? What the hell did I do?
Well, we're both wanted for the shootout
on the Vincent Thomas Bridge.
- Yeah, well, that's fair.
- No, it doesn't make any sense.
I mean, how'd the cops know
we were on the bridge?
The only people who could have ID'd us
were the guys in the truck,
none of them called it in.
Maybe someone on the inside
put out a APB to locate us.
Now we're talking
about dirty cops.
- What you doin'?
- Runnin' the numbers on the van.
No, plates are phony.
Damn it!
- Check the VAN.
- What?
- I thought they were all scratched off.
- Not underneath.
I pulled it when
I was wirin' the van.
- All units, 5-0-3, stolen police vehicle.
- Bingo. Address. Okay.
- Car wash at Venice and Crenshaw.
- They tracked us.
Let's ditch the car!
- We need a car.
- Yeah, yeah.
Hey, hey! Hey, hey!
Hey, could you pull over here?
- God!
- Use the badge.
- What?
Yeah.
Stop! National Security!
- I'm commandeering this vehicle!
- Lemme see that badge.
- Right, just step out of the car, ma'am.
- Don't you raise your voice at me.
Get out of the damn car!
Didn't your mama
teach you any manners?
At least you could
ask me nicely.
You call this
commandeering a car?
- You wanna shut the hell up?
- Don't be using that language in my car.
Sorry.
Now, I got no problem
giving you boys a ride.
But I don't take kindly to
being told to get outta my car.
No, sir.
I surely do not.
Warrant.
A warrant.
Look, they must've had
a warrant to raid the warehouse.
The dirty cop had to have access
to it to send his boys in first.
Same thing must've happened
at the storage place.
- So who's the leak?
- I don't know.
APB's go through
watch commander.
Washington?
Ain't that how it always is?
- What?
- You have absolutely nothin' to go on,
and already
you blaming the black man.
- I'm just throwing names out.
- I'll tell you how to find a dirty cop.
Pick up the phone
and call the police station.
Don't really matter
who answers.
What you gonna say?
- Thanks.
- Thank you.
- Okay, you boys behave now.
- No question.
- Take care.
- Should I have gotten her number?
- Definitely. She's very nice.
- I thought so too.
Is this the place?
Stay cool.
Can you pick this?
What? "Just because I'm
a black man... What?"
You were doin' good.
But why you said like this:
All black people don't do that.
Look, man, just let it flow...
Can you
pick the lock or not?
- Not without my tools.
- Hey, hey. Come on.
This is great.
A real stakeout.
My whole life, man,
I wanted to be a cop.
Ever since I was a kid,
watching "Quincy" on TV.
Quincy was a medical examiner.
Oh. I guess in the projects
we didn't get real good reception.
Hey, man. This is boring.
How long we been here?
- Comin' up on 12 minutes.
- Where the hell are these people?
Earl, this is a stakeout.
We could be sitting here for hours.
No wonder cops are so fat.
Ah, shoot.
Hey, whatever happened
to Charlie?
If you don't mind, I'd just ra...
I'd rather... not talk about it.
You sure?
Yeah.
You know, they shot him
right in front of me, man.
I couldn't do
a damn thing about it.
I'm sorry to hear that, man.
Who did it?
The guys we're looking for.
So that's why
this is personal.
Let me get this straight.
Your partner got killed...
you lost your job, you got thrown
in jail, your girlfriend walked...
and now you're a security guard
making 182 dollars a week?
Know what you are, Hank?
You're a black man.
Now, though, you gotta
think about it, though, right?
Glad to see you laugh,
man.
- Now, how long we been here?
- Oh, come on.
- Coming up on 13 minutes.
- I got to get somethin' to eat, man.
Earl.
Hey! Earl.
What are you doing?
No! Earl!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Earl, hey. Earl.
We're always early.
He's always late.
Damn it!
Call me back. They were spotted
at the police impound yard.
Get down and
get the goods.
Pain in the ass!
Are you okay?
Hell, no, I ain't okay, man.
I been shot!
Shit.
- It's him!
- How do you know?
Tattoo!
- Son of a bitch!
- Partner.
Go get 'im.
- Hank.
- Yeah?
You get 'im?
No.
- Come on.
- I ain't gonna make it, Hank.
I'm cold, man.
I'm cold all over.
I'm startin' to see
white light.
Ah, damn.
Even the light is white.
Come on. You hit
in the leg, Sally. Let's go!
- Don't bounce. Don't bounce!
- You gotta help me a little.
- You're bouncing!
- Your other leg.
Denise! Denise!
It's Hank. Hank.
- I thought I told you. It's over.
- I been shot!
You shot him now?
- No.
- What happened?
Look, it's a long story,
but... you gotta trust us.
We didn't do anything
wrong or illegal.
Then take him to a hospital.
No, no! We can't, cause
the cops are looking for us.
- What?
- It's complicated!
Look, Denise, I understand
you're a nurse, right?
I'm bleeding out here.
Now, y'all can bicker later. Come on.
- Please, please.
- Let me come in?
- All right.
- Yeah, go.
- Hey.
- Sorry.
- Take off your pants.
- Huh?
Take off your pants.
Earl? You're not wearing
any underwear.
I don't like to wear drawers, okay?
Makes me feel constricted.
So does dying. Now, hurry up,
Hank! Come on!
- I'll get you a towel.
- Better make it a beach towel.
- It's not that big.
- It ain't small.
Thank you, Denise.
That was very sweet of you.
All right, I'm gonna need you
to keep pressure on the wound.
Right. Okay, bend over the chair
and hike up the towel.
- What? I'm not like that, man!
- Do it!
Oh, oh. Well,
just say that, Hank.
Thought you was trying
to get a free ass shot.
Come on, Denise, now. Come on,
tell me the truth.
Earl, there's no bullet in you.
It went through... through
the bone, out the other side?
It barely touched you.
It's a scratch.
Denise, you think
I'm gonna need stitches?
- Yes.
- I knew it.
- Well, just...
- Oh! Whoa. You know what?
- What?
- I'll let it heal naturally.
- Oh...
- Yeah, yeah, that's right.
Oh, no!
- It's a bee...
- Calm down!
- A bumblebee! No!
- Don't move. Don't move!
Death from above!
No! Swish it out.
Death from above, man.
- Is it safe?
- Not for you, it ain't!
I can't believe your girl
can go off like that.
- She hits harder than you do.
- Yeah, this is it.
Marina Yacht Club.
This is where the call came from.
How we gonna get in?
- Split up.
- Excuse me, I want the big fat one.
Oh, that looks interesting.
What is it?
I don't know,
but it smells like ass.
You recognize anyone?
Man, it's so damn white in here,
my pupils haven't adjusted yet.
Hey. Hey, look.
- That's him.
- Son of a bitch.
What do you know?
It's the white guy.
A sad day
in Caucasian history.
- Where the hell the two of you been?
- Jimmy Buffet's in town. Come on.
You got five minutes.
It better be good.
- Can I get a chip?
- No.
You got a leak
and we know who it is.
- Now can I get a chip?
- No.
It's McDuff.
- I assume you have some proof.
- Yeah.
We been trackin' them knuckleheads
who hit my warehouse.
- The same guys who killed Charlie.
- Led us right to McDuff.
That's all very interesting,
but do you have actual evidence?
- No.
- No. But we got what he wants.
- What is that?
- The goods from the CIA heist.
- You got the CIA goods?
- Wait a minute. It was really CIA?
Crupps International Aerospace?
What CIA did you think
I was talking about?
Would you tell 'im,
please?
A year ago,
over 7 million dollars
in iovian coded atomic alloy
was stolen out of Crupps.
And to smuggle it
out of the country,
they had to melt it down
and recast it as beer kegs.
Feds tipped us off.
Our leak beat us to the punch.
That's right. McDuff. Offer to sell 'im
back his stuff. Oh, he'll bite.
- If he's dirty.
- Oh, he's dirty.
Now,
give the man a chip.
I appreciate you tryin'
to get me a chip.
But thinkin' that I was
talkin' about the actual CIA...
Yeah. I don't know
what I was thinking.
Hey, McDuff.
It's your buddies, Hank and Earl.
What's up, Duff?
Look, uh, we get
somethin' that you want.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
We're talking
beer kegs, bitch!
You two
are wanted felons.
Look, Frank, save it.
We know you're dirty.
- Listen to me...
- No, you listen to me.
Look, I don't know who
you're selling these things to.
I don't really care.
All we want is a piece of the pie.
Say, uh, 1 million dollars worth.
- We're talking six zeros, chump.
- So, what's your plan?
Meet us tomorrow morning, 7 a.m.
Uh, the old fort, Luna Point.
How'd you
find this place?
Uhh, I did a couple nights of security
watching some... construction equipment.
- It's perfect for us, though.
- How many boys Washington got?
I don't know. Uh...
I see... five or so.
- I'm startin' to feel all tingly and shit.
- Yeah.
I thought I shot you once already.
You're a tough little monkey, aren't you?
You into monkey jokes, right?
Didn't your mama
teach you some manners
when you were humpin' 'er?
- Did you bring the metal, Hank?
- You bring the money, Frank?
We'll see about that
when I see the kegs.
You know what? Let's just
forget about the money.
I think we already got
what we came for.
I don't think you'll find them
as helpful as you thought they'd be.
You see, my men aren't actually
members of the L.A. SWAT team.
- Where's Washington?
- I don't know.
Excellent question.
- Shit.
- Oh, man.
The brother's in on it?
He must've grew up
in a white neighborhood.
Gun. Scratch that.
He's a real brother, gettin'
messed over just like the rest of us.
Guns, gentlemen.
Look, I... No. Look!
Sorry. No, no. Look, look.
No, no, no, no! Go!
Washington,
get over here!
Get in! Get in! Get in!
I know a way out!
There's a tunnel
at the other end.
Down! Down!
What the hell happened?
I don't know.
They grabbed me after we talked.
Take a right! Come on!
Get through the other end!
Earl!
Come on! The tunnel!
Go, go!
Hank, come on!
Earl.
What? Where's Hank?
- I don't know.
- Hank!
Hank! Shit.
I gotta go find him.
- Okay, go ahead. My foot's busted up.
- You gonna be okay?
I'll be fine. Go!
Damn it!
Earl!
No!
Busted!
Son of a bitch.
Yeah!
Hey, Nash! Catch!
Who's a monkey now?
Monkey!
- Ah, shit. Hank!
- Hold on!
Whoops! Sorry!
- Hank!
- Hold on!
Good, good, good, good!
Whoa!
- Yes!
- Yeah!
- You the man!
- No, you are the man!
- Okay, I am the man!
Yeah, yeah!
Six months ago,
these two men were locked
in a conflict
that shook our city.
Today they stand together
as heroes.
Gentlemen, thank you for your
bravery and your selflessness.
Hank, welcome back
to the force.
Thanks.
- Earl, welcome to the L.A.P.D.
- You serious?
- Congratulations, Earl.
- Yeah. Thank you.
- Earl! That's enough.
- Oh.
Hey, check it out,
10:00 o'clock.
Pull over.
Excuse me.
Hey, uh, you wanna step away
from the vehicle, please?
Hank. Please, man.
Lemme show you how this type
of situation is properly handled.
Excuse me, Mr. Civilian,
who has rights.
Did you perhaps lock your keys
in your vehicle?
Yeah, I do it all the time.
They're right there in the visor.
Yeah, yeah.
Right there in the visor.
Well, for my partner's
peace of mind,
would you tell us
the numbers on your license plate?
- Sure, 2CQN654.
- Is he right?
Yeah.
Allow me to assist you,
instead of beat you senseless,
like some cops would.
- Thank you, officer
- You're very welcome.
- Have a good day, all right?
- I will. Thanks.
Hey, listen, man. Not everyone's
a criminal. Remember that.
My car! No, wait!
That's my car!
Course, it's always good
to have a backup plan.
I give up!
Ma'am, you may re-procure
your vehicle.
You idiot!
What the problem is?