-Where's the money?
-Money, money, money.
-What?
-You know what.
-All I know is I'm not going
to sit here another day.
-It's spring break.
-How are we going to get
enough money in time?
-I don't know.
We're the only ones
still here.
-It's spring break.
-I'm tired of seeing
the same thing.
-Spring break.
-This is our chance to see
something different.
-It's spring break.
-Just get the cash.
-Pretend like it's
a video game.
-We can do this.
-Spring break.
ALIEN: We're in a magic
place, ya'll.
You can change who
you are, ya'll.
Titties and big booties,
ya'll.
That's what life is about.
-Who are you?
ALIEN: My name's Alien.
-Why are you here?
ALIEN: I saw ya'll in there.
You look like nice people.
Come on, ya'll.
Why you acting 'spicious?
I knew ya'll was special from
the moment I saw you.
It was written on your faces.
-I just have a really, really
bad felling about this.
ALIEN: Let's cause
some trouble now.
Spring break, bitches!
[MUSIC]
ALIEN: I got my dark
tanning oil.
Lay out by the pool.
This is the American
dream, ya'll.
-Spring break
-Ya'll want to die tonight?
-Spring break.
-Get down!
-You're scared, aren't you?
-Spring break forever.
-Spring break forever,
bitches.
[SINGING BRITNEY SPEARS, "HIT
ME BABY ONE MORE TIME"]