one example
america's own space fighter
the air force's highly classified x
thirty seven d
launched in twenty ten
this military meeting space shuttle
could possibly be recognized in center
gets the invader
but america's small space force must
fight
an armada
workable experimental weapons exist in
lansing cases across the country
military leases
team weapons
literal regards
dr travis taylor has investigated one of
the most viewers and weapons of all
there
a real gone
it's been called the most powerful going
in the world
super magnets accelerator projectile
along twenty with allison to
unimaginable speeds
meaning of the house
thousands and thousands of miles per
hour
with the projectile whereas a missile
you're limited to hypersonic velocities
it's a with three thousand miles per
hour
do you know maybe ten times faster kisi
with modern technology
the generals ordered unproven weapon
bolted onto a truck bed
as the rust into combat
here
but the expiry
metallum weapons are no match for for a
technology that crossed the cosmos
and even if it isn't
there is no time to mass produce new
weapons five
if our planet stands a chance
the nations of growth must merge their
competing military central one
global army
park humanity
in the face of empyrean invasion
can the nations of birth
unite
r_r_
president reagan one state's beach where
he said to the united nations macy's you
may think about quickly our differences
worldwide
would finish if we were stationed in the
a m trade
from outside this work
our former enemies now become our allies
millions to sell it and i think
with us on the cell something shoulder
to shoulder with the taliban surviving
allies
interest darkest hour
the nations of the world
combine forces
the warrior
indeed of our entire species acts f
but that's partly sunny
for technology that can travel between
the stars
the defense organizations of the world
their realized there
multibillion dollar assets are not
working
their technology is so far superior to
ours
that hard
don't last long
now
deletes focus their attacks
fungus and some kind of a mission down
to the era surface
anything with madonna threat of
admission because the next priority
the lead air force clears the skies the
then blasts military targets around the
country
successfully located military targets is
simple
began in the fall of sorrow radar
signals
generator system urinating a radar polls
and that's something that we tracked
if you're dealing with the civilization
that's
capable of space travel you may not want
to call your attention
and their weaponry down upon your like a
reminder area you know that's one of us
detection systems or data
dvb-t craft seagull military
installations around
takeout
offer made a comment units over all the
government's armies of the world
uh... that's gonna happen very quickly
it may happen in in a matter of minutes
might take a few days but it's gonna be
very quick
didn't want to attack the infrastructure
of our society
the backbone of human civilization
itself
become so simple
undefended target
they're gonna try to get things that we
would use to resist right
that's why we put the bright spots on
the map to start taking them out
we got our power
have any power to do that
and so it is all over this battlefield
earth no
military units obliterated
cds ruined
infrastructural emanated
humanity
defeated
somewhere in the united states inside an
underground bunker
the leader of the fleetwood
always his nation's options
the plan to fight it gillian invasion
includes one remaining possibility
within devastatingly precautions
somebody have to tell
the president
mr president we think the nuclear option
you know one thing
nuclear weapons
the most powerful armaments ever
conceived on this planet
there are over twenty two thousand
active nuclear warheads on earth
the combined destruction could wipe out
the entire human species
twice over
this may be the only effective option
against the invaders
credit cards entered terrifying cost
who would killed millions of citizens
inning campbell to destroy the enemy
in america
only the president has the authority to
make that kind of decision
but i think you'd be very
remorse for regretful and it wouldn't
undertake that decision lightly
but at the end of the day i think you
decide that that was the right thing to
do
the president called principally case
the nuclear football
the portable launch codes for america's
arsenal
the first started our nation's capital
they've won ship is destroyed
it may cause the others to retreat
it's a demonstration of our destructive
power
and our resolve
was a decision from eight minutes
was the most effective way to use
so uh... my first prev be dropped bombs
on top of the vehicle
so that they at least the the spacecraft
with source you went below
store up from fallout
you would minimize the blast
land-based nuclear missiles are already
destroyed
but there is another delivery system
that may be on skates
you don't know where the submarines are
any given time
and so uh... the submarine has the
advantage that
in theory at least the concert this fire
ballistic missiles quickly submerge
again
disappear before the enemy as any
ability to really responded back
board
somewhere in the atlantic ocean
are suddenly rises from the depths
one hundred fifty feet below the surface
a patch opens
i've tried and true ballistic missile
bursts through this service
and takes place
it carries nearly three point lead
megatons of destructive power
two hundred fifty times the size of the
perot shimla blast
as its source toward its targets
the missiles to detections
breaks apart into the key warhead
these warheads are self-guided and not
dependent on satellites
the nuclear warheads dark toward the
alien vessel hanging over washington
d_c_
update of the planet riots unmanned spy
destructive
eight nuclear warheads
power of true hundred fifty promotional
bombs
into with regard to the future
puffery over our nation's capital
it is the most destructive military
attacking history
four miles of ground zero flap
we've been downtown d_c_
ninety eight percent of the population
but will it work
earth's mightiest weapon has had no
impact
the recent is simple
travel between the stars
requires protection
if they have the technology to get from
their star system to hear they have to
have a higher so metallurgy
or they might have sealed like in
science fiction
if u but really really really fast
spaceship
and michael meteorite size of the desk
that gives you
at a park a lot of anything spacecraft
this many times the largest nuclear
weapon ever built by man cac
so that they had shields
they can withstand a nuclear weapon
and how we're gonna do it may be scratch
their fate but we destroyed all city in
the process
our nation's capital which is destroyed
births armies are devastated
but in the secret plans for t_v_ in
indonesia the war isn't over
descr the beginning
from shielded bunkers in secret
locations to survive in the military
leaders issue orders for a surprising
new tactic
instead of attack
the ordered their forces to do the
opposite
runaway
very possible that the order because
get out of the city's and disperse
yourself as much as possible
it's preferable to entirely from
extinction extermination of human rights
idealistic and i think the best you can
do not present liable for gifts
military should be afforded to disperse
katie weapon take iraq take three days
worth of food and
winter where you can just go
it's time to move on
to fight another day
firsts remaining committee
cations hugs call for civilian
evacuation
everywhere
colwell
inmagine unnatural disaster on a massive
scale
vacation earthquake
the pacific tsunami
in hurricane katrina
combined
in every city in the world
the big differences
will not com
in the panic to flee
desperate crowds become writing marks
that
to manage twins on itself