PATRICK O'DELL: What's up?
This is day one--
I guess day two of the trip.
First day of skating.
We're in Medford, Oregon.
I noticed the Anti-Hero team
was up at like 8:00 in the
morning or something,
ready to skate.
The Girl team rolled
in about noon.
Mike, I noticed Girls slept in
later than Anti-Hero today.
MIKE CARROLL: Beauty rest.
It's kind of pretty unreal
watching [INAUDIBLE]
skate around.
I've never seen anything
like it.
PATRICK O'DELL: It's
pretty sick.
MIKE CARROLL: Everyone's
rippin'.
MALE SPEAKER: That
is beautiful.
MALE SPEAKER: This is called
Touch of Sparkle.
MALE SPEAKER: Maybe the
[INAUDIBLE] rock tail stall
combo again.
MALE SPEAKER: You gotta
complete it now.
There she goes.
PATRICK O'DELL: I don't know, I
think we're going to go to a
bunch of parks today.
Julien's tourguiding, so we'll
see where he takes us.
That's it.
I don't know.
Skate day.
MALE SPEAKER: What's
it about, helmets?
MALE SPEAKER: I guess.
What the hell?
MAX SCHAAF: Skate at
your own risk.
POLICE OFFICER: OK,
keep going.
MAX SCHAAF: Know
your abilities.
POLICE OFFICERS: How about,
approved helmets
required at all times?
MAX SCHAAF: Even for
grown ups, hey?
POLICE OFFICER: Doesn't say.
So that means yeah.
MAX SCHAAF: Well.
See ya.
POLICE OFFICER: You're
trespassed from the property,
so you need to leave.
So I'm following you.
PATRICK O'DELL: Why's that?
POLICE OFFICER: 'Cause
there's no
skateboarding without helmets.
PATRICK O'DELL: I'm
not skating.
POLICE OFFICER: But
you're trespassed.
So you can go.
PATRICK O'DELL: What
do you mean?
I'm not trespassing,
I'm just--
POLICE OFFICER: You can go.
JOHN CARDIEL: He came in
kind of hot, right?
You know license expired,
where's your helmets at, who's
the driver of the vehicle?
It's like, fuck you, dude.
MALE SPEAKER: Give me one
problem at a time.
JOHN CARDIEL: Right.
MAX SCHAAF: You know, John, how
whenever they come up, you
go, gentlemen.
You know, they say gentlemen?
JOHN CARDIEL: Right, right.
MAX SCHAAF: He came up,
and I go, gentlemen.
And he goes, start
your engines.
JOHN CARDIEL: Wow.
MAX SCHAAF: Yeah.
JOHN CARDIEL: Beat it.
MAX SCHAAF: Heard that one.
JOHN CARDIEL: Kick rocks.
MALE SPEAKER: That was sick,
did you see that?
PATRICK O'DELL: What
did he do?
MALE SPEAKER: Step hopped the
whole fucking island, dude.
Film this shit, bro.
PATRICK O'DELL: It seemed like
with those two teams combined,
there's somebody that could
skate anything.
JOHN ALDEN: Yeah, yeah.
Like a good spark.
PATRICK O'DELL: Like it could be
a manual pad, or like a 13
foot wall, that somebody
could go.
JOHN ALDEN: Yeah.
Yeah.
It was rad.
Well rounded crew.
FRANK GERWER: What was one of
your favorite parts of the
tour, O'Dell?
Let me see that.
PATRICK O'DELL: All my favorite
things are swimming
spots and scenic--
JOHN ALDEN: Yeah.
PATRICK O'DELL: Remember
when we went to
that cold rock river?
JOHN ALDEN: The first one, like
when we started driving
through that field?
PATRICK O'DELL: It was
freezing cold.
JOHN ALDEN: Like the first
one we went to?
PATRICK O'DELL: I really
liked that.
JOHN ALDEN: Yeah.
PATRICK O'DELL: It
was like ice.
JOHN ALDEN: Yeah.
It was hella cold.
PATRICK O'DELL: Because I think
it was like melted snow.
MALE SPEAKER: Ah, come on.
MALE SPEAKER: Keystone.
This river's good for keeping
the beer's cold.
Throw 'em right there
at the base.
MALE SPEAKER: Pretty potent.
Pretty potent and brisk.
FRANK GERWER: Fuck,
that sucked.
MALE SPEAKER: Good way
to wake up, Patrick.
[SMACK]
MALE SPEAKER: See
now, that hurt.
MALE SPEAKER: It didn't
even hit anything.
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah, it did.
Here.
Take it.
MALE SPEAKER: Instant.
PATRICK O'DELL: Yeah,
that's pretty bad.
FRANK GERWER: Student number.
JOHN CARDIEL: You
got any more?
What are we doing?
ROBBIE RUSSO: I don't know.
I only got--
JOHN CARDIEL: What do
you want to do?
ROBBIE RUSSO: All I got
is big bills now.
JOHN CARDIEL: Come on,
sucker, come on.
ROBBIE RUSSO: Come on,
motherfucker, come on.
JOHN CARDIEL: Oh!
MALE SPEAKER: Aw, missed
it by that much.
Ouch.
JOHN CARDIEL: That's real talk.
Real talk.
MALE SPEAKER: John's taking
little kids' money and shit.
JOHN CARDIEL: Don't look
at me like that, Rick.
I just felt bad, dude.
Rick looked at me
like, bad, bad.
That was all.
PRESTON MAIGETTER: How's
it going, Pat?
PATRICK O'DELL: Where are we
going to go now, you know?
PRESTON MAIGETTER: Uh,
headin' to the
coast towards Brookings.
PATRICK O'DELL: Is there
a good park there?
PRESTON MAIGETTER: Yeah.
PATRICK O'DELL: You know
what John did here?
ROBBIE RUSSO: John?
PATRICK O'DELL: Yeah.
ROBBIE RUSSO: Aired
that thing.
PATRICK O'DELL: Yeah.
This is the third
park of the day.
Brookings, Oregon.
The park where Cardiel did
the back side 360,
and over the bowl.
Megajump over the bowl.
And now everyone else is
trying to get some.
It's pretty sweet.
MALE SPEAKER: I give it a go.
MALE SPEAKER: It's like a
fucking ski jump, dude.
It's insane.
PATRICK O'DELL: What's
the secret, John?
JOHN CARDIEL: The
secret is speed.
And a lot.
PATRICK O'DELL: And a lot.
JOHN CARDIEL: And a lot.
[SCREAMS]
MALE SPEAKER: Holy shit!
JOHN CARDIEL: Fuck yeah, dude.
A little icing on the cake.
Put it up on an arm.
PATRICK O'DELL: Can't turn
back once you're all in.
You have to do it.
You have to [INAUDIBLE].
MALE SPEAKER: What happens
then when you do?
Just fucking cruise, right?
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
Keep cruisin'.
Just go fast.
MALE SPEAKER: No turning back.
JOHN CARDIEL: Come on,
Robbie, come on.
Come on, come on, Robbie.
Ahh!
You know you want to, Robbie.
Give it all the juice.
ROBBIE RUSSO: I'm just scared
of [INAUDIBLE], man.
JOHN CARDIEL: You'll
make it across.
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah,
you got it.
FRANK GERWER: We'll all
blow at the same time.
We'll go, phew.
JOHN CARDIEL: You'll make it.
ROBBIE RUSSO: Ehh.
MALE SPEAKER: You got
it, Rob, you got it.
MALE SPEAKER: Once you roll
in, it's over with.
You got it.
Just do it.
ROBBIE RUSSO: I'm just scared
of [INAUDIBLE].
JOHN CARDIEL: You won't
not make it over, Rob.
FRANK GERWER: All right,
come one, Robbie.
Fly the chasm.
ROBBIE RUSSO: Scared [INAUDIBLE]
isn't it?
JOHN CARDIEL: Fly the chasm.
MALE SPEAKER: Whoo!
RICK MCCRANK: Let's do it.
You can roll in anything.
You could jump it.
Right here.
ROBBIE RUSSO: Ohh, shit.
PATRICK O'DELL: If you don't do
it, you're going to regret
it the whole trip.
ROBBIE RUSSO: I know.
Fuck.
PATRICK O'DELL: You're
going to want to
come back here tomorrow.
ROBBIE RUSSO: I should
just do it.
Fuck.
I'm just being--
I'm scared.
That's all it is.
It's my mind.
PATRICK O'DELL: Well,
you got it.
I'm watching you skate.
And it seems like you got
the board control
to just launch over.
MALE SPEAKER: Whoo!
Whoo!
PATRICK O'DELL: What
about Julien?
Had you seen him skate
in person?
ALEX OLSON: No.
He wouldn't skate that much.
Or he would, but he'd be trying
something, and everyone
would sit down and start
watching it.
And he'd be like, be over it.
He's kind of like [INAUDIBLE]
in that sense.
Like, doing his own thing, and
once five people notice it,
he's like, oh fuck.
I'm over it.
PATRICK O'DELL: Do you
like how he skates?
ALEX OLSON: Oh yeah.
He's one of my favorites.
[SCREAMS]