PATRICK O'DELL: Hey, were going
to Autumn's Skate Shop
to meet with Tim O'Connor.
And I brought a sharpie
and a Thrasher.
And we're going to watch him
wreck people because that's
what he's good at.
TIM O'CONNOR: All right.
PATRICK O'DELL: What
about that?
TIM O'CONNOR: Oh my god, right
off the fucking bat here.
Wait, what's up with
cursing and stuff?
It doesn't matter.
It's the internet.
PATRICK O'DELL: Yeah,
we can bleep it out.
TIM O'CONNOR: OK, jumping
Jehoshaphats.
First of all, never ever combine
extreme sports, OK?
Never make a hybrid
of the two.
This is his ad.
PATRICK O'DELL: You think
he landed that?
TIM O'CONNOR: He might
have landed this.
There's nothing to say.
I like this.
It's what I like to see.
He's been spared, except he
is going to get an Afro.
I once looked at a magazine that
somebody did back in the
day when I was at skate camp,
and every single human being
in the magazine they
drew an Afro on.
Let me do a Neck Face drawing
because that guy seems to be
everywhere.
Hey what does this
stuff look like?
What is going on right here?
One ad.
He got on a team and
he was just like, I
got one add in me.
And this is it.
He does it and he dies.
It doesn't even have the name
of the kid on this ad.
But maybe it's like introducing
a kid, but they're
also outroducing him because
he died right after he did
this first trick for
his Hawk clothing.
[BIRD NOISE]
You guys have no qualms of
me making fun of people.
Oh my god.
Is it a joke, or is it like I
dare you to do that trick with
these pants on?
Or is it purposeful?
That's the question.
This is, you know how you have
those old photos of yourself
when you're a younger kid and
you're like embarrassed like,
oh God, what was I wearing?
And like, ew, you know?
I wonder if they're going to
look back at these photos and
just be all embarrassed.
I feel bad.
This is mean.
I'm going to be the guy
that gets fucked up.
I'm going to get beat up.
Hold up.
[FART SOUND]
Did you get that?
Because that hurt.
I wasn't there, but a
photographer that was on a
trip with these guys
told me-- this was
an exact quote verbatim--
one of the guys at the demo, one
of his team riders said,
"Permission to rip, sir." And
Jamie Thomas, right back at
him, said "Permission granted,
soldier." And then they just
went in and landed everything
and won the demo.
I need that thing.
I need that thing to
hide my voice.
Yes, you are good.
But apparently not
at dressing.
And I put a little PS, a post
script in there, because he's
holding a gun.
A gat, if you will.
And I said PS, please don't
shoot me with that gun there.
I don't want to get shot.
Unless it will up
my board sales.
Like fucking 50 Cent
or something.
What's happening right here?
Is God looking at him at this
moment or something?
Look at the magical ray of light
that's shining upon him.
And yes, he is putting a
record into that thing.
Is that real?
Do they really make those?
PATRICK O'DELL: I
don't think so.
I think it's a Photoshop.
Or you think they really
make one of those?
TIM O'CONNOR: Maybe.
I mean, it looks huge
and outrageous.
PATRICK O'DELL: Well if they
make one, [INAUDIBLE]
would have it.
TIM O'CONNOR: Yeah, it's true.
This is true.