back pain
and the doctors realized that she was
miscarrying so she started asking them
after an abortion because the pain was
excruciating however out the fetus
allegedly still had a heart beat
and uh... the doctors told her that they
would not uh... abort because they only
abort in cases where the woman's life is
in danger
and so they they had not heard the
abortion
uh... few days later
uh... it she died from something known
is that set the senior
and uh... it was a yuko live uh...
infection that she had
and you know she left behind a husband
and their devastated and the fact that
doctors denied her this abortion
is just
ridiculous it's ludicrous
yet in
this is a problem when we make decisions
like this
uh... that are not based
on logical reason
or even honest the humanity of the
people say they do this for morality is
this for al is this moral miss the
muslim world we have ever heard doctor
saying that they won't
operate when she obviously even she was
vomiting proper
whole day she was an extreme pain
obvious issue has and we pay
long infection in the beginning to our
meeting today in the right before so for
us
but that by the end of the baby was in a
survive anyway
she asks for an abortion multiple times
and he she was desperate at one point
com she was fully dilated
uh... and and feed the miscarriage it
shoes in the process of having a
miscarriage and she asked for them to
you know opal abort you know get get
this out of my body
uh... and the doctors told her it only
take a few minutes just you know just
wait it out
uh... as she was you know japan meeting
and the arctic fluid it was an issue
isn't horrible condition and they still
denied what she asks for and out her
husband says that doctors told her uh...
i'm sorry the doctor said that you know
this is a catholic hospitals
and that's what the long island that's
the law yeah
uh... and at the husband says i had
neither irish nor catholic
but they said there was nothing they
could do
this vessel exactly what's wrong with
this
why are you putting your morality on me
begin this to my wife
hinman
curious i'm furious and it is that my
wife
why do why i have to listen to your
insane rules
from new orleans is taxed well i think
that no one should marketing handle
religion was fall it's that's what's out
there we would do
for western democracies assault
believe in that is just
this barbarism when you see the actual
effects of it
you know oftentimes when we talk about
extremism we talk about countries in the
middle east but when you look at some of
the laws that island house when it comes
to contraception when it comes to you
abortion you realize just how religious
there really are
for instance it wasn't until nineteen
eighty five that ireland allowed uh...
people over the age of eighteen to
purchase condoms without a prescription
contraband completely until about
nineteen seventy nine on cell n and
recently what relatively recently in two
thousand five
three women now filed a lawsuit against
ireland because they have to travel out
of the country to receive an abortion so
understand because that sounds really
confusing
are they supposed to be a billboard
generally not get the life is in danger
as it was in this case and we started
talking about
well that's the problem according to the
constitution abortion is
flat out the legal
but in nineteen eighty two supreme court
ruled that
it could be legalized the situation one
woman's lives at risk
if you continue the pregnancy the
problem is nobody knows how to interpret
that
this for that's conflicting
and so some hospital say well no we're
not gonna do the work no matter what
some hospitals do
that's nowhere to run a country and that
not only is that no way to run the
country apples completely
and against your pro-life stance because
women are dying as a result of your
refusing to terminate
uh... a pregnancy you know i've done up
fears that is not viable
right fears that isn't even gonna
survive
you know it like in this case they know
that she is going through a miscarriage
so you're not saving anyone's life in
this situation but in this case i think
the doctors were so afraid of breaking
the law that they decided to play it
safe and just not do anything about it
army go further i think uh...
for the most religious people
that take it for this kind of extreme
ravine most
the moral people
in the world
and so it's not like already religion
and its morality or dividend or they're
just the same as there is no doubt
they're not the same as everybody's
when you takes stupid laws that don't
meet any sense
that our team in your bible it doesn't
even say you should have an abortion
your bible
anne apply to everybody what they are in
your religion about your religion
whether a group and they don't agree and
some people dying because of it that's
is the moral of act as you could
possibly do and why
because law an auto
some and purpose in teen sixteen hundred
years ago made a political document
that he said jesus might have said
o_j_'s of those friends might have said
before that he has been swept this
assaults
don't they
there in the pump daring leonard i like
that and now we have these neanderthals
in america that want to take us back to
me is dark in the thousands nobel's
across the country
walk back
reproductive rights
i can't believe we're having this comes
as it did so many states
their weight
i'm so sick of people's religion then
and so sick of it
and possibly know you have to do my
review that do my religion
block wall
while at the rear of the trip
i don't i don't believe her religion
i don't believe it get the effects well
question about it
i don't have responded i was fresh air
date
but analysis i'll plan allows a_t_p_
it's a blue
so idon't yesterday tracker autorad
quite like
they saw and heard
progress police
in a couple of logic and reason but we
have a conversation about haiti
update here as a result
basis for this law ok fine don't talk
about it
but you can't have a place that i got i
think
two thousand years ago told the
pocketbooks
that he talked about that will assist
but he said harris has seen in her body
canceled at last fall
internet back
fifty hundred years ago as it may be you
shouldn't do this so that events i'd
like your wiped out
stopped you
fundamentalist bullshit