SPIKE JONZE: (SINGING) Sailor,
sailor, Come home.
Oh, sailor, sailor, come home.
How's that?
SHANE SMITH: Super cool.
SPIKE JONZE: Super cool.
All right, so Shane--
SHANE SMITH: Oh, shit.
SPIKE JONZE: What?
SHANE SMITH: My tutti
went frutti.
How do you keep yours?
SPIKE JONZE: Give it
a double wrap.
SHANE SMITH: Double.
SPIKE JONZE: Where does
Vice go from here?
What's the plan for
your company?
SHANE SMITH: I think that
because it's getting bigger
and bigger now, it's either
going to become a next
generation media company, or
it's going to flare out.
Just really spectacularly.
We're just going to spend $100
million on a party and then
not show up the next day.
End up in Vietnam selling
Cokes on the beach.
SPIKE JONZE: How are you
going to decide which
way to go with it?
SHANE SMITH: Well,
I won't decide.
SPIKE JONZE: Oh.
SHANE SMITH: It'll be a thing.
SPIKE JONZE: When are you
that your happiest?
SHANE SMITH: I'm at my happiest
when I'm in my bed
with my wife and my
baby, because I
love them both insanely.
Like, it's like love you've
never felt before.
Like, you have a baby, and
you're just like, all I want
to do is make the baby happy.
I was a pretty selfish
guy my whole life.
I was essentially a teenager
till I was
like, in my late 30's.
And I lived for my own pleasure,
and you know, ego.
And then when you have a kid,
your ego goes out the window,
and all your pleasure--
not all of it, but like,
comes from them.
And oh, I bought a house.
That makes me feel happy,
but not for me.
But because like, my kid has a
place to live, and my wife as
a place to have the baby.
That's when I'm happiest.
But I like shooting.
I like coming to crazy
places and shooting.
Not because of the shooting
and stuff, but because it
forces me to think about
stuff that I've never
thought about before.
You know?
And so that makes me happy.
SPIKE JONZE: How should
this interview end?
SHANE SMITH: You should ask
me how it all ends.
SPIKE JONZE: Shane Smith,
how does it all end?
SHANE SMITH: I just got married,
and I had a baby.
And now I want to build
a family seat.
And I want to find it by a
beautiful cove, like this one.
Remote.
And I want to build a house
where my kids can grow up, and
where you can come visit me.
And the young kids can make
Vice, and we can make books
and movies, and TV shows.
Or model airplanes.
Or whatever the fuck
we want to make.
And we'll grow old happy.
We'll grow big beards, and
we'll eat sausages.
And we'll drink lemonade.
And we'll lie in the hammock.
And we'll discuss why you're
still a bastard.
SPIKE JONZE: OK.
SHANE SMITH: Can we go
for a swim now, papi?
SPIKE JONZE: Yeah.
[MUSIC PLAYING]