CLAIRE TRIMER: Well, name is
Claire Trimer, and I'm a baby
sloth wrangler at a sloth
sanctuary in Costa Rica.
Well, we probably have about 135
sloths here, under a roof,
that we're caring for.
There's pretty much
sloths everywhere
you look around here.
I have several roles here.
One of them is to supervise
the babies.
I weigh them every morning.
I keep after the
health issues.
Whoop.
You went poo yesterday.
Sometimes their mothers die.
And in that way they're
orphaned.
Sometimes if a mother senses
that a baby is too weak to
survive, or they actually have
some kind of problem that the
mother has sensed, these babies
are not strong enough
to cling, and they fall to
the ground repeatedly.
A mother sloth is vulnerable
every time she
comes to the ground.
And if she thinks that this
sloth is not going to survive,
she's not going to keep coming
to the ground and risking her
life over and over again.
KRISTA TITCHENER: I love sloths,
because it's been my
favorite animal for
about 10 years.
But I love their sweet
little face.
They don't ever want
to hurt anybody.
They just want to be happy
and be peaceful.
And I just love their
sweet smile.
My day as a volunteer involves
a lot of hard work.
You know, your payoff for the
day is getting to interact
with the sloths and play with
the sloths and maybe even hold
this sloth's babies and
take them for walks.
CLAIRE TRIMER: This is Alfy.
He's actually a year old.
We don't know why, but Alfy
never gained a lot of weight,
and his fur is still the
texture of baby fur.
KRISTA TITCHENER: At 6:00 AM in
the morning, we clean out
their cages.
We really get to wake them up,
which is a great time for us.
One of our favorites is Delilah,
and she will actually
pull the towel back over her
head because he doesn't want
to see you in the morning.
She's way too tired.
Sid is our absolute favorite.
My sister and I decided
to adopt Sid.
KIM CATALA: Adopting him
does not mean that we
can take him home.
We wish we could.
But we know we can't.
So we just signed a little
certificate that we were
adopting Sid.
The money goes to the program.
And then we'll write to him
and send him letters and
everything.
He'll like actually grab
you under your arms.
Like he likes to
be slow-danced.
Should we dance, Sid?
CLAIRE TRIMER: Occasionally,
someone says, how can you tell
them apart?
And I always want to go, how can
you not tell them apart?
Yeah, you can tell them apart.
You can tell your children
apart, so you can tell the
baby sloths apart.
Yeah.
They're just a huge
part of my life.
I'm with them almost
every single day.
And they are sort of
like my children.