arisen
uh... republicans and democrats on
capitol hill go crazy at bat we started
so what exactly did they do
well this on background checks so it
looks like something's gonna pass while
ok maybe maybe
son set in stone yet and there are a
soul pose
so uh... what is going to pass well
gottschalk while they didn't have it
that sounds pretty good right
and and
online sales i also
and as we did get a minute that like you
can't have any decision you know that
grant ect
so most
symbol in the world as we said a million
times
ninety one percent of americans
agree there should be background checks
that but don't get too excited
because there is a little paull
loophole is
well regards as know each other and it's
just a private sale
that's totally ok
well that creates a bit of a problem
right adam winkler who is well the
topics in the country about this is a
law professor at u_c_l_a_
he's author of gunfight
the battle wrote the right to bear arms
in america respected by both sides he
says
it doesn't close a private sale will
pull it just reshape said
in fact look at this is a squall
private sale still won't require
background check
so long as they occur outside ago show
or without a publicized advertisement
there's nothing the law that prevents
someone from going to a gun show
finding the gun he likes
than meeting the seller offsite to
complete the cell without a background
check
well that's your id chariot loophole
deguerin
drive a mac truck through
so welcomed the compromise
by the way there are a still opposes it
okay now we had to learn a second
that there is something else looks like
is gonna pass which is hey you know what
we had an attractive os guns they're
going to legal
ed
purposes okay
elise straw men sales with somebody buys
if someone else and gives them
is a camp asa background check or
something along those lines well you may
get a crack crime to buy guns and they
have been vigils legally barred from
possessing does wow that's really tough
too which is that possible
has of course i can really go ok alright
hold on
but it would also make it explicitly
will you go
to traffic tour more guns the person had
reasonable cause to believe a crime
would be committed with any of those
fireworks
as lobbing oppose is they're awesome
did you hear that
if you think somebody's gonna commit a
crime
you can't sell two or more guns to them
anyone i mean come on when you do not so
much dot nancy according to some assault
weapon
buddy you know him twelve cell two or
three of the message will straight
these are the compromises that come out
of washington
bucket el portal to celebrate this
was about to celebrate
excuse me for not celebrated by the way
the celebrity about that
have gotten gotten god
can't happy here and i think that's the
magazine van
that the issue and have travel invented
by both a very short period of time
having times and then then
and tackle while reloading all the time
but they don't have to reload very much
resembles mike tyson is guilty of is
that ban those
not weekend than those not not not not
cellular well consideration
the republicans were filibustering all
this anyway
this walk down piece of crap they work
filibuster
now luckily
they lost
they at sixty eight votes to break the
filibuster why i
for taking
not impressed by any of this
now of course president obama set the
tone early on
when in the state of the speech he gave
this rousing but completely nonsensical
uh... applause line
grabbing get hurt
the
family and
family
family uh... here
uh...
and
now at warner back then that or yes was
for a boat you know so we look
so finally he's getting about but not
all the things he says he won the vote
on so let me is
mike tyson exists at a
night universal background check
this is a non universal background check
there's a background check
if you're an idiot you can't get past it
they play at the end of the parking lot
and by the gun there
okay great
so present obama's gonna be a guest in
something like this is
this is almost here
nothing right this is so water dept
utah balmy elizabeth also party
immediately cisa well this is quote this
is not my bill there are aspects of the
agreement that i might for to be
stronger
they're good people on both sides of
this issue now what i think we have
everything to know that we've gotten do
something
december title dot box
now a lot of work remains
the senate must overcome obstruction by
defeating a threatened filibuster
and allow boat on this another
common-sense reforms
to protect our kids in our communities
anne bill still has a clear the house
understand all things he's doing there
well you know i didn't give you what you
wanted but it's a tiny bit up five
percent change
mentioned complex
historic on reform a layout we had
overcome of that uh... photo so we get
all thanks got we finally have all about
it what different inbuilt them by the
way you see that
then a but don't get me wrong
even though i didn't get ninety nine
point five percent of what i wanted
it's also clear the house don't don't
worry about me arcade neatly say yes
all worry about the republicans want
they want so yes i was
uh... he then goes on to say so what did
he pass the american people stand up and
raise their voices
because these measures to serve a boat
and so the families and communities
they're designed to protect
uh... ok self that's the one side of the
equation he gets very little of what he
wanted
and he's firing off by our war straight
and say and work hard
and on the lively for this watered down
tiny little bit of reform
now we turn to the n_r_a_
what is their position
and they got almost everything they
wanted they'll even mind the provision
that if yours
selling to a guy you know it's gonna
commit a crime
ish in some to guns wow what a we got on
that one ok thanks guys right
but did you want a provision
even though it's got a jury a loophole
you're doing a background check as
somebody
kazan they wanna make illegal gun by a
more position 'cause they're upset
gunmen effect as the one i have
more criminals with guns
cuz then this here's the regular
citizens to the criminals buy more guns
and the regular citizens
is here to buy more guns of course
n_r_a_ once
illegal gun sales right or gun sales to
people who commit crimes with a much
insight and they're not gonna be leagues
n_r_a_'s preventing them from being a
legal so chris cox their head of n_r_a_
inappropriately named
says there are a will oppose any
amendments offered to as six four nine
they restrict fundamental second then
the freedoms including but not limited
to proposals that would ban
probably lawfully owned firearms and
magazines or penalize the private
transfer or firearms
than expansion a background checks
this includes a
misguided compromise proposal drafted by
senator still mansion
pat toomey chat show work
as we have noted previously spending
account shows or also air
will not reduce violent crime or keep
our kids safe in their schools
given the importance of these issues
though some all in tiananmen minsk or
proposals will be considered in n_r_a_'s
future candidate evaluations
in other words no no no no no knocked it
that's all we give you an actor
no background checks whatsoever if you
want corn any way shape or form or a
great jointly will run ads against his
allies guy is not a garden that is india
it terrible like apple tv grease on
ninety-one
presented because that's what they're
threatening to do
uh... seem so scary period
he live in a democracy
but in reality what they're going to do
is
bier spent as lying about your record et
cetera they possess when they use the
money for so
but it gets worse
they also say quote
passionate failed to do so mean need all
the requirements
the n_r_a_ will make an exception to our
center policy of not scoring
procedural votes
as strongly oppose a cloture motion to
moved to file past univ
of at six four nine
now what know were they throw cloture
motion as six for and what it was a
they're saying
you get a final vote on this bill begin
filibuster the meaning the oil spill
must repent
this eight if you don't filibuster
you know one of those extraordinary step
of filibustering this
even though we don't know lingering
filibusters
regrading this one
and a marketing guess your record
and then run ads against
even though they got almost
everything they wanted
president obama me in his nature
total an under cravin weakness susan
louise
allotment what
and their are a says the and so on
not interested
the battle down here in florida
i know you got my fee per get between my
toes
and that's how politics is played in
america
with the republicans
bashing the democrats into the ground
and the democrats saying
please may i have another
this proposal by mentioning to me stock
it's either since tabloid has almost
nothing
it's this are removed from not playing
and he was all but a lot begging for it
and then i think that i think i mean and
you knew that
okay you know every time there's a
question of all what we did
all what did you know there are
republicans in the world
all really what you think i have
caroline
here's what you do
kevin issue or ninety one percent a
country grease review how many times you
make me say this
so you're right on a commission marks
you say in all of the year old
okay
your guest background just i wanna
universal background check you are
watching us now universal background
check
no balls knocks at times
right one gets me
andy take your money and boomers giving
you money
will he take bloomberg's what do you
take your own money
in the white them off the map
but people signed in washington like you
can't do that
all-white couldn't you
what do you mean ninety five percent of
the country how much do use sock at
politics
demands of the country you need a
hundred and twenty eight percent of the
country
how much do you suck at politics
you give me ninety one percent on any
issue
and i won't break my opponents back
introduced spinal fluid
but these are resolved all of you know
israel
it's
who believe that you want to send the
groom's problem was that i was there was
already in oregon and separate
them sometimes that it
you are you said to me how does anybody
column so the democrat did produce