NINA MAK: When the media covers
pet cloning, it's often
fluff pieces and these warm,
fuzzy pieces about, oh, look
how cute these animals
are and isn't it cool
that we could do this?
And there's very little
coverage, if any, of what it
really meant to clone that
animal and what it took.
DR. DUANE KRAEMER: I think
it more of reproduction.
If we had created her, we'd
have started from
nothing and made her.
But we started with ova from
other cats and cells from
another cat and just put them
together in a way that they
could reproduce.
That's not vastly different
than people
that arrange for mating.
It's just that we threw
in some technology.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
DR. DUANE KRAEMER: I'm
Duane Kraemer.
I'm a professor at Texas
A&M University.
I've been working in the area of
embryo transfer cloning and
genetic engineering.
My dream was to become
a farmer.
And I went to the university
intending to just get what I
needed to come back.
And then I got bit by
the research bug.
My father was very disappointed
that I didn't
come back to the farm.
My mother said, well, I knew
you'd find something better.
And I didn't mean that it was
better, it was just different.
Cloning, as it's most
customarily practiced at the
present, involves the transfer
of nuclei from cells and
transferring those cells into
eggs where the nucleus has
been removed, and then the
nucleus from the animal to be
cloned is put in its place.
If it's a mammal, those new
embryos then have to be
transferred into recipient
females for them
to carry on to term.
And usually, those recipient
animals nurse them and raise
them as well.
This is the first of the
deer to be cloned.
This is Dewey.
Students named him after me.
I think it's because I insisted
that he be allowed to
be born natural birth.
And he survived.
I think that earned me that
privilege, I guess.
NINA MAK: The truth is that
cloning is highly experimental
and very problematic.
And most of the time,
it doesn't work.
Only a few clones have
actually been born
successfully.
And of the ones that have
been, a good percentage
actually end up dying within the
first six months, because
they have some sort of
complication, health
abnormality, a physical
deformity,
something like that.
You talk about using a very
large number of animals to
even try to produce
just one clone.
DR. DUANE KRAEMER: Some people
just don't like anything
that's unnatural and think
they can abide by that.
But of course, most of the
things they do are unnatural.
I think it has to do with the
Hollywood version, to some
extent, of cloning.
They have always pretty
much made it a
monster kind of activity.
Well, I hope that there will be
continued research to make
it more dependable.
At present, about 25% of
offspring have some type of
abnormality.
They're developmental
abnormalities.
They're not mutations.
They don't get passed on
to the next generation.
But they need special care.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
DR. DUANE KRAEMER: These
are microscopes we
use to find the eggs.
We have to get the eggs
out of ovaries.
It is simple after you
learn how to do it.
But there are just many,
many details
that have to be followed.
And if you do one thing wrong,
then the chain is broken and
you get nothing from it.
Well, our team is working on
a genetic engineering of
livestock to produce animals
that are resistant to disease.
This is the cloned bull that's
resistant to brucellosis,
which is a disease that causes
abortion in cattle and
undulant fever in humans.
The original bull was naturally
resistant to it.
His cells that were used for
cloning him have been stored
for 15 years.
His name is Bruce after
brucellosis.
The process of selective
breeding to produce superior
individuals has been going on
for many years, even using
natural breeding.
And then embryo transfer and
artificial insemination made
that process more efficient,
where you could get more
offspring from the genetically
valuable animals.
If they're superior and can't
reproduce by themselves, then
the techniques such as cloning
can produce offspring.
Anything we do could be used
incorrectly and wrongly.
And most things are by somebody
somewhere, sometime.
GEORGE W. BUSH: Chinese
scientists have derived stem
cells from cloned embryos
created by combining human DNA
and rabbit eggs.
Others have announced plans to
produce cloned children,
despite the fact that laboratory
cloning of animals
has led to spontaneous abortions
and terrible,
terrible abnormalities.
Human cloning is deeply
troubling to
me and to most Americans.
DR. DUANE KRAEMER: The issue of
human cell storage is one
that we have not dealt with.
We don't have any--
don't even have my cells
stored here.
We have not worked at all
with the human cells.
Anyone who could effectively
culture and preserve cells
from animals would be able to
do so with humans as well.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
DR. DUANE KRAEMER: I still
get goose bumps
when I see an embryo.
It's just kind of thrilling to
be able to see something as
simple as a little embryo that
you know can develop into
something as complex as
a complete individual.
CC was, I think, a special cat,
because she was the first
of the pets to be cloned.
It's not a new creation.
We're just helping with
reproduction.
Cats had more to do with
it than we did.
It was their eggs that made it
possible and the recipient
that made it possible.
I'm pleased with the result
and pleased to have been a
part of it.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
SHIRLEY KRAEMER: Come on over
and meet those kitties.
-Yeah.
SHIRLEY KRAEMER: Yeah,
come on over.
-Grazie.
SHIRLEY KRAEMER: Right over
here's their house.
DR. DUANE KRAEMER: She's
up in that window.
SHIRLEY KRAEMER: She's
And that's her favorite place.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
SHIRLEY KRAEMER: Hi, CC.
Come on.
Say hello, CC.
Hi, Cece, how you doing?
How you doing, CC?
I worried when CC
was expecting.
I thought, oh, what if she's
born with two children without
ears and one without a tail?
I'm going to have to say,
oh, this is not good.
But she came through for us.
She came through.
CC came through.
CC's a good kitty.
She said, I know, I know.
She knew exactly what to do.
I really worried about that,
because I thought, I'm going
to have to buy little bottles
and feed each kitten.
No, I didn't have to.
She was a wonderful mother.
DR. DUANE KRAEMER: It's
in the genes.
SHIRLEY KRAEMER: It's
DR. DUANE KRAEMER: Different
species have different
instincts and behaviors.
That's one thing about
the clones.
They all act like their
own species.
SHIRLEY KRAEMER:
Species, yeah.
DR. DUANE KRAEMER: It's a
privilege to have been in a
situation where we could do this
and also to be able to
enjoy her is an added
privilege.
If people want to use their
resources to get a genetic
copy of their original
pet, I don't see
anything wrong with that.
NINA MAK: There's a life that
gets lived-- a beginning,
middle, and an end.
And it's hard to deal
with the end.
But that's part of life.
And trying to prevent that from
being a part of life with
this idea that you could somehow
have the same animal
your whole life--
these are still animals, and
they still very much matter.
And to treat them like objects,
it's not really
something that I find
acceptable.
DR. DUANE KRAEMER: They say,
accusatory, you're playing
God, creating something.
No more than anybody
else is creating.
Besides, I'm doing it to serve
God, not to take his place.
And I'm not playing.
This is my vocation--
work, but really good work.
SHIRLEY KRAEMER: There
you go, CC.
[MUSIC PLAYING]