shows on youtube, this is Genesis Week.
[Music]
And a welcome to this episode of Genesis
Week, the weekly program of creationary
commentary on news, views and events
pertaining to the origins controversy,
exclusive right here on youtube.  Every
single show has been in the top ten most
talked about videos in Science and
Technology on youtube. We bring you the
information the anti-creationists don't
want you to see or hear, and we show the
glory of God in the Creation.
Remember if you get lost in cyberspace,
just punch in wazooloo.com or
genesisweek.com, and you will find us, or
click the ever-so-convenient subscribe
link up top. I'm your host, Ian Juby.
Ratcliffe, et al,  reporting in the
Proceedings of the Natioanal Academy of
Sciences claimed to have produced a
multi-celled organism from single-celled
brewer's yeast - you know, the stuff beer
is made of.  There's gotta be a good
science experiment involved then right?
Christie Wilcox, of Scientific American,
wrote about the paper in her Science
Sushi blog:
Selective pressure indeed! What did they
use for selective pressure?  Wait for it!
Wilcox explains:
Ya - real gentle like.  If we head on over to
the original paper, which is available here,
we find that the researchers used good ol'
gravity to turn a single-cell critter into a
multicelled critter. Now as we all know,
gravity doesn't do that. So how exactly
did they use gravity to accomplish what it
normally doesn't do?  Well let's just say
they were little more aggressive in their
use of gravity:
That's right, 60 times in the centrifuge at
100 G's!!!!!
100 times the force of gravity caused the
single cells to cluster together into
snowflake-like groups.
In other words, the yeast clusters that
survived the centrifuge don't survive as
well in real life.  But their characteristics
allow them to survive better... in a
centrifuge.  So this "evolution" of
multicelled organisms (if that's what you
want to call them) just requires 60 rounds
in a centrifuge, at 100 g's, and voila! You
have multicellular life!  So, which came
first, the multicelled organism, or the
centrifuge? According to the latest
scientific research, the centrifuge came
first!
[swoosh]
1 pound of Brewer's yeast $8
1 laboratory centrifuge, $2,500
lab services to spin yeast in the
centrifuge at 100 g's, $200 per hour.
Making multicelled life that took no
intelligence to make, priceless.
There are some forms of life money can't
buy. For everything else, there's
mastercard.
[swoosh]
Furthermore, the researchers noticed the
involvement of cell death with the
reproduction of these alleged multicelled
organisms.  Obviously this has nothing to
do with real-world multi-celled orgnanisms
which involve reproduction by giving rise
to living cells.  But that aside, even if the
researchers have produced a multi-celled
organism, all they've done is shown that it
took intelligence to make it, and the
intelligent designers even admitted in the
article itself, that their multicelled life will
not survive as well as the single-celled
yeast in the real world.  In other words,
natural selection will weed out the
"multicelled yeast".  This is completely in
line with one of the many points I made in
my "Natural selection" rant, that
single-celled organisms will be favoured
by natural selection, therefore natural
selection cannot be the guiding force for
evolution, because it would weed out
multicelled organisms, like us, thus
inverting the evolutionary tree of life.
In the words of Dr. Duane Gish,
"It's amazing what an unbeliever must
believe to be an unbeliever"
Wilcox was quite correct in stating that
the creationary thinkers would say that
the origins of the first multicelled
organism, and the first life, require a
Creator.  This latest research only serves
to demonstrate that fact in multiple ways.
Whadya know, Jesus was right about
Creation - 2,000 years ago.  Hmmm....I
wonder what else He was right about?
Hmmm?
Marcelo Gleiser, of Dartmouth College,
wrote an NPR blog entitled "Why do so
many have trouble with evolution?" in
which he asked a series of provocative,
and frankly leading questions.
For example, he said:
Really? And what fossil evidence would
that be pray tell?  From the Cambrian,
right through quarternary, we find fossils
of organisms that have not changed!  The
coelacanth first appears in the fossil
record - according to your evolutionary
timescale, 407 MILLION years ago - yet it
is still around today, unchanged.  Same
with the Ediacaran fossils of Mistaken
Point, Newfoundland - we find fossils of
what sure looks like a sea pen, and the
fossil trails of sea anenomes.  How do we
know what they are? Cause they're still
around today. Same thing with
Lepisosteus, Arnia, Heliobatis, and
knightia, as well as the palm fronds from
the green river formation - all around
today. Nothing has changed.  I could give
you probably hundreds of examples like
this, but you get the point. What we see in
the fossil record is stasis, and extinction -
neither of which help evolution, but
certainly do fit the Genesis account of
Creation, and judgment in a worldwide
flood.
Gleiser claimed these fossils are
Hogwash.  How many dozens of examples
would you like of "carefully dated" fossils
that later on were re-dated because the
"careful dating" didn't give the age the
evolutionary scientists wanted?  Hmmmm?
Skull 1470 was a classic example, using
dozens of dating tests, confirming one
another - until the fossil was determined
to have been another age based on
evolutionary assumptions - at which point
a whole pile more careful dating was
conducted thus proving the "new" date.
Radiometric dating doesn't date the
fossils - evolutionary assumptions date
the fossils, end of discussion.
Gleiser went on:
Again, apparently Gleiser is unaware of
the facts, so allow me to enlighten.
Bacterial resistance to antibiotics is a
change in the population of the bacteria -
the resistant bacteria was already there,
there was no "evolution."  This was
demonstrated by the discovery of bodies
from Franklin expedition to the Canadian
High Arctic, in 1845. After getting
stranded in the Arctic, the entire crew
died one by one, and some of the bodies
were buried on Beechey Island.  These
bodies were exhumed in the 1980's, and
bacteria from the intestines of the bodies
were discovered to be resistant to
antibiotics!  This was some 140 YEARS
before antibiotics were even invented!
Obviously, the resistant bacteria already
existed, thus there is no "evolution" going
on here. Antibiotics are simply killing off
the bacteria that are susceptible, leaving
behind a population of bacteria which are
less evolved, because you've now lost
some of the variation within that
population - you killed them off!
Gleiser then levels a criticism against
Creationary thinkers:
HOGWASH!  Not only has he leveled this
criticism against myself, he has also
leveled it against the founding fathers of
the sciences, who, like myself, considered
it God's calling on their lives to search
out and understand the Created world.
You know, people like Newton, Pasteur,
Kepler, Boyle, Pascal, Babbage, Joule,
Faraday, Maxwell, Sedgwick, Owen, and
numerous other fathers of the modern
sciences.  Then there's modern scientists
like Dr. Raymond Damadian - the inventor
of the MRI, Dr. Keith Wanser, professor of
physics at Cal state and author of 48
published papers and 7 US patents. Or
Dr. Jonathan Sanford, co-inventor of the
"Gene gun", or Dr. Robert Herrmann,
retired professor of mathematics at the
US Naval Academy who ranks in the top
2% of in the production of peer reviewed
papers, including over a dozen
peer-reviewed papers directly related to
his General Intelligent Design model.
Obviously, Gleiser's criticism is just plain
untrue.
This has nothing to do with whether or
not I like evolution Mr. Gleiser, this has
everything to do with THE TRUTH, to
which evolutionary theory seems to have
a strange allergy.
[Scary, dramatic music]
Wahoo! Mail for me?
Once again Genesis Week was in the top
ten most talked about shows in Science
and Technology on YouTube, thanks to
everyone who watched, and those who
were brave enough to comment.  Lawilson
kicked things off with more of his
delusional rants:
Lawilson has flown off the handle like
this, many, many times, throwing out a
rash of  false accusations, and again
demonstrating that he didn't even
understand what I said. Joe Taylor had
nothing to do with the Nova Scotia tracks
- I said *I* did the research.  And anybody
who knows Joe Taylor knows that he is a
highly-religious tea-totaller in the extreme,
so frankly your slanderous accusations of
his being a drunk is, utterly ridiculous!  I'm
trying to be polite here in my wording,
which is extremely difficult because your
remarks are SO ludicrous!  How could you
even say this publically, knowing that
people who know Joe Taylor personally
are going to read your remarks and point
out your foolishness?   You have yet to
demonstrate how the tracks I have
discussed are "fabricated," and as for
Baugh's "fabricated" tracks, have you
forgotten that those were excavated from
underneath 18 inches of solid rock, which
was broken up and removed in front of
dozens of eye witnesses. In fact, usually
Baugh was standing there, watching, and
not even being the one digging.  Hundreds
of eye witnesses over the years will bear
testimony to this, and you have just called
all of them frauds and liars as well.  Lance,
I keep telling you, and keep hoping that
one day you will learn not to embarrass
yourself, flying off the handle like this,
hurling around such ridiculous,
unfounded accusations.  So far, it appears
you still have not learned your lesson.
When will you learn that when you do
this, the only who winds up looking bad,
is you?
There were a number of noteworthy and
very interesting comments left on the last
program, to which I have nothing to add!
A couple of interesting comments were
left in discussion by IloveYouViruses and
TheScienceFoudation:
Thank you, and I agree!  The problem I run
into is what words should I use? For
example, I agree that extinction is an
assumption, but the point being that even
if that assumption is correct, it doesn't
help evolution, so I play by the
evolutionary rules to show that it still
doesn't support evolution.  As for the
progression of time allegedly evident in
the fossil order, thanks for mentioning
this because nowhere do I mean to imply
that there is a fossil order. My own
first-hand research all over North America
has shown me over and over again that
there is NO fossil order.
Which brings us to
TheScienceFoundation's interesting reply
to what IloveYouViruses had to say:
I actually partly agree with
TheScienceFoundation here; the problem
is the alleged sorting is non-existent.  Yes,
there is a partial sorting where typically
you find one type of organism with
another, but even that tends to be
inconsistent, and it's actually
inconclusive.  For example, Coelacanths
and whales live together today, in the
same environment. We also find them
both in the fossil record, but to the best
of my knowledge, they have never been
found together in the fossil record.  So the
absence or presence of a fossil in a
specific layer really has nothing to do with
whether or not the organism was there.  I
could give you literally dozens of
examples like this, where we know the
organism was present, but yet not
preserved in the layer.  Thus the alleged
fossil sequence is invalidated on this one
point alone.  I would suggest that the
evidence for hydrodynamics is in the
sedimentology.
[laughing] Uh - in what way, pray tell, is
removing ratings "dishonest?"  In fact,
throwing around false accusations, like
falsely accusing me of being dishonest, is
dishonest.  I turned off ratings because of
anonymous abuse. If people want to
abuse me, they can leave a comment.
None of this cowardly anonymous ratings
stuff - you stick your name on your
comment and be accountable for your
words and actions.  Because I want the
whole world to see who the abusers are,
and just what kind of people they are.
Vegavis had some more to say on the
Horton bluff trackways:
Again, thanks for writing in, but I need to
ask a few questions: Found a new
specimen of what? More of the fossil
footprints? Or Baropezia itself?  Where is
the fossil foot of baropezia to compare to
the fossil footprints?  The footprints of
what is claimed to be baropezia elsewhere
do not even vaguely resemble the Horton
Bluff tracks.  In fact the original reports
specifically mention the absence of claw
impressions at the Horton Bluff tracks. As
I mentioned, and anyone can go to the
trackway and verify for themselves, the
tracks were clearly made by a bipedal
animal.  The tracks perfectly match a
known creature - the ostrich.  However,
that interpretation is rejected in favour of
an unknown organism - baropezia.
Lastly, TubeNotMe brought up another
interesting example of fossil bird tracks:
Thanks for writing in.
Well that's enough for this week - thanks
for making Genesis Week one of the most
talked about programs on youtube.  Join
me again next Thursday, and please
share the show with your friends using
the convenient "Share" button down
below - easily posting it on twitfaceplus.
As Jesus said, i am the Way the TRUTH
and the LIFE, no man comes to the Father
but through me."  See you on the flip side.