JACK NARRATING: Blood
and violence--
these properties reside in the
soul, along with God and love
and such things.
So when people say that violence
followed my brothers
all their lives, I am inclined
to disagree.
It was always there--
within.
-We are survivors.
We control the fear.
And without the fear, we are
all as good as dead.
-This here's the new deputy.
He wants to work it
out so everybody
gets to do some business.
-I'm going to make your life
real difficult from now on if
you don't toe the line,
country boy.
-Don't you ever touch
me again.
-There's a feeling around
these parts that these
Bondurants is indestructible.
-[CHUCKLES]
Do you mean immortal?
Do you have any idea what a
Thompson submachine gun does
to a mortal?
[GUNFIRE]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
-Pure corn whiskey.
-That's impressive.
-You want more of this stuff?
-As much as you can bring me.
-You're an outlaw, Jack.
-No.
It's just a matter
of perspective.
-This is a war they's
a-waging.
You ain't going to survive.
-I'm a Bondurant.
We don't lay down for nobody.
-Ain't that just like you to
believe your own damn legend.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
JACK NARRATING: My brother,
Forrest, once said, nothing
can kill us.
We can never die.
But nobody leaves this
world alive.
[GUNSHOT]