FRED GALL: See, if I brought
some dudes to this, they'd be
like, are you fucking
serious, man?
I don't know if I'm gonna
be able to rig this one.
I'll try, though.
Fuck it, let's move on.
That's good enough, right?
PATRICK O'DELL: Hi.
Welcome back to the Epically
Later'd show.
This episode, I went out to
Jersey, met up with Fred Gall.
He took me around.
We looked at spots, incredibly
crappy spots that you gotta
skate if you're from New Jersey
or if you're from the
East Coast.
I think Fred brought something
refreshing to
skating in the mid-'90s.
Those Eastern Exposure videos
were just guys hauling ass
down the street, skating
switch--
you know, pole jams and late
shove-its and stuff.
[CHEERING]
PATRICK O'DELL: That's it.
This is a day in the life
with Freddy Gall.
FRED GALL: So what's up, man?
Check it out.
You know, usually all these pro
skaters, they got their
hot rides and shit.
Well, I rock my grandmother's
station wagon, man.
Love this car.
I learned to ollie in this
driveway, actually.
I'll show you.
I have a parking block that we
stole when I was 10 years old,
and it's still there.
It's been in my grandmother's
driveway for 18 years.
PATRICK O'DELL: You're still
the skate whiz to her?
FRED GALL: Yeah.
28-year-old skate whiz.
We'll go meet her right now.
Hello.
Hi.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Oh.
Not me.
FRED GALL: Well, now
it's a flower--
FRED GALL: It's all right.
I'm just showing them.
Yeah, this has been here
for 18 years now.
Used to slide good.
I don't know, it doesn't
look like it anymore.
No complies and stuff.
It's pretty funny.
FEMALE SPEAKER: He had
a ramp right there.
And he would skate all day,
all night, clunking away.
And of course, I took him
to all the stores
to get him his clothes.
You see, I don't understand
his profession.
I don't understand it.
And when he'd say, look it,
I'm getting a sponsor.
Look at my picture in a
magazine, or on the boards and
the sneakers.
I couldn't comprehend.
How could this all happen?
FRED GALL: This is my
first board graphic.
Neil Blender drew it on,
like, a napkin or
something like that.
And I was pretty hyped.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yeah, we're
very proud of him.
Except get a job, Fred.
Yeah, we all care
and love Freddy.
He can do no wrong in my eyes.
I'll tell you that.
You can lambast him once
in a while, but--
PATRICK O'DELL: What
do you mean?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Huh?
PATRICK O'DELL: What do
you mean, lambasted?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Lambasting.
PATRICK O'DELL: What
does that--
FEMALE SPEAKER: Just slapping
him, you know.
JAKE PHELPS: Oh, I would say
Frank the Tank, that's '94.
Switch 5-0 hubba hideout
on the cover.
I think he came out here and
he pretty much blew it out.
I think it was in the
Eastern Exposure
vid, he did some shit--
Freddy, he's a really
good skater.
He still is a great skater.
And he went for it.
I could see this look on his
face that he genuinely had the
same stoke that he had when he
was a little kid when he first
bombed a hill on his driveway.
DAEWON SONG: He's been
around for a while.
He's one person you can
say paid his dues.
Eastern Exposure videos,
all that stuff, yeah.
He's one of the guys.
He's more raw.
He's kind of like
a Ricky Oyola.
There's so many different types
of skating nowadays that
it's good you got those
guys around.
FRED GALL: I mean, I watch them
till this day, and they
get my psyched to go
skate and whatnot.
It's just a good
vibe and that.
It's like, we never really
had a legit filmer.
Dan was the first dude
to come and film.
And we'd be so psyched, because
it was so clean and
looked so legit that that's
what actually got us real
hyped on film, was his style of
filming and him being down
to just come down to Philly all
the time and just film.
Other than that, we would
just film each other
with whoever's camera.
Back then, it was just like
everything was new, so you
could just do whatever.
And it was all tricks
no one had done.
I mean, now I'll go out and
fucking pull my hair out
sometimes trying to film video
parts, because you gotta keep
it up to par.
PATRICK O'DELL: You think
there's some way in that all
the Jersey skaters
are similar?
FRED GALL: Yeah, definitely.
I mean, people who grow up in
Cali and they got all the
perfect ground at the schools
and stuff-- like, we're used
to skating shitty spots.
They always look
great on film.
They always look cool and
definitely different.
MALE SPEAKER: Damn.
FRED GALL: I bring people
to some spots and
they hate them, man.
And they're just like, how the
fuck do you skate this shit?
I don't know, I like
that shit.
We would skate New York City
a lot before Newark.
I mean, because it's
always real ghetto.
But just search it out, and
there's definitely spots.
Check it out.
Up here's--
this is Seth Boyden,
some of the most
dangerous projects in Newark.
It'll be up here on the right.
Yeah I wouldn't--
I don't know.
If there was a spot in there--
FEMALE SPEAKER: [INAUDIBLE].
FRED GALL: --I'd probably
go skate it.
I've definitely put myself into
bad situations before.
I actually got robbed in Albany
a couple months back.
I got fucking hit in the face.
I don't know what he hit me
with, but it wasn't no fist
because it fucking broke my
sinus cavity right here, and
fractured this cheek bone.
PATRICK O'DELL: So how old
were you when you were
skating, first starting to
go to New York City?
FRED GALL: Like, 11 years
old, I think.
It was in my first
banks contest.
And my mom used to bring
me and shit.
She would pull the
car right up.
That's when the banks were like,
you could do anything.
Just park at the banks.
My mom would drink tall
cans of beer while
I skated all day.
My mom made me this shirt.
And it's--
what was going to be my-- it was
a joking graphic, but she
just drew kicking down
the Twin Towers.
And now look what
happened now.
They really fell down.
It's fucked up.
It's kind of spooky, man.
This was given to me, dude.
I went to my friend's house.
He's like, yeah, I got
a Hosoi board.
I'm like, you gotta be
fucking kidding me.
You got a original
Hosoi board?
He's like, here, you
can have it.
I was like, thank you
so much, dude.
What can I give to you?
PATRICK O'DELL: Do you have any
boards that you've skated,
like, old boards that--
FRED GALL: See, you could ask my
grandmother about that one,
because my basement used to be
stacked up with Alva boards,
every single board
I had in my life.
And she likes to throw
things out.
And I came over one day
and they were gone.
And I go, no, you didn't.
Please tell me you didn't.
Yeah, she threw, like,
50 boards away.
PATRICK O'DELL: He seems like
he's had comebacks over and
over, like he's one of
those people that--
JAKE PHELPS: Well, I
think that he can
do whatever he wants.
I mean, a lot of skaters
are like that.
I mean, just because someone's
not doing something-- do you
think Heath and Fowler can't
still fucking ollie over your
fucking car?
Do you think Julian
still bombs hills?
Yeah, probably.
FRED GALL: This is my
backyard, basically.
Grew up hitching trains over
here, painting them, whatever.
The freight yard's there,
so it's like a
playground back here.
I don't know if you should put
the weed part in, but you can
film it anyway.
Because Granny's gonna
wanna watch it.
I mean, I've taken them far as
hell this way, but I've gotten
really worked as a kid holding
on to the back.
And it really starts hauling
ass, and you gotta jump off on
to this shit.
I don't know, man.
I got severely worked,
and I didn't do
it for a while again.
Just land and just cut
up everywhere.