1/2 million views so far.
EMMA CLARK: I can't believe
she would do this.
FEMALE SPEAKER: RPattz and I
went to Carlisle to meet the
girl behind the meme.
[THEME MUSIC]
EMMA CLARK: Oh my God.
Oh [INAUDIBLE].
FEMALE SPEAKER: So what were
your main interests, and what
was your life like before
Twilight, if you can give me a
bit of an Emma Clark biog?
EMMA CLARK: I didn't
enjoy my work.
I didn't have much
of a social life.
And then all of a sudden, there
was just like, videos
and then friends and
then people who I
shared interests with.
And I'd just never
had that before.
My whole life is built around
it, and I love it.
I love the fact that I've just
got such a brilliant life that
I never had before.
And it's so refreshing.
You get rubbish from
people, as well.
People say, oh, you fat
this and you fat that.
And it's fine.
They're still watching the
video, so it's fine.
FEMALE SPEAKER: So we're
off to Chez Emma now.
Maybe I'm going to become
a Twihard like you.
EMMA CLARK: Do it.
Do it.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Your tattoo
isn't Twilight-related, is it?
EMMA CLARK: It stands for
bullshit, to remind me never
to ever put up with any.
And it stands for Bella Swan
and Buffy Summers.
And be safe and be
strong, which
are quotes from Twilight.
Come in.
FEMALE SPEAKER: So this is
where the magic happens.
What do you do to psych yourself
up before you're
making a vlog?
EMMA CLARK: I find it helps if
I'm angry when I start making
a video, because then it's
easier to kind of-- grrr.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
And do you script any of it,
or is it all of the cuff?
EMMA CLARK: Just press record
and whatever happens, happens.
And if it's rubbish, then I
deliberately won't edit it
out, because the more
embarrassing and annoying
stuff is what makes the
videos so watchable.
FEMALE SPEAKER: So this
is your bag of
Twilight goodies, right?
EMMA CLARK: Yes, for
the time being.
I've got other stuff, but it's
kind of in safe hiding.
This is my necessary stash.
It's just gorgeous.
I've got my original copy, all
my photos with the cast from
years of conventions.
FEMALE SPEAKER: What about
Kristen Stewart?
EMMA CLARK: I met her as well,
but they weren't doing
pictures, which I'm not that
bothered about now, obviously.
Oh, I don't understand how
she could do this.
Why?
Why would you cheat on
Robert Pattinson?
What's the point of that?
What do you stand to achieve by
cheating on Robert Pattinson?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Where were you
when you heard the news or
whatever-- when you
saw the pictures?
EMMA CLARK: When I first found
out, it was about 3 o'clock in
the morning.
How can you say publicly that
you're so sorry, and you love
him, and yet, you did it?
It just doesn't make sense.
The way he looked at her before
it all happened--
it was like there was no
one else in the room.
It was like it was
Edward and Bella.
And I think that's why it's so
shocking to so many people,
including me.
No.
FEMALE SPEAKER: What word
comes to your mind?
EMMA CLARK: Hussy.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Oh, God.
Are you scared about
Twilight ending?
EMMA CLARK: It's going
to be a bereavement.
I am in love with this book, and
I'm in love with everybody
that made it what it is--
and the movie-- and I just don't
want it to end, because
it means so much to me.
It kind of doesn't
have to end.
I don't want it to.
I want it to keep going.
It's going to be-- oh my
God, what do I do now?
What do I do with my life?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Thanks so
much for having me.
EMMA CLARK: Yeah, thank you.
FEMALE SPEAKER: It was
so nice to meet you.
EMMA CLARK: It was
nice to meet you.
Thanks.
FEMALE SPEAKER: See you
on the internet.
EMMA CLARK: See you soon.
[THEME MUSIC]