- The old appeals to racial,
sexual and religious chauvinism
to rabid nationalist fervor
are beginning not to work.
-The business of who I am
and whether I'm good or bad
or achieving or not, all
that's learned along the way.
-It's just a ride
and we can change it anytime we want.
It's only a choice.
No effort, no work, no job,
no savings of money.
-I realized that I
had the game wrong
that the game was to find
out what I already was.
-We were saying,
how very important it is
to bring about,
in the human mind
the radical revolution.
The crisis is a crisis
in consciousness.
A crisis that cannot, anymore
accept the old norms
the old patterns
the ancient traditions.
And, considering what
the world is now
with all the misery
conflict
destructive brutality
aggression
and so on...
Man
is still as he was.
Is still brutal
violent
aggressive
acquisitive
competitive.
And, he's built a society
along these lines.
.
ZEITGEIST ADDENDUM
"It is no measure of
health to be well adjusted
to a profoundly sick society.
" J. Krishnamurti
-Society today, is composed
of a series of institutions.
.
From political institutions
legal institutions
religious institutions.
To institutions of social class
familial values
and occupational specialization.
It is obvious the
profound influence
these traditionalized
structures have
in shaping our understandings
and perspectives.
Yet, of all the social
institutions, we are born into
directed by and conditioned upon
there seems to be no system
as taken for granted
and misunderstood
as the monetary system.
Taking on nearly
religious proportions
the established monetary
institution exists
as one of the most unquestioned
forms of faith there is.
How money is created, the
policies by which it is governed
.
and how it truly affects society
are unregistered interests of the
great majority of the population.
In a world where 1% of the population
owns 40% of the planet's wealth.
In a world where 34.000
children die every single day
from poverty and
preventable diseases
and where 50% of the
world's population
lives on less than
2 dollars a day...
One thing is clear.
Something is very wrong.
And, whether we are
aware of it or not
the lifeblood of all of our
established institutions
and thus society
itself, is money.
Therefore, understanding this
institution of monetary policy
is critical to understanding why
our lives are the way they are.
Unfortunately, economics is often
viewed with confusion and boredom.
Endless streams of
financial jargon
coupled with
intimidating mathematics
quickly deters people from
attempts at understanding it.
However, the fact is:
The complexity associated with the
financial system is a mere mask
designed to conceal one of the most
socially paralyzing structures
humanity has ever endured.
"None are more
hopelessly enslaved
than those who falsely
believe they are free."
-Johann Wolfgang von Goethe
- 1749-1832
-A number of years ago
the central bank of the United
States, the Federal Reserve
produced a document entitled
"Modern Money Mechanics".
This publication detailed the
institutionalized practice
of money creation as utilized
by the Federal Reserve
and the web of global
commercial banks it supports.
On the opening page the
document states its objective:
"The purpose of this
booklet is to describe
the basic process
of money creation
in a 'fractional reserve'
banking system."
It then proceeds to describe
this fractional reserve process
through various
banking terminology.
A translation of which
goes something like this:
The United States government
decides it needs some money.
So it calls up the
Federal Reserve
and requests, say,
10 billion dollars.
The FED replies saying:
"Sure, we'll buy ten billion
in government bonds from you".
So the government takes
some pieces of paper
paints some official
looking designs on them
and calls them treasury bonds.
Then it puts a value on these bonds
to the sum of 10 billion dollars
and sends them over to the FED.
In turn, the people of the FED
draw up a bunch of impressive
pieces of papers themselves
only this time, calling them
"Federal Reserve notes"
also designating a value of ten
billion dollars to the set.
The FED then takes these notes
and trades them for the bonds.
Once this exchange is complete
the government then takes the ten
billion in federal reserve notes
and deposits it into
an bank account.
And, upon this deposit
the paper notes officially
become legal tender money
adding ten billion to
the US money supply.
And there it is, ten billion
in new money has been created.
Of course, this example
is a generalization.
For, in reality, this transaction
would occur electronically
with no paper used at all.
In fact, only 3% of the US money
supply exists in physical currency.
The other 97 percent essentially
exists in computers alone.
Now, government bonds are by
design instruments of debt.
And when the FED
purchases these bonds
with money essentially
created out of thin air
the government is
actually promising
to pay back that
money to the FED.
In other words, the money
was created out of debt.
This mind numbing paradox
of how money or value can be
created out of debt or a liability
will become more clear as
we further this exercise.
So, the exchange has been made
and now ten billion dollars sits
in a commercial bank account.
Here is where it gets
really interesting.
For, as based on the
fractional reserve practice
that ten billion dollar deposit
instantly becomes part
of the bank's reserves
just as all deposits do.
And, regarding
reserve requirements
as stated in "Modern
Money Mechanics":
"A bank must maintain
legally required reserves
equal to a prescribed
percentage of its deposits".
It then quantifies this by stating:
"Under current regulations
.
the reserve requirement against
most transaction accounts is 10%".
This means that with a ten
billion dollar deposit
10%, or one billion, is held
as the required reserve
.
while the other nine billion is
considered an excessive reserve
and can be used as the
basis for new loans.
.
Now, it is logical to assume,
that this nine billion
is literally coming out of the
existing ten billion dollar deposit.
However, this is
actually not the case.
What really happens, is
that the nine billion
is simply created
out of thin air
on top of the existing 10
billion dollar deposit.
This is how the money
supply is expanded.
As stated in "Modern
Money Mechanics":
"Of course they" -the banks-
"do not really pay out loans for the
money they receive as deposits.
If they did this, no additional
money would be created.
What they do when
they make loans
is to accept promissory
notes" -loan contracts-
"in exchange for
credits" -money-
"to the borrowers'
transaction accounts."
In other words, the nine billion
can be created out of nothing
simply because there is a
demand for such a loan
and that there is a 10
billion dollar deposit
to satisfy the reserve
requirements.
Now, let's assume that
somebody walks into this bank
and borrows the newly available
nine billion dollars.
They will then most
likely take that money
and deposit it into
their own bank account.
The process then repeats.
For that deposit becomes
part of the bank's reserves.
10% is isolated and in turn 90% of
the nine billion, or 8.1 billion
is now available as newly
created money for more loans.
And, of course, that 8.1 can
be loaned out and redeposited
creating an additional
7.2 billion.
To 6.5 billion...
to 5.9 billion... etc.
This deposit money
creation loan cycle
can technically go
on to infinity.
The average mathematical result
is that about 90 billion dollars
can be created on top of
the original 10 billion.
In other words,
for every deposit
that ever occurs in
the banking system
about nine times that amount can
be created out of thin air.
Money-Jitters.
Ask the obliging Bank of America
for a jar of soothing
instant money.
M-O-N-E-Y in the form of a
convenient personal loan.
So, now that we understand
how money is created
by this fractional
reserve banking system
a logical yet illusive
question might come to mind:
What is actually giving this
newly created money value?
The answer: the money
that already exists.
The new money essentially steals value
from the existing money supply.
For the total pool of
money is being increased
irrespective to demand
for goods and services.
And, as supply and demand finds
equilibrium, prices rise
diminishing the purchasing power
of each individual dollar.
This is generally
referred to as inflation.
And inflation is essentially
a hidden tax on the public.
-What is the advice
that you generally get?
And that is, inflate
the currency.
They don't say:
debase the currency.
devalue the currency.
They don't say: cheat the
people who are safe.
They say: lower the
interest rates.
The real deception is when we
distort the value of money.
When we create money out of
thin air, we have no savings.
Yet there's so called "capital".
So, my question
boils down to this:
How in the world can we expect to
solve the problems of inflation
that is the increase in the supply
of money, with more inflation?
-Of course, it can't.
The fractional reserve
system of monetary expansion
is inherently inflationary.
For the act of expanding
the money supply,
without there being a proportional
expansion of goods and services
in the economy, will
always debase a currency.
In fact, a quick glance at the
historical values of the US dollar
versus the money supply,
reflects this point definitively
for the inverse
relationship is obvious.
One dollar in 1913 required
$21.60 in 2007 to match value.
That is a 96% devaluation
since the Federal Reserve
came into existence.
Now, if this reality of inherent
and perpetual inflation
seems absurd and
economically self defeating
hold that thought, for
absurdity is an understatement
in regard to how our financial
system really operates.
For in our financial
system money is debt
and debt is money.
Here is a chart of the US money
supply from 1950 to 2006.
Here is a chart of the US national
debt for the same period.
How interesting it is that the
trends are virtually the same.
For the more money there is,
the more debt there is.
The more debt there is,
the more money there is.
To put it a different way, every
single dollar in your wallet
is owed to somebody by somebody.
For remember:
The only way the money can come
into existence is from loans.
Therefore, if everyone in the country
were able to pay off all debts
including the government
there would not be one
dollar in circulation.
"If there were no debts
in our money system
there wouldn't be any money."
-Marriner Eccles- Governor of the
Federal Reserve September 30th, 1941
-In fact, the last time
in American history
the national debt was
completely paid off was in 1835
after president Andrew Jackson
shut down the central bank
that preceded the
Federal Reserve.
In fact, Jackson's entire political
platform essentially revolved
around his commitment to
shut down the central bank.
Stating at one point:
"The bold efforts the present bank
has made to control the government
are but premonitions of the fate
that awaits the American people
should they be deluded into a
perpetuation of this institution
or the establishment
of another like it."
Unfortunately his message
was short lived,
and the international
bankers succeeded
to install another central bank
in 1913, the Federal Reserve.
And as long as this institution
exists, perpetual debt is guaranteed.
.
Now, so far we have
discussed the reality
that money is created out
of debt through loans.
These loans are based
on a bank's reserves
and reserves are
derived from deposits.
And through this
fractional reserve system
any one deposit can create 9
times its original value.
In turn, debasing the
existing money supply
raising prices in society.
And, since all this money
is created out of debt
and circulated randomly
through commerce
people become detached
from their original debt
and a disequilibrium exists
where people are forced
to compete for labor
in order to pull enough money
out of the money supply
to cover their costs of living.
As dysfunctional and backwards
as all of this might seem
there is still one thing we have
omitted from this equation.
And it is this element
of the structure
which reveals the truly fraudulent
nature of the system itself.
The application of interest.
When the government borrows
money from the FED
or when a person borrows
money from a bank
it almost always has to be paid
back with accrued interest.
In other words, almost every
single dollar that exists
must be eventually returned to a
bank with interest paid as well.
But, if all money is borrowed
from the Central Bank
and is expanded by commercial
banks through loans
only what would be referred
to as the "principal"
is being created in
the money supply.
So then, where is the money
to cover all of the
interest that is charged?
Nowhere.
It doesn't exist.
The ramifications of
this are staggering
for the amount of money owed back
to the banks will always exceed
the amount of money that is
available in circulation.
This is why inflation is a
constant in the economy
for new money is always needed
to help cover the perpetual
deficit built into the system
caused by the need
to pay the interest.
What this also means,
is that mathematically
defaults and bankruptcy are
literally built into this system
and there will always be
poor pockets of society
that get the short
end of the stick.
An analogy would be a
game of musical chairs
for the once music stops,
somebody is left out to dry.
And that's the point.
It invariably transfers true wealth
from the individual to the banks.
For, if you are unable
to pay for your mortgage
they will take your property.
This is particularly
enraging when you realize
that not only is such
a default inevitable
due to the fractional reserve practice,
but also because of the fact
that the money that the
bank loaned to you
didn't even legally exist
in the first place.
In 1969 there was a
Minnesota court case
involving a man
named Jerome Daly
who was challenging the foreclosure
of his home by the bank
which provided the
loan to purchase it.
His argument was that
the mortgage contract
required both parties
-being he and the bank-
each put up a legitimate form
of property for the exchange.
In legal language this
is called consideration:
[ a contract's basis.
a contract is founded on an exchange
of one form of consideration
for another. ]
Mr. Daly explained that
the money was, in fact
not the property of the bank, for
it was created out of nothing
as soon as the loan
agreement was signed.
Remember what "Modern Money
Mechanics" stated about loans?
"What they do, when
they make loans, is to
accept promissory notes
in exchange for credits.
Reserves are unchanged by
the loan transactions.
But, deposit credits
constitute new additions
to the total deposits
of the banking system."
In other words, the money doesn't
come out of their existing assets.
The bank is simply inventing it,
putting up nothing of its own
except for a theoretical
liability on paper.
As the court case progressed
the bank's president Mr.
Morgan took the stand
and in the judge's personal
memorandum, he recalled that
the Plaintiff - bank's
president - admitted that
in combination with the
Federal Reserve Bank
did create the money and credit upon
its books by book-keeping entry.
The money and credit first came into
existence when they created it.
Mr. Morgan admitted that
no US Law or Statute existed which
gave him the right to do this.
A lawful consideration must exist and
be tendered to support the note.
The Jury found that there was no
lawful consideration and I agree.
He also poetically added:
"Only God can create something
of value out of nothing".
And, upon this revelation
the court rejected the
bank's claim for foreclosure
and Daly kept his home.
The implications of this
court decision are immense.
For every time you
borrow money from a bank
whether it is a mortgage
loan or a credit card charge
the money given to you
is not only counterfeit
it is an illegitimate
form of consideration
and hence, voids the
contract to repay.
For the bank never had the money
as property to begin with.
Unfortunately such legal realizations
are suppressed and ignored.
And the game of perpetual wealth
transfer and perpetual debt continues.
And this brings us to
the ultimate question:
Why?
During the American Civil War
President Lincoln bypassed
the high interest loans
offered by the European banks
and decided to do what the
founding fathers advocated
which was to create an independent
and inherently debt-free currency.
It was called "The Greenback".
Shortly after this measure was taken,
an internal document circulated
between private British and
American banking interests, stated:
"...slavery is but
the owning of labor
and carries with it
the care of laborers.
While the European plan
is that capital shall control
labor by controlling wages.
This can be done by
controlling the money.
It will not do to allow the Greenback...
as we cannot control that."
The fractional reserve policy
perpetrated by the Federal Reserve
which has spread in practice
to the great majority
of banks in the world
is, in fact, a system
of modern slavery.
Think about it, money
is created out of debt.
And what the people do
when they are in debt?
They submit to employment
to pay it off.
But if money only can only
be created out of loans
how can society
ever be debt free?
It can't and that's the point.
And it is the fear
of losing assets
coupled with the
struggle to keep up
with the perpetual debt and
inflation inherent in the system
compounded by the inescapable scarcity
within the money supply itself
created by the interest
that can never be repaid
that keeps the
wage-slave in line.
Running on a hamster wheel,
with millions of others
in effect powering an empire
that truly benefits only the
elite at the top of the pyramid.
For, at the end of the day, who
are you really working for?
.
The banks.
Money is created in a bank and
invariably ends up in a bank.
They are the true masters
along with the corporations
and governments they support.
Physical slavery requires
people to be housed and fed.
Economic slavery requires people
to feed and house themselves.
It is one of the
most ingenious scams
for social manipulation
ever created.
And at its core
it is an invisible war
against the population.
Debt is the weapon used to
conquer and enslave societies
and interest is its
prime ammunition.
And, as the majority walks
around oblivious to this reality
the banks in collusion with
governments and corporations
continue to perfect and expand
their tactics of economic warfare
spawning new bases,
such as the World Bank
and International
Monetary Fund [IMF]
while also inventing a
new type of soldier:
The birth of the
Economic Hit Man.
"There are two ways to conquer
and enslave a nation.
One is by sword. The other is by debt."
- John Adams - 1735-1826
-We economic hit men, really have been
the ones responsible for creating
this first truly global empire
and we work many different ways.
John Perkins Former Chief Economist for Chas. T.
Main Inc. Author: Confessions of an Economic Hitman
But perhaps the most
common is that we will
identify a country that has resources
our corporations covet, like oil
and then, arrange a huge
loan to that country
from the World Bank or one
of its sister organizations.
But the money never actually
goes to the country.
Instead it goes to
our big corporations
to built infrastructure
projects in that country.
Power plants, industrial
parks, ports.
Things that benefit a few
rich people in that country
in addition to our corporations
but really don't help the
majority of the people at all.
However, those people, the whole
country is left holding a huge debt.
It's such a big debt they can't repay
it and that's part of the plan
that they can't repay it.
And so, at some point
we economic hit men, go back
to them and say, "Listen,
you owe us a lot of money.
You can't pay your debt. So, sell your oil
real cheap to our oil companies
allow us to build a military
base in your country", or
"send troops in support of ours to
someplace in the world like Iraq"
or "vote with us in the next
UN vote", to have their
electric utility
company privatized and
their water and sewage
system privatized
and sold to US corporations or
other multinational corporations.
So there is a whole
mushrooming thing and
it's so typical of the way the
IMF and the World Bank work.
They put a country in debt and it's
such a big debt it can't pay it
and then you offer to refinance that
debt and pay even more interest
and you demand this quid pro quo
which you call a "conditionality"
or "good governance"
which means basically that they've
got to sell off their resources
including many of their social
services, their utility companies,
their school systems sometimes,
their penal systems
their insurance systems,
to foreign corporations.
So it's a double - triple
- quadruple whammy!
IRAN; 1953
The precedent for economic hit men
really began back in the early 50's
when the democratically elected
Mossadegh who was elected in Iran.
He was considered to be the hope
for democracy in the middle east
and around the world. He was in
Time-Magazine's "Man of the year". But...
one of the things that he ran
on and began to implement was
the idea that foreign oil companies
needed to pay the Iranian people
a lot more for the oil that
they were taking out of Iran
and the Iranian people should benefit
from their own oil. Strange policy.
We didn't like that of course.
But...
we were afraid to do what
we normally were doing
which was to send in the military.
Instead we sent in one CIA agent
Kermit Roosevelt, Teddy
Roosevelt's relative.
And Kermit went in with a
few million dollars and
was very, very effective and efficient
and in a short amount of time
he managed to get
Mossadegh overthrown
and brought in the shah
of Iran to replace him
who always was favorable to oil.
And it was extremely effective.
[ Revolt in Iran ]
"Mobs overthrow Tehran.
Army officers shout that Mossadegh
has surrendered and his regime as
virtual dictator of Iran is ended.
Pictures of the Shah are paraded
through the streets as sentiment reverses.
The Shah is welcomed home."
So back here in the United
States, in Washington
people looked around and said:
"Wow, that was easy and cheap".
So this established
a whole new way
of manipulating countries,
of creating empire.
The only problem with
Roosevelt was that he was a
card carrying CIA agent.
And if he'd been caught
the ramifications could
have been pretty serious.
So very quickly, at that point,
the decision was made to
use private consultants to
channel the money through the
World Bank or the IMF or one
of the other such agencies
to bring in people like me, who
worked for private companies.
So that if we got caught
there would be no
governmental ramifications.
GUATEMALA 1954
When Árbenz became
president of Guatemala
the country was very
much under the thumbs of
United Fruit company, the big
international corporations
and Árbenz ran on this
ticket that said: "You know
we want to give the land
back to the people".
And once he took power, he was
implementing policies that would
would do exactly that, give the
land rights back to the people.
United Fruit didn't
like that very much.
And so, they hired a public relations
firm, launched a huge campaign
in the United States to convince
the United States people
the citizens of the United States,
the press of the United States and
the Congress of the United States,
that Árbenz was a soviet puppet
and that if we allowed
him to stay in power
the Soviets would have a
foothold in this hemisphere.
And that, at that point in time, was
a huge fear on everybody's mind
of the red terror, the
communist terror.
And so, to make a long story short,
out of this public relations campaign
came a commitment on the part of the CIA
and the military to take this man out.
And in fact, we did. We sent in
planes, we sent in soldiers, we sent
in jackals, we sent everything in to take him out.
And did take him out.
And as soon as he was
removed from office
the new guy that took over after him
basically reinstated everything to
the big international corporations,
including United Fruit.
[Ecuador 1981] Ecuador, for many, many
years had been ruled by pro-US dictators
often relatively brutal.
Then it was decided they were gonna have
a truly democratic election.
Jaime Roldós ran for office and his main goal
he said, as president would be
to make sure that Ecuador's
resources were used to help the people.
And he won. Overwhelming.
By more votes than anybody had
ever won anything in Ecuador.
And he began to implement
these policies.
To make sure that the profits
from oil went to help the people.
Well, we didn't like that
in the United States.
I was sent down as one of several
economic hit men to change Roldós.
To corrupt him. To bring him around.
To let him know, you know.
"Ok, you know, you can get very rich,
you and your family, if you play
our game. But if you continue to try
to keep these policies you've promised
you're gonna go.
" He wouldn't listen.
He was assassinated.
As soon as the plane crashed, the
whole area was cordoned off.
The only people allowed in were
US military from a nearby base
and some of the
Ecuadorian military.
When an investigation
was launched
two of the key witnesses
died in car accidents
before they had a
chance to testify.
A lot of very, very strange
things that went on around
the assassination
of Jaime Roldós.
I, like most people who've
really looked at this case
have absolutely no doubt that
it was an assassination.
And, of course, in my position
as an economic hit man
I was always expecting
something to happen to Jaime
whether it'd be a coup or assassination,
I wasn't sure, but that
he would be taken down, because he
was not being corrupted, he would
not allow himself to be corrupted
the way we wanted to corrupt him.
PANAMA 1981
Omar Torrijos,
president of Panama
was, you know, one of my favorite people.
I really, really liked him.
He was very charismatic. He was a guy
who really wanted to help his country.
And when I tried to bribe him or
corrupt him, he said: "Look, John"
- he called me Juanito
- He said: "Look Juanito,
I don't need the money.
What I really need is for my country
to be treated fairly.
I need for the US to repay the
debts that you owe my people for all
the destruction you've done here.
I need to be in a position where I can
help other Latin American countries
win their independence
and be free of this
of this terrible
presence from the North.
You people are
exploiting us so badly.
I need to have the Panama Canal back
in the hands of the Panamanian people.
That's what I want.
And so, leave me alone, don't, you
know, don't try to bribe me".
It was 1981 and, in May, Jaime
Roldos was assassinated.
And Omar was very aware of this.
Torrijos got his family
together and he said:
"I'm probably next, but it's OK
because I've done what
I came here to do
I've renegotiated the Canal.
The Canal will now be in our hands.
" He'd just finished negotiating
the treaty with Jimmy Carter.
In June of that same year,
just a couple of months later
he also went down in
an airplane crash
which, there's no question, was
executed by CIA sponsored jackals.
A tremendous amount
of evidence that
one of Torijos' security guards
handed him, at the last moment
as he was getting on the
plane, a tape recorder.
A small tape recorder
that contained a bomb.
VENEZUELA 2002
It is interesting to me how this
system has continued
pretty much the same way
for years and years and years,
except the economic hit men
have got better and
better and better.
Then we come up with, very recently,
what happened in Venezuela.
In 1998, Hugo Chavez
gets elected president
following a long
line of presidents
who'd been very corrupt and
basically destroyed the economy
of the country.
And Chavez was elected amidst all that.
Chavez stood up to
the United States
and he's done it primarily
demanding that Venezuelan oil
be used to help the
Venezuelan people.
Well, we didn't like that
in the United States.
So in 2002
a coup was staged, which
there's no question in my mind
and most other people's minds,
that the CIA was behind that coup.
The way that that
coup was fomented
was very reflective of what Kermit
Roosevelt had done in Iran.
Of paying people to go
out onto the streets
to riot, to protest, to say
that Chavez was very unpopular.
You know, if you can get a few
thousand people to do that
television can make it look
like it's the whole country
and things start to mushroom.
Except in the case of
Chavez, he was smart enough
and the people were so strongly
behind him, that they overcame it
.
which was a phenomenal moment in
the history of Latin America.
IRAQ 2003
Iraq, actually, is
a perfect example
of the way the whole
system works.
So we, economic hit men, are
the first line of defense.
We go in, we try to
corrupt the governments
and get them to accept
these huge loans
which we then use as leverage
to basically own them.
If we fail, as I failed in
Panama with Omar Torrijos
and Ecuador with Jaime Roldós,
men who refused to be corrupted
then the second line of defense
is we send in the jackals.
And the jackals either overthrow
governments or they assassinate.
And, once that happens and
a new government comes in
boy it's gonna tow
the line because
that new president knows what
will happen if he doesn't.
In the case of Iraq, both
of those things failed.
The economic hit men were not able
to get through to Saddam Hussein.
We tried very hard, we tried
to get him to accept a deal
very similar to what the House of
Saud had accepted in Saudi Arabia
but he wouldn't accept it.
And so the jackals went
in to take him out.
They couldn't do it.
His security was very good.
After all, he at one time,
worked for the CIA.
He'd been hired to assassinate a
former president of Iraq and failed
but he knew the system.
So, in '91, we send in the troops
and we take out the Iraqi military.
.
So, we assume at that point
that Saddam Hussein
is gonna come around.
We could have taken him out,
of course at that time
but we didn't want to.
He's the kind of strong man we like.
He controls his people.
We thought he could control the Kurds
and keep the Iranians in their
border and keep pumping oil for us.
And that once we took out his
military, now he's gonna come around.
So the economic hit men go back
in in the 90's, without success.
.
If they'd had success he'd
still be running the country.
We'd be selling him all
the fighter jets he wants
and everything else he wants, but they
couldn't; they didn't have success.
The jackals couldn't
take him out again
so we sent the
military in once again
and this time we did the
complete job and took him out.
And in the process,
created for ourselves
some very, very lucrative
construction deals
to reconstruct the country that
we'd essentially destroyed.
Which is a pretty good deal
if you own construction
companies, big ones.
So, Iraq shows the three stages.
The economic hit
men failed there.
The jackals failed there.
And as a final measure the military goes in.
And in that way we've
really created an empire
but we've done it very, very subtly.
It's clandestine.
All empires of the past
were built on the military
and everybody knew they
were building them.
The British knew they were
building them, the French
the Germans, the
Romans, the Greeks
and they were proud of it, and
they always had some excuse
like spreading civilization,
spreading some religion
something like that, but they
knew they were doing it.
We don't.
The majority of the people in
the United States have no idea
that we're living off the benefits
of the clandestine empire.
That today there is more slavery
in the world than ever before.
Then you have to ask yourself;
well, if it's an empire,
then who is the emperor?
Obviously our Presidents of the
United States are not emperors.
An emperor is someone
who is not elected
doesn't serve a limited term
and doesn't report to
anyone, essentially.
So you can't classify our
presidents that way.
But we do have what I consider to
be the equivalent of the emperor
and it's what I call
the corporatocracy.
The corporatocracy is
this group of individuals
who run our biggest
corporations.
And they really act as the
emperor of this empire.
They control our media
either through direct
ownership or advertising.
They control most
of our politicians
because they finance
their campaigns
either through the corporations
or through personal contributions
.
that come out of
the corporations.
They're not elected, then
don't serve a limited term
.
they don't report to anybody
and at the very top
of the corporatocracy
you really can't tell
whether the person
is working for a private
corporation or the government
because they're always
moving back and forth.
So, you know, you've got
a guy who one moment
is the president of a big
construction company like Halliburton
and the next moment he's Vice
President of the United States
or the President who was in the oil business.
And this is true
whether you get Democrats or
Republicans in the office.
.
You have this moving back and
forth through a revolving door.
And in a way, our government
is invisible a lot of the time
and its' policies are carried
out by our corporations
on one level or another.
And then again
the policies of the
government are basically
forged by the corporatocracy, and
then presented to the government
.
and they become government policy.
So, there's an incredibly
cozy relationship.
This isn't a conspiracy theory type of thing.
These people don't have to
get together and
plot to do things.
.
They all basically work under
one primary assumption
and that is that they
must maximize profits
.
regardless of the social
and environmental costs.
-This process of manipulation
by the corporatocracy
through the use of debt, bribery
and political overthrow is called
Globalization
Just as the Federal Reserve keeps
the American public in a position
of indentured servitude though
perpetual debt, inflation and interest
the World Bank and IMF serve
this role on a global scale.
The basic scam is simple.
Put a country in debt either
by its own indiscretion
or through corrupting the
leader of that country
then impose "conditionalities" or
"structural adjustment policies"
often consisting
of the following:
Currency devaluation.
When the value of a currency drops,
so does everything valued in it.
This makes indigenous resources
available to predator countries
at a fraction of their worth.
Large funding cuts
for social programs.
These usually include
education and healthcare
compromising the well-being
and integrity of the society
leaving the public
vulnerable to exploitation.
Privatization of
state-owned enterprises.
This means that socially
important systems
can be purchased and regulated by
foreign corporations for profit.
For example, in 1999,
the World Bank insisted
that the Bolivian
government sell
the public water-system
of its third-largest city
to a subsidiary of the US
corporation "Bechtel."
As soon as this
occurred, water bills
for the already impoverished
local residents, skyrocketed.
It wasn't until after a
full-blown revolt by the people
that the Bechtel
contract was nullified.
Then there is trade
liberalization
or the opening up of the economy
through removing any
restrictions on foreign trade.
This allows for a number of
abusive economic manifestations
such as transnational
corporations
bringing in their own
mass-produced products
undercutting the indigenous production
and ruining local economies.
An example is Jamaica;
which, after accepting loans and
conditionalities from the World Bank
lost its largest
cash crop markets
due to competition
with Western imports.
Today, countless farmers are out of
work for they're unable to compete
with the large corporations.
Another variation is the
creation of numerous
seemingly unnoticed, unregulated,
inhumane sweatshop-factories
which take advantage of the
imposed economic hardship.
Additionally, due to
production deregulation
environmental destruction is
perpetual, as a country's resources
are often exploited by the
indifferent corporations
while outputting large amounts
of deliberate pollution.
-The largest environmental lawsuit
in the history of the world
today is being
brought on behalf of
30,000 Ecuadorian and
Amazonian people
against Texaco, which is
now owned by Chevron;
so it's against Chevron, but for
activities conducted by Texaco.
They're estimated to
be more than 18 times
what the Exxon Valdez dumped
into the Coast of Alaska.
In the case of Ecuador
it wasn't an accident.
The oil companies did it intentionally.
They knew they were doing it
to save money rather than
arranging for proper disposal.
-Furthermore, a cursory glance
at the performance
record of the World Bank
reveals that the institution,
which publicly claims to
help poor countries develop
and alleviate poverty
has done nothing but increase
poverty and the wealth-gap
while corporate profits soar.
In 1960, the
income-gap between the
fifth of the world's people
in the richest countries
versus the fifth in the poorest
countries was thirty to one.
By 1998, it was
seventy-four to one.
While global GNP rose 40%
between 1970 and 1985
those in poverty actually
increased by 17%.
While from 1985 to 2000
those living on less than one
dollar a day increased by 18%.
Even the Joint Economic
Committee of the U.S. Congress
admitted that there is a
mere 40% success rate
of all World Bank projects.
In the late 1960's,
the World Bank
intervened in Ecuador
with large loans.
During the next 30 years,
poverty grew from 50% to 70%.
Under or unemployment
grew from 15% to 70%.
Public debt increased from
240 million to 16 billion
while the share of resources
allocated to the poor
went from 20% to 6%.
In fact, by the year 2000, 50%
of Ecuador's national budget
had to be allocated
for paying its debts.
It is important to understand:
The World Bank is, in fact
a U.S. bank, supporting U.
S. interests.
For the United States holds
veto-power over decisions
as it is the largest
provider of capital.
And where did it get this money?
You guessed it.
It made it out of thin air
through the fractional
reserve banking system.
Of the world's top 100 economies,
as based on annual GDP
51 are corporations and 47
of that 51 are U.S.-based.
Walmart, General Motors and Exxon
are more economically powerful
than Saudi Arabia, Poland,
Norway, South Africa
Finland, Indonesia
and many others.
And, as protective trade
barriers are broken down
currencies tossed together and
manipulated in floating markets
and State economies overturned
in favor of open competition
in global capitalism,
the empire expands.
-You get up on your
little 21-inch screen
and howl about America
and democracy.
There is no America,
there is no democracy.
There is only IBM,
and ITT, and AT&T
and Dupont, Dow, Union
Carbide, and Exxon.
Those are the nations
of the world today.
What do you think the Russians talk
about in their councils of state?
Karl Marx?
They get out their linear
programming charts
statistical decision theories,
min and max solutions
and compute the
price-cost probabilities
of their transactions and
investments, just like we do.
We no longer live in a world of
nations and ideologies, Mr. Beale.
The world is a college
of corporations
inexorably determined by the
immutable by-laws of business.
The world is a business, Mr.
Beale.
"Taken cumulatively, the integration
of the world as a whole
particularly in terms of
economic globalization
and the mythic qualities of
"free market" capitalism
represents a veritable
"empire" in its own right.
Few have been able to escape the
"structural adjustment" and
.
"conditionalities" of the W.
B, the IMF, or the WTO
those international financial
institutions that, however inadequate
still determine what economic
globalization means.
Such is the power of globalization that,
within our lifetime, we are likely to see
the integration, even if unevenly, of
all national economies in the world
.
into a single global,
free market system."
-The World is being taken over
by a handful of business powers
who dominate the natural
resources we need to live
while controlling the money we
need to obtain these resources.
The end result will
be world monopoly
based not on human life but
financial and corporate power.
And, as the inequality
grows, naturally
more and more people are
becoming desperate.
So the establishment was forced
to come up with a new way
to deal with anyone who
challenges the system.
So they gave birth
to the "Terrorist."
The term "terrorist" is
an empty distinction
designed for any person or group
who chooses to challenge
the establishment.
This isn't to be confused
with the fictional "Al Qaida"
which was actually the name
of a computer database
of the U.S.
-supported Mujahideen in the 1980's.
"The truth is, there is no
Islamic army or terrorist group
called Al Qaida. And any informed
intelligence officer knows this.
But there is a propaganda campaign
to make the public believe
in the presence of an identified entity...
The country behind this propaganda is the U.S."
- Pierre-Henri Bunel, Former
French Military Intelligence
In 2007
the Department of Defense
received 161.8 billion dollars
for the so-called global
war on terrorism.
According to the national
counter-terrorism center
in 2004 roughly 2000 people
were killed internationally
due to supposed terrorist acts.
Of that number,
70 were American.
Using this number as a general
average, which is extremely generous
it is interesting to note
that twice as many people die
from peanut allergies a year
than from terrorist acts.
Concurrently, the leading
cause of death in America
is coronary heart disease, killing
roughly 450,000 each year.
And in 2007, the government's
allocation of funds for research
on this issue was about
three billion dollars.
This means that the US
government, in 2007
spent 54 times the amount
for preventing terrorism
than it spent for
preventing a disease
which kills 6600 times more people
annually, than terrorism does.
Yet, as the name terrorism and
Al Qaida are arbitrarily stamped
on every news report relating to any
action taken against US interests
the myth grows wider.
In mid 2008, the US Attorney
General actually proposed
that the US Congress officially
declare war against the fantasy.
.
Not to mention, as of July 2008,
there are now over 1 million people
currently on the US
terrorist watch list.
These so called
"Counter-Terrorism Measures"
of course, have nothing to
do with social protection
and everything to do with
preserving the establishment
amongst the growing
anti-American sentiment
both domestically
and internationally
which is legitimately founded on
the greed-based corporate
empire expansion
that is exploiting the world.
The true terrorists of our world, do
not meet at the docks at midnight
or scream "Allah Akbar"
before some violent action.
The true terrorists of our
world wear 5000 dollar suits
and work in the highest positions of
finance, government and business.
So, what do we do?
How do we stop a system
of greed and corruption
that has so much
power and momentum?
How do we stop this aberrant group
behavior, which feels no compassion
for say, the millions slaughtered
in Iraq and Afghanistan
so the corporatocracy
can control
energy resources and opium
production for Wall St. profit?
Before 1980, Afghanistan produced
0% of the world's opium.
After the US/CIA backed Mujahideen
won the Soviet/Afghan war
by 1986 they were producing 40%
of the world's heroin supply.
By 1988, they were producing 80%
of the total market supply.
But then, something
unexpected happened.
The Taliban rose to power and by 2000, they
had destroyed most of the opium fields.
Production dropped from 3000+ tons
to only 185 tons, a 94% reduction.
On Sept. 9th 2001, the full Afghanistan
invasion plans were on President Bush's Desk.
Two days later they
had their excuse.
Today, opium productions in
US controlled Afghanistan
which now provides more than
90% of the world's heroin
breaks new production
records nearly every year.
How do we stop a system
of greed and corruption
that condemns poor populations
to "Sweatshop-Slavery"
for the benefit of
Madison Avenue?
Or that engineers
false-flag terror attacks
for the sake of manipulation?
Or that generates built-in
modes of social operation
which are inherently
exploitative?
Or that systematically
reduces civil liberties
and violates human rights
in order to protect itself
from its own shortcomings.
How do we deal with the
numerous covert institutions
such as the Council
on Foreign Relations
the Trilateral Commission
and the Bilderberg Group
and other undemocratically
elected groups
which, behind closed doors
collude to control the political
financial, social and environmental
elements of our lives?
In order to find the
answer, we must first find
the true underlying cause.
For the fact is:
The selfish, corrupt power
and profit- based groups
are not the true
source of the problem.
They are symptoms.
"Greed and Competition are not the
result of immutable human temperament...
...greed and fear of scarcity are in
fact being created and amplified...
the direct consequence is that we have to
fight with each other in order to survive.
- Bernard Liertaer
- Founder of the EU Currency System
-My name is Jacque Fresco.
I'm an industrial designer
and a social engineer.
I'm very much
interested in society
and developing a system that might
be sustainable, for all people.
First of all, the word "corruption"
is a monetary invention
that aberrant behavior
behavior that's disruptive
to the well-being of people.
Well you're dealing
with human behavior.
And human behavior appears to
be environmentally determined.
Meaning, if you were raised by
the Seminole Indians as a baby
never saw anything else, you'd
hold that value system.
And this goes for nations, it goes
for individuals, for families.
They try to indoctrinate their
children to their particular faith
and their country and make them
feel like they're part of that.
And they build a society,
which they call established.
They established a workable point of
view and tend to perpetuate that.
Whereas, all societies are really
emergent, not established.
And so they fight new ideas
that would interfere
with the establishment.
Governments try to perpetuate
that which keeps them in power.
People are not elected to political
office to change things.
They are put there to keep
things the way they are.
So you see, the basis of
corruption is in our society.
Let me make it clear.
All nations then are basically corrupt
because they tend to uphold
existing institutions.
I don't mean to uphold
or downgrade all nations
but communism, socialism, fascism,
the free enterprise-system
and all other sub-cultures
are the same.
They are all basically corrupt.
-The most fundamental characteristic
of our social institutions
is the necessity for
self-preservation.
Whether dealing with a corporation,
a religion or a government
the foremost interest is to
preserve the institution itself.
For instance, the last thing
an oil company would ever want
is the utilization of energy
that was outside of its control.
For it makes that company
less relevant to society.
Likewise the Cold War and the
collapse of the Soviet Union
was, in reality, a way to
preserve and perpetuate
the established economic and global
hegemony of the United States.
Similarly, religions
condition people
to feel guilty for
natural inclinations
each claiming to offer the only
path to forgiveness and salvation.
At the heart of this
institutional self-preservation
lies the monetary system
for it is money that provides the
means for power and survival.
Therefore, just as a poor person
might be forced to steal
in order to survive
it is a natural inclination
to do whatever is needed
to continue an institution's
profitability.
This makes it
inherently difficult
for profit-based institutions to
change, for it puts in jeopardy
not only the survival of
large groups of people
but also the coveted
materialistic lifestyles
associated with
affluence and power.
Therefore, the paralyzing necessity
to preserve an institution
regardless of its
social relevance
is largely rooted in the
need for money or profit.
[ Industry ]
- "What's in it for me?
" is the way people think.
And so if a man makes money
selling a certain product
that's where he's going to fight
the existence of another product
that may threaten
his institution.
Therefore, people
cannot be fair.
And people do not
trust each other.
A guy will come
over to you and say
"I've got just the house you're looking for.
" He's a salesman.
When a doctor says, "I think
your kidney has to come out."
I don't know if he's
trying to pay off a yacht
or that my kidney
has to come out.
It's hard in a monetary
system to trust people.
If you came into my store and I
said, "This lamp that I've got
is pretty good, but the lamp
next door is much better."
I wouldn't be in business very long.
It wouldn't work.
If I were ethical,
it wouldn't work.
So when you say industry cares
for people, that's not true.
They can't afford to be ethical.
So your system is not designed to
serve the well-being of people.
If you still don't understand that
there would be no outsourcing of jobs
if they cared about people.
Industry does not care.
They only hire people
because it hasn't
been automated yet.
So don't talk about
decency and ethics.
We cannot afford it and
remain in business.
-It is important to point out that
regardless of the social system -
whether fascist, socialist,
capitalist or communist
the underlying mechanism is still
money, labor and competition.
Communist China is no less
capitalistic than the United States.
The only difference
is the degree
by which the state
intervenes in enterprise.
The reality is that
"Monetary-ism", so to speak
is the true mechanism
that guides the interests
of all the countries
on the planet.
The most aggressive and
hence dominant variation
of this monetary-ism is the
free enterprise system.
The fundamental
perspective, as put forth
by early free market
economists like Adam Smith
is that self interest and competition
leads to social prosperity
as the act of competition
creates incentive
which motivates
people to persevere.
However, what isn't talked about,
is how a competition based economy
invariably leads to
strategic corruption
power and wealth consolidation,
social stratification
technological paralysis, labor
abuse and ultimately a covert form
of government dictatorship
by the rich elite.
The word "corruption" is often
defined as moral perversion.
If a company dumps toxic waste
into the ocean to save money
most people recognize this
as "corrupt behavior".
On a more subtle level, when
Walmart moves into a small town
and forces small
businesses to shut down
for they are unable to compete,
a grey area emerges.
For what exactly is
Walmart doing wrong?
Why should they care about the Mom
and Pop organizations they destroy?
Yet, even more subtly, when a
person gets fired from their job
because a new machine
has been created
which can do the
work for less money
people tend to just accept
that as "the way it is"
.
not seeing the inherent corrupt
inhumanity of such an action.
Because the fact is, whether
it is dumping toxic waste
having a monopoly enterprise
or downsizing the workforce
the motive is the same: Profit.
.
They are all different degrees of
the same self-preserving mechanism
which always puts the well-being
of people second to monetary gain.
Therefore, corruption is not
some byproduct of monetary-ism
it is the very foundation.
And while most people
acknowledge this tendency
on one level or another,
the majority remains naive
as to the broad ramifications
of having such a
selfish mechanism
as the guiding
mentality in society.
-Internal documents show
that after this company
positively absolutely knew
that they had a medication that
was infected with the AIDS virus
they took the product off
the market in the US
and then they dumped it in France,
Europe, Asia and Latin America.
The US government
allowed it to happen.
The FDA allowed this to happen
and now the government is
completely looking the other way.
Thousands of innocent hemophiliacs
have died from the AIDS virus.
This company knew absolutely
that it was infected with AIDS,
they dumped it because they wanted
to turn this disaster into a profit.
-So you see, you have
built-in corruption.
We're all chiseling
off each other
and you can't expect decency
or that sort of thing.
Politics
...a feeling that they
don't know who to elect.
They think in terms
of a democracy
which is not possible in a
monetary based economy.
If you have more money to
advertise your position
the position you desire in
government, that isn't a democracy.
.
It serves those in positions
of differential advantage.
So it's always a dictatorship of the
elitist, the financially wealthy.
.
"We can either have democracy
in this country or
we can have great wealth
concentrated in the hands of a few,
but we can't have both."
- Louis Brandeis - Supreme Court Justice
-It is an interesting
observation
to note how seemingly
unknown personalities
magically appear on the scene
as presidential candidates.
Then before you know it,
somehow you are left to choose
from a small group of
extremely wealthy people
who suspiciously have the
same broad social view.
Obviously it's a joke.
The people placed on
the ballot are done so
because they have been
pre-decided to be acceptable
by the established financial
powers who actually run the show.
Yet many who understand this
illusion of democracy, often think
"If only we could just get our honest,
ethical politicians in power,
then we would be okay".
Well, while this idea, of
course, seems reasonable
in our established
oriented world view
it is unfortunately
another fallacy.
For when it really comes down
to what is actually important,
the institution of politics and
thus politicians themselves
have absolutely no
true relevance as to
what makes our world
and society function.
-It's not politicians
that can solve problems.
They have no technical
capabilities.
They don't know how
to solve problems.
Even if they were sincere, they
don't know how to solve problems.
It's the technicians that produce
the desalinization plants.
It's the technicians that
give you electricity.
That give you motor vehicles.
That heat your house and
cool it in the summer time.
It's technology that solves
problems, not politics.
Politics cannot solve problems 'cause
they are not trained to do so.
-Very few people today
stop and consider
what it is that actually
improves their lives.
Is it money? Obviously not.
One cannot eat money or stuff money
into their car to get it to run.
Is it politics?
All politicians can
do is create laws
establish budgets
and declare war.
Is it religion? Of course not.
Religion creates nothing except
intangible emotional solace
for those who require it.
The true gift that we
as human beings have
which has been solely
responsible for everything
that has improved our lives
is technology.
What is technology?
Technology is a pencil
which allows one to solidify ideas
on paper for communication.
Technology is an automobile, which
allows one to travel faster
than feet would allow.
Technology is a
pair of eye glasses
which enables sight for
those who need it.
Applied technology itself is merely
an extension of human attributes
which reduces human effort
freeing humans from a
particular chore or problem.
Imagine what your life
would be like today
without a telephone, or an oven
or a computer, or an airplane.
.
And, everything in your home,
which you take for granted
from a doorbell, to a table
to a dishwasher, is technology
generated from the creative scientific
ingenuity of human technicians.
Not money, politics or religion.
These are false institutions.
- ...and writing your
congressman is fantastic.
They tell you to write your congressman
if you want something done.
The men in Washington should be
at the forefront of technology.
The forefront of human study.
The forefront of crime.
All the factors that
shape human behavior.
You don't have to write
your congressman.
What kind of people are they that
are appointed to do that job?
The future will have
great difficulty...
and the question that's
raised by politicians is:
How much will a project cost?
The question is not "how
much will it cost".
Do we have the resources?
And we have the resources
today to house everyone,
build hospitals all
over the world,
build schools all over the world
the finest equipment in labs for
teaching and doing medical research.
So you see, we have all that,
but we're in a monetary system
and in a monetary
system there's profit.
-And what is the fundamental mechanism
that drives the profit system
besides self-interest?
What is it exactly that maintains
that competitive edge at its core?
Is it high efficiency
and sustainability?
No. That isn't part
of their design.
Nothing produced in our
profit based society
is even remotely
sustainable or efficient.
If it was, there wouldn't be a
multi-million dollar a year
service industry
for automobiles.
Nor would the average
lifespan for most electronics
be less than three months
before they're obsolete.
Is it abundance?
Absolutely not.
Abundance, as based on the
laws of supply and demand
is actually a negative thing.
If a diamond company finds
ten times the usual amount of
diamonds during their mining
it means the supply of
diamonds has increased
which means the cost and
profit per diamond drops.
The fact is: efficiency,
sustainability and abundance
are enemies of profit.
To put it into a word
it is the mechanism of scarcity
that increases profits.
-What is scarcity?
Based on keeping
products valuable.
Slowing up production on
oil raises the price.
Maintaining scarcity of
diamonds keeps the price high.
They burn diamonds at the
Kimberly Diamond Mine.
They are made of carbon.
That keeps the price up.
-So then, what does it mean
for society when scarcity
either produced naturally
or through manipulation
is a beneficial
condition for industry?
It means that sustainability
and abundance
will never ever occur
in a profit system
for it simply goes against the
very nature of the structure.
Therefore, it is impossible to have
a world without war or poverty.
It is impossible to continually
advance technology
to its most efficient
and productive states.
And, most dramatically
it is impossible to
expect human beings
to behave in truly
ethical or decent ways.
"Human nature
or human behavior? "
-People use the word instinct
because they can't account
for the behavior.
They sit back and they evaluate
with their lack of
knowledge, you know
and they say things like
"Humans are built a certain way.
Greed is a natural thing"
as though they'd worked
for years on it.
And it's no more natural
than wearing clothing.
-What we want to
do is to eliminate
the causes of the problems.
Eliminate the processes
that produce greed and
bigotry and prejudice
and people taking advantage
of one another and elitism
eliminating the need for
prisons and welfare.
We have always had
these problems
because we have always lived
within scarcity and barter
and monetary systems
that produce scarcity.
-If you eradicate the
conditions that generate
what you call socially offensive
behavior, it does not exist.
.
A guy says: "Well, isn't that in-born?
" No it's not.
.
-There is no human nature;
there's human behavior,
and that's always been
changed throughout history.
You're not born with bigotry and
greed and corruption and hatred.
You pick that up
within the society.
-War, poverty, corruption,
hunger, misery, human suffering
will not change in
a monetary system;
that is, there will be very
little significant change.
It's going to take the redesign
of our culture, our values
.
and it has to be related to the
carrying capacity of the earth
not some human opinion or
some politicians notions
of the way the world ought to be
or some religious notion of
the conduct of human affairs.
And that's what The
Venus Project is about.
The society that we're
about to talk about
is a society that is free of
all the old superstitions
incarceration, prisons,
police, cruelty and law.
All laws will disappear
and the professions will disappear,
that are no longer valid
such as stockbrokers,
bankers, advertising.
Gone! Forever!
Because it's no longer relevant.
-When we understand
that it is technology
devised by human ingenuity
which frees humanity and
increases our quality of life
we then realize that the most
important focus we can have
is on the intelligent management
of the earth's resources.
For it is from these natural
resources we gain the materials
to continue our path of prosperity.
Understanding this we then see
that money fundamentally exists
as a barrier to these resources
for virtually everything
has a financial cost.
And why do we need money
to obtain these resources?
Because of real or
assumed scarcity.
We don't usually pay
for air and tap water
because it is in
such high abundance,
selling it would be pointless.
So then, logically
speaking, if resources
and technologies applicable to
creating everything in our societies
such as houses, cities and
transportation, were in high enough
abundance, there would be
no reason to sell anything.
Likewise, if automation and machinery
was so technologically advanced
as to relieve human
beings of labor,
there would be no
reason to have a job.
And with these social
aspects taken care of,
there would be no reason
to have money at all.
So the ultimate
question remains:
Do we on Earth have
enough resources
and technological understanding
to create a society
of such abundance
that everything we have now could
be available without a price tag
and without the need for
submission through employment?
Yes, we do.
We have the resources and technology
to enable this at a minimum
.
along with the ability to raise
the standards of living so high
that people in the future will
look back at our civilization now
and gawk at how primitive and
immature our society was.
-What The Venus Project proposes
is an entirely different system
.
that's updated to
present day knowledge.
-We've never given
scientists the problem of
how do you design a
society which would
eliminate boring and
monotonous jobs
that would eliminate
accidents in transportation
that would enable people to
have a high standard of living
that would eliminate
poisons in our food
give us other sources of energy
that are clean and efficient.
We can do that out there.
[A resource-based economy.]
The major difference between a
Resource-Based Economy (RBE)
and a monetary system
is that a RBE is really concerned
with people and their well-being,
.
where the monetary system has
become so distorted that the
concerns of the people are really
secondary, if they're there at all.
The products that are turned out are
for how much money you can get.
If there is a problem
in society and
you can't earn money from solving
that problem, then it won't be done.
The Resource-Based
Economy is really
not close to anything
that's been tried.
And with all our technology
today we can create abundance.
It could be used to improve
everyone's lifestyle
abundance all over the world if
we use our technology wisely
and maintain the environment.
-It's a very different system and
it's very hard to talk about
.
because the public is not
that well enough informed
as to the state of technology.
[Energy]
At present, we don't have
to burn fossil fuels.
We don't have to use anything that
would contaminate the environment.
There are many sources
of energy available.
-Alternative energy solutions
pushed by the establishment
such as hydrogen, biomass
and even nuclear
are highly insufficient,
dangerous and exist only
to perpetuate the profit-structure
that industry has created.
When we look beyond the propaganda
and self-serving solutions
put forth by the
energy companies
we find a seemingly
endless stream
of clean, abundant and renewable
energy for generating power.
Solar and wind energy are
well known to the public
but the true potential of these
mediums remains unexpressed.
Solar energy, derived
from the sun
has such abundance that one
hour of light at high noon
contains more energy than what the
entire world consumes in a year.
If we could capture 1/100th
of a percent of this energy
the world would never have to
use oil, gas or anything else.
The question then,
is not availability
but the technology
to harness it.
And there are many
advanced mediums today
which could accomplish just that
if they were not hindered by the
need to compete for market share
with the established
energy power structures.
Then there's wind energy.
Wind energy has long
been denounced as weak
and due to being location
driven impractical.
This is simply not true.
The US Department of
Energy admitted in 2007
that if wind was fully harvested in
just three of America's 50 states
it could power the
entire nation.
And then there are the
rather unknown mediums
of tidal and wave power.
Tidal power is derived from
tidal shifts in the ocean.
Installing turbines which capture
this movement generates energy.
In the United Kingdom, 42 sites
are currently noted as available
forecasting that 34%
of all the UK's energy
could come from
tidal power alone.
Wave power, which
extracts energy
from the surface
motions of the ocean
is estimated to have
a global potential
of up to 80,000
terawatt-hours a year.
This means 50% of the entire
planet's energy usage
could be produced from
this medium alone.
Now, it is important
to point out that
tidal, wave, solar
and wind power
requires virtually no
preliminary energy to harness
unlike coal, oil, gas, biomass,
hydrogen and all the others.
In combination, these
four mediums alone
if efficiently harnessed
through technology
could power the world forever.
That being said, there
happens to be another form
of clean renewable energy,
which trumps them all.
Geothermal power.
Geothermal energy utilizes
what is called "heat mining"
which, through a simple
process using water
is able to generate massive
amounts of clean energy.
In 2006, an MIT report
on geothermal energy
found that 13,000 ZJ of power are
currently available in the earth
with the possibility of 2,000
ZJ being easily tappable
with improved technology.
The total energy consumption of
all the countries on the planet
is about half of a ZJ a year.
This means about 4000
years of planetary power
could be harnessed in
this medium alone.
And when we understand that
the earth's heat generation
is constantly renewed, this
energy is really limitless.
It could be used forever.
These energy sources
are only a few
of the clean renewable
mediums available
and as time goes on,
we will find more.
The grand realization is that
we have total energy abundance
without the need for pollution
traditional conservation
or, in fact, a price tag.
And what about transportation?
The prevailing means of
transportation in our societies
is by automobile and aircraft
both of which predominantly
need fossil fuels to run.
In the case of the automobile,
the battery technology
needed to power an electric car
that can go over a
hundred miles an hour
for over two hundred
miles on one charge
exists and has existed
for many years.
However, due to battery patents,
controlled by the oil industry
which limits their availability
to maintain market share
coupled with political pressure
from the energy industry
the accessibility and affordability
of this technology is limited.
There is absolutely no reason,
other than pure corrupt
profit interests
that every single
vehicle in the world
cannot be electric and utterly clean,
with zero need for gasoline.
As far as airplanes,
it is time we realize
that this means of travel
is inefficient, cumbersome
slow, and causes far
too much pollution.
This is a maglev train.
It uses magnets for propulsion.
It is fully suspended
by a magnetic field
and requires less than 2% of the
energy used for plane travel.
The train has no wheels,
so nothing can wear out.
The current maximum speed of
versions of this technology
as used in Japan, is three hundred
and sixty one miles per hour.
However this version of the
technology is very dated.
An organization called ET3
which has connections
with The Venus Project
has established a
tube-based maglev
that can travel up to
4000 miles per hour
in a motionless,
frictionless tube
which can go over
land or under water.
Imagine going from LA to New
York for an extended lunch break
or from Washington D.C.
to Beijing, China, in two hours.
This is the future of continental
and intercontinental travel.
Fast, clean, with only a
fraction of the energy usage
we use today for the same means.
In fact, between
maglev technology
advanced battery storage
and geothermal energy
there will be no reason to
ever burn fossil fuels again.
And we can do this now
if we were not held back by the
paralyzing profit structure.
[work]
-Now America is inclined
toward fascism.
It has a propensity by its
dominant philosophy and religion
to uphold the fascist
point of view.
American industry is essentially
a fascist institution.
If you don't understand that, the
minute you punch that time clock
you walk into a dictatorship.
-We're given notions about
the respectability of work.
And I really look at it
as being paid slavery.
-You're brought up to believe
that you shall earn your living
by the sweat of your brow.
That holds people back.
Freeing people from drudgery
repetitive jobs which
make them ignorant.
You rob them.
In our society, that is a
resource- based economy
machines free people.
You see, we can't imagine that
because we've never known
that kind of world.
[automation]
-If we look back at history
we see a very clear pattern
of machine automation
slowly replacing human labor.
From the disappearance
of the elevator man
to the near full automation of
an automobile production plant
the fact is, as technology grows
the need for humans in the work force
will continually be diminished.
.
This creates a serious clash
which proves the falseness of
the monetary-based labor system
for human employment is
in direct competition
with technological development.
Therefore, given the fundamental
priority of profit by industry
people through time will
be continually laid off
and replaced by machines.
-When industry
takes on a machine
instead of shortening the
work day, they downsize.
You lose your job so you have
a right to fear machines.
-In a high technology,
resource-based economy
it is conservative to say that about
90% of all current occupations
could be phased out by machines.
Freeing humans to live their
life without servitude.
For this is the point
of technology itself.
And through time,
with nanotechnology
and other highly advanced
forms of science
it is not far fetched to see how
even complex medical procedures
could be performed
by machines as well.
And based on the pattern, with
much higher success rates
than humans get today.
The path is clear but our
monetary-based structure
which requires labor for
income, blocks this progress
for humans need jobs
in order to survive.
The bottom line is that
this system must go
or we will never be free
and technology will be
constantly paralyzed.
-We have machines
that clean out sewers
it frees a human being
from doing that.
So look at machines as
extensions of human performance.
-Furthermore, many
occupations today
will have simply no basis to exist
in a resource-based economy
such as anything associated
with the management of money
advertising, along with
the legal system itself.
For, without money, a great
majority of the crimes
that are committed today
would never occur.
Virtually all forms of
crime are a consequence
of the monetary system, either
directly or by neurosis
inflicted through
financial deprivation.
Therefore, laws themselves could
eventually become extinct.
-Instead of putting up a
sign "Drive carefully
slippery when wet," put
abrasive in the highway
so it is not slippery when wet.
And if a person gets
in car, they're drunk
and the car oscillates
a great deal
there's a little pendulum
that swings up and back
and that will pull the
car over to the side.
Not a law... solution.
.
Put sonar and radar on automobiles
so they can't hit one another.
Man-made laws are attempts
to deal with occurring problems
and not knowing
how to solve them
they make a law.
-In the United States,
the most privatized
capitalist country on the planet,
it should come as no surprise
that it also has the largest
prison population in the world
growing every year.
Statistically, most of these
people are uneducated
and come from poor,
deprived societies.
And, contrary to propaganda, it is
this environmental conditioning
which lures them into criminal
and violent behavior.
However society
looks the other way
in regard to this point.
The legal and prison systems
are just more examples
of how our society
avoids examining
the root causes of behaviour.
Billions are spent each
year on prisons and police
.
while only a fraction is spent
on programs for poverty
which is one of the most
fundamental variables
responsible for crime
to begin with.
And, as long as we have
an economic system
which prefers and
in fact creates
scarcity and deprivation,
crime will never go away.
[incentive]
-If people have access to
the necessities of life
without servitude,
debt, barter, trade
they behave very differently.
You want all these things
available without a price tag.
Now then, "you gotta have a price
tag, what will motivate people?
A man gets everything he wants,
he'd just lay around in the sun."
This is the myth
they perpetuate.
People in our culture
are trained to believe
that the monetary system
produces incentive.
If they have access to things, why
should they want to do anything?
They would lose their incentive.
That's what you're taught to
support the monetary system.
-When you take money
out of the scenario,
there would be different incentives,
very different incentives.
-When people have access to
the necessities of life,
their incentives change.
What about the moon
and the stars?
New incentives arise.
If you make a painting
that you enjoy
you will enjoy giving it to
other people, not selling it.
[education]
-I think most of the education that
I've seen today is essentially
producing a person for a job
It's very specialized.
They're not generalists.
People don't know a lot about
a lot of different subjects.
I don't think you could
get people to go to war
if they knew a lot
about a lot of things.
I think education is mostly rote
and they're not taught
how to solve problems.
They're not given the tools,
emotionally or within their own field
of how to do critical thinking.
In a resource-based economy, the
education would be very different.
-Our society's major concern
is mental development
and to motivate each person
to their highest potential.
.
Because our philosophy is; the smarter
people are, the richer the world
because everybody
becomes a contributor.
The smarter your kids are,
the better my life will be.
.
Because they'll be contributing
more constructively
to the environment
and to my life.
Because everything that we devise
within a resource based economy
would be applied to society, there
would be nothing to hold it back.
.
[civilization]
Patriotism, weapons,
armies, navies
all that is a sign that
we're not civilized yet.
.
Kids will ask their parents:
"Didn't you see the
necessity of the machines?
Dad, couldn't you see
that war was inevitable
when you produce scarcity?
Isn't it obvious?
Of course, the kid will understand
that you were pinheads,
.
raised merely to serve the
established institutions.
We're such an abominable,
sick society
that we won't make
the history book.
They'll just say that large nations
took land from smaller nations
used force and violence.
You'll get history talked
about as corrupt behavior
all the way along until the
beginning of the civilized world.
.
That's when all the
nations work together.
World unification, working
toward common good
for all human beings
and without anyone being
subservient to anyone else.
Without social stratification,
whether it be technical elitism
.
or any other kind of elitism,
eradicated from the face of the Earth.
.
The "state" does nothing
because there is no "state".
Because there is no state...
The system I advocate, a
resource based global economy
is not perfect, it's just a
lot better than what we have.
.
We can never achieve perfection.
"My country is the world...
and my religion is to do good."
.
- Thomas Paine - 1737-1809
-The social values
of our society
which has manifested in
perpetual warfare, corruption
.
oppressive laws, social stratification,
irrelevant superstitions
.
environmental destruction,
and a despotic
socially indifferent, profit
oriented ruling class
is fundamentally the result
of a collective ignorance
of two of the most basic insights
humans can have about reality.
The emergent and symbiotic
aspects of natural law.
The emergent nature of
reality is that all systems
whether it is knowledge,
society, technology
philosophy or any other creation
will, when uninhibited, undergo
fluid perpetual change.
.
What we consider
commonplace today
such as modern communication
and transportation
would have been unimaginable
in ancient times.
Likewise, the future will
contain technologies
realizations and
social structures
that we cannot even
fathom in the present.
We have gone from
alchemy to chemistry
from a geocentric universe
to a heliocentric
from believing that demons
were the cause of illness
to modern medicine.
This development shows
no sign of ending
and it is this awareness
that aligns us and leads us
on a continuous path to
growth and progress.
.
Static, empirical
knowledge does not exist
rather it is the insight of
the emergence of all systems
we must recognize.
This means we must be open to
new information at all times
even if it threatens our
current belief system
and hence, identities.
Sadly, society today has
failed to recognize this
and the established institutions
continue to paralyze growth
by preserving outdated
social structures.
Simultaneously, the population
suffers from a fear of change.
For their conditioning
assumes a static identity
and challenging
one's belief system
usually results in
insult and apprehension.
For being wrong is erroneously
associated with failure.
When in fact to be proven
wrong should be celebrated.
For it is elevating someone to
a new level of understanding,
furthering awareness.
The fact is, there is no such
thing as a smart human being
for it is merely
a matter of time
before their ideas are updated,
changed or eradicated.
And this tendency to blindly
hold on to a belief system,
sheltering it from new, possibly
transforming information
is nothing less than a form
of intellectual materialism.
The monetary system
perpetuates this materialism
not only by its
self-preserving structures
but also through the
countless number of people
who have been conditioned
into blindly
and thoughtlessly upholding
these structures
therefore becoming self-appointed
guardians of the status quo.
Sheep which no longer need a
sheep-dog to control them.
For they control each other
by ostracizing those who
step out of the norm.
This tendency to resist change
and uphold existing institutions
.
for the sake of identity,
comfort, power and profit
.
is completely unsustainable
and will only produce
further imbalance
fragmentation, distortion,
and invariably
.
destruction.
It's time to change.
From hunters and gatherers
to the agricultural revolution
to the industrial revolution
the pattern is clear.
It is time for a
new social system
which reflects the
understandings we have today.
The monetary system is a
product of a period of time
.
where scarcity was a reality.
Now, with the age of technology, it
is no longer relevant to society.
.
Gone with the aberrant
behavior it manifests.
Likewise, dominant world views,
such as theistic religion
operate with the same
social irrelevancy.
.
Islam, Christianity, Judaism,
Hinduism and all of the others
exist as barriers to
personal and social growth.
For each group perpetuates
a closed world view.
And this finite understanding
that they acknowledge
is simply not possible
in an emergent universe.
Yet, religion has succeeded in
shutting down the awareness
of this emergence
by instilling the psychological
distortion of faith upon its followers.
.
Where logic and new
information is rejected
in favor of traditionalized
outdated beliefs.
-The concept of God
is really a method of accounting
for the nature of things.
In the early days people
didn't know enough
about how things formed,
how nature worked.
So they invented their
own little stories
and they made god
in their own image.
A guy that gets angry
when people don't behave right,
he creates floods and earthquakes
.
and they say it's an act of God.
-A cursory glance at the
suppressed history of religion
reveals that even the
foundational myths themselves
are emergent culminations developed
through influence over time.
For example, a cardinal
doctrine of the Christian faith
is the death and
resurrection of Christ.
This notion is so important
that the Bible itself states
'And if Christ be not risen
then is our preaching vain and
your faith is also vain'.
Yet it is very difficult to
take this account literally
for not only is there
no primary source
denoting this supernatural
event in secular history
awareness of the enormous
number of pre-Christian saviors
who also died and
were resurrected
immediately puts this story in
mythological territory by association.
Early church figures,
such as Tertullian
.
went to great lengths to
break these associations
even claiming that the devil
caused the similarities to occur.
Stating in the second century:
"The devil, whose business
is to pervert the truth
mimics the exact circumstance
of the Divine Sacraments.
He baptizes his believers and
promises forgiveness of sins
he celebrates the
oblation of bread
and brings in the symbol
of the resurrection.
Let us therefore acknowledge
the craftiness of the devil
who copied certain things
of those that be Divine."
What is truly sad however
is that when we cease the idea
that the stories from Christianity
Judaism, Islam and
all the others
are literal history
and accept them for
what they really are
which are purely allegorical
expressions derived from many faiths
we see that all religions
share a common thread.
And it is this
unifying imperative
that needs to be recognized
and appreciated.
Religious belief has caused
more fragmentation and conflict
than any other ideology.
Christianity alone has
34,000 different subgroups.
-The Bible is subject
to interpretation.
When you read it, you say
"I think Jesus meant this.
I think Job meant that.
Oh No! He meant this."
So you have the Lutheran, the
Seventh-day Adventist, the Catholic
and a church divided
is no church at all.
And a church divided,
And this point on division
which is a trademark of
all theistic religions,
brings us to our second
failure of awareness.
The false assumption
of separation
through the rejection of the
symbiotic relationship of life.
Apart from the understanding that
all natural systems are emergent
where all notions of reality
will be constantly developed
altered and even eradicated
we must also understand that
all systems are, in fact
invented fragments, merely for
the sake of conversation.
For there is no such thing
as independence in nature.
The whole of nature is a unified
system of interdependent variables
each a cause and a reaction, existing
only as a concentrated whole.
-You don't see the plug
connected to the environment
so it looks like we're
free, wandering around.
Take the oxygen away,
we all die immediately.
Take plant life away, we die.
And without the sun,
all the plants die.
So we are connected.
-We really must take into
account the totality.
This isn't just a human
experience on this planet,
this is a total experience.
And we know we can't survive
without plants and animals.
We know we can't survive without
the four elements, you know?
And so, when are we gonna really
start taking that into account?
That's what it is
to be successful.
Success depends on how well we
relate to everything around us.
I'm very aware of the
fact that my grandson
cannot possibly hope to
inherit a sustainable
.
peaceful, stable,
socially just world
unless every child
today growing up in
Ethiopia, in Indonesia, in
Bolivia, in Palestine, in Israel
also has that same expectation.
You've got to take care
of the whole community
or you're gonna have
serious problems.
And now we have to see that the
whole world is the community.
And we must all take care
of each other that way.
And it's not just a
community of human beings
it's a community of plants
and animals and elements.
And we really need
to understand that.
That's what's gonna bring
us joy too, and pleasure.
.
That's what's missing
in our lives right now.
We can call it spirituality,
but the fact of the matter is
.
joy comes from that
bliss of connectedness.
That's our god spirit, that's
that side of ourselves
that really feels it, and you
can feel it deep inside you.
It's this amazing wonderful feeling,
and you know it when you get it.
.
You don't get it from money,
you get it from connection.
.
-Now if that isn't a
hazard to this country.
How are we gonna keep
building nuclear weapons
you know what I mean?
What's gonna happen
to the arms industry
when we realize we're all one?
It's gonna fuck up the economy.
The economy that's fake anyway.
Which would be a real bummer.
You can see why the
government's crackin' down...
...on the idea of experiencing
unconditional love."
"I believe that unarmed truth
and unconditional love
will have the final
word in reality."
- Dr. Martin Luther King Jr.
- 1929-1968
-Once we understand that the
integrity of our personal existences
are completely dependent
on the integrity
of everything else in our world
we have truly understood the
meaning of unconditional love.
For love is extensionality
and seeing everything as you
and you as everything can
have no conditionalities
for in fact, we are all
everything at once.
-If it's true that we're all
from the center of a star
every atom in each of us
then we're all the same thing.
Even a Coke machine or a cigarette
butt in the street in Buffalo
is made out of atoms
that came from a star.
They've all been recycled
thousands of times
as have you and I.
And therefore, it's only me out there.
So what is there
to be afraid of?
What is there that
needs solace seeking?
Nothing. There's nothing to be
afraid of because it's all us.
The trouble is we have been
separated by being born
and given a name and an identity
and being individuated.
We've been separated from the oneness
and that's what religion exploits.
.
That people have this yearning to
be part of the overall one again.
So they exploit that.
They call it god, they say he has rules
and I think it's cruel.
I think you can do
it absent religion.
"An extraterrestrial visitor examining
the differences among human societies
would find those differences trivial
compared to the similarities
Our lives, our past and our future are
tied to the sun, the moon and the stars...
We humans have seen the atoms which constitute all
of nature and the forces that sculpted this work...
.
And we, we who embody the local eyes and ears
and thoughts and feelings of the cosmos,
we have begun at least to wonder about our origins...
star stuff contemplating the stars
.
organized collections of ten
billion billion billion atoms,
contemplating the evolution of
nature, tracing that long path
by which it arrived at consciousness
here on the planet earth...
Our loyalties are to the
species and to the planet.
Our obligation to survive and flourish
is owed not just to ourselves
but also to that cosmos ancient
and vast from which we spring.
We are one species.
We are star stuff harvesting star light.
- Carl Sagan - 1934-1996
-It's time to claim the unity
our outmoded social
systems have broken apart
and work together to create a
sustainable, global society
where everyone is taken care
of and everyone is truly free.
.
Your personal beliefs,
whatever they may be
are meaningless when it comes
to the necessities of life.
Every human being is born naked
needing warmth, food,
water, shelter.
Everything else is auxiliary.
Therefore, the most
important issue at hand
is the intelligent management
of the Earth's resources.
This can never be accomplished
in a monetary system
for the pursuit of profit is
the pursuit of self interest
and therefore imbalance
is inherent.
Simultaneously,
politicians are useless
for our true problems in life
are technical not political.
Furthermore, ideologies
that separate humanity
.
such as religion, need strong
reflection in the community
in regard to its value,
purpose and social relevancy.
Hopefully, through time
religion will lose its materialism
and basis in superstition
and move into the useful
field of philosophy.
The fact is, society
today is backwards
with politicians constantly talking
about protection and security
rather than creation,
unity and progress.
The US alone now spends about
$500 billion dollars
annually on defense.
That is enough to send every
high school senior in America
to a four year college.
In the 1940s the
Manhattan Project
produced the first true
weapon of mass destruction.
This program employed 130,000 people,
at an extreme financial cost.
Imagine what our life would be like
today if that group of scientists
instead of working on a
way of killing people
worked on a way to create a
self-sustaining abundant world.
Life today would be very, very
different if that was their goal.
.
Instead of weapons
of mass destruction
it is time to unleash
something much more powerful.
Weapons of Mass Creation (WMCs).
Our true divinity is in
our ability to create.
And armed with the understanding of
the symbiotic connections of life
while being guided by the
emergent nature of reality
there is nothing we
cannot do or accomplish.
Of course, we face
strong barriers
in the form of established power
structures that refuse to change.
.
At the heart of these structures
is the monetary system.
As explained earlier, the
fractional reserve policy
is a form of slavery
through debt
where it is literally impossible
for society to be free.
In turn, free market capitalism
in the form of free trade
uses debt to imprison the world
and manipulate countries
into subservience to a handful of
large business and political powers.
Apart from these
obvious amoralities
the system itself is
based on competition
which immediately
destroys the possibility
of large scale collaborations
for the common good.
Hence paralyzing any attempt
at true global sustainability.
These financial and corporate
structures are now obsolete
and they must be outgrown.
Of course, we can not be
naive enough to think that
the business and financial elite are
going to subscribe to this idea
for they will lose
power and control.
Therefore, peacefully yet highly
strategic action must be taken.
The most powerful course
of action is simple.
We have to alter our behavior
to force the power structure
to the will of the people.
We must stop
supporting the system.
The only way the
establishment will change
is by our refusal to participate
while continuously acknowledging
its endless flaws
and corruptions.
-They're not gonna give
up the monetary system
because of our designs
or what we recommend.
The system has to fail
and people have to lose confidence
in their elected leaders.
That will be a major
turning point
if The Venus Project is offered
as a possible alternative.
If not, I fear the consequences.
The trends now indicate that
our country is going bankrupt.
The probability is our
country will move
toward a military
dictatorship to prevent riots
and complete social breakdown.
Once the US breaks down,
all the other cultures
will undergo similar things.
-As of now, the world
financial system
is on the brink of collapse
due to its own shortcomings.
The controller of
currencies stated in 2003
that the interest on
the US national debt
will not be affordable
in less than ten years.
This theoretically means total
bankruptcy for the US economy
and its implications for
the world are immense.
In turn the fractional reserve
based monetary system
is reaching its theoretical
limits of expansion
and the banking failures you are
seeing are just the beginning.
This is why inflation is skyrocketing,
all debt is at record levels
.
and the government and FED
are hemorrhaging new money
to bailout the corrupt system.
For the only way to
keep the banks going
is by making more money.
The only way to make more money is
to create more debt and inflation.
.
It is simply a matter of
time before the tables turn
and there's no one is
willing to take new loans
while defaults grow
as people are unable
to afford their current loans.
Then the expansion
of money will stop
and contraction will begin
on a scale never before seen
ending a century
long pyramid scheme.
This has already begun.
Therefore, we need to expose this
financial failure for what it is
using this weakness
to our advantage.
Here are some suggestions:
Expose the banking fraud.
Citibank, JP Morgan Chase
and Bank of America
are the most
powerful controllers
within the corrupt
Federal Reserve system.
It's time to boycott
these institutions.
If you have a bank account or a
credit card with any of them
move your money to another bank.
If you have a mortgage,
re-finance with another bank.
If you own their stock, sell it.
If you work for them, quit.
This gesture will
express contempt
for the true powers behind
the private banking cartel
known as the Federal Reserve.
And create awareness about the fraud
of the banking system itself.
Two: Turn off the TV news.
Visit the emerging independent
news agencies on the internet
for your information.
CNN, NBC, ABC, FOX
and all the others
present all news pre-filtered
to maintain the status quo.
With four corporations owning
all major media outlets
objective information
is impossible.
This is the true
beauty of the internet
and the establishment
has been losing control
because of this free
flow of information.
We must protect the
internet at all times
as it is truly our
savior right now.
Three: Don't ever allow yourself,
your family or anyone you know
.
to ever join the military.
This is an obsolete institution
now used exclusively for
maintaining an establishment
that is no longer relevant.
US soldiers in Iraq work for US
corporations, not the people.
.
Propaganda forces us to
believe that war is natural
and the military is an
honorable institution.
Well, if war is natural
why are there 18 suicides
every single day
by American veterans who have
post-traumatic stress disorder?
.
If our military men and
women are so honored
why is it that 25% of the American
homeless population are veterans?
.
Four: Stop supporting
the energy companies.
.
If you live in a detached
house, get off the grid.
.
Investigate every means of making
your home self-sustainable
with clean energy.
Solar, wind and other
renewable energies
are now affordable
consumer realities
and considering the never ending
rising costs of traditional energies
it will likely be a cheaper
investment over time.
If you drive, get the
smallest car you can
and consider using one of the
many conversion technologies
that can enable your
car to be a hybrid
electric or run on anything
other than establishment fuels.
Five: Reject the
political system.
.
The illusion of democracy is
an insult to our intelligence.
In a monetary system, there is no
such thing as a true democracy
and there never was.
We have two political parties
owned by the same set
of corporate lobbyists.
They are placed in their
positions by the corporations
with popularity artificially
projected by their media.
In a system of
inherent corruption
the change of personnel
every couple of years
has very little relevance.
Instead of pretending that the
political game has any true meaning
focus your energy on how to
transcend this failed system.
And six: Join the movement.
.
Go to the thezeitgeistmovement.
com
and help us create the largest
mass movement for social change
the world has ever seen.
We must mobilize and
educate everyone
about the inherent corruption
of our current world system
along with the only true
sustainable solution
declaring all the natural
resources on the planet
as common heritage to all people
while informing everyone as to
the true state of technology
and how we can all be free
if the world works together
rather than fights.
The choice lies with you.
You can continue to be a slave
to the financial system
and watch the continuous wars, depressions
and injustice across the globe
while placating yourself
with vain entertainment
and materialistic garbage;
or, you can focus your energy on true,
meaningful, lasting, holistic change
which actually has the
realistic ability to support
and free all humans with
no one left behind.
But in the end, the
most relevant change
must occur first inside of you.
The real revolution is the
revolution of consciousness
and each one of us first
needs to eliminate
the diversionary,
materialistic noise
we have been conditioned
to think is true;
while discovering,
amplifying and aligning
with the signal coming from
our true empirical oneness.
It is up to you.
-What we are trying in all these
discussions and talks here
is to see if we cannot radically bring
about a transformation of the mind.
Not accept things as they are
but to understand it, to
go into it, to examine it
give your heart and your mind with
everything that you have to find out
a way of living differently.
But, that depends on you
and not somebody else.
Because in this
there is no teacher
no pupil
there's no leader
there's no guru
there's no master, no savior.
You yourself are the teacher and the pupil, you're
the master, you're the guru, you are the leader
you are everything!
And
to understand
is to transform what is.