ALEX MILLER: This is me
asleep on a plane,
dreaming of being a killer.
I'm heading to Ardnamurchan,
the most westerly point of
mainland Britain.
A place filled with
little more than
seagulls, sheep, and deer.
I've booked a week in the
hunting lodge of Ardnamurchan
Estate, a huge expanse of
mountainous land where deer
stalking is still
a way of life.
Here, for a little more than
200 quid you can stalk and
butcher your own
Highland deer.
I'm a lifelong supermarket
carnivore, but soft as I am, I
wanted to see, taste, and feel
the death behind my dinner.
It was a long trip.
And the roads were dark
and confusing.
We were going to one of the
most isolated places in
Britain with no idea what
was waiting for us.
Would there be a blue-faced
"Deliverance" tribe dressing
in the skin of outsiders?
Or just a small group of old
women huddling around a pillow
box and discussing heather?
I'm a little bit worried that
I'm not going to fit.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
ALEX MILLER: Deer stalking is
the most traditional form of
hunting in the world, as the
practice has remained
practically unchanged since
the English aristocracy
introduced it in the 1850s.
It might seem quite primeval,
but stalking a deer looks
practically vegetarian compared
to more common types
of food production.
We've all heard that intensive
farming is melting the planet.
The battery chickens are
terribly depressed and ill
educated and that every child
born since 1987 thinks meat is
grown in freezer aisles.
But it's not all like that.
In the highlands of
Scotland, the
hunter-gatherer is still king.
So it's there that I'm going to
live, kill, and feast with
the last remaining indigenous
tribe in Britain.
Is that the kind of
thing we trek on?
The knife coming up
from the ground?
It's completely sheer.
Look at that.
Surely deer can't
live in that?
I can't live in that.
There's no way I'm going to be
able to survive if you put me
there for five minutes.
We're going to go and stalk
some deer in the
next couple of days.
Do that.
Do you not fancy my chances?
-If you never shot a rifle
before, no chance.
ALEX MILLER: What
you on about?
He's telling us that we haven't
got a chance of
getting a deer.
-In Ardnamurchan?
ALEX MILLER: We're going
to go stalking.
-No chance.
In Ardnamurchan?
ALEX MILLER: Yeah.
-Oh, you'll get a deer.
-Ah, but it depends if he's
a good shot or not.
ALEX MILLER: Do you think
I look like a good shot?
-No.
ALEX MILLER: I mean I'm not--
After traveling for 15 hours,
losing ourselves in the
thundering roads, we arrived.
We were greeted with nothing
but darkness.
Wow.
This has got murder written
all over it.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
ALEX MILLER: When the morning
came the darkness had gone,
exposing this incredible
landscape and the hunting
lodge we were staying in.
For a mere lodge, it looked an
awful lot like a castle.
Donald Houston, the owner
of the estate, came
to welcome us in.
DONALD HOUSTON: The reality
of living up here in the
isolation is something that most
people can't cope with.
The nearest supermarket
is two hours away.
The nearest cinema's
two hours away,
there's absolutely nothing.
ALEX MILLER: Do you find that
all the people that come have
the kind of right sense
of respect for the--
DONALD HOUSTON: Some
do, some don't.
There are a number of people
and, I suppose, an increasing
number of people who get a list
of all the animals they
want to shoot worldwide, and
then it's just ticking a box.
So on occasion we have had
people that fly in in the
morning, shoot an animal, fly
back out in the afternoon.
ALEX MILLER: Do you find that
kind of approach a bit
distasteful?
DONALD HOUSTON: Yeah, yes.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
ALEX MILLER: I'm from Camden.
And while street crime may be
growing sport down south, I've
never actually held
a gun before.
To train us up as marksman,
Alistair McLoughlin--
otherwise known as Titch-- the
local fisherman and sometimes
poacher took us into an extinct
volcano hunting for woodcock.
This would be the first baby
step on my journey towards
becoming a hunter.
I'm locked in.
I'm so un-countryside.
ALISTAIR MCLOUGHLIN: Well, this
shotgun here's a 12 bolt.
Be careful, don't put any bigger
shells in it or you
could end up with an explosion
on your hands.
Aye, they're good enough guns.
Do the job.
ALEX MILLER: Carrying the
shotguns, we started
to feel like men.
Like seasoned hunters,
like killers with
nature at our mercy.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
ALEX MILLER: When Titch worked
out how lame we were he made
us practice on some
clay pigeon.
ALISTAIR MCLOUGHLIN: Get ready
with that safety now.
ALEX MILLER: All right, yeah.
ALISTAIR MCLOUGHLIN:
Now that's on.
Now don't touch the trigger
once you push it forward.
ALEX MILLER: All right.
ALISTAIR MCLOUGHLIN:
You ready?
ALEX MILLER: Go ahead.
Hey.
ALISTAIR MCLOUGHLIN: First
shot, first bullet.
ALEX MILLER: Oh, that's
my ears ringing.
Very good at this though,
a very good marksman.
Oh well, magic doesn't
strike twice.
ALISTAIR MCLOUGHLIN:
No, this one here.
Just push if forward and you're
ready to take the shot.
ANDY CAPPER: OK.
We got a grip.
ALISTAIR MCLOUGHLIN: OK,
you got a good, tight
grip in your shoulder?
ANDY CAPPER: Yeah.
ALISTAIR MCLOUGHLIN:
You ready?
OK?
ANDY CAPPER: Swap.
ALEX MILLER: It's all in
preparation for him taking us
out to shoot some actual
real birds.
I can't remember what kind of
birds we're going to shoot.
-Woodcock.
ALEX MILLER: We're going
to go shoot woodcock.
ALISTAIR MCLOUGHLIN: Ready?
ANDY CAPPER: Yep.
ALEX MILLER: Which I'm pretty
hyped and ready.
I got bloodlust,
I got gun lust.
I got mine first time.
I was like Terminator.
ALISTAIR MCLOUGHLIN: The deal
is, from this point is you two
are going to be to on either
side in a minute.
And we're going to go in through
the trees here, and up
and around.
And any woodcock that
jumps out, I'll show
it to you is woodcock.
But wait for them to be high.
And the most important thing
is don't shoot the dogs.
ALEX MILLER: All right.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
ALEX MILLER: It's really,
really windy.
You can barely walk forwards.
Even if there was a woodcock
I'm pretty sure I couldn't
open my eyes to get it,
this stupid country.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
ALEX MILLER: Ah, Andy got one.
I'm amazed.
ANDY CAPPER: Hit the first shot,
I see a bit of feather.
Second shot, I see something
go around the corner.
But I don't know if I've
got it or not.
Well, I feel bad
for the family.
ALEX MILLER: We couldn't
find Andy's bird and it
was windy as hell.
But I had a gun.
So I started shooting the shit
out of the river and the sky
just to show mother nature
who was boss.
I was developing the cocky
strut of a killer.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
ALEX MILLER: If I'm honest, I've
been trying not to think
about doing this for about
the last three weeks.
There's something a bit
distasteful about being the
young go-getting media type from
the city, flies off and
slaughters beautiful creatures
for a documentary.
Last night I had some pretty
unsubtle dreams.
I was lying in a bed and someone
had cut a square into
my stomach and ripped organs
out of me, which are two
things that I pretty much have
to do to this deer today.
We're going to go and meet the
head stalker, Niall Rowntree.
Don't know that much
about him.
But we know that every day he
gets up early in the morning,
loads his rifle, and goes
and kills deer.
So he should probably be able
to deliver what we want.
Yeah, you can tell a man's
serious about death when he
keeps the carcasses
up on the wall.
We don't get to shoot a stag
because it's the wrong time of
the season.
We're going to shoot a woman.
Which is, for some
reason, darker.
NIALL ROWENTREE: And what you
want to do today when we're
out is any instructions you get,
for your own safety in
particular, follow
them in detail.
And if we're approaching
deer you want to be in
single file behind me.
Avoid fast movements.
Avoid the classic thing
everybody does, and you can
watch this.
Is when you're out stalking up
on deer, very often people
will do that to see what
you're looking at.
And because they're programmed
on movement, If you stick your
head around the corner of a hill
or a skyline they'll see
it quite easily and
they'll take off.
Their sense of preservation
is better than ours.
ALEX MILLER: How close
are we able to get?
NIALL ROWENTREE: We'll ideally
aim to be about 100 metres.
ALEX MILLER: OK.
If you do get a good shot in how
long does it take before
the animal dies?
NIALL ROWENTREE: If you hit it
properly with your instructor
to shoot it today the animal
will die instantly.
It'll collapse in
front of you.
And that'll be it.
ALEX MILLER: Before I was
allowed to take a life I had
to pass a shooting test.
If I missed the target more
than once in four shots I
wouldn't be allowed to do it.
This was to make sure I wouldn't
mess it up, blow an
eye out, and leave a
disabled deer to
slowly down on the mountain.
Slowly, methodically, Niall
took me through
the shooting process.
Three times out of four
I nailed the target.
And so I was clear to hunt.
NIALL ROWENTREE: That's smack
in the middle of the
red plate this time.
ALEX MILLER: Sweet.
On the way to the store we
paused to feed some stag.
I guess that was some cruel
perch on Niall's behalf.
Because once hundreds of these
amazing animals have lept over
the landscape to be fed by
you, you realize what a
beautiful thing you're
killing.
NIALL ROWENTREE: They've been
my whole life all my life.
I mean I can remember going to
see deer since I was a tiny
little boy.
And I've been fascinated with
them since day one.
For what we sell as a product
to foreign visitors we would
probably cull that old stag
this coming year.
That stag-- to give you an
idea-- is worth about a
thousand pounds to
us to a client.
But he's cheekier than
he ought to be.
You see the head tilting
down at you there?
But if you stare at him too
much he bottles it.
They don't like being
stared at.
ALEX MILLER: Do they ever
attack humans ever?
NIALL ROWENTREE: My father was
very badly mauled by one when
I was a kid, but it
was a park stag.
If they lose their fear of man
they become dangerous.
He was quite badly lacerated
with him.
He was struck in the head
and then two or three
times in the body.
Yeah, I think if I hadn't shot
the stag when it was attacking
him it might've killed him.
ALEX MILLER: You shot the stag
when it was attacking him?
NIALL ROWENTREE: Yeah.
ALEX MILLER: You saved
your dad's life?
NIALL ROWENTREE: Yes.
ALEX MILLER: That's a pretty
cool thing to be able to do
when you're 13.
NIALL ROWENTREE: You
do your best.
ALEX MILLER: A good one
to have over your
old man, isn't it?
So we've actually just been this
close to deer, beautiful,
beautiful stags.
Which is a lovely experience,
only we're on our way to kill
their girlfriends.
With any luck, one of the female
deers will attack us
and I'll have to shoot her
out of an act of charity.
Deer stalking is centuries
old, one of the most
traditional forms of hunting
in the world.
And the vast majority
of venison is still
produced this way.
The deer are culled in order to
promote the health of the
land and the ecosystem.
The stalker's prey is
chosen specifically.
Once it's been shot, the carcass
is butchered locally
and exported as organic
free-range meat.
The process is a large part of
a local economy short of many
other options.
Tourists like me-- we were
continually assured--
only help to keep this
part of the world
from becoming a desert.
So remember, getting these
pretty things is dead ethical.
NIALL ROWENTREE: We'll try and
whisper to one another.
But once we get really close we
might not be able to speak.
It might just be hand signals.
So if you're happy--
quite simple-- thumbs up.
You're not so happy, nod your
head, shake your head.
Exactly like that.
If you burst into tears
I'll know you're not
feeling up for it.
-Where's the nearest hospital?
NIALL ROWENTREE: Fort William.
-How far away is that?
NIALL ROWENTREE: That's
about 70 miles away.
ALEX MILLER: Good, good.
Is this kind of the normal
steepness that we'll be
dealing with?
NIALL ROWENTREE: Yes.
This is going from sea level
to nearly 1800 feet.
How heavy is this thing?
The biggest stag we shot here
last season in 2008
was 24 stone 1.
ALEX MILLER: So I mean, when you
were dragging them back do
we let gravity do most
of the work?
NIALL ROWENTREE: No.
ALEX MILLER: No?
You let us do the work?
NIALL ROWENTREE: Yeah,
you'll do the work.
ALEX MILLER: Oh good.
We haven't gone that far, still
really quite exhausting.
NIALL ROWENTREE: How
old are you?
ALEX MILLER: I'm 25.
NIALL ROWENTREE: Embarrassing.
ALEX MILLER: How old are you?
NIALL ROWENTREE: 44.
ALEX MILLER: We've just
climbed up some of the
steepest stuff I've ever walked
up for about an hour.
It's pretty tiring.
The view's absolutely
incredible.
But Niall's just told us that
he's spotted the deer just
over the ridge there.
As he puts it, the game is on.
Which means it's going to be
quite quiet and single file
from now on.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
NIALL ROWENTREE: The idea
is to disturb them
as little as possible.
So once you've shot,
you don't move.
And if everything goes according
to plan, the animal
will drop where it's shot, and
the others will look around to
try and figure out what's
happened, and then quietly
drift away.
The main group is only
80 meters away.
ALEX MILLER: Suddenly, Niall
dropped to his knees.
We all followed him, and crawled
through icy mud for
about 30 meters, until
we reached a
mound, my grassy knoll.
We stayed frozen for at least
30 minutes while Niall chose
our victim.
Eventually he beckoned.
I crawled alongside him and he
pointed out which deer I was
going to shoot.
NIALL ROWENTREE:
Now's the time.
[GUNSHOT]
ALEX MILLER: Oh wow.
NIALL ROWENTREE: Don't move,
don't move, don't move.
It's well hit, it's well hit.
OK?
Just wait.
Just let them come.
Now reload your rifle, please.
Pull it back, straight
forward.
Safety off and wait
for instructions.
See the animal falling?
Down she goes.
And it's over.
Safety on, finger off.
[MUSIC PLAYING]