ELANA ADLER: Hi, I'm
Elana Adler, and
we're Hedgeboken Hedgehogs.
-That's awesome.
ELANA ADLER: The bane of
my mother's existence.
-It's so weird because they're
so cute, I want to pet them.
But then--
ELANA ADLER: They're fine with
being petted once you're
holding them.
But when the hand just comes
at them, they freak.
Because they don't know
what's going on.
They're very independent.
They'll take you or leave you.
If you want to interact
with them, great.
They do enjoy the company.
But they're also just fine
about being on their own.
That's definitely cute.
-There they are.
What's with the tubing, the fact
that they always like to
go into tubes?
ELANA ADLER: It's because they
like to burrow and dig.
So they're digging.
There are two of
them in a tube.
-Got a double tube action.
ELANA ADLER: It's a
push me, pull you.
-So do you know why hedgehogs
are illegal in certain states?
ELANA ADLER: I know California
they're illegal.
But I think that has a lot to do
with them cracking down on
any animals that could be
introduced and potentially
become feral there.
Is this is Isabella.
She's very friendly.
She's what we call a chocolate
chip, because she has a lot of
white quills with some brown
quills interspersed.
So this is a Chock.
I have two little snowballs
to show you.
Some people don't like
the albinos.
You either love them
or you hate them.
I think they're very cute.
Their quills are just
growing in.
They had their first baby set.
Now they're getting
a bigger set.
And he's actually being very
good, because he's letting us
see his nose.
See if they want to
run down the hall.
-They're so wobbly.
ELANA ADLER: Look how nicely
that girl is cooperating.
This is Oren.
He's one of my boys.
I'm a big pudgemeister.
[MUSIC PLAYING]