BRYAN IGUCHI: Yeah.
This pretty much has
been my playground
for the past 15 years.
I started renting snowmobiles
down the road and looking for
rideable terrain.
SHANE GRIMES: So do you think
you were some of the first
snowboarders out here?
BRYAN IGUCHI: Pretty
much, yeah.
To snowboard in this area?
For sure.
WILLIE MCMILLON: Growing up here
in the back country, we
probably rode for seven, eight
years without a transceiver,
without a probe,
even backpacks.
We just carried our board way
out in the middle of--
I mean, we had no idea
what we were doing.
I feel really safe going out in
the back country with him.
He knows his shit.
And it's just like, tell
me what to do, dude.
BRYAN IGUCHI: First I'm trying
to identify any weak layers in
the snow path.
So looking here, I see
here is a layer.
I want to test this layer.
This is the new snow
that we had in the
last couple of days.
And first, let's check
densities.
So this is the kind of layer
I'm looking at right here.
If I want to test that, I do
a compression tap test.
MIKE RANQUET: Bryan Iguchi
definitely embodies or
epitomizes the Jackson
Hole rider.
In the mid to late '90s, he just
disappeared there without
a plan, just went there to get
away to the mountains.
And that's one of the few
places, I think, in the United
States where you can still do
that without the Mickey Mouse
hype of major ski areas.
BRYAN IGUCHI: OK.
So now I'm just isolating a
column of snow and then
cutting it back.
So this is a free-standing
block of snow.
I'm going to do a shovel tap
test and look for any shears.
One.
I've got immediate shearing,
I got an easy shear.
BJORN LEINES: Down about
eight inches?
BRYAN IGUCHI: Yeah.
I'd say down 20 centimeters.
OK, really soft, so
I'm guessing a
storm interface layer.
One.
Four.
WILLIE MCMILLON: I think a lot
of the pros these days like--
a lot of what I see is these
kids growing up in the park.
And then they're like, wow,
I'm making a lot of money.
I guess I've got to learn
how to ride powder now.
And then they go out in
the back country.
And it's like they can't
ride a sled.
They don't know how
to dig a pit.
They probably can't even find
a transceiver buried in the
yard, you know?
And I think he's kind of
the regulator of that.
If these crews come out, he's
not going to let kids
get away with that.
He's going to make them find a
peeps in his yard before he
takes them out.
BJORN LEINES: Solid
underneath.
SHANE GRIMES: Are you
counting your packs?
BRYAN IGUCHI: Yeah.
None of them are interesting.
BJORN LEINES: This typically is
more of a continental snow
pack up here where we are?
BRYAN IGUCHI: It's more inner
mountain to some of the
washouts down at the Tetons.
But here, it's more like
Colorado style.
It's colder, hollow,
[INAUDIBLE].
BJORN LEINES: Yeah,
you know that.
BRYAN IGUCHI: Not
as much snow.
BJORN LEINES: Right.
BRYAN IGUCHI: Well, I wouldn't
want to be riding those big
lines over there.
BJORN LEINES: Fuck no.
I wouldn't want to be out on
anything hanging or anything
not supported.
BRYAN IGUCHI: Hear that
crust layer there?
WILLIE MCMILLON: A lot
of times we're not
into it, you know?
We'll go out, and he'll be
like, let's dig a pit.
And you're just like,
dude, seriously?
And we'll dig a nine-foot pit.
And then we're worked.
And we can't even strap
in, you know?
But he's diligent about it.
BRYAN IGUCHI: OK, I'm guessing
it's going to pop
somewhere in here.
BJORN LEINES: What's that?
BRYAN IGUCHI: Let's
see if I can--
this is such a delicate block.
Oh, OK.
Oh, I'm seeing surface
over here.
Oh, no, these are preserved
stellars.
If you come here and
look at this.
BJORN LEINES: Those
are-- yeah.
BRYAN IGUCHI: That's a storm
interface, perfectly preserved.
OK.
BJORN LEINES: Mm-hm.
Look at how huge they are.
BRYAN IGUCHI: I know.
BJORN LEINES: Those didn't
get big, they just--
BRYAN IGUCHI: They just
melt right away.
BJORN LEINES: Mm-hm.
BRYAN IGUCHI: Yeah, you see
how they [INAUDIBLE].
So basically, it's a storm
interface layer.
So it was a temperature
change or whatever.
A little density change there.
BJORN LEINES: This is what you
don't want, one from the hand.
And it's easy style
of breaking off.
BRYAN IGUCHI: Yeah.
DAVE DOWNING: Jackson Hole?
Yeah.
I think it's always been
kind of a rad place to
snowboard, you know?
A lot of old Fall Line films
are filmed in Jackson Hole.
And then there's always cycles
in snowboarding, like certain
places become popular,
you know?
And then they kind of
fade off, you know?
One year it might be Colorado.
One year it might
be Utah, Tahoe.
And right now, I think
a lot of people are
going to Jackson Hole.
They're having a
killer winter.
And so a lot of people
are going there.
[LAUGHS]
KEVIN JONES: His progression
is always a step ahead.
Pretty soon, I think, it's going
to be protocol that all
these riders that are venturing
in the back country,
but they don't know things
about the back country.
It's like this white stuff that
you love, it can kill you
very easily on the wrong day.
And Guch, you know, everybody
he's around, it's like just
having him around makes the
whole crew more aware of
what's going on around us.
BRYAN IGUCHI: Yeah, OK.
This is a crystal screen
in a loop.
So it's a magnifying glass.
You just look to see what the
snow crystals that the failure
surface is on.
Yeah, it's definitely some
old surface hoar.
TRAVIS RICE: It's one thing if
you're just going out and
riding and having fun.
But if you're trying to shoot
with photographers or film,
man, it's a whole
other dynamic.
You've got to time things right
with what time of day
you should be at
certain places.
The snow's bad here.
You should try here, all the
different zones that surround
this area here in Jackson.
And for me, for two years, it
was amazing being lucky enough
to ride here locally with a guy
like Guch who had put in a
bunch of years all by himself,
basically, trying to figure it
out for himself.
KEVIN JONES: Safety is huge.
I mean, he's watched one of his
friends die right in front
of his eyes, you know?
When Tristan died, that same
year Craig Kelly died and Jeff
Anderson died.
It was like, holy shit.
I guess, all of a sudden,
it isn't just
happening to other people.
It's people within our--
this is really hitting
home now, you know?
BRYAN IGUCHI: It's a lot more
reactive here than it is in
the Tetons.
SHANE GRIMES: Yeah?
BRYAN IGUCHI: Yeah.
It's all changes in whether.
That's a really firm
block of snow.
SHANE GRIMES: So that was a
couple of storms ago, a real
heavy, wet one?
BRYAN IGUCHI: And you
see all that?
It's just like facets,
like sugar.
So you could propagate--
it could step down
further down.
It's definitely not a good
looking snow pack.
I wouldn't want to go on
anything too big or anything
with a high consequence.
I feel good about just small
landings, jumps and things
we've been doing.
But I wouldn't want to ride
too many big lines.
SHANE GRIMES: Yeah.
BRYAN IGUCHI: No, I wouldn't
want to ride
any big lines here.
Like I wouldn't go in
there right now.
PAT BRIDGES: A lot of people
say, why doesn't snowboard
media focus as much attention
on the pedigree of the sport
or what the legends are doing
now or guys who are 40 years
old and pro still and stuff?
Well, the guys who are 40 and
pro still don't ride like Guch
does or as much as Guch does.
Or they've stopped progressing
or evolving themselves.
He never stopped.
SHANE GRIMES: So we're going
to hit some small jumps, or
jump with protected landings.
Try to keep this safe.
BRYAN IGUCHI: Try, yeah.
PAT BRIDGES: It just so happens,
because of his stoke
on riding, he's gone from riding
in Jackson Hole with
guys like Lance Pittman and
Willie McMillon to riding with
the next generations of Jackson
riders like the Rices
and Mark Carters and to ride
in the next generation of
Jackson Hole riders.
And that's just because he's
in the lift line and he's
riding every day.
BILLY ANDERSON: He's
just dedicated.
And I think that that's gotten
him to where he is, is he
loves snowboarding.
And I think he was really
committed, coming from a
pretty hard core skate and surf
background in Los Angeles
and taking that to the snow.
He kind of had not a chip on his
shoulder, but he was tough
and focused.
BRYAN IGUCHI: Well, for a few
years now I've just start
taking some more advanced
avalanche courses.
I did my Level 1 in
Canada at the
Professional Operations class.
I'm trying to get my head
wrapped around more of the
science part of it.
You get experience
in the mountains.
And you kind of get a feeling
for what's going on and make
decisions on what you've
seen in the past.
You get an idea of what
signs to look out for.
I'm on more of a mission
now to quantify what
I'm seeing and why.
So I'm getting more into looking
at the structure of
the snow pack and looking
at the more
scientific part of it.