kidnapped.
George and I were set to drop the ransom. Time was of the essence.
Are you sure we're in the right place?
The botanical gardens at closing, George.
The instructions were quite clear.
It just seems like we're the only ones here.
(Constable) Irwin? Sir, Sir! (Constable) Worsley?
The detective is looking for you. And FYI (For Your Information)?
He's not in a good mood.
FYI? Is that a woman constable?
No Sir--She's a sergeant! She's wearing trousers!
Are you serious? Are you even serious?
You need to grow a pair ...
No, no! You need to grow a pair (of testicles) and do your job like man!
Is this HIM?
George?
Only my grandmother calls me that and she's dead.
Nice suit.
Where do they these pencil-necked geeks?
Crandall's refusing to do-over because we screwed up the drop.
We got to find his daughter ASAP (as soon as possible).
Grace Crandall?
Oh, so you don't just dress stupid.
What's ASAP?
How could this be?
Where was I? In a dream?
It felt so real.
Even the same girl had been kidnapped.
But I had to get back and find the real Grace Crandall.
I just couldn't see how.
What else can I do but go along.
All right, car rules: no eating, no drinking, no smoking, no touching, no breathing.
Oh! This is a lovely
lovely modern automobile!
I wonder how fast it goes? It smells a bit strange.
Uh... Shall I crank the engine?
No, you shall shut up. I got the engine.
We're going to see my "narc". She's undercover.
"Narc"?
Yeah, narcotics (police officer). You know, they investigate cocaine and heroin?
Why? Those drugs are perfectly legal!
I think you've been doing some of those drugs!
uh...Ha, ha, ha....
This wasn't the Toronto I knew. This was a Toronto even George could not have imagined.
Buildings as tall as the clouds, automobiles and people crowding the streets.
Everyone seemed so impatient, especially my new partner.
Get out of my way!
That's not very nice, George.
That's Crabtree.
Oh! Is that legal?
Julia?
Shut up! You're blowing my cover!
Who's the rookie?
He's my new partner, Detective Murdoch.
He's cute.
He's kind of uptight, but he's cute.
What do you got for me Jules?
It seems you little kidnapped heiress had a big nasty habit.
What? Blow (Cocaine)?
Gambling. She was in deep (in debt).
Three guesses as to who played the bookie.
I recognize this building.
Yeah, every cop in town knows this building.
And HE'S why.
Is that...?
Brackenreid.
Toronto's number one bookie. He's a nasty character.
He's going down this time. I don't care if it costs me my badge.
Everything was upside down!
Inspector Brackenreid a crime lord?
Julia undercover?
Drugs illegal?
Women policemen?
Toronto, but not Tornto.
But strangest of all,
the same crime
in two different ages.
Now I had to save the life of not one
but two Grace Crandalls. And I had no idea how.
Oh, George. I think you should slow down.
I'm going to be sick!
Henry?
Well, well, well.
Detective Crabtree.
Can I help you?
No.  Thanks.
George!
Are you my grandmother? No, so don't call me George.
You're my partner, so get my back and keep mouth shut!
Police brutality!  --You shut up too!
Wait, Higgins.  We must act like a gentleman that we are.
You're coming for a ride downtown (to the police station).
Always happy to help out the "Boys in Blue", son?
H, be a good boy and mind the pub while I go for a ride with my good pals here.
Oh and do me a favour?
Give my brief a call.
That's "lawyer" to you, son?
Are you all right, Henry?
So we can see them
but they can't see us?
You've never seen interrogation before?
Well not through a half-silvered mirror.
I don't know why it didn't occur to me.
It's ingenious!
You really appreciate the little things, don't you?
This world is full of
man's ingenuity.
It's humbling.
You are SO strange.
And SO not my type!
This Julia was so different,
yet so much the same. I was happy to be
working with her again free from our
former restraints, at least in this world.
Well, if it isn't the "Hogtown Hustler"!
They're starting.
Ah yes, of course.
Take off your glasses, Brackenreid.
Your future's not that bright.
Where's the girl?
You'll have to be more specific.
You know I know.
Is that a riddle?
Grace Crandall had a gambling problem.  She owed you money. You thought that by kidnapping her, you not only collect your dough,
but also a healthy bonus from her old man on top.
What a fiendish plot.
I hope you catch the devil behind it because despite what your compunctions believe otherwise,
I'm not in the book-making business.
Just tell me where she is!
You've got nothing on me.
And I've got nothing to tell you.
What!?!
Sorry, Sir.
Mr. Brackenreid's lawyer is here.
Ah, it seems that our time is up, Detective.
An entertaining chat as always.
Oh and, I would like to wish you the best with this missing girl.
Hi George! -- He can't see you.
-- Right!
What do you mean you need PROOF!
He's quite unpleasant.
I would have used a different word.
The inspector is correct.  We do require
evidence but George is right about
Brackenreid, isn't he?  Don't call him George.
Seriously.
You can't be principled to be a cop in the city.
I don't think that's true.  You're so old-fashioned.  It's cute.
Are you sure we've never met before?  You just seem so familiar.
Julia, would you believe me if i told you
that I'm not from here?
Yes! I would believe you.
What I mean to say ...
My case!  My way!
Screw this!
Brackenreid is so guilty, I can smell it!
And I don't care what some paper-pushing,
political butt-kisser has to say about that.
I'm going to get Grace Crandall.
You two can decide if following some lame procedure is more important
than saving a girl's life.
That's a very good point.
Aren't you ... ?  -- Grace Crandall.
--I escaped.  --From whom?
Dr. Grace?
Doctor?
Murdoch, she just needs some air.
Grace Crandall was safe but how and why?
Was Brackenreid behind this?
Was there more than met the eye?
Even if i could somehow leave this time,
I wasn't quite prepared to give up
Julia again.
Did I belong here with her or in 1899 without her?
A door was open.  I ran.
Where were you?
I don't know. It was dark.
Well, when you ran through the door where did you come out?
I don't know.
I just started running and now I'm here.
Who kidnapped you?
I don't know.
Did you hear any voices?
Maybe.
How many?
I couldn't tell.
Were they male or female?
I really don't remember.
What DO you remember?
I was at home.
I heard a noise.
And then I smelled something sweet.
I passed out. I woke up and saw the open door,
and now I'm here.
Did you run here ASAP?
Even if she was chloroformed, she would at
least remember some landmark between
the captor's lair and here.
Yes, thank you Poindexter.
He makes a valid point.
Who is this Poindexter?
You were raised my monks in Tibet, right?
No, Jesuit priests in Nova-Scotia.
That explains a lot, actually.
Look, Brackenreid is the missing link in whatever is going on here.
I'm going to stake him out and see if I can find some answers.
Are you two in or not?
"Stake out" means "watch".
Uh... yes!
Well, perhaps we should stake out Grace Crandall as well.
She seems to have something to hide.
Oh well, looky here!
Maybe there's a cop under that monkey suit after all.
And don't let that go to your head.
Brains can only get you so far in this world.
I'll tail the Crandall girl and you two, (Can you) play nice?
I don't like your suit either.
He has just gone back inside.
He's still alone.
Incredible!
This camera uses no mirrors at all!
And this tiny electronic wafer appears to be where all of the images are stored.
Oh my god, just make some more coffee, will you?
Everyday conveniences automated!
The implications are astounding.
Murdoch, do me a solid and shut up, will you?
I'm trying to concentrate here!
A "solid".  That's a favour, yes?
Yeah.
"Full HD" Oooh!
George, have you considered the possibility of any other suspects?
No.
Given that we have no evidence linking
Brackenreid to the crime perhaps it would behoove us
No! It's not going to behoove us to do anything except what we're doing, ok?
You appear to be losing your objectivity.
If you don't like the way I do things, there's the door.
Or better yet, there's the second-storey window.
What is that?  It says "Joolz".
Yeah, well, answer it.
Hello?
Jules, what's up?
I lost Grace.  --What?
--She was right here and then she disappeared.
Was she captured?
No! Oh, dammit!
I didn't lose her.
She meant to ditch me.
If Grace Crandall led Julia to a specific location,
That means they're on to her.
Julia, you got to get out of there NOW!
--Higgins.  --Julia??
Something was very wrong.
Where was Miss Crandall?
Was Brackenreid behind this?
What had become of Julia?  Was she in danger?
And if she was in danger here,
what was happening to her in 1899?
"Please hang up and try your call again."
We have to inform the inspector.  --There's no time.
We need reinforcements from the station house.
No, we don't. And besides, we know it was Brackenreid who snatched her.
How do we know that?
I just know.
George, we were watching him at the time that Julia was snatched.
Well then, it was one of his cronies.
That's a rash assumption.
And it was your rash actions that got her trouble in the first place.
Hitting me isn't going to save her.
No, but it might make me feel better.
Brackenreid's on the move!
The cocky bastard!
LEAVE HIM TO ME!
I take the lead.
We're of the same rank.
I take charge!
Your methods haven't proven to be successful yet.
Listen, you just shut your mouth ...
... and watch your back.
Yes, I know.  Hey, hey!
Gentleman, what a surprise!
Detective Julia Ogden has gone missing.
We know you're behind it.
Are you having a laugh, George?
Is he having a giraffe?
I assure you he's being quite serious.
Tell us where she is!
You're starting to give me your right arm!
Don't make me report your for harassment again.
I'll give you something to report!
Allow me an attempt.  Tell us where she is!
That's exactly what I said!
Listen, you two have been watching me for ages.
You know better than anyone
that I had nothing to do with your bird's disappearance.
In fact, you two are my alibi!
Well, I can see how upset you both are.
So I'll tell you what.
I'll be sure to keep your missing detective in my prayers.
How does that sound?
What do we do?
Well, we have options.
I wasn't talking to you.
The first of which is to contact the station
and have them dispatch constables
to comb the area.
No.
The deeper I was pulled into this investigation,
the more enchanted I became with this strange, world around me.
Humans, vehicles, information all
moving so fast.  How did one keep up?
And who was the George of the future?
He was so hot-tempered and rash.
Was this what one had to come to survive
in this modern age?
Would we ever be able to see eye-to-eye?
What are you doing? Get out of my way!
Julia's safety must eclipse any issues
you might be having with your superiors.
I'm on suspension right now. Are you happy?
The sheer irresponsibility of continuing
to pursue an avenue of investigation
without the support of your superior ...
Oh, of course, because you never break any of the rules!
I try not to.
Oh! That's a real shocker!
That's the least of our concerns at the
moment.
Exactly!  We should be following Brackenreid
instead of you rapping my knuckles here.  Now, get out of my way!
I don't believe to be the best use of our limited time.
I don't care what you believe.  Move or be moved.
I will agree to move if you agree to retrace Grace Crandall's steps.
I don't do well with ultimatums.
At the very least
It will give us Julia's last known whereabouts.
And then perhaps we can look for trace evidence at the location of her abduction.
This is not time for reasoning.  I'm going this one alone.
I'm afraid I can't let you do that.
Well, I'm afraid you have no choice.
You know what, Murdoch?
I would say that I'm sorry for this, but I'm not.
Sorry for what?
THIS.
Murdoch!
Murdoch, are you all right?
Where is she?  --Who?
Julia!  Where is she?
Doctor Ogden?
Why are you asking about her?
I was back in 1899.
It seemed that George Crabtree had a painful way of making me change
timelines
if i was ever anywhere else at all.
But dream or no dream,
this wasn't where I needed to be.
Julia was still missing
and the Crabtree of the future was out of control.
Would I be able to get back to 2012
or was I home for good?
The ransom drop was a  fiasco, we've got no new leads,
Crandall is breathing down our necks ...
Grace has a gambling problem.
Dr. Grace?
No, no. Mr. Crandall's daughter,
Emily Grace.
You mean Grace Crandall.
That's what I said.
Emily Grace is our coroner.
She has a heavy gambling problem and if
you find her bookie, you will likely find her.
And how could you have possibly discovered this?
It's a long story, Sir.
It might be worth a look, Sir.
Fine.  Crabtree, see what you can find, but quickly.
And you, get some rest.
I think that knock to the nap left you a bit mixed up.
Come on, Crabtree.
Sir, as per your earlier enquiring,
Dr. Ogden is attending a fundraiser at the Flatiron.
The Flatiron Building!
That's Brackenreid's pub!
The inspector owns a pub?
That's where he's keeping Julia!
George, I need you to do me a solid.
A "solid", Sir?
Yes, George. I need you to hit me.
No, Sir.  I couldn't possibly (do that).
George you can do it!
Just like you did by the car!
The car?
What car?
Just like you did it in the park, George. Hit me!
All right, Sir.  But let it be known, I'm very uncomfortable with this.
George, do it!
Oooh!
It worked!
I was in 2012 once again.  I knew I had to get to the Flatiron Building
and fast.
But I could only hope that I arrived in time.
George!
Detective Crabtree!  --Right!
Keep your voice down. You're going to ruin everything.
She's here!  Julia is here!
I know.  --You do?
Have you seen her?
No, but where else could she be?
What do you know?
Oh, uh. Not a thing.
Well then how do you know she's here?
Oh, uh.
It's just a feeling.
Well, that doesn't sound like you, but it's good enough for me.
You know what stinks about this whole thing?
What's that?
There's no way that we couldn't have seen her being brought in here.
This building was built in the nineteenth century.
If you say so.
All buildings were heated with coal back then.
Fascinating.
The coal was kept in a dedicated coal room in the basement.
Where the pub is!
That's right.
If the room still exists, it could likely access the city's sewer system.
So, if Brackenreid brought her in that way,
we wouldn't have seen anything.
Which would also explain why we didn't see him leave
at the time Julia was kidnapped.
Not bad.
What kind of a cop knows anything about the nineteenth century?
Oh, you could say that I have a passing interest in that time period.
It was my constant challenge to always
appear like I belonged here in this time.
For some reason
the Flatiron building appeared to
be the key to solving a crime in this
present reality and in my life of the past.
If that life even still existed.
Where's your weapon?
In the armoury?
What?  You're not carrying (a gun)?
Neither are you.
They won't let me carry a piece since my last suspension.
What's your excuse?
You don't require firearms where I come
from to search a building.
What is this perfect place you come from where no one needs firearms
and everyone gets along in perfect harmony?
Oh, there's plenty of discord, trust me.
Discord, yeah right!
Have you ever done any REAL police work?
A lot!
I assume you have a plan, then?
Yeah, I do.
We wait until the place closes, and then we break in and find Jules.
I have a better idea.  Oh yeah?  What's that? I'm all ears!
We kick down the door on three.
And then what?
Well, that's it.  Yeah, I like it!
One, two, three!
I had always been a cautious man.
but he who hesitates is lost.
I had hesitated before with Julia, and it cost me her love.
and I couldn't allow it to cost Julia her life.
No matter what the consequence to save her,
I would have kicked down a thousand doors.
But would I find her on the other side alive?
Three!
Hey, hey!  You'll pay for that!
Now, where would this secret coal room be?
This way!
Oh, bollocks!
Let's see your hands like cop and cowboy.
Take it easy, George, my old china?
Planning a vacation?  --Let me guess.
You two are in love.  --Screw you!
That's why you faked the kidnapping.
So your daddy would finance the honeymoon.
Then you took Jules to keep her from discovering your secret.
Not the smartest play.
That's exactly what I said!
Shut up!  All of you!
Put down your gun!
Do what I say or she gets it!
Do you feel fortuitous?
Well, do you?  Hooligan?
Why throw these away?
It seems like such a waste.
Hey, is he still in there?
Yes they've been in there for quite some time.
I just finished the interview with Grace Crandall.
Apparently, they were going to skip across
the border on a train to Buffalo
and then catch a flight to Fiji.
What women will do for love.
Not just women.
So, I have these two tickets to West Side Story.
You know, the musical?
Two kids from opposite sides of the tracks?
Star-crossed lovers?
Ah... Shakespeare: Romeo and Juliet
Yeah.
Like a less boring version.
Anyway so,
if you don't have any plans ... ?  Well?
No more suspensions, and I got Aunt Daisy back!
Aunt Daisy?
Oh my!
And Brackenreid is finally in jail.
Congratulations, George.
Don't call me that!  Just don't.
Crabtree, grab your phone I want a picture with you two.
Wait.  Your telephone has a camera inside?
Could it be real?
A chance to start over with Julia all over again in this strange time?
Yet I knew I couldn't stay.
I had to return to find the Grace Crandall of 1899.
It develops it as well?
The photo wasn't THAT bad!
George.
How many times!?!
I need you to do me a favour.
Yeah, good luck with that!
I need you to hit me--HARD.
Murdoch, I don't want to hit you.
Hit me, GEORGE!
Murdoch!  Murdoch!
Dr. Grace?
No, no, no.  You don't need a doctor!  Just some ice.
Sir, you were right!
The Crandall girl is heavily in debt
and  we haven't been able to find bookmaker yet, though.
She's not just in debt to him, she's in love with him!
The two of them were in on the scheme together.
Now, how could you possibly know that?
Sir, I believe you'll find them at  Union
Station awaiting a train to Buffalo.
Sir, he hasn't been wrong yet.
Come on then, Crabtree. Let's go!
George?  Doctor Ogden?
Yes, Sir. She wants to see you.
She's very concerned about your injuries.
She has made me feel quite guilty about it. But she suggests that I apply some cold meat to the side of your face ...
Crabtree!  I said let's go!
How are you?
I heard you sustained a few good blows
to the head!
I had quite a dream while I was unconscious.
May I ask what about?
I was in a future Toronto.
It was very
large and busy!
Tall buildings filled the sky.
Airplanes
soaring through the clouds. It was incredible!
It sound glorious!
But only you could have such a dream!
William,
I have two tickets to Romeo and Juliet.
Perhaps you would like to escort me?
Oh! Star-crossed lovers!
How could I not?
Wisteria Borealis!
Everything had turned out for the better.
The case was solved.
The Crandall girl was safe
and even here in 1899,
Julia and I were starting over.
I might never know if my journey to the future was real,
but I was happier for it.
I could not have asked for anything more.
In eighteen hundred and ninety-nine
Two Toronto cops are out to solve a crime
George accidentally knocked Murdoch out
And the plot gets thicker without a doubt.
Our hero wakes up in twenty-twelve
Same crime, same crook, same city as well.
Even George is in, but call him Crabtree
Gotta solve a crime in this century.
In the Flatiron is Brackenreid's pub
His old partner, Higgins, is Brackenreid's thug.
Grace is held hostage, but something ain't right.
A time-travelling mystery's going down tonight.
It's the Murdoch Effect
So now Grace is free, but she's hiding something.
Brackenreid laughs because the cops have got nothing.
Now Murdoch's all worried because Julia is missing.
And he sets off on a brand new mission.
Our heroes bust into Brackenreid's pub
And find out he and Grace are in love.
She was in on the plot the whole damn time
And it was time for them to pay for this crime.
Julia's safe so all is right
But her man's got to go back in time tonight.
He see's the Julia that he loved back then
And that's how this time-travelling mystery ends.
It's the Murdoch Effect.