complex and complicated guy, but
we had no idea that things
were as dark as they were.
We were super saddened
by the events
this morning in Arizona.
He was a very charismatic
guy, right?
The whole piece that you're
about to see is a PR tour,
essentially.
He's a spinster.
He was very well aware of the
perceptions of him and did his
best to counteract that and to
show a different side of what
he was doing.
At the same time, we
knew about him.
We had done our research, we had
done our pre-production.
And we knew that there
were photos of
him at neo-Nazi rallies.
We knew that he had made
statements to the press in the
past that were horrible
and awful.
And we asked him about those,
and he very kind of slickly
and slyly denied and danced
around them, so they didn't
become a centerpiece
of the piece.
And I guess, in retrospect, I
guess I wish we did hammer on
that a little bit more.
Overall, someone that we spent
time with and shared a meal
with has done something so
god-awful and tragic.
So it caused us to think we
should revisit our piece, the
Vice Guide to Border Militias,
and share it with you guys.
So this is the Vice Guide
to Border Militias.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
RYAN DUFFY: So the private
militia has kind of come
roaring back to life
in America in
the last couple years.
And they're rattling around a
bunch of different causes.
Now for J.T and the Ready
Rangers, it's this stretch of
land here in Stanfield,
Arizona.
Basically, it's no man's land,
3,000 acres of American soil
that US citizens are discouraged
from entering and
illegal immigrants regularly
travel through while sneaking
across the border.
So J.T. Ready and the Ready
Rangers have stepped in.
J.T. READY: We do kind of have
a Wild West spirit out here.
We have very liberal gun laws.
You can own machine guns.
You can legally own grenades,
tanks even.
We got some terrorist coming
at us with machine guns and
ski masks in the middle of the
desert, we're allowed to shoot
him right in the face.
And we want him to know
there's Americans
standing the line.
RYAN DUFFY: The Ready Rangers
are a bunch of volunteers out
here patrolling 160
miles of desert.
And to be clear, absolutely
no one has asked them to.
J.T. READY: OK, here you go.
See this ski mask?
You don't wear those out here
in this heat, unless
you're a bad guy.
RYAN DUFFY: J.T. is all about
being the good guy.
And part of that is making
the bad guys look
really, really bad.
J.T. READY: Life is very low
on the totem pole when it
comes to the cartel.
There's a thing called rape
trees, cutting off body parts.
They mail them back to Mom
and Pop down south.
Bloody undergarments, Los Zetas,
pockets full of feces.
When the coroner comes out here
and tries to remove that
duct tape, it takes her
face with them.
And they'll leave heads and
things like that on the
border, just all packed
in there like Amistad.
RYAN DUFFY: J.T. wanted us to
know that even though he wants
to shoot drug smugglers directly
in the face, he's
totally into helping out the
regular, old, illegal
immigrants he finds.
J.T. READY: We try to give the
regular UDAs as much respect
as possible, that includes out
of our own pocket, water,
limes, they like limes.
They like garlic and
stuff like that.
We try to think of their
cultural stuff.
RYAN DUFFY: Could you imagine
if you were starving in a
desert for a week, it was 110
degrees in the shade, and a
dude found you and was like,
oh, don't worry, I'm
going to help you.
Here's a lime and a clove of
garlic because I understand
your culture.
J.T. Is so focused on getting
his side of the story out
there that he turned our border
patrol into some sort
of international press junket,
with a bunch of crews filming
the Ready Rangers getting
the job done.
The craziest part about all of
this is what J.T. Is doing is
totally legal.
Not only has the US government
not figured out how to
regulate the border, they've
also let guys like J.T. wander
around the desert with
some buddies and a
military-grade arsenal.
And that makes him feel
like an American hero.
J.T. READY: I'm just out there
bearing assault rifles and
saving lives and looking
for narco-terrorists.
That which doesn't kill
me makes me smarter.
And that which does kill me
will make me a martyr.
[MUSIC PLAYING]