I'm Maurice Sendak.
We are now sitting in my barn.
It's where I come and
work when I want
it to be very quiet.
There's no radio here, there's
no TV, there's nothing here.
Just me and Herman, the German
Shepherd, who says nothing.
He doesn't critique my work,
doesn't cluck his tongue.
When he has to take a leak, he
just tells you, straight out.
Well, I've had infinite
amount of dogs, but
Herman is the best.
And also he's the
best trained.
Because of my legs and back,
he walks slowly,
he looks after me.
Aside from her, he's the only
thing that makes me happy.
SPIKE JONZE: Aside from Lynn?
Does Lynn live with you?
MAURICE SENDAK: Yes.
She's the woman in my life.
She is the only woman
in my life.
LYNN CAPONERA: That's
not true.
You have a lot of women
in your life.
MAURICE SENDAK: Yes.
LYNN CAPONERA: Women
love Maurice.
Maurice gets proposed
to at least four or
five times a year.
MAURICE SENDAK: It's
terrifying.
SPIKE JONZE: Keener
proposed to you.
MAURICE SENDAK: Who?
SPIKE JONZE: Catherine Keener
wanted to marry you.
MAURICE SENDAK: I want to marry
her, too, but it's not
likely we'll get it together.
CATHERINE KEENER: Hi, Maurice.
I'm practicing.
Hi, Maurice.
Did you have brothers
or sisters?
MAURICE SENDAK: I had.
CATHERINE KEENER:
They're gone?
MAURICE SENDAK: They're gone.
They were wonderful, truly
wonderful people.
CATHERINE KEENER:
Girls or boys?
MAURICE SENDAK: One brother,
one sister.
I'm the baby.
CATHERINE KEENER: You
are the baby.
I could tell.
You seem like the baby
in the line-up.
SPIKE JONZE: How do you tell?
MAURICE SENDAK: How
do you tell?
CATHERINE KEENER:
I don't know.
I just feel it.
SPIKE JONZE: I was telling
Keener how a lot of your
family and experiences with your
family have wound up in a
lot of your work.
Is that true?
MAURICE SENDAK: No.
SPIKE JONZE: No?
You told me that--
MAURICE SENDAK: I make
up a lot of shit.
But I can't tell
the real story.