is a very much of it
credible polling organization and uh...
and as i said it would simply the most
accurate
in the last election cycle okay
so at first we start with amazing
political facts a global warming is an
approx
illegally thirty seven percent of all
voters say yes
fifty eight percent republicans say yes
forty one percent of independence
that sounds huge majority of republic
boaters
who say that
it's not this global warming is manmade
global warming
temperatures
rising
is a hulks
but the tensions
are rising
the thermometers don't have a well-known
liberal bias
that's a fact
but probably
thirty seven percent of american voters
and fifty eight percent or problems that
buildings made up
weather
the sun mon
carbon dioxide are all well known
liberal bias
on real
alright nasty and a political ignorance
that saddam hussein sa manila nine
eleven others also fact
he did not
if you want you know as bush in cheney
they say he did not knoll person who
knows any information about this
liza saddam hussein was connected nine
eleven
so for some erica's get it one
uh... unfortunate percentage of the time
twenty eight percent of voters say yeah
sam did it
and thirty six percent of romney voters
of course
so we have slightly more inner
republican voters there saying the
saddam hussein did now not not all
cooked a
things a wrong here and in america who
are right on some of those top
and i will conspiracy theories are off
so for example on j_f_k_
fifty one percent of voters believe it
was a larger conspiracy but only twenty
one percent say boswell act alone
now there is
tremendous evidence that oswald did not
act alone
so that fifty one percent
could be right
there are conspiracies
as a crime in we see the people get
together and do things and it's called a
conspiracy
could have happened in some cases that
have all the government of course a kind
of
in fact we've seen it over and over
right
but it question is when how
you can just pull it out as you're about
to see in some of the crazier things
but just physical something stays as it
is not true or nikki betrayal on that
here's our guests are c_f_o_
how do people believe in the new world
order that there's a secret group of
obese
they're secretly will be your decisions
are willing to sell
twenty eight percent of voters overall
thirty eight percent of romney voters
believe that there's a new will order
the rockefellers of several are
actually all the decisions
that's a stunning number of crazy people
look are their powerful and rich people
who are more influential because they
did a lot of money to publishers accor
missile as there are
but they're not synonym builder for
smoke-filled room go up by rubber ball
and at those or out those who turned up
war was that that would in all of it all
of broccoli but
this is sufficient for news that they
did and that
serious crazy way
issued anti-christ
thirteen percent of all to say yes
twenty-three set around me berserk thing
about that that's more than one in five
romney voters who believe that the
president the united states is the
anti-christ
the antichrist
but we're not done with crazier
twenty nine percent of voters believe
that bailey's exist
now i'm dual long list here
that's twenty nine percent for baghdad
okay and by the way it was probably do
exist has on what you mean by aliens as
their water on other planets
they certainly could be marathi big
color shape guys who landed here not
necessarily in fact
haha twenty one percent was do think so
though because they say
there you are folk ration roswell
celeste where one percent of us
unless you find a believe
even if there might be aliens that are
somewhere out in the universe
now let's have a little bit of fun
how bout number of people who believe in
bigfoot fourteen percent
how about of people who believe that the
u_s_ government allowed nine eleven i
happen
those the truth is spoken the sentence
present numbers that low to be honest
with you
uh... voters who believe osama bin laden
is still alive
six percent
and uh...
boaters who think the moon landing was
fake
seven percent
that's always my favorite
the moon landing was fake really really
we bother the but why
all where it can be sure that they are
when it was a hollywood so this stage i
saw the shadow out for christ sake that
over to really mad
by aboard a donated
five percent believe
that the exhaust see in the sky behind
airplanes
no no no no no
not exhaust
it's a secret chemical sprayed by the
government for centuries
fibers of the country that's one twenty
people believe it off the hard part of
those gallery on
there comes a discordant salts
but my
new favored 'cause i've never even heard
this one before
four percent of voters believe
that loser people secretly controller
lizard people
as almost one in four th well one in
twenty five
lizard
that can't be true man
if it's true
one out of every twenty five americans
isn't has literally lost our minds
to speak about men
they're out there thank you
she was a person
we're set chemical coming out of there
ways than one
fathers and of course the president but
i've got another was a person