MIKE HATCHETT: Dave broke his
femur in 1994, and that was
kind of the beginning
of the end for Dave.
And he had dabbled around
filming a little bit.
But that next year's when he
actually, in '95, when he
picked up a camera and actually
started shooting.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
DAVE HATCHETT: Definitely, the
first couple of years were
tough behind the camera and
watching all the new riders
ride the lines.
And especially when one of the
rookies would blow it, I'm
like, dude, I could
ride that thing.
Come on.
But at the same time, it was
kind of a relief to not be so
putting your ass on the line.
And the kind of riding
that I did--
the big mountain riding and just
going fast through rock
lines and trying to flash these
wicked chutes and rocky,
peppery lines--
it's a bit of a relief, for
sure, to be behind the camera.
MIKE HATCHETT: He doesn't have
any formal experience or
training, other than me
just saying, here's a
camera, there you go.
Focus.
Composition.
I just explained a few
things to him.
And he just basically started
pointing and shooting.
So that's how Dave learned.
DAVE HATCHETT: One of my
favorite shots that I've ever
shot of a snowboarder was Tom
Burt doing the Tom Burt Spines
up on Donner.
And I actually had to
rope in to film it.
I had to use snowboards
as a belay.
And I put a harness on it, and
I got down on this ledge.
And I got this kind of cool shot
where I kind of panned
the camera, and he came down,
and he fell away.
And it just looked
really cool.
It gave it a really
cool perspective.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
DAVE HATCHETT: And the line
was just incredible.
The line had never been
snowboarded before.
It was one of the steepest,
gnarliest spines for sure, at
that point, that anyone
had ever done.
And Tom greased it really well
on the snowboard, and I got
the shot really good, too.
So it was kind of really
satisfying to see those
elements come together as a
team, as Tom as a rider, and
me as a filmer.
It was almost as satisfying as
riding it myself, although I
don't know if I'd actually
ride that line.
Maybe.
JEREMY JONES: When Stanner was
shooting TB6, I was up there
just dirtbagging it.
And the Hatchetts saw my tracks
in the mountains and
were like, we'd love to
look at that footage.
They had already had TB6 pretty
darn close to cut, and
then they got this footage and
were like, we've got to put
this in the movie.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
JEREMY JONES: Still to this day,
going down to Spreckels
Theatre in San Diego for the
premiere, I'm still like, I'm
in there, I don't know
exactly how much.
And then my stuff comes on at
the end of the movie, and just
seemingly, the place erupted in
like the loudest cheer I'd
ever heard.
And I was shaking after that.
It was one of the highlights
of my snowboard career.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
MIKE HATCHETT: We used to do all
the main world premieres
at Spreckels Theatre.
And look, this is the second
row totally full.
I think it sat 1,200 people at
the time, and it was packed.
You couldn't even stand.
There was not a seat available
in the place.
JEREMY JONES: Hearing all these
people who didn't know
who I was--
I was unheard of--
and just a full house of one of
the loudest cheers of the
night was a really cool thing.
JUSSI OKSANEN: When I grew up,
I liked Standard movies, but
I've never really appreciated
the powder riding
and lines and stuff.
And the first day I went
out, I went with
Burt and Noah Salasnek.
And they were riding some lines
in Tahoe Donner and it
was so humbling.
I was just like, holy shit.
And it just put everything in
perspective, like what those
guys were doing and how
good they were.
LONNIE KAUK: Michael would
always just randomly send
these videos to my dad.
And my dad would be like, yo,
dude, check this out.
And I'd be like, dude,
that is the sickest
thing I've ever seen.
It's just so cool.
I was like, who are
these guys?
Like, these guys were just
shredding all the time.
Like, that's what
I want to do.
MIKE HATCHETT: I had heard
about Lonnie through the
grapevine, obviously, ripping
the park in Mammoth.
And everybody would always say,
Lonnie just laps the park
all day to the bitter
end and just stomps
everything, goes huge.
And I just looked, and I could
just tell that if he was given
the opportunity with the right
film crew and the right riders
that he was probably going to
shine and do really well.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
LONNIE KAUK: There's
no future, yeah.
But the future was just the
next day when you could go
shred and then watching the
movies and seeing the guys.
But then I'm like, damn,
I'm so far from this.
And I started--
I got a job at Mammoth,
being a janitor.
And it's so funny, because today
was the first time I met
Kevin Jones.
And I was like, dude, you've
got no idea, dude.
Last time I seen you, I was
freaking mopping the floor at
Main Lodge, dude.
So that's pretty sick.
MIKE HATCHETT: I finally
decided, you know what, I
think it's time to give Lonnie
a chance, give him a shot at
filming with us.
And I've always gone the extra
mile for Lonnie, because I've
known his dad, and I've known
his upbringing in
Yosemite and stuff.
And I'm stoked to see
how far he's come.
XAVIER DE LE RUE: It's like, to
be honest, growing up where
we grew up, it's just impossible
to think about
where we've been getting.
And Mike definitely
helped me a lot.
And has been basically giving
me so much opportunities.
Like right now, my career has
just got to the next level
because of Standard Films.
JUSSI OKSANEN: Those guys
just worked so hard.
And that's all I knew.
So I just went with the flow,
because I didn't really speak
English or anything.
I really wanted to work,
but I was just kind
of out of my element.
And then being in the
backcountry too, that was--
I've never ridden powder before,
really, that year.
TIM MANNING: Off the resort is
a whole other situation.
So we sometimes called it
snowboard film tryouts,
because we'd take a crew of guys
in the backcountry for
their first time and try to
survive throughout the day.
Keep them away from cornices,
keep them away from dangerous
situations that they had
no idea what they
were involved with.
But we knew that if we could
just get them to these jumps
that we wanted to build, it was
a fairly safe situation.
And then they could
do their stuff.
JEREMY JONES: The Hatchett
brothers are incredible
teachers of everything
to do with filming.
So these riders that come up--
Jussi Oksanen and Kevin
Jones, you name it--
they showed these guys where to
build jumps, how to build
jumps, just doing everything
they could to help everyone to
go into the mountains safely
and ride cool stuff.
CHAS GULDEMOND: Obviously, the
TB series was amazing.
All those older guys just
murdered it, and we're still
trying to live up to
what they did then.
But now, kind of in our own way,
spinning like maniacs and
hitting big park jumps, and
it's kind of crazy.
But I'm pretty stoked to be part
of this generation, as
well as jealous to not
be in the generation
of all those dudes.
MIKE HATCHETT: TB4 to 6 was when
the pendulum just swang,
and the video sales were going
through the ceiling,
sponsorships were up, all the
riders were getting paid good.
And it was just like, yeah.
It was just all of a sudden
like, yeah, I can buy a house
now, I can make a living
off of this.
And that lasted until like
2010, and then it slowly
started tapering off.
And now, it's just a completely
different ball game.
Now, you just really don't make
that much of money making
a snowboard video.
And I never got into it to make
money, so I don't feel
much different.
I got into it because I like
to make movies, and I like
snowboarding.
So the money thing's
never really--
it was great when it was there,
and we made good cash.
And I saved some of it
and then lost it all.
And now I--
it's like making TB2 again--
broke and making a video.
But it still feels good.