of concern.
It's time for the United States
of America to take
responsibility for the pain,
and suffering, and torture,
and murder that's going on
throughout Latin America.
SHANE SMITH: Maybe one of the
reasons that Mitt Romney is so
concerned with the drug wars
taking place just south of the
American border is that it
affects him and his family
personally.
Hi, I'm Shane Smith and we're
here at the VICE headquarters
in Williamsburg, Brooklyn.
Now Williamsburg is ground zero
for hipsters, which means
it's also ground zero for
partying, which means it's
ground zero for cocaine.
Now VICE has talked a lot about
cocaine over the years.
In fact, one of our magazine
covers featured a mirror with
a big line of coke
chopped up on it.
But recently we followed a story
that made us think twice
about our historical fascination
with coke.
And it has to do
with Mormons--
as in Mitt Romney's family
type Mormons--
Mexican drug cartels, polygamy,
kidnapping, cocaine,
and finally, murder.
Now it's a freaky,
freaky story.
And it's taking place just
south of the US border.
So we went to check it
out first hand to see
what was going on.
We just passed through from El
Paso, Texas, which is actually
one of the safest cities in
America, into Juarez, Mexico,
which is actually one of
the most dangerous
cities in the world.
In fact, it's the most dangerous
city in the world
for journalists.
And we're driving with a camera
rolling, which is, in
retrospect, very
fucking stupid.
People always ask me what the
most dangerous place I've ever
been to is.
And when I say Mexico, they're
a bit flummoxed
and they say, Mexico?
I've been to Mexico.
I've been to Cancun, Joe's
tequila foam party,
and Boom Boom Room.
But this Mexico here in Juarez,
is the Mexico run by
the narco lords.
They don't care about what
you're shooting.
They don't walk up and say, hey,
what's that camera for?
They just see a camera and go,
that can't good, and bam.
Now the drug lords that rule
northern Mexico are like most
mafia around the world.
They're very wealthy, and
they're insanely ruthless.
But the thing that sets the
Mexican cartels apart from the
other mobs is their seemingly
profound love of murder.
They put other crime syndicates
to shame with the
sheer scale of their killing,
not to mention the gruesome
eye-catching way they present
their murders with a kind of
evil inventiveness.
And it's not just traditional
gang on gang violence either.
The cartels kill anyone and
everyone in their way.
Rivals, witnesses, journalists,
politicians, and
police are all targets.
And rather than hiding the
bodies like most criminals,
they actually want
you to see them.
And they want you to know
exactly who did it.
In fact, the war on drugs in
Mexico is so violent that its
body count is almost 10 times
that of American soldiers
killed in the real wars in
Iraq and Afghanistan.
And in a country where it's
supposedly illegal to own
guns, the narcos are armed
to the teeth with
state-of-the-art weaponry, 90%
of which are smuggled in from
the United States, which is
something we got to see first
hand as soon as we arrived
in Juarez.
MEXICAN OFFICIAL:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
SHANE SMITH: We came in here and
we saw this huge bunker.
And we're like, oh.
This is where they hold all the
guns, and all the drugs,
and everything in this big,
massive concrete bunker.
And they're like, no, no.
The drugs and the guns are
here in the trucks.
That's a nightclub called
the Sphinx.
So last night the police caught
these guys trying to
smuggle in 268,000 rounds of
ammunition in a truck with
Oklahoma plates.
It was driven by a
guy from Dallas.
Over a quarter million rounds
of ammunition, this is the
kind of firepower
that they have.
This is a .30 caliber Browning,
which shoots super
fast and can shoot through
armored cars.
And then they have this
anti-aircraft, .50 cal.
Can I pick it up?
MALE SPEAKER 1: No.
No.
You can't touch that.
SHANE SMITH: Shit, I did.
I put my finger on it.
I'm going to get in trouble.
They just confiscated
these weapons.
And I touched the .50 cal.
And they haven't dusted
them for prints yet.
So now my prints are
on a murder weapon.
Not good.
MEXICAN OFFICIAL:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
MITT ROMNEY: These look like
they're from America.
America, America, America, all
the guns are from America.
They're all homicides?
They've tested them out?
MEXICAN OFFICIAL:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
SHANE SMITH: Oh, sorry.
That was loud.
It smells very strong.
Holy Jesus, I know this doesn't
look like crazy.
But you can smell.
Wow, it's a lot of drugs,
drugs and flak jackets.
So this is sort of a rustic
type of smuggling.
They call it a burrero, which
is like a donkey.
And they just walk through
the desert with the
pot on their back.
So the market for the
drugs is America.
The market for the weapons
is here in Mexico.
And they go like this.
When you look at this, like
.50 cals, assault rifles,
military grade machine guns,
you realize, OK, how do the
police fight them, let along
regular people, let alone
Mormons who aren't allowed
to own guns.
It's crazy.
So we're about 200 miles
south of Juarez now.
And we're out in the
middle of nowhere.
This is like the narco
superhighway.
There's actually 300 different
smuggling trails
right through here.
There's no big wall
or anything.
You can just walk off into
the desert with your
pack full of cocaine.
And then, all of a sudden,
folks in Williamsburg and
hipsters are doing coke.
As you're out here, it kind of
dawns on you that there's
nowhere to go.
Like if something happens or
if somebody even chases us,
where are we going to run to?
Because you can't trust
the police.
You especially can't trust the
local police because they're
all corrupt.
So basically, right now, it's
a straight shot to the
Mormons, their guns,
and their god.
Ah, we've come to
God's country.
MALE SPEAKER 2: Joel LeBaron
was killed by his
own brother, Ervil.
He started to kill in
the name of God.
SHANE SMITH: That's
some crazy shit.