to this incredible place called Gualeguaychú,
in the provence of Entre Ríos. And here,
I will make for you guys a braised bondiola
with a white and creamy risotto beside the
river.
Let me show you how to start. Here I have
the meat - bondiola, pork. Situated, located
on the back side of the neck. Now I will season
it using pepper, some salt and drizzle it
using olive oil. What we're going to do now
is to take the meat to my Parrilla. Don't
have a Parrilla? Don't worry, you can replace
it using a grill. Now you will listen to the
sounds of heaven. This is what we are looking
for, the contrast between the crust and the
inside which will be smooth, it will be soft,
it will be wonderful. And what we are making
here is to make it flying first class! We
are making an upgrade to the pork!
Come and look at this. Let me show you what I
am talking about. This beautiful and amazing
crust. While this is searing from all the
sides, I will use a big pan and inside I will
put baby carrots, small onions. This will
be like the bed of our pork. Some thyme, good.
And the amazing bondiola, incredible, amazing
and tasty. Take it to your pan, spread a tablespoon
of mustard, some sweet soya sauce. Look at
this, look at the consistency. Now also, black
beer! To the pan, 1 bottle. Look at this my
friends! This is like a festival of flavours.
And a party of all ingredients joining inside
and sweet potatoes in syrup! I buy them on
the market, you do not know where to get them
you can just buy any fruit you like in syrup
or if not you can replace it with any fruit
you like. I will put them all because I like
them very much and I'm also spreading in some
of the syrup. Put on the lid, let them join
the party and take this to the fire. Put it
over here and now my suggestion - three hours.
In three hours come and look at it like me,
which I am going to do something else here
in Gualeguaychú beside the river and we'll
come back in three hours.
I have just finished my test on the tractor
driving licence. I had an excellent and now
I can drive tractors everywhere. Now I didn't
forgot about my bondiola. So now, I think
it is almost ready I will prepare a white
and creamy risotto. Very simple because all
the flavours are here inside, as I told you,
in this festival. Ok let's begin with the
risotto. You have some butter, put it to melt.
Half an onion. Take this onion to your pan
- good. Now add two cups of rice, carnaroli
rice. Look at this beautiful risotto rice.
Now pour in one, two cups. That's ok. Mix
it. It is very simple but we have to keep
on stirring. Now add some stock, yeah baby!
Some salt and pepper would be great. Pepper,
salt! It will take around fifteen minutes
to be ready. Keep on adding some stock when
it requires. But now over here I have the big
guest, my bondiola! Oooooh! Look at this,
the liquids have reduced. Everything is of
the colour of the beer! Super amazing. Look,
these are shreds of glory.
Mmmmmmm great!
Now take a very nice dish or plate. Add a
nice and generous spoon of your risotto. Now
take your pork, take the flavours to the dish
right now.
Amazing! Now, the final touch,
your nice vegetables, your beer, your mustard,
oh my God! Good! Finish it up using some sprouts.
Super amazing, look! This deserves to be eaten
in a great spot. Mmmmmm, totally an upgrade!
So now, sorry? sorry? Information has come
in that you haven't subscribed to Jamie Oliver's
Food Tube channel. Are you guy's crazy?! If
you like this and want more of these videos,
don't forget to subscribe. My name is Felicitas
Pizarro. And remember - you are what you eat
and today we are braised bondiola with a white
and creamy risotto.