JACOB: Last week,
superstar DJ David Guetta
let his fans know that he
has a surprise for them,
if he gets to 50 million
likes on Facebook.
We have that surprise right now.
You are not going to
see this anywhere else.
This is the exclusive sneak peak
of his brand new documentary,
and it is amazing.
DAVID GUETTA: When I play in
a country for the first time,
or in a place like this,
where it's quite a challenge
to be in the middle
of the desert,
I don't really know
what to expect.
And that's what is so
challenging and exciting
about being a DJ.
[MUSIC - DAVID GUETTA,
"TITANIUM FEAT.
SIA"]
JACOB: It was filmed at
the lowest point on Earth,
near The Masada
in Israel, and it
features him
talking about what's
to come from his new album.
If you want to see
the full feature,
go to his Facebook page,
hit the like button.
He is so very, very close.
LIZZIE: Mary-Louise Parker,
Hannah Hart, lots of wine.
Need I say more?
The newest episode
of "My Drunk Kitchen"
features these two
lovelies baking brownies
in the name of charity.
HANNAH: Do you
know how hard it's
going to be for me
to resist asking you
if you want to make
fried green tomatoes?
MARY-LOUISE PARKER: Ahh!
HANNAH: I think that
actually, you're
here to support a cause that
we both are very excited about.
MARY-LOUISE PARKER:
Yeah, HopeNorth.org.
It's a school, it's a
40-acre campus outside--
I can say 40-acre campus now,
I won't be able to say it
in probably about 20 minutes--
HANNAH: That's why
I'm asking you now.
LIZZIE: If you want to find out
how a ten dollar donation can
get you the chance to bake
with the cast of "Weeds,"
head over to Hannah's channel.
JACOB: In the mid 1980s,
a 28-year-old woman
became the voice of freedom
for an entire country.
JACOB: The New York Times
just posted this short doc
on Irina Margareta
Nistor, illegally dubbed
than 3,000 movies
that were smuggled
into Communist Romania.
JACOB: She had to keep her
identity a secret for years,
but she's said to have the most
recognizable voice in Romania,
aside from Communist
leader Ceausescu.
JACOB: This is really
an incredible story.
You have to watch it.
ALI: This might be one of
my favorite discoveries
of all time.
I give you the final scene
of the 1995 classic, "Seven."
This time with more fruit.
MALE SPEAKER: California,
you stay away from here.
You stay away, you hear me?
Whatever you hear, don't
you come down here.
The cheese stands alone!
Tomato!
MALE SPEAKER 2: Here he comes.
MALE SPEAKER 3: What?
MALE SPEAKER 2: Wish I
could've lived like you.
FEMALE SPEAKER: These
guys are brand new.
They've only been
posting for a month,
and this is their
biggest video yet.
ALI: They've already done
"The Usual Sustenance"
and "Reservoir Snacks,"
and now they're
looking for suggestions
for what to do next.
So head on over
to their channel,
and drop a line in
the comments section.
JACOB: Brodie Smith is a
three-time Ultimate Frisbee
National Champion,
and he's pretty much
the only dude I would want
to hang out with at a picnic,
ever.
BRODIE: YouTube nation,
what is going on?
I run the Brodie
Smith 21 channel.
I do a bunch of different
Frisbee trick shots
all over the world,
and I actually
got the ability to go to Dubai.
You'll see in this video,
me jumping out of airplanes,
throwing Frisbees
off of ski slopes,
throwing Frisbees off
of camels, and doing
all sorts of crazy
stuff in the city that's
really from the future.
So definitely go, watch
it, tell me what you think.
And I hope you enjoy it.
JACOB: This is the part of
the show where you tell us
what to watch.
MORIAH: I wanted to share my
song that I wrote for PewdiePie
with YouTube Nation, because
PewdiePie is awesome,
and YouTube is awesome.
[MUSIC - "A Song For PewdiePie"
on MissMoMusic64]
JACOB: I cannot wait to see his
response to this video, Pews,
ball's in your court.
Bro fist!
We want to see you
guys on the show.
Film yourself
talking about a video
you love, and then post it with
the hashtag, YouTube Nation.
Now play us out, Slick Mahony!
[MUSIC - "Rock That -Slick
Mahony" on TurquoiseJeepMusic]