Folks--
MALE SPEAKER: We're zooming.
We're zooming.
FREDDY CORBIN: I love ya.
It's going to be a good thing.
OK, so you can turn it off.
Da, da--
MALE SPEAKER: Hey, you're
going second, right?
FREDDY CORBIN: Da, da.
MALE SPEAKER: The biggest
nerds in the world.
FREDDY CORBIN: OK.
I leave Malibu to my brother.
All the Jesus shit to Eileen.
And everything else
goes to John.
EDDY DEUTSCHE: Last will and
testament right here.
Al, you get everything, baby.
MALE SPEAKER: Right on.
EDDY DEUTSCHE: Everything.
MALE SPEAKER: Igor?
IGOR MORTIS: I want
Eddy's machines.
EDDY DEUTSCHE: And Igor can
have a couple machines.
But you get to pick them.
And Freddy--
FREDDY CORBIN: But you're
going to be dead.
MALE SPEAKER: You can't leave
shit to each other.
MALE SPEAKER: Guy?
GUY ATCHINSON: Amy gets
everything except the tattoo
shit, which I'm giving
to Mad Jack.
MALE SPEAKER: All right.
And Igor?
IGOR MORTIS: I'm taking
it all with me.
EDDY DEUTSCHE: He doesn't
have anything.
That's why!
IGOR MORTIS: Bad omen.
FREDDY CORBIN: Just
don't get nervous.
I know you're going to
jump 9,000 feet.
Just don't get nervous.
MALE SPEAKER: Ahh,
right on the pad.
MALE SPEAKER: Eddy!
Was it fun?
MALE SPEAKER: He doesn't
remember.
He missed most of the jump.
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
MALE SPEAKER: Smiling
all the way down.
FREDDY CORBIN: Go nuts.
You can pull all my videos
off the shelf.
Here's some water.
I need some for work.
Here.
Now he's going to want this.
Go ahead.
It's cheap.
Now this is a cool photo.
This is doing the last
tattoo at Realistic.
That's Howie the Cosmic
Commander.
This would probably be about
June or May of '91.
And you'll recognize those
screens in the tattoo time.
Realistic Studio was
opened up in '74.
I had the honor of working
there in '90 and '91.
And what it was was Ed went over
to Japan after hanging
out with Jerry in Hawaii and
stuff, and when he came back
he wanted to open up, basically,
the United States'
first appointment only non
walk-in tattoo shop.
There was no sign.
You couldn't see it
from the street.
That's where Bob
Roberts worked.
Greg Irons worked there.
Phillip sat in there.
Leo Zulueta worked there.
What happened was, Realistic,
the lease was coming up, and
Eddy wanted to move
to San Francisco.
And we wanted to work together,
but we didn't want
to work in that back
room format.
We wanted a walk-in
tattoo shop.
We, basically, were going to
open up a shop and we were
going to hire Igor Mortis and
Dan Higgs, and that's where
the whole Temple Dude
tattoo came from.
Because we were going to work
a convention, I think in New
Orleans together, but we weren't
going to really be
able to talk about
the shop yet.
But we felt, out of respect, we
should go to Ed first and
ask Ed if he wanted
to own the shop.
And we were driving across the
Bay Bridge he actually brought
it up, so what are you
going to do Fred?
Your lease is coming up.
I been wanting to talk
you about that.
I got this idea.
He drove from the bridge to
Columbus and was like, this is
where I wanted to open up
when I first got back.
And the next morning he
had the place rented.
That's how he operates.
He just gets shit done.
So we opened up Tattoo City on
July 1 of '91, and I worked
there till about '96.
If I were to be really truthful,
it was really
difficult working with Eddy
Deutsche and Ed Hardy, because
I had only been tattooing
a few years.
And Eddy was amazing
from the gate.
And Ed Hardy was the best
tattooer in the world.
Like living in a fishbowl.
We opened up Tattoo City and
people are coming in and just
expecting me to be able to--
I want a back piece of this,
and I want this.
And I wasn't ready to do big
tattoos like that yet.
There were some that
I could do.
I could do a big Jesus head back
piece or a big rock of
ages maybe because they
were simple enough.
But I couldn't do wind bars or
Japanese water back then, and
stuff like that.
I still had to learn how
to do all that stuff.
I did feel a lot of pressure, to
be honest, to be able to do
anything because I worked for
Ed Hardy at Tattoo City.
I think a big dynamic of one of
the reasons that I got into
drugs even was because there
was so much pressure.
I never got into heroin
and stuff because I
had a career going.
Like, I work for Ed Hardy.
I didn't take this
shit lightly.
I'd start popping Valiums
at the end of the day.
And I'll say, it kind of helped
for a while, because
you're working all day and
you're tattooing somebody,
that's a pretty serious thing.
You know what I mean?
It's not like a haircut.
It doesn't grow back.
And I remember the first
time I used to--
this was before cable--
I used to love David
Letterman.
And I'd watch David Letterman
and I remember smoking a joint
and taking a couple Valiums and
feeling that feeling, that
kind of calmness and serenity.
Like, oh, wow.
This feels really good.
And I got into--
when I started getting my ribs
tattooed I started taking some
dilaudids and some
morphine pills.
And my brother, unfortunately at
the time, was getting into
heroin and using heroin.
And there was nobody shooting
up, there was no junkies
hanging around, it was like,
let's just buy a little bit
and smoke it on some foil.
And it seemed at the time, not
innocent, but not harmful.
It didn't seem as harmful
as it really was.
And ironically Ed had given me
a month off because I was
doing so good.
I mean, we had closed Realistic
and opened up Tattoo
City and I was working
my ass off.
He said, Freddy, you've
been doing so good.
You should take a
month off, dude.
And that was the month
I got strung out.
Because I just laid around my
house and covered the windows
and slept for-- would just go
into my room and not come out.
And I would try the 90 meetings
in 90 days thing.
It's just not me.
And then I would go through
periods of just
giving up even trying.
I had gone to Amsterdam and I
was living in the Red Light
District and I was
using a lot.
And some crazy shit went down.
My brother got in
a car accident.
My brother was a paraplegic.
I called Ed and let him know
what was going on and that's
kind of when I got canned at
Tattoo City and stuff.
I wanted to tell Ed that I was
strung out because I really,
really respected him.
But Ed's business.
So I always knew that Ed would
be like, well, Freddy, I love
ya and I appreciate you telling
me but you gotta go.
And I was fine with that.
But I wanted to kind
of go to him--
it sounds silly in
retrospect--
but I wanted to kind of get
clean and then go to Ed and
say here's what's
been going on.
But in the midst of my grandiose
plan of trying to do
this and figure out all this
crazy shit, because it's like
you're getting caught
up in a shit storm.
He basically canned me.
And then, from what my mom tells
me and Eddy and stuff,
that he was really concerned
at first.
It was like, what are
we going to do?
We gotta get him into rehab.
But by the time I was walking
through the gate, he was
yelling at me and screaming at
me and all kinds of shit.
So I think he just got
kind of angry.
Then it was like
all eyes on me.
Around the world.
What's Freddy going to
do kind of shit.
It's just really good gossip.
That's pretty much it.
It's like, I think there's
a couple dynamics.
There's it's great gossip.
There's the hater aspect.
And then there's the concerned
friend aspect of it, too.
There were people that really
loved me that were
concerned about me.
There were a lot of people
that were stoked.
I don't mean stoked to
see me go down, but
like, I had '66 Chevelle.
I was young, I was making
money, I was
working for Ed Hardy.
I was kind of rolling.
JASON MCAFEE: I don't really
know if I think that's the way
people wanted to see
it go for Freddy.
Even though he might say that,
I don't really think so.
I think people love him and
never really want to be like,
yeah, fucking Freddy's
fucked up.
Or Freddy fuckin' blah, blah.
I think that could be
his own little thing
going on with him.
I didn't know about the Tattoo
City thing, and why he got
fired, or the stuff with him and
Ed, or drugs or whatever
had been going on with him.
He was very open about it.
He's a very open person, and was
very like, hey, man, just
want you to know, this is
what's happened and
you might get shit.
And people are always going to
be like, oh, Freddy Corbin
because he's messed
up or whatever.
But he's been through
some bad shit.
People dying, his brother
getting in an accident and
being paralyzed, his brother
dying recently.
Things just with
his whole life.
Like, he's had a pretty
rough run.
And he's come out on top
and been amazing.
There's something about him,
that his soul and his heart is
just so genuine and so real.
And no matter if he was drugs or
not or weed or whatever the
fuck he was doing, there's this
part of him that you just
care about and I love
no matter what.
FREDDY CORBIN: Of course I
wanted to do the right thing,
whatever that was.
So I got off dope.
I stayed clean for a little
while, but not long.
And then I ended up going back
to Amsterdam and kind of just
bailing the whole scene.
I continued to use in Amsterdam
for a while, and
even here in Oakland for a
little bit, and then just
wasn't happy.
It just wasn't working for me.
Just staying well and
just darkness,
just living in darkness.
So my friend Vinny was always
really cool about being really
supportive in a non-judgmental
kind of way, was always there
for me as a friend.
And even my wife Lisa, who was
then my girlfriend, as
stubborn as we both can be,
and as much as we're on
opposite ends of the spectrum
when it comes to things like
religion or going to India or
shit like that, she was always
there for me, too.
So the two of them are really
instrumental in me kind of
getting my shit together.
LISA CORBIN: A lot
of us have gone
through the similar things.
It is helpful to have other
people because they can kind
of call you on your shit.
But there are times when
we were all just
like, what can we do?
At a loss.
And there are times with Freddy
that were very scary.
Knowing Freddy has been a
journey, and sometimes I've
had to hold on with the tightest
ropes I've ever had
to hold on to in
my entire life.
And I go through all that doubt
of, what am I doing?
Am I crazy?
But there was always
something there.
There's always that bond.
There was always that
connection.
And it's just been amazing to
see him pull through that.
There must have been something
deep down that
made him want to live.
And then we have Sonny,
our awesome son.
And he's just sort of taken, I
think, some of that energy and
put it into him and they have
a beautiful relationship.
Makes me jealous sometimes.
FREDDY CORBIN: [HUMMING]
Ready for the dip?
Can you dip?
Oh, that's the sound.
I guess you do the right thing,
good things happened.
Because I was always petrified
of having a kid, because I had
been strung out for
so many years.
So it was just like, I wouldn't
be a good father.
I could never do this or
how would this work?
The two things that petrified me
the most were getting clean
and having a kid.
And I eventually was
able to get clean.
Sonny, my son, has just been the
coolest thing in my life.
Because I think when we were
talking earlier, I said I
could have never imagined having
a kid, and I can't even
imagine what it would be
like to not have him.
And I named him after
Sonny, kind of.
But Sonny was such a notorious
fuck-up, Sonny Tufts, that it
was like, did you name
him after Sonny?
Well, not really.
I really just kind of learned
how much I loved that name and
how endearing it was to me
because of my friend and
because of knowing him so long
and stuff like that.
JASON MCAFEE: I tell
him all the time.
I'm just like, dude, from when I
met you to now, it's insane.
When I met him, he lived three
blocks up in this dark,
shitty, fuckin' depressing
apartment.
it was just this den of, like,
you sat on a couch and you
would melt in it and
almost fall asleep.
I would get there and just be
like, 11:00 in the morning
coming to work, and
I was just--
And just to see where he's come
from to like, getting
married, having a baby, owning
the two successful shops.
His house, his life, he's
changed so, so much.
And definitely, it's Sonny.
Seeing him be a dad
is unbelievable.
I've never seen someone attack
it so strongly and so
passionately and become--
he's a rad dad.
FREDDY CORBIN: Look at you.
There you go.
Do it.
Yes.
Yay!
Yeah.
You conquered.
TIM HENDRICKS: It's hard to tame
a free spirit, and he's
the ultimate free spirit.
So I think this is one way of
doing it organically and
naturally, is having a kid
and having a family.
He's still Freddy.
Nothing changed about him.
I admire people like that.
He's an extremely fun time.
Freddy could have fun
in a cardboard box.
MAX SCHAAF: The weirdest
thing to me is, he
goes to Burning Man.
And he's like, it
was insane, bro.
And I never want to
go to Burning Man.
I just don't have any desire to,
but when Freddy tells you
about it you're like, what?
What?
Oh my god, really?
Because he's just that cool.
FREDDY CORBIN: I feel like
Burning Man prepared me for
India, because at Burning
Man, anything goes.
You could be talking to some
really cool fuckin' people
that are just really down, and
the next thing you know you've
got some crazy dude tripping on
acid who's flailing and not
knowing where the fuck
he is, or whatever,
because there's no rules.
And India is the same way.
India is no rules.
We have this term.
It's like, both and.
It's profound, profane, and
then a little bit more.
India is so intense.
You could see a dead person
in the street.
There's lepers.
There's people begging.
There's poor kids begging,
running around
with no pants on.
There's just a lot of poverty.
A cliche that people say is
that India is the most
beautiful and the most
horrific place that
you'll every go.
And it's true.
So you'll be out boating
and you'll see a
carcass floating by.
A bloated human body
will just--
I've seen a dog with a hand in
it's mouth cruising off like,
I got some food.
It's just bizarre.
First time I was there, I was
like, if I stayed at this one
hotel, I could maybe bring
Lisa and her mom here.
Her mom's really cool.
And I'm just like, why am I
wasting my time trying to turn
them on to something that
I think is really cool?
My wife has no desire
to go to India.
It's too dirty for her.
She won't even go camping.
If there's not a toilet,
she's not interested.
LISA CORBIN: Freddy's spiritual
side is very
separate from our
relationship.
It's not something that we
share or do together.
So his trips to India, or
Burning Man, or Brazil, or the
tea ceremonies, or the parties
that he goes to, like the
alchemy parties.
Freddy, I think, maybe got
opened up to different things,
but I think he's always
been a spiritual.
JASON MCAFEE: His spiritual side
is, all over the place,
in a good way.
I think Freddy believes and
dabbles in a little
bit of all of it.
There's obviously a lot Jesuses
here and a lot of
Christian stuff and
all this stuff.
And he even sometimes will say
that's what he is and what he
does, is he's a Christian.
But he believes so much in
Buddha and all these other
kinds of religions and forms
of religion that I think he
takes pieces from all of it.
He's definitely got a
lot of spirituality.
Wherever it comes from, I
couldn't really pinpoint.
FREDDY CORBIN: I don't feel
bound by any dogma of any
religion whatsoever.
And I consider myself a
Christian because I'm down for
Jesus and I believe in what he
was here for, as well as
Buddha or Martin Luther
King or Gandhi or
anybody of that nature.
I'm just kind of into
positive energy.
And I think we're all God's
fuckin' children.
We're all brothers and sisters
no matter what religious sect
or color or size or
sex or whatever.
Huh, Son?
And don't trust the
government.
LISA CORBIN: I think, actually,
when Freddy's
brother passed away because
of his involvement in his
spirituality, it really helped
them through it.
Because I think that he was in
a place where he was able to
accept it and felt that it was
maybe the universe had
actually let things happen
in a way that was best.
He handled it in a way, I think,
that was the best--
I don't know.
He got through it and I think
he got through it because of
what he believes in.
And it didn't send him over
the edge, because a lot of
those things--
Freddy lives on the edge.
A lot of us have lived
on the edge.
And it's one of those things.
Death can be one of
those things that
might put you there.
FREDDY CORBIN: My brother
was kind of a lone wolf.
I was one of his few friends so
I decided to do his funeral
on the Ganges, just take his
ashes to India and do it
there, do his little
funeral there.
And it's-- they call
it a puja.
So you do a puja for the dead
and then you do a puja for the
people that you love
that are alive.
And so the first day was a lot
of burning, and certain
incense and smoke and stuff.
And then the ones for your
living loved ones, a lot of
flowers, water.
The living day one, I had to
hold this pitcher of water
over the shiva lingam, which is
basically like a penis and
vagina statue.
It represents fertility
and the cycle of life.
I had to pour this huge pitcher
of water over it.
They fill it up and then
I'd have to hold it.
And then they fill
it up again.
And by the third time, I'm
kind of holding my arm.
I came home and I said to Lisa--
because she had been
wanting to get pregnant
for a while.
I came home and I said to Lisa,
I said, well, if you're
ever going to get pregnant,
it's going to happen now,
babe, because I had to hold this
penis water thing over
these flowers.
And I was just kind of
joking about it.
And she said, well, if I get
pregnant, I'll turn Hindu.
She literally said that.
And right after we got married
and got locked into this
house, she turns up pregnant.
And I'm convinced that
definitely helped.
I'm not saying that was
the cause of it.
Obviously, sperm had a
lot to do with it.
But I think stuff like that
helps, and my beliefs.
That intention is a big part
of anything that we do.
Peel it.
All right.
That was cool.
[MUSIC PLAYING]