From the fires of a sun's birth... twin planets
emerged.
Venus... and Earth.
Two roads diverged in our young solar system.
Nature draped one world in the greens and
blues of life.
While enveloping the other in acid clouds...
high heat... and volcanic flows.
Why did Venus take such a disastrous turn?
For as long as we have gazed upon the stars,
they have offered few signs... that somewhere
out there... are worlds as rich and diverse
as our own.
Recently, though, astronomers have found ways
to see into the bright lights of nearby stars.
They've been discovering planets at a rapid
clip... using observatories like NASA's Kepler
space telescope...
A French observatory known as Corot ...
...And an array of ground-based instruments.
The count is approaching 500... and rising.
These alien worlds run the gamut... from great
gas giants many times the size of our Jupiter...
to rocky, charred remnants that burned when
their parent star exploded.
Some have wild elliptical orbits... swinging
far out into space... then diving into scorching
stellar winds.
Still others orbit so close to their parent
stars that their surfaces are likely bathed
in molten rock.
Amid these hostile realms, a few bear tantalizing
hints of water or ice... ingredients needed
to nurture life as we know it.
The race to find other Earths has raised anew
the ancient question... whether, out in the
folds of our galaxy, planets like our own
are abundant... and life commonplace?
Or whether Earth is a rare Garden of Eden
in a barren universe?
With so little direct evidence of these other
worlds to go on, we have only the stories
of planets within our own solar system to
gauge the chances of finding another Earth.
Consider, for example, a world that has long
had the look and feel of a life-bearing planet.
Except for the moon, there's no brighter light
in our night skies than the planet Venus...
known as both the morning and the evening
star.
The ancient Romans named it for their goddess
of beauty and love.
In time, the master painters transformed this
classical symbol into an erotic figure.
It was a scientist, Galileo Galilei, who demystified
planet Venus... charting its phases as it
moved around the sun, drawing it into the
ranks of the other planets.
With a similar size and weight, Venus became
known as Earth's sister planet. But how Earth-like
is it?
The Russian scientist Mikkhail Lomonosov caught
a tantalizing hint in 1761. As Venus passed
in front of the Sun, he witnessed a hair thin
luminescence on its edge.
Venus, he found, has an atmosphere.
Later observations revealed a thick layer
of clouds. Astronomers imagined they were
made of water vapor, like those on Earth.
Did they obscure stormy, wet conditions below?
And did anyone, or anything, live there? The
answer came aboard an unlikely messenger....
an asteroid that crashed into Earth.
That is... according to the classic sci-fi
adventure, The First Spaceship on Venus. A
mysterious computer disk is found among the
rubble.
With
anticipation rising on Earth, an international
crew sets off to find out who sent it... and
why.
Approaching Venus, the astronauts translate
the contents of the disk. The news is not
good.
In a desperate attempt to prevent an interplanetary
war... and save their home planet... the crew
embarks on a dangerous mission.
They descend to the planet's dark surface
to confront the adversaries.
What they find is a treacherous, toxic world.
No wonder the Venusians want to switch planets.
It turns out that the aliens had already been
destroyed... by their own machines.
The new rulers of Venus are not in the mood
for visitors.
They repel the Earthlings with anti-gravity
technology.
Unfortunately, two astronauts are left behind
to perish.
So what if the aliens found a way to come
to Earth?
Think Zontar, the thing from Venus.
It was now time to get serious about exploring
our sister planet.
BREAK
NASA sent Mariner 2 to Venus in 1962... in
the first-ever close planetary encounter.
Its instruments showed that Venus is nothing
at all like Earth. Rather, it's extremely
hot, with an atmosphere made up mostly of
carbon dioxide.
The data showed that Venus rotates very slowly...
only once every 243 Earth days... and it goes
in the opposite direction.
American and Soviet scientists found out just
how strange Venus is when they sent a series
of landers down to take direct readings.
Surface temperatures are almost 900 degrees
Fahrenheit, hot enough to melt lead, with
the air pressure 90 times higher than at sea
level on Earth.
The air is so thick that it's not a gas, but
a "supercritical fluid." Liquid CO2.
On our planet, the only naturally occurring
source is in the high-temperature, high-pressure
environments of undersea volcanoes. It comes
in handy for extracting caffeine from coffee
beans... or dry cleaning our clothes.
You just wouldn't want to have to breathe
it.
The
Soviet Venera landers sent back pictures showing
that Venus is a vast garden of rock, with
no water in sight.
In fact, if you were to smooth out the surface
of Venus, all the water in the atmosphere
would be just 3 centimeters deep.
Compare that to Earth... where the oceans
would form a layer 3 kilometers deep.
If you could land on Venus, you'd be treated
to tranquil vistas and sunset skies, painted
in orange hues.
The winds are light, only a few miles per
hour... but the air is so thick that a breeze
would knock you over.
Look up and you'd see fast-moving clouds...
streaking around the planet at 300 kilometers
per hour. These clouds form a dense high-altitude
layer, from 45 to 66 kilometers above the
surface.
The clouds are so dense and reflective that
Venus absorbs much less solar energy than
Earth, even though it's 30% closer to the
Sun.
These clouds curve around into a pair of immense
planetary hurricanes as the air spirals down
into the cooler polar regions.
They are made up mostly of sulfuric acid droplets...
possibly a bi-product of sulfur dioxide emitted
by volcanoes.
Along the equator, they rise in powerful storms,
unleashing bolts of lightning.
Just like earth, these storms produce rain...
only it's acid rain that evaporates before
it hits the ground.
At higher elevations, a fine mist forms...
not of water but of the rare metal tellurium...
and iron pyrites... known as fool's gold.
It can form a metallic frost... like snowflakes
in hell.
Still, the mountains of Venus offer no relief
from the heat. They are part of what makes
Venus so extreme.
Scientists have identified around 1700 major
volcanic centers on Venus ranging from lava
domes... and strange features called arachnoids
or coronae... to giant volcanic summits.
The planet is peppered with volcanoes, perhaps
in the millions, distributed randomly on its
surface. Venus is run through with huge cuts
thousands of kilometers long that may well
be lava channels.
Our sister planet is a volcanic paradise,
in a solar system shaped by volcanism.
The largest mountain on Earth, Hawaii's Mauna
Kea volcano, measures 32,000 feet from sea
floor to summit.
Rising almost three times higher is the mother
of all volcanoes: Olympus Mons on Mars.
Jupiter's moon Io... is bleeding lava. It's
produced deep underground by the friction
of rock on rock, caused by the gravitational
pull of its mother planet.
Then there's Neptune's moon Triton... with
crystals of nitrogen ice shooting some 10
kilometers above the surface.
Saturn's moon Titan... with frozen liquid
methane and ammonia oozing into lakes and
swamps.
On our planet, volcanoes commonly form at
the margins of continents and oceans, where
steep mountainsides fall off into deep undersea
trenches. Here, the vast slabs of rock that
underlie the oceans push beneath those that
bear the continents.
Deep underground, friction between these plates
can melt vast amounts of rock.
Magma mixes with water... and the rising pressure
forces it up... in explosive eruptions.
On Earth, volcanoes can blast into the upper
atmosphere, in a hail of ash, rock, dust,
and lava.
On Venus, the scene is very different. In
the high-density atmosphere, volcanoes are
more likely to ooze and splatter... sending
rivers of lava flowing down onto the lowlands.
They resemble volcanoes that form at hot spots
like the Hawaiian islands. There, plumes of
magma rise up from deep within the earth,
releasing the pressure in a stream of eruptions.
To see a typical large volcano on Venus, go
to Sappas Mons... at 400 kilometers across
and 1.5 kilometers high.
The mountain was likely built through eruptions
at its summit. But as magma reached up from
below, it began to drain out through subsurface
tubes or cracks that formed a web of channels
leading onto the surrounding terrain.
Is Venus, like Earth, still volcanically active?
Finding the answer is a major goal of the
Venus Express mission, launched in 2005 by
the European Space Agency. Armed with a new
generation of high-tech sensors, it peered
through the clouds.
Recording the infrared light given off by
several large mountains, it found that the
summits are brighter than the surrounding
basins. That's probably because they had not
been subject to as much weathering in this
corrosive environment.
This means that they would have erupted sometime
within the last few hundred thousand years.
If these volcanoes are active now, it's because
they are part of a deeper process that shapes
our planet as well.
On Earth, the release of heat from radioactive
decay deep in its mantle is what drives the
motion of oceanic and continental plates.
This process is dependent on erosion and other
processes associated with water.
With no water on Venus, the planet's internal
heat builds to extreme levels, then escapes
in outbreaks of volcanism that may be global
in scope.
That may explain why fewer than a thousand
impact craters have been found on Venus. Anything
older than about 500 million years has literally
been paved over.
So why did Venus diverge so radically from
Earth when it was born in same solar system
and under similar circumstances?
BREAK
There is growing evidence, still circumstantial,
that Venus may in fact have had a wetter,
more Earth-like past.
One of the most startling findings of the
early Venus missions was the presence of deuterium,
a form of hydrogen, in Venus' upper atmosphere.
It forms when ultraviolet sunlight breaks
apart water molecules.
Additional evidence recently came to light.
Venus Express trained its infrared sensors
on the planet's night side... to look at how
the terrain emits the energy captured in the
heat of the day.
This picture is a composite of over a thousand
individual images of Venus' southern hemisphere.
Higher elevation areas, shown in blue, emit
less heat than the surrounding basins.
That supports a hypothesis that these areas
are made not of lava, but of granite.
On Earth, granite forms in volcanoes when
magma mixes with water. If there's granite
on Venus, then there may well have been water.
If Earth and Venus emerged together as twin
blue marbles... then at some point, the two
worlds parted company.
Earth developed ways to moderate its climate,
in part by removing carbon dioxide, a greenhouse
gas, from its atmosphere.
Plants, for one, absorb CO2 and release oxygen
in photosynthesis. One square kilometer of
tropical jungle, for example, can take in
several hundred tons of co2 in just a year.
That's nothing compared to the oceans. In
a year's time, according to one recent study,
just one square kilometer of ocean can absorb
41 million tons of CO2.
Earth takes in its own share of CO2. When
rainfall interacts with rocks, a chemical
reaction known as "weathering" converts atmospheric
CO2 to carbonate compounds. Runoff from the
land washes it into rivers and the seas...
where they settle into ocean sediments.
To understand how much this can influence
the climate, look back into Earth's history.
The formation of the Himalayan Mountains and
the Tibetan Plateau around 50 million years
ago exposed massive amounts of rock... and
led to an increase in rainfall.
Over time, so much CO2 was removed from the
atmosphere through weathering that it sent
Earth into a period of global cooling that
has lasted to this day.
With little water and no oceans, Venus has
no good way to remove CO2 from its atmosphere.
Instead, with volcanic eruptions adding more
and more CO2 to the atmosphere, it has trapped
more and more of the sun's heat in a runaway
greenhouse effect.
Venus is so hot that liquid water simply cannot
survive on the surface.
Nor, it now seems, can it last in the upper
atmosphere.
As our solar system moves around the galaxy,
it is lashed by a fierce wind of charged particles.
The sun blocks this galactic wind with a powerful
solar wind.
It reaches its peak in the wake of great looping
eruptions on the surface of the Sun, called
coronal mass ejections.
Fortunately, Earth has its own line of defense.
Plumes of hot magma rise and fall in Earth's
core as it spins, generating a magnetic field
that extends far out into space.
It acts as a shield, deflecting the solar
wind and causing it to flow past.
It's this protective bubble that Venus lacks.
Venus Express found that these solar winds
are steadily stripping off lighter molecules
of hydrogen and oxygen. They escape the planet
on the night side... then ride solar breezes
on out into space.
All this may be due to Venus' size... 80%
that of Earth. This prevents the formation
of a solid iron core... and with it the rising
and falling plumes that generate a strong
magnetic field.
There may be another reason too... according
to a theory about the planet's early years.
A young planet Venus encountered one or more
planet-sized objects... in violent collisions.
The force of these impacts slowed its rotation
to a crawl... and reversed it... reducing
the chances that a magnetic field could take
hold.
This does not mean that Venus was Earth-like.
Another theory holds that the planet's primordial
oceans were actually held as vapor in its
atmosphere... and replenished by icy comets
in the early years of the solar system.
So what can we glean from the evolution of
planet Venus?
For one thing, as we continue to scan the
cosmic horizons for worlds that may resemble
our own, the story of Venus will stand as
a stark reminder.
It takes more than just the right size, composition,
and distance from the parent star... for a
planet to become truly Earth-like.
No matter how promising a planet may be, there
are myriad forces out there that can radically
alter its course.
For here was a world... Venus... poised perhaps
on the brink of a glorious future.
But bad luck passed its way. Now, we can only
imagine... what might have become of Earth's
sister planet?