LUIS CEDENO: The fact of the
matter is that Chavez has
never spoken about crime
and violence.
To not recognize that crime and
violence is the number one
issue is overlooking a huge
reality of what Venezuelan
people are living today.
Now apparently, at last, the
president has said that crime
is a problem--
after 12, 13 years--
but this time of ours,
too little too late.
RYAN DUFFY: With the government
not addressing the
crime and violence issue until
very recently, local news
reporters have taken
it upon themselves
to educate the public.
Right now we're on our way to
meet Davis Ramirez who's the
local crime reporter
for El Universal.
We're going to tag
along with him on
his beat around Caracas.
DAVIS RAMIREZ MIRANDA:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
RYAN DUFFY: During our
interview, Davis got a call
about a body that was found
in downtown Caracas bound,
tortured, and decomposing.
We sped off to the scene.
DAVIS RAMIREZ MIRANDA:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
RYAN DUFFY: In 2008, the year
that crime became the number
one public issue, the government
stopped releasing
official figures
to the public.
Now reporters like Davis are
forced to construct these
numbers on their own.
[?
CONSUELO DE DUARTE:
[SPEAKING SPANISH] ?]
DAVIS RAMIREZ MIRANDA:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
RYAN DUFFY: After a day of
chasing bodies, we hit another
regular stop on Davis's beat,
Caracas' only morgue.
And the only place to get an
accurate count of the victims.
DAVIS RAMIREZ MIRANDA:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
RYAN DUFFY: So are this many
journalists here every day?
DAVIS RAMIREZ MIRANDA:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
RYAN DUFFY: Are there official
government channels that are
here as well, or is it all
opposition coverage?
DAVIS RAMIREZ MIRANDA:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
RYAN DUFFY: There's kind of this
weird duality to this.
Where on one hand it feels
really uncomfortable and
really predatory, and you're
just standing around waiting
on something terrible
to happen.
On the other hand, it's
information service.
There's no other way to find out
these statistics and the
actual homicide numbers because
the government doesn't
release them.
So there really is no other way
to get this information
than to be here waiting
for people to die.