JOANNA FUERTES-KNIGHT:
The Royals!
Rulers of this mighty kingdom.
Now, the queen may be having a
glorious nationwide party for
her Diamond Jubilee, but it's
going to be nowhere near as
good as my patriotic picnic.
Harry!
MALE SPEAKER: Jubilee picnic.
JOANNA FUERTES-KNIGHT: So today
for my royal hamper, I'm
going to be making a pink
lemonade Victoria sponge, some
cava-jam with scones, and then
some dog food sausage rolls
for the corgis.
Arf, arf, arf.
MALE SPEAKER: Pink
lemonade cake.
JOANNA FUERTES-KNIGHT: So I've
decided to bring the Victoria
sponge up-to-date and make
a pink lemonade cake.
It's like any other cake, you're
going to start with
breaking some eggs.
Harry's my favorite, because I
imagine if it wasn't a royal
he'd just be daggering
some girl at Oceana,
knocking back Reefs.
I kind of feel sorry for the
queen, because her life is
just an endless stream of being
forced to go to public
events, looking at things.
When I bet all she really
wants to do
is hang out at Windsor.
Walking around with a rifle,
with a Rothman fag hanging out
of her mouth and just finding
wild rabbits to
shoot in the face.
If I were the queen, I would
just get a hologram like
Tupac, and send it out to
do all the shitty work.
Make sure it's whisked
thoroughly.
And then you're going to
put it in the two tins.
So it's one in the pink
and two in the tins.
MALE SPEAKER: Cava-jam scones.
JOANNA FUERTES-KNIGHT: So the
jam is really simple.
It's just blueberries,
sugar, and some cava.
And you're going to dump
that all in a pan.
It's really funny.
I guess from the outside looking
in, as a nation we
must look really patriotic.
Because whenever there's any
kind of royal bank holiday,
everyone has a party and
gets shit-faced.
It's almost like a nationwide
Nottinghill
carnival for white people.
MALE SPEAKER: Dog
sausage rolls.
JOANNA FUERTES-KNIGHT: Now, I
don't want to leave out the
best bit of the royal family,
and that's the Queen's corgis.
So I'm going to make them some
dog food sausage rolls.
So the first step is to roll
out some puff pastry.
I couldn't be fucked
to make my own.
You have to be an idiot with too
much time on their hands
to make your own puff pastry.
I like corgis.
Because you know when you look
at something really cute and
you want to crush it?
Just things that are already
pudgy with big eyes, you want
to squeeze it to death.
They're so cute, I want
to crush their skulls.
Oh, fuck it.
Oh, I got it on my crotch.
And now to roll them up
into roll shapes.
You're going to pop
these in the oven.
They go all puffed
up and golden.
MALE SPEAKER: Cake layers.
JOANNA FUERTES-KNIGHT: So I've
used most of the homemade
cava-jam already in my scones.
I'm just going to put
it in the filling
of my lemonade cake.
I'd rather have a chemical
rainbow in my mouth than bite
into a bean burger that
takes like a coaster.
That's what science is for,
making things better.
I'm really sick of all these
pretentious foodies.
Good food doesn't need fancy
ingredients to taste delicious.
There you go.
It's a cake fit for a queen.
Who's a good corgi, hm?
Good corgi.
Aw!