-You're incredibly
irresponsible.
-You don't listen.
-You're crazy.
You're selfish.
-You're not the only
person, Charles.
CHARLES SWAN III: I thought
it was different with her.
But then, poof.
-I don't want to be
with you anymore.
CHARLES SWAN III: I
can't concentrate.
I think of her every minute.
KIRBY STAR: Whoa, whoa.
Zing, rewind.
What did you do?
CHARLES SWAN III: She said she
didn't want to be in the
drawer with all the
other girls.
KIRBY STAR: Well, obviously
I totally agree with that.
I'm lost.
I have no idea what we're
talking about.
CHARLES SWAN III:
Look at that.
Howdy, ladies.
[INDIAN CALLS]
CHARLES SWAN III: Go,
go, go, go, go.
KIRBY STAR: Ah!
CHARLES SWAN III: You hit?
KIRBY STAR: No, but I think I
might have pulled a muscle.
SAUL: Are you a man?
CHARLES SWAN III:
Of course am.
SAUL: Show me.
CHARLES SWAN III: Ivana,
can't we just talk?
[GROANING]
I'm hit.
KIRBY STAR: Savages.
MARNIE: I know that you're
thinking something terrible.
KIRBY STAR: I've got a whole
theory about that.
It's on my record.
There is an organizational
called the SSBB, the Secret
Society of Ball-Busters.
SAUL: Get in here now.
-Fire.
CHARLES SWAN III: What
the hell was that?
SAUL: That was pretty close.
Who wants popcorn?
CHARLES SWAN III: I don't think
I have the ability to
fall in love again.
-You're nuts.
CHARLES SWAN III: I know I am.
I've been dreaming about
you my whole life.
KIRBY STAR: You've heard about
the Battle of the Sexes.
This is it.
CHARLES SWAN III: So there's
hope for me?
SAUL: There's always hope.
You got any whiskey?
KIRBY STAR: Ah.
SAUL: All right, this,
this is gonna hurt.
KIRBY STAR: Ow.
[SCREAMING]
SAUL: Oh, god.
Oh.