PAUL POLANSKY: No country
wants them.
They're the people that
nobody wants.
And of course, the Albanians
fought tooth and nail not to
let them come back to their
original neighborhood.
They didn't want Gypsies back
in their community.
And this is the bottom
line in Kosovo.
THOMAS MORTON: We are on our way
to a refugee camp set up
by the UN in 1999 for the
Gypsy community here.
And we've heard terrible things
about the conditions of
the camp and health of the
people who are there.
S we're just going to
go and check it out.
In simplest terms, the conflict
in Kosovo is between
the Serbian north and
the Albanian south.
But it's not that simple.
It's not simple at all.
There's Serbian enclaves in the
south, Albanian pockets in
the north, something called
Illyrians kind of in the
middle, and like the rest of
Europe, Gypsies pretty much
everywhere.
The Gypsies, or Roma, are a
nomadic people who have been
roaming around Europe since
the Roman times.
They're in every major country
in Europe and are heavily
discriminated against everywhere
they live.
Western Europeans, even
supposedly tolerant Dutch
types, accuse Gypsies of being
thieving, lying, welfare
cheats, and generally a lot
less charming than their
depiction in children's cartoons
or that Cher song.
But while in most of Europe,
Gypsy mistreatment starts and
ends with making fun of them and
not hiring them for jobs,
in Kosovo, their treatment is
a million times harsher.
To help solve the problem of
the Gypsy refugees, the UN
invited Paul Polansky, an
American Gypsy expert, to come
to Kosovo and help them
set up camps.
PAUL POLANSKY: The EC
Commissioner for Human Rights
issued a written report saying
that this was the worst human
rights violation in Europe
in the past decade.
THOMAS MORTON: During the 1999
war in Kosovo, as Albanian and
Serbian forces wailed on each
other, NATO began a bombing
campaign in support of the
Albanians, displacing hundreds
of thousands of people,
including most of
the region's Gypsies.
PAUL POLANSKY: Well, I came
to Kosovo in 1999--
as almost every Western
journalist--
pro-Albanian.
We'd read in the "New York
Times" and heard in the media
that the Albanians were
being ethnically
cleansed by the Serbs.
And that's true.
But there was another
side of the coin.
And I put it down to the abused
becoming the abuser.
The Albanians had suffered
under the Serbs for many
generations, and now they
have become the abusers.
The UN opened a few
IDP camps--
internally displaced people
camps-- and so they needed an
expert to advise them.
And that's what they brought
me to Kosovo to do.
SKENDER GUSANI:
[SPEAKING SERBIAN]
THOMAS MORTON: It's obviously
depressing in here.
And it's like an atrocity for
people in modern Europe or
anywhere to live like this.
But everybody's super
house-proud.
They've taken care
of this place.
It doesn't smell.
It's clean--
as much as it can be.
Everybody's house is nice.
Everybody's house is
decorated great.
Even the graffiti's
pretty well-done.
SKENDER GUSANI:
[SPEAKING SERBIAN]
THOMAS MORTON: On top of
everything-- the cramped
conditions, the hole in the
roof, never mind the fact that
if any of the residents
step outside the
camp, they risk a beatdown--
every single child
inside the camp
has severe lead poisoning.
PAUL POLANSKY: There were about
1,800 tents built on the
tailing stands of the mines.
And the pollution from the
smelter drifted right over
their camp.
Their blood samples were sent
to a lab in Belgium.
And Belgium said, please
retake the test.
There's no such levels in
medical literature.
And so the tests are retaken and
found that these children
had the highest lead levels
in medical literature.
And so, the UN medical team
said, Doctor Kouchner, you
must evacuate these camps.
Well, he didn't.
And so that's where I broke my
relationship with the UN.
We still have 40 families
in a toxic wasteland.
And the other 100 were only
moved off in January and
December of this past year.
In 11 years, more than 100 Roma,
mainly children, died in
these camps on this
toxic wasteland.
SKENDER GUSANI:
[SPEAKING SERBIAN]
THOMAS MORTON: Gusani's camp is
actually the second one the
UN set up in the area.
The original camp, the one built
over an industrial waste
site which caused all the
lead poisoning, is
actually still open.
Conditions there are obviously
worse than what we saw in
Leposavic, and the effects of
the lead poisoning are even
more drastic.
IVA PROLIC: [SPEAKING SERBIAN]
THOMAS MORTON:
[SPEAKING SERBIAN]
FERUZ JAHIROVIC:
FLANZA JAHIROVIC:
[SPEAKING SERBIAN]
FERUZ JAHIROVIC:
FLANZA JAHIROVIC:
[SPEAKING SERBIAN]
THOMAS MORTON: Are these from--
OK.
IVA PROLIC: It's her lead
poisoning results.
THOMAS MORTON: OK.
64.
IVA PROLIC: [SPEAKING SERBIAN]
PAUL POLANSKY: Every single kid
that has been moved off
this toxic wasteland has
a lead level between 15
micrograms per deciliter and 45
micrograms per deciliter.
Brain damage starts at 10
Every kid is born with
irreversible brain damage.
And yet, they're telling us
there's no medical treatment.
IVA PROLIC: Under is the therapy
that she's been into.
THOMAS MORTON: When they stopped
giving treatment, did
they say why?
FERUZ JAHIROVIC:
[SPEAKING SERBIAN]
THOMAS MORTON: Have any local or
international organizations
offered you medical help?
FERUZ JAHIROVIC:
[SPEAKING SERBIAN]
IVA PROLIC: [SPEAKING SERBIAN]
PAUL POLANSKY: You have to
wonder why they put the Gypsy
camp in a place that was
first, highly polluted,
second, surrounded by
Albanian villages.
Then they withdrew security.
So you have to wonder, did they
want us wiped out so they
wouldn't have to handle a Gypsy
problem in the future?
THOMAS MORTON: As of making
this, it's been 12 years since
the end of the war in Kosovo.
Both temporary refugee camps
are still packed.
And what talk there was about
helping families move back
home has trickled
to a whisper.
The whole deal underscores the
fact that, for all its
rhetoric, the UN's not primarily
a humanitarian
organization, but
a political one.
All this raises the question
of whether they're
intervention in these cases
actually does more good than
it does harm.
PAUL POLANSKY: We didn't have
AIDS in Kosovo until UN police
brought it from Africa.
THOMAS MORTON: Jesus.
PAUL POLANSKY: We didn't have
brothels and houses of
prostitution until UN police
made loans and investments in
Kosovo to start the drug trade
and the prostitution trade.
They're not answerable to
anybody, and that's how these
kind of things can happen.
They have diplomatic immunity.
So this is our new crusade, is
to try and do draw awareness
that they're refusing to
medically treat these kids.
Now, if it was their
kids, they would
find a medical treatment.
THOMAS MORTON: Kids.
[SERBIAN].
Keeping up.
This is kind of like the scene
in "The Goonies" where Troy
grabs Brent's hand.
But I think the roles are
a little reversed.
[SERBIAN].