if you're emotionally attached to something,
it means you're subjective. There are people
that nail pieces of wood together, then they
kiss it, before that, they don't kiss it.
Till you nail it so it looks like a cross,
then you kiss it. You know what I mean? So,
what was the day before it was a cross? 2
pieces of wood, or some copper that wasn't
cast in a form of a cross. And a cross is
a crucifix which was long before people wore
it, it was to crucify people, so it was a
symbolic, depending on what culture you come
from. That's why I can't accept anything except
the sciences - the shape of an airplane wing
is designed for a certain lift. The shape
of the plane is designed for certain conditions.
So, you can't - when I say you can't exceed
your environment, that means you can't exceed
what you've been exposed to. You can't, if
somebody gave you a brand new microscope,
and you said the objective lenses are insufficient.
If you're a cannibal, you know what I mean?
If you give a cannibal a watch. He doesn't
look at it and say, "the gears are not precise,
they're 10,000th of an inch off" - he can't
say that. That's what I mean by a person can't
exceed their environment. If you got in an
airplane if you're able to, you know, 2000
years from now, a guy might look at our plane
and say "I'll never get into that crate."
Our airplanes would come through as a crate,
or something else. But certainly, if you're
born 2000 years from now, you couldn't have
same values and survive. The nation that can't
exceed it's own environment will be surpassed.
Do you know what that means? Another country
will surpass us. If China can't get passed
where they're at, if they stop and just take
in manufacturing and don't go into automation
and modification, they will remain. There
are many nations out there that are so primitive
they do things the way they did a thousand
years ago, and that's up the Amazon river.
The natives build rafts the same way they
did a thousand years ago, no change. They
bond a bundle of read together, tie it all
together, cause that's all they ever see,
they never leave the area. So if you say "they're
stupid" - no they're not, they live in a fixed
environment, where things are fairly uniform
and not enough change. They don't have visitors
from other tribes that bring them other things,
otherwise they might be brought up to hate
other tribes or they might be brought up to
trade. The nations that trade undergo change,
cause they meet people that are different,
and they get things that are different. No
nation all developed a vase. If a nation developed
a vase and you're nation didn't, and they
show you how they carry water, orange juice
around, you don't have any means of doing
it except this way, so you undergo change.
The more nations that meet and share ideas,
not just meet, if they share ideas they undergo
modification. But if my people undergo too
much modification, I can't control them, so
I put a fence around my country and keep out
forgein ideologies. Or if books that come
into my country that change people, so I can't
control them, I forbid pornography or whatever
it is I forbid. Am I right, am I wrong? All
nations wish to survive, they can't if people
read different kinds of books, different kinds
of characters, different kinds of social systems,
you can't control your people that way. So
you say "I believe in democracy" nobody believes
in democracy, they believe in what they've
been conditioned to believe in. They can't
believe in democracy otherwise they go hear
communism, socialism, free love and all, they'd
say "I don't know enough about them to make
up my mind which is right" they'd speak like
that - "I don't know enough about it." Do
you understand what I'm saying? I'm upsetting
the apple cart, so that there are no values
except the values that preserve nature man
and his relationship to his fellow man and
nature. This is the only laws I know of, well
if you don't care of the forest, we let them
burn and die, we will suffer. If we polute
the oceans, we will suffer, those are things
I accept. I don't know any other system. Will
they do that in the future? I think they'll
control things in the future, weather, hurricanes,
earthquakes, everything. Man will learn to
control things, in his behalf, not - the other
organisms that he keeps alive would be supportive
to that culture, do you understand that? That's
why it'd be very difficult to deal with people
who came from another planet, with a different
gavitational field, different lighting systems,
if they develop - they don't have to look
like us, whatever they develop they'd be reflecting
their culture. So a guy says, I'd like to
share ideas with you, well only if they lived
here and they had all kinds of methods of
evaluation. But they wouldn't want to associate
with us because we're too limitted. If they've
been around longer. So, I can't say that Fresco
tells the truth, I can only say that Fresco's
world is based upon survey, related to man
and his relationship to the environment. That's
what I mean by mechanistic. Cause I asked
once, a writer of a scientific book, "you
think man is a machine?" he says "that's the
old mechanistic point of view that man is
a machine." He didn't say "what do you mean
by machine?" There was no semantics at the
time, you know what I mean? To know what a
man is talking about. By machine I mean that
the eyes can not move to that position unless
there's a muscle that pulls it there, unless
there's a mechanism in the brain, or a bright
light cause the eye to look at it. So I want
to make little dolls, with little magnets
in their heads, you don't see, if I hold a
magnet there, the eyes will focus on it, if
I move it, but not really. Normal people would
think gee the machine is looking at where
ever you hold that. I can simulate that. You
can make a machine to have facial expressions
in sympathy. If you say "I bought a new car
and I lost it, i forgot to put the brakes
on, it went off a" - the machines eyebrows
change - say "my god, I'm sorry to hear that"
- but it won't feel anything. It'll react
as though it felt something. A machine can't
feel. Bad or good about you, it can only react
to the way it's circuits are built. Do you
understand that? That's why a machine will
never say I'm going to take over, cause it
doesn't have ambition. It doesn't say "your
wife is prettier than mine", or "that machine
looks nicer than the other machine" it has
no such reaction, nor can it be given that.
No matter how you circuit a machine it can
say that, "that machine is rusting, and it's
going to disintegrate" and it can even cry,
but it won't feel anything. It's like a movie
of an actor doing, and you know that he didn't
lose his wife, and he didn't get shot, although
he got shot in the movie, the movie can't
feel, it can simulate feeling and that's why
a person says, "he's a good actor" meaning
he can get you to cry or she can get you to
cry. Y'say "they're good actors," and sometimes
people use that in marrying a rich man, a
girl might say "you're so wonderful, I love
you" and the rich man feels flattered and
he marries her, then she spends a lot of money
on a lot of things. That's simulating love.
Do you know what I mean? A prostitute that
says "you're a lousy lay" after the day is
over, you won't come back. She says "I really
enjoyed that sexual" - you know, after all
there are people that simulate good and bad,
right and wrong. Knowing the difference is
difficult, if they're good at it. A salesman
who sells you something, simulates being your
friend "let me advise you that the Ford car
is better built than any other car today,
believe me, I'm doing you a favor" is he a
car salesman? Or a fireman? You know, what
is he? If he's a salesman and a church goer,
that believes in god, he'll say "I say a chevy's
best if you live in rough terrain, or a jeap'd
be better than a chevy" you know what I mean?
That's an honest guy. He says "that's what
I know about cars" but a person can't work
for general motors and say "get yourself an
Italian car" I bought a Totra a Czechoslovakian
car, you know the Totra? I bought it and a
mechanic said "I'm not gunna work on your
car, it's from a communist country" he said
that to me. I said "is there a communist shit?
Or a Greek shit? Or a Greek pain? Or a communist
pain?" there's no such thing as communist
science or Czechoslovakian science, there's
only science and they call people scientists
that are not generalists, that are in one
field. He's an optical scientist. He knows
how to grind lenses. But he's not a scientist.
To me a scientist's one who's interested in
everything, has loyality to methodology. That
means, if a Greek comes up with a cure for
cancer you honor him. If a Japenese scientist
comes up with a cure for cancer, you honor
him. You honor any human being worthy of honor.
but you don't honor only your own kind. He
was an american, that's what I like about
it. Patriotism pulls a shield up infront of
us so we can't see things as they are. We
can't even hear the differences of nations.
We get mad at them. If they don't uphold american
values, or our concepts of freedom and democracy,
we get mad at people and that's what they
want you to do. They want you to have loyality
to what they teach. But if you have loyality
to methodology, you get rid of a fountain
pen, if it leaks and you buy a ballpoint pen,
because no matter where it was invented if
it works better than the other pen, you use
it. If Filipinos come up with a new type of
eye glass, that gives you better vision, you
use it. You honor them, because you don't
- "gee I hope a Greek did it, 'cause I'm
greek." You blind yourself. You understand?
I don't like traditional Jews, or traditional
Catholics, or traditional Americans, you understand?
Or any traditional group. But not because
they're Filipinos, because of their values,
and the values they pick up. So if you discriminate
- "I don't wanna live nextdoor to a clansman,
because he's - let's go out and beatup a Jew
or a nigger or a Filipino, or any damn foreigner"
I don't find that fulfilling, I find that
to be a limitted viewpoint. Racial prejudice
is like patriotism toward a certain race.
"I'm a Greek and I'm proud of it" once you
do that, you damage a person. Say "I'm a Greek,
and I like certain Greeks, and Filipinos,
and certain blacks, and certain Italians"
- if you meet Italian gangsters you say "Italians
are gangsters" that's when you're projecting,
one set of values into all Italians. Anyway,
that ought to give you some perspective of
the world you live in.