CARL AZUZ, CNN ANCHOR: Jumping right in today
with something that hasn`t happened in nearly
600 years: the pope is resigning. Pope Benedict
XVI made the announcement yesterday. He said
the reason is his "advanced age". He`ll turn
86 in April. He will officially resign at
the end of this month. There are three parts
of the story we want to look at. First, popes
in general. The title comes from the Latin
word for father, and the tradition goes back
nearly 2,000 years. In that time, there have
been 265 popes. Christianity is the world`s
largest religion. Roman Catholics are the
largest group of Christians, and the pope
is the head of the Roman Catholic Church.
So, the person who holds this title, is a
major religious leader. He is also a world
leader. The pope is the head of state for
Vatican City, the world`s smallest country.
Second, who is this pope? Who is Benedict
XVI? His birth name is Joseph Ratzinger. When
someone is elected a new pope, he traditionally
chooses a new name. Cardinal Ratzinger picked
Benedict. He was born in Germany in 1927,
became a priest in 1951, was made a cardinal
in 1977, and in 2005 he was elected pope.
He`ll stop being pope in February, 28th, at
8 p.m. local time in Rome.
So, what happens next? The college of cardinals,
leaders in the Catholic Church will get together
for something called a conclave -- that`s
where they all elect a new pope. They each
cast ballots, and if someone gets two thirds
of the vote, plus one more that person becomes
the new pope. If no one gets that many votes
the first time, then the cardinals vote again.
A spokesman from the Vatican said the elections
would probably be sometime in March. He expected
there to be a new pope by Easter.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
TOM FOREMAN, CNN CORRESPONDENT: It`s a report
card and it`s a prognostication. It is the
president saying, this is what I would like
to do in the coming year.
The State of the Union is essentially a homework
assignment from the framers of the Constitution
to every president who`s lived ever since.
The Constitution tells them that they periodically
must tell Congress how the country is doing.
If a president wants to lean hard to one side
or hard to the other side, then you might
see more political purpose in the State of
the Union, although often it`s just a general
sense of let`s move this direction.
The whole thing is a huge pageant. The president
comes walking in, escorted by members of the
House and Senate, the Sergeant of Arms announces
him and everybody stands, and cheers. And
there`s quite a crowd there. Everyone has
assigned seating, right behind the president
you will find the speaker of the U.S. House
of Representatives, and the President of the
Senate, which will be the vice president of
the United States, and then the two parties
generally, generally stay on their side of
the isle, although recently they started sitting
with each other to suggest that they can get
along a little bit better than most of us
think. You typically have the Supreme Court
there, the joint chiefs of staff. They are
representing the military, and the First Lady
will also be there, usually with some sort
of special guest, in recent years. That will
illustrate some point the president is making.
One of the coolest parts of the presidential
address is always the missing cabinet member
and fearing out who it`s going to be. One
member of the cabinet always has to be somewhere
else, in case something terrible happened,
so presumably, you could have the secretary
of agriculture sitting somewhere thinking
about hog futures, and suddenly he is the
president of the United States, which would
be a huge shock to him.
Since the 1960s, the opposition has also issued
a response. That is someone selected by the
opposing party to stand up and refute what
the president said or say, perhaps, we have
different ideas about how the government should
be conducting itself and where we should be
going in the coming year.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: The State of the Union speech is tonight.
Special coverage starts on CNN at 7 p.m. Eastern,
the president speech will start at 9. And
the Republican response will be after he finishes.
Before we hear what the president has to say,
we`d like to hear what you would like him
to say. Tell us on our blog today at cnnstudentnews.com
Our next, we want you to check out the storm
chaser video we shot Sunday in Hattiesburg,
Mississippi. The state was hit by several
storms, and look at this tornado. Part of
the severe weather. The storm chasers pull
up to the area that the tornado just ripped
across. You can actually see some of the damage
that it had just left behind. The Hattiesburg
mayor said one good thing is that this twister
hit on a Sunday, which meant most of the buildings
that were damaged were empty. We`ve got a
video that explains how tornadoes form, where
they are most likely to show up. You could
check that out in the resources box on our
home page.
October, 2009. U.S. Army post in Afghanistan.
53 American soldiers were attacked by an estimated
300 Taliban fighters. Staff Sergeant Clint
Romesha was there. More than half the Americans
were killed or wounded, including Romesha.
But he led counterattacks against the Taliban
forces that helped the Americans regain control
of parts of the base. It helped them recover
comrades who were killed or wounded, and it
gave them time to call for support. Because
of his actions that day. Sergeant Romesha
is the newest recipient of the Medal of Honor.
It is the military`s highest decoration given
to troops who risk their lives while going
above and beyond the call of duty. Clint Romesha
is the fourth living person to earn the Medal
of Honor for actions in Afghanistan or Iraq.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today`s "Shoutout" goes
out to the social studies teachers and students
at Lincoln Middle School in Indianapolis,
Indiana.
Which U.S. president was born on February
12, 1809? You know what to do. Was it Thomas
Jefferson, Ulysses Grant, Andrew Jackson or
Abraham Lincoln? You`ve got three seconds,
go!
Today marks 204 years since Abraham Lincoln
was born. That`s your answer and that`s your
"Shoutout."
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: January 1st, 1863, America was entering
its third year of a devastating civil war.
President Abraham Lincoln decided to broaden
the goals of the war beyond the battlefield
and take historic action on the question of
slavery. He picked up a pen and signed the
document known as the Emancipation Proclamation.
It would become one of the most powerful presidential
actions in American history. The proclamation
said that "all persons held as slaves within
any State of designated part of a State, the
people whereof shall then be in rebellion
against the United States, shall be then,
thenceforward, and forever free."
Some historians estimate these words freed
as many as 4 million slaves. Some former slaves
in occupied territories then joined Union
Forces, the liberated became liberators. It
also changed the character of the Civil War.
The Union was now fighting to create a new
United States, one without slavery. Historians
have called the proclamation the first step
toward freedom for African Americans. It did
not completely end slavery in the U.S., it
technically freed the slaves only in the Confederacy,
the states that were fighting the Union. But
the proclamation tipped the scales in favor
of those who wanted slavery to end. In the
years and decades that followed what became
known as the civil rights amendments, the
13th, 14th and 15th amendments to the Constitution
freed all slaves, gave them the same legal
rights enjoyed by white Americans and gave
black men the right to vote. The document
that started it all, the original Emancipation
Proclamation, is kept in the National Archives
in Washington, D.C.
When we reported last week to the U.S. Post
Offices planning end Saturday delivery, 53
percent of the students on our blog said this
will matter. Allen says he has checks, college
applications and family letters in the mail.
Meghan writes her boyfriend is a Marine, "the
only way I will soon be able to talk to him
is through letters and mail." Lisa calls this
"... no big deal to people of the 21st century"
who email, text or call if something needs
to be shared. But Priscilla argues, "It`s
not the same as a tangible letter." It`s harder
to keep a treasured letter when all it is,
is a bit of data on computer."
Walking a dog -- not that interesting. Walking
a horse -- getting better. A dog walking a
horse, jackpot. Now, the pooch is persisting
in this Youtube video, but the mare just wants
to mosey. So it looks like our main event
is a good old-fashioned tug of war. You think
the horse would rein supreme, but it`s been
settled with the walking companion, and obviously,
wants to unleash its energy. So, eventually,
the horse does give in, and let the dog dictate
the pace, even if it did this start this whole
thing of as a naysayer.
All right, it`s time for us to walk off. Teachers,
we want to hear your thoughts on today`s show,
on any show. Go to our homepage, look for
the feedback link in the resources box. We`ll
see everyone back here tomorrow for more CNN
STUDENT NEWS.