But in a race between delivery
bike and delivery truck,
will our design fail to deliver?
ROG: You're on fire!
TRAVIS: I'm Travis Taylor.
I'm a rocket scientist in
the space and defense industry
here in my hometown
of Huntsville, Alabama,
where my daddy
helped build the rockets
that sent us to the moon.
DADDY: Have y'all been
drinking rocket fuel again?
TRAVIS: Sometimes big science
moves too slow for me,
so come the weekend,
I round up my best friend Rog,
my nephew, Michael,
and my buddy, Pete,
to tackle important problems
with a little
down-home ingenuity.
ROG: Damn it, boy!
TRAVIS: Right on.
Hey, is there any more
beers in the cooler?
This weekend started off
a bit different.
The whole gang came over
for a video call
with John Schnatter,
the CEO and "Papa"
of Papa John's Pizza.
He wanted to talk to us.
Now, this should be interesting.
Hey, John!
Yeah, it's Travis Taylor
and the rest of the guys here.
JOHN SCHNATTER:
You know I'm a fan of the show,
and I know you're
a fan of my pizzas.
TRAVIS: Yeah, cool.
JOHN: I wanted
to talk to you guys
about something
we're working on at Papa John's.
As you know,
we're constantly improving.
In some big cities we're testing
the concept of using bicycles
to deliver pizza faster,
so I thought
maybe you could come up
with some of that
redneck ingenuity
to help us build
the ultimate pizza bike.
TRAVIS: Well, I believe
we can do it.
What we need to know, though,
is what you need
a pizza delivery bike to do.
JOHN: I think it needs to carry
multiple pizzas and drinks,
it needs to keep the pizza hot,
and it needs
to keep the drinks cold,
and it needs to communicate
back to home base.
TRAVIS: Yeah! We can come up
with something great for you.
JOHN: Appreciate it.
Thanks, guys.
TRAVIS: We understand why
Papa John wants to do this
because if you're delivering
pizzas in the city
and you've got all that traffic,
it'd be a lot easier
if you could zip in and out,
and the more pizzas
you could put on the bike,
the better off you'd be.
Look, we got to have
all these things.
Let's think about it.
If you got a bicycle...
I think our biggest challenge
is keeping the pizza hot
while on a long bike ride.
So, instead of using
some kind of warming bag,
I want to create an actual
pizza oven on the bike.
It's a pizza kitchen on wheels.
Somehow we got to put an oven
back in here
that's gonna hold five pizzas.
The big challenge of this build
is gonna be weight and balance
because we're gonna be adding
at least 40 pounds
to the back of this bike
with the drink cooler
and the pizza oven.
And since everything has to be
custom-fit to the bike,
we can't just go buy
our components off the shelf,
so we cooked up our own recipe
for our homemade pizza oven.
The first ingredient
is angle aluminum,
which we'll use
to whip up a rack
that will fit five pizzas.
Then we'll blend in parts
from a camping stove,
like battery-powered
heating elements and wiring
and attach them along the frame.
For the finishing touch,
we'll cover the whole thing
in insulation
and skin it with aluminum,
and--bam--we've got
ourselves a pizza oven.
I put Pete and Rog
working on the oven.
Rog, you and Pete figured out
how big that pizza oven's
got to be yet?
ROG: Yeah. I don't have
any fancy degrees or anything,
but something tells me
this pizza oven
has to be big enough
to fit a pizza box.
TRAVIS: Well, why aren't
you working on it?
Where's Pete? ROG: Pete!
TRAVIS: I picked up
some empty pizza boxes
we could use during the build
to make sure everything
fits perfectly.
TRAVIS: I don't know
how to make a pizza box.
There's got to be a trick
to making a pizza box.
ROG: How many rocket scientists
does it take
to put together a pizza box?
MICHAEL: Hang on,
I think you gotta start up here.
There you go.
That's got to go on the inside.
[laughs]
TRAVIS:
That will do good enough.
MICHAEL: Push the little tops.
TRAVIS: Yeah, like that.
All right, that's close enough.
ROG: We wanted the pizza boxes
to slide into a rack,
so we notched out
and bent some aluminum angle
to make a frame.
PETE: Just take that over
to the grinder.
TRAVIS: While those guys
worked on the oven rack,
me, Michael, and Daddy
got the oven platform together.
DADDY: We thought,
"This is gonna be
the easiest thing we've
ever done," but I'm concerned.
Every time you jump into
one of these all you gotta do's,
you wind up on
the short end of the stick.
TRAVIS: Just bolt it together.
TRAVIS: You got a level.
Where's the level, Daddy?
ROG: I know a lot about pizza,
so when I saw Charlie
with that level,
I had to step in before
they made a major mistake.
Hey, hey, before
you tighten it,
do we not want the pizzas
at an angle?
MICHAEL: We want 'em level.
ROG: I was trying to tell 'em
if the oven
wasn't angled up on the back,
those pizzas were gonna fly out
as soon as he started pedaling.
ROG: Them pizzas gonna
fall out of that.
DADDY: Alright, there you go.
MICHAEL:
We're gonna pick it up level,
You wanna go higher than level?
ROG: Just a little bit.
DADDY: That's a hair
above level right there.
ROG: You can't weld nothing.
TRAVIS: Before we welded
anything to the platform,
I wanted to check the weight
and balance distribution
of the bike.
So we loaded about 30 pounds
of sandbags onto the rack,
and then I took it
for a test drive.
Crap, look at that!
God!
What?
I'm not doing that!
DADDY: That's got to be
operator malfunction.
MICHAEL:
Holler at him. Tell him.
DADDY: Operator error!
TRAVIS: The problem seemed to be
that the weight of the bags
was out over the end
of the wheel.
Normally, a bike has most
of the weight over the center.
Now the weight
was way off-center,
and it was making me barely able
to keep the bike upright.
We've got a lot to change
and to straighten out
and rethink,
and we're gonna get there.
Yeah, I don't know what
to say about it right now.
DADDY: This thing's going
every way but right.
Now, who would've thought
it'd be complicated
to build a bicycle for pizza?
TRAVIS: We messed around with
the placement of the sandbags
to adjust the center of gravity.
MICHAEL: Is that any different?
TRAVIS:
Yeah, that's a lot better.
And it made it ride less wobbly.
Now that we've figured out
a better weight distribution...
Yeah, I could ride on this.
We got back to work
on the oven and the cooler.
Well, let's go.
Get that weight off there.
Let's mount that oven.
Finish building
that oven Pete, Rog.
What are y'all doing?
Build that thing!
ROG: I got my part done.
TRAVIS: Where's the other part?
TRAVIS: We used the elements
out of a 12-volt camping oven
to put in our pizza oven.
These things should work fine,
and they work off of
a 12-volt battery.
Rog worked on the door
for the oven,
while Pete did the wiring.
PETE: Rog, I think
we're about ready
to put this thing together.
TRAVIS: I took it upon myself
to build the cooler
for the two-liter soda bottles.
The oven and the cooler
were both covered
with insulating foam
to keep the heat
and the cold in.
Then we covered them
in sheet metal
for protection
from the elements.
PETE: Chefs,
step away from your tables.
MICHAEL:
There's our battery ready.
TRAVIS: When Michael
finished installing the battery,
I sent him to get some pizzas
so we could do a test run.
Now we just need to get the
cooler and the oven on the bike.
MICHAEL: Why don't we just
bungee cord it on there?
TRAVIS: No. Make me a frame
that it slides into.
Put a stop right here.
Just come up over it with
the three-quarter inch tubing.
Or one inch, I don't care.
MICHAEL: You need to wait
till you get the oven in there
and mount it in so it slides.
TRAVIS: And before long,
it looked ready to ride,
until I saw
what Michael was doing.
TRAVIS: Yeah, I don't like it.
I told you what to do.
I do not want it bungeed on,
Michael Taylor,
'cause look--
when you start doing that,
that bungee's
going to let it do that.
I want you to weld me
a bar across here.
ROG: He done told you!
TRAVIS: Hardheaded boy!
ROG: I'm tired of counting
how many times he told you.
DADDY:
I've tried to argue with them.
I never win
with either one of 'em.
They're both just hardheaded,
and I tell 'em
they take it after
their mother and their grandma.
TRAVIS: Daddy, I wouldn't
be saying that out loud.
ROG: I don't know what Travis
has against bungee cords,
so Michael welded it up
just like he asked,
and once again,
the diva got what he wanted,
and we loaded her up
with pizza,
which gave me an idea.
Hey, somebody got to
feed them kids, man.
TRAVIS: What?
Feed them kids?
ROG: Yeah, carry it over
to my house.
TRAVIS:
Carry it to your house?
All right,
well, that's about what?
Five or six miles from here?
That's not a bad delivery test.
ROG:
I don't think it's that far.
TRAVIS: I'm gonna deliver
these pizzas to Rog's house.
I'm gonna test drive
the fully loaded bike
for a few miles
to make sure
that all the earlier weight and
balance problems are solved.
Once that's settled, we'll add
the communications systems
that Papa John wanted.
MICHAEL: Now kick that thing up,
and it'll stay. There you go.
TRAVIS: We'll make it look cool
and present
the finished bike to him.
So I hit the road
with pizza bike version one.
ROG:
Shake it, don't break it!
Look at him wiggling like that.
MICHAEL: Don't shake the Cokes!
TRAVIS: It took a little bit
just to get started
because the bike
is a little unstable.
PETE: Drain a gear and push it!
TRAVIS: Whoa!
Can't stand up on it.
You certainly can't stand up
on the thing to climb hills.
That's a problem.
MICHAEL:
Drive that thing straight.
Keep it in the road!
TRAVIS: Shut up!
PETE: I'm a little bit
concerned about this bike.
It just seems like
it's really wobbly.
ROG: Don't lose him, Pete.
TRAVIS:
If I get going really slow,
then I start wobbling,
and it gets pretty scary.
MICHAEL: Need me
to get out and push?
TRAVIS: Shut up!
Crap!
ROG: You all right, bubba?
MICHAEL: You all right?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
As it started wobbling,
the front tire got off the road,
and I crashed pretty good.
Crap!
You get too slow,
you just can't...
you can't handle it.
DADDY: We were
concerned he got hurt,
but we checked on him.
He wasn't hurt; just his pride.
ROG: Stay with it.
TRAVIS: Well, hope
they don't mind us delivering
some shook-up Coca-Colas, Rog.
Center of gravity's
just way high.
Soon as you slow down
to climb a hill,
then it's just--I mean,
it's all my strength
to just keep it from
falling over side to side.
Center of gravity has gotta be
lower to the ground.
MICHAEL: You gonna go to Rog's,
or we gonna load it up?
TRAVIS: Well, I mean,
I can get on over this hill.
DADDY:
Travis gets back on the bike,
and he's still gonna take
these pizzas over to Rog's.
PETE: All right, ready?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
DADDY: And he gets about
a quarter mile on up the road.
ROG: I smell something.
MICHAEL: I smell something.
[horn honking]
ROG: You're on fire!
DADDY: Hey, Travis!
And the whole back end
of the bike is on fire.
[honking]
And he don't even know it.
Daddy: These experiments are
dangerous.
These guys are real rocket
scientests.
Don't try this at home.
TRAVIS: The CEO of Papa John's
asked us
to build him a prototype
for a pizza delivery bike,
but so far...
Crap!
It hasn't delivered.
But I hadn't even seen
the worst of it yet.
ROG: You're on fire!
DADDY: The whole back end
of the bike is on fire.
And he don't even know it.
DADDY: Look out.
You're on fire, boy!
ROG: Who's gonna
feed them kids?
TRAVIS:
I didn't know it was on fire
until it was getting
out of hand,
and Daddy and Pete were
honking the horn and yelling,
and Michael and Rog were yelling
that I had a fire.
I thought they were telling me
I was just on fire
and was riding pretty good.
MICHAEL: What in the world?
DADDY: How could that thing
catch on fire in there
with a pizza?
TRAVIS:
When I crashed back there,
I bet we shorted out
them heating elements.
I think your kids
are gonna have to eat
some peanut butter and jelly
tonight or something.
MICHAEL: Get in the truck.
Let's load this bike up.
TRAVIS: It's been
a long, tiring day,
so we decided to pack it in
and start bright and early
tomorrow morning.
We've got a lot of fixing to do
if we're gonna have a working
pizza bike to show Papa John.
But one thing
I wanna make sure we got
is somehow for me to know if
this thing were to catch on fire
or start getting too hot,
that I could shut it off.
First thing we got to do
is keep the oven
from catching on fire again.
So I'm thinking we need to put
a temperature probe in there
that somehow's
got a screen up here
that I can tell if it's getting
too hot or whatever.
The biggest thing with this bike
right now is stability.
It wobbled like crazy.
The reason the bike wobbles
is that the center of gravity
is still too far to the rear.
Can't move the oven up.
We have another option:
make the bike longer.
You know, when we went to
the beach a couple years ago,
Calista wasn't old enough
to ride a bike yet,
but she was old enough
to pedal a tricycle,
and I rented this bike.
It had one wheel come off here,
and it had handlebars on it
and a pedal.
Yeah, and she rode it,
and that thing was stable
as all get out.
We went over trails and stuff.
That's what we need.
We need one of those.
Why don't you and Rog
call around
and see if y'all can find one,
then maybe run over
and get one somewhere.
ROG: Road trip, man.
MICHAEL: Let's ride, man.
TRAVIS: The beer stores
ain't open yet,
so y'all oughta be back soon.
Now the plan is to
add a kid's trailer bike
to our pizza bike--
a third wheel which will
change the center of gravity,
making the bike more stable.
And we'll fix
the oven and cooler.
We'll put
a see-through door on it
and a temperature gauge
with the read-out
mounted on the handlebars.
That's also where we'll need to
put the GPS and a Smartphone.
While we're at it,
we decided to throw in
a sensor alert system,
which will warn us if we get too
close to crashing into anything.
While they were gone, we started
figuring out how to fix the oven
and how to mount all that stuff
to the handlebars.
ROG: You ain't done nothing,
man, since we been gone.
MICHAEL: It don't look like
y'all doing nothing.
TRAVIS: Oh, shut up. We've been
working hard up in here.
ROG: Charlie's the only one
that's been working, I bet.
TRAVIS: Hey, look at that.
That's it right there.
That is exactly
what I was talking about.
Hey, y'all break that bicycle
while you're at it.
MICHAEL: I'm trying. This thing
don't wanna go together.
Too many moving parts here.
TRAVIS: Well, quit moving!
ROG: Y'all be cool.
MICHAEL: We should
walk off this job here.
TRAVIS:
We had some minor setbacks,
but it's all
coming together now.
Before long, our third wheel
was set and the oven was ready.
MICHAEL: We got us a good
set up oven now.
TRAVIS: I've been working
on communication systems
with a GPS, proximity sensors,
and all kinds of cool stuff.
Next we need to get all that
mounted on the handlebars
and wired up to the batteries.
Watch out. There's cameras
and sensors everywhere
wired onto this thing.
PETE: And it's heavy.
TRAVIS: It is heavy.
All right, that seat post
goes into the seat post hole.
PETE: Okay.
TRAVIS:
Into the saddle hole, Pete.
PETE: Once I knew what
the trailer would look like,
I built a much sturdier mount
for the oven
and dropped it about six inches
to bring
the center of gravity lower.
TRAVIS: And then
right into the handlebar mount.
That bar ends--that's about
right where the bar's pointing.
MICHAEL: No, you got to
point it down.
TRAVIS: No, bar handles
are like that.
I raced for years, Michael.
And I raced on this bicycle.
I know right where I want 'em.
Then we added
the best part of all:
power assist.
Back when I was huffing
and puffing up that hill,
I thought, "Man, I need help."
So we're making
an electrical bike engine
out of two power drills.
We'll attach 'em
to the rear pedals
with triggers
on the handlebars,
and when those drills
start spinning,
it'll be like having
another person pedaling.
We need to hurry up
and get this done, y'all,
'cause we got to test
this thing for Papa John.
What I'm thinking we're gonna do
is I'm gonna race Michael
delivering pizzas.
We'll go over to the University
of Alabama Huntsville,
and we'll deliver some pizzas
to some college kids
or something over there.
I'm gonna be pedaling this,
and then Michael, I figure,
can be the pizza delivery boy,
using his truck.
MICHAEL: You can't compete
with a pickup truck.
TRAVIS: We shall see.
We're gonna have us a race
that will prove the pizza bike
is a better delivery system
than a car.
Michael thinks
he's gonna win this race,
but he doesn't
realize my advantage.
Delivery trucks
get around great
on the country roads
around here,
but the pizza bike
will really come in handy
in high-density areas,
like a city or college.
I know that the students
at the University
of Alabama Huntsville
order a lot of pizza,
so it's the perfect place
for our test,
if we can just
get this thing finished.
PETE: After we got
our communications array
and the oven and cooler
mounted again,
we added the final element:
training wheels.
Travis says they're to hold
the power drills in place.
That's what he says, anyway.
TRAVIS: We got to UAH
with the pizza delivery bike,
then we checked in with the
on-campus Papa John's kitchen.
This is where
we'll pick up the pizza orders
for the college kids.
Before we kicked off the race,
I wanted to show John
the finished bike.
JOHN:
Let's take a look at the bike.
TRAVIS: This is the bike
that we made.
Look right here.
This is our pizza oven.
You can put five pizzas in it.
You got fans, heating elements
that keep 'em warm.
We got motors on this thing
to help us get up a hill.
This is where the drinks go,
in the cooler.
Then up here,
here's our control board.
We got GPS right here.
We got proximity sensors
tell us if somebody's around.
Then we also have
a temperature gauge,
tells what temperature
the oven is.
And then, yeah, we got a horn
in case we need
to honk at anybody.
So then right here we got
triggers to run the drills.
So this is the bike, and we're
about to have a competition.
JOHN: That's unbelievable!
You guys put
a lot of work into it.
I'd love to see what it can do.
TRAVIS: All right, cool.
Let's get ready to do this test.
Michael,
I'm gonna whip your butt.
MICHAEL: You ain't gonna do it.
Let's go get some pizza.
We'll be back, John.
There's no way
he can out-pedal me.
DADDY: The pizza's are in there,
so let's go get 'em.
So, are you ready?
Get set...
Go!
TRAVIS:
You can't deliver nothing!
MICHAEL: Yeah, I can.
MAN: Pick one!
[laughing]
Good luck, guys!
TRAVIS: Thanks, man!
ROG: They came out of the store
about the same time.
I jumped in the truck
with Michael as an observer
while Travis loaded up the bike.
MICHAEL: Hey, Uncle Travis,
we'll see you later.
TRAVIS: Yeah, I hear you.
ROG: Stay with it, mule!
TRAVIS: We built
the ultimate pizza delivery bike
for Papa John's.
Now we're putting it to the test
with a race at the UAH campus.
Michael's already off to the
first delivery in his truck.
My start isn't going as well.
PETE: Good luck, Travis.
DADDY: Good luck, son!
TRAVIS: We'll see, y'all.
PETE: Show 'em how it's done.
MICHAEL: I was pretty confident
that my truck
would beat that bike,
but I saw Uncle Travis
had some tricks up his sleeve.
ROG: There he is right there!
TRAVIS: They may be
a lot faster on the road,
but I can cut through
parking lots,
ride on the sidewalks,
or whatever it takes
to shave off seconds.
Plus, I know this campus
really well.
MICHAEL: Where are we at?
ROG: I don't know.
PETE: Since Travis was gonna
take some shortcuts,
Charlie and I couldn't
follow him by truck,
but he kept us updated.
TRAVIS: Hey, Pete, I can see
Michael up ahead of me.
I'm almost to my first delivery.
PETE: Awesome, awesome.
TRAVIS: You can't
deliver nothing!
ROG: Stay with it, mule.
TRAVIS:
Did y'all order a pizza?
MICHAEL: Hey!
TRAVIS: You watch out.
Don't drop it!
MICHAEL: Hey, did you
order this pizza?
Here you go, man.
Look at that.
Have a good one.
See ya!
TRAVIS: Thank you, man.
Y'all have a good one.
MICHAEL:
Where are we going next?
TRAVIS: Game on!
You can't deliver nothing!
MICHAEL: I'm getting hungry
smelling all them pizzas, Rog.
ROG: I'm fixing
to open one of 'em up.
After the first stop,
I was thinking,
those college kids don't need
double of all those pizzas.
MICHAEL: Do it. Get us a piece
of pizza out of the bottom box.
ROG: It's free pizza
for them anyway.
MICHAEL: We can't eat
all of 'em now.
TRAVIS: I think
I've caught up with Michael
or I'm ahead of him.
PETE: Hell, yeah.
Keep going, man.
MICHAEL: Uncle Travis, he cut
through everywhere in the grass.
I had to go around these
stop signs and red lights.
MICHAEL: Another red light.
TRAVIS: Oh, sh...ah!
Hello!
Here's your pizza.
Hold on, I got you a drink.
MICHAEL: Here it is.
PETE: How you doing, Travis?
TRAVIS: I just delivered
the second pizza.
I don't see Michael nowhere.
ROG: Where's Travis?
There he is right there!
Look at him!
TRAVIS: Ha! Ha ha!
You can't deliver nothing!
MICHAEL: That made me mad
when he passed us by,
him just off-roading
all over campus.
MICHAEL: Yeah! This woman
ordered this pizza.
Hey, have a good day!
TRAVIS: Man, Michael
was right on my tail,
and he could catch me
any minute.
I wasn't about
to let up for a second.
This is a race to the finish.
Oh! Whoa.
I was getting pretty tired,
and the race was
getting down to the wire.
When I hit this incline,
I knew it was time
to kick in the power assist.
Nice.
Hey Pete, I just used
the drill motors.
It worked out awesome.
It's giving me a little bit
of advantage, I hope.
PETE: Well, that is
too cool, man.
TRAVIS: The final stop
was at a fraternity house.
Man, I was really hoping these
guys didn't have pizzas already
when I pulled up.
Woo! Some of you fellas order
some pizzas up in here?
Yeah! Hey, Pete, I'm delivering
my last run right now.
PETE: All right, man.
We're gonna see you out front.
We're on our way.
TRAVIS: Pass 'em around.
Y'all have a good one.
Y'all stay with it.
MICHAEL:
What's going on, fellas?
They already had some pizzas,
so I knew Uncle Travis beat us
and was on his way
back to Papa John's.
DADDY: Well, looks like
you beat Michael.
TRAVIS: I beat him like crazy.
First thing I did
was call up Papa John
to fill him in on the race.
Hey, John, we beat Michael
in the delivery truck.
I still don't see him anywhere,
so we made one heck
of a pizza delivery bike.
JOHN: You guys are winners.
Great job!
I love the fact that your bike
is really pushing the envelope.
TRAVIS: It is. Heck yeah!
JOHN: If some of the kinks
get worked out, who knows?
Maybe you guys
can get a contract,
or at least trade it in for
a bunch of Papa John's pizzas.
TRAVIS: That's right!
This has been a fun trip.
Thanks a lot.
JOHN: Great job.
PETE: There they are.
DADDY: I guess you know
who won this race.
TRAVIS: I proved real quickly
that I could deliver something
and that Michael
couldn't deliver nothing.
The ovens worked good.
It turns left better
than it turns right.
MICHAEL: You could deliver pizza
to NASCAR races.
TRAVIS: I could deliver
pizza at NASCAR, man.