MARC GAGNE: A lot of people
ask why is he so
good at what he does?
Or why is anybody so good
at what they do?
If I could answer that question,
I'd train a bunch of
riders and retire.
JAKE GAGNE: My dad used
to race motocross.
And I used to go to the track
and watch him when I was
really young.
And so he got me into it
and he got me started.
Yeah, I pretty much live and
breathe and eat and sleep
motorcycles.
It's what I love doing.
So every kind of motorcycles.
I love motocross and I love road
racing and everything.
I just love riding and racing.
MARC GAGNE: There's Jake
[INAUDIBLE] when he was young.
There's me and the wif--
[INAUDIBLE] marriage.
Here's Jake when he first
started out, a little 50.
He's probably about eight
years old right there.
Then he got a lot of plaques
over on the wall over there.
Back in the old days we used
to put all that stuff up.
Now in case it gets cold
in the winter we've
got a lot of firewood.
JAKE GAGNE: Yeah, all these
trophies, pretty much every
single one I think is from
motocross racing
just since I was seven.
So can't keep a lot of them in
the house because they just
get all over the place.
MARC GAGNE: Come on in.
MAUREEN GAGNE: Want
chicken salad?
MARC GAGNE: This is Jake's
humble abode.
MAUREEN GAGNE: He comes home
from Europe every time he
wants mom's cooking,
that's for sure.
Well, his favorites are my
chili, spaghetti, my carne
asada, my barbecues--
I cook every night
for my baby.
And he doesn't like tomatoes.
He likes lemon pepper.
JAKE GAGNE: She takes care of
me, she makes me food--
all the stuff a mom should
do, so she's good.
MAUREEN GAGNE: Actually, this
is low-fat bacon, also, and
all-wheat toast.
MARC GAGNE: This is
the living room.
There's Jake's bicycle.
He watches TV, that's his--
what do they call those, Jake?
JAKE GAGNE: Bicycle.
MARC GAGNE: What kind?
JAKE GAGNE: Spin.
MARC GAGNE: Spin bike, yeah.
Thanks, pal.
So that's his spin bike.
He tells me he puts in an hour,
hour and a half a day.
MAUREEN GAGNE: I think he's a
normal teenager with a little
bit of a 'tude.
But he's a good kid and
he's very smart.
And he's always had a 4.0
average in school.
MARC GAGNE: The toughest change
for me is the fact that
he's a teenager.
And he's no different than the
teenager down the street, to
the extent that he thinks he
knows everything and he thinks
he doesn't need his dad
or his mom anymore to
tell him what to do.
Dad's just the one that keeps
everything in check.
So I'm the bad guy.
JAKE GAGNE: He just yells and
gets mad at everything.
MAUREEN GAGNE: He doesn't
really yell.
He just--
JAKE GAGNE: No, he yells.
MAUREEN GAGNE: Jacob!
That's when we know.
MARC GAGNE: Maureen's never
been one to go to the
racetrack and watch
tons of races.
She always likes to wait to
hear and see what happens.
And you can't blame her, it's
her kid running around out
there so it's a little
different.
Us dads, we love to get
out there and get
it and make it happen.
MAUREEN GAGNE: I get nervous
when my son races.
So it's better for me to be
home, and he's in Europe.
And then I can watch him with
my girlfriend or my family
watching him live,
and when I'm in
another room, screaming.
MARC GAGNE: This is some stuff
from Toriano Wilson, he's the
one youngster that died
last year in Virginia.
We always like to keep
him in our thoughts.
I think Jake's still
wearing stickers on
his helmet for Toriano.
JAKE GAGNE: Toriano Wilson, he
was a great rider, and he was
my friend and stuff.
But you've got to try not to
think about it when you're out
on the track.
And just try not to
think about it.
Keep it in the back
of your head.
MAUREEN GAGNE: I'm going
to start crying.
JAKE GAGNE: I know mom, she
gets worried and stuff.
But I know that she still
trusts me and thinks
that I'll be OK.
MAUREEN GAGNE: I just want him
to be happy, and this is what
makes him happy.
And I'm not going to damage his
dreams, no matter what.
If I told him he couldn't ride
again-- if I was his only
parent and I said you can't ride
anymore, you would hate
me for the rest of
your life, right?
JAKE GAGNE: Yeah.
MARC GAGNE: The only thing
I've ever asked of my son
since we've been racing is
just never to give up.
So that's a thing you learn in
life, that you never give up
no matter what.
You get knocked down,
you get back up.
So that's all I've really
ever asked from him.
But I think he's got an
incredible amount of pressure.
One, to do very well
at school.
Two, to stay away from any bad
elements that a 15-year-old
might get into.
I mean, there are still
kids out there, kids
like to have fun.
There's girls--
I mean, hormones are raging
at 15-16 years old.
BECKY: I grew up in Ramona
near Jake, and we went to
middle school together and
that's how I know him.
MARC GAGNE: Girls Jake
stays away from.
His term is they're kind of
dream killers right now.
BECKY: Everybody at the high
school talks about who he is
and what he does and
how great he is.
And he's always in the
"Sentinel." I'm
really jealous of him.
He look like he has fun out
there street racing and he
does really good.
And he's really fast, and
the bikes look like
it's so much fun.
MARC GAGNE: His interest lies
mainly in doing well in the
sport he's chosen.
And he knows that four or five
years from now he can go back
and have all the young
girlfriends
he'd like, I'm sure.
So it's just a matter
of staying focused.
JAKE GAGNE: So it's 11 o'clock
here and I just woke up and
went to bed at like 1 o'clock
earlier today.
And I'm just staying
on European time.
They all go to sleep when I'm
getting up, and then I'm up
all morning in the dark,
so that kind of sucks
[INAUDIBLE].
MARC GAGNE: Basically what Jake
does, usually two weeks
prior to an event unless they're
back to back like they
are now, he'll start going to
bed at 4 o'clock in the
afternoon, 3 o'clock
in the afternoon, 2
o'clock in the afternoon.
Works his way up to about noon,
11:00 AM and then turns
around and gets back up about
when I go to bed at night
about 10:30-11:00 PM.
And then he'll stay up and do
his homework in the wee hours
of the morning when
it's all dark.
JAKE GAGNE: There's nothing
really to do this
early in the morning.
A.J.: When he first started
racing he did motorcycles, and
it didn't really mean a lot to
me until he started doing
really good in Rookie's
Cup and stuff.
DILLAN: We saw some videos of
him, and we were like oh,
damn, he actually is good.
A.J.: He doesn't come to school
anymore so everyone's
always wondering how he does.
And people see it
on TV sometimes.
DILLAN: It kind of sucks,
because it's taking away from
our hanging out and stuff.
But he's going somewhere in
life, he's doing something
cool and I'm stuck in Ramona.
I've never really asked
Jake to go to a party.
I know he'll say no.
A.J.: His dad would freak out.
DILLAN: I think he's scared that
his dad will find out.
A.J.: Yeah.
MARC GAGNE: If his friends say
that they miss him, they
probably do.
But that was a choice that Jake
and I and his mom made.
He knows going in that
it's going to
require some sacrifice.