But taking my makeup off is one of the
most insecure thing I can do, personally.
it's gotten a lot better which is
sad to say
i mean it's a good thing to say but
it still looks awful.
sSo I am going to show you what my face looks
like without makeup
um
Then I am going to show you how I apply my
foundation so that I look like this.
Also, I am in the living room today
because i feel it
has better lighting then in the other room
So tell me if you like this better or
if you want me to film videos somewhere else
um I hope that this helps you
if you guys have acne or even if you dont
and just want flawless skin
I hope this works for you. i will not go over blush eyes
or other makeup, I have a contouring
and highlighting video you can look at that.
I will post a link
But this is just how I do my foundation. And it changes just
about every month Im thinking
to keep updating these kind of videos
just to show you
Hopefully this helps you and hopefully you enjoy
Ill talk to you soon, bye
Here I am with no makeup
No nothing, no eye makeup
and
and I feel really disgusting
My nose is clogged up Its way too early
um this is probably the most nerve racking
thing that I could possibly do
This is my biggest insecurity
but this is my face
the sad part is that this is a lot better
than it was before
It is still all over my chest my back
um it is everywhere and you can
see it goes down my neck
uh... its all across the side
you can see it on the ear
It has been like this and it has gotten a lot better
but it's still really bad
so it is my biggest insecurity
I am wearing my bathrobe and pajamas
Because sometimes I spill makeup
and I don't want to ruin clothes
The first thing I do
because i have extremely oily skin
um I take this smashbox antishine
and what that does
it basically
stops you from getting oily
i get oily around my nose
around a little bit around my T zone
Im only going to take that much
and I will spread this everywhere
I need to be oil free
for me thats mainly my nose
yeah
I usually do it on my nose every day
sometimes my T zone
it really depends on where you get shiny
most often
Im just trying to get this makeup on
as soon as possible
so that you do not have to
look at this
Take a primer you can use any primer
you can use
anything rom sephora to
mac to bare minerals
You can use any primer
but for me
personally my favorite for a long time
has been veil primer
made by hourglass
it has sun protection and I put it on my face
and it is just like
rubbing pearls into your skin
because it's like velvet
I can rub my face my face all day long
and i always carry everything that i
do down my neck just because
well I have acne there
the next thing I use is foundation and my daily routine
changes probably every month
maybe even every week
it's nuts
but recently i've started
this is november
now its december I like the Lorac Foundation
But it is heavy
but recently I have been using
where is it
I use a couple different things and recently
I have been hooked on these The Makeup For Ever HD Foundation
I think these are my all time favorite
I think I will use these for the rest of my life
but in a month it will change again
I use numbers
125 and 120
I used 130 for a little time
but they look like this
all you need is 2 squirts
and you want to spread that all over your face.
You can dot it on
I will scoot closer so you can see
I try to dot it on
I use clean fingers to put on foundation
many people use brushes. I like brushes
I will do a video with brushes soon,
"Soon" I say that funny I will do the video soon
to show you how. But I
absolutely love using my fingers
I just feel that it is
such better coverage, looks airbrushed
and then I can add layers on top
If you want to layer foundation
mix it with mac's fix plus spray
from MAC cosmetics
that way it will dry quicker
just put on more layers
and again i like very full coverage
so we want to blend that in together
and this is color 120
after that I use
color 125
as you can see it is a slightly darker
color and i'm going to put this only
on the outer areas on my face
and down my neck
the reason why is because the
lighter color is in the middle of the face
is really going to highlight that
and I always do highlighting and contouring
so it adds to the photoshopped flawless effect
I like to use a headband
to try to protect my
hair line
but its way too early in the morning
so I forgot to grab that
also
make sure you get the bottom of your nose
so you don't have
5 different colors going on there
I also put foundation on my lips
so that I can shape my lips
when you shape your lips take a Q TIP
wherever the foundation is
it looks like your skin
and wherever else it is looks like your
lips I know i look crazy right now
but it works really well
So I will use Mac's
studio finish concealer
in color NC 30
sorry my camera battery died but
basically what I did is use
MAC concealer
I dotted it on my problem areas
not much on my neck just big pimples on the face
I put it on my neck in the past
I just emulsify and blended in
using my finger
if you use a warm brush or warm finger
it works a lot better
and like I said I usually like using my clean
hands with foundation but I will do a video
with brushes later
Next thing to do
is take two different powders to set the foundation
because the foundation is a little bit wet
and it makes you look a
little bit oily
so what I will do is
start off with brush number
and i'll actually go with two different colors
the first one is
Mac NC 5
and i'm going to rub it like this
in a circular motion so
I get it on the brush
um
Im just going to pat the lighter color
pat it over
and tilt my head back so it doesn't spill
and stays on the face and I will pat this
on the inner triangle of my face
I talk about the triangle of the face in
highlighting and contouring video so if you have not seen it
watch it because it is what
I do after foundation
yeah
but ya basically put this on
that part of your face that you need
it to be lightest which is the very middle
I tilt my head back so that powder stays there
until it is evenly blended
the next thing im using is
smashbox halo
this is in the shade of
Light
and i just got this it is new but I have been using it alot
because I loved the other colors
they were out of the other colors so I
have to use color light now
but it looks like this and you twist it
twisting it shaves powder off
if you can see that
basically the powder comes out once you
turn it
so you take a bit on top of your brush
and i'm just going to put
this all over the outside of my face
this would be the lower cheeks
up a little bit on the forehead temple
and all over our neck and chest
I will then take one of my favorite powders
it is from the
makeup for ever
this is the HD micro finish powder
and you should probably put it on with a different brush
but Im going to use this one for the sake of
saving brushes because I have to go
later today
and put makeup on friends for a birthday
but as you can see this is just the
finest powder
in the entire world
it is
is just light and fluffy in every way
you see that
and this is a setting powder and
i'm going to use this to set my foundation and powder
because the powders
from mac and smashbox
are a little bit thicker
so this one is so ultra small
it will get into the spaces
that other powders missed
and it smells really fresh
I don't know it smells like clean laundry to me
that ensures that
our entire face is set
mac fix plus spray and I absolutely love
the spray is a dream come true
I will hold it a foot or 16 inches away from my face
close eyes and spray
"spray noises"
Like i recommended you can also mix this
with a little bit of foundation you just pump
foundation onto your hand spray it on and mix it with
your brush and put it on with a foundation on concealer brush
fI will show you in another video how to do taht
and that will help
so that you
can layer on more layers
of foundation
but that is what I do
I let it dry
and Viola, there is it!
you have flawless looking skin
then I do contouring highlighting blush and eyes
I have other videos on how to do that
feel free to look at them if you have not seen them already
and then I also use a Q tip to take
foundation off of my lips to chose the shape
so that I can control what shape my lips are
I show you that in another video
called "Lip Shaping"
but um..yeah
so stay tuned! Click subscribe, the yellow button
it is completely free no charge
so you know when I update videos
and I hope you enjoyed this
I hope you can have flawless skin too
I will post acne updates, products used, and more videos
in the bottom tab. Talk to you soon! Bye!