All that, plus Tyler
Ward checks in.
This is "YouTube Nation."
[THEME MUSIC]
JACOB SOBOROFF: Alexander
Kulabuhov posted a video
from Kiev on Sunday that you
have absolutely got to see.
The massive
demonstrations in Ukraine
escalated last weekend after
controversial new anti-protest
laws were passed.
ALEXANDER KULABUHOV: Right
now I'm breaking the law.
Because recently the
government took the law
that if you wear a helmet-- a
helmet-- it's against the law
and you are going to jail.
JACOB SOBOROFF: This all
started two months ago
when President Yanukovych
refused a trade agreement
from the EU and accepted
aid from Russia.
Alexander is doing
something so important.
He is dedicating his channel to
communicating first-hand news
from the ground.
ALEXANDER KULABUHOV:
We need your support.
Like, comment, and
share this video
with your
English-speaking friend.
Because there's no information
from Ukraine in English.
JACOB SOBOROFF:
This is an extremely
complicated and volatile
situation, something that's
definitely worth
paying attention to.
And we put together a
playlist with a whole lot
more about what's happening.
EARNEST: One of the
biggest videos of the day
has Arnold Schwarzenegger
at Gold's Gym
in Venice, California.
And he's disguising
himself, but not really.
ARNOLD SCHWARZENEGGER: Remember
we do everything in reps.
So you've done two
reps of water drinking.
Usually we do 10
reps of everything
so do another rep
of water drinking.
Stand up straight.
Very good.
Rep number seven.
You have elbows and you
have knees, so touch them.
Very nice.
EARNEST: He made this to
support After-School All-Stars,
an organization that provides
free programs to children
across the country, from
tutoring to fitness.
And it's a hit.
It already has over
5 million views.
When he's having fun,
you're having fun.
JACOB SOBOROFF: Motor
Trend Technician
is car porn at its finest.
For their 100th episode,
they're in Spain,
taking the new Porsche
918 Spyder for a spin.
LAGO: What world is this,
where we can have this?
You can have 900 horsepower, and
you can have an electric mode
too, that drives the car when
you don't want to burn gas.
I mean, that's absurd!
JACOB SOBOROFF: Yep, you heard
that right-- 900 horsepower
with the fuel economy
of a Toyota Yaris.
That's nuts.
Motor Trend is the
number one auto channel,
with more than two
million subscribers.
They post new episodes
of the series "Ignition"
every single Monday.
TYLER WARD: Hello
"YouTube Nation."
I am Tyler Ward, and I'm
here at the YouTube Space LA
shooting a video for my new
song, "Keeping Secrets,"
off my brand new
album, "Honestly."
So a video I'd like to
share with you guys today
is one of my favorites
when I'm feeling
like I want to be intoxicated
but I'm really not.
So I just put this video on.
It's crazy, it's like--
[MUSIC_-_BONOBO,_"CIRRUS"]
It's a song called
"Cirrus" by Bonobo.
[MUSIC_-_BONOBO,_"CIRRUS"]
TYLER WARD: So
the video actually
was released last January.
And if you're not one of the
2 and 1/2 million people that
have seen this, then you
should go check it out.
JACOB SOBOROFF: Imagine
if all of the Wi-Fi
went down in the entire
world and you could not
Instagram your tacos.
The horror!
Charlie McDonnell's new
short plays out this scenario
to perfection, and it
gets real ugly, real fast.
-It's happened.
May god have mercy on us all.
[SCREAMING]
-Gourmet Live, Gourmet Live!
-Where-- where--
where's the [INAUDIBLE]?
[SCREAMING]
JACOB SOBOROFF: Charlie's
been posting blogs since 2007.
And actually he was the first
Brit to hit 1 million subs.
In March he challenged himself
to make five short films.
"Offline" was his second,
and he just the making of.
CHARLIE MCDONNELL: The truth is
that I hated editing this film.
When I got home and
looked at the footage
that I had and tried to
put something together,
I just didn't think
it was any good.
And so I did the
worst possible thing
you can do when you're scared.
I ran away.
And I hoped the film
would edit itself.
JACOB SOBOROFF: We're
glad you did edit it, man.
And I can't wait to
see the next one.
For now, we put
together a playlist
of some of Charlie's
greatest hits.
The only thing more
moving than nostalgia
is nostalgia you can dance to.
SHAYDA: Hi, I'm Shayda, and I
work here at "YouTube Nation."
I wanted to share
this video with you
because it's one of the most
creative uses of old technology
I've ever seen.
[MUSIC - JULIAN
CORRIE, "POLYBIUS"]
JACOB SOBOROFF:
Composer Julian Corrie
created that song using a
Commodore 64, a Sega Mega
Drive, and floppy
and hard drives.
So cool.
We want to see you
guys on the show.
Just make a quick video of
yourself talking about a video
that you love,
then post the link
with the hashtag #youtubenation.
Until tomorrow my friends.
We've got links below.
Playlists are about to come up.
Now play us out Flula with
a little "Polar vortex,
you freeze my cortex."
[MUSIC - FLULA, "POLAR VORTEX"]