Hi everyone I'm Paddy Kim. Get ready and pack your bags for the playground known as New Zealand
a country whose people are nicknamed for their famous flightless bird : the kiwi
New Zealand. It was discovered by humans less than a thousand years ago
then rediscovered by moviegoers in 2001
when the island nation stunning landscapes
where splashed across theatre screens worldwide standing in for Middle Earth in the Lord of the Rings
New Zealand's two main islands lie up the south-east cost of Australia
put together the north and south Island are about the size of the Colorado
but they pack plenty of geography into a small space
from the picks of the Southern Alps,
to Mossy forests ideal for hiking
the scenery here lures not just sightseers but travelers looking to go outside and play.
The majority of New Zealanders, about 75%, live on the north island
Its biggest city, Auckland is also the biggest city in the country
and nearly surrounded by water.
Auckland claims to have more boats per person than any other city in the world.
So it's a great place to sample a favorite kiwi pastime : sailing.
If you want to get away from the city lights,
Tangariro National Park is one of the north island's most popular places to go hiking or trekking as the kiwis call it.
Bubbling mud signals that the area is still volcanically active.
But most people seeking adventure head for the south Island where there is fewer people and more wilderness
Christchurch is the gateway city.
Originally settled by the British it's been called the most English city outside of England
You can even go punting on the Avon river passing trough the botanical gardens.
a relaxing way to unwind from an international flight.
Nearly a third of the south island is protected as national parkland.
There are trails for trekking, rivers and lakes for kayaking, caves to explore
rocks to climb, and plenty of mountains for biking.
The fly fishing is considered some of the world's best. Fishing here may look serene
but landing a beauty in this pristine setting is heart-pounding in it's own way.
all right, here we go !
While you're outside, keep your eyes open for New Zealand's native wildlife. Fur seals are common along rocky coasts
At Curio bay, you can spy yellow-white penguins coming ashore
after their daily fishing trip from late afternoon until sunset.
For a closer look at wildlife, head to the town of Kaikoura
her deep waters close to shore attract a wide variety of marine mammals.
Hop on a whale watching tour for a chance to see humpbacks, sperm whales and orca whales
and with it's clear water and good visibility
Kaikoura may be the best place in New Zealand to put on some flippers and go swimming with dolphins
If you're planning to be outdoors,
the best time to visit New Zealand is during its summer months of December, January and February.
the most flexible way of getting around is by rental car
just remember to drive on the left !
and watch out for sheep on the way to your next destination.