them Nike Dri-FIT socks,
keep your feets warm.
It's kind of the perfect
weather to hold
a city down, man.
I can't wait to fuck some
bitches in sweatpants.
On that.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
EDDIE HUANG: What's up ya'll?
Today I'm fresh off the boat.
I'ma take you to the mission
for three of my favorite
burritos, then hop over to Daly
City, get a fresh cut,
and eat some Filipino food.
Which while I find delicious,
is still looking for its
Captain Kirk to translate it
to the American palate.
Can a brother get
some tortillas?
Yo, so Daly City, this Pinoy
town, huh Jules?
JULIUS ARRIOLA: Yes sir.
They like to call this place
Lil' Manila, man.
No shit.
EDDIE HUANG: Why did
that happen?
Is it just like mad
hospitals here?
I saw the Jollibee coming in.
JULIUS ARRIOLA: Oh,
there you go.
EDDIE HUANG: So ya'll
got to be here.
I feel like Filipino food just
gets disrespect, like not
enough people talk about it.
Why do you think that is?
CHAD GABRIEL: I think just
the way it looks.
It's not really appetizing
by the sight.
It looks like already
chewed up food.
And people get the misconception
that it probably
tastes nasty.
EDDIE HUANG: I feel like a
lot of it's packaging.
Because Americans will bring
people to a sushi lunch,
business lunch.
I doubt many people are like, yo
let's go get these seasick
power lunch.
You know what I'm saying?
Them motherfuckers.
[GUITAR PLAYING]
EDDIE HUANG: All right, Farolito
burrito, tong.
[GUITAR PLAYING]
EDDIE HUANG: The things
that really drive
you crazy are nuance.
And in Chinese we call this
"shinway", where it's like a
flavor that's not too heavy,
not to light, just there.
And it's just enough that you
want more, and you're not
satisfied, and you
keep coming back.
That is the goal of every chef
cooking something, is that he
wants to make you a dish you
never want to stop eating.
That's what fucking
burrito is.
Where my burrito man at?
Thanks, dude.
Yo, Diddy got the umbrella
carrier , I got the burrito
carrier, son.
[INAUDIBLE] got Spliff Star
to carry his weed.
I got someone carry
my burritos, kid.
All right?
G shit.
[LAUGHTER]
[PIANO MUSIC]
JULIUS ARRIOLA: Even going back
to being a barber, and
Filipino barbers, and Filipino
barber shops in general.
In recent times, I feel like
we're able to build a
foundation of acceptance of
being a Filipino barber, and
being in a Filipino owned
and ran barbershop.
Before people used to be like,
ah, man Filipinos can get down
with fades and line-ups?
I don't think so, man.
Over time we were able
to prove ourselves.
Jealous Guys, San Francisco.
Ayinde, right here.
Casa.
Eddie.
EDDIE HUANG: Hey, nice
to meet you.
Are you the one with
that duck tail?
JULIUS ARRIOLA: Oh yeah, that
San Francisco duck tail, man.
AYINDE: Yeah, my shit fucked
up right now, though.
EDDIE HUANG: Yeah, that's fine.
Wolfy?
Oh, damn.
So how did that start though?
AYINDE: The Fillmore niggas,
in San Francisco.
Filmore was like the
Harlem of the West.
They was always on the
fashionable shit.
They got all the bitches,
in that
neighborhood in San Francisco.
So they started wearing
the tails.
And it was either the
box or the shag
going all the way across.
So once it got popular,
everybody in San Francisco
started doing it.
So when you go to Oakland,
Richmond, Vallejo, [INAUDIBLE]
everybody neighbor
in San Francisco.
EDDIE HUANG: I mean I had a rat
tail when I was a kid, but
that's totally different.
That's like black's
man mullet.
AYINDE: It Yeah, that's
what it is.
That's all it is.
EDDIE HUANG: That is the
black man's waterfall.
Sure, he got the strap kid.
Eh.
So you all are a group?
AYINDE: Yeah, we The
Jealous Guys.
EDDIE HUANG: I never heard
anyone claiming to be the
haters, though.
AYINDE: It's how you do it.
Know what I'm saying?
Because music don't got too much
emotion in it no more.
EDDIE HUANG: There
is some emotion.
Vale is an emotional man.
That is an emotional man.
He was just talking about Lotus
flowers and bullshit.
AYINDE: Oh, that shit?
We fuck with Lotus
flowers, though.
That's pussy, right?
We fuck with Lotus flowers.
EDDIE HUANG: I hope so.
AYINDE: That's also what
the duck tail is for.
When she want to grab the
back of the tail.
She can't handle it, because
the tongue too deep.
Nigga, know what I'm saying,
use the tail.
Know what I'm talking about?
[MEXICAN MUSIC]
EDDIE HUANG: Oh, Carne
Asada at Taqueria.
Alright?
In comparison with the
other burritos, this
one is a little smaller.
It's a little tighter,
and I like that.
There's not rice in here.
I would prefer a little
bit of rice.
Rice provided a nice texture.
In here, the flavor of the
protein overpowers the
avocado, the tomato,
the beans.
They do everything well.
I just kind of wish there was
some rice, a little more
toothsome tortilla,
but very good.
We out.
[MEXICAN GUITAR]
EDDIE HUANG: That is?
I don't want the sauce on it.
I want the foil burrito.
They just dying to give me this
Mexican sushi with the
bukaki accoutrements on top.
No bueno, kid.
[MEXICAN GUITAR]
EDDIE HUANG: I like these
because it's got the tortoise
light and then the gold.
Oh, it's like your shit.
Yeah, son.
We kind of doing
the same thing.
JULIUS ARRIOLA: Yeah, tortoise
with the gold.
EDDIE HUANG: Oh yeah, twin.
What's good twin?
Oh yeah, so this your spot?
JULIUS ARRIOLA: Yeah, man.
Pampanga's Cuisine,
they call it, man.
EDDIE HUANG: I smell it, man.
I smell the grilled pork.
Oh man, what do they got here?
Hi, how are you?
Good.
JULIUS ARRIOLA: So they
got a whole bunch of
stuff, today, man.
EDDIE HUANG: What's that?
Beans?
What's in the beans?
What vegetable?
If we don't tell Americans
what's in
there they gonna bug.
You know what I mean?
They need to know.
Come on.
Let's make it sound
delicious to them.
All right?
What's this?
Menudo.
Pork and what else?
Just pork?
I see potatoes.
I see carrots.
What's in the sauce?
Tomato sauce.
We gotta make this sound
more appetizing, god.
You got to give me more.
Come on.
You're not selling your
food properly.
All right.
JULIUS ARRIOLA: Awesome, man.
EDDIE HUANG: Yeah, man.
This is a Filipino feast, man.
JULIUS ARRIOLA: The
Sisig has been a
craze out here, recently.
The Senior Sisig that's
the food truck.
They've done Filipino-Taqueria
fusion.
Instead of carne asada, they put
in Sisig as replacement.
And it's been a hit, man.
EDDIE HUANG: I'm down
with people
taking my Filipino food.
You know what, I think people
will be more receptive to it
if it's in a taco, or
if it's in a bow.
If that's what has to happen for
people to actually start
to experience our food.
That's great, but that is kind
of sad part that people won't
just eat our food as is.
Do you know what I mean?
But then on the converse, my mom
and my grandparents, they
weren't the most receptive
to other cultures' food.
So it's not intrinsic
to America either.
I think our generation, it's
is our job to break the
barriers and get people outside
their comfort zone.
Finally, after multiple tries,
the Taqueria Cancun burrito.
Even in this state, a burrito
palate fatigue.
I'd eat two of these joints.
Nice tortilla.
There's a little bit of even
flakiness to this tortilla,
because it was on the griddle.
I think that this carnitas
can't be topped.
This is one of the best carnitas
I've ever had.
I liked Farolito the best,
but all three of them had
something different.
Taqueria had a very nice size,
very easy, it was an unwieldy.
This one, I think, might
have the best protein.
It's tender and delicious, very
moist, packs a punch.
But overall, as a package,
I think El Farolito.
Just enough, man.
It's a very balanced
hand that they're
cooking with over there.
To me that's hands
down, numero uno.
Alright?
Just so you know, you got a lot
of spots on the camera.
CAMERAMAN: Yeah, I know.
I can't even see it.
[SLAP SOUND]
EDDIE HUANG: You know
what's funny?
In New York we'd shit on
something in a mini mall.
We'd shit on being next to
the Karaoke Depot, or the
laundromat, and the dental.
I mean, this doesn't look like
some ill, [INAUDIBLE]
OG culture.
It's not something that New
Yorkers would bug over, but
you start to realize there's
some real shit here.
It looks different.
The symptoms of culture that
you should be up on are
different in Cali than
they are in New York.
So it's fun to kind of discover
the new language,
where I can't just roll by a
mini-mart and assume it's
going to suck.
But San Francisco, I got to say
man, it's got a lot of the
things that I love
about the city.
There's a lot niche culture.
There's a lot of alternative
things going on.
But they know how to
relax out here.
It's definitely something that
I need to learn how to do.
So, we fresh off the boat
and we out motherfucker.