FILM NARRATOR: This May Day
celebration in Moscow gives
the Russians the opportunity
to crow loud and
long over the West.
The face of a people
whose leaders
would wipe out democracy.
SHANE SMITH: We all know the
images of old Soviet Russia.
But in the 1980s, as the walls
in Eastern Europe were coming
down, something really
freaky happened--
Soviet parallel cinema.
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
PASHA: We don't like
any movie.
We close your screen.
SHANE SMITH: No one overarching
theme to parallel
cinema, except that they're
all anti-establishment.
They are madness on film.
So when we saw them, we realized
we have to go Russia,
and we have to meet them.
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
[RUSSIAN MARCH]
SHANE SMITH: So right after the
Russian Revolution in the
1920s, there was a big
creative explosion of
experimental cinema in
the new Soviet Union.
Vertov, Eisenstein--
all the big boys were
making their films.
Lenin believed that film was the
most important of artistic
expression, because most of the
people were illiterate.
But then Stalin took over.
And then you have 60 years
of socialist realism--
workers going off to work,
farmers going off to farms,
soldiers going off to soldier,
et cetera, et cetera.
Until the 1980s, when the
Soviet regime started to
crumble and Gorbachev brought
about Perestroika and
Glasnost, which means
restructuring and reforming.
And for a tiny little window,
there was a time when you
think, maybe I could make
something and the KBG won't
put me in jail for the
rest of my life.
So this new experimental cinema
started for the first
time since the '20s.
And it was called
parallel cinema.
[RUSSIAN MARCH]
SHANE SMITH: The first person
we met up with was Boris
Yukhananov, one of the founding
fathers of parallel cinema.
We found him at Cine Fantom,
which is now a theater but has
been at various times a film
festival, a magazine, and a
meeting house where all the
parallel cinema directors and
actors would get together
and make their films.
[SPEAKING RUSSAN]
SHANE SMITH: Next, we headed
over to see another founding
father of parallel cinema,
Gleb Aleinikov.
Gleb and his brother, Igor,
made tons of films in
the '80s and '90s.
They're actually probably the
most famous and prolific.
[RUSSIAN MARCH]
SHANE SMITH: Igor is dead.
He died in a plane crash.
But Gleb is running
the second-largest
TV station in Russia.
So we went there and asked
him, how were these crazy
films received?
Who watched them?
And did they have any
problems when they
showed them to people?
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
[RUSSIAN MUSIC]
SHANE SMITH: The parallel cinema
movement and the fine
arts movement happened
at the same time in
Russia in the '80s.
And when we were talking to the
founding fathers of the
cinema part, they kept
on saying, you
have to Oleg Kulik.
You have to talk
to Oleg Kulik.
He's a performance artist that
was really part of the initial
burst of parallel cinema.
Famously, he was the dog for a
year, where he would go all
around Europe and Russia
naked, on a
chain, attacking people.
In fact, he got arrested.
He got arrested in Germany,
and Sweden,
and France, and Russia.
And now he's the Messiah.
He's the Messiah of
a new religion,
the religion of nothing.
So we went to go see him.
And let me tell you, his bio and
his reputation do not live
up to meeting the
man in person.
Here he is putting his had
up a cow's vagina.
Here he is acting as a bird.
Here he is with some pigs.
Horse biting his nipple.
Here he is with a buddy.
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
SHANE SMITH: And they need a
messiah for the new religion?
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
SHANE SMITH: So the messiah
spent the afternoon explaining
his religion to me.
And he showed me all kinds of
images, and all kinds of
supporting materials.
And I didn't really get it.
And I left at the end of the
afternoon, really in dire need
of a drink.
We're here in Moscow.
It's cold.
But we're going to go meet Andre
Silvestrov, who's one of
followers of alcho cinema, which
is cinema of the booze.
Hello.
How are you?
Shane.
Shane, hi.
Pasha?
Nice to meet you.
PASHA: Now we start to
shoot alcho cinema.
Now, yes, immediately.
SHANE SMITH: And so alcho
cinema, is it a movement like
parallel cinema?
Or just defining films that have
a lot of alcohol in it?
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
SHANE SMITH: So can we make a
film with you guys, a parallel
cinema film?
PASHA: OK.
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
PASHA: You must drink
tomorrow.
SHANE SMITH: OK.
I have to go to bed now, then.
PASHA: Good evening.
SHANE SMITH: So we were drunk.
And we were excited.
Because the next day we were
going to make some movies.