DAN SANTORO: I'd do
probably like--
JEFF OGIBA: Just a little one?
DAN SANTORO: Yeah.
Like that more, you know?
JEFF OGIBA: Like here?
DAN SANTORO: Yeah.
I think that's a good spot
for it, actually.
JEFF OGIBA: I don't know.
So I don't know.
DAN SANTORO: Oh, I
love that frog.
JEFF OGIBA: Well--
DAN SANTORO: What do you want?
Fucking like American
flag rip-out?
Jesus Christ.
Everything I do is silly.
JEFF OGIBA: What does
it say, though?
DAN SANTORO: It says that you
like fucking Bluegrass.
You don't mind amphibians.
And you definitely get high.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
DAN SANTORO: I think this is an
interesting design, simply
because it's not like some
kind of famous thing.
It's not like some kind
of iconic graphic.
It's not like a Gibson girl
or something like that.
But you know it was pulled off
of something, which I think is
really interesting.
It might have been pulled
off of a candy
wrapper or a cereal box.
I think that's really cool.
In the beginning, we didn't
know how to make
a good tattoo design.
Neither of us did.
Right, Jeff?
Jeff is a long-time
friend of mine.
We went to high school
together.
I learned by doing a bunch of
really shitty tattoos on him.
Like in the very beginning,
he wanted to just get line
drawings and hardcore
band things.
But now, yeah, he just wants to
get really funny, goofies.
It's goofy, but at the same,
sort of like mystical stuff.
That's what he's into.
I just wanted to do a tiger
on his forearm.
And he convinced me to do a
tiger on a flying carpet
jumping through atom symbols
and like the galaxy and all
this stuff like that.
And normally, that would
be a terrible idea.
But it works on him.
And I think I did a pretty
good job on that one.
He's just one of those people
that, no matter what I do or
do to him, it's all good.
We're friends, you know?
My wife and him were just having
a conversation about,
potentially, in the future,
opening up a record store.
And then, within six months,
we had the grand opening.
So it was just a really cool
thing, because it's like a
pipe dream that every kid has
with their best friend when
you're in high school.
When we're older, we're
going to have a
record store one day.
And half the people don't even
talk to their friends from
that time period any more.
And here we are,
grown ass men.
And we have a record store.
Sommer is usually the face
of this place, up
front making coffee.
Jeff is the record guy.
And I do the antique
stuff, when I can.
JEFF OGIBA: We all do a little
bit of everything.
I end up in piles of records
mostly, dealing with weirdos,
taking phone calls, going out
to visit people who--
DAN SANTORO: Try and rob you.
SOMMER SANTORO: [LAUGHS]
-What are some indicators that
it's going to be a good buy?
JEFF OGIBA: These
are my uncle's.
And he just overdosed
on heroin.
[LAUGHTER]
DAN SANTORO: Yeah.
That's usually a good
sign, right?
Johnny Thunders got
you into heroin.
You know?
Sinatra did not, you know?
JEFF OGIBA: Soon as you hear a
little bit of the history, you
know right away that
there's a chance.
DAN SANTORO: I had a guy come
in here with a bunch of
antique medical charts.
He was a teacher.
And they were in the facility
closet of the science lab.
And he had taken them 20
years ago or something.
And they were probably
sitting in there for
60 years, you know?
Again, someone that's going to
do that is kind of weird.
But I like that.
Those are my people,
really, you know?
[LAUGHS]
That's my nationality.
I grew up in a relatively
old house.
And my father actually used
to have a military store.
My father was a World War II
collector, specifically
Italian Fascist stuff.
And then he also dealt
in a little German.
And they had that
for a few years.
And then, when they closed it
down, they brought everything
into the house.
So it was like the scariest
thing ever.
I used to go down to try
to work on models.
And there'd be two full dressed
Black Brigade soldiers
standing next to me.
It was a weird situation
to grow up in.
But it was pretty
normal to me.
And I actually really loved the
fact that that was kind of
normal to my parents.
So it's funny.
Some people walk through the
doors here and they're just
hit in the face with, I don't
know, the whole store.
They can't wrap their head
around why anybody would buy
any of this.
But for us, I mean,
this is my life.
This has been my life.
All of us.
It's like I travel on the
weekend quite a bit, when I'm
not tattooing.
Flea markets, yard sales,
Craigslist.
I get it anywhere
I can, you know?
It's a pretty small window
of opportunity
for me to get stuff.
So all week, I'm trying
to line stuff up.
STEVE BOLTZ: He's a
bit of a picker.
I mean, he likes to
go to antique
stores and antique fairs.
And then, of course, Black Gold
now has given him purpose
in that hoarding.
I think, before, it was just
like having stuff.
We all like to just
have stuff we like
to look at or whatever.
But now he's got the store.
Now he can actually
justify having as
much of it as he wants.
BERT KRAK: A lot of stuff that
Dan looks for is kind of tied
into tattooing, as far as what
the image is or it's got those
rock of ages things.
It's like classic tattoo motifs
that he looks for.
I guess it's stuff that
tattooing has borrowed from
the real world, you know?
STEVE BOLTZ: Dan's object
hoarding, it comes mainly from
tattooing, I would imagine,
even though there's other
influences, because you just
are exposed to so many
different types of art.
You think about tattooing now,
well, that crawling panther
has been drawn for us already.
You know what I mean?
But there was a time when
it didn't exist.
And somebody came in and
wanted a panther
crawling up their arm.
Well, Coleman or one of these
guys had to find some sort of
reference for this.
And a lot of early designs,
they'll come from old
children's books or comics
or whatever.
Or the Kewpie is
a good example.
A Kewpie was an actual doll.
Then it became a tattoo
icon over the years.
But now, because we know that
Kewpie so well, well, you go
into an antique store or
something and you see a little
Kewpie doll sitting on the
shelf, you're like, oh, there
it is in 3D.
DAN SANTORO: Oh yeah.
Here's another thing.
That thing is ready to
be a tattoo too.
There's a Kewpie little
home butler thing.
But it's a Kewpie.
Who doesn't want that?
My house has, more or
less, looked like
this for a long time.
It went from "Star Wars" toys,
as much as I can fill.
I thought it was corny
for a while.
So then I did the thrasher
cut out thing.
As long as the walls just
looked like culture
vomit, I was happy.
You know what I mean?
And then it became like
tattoo flash.
And then tattoo flash kind of
evolved into old circus prints
and lithographs that were what
a lot of the tattoo stuff was
derived from, and so on,
and so on, and so on.
And then, the next thing
you know, you've
got a lot of stuff.
[ORGAN MUSIC]
ELI QUINTERS: It's not
a big apartment.
And he's filled the walls.
But it's all amazing
stuff, you know?
It's top of the line taxidermy,
old tattoo flash.
It's just the way he wants it.
You know what I mean?
It's a good representation
of the stuff that
he's passionate about.
[ORGAN MUSIC]
DAN SANTORO: Oh!
I just found this at
a flea market.
It's a studio portrait of a
mother and two children.
And the two kids are on
a taxidermied ostrich.
It's like anything, you know?
You get into collecting
one thing.
And then you start to pick up
the subtleties that make one
thing more appealing
than the other.
I've been flea marketing
for a long time.
And if I had seen something
like this, I'd probably be
interested in buying it.
But I wouldn't know why.
Whereas now, I'm a little bit
more immersed in collecting.
It's pretty easy to
pick up on what
makes something desirable.
So to me, that's
very desirable.
It's an ostrich.
How often do you see an ostrich
in a photo from the
turn of the century?
This is a photo I picked up
that I thought was pretty
interesting, just in a
box of random photos.
It's obviously some kind
of carnival performer.
But she's reading a magazine.
And the back ad of the magazine
is, "Tattoo your
lips." Another stony tattooing
the inside of a woman lips.
ELI QUINTERS: Very well-studied
in stuff of that
era, of when American tattooing
came to life.
He knows a lot about that
era in history anyway.
And so I think he collects
a lot of that stuff.
So he's very well-studied
in antique flash.
And he knows a lot
about that stuff.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
DAN SANTORO: I have a lithograph
of that at the
store right now.
That's the one that I said you
see a lot of the lithographs
that old tattooers
pulled from.
That particular image, I had
never seen recreated as a
tattoo before.
And I had actually obtained
this about
five, six years ago.
And I was like, oh, that's
the coolest thing.
I didn't know who did it.
It came from the same collection
that a bunch of
other stuff that I was told
was Coleman came from.
He was a tattooer
from Virginia.
He just was the pioneer
of a lot of the
style that we see today.
He had a knack for drawing
really pretty women.
And everything he did was a
step above everything else
that was going on at the time.
This is a famous photo of
Coleman outside his shop.
So I've seen this photo
hundreds of times.
I was like, oh, if I could only
see around the corner of
that, you know?
And then, when this book came
out, boom, the other wall.
And that made my day.
100%, that is that.
I was told his shop
burned down.
Then a lot of the stuff got
kicked to the curb.
And the woman that I acquired a
lot of this stuff from, her
husband had gone and, I guess,
picked up a lot of this stuff,
literally, off the
side of the road.
And so that's why something
like that exists.
That was just two of the designs
on the sheet that
weren't scorched.
There's a photo of
him tattooing.
It's that famous photo of him
tattooing with the visor.
There's all the flash
on the wall.
He's got one sheet
off the wall.
And it's propped up
on his station.
And these two designs
are on that sheet.
But it had been cut.
A lot of this stuff got cut.
One thing that I really don't
ever want to be is
self-absorbed.
And when someone asks me to talk
about all these things
that I've surrounded myself
with, it makes me feel like
I'm self-absorbed.