DERRICK ROSAIRE: We've got
18 bears to take care of.
They've got 38 lions and
tigers, a petting zoo.
There's just a lot of
stuff around here.
KAY ROSAIRE: We've always been
saving animals all our lives.
We rescued everything
that needed a home.
We are pro-animal.
We are animal welfare.
But there's a big difference
between animal welfare and
animal rights.
MALE SPEAKER 2: Both elephants
were forced to perform almost
until the day of their deaths.
MALE SPEAKER 3: How can we
consider ourselves civilized
while we continue to allow the
suffering and abuse of animals
simply for entertainment?
CLAYTON ROSAIRE: PETA, the
People for the Ethical
Treatment of Animals, they think
the animals are better
off dead than working for
us, happy, alive,
in this nice area.
It's messed up, huh?
Uh-oh.
There goes the mic.
This is what I really love,
otherwise, I'd have done
something else.
It's not like my family's not
like, [WHIP SOUND], you will
be a dog trainer.
You get to choose what
you want to do.
It's what you love.
RYAN DUFFY: Did you just
get pissed on?
FEMALE SPEAKER 1: This is
how they train them.
This is wrong!
MALE SPEAKER 4: This gives
the circuses across
America a black eye.
This is exactly what people
protest against.
PAM ROSAIRE ZOPPE: There
basically is
no more circus anymore.
It's a dying art form.
KAY ROSAIRE: I think people will
miss it when it's gone.
If they don't pay attention,
it will be.
DERRICK ROSAIRE: Don't
even think about it.
RYAN DUFFY: I don't know
if you guys do this.
It's up to you, but if I were
you, my pick up line would be,
hey, I train fucking bears.
DERRICK ROSAIRE: I have
a little better pick
up line than that.
I point at my leg.
RYAN DUFFY: Whoo, what the
hell happened there?
DERRICK ROSAIRE: And that's what
happens when you screw up
working around bears.
RYAN DUFFY: Holy fuck, dude.
CLAYTON ROSAIRE: Say hi.
RYAN DUFFY: Hi buddy.
CLAYTON ROSAIRE: Oh, shit.
RYAN DUFFY: Oh, dude.
CLAYTON ROSAIRE: Sorry,
I had to.
Did you hear the squeaking
noise again?
That was his hiney.
RYAN DUFFY: We're here in
Sarasota, Florida, with one of
the last great American
circus families.
CLAYTON ROSAIRE: We try to
rescue all the exotic animals
that we can, and then I'm really
pushing in the future
that we'll be able to rescue a
lot of exotic dancers. 'Cause
they need a home--
[LAUGHTER]
KAY ROSAIRE: You're so bad.
RYAN DUFFY: The Rosaires are a
10th generation circus family
dating all the way back to
royal court jesters in
medieval England.
KAY ROSAIRE: Yeah, we have
a really long history.
Here's my grandfather
and my grandmother.
My father had a broken back when
he was a little boy, and
so he had to quit doing
aerial things.
He couldn't do anything
acrobatic anymore.
And he always loved animals, so
he focused on animals his
whole life.
RYAN DUFFY: In 1960, Kay's
father, Derrick Rosaire, Sr.,
immigrated to the United States
from South Wingfield,
England, to appear on The Ed
Sullivan Show with his
equestrian act, Rosaire and
Tony the Wonder Horse.
He went on to perform on the
Tonight Show with Johnny
Carson and at the White House
for President Nixon.
KAY ROSAIRE: The culture in
America has a different view
of circus because of P. T.
Barnum and his attitude about
sort of shocking people.
He changed the atmosphere of
the circus in this country.
We're also in an era now where
people don't go out as
much as they do.
They're not used to live
entertainment.
But the biggest impact
on the circus was the
animal rights activists.
MALE SPEAKER 3: Circuses cannot
provide animals with
the facilities they need to
be healthy and happy.
MALE SPEAKER 5: Many of
these animals will
literally go insane.
FEMALE SPEAKER 2: Animal abuse
is billed as family
entertainment.
Although zoos claim to be
educational, they are still
profit-making enterprises that
too often put their own
commercial self-interest in
front of animal welfare.
KAY ROSAIRE: All the animals
that I ever trained were all
animals that needed a home.
I always rescued.
I never bought any animals.
So I had always done that.
And then after I had more than
I could handle, I just wanted
to rescue more.
So as my career blossomed,
and I had the
money, I built the facility.
RYAN DUFFY: The Big Cat Habitat
began rescuing animals
in 1987 and has since grown
to feature three housing
complexes, adjoining exercise
habitats, and pools, and it's
currently home to tigers,
ligers, lions, bears, and
basically, anything else with
fur, a shell, or wings.
GIRL: Well, I came here to study
a little bit about the
different animals, and I've
never really seen any kinds of
animals like these before.
FEMALE SPEAKER 3: We've
been here before.
We love animals.
This is a great place to bring
people to show them what
they're doing with preserving
these animals and taking good
care of them.
KAY ROSAIRE: My brother started
being a softy for
bears, and Pam with
the chimps.
And so it just sort of naturally
evolved into this.
Why you got to bug me, huh?
RYAN DUFFY: Caring for these
animals is a 24/7 job.
And for Pam, Kay's sister, they
might as well be family.
PAM ROSAIRE ZOPPE: Well, I tried
everything, and I like
chimps the best.
I raised my daughter
with a chimp.
When my daughter was born, one
of my chimps was pregnant, and
I didn't even know it.
And his mother died
when he was born.
So I ended up breastfeeding
him.
I don't know, I just felt so bad
for their plight because
they've always been mishandled
and mistreated.
So my heart went out to them.
I started buying little baby
chimps that were heading for
research when I was
a teenager.
And Newton was probably the
best chimp I ever had.
It was quite interesting to
raise him along with a child.
Newton was an excellent cook.
RYAN DUFFY: Cooks
meaning what?
PAM ROSAIRE ZOPPE: Cook food.
My plan was to do a cooking
program and call it Newton's
Kitchen, but we filmed the
first one, and five days
later, Newton had a
stroke and died.
KAY ROSAIRE: Kayes Lions
is my uncle.
That's why I'm named Kay.
My uncle had been a famous lion
trainer in England during
the '30s and '40s.
And then when I was in high
school, I had the chance to
work with Clarence, the
cross-eyed lion.
And that's when I started
working with big cats, and I
was hooked on them.
That's what I decided
I wanted to do.
And it was interesting, because
sometimes I'd have her
mouth open, and I'd be putting
my head in her mouth in these
big auditoriums with the super
troupers, and I could see the
spotlight shining in
through her nose.
It gave me chills when I
realized how lucky I was and
never got hurt.
13,000 times.
Well, because I did an average
of about 500 shows a year.
RYAN DUFFY: Anyone who questions
circus people and
their care for animals, and the
conditions, should have to
come here at 8:00 AM and clean
up tiger shit with these guys.
Because there's no way you'd
do that if you don't truly
love animals.
CLAYTON ROSAIRE: You get up, you
clean everybody out, make
sure everybody's got
fresh water.
Here at the habitat,
they all rotate.
They all have these big outdoor
habitats that they get
to run and play and
everything.
It's a full day.
You really have to spend most
of the day with the animals.
RYAN DUFFY: It's just
a different smell.
It's not even like shit.
It's pure dead animal.
CLAYTON ROSAIRE: You know what
I'm saying, one little
slip-up, and you could be
that turd down there.
RYAN DUFFY: Oh, that
is terrible.
CLAYTON ROSAIRE: It's
rewarding, isn't it?
CLAYTON ROSAIRE: You know, way
back in the old days, a lot of
the videos they showed when
they're trying to make it look
bad, a lot of those animals
were from the wild.
They got them from wild animal
parks, and they'd just go in
and grab a couple and throw them
in a truck and sell them.
Times were different, so
those type of acts
were totally different.
You never saw in the old days
a tiger trainer petting a
tiger, because it was a
different relationship.
Well, times change.
You have to learn to work with
the animals and be a part of
their family and have them
be a part of your family.
You don't have to be
cruel to them.
You don't have to abuse them.
They can be great kids,
and they can love you.
There's always been a connection
between man and
beast, and we just show
them how it can be
done the right way.
KAY ROSAIRE: Our mission has
become really important over
the last 20 years, because the
environmental issues that are
going on with animals
disappearing and all of that,
we are able to let people see
them up close and personal.
And it makes them much
more willing to
help them in the wilds.
We just lost my brother.
This is my brother, Derrick,
with the bear, Peter.
RYAN DUFFY: That's
a great picture.
Derrick Rosaire, Jr.
died in 2010.
And since then, his sons have
taken over his place as
caretakers of the bears.
FREDERICK ROSAIRE:
Aspa, wave, wave.
Higher.
Give me a good wave.
DERRICK ROSAIRE: Well, the big
male we have down at that end
weighs 1,500 pounds.
He stands 11 foot tall.
That's an average male Kodiak.
FREDERICK ROSAIRE: But
everything you do with them,
you have to do nicely.
You have to be very gentle about
it, because if you try
to force them, they eat you.
DERRICK ROSAIRE: If it wasn't
for circus, five species of
bears would be extinct.
Yeah, it's what we've
all our lives, it's
what we're good at.
And lay down.
KAY ROSAIRE: You know, it's
amazing, because had our
circus friend not sent it to
me, we never would have had
any of this stuff.
Because by the time the
newspaper articles came out,
my parents were already
in the next city.
It's neat to have
all this stuff.
ELLEN ROSAIRE: Well, my dad was
a fabulous horse trainer,
because he didn't really--
he called it teaching.
He would teach them,
and that's how
we've always trained.
Just the lips.
OK, wide, good boy.
We all work with all different
kinds of animals.
I went with horses, because
I love to ride.
I have a need for speed.
I've been riding for more
than a half a century.
And I still will get
on a horse and
just go ripping away.
I love it.
We love what we do, and
obviously they love us.
Give me a hug.
Good.
I think there's a decline
in live family
entertainment of all kinds.
There's so much going
on in the world now.
There's so many other forms of
entertainment happening.
There's a lot to choose from.
And people don't always take
the time to enjoy a live
performance.
For some reason, it's way
easier to just say,
oh put the TV on.
PAM ROSAIRE ZOPPE: See the
old-fashioned clothes?
So it was quite a thing when
the circus came to town.
They would parade into town.
They'd all line up and
all come in together.
And during the Depression, there
were over 44 circuses in
this country, and they
did very, very well.
People were seeking affordable
entertainment.
When you went to the Ringling
show, and you saw Gunther
Gebel-Williams, it warmed
your heart.
There's none of that now.
You know, there's something to
be said for the old school.
CLAYTON ROSAIRE: --at the
beginning of his training.
Everybody please say
hello to Handsome!
Come on, Handsome, let's
go, big guy!
Handsome--
PAM ROSAIRE ZOPPE: I think
there'll always be circus, and
to which level, or how
many, I don't know.
But I'm sure it'll be around.
It's been in this country for
over 220 years, I believe, so
why would it stop?
CLAYTON ROSAIRE: Circus is
supposed to be a place where
you can take your entire family,
mom, dad, the kids,
everybody, and make
them all happy.
That's what circus
is all about.
In one form or another, it
will still be around.
FREDERICK ROSAIRE: As long as
people need entertainment,
it'll be there.
DERRICK ROSAIRE: The
show must go on.
That's one of our sayings.
It's a shitty saying,
but it works.
[APPLAUSE]
KAY ROSAIRE: Everytime you
hear something, oh, the
courtroom erupted into a
three-ring circus, you know,
it's such a misnomer because
there's nothing more organized
than a three-ring circus.
CLAYTON ROSAIRE: When you're
ready, of course.
And they need all that stuff.
Just so you know, Mr. Cameraman,
it's good luck to
get peed on by a tiger.
RYAN DUFFY: Did you just
get pissed on?
I like that.
CLAYTON ROSAIRE: You actually,
physically, now--
I don't know if you know this or
not, but you belong to her.
If she had a motorcycle right
now, you would be riding on
the back of that motorcycle.