I was the kid in school that
would make the poster for
brushing your teeth
if the teacher
asked me to or whatever.
But I actually fell out of
it for a little while.
I'd pierce my ear and
get called a fag.
And my best friend was gay.
So leaving high school was the
best thing that ever happened
to me because I got to be my
own person and not have to
deal with getting bullied and
all that other stuff.
So I started doing art
a lot more once I
had left high school.
And I was really interested in
punk rock, and I'd always
wanted to move to San Francisco
because I would come
to Berkeley and Haight Street
and was so turned on by it.
I saw beautiful people.
I saw European city style.
I saw people that were
liberal thinking.
I saw freedom.
So I always knew that
I'd be here.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
TIM HENDRICKS: The first time I
ever heard of Freddy Corbin,
I was a kid, and I was just
getting into tattooing.
Breaking out in it and meeting
some of the older guys.
And there was this magazine
write-up.
And it said Mr. Niceguy
right on the front.
And I remember seeing it and
being like, who's this little
skinny guy?
This guy kills it.
Even before I got to know
Freddy, if somebody asked me
hey, I'm going up to the Bay
Area, and I want to get a rad
black and grey tattoo
while I'm up there.
I'd be like, well, you've got to
go to Temple Tattoo and get
tattooed by Freddy Corbin.
He took what he knew from
learning from these old
schoolers and brought some black
and grey twist on it.
He made--
I don't know man,
he made a mark.
It's hard to describe.
It's not even really--
like I said, it's Freddy
Corbin style.
JASON MCAFEE: I'd never seen
anyone do a Day of the Dead
skull until Freddy.
When I saw one I was oh, it's
those little, like, candy
sugar skull things.
As a tattoo?
And I think he definitely
brought that
kind of style to tattooing.
TIM HENDRICKS: That style of
doing sugar skulls had been
copied so many times that kids
these days have no idea where
it came from.
FREDDY CORBIN: I mean I will say
that I saw a painting of
one that Malone did before
I ever did one.
So Malone probably had
done one or two.
And Scott Sylvia also was doing
them simultaneously.
So I think it would be safe to
say, as egotistical as it
might sound only because you
asked the question, that Scott
and I might have started the
Day of the Dead thing.
Greys, sugar skull greys,
but who knows?
I never got caught up
in having a thing.
I eventually got known for doing
religious tattoos and
stuff but I love doing
lettering and
black and grey tattoos.
I love that whole East
LA, Chicano look.
I love old English next to
Jesuses next to Guadalupes and
big low rider cars.
And I love that stuff.
JASON MCAFEE: He does a lot
of stuff that I love
to watch him tattoo.
I really, really like when he's
about to start some big
lettering thing.
I don't think people really get
what a craft that is to be
able to do lettering
that good.
Watching him write something
out, there's times when I'm
like, dude, I'm having trouble
with this name.
Would you help me out?
And in just one pass, he'll
write the most beautiful name
you've ever seen.
He's just so good with it,
it's unbelievable.
FREDDY CORBIN: Basically, I was
fortunate enough to work
with a guy named Hollywood,
Mark in Amsterdam.
And he had gone to school
with Cartoon.
They had gone to graphic
art school together.
And he taught me a
lot of tricks.
JASON MCAFEE: I mean, there's
probably so many kids and
tattooers out there right now
who don't even know who
Freddy Corbin is.
He was the young guy, but now
he's become the older
generation.
He's been doing this for 27
years or something crazy.
He is that guy now that people
pay respect to and have love
for and show it.
FREDDY CORBIN: Back then you had
to be half a cowboy to get
into the business.
Tattoo shops drew a weird type
of folk, you know what I mean?
And it was a weird type of
folk that was drawn to
tattooing, especially with
the stigma behind it.
So you were pretty much
embracing an outcast culture.
We were all outcasts.
Do you want hop up?
MALE SPEAKER 1: Yeah.
FREDDY CORBIN: Let me look
at them if you stand real
natural, real straight.
I think they look even.
I always was trying to
be a good tattooer.
I look at tattooing
like any trade.
Like being a plumber or a
shoemaker, or whatever.
I just want to be good at it.
I just want to own a shop
that's going to be an
institution of good tattooing
so people can come and know
that no matter who's working
there that day, that they'll
get a solid tattoo, they'll get
treated with respect, and
they'll leave happy.
That's my goal.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
MAX SCHAAF: Freddy has two
shops, Temple and 13.
And Temple is the
original one.
And going to Temple is like, you
walk in, and you're like,
ooh, Temple.
This is a place,
this is gnarly.
It's a cool place to be.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
FREDDY CORBIN: It
took me a while.
I had to postpone it a year.
I tried opening up in '97.
Couldn't get a place so I put it
on hold and then came back.
And then in '98 opened
up Temple Tattoo.
Now it's me, Heath Preheim,
Jason McAfee, and Chummy
Alexanian works there
part time.
Jason McAfee I met through
tattooing him.
He's a super solid dude.
We clicked, and I asked him to
come cover while I went to
Japan that first Tokyo
convention.
JASON MCAFEE: And he
randomly called me.
And I almost had a heart
attack in the shop.
We all did.
Me and Chops, and Kelly Krantz
and all these guys were like,
what the fuck?
How come Freddy Corbin
called you?
I don't know, I met him once.
And I was like, oh my god.
Like it was meeting some famous
rock star or something
for me at that time
because I was so
obsessed with tattooing.
And he gave me that for my
birthday couple years ago,
which is from a Tattoo Time
book, it's the original.
And it was a weird, emotional
thing because I'd looked at
that piece of flash forever
and ever and ever
since I was a kid.
And then to be holding it and
have it was like, oh my god.
I got the Tattoo Time books, and
that's how I first heard
about Freddy Corbin.
They're the old books that
Ed used to put out
on tattoos and stuff.
And I was probably 16.
I would look at them
and see pictures of
Freddy's tattoos in there.
Something attracted me
to the Freddy ones.
He's also the first
young dude.
To see this young guy with all
these old guys pop up and be
this little ghetto Nick
Cave kind of dude.
Like cool hair, and he had
diamonds in his teeth and
Mexican style frames.
MALE SPEAKER 2: Hey, how
are you doing Freddy?
Look at these.
JASON MCAFEE: He was a
sharp looking dude.
He wore cool jean vests with
Jesus on them, and he drove
cool, old cars, and that just
wasn't really happening.
HEATH PREHEIM: That's one of
those names, like when is the
first time you heard
Chevrolet?
I think I heard these
older, punker
girls say Freddy Corbin.
And it was one of those names
when you heard it where you're
like, man that's a cool name.
That dude must be cool.
And that's how it has
been to this day
[MUSIC PLAYING]
HEATH PREHEIM: He's
one of those dudes
that has that thing.
You or I might walk into the
room and be like, did you hear
I had a kid?
Did you hear I got
my face tattooed?
Duke Freddy, he walks into the
room and that's who he is.
You have to be, has he always
had that fucking
tattoo on his face?
He's fucking cool.
TIM HENDRICKS: Especially
today, you see all these
people with face tattoos
and neck tattoos.
And it's like, oh, my indie
band got signed.
I'm only 21, but I'm going
to get my neck tattooed.
With Freddy, he's been around
this for so long that he just
wears it well.
There's no one else that
can wear a face
tattoo like Freddy Corbin.
HEATH PREHEIM: I never thought
about it 'til right now, but I
can't picture him as a kid.
Like a 14-year-old or a
16-year-old in school reading
Catcher in the Rye.
He's always been slicked
back hair, tattoos.
How are you doing
bro, hey bro.
Bro is a gross word when most
people say it, but when he
says it, you're like
ah, yeah, bro.
JASON MCAFEE: Thanks
for the birthday
vacation, working here.
FREDDY CORBIN: Oh, of course,
you deserve it dude.
I told him the smartest thing he
did was fucking stay home.
At home vacations are
the way to go.
JASON MCAFEE: It's been nice.
HEATH PREHEIM: It's funny
because Jason McAfee is one of
my best friends.
And I go by 13 every day.
It's on my route.
And Freddy lives by 13 so
that's why I see him.
[LAUGHING]
FREDDY CORBIN: OK, yeah.
Can I ask you how do you feel
about this neighborhood being
gentrified?
MALE SPEAKER 3: We need
more marijuana.
FREDDY CORBIN: Oh yeah we do.
I hear that brother.
I say we never trust our
government, sonny, never.
Never get the chip, never
trust the president.
HEATH PREHEIM: 13 is a real
fucking tattoo shop.
Everyone's good that
works there.
But they're all fucking
fuck-ups that
tattoo, and it's rad.
Freddy's smart enough to hire
dudes that want to work.
Dudes that like to party.
Because I think that's important
in tattooing.
They used to have Friday
the 13th parties,
and you get $13 tattoos.
Freddy did a 13 on my butt as
a joke, but that's my only
Freddy Corbin tattoo.
I was drunk, and you leave there
like, god, who's going
to fucking clean this up?
What's Freddy going to think?
Freddy's going to walk in there
and go, I've done that
1,000 times bro.
Did you guys have a good time?
Hey next time, don't let someone
sit on my chair.
Or whatever, it's going
to be that simple.
FREDDY CORBIN: I'm not
really their boss.
I'm their friend, and I just
happen to be their boss.
It was a free for all for a
while because like I was
saying, we're all brothers
so nobody wants to
rat out their brother.
And when it comes down to
it, what I say goes.
And they all give me that
respect and they are all
wonderful about that.
It's almost like I've had to say
OK, if you're not going to
come in, you have to call me and
tell me because no one's
going to rat you out.
I need to know what's
going on.
I'm not going to be mad, but
I kinda gotta need to know
because there's been times where
someone will say oh, I
want to go down--
I'll go to send somebody up
to 13 because we're busy.
That's another reason why I
opened is to be our own
competition.
Tattoo 13, it was
a guerilla move.
I knew that this neighborhood
was going to blow up.
And I knew that--
I actually tried to open up in
this neighborhood, but nobody
would rent to me.
I opened it up about
a year and a half
after I opened up Temple.
It was premature.
I knew that it was premature,
but I went for it.
And it worked out really well.
I'm glad I didn't listen
to anybody.
OK, bye, you guys.
HEATH PREHEIM: I mean, our
economy is fucked right now,
but they're tattooing
every day there.
Jason's got a kid
and an ex-wife.
And he's gotta handle his
business and still party and
have a good time.
And he can do that working
for Freddy.
Freddy opened Temple
13 years ago.
So Jason was there from
the beginning.
JASON MCAFEE: I've seen the shop
go through so many insane
changes, it's pretty nuts.
Freddy was the first white
guy on this whole block.
When I first started working
here, everyone
thought I was him.
I would go to the store, and
they'd like Freddy, what's up?
And I was like oh,
I'm not Freddy.
He popped up in the middle of
this area and people were just
like, what the fuck?
Downtown Oakland used to
be totally different.
FREDDY CORBIN: This is actually
after we had been
open, and the windows got busted
out from the protests
from Oscar Grant getting shot.
HEATH PREHEIM: I'd tell someone
next to me on the
airplane, I'm from Oakland.
"Oh, god." That's what
everyone thinks of Oakland.
He could have opened a shop
in San Francisco.
Man, I get choked up thinking
about him making that decision
because Oakland means
so much to me.
But he chose to open
a shop downtown.
That neighborhood, when he
did it, was way cutty.
We'd skateboard there on
weekends because there's no
businesses down there.
No one wants to be down there.
There's no reason to
be down there.
FREDDY CORBIN: I don't want to
say it was a huge ghetto, you
know what I mean?
But it was crack head heaven.
So there isn't really a
reason to come over,
you know what I mean?
But I've worked in so many
low income areas and
was cool with that.
Plus I knew it made sense that
with San Francisco blowing up
the way it was, like Manhattan,
people have to
migrate east.
HEATH PREHEIM: The weed places
and all that shit are there
now because of him or because
someone had to pave the way.
And Freddy was the dude that--
it probably was the price,
probably how the space was
shaped, he knew he could
fit everyone in there.
But had enough foresight to
say, this is the spot.
FREDDY CORBIN: This is some
early Temple, Temple Tattoo,
Oakland tattooing.
"Fuck the world, I'm a killer,
you just don't know it yet."
This was this little Crip kid
that I had covered up BK on
and put his family's name on
him and stuff like that.
Even though I'm not really into
violence or whatever, I
love that whole East LA
gangster imagery.
I've always been really,
really attracted to it.
And that's why I've always
really liked working in places
like Philly, or Oakland, or
Sacramento, where there's a
bunch of kids from the hood
getting tattooed.
I could do tattoos like that all
day for weeks and not be
bummed out about it
at all, you know?
Anywhere there's a low income
area, you knew it.
You'd do pit bulls, you'd
do grim reapers.
You'd do cash money maker,
you'd do money signs.
Fuck the world, the world
with the fuck you finger
busting out of it.
Playboy bunny ring,
shit like that.
I think it's hilarious.
I love doing it too.
It's cool shit.
[MUSIC PLAYING]