-Yeah.
Did he jet?
-I guess, dude.
But you tell me he shouldn't
never talk shit because we
don't be talking shit
about nobody.
-That's cool.
-You respect us, we respect you,
you know what I'm saying?
-That's cool.
-Tell your boy,
-Where's his board at?
-I'll keep the [INAUDIBLE]
focused in on him.
PATRICK O'DELL: Hi, welcome back
to "Epicly Later'd." This
week's episode is about
the Menace team.
And it's not about any specific
person, it's just
sort of about a cultural
shift in skateboarding.
-Fuck you got to say, niggah?
PATRICK O'DELL: You know, LA,
New York, all these city kid
skaters that kind of came
together as the team Menace.
It's kinda thuggy, it's
kind of dangerous.
When I was a kid and somebody
had like the NWA tape and it
was really bad to have.
Menace was like skating's
version of that--
like skating's NWA.
Some of these skaters, like
Fabian and Steven Cales, they
ended up doing a lot
of time in jail.
Joey's found religion,
he has a family, he's
doing really well.
We caught up with Eric Pupecki
in Rhode Island.
Javier Nunez is doing great,
he's an actor.
So these shows aren't perfect.
Maybe four or five times I made
a plan with Green and
then it fell through.
I'm not talking shit on the guy,
I'm just saying he's hard
to a hold of.
Basically I'm saying
we don't have the
Kareem Campbell interview.
That's how it is.
For a long time I've kind of had
this on the back burner as
an episode I wanted to do.
Like, I should do a
Menace episode.
So I'm glad this is finally
coming out.
I hope you enjoy it.
BILLY VALDES: We had no Kareem
for, I don't know, forever.
He'll probably deny this,
but I claim I
taught him 360 flips.
This is when he was
on World SMA.
And I was trying to
get on Grind King.
That's like '89 or something.
PATRICK O'DELL: Tell me about
exactly how you got on Menace?
BILLY VALDES: Kareem was a hot
boy at the time, winning all
these contests.
Skating for world after
the whole, basically,
Girl/Chocolate team
now, or then--
I guess now it's
different, too.
Al Quinn started Girl
Skateboards, and Kareem had an
opportunity to start
his own company.
And since we had all been
friends for a while, I guess
he saw something in this.
No, that's boring.
SOCRATES LEAL: Kareem came
back, got on World.
We were all psyched.
And he was on World for a couple
years before he came up
with the idea for Menace and
just put together a team of
dudes that hung out in LA.
They always hung out at
that extra large shop.
So he put together that team
and said hey, wouldn't you
mind filming these guys?
I was like, oh yeah, I'm down
to film these dudes.
This is the first transfer tip
for Menace because that was
their first logo right there.
PATRICK O'DELL: What were the
plans with all the footage?
SOCRATES LEAL: Well, of course
we were going to try to make
them a video.
PATRICK O'DELL: What were
the challenges of that?
SOCRATES LEAL: That Kareem
needed to approve it.
It's his company and his first
video, and I feel him on that.
He wanted to make sure
it was top notch.
PATRICK O'DELL: He didn't think
it was good enough?
SOCRATES LEAL: I can't put words
in his mouth, you know?
All I know is that he just
kind of put a stop on it.
Filming for Menace was one of
those deals where it was at
the moment.
If you were there at a spot,
and I had the camera and
everyone else was kind
of along with
it, it would happen.
And if it didn't for whatever
reason, like we'd get kicked
out of a spot or he'd break his
board, then that day was
over and that would never
happen again.
PATRICK O'DELL: Were you ever
worried about going to some of
the sketchy neighborhoods
and stuff like that?
Because I always heard of like
Lockwood, people get their
cameras stolen.
SOCRATES LEAL: Yeah.
I mean, I found out about all
that after I had been filming
it for like a year or two.
One day we were there filming,
it was like a 4th of July, and
I remember hearing the shots.
But I was filming lines running
around the schoolyard.
PATRICK O'DELL: Originally,
not that many
people skated here?
FABIAN ALOMAR: No.
It was only a few gang members
right here from La Medalla
neighborhood.
And then when we started skating
here, they would kind
of give us a little
bit of static.
I've got uncles from that
same neighborhood.
And it turns out that my uncle
snatched them up and told them
that's my nephew and
his friends.
Those dudes are cool to skate
here whenever they want.
And you know, back then
I wasn't even trying
to look for no beef.
We were just trying to skate.
Trying to get away
from the beef.
GUY MARIANO: These kids were
like the outcasts of
skateboarding.
They didn't have the skateboard
image that people wanted.
I really like the fact that
when Menace was started,
Kareem was really good friends
with everybody in
skateboarding.
He could have handpicked just
top skaters, but he came for
Billy, Joey, Eric Pupecki
and Fabian.
It was the real thing.
It was just like you guys are a
little crew, and I want it.
ERIC PUPECKI: It was like kind
of the same thing as the
deluxe deal.
They don't know what
to do with me.
That's what Menace
is all about.
The team of guys that
no one knows what
the fuck to do with.
All right, I'll take
you, you and you.
Boom, now we got a team or
misfits or whatever.
-All you motherfucking
corns, eat.
ERIC PUPECKI: Like I
said, no contracts.
Not even like, hey Eric, would
you like to be on Menace
skateboards?
One day I'm on Menace now, I'm
hanging out with all of them,
I'm on the team.
So it was just kind
of nonchalant.
So that's why there was
no real money either.
It was just different times.
LEE SMITH: I skated for
ATM for about, I guess
it was like a year.
And that turned to 60/40
and kind of dissolved.
And then when Joey and those
guys got with Kareem, I guess
Kareem was looking for an am.
And they were like well, we were
already skating with Lee
on 60/40 at ATM, so let's
bring him over.
STEVEN CALES: I got out of
prison, right, and I'm hanging
out with Maurice Key.
He was going on a World
Menace tour.
So I said, man, I'm just going
to go see my boys.
So I'm on parole and I'm not
supposed to leave, but I know
I could sneak away
for a weekend.
I met up with Kareem
and all these guys.
And so we went skating, and
we did those demos.
I skated in the demos and
whatever, and I guess I skated
good enough and maybe the World
went back to wherever it
went to and I was on.
I was on Menace and somebody
was like hey, this little
kid's on Menace, too,
from out here.
And I was like oh yeah, who?
PATRICK O'DELL: What
did he look like?
STEVEN CALES: He's just little
with big hands and big arms.
He was a little pothead.
I was like dang, this
is a bad ass kid.
But it reminded me of me
because I was doing
that at that age.
JAVIER NUNEZ: Yeah, well I'm
not "Little Hob" no more.
Everyone knows me
for Little Hob.
It's been documented.
So like I said, from 11 to 13
being in New York a lot of
things were rolling for me.
Me and Maurice were skating that
night and Kareem happened
to see us do our thing.
Got Maurice Key on
World Industries.
And he put me on Menace before
it actually started, but it
was in the process of becoming
the real thing.
BILLY VALDES: We had plans for
Ivan Perez in Brooklyn.
I wanted to get Rick Ibaseta
on the team.
PATRICK O'DELL: Socrates was
saying that Shiloh was going
to get on, too.
Or, these was talk of
that or something.
BILLY VALDES: That's between
Shiloh and Kareem.
I don't know, I thought
at first it was, too.
I think that was the
original plan.
I don't know who changed it.
Kareem's the mastermind.
Like it said, if you look at
the bottom, [INAUDIBLE]
Mastermind distribution and
he's lurking in the
background.
PATRICK O'DELL: Are they much
different from 101, Blind,
Plan B, World?
SOCRATES LEAL: Well, yeah,
image-wise definitely.
Because right off the bat, it
seemed like their whole thing
was a thugged out image,
the whole Menace.
In the first one, I was like
beating up that kid.
SOCRATES LEAL: Yeah,
that wasn't a skit.
We were at Lockwood and that
was a friend of theirs.
And for some reason they always
use to get off on
hitting him really hard.
So yeah, that day it started
off as something simple.
And one of the dudes might let
a couple of those kicks or
punches go a little too far.
He got a little hurt
on that deal.
I think maybe they thought they
had to put a little more
effort into it because the
cameras were rolling.
JOEY SURIEL: Nothing was
scripted, everything was
spontaneous.
Before I can only probably count
two or three people that
ever used hip-hop in
a skate video.
Now looking back at those
specific times, it was just us
really showing the skateboard
world skateboarding through
our perspective.
-Like this, like this, yeah.
-Make it look like that,
bitch ass niggas.
-And I'll be honest with you,
I never thought that we made
the impact that obviously I've
come to know that we made.
Just from the response that
we've been getting from all
these people that we deal with
now on a different level.
And say wow, I remember what an
impact it had on our lives.
And we'd see that video part
over and over again every time
we'd go out and skate.
And I've said this before, I
don't think it had anything to
do with cutting edge
skateboarding.
But I think it had more to
do with the way we were
presenting skateboarding.
It wasn't like we were
inventing tricks.
But it was like the stuff we put
out, it was quality and it
was genuine.
-I think Valele thought Joey
was skating around with a
blunt around on the course.
-I think he thought a lot
of our behavior was
inappropriate.
-Back in those days,
skateboarders shouldn't
represent themselves that way,
which I think is corny.
Because I mean, you look at
fucking old Alva Dogtown Days.
We just kind of pulled an Alva
move in the '90s, I guess.
Got psyched on ourselves.