-If anyone in the crowd have a
headache, I can heal them in a
couple seconds.
You want to come?
All right.
And you can also use
some Psalms 3.
For our liquid, olive oil.
I put olive oil over this.
And I say, Lord, how are they
increased that trouble me.
Many are they that rise
up against me.
Many there be which say of
my soul, there is no
help for him in God.
Selah.
But thou, O Lord, are
a shield for me.
My glory, and the lifter
up of mine head.
I cried unto the Lord with my
voice, and he heard me out of
his holy hill.
I laid me down and slept.
I awaked, for the Lord
sustained me.
I will not be afraid of ten
thousands of people that have
set themselves against
me round about.
Arise, O Lord.
Save me, O my God, for thou hast
smitten all my enemies
upon the cheekbone.
Thou hath broken the teeth
of the ungodly.
Salvation belongeth
unto the Lord.
Thy blessing is upon
thy people.
Selah.
Let the words of my mouth and
meditation of my heart be
accepted in thy sight, O Lord,
my strength and my redeemer.
Give me your full name.
-Nicholas John Devereux.
-Father of the world, may thou
pleaseth me to be my physician
and helper.
Heal Nicholas--
-John Devereux.
From his headache.
Because I can find help with
thee and only with thee is
action to be taken.
In the name of God the
Father, God the Son,
God the Holy Spirit.
And the word
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
represents Lord of the word.
is a evil word.
The [INAUDIBLE] of the
head is right here.
Just a simple.
KRISHNA ANDAVOLU (OFFSCREEN):
How's your headache?
-Waiting.
-You're still waiting?
-Mm-hm.
Give it a second.
-As you can see from my facial
expression, I'm feeling much
better than before.
It feels--
vast improvement, vast
improvement from prior to
seeing Joseph.