MALE SPEAKER: And your hand
shakes from Parkinson's?
THOM DEVITA: Yes, and you
noticed my hand shaking?
MALE SPEAKER: And how long ago
did Parkinson's set in?
THOM DEVITA: About a year
and a half ago.
I was born with a
central tremor.
A central tremor shakes when
you pick something up.
Parkinson's stops when you
pick something up.
When the Parkinson's stops, the
central tremor immediately
takes over.
MALE SPEAKER: That
got you all in.
THOM DEVITA: There's
also another one.
You ever see somebody so
scared they shake?
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
THOM DEVITA: I asked this today
of the neurologist, if
being scared could make your
hands shake, if that was part
of a central tremor.
He says no, no, no, but that's
another kind of tremor and he
had a name for it.
I forgot the name, but I
think I got that also.
MALE SPEAKER: You have
all the tremors?
THOM DEVITA: All the
three tremors.
MALE SPEAKER: What are you
scared of, you think?
THOM DEVITA: It's mental.
You don't know, the mind works
without even you knowing it.
JOHN WYATT: Well, somebody
else told me that Thom
actually moved to Newburgh,
New York.
I know that he moved there,
because his wife took an
engineering job for IBM.
When I got up there, he greeted
me on the porch.
And I said to him, Thom,
I'm shocked that you
moved out of New York.
You never were comfortable
being outside of it.
And he said, but think
about this.
I always lived a couple blocks
from the Hudson River.
When I was a kid in Harlem, we
lived near the Hudson River,
when I was on the Lower East
Side, I wasn't far from it.
And then he pointed, and
he said there it
is, two blocks away.
MALE SPEAKER: How long have
you lived over here?
NICK BUBASH: Remember when we
moved out of your apartment on
Fourth Street?
There was that one closet
we'd never open, and you
said don't open it.
You remember that?
There was so much stuff.
Remember we had to hold the
stuff, I think [INAUDIBLE]
held the stuff.
And then we slammed the doors
of the truck real fast so it
wouldn't all fall out.
There was so much stuff.
We took the doors off the
hinges, everything, because he
had made art out
of everything.
And I drove the truck and Jenny
went the wrong way.
Oh boy, it was crazy getting
up here, but we did it.
SCOTT HARRISON: I mean, I'm sure
he probably would have
preferred to stay in Manhattan
his whole life, but that
didn't work out.
NICK BUBASH: Yeah, we
took a train out.
You remember when Cliff
Raven came?
SCOTT HARRISON: But he said if
you're not in Manhattan, you
might as well be anywhere.
And Newburgh was anywhere.
ROBERT RYAN: It's definitely
a pilgrimage.
I always feel great
after I go.
Well, first you make an
arrangement to go see him.
THOM DEVITA: Visits
by referral only.
ROBERT RYAN: Once the dog
mellows out and then you can
walk a little bit more
freely around.
And he'll start to show you all
this amazing art that he's
been making since he's moved
up there, and probably even
before he was up there.
His work area and his living
area are the same thing.
He lives within what he's
creating every day.
Going into Thom's home
studio was like the
next level for me.
I had seen his tattoos, I had
seen some of the art that he
had been making.
But to see it in his place is
like, now you're seeing the
true living art, it's
everywhere.
It's like going to a museum.
By the end, I'm not sure
what I'd even seen.
I'm just overwhelmed, there's so
much of it and it's such a
strong, powerful volume that
it's kind of disorienting
after a while.
THOM DEVITA: You want to
see a Sailor Jerry?
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
Is that an original?
THOM DEVITA: Yes.
MALE SPEAKER: And you put this
Gotham Tattoo stamp on it?
THOM DEVITA: Yes, it
belongs to me.
I can do anything
I want with it.
That's the way I feel about art,
if it belongs to you, you
can do anything you
want with it.
Unless you made a deal with
the artist that you
couldn't touch it.
I collect all kind of things.
MALE SPEAKER: I've noticed.
THOM DEVITA: I think they're
nice, they're good-looking.
NICK BUBASH: Thom and I were
always hunting for objects.
We'd go trashing, go into
stores, and antique stores or
junk shops.
And we were always looking
for objects, constantly.
That was one of his big things,
he got a lot of
inspiration out of anything.
My relationship with Thom
deVita, well, at this point I
suppose you could
say good friend.
But he was my mentor,
my teacher.
I first met him, I think,
about 1971.
MALE SPEAKER: Did you teach
Nick how to tattoo?
THOM DEVITA: You never tattooed
before you met me.
NICK BUBASH: No.
THOM DEVITA: He's the only guy
who ever tattooed in my shop.
NICK BUBASH: I tattooed in his
shop on Fourth Street.
I can't remember how
I found him.
I think I just found him, and
there he was, he was sitting
on the stoop.
I walked up to him and
said I was interested
in getting a tattoo.
I followed him into
his studio, and
that's how I met him.
I looked for him and
I found him.
I got these in 1973 or
something like that.
There's a big fish.
Here, I'll take my shirt off if
you promise not to take a
picture of my body.
I'm getting old and fat.
THOM DEVITA: I'm getting
old and skinny.
I am old and skinny.
NICK BUBASH: This is a
early Japanese fish.
MALE SPEAKER: It looks a lot
like your style of tattooing.
NICK BUBASH: It's where
it all began, man.
ROBERT RYAN: Definitely two guys
that have spent a lot of
time together and have been
through a lot together.
And I think they're probably
best friends, as far as best
friends can be.
NICK BUBASH: Good bye.
I love you, you old
[INAUDIBLE].
THOM DEVITA: I'm not a hugger.
NICK BUBASH: He won't hug you.
ROBERT RYAN: And Nick has so
much respect for Thom.
I think he feels like Thom
helped him in a great way.
NICK BUBASH: When I met him,
he was probably 40.
I was 19.
I was trying to make art, and
I was doing everything you
have to do to stay alive
in New York.
I was driving a cab, I was doing
landscaping, I was doing
whatever I needed to do.
I was basically just a working
stiff with an idea that I
wanted to be an artist.
I found Thom.
I saw what he was doing.
I really got turned on
by the fact that he
was actually an artist.
I thought well, I'm going to do
some big drawings and take
them down here and
show them to him.
So I did some big
dragon drawings.
And when he saw the drawings,
I can remember clearly, he
said to me, you can come back
here anytime you want to come.
And I said OK, man, and I
was there all the time.
deVita's influence was
enormous on me.
Thom taught me the mental part
of it-- the attitude, the
lifestyle, and how you create
your own reality.
He was my greatest influence.
ROBERT RYAN: The deVita
influence on Nick's work is
very, very strong.
NICK BUBASH: "The Porcupine of
God," it's painted over an old
lithograph.
ROBERT RYAN: And Nick comes
from definitely a more
schooled art background.
He does fine art sculpture,
and he does also great
paintings and drawings and
he does these amazing
assemblages.
You can definitely see Thom's
influences there, and it's
really present in his work.
NICK BUBASH: Thom did a
lot of assemblages.
I think that's probably where
I got the inclination to
assemble things into works of
art, because he that a lot.
This is the thinking table.
Believe it or not, there's
order to this.
And my philosophy is that
I bring order to
the chaos that surrounds.
The chaos forces the order.
This one I imagine is like a
prehistoric animal with the
largest set of horns ever
seen or ever discovered.
These things evolve.
And sometimes I'll get obsessed
with one object and
I'll start working on it.
But at times I'll be passing by
and I'll move something on
it or change something.
That's kind of how
this table works.
But as you can see, I have a
million things down here and
I'm adding to them.
Hopefully I'll get up to two or
three million before I die.
Thom's never been
to this studio.
I think it's kind of getting
hard for him to move around.
He's getting tired and old.
Who knows, he may
live to be 100--
I hope he does.
I hope he lives to be 200.
I hope he outlives me
because I don't want
to see him go ever.
So here's the list of things
you have to do, right?
These are the books you have
to sign and number.
Number two, I think all
you have to do is--
THOM DEVITA: I won't remember
all of that.
NICK BUBASH: Well look, books
to sign and number.
Two, 17, 18, 19, 20.
THOM DEVITA: Here's what I
wanted you to do, is to do one
of these for yourself.
This was you can tell
me [INAUDIBLE].
NICK BUBASH: OK, give
me a piece of paper.
If you have any questions,
you know what to
do with those books.
I'm going to call you every
goddamn day until--
THOM DEVITA: After you
sell them all.
ED HARDY: Oh, he drives
Nick crazy.
I mean, Nick will tell you.
He'll call me up and
go Jesus Christ.
And we're trying to help
Thom out a lot, but
he's just who he is.
THOM DEVITA: What were
we going to do?
NICK BUBASH: We're going to
work on my piece here.
THOM DEVITA: Oh, we're going
to do it on the original?
NICK BUBASH: No, on this one.
Yeah, on the original,
not on the book.
THOM DEVITA: OK, I'm confused.
NICK BUBASH: We collaborated
on a bunch of stuff.
He would send me stuff and then
I'd re-do it, and then
he'd re-do it.
And finally he told
me [INAUDIBLE]
I didn't know what I was
doing and he quit.
He didn't like what
I was doing.
Were you going to make the
whole goddamn thing red?
THOM DEVITA: No, Sherlock.
If you don't like it,
you can erase it.
NICK BUBASH: If I don't like
it, I can erase it.
He was never mean or harmful.
He would criticize
you, there's no
two ways about that.
He would say well,
do you like this?
And I'd say no, I
don't like it.
And he'd say well, you
just aren't advanced
enough to like it.
THOM DEVITA: Nick, did you
see the poster for the
show we were in?
This is one that I made up.
NICK BUBASH: Mine and Ed's don't
have the copper border
that he put on there.
But when I go home I'm going to
put a copper border on mine
same that Thom did.
THOM DEVITA: You don't know
what brush I used.
NICK BUBASH: Well, I mean, how's
anybody going to know?
THOM DEVITA: If I hadn't told
you it was copper, he would
have done it in gold.
NICK BUBASH: No.
You know what, you
can use that.
I know what to use.
THOM DEVITA: Well, you would
have done it in gold.
NICK BUBASH: No, I would
have done it in copper.
I've learned to use copper.
JOHN WYATT: It could be
argumentative, but I think a
lot of that was he liked to
play a lot of semantics.
ROBERT RYAN: That's me
getting tattooed.
I'm not sure who took
this photo.
So you remember?
THOM DEVITA: I claim all them
things to be mine beyond
[INAUDIBLE].
ROBERT RYAN: But you couldn't
do the tattoo and take the
photo at the same time, so
someone had to take it.
THOM DEVITA: That's
not important.
MALE SPEAKER: Do you ever get
nervous that you're going to
misspeak around him?
ROBERT RYAN: Always.
But he'll tell me
that I misspoke.
THOM DEVITA: It's true, but
it's a little mixed up.
No, that's not what
I'm saying.
I said yes, yeah, no.
ROBERT RYAN: Ed still has the
stencil for your dragon on the
center of your chest.
THOM DEVITA: No, he doesn't.
ROBERT RYAN: No?
THOM DEVITA: I got
the stencil.
ROBERT RYAN: Oh yeah?
THOM DEVITA: I was thinking
about it the other day, but I
haven't seen it for a while.
ROBERT RYAN: Do you think
maybe he took it?
THOM DEVITA: No.
Unless I cut another stencil
and I gave him that one.
CLAYTON PATTERSON:
Thom is an au
contraire kind of character.
His whole thing is
kind of arguing
and setting up debates.
And it's a certain kind of
Italian, a little Sicilian
kind of thing.
Throwing a lot of salt in there
and the fire and getting
the sparks going.
NICK BUBASH: [INAUDIBLE]
machines and you could tattoo
with them, but it was tough.
It was tough to get the
coloring with them.
THOM DEVITA: No, you could
tattoo with a Spaulding
machine if you know
how to tattoo.
NICK BUBASH: Right,
that's true.
THOM DEVITA: If you don't know
how to tattoo, you got to go
to somebody else maybe.
NICK BUBASH: Do you understand
my point?
Like, with a better
tool you can--
THOM DEVITA: No.
ED HARDY: I don't know if I've
ever seen Thom visibly excited
in my life, except if he gets
mad about something.
He's really stubborn.
He's really opinionated.
I mean, you can get into an
argument with him about what
the correct term is if you're
locking the card door.
I mean, you just get into
stuff all the time.
THOM DEVITA: What's this guy you
mentioned the other day?
NICK BUBASH: R. Crumb.
THOM DEVITA: Yeah,
I dislike him.
NICK BUBASH: You don't
like R. Crumb?
THOM DEVITA: No, I don't
like cartoons.
You understand that?
NICK BUBASH: But you've got
nothing against R. Crumb?
THOM DEVITA: I don't know
him, so I don't know
anything about him.
I don't like his work.
NICK BUBASH: You don't
like his work?
THOM DEVITA: I don't
like cartoons.
NICK BUBASH: OK, all right.
You don't like cartoons.
I get the point.
You didn't even like Al Capp?
THOM DEVITA: Not even Al Capp.
MALE SPEAKER: Do a lot of kids
skateboard past your--
THOM DEVITA: No,
not that many.
NICK BUBASH: Thom puts rocks out
there so they can't do it.
THOM DEVITA: No, I
don't mind kids.
It looks all right for kids.
But for grownups to be on a
skateboard, it looks stupid.
NICK BUBASH: Yeah.