uh... is because the get heat revealed
information the government did you want
you know it's arleigh secrets
well the guardian has done a terrific
piece along with bbc
uh... headache
at that
shows exactly what we're off to his ad
features two guys colonel james
kaufman retired and colonel james still
retired
they were quite retired because they
went back into iraq and work with
general petraeus
and the rest of our forces
to help the iraqis set up special police
commandos
now those
special police units
one-up doing a tremendous amount of
torture
and oh by the way some desk once
in fact at the height of the civil war
in iraq
three thousand people were showing up
dead
every single moms
are was name enough to believe at the
time
that hey listen we open up that
pandora's box so we were responsible for
what happened afterwards
but i didn't think that we actually
participated in
well it turns out that we at least gave
tacit approval and oftentimes active
approval
for exactly some of the most hideous
things
that were being done in iraq
and when you see that
district colonel james till you begin to
understand why
first of all he was the same exact i we
sat down the el salvador
to set up the
death squads there
and guess what i have an el salvador
a tremendous civil war just like in iraq
where there are desk was and then
retaliation
and ambitious cycle of violence so why
not repeat that mistake in fact
celebrated castio as a senior d_e_a_
agent
when he got that still was characterized
another office of the hour on spoke his
reset
i first heard about colonel james still
gonna rock and i said
they're gonna implement what is known
as a salvadoran option in iraq
and that's exactly what happened and i
was devastated 'cause i knew the
atrocities that we're going to current
iraq
which we do have occurred
in south howell salvador
and of course it turns out he was right
about that
in case you're wondering you forgot also
there was a long time ago
how many people be killed in the war now
some of the wrist most country in the
latin america
seventy five thousand s
thanks a lot colonel steel really
appreciated
so of course dick cheney rumsfeld look
at them go mission accomplished nicely
done right wing death squads
let's enum over iraq
throughout the guardian piece you see
rumsfeld lavish ng preys on steel
all we've got the right guy in iraq
this guidance steel he's doing the right
things for us
and of course
cheney had worked with him in panama as
well when he was part of the george h w
bush administration
uh... and by the way so now so there was
thirty five thousand as having doubts
that we have in iraq
well according to those same documents
that were leaked through with the leaks
but is the government estimates so it is
actually incredibly conservative ulo
one hundred nine thousand and thirty two
deaths in iraq between oh four oh nine
including over sixty six
fallows and
civilians
we must be sold proud
not even associated press has both of
those numbers at higher livid over a
hundred ten thousand that's
course some other organizations in the
past may be the best
up to six hundred thousand i mean the
scene one estimate over a million
but everyone agrees at least a hundred
and ten thousand deaths
including a tremendous numbers for
itself
where these guys are these connected to
java trails and higher correct
pearl jam's cough and cold sore in
stripes that he was quote
the traces eyes and years
out on the ground in iraq
fantastic
uh... now
let me go to
the video from
uh... this series todd green tree
who's gonna talk about colonel steals
role
it'll still rescue vehicle
who understands how to conduct
intelligence driven operations projects
operational sells insurgency terrorist
organization
so he knows how to operate that
is a good to be a successful because i a
definition of success right
but one thing is clear
he's doing this
at the behest of don so they came in job
but resin fact
gentle mont hubbard elsa mari
who was uh... senior general iraq at the
time said
they worked hand-in-hand now that's a
sure frantic hoffman
and uh... temperate rain is
i never saw them apart
in the fifth forty or fifty times i saw
them inside the detention centers
they do everything that was going on
there
the torture
hobo kinds of torture
general
ought not to be was ahead of the special
commandos
so that anybody knows what i have been
it was ham he's a guy who ordered all of
it
he says quote
until i left
that america's new about everything i
did
they knew what was going on in the
interrogation is
and they knew the detainees
so did we know what was happening you
better
no question about it
jumble one guy that i also mari again
quote
they were secret never declared
but the american top brass in iraqi
leadership new all about these prisons
the things that went on their
controlling murder
porter the hardly a sort of porter
i've ever seen
so they sought and they said the
americans absolutely nobody researching
deporting
detention centers let alone the best was
roaming the country
so then we go to general montevideo
somali one more time he says
now beginning to describe the torture
i remember a forty-year-old was tied to
a libros columns
and he was tied up with his legs above
its head
whose whole body was blue
because of the impact of the cables
with which he had been beat
now there's more videos explaining some
of the torture
including by american journalist and
western journalists there at the time
they were too extreme detainees for
information on the insurgency
this year's to spin on the other side of
things also that you know as you see
this is not staying until the discomfort
level
first of all the things that went on
that at least ratings and about
courtroom provides the idea sort of sort
of thing i have received but two dot he
is
so does present but i revert with the
time was on assignment from the new york
times
another reporter peter masa also
assignment there
and they saw what they're all eyes what
was happening
more on that
lena lou linda library into here in
seattle and i was making rice and tomato
terrible screens this initial all our
lives
but it wasn't they're kind of religious
ecstasy or something like that these
were the first things that uh...
tenncare
business to start shutting
that at the clock willing for the
streets
these last two screens online
house lost
the manager and their seeming to enjoy
um... the prisoner screams
was a man who conducted those operations
he's also the same one that i quoted
earlier saying that america's new
everything i did
and those other two were reporters
who couldn't believe
that they would be interviewing steel
and there would be a blot of pooled near
the detainees is still would be
would find any relevant would move on
there was one
pepper tubular time according to those
two regulus present peter mah sin and
some other generals that were there
including the gentleman i
quoted earlier more montana also mari
saying i was well colonel steel
they open the door
and you see a guy hanging upside-down
bloodied
this note
calmly closes the door and moves on
he knows what's happening
so what in fact that they did
let's hear from one of the guys who was
to work
schindler everyone though
will be blindfolded and handcuffed
behind our banks and then they would be
to shovel sometimes would be tied to a
space wall will be home from the ceiling
by opponents of the national news will
be dissipated and wallow
literally stores long litany
electrocuted me let me from the ceiling
they're pulling up my is with players
stamping ahead asking about my wife
saying they would bring her head
i remember adams how they came into the
library but he told captains arriving
captain allen resume the prisoners
turned dislocated shoulders like this is
because people were having to undergo
surgery when they were released in the
library
at one point they actually ran a reality
show in iraq in is unbelievable
with a we show the tortured detainees
kind of rubbing it in people's faces is
what we do so you better watch out
now that was the height of the sectarian
conflict with thousands are dying every
single mom
was a really like it was a turn people
finally jumper trance have a call in and
say hey listen at least though show the
tortured people on t_v_
is he not merciful
now if you don't believe
iraqi generals are you going to believe
the reporters a you don't believe the
people who were torture
well the guardian also found
some u_s_ soldiers and troops
that were there
recourse on them thus a man from the
sixty nine armand rasmus soldier
who's appointed some are in two thousand
five he says
it was like the nazis
the gestapo basically
they the commandos
would essentially torture anybody that
they had good reason to suspect
knew something was part of this urgency
were supporting it
and people knew about that
in saying that
the troops knew all about the americans
knew about it
the commanders knew all about about it
one of these brave u_s_ troops execute
on the record is names neal smith
there's a twenty-year-old mc medications
some are
he's now born again christian and trying
to make amends for what he thinks he did
in rak nieces qu
what was pretty widely known in our
battalion deftly inopportune
was that they were pretty violin with
their interrogation is
they would be people shocked electric
shock
stabbed them i don't know what else
sounds like pretty awful things
one last soldier
who was actually handing over people to
be torture
these detainees said quote
if somebody gets arrested
and we hand them over to mold
they're going to get their balls hooked
electrocuted
where they're going to get beaten or
raped up an ass with a coke bottle
or something like that
what we
the right wing that's wise to do in el
salvador
that led to a broadcast civil war there
with seventy five thousand dead
we get a d_n_a_ in iraq
and what we have
the same exact results
desk once courtroom
elimination of political opponents
and what happened
a hundred and ten thousand dead
at least
we for the love of god stop sending
colonel steeled into these situations
this is what we found out about our
government
this is what our democracy was up to
if we can all about being decent human
beings
the light on for the world as we claim
we are
we should never do this again
colonel still is not an american hero
he does not productive
he is the exact opposite result so would
be seen him in beings would want
these are not some sort of
glorious heroes as they were
review you know
made out to be by the right wing during
the contra scandal by the ricardo still
involved in the contra scandal of course
and they do these hideous things again
and again
and we have to stop them
the fact that god we found out
where they did this time around so that
we might be for people to prevented the
next time around
and how do we find out bradley many
that is of course twice
possibly facing a life sentence
how about the guys who
did the torture
who ran the desk wives
who taught people how to do the torture
in the best clubs
they of course
are free to go