who are in order,
Bonnie Burton.
BONNIE: Hello.
FELICIA: Kiala Kasebee.
KIALA: Hello.
FELICIA: Veronica Belmont.
VERONICA: Hello.
FELICIA: And me, Felicia Day.
Monthly we have a different book
and a different alt book
that we discuss.
And we talk about just general
things as well
that are on our forums.
We have a group on
goodreads.com.
And it's under Vaginal Fantasy
so just search there and you
can join in on the discussion
during the month around the
books that we're reading.
Before we get into the book this
month, which was Succubus
Blues, how's was everybody's
holiday?
BONNIE: First of all,
you have to mention
we're all in our pajamas.
FELICIA: Oh yeah.
And I don't even understand
how that happened.
BONNIE: That's my fault.
Because it's a Sunday and on
Sundays I get up late gamer
style like at around one
and then walk my dog.
And then get back into my pj's
and spend the entire day
reading comics.
VERONICA: Your dog lets
you wake up at one?
BONNIE: My dog is awesome.
Sophie has a snooze button.
VERONICA: Oh my God.
KIALA: Well I just never
get out of my pajamas.
But these are fancier pajamas
that I got for Christmas.
BONNIE: They are.
Are those silk?
KIALA: Yeah, or something.
They're silky.
FELICIA: Was that the best
present that you got?
KIALA: No, I think this was the
best present that I got.
BONNIE: Aw.
VERONICA: That's cute.
KIALA: It's a Squishable and
it's limited edition.
And it's like 35 out of 1,000.
And I named her Anna
Kareninamonk, because I've
been watching Anna
Karenina a lot.
I love her.
BONNIE: Do you want
to see what I
got myself for Christmas?
FELICIA: Is that the favorite
thing you got for Christmas
that's saying something
about yourself?
BONNIE: I got a dead bat.
VERONICA: Whoa, hey, dead bat.
That's a dead bat.
BONNIE: It's a dead bat.
VERONICA: That's nice.
BONNIE: Thanks a lot.
It's for my taxidermy
collection.
FELICIA: Where do you go to get
something like that Bonnie?
BONNIE: Believe in or not, San
Francisco has two whimsical
taxidermy stores.
One's called Love To Death which
is on Oddities, which
you can watch the TV
show Oddities.
And the other one's called
Paxton Gate and it's in the
[INAUDIBLE].
I'm like Norm at both of them.
They know me on a first
name basis.
Because I have a lot of
taxidermy in my house, which
probably explains why I'm
going to die alone.
KIALA: Paxton Gate's the one
right by the McSweeney store,
the pirate store, right?
BONNIE: Yeah, it's right next
to McSweeney's store.
KIALA: And Borderlands
on that same--
FELICIA: That sounds like
a fun place to visit.
VERONICA: On the most
awesome block ever.
KIALA: Yeah it's the
best block and it's
just an amazing store.
BONNIE: Yeah Felicia next time
you come visit, and Kiala, we
have to do a little trip.
KIALA: That's my favorite area,
Valencia, that whole area.
BONNIE: Veronica, yeah, you
know that area well too.
VERONICA: Definitely.
BONNIE: Everybody knows
that place.
FELICIA: Veronica you got
something for Christmas that
you should bring in the room.
BONNIE: Yes.
VERONICA: I can't bring it
in the room but hold on.
Let me show you the thing.
Hold on, let's see.
FELICIA: You've got
to bring that in.
VERONICA: Let me get inception
for a second.
Can you see it?
FELICIA: Aw.
Oh my gosh.
VERONICA: That is Liberty.
BONNIE: Why aren't you tweeting
the puppy more?
VERONICA: I'm trying to,
although I'm so busy half the
time trying to get her to not
destroy me that it's kind of
difficult to.
She's a biter.
She's a little bit of a biter.
So she's great though.
She's a guide dog puppy that
we're raising until she's
around 15 months if all goes
according to plan.
And then when she's 15 months
she'll hopefully go to guide
dog puppy college and help
out a blind person.
BONNIE: Aw.
FELICIA: That's beautiful, but
I would never be able to let
my puppy go.
KIALA: That's going
to be hard.
FELICIA: That's going to
be horrible, dude.
VERONICA: She's a lot of work
so we'll see how that goes.
FELICIA: I told you dogs
were not easy.
They'll come up to me
and look at you
like, let's do something.
And you just--
what do you want from me?
BONNIE: I don't know but
my dog's pretty cool.
She's asleep right now.
VERONICA: Well the hard part is
by the time they get really
well trained and kind of chill
and you can take them
everywhere is when you have
to give them away.
So by the time you get to that
perfect point you're like, OK.
Go out into the world.
BONNIE: It's almost
like dating.
As soon as they're awesome,
they leave.
VERONICA: Yeah.
KIALA: I'm opening this because
I can't stand--
FELICIA: Oh yeah, what are
we drinking today?
VERONICA: Hot Toddy.
FELICIA: What's in a Hot Toddy
Veronica, for people who
aren't familiar?
VERONICA: I'm using Bulleit
bourbon, also
honey, lemon, and tea.
FELICIA: Nice.
VERONICA: My little tea
plant from Adagio.
FELICIA: What are you
doing, Bonnie?
BONNIE: I'm drinking,
in my Batman
glass, coffee and Kahlua.
FELICIA: Oh nice.
Kiala, what are you drinking?
KIALA: Tiny champagne.
A Chandon--
VERONICA: Do you have
any orange juice?
KIALA: No.
It's a mimosa without, just
hold the orange juice.
BONNIE: It's just Mo.
Mi.
VERONICA: It's a mo.
BONNIE: Sa.
KIALA: But it's a
twist off cap.
I am the trashiest.
BONNIE: You know what?
VERONICA: I don't like
twist off caps.
KIALA: I like them but
I feel not classy.
BONNIE: You should try the
Sophia Coppola champagne.
I think it's pink and that
has a twist off cap.
FELICIA: Ooh.
I like her movies.
BONNIE: Also if you want to make
Bellinis there's a really
good peach champagne.
FELICIA: You had grumpy
cat face on Kiala.
KIALA: Yeah--
BONNIE: OK.
Well--
FELICIA: Oh wait,
sorry Bonnie.
KIALA: Oh I'm sorry Bonnie.
FELICIA: You were finishing
your pink champagne.
Pink champagne.
BONNIE: Oh yeah, I was just
saying that I drink way over
the top lame ass champagne.
So I always drink peach flavored
champagne, and I mix
it with peach juice,
and make Bellinis.
Oh you guys are all making
a horrible face.
VERONICA: We were making
the grumpy cat face.
FELICIA: We're doing
grumpy cat face.
BONNIE: Am I being
too white trash?
I mean, I only drink Cristal
in a diamond goblet.
VERONICA: You've got to get
sturgeon face in there too.
It's all about the
sturgeon face.
BONNIE: No, do grumpy cat.
Do grumpy cat, Veronica.
Grumpy cat.
VERONICA: There we go.
FELICIA: I think we lost--
I went to Jamaica for
the holidays.
And I didn't do--
well I actually didn't
do much.
But at the airport they had a
couple things that I got.
So I'm drinking this overproof
rum, which I
didn't know they made.
I don't understand.
Is that more alcohol then?
VERONICA: Yeah, I guess.
Is that like overclocking
your PC except with rum?
FELICIA: It's 63%
volume alcohol.
Is that a lot?
BONNIE: Let's find out.
VERONICA: 60%?
60% is pretty high.
FELICIA: 63.
VERONICA: 63% is pretty high.
FELICIA: And then I got this
Magnum Tonic Wine with iron
and vitamins made
with vigorton.
VERONICA: What?
I want that.
FELICIA: No but look, I just
thought it was appropriate for
Vaginal Fantasy.
BONNIE: Is that Magnum
P.I. on it?
FELICIA: Look at the label.
There's a guy and a
girl making out.
There's her booty.
There's a guy.
KIALA: That is a monkey.
BONNIE: That's a monkey.
FELICIA: No, it's a lady.
BONNIE: It's a monkey holding
a coconut on a skateboard.
FELICIA: No, it's a chick with
some boobs, coconut boobs.
BONNIE: This is the worst
workshop test ever.
VERONICA: I've got
a lovely bunch of
coconuts, do do do do.
FELICIA: No, no.
It doesn't look good.
It's gotten vigorton on it.
VERONICA: That's what my mom
got me for Christmas.
KIALA: It sounds Australian.
BONNIE: Wait, what?
What's that?
VERONICA: My mom got me
this for Christmas.
BONNIE: Is that two
guys making out?
FELICIA: Oh no.
What is that?
KIALA: Modernism
and the Women's
Popular Romance in Britain.
I read that for everyone.
Because I read.
VERONICA: Thank you.
BONNIE: Thanks for reading
aloud, thank you.
VERONICA: And I think that looks
like Matthew McConaughey
on the cover.
KIALA: It does.
And Myrna Loy.
Myrna Loy and Matthew
McConaughey.
BONNIE: We're in the
French [INAUDIBLE].
The French [INAUDIBLE].
VERONICA: By Martin Hipsky.
I'm going to read it.
It's going to be pretty cool.
FELICIA: That's really cool.
OK.
So I guess we should get
on with the show.
BONNIE: Which one are we
talking about first?
FELICIA: Well, I want
to give a shout out
to the local meetup.
The local meetups.
We had a bunch of meetups
this month.
And there's some people who
are getting together in
various places in January to
talk about this month's book.
In New York City a group
met at Argo Tea.
In Orange County a bunch of
people met at the Disney's
Grand Californian hotel.
In Portland people
met at Lucky Lab.
Washington D.C. had a meet up
at the Portrait museum.
And upcoming ones, North
Hollywood is meeting on the
sixth to discuss the books we're
talking about now at the
SteamPunk Cafe.
The Twin Cities is
having a meetup.
Atlanta is putting together
a meetup.
And there's one in Chicago.
So if you want to make your own
meetup you just go to the
Goodreads Group and there is a
thread for local meetups and
they're actually really fun.
So there tend to be a bunch
every month that everybody
gets together to do.
So yes.
The book this month is called
Succubus Blues.
And I will give you a
short description.
"When it comes to jobs in hell,
being a succubus seems
pretty glamorous.
A girl can be anything
she wants.
The wardrobe is killer, and
the mortal men will do
anything just for a touch.
But Seattle succubus
Georgina Kincaid's
life is far from exotic.
She works at a local bookstore
and she has easy access to the
sexy writer Seth Mortensen but
there's something wicked going
on in Seattle's demon
underground." So that is by
Richelle Mead.
That was the book we all
read this month.
And what did we think
about it?
BONNIE: I liked it.
FELICIA: And why?
BONNIE: The end.
FELICIA: Thank you for joining
Vaginal Fantasy with me.
VERONICA: I liked it.
BONNIE: I told you that I read
all the comments and they said
I needed to not talk so much.
So that's it.
FELICIA: Never read the
comments Bonnie.
BONNIE: I know, but I have to.
VERONICA: There's a Twitter
account called "Don't Read
Comments," and all
it is a daily
reminder to not read comments.
BONNIE: As one of the hosts it's
our obligation to answer
questions in the comments too.
VERONICA: Yeah.
I get it.
BONNIE: I liked it because
weirdly enough I super
identified with the main
character because I drink
three mochas a day and
I talk to my pet.
And I crush on authors.
And I've had author encounters
where I was a total idiot
because I didn't know
who they were.
And, yeah.
There's just a lot of things.
Other than the fact that I
can't shapeshift into hot
chicks with horns yet, I really
identified with her.
I liked her.
And I liked the writing
style in this book.
It was really easy
to get into.
There wasn't a lot of hardcore
sexy times enough.
But I just liked the writing
style and I liked all the
characters.
And I could picture it as a TV
show or a movie really, really
fast and easily.
I read the book quickly
because I didn't
want to put it down.
Which is funny because the main
character, Georgina in
the book, she talks about how
she reads books slowly because
she really wants that first time
she reads a good book to
last a long time, which
I've done that too.
I didn't do that
with this book.
I just read it really quick.
It was really good.
I liked it.
FELICIA: It's funny that you
say that about a TV show
because there is a Canadian
show called Lost
Girl about a succubus.
And I think it's on Syfy
channel right now.
I've always wanted
to marathon it.
BONNIE: It's good.
FELICIA: But a lot of people,
especially on Twitter, are
really big fans of it.
So I'm going to definitely
check it out.
And then someone said this book
was optioned to be a TV
show last year.
So you never know.
VERONICA: That almost never
means anything unfortunately.
FELICIA: Kiala, what did
you think of the book?
KIALA: I really liked it.
I thought that there was some
kind of cliche, sloppy writing
bits, but overall I
really liked it.
And I liked her crushing on an
author, because I've gone
through that exact same thing.
In fact, one time Dan Kennedy,
he's one of my favorite
writers from McSweeney's.
Yeah, from Moth.
And he was coming here to read
at Powell's and I have friends
who work there and they
know him very well.
And I thought that I was going
to get a chance to meet him,
we were going to go
out afterwards.
But I wasn't sure that
was going to happen.
It was all kind of new.
And I had written a blog post on
my personal blog about how
I wanted him to look at me and
tell me we were going to run
away together and he was going
to take away from all this
filth and poverty.
And so we we all did end up
going out after his reading.
And then they told him about my
blog post and he pulled out
his iPhone and he read
it aloud to me.
VERONICA: Oh my God, that
was embarrassing.
That's like a Moth episode.
That's basically
a Moth episode.
BONNIE: Nice.
KIALA: And then at the end of
the night he shook my hand and
he looked down at me and he
said, "I'm going to take you
away from all this filth
and poverty." And it
was the best thing.
VERONICA: But then he didn't.
BONNIE: Obviously he didn't.
VERONICA: He didn't.
FELICIA: He's a liar.
KIALA: He's a liar.
VERONICA: He's a liar.
KIALA: Anyway, so that, I really
identified with that.
And I actually enjoyed
the story a lot.
And I was surprised
at the end.
I thought I knew what was going
to happen and I didn't
know what was going to happen.
FELICIA: That's interesting.
OK, Veronica, you look
a little skeptical.
What do you think?
VERONICA: No, I loved it.
I thought it was fun.
I thought it was a really
great book.
I had a great time reading it.
Georgina as a character I think
was probably one of the
more relatable characters
we've read in
a really long time.
I could picture everything
in her life so exactly.
It's one of the first books
where I was almost picturing
myself as her, except obviously
not as hot because
she's super hot.
But at the bookstore--
FELICIA: You're super hot.
BONNIE: You're super hot.
Come on.
VERONICA: But at the bookstore
I was picturing my hometown
Barnes and Noble and there was
this little metaphysical store
that I used to go to when I
was a teenager in my town.
I was picturing that as
the place she went to
go talk with Eric.
Or whatever his name was.
And just the clubs I used to go
to in Boston is where she
got trashed that night that they
were playing the show and
she went and made out with
him near the bathroom.
So all of that stuff for some
reason, it was like maybe it
was because it was modern
times and she was really
living more in the regular world
than any other kind of
fantastical kind of world.
It was just really easy
to relate to her.
And I knew one of the two love
interests was going to be the
trouble at the end.
I knew it was one of them.
I just couldn't really figure
out who it was until right up
when it happened.
And then I thought that the
sister being the other, the
sister being the bitch
from the other
bookstore, that was fun.
That was a fun little twist.
So it all came together
really, really
nicely in the end.
And I liked her very much
as a character.
So I thought this was
a series I would
like to continue reading.
FELICIA: Yeah, I definitely want
to pick up the next one.
By the way, your
not being sexy.
Somebody just sent a comment,
said they want to
put a baby in you.
So come on.
KIALA: Baby [INAUDIBLE].
VERONICA: I've got a puppy,
that's enough to deal with.
No babies.
One thing keeping me up at night
is all I need right now.
FELICIA: Oh my gosh.
I agree with everybody here.
I actually was a fan of this
author from her other series
which I can't remember
the name of it.
It's about a shaman or,
I don't want to
talk about that series.
But it was a very enjoyable
series too.
So I'd never read this one.
And I think this was one
of her first books.
She also has a very popular
series called
Vampire Academy, I think.
VERONICA: I've hear
of that, yeah.
FELICIA: Yeah it's a teen
series, which I don't really
read a lot of teen series.
VERONICA: That's out on
Penguin, isn't it?
That's Penguin.
FELICIA: Yeah I think so.
BONNIE: How is that
not a TV show?
That sounds like that
should be a TV show.
FELICIA: I think everything gets
optioned and then it just
never gets made.
That's just TV for you.
But I really liked
the characters.
I agree.
I definitely wanted
to live her life.
It was very relatable
and grounded.
The only thing I kept wondering
was like, she wasn't
a succubus very often.
So there was never a lot of
conflict with her succubus
needs or job.
There was not a lot of pressure
on her to fulfill the
succubus need.
And she's been a succubus for
1,000 years or hundreds of
years or whatever, it felt like
she would have had more
of a job there.
But if you suspend your
disbelief there I loved all
the characters around her.
I've fanned on so
many authors.
That's my trigger point.
I don't care about actors.
But I actually sent a tweet to
Graham Linehan who does IT
Crowd because I've been
obsessed with him.
BONNIE: And he also does Black
Books and Father Ted.
FELICIA: Oh I know, I
watched all of them.
KIALA: I love Black Books.
FELICIA: Yeah, Black
Books is amazing.
And I have Father Ted.
It just got here.
Every single episode.
So I tweeted to him and he
actually responded to me, and
I literally started sweating
everywhere.
BONNIE: He's pretty awesome.
He's Glinner on Twitter
in case any of you
want to follow him.
FELICIA: And it's really funny
too because now I follow him
in a creepy way.
BONNIE: He followed me for a
little while until he realized
how much I tweeted him and he
wised up and unfollowed me
which is totally fine.
KIALA: That happened to me
with William Gibson.
BONNIE: Yeah, me too.
FELICIA: What, he followed
and unfollowed you?
KIALA: Yeah he followed
me for two years.
And I was afraid to look.
And then finally I looked one
day and he was not following
me anymore.
And I'm like, oh my God, no.
VERONICA: That's the
worst thing.
Do you guys have people
who you do that?
You check every so
often to see if
they're still following?
And you're like, oh my God, I
don't want to click because I
don't want to know.
I don't want to click.
I don't want to know.
BONNIE: I do that
all the time.
There's a site called
Who Unfollowed Me.
VERONICA: Why would you
ever look at that?
FELICIA: No, Bonnie.
VERONICA: What is
wrong with you?
KIALA: You're a masochist.
BONNIE: I just look at it
because sometimes I follow
people just as a favor.
And then if they're not
following me anymore I
unfollow them.
I do that.
Or just like magazines or TV
shows that have been canceled
or whatever.
And then I looked at it the
other day and two friends I
really thought I was close
with unfollowed me.
And I'm like, OK.
I'm not going to take
it personal.
And then two celebrities that
I sort of pseudo stalked
unfollowed me.
And then I remember Noel
Fielding from Mighty Boosh
followed me for five minutes
and it was the best five
minutes of my life.
And I think I DM'd him something
really horrible
like, hey, do you want me to
send you a [INAUDIBLE]?
VERONICA: Oh, you shouldn't
DM people ever.
KIALA: I drunk DM'd
Clive Barker.
He still follows me though.
BONNIE: [INAUDIBLE] at us.
[INAUDIBLE]
because remember we said that
I said that I didn't think
there were sexy times in his
books and he got all freaked
out and he tweeted at
us that there was.
VERONICA: Really?
BONNIE: Yeah.
VERONICA: Well I had the best
finding out of someone
following me ever in my life
a couple of weeks ago.
And I'm scared to even say it
out loud because I don't want
him to unfollow me.
Andrew W.K. I nearly
pooped a brick.
Because I love Andrew W.K.
He's one of my favorite
musicians and I used to go to
his shows all the time.
And he's so party positive.
And I tweeted something about--
what did I tweet about?
Oh, it was a long story.
But he tweeted back at me and
I was like, oh my God.
What?
Where?
What's happening right now?
BONNIE: This is why
I love Twitter.
Because I think it was yesterday
I was tweeting with
some people that were all
watching Starship Troopers.
And we're tweeting
at each other.
And it was all girls tweeting
And then Casper Van Dien who's
in the movie tweeted at us.
And we all started tweeting each
other Starship Trooper
stuff and totally
fangirl like.
I'm like, what the hell?
This is awesome.
VERONICA: That's amazing.
BONNIE: That's why I love
Twitter, is because I think
it's great that both actors and
authors get a chance to
freak out their fans.
FELICIA: And you can interact
with people and you don't have
all these preconceived notions
of who you are.
BONNIE: Which is funny because
in the book, in the succubus
book that we read, the very--
KIALA: Oh, we read a book?
FELICIA: Oh yeah, that thing?
KIALA: That show we're supposed
to be having?
BONNIE: No, this is
all relevant.
This is all relevant.
Because he doesn't know
what her favorite
author looks like.
Which I find that hard to
believe because when I have a
favorite author I stalk
them like crazy.
KIALA: Use Google Image
immediately.
BONNIE: Yeah I know everything
about them.
I know their eye color and their
cat's name and what they
eat for breakfast.
I am down with this.
And so when she's like, I don't
know who this author is,
as an author sometimes I have
that fantasy of I have this
revolving fantasy in my brain
that Benedict Cumberbatch is
going to meet me at a party
and it's going to be at my
book signing party and he
doesn't know what I look like.
And he's going to be like, I
really love this author.
And I'll be like, oh really?
Tell me more.
FELICIA: Wow, this sounds
like a beginning
to a bad porn, Bonnie.
BONNIE: You know this is sad.
Since I only write non-fiction
kid books I doubt I'd have a
book party where Benedict
would show up.
FELICIA: You don't know.
KIALA: Unless he has a kid.
VERONICA: And then it
might be too late.
BONNIE: It's never too late.
VERONICA: Never too late.
FELICIA: OK.
A lot of people [INAUDIBLE].
BONNIE: OK go ahead, go ahead.
FELICIA: You didn't ruin his
marriage, you just forgot it.
KIALA: Sorry.
FELICIA: Wow.
OK.
People on the forums really
liked the book.
Camille who's one of our oldest
forum members said, the
book has some of the greatest
quotes I've ever found in some
of these books.
And he's the one who posted that
it got bought, the rights
got optioned.
The only negative thing, a lot
of people basically said the
ending, they could tell in
advance that Roman was going
to be the bad guy.
VERONICA: Oh, well aren't
you guys smart.
BONNIE: Didn't you know?
Couldn't you tell from the fact
that he couldn't put a
bookcase together?
VERONICA: What?
FELICIA: What?
BONNIE: Remember in the
beginning in which he comes
over to help her put her
bookcase together, and he lied
about knowing about
how to put--
why am I the only one
that remembers this?
FELICIA: I do remember that
he was pretty sweet.
KIALA: No, I remember
that but--
BONNIE: No, I know, but I just
made a joke that bad guys
can't put Ikea furniture
together.
FELICIA: Oh, is that
a known thing?
BONNIE: No, I just made it up.
I don't know.
I tried to be funny,
this isn't working.
Kiala, what did you think?
VERONICA: Drink more.
KIALA: I was pretty sure that
it was Roman but then I
thought that was too obvious.
And then actually for a while I
thought that maybe Seth was
a shape shifter and I
thought he and Roman
were the same person.
But then they were at the same
place at the same time and
then I realized that
wasn't true.
BONNIE: That would
be cool though.
FELICIA: Melissa had a really
good point on the forum.
She said she really got into
the book in the last half.
Which I agree, it definitely
picks up in the last half
after the whole plot, the
Nephilim plot gets started.
But it was weird, she got into
it after Carter and wanted
Carter to get together with
Georgina, which I wanted too.
KIALA: Me too.
FELICIA: Carter the angel.
KIALA: Yes, he was so
sweet and strong.
And I kept picturing him
as Misha Collins from
Supernatural.
BONNIE: Supernatural,
I did that too.
The minute they described him
I'm like, oh, Misha Collins.
KIALA: I was like,
oh, it's Cass.
FELICIA: Yeah, because
he was like the sexy,
understanding angel guy.
He's kind of like Cass.
KIALA: I pictured him like that
kind of personality wise.
But honestly picturing him, I
pictured him as Eric Northman.
VERONICA: Really?
That seems a little
large for me.
FELICIA: Really?
VERONICA: Maybe a little
bit too big.
KIALA: Because he was
like a big angel,
like tall and angely.
BONNIE: Angely.
VERONICA: See my problem is I
never picture people in books
as people from the real world.
They always form into
their own things.
It's why I have a
really hard time
with the casting questions.
BONNIE: So I started a Pinterest
board called Sexy
Lads, so if any of you follow
me on Pinterest.
And that's where I put
all my casting picks.
FELICIA: I don't know how
I feel about that.
Is that objectification?
Like if a guy did that about
girls would I be offended?
BONNIE: I do it with
girls too though.
When we think about what
actresses should play the
parts in the books we read, I
do this with actresses too.
I just haven't made a
Pinterest board yet.
I will.
FELICIA: I had an equal
opportunity objectification.
BONNIE: It'll probably just be
mostly Eva Green but yeah,
I'll do it.
FELICIA: Eva Green is who I
thought of Georgina for.
BONNIE: Yeah I know, me too.
KIALA: I had a Pinterest porn
board for a short period of
time because I thought
it was funny.
VERONICA: Did they
take it down?
Did they make you
KIALA: No, I took it down.
BONNIE: Is it still there?
I couldn't bring myself
to pin anything.
FELICIA: Is it like an
empty porn board?
BONNIE: That's like my life.
My life is an empty
porn board.
FELICIA: Oh God, Bonnie.
BONNIE: Sorry, apology
to [INAUDIBLE].
I'll drink more.
Let's talk about
the book, yay.
FELICIA: OK let's talk
the characters.
Georgina.
Sam on the forums loved the
main character, although I
expected her to do more
supernatural things.
She didn't seem to have any
female friends which I thought
was interesting.
And then he wants to know, is
that standard for a succubus
or was a function of her
being a succubus?
What did you guys think?
She had a couple of female
coworkers that were
friends with her.
VERONICA: They weren't
friendly.
Yeah they weren't central
characters at all.
BONNIE: She didn't have
a sassy galpal.
VERONICA: Yeah the only other
major female character was
antagonistic towards her.
FELICIA: Yeah, that's
interesting.
Do you think that's
because she was--
KIALA: So overtly sexual?
FELICIA: Yeah because
you'd think it
would be the opposite.
Like she'd have more female
friends because her only
function is to use her
sexuality to feed.
VERONICA: So maybe she just
doesn't drawn women like that.
BONNIE: She could have attracted
more lesbians, I
don't know.
FELICIA: Also there was actually
a big thread on the
forums about evil as good.
Some people, Jude I think,
started that thread about how
they felt uncomfortable with the
sympathet-- thetification?
Is that a word?
It's not.
Let me drink more.
Making evil characters
more sympathetic.
Because basically her function
on earth is to corrupt people.
VERONICA: But that's silly.
Because there's so many amazing
characters from so
many different stories.
They're supposed to be
evil but they're more
complicated than that.
KIALA: Or like Battlestar
Galactica and all the Cylons.
VERONICA: That's just
the whole point.
You have to have a complicated
character.
You have to have a character
with a lot of dimensions.
And just because they have an
evil job to do or what is
assumed to be an evil job, I
guess it is an evil job.
Bringing their souls into hell,
I guess it's that's
[INAUDIBLE].
FELICIA: Actually she didn't
do a lot of it.
But if she actually did more of
it, you probably wouldn't
have liked her as much.
BONNIE: Let's be honest.
It's not like she did it.
She basically played
on people's
cravings and interests.
KIALA: Yeah they wanted it.
BONNIE: It's ultimately your
decision whether or not you
want your soul to go to heaven
or hell in this book.
If you just choose to give it
up to have sex with a hot
chick then that's--
VERONICA: She's an enabler.
She's an enabler and that's
what it comes down to.
KIALA: I didn't like that stupid
characterization at the
beginning of that it was a
geeky dude living in his
parent's basement.
He was a 34 year old virgin
with Cheeto fingers.
BONNIE: Cheeto fingers
are hot.
VERONICA: You can lick it off.
Like aah.
KIALA: It was so annoying.
Things like that
were annoying.
BONNIE: Veronica, you're going
to be an animated gif of
licking your fingers
before you know it.
VERONICA: Oh God.
It's too late It's
already happened.
It already exists.
KIALA: Yeah, it's
on now already.
I didn't like that.
I didn't like a lot of her
textbook psychologically
damaged, in your face sexuality,
like she only could
identify with people that were
sexually attracted to her.
Like every single man, every
single character in that book
was somebody that she only
related to sexually.
Well other than her gay
vampire best friends.
FELICIA: Yeah that's true.
But also I thought it was kind
of convenient and total wish
fulfillment when she could
change her appearance and all
her clothing instantly.
It was so convenient.
KIALA: It's like a fantasy.
Like a lady fantasy.
FELICIA: It was such a
lady fantasy which
I was jealous of.
She never has to spend any
money on clothing.
BONNIE: That reminded me a
little of Tonks in Harry
Potter because she could change
her hair at any point.
And I'm like, I've dyed my
hair a lot of times.
And if I could just change my
hair without it turning into
like, horrible over dried wet
noodle situation I would do
that in a heartbeat.
VERONICA: By the way, your hair
looks great today Bonnie.
KIALA: It does.
BONNIE: If you follow me on
Pinterest, you might notice
that I had might dye it soon.
FELICIA: [GASP]
What color?
BONNIE: Violet.
VERONICA: Red?
Violet.
KIALA: Violet, oh.
FELICIA: I like this.
Veronica I don't have
bangs anymore.
BONNIE: I know, what happened
to them bangs?
FELICIA: I'm going to
get them trimmed.
It's just, I don't know.
It was too traumatic last
time, looking too much.
BONNIE: Why?
You know who I thought
you looked like?
You actually look
like Amy Pond.
FELICIA: With the bangs?
BONNIE: Yeah.
FELICIA: I like that.
BONNIE: That's a compliment.
FELICIA: I mean, I'm going
to get them trimmed.
I just feel like I'm
in the presence of
the mistress of bangs.
And to be a pale imitation
of bangs.
Do you cut your own bangs?
VERONICA: I do.
KIALA: Really?
Well I get my hair cut once
every month and a half, but
then for touch ups
I do my own.
FELICIA: Yeah that's
what I need to do.
I didn't know that I was
in for maintenance.
BONNIE: I cut my bangs.
I have to cut my bangs
straight every
two weeks or so.
VERONICA: Yeah.
It's a pain.
It's a pain in the butt,
but it's worth it.
BONNIE: You get used to it.
KIALA: I was going to say just
on that Lady Fantasy thing,
there's a series of--
I can't remember who writes
them-- but a series of novels
where the woman, she discovers
she's got this magic, and
every time she uses it, it
expends so much energy she has
to eat and eat and eat.
It also made her really
young and beautiful.
And then she has to eat all the
time and she can't gain
any weight.
Whereas before, she would gain
weight all the time.
BONNIE: Does she have to
eat a certain thing?
KIALA: She just has to
eat a lot of food.
Just binge eat.
But she can't keep weight on.
And it's kind of messed up.
But that was just my
feeling about it.
FELICIA: Silvy Marie on the
forums mentioned her sleeping
with Warren and she
was very upset.
She went to somebody she knows
to get a fix but she didn't
really need it.
And she lost respect
for her then.
BONNIE: I didn't like Warren.
FELICIA: I didn't like Warren
either but I though, I didn't
like her then, but then
I liked the fact that
I didn't like her.
In that it made more
three dimensional.
You don't have to be perfect.
A lot of these books that we
read and the ones that I don't
even list on my good reads,
I can't engage with them.
Because the person is so perfect
you just feel like
she's a martyr.
OK, just mess up once please?
Because you read about a person,
it doesn't feel real.
So that's why I kind of liked
her, knowing that she was
making a bad decision but just
indulging herself with Warren.
VERONICA: Do you think it was on
purpose that they chose one
of the most unlikable
characters?
That she made Warren really
unlikable in order for us to
not feel so bad about Georgina
sleeping with him to get some
powers back?
FELICIA: I think so.
Well also you don't want to
muddy the waters because if he
was sympathetic then what's
going on with
Seth and then Roman?
It would just muddy
everything up.
Like I said, I wanted her
to get with Carter.
VERONICA: That wouldn't
give her any power.
Because he's also
supernatural.
FELICIA: Oh, that's true.
VERONICA: What about
her little friend?
The guy that worked at
the store with her?
KIALA: Doug.
VERONICA: Doug, yeah.
Like if she ends up with
Doug, that would
have been like, whoa.
He's a super nice guy and he
really likes you and now
you're using him.
But with Warren it's like they
mutually use each other.
FELICIA: Exactly.
BONNIE: I don't want to get too
personal here, but usually
when you have a you-know-what
buddy--
I can't swear on this channel,
but you know what I mean--
if you have a sexy times buddy,
chances are that sexy
times buddy isn't the most
redeemable of people.
Because they're using you as
much as you're using them.
I don't know, I'm just saying.
FELICIA: I don't
know about it.
BONNIE: Fits the profile
of the douchebag that--
KIALA: I haven't had one, but
it's not a moral reason.
I just have never had one.
BONNIE: Wow.
Am I the only one
who's had one?
Many?
A few?
FELICIA: Anyway.
Talk about Seth who was one of
the main love interests.
A lot of people really liked
Seth because he was classified
as a beta male.
Which we all, in a lot of these
Vaginal Fantasy book
club picks have had very
dominating men
who are very pushy.
And the girl's like,
no, no, no.
OK fine.
I like you.
And that's become the archetype
of the romance hero.
Seth is kind of the
opposite of that.
He's actually very shy and the
main character doesn't know
what to do with him.
And a lot of people loved him.
Stacey, I loved the emails
that he sent to her.
And what did you guys think
about him as the hero?
BONNIE: Isn't that frustrating
though?
Isn't that kind of frustrating
to have a guy that's really
good at writing emails but when
you're face to face can't
hold a decent conversation
with you?
KIALA: Yeah.
I know one guy like that.
And it's really annoying.
BONNIE: It's annoying.
Yeah.
FELICIA: I had a boyfriend in
high school that gave really
good phone.
He had a great voice, but then
when you met him in person it
was like, this is weird.
VERONICA: Not the same.
Not the same.
I've had a lot of IM boyfriends
like that.
They're really good over IM, and
then in person it's just
like, you're weird.
KIALA: Yeah.
Or the opposite where they're
really great in person but
then they misspell everything
in texts.
Or too many emoticons.
And you're like, oh God, no.
VERONICA: It's like a smiley
face after every sentence.
KIALA: Yeah lol.
BONNIE: Have you ever broken
off anything with someone
because they kept using
the wrong "there?"
KIALA: I would.
FELICIA: I would, yeah.
KIALA: If they didn't correct
themselves, or the wrong
"your."
BONNIE: Like over.
And once or twice is fine,
but all the time.
And mixing up "your"
with "you're."
VERONICA: I don't understand
internet speak sometimes.
BONNIE: Really?
VERONICA: Like, I get it.
I get it.
I just don't understand
why it's so prevalent.
FELICIA: Because everybody
does it.
KIALA: [INAUDIBLE].
VERONICA: No, no.
Not like lol, meme speak.
That's different.
BONNIE: I still don't know
what the hell "YOLO" is.
VERONICA: You only live once.
You only live once.
BONNIE: Really?
VERONICA: I'm going to go ride
on the top of my car, YOLO.
I'm going to ghostride
the whip, YOLO.
I'm going to go put a badger
in my pants, YOLO.
FELICIA: Badger?
Where did that come from?
KIALA: I still don't--
SMH?
I can never remember what--
it's So Much Hate, right?
VERONICA: Oh is that
what that means?
BONNIE: Is that what that is?
FELICIA: I wouldn't know
that one either.
KIALA: I don't know.
I think that's it.
VERONICA: TLDR is one
of my favorites.
BONNIE: What's that one?
VERONICA: Too Long,
Didn't Read.
FELICIA: That's the most
insulting one.
Just put some effort in
or don't join the
conversation, please.
VERONICA: No, you want to know
what the most insulting
hashtag of all time is?
BONNIE: What?
VERONICA: First World
Problems.
People respond to me and now
this is going to happen all
the time because
I'm saying it.
FELICIA: I'm going
to do it now.
VERONICA: It's a first world
problem that I'm complaining
about first world problems
in hashtag.
BONNIE: Start the
#vaginalproblems.
FELICIA: First world problems
is having a
Twitter account, OK?
VERONICA: It's like, it's
redundant, we know, we know.
Everything I complain about on
here is a first world problem.
Let's just put that out there.
BONNIE: Maybe we should
do succubus problem.
VERONICA: Succubus problem.
FELICIA: Oh, succubus problem.
BONNIE: Let's do that
as a hashtag.
Hey, have we trended yet?
I still think Vaginal Fantasy
needs to trend today.
If everyone's watching this,
tweet it so it trends.
Because I don't want people to
be confused because it's a
football Sunday.
KIALA: Yeah it's Sunday, there's
nothing else going on.
Come on.
FELICIA: There's so much
sportsball talk on there.
I just don't even check
on Sundays.
BONNIE: No, it's either Sunday
used to be just football or
Walking Dead, right?
That's basically all
Sundays were.
FELICIA: And awards shows.
BONNIE: Right.
VERONICA: I try not to get mad
at the football talk because
once spring and summer
rolls around it's
baseball talk for me.
So I have to let the football
talk happen.
BONNIE: See, I'm all
about soccer talk.
VERONICA: Soccer talk.
That's like early in the
morning, that's like 6 AM.
I used to live above a bar
that played all of the
international soccer games,
football games.
BONNIE: Was it Mad Dog?
VERONICA: It was Mad Dog.
It was Mad Dog.
And I don't live there anymore
so don't go there.
BONNIE: I was downstairs.
While you were asleep I was down
at Mad Dog trying to hit
on every British football fan
in the bar at 6 in the
morning, and I was not
doing a good job.
VERONICA: Oh so you mean while
you guys were screaming at the
top of your lungs at
football games at 6
o'clock in the morning?
BONNIE: I have no idea
and I don't even know
how they play it.
I just go for the short shorts
and the accents.
I'm shallow.
KIALA: Is Mad Dog the one
that's right next to
Rosamunde's?
VERONICA: Yeah across
the street.
Toronado's right next door.
BONNIE: So if you're in San
Francisco, go to Mad Dog in
the Fog and you can early
in the morning watch.
VERONICA: It's like a
weird DJ bar now.
It got too hip.
They redid it and it's
not as good.
But we are way off.
FELICIA: If somebody's grading
us they can go to hell.
BONNIE: Can we do
the casting now?
Because I had ideas
of who's what.
FELICIA: Well I did want to
talk about one last thing
[INAUDIBLE] in Roman, the other
love interest guy who is
the opposite of Seth.
He was extremely pushy, he
wouldn't take no for an
answer, and he ends up
being the bad guy.
And a lot of people, Erin on the
forums said, I hate Roman,
I'm halfway through.
And that was before she even
knew he was a bad guy.
And the creepy way that
Roman treated people
sent me crazy vibes.
They seemed stalkery and rapery,
or was he charming?
Was the persistence creepy
to anyone else?
VERONICA: It was a little
creepy at first.
Well, actually it was creepy
the whole time.
I thought Roman was a
little bit creepy.
He came on a little
bit too strong.
KIALA: Yeah I didn't like that
he walked her home from the
bar because you shouldn't
ever do that.
FELICIA: She never should have
had him walk you home.
KIALA: No.
VERONICA: Stranger danger.
KIALA: You get right in a cab.
No.
BONNIE: She can take care
of herself though.
I mean, I don't know.
She's the one that pointed
him out though.
She's the one that started all
this mess because she's been
trying to tell everyone she had
a date, which she didn't.
VERONICA: But he could
have played it cool.
I mean, he played it
cool at the time.
But he could've been like, OK.
Having fun.
Bye.
FELICIA: Well it turns out he
was going to murder her.
He was going to murder her if
she hadn't have called him
over to help out with
that conversation.
Yeah, I think in the context
of him being a murderer it
wasn't as creepy.
But without him being the
murder, had he been a
legitimate love interest at the
end, I would have said, oh
that guy's creepy, please
don't go with him.
But when he turned out to be a
psycho at the end I was like,
oh, I saw that.
He wasn't as bad as
he could've been.
KIALA: I thought the walking
home from the bar was just
really presumptuous
and creepy.
Like you shouldn't ever trust a
dude that wants to do that.
But other than that, his
persistence wasn't rapey.
I didn't think it was rapey.
He didn't try to do anything.
He respected that.
He respected that she wasn't
ready to do anything.
FELICIA: Well considering the
one sex scene in the book, or
the one of two or three, but
the big one was with him,
after you find out he's the bad
guy it's a bold writing
choice which I thought was
kind of refreshing.
And the fact that she nuanced
his character in a way that
you weren't like, get
away from him.
Which I still think that's
really good writing where you
can have a three dimensional
character like that.
VERONICA: It's pretty messed up
that he was like, yeah, I
was going to kill you.
But then I fell in love with
you so you're fine.
It's good.
We should just run
away together.
BONNIE: That's a spite thing.
I'm sorry.
You know what the
funny thing is?
Is that, I think a lot-- and I'm
going to be presumptuous
here and I apologize to any
guys that are watching--
but I think a lot of guys think
that girls want to be
walked home from bars, and
they want a guy that's a
little bit more, I don't want
to say forceful but a little
more aggressive.
Because I live in a city full
of apathetic hipster dudes
that could basically take their
pick of chicks, and so
they don't do any effort.
So when you see somebody in
a book like that making an
effort, yeah he came off kind
of creepy, kind of stalkery.
But when you look at a lot of
romance novels and movies and
TV shows where the guy's making
that extra effort to
bring flowers, to find out where
she lives, to offer to
build her stupid crappy IKEA
bookcase for her, that to me
seems flirty, not oh my God,
this guy's going to
kill me in my sleep.
So maybe I'm just living a
dangerous life, but I thought
it was cute that he was a little
bit more aggressive
instead of her having to
chase down everybody.
VERONICA: SMH Bonnie, SMH.
Which means apparently
shaking my head.
KIALA: Oh maybe that's
what it means.
VERONICA: That's what the
YouTubers tell me.
KIALA: I like So Much Hate.
That's what I've decided
it means.
VERONICA: I think it
could be both.
FELICIA: I'm just going back
to I just think it's good
writing that you can have these
two interpretations
where it's definitely like, oh
my God, I hate that guy.
And he was obviously
a creeper.
I just think it's
good writing.
OK, let's do casting.
BONNIE: OK.
So Roman, I said Jay Ryan who
plays the guy on Beauty and
the Beast, because rwar!
KIALA: Really?
BONNIE: Yeah.
FELICIA: Or Roman?
BONNIE: Who?
Not the British guy on
Beauty and the Beast.
The new Beauty and the Beast.
Roman.
FELICIA: For Roman?
BONNIE: Jay Ryan from Beauty and
the Beast is like Roman.
And Carter, I got Misha stuck
in my head because of
Supernatural.
I can't not think of that.
I mean, Supernatural's always
going to do that to me.
FELICIA: I'm going to
be on in January.
January, my episode's on.
KIALA: Yay.
BONNIE: You what?
FELICIA: My episode.
[INAUDIBLE]
episode's [INAUDIBLE].
KIALA: Yay.
It is always so weird to see you
on episodes that I watch.
It's amazing but
it's so weird.
FELICIA: It's a really good
episode, you guys.
BONNIE: By the way, Jared
is a huge Star Wars fan.
FELICIA: Oh, that is amazing.
BONNIE: And he always has his
kid dressed as Yoda on his
Twitter and it's [INAUDIBLE].
FELICIA: Both of them
are awesome guys.
OK, back to it.
Who was your Seth, Bonnie?
BONNIE: And then Seth was kind
of hard because Seth was
supposed to be sort of like
this geeky guy but he was
attractive, but he was
downplayed quite a bit.
I don't know.
I couldn't figure out who
to have for Seth.
And then Eva Green
for Georgina.
FELICIA: I had Eva Green for
Georgina, which is so weird.
Roman was Richard Grieco
from 21 Jumpstreet.
BONNIE: Oh my God,
you did not.
FELICIA: And Seth
was Ira Glass.
VERONICA: Really?
FELICIA: Yeah.
VERONICA: Huh.
KIALA: Really?
VERONICA: I can picture Seth
in my head, but he doesn't
look like any actor that
I can think of.
KIALA: Ira Glass?
BONNIE: Ira Glass?
FELICIA: Ira Glass is cute.
VERONICA: That's too
cute, I think.
Ira Glass is too good looking
maybe for Seth.
And too tall.
FELICIA: He is cute
and very smart.
I met him once.
KIALA: No, he's cute.
VERONICA: Veronica, what about
the hot British guy that you
interviewed on Sword and
Laser Joe Acra--
Acra--
VERONICA: No, Joe Abercrombie?
No.
Too hot.
FELICIA: No, he's really hot.
I hung out with him at
the last [INAUDIBLE]
I was at in Australia.
He can tan.
BONNIE: He is so hot.
VERONICA: He's so hot.
This is really unprofessional
of me, Bonnie.
You should not have
brought this up.
BONNIE: You don't understand.
I was tweeting at you when you
aired that episode, and it was
like, hot, hot, hot.
It's like a running joke in the
Sword and Laser community
that I think he's really
good looking.
He's married with children.
I'm married.
It's not a thing.
BONNIE: I would pay good
money to see both
his sword and laser.
FELICIA: Whoa.
BONNIE: Yeah.
Hot.
FELICIA: I had an author dinner
where we all went out.
Rachel Caine and
Trudy Canavan.
And then him and a couple
of other authors.
We all went out.
And then we went really out late
to get dessert at this
weird dessert cafe in the
middle of Adelaide.
But it was really fun.
They're all really cool.
VERONICA: I like him a lot.
He's great.
So I actually have a
casting for once.
I almost never have castings.
But Roman for me was Christian
Camargo who played the ice
truck killer on Dexter.
He's Dexter's brother.
KIALA: Oh, his brother.
VERONICA: Yeah, his brother.
The kind of handsome
but kind of creepy.
A little menacing
a little bit.
Yeah.
That popped into my head.
That's why I got all excited
when we started
talking about casting.
I'm like, oh my God,
I got one.
FELICIA: You got one.
What about you, Kiala?
KIALA: I pictured Roman
as Michael Fassbender
because I always do.
FELICIA: You always do
Michael Fassbender.
KIALA: I know.
I know.
And then I pictured Carter, I
think we talked about this but
we'll just talk about it, Misha
Collins [INAUDIBLE] in
his persona but I pictured him
as Eric Northman and I can't
think of the black guy's name
right now, but yeah.
VERONICA: Sarsgaard.
KIALA: Sarsgaard.
VERONICA: Which one, though?
KIALA: Not Peter.
Not [INAUDIBLE].
Something Sarsgaard.
VERONICA: Alexander?
KIALA: Alexander Sarsgaard.
VERONICA: Alex Sarsgaard
KIALA: And then for Seth,
I don't know.
BONNIE: I know, right?
VERONICA: Yeah Seth is hard.
BONNIE: At first I thought maybe
Seth could be like David
Tennant with glasses.
FELICIA: Oh, oh, oh, oh.
The new Q in James Bond.
BONNIE: Oh, perfect.
VERONICA: Oh.
Wait as who?
Who as Seth?
BONNIE: Seth--?
VERONICA: It's too hot.
BONNIE: Really?
VERONICA: Too hot still.
That guy's really hot.
FELICIA: No he is really hot.
KIALA: But I thought
Seth was hot.
I thought he was cute.
FELICIA: I think he's hot.
He can be hot.
He doesn't have to not be hot.
BONNIE: He can be hot.
FELICIA: I think he's a
little older though.
VERONICA: Yeah, older.
For some reason I picture him
with sandy brown hair,
glasses, kind of
stockier build.
Not thin but not fat either.
KIALA: Like Zach Galifianakis?
VERONICA: Too stocky.
A little too stocky.
BONNIE: Now I'm picturing him as
Zach, and that's hilarious.
VERONICA: Not a built guy,
just like a normal dude.
KIALA: Like a dude, like a
hipster dude in Portland that
drinks a lot of beer.
And rides a bike but when he's
drunk so he doesn't really--
VERONICA: Because in San
Francisco you say hipster dude
and I think of super
skinny tight jeans.
KIALA: Not here.
VERONICA: Not that
kind of guy.
Like lumberjack hipster.
KIALA: Lumberjack hipster.
I built this record store
with my bare hands.
FELICIA: Just do to Abbot Kinney
in LA, you'll see 55
Seth's on the street.
VERONICA: But no beard.
I don't see him as
having a beard.
BONNIE: I think he's like
a Wilco kind of hipster.
KIALA: Oh, Chris Pratt.
VERONICA: I don't know
who that is.
KIALA: From Parks
and Recreation.
BONNIE: Yeah, the dumb guy
who works in [INAUDIBLE].
VERONICA: Too young looking.
Too young looking.
FELICIA: Marie B. says Martin
Freeman on the comments.
VERONICA: Also too young
looking for me.
BONNIE: How about Ron Swanson?
VERONICA: No, too old looking.
Too mustachey.
KIALA: I thought of him as young
because he had all the
t-shirts and stuff.
FELICIA: Oh, Sam from
True Blood.
Sam Merlotte.
VERONICA: Way too handsome.
Way too handsome.
KIALA: Sam from True Blood saw
me crying at DragonCon.
BONNIE: Why were you crying
at DragonCon?
KIALA: Oh God, I just had some
bad news and I was hiding in
the kitchens and he walked back
and he saw me crying.
And then five minutes
later Spike walks
through and saw me crying.
BONNIE: Did get a hug?
VERONICA: They didn't
console you?
KIALA: No.
I wanted them too.
BONNIE: Man, Spike consoling
you at DragonCon?
You know how many fantasies
that would've
completed for all of us?
KIALA: I know.
Oh wow.
VERONICA: OK so someone on the
chat said Seth Green as Seth.
That actually popped into
my head except still
a little bit stockier.
BONNIE: Seth's cute though.
KIALA: Yeah.
FELICIA: I don't agree with your
vision of Seth but OK.
VERONICA: OK.
It's fine.
We don't have to agree.
FELICIA: It's fine.
BONNIE: I feel creepy for
saying this because I'm
friends with Seth and I think
of him like a brother.
But he's still pretty cute.
He's doable.
Whereas I think Seth in the
book, that's a stretch.
FELICIA: Really?
VERONICA: I wanted Seth in the
book to be cute enough that--
this is really not
cool to say--
BONNIE: Say it.
VERONICA: Like not an immediate
overwhelming
attraction.
The way that Georgina felt.
Not like, oh wow.
This guy's really hot.
But more like, you're attractive
and I'm really
getting to know you.
And I feel like we really
connect on a brain level.
And so I'm beginning to get more
attracted to you through
our mutual respect for
similar interests.
BONNIE: So smart's
the new sexy.
VERONICA: Yeah, and then all
of the sudden you find
yourself finding that
physical attraction.
Maybe it wasn't there at the
beginning but it kind of
develops over time.
BONNIE: Someone on Twitter,
Jem on Twitter said Anton
Yelchin from Star Trek
could be Seth.
The new Star Trek.
I don't know.
FELICIA: Wait let's move on
because we want to talk about
Dragon Actually.
VERONICA: Is he Chekov from
the new Star Trek?
BONNIE: Yeah.
KIALA: Yeah.
FELICIA: Who read
Dragon Actually?
BONNIE: I did.
KIALA: I read half.
BONNIE: Look at those abs.
FELICIA: We all read
most of it.
OK.
So what did we think
of this one?
This was the alt book and I want
to read just the blurb.
"It's not always easy being a
female warrior with a nickname
like Annwyl the Bloody.
Men tend to cower in
fear or salute.
But for once it would be nice to
talk to a real man the way
she can talk to Fearghus
the Destroyer."
VERONICA: Too bad Fearghus--
KIALA: Fergus.
VERONICA: Fearghus.
KIALA: Fearghus.
FELICIA: Fearghus
in the dragon.
And with him Annwyl
feels safe.
But there's a twist.
Blah blah blah.
OK.
So basically it's kind of a
medieval book about a girl who
has a loving relationship
with a dragon.
And then this knight
comes in and he's
like Mr. Sex On Wheels.
Turns out, same guy.
BONNIE: Look at those abs.
VERONICA: I doubt she
did a dragon.
She did did a dragon.
FELICIA: So what do we think
of this book Veronica?
You start this one.
VERONICA: So it was
really funny.
Well first of all I got a big
kick of the fact that it is
medieval kind of feel, but they
totally speak regular.
Like they're hanging out at
the coffee shop down the
street style talking.
Which is fine sometimes, but it
just didn't really fit with
the setting all that much.
FELICIA: There was somebody--
I have to read this quote--
somebody said that it felt
like it was kind
of out of the eighties.
Like everybody just had
really big hair.
Like it came out in 2008
but it felt like
a massive 80s vibe.
It was Claire.
All the hair band maids, or
the dragons were rocking.
VERONICA: Well how stupid was
she to not realize that it was
the same guy?
It took forever.
It took freaking forever.
BONNIE: It was such a Lois
Lane moment where
you're like, come on.
It's so obvious.
FELICIA: OK.
Keep going.
Sorry, I'm interrupting.
VERONICA: I also thought that
the book was going to be a lot
longer because I was reading
it on Kindle and there's
actually two books in
the Kindle addition.
So I was like, what else are
they going to put in this book
[INAUDIBLE]?
How much more can they talk
about this storyline?
There's two books.
There's the story of the mother
dragon and her mother
that kicks off at the end
of the dragon book.
KIALA: Oh well we then I thought
we read more of this
than I thought I did.
FELICIA: Yeah you did.
It's only 60% of the Kindle is
the book that was the alt.
KIALA: Oh I was almost done.
FELICIA: Yeah it really
goes on forever.
BONNIE: And so I don't know
what you're talking about
because I still don't
own a Kindle.
So I just read real books.
FELICIA: Bonnie I need to
send you my Kindle.
I have a Kindle 2.
I'll send it to you this
week, I promise.
BONNIE: But then I won't be able
to touch the abs while
I'm reading.
VERONICA: Yeah.
FELICIA: True.
VERONICA: You can't show
off on Muni with a
Kindle quite the same.
BONNIE: Oh I make a lot of
friends on Muni by the way.
When I read this book on Muni
last time I get hit on a lot
by cray cray.
Cray.
KIALA: Is that good?
BONNIE: I don't know.
But I was reading this and this
burly guy sat next to me
and was like, oh that book
looks interesting.
What's it about?
Dragon Actually, is it
like Love, Actually?
And I'm like, well kind of.
I was like, it's a dragon
and he said she's--
VERONICA: [INAUDIBLE]
He's a dude, and actually
he's a dragon.
BONNIE: Yeah.
So I'm trying to avoid
it, right?
And he just looks at me like,
oh this girl's easy.
FELICIA: OK Kiala, what
did you think?
KIALA: Sorry [INAUDIBLE].
That's my boyfriend but actually
he's a dragon.
VERONICA: Actually,
yeah, he is.
He's a dragon.
KIALA: He's totally a dragon.
VERONICA: Oh my God, you
guys, actually we've
totally been dating.
Totally a dragon.
KIALA: I'm actually a dragon.
VERONICA: Totally a dragon.
FELICIA: Kiala, what
did you think?
What did you think?
KIALA: OK.
I thought it was really silly.
But the sex scenes
were really good.
FELICIA: Oh my God.
Veronica snorted.
BONNIE: Oh wow.
Veronica's drunk.
FELICIA: She snorted so hard.
KIALA: She did it again.
She did it again.
VERONICA: Yeah but
[INAUDIBLE].
FELICIA: What's going on?
We're so drunk right now.
KIALA: But you guys,
he'll light your
cigarette with his face.
VERONICA: I don't even have to
drive on the 405 anymore
because I fly on him, because
he's a dragon.
Isn't that amazing?
KIALA: But you know what?
He totally found out when I
wasn't a virgin anymore.
BONNIE: Oh my God.
KIALA: Um--
BONNIE: We all need to be
twirling our hair when
he talk like that.
Oh yeah, it is so
embarrassing.
I can't believe it.
FELICIA: Bonnie what did
you think of the book?
BONNIE: Aside from it
being crazy jail--
like crazy bait on Muni, OK
first of all, let me tell you
something about this dragon.
I was turned on by the dragon,
here I'm doing this.
I was turned on by the dragon.
You know why I was turned
on by the dragon?
Because he has a freaking
library in his cave.
VERONICA: That is awesome.
KIALA: Yeah.
BONNIE: If you want to get me
turned on, have a whole room
full of books.
That will turn me on.
I don't care if you're
a dragon.
a succubus.
I don't care if you're
a Republican.
Well maybe Republican.
But [INAUDIBLE].
Well no.
If you're a hot Republican
dragon with a library, I'm
willing to look over that.
Seriously.
KIALA: Depends on what's
in your library.
BONNIE: And he picked
out books for her.
Come on.
That is hot.
FELICIA: It was hot as the
dragon, but what about the
knight part?
There was a lot of
sex in this book.
VERONICA: It was kind
of intense.
BONNIE: Yeah thanks for the
sex book because that
fulfilled a lot.
FELICIA: See.
Everybody talked
that wanted it.
Gave it to you.
BONNIE: Yeah I appreciated
having a book
full of sex and dragons.
[INAUDIBLE]
dragon sex, actually.
I don't know why they left
that out of the title.
VERONICA: Dragon sex better
than dinosaur sex.
KIALA: Actually.
VERONICA: Actually.
BONNIE: Yeah.
[INAUDIBLE]
vanilla oil.
FELICIA: And Emily on the forums
on the question was
like, does Vaginal
Fantasy have to
be good to be adorable?
Because I think it's a perfect
description of the book.
Just don't even criticize
it, guys.
Somebody was like, they were
watching an '80s dragon movie
and they're like, I can
do this better.
Oh wait I won't.
I'll do it [INAUDIBLE].
BONNIE: Which one?
Was it Krull?
FELICIA: It was Krull.
KIALA: Krull is amazing.
BONNIE: I love Krull
BONNIE: That would
be so great.
Krull is awesome.
It has everything you could
possibly need and Liam Neeson.
FELICIA: Huge hair.
That girl has huge hair.
KIALA: Oh, it is so good.
With her little face?
BONNIE: Yeah.
FELICIA: Yeah.
But I hated the word toerag.
Does anybody remember that?
KIALA: Yes.
FELICIA: I read it four
or five times in
the book as an insult.
I'm like, what is going on?
What is a toerag?
KIALA: Why would you have
a rag on your toe?
And why is that an insult?
VERONICA: Alright toerag.
Toerag.
FELICIA: It's literally six or
seven times in this book.
Somebody calls you,
you toerag.
KIALA: Yeah.
BONNIE: Yeah.
KIALA: The first time I read
it, I read it as kind of
Scottish or something
like [INAUDIBLE]
or something like a name.
And I was like, oh, toerag.
FELICIA: No, it was an insult.
VERONICA: You you toerag.
KIALA: [INAUDIBLE] for
moving, you toerag.
But it wasn't like that.
That's a bad accent.
VERONICA: What does that
mean, you guys?
It's a rascal.
OK, they say it's a rascal.
FELICIA: What's a rascal?
Is that a known insult?
A rapscallion is a toerag?
I've never heard that.
KIALA: The little thing that
fat people ride around on?
FELICIA: A lot of people
in the comments know
what a toerag is.
VERONICA: Yeah YouTubers
know what toerag means.
Is it from the '80s?
--Someone says.
A scoundrel, like a scumbag.
They're saying on IRC now.
FELICIA: Scumbag?
Is it a British thing?
VERONICA: But what
does it mean?
KIALA: Where is the etymology?
FELICIA: Oh it's British.
It's British means scum.
BONNIE: Oh.
VERONICA: But why?
But why?
FELICIA: That's a whole
different question.
KIALA: Maybe you can't afford
socks and so you put
rags on your feet.
BONNIE: Yeah there you go.
It's a Cockney thing.
FELICIA: I don't buy it.
KIALA: So you put rags
on your feet.
BONNIE: It's probably Cockney.
FELICIA: I don't buy it.
BONNIE: I don't know.
FELICIA: There was also
a lot of spanking.
VERONICA: There was
But spanking's kind of hot.
BONNIE: That was good though.
FELICIA: It wasn't
bad spanking but
it was copious spanking.
BONNIE: Really?
Copious?
KIALA: There was a
lot of spanking.
BONNIE: OK.
KIALA: [INAUDIBLE]
Veronica.
FELICIA: There was a toerag's
worth of spanking.
VERONICA: That's a unit
of measurement?
FELICIA: I don't know.
I don't know anymore.
VERONICA: A metric toerag.
BONNIE: I don't think there's
such a thing as copious
spanking, is there?
FELICIA: I mean, it depends
on your level of spanking.
BONNIE: I don't know.
FELICIA: OK Pixie Fleming 89.
The definition of toerag derives
from Old England where
convicts used to tie bits of
shirt around their toes and
feet as makeshift socks.
Hence toerag means criminal
or rapscallion.
KIALA: See?
I figured that out.
FELICIA: You did.
KIALA: Well I just saw
Les Miserables, so
it's probably in there.
VERONICA: [INAUDIBLE]
I don't have time to Google
things, jeez.
FELICIA: [INAUDIBLE]
Anne Hathaway.
KIALA: Literally I almost passed
out from trying not to
cry because my mom was
sitting next to me
sobbing like a baby.
I was trying to not hold it in
and I almost passed out.
BONNIE: Am I bad if I just
pretended Le Mis was a
Wolverine prequel?
VERONICA: You keep saying that.
OK.
So I went.
I tried to go, and our
theater broke down.
FELICIA: I saw you said
that on Twitter.
VERONICA: You did.
It was terrible.
I love you Bonnie.
But you already made
that joke.
And I really love Les Mis so
it hurts me in my guts.
BONNIE: You know what?
It's really [INAUDIBLE] on Les
Mis, it's a [INAUDIBLE]
on Wolverine.
VERONICA: OK.
All right.
We can agree on that then.
FELICIA: The last half of Les
Mis was kind of a snoozer.
OK?
But the first half
was excellent.
VERONICA: I haven't
seen it yet.
Because I tried to go and
I couldn't see it.
KIALA: It is just the sobbiest
sobb, sobb, sobby sobby.
Everyone in the entire theater
is just crying out loud.
VERONICA: We saw Book of
Mormon last night.
It was pretty good.
KIALA: Oh, was it funny?
VERONICA: It was really funny.
It was really funny.
BONNIE: Hey Felicia, when you
said that Anne Hathaway should
win the Oscar, I thought
you meant for Catwoman.
FELICIA: I think half the
people that follow me on
Twitter actually believe that.
KIALA: She was really
good in Batman.
VERONICA: She was good.
FELICIA: OK.
Guys, before we wrap up, there
was a couple of questions
because I think we've done
Dragon Actually, all right?
You guys will know what you're
going to get into when you get
Dragon Actually.
There are a couple of just
general questions people
posted on the thread.
This is our year anniversary.
Well I guess next month.
We started in January.
And this is the end
of the year.
So as a couple of reflection
questions, what would your new
year Vaginal Fantasy
resolution be?
KIALA: To drink more.
FELICIA: OK.
KIALA: I don't know.
Maybe I will try to always
read The Ultimate.
Because I really have no
excuse not to read it.
FELICIA: Yeah.
Oh that's a good one.
I'm going to try to pick
more books that I
haven't read before.
Oh I want to poll
the forums more.
Because these were
forum picks.
You guys voted on the forums.
So I'm thinking maybe
every other month
we'll do you guys pick.
I don't know.
KIALA: Yeah I think that
would be great.
BONNIE: Yeah.
VERONICA: That's a good idea.
FELICIA: Because I always feel
such incredible guilt.
We all picked one in a month.
And you feel like you
disappointed your friends.
It's like, oh no.
People don't like my book.
VERONICA: Yes.
FELICIA: It takes
such pressure.
So I think if we do every other
month the forum gets to
pick the books.
Oh and actually next month
is a forum pick as well.
Because it didn't go with
this one as an alt.
So I picked one and three and
then number two is going to be
the book next month.
BONNIE: I think it's a good idea
because when we do our
meetups, well when Veronica and
I did the meetup in San
Francisco, everyone that was
there had really good
suggestions of books
we should read.
And so I feel like leaving
it up to the
forums is a good idea.
FELICIA: Yeah and it might be
best to have people be able to
do write-ins and see what
people are voting for.
It'll just be a public discourse
over the month.
So that way even if you don't
have one to volunteer other
people can write one
in and post it.
You could change your
vote too to see.
So we'll be able to have a
really good process where it's
not a surprise.
So that will be my--
Also, what was your favorite
book of the year?
And were there any books
that you regretted
reading this year?
BONNIE: Oh.
You mean from our group
or just in general?
FELICIA: Just in general.
VERONICA: The worst book.
Oh that's hard.
There were some stinkers.
KIALA: Yeah.
FELICIA: I feel the most bad
about that sci-fi one, the
Linnea Sinclair one.
KIALA: That's the one I
was thinking about.
The space one?
FELICIA: Yeah because that was
such a bad book and she's a
much better author than that.
And I wish I had picked the book
that I wanted to pick,
Hope's Folly, because that is a
great book and we would all
have enjoyed it more.
And I picked her first book
because I was worried about
continuity which didn't
really apply either.
And I picked one that didn't
represent her as an author as
well as I could have.
VERONICA: Yeah I can't
think of which one
was my least favorite.
That was up there.
But I think that my resolution
is going to be to make sure I
take more notes on lines and
things that I like while I'm
reading so I can call them
out later on the show.
And also to really practice
with my casting.
I've got to get on
the casting.
BONNIE: You don't have
to do that, Veronica.
That's just something I do.
VERONICA: I actually get anxiety
the day of the show.
I'm like, I haven't thought
of any casting.
BONNIE: That's why I like
Pinterest because if you want,
when you're on Pinterest you
just pin hot guys that you
think would work well.
And then you have this already
ready to go so when we do Vag
Fan you can just look at
it and go, oh that guy.
VERONICA: Yeah.
FELICIA: Yeah.
No it's a very nice board
you have there.
I have to say, I was like, oh.
This could solve a lot
of my problems.
BONNIE: If any of you follow
me on Pinterest you'll see
that I have a Benedict
Cumberbatch problem.
KIALA: Yes.
And on Tumbler.
BONNIE: And on Tumbler.
KIALA: Thanks a lot.
My Tumbler dash is all
Cumberbatch all the time
because [INAUDIBLE].
BONNIE: Sorry.
I can't help it.
I'm so excited for Star
Trek that I just--
I-- oh man.
FELICIA: Oh did you have casting
for Dragon Actually?
I had casting.
BONNIE: Well let's see.
What's your casting?
FELICIA: Jessica Biel
and The Rock.
VERONICA: I love The Rock.
I love The Rock.
FELICIA: I was just like,
I want to see them.
They're amazing.
They're both amazing.
VERONICA: What's that
new movie he's going
to be in with Marky--
KIALA: Mark Whalberg.
FELICIA: Yeah Mark Whalberg.
KIALA: I forget what
it's called.
VERONICA: Marky-Mark.
KIALA: Or Fighters.
BONNIE: I have a hard time
picturing what the dragon
should-- hmm.
I think the guy maybe from
Arrow but with long hair.
FELICIA: Oh, with '80s hair?
BONNIE: Yeah.
With '80s hair.
But '80s hair is such a turn off
for me with guys if it's
not like John Cusack,
feathered hair.
KIALA: What if it was just
like Adrian Paul from
Highlander, the series?
BONNIE: Yeah.
FELICIA: A comment on the forums
that made me laugh a
lot about Dragon Actually, Megan
says, it was like the
author watched Dragon Heart
and thought, you know what
this needs?
More nipples.
And for Dennis Quaid
to be a woman.
BONNIE: Yeah.
Yeah.
Actually.
That's a good idea.
Or not even Dragon Heart.
What's the other one with
Christian Bale?
KIALA: Oh, Rain of Fire.
Rain of Fire.
BONNIE: I love that movie.
KIALA: That's a really
good movie.
FELICIA: It's amazingly
bad and amazing.
Why don't they make more
movies like that?
BONNIE: I know, right?
I miss dragon movies.
KIALA: Oh, and Christian Bale
as the dragon would be nice.
BONNIE: Yeah.
That's what I was thinking
because of that movie.
KIALA: Because he's
got the beard.
BONNIE: Yeah.
Like a scruffy, scruffy
Christian Bale.
I don't know.
I like dragon movies.
I wish they'd make more.
FELICIA: They should.
It's a really high
quality choice.
There needs to be more
everything like that.
BONNIE: So my Vaginal Fantasy
goal this year.
Don't focus so much on the
comments, I guess, on our
YouTube channel.
Even though I'm programmed
to answer every question.
I'll try not to take things
personally when the people
tell me to shut my
big old face.
And I don't really have
a least favorite book.
Because even the crappy books
we've read for Vag Fan I've
liked them because you've
gotten me to read more.
So I'm just thankful that
I'm reading more.
And then I'm just thankful that
I'm in this group and
that I got you guys all
to read Cthulhurotica.
VERONICA: Yay.
FELICIA: That was a good pick.
KIALA: Yeah and I
enjoyed that.
Oh also I'm going
to talk more.
I'm trying.
Shy.
FELICIA: Your hair looks
excellent too
today, by the way.
KIALA: Oh.
Thank you.
BONNIE: It does.
FELICIA: You're quite welcome.
OK we're going to wrap it up.
Next month's hangout is
on January 29 at 8 PM.
We're going back to
Tuesday nights.
Although this afternoon was
kind of fun actually.
BONNIE: I like this.
VERONICA: It was fun.
KIALA: It was nice.
And good lighting.
FELICIA: Yeah it's very
good lighting.
We're all very alert.
And then a lot of people in
Europe were able to tune in
for the first time.
VERONICA: The problem is now
that I'm drunk at 3 o'clock in
the afternoon.
KIALA: Yeah me too.
BONNIE: Honestly, I'm glad that
we did this because I
like seeing you guys
in daylight.
And also the fact that all of
our UK and Europe fans get to
watch us because I'm a
huge Anglophile so
that's kind of hot.
FELICIA: Well if you guys start
a thread on the forums
about the time we could talk
amongst ourselves if there's
any flexibility with moving.
Just start a thread on the
forums and we'll discuss it.
And then our next month's book
is the number two polled pick
that you guys voted
for this month.
It is Outlander, by Diana
Gabaldon which is being
adapted by Ron Moore for a TV
show which is kind of cool.
And as an alt pick, I picked
In Bed With A Highlander by
Maya Banks.
Extremely smutty.
BONNIE: Really?
VERONICA: Nice.
FELICIA: Well Outlander
is such a meaty book.
It's kind of like
Crucial Start.
I don't know if we'll actually
get to the alt to discuss it
because Outlander is pretty
thick and intense.
But I'll try.
But anyway, for you guys'
enjoyment, it's a much less
serious version of
the Highlander.
BONNIE: The author of Outlander
is pretty excited
that we're reading it
for Vag Fan too.
FELICIA: Oh really?
Oh that's great.
VERONICA: No pressure.
KIALA: I've always wanted
to read this book too.
I've picked it up so many times
since I was like 17.
Has it been out that long?
I don't know.
I'm old.
FELICIA: [INAUDIBLE] you are.
OK.
Well thanks you guys.
We'll see you next month,
January 29.
VERONICA: I've got go hang
out with [INAUDIBLE].
And [INAUDIBLE] too.
FELICIA: Oh yeah.
All right bye guys!
KIALA: Goodbye.