about stuff, and I'd be like,
OK, well, everything has to be
like just perfect.
And I still kind of am.
It's like there are sometimes
that if something's happening,
I get a little irritated
about something.
But for the most part, I learned
how to relax and just
go with the flow and know that,
at the end of the day,
all the work that I've done
was put in my camp.
And the result will be the
result no matter what it is.
-This is what we do and
why we do it, baby.
No doubt, nobody does
it any better.
This is your night,
your fight.
You get it right, son.
All that hard work, all that
time in the gym, now it's time
to get it done.
-When you get over there today,
please, please make
sure when you go up in front
of the commission that you
identify specifically the people
that you want on your
corner shoot tomorrow.
Travis Browne.
TRAVIS BROWNE: Yep.
The thing about fighting, for
two months, we're doing
everything for ourselves.
Like, nobody else is going to
get in that damn cage with us.
You know?
So for two months straight
before a fight, we are some of
most selfish people out there.
And we have every right to be.
So after the fights or even
leading up to the fights--
it gets even that much
more intense
leading up to the fight.
I fought Chad in April, and I
went back a week later to
train for 146 just
as an alternate.
And then I went back two weeks
later to train for my fight
with Ben Rothwell.
That got cut a week
before the fight.
And then I went home for two
weeks and then came back and
did another seven week
camp for this fight.
So it was like rough, bro.
-What have you guys been
chatting about so far?
They're from New York.
You've got a fight tomorrow.
TRAVIS BROWNE: Yeah, we've
got a fight tomorrow.
You guys came in.
-I saw Big Foot in the hotel.
He looked a little
scared actually.
TRAVIS BROWNE: Oh, did you?
-He did, yeah.
-He didn't really look
as big as I expected.
You're actually a lot taller.
TRAVIS BROWNE: Oh, yeah.
I'm a lot taller.
But he's a big dude.
Did you shake his hand?
-No.
TRAVIS BROWNE: His hands
are like this big.
With Silva, there's little
things that he does that we
just have to be careful about.
In the long run, I'm just
training to train.
I'm just training to fight
like I'm going to fight.
My style isn't going to change
regardless who it is.
I'm one of the taller guys
in the division.
I have one of the
longer reaches.
So I'm just going to use that
in every single fight I can.
-Travis Hapa Browne versus
Antonio Big Foot Silva.
246 for Travis Browne.
TRAVIS BROWNE: I think usually
the guys that feel like they
have to try and intimidate
somebody are usually the ones
that feel like they have
something to make up for.
You know?
I go there.
I do my stare down, and I'm good
with just walking away.
But if somebody wants to get
in there and get in my face
and try to posture on me to
make me back down, they're
going to get it right back.
And that's what happened
today.
He got where we are like
touching noses and all this
kind of stuff.
And Dana had to come in.
And at that point, I'm not
going to back down.
If you're going to bring it up
like that, you better be able
to back it up the next day.
-Travis, can I get
your autograph?
TRAVIS BROWNE: Yeah.
For sure, bud.
-Thanks, dude.
[CHATTERING]
-Thanks, man.
Can I get a picture
with you too, bro?
TRAVIS BROWNE: Yeah.
-Good luck, dude.
TRAVIS BROWNE: Thanks, man.
Fans coming up to you wanting to
take your picture, or have
an autograph, or just talk for
a little bit or something is,
for me, that means I'm
doing my job right.
It means that they're interested
in me as a fighter,
and they're excited
to watch me fight.
That's why they bought the
ticket, to go and spend the
night there waiting for me to
get into the cage and knock
somebody out.
Today during the stare down,
my opponent kind of got a
little close.
And he wanted to keep
an eye on me.
So I was just showing him that
he's got a fight tomorrow.
You can't look away, you know?
You can't submit like that.
So he knows.
He knows what's coming
down tomorrow.
And I look forward to it.
I try to eat these pretty
plain, even
though this is curry.
It's still eight hours
before my fight.
So my next meal will
be pretty bland.
I just try to eat stuff
that gives me energy.
The day of my fight, in the
morning I'll be waking up.
And I'll just be warming up with
my coach and really just
going over last minute
game plan things.
And just break a sweat, hitting
pads, doing a little
bit of wrestling, staying
focused on our game plan.
That way when I'm in the cage,
it's just second nature.
I don't have to think
about it.
It just happens.
It helps you get over that first
hump in the day where
you might feel a little
sluggish, a little slow, or
something like that.
That way when you're warming up
right before you walk out
for your fight, you're already
on your second wind.
You're like, OK, I'm
ready to go.
This is it.
There's nothing holding
me back.
And you're walking into that
arena knowing that you're
ready to fight.
-Mr. Browne, what's up, baby?
TRAVIS BROWNE: What's up?
-All the way down on
the end, baby.
All the way down on the end.
TRAVIS BROWNE: Coach, that
spin kick's coming nasty.
-Is it?
TRAVIS BROWNE: Yeah.
With coach Jackson and coach
Wink has really helped me in a
couple different ways.
They have the perfect yin
and yang tactics, I
guess you could say.
But really it's the environment
that they've
created in the gym also with my
training partners and the
environment where the gym is.
Definitely my striking has
come around a lot.
I've really learned what
my body can do.
And I think coach Wink has had
a lot to do with that.
He's like, oh, you like that?
Yeah, let's work it.
Let's make it a weapon and
go out and perform and
do what I do best.
And I already have the mentality
that I'm going to go
in that cage, and I'm going to
go in that cage to hurt you.
I'm not your friend.
I'm not your family.
And even if I was, if you're in
that cage with me on flight
day, I'm still going
to try to hurt you.
Because you're going to try to
do the same thing to me.
-Travis Hapa Browne.
[FIGHT COMMENTARY]
-Declaring the winner by TKO
Antonio Big Foot Silva.
TRAVIS BROWNE: At this point
it just motivates me.
It pisses me off that somebody
like that is going to make a
name off me.
He's my first defeat.
And being cordial and all that
kind of shit put aside, that
mother fucker doesn't beat
me on my worst day.
I got injured in the fight.
And I wouldn't mind that being
my first fight back.
I want that fight back,
everybody knows it.
And all it's going to do is
motivate the fuck out of me.
If I wasn't motivated
before, I am now.
My whole thing is that if he
was better than me today, I
wouldn't have a problem
with it.
But the fact that I got injured
and I was hurt in the
first fucking 30 seconds
of the fight, just
fucking pisses me off.
And for him to make a staple in
his career off of my name,
makes it even worse.