and the culture and politics
behind them.
This time, we're in the party
capital of the Middle East--
Tel Aviv.
-[SPEAKING HEBREW]
-I wanna go home.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
-We are in Israel for
Tel Aviv's second
fashion week in 30 years.
But had it been scheduled
any later, it
may not have happened.
No sooner had the last model
left the runway, the conflict
between Israel and Palestine
escalated to the worst it's
been in recent history, with
Tel Aviv's Iron Dome being
breached for the first time by
missiles sent from Gaza.
-Tel Aviv came under rocket
attack for the
first time in 21 years.
Hamas fired over 300 rockets
at Israel in 24 hours.
-Tel Aviv is the economic center
of Israel, and secular
tourist haven.
Known for it's 24-hour party
lifestyle and thriving gay
scene, it's not hard to see why
it's gained a reputation
as the home of hedonism
in the holy land.
The event kicked off with
a press junket where the
president of Tel Aviv fashion
week fielded questions from
local and foreign press.
-Body mass index, or BMI, is the
globally accepted method
for estimating human body fat
based on an individual's
weight and height, and a BMI
of below 18.5 is considered
underweight.
The law is contentious because
BMI is a general measurement
and doesn't take things like
genetics or race into account.
The opening show was none other
than Italian fashion
house Moschino.
I was intrigued to hear what
such a big designer would
think of the law.
-Moschino being such a stalwart
in this fashion
industry, you know, you work
with the best models, the
biggest faces in the industry.
Somewhere like this that maybe
next year they're not going to
be able to work with the
international standard of
models because of
their BMI law.
What do you think about that?
BILL SHAPIRO: Fashion is
about making women
feel cool and beautiful.
You know, fashion sells a
dream, and everything's
supposed to look as beautiful as
possible, but that doesn't
necessarily mean
ill, obviously.
-Cool and beautiful.
I couldn't agree more, but
couldn't help but wonder how
the global fashion industry
would be affected if
legislation was passed
worldwide.
The very makeup of high fashion
would be impacted.
-You're going to be the first
fashion week whose size of the
model is dictated by law.
How does that make you feel?
-How can you hope to compete
with an international
aesthetic standard of how models
should look if you're
not allowed to use that
look anymore?
-I could understand
that [INAUDIBLE]
didn't want his fashion week to
be engulfed in an argument
about anorexic models, but to
say it doesn't matter just
sounded obtuse, especially
given the facts.
-Across town, there was another
fashion event being
held by people who think
this matters very much.
Simply U, a model agency that
strictly represents girls with
a healthy BMI, was having a
dinner during the fashion week
to commiserate its models for
being too overweight for
current catwalk standards.
Simply U was founded by Adi
Barkan, an Israeli fashion
photographer, model agent, and
one-time publisher of racy
magazine, Bikini.
-[SPEAKING HEBREW]
-Adi's career took a u-turn
in the 90s when a model he
advised to lose a few pounds
consequently almost starved
herself to death.
-Since then, Adi has put all
his energy into pushing
through legislation stating that
models with a BMI under
18.5 will not be able to work,
and Photoshopped advertising
images must carry
a disclaimer.
-[SPEAKING HEBREW]
-Adi believes that by targeting
the fashion industry
through how they can
advertise, he's
got them by the balls.
If they breach the code,
the lose money.
-Adi Barkan is not the only
Israeli photographer to broach
social issues with his work.
We went to meet another guy who
creates such controversial
imagery we had to seek him out
in a concealed, underground
shoot location.
-Lior Nordman had tongues
wagging when he did a shoot
for fashion magazine
"BelleMode," in which he
parodied a news story about
segregation on public buses.
Women face harassment unless
they sit at the back of
certain buses serving
ultra-orthodox communities,
who believe there should
be no public
contact between the sexes.
He went on to confront further
religious and political taboos
in his ongoing series, "Why
Can't We All Just Get Along?,"
which features characters of
different religions and same
genders getting on really
rather well together.
-Even though it had been fun,
there were definitely some
moments where I wondered if
this was the kind of thing
that gets a fatwa put
on your head.
There was something a bit
carpe diem about Lior's
attitude to sensationalizing
such a situation.
But upon my arrival back in
fashion week, it seemed Lior
wasn't the only one putting his
own spin on the conflict.
-Before we knew it, it was the
end of the two day long
fashion week.
Mr. Moschino had said fashion
week was about selling a
dream, but in this case, it
felt like Tel Aviv fashion
week was about selling
Tel Aviv.
Despite its reputation as a
liberal, European-style city,
its location means most people
approach it with caution.
And if any creative industry
were to thrive, it needs to be
regarded differently.
And unfortunately, the day
after the fashion week
finished, something happened
that showed just why that is.
The Israeli defense force
launched something called
Operation Pillar of Defense
to eliminate militants and
weapons sites in the Gaza
Strip, which began by
assassinating Hamas military
chief, Ahmed al-Jabari, in a
targeted missile attack
in Gaza City.
Suddenly, the bomb hats
didn't feel so funny.
The next morning, we were
hanging out on a test shoot
with some of girls from
Adi Barkan's agency.
Our original plan had been to
spend some time with female
soldiers of the Israeli Defense
Force, but after
launching Operation Pillar of
Defense, they cancelled.
The IDF is unique in that it's
the only army in the world
that requires national service
to be completed by girls.
To the delight of weird war
nerds across the world, the
IDF is full of girls
like this.
No one is exempt, not even
bona fide supermodels.
-Esti Ginzburg, 19-year-old
Israeli supermodel, recently
decided, unlike some other
Israeli celebrities, to not
avoid serving her obligatory two
years of military service.
ESTI GINZBURG: If you live in
this country, and you grow up
in this country, then you have
to serve and do the minimum.
It's the values that
I grew up on.
And I always knew that I'm going
to go in, and even tough
it's hard, it's what
I need to do.
-As a result, the girls
of the IDF have become
something of a fetish.
Whole websites are dedicated to
the hot girls of the IDF.
And I'd been super excited about
learning how to do this
from a hot tank instructor.
-But as the day wore on, it
became clear that there was a
steady escalation of
violence in Gaza.
The reality of being a part
of one of the most heavily
engaged armies in the world
quickly eclipses any
superficial fantasies about
girls with guns.
We shared a taxi home with
Margo, one of the models from
the agency.
The driver seemed agitated.
The latest news on the
radio explained why.
-[SPEAKING HEBREW]
-As we drove back into the
center of Tel Aviv, everything
seemed eerily normal.
There were no signs of anyone
freaking out in the streets.
But we thought we'd better head
back to the apartment and
get the facts.
Things weren't looking good.
Hamas said, Israel had opened
the gates of hell, so we're
retaliating.
For the first time since the
Gulf War in 1991, Tel Aviv
residents were hearing the
whine of air raid sirens,
warning them to take cover
from incoming missiles.
-[SPEAKING HEBREW]
-The Israeli Air Force pounded
dozens of targets in Gaza,
including missile storage
facilities
and launching sites.
Among the weapons destroyed were
rockets that could hit as
far as 25 miles into Israel.
Defense minister, Ehud Barak,
has mobilized the first
reserve infantry units.
-55,000 Israeli troops were
being mobilized along the
border, and among them,
Margo's boyfriend.
That really brought
the news home.
The foreign office was advising
people to get out of
the country, but it was late,
and we decided to sleep on it
and see what the morning
looked like.
[AIR RAID SIRENS]
-Oh, you fucking--
-I'd never heard an air
raid siren before.
What you're meant to do is take
shelter underground, not
stand out on the balcony like
us, trying to spot the rocket
like some kind of firework
display from hell.
-I'm googling like, what to do,
siren, basement, Tel Aviv.
-Soon, people had returned to
the streets from wherever
they'd sheltered and got on
with whatever they'd been
doing before.
-Somebody's delivering pizza.
-It was as if nothing
had happened.
Even on the beach a mere half
mile from where the rocket had
smashed into the sea, friends
played Frisbee, and dads did
Tai Chi with their kids.
None of this [INAUDIBLE] with
the official foreign office
advice to get out now.
And as we made our way home
to pack, I wish we'd
had more time here.
However, all our appointments
had been cancelled, and there
was nothing we could do.
[MUSIC PLAYING]