TOM SACHS: My name
is Tom Sachs.
I'm 45 years old.
This is my Space Program.
Scientists will be analyzing
Mars soil samples, determining
whether it's safe to inseminate
the Mars surface.
VAN NEISTAT: The same energy and
the same skill that NASA,
the other NASA, used to get
their people to the moon, we
are using here.
And we're using all the money
we can get our hands on.
We're using all the hours we can
get out of ourselves, all
of our brain power, all
of the research, to
accomplish this mission.
And in that respect, we
are going to Mars.
LT SAM RATANARAT: There's a
real buzz in the studio.
And everyone's always working
on something different.
And if people are helping each
other, and there's always
people coming in for
studio visits.
And it's just kind of--
it's really alive, and
it's really great.
It's the best job
I've ever had.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
TOM SACHS: The space program
ended in October with the
closure of the shuttle
program.
It's clear that companies like
SpaceX, Elon Musk's private
thing, or Richard Branson or
the Google guys, everyone's
got their own space
program now.
And that's where
the money's at.
And I think that my space
program has as much teeth as
theirs do because mine wins
hearts and minds.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN): Three,
two, one, main engine
start, zero, and lift off of
the Atlas V with Curiosity,
seeking clues to the planetary
puzzle about life on Mars.
TOM SACHS: The Mars Science
Laboratory, MSL, Curiosity's
landing on Mars on August 4
is the greatest scientific
machine we've ever created.
It's a fantastic rover that
has a mass spectroscopy
machine, laser emulation,
great cameras.
And a rover, it runs on like
a nuclear-power battery.
It's the most miraculous
thing.
But you might not even
know about it.
And your viewers might not
know about it because it
doesn't have any people on it.
And, as sexual, reproducing
beings, it's important that we
go to other planets to
encourage people.
I mean, when Neil Armstrong
stepped on the moon, you
imagined yourself
in his shoes.
When that robot does laser
emulation, it's really hard
for you to even imagine
what that idea is.
I think we have to go to Mars.
It's an important place to go
from a scientific perspective.
If you want to look at
the big question--
where did we come from?
Mars has evidence of that there
used to be water there.
If you took one semester of
sedimentology in college, you
will believe that water was
there, if you just study the
facts, the pictures,
and understand how
water erodes rock.
And why is that important?
Well, wherever there was
water, there was life.
GORDON MILLSAPS: This
is the only--
not even NASA has like a
completely freestanding LEM
module like this, aside from the
ones that are on the moon.
What we've got in here is
everything that the two
astronauts will need for the
full mission, and then some.
Everything from--
I mean, we might put a little
more emphasis on vibe than the
normal space program because we
have the DJ mixer over here
with the CD player
and an iPod dock.
We have the tequila, vodka,
and whiskey bar, including
blunt pumps running through our
own homemade dispensers.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Seven, six, five,
four, three, two, one.
Lift off.
VAN NEISTAT: That's
like the master.
And then you have all of the
different cameras that are
spaced out.
So this is a chronological order
of the things that are
going to happen.
Right?
So this is where you suit up,
in the quarantine, this is
where the astronauts
will suit up.
And then, eventually,
we get to the launch
pad is right there.
That's the rockets, et
cetera, et cetera.
And what this is basically a
time line of the mission.
GORDON MILLSAPS: What
I've learned
about the space program--
partly through our own work,
but also through our
partnership with the folks at
Jet Propulsion Laboratory,
with whom we've had a bit of a
back and forth think tank over
the past two years-- where they
fly over to us, drink
tequila, and talk about art.
We fly over to them, drink
vodka, and talk about science.
It's really that it's
just some dudes
in a glorified garage.
When they come over to our
studio, and we talk about the
steering on the rover,
where we took a golf
cart, cut it in half.
And the winch, mounted it to the
steering so that you could
have push-button steering
in your right hand.
We all sat around and just kind
of fucked around with
ideas with our buddies
from JPL.
And then we were like, man, how
did you put those airbags
on the Pathfinder
mission to Mars?
And he was like, I don't know.
We just tried some stuff, just
like we're doing now.
And once it stopped popping,
we thought it might work.
So we kind of realized there's a
greater affinity between the
work that we have and
their work than we'd
ever thought before.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
GORDON MILLSAPS: This isn't just
plywood and some artists,
like, trying to tell you that
we're definitely going to Mars
on the Park Avenue Armory.
Like, we're actually dealing
with our friends at NASA and
Jet Propulsion Laboratory.
We're actually figuring out real
systems and talking about
existing systems.
And it's our hope that some of
that little stoke, little bit
of excitement-- if one
five-year-old comes out of
here with an idea that sticks
with him for a few years, long
enough to get him to go and
study things a little bit
deeper, every little bit
of it's worth it.
TOM SACHS: I think what I've
learned from NASA is stay out
of headquarters.
Don't ask permission
from government.
Do it yourself because they
will only mire you in
bureaucracy.
They will crush your spirit.
Don't get a motorcycle
license.
That's what I learned.
Ride safe, but don't get
involved in the system.
[MUSIC PLAYING]