So let's say we were
doing geoengineering
because we wanted to make
the weather
a little bit better.
There'll be monsoon failures
during that period.
There'll be huge hurricanes.
The global studies indicate
there will be
some impact
on precipitation patterns.
Might involve large-scale
regional agricultural disruption
lasting a number of years.
Potentially two billion people
could have their food disrupted
by such interventions.
That the aerosols can--
at least in these models,
simulations, or indicated
by these simulations--
can offset most climate change
in most places most of the time
for both precipitation
and runoff.
But it's likely to cause some
damage in some places.
[theme music playing]
When I grow up, I wanna be
either an artist or a teacher.
I wanna grow up in a world where
there's lots of nature.
I love nature.
How can I look my children
in the eyes...
and not try to shed the light
on this issue,
knowing every breath they take
is--is laden with these metals?
I have been forced to conclude
that there is no greater
or no more immediate threat
to anything
that lives and breathes
than the global
geoengineering programs,
short of nuclear catastrophe.
Geoengineering is defined
as the artificial modification
of the earth's climate.
Geoengineers are proposing
spraying 10 to 20 million tons
of toxic aluminum and other
substances into our sky
for the stated goal
of cooling our planet.
So let me distinguish
these two different, uh, kinds
of geoengineering
as clearly as I can.
So the first one is--we call
solar radiation management,
and that's the idea that
you could put reflective,
mostly reflective particles
or other means
to make the earth whiter,
effectively to increase
the earth's reflectivity,
reducing the amount of--of heat
that's absorbed by the sun
and therefore exerting some
overall cooling tendency
on the earth.
I think, though, the initial
results of climate models
indicate that reflection
of sunlight away from the earth
can offset most climate change
in most places most of the time.
But it will damage some places.
We've mostly thought
about sulfur.
Nevertheless, there might be
some good reasons
to think about aluminum.
Turns out, first of all,
there's been a lot of work
on the environmental
consequences of aluminum
in the stratosphere.
There's a bunch of papers going
back to the '70s
that look at the radiative
and ozone--
ozone destroying properties
of aluminum in the stratosphere,
and those make you think it
might be useful.
Do this in just a jet
in a very simple way.
Make high-quality aluminum
particles just by spraying
aluminum vapor out,
which oxidizes.
So it's certainly, in principle,
possible to do that.
Since we released "What
in the World Are They Spraying,"
hundreds of people
from around the world
have began taking rain tests.
What they're finding
is what many are calling
the chemtrail
geoengineering footprint
of aluminum, barium,
and strontium.
So we're finding this Welsbach
footprint internationally,
all over the world,
wherever they take samples
and get a, uh, chemical analysis
of rain and snow water.
This is quite common.
Wherever you see the jet
chemtrails go over,
you're gonna get aluminum,
barium, strontium
coming down on you.
Why would we not believe
that it's happening
when what we see in the sky
matches exactly the express goal
of numerous geoengineering
patents, about 160 or more?
Why would we not believe this
is happening when every element
showing up in the rain tests
are the primary elements named
in those
geoengineering patents?
Why would we not believe this
is happening when we have
escalating levels in very short
time frames, as much--
as short as five years,
we see rain levels
of aluminum, for example,
escalating as much as 50,000%?
California air quality studies
do not show these metals
migrating from China,
and it's of recent origin.
So, you know, this bombardment
of heavy metals
that's raining down on us is
coming from somewhere.
Why would we not believe
geoengineering is occurring
when the weather patterns are so
altered here
in exactly the manner stated
by geoengineers
and reports on the consequences
for geoengineering,
which are diminished rainfall,
which are increased ozone
destruction.
We have a massive ozone hole
in the Northern hemisphere now.
Should aluminum be in the soil
and the rain?
And yes, it should be
in the soil.
It's naturally there.
Always was there.
And should it be in the rain?
Well, absolutely not.
But the standard reply has been,
"Your samples are contaminated."
But since we are getting samples
now that show zero aluminum,
and we're getting lots
of barium and strontium
and zero aluminum.
So that just proves that if
there was dirt in our samples
of some sort,
dust blown up from the ground,
we should get some aluminum
in some detectable quantity.
The primary ingredients in
geoengineering are specifically
the oxides of metals,
including aluminum oxide.
This is devastating plants,
totally devastating.
The trees are dying.
Why?
Approximately two years ago,
I rode in the back--
and you can ride in the back
of my place for miles.
You can go all the way
through the woods, you know,
creeks and everything,
and it was--I say was--gorgeous.
And the day before yesterday,
I took a ride,
and I rode in the back,
and what I found
was total devastation.
As I pointed out before,
Michael, we're seeing,
as in this example here,
very hardy, native plants
completely flash out dead.
That looks like it's been hit
with some kind of a chemical.
And we've only seen this
in the last couple years.
And there's another one there,
there, back over there.
We're seeing mature
madrone trees,
which are 70, 80 feet high,
flash out dead just like this.
USDA refuses
to investigate it.
The pH typically around here
should be about 5.6.
Well, since the contrailing
got heavy,
I watched the pH here
in these forests, well,
go up I guess would be
the word.
from 5.6, it went about 20 times
more alkaline.
Very big red flag of fallout
from these materials
are pH changes
to the forest floor.
We have very extensive studies
from the U.S. Department
of Agriculture
on the soils in our region,
and those soils have changed
in five to six years.
The pH's have changed in this--
in this area
as much as 10 to 12 times toward
alkaline in five to six years.
I've personally been
in the forest testing
with USDA soil scientists
who just scratched their heads
and seemed to have no
explanation
for incredibly profound
changes in pH,
which is affecting the
ecosystem here tremendously.
Aluminum buffer action,
aluminum hydroxide
is what we think it is,
uh, plus the barium carbonate,
strontium titanate,
strontium oxides,
barium oxides,
probably some aluminum oxides
in there.
But this has apparently driven
our acid soils
about 20 times more alkaline,
to about 6.8.
There are simply too many dots
here that connect.
Our skies are almost
never blue anymore.
That is a named consequence
of geoengineering.
The amount of lost sunshine
hitting the planet right now
is beyond belief.
If people look up the term
"global dimming," they will see
that fully 20% of the sun's rays
that reached the planet
several decades ago are
no longer reaching the planet.
I mean, that's a profound change
that few people even know
is occurring.
And you have very visible
occurrences in the sky
from the aircraft,
a very visible sun blocking,
expanding, dingy trails
that are exactly
what geoengineering patents
describe.
Heavy aluminum--I'm talking,
like, in the 40s and 50s,
up to 3,000, 4,000, 5,000--
that's still common.
Uh, barium, strontium,
to, um, oh,
somewhere 40 or 50 to,
again,
about 2,000 or 3,000.
Same for both barium
and strontium.
Where is this mountain
of metal coming from?
Why is asthma, A.D.D.,
Alzheimer's, autism--
all elements related
in many studies to aluminum
or particulate inhalation--
why are these el--
why are these ailments
going off the charts with no
apparent explanation?
Why has respiratory mortality
in the continental United States
gone from eighth on the list
to third in six years?
And no one seems to ask
any questions,
why everybody, uh, every other
person has asthma now,
why every other commercial on TV
is an allergy medication.
And again, when David Keith,
the world's most recognized
geoengineer,
was asked on the record,
had there been any studies done
as to the consequences
of dumping 20 million tons
of aluminum into the atmosphere,
his answer was patently, "No."
While geoengineers claim that
their models
are to cool the planet, a number
of studies now are arising
that indicate,
yes, temporarily,
there will be, regionally,
cooling as these particulates
reflect the sun.
However, they actually
at night act as a blanket
and will warm the planet.
So the question now remains,
"Why in the world
are they spraying?"
One of the things that
geoengineering is about,
when you're environmentally
doing something
with the atmosphere,
is that you can be engaged
in weather modification.
Historically, weather
modification
in the United States began
to be looked upon
in the 1940s as something
that people would want to do.
And so they started looking
at making it--enhancing snow,
enhancing rain.
They started looking
at hurricane control.
There was a whole bunch
of projects in the '40s
that started.
One was Project Stormfury,
which turned into a disaster
when they tried to modify
a hurricane.
I'm Mark McCandlish.
And for the better part
of 30 years, I worked
in the Aerospace and Defense
Industry.
I had a secret clearance
twice during my career.
Some of the technology that I
saw or participated
in the creation of
tends to play a role
in, um, some of the things that
are used to control the weather.
The very distribution processes
being employed
in the aerosol campaign--
manipulating the weather, crops,
um, you know,
taking over the--the, uh,
the food production
or controlling the food
production,
the military applications--
the process evolved
when they realized in the--
in the 1800s that you can put
things into the environment
that will influence
the uptake of moisture
and where it drops
out of the atmosphere again.
My name is Scott Stevens.
I, uh, was a television
weatherman for 20 years.
These chemtrails are absolutely
required to impact
whatever weather event
they were designing.
And the trails were an absolute
necessary ingredient
for them to achieve their
weather modification goals.
So we're finding the aerosols,
the metal particulates,
all of those can be used
and leveraged to create
weather events that are
several standard deviations
or outside what would be
typically normal.
When the geoengineering really
got underway with the Russians
in the mid-'70s, we ended up
with snow in Miami.
We ended up even with frost
deep into Mexico.
You know, the bizarreness
of the weather really exploded
on the scene when, uh,
when weather engineering
got going in the mid-'70s.
The Dakotas, in winter,
they recorded a temperature
of almost 100 degrees,
94 degrees.
It broke the former record
by 32 degrees.
There's very profound things
that people don't notice.
Blue skies almost never.
We almost never have dew
on the ground.
That's a known consequence of
geoengineering, if they did it,
which they appear to be.
It sucks the moisture out
of the atmosphere.
It doesn't descend,
doesn't form dew.
We have massive temperature
disruptions.
People are starting to wonder,
"Why is it 80 degrees one day
"and then snowing the next day
at 50 degrees or 45 degrees,
and then back up to 80
the day after that?"
When you push and pull
the climate with these--
these manipulations programs,
of which there's
a mountain of data
to corroborate their existence,
then you start to have massive
fluctuations in the system.
And we saw in March,
in the continental U.S.
there were 15,232 temperature
records broken.
That's profound.
Some of the daytime highs,
the former records were broken
by as much as 32 degrees.
Don't people wonder what
in the world is going on?
Whether they want to make it
snow at 45, 46, 47 degrees--
I remember when 38, 39
was a big deal.
Those kind of snowfalls
in the upper 30s.
And now that's been pushed
into the 40s.
There's a patent called
"Ice nucleation for Weather
Modification".
This is a patent from NASA.
It can be found online
in its full form.
This patent is for the creation
of artificial snowstorms
from what would have been
rainstorms.
However preposterous it sounds
to people,
if they look up
"Chinese create snowstorms",
they will find a long list
of articles
where the Chinese Bureau
of Weather Modification
openly admitted that they were
creating snowstorms
until they did a billion
dollars' worth of damage
in Beijing.
So my question would be,
if the Chinese can do this,
and NASA has a patent
for the same purpose,
why would we believe snow events
here are natural,
when it's snowing now,
regularly, at 45 degrees,
sometimes 50 degrees--
heavy, wet, concrete snow
that's full of aluminum,
full of barium,
full of strontium?
Consider the ice pack
in their first aid kit
that can sit dormant
at room temperature for decades,
until the chemicals
are mixed together,
at which time it creates ice.
As an on-air meteorologist,
I had a responsibility
to my audience.
There were storms that were not
behaving as they were modeled
or they historically
would have responded.
If you can control where
moisture is collected
and where it's dropped,
so to speak,
in the form of rain or any other
kind of precipitation,
then you can really--you can
do everything.
You can steer
the weather system.
If you want to be able
to manipulate the weather,
one of the things we know about
the materials
that are being used
in the aerosols--
we--we've seen everything
from aluminum oxide,
barium salts, strontium,
copper sulfate,
uh, potassium iodide, um,
a number of different kinds
of things,
each of which have different
levels of reactivity
with the moisture in the air.
Some, like aluminum oxide,
tends to sequester
the moisture.
The aluminum oxide
nanoparticles,
which are microscopically fine
and uniform in size,
attract the humidity
and the moisture in the air,
and they can--it basically forms
like a nucleation process,
where the moisture condenses
on these particles.
The--with cloud seeding,
the cooling will be achieved
by making clouds reflect
a bit more sunlight
back to space
than they would otherwise.
And less sunlight reaching
the surface would tend
to cool the planet.
These aerosol particle act--
particles act
as something called
cloud condensation nuclei,
and, um, this is--these are
sites where--
these particles act as sites
where cloud drops can form.
Well, the one thing that
we know has happened is,
because these
are nanoparticles,
and they float like mad
with a little bit of, uh,
moisture added to them.
They go over
the Continental Divide.
They dumped all
of California's rain
into the Mississippi Valley,
which is the reason
they're having floods
and tornadoes and fierce storms
and odd weather back east.
The effect here
in California is drought.
Now, then, if you hit
that area of the sky
with a beam of a particular kind
of radiation,
and you can heat
those particles up,
just like heating up,
you know,
your--your cup of coffee
in the microwave,
these particles begin
to vibrate and resonate,
if you use the right frequency
of--of, uh, RF energy,
that they then heat
the surrounding air,
and they will take all
of that air
and the moisture
that is in it
to a higher altitude,
where it's much colder,
and it'll condense and then
become a low pressure system.
Well, there--there's a couple
of locations
where they tend to be
very interested
in--in leaving their trails.
The big one and the surprising
one for me
is under areas
of high pressure,
where you would--you would
expect to see the blue skies,
the dry conditions.
Those are prime targets
for trailing.
Couple of reasons:
High pressure is--is stable.
It's relatively still.
You know, we've got the, uh--
the clockwise flow around it.
And if you accentuate the high,
so it's very easy
to add those particulates
of aluminum, barium,
and whatever else
they want to put in there,
and as you add heat to that,
those particulates then
radiate the heat
into the atmosphere,
and it warms.
And what does a warming
atmosphere do?
Boom, it expands.
So that's one way.
It's a very simple way,
but it's very apparent,
because under the high pressure,
it's supposed to be quiet.
It's supposed to be still.
It's supposed to be blue.
And we're not seeing that.
Then as the storm approaches,
the high begins to recede.
And then they're running
the flights back and forth,
back and forth,
and literally seeding
the leading edges of the cirrus.
So the cirrus canopy
is accentuated.
That cirrus canopy, which
would maybe be 200, 300 miles
at a head--at a head of a cold
front is now 400, 450 miles.
Based on geoengineering data,
it would appear
the Pacific Northwest gets
an excessive amount of--
of the fallout
from these programs,
because much of the weather,
much of the precipitation
in the storm tracks
and the jet stream
move across us.
So, as stated by globally
recognized geoengineers
like David Keith,
that that's the type of area
they would want
to seed these particulates,
as incoming fronts start
to cover landfall,
and that's exactly
what we see here.
When there's any kind
of incoming front,
we see jets everywhere.
The global studies indicate
there will be some impact
on precipitation patterns,
and obviously, there's a lot
more opportunity
for work in that area.
After studying
my time lapse surveillance,
one of the reasons
I discovered for the trails
was that the persistent ones
would break.
They would misshape it
or deform,
and other planes would come
along and precisely mark off
those locations of--
of deformation.
And you're not gonna get that
with a regular fleet,
so this had to be one
of the primary purposes
for chemtrails, in my opinion,
was to measure off
where we have these
discontinuities showing up
in the atmosphere.
And in doing these actions
and discovering those zones
where there's different
energies in the atmosphere,
I think that plays
very closely
into their
weather engineering programs
of mark, surveil,
and then that data goes
into--into a weather model
that they can then use
to forecast, or, once again,
engineer the weather
to their designs.
But you can also influence
what happens locally
with the atmosphere
by, um,
painting the materials that
these aerosols are made of
with different kinds of radio
frequency, or RF energy--
radar, microwave,
the HAARP system.
You know, HAARP is, um, uh,
an array,
a field of antennas,
radio frequency antennas.
They're 72 feet tall,
then they have a crosstie
pulled across the top that's
about 60 feet in each direction.
180 of these are
in the array today,
so you can imagine this field
of antennas.
What happens is,
by firing each one,
they produce radio frequency
energy that normally comes off
of an antenna, spreads out
rather rapidly.
Same principle...
principles in physics
would be like a flashlight
shining on a wall.
You know, you start
with a narrow beam,
and by the time you hit the
wall, you've got a wide beam.
The idea with HAARP is to
get it to focus or concentrate
that radio frequency energy
so it doesn't spread out,
so you can hold it tighter
together and then manipulate it
in very specific ways.
Weather control
is a broad topic.
So there's lots of ways to
control or manipulate weather.
HAARP is one of them.
Because you also have
private sector companies
getting into this business
of weather modification.
In the case of HAARP,
do you need, uh--
People always ask me,
you know,
"Do you need particulates
dispersed in the atmosphere
to make it more effective?"
You actually don't.
Would it make things
more possible?
Could you enhance
certain effects?
Probably so.
Could you control energy
distributions more efficiently?
Probably so, because you're
putting in conductors
or you're putting
in reflectors.
You're putting in
particulate material.
If you've ever experienced
a hailstorm
and you've picked up
one of the hailstones,
and you slice it open
with a razor blade,
you'll see that it's layer
upon layer upon layer of ice.
Now, hail is usually formed
where you have
a low-pressure system
where there's a tremendous
updraft of air.
The air gets warmed up
by the sunlight
ahead of the storm.
The air rises.
It takes the moisture
that's in the air
up to a higher altitude,
where it's much colder.
The moisture begins to condense
into water droplets,
but the updraft is so powerful
that the water is carried
to extreme altitudes,
where it freezes,
and it begins to fall.
And as it falls,
it starts to be caught up
in the updraft again,
so it's circulated
up into the air again.
And so each time it's
lofted up into the atmosphere,
more of the moisture that is
condensing on the outside
of this--
this nuclei of ice
begins to form another layer,
another layer.
And each time it's caught back
in the updraft,
it goes up again, and it gets
another layer of ice.
And so, if you have
a system like HAARP
working in conjunction
with aerosols,
chemtrails that are spraying
in the air,
you can actually create updrafts
that are so powerful
that you can have these
hailstone circulation patterns
going over and over again,
where you get hailstones
the size of baseballs,
or even softballs.
The weather has always been
a strategic...
desire to control
by the generals,
whether it was Napoleon,
marching towards Moscow,
or Hitler,
in his Russian campaign,
or our own Pacific fleet
trying to understand typhoons
and use them
for our strategic advantage.
War and weather are
very closely connected.
And they've been connected
ever since about 1812 or so,
maybe earlier than that.
Hannibal had to face
the snows in the Alps.
And so there's
a long history
of weather
and warfare interactions.
Environmental manipulation
is like the ultimate method
of covert warfare because you
can literally shut down
food production.
You can create a situation
where the people
within a country revolt
against their own government,
and you're invited in
to mop up the mess.
The issue of owning
the weather by 2025,
it's this
military publication.
We've quoted it as far back
as, I think, '94 or '95, even.
But you go back
to these earlier reports,
and you look at, sort of,
what was the objective?
And the objective
is exactly that:
control the battlefield
environment.
Environmental factors give you
an absolute advantage.
If you can weaken your adversary
before you have to fire
the first bullet,
maybe you even win the war.
Whether it's incredibly
historic sandstorms
when we're invading Iraq,
or you want to drought out
or flood out a dictator
that you're not happy with
or obscure a beach
when there's a landing,
or if you just want to make
money on the futures market.
Owning the weather by 2025,
using the weather
as a force multiplier.
And this kind of goes back
to what I was saying before
about if you can--
if you can control where
a weather system goes
and how much or how severe
the weather system is,
then you can do other things.
Like you may have heard
more recently
that many of the aircraft
that we've been developing
are what they call
"all-weather capable,"
which means that they can fly
in any kind of weather.
They can shoot and target
the enemy
under really nasty weather
circumstances.
And these are all things that
you can use to your advantage
if you happen to be controlling
the weather, also,
because you can have
a terrible storm front come in
and make it difficult,
if not impossible,
for the enemy to operate
on the ground
or to fly their aircraft
if they don't have aircraft
that are as sophisticated
as the ones that you have.
And so, by creating or using
the weather
as a force multiplier,
as the title implies,
that you can achieve
an advantage over an enemy force
that gives you the upper hand.
One of the ideals of the--
of the Air Force
is to have this all-weather
Air Force,
or to have their pilots
coming back safely
and using the weather
as a salient against the enemy
and clearing out
their own airports
from, say, from ice, fogs,
or from bad weather.
And so if we could--if--
the idea here is that
if we can fly
and they can't,
that's a great military
advantage.
There was also research studies
on hurricanes
that the scientists were truly
curious about the behavior
of hurricanes,
but their military patrons
were very interested
in how to steer them
or direct them in certain ways,
almost as a--
as a guided weapon.
This jet stream's moving
across, and it shoots
50 miles north
and then 75 miles east
and then drops back south again
and kind of goes on its way.
And they attributed
that little dog leg
in the jet stream in Alaska
to swinging storm systems
out of Central Texas
into Central Florida,
where they deposited a couple
of tornadoes
in the middle of Orlando
that were, like, really rare
to see in that part
of the country.
And so people remember
that event,
and they remember
that situation.
But it'd be a good example
of a very small change in Alaska
in terms of a jet stream,
and what kind
of a lower-48 effect
that would have.
And that's again where
weather modification,
small input in one place
could have tremendous change
and unexpected outcome
in another.
You can create weather systems
that are so severe,
they culminate
in battlefield denial,
where the enemy is not able
to use the roads
or the bridges or--or get
through the environment
because the weather
is so severe.
And you can--you can use the
weather to destroy his crops,
deny him a food source,
destabilize his population,
because people get hungry,
and when they're hungry,
they get angry and nasty,
and they don't like
what's happening.
So there's lots of different
things that you can do
with the materials.
It's all how you use them
in the environment,
how you apply it.
One of the biggest concerns
of early cloud seeding
weather control activities by
the General Electric Corporation
came from their lawyers,
who thought that the corporation
was totally vulnerable
to lawsuits
because if they started
to make fair or foul weather,
the people down below
in Massachusetts,
or downwind of Schenectady
could institute massive
lawsuits that could put G.E.
out of business.
So the first response
to weather control
from their in-house lawyers
was to shut it down,
was to give the project
to the military
and ask them to do it,
with the G.E. lawyers
only being the consultants
on the project.
So they were allowed
to suggest and, uh,
design certain activities,
but they weren't allowed
to touch anything
or throw anything
out of the plane.
The United States government,
during the Vietnam War,
perfected weather
modification techniques,
and also they perfected
releasing toxic chemicals
like Agent Orange over many
areas to defoliate land,
trees, grasslands,
and other areas.
But this is technology that
does come up,
and it comes up when--
when you see
that the technology
has advanced far enough
to where the practicality
of utilizing it
in the battlefield environment
and the temptation
by administrations--
I mean, the best covert war
is using environment itself
against your adversary.
There was a military moment,
and it was actually
from pretty recent history,
and this was
the U.S. military thinking
that they might be able
to control the monsoon
over Vietnam
during that conflict.
And so only a few--a handful
of top-level military advisors
and the president were informed
that they were going to try
to make it rain
over the Ho Chi Minh Trail
and try to have
some military advantage
by doing this kind
of intervention.
When you start talking about
manipulating the environment,
we have treaties that
go back to the mid-'70s
that forbid this, number one,
as weapons of war.
So the perfection of weather
modification took place,
but it became apparent that
using weather modification
for wartime purposes
was not acceptable
to the United States
government
and other nations
of the world.
So therefore, the ENMOD Treaty
came into being
and was signed
by the United States government
after passing Congress.
The reason it was signed
and implemented
was because it would ban
warfare weather
modification techniques
and use
during times of war.
Almost all of our treaties
that we've signed,
including the non-proliferation,
counter-proliferation treaties,
chemical treaties--you know,
the ones that were signed
recently, the last few years,
uh, you know, back maybe
a decade now, I guess.
Times goes.
But they had
domestic exemptions,
and so does
the environmental treaty,
where you can do
whatever you want
in your own territorial
boundaries.
I mean, you start manipulating
weather in one part of-
of the planet, it doesn't look
on the ground and say,
"Oh, yeah, wait.
This is the boundary of--
a political boundary."
It fails to recognize those.
So you start to talk
about geophysics
and manipulating
the planet itself.
Then it's a question of--
those kinds of exemptions
shouldn't even be allowed.
Meteorology and the military
have a very long history,
as I said.
And it goes into this strategic
advantage that multiplies
your traditional force--
that is, your armament--
into using nature
to your advantage as well.
They want to create a storm
in the Southeast,
then they'll start engineering
out of the North Pacific.
That's where the trails
will be,
because you want
to work out
several days ahead of time
so you have less input.
And you multiply that
over a couple of days,
you can have a big result
in five days' time.
So small input upstream,
big result downstream.
And one of the rules is
always work with what's coming.
Don't try to necessarily work
against it.
You can kill a storm in place.
That's easy to do with HAARP.
You just change
the polarization.
You change the ionization
of the atmosphere,
and the storm
will fall apart.
It will affect the setting up of
the storm tracks,
the jet stream, the location
of the storms,
and so you end up with--
an intervention
on the solar side of things
would pretty directly begin
to affect
the weather patterns.
And so climate control,
or attempted climate control,
and weather control lie
on this very large spectrum
of intervention.
It's also true that
if you can forecast climate,
you can control
a lot of futures markets,
and you could know--if you
had the best information,
or if you had some leverage
over what the climate system
is going to turn out to be,
you would be able to invest
in advance
and own your crop futures
and your agricultural
activities and--
And not just agriculture,
but weather affects--
I think it's something like
80% of the U.S. economy
is weather-sensitive.
And so all kinds of businesses
would like to see
some weather edge or some
advantageous information
that they would have.
It's absolutely, entirely
possible to profit
from the weather.
Hi, my name is Michael Agne.
I'm an independent trader...
trading commodities
at the C.M.E. Group,
member of
the Chicago Board of Trade,
and I've traded derivatives
and futures cash
for over 15 years.
Weather derivatives are
financial instruments
that firms would use
to hedge risk
concerned with adverse
weather conditions.
The first weather derivative was
originally traded by Enron
back in 1997.
Weather derivatives started
in 1999 at the C.M.E. Group.
Big utilities reinsures
to hedge against hurricanes
or tornadoes or flooding,
some sort of catastrophe.
Hedging against a cooler summer
or a warmer winter.
Let's just say I was insuring
a product for 5 million,
no matter what it was.
Let's say if it was
a utility company,
a farmer,
whatever it was.
Let's say I had $5 million
worth of crop,
but I can do derivatives that
are worth double that amount,
and I can then control
the effects
to where I collect
on the insurance
that's worth 10 million,
as opposed to selling the crop
for five million.
Yes, I could definitely
profit from that.
2010, 2011, Southern Illinois,
Missouri,
those--those, you know,
we had a high peak
of tornadoes,
and those types
of adverse weather conditions
definitely raised the price
of commodities
as well as drove
the volatility,
which also raises the price
of commodities.
You're gonna make more money
if a crop fails.
You're creating insurance
that's over the price
of what your crop is worth,
let's say.
So what if you can control
the weather?
You control
how these products grow.
And if you had an insight
to how these products were
actually seeded
and what products you used
to actually grow those items--
corn, soybeans--and you can
control that market,
it's unlimited profit potential
if you can control the weather.
If you want to send you know,
cold into the Midwest,
you buy at pipeline capacity,
you buy up options on heating
and cooling degree days.
You buy derivatives off of--
off of rainfall.
There are mechanisms
that you can make
hundreds of billions
of dollars annually
and defray a huge chunk
of the cost of this
just on the Chicago Mercantile
Exchange,
playing with derivatives
in the weather market.
Weather derivatives are
basically--
you're betting that there's
gonna be a weather disaster,
and you're betting that it's
going to occur
within a particular timeframe
in a particular location,
and then, you know,
the money that you put up
basically is like a bet.
It's like a wager
saying that, uh,
this incident's
gonna happen here.
And then, when it does happen,
there's a big payoff.
And that big payoff is something
that motivates people
to continue to participate
in this kind of thing
and maybe even feed
the very process
that's causing the bad weather
to happen,
particularly if there's
a connection
between the people that are
seeding the clouds
and the people that are
making investments.
This is a new opportunity.
It's a new tool
for investors.
You know, even if, uh,
someone has no interest in,
you know,
going on the offensive side
and buying things, um,
it definitely behooves them
to be aware
of what's going on out there.
The extreme weather is here.
You know, and it's not gonna
reverse itself.
The weather event has to be
severe.
Ionospheric heating,
in fact,
these instruments, um,
when they were first utilized,
which was in the former
Soviet Union back in the '70s--
they started out then--
they still call these
ionospheric heaters
because, in one mode
of operation,
you can literally create--
above this instrument
on the ground,
you can heat an area 30--
up to 30 miles in diameter
in the ionosphere.
So you heat it up,
and by heating it,
it literally raises it.
So you can then imagine
this column
moving up several hundred
kilometers out,
and then the lower atmosphere
begins to rush in
and fill that vacant space,
that void.
And then, as a result,
you're altering pressure systems
for, you know, quite a--
quite a distance,
which of course
alters the weather.
You're also able,
if a jet stream is coming
in the area,
you're able to alter
its course.
And if you alter a jet stream
even a small amount,
then the swing factor on the
other end,
you can move it,
so you're moving storms, say,
out of the Midwest
onto the East Coast
or this kind of thing,
by just swinging it high in--
in terms of its flow
and getting it redirected.
Okay, so now if we look
at precipitation,
much has been made
of this issue of, uh,
damage from precipitation.
Which the particulates
that these trails intro--
have a--have introduced
into the sky are--
Let's just say the storms
can develop more violently,
more quickly, um,
in places that are
not necessarily as, uh, where
you would expect them to be.
And so we see more flooding.
We see more intense droughts.
We see rainfall rates
of 1 to, you know,
2 1/4 inches an hour
that are just bizarre.
And sometimes even rainfall,
you know, 1 1/4 inch a minute.
It's just unheard of.
And so you have an area that's
already been heated
by the sun's rays,
and then you have the aerosol
drift in over that area.
And it's reflecting both ways.
It's reflecting the heat
of the sun back out,
but it's also trapping
the heat
that's already been created
there by the sunlight.
So it will actually create
more heat and trap heat inside
and closer to the atmosphere.
It can actually exacerbate
global warming problems.
And if you become more aware of
what's happening,
where the global
commodities are,
what extreme weather events,
you're one step ahead of them.
The nature of the risk and our
ability to respond to the risk
is much greater in the case
of the scenario
that might involve
large-scale regional
agricultural disruption
lasting a number of years.
So the agenda was drought.
The agenda was
to kill the storm
at least in that one
particular spot.
You see a tremendous and
significant loss of property
and, uh, crop production.
Many times, this will cause
farms to go out of business,
and when farmers
go out of business,
they usually have to sell.
And then if there's somebody
waiting in the wings
to buy their land and then
turn that land over
to the production
of genetically modified crops,
you can see where
there would be
kind of a strategic advantage
there.
There's something that
happened in the Midwest,
and I'm sure everybody's
heard about the flooding
in the Midwest.
And what happened is, um,
George Soros
and his big corporate monolith
went in and started buying up
the farmland.
So not only is it--is it
creating all these stresses,
it appears to be
a corporate land grab.
In other words,
when the farmers,
the small farmers
go out of business,
they're wiped out through these
droughts and everything,
then the big guys come in,
buy up the land.
And if you think
of Western history,
there's a lot of it concerning
water rights
and even water wars.
And so they were shooting
about access to, uh, water,
to water your livestock.
And now people are thinking,
or at least the people who are
involved in weather control
sometimes think
about the river of moisture
above our heads, and,
"Jeez if we could
just tap that."
But that too is a, uh, a water
right that would involve
access to, uh, to people
that felt like maybe they had
prior rights over it.
And you're reducing the food
security of people
through deploying these kinds
of approaches that...
Potentially 2 billion people
could have their food disrupted
by such interventions.
I've been an organic farmer
my entire life...
and I've been, um,
in the last eight years,
been certified organic.
And so I've been growing food
in a way that feels healthy,
where I have the most energy,
and now it's not so healthy.
I want to pass a really nice,
healthy soil,
rich soil earth on
to the children
and have it be fertile.
My name is Joel Gilcoca.
I've been farming on this land
for about five years...
since 2007, and I'm certified
organic since 2001.
Ten years ago, when I started
working for myself,
we can grow cilantro,
no problem.
We can grow basil,
We can grow Chinese cabbage
without get trouble
or any vegetable.
But ten years after--I mean,
five years after that,
everything start decline.
Could you add
something to the environment
that would affect
a large population?
The answer is absolutely yes.
I started seeing chemtrails
being laid overhead
more frequently
and noticing the change
in the crop production.
What we see in our area
anytime there's
convective clouds,
a large cumulus cloud forming
and beginning to rise,
we hear aircraft
in the vicinity.
We see them actually flying over
these convecting clouds,
and then in a very short time,
before those clouds generally
will drop any precipitation,
we'll see the entire cloud
more or less dissolve
into what looks like
a massive smoke bank.
If you can control
the weather,
then you can control
where the rain falls
or where it doesn't fall.
And if you can do that,
then you can control
whose crops survive
and whose crops thrive.
And if you happen to be
favoring, um, a corporation
or a group of corporations that
are flooding the market
with genetically
modified crops,
you can see how
manipulating the weather
can actually change
the market share
that one or more
corporations have.
Um, and there's, you know,
there's lots of different ways
that you can do it.
You can do it
by denying precipitation
or by giving too much.
You can cause, uh, you know,
unusually large hailstones
to come out of the sky
and completely obliterate
a crop of corn.
There's lots of different ways
that you can do it.
Um, you know, tornadoes,
rip up an entire town,
like Joplin, Missouri,
I think it was.
If you look back at the tapes
of those weather systems,
and you look five days
prior to that,
you'll see that in those days
preceding those events,
there was all kinds of aerosols
being sprayed
all along the California
coastline,
where the moisture
for those storms came from,
where those storm systems
originated.
You know, it's--
I mean, it's insidious,
when you think about it.
Oh, my God, I've seen,
since the chemtrails have come,
there's a direct correlation
with the way the health--
The food doesn't look
as healthy and vibrant,
and less of it.
And that concerns me.
And of course, all crop losses
are related
to weather modification
problems.
Either climate,
uh, worldwide weather,
or local weather, which is
called micro-climates.
And these micro-climates
definitely determine
what crop grows where
and in which community.
And so, therefore,
without stable micro-climates,
we can not produce
as much food
for the rest of the world
and ourselves
as when we have
more stable micro-climates,
not only in the United States,
but in other countries as well.
We fertilize it
really good,
and they still have a lot
of trouble to produce.
And I think this is not fun,
because we losing
a lot of money
put them into this kind
of production.
In 2008, 2009, three times
I losted my complete planting
of Chinese cabbage.
Weather events is one
of the key components
to most, uh, commodities
that are traded.
Let's just say your agricultural
group--corn, soybeans, wheat,
something along those lines,
weather is by far the largest,
uh, affecting factor
in the price of those
commodities.
If one farmer's crop fails,
we have a major crop failure,
say, in corn,
now that's going to affect
every other company
that uses corn
in their manufacturing process.
There's gonna be less of it.
And anytime there is less
of something,
that creates a price rise.
Demand rises.
Okay?
Because there isn't any of it.
There's only one thing.
You've got five people
that want it.
So they're gonna pay
more money for it.
The companies know that.
So they're gonna
hike the prices up anyway.
The consumer actually sees
the big brunt end
of the higher, you know,
cost in the commodity
due to the adverse
weather condition.
Obviously, the consumer will pay
that price.
I've noticed that the rainfall
is less predictable,
and then, when it does rain,
it does rain periods of time
that's more,
more, like, longer periods.
So not only do we have
the pollution,
not only do we have
stunted growth,
but we also have changes
in weather.
And there's been
severe changes in weather
all across the globe.
I don't have a clue
how bad they are,
but I know they are affecting
already in the--
in certain plants, you know,
like basil, cilantro,
and sometime the broccoli
get too much, uh, fungus.
It can be from those thing
because, um,
no matter what we do,
it doesn't fit.
It not working right.
It appears to be a fungally
related ailment.
And if one looks at
the species extinction rate,
which today
is estimated to be
1,000 times
natural variability,
that's 1,000 times normal,
a figure you'd think would
alarm most reasonable people,
which is 100,000% of normal,
and 70% to 80%
of that extinction,
plant and animal,
is related to fungal infection.
Geoengineering particulates
are known to proliferate
fungal reproduction.
Abiotic stresses are drought,
cold, heavy metals,
excess moisture in the soil,
and Monsanto has a patent
that actually addresses
all of those
abiotic stresses.
And the plants
that it addresses
is everything from apples
to zucchini.
2011 was one
of the worst years
for things that create
abiotic stress.
They had 12 worldwide
severe weather problems.
This destroyed a good portion
of the food supply.
Now I'm having a hard time
growing cherry tomatoes outside
under these conditions,
and I've turned to having
to build a greenhouse,
where I'm now growing large
tomatoes, heirlooms.
And they are producing
really nice, big tomatoes.
I see that the tomatoes that I
planted now are really healthy,
and the ones outside
are dying.
The Midwest grows 40%
of the world's corn.
And it does have a tendency
to flood,
so we can expect
more and more flooding,
according to the statistics.
The E.P.A. statistics say
that there's going to be
more and more flooding.
Monsanto is one of the world's
largest chemical companies.
They also own 90%
of the seed companies
in the world right now,
and they
are the largest company
putting out
genetically modified seeds.
So what does Monsanto do?
Corn is the lead-in because corn
is in just about everything.
Corn is the main crop,
and Monsanto leads in
with corn products
before it does anything else.
So what we have is
Monsanto leading in
with a drought-resistant corn
and an abiotic-stress-
resistant corn.
The drought and the flooding,
it's all the same patent.
Monsanto has a patent
for abiotic stress.
Abiotic stress is the drought.
It's the flooding.
It's the excess soil.
It's anything that's going
to stress a plant.
G.M.O. is
Genetically Modified Organism,
and it's also called G.E.,
Genetic Engineering.
Well, the history
of farming has been,
a farmer will plant a seed
into the ground,
and there will be nutrients
in the ground
that will enable that plant
to grow,
and then at the end
of the growing season,
they will take
some of the seeds,
and they will save them
for next year,
and they'll grow
their next crop.
But what is going on with
the genetically modified seeds
is they're what's called
terminator seeds.
A terminator seed will not
produce other seeds.
With the terminator seeds,
these farmers have to go back
to Monsanto every single year
and purchase these extremely
high-priced seeds.
There have been studies
outside of the United States
showing that genetically
modified seeds,
the plants that come
from them,
are extremely harmful to humans
and other life on this planet.
Uh, when I started farming,
I produce 100% my crops.
But in the last four years,
I've been declined
to 50%, 75%
if I took into later crop,
because I've been lost
everything.
And that's why I start moving
all different crop,
so I can cover the loss.
Well, my food production
has declined at least by 60%
in the last, I don't know,
ten years.
I've noticed banana stalks
are smaller,
and certainly the tomatoes--
I'm hardly getting any.
I use to get bushels
of tomatoes,
and now I can barely
get a bowl.
My concern--it can be,
you know.
It's possible if they go-
we go and run out of business
if they continue doing that.
They really need to stop
they're doing.
That's all I believe,
because we cannot change
the system, you know,
the Mother Nature.
We have to keep going
the way it is.
It's not possible.
On the other hand, the,
you know,
heat stress is going to be
one of the things,
or thought to be
one of the things
that might limit production
of crops
throughout the tropics.
And so there are some questions
of tradeoffs,
of, you know, when--
if you think you're gonna
benefit many people
and harm some people,
how do you deal with this
issue of equity, and what--
I mean, what are the options
for dealing with that?
A really interesting thing that
I've found
is that the E.P.A.
has concluded
that incidents
of heat stress,
drought, flooding, cold,
any type of abiotic stress
is on the increase.
And loss due to that
is going to double by 2030.
Then you put yourself up
as the solution.
So when all of this weather
comes and wipes you out,
or you have
a drought problem,
"Oh, drought?
We've got the seed for you.
"Here is our drought-tolerant
corn, just for you,
"and it'll solve
your problems.
"Oh, by the way, you have
to sign this agreement,
"this 40-page agreement,
"so that when you go ahead
and plant these seeds,
you now belong to Monsanto."
The weather disasters seem
to be directly correlated
to an increase
in Monsanto's sales.
So there will be the have
and the have-nots.
And one of the things
that's being discussed
under global geoengineering
is which countries
will be the haves
and which countries
will be the have-nots
when that type of climate
remediation is undertaken
by many people
at a certain level,
mostly private corporations
funded by the U.S. government,
they are hoping.
The fact that it's cheap isn't
necessarily a good thing at all.
As I'll come to in a second,
the fact that it's cheap
is part of the hard problem
of governance.
The fact that it's cheap means
any small state
or even, conceivably,
individuals could do this.
And that is
a very dangerous thing.
There's only probably
under $10 million per year,
and maybe far less than that,
being spent
on geoengineering research.
Um, it's a mix of a handful
of government grants
and some private money,
including support
from Bill Gates.
Bill Gates invests
in geoengineering.
Geoengineering destroys crops.
Monsanto supplies the seed
to replace those crops.
Bill Gates invests in Monsanto,
so Bill Gates makes
a ton of money,
Monsanto makes a ton of money,
and the small farmer
gets squashed.
Corn prices go higher
because of a severe drought
in this country,
um, you know, where 41%
of the country--
the world's supply
of corn comes from.
So corn prices are higher.
The farmer has more money.
So what does he do?
He buys fertilizers,
which dries up the mosaic stock,
and--or he could purchase
genetically modified seeds
from Monsanto.
You've got severe,
severe drought in Africa.
In 2011, there was
a severe drought.
This is causing nothing
but death.
It's causing starvation.
It's causing malnutrition.
It's causing
a severe water shortage.
How do you grow anything
without water?
You cannot grow anything
without water.
So what does Monsanto do?
They say, "Oh, we got a
drought-tolerant corn for you."
There's been
an excessive push
to get bioengineered crops
into Africa.
They look at severe conditions
as an opportunity.
They're disaster capitalists.
So here you have farmers,
and they've got flooding,
they've got droughts,
they've got everything that
totally wipes them out.
So what happens?
Okay, they--if they plant it
early enough in the year,
they can go ahead
and try and plant again.
So buy more seed.
Okay?
Buy Monsanto seed.
So they're just raking up
on that end of it. Okay?
So if you can create enough
weather manipulation,
you can shorten
growing seasons,
you can create enough
of that disaster,
and you've got
the seed supply,
they've got to come to you.
Geoengineers have stated
on the record
that if global geoengineering
were started,
it could cause droughts
in Asia and Africa.
And they state that
to the American public
for probably obvious reasons.
Why would they tell
the American public
that it could also cause
droughts here?
Why wouldn't it cause
There's nothing special
about America
and the geography here
that would not have the same
effect as Asia and Africa.
If the atmosphere is filled
with particulates,
those particulates diminish
and disperse rainfall, period.
There's too many
condensation nuclei,
so the water droplets do not
combine and fall as rain.
They simply adhere to those tiny
particles and migrate further.
And that's exactly
what we see.
One of the suggestions
about geoengineering has been
that we genetically modify
trees and plants,
um, we genetically modify crops
to be aluminum resistant,
and this is ongoing
at this time.
And part of the geoengineering
scheme is to say,
"We're gonna put all these
chemicals and particles
"into our atmosphere,
"which is going to cause
air pollution, water pollution,
"changes in soil pH,
"and could disrupt agriculture
crop production
to a great degree."
So, therefore, instead of
saying that maybe this isn't
a good idea that we pollute
our air, water, and soils
with the chemicals we're gonna
put into the atmosphere,
which do come back down,
there's a scheme abounding
which is happening right now
to modify some crops so that
they are aluminum resistant
to the types of chemicals
and particles
they're gonna put
into the atmosphere.
It's just gonna get worse
until the point
where we're not gonna able
to grow anything at all
unless it's a Monsanto
genetically modified,
abiotic-stress-resistant seed.
The chemical companies
and the genet--and Monsanto
and all of these companies
are working together
to make us totally dependent
on their products
for growing corn
or growing any kind
of agricultural product
or trees, whatever.
We're going to corporatize not
only where the rainfall goes
and who gets it
through geoengineering and
weather modification schemes,
but we're also going to say
that these are gonna be
the only crops
that are gonna grow
in areas where we're putting in
toxic chemicals
that are coming down
and altering the soils.
One of the most basic things
about human society
is that we need
food and water.
And these are two
of the things that, uh,
are most severely dependent
upon good weather--
rain at the right time
of the year,
sunshine so crops can grow.
Not enough sunshine,
and they don't grow.
Too much water,
the plants die.
Not enough water,
All of this goes back
to the amount of food
that's available.
So if you starve people,
they will be vulnerable.
They will be much easier
to manipulate and force to do
whatever the government
wants them to do.
So if you control how much food
there is or its availability
through things
like the weather
or using the weather as
a strategic tool, militarily,
um, you can, you know,
dramatically influence
what's going on
in the country.
And by doing that
over and over again
sequentially
through a region, um,
it's possible that you can
change the, um,
the political spectrum
over an entire region
by doing this
over and over again.
Um, maybe even, you know,
do it over
a much wider region.
Create so much instability
that you're able to, you know,
come in and say, "Oh, we have
these wonderful,
"fast-growing crops, you know,
genetically modified.
"And you know, this--
you'll have--
you'll have something to eat
in less than three weeks."
You know, um, and I imagine
that, uh, you know,
if you can control
the food supply,
that you can then consolidate
the financial
and the political interests
of a country.
Could predicting the weather
enable a group
or a specific entity
to profit from that knowledge
of knowing what type of weather
or weather pattern will be?
Absolutely.
That's what all commodities
are driven by.
They're driven by predicting
the weather,
how the weather will be
in a certain location,
and that directly
is correlated
to the price
of that commodity.
Absolutely.
There's no doubt.
While there are a number
of agendas associated
with these damaging programs,
one thing is for sure:
They can be used
to control our weather
and thus corporatize every
natural system on the planet.
This enables certain
individuals to consolidate
an enormous amount of both
monetary and political power
into the hands of a few,
at the expense of every
living thing on the planet.
Just by definition,
the geoengineering programs
are a direct assault
on the most elemental aspects
of nature.
What we're doing
when we modify the weather
is we're changing
the world's climate,
and we're changing
the micro-climates.
And we are doing it.
There are things we can say
for certain.
There's a mountain
of metal raining down on us.
We're certainly breathing
that metal.
We have documented
from the computer modeling
some unintended consequences.
If such a contamination
is present,
shouldn't we investigate?
Shouldn't local agencies
investigate,
which they have
patently refused to do?
There's no question that
large-scale climate engineering
is untested and dangerous.
I would disagree quite
strongly that it is--
um, doesn't exist.
I think that the capacity to do
it in engineering terms
most certainly exists,
and that's part of the reason
we have to think seriously
about how we manage that.
We are breathing a mountain
of metal,
and that can't be denied.
If geoengineering continues,
and the weather manipulation
continues,
and genetic modification
continues overtaking,
we're going to lose
our ability to grow
good, nutritious food.
We are going to lose
our ability to thrive.
I personally consider this
ongoing toxic dumping
into our atmosphere to be,
along with nuclear radiation,
the most dangerous threats
to our health
and to our environment.
We've seen UV scales
go off the charts,
which are a known consequence
of geoengineering,
ozone destruction.
We've seen rainfall patterns
disrupted in ways
that meteorologists don't seem
to be able
to explain or predict.
The challenge that all
of these weathermen face,
all of them, whether they're
aware of it or not--
sooner or later,
they will be aware of it.
And I went through a period
after the epiphany of,
"How did I not
see this sooner? How?
"I mean, seriously,
"I'm supposed to do this
for a living.
How did I not see this?"
We have--seem to have lost
our moral fiber
and our ethical compass
when we talk about
that we all should live
within an experiment
that somebody else
is conducting.
If you knew or could predict
the weather at any given time
in any given area,
then you control the fate
of mankind
and what they pay
for everything.
Washington is not responsive
to the average person.
It's responsive
to commercial interests,
who can spend millions
on campaigns now
without restriction,
who literally drive
the policy-making
in Washington, D.C.
I guess I'm under the belief
that you can't control
the weather.
Um, you know, I hope someday we
could control the weather.
Power becomes
an addictive thing.
We're taking what
the Creator has created,
usurping his authority,
and bringing it
under the authority
of corporations.
I'm worried that one person
or one group
would try to have that much
leverage over the whole planet.
I don't believe that anybody
has the right to play God,
especially when they're putting
particles and chemicals
into the atmosphere,
which there's unintended--
and consequences
that are known.
We don't know it all.
We can not assume the role
of Creator
without dire consequences.
This is not a good idea.
And this is not a reason
to take and do a test.
The atmosphere and the earth
belong to all of us.
It provides the food we eat,
the air we breathe,
the water we drink,
and no one should have
the right to own it.
The biosphere is at risk
from top to bottom.
Though you have climate
scientists
calling for emergency
geoengineering due to events
like methane mass expulsion,
which appears to be occurring
in the Arctic...
It would have
a significant impact
on the way that we operate.
Notice it also has enormous
political, social,
and economic implications.
And so we don't want to have
some giant planetary oops,
I mean, capital oops, in which
you have a loss of life.
It's much, much harder
to actually figure out
the environmental risks
and effectiveness
of these new methods
than it is to cook them up.
They're creating
an artificial environment
to replace
the natural environment.
Shredded ozone layer,
global droughts,
toxified soils,
poisoned populations.
Don't these issues matter?
Affecting ecosystems in ways
we've never been able before.
Um, the whole concept
of literally playing God
with the technology we have
at our fingertips today.
And however
the climate changes,
wouldn't we be better to let
the planet react on its own,
instead of trying
to play God?
It doesn't have any benefits
to society at all.
It doesn't benefit the plant.
It doesn't benefit the farmer.
It doesn't benefit
the environment.
It's all about money,
and weather is another form
of commoditizing,
a way the central command group
can commoditize
another form of our life.
Whereas the E.P.A. has stated
that there is going to be
more weather,
and they're attesting
it to climate change.
Well, I agree.
It's changing.
The weather's changing.
Now, the real issue is, is it
natural or is it manmade?
And if it's manmade,
who's doing it?
Is it the geoengineering guys?
That's what I believe
if geoengineering continues,
that whatever changes
are happening to the planet,
we will exponentially worsen
those changes
and poison everything
in the process,
and, indeed, with the amount
of metal falling on us,
that poisoning appears to have
been occurring now
for quite some time.
Why are you spraying
that stuff in our sky?
It's accumulating massive
amounts of wealth
in very few hands.
And that's what
they're trying to do
in all aspects
of these economies.
The money's not worth it.
This is my future.
I encourage people to get
involved in the projects
they're interested in,
whether it's this one
or some other one.
To thrive,
we need to organize
locally, nationally,
and globally
to expose and stop
this practice immediately.
Please quit free-riding
on our future.
But do what you can do.
And I think that's really
the answer for all of us,
is recognize that there is
a network more powerful
than the Internet.
It's the human race.
We are connected in a way
that's quite powerful.
The fact is, acting on what
we know to be right and true,
doing something
about what we care about
that we can do.
Please tell everyone
you know about this.
Bring this message
to community meetings,
demonstrations,
and other public events.
The work we're doing
will provide cover
for others to come out.
And I'm most interested
in whistleblowers.
Send this film
to environmental farm groups,
media groups, A.D.D.,
Alzheimer's, asthma groups,
and other organizations
that would do something
if they only knew.
Because we deserve--
deserve a future.
And if you control
the weather,
you're in control
of the planet.
It's that simple.
Some people address
this issue in fear.
Some people address it
in anger.
I address this in faith.
Faith believing that we,
collectively, as human beings,
as humanity, have the power
and the ability
to stop these
damaging programs.
[Skull's "Cry Die"]
All right, now here we go.
[singing]
I look up to the sky
Can you tell me why?
I don't wanna
see you cry
I just wanna see
you smile, baby
I look up to the sky
Can you tell me why?
I don't wanna
see you die
I just wanna see you
smile, baby
Me look up in da sky,
and me can't see clear
Blue skies are gone
and white lines appear
Dem say it's natural
Me no believe dem
Dem say it's vital
Me no listen to dem
Something strange
is going on
Feel it in my heart
Sensing something strong
All right,
now here we go
Gotta save the future,
put the rumors to rest
Gotta help the children,
gotta give it the best
Can't stand around,
be blind to the facts
Can't take it no more,
how can we relax?
I look up to the sky
Can you tell me why?
I don't wanna
see you cry
I just wanna see
you smile, baby
I look up to the sky
Can you tell me why?
I don't wanna
see you die
I just wanna see you
smile, baby
Living on earth,
we must respect the earth
Human and animal,
we all deserve
The right to peace
and opportunity
But nowadays, we're blind
We can't see
Hidden agendas
But we can't surrender
Children are our future
We must remember
Oh, oh
Don't know
what's going on
Yeah
We must stand up
for the earth
Oh, oh
Don't know
what's going on
Tell ya
We must stand up
for the earth
I look up to the sky
Can you tell me why?
I don't wanna
see you cry
I just wanna see
you smile, baby
I look up to the sky
Can you tell me why?
I don't wanna
see you die
I just wanna see you
smile, baby
We want the truth
Give us the truth, yo
We want the truth,
gotta save our youth
We want the truth
Give us the truth
Unite as one,
bring out the proof
Living on earth,
we must respect the earth
Human and animal,
we all deserve
The right to peace
and opportunity
But nowadays, we're blind
We can't see
Hidden agendas
We can't surrender
children, our future
We must remember
All right
Ay, ay, ay, ay
All right,
now here we go
I look up to the sky
Can you tell me why?
I don't wanna
see you cry
I just wanna see
you smile, baby
I look up to the sky
Can you tell me why?
I don't wanna
see you die
I just wanna see you
smile, baby