MICHAEL MOYNIHAN: Militant
unionism in Belfast is
localized in two communities--
the Shankill, a mile and a
half road that lies just
around the corner from the
Catholic Falls Road, and the
hyper-British Protestant
enclaves of East Belfast.
In the 1970s, the Shankill was
ground zero for loyalist
paramilitaries, famously home
to the Shankill Butchers, a
bloodthirsty group of killers
that targeted random Catholics
for torture and execution.
And in 1993, the IRA blew up a
chip shop on the Shankill,
killing nine Protestants.
Today, both the Shankill
and East Belfast
are relatively peaceful.
The locals are friendly
and accommodating.
But with these monuments and
murals celebrating Ulster's
contribution to World War I,
and more threateningly,
various Protestant
paramilitaries, it can feel
like an earlier,
uglier decade.
Alastair introduced us to Rab,
a very connected and very
influential guy in East Belfast
who attempted to
explain the palpable anger we
were witnessing so many years
after the Good Friday
agreement.
RAB: Unfortunately, on these
interface areas, on both sides
of the fence, you know,
it hasn't moved
on for these people.
Because one stone, one
brick is too much.
There's no peace process
for these people.
MICHAEL MOYNIHAN: We were
talking to Alastair, and he
was saying that this kind of
stuff is not the kind of
laundering of the 12th.
But it's to make the 12th more
of a family type exercise,
more for the kids, more
looking towards
the history of Ulster.
Whereas it's trying to get away
from something like this,
which is more sectarian.
I mean, what do you
think of that?
RAB: Well, I think
they're here.
If we went back five or six
years ago, you'd have had
[INAUDIBLE], and you'd have
shows of strength.
And you would have had all
types of different
paramilitaries at these
here bonfires
having a show of strength.
You know, them days
is well gone.
MICHAEL MOYNIHAN: For those
who aren't from Northern
Ireland, taigs are Catholics?
RAB: Yes.
MICHAEL MOYNIHAN: So
kill all Catholics.
That seems pretty provocative.
RAB: It does.
But whenever you go to the
backdrop of what's happened
here over the last couple of
weeks, I mean, you have to
remember from the Catholic
church across the road there,
there was actually three
shots fired.
There was actually a newspaper
photographer that was shot.
And there was two individuals
from this community who were
also shot and wounded.
So that's just sort of
a direct response to
that, I would say.
There was no shots coming from
the marcher's community.
The young people wouldn't be,
you know, getting back to that
sort of rhetoric again
of kill all taigs
MICHAEL MOYNIHAN: On the ground
in East Belfast, we
were a long way from the
language of the peace process.
Officially, paramilitary
activity is an unwanted relic
of the past and danger
to the future.
But in working class,
Protestant, and Catholic
neighborhoods throughout the
city, we heard endless tales
of attacks by sectarian enemies
and the worthlessness
of the police force.
MICHAEL MOYNIHAN: We were
quietly told earlier in the
day that it would be inadvisable
to show up at
certain bonfires uninvited with
a camera crew in tow.
So we went with Rab to a bonfire
in his neighborhood.
He cleared the way.
And everyone, we soon
discovered, listened to Rab.
FEMALE SPEAKER: We're
rocking it.
[DRUMS PLAYING]
MICHAEL MOYNIHAN: Rab took us
into the local community
center to listen to the bands
warming up for tomorrow's
parade and pumping up the crowd
with songs celebrating
their British-ness.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
MICHAEL MOYNIHAN: The bonfire
organizers seemed to be
experienced in the art of
Molotov cocktail production.
And they generously allowed me,
after a bit of pleading,
to take part in the burning of
this tower of flags, political
posters, and symbols
of Catholicism.
I do want to point out that
there's a big canister of
petrol right there.
Everybody seems to
be OK so far.
But I'm anticipating a major
accident and major burns.
But it's all for William
of Orange.
It's like [INAUDIBLE].
[CHEERS]
MICHAEL MOYNIHAN: My first
Molotov cocktail, or petrol
bomb experience was a bit
anti-climactic because it was
kind of a shitty throw.
But they lit it while
they were explaining
how to throw it.
It just was on fire.
I had to get rid of it.
Everywhere we turned, there were
gasoline cans just inches
from enormous, terrifying fires,
kids full of cider
falling off of flaming
pallets.
But it was a friendly drunken
crowd, a happy celebration
amongst tribal peers.
MICHAEL MOYNIHAN: But this was
the night before the July 12
march, a warm-up for
the main event.
The real action would be
tomorrow, the day of Northern
Ireland's most contentious
parade when Protestants march
and, in a few areas of the
city, Catholics try to
confront them.
And all of this only weeks after
another major flare-up
of sectarian violence
in Belfast.
[MUSIC PLAYING]