BARACK OBAMA, PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES:
We haven`t finished everything we set out
to do in 2008, but you know that every single
day that I set foot in that office, I am thinking
about you. I am fighting for your families.
And with your help, I`ve been keeping the
commitments that I made.
MITT ROMNEY, GOP PRESIDENTIAL CANDIDATE: The
Obama campaign is slipping, because it can`t
find an agenda to help the American families.
But our campaign is growing into a movement
across this country that says we`re going
to get America back, we`re going to get America
strong, we`re going to provide for our families.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
CARL AZUZ, CNN ANCHOR: Powerful words from
the candidates. Today we`re going to look
at their campaigns` big push with less than
two weeks to go until election day. I`m Carl
Azuz. Welcome to CNN STUDENT NEWS.
Visiting four states might sound like a full
vacation. You pack up your car, spend a few
days in each spot. If you`re a presidential
candidate, that`s not a one-week trip. You
do that in a day. From now through November
6th, Mitt Romney and Barack Obama will be
all over the country. This is what former
Governor Mitt Romney`s day looked like yesterday
-- moving around the state of Ohio, visiting
campaign rallies in three different cities.
So Thursday in Ohio, on Tuesday he was in
Colorado, Iowa on Wednesday, plus visits to
Nevada, Florida and Virginia were scheduled
for this week as well. President Obama just
wrapped up a campaign trip that took him to
eight states in 48 hours. Wednesday, he went
to Iowa, Colorado, Nevada and California.
On Thursday, he started the day in Florida,
and then hit Virginia, Illinois and Ohio before
heading back to the White House in Washington.
That stop in Illinois was a quick one but
a historic one. The president went to Chicago
to cast his ballot early. It`s the first time
that a U.S. president has used early voting.
You might have noticed the candidates are
visiting a lot of the same states. Those are
what`s known as battleground states or swing
states. Political experts say it`s not certain
which candidate will win those states on election
day, which is why the candidates are likely
to spend a lot of time campaigning there.
Next up today, we have an update for you on
Malala Yousafzai. The teenager was shot by
the Taliban for demanding education rights
for girls in her home country of Pakistan.
Malala was moved to the United Kingdom for
medical treatment. She has a long recovery
ahead of her, but doctors say she is making
progress. She`s in stable condition, and can
communicate with hospital staff by writing
notes. Malala hasn`t been with her parents
since she was moved to the U.K. That changed
yesterday. Her mom and dad, he`s the one speaking
here, they flew to the United Kingdom from
Pakistan to be with their daughter. Pakistani
police have identified this man, Atta Ulla
Khan (ph), as the main suspect in Malala`s
shooting. Yesterday, he was still out there.
Six other men had been arrested in connection
with the attack, though.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: See if you can ID me. I`m
a U.S. national monument that`s more than
300 feet tall and weighs more than 150 tons.
I was a gift from France. In one hand, I`m
holding a tablet, and in the other, I`m holding
a torch.
I`m the Statue of Liberty, and Sunday is my
126th birthday.
AZUZ: The day after its 125th birthday, the
statue was closed for repairs, set to open
back up on Sunday. Zoraida Sambolin joined
a few wounded warriors, U.S. military veterans
who were injured in combat, for a sneak preview
of some of the monument`s upgrades.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
ZORAIDA SAMBOLIN, CNN CORRESPONDENT: The Statute
of Liberty`s crown and interior have been
closed for a year, but for retired Marine
Corps Larry Hughes, it`s seemingly been longer.
That`s because the observation level of this
iconic symbol of freedom was not wheelchair
accessible until today.
LARRY HUGHES, VETERAN: Amazing.
SAMBOLIN: Hughes, a Vietnam vet, is taking
the inaugural ride in a newly installed elevator
to the statue`s observation deck.
HUGHES: Just to be here was something that
never really entered into my mind, because
something I hate to be turned down, I hate
to be rejected. So I`m no longer being rejected.
I`m being here.
SAMBOLIN: The new elevator is just part of
a year-long, $30 million renovation that also
includes upgrading stairwells and making safety
improvements. The end result -- a more accessible
Lady Liberty that will allow an additional
26,000 visitors each year a chance to enjoy
her spectacular views.
KIRK BAUER, VIETNAM VETERAN: When these adaptions
are made, it opens up tremendous opportunities
for all of us.
SAMBOLIN: Among the first to see the new renovations,
two generations of severely wounded warriors.
I joined Kirk Bauer, who lost his leg in Vietnam,
and Jesse Acosta, who suffered injuries to
his hip from a roadside bomb in Iraq, on the
146-step climb to the top.
So you stuck your head out of?
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: The crown.
SAMBOLIN: The crown. What do you think, is
this what you expected?
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Fantastic. Actually, it`s
more tight than I thought looking up, but
it is just an incredible view.
SAMBOLIN: The renovation was full of challenges.
Because of the statue`s location and because
they had to do it all without drilling into
any part of the historic structure.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Today`s Shoutout goes out
to Mr. Martin`s (ph) American government classes
at Minden high school in Minden, Nebraska.
What is the name of the computer coding system
that uses zeros and ones? Here we go. Is it
binary, HTML, Linux or Metacarpal? You`ve
got 3 seconds, go.
Binary means made of two parts, and binary
code is made up of two things, zeros and ones.
That`s your answer and that`s your shoutout.
AZUZ: If you translate the word "hi" to Spanish,
it`s ola. To German, it`s hallo. To binary,
it`s 0110100011101001. I had to practice that.
Seems kind of complicated, but it also could
be more lucrative. It could pay you more down
the road. Laurie Segall looks at the coding
in the classroom.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
NAQUAL ROBINSON, HIGH SCHOOL STUDENT: Another
I and an equal sign and an I plus one.
LAURIE SEGALL, CNN CORRESPONDENT: It sounds
like gibberish. You like this better than
Italian?
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Yes.
SEGALL: Better than French? It`s computer
code, and it may be more valuable than any
other language high school students study.
HENRY FERSKO, HIGH SCHOOL STUDENT: That`s
where you have the most jobs right now, I
would say, in technology and stuff.
SEGALL: Becoming a lawyer or a doctor is now
passe. With unemployment for 20- to 24-year-olds
at 12.4 percent, the hot job now? Tech entrepreneur.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: So how do you call the
function?
SEGALL: But to join the club, you`ve got to
speak the language not many are fluent in
-- programming.
Do you think this is increasingly important
for college students and for the job market
for people to learn these kind of skills?
KLANA LOWERY, HIGH SCHOOL STUDENT: Of course,
of course, because new technology is being
like built every day. You`ve got iPhones,
you got all that type of stuff. So it`s like,
you can use this stuff to actually help you
understand it.
SEGALL: Salaries for people with coding skills
are high. Entry-level software engineers at
companies like Google and Facebook pay in
the six figures.
Now, over a 40-year career, the engineering
major can make over $1 million more than the
average college grad, so it`s definitely a
job that pays, and one where these tech skills
are necessary. But the problem is, computer
science software engineering firms can`t find
enough skilled workers. Enter Codecademie,
an online company that teaches the average
Joe the most basic programming skills. Now
they created a curriculum specifically for
schools.
ZACH SIMS, FOUNDER, CODECADEMY: There`s not
enough teacher training for teachers who are
interested in learning to become computer
science and programming teachers, either.
SEGALL: Teacher Courtney Ginsberg decided
to learn coding at the Codecademie web site.
Now she`s using it to help her students get
prepped for the job market.
COURTNEY GINSBERG, TEACHER: It`s getting harder
and harder for my students to get even the
after-school jobs they got a few years ago
when I started teaching.
SEGALL: Codecademie says it`s in nearly 2,000
schools now, another step towards building
the strength of America`s tech labor force.
And for kids today who have an iPhone in hand
and spend a lot of time on apps, the idea
of building one for a living does not sound
bad. They grew up on Facebook and paid attention
to the story.
RANDI ZUCKERBERG, FOUNDER AND CEO, ZUCKERBERG
MEDIA: I think we`ve just seen so many really
cool success stories of young people who,
you know, came to Silicon Valley with a dream
and hit it really big. I think we`re also
in a very interesting economic time in this
country, and people are more open to taking
risks and trying something new.
SEGALL: Do you think you have the next Mark
Zuckerberg in your class?
GINSBERG: That would be amazing.
SEGALL: Laurie Segall, CNNMoney, New York.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: High school kicker Anthony Storego (ph)
hasn`t missed a field goal this year, and
he didn`t miss this one, either. The difference?
The kick in this Youtube video was a game
winner that happened with just 21 seconds
left on the clock. That`s a tough situation,
but Anthony is used to overcoming adversity.
He lived in nearly a dozen foster homes growing
up, and Anthony suffers from autism. But on
the football field, he`s just another one
of the guys. Well, except for when he hit
that game winner last Friday. Then, as his
quarterback put it, Anthony was the man. And
if he keeps up his streak of perfection, he`ll
definitely give his team a leg up on the competition.
We`re running out of football puns. Sooner
or later, we`re just going to have to punt,
but there`s no time left on the clock for
us, so have a great weekend. See you later.