HAMILTON MORRIS: Juan lights
a stick on fire and gets it
glowing orange.
The captain does not react.
He takes two more burns the same
way, and then Juan begins
to rub the jelly into
all three wounds.
[SPEAKING PORTUGUESE]
HAMILTON MORRIS: Does
he feel anything?
[SPEAKING PORTUGUESE]
MALE SPEAKER: He's beginning
to feel it.
[SPEAKING PORTUGUESE]
HAMILTON MORRIS: The captain
stands with a
far-off look in his eye.
Then he sits down and puts
his head in his hands.
He says that everything is
spinning, and that he can feel
it in his gut.
They pour a bucket of water
over his burns and head
because they think it will
counteract the venom.
[SPEAKING PORTUGUESE]
HAMILTON MORRIS: And then
the captain jumps
into the piss river.
He looks at me and says
that he's fine.
Now it's my turn.
Juan picks up a stick off the
ground and lights it on fire.
It's much thicker than the
sticks the Mayoruna use.
Ah!
[SPEAKING PORTUGUESE]
HAMILTON MORRIS: No sensation
yet, no sensation yet.
Now it stings.
The site of the burn now hurts
a lot more than when he
initially did it.
Still no psychoactive effect.
No psychedelic effect.
No visual distortions.
Gracias.
Nothing at first.
Then slowly, an opiated
high creeps over me--
a drunken-headedness.
It feels good.
I feel high, or sort of a little
bit disassociated.
It's not necessarily
unpleasant.
[SPEAKING PORTUGUESE]
MALE SPEAKER: What's your
feeling right now, man?
HAMILTON MORRIS: Very little.
I mean, I feel an extreme pain
in my arm where I was burned
and had venom rubbed
in the wound.
And I feel a little bit
high, in a good way.
Let me get one more.
Ooh!
Yowza.
You got it that time?
Did you get it that time?
Si.
Good, yeah, everybody make
sure they touch it.
Jesus Christ!
Juan then reapplies the poison
jelly to my wounds.
Reapply to the other wounds
while you're at it.
Please fan me?
If they need to give me
a thousand of these
I'll fucking do it.
Now there's a new sensation
taking over the arm like it's
falling asleep.
Like a pins and needles
sort of sensation.
And it's happening in
both of my hands.
I'm losing sensation in
It's feeling more
sinister now.
It's very strange.
My mind is saturated with a
distinct drunken weirdness.
It's bad.
It's unpleasant.
Part of me wants to lay down.
Just lay down in the hammock
or something.
Ah, gracias, gracias, gracias.
I feel like a frog.
The people that surround me fan
me like I'm an emperor.
I lay shirtless on
a plastic tarp.
My stomach is in excruciating
pain.
The frog and me exchange
a glance.
If they think I should do
another one, I would consider
doing another one.
I request a fourth burn--
more sapo than The Captain.
Who's the mujer now?
Numero quattro.
Oh, wow, yeah.
Feeling it much more strongly
in my head now.
MALE SPEAKER: Oh yeah?
The drunkenness in my
head is very strong.
There's some mild, closed-eye
visuals.
It does feel slightly
psychedelic.
I think it might be best for me
to lay in my hammock now.
Unless they think I should
wash my wounds.
I'm feeling extremely woozy.
[SPEAKING PORTUGUESE]
HAMILTON MORRIS: The captain
insists that I submerge myself
in the shit river in order
to sober myself up.
I say I don't want to.
There's no pharmacological
reason that getting wet would
clear the venom from
my bloodstream.
But he insists, so I let him
pour gasoline jugs of piss
over my head.
[SPEAKING PORTUGUESE]
HAMILTON MORRIS: As the frog is
returned to a tree, I lay
down in the boat because I'm
feeling extremely nauseous.
The poison that was still in
my blood begins working its
purging magic.
The captain takes me out to a
private clearing on the edge
of the river.
For most people,
the frog causes
uncontrollable vomiting.
But I did the frog on an empty
stomach, so in my case the
purge came the other way.
Aspects of the experience were
euphoric and I would consider
repeating it.
But I'm pretty certain I could
achieve the exact same effects
by rubbing the jelly
inside my nose.
Neither the water nor the
purging made me sober.
And I lay in my hammock feeling
disassociated and
nauseous for the next
three hours.
I feel really fucked up.
Really exhausted, like I just
ate a pound of Valium.
And I don't feel too great.
I think I could still
vomit at any moment.
My stomach is just
in awful turmoil.
I wake up today feeling
like shit.
I do not have supernatural
powers, nor do I have a
resistance to thirst
or hunger.
How these drug rumors get
started, I have no idea.
Indians, right?
I eat an egg for breakfast and
pet the monkey orphan's head
one last time.
Goodbye little monkey.
I wish him the best.
I hope he grows up big and
strong, and that he's treated
like a child.
Then it's time for
gift giving.
We give the shaman's family our
hammocks, our boots, as
well as an erotic porcelain
statuette of two pigs making
love which they seem
to cherish.
[SPEAKING PORTUGUESE]
I like them.
So we got what we wanted.
I did the frog.
It was insane.
I have the scars right now which
are starting to heal.
But we also went to the jungle
and got a giant bale of
ayahuasca vine.
And it left me a little hungry
for some ayahuasca.
So once we get back
to Tabatinga we're
going to look around.
Apparently it's very common to
find the DMT containing leaves
and we'll mix up some ayahuasca
on our own.
Returning to the city fills
me with an incredible joy.
My mosquito bites become less
itchy, my sunburn's less
peely, and my intestine less
colonized by parasites.
The skies are clear and the
banks of the Amazon are
monotonously beautiful.
Tomorrow I will prepare
the magical brew.
Tonight, I rest.
We're back in Tabatinga.
And we're on our way to meet
the ayahuasca shaman who's
going to give us something they
call tue, which I think
is the DMT-containing plant.
Because when we were still in
the jungle, the shaman there
only gave us half of
the ayahuasca brew.
So now we're going to get
the rest and we'll mix
it up at the hotel.
We arrive at the shaman's house,
and I'm surprised to
find it's a wizened old woman
wearing an all pink outfit.
We asked her if she has
tue to sell to us.
She tells us she does, but that
if I were to drink it I
would permanently
lose my mind.
[SPEAKING PORTUGUESE]
HAMILTON MORRIS: Can you ask
her if tue has other names?
[SPEAKING PORTUGUESE]
HAMILTON MORRIS: She leads us
through her house, and then
out to her garden of
medicinal plants.
She brings us to a plant and
tells us that is tue.
This is the tue, I'm assuming.
Some people are calling it the
Colombian Devil's Breath.
They call it a Angel's Trumpet,
Devil's Trumpet.
It's the deliriant that
will give me a
miserable nightmare trip.
And this is what the shaman was
telling me that I needed
to get, was this Devil's
Trumpet stuff.
It's good we cleared that up and
he didn't have any on him
at the time because that
would have been really
unfortunate for me.
She then brings me to another
corner of her garden, where we
see a small tree with
lush, green leaves.
[SPEAKING PORTUGUESE]
HAMILTON MORRIS: Fantastic.
This is the chacruna, or
psychotria viridis plant.
It contains DMT and pretty
much nothing else.
This is, I think, the
gold standard for
ayahuasca and brewing.
We pay for the chacruna, and
leave for our hotel with all
the ingredients needed
to brew ayahuasca.
Our hotel was nice enough to
let me use their kitchen
brewing ayahuasca for the
rest of the afternoon.
In two hours I'll strain
what's left, and
that will be that.
Here we are at our hotel room
in Tabatinga, and I just
finished brewing
the ayahuasca.
This is the MAOI, it's
the ayahuasca vine.
Definitely the worst thing I've
ever tasted, and I've
tasted a lot of terrible,
terrible drugs.
But I'm going to try and get
through about half of this.
Here I go.
Oh my God.
OK.
Little sips, it's too difficult
to swallow big ones.
Around sunset I start
drinking the vine.
It's truly the most
awful-tasting substance on the
planet, and each sip takes me
within a nano-gag of vomiting.
Sip, gag, sip, gag.
The vine hits me like a
tsunami of warm milk.
I've never been so drowsy
in my life.
I then drink the chacruna
leaves.
I fall asleep and have strange,
apocalyptic dreams.
As I fall deeper into an
ayahuasca induced trance,
strange visions and dark
premonitions overtake me.
In the midst of these visions,
I realize that the sapo is
only one amphibian enigma in
an endless jungle of mind
altering mysteries.
There's so much territory
left to explore--
hypnotic giraffe bone marrow in
Sudan, sedative sea sponges
in the Caribbean, dream fish of
the Pacific Ocean, narcotic
silkworms in China, and unknown
synthetics from
magical laboratories
across the globe.
Whoa.
Oh my God.
The ayahuasca makes me
extremely tired.
I take a Ritalin to combat
the sleepiness.
Yup.
I guess it's time for a walk.
Coma juice.
It just made me into a thousand
year old man.
I got a boat.
It's really just like
the boat we were in.
It's the exact same boat, only
it's a lot more feathers than
the boat we were on.
And that's one hammock
in the middle--
it's a one-person.
The frog was good.
What's next?