over your life
but
melbourne red-baiting hungry tattered
that steve crude from the surviving
remnants of a devastated make sure it
for
because the boulders bernhard is running
what are your network heard about the
bull run
you know i've heard landed at all began
victory was very much in doubt
again we are back
there will be doable david
but i have happily competent we will
have been
survival
is only a first step
humanity must band together
and fight
there are
deleon harvesters script
but for perth survivors
the terrifying harvest
becomes an opportunity
well the biggest problems with fighting
would be getting inside the technology
revolving
orleans resting
they've got the shield
figure out a way to get insider shield
in your life to have a lot more
effective damage
but there's a simple
using the aliens own technology
the alien scripture
becomes attract
the
caa
there
how
how hot
the human resistance has scored a
victory
it's a small one but it brings hope
three hours
these military tactics are important
strategic part of the plan to fight
indian innovation
we're back again with your time
grilling gate warfare before we have
faith
risque computer gets t_v_ and high tech
so survivors must fight them with www
tech
the plan to resist the aliens is based
on history
wars from the american revolution to the
iraq campaign
tactics and small-scale explosives
held leveled the playing field for a
technologically inferior fighting force
lots of little blows into as much damage
is
as one big word generally speaking
lots and lots of little bloated much
more psychological damage
military strategists have a name for
this approach
a symmetric warfare
i'm in a bit of a question of course war
default
does this become more and more than
technology
for those of the come a long drawn-out
the insurrection area campaign
we can cut by him
the same way in the same organization
that he's used to fighting
he's probably got it features
so even if i could orville disconnected
his soft spots his commander control no
to this was just too close
you've got a attack when it's not
expected
today one of the greatest experts in a
symmetric warfare
is also one of the largest defense
departments in the world
the pentagon
paperwork
the hard way
our military has had
at this point by nine year
hard core class
on how to be insurgents
they've been fighting for nine years
in iraq
and afghanistan
america's overwhelming firepower can
sometimes to feed it with a simple
roadside bombs
to low-tech mein type of weapon
but it causes concern among state
technological poor status can't find
officially casual user occurring
furor when it's going to happen where
it's going to happen
so it has a wearing down effect on me up
early portions
the insurgents also change their tactics
regularly any new idea is always good
as the first time we use it
they got a barrage explosive devices
when they first argues nose and mouth
the iraqi a war
they used the doorbell buzzers
cellphone ringers and we would figure
out how they were doing that they would
switch to something else
they would use radio communications than
they would switch to something else
the strategies are effective
into thousand eight
seventy percent of american deaths were
from improvised explosive devices
one method the pentagon users to create
contra strategies to such a deadly
attacks
decision team
a war game
america's military finance its tactics
based on computer simulations and
teachers wargames
these are often highly classified
projects using some of the most powerful
computers in the world
these computers sooner
resource helped establish america
strategies protocol around the world
when travis steelers computer simulation
is running for interviewing an invasion
boarding scenario
the warranty short
bikini and swim
everytime
sometimes within an hour
but when the time frame of the war game
is extended from deeds to here's
the results change
in the long run
is all about it you can kill them faster
then they can replace their troops
then you can chip away at that spellman
whittle that down
i mean you can overwhelm
these wargames form the basis of the
plan for a indian resistance
it's a simple rule of guru warfare
small attacks on a constant pieces keeps
the war going on
six months of observation has also
uncovered a critical characteristic of
the invaders
their numbers aren't increasing
forces had mentioned true far from
to rely on reinforcements
that means every lost unit
be replaced
and that's a pretty ron
the computer simulation now favors
the winner of a war is what is the
largest population in and could be
aliens
here are two years ago we used to be a
more aliens here too but the mother
we might end up
in a numbers game
thrust
students can take lessons on survival
from the most populous creatures on
earth
pants
and societies
and those of other social insects are
decentralize there's no central leader
or police worth the rules get sent out
and uh... this is a real smart way of
organizing society's it's very hard to
fight
not hard for full systems like annette
calling so you can kill all the and she
want in your kitchen
and it's probably not going to matter to
the caller ip all
banding together helps keep the
individual lives
and keeping the groups small in separate
helps make the human species less
vulnerable to extinction than it is
obvious that yes
the goal is not too and i believe
powerful invader it's to make him want
to leave
or really have to is figure out a way to
hold out much longer
hopefully
bills that have been too busy part of
this day
billowed up their bags please
the strategy always to bring the battle
to the enemy
no weapon is off limits
including what may be good
deadliest of what's left in the arsenal
the human body
time may be running short for grad
school armies
and the entire planet
the alien newcomers are what biologists
call
invasive species
than invasive species as one that moves
into an area that's never previously
occupied
and disrupts the local ecology
as successful invasive species is
could it moving around
and disrupting the landscape usually
through aggressive behavior
which can be there for fighting or just
domination of space
once
the suspension system
case in point
fire ants in the american south
these stealing resume in the past first
came to america on a single cargo ship
in nineteen thirty
they began to spread
conquering every other camps species in
their path
these amps actually kill off
every other empathic and scattered
reload mandible salon
invasive and sweep over the landscape
producer away and there's no evidence
that they back off
today
fire ants are found from maryland to
california
history does change forever once
abrasive species comes up
now
the bands of human guerrillas hope to
drive off the invasive aliens
before they transform the environment of
our planet to their poll meets
one way to fight an invasive species
is to create more of the local species
the war against the in the invasion will
mean
if we're gonna create a long-term
resistance were up to change our talked
about what's except born culture and
society
if there's a female bits of birthing a
change in these big break with his meany
children as you possibly can
so there might be fertility drugs in
houston
a breeding program will require multiple
makes
more children
will require multiple pregnancies
anyone not pregnant
becomes a warrior
mail or female
human being that's at the age of say
fourteen or older would need to be
carrying a weapon
we have to create a
total resistance
every human being that's a lot
but the economy may be hard to find
birth survivors have noted that
decide robots aircraft
unsaid ever appeared outside their craft
perhaps they
through technology
has a very good reason that i am
wouldn't want to get outside of his
character wanted lana leah
discussion realized pledged g wellesley
rises novel war the world's
muscle the folks that are pledging an
atmospheric bolbo combat scarier and
diseases of wallop in the classic u
aliens are destroyed by the
cheerio thought could science-fiction
hold the key for proof survivors
could bacterium or of violence to
support her attackers
viruses
in a particular have death
the balkan engage with organic greens
that he bobbing its head
maybe we could table about lodging web
in contract those they do it
their dreams and for developed to fight
against that provide
bacteria and disney's current rampant
among survivors deprived of antibiotics
and other matters
now
some of the sick and dying turning their
illness into a weapon
biological soon decide bombers
self-sacrifice isn't just a human trait
it's a natural survival mechanism when a
species