work the double crochet in the fourth chain
insert your hook through the chain
wrap the yarn over, pull it through
there are three loops on the hook
wrap the yarn over, pull through two loops
you have completed your first double crochet
the beginning chain three will count as the first stitch
that is something to keep in mind
when you come back round on row two
you will need to work a double crochet
in top of the chain three
so your stitch count is even on each row
to work the next stitch, wrap the yarn over your hook
put it through the next chain
wrap the yarn over the hook, pull it through
wrap the yarn over the hook, pull through two loops
that completes the next double crochet
wrap the yarn over your hook
insert the hook through the next chain
wrap the yarn over, pull it through
wrap the yarn over, pull through two loops
wrap the yarn over your hook, pull through two loops
working the next double crochet, wrap the yarn over your hook
put the hook through the next chain
wrap the yarn over the hook, pull it through, there are three loops on the hook
wrap the yarn over, pull through two loops
wrap the yarn over your hook
put the hook through the next chain
wrap the yarn over, pull it through
there are three loops on the hook
wrap the yarn over, pull through two loops
wrap the yarn over, pull through two loops, to complete the double crochet
the next few stitches will be worked in slow motion
there will be no sound
wrap the yarn over your hook
put your hook through the next chain
wrap the yarn over, pull through the chain
wrap the yarn over your hook
pull through two loops
wrap the yarn over
that completes the double crochet
wrap the yarn over your hook
insert the hook through the next chain
wrap the yarn over, pull through the chain
wrap the yarn over the hook
pull through two loops
pull the yarn through two loops
that completes the double crochet
wrap the yarn over your hook
put the hook through the next chain
wrap the yarn over the hook
pull through the chain
pull through two loops
wrap the yarn over
that completes the double crochet
we are at the last chain
working the last double crochet
of this row
this is what it looks like
we have ten double crochet
this includes the beginning chain three, which will count as a stitch
working a chain three
this is the technique that is taught by many of the books
I do have other tutorials with variations
showing how to work the step up, to the next row
sometimes the chain may not give the edge a very neat appearance
which is why you may want to use something different
working the first double crochet
wrap the yarn over the hook
put the hook below the two loops at the top of the stitch
just like that
wrap the yarn over, pull it through
there are three loops on the hook, wrap the yarn over
pull through two loops, then two loops
this is what it looks like
wrap the yarn over the hook
put it below the two loops at the top of the stitch
wrap the yarn over, pull it through, there are three loops on the hook
wrap the yarn over, pull through two loops
wrap the yarn over the hook, pull through two loops
wrap the yarn over the hook
put the hook below the two loops at the top of the stitch
wrap the yarn over, pull through, there are three loops on the hook
wrap the yarn over, pull through two loops
I will work the next few stitches in slow motion
so there will be no sound
wrap the yarn over your hook
put your hook below the two loops at the top of the next stitch
pull the yarn through
there are three loops on the hook
wrap the yarn over your hook
pull through two loops
that completes the double crochet
wrap the yarn over your crochet hook
put your hook below the two loops at the top of the stitch
wrap the yarn over, pull through the stitch
wrap the yarn over the hook
pull through two loops
wrap the yarn over your hook
put your hook through the next stitch
wrap the yarn over, pull through
wrap the yarn over, pull through two
wrap the yarn over your hook
insert your hook through the next stitch
wrap the yarn over the hook, pull through
wrap the yarn over the hook, pull through two loops
wrap the yarn over your hook
put your hook through the next stitch
wrap the yarn over, pull through the stitch
wrap the yarn over, pull through two loops
we are at the edge, working the last double crochet
this is working in the top of the chain
when you look at the chain
there are two loops at the top of the chain
one loop on the back side
I like to put my hook below the two loops
at the top of the chain
the one loop is at the back side
wrap the yarn over, pull it through
complete the double crochet
and it goes through the chain, just like that
work a chain three
turn
continue working the double crochet
working the last stitch on the edge
working the double crochet the same as the previous row
that completes the double crochet