exact location of our first drill activity
on Mars.
The images being returned by Curiosity show
a diverse collection of interesting features,
including sedimentary rocks, pebbles, cracks,
nodules, and veins.
The vein features are seen as a bright white
material, and we see them just about everywhere
we look in Yellowknife bay. The Chemcam instrument
has found that these veins contain elevated
levels of calcium sulfate, likely in the form
of bassanite or gypsum. Gypsum veins are also
seen here on Earth and associated with water
percolating through cracks and fractured rocks.
The exciting news from all of this analysis
is the candidate site where Curiosity will
conduct its first drilling activity.
This site is located only a few meters away
from the rover's current location, and lies
in a flat area, suitable for drilling.
The team hopes to drill directly into one
of the veins and place the powder into the
SAM and ChemMin analytical instruments. These
instruments will give us detailed information
about the composition of the material. We'll
be driving over there in the next few days.
We began our first drilling campaign at the
site we named John Klein.
John Klein has an area that has a set of flat
"plate-y" rocks that are perfect for the first
use of the drill.
We were able to place the arm safely and drill
vertically down into the rock to collect as
much sample as possible.
We started by making a very small divot to
test the hammering mechanism in the drill.
This worked perfectly, so we proceeded on
to make a mini hole.
Our mini drill test drilled 2 centimeters
down into the rock
We compared the tailings created by the mini
drill to the extensive set of test rocks that
we drilled here on Earth here at JPL and determine
that what we see on Mars are safe to ingest
in the system.
After these preparations we were all very
excited to move on to ready to move on to
the big event.
We drilled 6-and-a-half centimeters down into
the rock.
We used the camera at the end of the arm to
take pictures.
Here we see two holes, first on the right
is the mini drill hole and in the center of
the picture, we have the full hole.
The gray tailing tells us that there's something
different about the inside of this rock than
the surface of the rock.
In the coming weeks, one of the things we're
trying to do with this first hole is to use
this gray powder that we collect to clean
the internal surfaces of the drill.
We do that by moving the arm and swishing
the powder around.
This was a great week for Curiosity. We got
to see something we've all been waiting for
quite some time: sample in the scoop confirming
that our first drill on Mars collected as
we had expected.
This was an important event as this is the
first time the drill has been used on Mars
to collect sample for analysis by instruments
on the rover.
We use these computer-generated images to
help us visually identify how much we've collected.
We were able to estimate that we collected
about 14 cubic centimeters of sample, or about
a tablespoon, and this matched our expectations
of what we would see in the scoop when we
got to this point.
Our drilling capability gives us the ability
to get inside this rock. The first thing you
notice about the material is that it's a different
color. Gray not the reddish orange color on
the surface all around us. That reddish orange
color is a sign of an iron oxidation. A kind
of rusting process that's occurred all around
on Mars.
The next steps for the team are to finish
processing the sample with Chimera and then
put small portions into the SAM and Chemin
instruments for analysis of chemistry and
mineralogy.
This week the Curiosity science team released
its initial findings from its first ever drilled
sample on Mars. This sample was collected
from the "John Klein" drill site, which is
located about 500 meters east of where we
landed about 7 months ago.
Curiosity obtained her first drill sample
and passed that sample on to her onboard analytical
lab instruments, called CheMin and SAM. These
powerful instruments tell us about what minerals
are present in these rocks and whether they
contain the ingredients necessary to sustain
life as we know it.
What the Curiosity team has found is incredibly
exciting. When we combine what we have learned
from our remote sensing and contact science
instruments with the data that's coming in
from CheMin and SAM, we get a picture of an
ancient watery environment, which would have
been habitable had life been present in it.
As an example, the information that we're
getting from the CheMin instrument, tells
us that the minerals that are present in this
lakebed sedimentary rock at John Klein are
very different from just about anything we've
ever analyzed before on Mars. And they tell
us that the John Klein rock was deposited
in a fresh water environment.
This is an important contrast with other sedimentary
environments that we've visited on Mars, like
the Meridiani Planum landing site where the
Mars Exploration Rover, Opportunity, has been
operating since 2004.
At that site, the sedimentary rocks record
evidence of an environment that was only wet
on a very intermittent basis, and when it
was, the waters that were there were highly
acidic, very salty, and not favorable for
the survival of organic compounds.
This is in direct contrast to the fresh water
environment we're seeing here at the John
Klein Site.
The SAM instrument is telling us that these
rocks contained all of the ingredients necessary
for a habitable environment. We found carbon,
sulfur and oxygen, all present and a number
of other elements in states that life could
have taken advantage of.
All in all, these few tablespoons of powder
from a Martian rock have provided the Curiosity
science team with an exciting new dataset
that tells us that Gale Crater, and perhaps
all of Mars, contained habitable environments.
This is an incredible success for the Curiosity
mission to Gale, and the science team is looking
forward to digging deeper into Mars' ancient
watery past in the weeks, months, and years
ahead.