CNN STUDENT NEWS.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
BARACK OBAMA, PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES
OF AMERICA: After four years as president,
you know me.
AUDIENCE: Yes!
OBAMA: You may not agree with every decision
I`ve made, you may at times have been frustrated
by the pace of change, but you know what I
believe. You know where I stand. You know
I tell the truth. And you know I`ll fight
for you and your families every single day.
MITT ROMNEY, REPUBLICAN PRESIDENTIAL CANDIDATE:
The same path we`re on means $20 trillion
in debt in four years. It means crippling
unemployment continues. It means stagnant
take home pay, depressed home values. And
a devastated military.
OBAMA: Our fight goes on, Virginia, because
-- because we know this nation can`t succeed
without a growing, thriving middle class.
Our fight goes on because America`s always
done best when everybody has a fair shot.
And everybody is doing their fair share, and
everybody is playing by the same rules.
ROMNEY: If you believe we can do better ...
(cheers)
ROMNEY: If you believe America should be on
a better course ...
AUDIENCE: Yes!
ROMNEY: If you are tired of being tired ...
ROMNEY: Then I ask you to vote and work for
real change, because Paul Ryan and I are going
to bring real change to America from the day
one.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: If you think there were a lot of stops
on that map, it`s not even the half of it.
Ohio, Wisconsin, Virginia, Colorado, Iowa,
New Hampshire, Florida, Pennsylvania -- the
candidates are campaigning hard in states
that could go either way tomorrow. One of
the things that we are talking about this
weekend was a report that came out on Friday.
It said the U.S. economy added 171,000 jobs
in October. But that the nation`s unemployment
rate went up slightly, to 7.9 percent. The
candidates focused on different parts of that
report. President Obama referred to the added
jobs and said it shows that the economy is
improving. Governor Romney looked at the unemployment
rate and said it shows the economy is at a
standstill. The CNN election center is packed
with interactive resources that can help you
get geared up for election day. Check this
out.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
MANAV TANNEERU, SENIOR PRODUCER, CNN.COM:
This is Manav Tanneeru, I`m a senior producer
at CNN.COM. And I`m here to tell you about
a couple of features we have at out Web site,
that might help you get a better idea about
the election that`s coming around. One of
them is what we call the CNN electoral map.
It allows you to game out the presidential
race by assigning different states to different
candidates. The point of it is, to see who
gets the 270 electoral votes first. Now, after
you make your selection and you come with
a prediction, you can share with the family
and friends, the social media, email, different
methods.
Another feature we have is called the CNN
Campaign Explorer. We work with Google on
this feature. And it shows you different types
of data. It allows you to take a glance at
fundraising data, ad spending data, candidate
travel, and also polling. The last feature
we have is our polling interactive. It shows
you CNN poll of polls for the national race
and different battleground states like Ohio,
and Florida and Colorado and Nevada. States
you have heard a lot about in this presidential
election.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: It`s been one week since the storm Sandy
hit land. You`ve seen pictures of the devastation,
but what`s incredible, is to compare it to
what these areas looked like before the storm.
Like this New Jersey Pier, before totally
intact, after parts of it just ripped away.
We are seeing these kinds of before and after
images from up and down the coast. Originally,
analysts were predicting that Sandy might
cause $10 billion to $20 billion in damages.
Now, they are estimating between 30 and 50
billion. The victims of these storm are dealing
with all kinds of challenges, some things
are starting to get back to normal. For example,
New York City`s public schools are opening
back up today. But millions of people still
didn`t have power yesterday. No power means
no heat, and with the temperature dropping
New York officials say tens of thousands of
people will have to find other housing options.
Gasoline has also been in short supply. The
U.S. Defense Department is planning to bring
more in, but some residents have stood in
line for hours waiting to fill up.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: We saw the truck pulling
here, we are like, get the cans out, because
it`s better than waiting in the car.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: I ran out of gas, looking
for gas. So I walked here.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Right now, I`m just kind
of waiting it out. I think in a few more days,
hopefully, there will be fuel and all the
stuff will ease up.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: New York City`s subway tunnels were
flooded during the storm. System is coming
back online, but when Jason Carroll went to
look at the damage with the subway official,
he found out some sections still need a lot
of work.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
JASON CARROLL, CNN CORRESPONDENT: What is
it exactly that you`ll be doing down here,
because this is in the area clearly were you
are working now. I mean it`s ...
FRANK JEZYCKI, CHIEF INFRASTRUCTURE OFFICER,
MTA: Well, the station complex itself will
require a significant rehabilitation due to
the damage from the storm. The infrastructure
-- the electrical systems, the fare collection
systems. The lighting systems. The stairways,
the ventilation systems, the elevators, the
escalators, they are all pretty much ruined
from the water damage, from the surge damage.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today`s "Shoutout" goes
out to Ms. Holt`s classes at Westbrook Walnut
Grove High School in Westbrook, Minnesota.
During which war did the U.S. first practice
daylight-saving time? Here we go, was it the
Civil War, World War One, Spanish-American
War or World War II? You`ve got three seconds,
go!
The U.S. first observed daylight saving time
during World War I. That`s your answer and
that`s your "Shoutout."
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: But the idea of daylight saving goes
back further than that. Back in the 1700s,
Ben Franklin suggested getting up earlier
in order to use fewer candles. So that covers
the who and the when. As for why and where
this happens around the world, here is Reynolds
Wolf.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
REYNOLDS WOLF, CNN CORRESPONDENT: This is
not a complex issue. Daylight saving is basically
self-explanatory, it`s saving daylight.
Originally, daylight saving was one of those
things where it was -- originally for agrarian
societies, it was to use the -- get the most
use out of as much daylight as you possibly
could. It was certainly helpful with farmers,
certainly helpful with fisherman. But then
later, in later years it actually began -- daylight
saving was actually practiced for the sole
purpose of really saving energy.
We`ve been following daylight saving time
in the United States for quite a while. It
really first became official back during World
War I for the sake of growing extra food for
troops overseas. It was brought back for World
War II. But recently, it was the Energy Policy
Act of 2005 that was the real difference maker
that made it more of a formal type of exercise
that has been basically followed by every
state in the United States with a few exceptions
that, being, of course, Arizona, Hawaii, U.S.
Virgin Islands, Puerto Rico and the American
Samoa.
Internationally, it`s kind of a hodgepodge
around the globe. If you took a look at the
planet, and you were to light up places that
were experiencing daylight saving, you`d see
really just a hop, skip and a jump from one
continent to the other. It`s kind of varied
where you happen to go.
There are some places, I can tell you in Africa
where there are many spots they don`t practice
it. There are many places, obviously, in parts
of Asia. Europe, though, practices it for
the most part.
OK, now we are getting to the nitty-gritty
stuff. This is the stuff that drives people
crazy. To me, it`s daylight saving. It`s a
verb, it`s something we are doing. We are
saving daylight. Savings is a noun, that`s
something that you have in the bank. Obviously,
we are using the verb.
It`s very possible that at some point we may
indeed get rid of daylight saving time, but
for the time being, it is certainly here,
and something we got to deal with, for better
or for worse.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: On Halloween, a 14-year old in Oregon
elected to fight the bitterness of politics
with a sweet political costume. He went out
as a ballot box, the left side was for Obama,
the right side for Romney. His neighbors voted
by putting candy in the side they like more.
And they could vote multiple times. So, no
matter who got the most votes, this kid won.
He said there was a five percent margin of
error for any candy he ate while trick-or-treating,
not to mention the fact that he wanted people
to vote early and vote often, to totally stuff
the ballot box. To sweeten the pot for their
favorite candy dip.
There is no real harm in it, though, when
you think about it. The only potential corruption
could have been to his teeth.
We hope you answer the door when CNN STUDENT
NEWS knocks again tomorrow. See you then.