with a number of secrets.
Located a little over 20 million light-years
away, practically a neighbor by galactic standards,
Messier 106 is one of the brightest and nearest
spiral galaxies to our Milky Way. Although
it may not look particularly unique, some
of its features have baffled astronomers for
years.
Messier 106 has a supermassive black hole
at its centre. Although this is true for most
galaxies, this black hole is particularly
active and hungry, gobbling up nearby material
at a startling rate.
This huge black hole’s bottomless appetite
is behind much of the galaxy’s unusual behavior.
Messier 106 appears to be emitting powerful
radiation from its centre — something we
do not see with our Milky Way or other similar
spirals. This is caused by the very active
black hole at the galaxy’s centre, which
violently drags gas and dust inwards. This
material heats up, emitting bright microwave
and X-ray radiation as it does so.
However, this emission is not the most intriguing
feature of this spiral galaxy. This image
shows the galaxy’s other not-so-hidden secret
— alongside its two regular star-packed
spiral arms, it appears to have two more,
made of hot, glowing gas. While these extra
arms have been known about for decades, astronomers
were unsure of how they formed — until recently.
Yet again, the culprit is Messier 106’s
supermassive black hole. The extra arms are
actually regions of gas that have been heated
up to scorching temperatures of millions of
degrees. As material spins around and heats
up at the galaxy’s centre, the turbulent
motion causes jets of material to shoot outwards.
The jets disrupt and heat up all the gas in
their path, which in turn excites denser gas
towards the centre of the galaxy. This gas
is tightly bound together, so it remains roughly
straight. However, the looser gas further
out is blown away from the jets so that it
curves out of the galactic plane — creating
the arching red arms seen in this image.
These “extra” arms are very unusual, and
this poses a bit of a puzzle, because galactic
jets are actually quite common. It is not
just spirals that show jets — elliptical
galaxies do too, such as the spectacular radio
jets seen around the nearby galaxies Hercules
A and Centaurus A. And yet none of these shows
any of the features seen in Messier 106.
Some of the data for this image of Messier
106 was provided by amateur astronomer Robert
Gendler. Together with Hubble, these data
allow us to visualize the galaxy’s chaotic
center and mysterious structure better than
ever before.