I want to scream and
just go back to bed.
Don't drill into it bro.
I hate it!
Missi: It's
stressing me out!
Jesse Green: Really?
Missi: I don't know
what we're going to do.
Jesse Green: We're
not going to make it!
We're not going
to make it!
I am "the Machine"
Jesse Green.
A couple of years
ago I walked away
from my job as
a truck driver,
to chase my dream of
owning my own business
as a master
chainsaw sculpter.
I took a huge risk
in doing it,
but the rewards of
being my own boss
and doing exactly
what I want to do
are so worth it to me.
My employees,
including my own dad,
drive me crazy.
Get back!
But I can't do this alone.
I'm living my
dream and
I wouldn't have
it any other way.
All I know is, I like
Grandmas, I like clowns,
so I'm thinking I'm gonna
like Grandma the Clown.
My dad and I are on our
way now to go visit the
Big Apple Circus, their
star Grandma the Clown,
is retiring after 25
years and they want me
to make a sculpture
commemorating her.
Hundreds of
thousands of people,
are going to see
this sculpture,
this is a huge
opportunity for us.
I only ask one thing of
you, alright, listen.
Jay Green: What?
Jesse Green:
Please don't talk.
Jay Green: Is this
the speech again?
Jesse Green: Just
stand there and smile
and be cute.
Just let me talk
to my clients.
Jay Green: I mean if
they're talking to me,
what can I do?
Jesse Green: You can
exchange pleasantries,
you know what I mean,
like, you can be cordial.
You don't need to then
stand there while I'm
trying to tell them
something and say,
"Ah he's really good."
Jay Green: I
wouldn't say that.
Jesse Green:
You said that.
Jay Green: I
never say that.
Jesse Green: Every time.
I don't, it's not that
I don't appreciate it,
'cause I do.
Jay Green: I think
Jesse is learning to be
a good business man, but
he never lets me help him.
He's treating me
like he's the father.
Jesse Green: Just let
me talk to the clients.
Jay Green:
Alright, maybe.
Jesse Green: Hey!
What up?
Guillaume Dufresnoy:
Jesse.
Jesse Green: Guillaume,
this is my dad, Jay.
Jay Green: I understand
you wanted some kind of
sculpture or something?
Jesse Green: This is
my assistant Brett.
Jay Green: What
can we do for you?
Guillaume Dufresnoy:
Well, uh.
Jesse Green: This is
my assistant Kerrin.
Kerrin: Hi, Kerrin,
nice to meet you!
Guillaume Dufresnoy:
Nice to meet you.
Jay Green: I know Jesse
didn't want me to talk
but I had to bust his
chops a little bit.
Jesse Green: So my
wife Beth says you guys
have a clown that's
retiring and
you wanted a
sculpture, fill me in.
Guillaume Dufresnoy: I
thought it would be great
to have a piece by you
and if we could include
something from a
clown gag, she does.
Jesse Green: Guillaume
doesn't just want a
sculpture of Grandma;
he actually wants
a sculpture to do a
trick from her act.
This is not something
we normally do,
but if we're gonna keep
growing our business we
have to keep taking
on more complex and
challenging projects.
Guillaume Dufresnoy:
Alright let's go
meet Grandma.
Jesse Green:
Yeah, thanks.
Alright.
This is awesome, we're at
the Big Apple Circus.
Guillaume Dufresnoy:
And this is Grandma.
Jesse Green: Grandma
the Clown is a dude!
To be honest, I was a
little thrown by that.
Guillaume Dufresnoy:
And this is Jesse.
Barry "Grandma": I've
heard nothing about you;
it's an honor to meet me.
Jesse Green: They tell
me they want me to
immortalize you in wood,
you were interested in
having it squirt water.
Barry "Grandma": That
would be cool, yeah,
yeah, yeah, you can
make that happen?
Jesse Green: I can
make that happen if
I can get you in
full Grandma get-up.
All Grandma'd out.
Barry "Grandma":
Yeah, of course.
Guillaume Dufresnoy:
Okay guys,
let's go into
the ring.
Jesse Green: Alright.
I thought it was
a girl, but yeah.
Wow, should we
stand back?
That is the most
talented thing I've
ever seen in my life.
Grandma did a lot of
funny stuff for us,
but you know what,
the water squirting
trick was definitely
the funniest part,
this sculpture has
to squirt water.
Now that I've seen
Grandma perform,
I have a pretty good
idea of how we're
gonna do this project.
Barry "Grandma":
Have fun.
Jesse Green:
We'll see you man.
First we're gonna
need a fresh pine log.
We're gonna shave
down the bark and
cut out Grandma's
basic shape.
Using a smaller saw I'll
cut in the fine details.
And to finish up
we'll paint it and
add in the water
squirting device.
Are you guys ready for
another fun project?
Missi: What have you
got for us this time?
Jesse Green: The
Big Apple Circus.
Before I start carving,
I am meeting with my
finishers Missi and Keith.
They're the ones that
will paint the finished
sculpture and add on any
extra little details that
the client might want.
So Grandma clown's got
this water squirting bit
that she does so that's
what we want to do.
We want to make the
actual sculpture
squirting water.
Keith: Figures.
Missi: What?
Keith: The
impossible again.
Missi: Squirt water?
Jesse Green: Nothing
you can't handle.
Missi: I'm used to crazy
deadlines around here.
That doesn't bother me.
I'm more worried
about doing things
we've never done before.
And we have never done
anything like this.
This is definitely going
to be a challenge.
Jesse Green: The
circus is only in town
for a little while.
Missi: How much time
do we have on this?
Jesse Green: Ah,
a couple days.
You can do it.
Missi: All in two days?
Jesse Green: Yeah.
Missi: Oh my God.
Jesse Green: Start
wrapping your head
around the water
squirting thing because
that's what's going
to sell this piece,
you know what I mean.
Keith: Stop talking.
Go to work.
Jesse Green:
Alright, I'm out.
Keith: Alright.
Missi: See ya.
Kerrin: Alright, bye.
Keith: Alright.
Missi: Oh my God.
Jesse Green: Oh God,
I'm gonna carve you!
Let's do it.
Now it's time for me to
start carving out Grandma,
this is literally
the part of the job
that I live for.
Jay Green: That
makes me cringe.
I know what
the saw can do.
His mother would
kill me if I ever
let anything
happen to him.
Jesse Green: What I do
is wicked dangerous.
Chainsaws are
wicked dangerous.
Over 30,000 people
every year are
injured by chainsaws.
Every moment of
every second that
I'm carving I have to
think about safety.
I have to think about
keeping myself from
letting that chain
cutting my face off.
But I love it.
Missi: I have a feeling
that a pickup truck is
going to work best,
because it's gonna give us
more room to maneuver.
Keith: We have next to no
budget to make Grandma
squirt, so we're at the
junkyard to get some
windshield washer parts.
If we don't get this
project to work right
Jesse's gonna blame us.
And that just sucks.
I'm not seeing
what we need.
Nope.
Looks like it's
already gone.
Ah.
Missi: That's
not gonna work.
We've gotta go smaller.
Keith: Too big, that's
actually an alright size.
There we go and
there we go.
We got our button.
We found the pump.
Now we have to take it
back and test it out to
see if it works.
Missi: Good job.
Keith: Awesome.
Beth Green:
Looks awesome.
Jesse Green: My
wife Beth runs the
day to day business.
She's the glue that
keeps whole thing going.
She keeps the
business running;
she collects the money,
talks to the clients.
There's no possible
way I can do any of
this without her.
Beth Green: So Guillaume
from Big Apple Circus
just called and he
wants you to deliver
this opening night.
But you're going to do it
in front of 1,500 people.
Jesse Green:
Like literally
during the circus?
Beth Green: So basically
you can't be late.
If you're not there
at the beginning of the
circus 1500 kids
will be crying.
Jesse Green: I've
delivered in front of
crowds before but
it's going to be scary
standing there in
front of 1500 people.
This thing's got to
work perfectly or
I'm going to
look like a fool.
Don't put that on me.
Dude, don't
put that on me.
Beth Green: You
can spit it out.
It's gonna be awesome.
Jesse Green: No I can't
just spit it out.
Beth Green: Yes you can.
Jesse Green: No, I
don't like deadlines.
You tell me now
that I have to
do it to the minute?
Beth Green: You're
wasting minutes now.
So if you put
those minutes
towards that sculpture.
I'm sincerely worried.
Jesse is horrible
with deadlines.
I'm not trying to be a nag
but we need him to deliver
this project on time
because we need the money.
I know I stress him
out by pushing him but
that's the only
way we get it done.
I just need you
to get it done.
Jay Green: Jesse
never did well with
any kind of deadlines
and that's why Beth
takes over the daily
business part.
Jesse, he's an artist.
Jesse Green: I'm,
we're well underway.
Beth Green: Good job.
Jesse Green: Thank
you very much.
Brett: I want to
go to the circus!
Jesse Green: No!
I forgot the glasses.
I made a huge mistake.
I (bleep) up.
I cut off any part that
I could have used on
Grandma's face to
make glasses with.
It's just a stupid
rookie mistake and
now I don't know what
the (bleep) I'm gonna do.
Jesse Green: I made
a huge mistake.
I cannot believe I forgot
Grandma's glasses.
It's not gonna be an
easy fix but I'm gonna
have to figure
something out.
Beth Green: Hey!
How's it going?
Jesse Green: I forgot
Grandma's glasses.
See.
Beth Green: Oh, do you
have to start over?
Jesse Green: I
can't start over.
Beth Green: Well
how are you gonna
fit the glasses in?
Jesse Green: I can
cut away from here.
I can round these
cheeks down.
I can pull
the mouth back.
Flatten, flatten.
Beth Green: Are you
gonna stay on schedule?
That's all I care.
Jesse Green: What
choice do I have?
Beth Green: You don't.
Jesse Green: It's
gonna get done.
It's gonna get fixed.
I'm gonna do the glasses.
Beth Green: Alright.
I'm gonna go make
banana bread.
Jesse Green: Oh
that sounds good.
Yeah, with the
chocolate chips
and the, and the nuts.
I got the glasses
figured out.
Solution, push the
whole thing back.
You don't just cut one
thing you cut 28 things.
I squared it and
voilà we are fixed
and all will be
right with the world.
Kills after a while.
What's happening?
Missi: I think we have
your water feature.
Do you want to see 'em?
Jesse Green: Yea.
Missi: I think you'll
be impressed.
Keith: For the Grandma
sculpture Jesse
wants to project water
out of its mouth.
We've come up with some
solutions to the problem.
Missi: So now our
job is to talk
Jesse into using it.
Otherwise we'll have
to start from scratch
and I don't
want to do that.
Jesse Green: Is this
going to self destruct
in like 30
seconds or what?
Missi: No actually
it's like a pump.
Jesse Green:
Let's see it.
Ooh, look at the flow!
Missi: This could work.
It's up to you
ultimately.
Jesse Green: I don't know.
I don't think something
with that many parts
is the most practical.
Keith: This works!
And Grandma
shooting her water.
It's the same thing.
Jesse Green: Yeah, but.
Missi: And you
want it realistic.
Jesse Green: It's cool,
but it's a big battery.
And I don't know if
it's gonna be practical
to send down the
line with these guys.
Can we set it up
with maybe just a
bunch of AA
batteries instead?
Keith: No bro.
With a smaller
battery it's going to
look like she's
spittin' up on herself.
Jesse Green: I
think that Keith and
Missi's windshield washer
solution is too complex
but I have to trust them.
It's what I pay them for;
I just hope that I don't
end up regretting this.
Just tell me
you guys guarantee
it's gonna work.
Missi: I won't
let you down.
Neither will Keith.
Jesse Green: Alright, I'm
going back to carving.
Keith: Alright, big boy.
Jesse Green: The
fine cut is the thing
that makes it
or breaks it.
It doesn't look
like Grandma until
I get the
detail in there.
Just kind of
delicately touch it.
Just a little touch
makes all the difference
in the world.
What do you think?
Jay Green: Looks
like (bleep).
Jesse Green: I'm
done carving and
now it's time
for finishing.
We are not out
of the woods yet.
It can go literally
straight out the
back of her neck.
Jay Green: No, it can't.
Jesse Green: Why?
Keith: Because the water
will go straight down.
We want it to shoot
at a projectile up.
Jesse Green: Oh.
To make this
chainsaw sculpture
squirt water we're gonna
have to drill 2 holes
for a water tube, one
in Grandma's mouth
and the other
in her hand.
Jay Green: Once you start
it, it's gonna be fine.
Jesse Green: Why is it
jumping around like that?
Jay Green: Just drill it!
Jesse Green: I want
to know why it's
jumping around like that!
Jay Green:
Because it's long!
Don't worry about it.
Do it again,
do it again.
Jay Green: I wish
Jesse would just
listen to me sometimes.
Keith: Down,
down a little.
Beautiful!
Jesse Green: Success dude.
To hit that exact spot
out the back is not luck.
Sometimes I even
impress myself.
Jay Green: Do you
want the ruler again?
Jesse Green: No, I'm
just going to drill
from the side sight.
I can see.
Jay Green: Oh!
Jesse Green: Son of a.
Back it out.
Jesse Green: No
(bleep) back it out!
That drill bit was
supposed to go through
the hand and the next
thing I know the drill
bit was coming out
of Grandma's hip.
Hip surgery is not what I
had planned for Grandma.
What the (bleep)!
I could not be more
beside myself right now.
I want to scream and cry
and just go back to bed.
Jay Green: We can fix it.
All you have to do is
fill this a little bit.
Turn this at an angle.
It's, it's fine.
Relax.
Jesse sometimes
over-reacts.
If he just calms down he'd
realize it's not that bad.
Jesse Green: My dad
is very quick to
say it's no big deal.
It's a big (bleep) deal!
One more thing to fix!
What's next?
Let me ask you
that, what's next?
Missi: Hey!
Jesse Green: Hey,
question for you.
Do you think I need to put
the black glass eyes in?
Missi: I don't
know but it needs
a bridge of the
nose, doesn't it?
Kerrin: Yeah.
Jesse Green: I straight up
left something right out.
The bridge nose piece,
yeah I left that off.
(Bleep).
How the (bleep) am
I gonna do that?
Do you think I need
an eye piece that bad?
Missi: I noticed it
but I notice details.
Sorry.
Jesse Green: Missi is a
little too good at details,
she makes me feel
like I suck at details.
But she's right and
now I have to fix it.
That is such a small area.
I think it's
gonna look funny.
I have a deadline.
This is the
second time now;
I've screwed up
on the glasses.
I gotta figure
out what to do.
I'm just gonna come
back to it later.
Finish this off, will ya?
What a nightmare.
Keith: Jesse's make a
big deal about Grandma's
glasses, but I came
up with an easy fix.
Missi and I thought we
could bend a piece of wire
across to form the
bridge of the glasses.
So after I primed the
sculpture Missi went
ahead and installed
the bridge.
Problem solved.
We think Jesse's
gonna love it.
Jesse Green: What
the hell is this?
Missi: Are you
being serious?
Jesse Green: No, yes
I'm being serious.
First of all, I can't
believe you just
straight out drilled
holes without (bleep).
Keith: I really
didn't go deep,
we can sand that away.
Jesse Green: Don't
drill a hole before
you talk to me
about it, dude!
The carving is done,
like don't dig into it,
don't drill into it, bro.
If you really are looking
to piss me off go ahead
and drill holes in my
finished sculpture.
Not only did Keith and
Missi do that but the
metal piece they stuck
in there for a bridge,
looks like (bleep).
It looks random though.
You see what I'm saying?
Missi: What if you had
this metal here and
you had another piece
of the same metal
coming around here.
Jesse Green: It doesn't
even match the color.
She has silver things.
You know what
I mean, like.
Missi: It can be painted.
Jesse Green: I hate it.
Keith: Jesse came in
and I was expecting a
high five and a yeah
bro but he basically
crapped on the whole idea.
It puts us back
at square one.
Jesse Green: It
has to be perfect.
I'm not ticked off.
Missi: You're something.
What's the other
word for it?
Jesse Green: Picky.
Don't fill in the holes
yet, just paint it.
Leave this the
(bleep) off.
We'll figure
it out later.
Missi: Okay.
Jesse Green: If it
looks uneven anywhere,
I'm just gonna
be like this,
you know what I mean.
Missi: Jesse is a bit
of a control freak.
Jesse Green: I see a
couple spots to fix.
Missi: He's the type of
artist that likes to
have his hands on every
aspect of a project.
Jesse Green: It's a
chainsaw sculpture
so it's got to be perfect.
Missi: If Jesse would
leave us alone and just
concentrate a little
bit more on carving,
instead of painting, we
could get a lot more done.
Jesse Green: Are you
gonna fix this now.
Missi: Yeah, it still
needs the touch up, so.
Jesse Green: And
this and this.
Missi: I'll
touch it up.
This needs a
second coat.
Jesse Green: And
this and that.
Missi: You're
stressing me out!
Knock it off!
Oh my God, Jesse
you're so controlling.
Enough already!
Keith: Ah, perfect!
We're through.
After we finished painting
it was time to get
the water pump and
the tubing installed
in order to make
Grandma squirt.
We should probably
test it, you think?
Missi: Absolutely,
test it.
Keith: Alright,
are you ready?
Missi: Careful.
Wow!
That goes far.
Keith: Oh, that's a
nice little squirt.
Missi: It's better
than like I expected.
Beth Green: It takes like
an hour to get there.
Jesse Green: I know, Beth.
Beth Green: We
need to wrap it up!
Are you guys
almost ready?
Five minutes.
Jesse Green: We are
working as hard
and as fast as we can.
Beth Green: It's deliver
or starve today.
Jesse Green: Get out
the way so I can finish.
I'm begging you.
Beth Green: If he doesn't
deliver this on time
we may not get paid.
We really need
the money.
If I can keep
him on track,
I'm really just
looking out
for our best interest.
Missi: I know you didn't
like the bridge idea made
out of metal but I painted
a couple the same color as
the frame of the glasses.
Does that look better?
Jesse Green: Aww, that
makes a big difference.
Missi: And it doesn't
stand out too much,
but still it's like that
makes sense to be there.
Jesse Green: See, Missi I
knew you'd figure it out.
Missi: Of course.
Jesse Green: How
come you didn't think
of that before?
I don't know why I
doubt you, Missi.
Keith: We gotta be able
to get the reservoir in,
so it fits.
Jesse Green: Dude, I want
to know that this whole
thing works before
I leave here.
Keith: Don't worry, we
aren't gonna make you
look like a fool in
front of 1500 people.
Jay Green: Just stand
right in front of it and
I'll be very happy.
Jesse Green: Don't you
dare squirt me with that.
Jay Green: Okay, go ahead.
Missi: Nothing?
Oh.
Jay Green: What the hell?
Keith: That's
very lackluster.
Missi: Oh, yeah.
Jay Green:
What's happened?
Missi: That's not as far
as it went the other day.
Jesse Green: Whoa.
Missi: What do you want
me to do, anything?
Keith: Hold your fingers
together and pray.
Jesse Green: Really?
It's minutes before we
have to leave for the
circus and the water
pump is not working.
Really?
Like really.
Is that really what's
happening right now?
This, really?
Jay Green: What the hell?
What's happened?
Missi: That's not as far
as it went the other day.
Jesse Green: Really?
Jesse Green: It's minutes
before we have to leave
for the circus and the
water pump is not working.
We have no idea
what's wrong.
Jay Green: Do that
again, give it a shot.
Missi: It's gotta
to be the battery.
Jay Green: It's
gotta be the battery.
Missi: We have to go
get another battery.
Jesse Green: Where
do you get that?
Jay Green: I don't know.
Missi: Hardware store?
Jay Green: A
hardware store.
Try anything.
Jesse Green: I
hate detours.
Missi: You don't have
to worry about it.
I'll handle it.
I won't let you down.
Haven't yet.
Jesse Green:
Missi's saying she's
never let me down.
If that's true then why
isn't this thing working?
I thought this
was the solution
windshield wipers.
Missi better fix
this problem because
battery or not we have
to get to the circus.
Keith: Let's get
this baby wrapped up.
Jesse Green: Grab
that sheet somebody.
If this touches
the ground, Brett,
I swear to God Texas
Clover Leaf times 10.
Jay Green:
We're in a rush,
Jesse's going crazy,
everybody else
is going crazy.
He always manages
somehow to work right up
to the last minute.
This is going to be
extremely tight.
Beth Green: No detours
go the fastest route.
Jesse Green: I
know how to go.
Beth Green: You sure.
Jesse Green:
I'm from here.
Beth Green: You're going
to be there, right?
Jesse Green: Sure.
Beth Green: Like soon.
Jesse Green: Yeah.
I really hope Missi
can get that battery
or we are (bleep) screwed.
Missi: I am on my way
to the hardware store
to try to get
this battery.
I'm hoping that is the
issue that we're having
'cause if it's not I don't
know what we're gonna do.
I'll be in big trouble
that's for sure.
Hey.
Jesse Green: Hey, did
you get a battery?
Missi: I'm on my way,
if you keep calling me
it's gonna
take more time.
I gotta concentrate
on driving and
where I am because I,
we are in the
middle of nowhere.
Jesse Green: We are
just barely gonna
make it I think.
Oh God!
We're not
gonna make it!
gonna make it.
Jay Green: We're
Jesse Green: I don't
think we're gonna make it.
Jay Green: They can't
start without you.
Jesse Green:
Yeah they can.
We might literally be
presenting this thing by
the porter potties
after the show.
Oh Grandma.
Jay Green: Easy!
Jesse Green: Don't tell me
easy it's a speed bump.
Guillaume Dufresnoy:
Hey Jesse!
Jesse Green:
Hey Guillaume,
nice to see you again.
Guillaume Dufresnoy:
Welcome.
So, everything's good?
Jesse Green:
Everything's good.
Guillaume Dufresnoy:
You know what?
10 minutes before we go.
Jesse Green: I will
bring it right in.
No problem.
Thanks man.
Guillaume Dufresnoy:
Take care.
Jesse Green: Dude where
the hell is Missi?
Keith: I called her.
She'll be here any minute.
Jesse Green: (Bleep),
what the hell does
that mean dude?
Keith: I don't
have a GPS on her.
Jesse Green: We
are minutes to
show time and we still
have no battery.
If Missi doesn't show
up right now this is
gonna be a
spectacular disaster.
Missi: Hey!
I got it.
Keith: Awesome.
Missi: I told you I
wouldn't let you down.
Keith: I told
you any minute.
Jesse Green: Thank you.
Let's go.
Come on.
Keith: Alright, I
don't think we have
time to test it.
Radio: 90 seconds,
90 seconds.
Jesse Green: Come
on, come on, come on.
Keith: Oh, it's stuck.
Radio: You got
30 seconds now.
Jesse Green: I
need more time!
The walkie talkie's
going, "90 seconds,
60 seconds, 10 seconds."
I'm not sure if this
thing's gonna squirt
and I just hope
to God it works.
Guillaume Dufresnoy:
Good evening.
Jesse Green: Is the
battery hooked up?
Keith: Everything
is all set.
Everything is all set.
Jesse Green: Ready,
ready, ready, ready!
Radio: That's your
cue, that's your cue.
Stage Manager: You're
on Jesse, you're on.
Guillaume Dufresnoy:
Ladies and gentlemen,
"the Machine" Jesse Green.
[audience applause].
Jesse Green: How's
everybody feeling tonight?
[audience applause].
At this time I'd like
to call out Grandma so
we can unveil
this sculpture.
Grandma, Grandma!
I've been commissioned
to honor you in wood.
Would you like to see
what I came up with?
And, go!
[audience applause].
Guillaume Dufresnoy: You
never looked that good!
Jesse Green: Grandma
seems genuinely touched
and Guillaume seems to
like the sculpture too.
Now comes the
moment of truth.
I'm just praying that
this water pump works.
Grandma would you
mind showing us
that trick of yours?
[audience laughing].
Jesse Green: That's good.
Grandma I don't know
if I can match that,
but I do have a trick that
I'd like to show you.
Allow me to demonstrate.
Let me just reach down
into this Grandma's bag of
tricks and, uh, let's see
what we can come up with.
[audience applause].
Guillaume Dufresnoy:
I think it couldn't
have gone better.
The results are great and
it had the water
spitting feature
which is really
what I wanted.
I'm a happy client
with a happy clown.
Jesse Green: What
can I say man?
Presenting the sculpture,
in the Big Top,
was an awesome
experience.
My team came through
in a big way.
I still can't
believe we get to
do this for a living.
Have a great
circus everybody!