CARL AZUZ, CNN ANCHOR: Welcome to CNN STUDENT
NEWS. I`m Carl Azuz. It`s Thursday, but the
political world is still buzzing about President
Obama`s State of the Union address. These
speeches can give an idea of what issues a
president wants to focus on. Tuesday night,
he talked a lot about the economy, specifically
creating job for the American middle class.
It`s something that Senator Marco Rubio discussed
in the Republican response, too. Why is there
so much attention on this?
In 2009, when he took the oath for the first
time, about 133 million Americans were employed,
and that number was already dropping dramatically
as we came out of the Bush years, and it kept
dropping until February of 2010 when it hit
its lowest point. Then we began this long
slow grind backup to where we are today. Right
now we have 1.2 million more jobs than we
did when President Obama first took office.
That`s not nearly as robust as people would
like to see. But more importantly, think about
this: the jobs we lost over here simply weren`t
as good as the jobs we gained back over here.
I`m going to explain what I`m talking about.
Rutgers University did a study where they
talked to a lot of people who`d lost jobs
and then regained other jobs. They found that
22 percent of those people said the jobs that
they have now pay about the same as the job
they lost before. Beyond that, another 24
percent said, they`re being paid more than
they were before, but now look at this number:
because it`s the big one: more than half the
people say, their new job pays less than their
old job. These are the people who really are
struggling out there. They are working as
hard as they can and they just cannot move
ahead in any way, shape or form.
Next story today: remember that massive blizzard
that hit the north- eastern U.S. last weekend?
Look at this video from Connecticut and watch
how much snow is building up around this clock
post. This is just one night. Some parts of
the state got up to three feet of snow. In
the city of Waterbury, all of the schools
have been closed since the blizzard hit. You
might think that sounds all right, but when
the city asked for help shoveling the snow,
a lot of the students showed up to pitch in.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
FRANCHESA VILLAR, STUDENT: Because this is
our community, everybody needs to help out,
and we`re all a family.
MAYOR NEIL O`LEARY, WATERBURY, CONNECTICUT:
You`ve got teachers here, you`ve got adults
here, as you can see. You`ve got a bunch of
students here. So, you know, this is, you
know - I`m amazed at the turnout, to be honest
with you.
ARIANNA MCDONALD, STUDENT: Like if you had
been staying in the house for like four days
straight without school, so we just wanted
to come help, especially elementary schools.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today`s "Shoutout" goes
out to Ms. Krueger`s world geography class
at Orr Middle class in Las Vegas, Nevada.
What religious observance marks the start
of Lent? You know what to do. Is it Palm Sunday,
Shrove Tuesday, Ash Wednesday or Good Friday?
You`ve got three seconds, go!
Lent starts on Ash Wednesday, and ends six
and a half weeks later on Easter. That`s your
answer and that`s your "Shoutout."
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Those six and a half weeks start this
week. Yesterday, it was Ash Wednesday, religious
ceremonies around the world marked the observance.
In Vatican City, the home of the Roman Catholic
Church, Pope Benedict XVI led an Ash Wednesday
mass. This is the last one he`ll lead as pope.
On Monday, he announced his resigning at the
end of this month. So with Ash Wednesday,
Lent has officially started, here`s a look
at what that`s all about.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: For Christians, Lent is
a season of prayer, of paying penance for
sins and for sacrifice. That`s the one act
we all associate with Lent, giving something
up.
Lent is for Christians, the period leading
up to Easter. The period lasts for 40 days
and corresponds to the 40 days that Jesus
is said to have fasted in the desert before
beginning his life of ministry.
Most of us associate Lent with Catholicism,
but the truth is, there are many different
kinds of Christians that celebrate Lent. Eastern
Orthodox Christians, various mainline Protestant
denominations, Presbyterians and Methodists,
among them. And in recent years, we`ve seen
a trend toward Evangelical churches, which
have traditionally avoided Lent, expressing
interest in it and beginning to celebrate
it or observe it in some fashion.
Some give up chocolate. In recent years, there
have been Christians that have given up Facebook,
or social networking for 40 straight days,
which is, you know, impossible for some of
us to imagine. It really varies widely what
people choose to give up for Lent.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: I`m planning on giving
up any kind of sweets, chocolate, cake, gummies.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: For a Lent, I`m going
to be giving up meat.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: I`m going to give up fat
food. Fat burgers, in particular.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: I really want to try
to be a healthier person. I want to start
working out and eating right.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: There`s always some time
during Lent that you think about you wish
you didn`t give it up. But when you get to
the end you always feel good about it.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: So, what would you give up? Whether
or not you observe Lent, what`s something
you enjoy that you`d try giving up for 40
days? Vegetables don`t count. Check out our
blog at cnnstudentnews.com
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Is this legit? The word
"valentine" comes from the Latin word for
heart.
Nope. It comes from St. Valentine, the patron
saint of love.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: You don`t need to live in Lovejoy, Georgia,
Romance, Arkansas or Valentine, Texas to feel
the love this Valentine`s Day. 62 percent
of adults say they celebrate it. And let me
count the ways how. Many people buy stuff,
candy stuff, gifty stuff, cards, jewelry,
flowers. Those little hearts that say "I do."
The average person will likely drop $130 bucks
on Valentine`s Day and men are the bigger
spenders. They`ll shell out between $150 and
$175, about twice what women will spend. Many
of those who procrastinate might find themselves
in flower shops. The application FourSquare
(ph) says they are the most popular spot for
last minute Valentine shoppers, and afterward,
likely a French restaurant or a cupcake shop.
Two popular places to celebrate love. Of course,
here is another way: sustained smooching,
liplocked lovers in Thailand are going for
the Guinness world record. It`s currently
set at 50 hours and 25 minutes. Yes, two people
actually kiss that long. Will their romantic
record be broken up? Until we know for sure,
our lips are sealed.
Finally today, we`re going from smooches to
pooches. And one in particular, that`s getting
a lot of love. His name is Banana Joe, he
is the top dog at this year`s Westminster
Kennel Club Dog Show. Joe is an affenpinscher.
That means monkey terrier in German. He is
the first of his breed to take home top honors.
At Westminster, winning the title is hard
enough, but when good dogs face off against
bad hair, that`s when the fir really flies.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
JEANNE MOOS, CNN CORRESPONDENT: Who hasn`t
had an important occasion when you want to
look your very best, and then you venture
outside, only to discover it`s a dreaded bad
hair day.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Oh, it is. It was. We
had to buy an umbrella and a poncho outside
of the hotel to get him here.
MOOS (on camera): You put the poncho on him
or on you?
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Him.
MOOS (voice over): Day one of the Westminster
Kennel Club Dog Show in New York was rainy,
foggy, slushy, enough to curl even a showdog`s
hair.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: They can curl, they can
go frizzy on you, just like, you ladies, they
can have a bad hair day.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: And his hair going, and
soaking this up.
MOOS: Rain left this long haired dachshund
with ridges. They blow- dried him, then used
a special comb to try and smooth him out.
(on camera): Whose hair got it worse? His
or yours?
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Mine doesn`t count.
MOOS (voice over): Sure, there are worse things
that could happen than getting rained on.
You dog carrier could crash. But rainy weather
is a big deal to a dog with dreadlocks.
(on camera): So they are naturally occurring
dreadlocks?
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Yes.
MOOS (voice over): Or a bearded collie?
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: If you look good coming
out of the shower, then come out of the shower,
but if you don`t ...
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Then ...
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Then dry your hair.
MOOS: Danny, the cavalier King Charles spaniel,
required flat ironing.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Everything wants to go
the wrong direction.
MOOS (on camera): I just came from makeup
and they just did that to me.
(voice over): But if rain makes for a bad
dog hair day, this looks counterintuitive.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Yeah!
MOOS (on camera): What is this thing?
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: It`s actually a fog machine,
but it gets him soaking wet, sorry.
MOOS (voice over): First, she soaked Beowulf,
then she blow dried and fluffed him, to give
him more volume. And then there are dogs like
Violet (ph).
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: A curl and then the tail--
MOOS (on camera): The rain didn`t do this?
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: No.
MOOS (voice over): Violet never left the indoors.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: She`s having a good hair
day.
MOOS: When it`s a bad dog hair day, you can
always get rid of the bad hair.
(on camera): Can I have this?
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Yes, you may.
Jeanne Moos, CNN, New York.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: If you can keep your cool in that kind
of harried situation, you definitely deserve
a round of a paws. Teachers, don`t forget
to tail us your thoughts on today`s show.
The feedback links on our home page. Have
a very happy Valentine`s Day, everyone.