I can't always explain my experiences
in relation to the dogmas or doctrines of
every faith, but as bad as some of these
demons are, which they are very, very serious
and they are by far so rabid in this world.
It's almost impossible to even explain.
One night I was given to go over a particular
US city and the entire upper atmosphere was
filled with so many demons it was almost impossible
to get through it... and when I got through
it I was exhausted for like two weeks, and
it was a particular city where there was just
really dominantly dark at that point, and
so we have to recognize that much of what
we believe to be true really isn't. There
is more to what we're doing here than what
we maybe want to deal with.
I believe that this world that we're experiencing is,
to put it kindly, small potatoes. It's like a
little experience that God has given us for our
benefit and edification and our spiritual
development. This is not graduate school by
any means. It's more like nursery school.
When I asked Jesus, 'Is this like elementary
school? He said no. And I said kindergarden?
He goes no. And I said, "Nursery school?"
And He says, "Mmm, like nursery school." The
lessons of this world are avoid evil and love
good, be kind to one another... these are
not really difficult or intellectually challenging
lessons that were learning down here and which
plenty of people are failing to learn.
It's possible that if you are not progressing
properly in this realm that you could go backwards
but that's usually for people who are engaging
in seriously destructive things. Dominantly
dark and evil would be people who are engaging
in murder, rape... serious, serious acts against
life, because the way energy is perceived
in the mystical realms is acts for or against
life. And so to go into the dominantly dark
and evil realms you would have to do some
pretty bad stuff. However, just having the
issues of vanity and lust could put you in
a lower realm.
This is just a small portion
of what I was shown, it's called the universal
sphere of realms. We are in here... this is
the third realm and this is the fourth realm.
This fourth realm is the astral plane. This
third realm would be a third dimensional reality
which we reside on. In the very center is
the first realm which, as you can see, is
totally black - that's total darkness, that's
where pure evil resides. The second realm
is where dominant darkness resides. When you're
dealing with realms one and two, you're dealing
with purgatories and hell realms - both of
these are even lower realms than we are. And
when you're dealing with three and four you're
dealing with purgatories and people who are
trying to reach beyond into realms five and
above, which go out into higher and higher
gradations of light. But these four realms
together make up what is called the border
worlds - the underworlds - and so the reason
why this is important is because if you understand
this is where we are... and God is somewhere
way out there, than what I'm going to try
to describe and explain makes a lot more sense.
When we die, we human beings have no power
to ascend or descend spiritually. We are taken
by guides... who could be either angels or
demons... to what we carry in our hearts. If
we carry hate in our hearts we go to a world of
hate, and if we carry love in our hearts
we're carried to world of love.
It's not good enough just to be nice, to speak
nicely and have a seething mind filled with eros
and thanatos. Because when you die, it's
that seething mind that will carry your spiritual
gene into places where seething beings live...
and you don't want to go in seething places.
In the mystical realms you see what
is called the energetic truth about a person
or another being or a spirit. In the physical
realm we can all disguise ourselves in any
way that we choose. We can be a wolf in sheep's
clothing in the physical realm, but when
you're in the mystical realm what you really
are is what people see.
And there's no deception and there's
no fooling around. You can't get out of it.
You can say, "I don't want this."
Well, that ain't going to do you any good because
you spent your whole life building your heart.
What we are doing here in this world
is building a heart of love
or building a heart that's not love.
We have to become more like God
in order to go to a higher place.
We go where we're compatible,
as depressing as that may be.
I remember many times that the angels would
show me, "How would you save a world that
serves its function to perfection?" And I
would say, "What you do mean?" And they would
say, "The mortal realms are where the battles
between good and evil rage. They rage around
you, they rage inside of you. This world
is functioning to perfection." The purpose
of being in a mortal realm is to become aware
of that interior process that has to begin,
of purification, and that's when we start
understanding... we understand
that the goal is God.
If you leave your mind filled with
unconscious drives of greed and hatred, eros
and thanatos, then they will drive you into
bad life forms. So the whole goal in a contemplative
culture is to go into the unconscious and
become conscious of it, and to cleanse yourself
of the negative, ego-centered, ignorance-dominated
drives. Like 'I want this' or 'I hate that.'
Why is it so important to purify the soul?
Because that's the true you; that's
who you are. Most people get caught
up with how they look, or they look at the
vehicle that carries the self. It's just
like the person who wants to get a nice body.
They go to Gold's Gym and they lift the
weights and they do the push-ups and the sit-ups
and all these kinds of things. So now, you
do all of that so that you can have a beautiful
body, and what do you do for the inside? So
there's work that you have to do on the
inside so that you can make sure that you
get rid of those vices.
One of the things I've learned
in the spiritual realms is that
a thought of vice is actually what gives dominion
for a demon of that vice to come in and be
around you. So let's say you have a greedy
thought... that is enough grounds for a demon
to come around and start suggesting things
to you. If you have the opposite thought where
you want to be charitable to somebody... that
also gives the same permission for an angel
of that virtue to come in and be around you,
as well. And this is where you begin understanding
the battle that goes on around us.
We've all seen these movies in
which you've got a good
angel and a demon sitting on someone's shoulders
saying, "Go ahead and do this, no, go ahead
and do that." Pulling the dark side and the
bright side of us sort of thing. It's the
truth. As we sit here right now there are
myriads of angels and myriads of demons, there's
light and darkness that's constantly
vying for our soul.
The best way to always describe
what a demon is... is something that was cast
out, tossed down here on earth, into hell,
the pit, whatever you want to call it, and
it's to wreak havoc, to undo everything on
a positive level, to be able to break down
people, to break down their life structures
and to do things on a totally negative level.
In order to begin purifying and begin getting
rid of some of our vices, we have to start
behaving differently and thinking differently
because if you understand that when you
have a simple thought of greed or a simple
thought of vanity, you're giving dominion
for a dark force to be around you and influencing
your thoughts, then you become more and more
aware of how much more vigilance you have
to keep over your mind, heart, and soul so
that you are progressing.
Those that want to change have to first change
the way they think. If you don't change it, you can
dress up a certain way and it seems like everything
is okay... a person could, even a Muslim, he
can learn so many verses from the Koran, he
can stop eating pork, he can fast in the month
of Ramadan, but if he or she have not changed
the way they think, then their behavior is
going to be the same. They might camouflage
it for a while, but then when they get back
into the environment, the same thinking is
there, so the behavior is going to come right back.
St. Francis was gathered in the field
with some of his brothers right outside of
a small town in Umbria and there was a fellow
who had the ability to see demons. And as
he stood in this field he saw legions of demons
as far as he could see that were lined up
in the field who were just plotting as to
how to tempt these Franciscan Friars. Then
he walks down the street to the entrance to
the town and there's one old demon sitting
there yawning, leaning back by the side of
the entrance to the town, and he went to
one of the Franciscan Friars and he said,
"Brother, I've been given this gift to be
able to see these things. Why are there millions
of demons here with you twenty in the field and
only one by the gate that's filled with all
these people," And he said, "Because all that's
needed is one little old demon in order to
bring those people to perdition... but the
devil has to work very hard in order to tempt
those who have given their lives completely to God."
What you have to understand is that
there's a continual warfare that goes on for
every soul on this earth. Much of the time
when we're here on earth, we're thinking all
the battles between good and evil are going
on outside of us but we don't recognize that
that battle is going on inside of us as well.
Anything that's good, a demon or a devil will
do in reverse. Now what do I mean by that?
If a person is a good person and they go to
church and they're trying to lead a halfway
decent life... they will rebel against that,
they'll try to break down that individual,
wear that individual down to be able to get
them to do mean, rotten types of things
and create all kinds of havoc.
What the forces of darkness want us to do is to
spend our life trying to grab for all the gusto that
we can get. To get stuff, and to get things...
and to treat people like things.
There really is a purpose for us being here, and
the purpose is not to live a worldly life, be
successful and all this stuff. The purpose has
to do with this purification process that God sent
us to the mortal realms to overcome. But
if you think about how brilliant this is of
the dark side, if the dark side can get
us to focus entirely on worldly things and
waste our time... works for him, doesn't it? Because
we waste an entire lifetime and accomplish nothing.
Are demons clever? They are the most
sophisticated, most cunning things you could
ever deal with. Why? They have the wisdom
of the ages. They have the knowledge of the
ages. They know how to manipulate things.
They know how to trick people. They know how
to do things very, very... cunning is the
best way I can describe it.
Now usually what happens
when people really turn their path towards
God is that they will begin what will become
almost a real warfare for their soul. And
a lot of people are really surprised by this.
But as long as we're kind of content and lackadaisical
about just living life and not doing anything,
the demons and Satan already has dominion
over us, so they don't have to make themselves
known. But when we turn away and we start saying,
"We want God," then they have to fight for us.
The more spiritual an individual
is, the more they pray, the more that they
are into their belief system, the more of
a target that individual actually can be.
Because trying to win a very spiritual individual
over - no matter what denomination you're
talking about... that's like the grand prize.
But you have to push through this warfare,
you cannot back down. Because that's their
goal, is that they want to wear you down
so you're so tired you're like, "This is
too hard, I'm just going to go back to my
lackadaisical lifestyle, nothing
bothered me then."
I think it's probably wise to
admit this about ourselves and our society
that evil is real, people are not always
going to be good or do good. And to be open
to the idea that some of those forces of evil
just as the forces of good may be
invisible, and that whether one calls it a
devil or not is maybe less important than
realizing that there are evils that we cannot
see, evils that are spiritual that we only
partially grasp, and we should be humbled
before reality, that we don't control
the good, we don't control the evil, and
there may be forces around us that can hurt us and
help us and we have to find our way between them.
The most powerful thing against
the demons in any of the spheres is - I'm
going to say something that the exorcists usually
say - which is confession. The sacrament of
confession is, according to many exorcists,
more powerful than the rite of exorcism, but
in my experience in the mystical realms...
the reason that's the case is because by confessing
your sins, you are taking away the dominion
that they have. They have dominion because
of your agreement to certain sins or vices
or ways of thinking.
You are your catalyst.
That's the best way I can describe that to
you. You are in control of your vessel. You
have to fight back. You have to protect yourself.
And the way I recommend to anybody is
I don't care if you worship a 5 pound quartz
crystal. I don't care what it is. As long
as it's on a positive. You call upon that
positive to be able to help protect yourself...
and you have to fight back.
In regards to some of the demons
associated with the deadly sins,
there is a demon of rage... and it's interesting
because the demon of rage operates
and appears very much like a person who has
an uncontrollable rage issue. It's a small
little snake, and you can see it in the mystical
realm, but when it becomes energized it becomes
huge, red, pumping with fury, and you've
got to get out of it's way... and so that's
one of the demons of rage.
Narcissism, which is an aspect
of pride, and a lot of these
things are offshoots of the deadly sins, but
like narcissism in particular there's a demon
called Gold Eyes. He's a very frightening
demon. When he is inside the soul of a person
he will appear as this gold light coming through
their eyes and he's so enraged... and it's
an imperialistic rage. It's like the rage
that you would see from someone who feels
very entitled. When you get this creature
to come out it's like a big raging wall of
fire... and that's narcissism and imperialistic rage.
The Gull demon is a demon of destructive
sexuality. The worst ones, which would be
the incubus and the succubus, these are much
more higher caliber demons, they have a lot
more strength and they can do a lot more damage
to a soul. These have to do with lust. You'll
see them as very attractive but when they
reveal themselves they're like a skeleton
with flesh hanging from it, spider webs... almost
like a corpse that's been decomposing. You
know how it says in the scriptures somewhere,
"Outside they look one way and inside
they're like a ravening wolf."
That's the way the demonic is.
One of the most important and most
disturbing demons to mention is called
the Lord Demon, and one of the reasons it's
so disturbing is because of its commonality.
Christ showed me this demon and I was so overwhelmed
by the power of this demon... and then He showed
me... it was a real, real mortal battle
to the death kind of thing. I mean, this demon
was really sneaky. The Lord Demon represents,
more than anything, self-intelligence... so
you have to have the ego, you have to have
the greed, and the avarice is anger that's
disordered. The Lord Demon is the most common
demon in the world today because we're so
smart as human beings, we're so self-intelligent,
that we're smarter than God, right? We want
the opinion of God, the opinion of the prophets,
saints, mystics and sages from all time, to
be of equal value to every single one of us
down here below. But in reality, it's not.
If you have to hold on to the self-intelligence
that, "I'm right. This whole concept of demons
is illogical. The concept that God would not
just love all His creatures no matter what
is illogical," then you're going to be visiting
with the Lord Demon. And the Lord Demon, Jesus
Christ also told me, was the most common cause
of damnation today. And that's interesting
because in Fatima in 1917, when the Blessed
Virgin appeared to the three shepherd children,
she had said the most common reason for souls
to go to hell at that time was sins of impurity.
But our society has become so arrogant
that we have become smarter than God. Think
about that. Think about us down here in the
third and fourth realm, and God somewhere
ad infinitum, and we believe that. That's
not going to allow us to grow. And the Lord
Demon is so sneaky, all he has to do is convince
you that it's illogical... religion is illogical,
the moral code is illogical, the ten commandments
are illogical. But if we think that we're
smarter than the simple moral code, we think
that anything can be changed according to
our simple whims, we become really vulnerable
to having a voice speaking inside of us telling
us we're right, and it gets harder and harder
to get away from this one because the Lord
Demon is really, really powerful. This is
not like some little pansy demon. This Lord
Demon is a scary creature, and he will come
to you and when you see him in the mystical,
when he becomes his true self, his teeth
are all pointy, he turns red and black and
blood oozes from his pores and his teeth,
and there's flesh on his teeth... he's the
most disgusting creature you'll ever see, but...
boy, is he good at what he does.
Before my experience with Jesus I was a successful,
A+, American guy, who believed that it's a
dog-eat-dog world, life is about competition
and winning and not being a loser. Life is
about not being the victim but being the aggressor
and I tried to bully my way in my relationships.
I tried to intimidate people. I didn't hesitate
to physically assault people and verbally
assault them. I did very well. I got
promotions, I got money, I got prestige, I
got honors. I was a winner. I was very aggressive
with my wife, with my children. A lot of people
despised me and I was glad of it because I
figured part of the quality of being a winner
was that there were casualties in your relationships
along the way. And my friends were people
that subscribed to the same sort of highly
assertive, self-centered, narcissistic, point
of view. I believe that there is no such thing
as an atheist, I believe that everybody has
a God. The only question is, "Who's your
god?" And for atheists, their god is themselves.
So they have these little bitty gods, which
is their self, and that was me and my friends.
We were all in love with ourselves and that's
who we worshipped. Having yourself as a god
fails in a crisis because you have nobody
to turn to because you can't do anything about
the circumstances, they're just collapsing
around you. I was dying in a hospital and
it was catastrophic, and you have nothing
left but hopelessness and despair and a very
fatalistic, nihilistic view of the world, that
life sucks and then you die and who cares.
Which is pretty bleak when you think about it.
And that's what I was believing when I
died on June 1, 1985 at 38 years old.
Your consciousness, when you die, doesn't
cease. That's the interesting thing is that
consciousness survives bodily death. And so
when you have a negative consciousness you
get to go into negative world... the world
where 'of like' people and like consciousness
and it's a very cruel and brutal and horrible place.
It was much like what has been described
as rats when they over-reproduce in too small
a cage and they just start gnawing on each
other. That's what they were doing... basically
people biting, tearing, ripping each
other apart continuously.
One of the things as a priest,
I've been a priest for 31 years, and
one of the things that is the most wonderful
moment in the day is when at 2:30 in the morning
you get a call to go to the hospital and somebody's
dying. At first you grumble that it's 2:30
in the morning - I got this 7 o'clock mass
tomorrow, I'm going to be tired all day, and
you whine about that. And then you get up
and you go to the hospital. But when you're
standing by that bed, and you look at everybody
standing around it, life is clearer and makes
more sense at that moment than it does any
other time during the day. Because at that
moment there's no one who dies saying, "I
wish I'd gotten more stuff. I wish I'd committed
more sin. I wish I'd been more selfish."
They all die saying, "I wish I'd loved more."
I thought about my life, and as I thought
about my life I realized, since I'd been a
teacher all my life, that somehow I'd missed
the whole point, that whatever the point
of life was not only had I missed it but I
failed it. I'd failed to recognize what the
course was about and I was clueless and whatever
I was supposed to have achieved I didn't achieve
it because I ended up in this cesspool... this
horrible cesspool. And so obviously
I was a big failure.
One of the beautiful things
about Hindu tradition is that God is very,
very accommodating, God is very open to
adjustment and whatever way a human being
happens to be heading or wandering, God is
able to go there and meet the person there.
The example is given in some scriptures that
if we are seeking God in a very basic way,
we're like little children running around
in the courtyard and God is like our mother
who will find us wherever we are, both to
protect us from harm and to make us well.
We can trust that God's love and mercy will
overcome our sinfulness. And that's true whether
we're the worst sinner in the world or whether
we've actually led a pretty decent God-fearing
upright life of kindness and mercy and compassion.
That God's grace is what brings us into a
right relationship with Him in the last analysis.
Yes, we respond by good works and so on and
so forth, and all we have to do is simply
acknowledge that we need that grace.
After the people in darkness had devastated me and
emotionally, psychologically, spiritually
had torn me down to nothing... I heard my voice
say, "Pray to God." And I thought I don't
pray, I don't believe in God... that's what
I thought... and the voice said, "Pray to God."
And I thought I don't know how to pray, I
don't pray. And the voice said, "Pray to God."
And I thought - I used to pray, I knew how
to pray once!
No matter where we are, the second
a soul wants God, God comes - just
like that! It's amazing to me because to me
that demonstrates mercy... that's what love
and mercy is, and that's the corrective,
merciful love of God. Because every single
one of these people - and many of these people
have written to me who've had these experiences
to hell and have called out for help - have
been so blown away by that merciful nature
of God their entire life changes.
There is in the universe a caring,
a love, a compassion,
some kind of meaning to the universe, and
I called out to that and I said, "Jesus please
save me." And with that, He - Jesus - the
being of light, the ambassador of God, came
over me and loved me and took me out of that
place. And that changed everything and my
whole life, my entire life for the past 25
years has all been about that moment and
trying to get people to say, "God I need you.
Jesus I need you. Allah help me." However
they can express it.
If we put our reliance back towards
where it should be, which is
on God, and we don't make ourselves our own
gods, we humble ourselves and let God lovingly
correct us and bring us through that path
of purification. He will! He will not leave
you behind. The only time people are left
where they are is because the really, truly,
honestly want to be there - and that's one
of the hardest things for people to understand
is that you stay there because you don't want
to do anything different, you like it the
way things are. You're compatible to it!
The dogma of materialism I think arose from
the dogma of the inquisition, of the Christian
Church, and burning Giordano Bruno and muzzling
Galileo Galilei and many other lesser people...
burning and muzzling. And so to escape from
that after the Renaissance and Reformation
and Enlightenment, the thinkers and intelligentsia
in Europe went to another extreme to get away
from being dominated by the church and being
threatened with hell and so forth, and so
they abandoned having a soul. They decided
we don't even have one. We're just
a species, we have genes, we have drives,
survival of the fittest, and went on through
all of those different theories. And then
they got to where they, like Carl Sagan, one
of his last books was When Demons Stalked
the Earth, and it had to do with the Fundamentalists
that he'd had to tangle with in Arkansas
and other places as a scientist. And the idea
was that if anything non-physical were admitted
to exist in the world, this would open the
door for all kinds of crazies and new inquisitions
and demented creationists... like the world
is 7,000 years old and the Grand Canyon was
made in a flash flood and Adam was a white
guy... just a silly bunch of stuff. And then
they'd end up getting political power, these
religions, and they'd start clamping down
on free thought and scientific discovery
like they did before.
Did the Garden of Eden really happen?
Was the world made, the universe made
in literally seven days... or six days and
a day of rest? I mean, is that how it really
happened? That God spoke the universe into
being? And sometimes in discourse religious
people can't get passed that - that it's real
facts - into a discourse about an even deeper
truth underneath which is a description of
the estrangement in the human community
and between human beings and God.
We let the details trip us up.
So the dogma of materialism in
a spiritual sense boils down to that view
of not understanding the common sense reality
and scientific viability of former and future
lives - in some form - and that's the heart
wrong view of our psychotic culture, which
thinks it's not connected to the world,
it can keep messing with the climate, it can
kill off all the animals, cut all the trees,
do whatever it is. The rapture people do it
as a sort of warped spiritual thing, but the
materialists do it because, 'I'm not
going to be here, so I'm going to use it
up.' And then they will say, 'Oh, no,
but I'm not unethical, I'm a humanist
and I care about my children so I'm
not going to wreck the planet." But actually
they are wrecking the planet.
If we waste the time here, if we don't take the
time to purify ourselves or to move upwards then
we're going to start circling. And what I
mean by circling is when you see people
for those who believe in reincarnation... and
I've had a lot of experiences myself - I didn't
believe in the reincarnation until I started
having mystical experiences about them and
I've had thousands of them now... but for those
who believe in reincarnation you end up coming
back and doing the same thing over and over
again, with the same characters, the same
configuration. And until you see, "I'm doing
something wrong here... there's a reason why
I keep doing the same thing." And it's made
more difficult because most people don't remember
their previous lives. But sometimes when people
become more spiritually alert you'd be surprised
how quickly they start remembering.
There's a very strong sense
in the most ancient parts
of Hinduism that we are, in fact, on a journey
that takes many lifetimes. To be a being in
this world is not done in a short period of
time, even if that short period of time is
100 years, but that the purification of nature,
the discovery of true identity comes in small
packets, which we would call one lifetime
or another lifetime. And in Hinduism, as in
Jainism and Buddhism, there is a sense that
one can be reborn again and again into new
bodies as one journeys along one's path.
There is no guarantee, of course, that every
body and every rebirth is better than the
one before because we're really faced with
the prospect of what do you do with the body
you have, what do you do with the opportunities
of your current life? And then, in a sense,
that if we use those well, we move into
more pure, more focused bodies that are directed
to the divine. And if we become distracted,
if we begin to forget who we are, then we
might come back in a body that is more immersed
in matter and less able to be open to the
divine. So, there is a way in which every
life is extremely important because it really
charts our way on the course, and yet every
life also is simply part of a much larger
journey that takes a much longer time.
There's a karmic understanding to everything
which is something that's not quite correct, and
there's an eternal understanding which is
the real truth. And so we circle and we keep
doing the same thing over because we have
a karmic understanding, which doesn't create
peace. It's very chaotic... we're usually
messed up. Once we reach that eternal understanding
there's peace. And that's one of the ways
you can tell. Like when someone meets a new
person, if it's an eternal thing there'll
be a lot of peace. If it's karmic, there may
be a lot of chaos and a lot of really intense
emotions and things like that. That may very
well indicate that there is an issue that's
coming up from previous existences that either
has to do with you and that particular person,
or it's just that this particular person is
going to play that role that has been played
for you before in previous existences... and
that's why it brings up all this intensity.
But a lot of times even something that starts
out karmic, if the two parties are seeking
an eternal solution, it can end up well. It
can become eternal. It can amend to an eternal
situation if the two parties both go in that direction.
I think a lot of individuals can
be reincarnated because there was karma carried
over from a past life. And some of the traditional
belief systems in that is that people keep
reincarnating and reincarnating until
they actually get it right.
So how does one become more spiritually alert?
You do so by doing what every
human being has done for the last
several thousand years. If you look at the
ancient sacred texts throughout history from
every single world religion it's the same
process. It's prayer - prayer is speaking
to God; Meditation is listening and trying
to get that answer; and Spiritual Reading,
which is utilizing the works of all those
people who've come before us who have figured
it out. And there are many, many people like
that from Tibet's Milarepa to Catholicism's
St. Francis DeSales and St. Catherine of Siena
to... Earth Store Bodhisattva was a Buddhist
monk who had a similar calling that I have
where he would actually go into hell realms
and liberate souls. So you do the spiritual
reading to form your conscience better. The
more of the spiritual reading you do, the
more sensitive you become to what is vice
and what is a virtue.
If you're not putting good thoughts
or good scripture in your mind
and in your soul, then something else is coming
in. So if you're a person who's always
in front of the television, always watching
violent movies or whatever the case may be,
always involved with that, then your soul
is being fed something but it's not being
fed anything that's going to elevate you
or lift you up. In order for your soul to
be lifted up you have read and study and reflect
and meditate on good things.
The worship, the prayer, the visits to Holy sites,
the reading of the books, are not to say the more
we have the better off we'll be, but all
of these are wisdom and advice that lead us
toward letting go of the things
that stand in the way.
Prayer is saying I want to be
a part of that life of God in me and to let
it more and more fill me, my conscious life,
so that more and more of how I live, how
I speak, how I listen, how I make choices
is caught up in what God
wants to do through me.
Just think about being in this world,
where you have to make a living, and it's
the hustle and bustle in life... always
running, always running and you take
out five times of the day where you have this
spiritual refreshment called prayer. You take
a break from all that hustle and bustle. It's
something that empowers you, and it's something
that keeps you grounded, because you can
get lost out there just going after the dollar. And then,
it's like nothing else counts, nothing else matters.
Prayer is a very powerful thing.
I recommend it to people continuously
no matter what your structure is, no matter
what your belief system is. There are all
sets of prayers in different belief systems
out there. I recommend very strongly to people
call upon that. It doesn't hurt to say prayers.
It's a very positive element in our lives.
A lot of times we believe when we're praying
that we should be answered in a certain way,
but in reality, we have to remember that God
knows exactly what we need at any given time.
And God's purpose isn't the same as ours.
Our purpose is often very motivated by the
fact that we're in denial that this is a temporary
place of existence. So God is not motivated
by continuing our denial about the impermanence
of this life. He's motivated by what is going
to give this soul the most progress spiritually
at this time. And I have seen many situations
where miraculous things have occurred and
many other situations where the answer is no.
Nobody can explain that except God because
only God knows why He says yes and why He
says no and why other times He says no, but
how about this? But it's because God has that
all-knowing where He understands
what we need to progress.
We live in a society that's got a lot of noise.
Listen to yourself and see what yourself
is saying. Take time out.
There are so many people that don't take
time out. Some people can't even go to
sleep unless the music is playing. They can't
go to sleep unless the television is on. And
there's noise everywhere, so shut it down.
Once you shut it down you're going to hear
something inside yourself. You have
something talking within you.
God will use anything and everything
to reach out to us. God always is.
God's always trying to connect with us.
We forget that. We think, 'Oh, I have to
go and find God.' But, in fact, it's more
like opening our eyes to what's already there.
God is reaching out to us all the time.
It's a lot like tuning your radio. Like when
you're in a rural area and you're trying to find
something to listen to and you're either pressing
the digital thing or turning the dial trying
to find a radio station. Then you get some
real terrible country-western thing... you're
searching, searching, searching for something
good to listen to - then finally you found it,
and you fine tune your radio just so you
get it. You got to seek God. And there's
a lot of voices out there like... chase the
ladies, get more money, grow more hair, have
flat abdominal muscles so you'll be desirable
to chicks... whatever. There are all these
voices out there booming at you all the time,
telling you all this like crazy and often
stupid stuff - and it's bad stuff. And so
to tune in God, which is always the voice
of love and kindness and peace and hope and
joy - that's how you recognize it, because
that's what it sounds like... when you get to
that voice and then to be able to focus on it.
And the thing that's not so hard is
it's there, and if you contemplate love,
contemplate goodness - you can find it.
I seek to be with God in praying. I seek to
be with God in hanging around with Him and
those who nobody else will have anything to
do with. I seek to be with God through the
sacraments in a wonderful way. I seek to be
with God through doing what is right, through
working for justice. So there are all kinds
of ways I seek to be with God, but at the base
of it all is shutting up and letting Him talk to me.
We all have guardian angels, we all have
forces around us that are trying to lead
us towards the good, but we've blocked it
all out with noise, with sin, with vice, with
just certain ways of thinking - so they can't
reach us. We have to re-open the channel so
that God can show us what He put us here to
do. And if we do that He will show us and
it becomes really easy because He does show
you every step of the way.
If you get quiet and say,
"God, what do I need to do?" God will
let you know, but it's not necessarily
in a big Charlton Heston booming voice broadcast.
It's more in the Elijah sense... in the small,
still inner voice. You just contemplate something
and then you know that you know that you know.
When my journey began Jesus came to me and
He said it was time for my purification and
He said, "Gather the ancient sacred texts
and all the ancient prayer books because you're
going to learn from them." And He took me
through - I didn't even know what they were.
He showed me and He told me... He would give
me these strange names, like the Holy Teaching
of Vimalakirti... I was like, "How am I going
to find that?" But I went through this process
and He would tell me what to look for. One
was the Dialogues of St. Catherine of Siena,
which explains Christian mysticism and redemption
in such a way that it remains my favorite
books to this day. I really loved the writings,
and was led to read the writings of Imam Ghazali
who is one of the mystical theologians of
Islam. He wrote a really great text called
the Ihya Ulumuddin - and I actually ordered
that from overseas. And it's interesting because
I compared that with the Catholic contemporary
which is Father Adolf Tanqueray's The Spiritual
Life: A Treatise On Ascetical And Mystical
Theology. And it's so interesting when you
look at the two and you look at many of these
things - because there's some Jewish books
that I'd like to mention as well - that they're
just like different sides of the same coin.
There might be a few different terms used
but it's the same idea - they go through the
purification of the soul through the virtues.
So what are the seven deadly sins?
They are gluttony, lust, greed, pride,
sloth, vanity, and avarice.
And the seven virtues which counterbalance
the seven deadly sins
would be prudence, justice, fortitude,
temperance, and faith, hope, and love.
And love is also charity - and faith, hope,
and love are in the area that's considered
supernatural virtues, as well. If you want
to talk about how to attain to the virtues
and to discard some of the vices, you have
to really take a close self-examination of
yourself, and spiritual reading is one of
the ways that you do this because that's how
you make yourself aware of things, because
many of the vices we have are so habitual
that we would never see it in ourselves. We
might see in someone else but not in ourselves.
So in order to attain those virtues you want
to engage in the spiritual reading, the prayer,
and the meditation, but then you also have
to practice the virtues that are opposite
to the vices that you know you have.
Let's say, for instance, you have an issue with lust.
You're going to need some temperance.
If you have a problem with greed, you're going
to need to experience the virtue of justice in order
to be more willing to part with your goods.
If you have a vice of greed, then you have to
become mindful of that and you have to give.
Greedy people don't like to give.
So if you turn it around and you start giving,
you can loosen that up a bit, and the hope
will be that at some point you're no longer
that greedy type person because you're
giving. If it's gluttony, again, you have
to back off from the table.
For those of us who, when we start
realizing that we have
some failings - because I've had a lot - and
I have been shown all of them and I'm sure
there's more to come. When you see them there's
a tendency to feel ashamed of yourself. I'll
never forget the moment when I got to see
my vanity through the eyes of God. It was
so profoundly humbling in the sense of I saw
vanity in all its ugliness. Everything I had
ever done up to that point in my life, including
the things that were good, were all done
for the wrong reason, because they all had
some kind of self-serving reason behind it.
Whether it's to make you do something good
for someone else to make yourself to feel
better, or you do something that's good but
you're doing it because it'll make you look
good... you do, whatever it is, some kind of
self-serving reason. That was really a big
turning point for me - it took me about a
month to recover from it. And I have been
told many times by my angels in the spirit,
"This is a time we want you to apply Buddhist
principles because otherwise we're going to
waste too much time with you in shame, where
we want you to understand this as a fetter,
this is something holding you back." Christianity
has it right - it's very correct - it's just
that Buddhism takes it more from an intellectual
standpoint, and that makes it a little quicker
because rather than spending a lot of time
thinking about how ashamed we are of what
we've done, we say, well, this is a fetter,
this is a hindrance, this is keeping me
from moving up towards the love that is God
so I'm going to let these things fall away.
When the Bhagavad Gita, like other Hindu texts,
talks about this yogic practice of simplifying
our lives, focusing, getting our bodies in
order, our morality in order, our spiritual
practice in order, it can at first sound very
complicated, it can sound as if there's
so many things to do. But, generally speaking,
it really is an effort to stop doing things,
stop worrying about things, stop needing things...
physically, mentally, psychologically coming
into a simpler and simpler state where one
is confronting and being confronted by ultimate
reality. And because traditions like that
of Hinduism and the Bhagavad Gita believe
that one finds one's joy in the presence
of the divine, ultimately being happy, rejoicing
in life, finding peace, come down to uncluttering
one's life, doing away with the things
that stand in our way and our obstacles and
coming to that simple presence of ourselves
and the divine. Once one gets there, this
is what we are made for, this is who we are.
And in that moment, we find the joy of our
life, we find the bliss - and there's no
reason ever to leave that condition.
The most difficult part of my experience was not
the hellish part that I experienced to get
to the good part - that was insignificant
compared to what Jesus told me about God's
disappointment with this world because it's
a whole lot bigger than me. The human race
has failed miserably in what God's hope and
expectation was what we can be. Granted, God
put us in a very challenging world - this
world is not easy - but the world that God
wants, and that God will get in the future...
it's going to happen because it's what God
wants, and God gets what God wants - one way
or another. That world is going to come about
and it's so different than the world we have.
God doesn't like the idea of propelling bits
of metal through exploding gases into each
other's guts to prove that you're right and
they're wrong. God doesn't like the idea that
a small portion of the planet has so much
resources and meanwhile there are people in
the world who literally don't have enough
to eat, don't have enough clothes to wear,
don't have enough shelter to keep themselves
dry when it rains. They don't have the minimal
resources for survival. And when they show
those miserable pictures of them on T.V. - it's
like, "Change the channel, don't bore me
with the starving children."
I remember I went to a church
to speak many years ago and
the pastor told me that he has a problem with
his congregation because they're rich - and
because they're rich they don't believe
they commit sin. So it's a challenge for
him to teach them certain things because
they think, 'Oh, I don't do that.' But
no, they can do it just like anybody else.
We don't realize how dumb it is that we focus
so much on mortal, impermanent things in this
world. We focus on how we look on the outside,
whether or not we have enough degrees, whether
or not we make enough money... and you know
the only thing that matters when you're on
that deathbed is the people you love and whether
or not you loved well, whether or not you
actually improved and progressed in your spiritual
life, if you moved closer to God
rather than further away.
People who want more and more
things are trying to make up for an inner
feeling of inadequacy and unfulfillment by
piling on outer things, but it never works,
right? And then as they do that, they get
angry with others because they think that
they want to take things from other people
so they imagine that other people
want to take things from them.
Living from your center, knowing who
you are, having a sense that you are living
what God created you to live is a pearl of
great price. And it can't be bought and no
one or nothing can take it away from you.
Careers come and go. Money can come and go.
There's nothing wrong with money. Money can
do great things, but it's a poor master.
It's a great tool, terrible master. We need
more to ground our sense of worth than money.
When people live too far from their center
you can tell, because they're always looking
to be entertained and distracted from the
emptiness they find inside.
The Buddhist legend of coming to the
guide and saying, "I'm suffering...
I can't deal with it." "Okay, well, I want
to help you. This is what you do: Go find
a home that has known no suffering." So the
person goes off to the home and says, "I'm
looking for a home where there's no suffering."
"Oh, no, that's not here." Tells him all the
suffering, and the person starts working with
them... then goes to the next home, same thing,
works with them. Before they know it, they
forget about their own suffering.
As the Dalai Lama says, if you want to be happier
yourself then make other people happy, and forget
about being happy yourself. Because as long as
you're worried about being happy yourself, you'll
be unhappy because you'll measure how
happy you are and then you'll not think
it's happy enough. You'll want another
ice cream cone, you'll want another extra
thing. But if you forget about how happy you
are and you're just trying to make another
person happy, then without even trying you'll
be happy. So as the Dalai Lama says, if you're
going to be selfish seeking your own happiness,
at least be a wise selfish and affect
other being's happiness.
Good deeds done well encourage more good
deeds done well. A lot of these
kinds of things we don't realize the astronomical
effect it has when we try to bring God into
what we are doing and we try to keep in mind
the well-being of everyone involved and everyone
around us that others mimic that and they start
doing the same. And so it multiplies, and
you bring more and more light into this world.
Every time there's an act of goodness, of
bringing God's light in the world, you're
bringing healing. There's a wonderful traditional
phrase in Jewish mysticism, it's very much
used in normative Jewish practice today, it's
Tikkun Olam. Literally, it means to repair
the world. The acts that we can do on a daily
basis that help bring healing to the world.
You're not commanded by God to fix everything...
but you are commanded by God to keep trying.
When Jesus told me that my fate was to come
back in this world and that I was not going
to go to heaven - which is what I wanted to do,
I argued as forcibly as I could to not send
me back here. I told Him that the world was
full of evil, it was a terrible place. And
He said, "Yeah, there's a lot of evil in the
world and there's a lot of bad stuff in the
world, but there's a lot of good and a lot
of loving people." He said, "What you
are in your heart is what you're going
to seek. If you seek hate, you'll find hate,
and you are hate. If you seek love,
you'll find love and you'll be love. If you
seek kindness, you'll find kindness, and you'll
be kindness." And so we have to be it, and
seek it, and then we will find it. So I said,
"But what's the point of sending me back?
Why would you want me to go back to that world?
If you really loved me you wouldn't send me
back to that place." And He said, "I need
you. I need you back there." I said, "You
need me to do what?" And He said, "I need
you to change the world." I said, "Whoa, whoa,
whoa... I'm not going to change the world!"
I said,"I don't even know if I could change
me. I don't know if I can be what you want
me to be, be the loving, kind person you
want me to be and asking me to be the Savior
of the world." He didn't say that, I said
it... I was sort of exaggerating my role. He
said, "No, that's really what I want you to
do. I want you to change the world." "That's
crazy," I said, "people that try and change
the world come out to a bad end. We're talking
about Stalin and Hitler and Genghis Khan... they
all wanted to change the world and they were
all megalomaniacs. I don't want to go back
and be a megalomaniac." He said, "No, no,
no... you got it all wrong. They were bad,
they were megalomaniacs. That's not how I
want you to change the world." And I said,
"Well, how do want me to change the world?"
He said, "Love somebody." And I said, "Okay...
but what's the rest of the plan?" He said,
"No, that's the whole plan." And I said, "If
I go back and love someone... that changes
the world?" And He said, "That's the plan.
That's it." I said, "What's the rest of the
plan?" He said, "That's the whole plan, there
is no more. Just love somebody." And I said,
"If I love somebody, how in the world will
that change anything?" And He said, "If you
love someone, really truly love them, they
will love someone, and that person will love
someone, and that person will love someone."
And me, being a clever fellow I was, I said,
"Yeah, and then they get run over by a truck
and that's the end of the plan." And He said,
"No... because I never said you're the only
one." He said, "There's a lot." And I said,
"Well, how many." He said, "Millions. Millions
of people are the instrument of change." And
I said, "Okay, but there are a lot of trucks
down there and a lot of bad stuff can happen
to thwart the millions of people trying to
love somebody." And He said, "Yeah, but I
have a backup." I said, "What's the backup?"
And He said, "Angels." And I said, "So you're
going to bring the angels into this?" And
He said, "The angels are already in it, they're
already intervening." He said, "So I got millions
of people, I got angels beyond counting all
trying to inspire people, encourage people,
help people." He said, "This is God's Will.
It is inevitable. It's going to happen one
way or another. It has to happen because
it's what God wants." And I said, "Well, when
you put it that way... when you put it as like
God's going to make it happen... sure, I'd
be happy to be part of it!" So anyways, this
is my interpretation: You're either part of
the program or you're against it. There's
no longer an opportunity to sit on the
fence and say, oh, look at the foolish loving
people doing the loving thing. Good luck
to them and the Boston Red Sox. And look at
the bad people going around fermenting hate
and fear and strife in the world. Good
luck to them. You can't do that anymore. You're
either in the program, which is God's program
of turning this world into a loving and kind
place or you're against the program. And
there's nothing in between.
We are told that you can't even go
to sleep if your neighbor's
hungry and you have food. The Prophet Muhammad,
peace be upon him, told us that our neighbors
are forty houses in front of us, forty houses
in back of us, and forty houses on the side
of us. And he told us that he received so
many instructions from Almighty about the
neighbor that he thought that the neighbor
was going to actually be in the will. That
you have to actually put the neighbor in the
will. So he told us to treat our neighbor
as we treat ourselves.
How do I love God in this life?
I don't do it by putting on all
kinds of fancy clothes with jewels and standing
and waving my hand and saying, "I love God."
I don't do it by standing in a pulpit and
saying, "I love God." I don't do it by wearing
a button that says, "I love God and He loves
me." I do it by going to the soup kitchen
down the street. I do it by buying a coat
for the guy I know is cold. I do it by taking
care of those who are the most broken in life
and loving them. How do you get to heaven?
By loving God... and by loving Him in my neighbor.
We can't journey back to God without taking
into account our obligation to our neighbor.
It's not just about me and God. It's about
me and the whole human community and how together
this earth can be more like the kingdom of
God, which is a community of justice, of love, of
peace. No one's God says, 'Hate your neighbor.'
Some fanatics in every religion distort,
perhaps, but rightly understood
the core of all religions is a journey of
love. A journey toward our fellow human beings
and toward God not away from them.
A lot of the times God is saying, "Just be. Just be
there with that person. You don't you have
to fix them. They're not broken. If they
got brokenness I'll fix them, you just love
them the way they are... just love them the
way they are." I've been with drug users,
prostitutes, alcoholics, murderers... I did
a ministry with a guy on death row for a long
time... and God was saying, "You don't have
to preach to these people, just love them.
I'll take care of the rest."
Love your neighbor as yourself,
everything else is commentary.
If you're really serious about that, you're
starting in a position of love.
If everyone just started with that,
that one thing, imagine
how different the world would be. "I love
you. Now let's talk."
In the Hindu religious traditions
there is a very universal sense
that we are all on the path, and that all
beings are destined toward a higher development,
toward true knowledge, toward ultimately bliss,
in union with the ultimate reality, or as
that reality, or with God. And I think the
good Hindu teacher can see a crowd before
her or him and realize that each person here
is on the spiritual path, has the same destiny,
and yet needs to be allowed to travel at his
or her own pace. And trying to make somebody
travel at somebody else's pace and speed
things up or slow things down only leads to
unhappiness for everyone. So everyone is on
the journey and yet people are at different
stages, just as we tend to be at different
stages of life depending on
our age or circumstances.
The goal for all of us is that we're trying
to get to God, and the only way we can do
that is by becoming more and more holy. Does
that mean that any of us are going to achieve
perfection in this life? Mm-mmm (no). But
we can become more aware and even just having
the humility to realize who we really are
in relation to God is a really good place to start.
I feel that as we are trying to
move forward and I think that the church is
trying to recognize the fact that they need
to open up and change some of their old methods.
I feel that a lot of them were looking at
it from the perspective that devils and demons
and these things were something from the stone
ages and it really didn't encompass our world.
The book of Revelation is a very unique piece
of literature because it's a kind of a literature...
apocalyptic literature, that was very popular
in those years immediately after the death
and resurrection of Christ in the early days
of the church, and it was not necessarily
meant as a prediction of the way things are
going to happen in a physical, historical
way. So to say that, in effect, we each participate
in our own kind of cosmic battle, our own
internal battle between light and darkness,
well, that's the theme of everything I've
saying along the way, it's true. And so one
can see this kind of cosmic battle as simply
being a description of what's going on inside
of each of us.
I think the very idea of the end of the
world is one of those concepts
that we have in mind without ever really knowing
what to make of it in terms of history. We
do have a sense that everything ends... summer
ends, winter ends, the day ends. We know through
the experience of death that so many people
we love, their lives come to an end. And I
think we can expand that and say the world,
too, will come to an end. It may be that the
Armageddon or the last judgment matters most
in terms of my life, my facing up to my destiny,
my facing up to the fact that some day this
life will be over and there are basic choices
to be made about to live
in the face of that reality.
Judgment is a little different than
people think because people think of judgment
as like an external group or individual saying,
"You're good, you're bad." That's not the way
it works. Our judgment is what our hearts are.
When I had my life review... I could summarize
my life review simply by saying I was judged
entirely by the quality of my relationships,
of whether my relationships were loving
and caring and compassionate and kind, or
whether my relationships with other people
were me being manipulative, and greedy, and
self-centered. And, unfortunately, I was the
latter and not the former.
One of the biggest issues that I see in
the world today is too
many people not realizing that there is a
function and a purpose for us being here, and
that function was told to me in a near-death
experience I had with Jesus Christ, and it's
very simple: We're supposed to go
from selfishness to selflessness.