GO TO THE REVIEW SESSION YOU ARE WELCOME TO
DO SO.
MR. KERN WILL BE AVAILABLE FOR YOU. SECOND
IS THAT
THERE IS A HANDOUT WHICH IS A PEANUT. MAKE
SURE ALL
OF YOU HAVE IT. WE WILL BE USING IN THE LECTURE.
FOR
THOSE OF YOU WHO WEREN'T HERE YOU WILL BE
AT
A DISADVANTAGE BECAUSE THE PEANUT MAY BE ON
THE
MIDTERM. SO, THOSE OF YOU WHO LOOK AT IT TODAY
WILL
HAVE A BIT OF AN ADVANTAGE. LAST TIME WHEN
WE ENDED
LECTURE I WAS TALKING TO YOU ABOUT THE ANGIOSPERM.
WE
SAID THAT THE ANGIOSPERMS TURNED OUT TO BE
SUCCESSFUL
GROUP AND INDEED OF MOST OF THE SEED PLANTS
ARE
ANGIOSPERMS. ABOUT 240 THOUSAND PLANTS ARE
ANGIOSPERMS. THE REASON THEY TURNED OUT TO
BE SUCH
A SUCCESSFUL GROUP IS REALLY FOR A NUMBER
OF REASONS.
FIRST OF ALL THEY DEVELOPED THE FRUIT TO PROTECT
THE
DEVELOPING EMBRYO. AND WE TALKED ABOUT THE
FLOWER
WHICH IS A WAY OF ATTRACTING A POLLINATOR,
AND IN FACT
THAT TAKES US TO REALLY ITS PART OF THE SECOND
AND
THIRD REASON OR ONE IN THE SAME IS WHICH THEY
DEVELOP
A MECHANISM FOR FACILITATED POLLINATION OR
FOR
FACILITATING THE TRANSFER OF POLLEN. THESE
ARE REALLY
IMPORTANT CHARACTERISTICS THAT THE ANGIOSPERMS
HAD AND
THAT IS WHAT MAKES THEM THE DOMINANT PLANTS
OF TODAY'S
EARTH.
TODAY, WHAT I WANT TO DO WITH TODAY'S LECTURE
WE
WILL BEGIN A SERIES OF TALKS OR LECTURES ON
THE GROWTH
AND DEVELOPMENT OF THE ANGIOSPERM PLANT BODY.
WE WILL TALK ABOUT, NOT TODAY, BUT EVENTUALLY
WE
WILL TALK ABOUT SOME OF THE BIOCHEMISTRY
AND
PHYSIOLOGY WHICH IS INVOLVED IN THE LIFE HISTORY
OF
THESE VERY INTERESTING ORGANISMS. NOW, IN
ORDER FOR
US TO STUDY AND UNDERSTAND BIOCHEMISTRY AND
PHYSIOLOGY
AND TO APPRECIATE IT, WE ALSO HAVE TO KNOW
SOMETHING
ABOUT THE STRUCTURE OF THE PLANT. WHERE DO
THESE
EVENTS OCCUR AND WHAT ARE THE TISSUES AND
CELL TYPES
IN WHICH THE EVENTS OCCUR? WE WILL BE SPENDING
TIME
IN THE NEXT LECTURE TALKING ABOUT THE CELL
AND TISSUE
TYPES AS SORT OF AN OPENING FOR THE PHYSIOLOGY
AND
BIOCHEMICAL EXPERIMENTS I WILL TELL YOU ABOUT.
WHENEVER WE TALK ABOUT GROWTH AND DEVELOPMENT
IN
PLANTS ONE OF THE POINTS WHICH UNDERLIES THE
DISCUSSION, AND YOU SHOULD KEEP THIS IN YOUR
MIND THAT
ONCE THE PLANT SENDS DOWN ITS ROOTS AND IT
PUTS ITSELF
IN A PARTICULAR SPOT IT IS THERE FOR THE REST
OF ITS
LIFE. IF THE WEATHER TURNS BAD OR WATER RUNS
LOW OR
IF A TREE GROWS OVER IT THAT PLANT CAN'T GET
UP AND
LEAVE AND GO SOMEPLACE ELSE WHERE THERE
ARE BETTER
CONDITIONS. IT CAN'T MOVE LIKE AN ANIMAL MOVES.
SO
PLANTS HAVE DEVELOPED MECHANISMS AND WE WILL
TALK
ABOUT MANY OF THEM TO HELP THEM SENSE CHANGES
IN THEIR
ENVIRONMENT AND RESPOND TO CHANGES IN THEIR
ENVIRONMENT. THIS IS REALLY GOING TO BE A
THEME IN
ONE OF OUR TALKS IS HOW DO PLANTS SENSE CHANGES
AND
HOW DO THEY RESPOND. REALIZE THAT A PLANT
IS
EVENTUALLY FIXED OR ROOTED OR TRAPPED WHEREVER
IT
HAPPENS TO PUT DOWN ITS ROOTS. LAST TIME WE
ENDED THE
DISCUSSION BY INTRODUCING YOU TO FERTILIZATION
IN THE
PLANT AND WE SAID FERTILIZATION IN ANGIOSPERM
RESULTED
IN TWO EVENTS. WE HAVE DOUBLE FERTILIZATION,
AND AS
A RESULT OF DOUBLE FERTILIZATION TWO DIFFERENT
TYPES
OF EVENTS OCCURRED. FIRST OF ALL, WE HAD THE
BEGINNING OF THE 2N EMBRYO. THEN, SECONDLY,
WE HAVE
THIS 3N OR TRIPLOID TISSUE WHICH I CALLED
ENDOSPERM.
WE WILL SPEND SOME TIME NOW TALKING ABOUT
BOTH
OF THESE TISSUES, BOTH OF THESE PRODUCTS
OF DOUBLE
FERTILIZATION AND RETURN TO ENDOSPERM IN A
MOMENT.
LET'S FIRST LOOK AT THE DEVELOPING EMBRYO
AND THEN WE
WILL LOOK AT THE ENDOSPERM.
IN ANGIOSPERMS WHAT WAS NOTICED WHEN PEOPLE
STARTED STUDYING THEM VERY CAREFULLY IS THAT
EMBRYO'S
TENDED TO FALL IN ONE OF TWO GROUPS.
IF YOU LOOKED AT THE MATURE EMBRYO I WILL
DO
A CARTOON HERE, I WILL POINT OUT THE PARTS
THAT ARE
IMPORTANT. IN ONE TYPE OF EMBRYO, THERE SEEMED
TO BE
TWO BUMPS.
AND THESE TWO BUMPS, BECAUSE THEY WERE
PRESENT IN THE EMBRYO, THEY ARE CALLED SEED
LEAVES,
BECAUSE THEY ARE PRESENT IN THE SEED. SEED
LEAVES.
OR THE TECHNICAL TERM THEY ARE CALLED COTYLEDONS.
AND
BECAUSE THEY HAVE TWO BUMPS OR TWO SEED LEAVES
THEY
ARE CALLED DICOTS. TWO COTYLEDONS, OR TWO
LEAVES AND
THE MORE CURRENT TERM NOW, RATHER THAN CALLING
THEM
DICOTS, YOUR BOOK REFERS TO THEM AS EUDICOTS.
BUT,
YOU WILL STILL FIND ME SLIPPING BACK TO
CALLING THEM
DICOTS. ONE TYPE OF EMBRYO THAT WE FIND WHEN
WE STUDY
THE MATURE SEEDS OF ANGIOSPERMS. THE SECOND
TYPE OF
EMBRYO WHICH WE FIND HAS, AS IT TURNS OUT,
ONE BUMP OR
ONE COTYLEDON. AND PLANTS HAVING THIS TYPE
OF EMBRYO
ARE KNOWN AS MONOCOTS. MONO MEANING ONE. IN
THE
ANGIOSPERMS YOU CAN DIVIDE THE GROUP OF PLANTS,
THOUSAND SPECIES, INTO ONE OF TWO SORT OF
SUBGROUPS,
BASED UPON WHAT THE EMBRYO LOOKS LIKE. NOW,
WHAT I
WANT TO SAY IS THAT IN SOME PLANTS, THESE
ARE
USUALLY EUDICOTS. USUALLY EUDICOTS, BUT NOT
ALWAYS.
THE EMBRYO ENLARGES AND ITS COTYLEDONS EVENTUALLY
FILL
THE SEED.
FILL THE SEED. SO, IF YOU COULD IMAGINE SEED
WHICH IS DEVELOPING WHICH HAD ENDOSPERM HERE,
AND
A SMALL EMBRYO HERE. YOU WAITED FOR SOME TIME
IN THIS
EXAMPLE THAT I HAVE GIVEN YOU, WHAT YOU WOULD
HAVE IS
MOST OF THE SEED WOULD BE FILLED WITH THE
EMBRYO.
THERE WOULD BE VERY LITTLE ENDOSPERM PRESENT.
AND
THIS TENDS TO OCCUR IN THE EUDICOTS. IN THE
MONOCOTS,
IN GENERAL, THE EMBRYO REMAINS SMALL IN THE
MONOCOTS.
MOST OF THE SEED IS FILLED WITH ENDOSPERM.
BUT WHAT I WANT TO SAY NOW, AND WE WILL EXPLORE
THIS STATEMENT IN A FEW MINUTES, THAT BOTH
COTYLEDONS
AND ENDOSPERM PROVIDE NUTRIENTS FOR THE DEVELOPING
SEEDLING. WE WILL EXPLORE THIS STATEMENT A
LITTLE
MORE VERY SHORTLY.
NOW, LET'S LOOK AT THE EMBRYO AXIS WITH THE
COTYLEDONS ATTACHED. AGAIN, WE HAVE TWO TYPES
OF
AXIS. IN THE FIRST TYPE, WE HAVE THE EUDICOT
WITH THE
TWO COTYLEDONS. THIS IS THE EMBRYO AXIS.
HERE IS THE EUDICOT. TWO COTYLEDON ATTACHED.
WE TEND TO GIVE THE NAME TO THE REGION ABOVE
THE
COTYLEDONS AND THE REGION BELOW. AND THE REASON
I
WANT TO GIVE YOU THIS TERMINOLOGY IS, YOU
WILL SEE IT
IN THE LAB AND IT WILL BE IMPORTANT WHEN WE
TALK ABOUT
HOW THIS SEED GERMINATES, THE REGION ABOVE
THE
COTYLEDONS IS CALLED EPI, FOR BEING ABOVE,
EPICOTYL, EPICOTYL. THE REGION ABOVE WHERE
THE
COTYLEDONS ARE ATTACHED TO THE AXIS. AND THE
REGION
BELOW, HYPO, MEANING BELOW COTYL. THE REGION
BELOW THE
AXIS. IF WE LOOK AT A MONOCOT, WHICH HAS ONLY
ONE
COTYLEDON, WE WOULD HAVE THE SINGLE COTYLEDON
AND WE
WOULD HAVE EXACTLY THOSE SAME REGIONS, THE
EPI AND THE
HYPO. NOW, THIS NEXT COUPLE OF MINUTES, WHAT
I AM
GOING TO TELL YOU, IS PROBABLY THE MOST IMPORTANT
POINT OR THE HARDEST POINT OF TODAY'S LECTURE,
BECAUSE
WE WILL BE REFERRING BACK TO IT AS WE GO FURTHER
INTO
THE CLASS. I WILL WRITE THIS DOWN FOR YOU.
AT EITHER
OF END OF THE AXIS ARE ZONES OF HIGH CELL
DIVISION
ACTIVITY.
WE CALL THESE ZONES OF HIGH CELL DIVISION
ACTIVITY, MERISTEMS.
SO, AT THIS END HERE WE HAVE A MERISTEM, BECAUSE
IT IS AT THE TOP, IT IS THE SHOOT MERISTEM.
AT THIS END HERE WE ALSO HAVE A MERISTEM.
BECAUSE IT IS AT THE BOTTOM, WE CALL IT THE
ROOT
MERISTEM.
NOW, WHY ARE THESE ZONES SO IMPORTANT?
THROUGH THEIR ACTIVITY,
NEW CELLS ARE PRODUCED
IN THE AXIS.
ARE PRODUCED.
NEW CELLS PRODUCED. SO WE HAVE THESE ZONES
OF
HIGH CELL DIVISION ACTIVITY. THE SHOOT MERISTEM
AND
THE ROOT MERISTEM. THEY DIVIDE AND WHAT I
AM SAYING
IS THROUGH THOSE DIVISION ACTIVITIES WE PRODUCE
MANY
NEW CELLS.
IF A CELL OR TISSUE, THIS IS THE HARD PART.
CELL OR TISSUE CAN BE TRACED BACK IN ITS ORIGIN,
TO
THE MERISTEM, THAT IS, IF A CELL OR TISSUE
ORIGINATED
AT A MERISTEM WE CALL THIS CELL OR TISSUE,
PRIMARY.
CALL IT PRIMARY. WE HAVE THE FIRST CATEGORY
OF CELL
TYPES I WANT TO INTRODUCE YOU TO OR TISSUE
TYPES,
WHICH WE CALL PRIMARY. WE CALL THEM PRIMARY,
BECAUSE
THEIR ORIGIN IS AS A RESULT OF CELL DIVISION
OR
MEITOTIC ACTIVITY AT EITHER THE ROOT MERISTEM
OR SHOOT
MERISTEM. THIS IS IMPORTANT POINT AND I WANT
YOU TO
MAKE SURE YOU ALL UNDERSTAND THIS. OKAY, NOW,
WHAT I
WANT TO DO IS TO EXPLORE THE SECOND TISSUE,
WHICH WAS
IN THE EMBRYO, NAMELY THE ENDOSPERM.
WE SAID THE ENDOSPERM IS 3N OR TRIPLOID. ALL
OF
YOU, MAYBE THERE IS A RARE EXCEPTION HERE
IN THIS
ROOM, BUT ALL OF YOU HAVE INTIMATE EXPERIENCE
IN YOUR
LIVES WITH ENDOSPERM. WHENEVER YOU EAT CORN
AND YOU
BITE INTO A EAR OF CORN WHICH MAY COME FROM,
NOT FROM
SAFEWAY, BUT MIGHT COME FROM, LET'S SAY ANDRONICO'S
OR
BERKELEY BOWL OR MONTEREY MARKET. WHEN YOU
BITE INTO
A CORN KERNEL AND YOU HAVE LIQUID WHICH SQUIRTS
ON TO
YOUR FACE WHEN YOU BITE INTO A CORN KERNEL,
THAT
LIQUID, WHICH IS SQUIRTING ON TO YOUR FACE,
IS LIQUID
ENDOSPERM. THAT MATERIAL IS NUTRIENT MATERIAL
THAT WE
LIKE WHICH IS SWEET AND PROVIDES THE NUTRITION
FOR THE
DEVELOPING SEEDLING HERE. NOW, WHEN THIS
EAR OF CORN
IS PRODUCED ON THE CORN PLANT AND IT IS FIRST
PRODUCED, THE LIQUID ENDOSPERM IS SWEET. LET'S
ASSUME
THIS EAR FALLS TO THE GROUND AND FOR SOME
REASON IT
WASN'T HARVESTED JUST LAID ON THE GROUND.
WHAT
NORMALLY HAPPENS IN NATURE IS THIS EAR FALLS
TO THE
GROUND, IF IT IS NOT PICKED OR EATEN BY AN
ANIMAL, THE
LIQUID ENDOSPERM TURNS TO STARCH. THIS IS
WHAT
HAPPENS IN SAFEWAY WHEN THEY LET IT SIT ON
THE SHELF
WITHOUT BEING REFRIGERATED. THE LIQUID ENDOSPERM
TURNS TO STARCH AND LOSES SWEETNESS. IN NATURE,
THE
EAR REMAINS ON THE GROUND IN A STATE OF STARCHINESS
THROUGHOUT THE WINTER, AND THEN WHEN SPRING
COMES THAT
STARCH IS CONVERTED BACK TO SUGAR AGAIN. AND
IS USED
BY THE DEVELOPING SEEDLING. MY QUESTION TO
YOU,
ANOTHER QUESTION WHICH I WANT TO ADDRESS IS
WHY GO
THROUGH THE PROCESS OF SUGAR TO STARCH TO
SUGAR WHICH
IS A BIO-CHEMICALLY, VERY EXPENSIVE PROCESS
WHERE IT
INVOLVES QUITE A BIT OF ENERGY, IF YOU ARE
STARTING
WITH SUGAR AND ENDING WITH SUGAR. WHY GO THROUGH
THIS
MIDDLE PHASE OF STARCH. QUESTION THAT I WOULD
LIKE
YOU TO THINK ABOUT. ANOTHER EXAMPLE OF LIQUID
ENDOSPERM THAT MANY OF YOU ESPECIALLY THOSE
OF YOU
FROM EAST ASIAN CULTURES ARE FAMILIAR WITH
IS COCONUT
MILK. I DON'T KNOW IF YOU CAN HEAR. THIS IS
COCONUT
MILK YOU CAN BUY IN THE STORE. COCONUT MILK
IS LIQUID
ENDOSPERM. THIS IS MATERIAL WHICH THE COCONUT
PLANT
DEVELOPS AND PUTS ASIDE FOR THE NOURISHMENT
OF THE
YOUNG COCONUT SEEDLING, UNTIL IT GETS ESTABLISHED
AND
CAN PHOTOSYNTHESIZE. IT IS A VERY RICH COMPOUND,
VERY
RICH IN COMPOUNDS AND NEVER HAS BEEN FULLY
ANALYZED
BUT AS YOU MIGHT GUESS IT CONTAINS EVERYTHING,
INCLUDING AMINO ACIDS THAT THE YOUNG SEEDLING
NEEDS TO
GET GOING. SO, IF WE TOOK A YOUNG COCONUT,
WHICH I
HAVE SOME EXAMPLES HERE, IF I MADE A CUT DOWN
THE
MIDDLE OF THE COCONUT WHAT WE WOULD SEE IS
FOLLOWING? HERE IS A COCONUT CUT DOWN THE
MIDDLE.
AT ONE END OF THE COCONUT IS THE EMBRYO. ONE
END OF
THE COCONUT IS THE EMBRYO. THE REST OF THE
COCONUT IS
THE ENDOSPERM. IT IS LIQUID ENDOSPERM. NOW
AS THIS
EMBRYO MATURES AND STARTING TO GROW, WHAT
YOU FIND
HAPPENING AND WHAT MOST OF YOU ARE EXPERIENCED
WITH IS
THAT THERE IS WHITE TISSUE, WHICH IS WHAT
YOU EAT WHEN
YOU HAVE COCONUT. THIS WHITE TISSUE ALONG
THE OUTSIDE
OR THE PERIMETER OF THE COCONUT. THIS WHITE
TISSUE IS
CELLULARIZED ENDOSPERM. THAT IS, EACH OF THESE
3N
NUCLEI, OF WHICH THERE ARE MILLIONS, MILLIONS
OF THEM,
HAVE NOW BEGUN TO PARTITION INTO INDIVIDUAL
CELLS SO
THAT IF YOU CUT THROUGH A MATURE COCONUT WHICH
IS JUST
STARTING TO GERMINATE THERE WOULD NO LONGER
BE LIQUID
ALL OF THE ENDOSPERM WOULD BE CELLULARIZED.
I HAVE
HERE A COCONUT WHICH HAS BEEN CUT DOWN THE
MIDDLE,
THIS COCONUT HAS BEEN CUT DOWN THE MIDDLE
WE JUST
DON'T HAVE THE COCONUT, WE HAVE THE FRUIT.
YOU ARE
LOOKING AT A SEED AND PART OF THE FRUIT
WALL. THIS IS
THE OTHER PART OF THE FRUIT WALL, WHICH WE
HAVE OVER
HERE. THIS FRUIT WALL HAS A SPECIAL PURPOSE,
BUT FOR
OUR TALK RIGHT NOW IT PROTECTS THE EMBRYO.
IF WE OPEN
THE SPECIAL COCONUT UP, LIKE SO, YOU CAN SEE
THE
FIBROUS NATURE OF THE FRUIT WALL AND HERE
YOU CAN SEE
THE ENDOSPERM, WHICH I HAVE TAKEN OUT OVER
HERE AND
PART OF THE SEED COAT IS THIS BROWN MATERIAL
ON THE
OUTSIDE. NOW, AT ONE END OF THE COCONUT WOULD
HAVE
BEEN THE EMBRYO, AND IF YOU LOOK AT COCONUTS,
I HOPE
THAT YOU WILL NEVER LOOK AT THEM THE SAME
WAY WHEN YOU
GO TO THE STORE, IF YOU LOOK AT A COCONUT,
THERE ARE
STRUCTURES ON THE BOTTOM, WHICH ARE KNOWN
COLLOQUIALLY
AS EYES. IF YOU LOOK CAREFULLY AT THESE EYES,
YOU
WILL SEE ONE OF THEM IS BIGGER, BIGGER QUADRANT,
WHICH
OCCUPIES THE COCONUT. THIS COCONUT ORIGINALLY
HAD 3
EMBRYOS THAT WERE FERTILIZED. IT DECIDES AS
SOME
POINT IN ITS DEVELOPMENT WHEN ALL OF THE EMBRYOS
ARE
SAFE AND SECURE TO ABORT TWO AND CONTINUE
TO GROW ONE
OF THOSE EMBRYOS. THAT EMBRYO IS FOUND UNDER
THE
LARGER QUADRANT, LARGEST QUADRANT. WHAT WE
ARE GOING
TO DO NOW, IS WE ARE GOING TO OPEN THIS COCONUT
UP AND
AS I TOLD SOME OF YOU WHOSE LAB I VISITED
YESTERDAY,
IF YOU SIT IN THE FRONT ROW MAKE SURE YOU
BRING
UMBRELLA OR WEAR YOUR RAINCOAT. SO, ARE WE
ALL SET
HERE. YOU GUYS ALL SET?
ALL RIGHT. WELL ACTUALLY, I ALREADY HAVE ONE
CRACKED. LET ME SHOW YOU THIS NOW.
PEOPLE THAT SAID, WE ARE NOT SITTING IN THE
FRONT HERE. HERE IS A COCONUT THAT I CRACKED
AND
OPENED UP. IF YOU LOOK CAREFULLY AT THIS COCONUT,
AGAIN WE HAVE THIS FIBROUS MATERIAL AROUND
THE
OUTSIDE, WHICH IS PART FRUIT WALL AND PART
SEED COAT
WHICH HAVE JOINED TOGETHER. IF WE OPEN IT
UP, I HAVE
TAKEN THE LIQUID ENDOSPERM OUT YOU CAN SEE
SOME OF THE
CELLULARIZED ENDOSPERM, THE WHITE TISSUE WHICH
WE EAT
WHICH IS VERY NUTRITIOUS AND NUTRITIOUS
FOR THE
REASONS I MENTIONED BEFORE. THE EYES WOULD
HAVE BEEN
AT THIS END OVER HERE AND I WILL SHOW YOU
A PICTURE OF
THIS IN A MOMENT, BUT IF YOU WANT TO COME
UP AFTER THE
END OF THE LECTURE YOU CAN SEE ONE OF THE
COCONUT
EMBRYOS, THE COCONUT EMBRYO THAT I TOOK OUT
FROM THIS
COCONUT WHEN I OPENED IT UP. IF YOU ARE EVER
AT
A BORING PARTY AND THEY ARE SERVING COCONUTS
AND YOU
WANT TO BECOME THE CENTER, GET A HAMMER AND
DISSECT
OUT THE EMBRYO. AND I PROMISE YOU, NO ONE
THE LOOK AT
YOU THE SAME WAY. I AM NOT SURE HOW THEY WILL
LOOK AT
YOU.
ALL RIGHT LET'S TALK ABOUT THE OTHER FORM
OF
MATERIAL, WHICH IS STORED INSIDE THE COCONUT
BEFORE I
SHOW YOU SOME SLIDES. THAT OTHER FORM OF MATERIAL
IS
STORED IN THE COTYLEDON OF THE EUDICOT. MOST
OF YOU
ARE USING MATERIALS OF THE EUDICOT EVERY DAY,
MATERIALS THAT ARE STORED IN THE COTYLEDONS.
WHEN WE
EAT PEANUTS, WHEN YOU EAT BEANS, WHEN YOU
EAT PEAS YOU
ARE ESSENTIALLY GAINING YOUR NUTRITION FROM
MATERIALS
THAT ARE STORED IN THE COTYLEDONS, IN THE
SEED LEAVES.
THOSE MATERIALS WOULD NORMALLY BE USED FOR
ESTABLISHING THE SEEDLING. SO, WHEN YOU OPEN
UP
A WALNUT AND TAKE OUT WHAT THIS CRINKLED STRUCTURE
IS
HERE YOU ARE ACTUALLY LOOKING AT A COTYLEDON,
AND THAT
COTYLEDON IS FULL OF OILS AND STARCHES AND
SUGARS AND
IT SERVES THE FUNCTION OF PROVIDING NUTRITION
TO THE
DEVELOPING EMBRYO. NOW I HAVE GIVEN OR ASKED
YOU ALL
TAKE OUT A PEANUT. I WOULD LIKE YOU TO TAKE
OUT THAT
PEANUT NOW. BUT DON'T OPEN IT YET. WHEN YOU
DO OPEN
IT, IF YOU CAN PUT YOUR SHELLS, GIVEN THE
CUT IN THE
BUDGET, THE SHELL WILL PROBABLY BE ON THE
FLOOR NEXT
YEAR, PUT IT IN YOUR POCKET DON'T THROW IT
ON THE
FLOOR. LOOK AT THE OUTSIDE OF THE SHELL. WHAT
IS
THIS MATERIAL ON THE OUTSIDE OF THE MATERIAL?
I SAID
THE SEEDS ARE ON THE INSIDE. WHAT WOULD IT
BE, MAKE
A GUESS. NOT THE SEED COAT. FURTHER OUT?
WHAT IS IT? IT IS THE FRUIT WALL. OKAY. SO
IN THIS CASE THINK OF THE APPLE. THE FRUIT
WAS SOFT
AND SWEET, BUT THE EMBRYO WAS STILL PROTECTED.
IN
THIS EXAMPLE, THE FRUIT WALL HAS BECOME HARD,
YET IT
IS STILL PROTECTS THE DEVELOPING EMBRYO ON
THE INSIDE.
IT IS NOT SOFT. IT IS NOT MEANT TO BE EATEN
BY
SOME ANIMAL FOR DISPERSAL. NOW I WOULD LIKE
YOU TO DO
IS OPEN THE PEANUT UP AND WHAT YOU WILL NOTICE,
THE
FIRST THING WHEN YOU ENCOUNTER, WHAT ARE THE
PEANUTS
THEY ARE SURROUNDED BY A BROWN PAPERY COATING.
WHAT
IS THAT BROWN PAPERY COATING? ANYBODY KNOW
WHAT THE
BROWN PAPERY COATING IS? YOU SAID IT BEFORE.
IT IS
THE SEED COAT. CORRECT. NOW, WHAT I WOULD
LIKE YOU
TO DO IS TAKE ONE OF THE PEANUTS AND CAREFULLY
SPLIT
IT IN HALF. WHAT YOU ARE SPLITTING IN HALF
YOU WIND
UP WITH TWO, LOOKS LIKE TORPEDO-SHAPED HALVES.
EACH OF
THOSE IS A COTYLEDON. AND AT THE BASE OF ONE
OF THEM
YOU WILL SEE THE NEW EMBRYONIC SHOOT AXIS.
SO, IN
THIS PARTICULAR CASE THE COTYLEDONS HAVE EXPANDED
TO
FILL THE SEED AND TO ABSORB ALL OF THE ENDOSPERM
AND
THEY PROVIDE THE NUTRITION FOR THE DEVELOPMENT
OF THE
YOUNG EMBRYO AXIS. LET'S LOOK AT A FEW PICTURES
OF
THE COCONUT.
OKAY, FIRST SLIDE IS OF A COCONUT HERE YOU
CAN
SEE THE 3 DIFFERENT EYES OF THE COCONUT. THIS
THE
LARGEST EYE. IT OCCUPIES THE LARGEST QUADRANT.
UNDER
THIS EYE IS THE DEVELOPING EMBRYO. EMBRYOS
WHICH ARE
PRESENT UNDER THESE TWO EYES HAVE ABORTED.
NOW, IF WE
TAKE THE HAMMER AND WE CRACK IT AND THE BEST
PLACE TO
HIT IT IS RIGHT WHERE THE 3 SUTURES, THE 3
ENDS MEET.
WE TAKE THE HAMMER WE CRACK IT AND WE CAN
GET OUT THE
EMBRYO. THIS IS A CENTIMETER SCALE HERE. AND
HERE YOU
CAN SEE THE EMBRYO. THIS WOULD BE THE SHOOT
END AND
AT THIS END OVER HERE WOULD BE WHERE THE COTYLEDON
IS
LOCATED. IF WE LET THAT COTYLEDON ENLARGE,
AS YOU
WOULD SEE IN THIS SLIDE HERE, THE EMBRYO
WOULD BE
LOCATED HERE AND AS IT ENLARGED ITS COTYLEDON
WOULD
GROW INTO THE LIQUID ENDOSPERM AND GRADUALLY
ABSORB
THE MATERIALS, WHICH WOULD THEN BE USED TO
HELP THIS
COCONUT BECOME ESTABLISHED, AS FAR AS ITS
DEVELOPMENT
IS CONCERNED. THIS IS THE COCONUT AND I ENCOURAGE
YOU
TO SPEND TIME EITHER LOOKING AT THE EMBRYO
HERE OR WE
WILL PUT THE COCONUT IN THE CLASSROOM, HAVE
A LOOK AT
IT OR WHEN YOU NEXT GO TO THE SUPERMARKET
YOU MAY TAKE
A LOOK AT IT. WE SAID THAT ANGIOSPERM'S WERE
SUCCESSFUL BECAUSE THEY DEVELOPED THIS FACILITATED
POLLINATION AND DEVELOPED THE FRUIT OR AS
YOU SAW THE
FRUIT WALL, OR IN THIS CASE, IT BECAME HARD.
THERE WAS ANOTHER REASON WHY THEY WERE
SUCCESSFUL, AND I WANT TO TALK BRIEFLY ABOUT
THAT
OTHER REASON BECAUSE IT IS IMPORTANT AND THERE
ARE
ALSO SOME INTERESTING STORIES ASSOCIATED WITH
IT.
THEY WERE SUCCESSFUL, IN ADDITION TO THE FIRST
TWO
REASONS THAT I PUT ON THE BOARD BECAUSE,
THEY ALSO
DEVELOPED MEANS OR DIFFERENT MECHANISMS FOR
SEED AND
FRUIT DISPERSAL. SO, MECHANISMS FOR SEED AND
FRUIT
DISPERSAL.
THESE ARE ONE OF THE ADDITIONAL REASONS WHY
THE
ANGIOSPERMS HAVE BECOME SO SUCCESSFUL. SOME
OF THESE
MEANS ARE PASSIVE. I MEAN PASSIVE IS THAT
THERE IS NO
OTHER ORGANISM INVOLVED.
YOU ARE ALL FAMILIAR WITH SOME OF THESE PASSIVE
MEANS. FOR EXAMPLE, DANDELIONS, IF YOU EVER
LOOK AT A
DANDELION IT MAKES A PARACHUTE-LIKE DEVICE,
WHICH
ALLOWS THE SEED OR THE FRUIT TO BE PICKED
UP BY THE
WIND. WIND IS A BIG DISPERSER OF SEEDS, ESPECIALLY
SEEDS THAT ARE SMALL AND LIGHT. FOR THOSE
OF YOU WHO
MIGHT COME FROM THE MIDWEST OR SOUTHWEST WHERE
YOU
HAVE EVER SEEN TUMBLE WEEDS BLOWING ACROSS
THE
HIGHWAY. A TUMBLE WEED IS A PLANT WHICH HAS
A
CONNECTION TO ITS ROOT SYSTEM AND AT SOME
POINT WHEN
THE SEEDS ARE MATURE, THE ROOT SYSTEM IN
THE SHOOT
SYSTEM ARE SEVERED FROM EACH OTHER AND THE
SHOOT
SYSTEM BECOMES MOBILE. SO, WHEN IT IS WINDY,
THE
WHOLE PLANT TUMBLES AND AS IT TUMBLES IT DISPERSES
SEEDS THROUGHOUT ITS ENVIRONMENT AND CAN TRAVEL
AND
DISPERSE SEEDS OVER GREAT DISTANCES.
ANOTHER EXAMPLE OF PASSIVE MEANS OF SEED AND
FRUIT DISPERSAL IS SHOWN HERE BY THIS COCONUT
PLANT.
HERE IS A PLANT, WHICH IS DISPERSED BY WATER.
THIS
HARD, FIBROUS FRUIT WALL ON THE OUTSIDE MAKES
THE SEED
BUOYANT AND ALSO MAKES IT RESISTANT TO SALT
WATER AND
ALLOWS THE WATER TO TRANSPORT COCONUTS OVER
GREAT
DISTANCES AND ALLOWS THE PLANTS TO BECOME
ESTABLISHED,
ON, AS YOU KNOW PICTURES OF TROPICAL ISLANDS,
VERY
DISTANT FROM WHERE THE ORIGINAL COCONUT STARTED.
THIS
DISPERSAL BY WATER IS ALSO USED BY A LOT OF
OTHER
PLANTS ON THE LAND. FOR EXAMPLE, YOU CAN IMAGINE
STREAMS OR RAIN WATER DISPERSING LARGE AMOUNTS
OF SEED
MATERIAL. NOW, WHAT I WOULD LIKE TO TALK
TO YOU ABOUT
ARE MORE ACTIVE MEANS OF DISPERSAL.
IT IS ACTIVE IS SORT OF A -- NOT QUITE THE
WORD,
BUT I CAN'T THINK OF A BETTER ONE. ALL OF
YOU ARE
FAMILIAR WITH THIS MEANS, WHICH IS ACTIVE,
AND I
SUSPECT ALL OF YOU HAVE UNWITTINGLY DONE THIS.
WHEN
YOU WALK THROUGH A WEEDY AREA OR FOREST AND
LOOK AT
THE CUFFS OF YOUR PANTS OR SOCKS YOU HAVE
THINGS STUCK
ON TO THEM. THOSE THINGS ARE EITHER SEEDS
OR FRUITS
WHICH HAVE HAD THEIR OUTER WALLS MODIFIED
WITH HOOKS
TO STICK ON TO YOUR CLOTHES. THIS WAS SUCH
AN
INTERESTING TOPIC TO A FELLOW AS TO HOW THESE
SEEDS
STUCK ON TO HIS CLOTHES HE LOOKED AT THEM
UNDER THE
MICROSCOPE AND HE FOUND THAT HE COULD REPEATEDLY
TAKE
THE SEED ON AND OFF, ON AND OFF, AND THE HOOK
WAS NOT
DAMAGED. THIS IS THE BASIS OF THE DISCOVERY
OF
VELCRO. THIS IS HOW VELCRO WAS DISCOVERED,
BY TRYING
TO UNDERSTAND HOW THIS PARTICULAR SEED OR
FRUIT COULD
REPEATEDLY BE PULLED ON AND OFF AND NOT
WEAR OUT. SO,
THAT IS A MEANS OF ACTIVE DISPERSAL. ANOTHER
MEANS OF
ACTIVE DISPERSAL IS ILLUSTRATED BY THE APPLE,
WHICH WE
TALKED ABOUT LAST TIME. THE APPLE IS A SWEET
FRUIT.
IT HAS AN ODOR TO IT. ANIMALS WANT TO EAT
THE FRUIT.
MANY PLANTS MAKE FRUITS THAT HAVE A GOOD TASTE
HOPING
THAT AN ANIMAL WILL EAT THEM AND DISPERSE
THE FRUIT TO
AN AREA WHERE THERE IS NONE OF THE PLANT GROWING.
NOW, IN THIS PARTICULAR CASE, WHEN THE ANIMAL
EAT THE
FRUIT, THE SEEDS GO INTO THE ANIMAL'S STOMACH
AND THE
ANIMAL HAS STOMACH ACID AND CAN'T DIGEST THE
SEEDS,
SEEDS AND THE ORGANISM, WHICH DISPERSE THEM,
BUT
MOSTLY THE PLANTS. HAVE HAD TO DEVELOP KIND
OF AN
UNDERSTANDING OF WHAT KIND OF ANIMAL WILL
DISPERSE
THEM. HOW LONG IS THE SEED GOING TO REMAIN
IN THE
ANIMALS STOMACH. HOW THICK SHOULD THE SEED
COAT BE SO
THAT THE SEED IS NOT TOTALLY DIGESTED BY THE
TIME THE
ANIMAL DEFECATES. SO, WHAT YOU FIND IS THAT
SOMETIMES
WHEN AN ANIMAL, WHICH IS THE WRONG KIND
OF ANIMAL THAT
EATS THE FRUIT, THE SEED NEVER GETS OUT. IT
IS
DIGESTED. THE RIGHT KIND OF ANIMAL IN AN AREA
WHICH
EATS THE FRUIT WILL PASS THE SEED THROUGH
ITS BODY.
BUT NOT ONLY IS THE SEED COAT DIGESTED JUST
TO THE
POINT WHERE THE SEED IS STILL ALIVE BUT MANY
PLANT
DEPENDS ON THE ANIMALS TO DIGEST THE SEED
COATS TO
WEAKEN THEM. SO, THAT BY THE TIME THE ANIMAL
DEFECATES AND THE SEED IS RELEASED TO THE
OUTSIDE THE
SEED COAT IS WEAKENED TO THE STATE WHERE THE
SEED CAN
GERMINATE RIGHT AWAY. SO, THERE IS THIS PARTICULAR
RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN THE SEED AND THE ANIMAL
THAT
DISPERSES IT AND SOMETIMES IF THAT ANIMAL
DISAPPEARS
THE SEED DISPERSAL WILL NOT OCCUR AT ALL OR
NOT IN
A VERY PRODUCTIVE WAY. FINALLY, THE LAST WAY
I WANT
TO TALK TO YOU ABOUT FACILITATED SEED AND
FRUIT
DISPERSION BY ANIMALS OCCURS WITH INSECTS.
INSECT I WANT TO TALK TO YOU MOSTLY ARE ANTS.
MANY SEEDS, AS IT TURNS OUT, WHICH ARE
ATTRACTIVE TO ANTS, HERE WE HAVE THE SEED.
THESE
PLANTS, WHICH PRODUCE THESE SEEDS THAT ARE
DISPERSED
BY ANTS ALSO PRODUCE A NEW TISSUE.
WE DON'T HAVE TO WORRY ABOUT THE NAME. A NEW
TISSUE WHICH IS OFTEN BUT NOT ALWAYS WHITE.
WHITE IS
ATTRACTIVE TO ANTS. OFTEN BUT NOT ALWAYS WHITE.
AND
THIS NEW TISSUE, THE ANTS FIND THEY CAN'T
RESIST IT.
WHAT THEY DO IS, THEY GO OUT, THE ANTS GO
OUT AND THEY
HARVEST SEEDS WHICH HAVE PRODUCED THIS NEW
TISSUE,
WHITE TISSUE, AND THEY CARRY THE SEEDS BACK
TO THEIR
BURROWS OR WHEREVER THEY HAPPEN TO BE LIVING.
THERE
IN THE BURROW, THEY CONSUME THE WHITE TISSUE
AND GET
THEIR REWARD FOR HAVING COLLECTED IT AND THEN
THEY
ABANDON THE SEED. AND, HERE WE NOW HAVE ESSENTIALLY
SEEDS PLANTED IN THE GROUND BY THE ANTS AND
DEPENDING
ON HOW DEEP THE SEED IS IN THE GROUND AND
UPON WHETHER THE GROUND IS DISTURBED, DEPENDING
UPON
WHETHER IT RAINS THOSE SEEDS WILL GERMINATE.
IT HAS
BEEN ESTIMATED IN AREAS LIKE NEW ENGLAND,
THAT A VERY
HIGH PERCENT 30 OR 40 PERCENT OF WILD SEEDS
MAY
ACTUALLY BE DISPERSED OR PLANTED BY ANTS.
NOW I WOULD
LIKE TO SHOW YOU, UH OH, SOMETHING HAS HAPPENED
HERE.
LET'S SEE IF WE CAN DO THIS AGAIN. IF NOT,
WE HAVE
ALWAYS THE BIG GUYS IN THE BACK THERE. HERE
WE GO,
LET'S LOOK AT THE NEXT SLIDES, EVERYTHING
LOOKS LIKE
IT IS OKAY. FOR SOME STRANGE REASON. THE FIRST
EXAMPLE OF A SEED THAT I WANT TO SHOW YOU,
DISPERSAL
IS ONE THAT GROWS OUTSIDE HERE THAT MANY OF
YOU MAY
HAVE SEEN AND PASSED. AND I ENCOURAGE YOU
TO STOP AND
LOOK AT THESE. THERE ARE SOME OF THESE GROWING
UP
NEAR EVANS HALL, FOR SURE. THIS IS CALLED
IMPATIENCE,
THIS PARTICULAR PLANT. HERE IS THE FLOWER
AND HERE IS
THE FRUIT OF THE IMPATIENCE. THIS PARTICULAR
FRUIT OF
THE IMPATIENCE, AND WE WILL LOOK AT IT IN
A HIGHER
POWER HERE, THIS PARTICULAR FRUIT IS UNDER
TENSION.
IT IS LIKE A SPRING WHICH IS READY TO POP.
INSIDE
THIS FRUIT ARE THE SEEDS. AND WHEN AN ANIMAL
COMES BY
OR IN YOUR CASE YOU COME BY AND BRUSH NEXT
TO THIS
SEED CAPSULE YOU CAUSE IT TO EXPLODE. AND
WHEN IT
EXPLODES, THE TENSION IS RELEASED AND THE
SEEDS ARE
CAST GREAT DISTANCES. IF IT IS AN ANIMAL THEY
ARE
CAST INTO THE ANIMALS FUR. THEN THE ANIMAL
WALKS AWAY,
PRESUMABLY THE SEED IS THEN DROPPED OFF AT
A NEW AREA.
THIS IS AN INTERESTING EXAMPLE OF TOUCH AND
IT WOULD
BE FACILITATED IN THE SENSE THAT IT IS ACTIVE.
HERE
IS ANOTHER EXAMPLE OF SEED DISPERSAL, THIS
IS PLANT
CALLED SALVIA, WHICH IS A PLANT THAT GROWS
HERE IN
CALIFORNIA. HERE, ALL YOU HAVE TO DO IS TOUCH
THE
CAPSULE AND THAT RELEASES THIS SPRING TENSION
AND THE
SEED GETS PROPELLED FORWARD. EXAMPLE OF WIND
DISPERSAL, THIS IS MILK WEED, LIKE WE TALKED
ABOUT
WITH DANDELIONS IN WHICH THE SEEDS PRODUCE
THIS TUFT
OF SOFT MATERIAL THAT MAKES THE SEED LIGHT
AND EASILY
TRANSPORTED BY THE WIND. FOR THOSE OF YOU
WHO ARE
COOKS, THESE PARTICULAR SEEDS, THIS IS NUTMEG,
AND
THIS IS MACE. THIS IS THE MATERIAL THAT IS
USED AS A
SPICE. IN THIS PARTICULAR CASE WHAT THIS SEED
HAS
DONE OR PLANT HAS DONE IS PRODUCE THIS STRUCTURE
WHICH
WE CALL MACE ON THE OUTSIDE OF THE SEED COVERING
THE
SEED WHICH MADE IT ATTRACTIVE TO WHATEVER
ANIMAL WAS
DISPERSING THIS SEED. THIS IS A RELATIVELY
LARGE
SEED. SO, PERHAPS THE ANIMAL PUT THE WHOLE
SEED ITS
BODY OR TOOK THE WHOLE SEED WITH IT AND THEN
CONSUMED
IT GRADUALLY BECAUSE THE MACE, THE ANIMAL
FOUND VERY
ATTRACTIVE. HERE IS AN EXAMPLE OF A SEED NOW
OR A
PLANT. THIS IS A MEMBER OF THE PEA FAMILY
IN WHICH THE
PLANT HAS MADE SORT OF THE IS CONTRASTING
TYPE OF
SITUATION WHERE THERE IS SHOWY RED BASE AND
BLACK
SEEDS, PRESUMABLY TO ATTRACT WHATEVER ANIMAL
IS
INVOLVED. HERE IS ANOTHER ONE WHERE WE HAVE
CONTRAST
BETWEEN THE BACKGROUND AND THE SEED TO AGAIN,
ATTRACT
SOME ANIMAL. HERE IS A SEED OF A TYPE OF
PALM. IT IS
ULTRAMARINE IN COLOR. A VERY UNUSUAL COLOR
IN THE
PLANT KINGDOM. ONE HAS TO PRESUME, ALTHOUGH
I DON'T
KNOW WHAT IT IS, THAT WHATEVER WAS USED TO
DISPERSE
THE SEED MUST KEY IN ON THIS PARTICULAR COLOR.
THIS
IS A VERY SUCCESSFUL ONE. THE LAST ONE I WANT
TO SHOW
YOU LOOKS LIKE EYES BUT THEY ARE NOT. THESE
ARE SEEDS
WHICH ARE DISPERSED BY ANIMALS, BY INSECTS,
LARGE ANTS
IN THE TROPICS. AND ON THE OUTSIDE YOU CAN
SEE THE
FRUIT WALL WHICH IS RED AND THIS WHITE MATERIAL
IS
THIS NEW LAYER OF TISSUE FORMED WHICH IS ATTRACTIVE
TO
INSECTS MOSTLY TO ANTS AND YOU CAN SEE THE
BLACK SEED
INSIDE WHICH IS USED BY THE PLANT TO GROW
ONCE IT IS
BURIED IN THE GROUND BY THE ANT. THESE ARE
EXAMPLES
OF SEEDS OF VARIOUS TYPES OF PLANTS AND OF
DISPERSAL
MECHANISM. OKAY. LET'S CONTINUE NOW AND WE
WILL LOOK
AT THE SLIDES IN A SECOND.
OKAY, YOU CAN PUT THE SCREEN UP, MAYBE.
FINALLY WHAT I WANT TO DO IS TALK ABOUT
GERMINATION OF THE SEED. AFTER THE EMBRYO
IS MATURE,
AFTER THE ENDOSPERM HAS BEEN ABSORBED IN THE
COTYLEDON
OR IS STILL PRESENT IN THIS MATURE COCONUT,
WHICH WE
HAVE HERE, I WANT TO TALK TO YOU ABOUT GERMINATION.
OF ALL OF THE STAGES IN THE DEVELOPMENT OF
A PLANT
PROBABLY GERMINATION IS THE MOST DIFFICULT.
BECAUSE, THE PLANT HAS TO GET ITSELF
ESTABLISHED, HAS TO GET WATER, HAS TO START
PHOTOSYNTHESIZING ALL BEFORE THE NUTRIENTS
ARE
EXHAUSTED INSIDE THE COTYLEDONS OR INSIDE
THE
ENDOSPERM. SO, THIS IS THE MOST DIFFICULT
TIME FOR
THE PLANT. I WANT TO TALK TO YOU ABOUT THE
TYPES OF
ISSUES THAT SEEDS HAVE TO ADDRESS IN THEIR
ESTABLISHMENT. THE FIRST ISSUE WHICH I WOULD
LIKE
TO POINT OUT TO YOU AND ALL OF YOU ARE AWARE
OF
THIS, IS THAT HERE IS THE GROUND LEVEL, AND
HERE IS
A SEED, LET'S SAY BURIED A COUPLE INCHES IN
THE
GROUND. THE SEED HAS TO GET UP TO THE SUNLIGHT
AND
START PHOTOSYNTHESIZING BEFORE IT RUNS OUT
OF
NUTRIENTS. IN ORDER TO GET UP TO THE TOP IT
HAS TO
PASS ESSENTIALLY, A MINE FIELD OF POTENTIAL
OBSTACLES. PERHAPS ROCKS ARE IN THE WAY, PERHAPS
THERE IS HARD SOIL. HOW DOES THIS SEEDLING
GET UP
TO THE TOP WITHOUT DAMAGING ITSELF? WE SAID
THAT
WE HAD THE MERISTEM HERE. THE MERISTEM. THIS
MERISTEM, IF THE SEED GERMINATED LIKE SO,
WOULD
HAVE TO PUSH UP AGAINST THE OBSTACLES THAT
WERE IN
THE GROUND. THIS MERISTEM, AS YOU MIGHT GUESS,
IS
A VERY DELICATE PART OF THE PLANT. THE PLANT
DOES
NOT WANT TO USE THE MERISTEM AS BATTERING
A RAM.
DOESN'T WANT TO USE THE MERISTEM. SO, LET
ME SHOW
YOU WHAT PLANTS DO AND THIS IS WHY I INTRODUCED
YOU
TO THE TERMS EPICOTYL AND HYPOCOTYL. IN MANY
PLANTS, INSTEAD OF USING THE MERISTEM AS
A BATTERING RAM, I WILL MAKE THE BIT HIGHER
FOR
YOU, THE SOIL LEVEL. WHAT THE PLANT DOES
IS THE
FOLLOWING: HERE IS THE SEED, HERE IS THE AXIS,
HERE ARE THE COTYLEDONS AND HERE IS THE MERISTEM.
MERISTEM IS LOCATED RIGHT HERE. AND THIS IS
THE
HYPOCOTYL.
SO WHAT THE PLANT DOES IS IT BENDS OVER. AND
THE BATTERING RAM BECOME THE HYPOCOTYL. THE
HYPOCOTYL
PUSHES ITS WAY UP THROUGH THE SOIL AND THEN
ONCE IT
GETS UP TO THE SURFACE OF THE SOIL IT STRAIGHTENS
OUT
AND THE PLANT STARTS GROWING UPRIGHT. IN MANY
PLANTS
THE HYPOCOTYL IS THE BATTERING RAM AND IN
SOME PLANTS
LIKE PEAS, AND YOU WILL SEE SOME OF THESE
IN THE LAB,
EPICOTYL IS THE BATTERING RAM.
FINALLY, I WANT TO MENTION THIS IS USUALLY
THE
SITUATION IN EUDICOTS. IN MONOCOTS WE DON'T
REALLY
HAVE A KIND OF A CLEAR EPICOTYL AND HYPOCOTYL,
EVEN
THOUGH I DREW IT FOR YOU. TECHNICALLY IT IS
THERE BUT
NEVER DEVELOPS TO A POINT WHERE IT HAS ANY
FUNCTION.
HOW DO MONOCOT SEEDS PROTECT THEMSELVES?
MONOCOT
SEEDS PROTECT THEMSELVES, SEEDLINGS PROTECT
THEIR
MERISTEM BY MAKING A COVER
OR A SHEATH, A COVER OR A
SHEATH, TO COVER THE MERISTEM.
REASON I WANT YOU TO KNOW THE NAME OF THE
SHEATH
IS BECAUSE WE WILL RETURN TO IT IN A DISCUSSION
VERY
SOON. I WANT YOU TO KNOW WHERE IT CAME FROM.
SO,
HERE IS THE SEED, HERE IS THE SHOOT AXIS,
HERE IS THE
MERISTEM. AND HERE IS THE COVER OR THE SHEATH.
COVERS IT UP LIKE SO. PROTECTS THAT MERISTEM.
IT IS
THIS COVER WHICH GROWS UP THROUGH THE SOIL.
WE GIVE THIS COVER A SPECIAL NAME, THAT IS
REALLY WHAT I WANT YOU TO KNOW NOW, PUT IT
IN YOUR
NOTE BECAUSE WE WILL RETURN TO IT. WE CALL
IT THE
COLEOPTILE. COLEOPTILE. WE WILL RETURN TO
IT LATER
ON.
FINALLY, WHAT I WANT TO DO BEFORE WE LEAVE
TODAY
IS TO GIVE YOU A FEW LANDMARK THAT WE NEED
TO HAVE AS
OUR VOCABULARY, ONLY A FEW FOR THE REST OF
THE
DISCUSSION OF THE PLANTS. SO LETS MAKE HERE
A PLANT
WHICH HAS ALREADY GERMINATED AND IS GROWING
OUTSIDE AS
YOU HAVE ALREADY. I WANT TO PUT A FEW TERMS
ON HERE
THAT WE'LL BE REFERRING TO FOR THE REST OF
THE CLASS.
SO, FIRST OF ALL WE WILL PUT A LEAF ON HERE.
THIS WHOLE THING IS A LEAF.
A LEAF. MOST OF YOU KNOW THIS TERM. LEAF IS
DIVIDED INTO TWO PARTS. THE BLADE, WHICH IS
WHAT YOU
KNOW OF AS THE LEAF OR THINK OF AS THE LEAF
AND A
PORTION WHICH CONNECTS THE BLADE TO THE STEM,
THAT IS
THE PETIOLE.
THE POINT OF ATTACHMENT OF THE LEAF, OF THE
LEAF
TO THE STEM IS CALLED A NODE. HERE WE CAN
HAVE
SEVERAL NODES. YOU HAVE A NODE HERE AND A
NODE HERE
AND NODE HERE.
AND AS YOU MIGHT GUESS WE HAVE A NAME FOR
THE
REGION BETWEEN NODES,
CALLED THE INTERNODE.
ONLY REALLY ONE OTHER THING THAT I NEED TO
PUT
ON HERE FOR YOU. SO HERE IS AN EXAMPLE OF
A PLANT, IN
WHICH YOU CAN SEE A SERIES OF NODES WHERE
THE LEAF IS
ATTACHED AND A SERIES OF INTERNODES BETWEEN
WHERE THE
LEAVES ARE ATTACHED. NOW WHY ARE NODES IMPORTANT?
WHY DO WE SPECIFICALLY DESIGNATE WHY A NODE
IS
IMPORTANT? BECAUSE IF YOU LOOKED HERE IN THIS
REGION, THIS SORT OF ANGLE BETWEEN THE LEAF
AND THE
STEM, THIS ANGLE IS CALLED AN AXLE. IF YOU
LOOKED IN
THE AXLE OR THE ANGLE BETWEEN THE LEAF AND
THE STEM,
YOU GENERALLY WOULD FIND BUMPS. AND WHAT ARE
THESE
BUMPS? THESE BUMPS BECOME THE NEW BRANCHES.
THAT IS
WHAT THEY BECOME, NEW BRANCHES. AND THEY ORIGINATE
FROM A BUMP WE CALL THAT BUMP BECAUSE IT IS
IN AN IS
AXLE. WE CALL IT AXILLARY BUD.
ON THIS EXAMPLE HERE
I WANT YOU ALL TO LOOK AT THIS; HERE WE HAVE
BRANCHES
GROWING OUT. EACH OF THESE BRANCHES, EVEN
THOUGH
THERE IS NO LONGER A LEAF STILL ATTACHED HERE,
EACH OF
THESE BRANCH WOULD BE GROWING OUT FROM A NODE.
SO,
EVERY PLACE THAT THERE IS A BRANCH, THERE
WOULD HAVE
BEEN A LEAF AND EVERY PLACE WHERE THERE IS
A LEAF
THERE WOULD HAVE BEEN A NODE. TAKE A LOOK
AT A PLANT
NEXT TIME. I WANT YOU TO REALIZE THAT ALL
OF THE
VARIETY THAT YOU SEE OUTSIDE OF PLANTS EXCEPT
FOR
FRUITS AND FLOWERS IS BASED UPON CHANGES IN
LEAVES,
PETIOLES, STEMS, AXILLARY BUDS, BRANCHES.
ALL OF THE
VARIETY. JUST A FEW SIMPLE ORGANS CHANGE AND
GIVE YOU
ALL OF THE DIVERSITY OF FORM.
LET'S LOOK AT THE LAST SERIES OF SLIDES. AND
REALIZE THAT THIS PLANT HERE IS A GENERALIZED
PLANT.
OKAY. HERE IS OUR GENERALIZED PLANT WITH THE
LANDMARKS WE PUT ON THERE A SECOND AGO, AND
WHAT I
WANT TO POINT OUT TO YOU ARE THE NODES, THE
INTERNODE,
THE VEGETATIVE AXILLARY BUD, WHICH HAS GROWN
OUT.
HERE IS AN EXAMPLE OF AN AXILLARY BUD THAT
HASN'T
GROWN OUT YET. AND WHAT I DIDN'T PUT ON THE
PICTURE
BECAUSE THERE WAS NO ROOM AS WELL AS SHOOT
SYSTEM
THERE IS ALSO A ROOT SYSTEM DOWN AT THE
BOTTOM AND WE
WILL SPEND TIME LOOKING AT THE ROOT SYSTEM.
HERE IS
GERMINATION THAT WE TALKED ABOUT WHEN A SEEDLING
IS
ESTABLISHED. NOW, THIS IS IN A MONOCOT. HERE
IS THE
COLEOPTILE AND THE COLEOPTILE IS PROTECTING
THE
MERISTEM WHICH IS BURIED DOWN HERE AT THIS
NODE
REGION. AS THE COLEOPTILE GROWS UP TO THE
SOIL IT
PUSHES SOIL AWAY AND AS SOON AS IT PERCEIVES
LIGHT IT
STOPS GROWING AND THE SHOOT SYSTEM, THE APICAL
MERISTEM SYSTEM, WHICH IS CONTAINED WITHIN,
BURSTS
THROUGH IT AND THE SEEDLING THEN IS ABLE TO
PHOTOSYNTHESIZE. HERE IS AN EXAMPLE NOW OF
ONE IN
WHICH THE, IN THIS PARTICULAR CASE, THE HYPOCOTYL
IS
THE BATTERING RAM, AS WE TALKED ABOUT BEFORE.
IT IS
THE REGION BELOW WHERE THE COTYLEDONS ARE
ATTACHED,
AND NOTICE, THIS IS THE PART THIS IS PUSHING
UP
AGAINST THE SOIL. NOT THE MERISTEM. BY THE
TIME THE
SEEDLING GETS TO THE SOIL SURFACE THE SEEDLING
NOW
BEGINS TO STRAIGHTEN OUT AND THE MERISTEM,
WHICH IS
INSIDE HERE OR OVER HERE, IS PROTECTED FROM
BATTERING
OF THE SOIL. LAST SLIDE YOU WILL SEE THIS
IN THE LAB
THIS IS WHAT HAPPENS. THIS REGION HERE IS
THE
BATTERING RAM, THE MERISTEM IS CONTAINED WITHIN
HERE.
HAVE A NICE WEEKEND SEE YOU ON MONDAY, I HOPE.