MITT ROMNEY: My dad had been
born in Mexico and his family
had to leave during the
Mexican Revolution.
He had big dreams.
We were Mormons and growing up
in Michigan, that might have
seemed unusual or out of place,
but I really don't
remember it that way.
My friends cared more about what
sports teams we followed
than what church we went to.
SHANE SMITH: So we're on our
way down here to Colonial
Juarez, which is in Northern
Mexico in Chihuahua state.
A lot of people may know that
Romney and his family are
actually from here.
His father was actually born
here in a Mormon colony.
But maybe what they don't know
is that these Mormon colonies
are still here.
And they're actually fighting
the narco cartels, the drug
cartels, that run this
whole region.
They're standing up and
they're fighting the
kidnapping and the violence
and the crime.
So the question is, what are
the Mormons doing down in
Mexico in the first place?
Mormons originally came down
to Mexico in the late 1800s
after the American government
forced the Mormon church to
ban polygamy.
The problem with this is that
Joseph Smith, the prophet of
the religion, held that polygamy
was actually a divine
commandment.
He believed that you could only
reach the highest level
of the celestial kingdom, or
heaven, if you are actually a
partner in a plural marriage.
So basically, the more wives
you had, the better
heaven would be.
And rather than give up their
place in heaven, many moved
down to Mexico to continue to
practice polygamy, and thereby
assure their place
in the afterlife.
Here in the seclusion of the
Mexican desert, they could
practice all the standard Mormon
rituals, like baptizing
the dead or wearing magic
underwear, but also the more
controversial plural marriage.
Or, as we were soon to find
out, the outright insane
practice of blood atonement.
So after about five hours of
some very nervous driving and
a couple of very thorough stops
at military checkpoints,
not to mention two stops at
drive-through liquor stores to
calm our very jangly nerves,
we finally arrived at the
Mormon promised land.
We left Juarez, which
is very dirty and
poor and very druggie.
And then all of a sudden you
come over this hill, and
there's orchards and
golf courses.
The streets are laid out nice,
they've got nice schools, kids
are playing baseball,
and there's angels.
And it's kind of like ah, we've
come to God's country.
Because it's beautiful here and
they obviously have money.
So this is why they're being
targeted by the narcos, and
this is why they have
to fight back.
So now we're going to go meet
some Mormons who are actually
fighting the narco cartel.
This is Brent LeBaron's farm.
They are sort of famously
secretive about their weapons,
their fighting, because they
don't want to be targeted
anymore by the cartels.
We're going to go meet him and
see if he'll show us around.
Brent?
BRENT LEBARON: Yeah,
how's it going?
SHANE SMITH: Shane Smith.
BRENT LEBARON: Brent LeBaron.
Nice to meet you.
SHANE SMITH: Nice to meet
you, how you doing?
BRENT LEBARON: I'm
very, very well.
SHANE SMITH: This
is your farm?
BRENT LEBARON: This
is my farm.
We farm chili and a little bit
of wheat-- all depends on the
time of the season.
SHANE SMITH: We've heard that
the LeBaron family, the
LeBaron colony, has sort of been
standing up to some of
the narco cartels.
BRENT LEBARON: Yeah, we've had
a few run-ins with them.
I don't like to say too
much about them.
But I'd love to show
you around.
Let's go.
SHANE SMITH: Let's do it.
Now, I didn't know what to
expect when I first met Brent.
And when I did, he
seemed to me more
American than most Americans.
In fact, I wouldn't have been
surprised if he told me he
played linebacker for Alabama.
But when he started to give me
the tour around the cemetery,
I realized that his story
was anything but normal.
BRENT LEBARON: This is a
graveyard where my grandfather
and great grandfather
are buried.
The original story is they come
down for the cause of
plural marriage to
continue it--
Mexico allowed it.
SHANE SMITH: So they wanted
to continue polygamy?
BRENT LEBARON: Yes.
My great grandfather, being a
fundamentalist, he broke away
from the Mormon church because
he had two wives.
That's when he went to establish
Colonial LeBaron.
They established five or
six colonies down here.
SHANE SMITH: The colony would
be like a family?
BRENT LEBARON: A few families.
SHANE SMITH: And then your
grandfather had 10 wives.
BRENT LEBARON: Yes.
Had children by eight
of those 10.
SHANE SMITH: And how many
grand kids did he have?
BRENT LEBARON: Between grandkids
and great grandkids,
they're probably pushing
the 400 mark right now.
SHANE SMITH: Wow.
All named LeBaron.
BRENT LEBARON: All
named LeBaron.
SHANE SMITH: Now, having more
than 400 grandchildren might
seem extreme to some, but it's
nothing compared to the shit
that Brent's Uncle
Ervil got up to.
He was a straight up
fucking lunatic.
Now Ervil not only had 13 wives
and over 50 children,
but he also used his own family,
including his own
kids, as assassins.
Dubbed "The Mormon Manson,"
Ervil and his family were
suspects in over 40 murders.
Joel LeBaron was killed by his
own brother Ervil because of
blood atonement?
BRENT LEBARON: Yes.
Well, Ervil tried to take over
the Church and he started
claiming blood atonement,
the right to kill
in the name of God.
If you oppose him, he has
the right to kill you.
Once Ervil snapped, he just
went on a killing spree.
He had his daughters killed,
his wives killed, his sons
killed and it just
went from there.
He went haywire.
SHANE SMITH: So Ervil goes on
this killing spree across
Mexico and the United States.
And at one point the Secret
Service is after him because
he threatens to kill
President Carter.
They finally captured Ervil in
1979 and sent him to prison,
and all the killing
stops, right?
Wrong.
And then after he dies
in jail, people keep
on killing for him.
He killed up to 25 people after
he died because he left
a sort of hit list, and they
just kept killing.
BRENT LEBARON: They
kept killing.
Yes, they did.
SHANE SMITH: Now as Brent is
telling me all this, I had to
keep in mind that this blood
atonement killing spree isn't
taking place in the 1880s
or anything, this is all
happening in the 1980s.
BRENT LEBARON: My grandfather
ran from him
for probably 10 years.
SHANE SMITH: Wow.
BRENT LEBARON: I mean,
he chased my
grandpa clear to Nicaragua.
SHANE SMITH: Your great uncle
was trying to kill your
grandfather?
BRENT LEBARON: Yeah.
Verlan M. LeBaron died in a
car accident right out of
Mexico City.
A lot of people have been
skeptical that actually Ervil
had something to do with it.
And his last recorded words were
"Brother, it looks like
you've been ran off the road."
SHANE SMITH: That's
some crazy shit.
BRENT LEBARON: Yeah.
That's just a modern-day
Cain and Abel here.
SHANE SMITH: Do you think that
that's one of the reasons why,
because you had this sort of
familial civil war, you got
tighter as a family?
So when the narcos came
after your family you
were sort of tougher?
BRENT LEBARON: Well, definitely
everyone was a watchman.
SHANE SMITH: Now what he's
saying here is that because of
Ervil, everyone in the LeBaron
clan watched out
for everyone else.
So when the cartels kidnapped
one of their
own, they were ready.
Eric LeBaron was only 16 when
he was abducted and held for
$1 million ransom.
And you didn't pay the ransom?
BRENT LEBARON: We didn't
pay the ransom.
SHANE SMITH: Even if you could
get the money and paid it,
they're just going
to keep doing it.
BRENT LEBARON: Just going to
keep coming and keep doing it.
SHANE SMITH: They'll just use
the money to buy more guns and
get more powerful.
BRENT LEBARON: Exactly.
If we don't sever the head off
this monster right now, it's
just going to get worse.
We had to go to the government
and say hey, you won't allow
us to bear arms, but you're
supposed to protect us.
SHANE SMITH: The protest forced
the government to put
pressure on the kidnappers.
And as is quite rare in these
situations, Eric was returned
unharmed after paying
no ransom.
However, it also served to
enrage the local drug lord
named El Rikin, who only lived
eight miles down the road from
Colonial LeBaron.
Now, this is a narco who loves
drugs so much that he actually
massacred 18 people trying to
get off the stuff at a drug
rehab center.
And now he's after
the LeBarons.
BRENT LEBARON: They had
threatened his family with a
hand grenade.
SHANE SMITH: So they said they'd
blow up the family with
the grenade unless
he surrendered.
BRENT LEBARON: Unless
he opened the door.
MALE SPEAKER: They shot them
four times in the head each.
10 children under the age of
seven were left orphans when
that happened.