I believe it's a gateway drug
to other drug violations.
The use of the illegal drugs in
this country is leading to
terrible consequences.
SHANE SMITH: Now we all know
Mitt Romney's stance on drugs,
but it was interesting to hear
Kelly's thoughts on the drug
war, considering it affects
him every day.
KELLY ROMNEY: To me, this used
to be the most peaceful place
in the world.
I used let my kids go to
[SPANISH], go to the shows, go
to dances, go to parties.
But now you keep
a close watch.
And it all has to
do with the drug
violence that has started.
When they started the
war on drugs, the
violence just escalated.
Most of the problems
that we have around
here are drug related.
And there's been some
kidnappings and some killings
from drug related things.
SHANE SMITH: Have there ever
been any Romneys kidnapped?
KELLY ROMNEY: Yeah, my brother
was kidnapped three
years ago in May.
I think they kept him for two
days, took him to a cave up in
the mountains.
We paid a small ransom.
It wasn't a lot.
They were mainly punks.
They weren't really
professionals.
SHANE SMITH: And most of the
weapons that are here in
Mexico are illegal weapons.
And most of those illegal
weapons are
coming from the states.
KELLY ROMNEY: Yes.
Fast and Furious, I'm sure
you've heard about that?
SHANE SMITH: Now, the Fast and
the Furious scandal he's
talking about refers to a case
where the American government
gave thousands of guns
to the cartels in
order to track them.
Then they proceeded to lose
track of them until they
surfaced again in the murder
cases of American agents.
KELLY ROMNEY: What, they think
that we're going to be able to
keep control of them or
keep track of them?
Nonsense.
I don't know what in the world
they were thinking sending all
those weapons to Mexico.
SHANE SMITH: And the Fast and
the Furious scandal is just
one of many that have seriously
embarrassed the
American government.
Now, perhaps, Mitt's hard line
stance on issues like guns,
immigration, and drugs
becomes more clear.
Because even though his father
was born in Chihuahua, Mitt
surely must want to distance
himself from the region,
because the region is
totally fucked up.
And it's not the first time
this has been the Romney
strategy, either.
When his father ran for
president, both his
citizenship and his Mormon
colony's polygamist roots were
called into question.
And his run for the White House
didn't last too long.
But Mitt Romney has to deal with
his family's polygamist
past, kidnapping, drug wars,
and in the extreme case of
Ervil LeBaron, crazy Mormon
blood atonement.
Now, having close familial ties
to all of this shit does
not a good presidential
candidate make.
Being on the front lines of
this, what do you think are
some of solutions to
these problems?
KELLY ROMNEY: Looking at it from
a perspective of someone
living here, we say, well, why
don't they legalize it in the
United States and cut out all
of violence in Mexico?
SHANE SMITH: Sure.
KELLY ROMNEY: As long as you
have the swimming pool over
there, this is going to
be the diving board.
SHANE SMITH: So as we began
our long drive back to the
border, I had lots of time
to think about what
we'd seen in Chihuahua.
I thought about the LeBarons
and the war against the
narcos, the kidnapping and
murders, and the length they
have to go to protect themselves
every day.
I also thought about what Kelly
Romney had said about
the US being the swimming pool
and Mexico being the diving
board, and how similar all this
is to America's history
with outlawing alcohol.
So we're just approaching the
border here back into America.
Feels like about a year has
passed since were here last.
As we were driving here from
Chihuahua, I was thinking how
prohibition in America led to
the rise of the mob, the Al
Capones, the Lucky Lucianos.
Our war on drugs, our
prohibition against drugs, has
caused the same thing.
You see it down here.
It's the blunt end
of the hammer.
It's rule of the thug.
You have $200 assassins.
And as long as there's
prohibition,
it's going to continue.
The war on drugs is a failure.
There have never been more drugs
in America and they've
never been cheaper or better
or higher quality.
And as we sat for hours at the
border, waiting to get back
into America, I thought about
the fact that Mitt Romney
might just be the
next president
of the United States.
MITT ROMNEY: God
bless America.
Thank you guys.
SHANE SMITH: Now, polygamy and
kidnapping not withstanding,
if he wins, he's going to have
some hard decisions to make
about decriminalizing
drugs and fixing
our immigration problem.
Because if he doesn't, Mexico,
his Mormon brethren, and
perhaps even his own
flesh and blood are
going to pay the price.
[MUSIC PLAYING]