MALE SPEAKER: What's all this
fucking shit on the wall?
JASON DILL: I woke up-- for like
a month straight-- just
with blood in my mouth.
MALE SPEAKER: How'd it
get on the wall?
Spitting?
JASON DILL: Yeah.
14 dental appointments and
they're still fucked up.
I know it's gross.
People probably think
it's fucked up.
I mean every day you come in
here you've got like--
literally, I'm not going
to look at it.
I'm just going to be like,
[SPITTING], spit it out.
I just had to see it,
just to make sure.
So I had to look at it every
day, knowing how
crazy it was getting.
It was just a reminder of
just how bad it was.
PATRICK O'DELL: Hi, welcome
back to the show.
This episode's about
Jason Dill.
And I know we already did
a Jason Dill episode.
But while I was making that, I
was looking at all of his old
parts and stuff.
And I thought it'd be cool to
do sort of the history of
Jason Dill.
JASON DILL: My very, very,
very first ad was I was
sitting in a shopping
cart with Caroll
sitting in the front.
Caroll, Ben Chibber, and
Anthony Oglesby.
Me and Anthony Oglesby
are the little guys.
Caroll is only like a
year and a half, two
years older than me.
But I remember them being like,
hey go get Caroll to go
shoot this ad.
Fucking--
what?
Like, I'm not going to
talk to this dude.
Like, it's Mike fucking
Caroll.
My first video part was
an A1 Meats where--
MALE SPEAKER: Is that the one
where you're running through
the-- doing like cartwheels
through the grass?
JASON DILL: Yeah, and doing
flips and shit.
I was 12.
I filmed for three days.
I was just, I can
bigspin that.
I can 360 flip that.
Like, just, all right, do it.
I don't remember like
ever taking time.
I would check out--
I remember seeing Ocean and
Marcus like really try shit.
I remember I got driven to 7th
Street, skate the head.
And I remember this one
kid had a box in
front of his house.
So I did like a nose bump 360.
And I'll hit some gap there.
Instead of like, yeah, I'm just
going to go fucking--
I was a little kid.
Like, I'm going to go
ollie this big gap.
All right.
You know, like Rick Howard, he
taught me how to do a bigspin
to frontside boardslide a day
before I got on Blockhead.
And I tried it in my contest
run for some
reason like a day after.
Who the fuck knows how
I made it to here.
Jesus Christ.
Because if you really think
about it from that perspective
and then so if you could only
imagine, like fast forward to
me skating with Ocean.
Like, those dudes are so far
in advance compared to my
prepubescent mind.
I mean, I'm sure Hensley and
them were doing it before.
But I didn't have the
opportunity to go skate with
Hensley in my prepubescent
years.
MALE SPEAKER: So did you
skate with Jeremy Wray?
JASON DILL: Yeah.
That's weird.
I was talking to someone
about this recently.
I don't even remember
how I met Jeremy.
I remember people doing pressure
flips, but Jeremy was
doing over knee-high
kickflips.
So he was a really big influence
on my whole deal.
MALE SPEAKER: What was the clip
where he does a gap and
you're in the clip?
JASON DILL: The Color Video.
I know I'm in that video because
I tried to ollie that
gap with Jeremy.
No, I didn't come anywhere
near Jeremy.
I don't think I got over it.
I don't even think I got my
board over it with my body.
MALE SPEAKER: Where is that?
Where's the mark?
JASON DILL: Give me five.
Over here.
MALE SPEAKER: How'd
he do that?
Nobody can--
I don't believe it.
It can't be possible.
I don't believe what
I just saw.
MALE SPEAKER: I even saw
it with my two eyes.
MALE SPEAKER: But I don't
believe what I just saw.
Look at these marks.
JASON DILL: I never
thought about it
until later, you know?
Thinking about it right now, I
never thought of myself being
in Jeremy Wray's shadow.
I was in Jeremy Wray's shadow,
but not in a bad way.
Those dudes were so
fucking gnarly.
It really helped me shape and
have what feeds me today.
Man, I've had a fucking
weird, wild ride.
When I was like a
fucking child,
how the fuck my mother--
how she let me do this,
I do not know.
My mom got this job.
And she went up to a business
trip in San Francisco, took me
with her, skated the
streets by myself.
I'm talking about sweat pants,
Converse, and a Batman t-shirt
with a mullet.
I was a goofy white kid from
Huntington Beach, man.
I was just fucking--
I was just enjoying
being there.
I wasn't even worried about
being accepted.
So that was my little early
EMB niche that I somehow
sorted out on my own.
And then by the time I was
15, I already rode for
Spitfire and shit.
So it's like, I think
I just got accepted.
And at that time, which was kind
of rad, they just lumped
me, Jeremy, and Jonas
together.
And hey were like,
fuck, all right.
You're on the team too.
MALE SPEAKER: Were you
there when Gino did
the backside heelflip?
JASON DILL: No.
I wasn't there when Gino did
the backside heelflip.
I talked to Gino on the phone.
I was just thinking about it,
when you mentioned that
Spitfire video.
What happened with the Spitfire
video was that I
didn't ride for anybody except
for Spitfire and Thunder.
And within that time frame, I
had already started filming
with this dude Dave Sloshbach
that was friends with Brian
Lotti that was trying to get
Gino and I to do this offshoot
company, World Industries.
And then, thank god, fucking
right before Brian Lotti left
skateboarding, he left our
footage on Natas's desk.
Natas had a desk to
leave footage on.
Natas called Gino's house.
I remember sitting there, being
like, fucking Natas is
on the phone.
And he was like, do you
want to ride for 101?
So we got on 101, and
immediately released Snuff.
It was the footage of us skating
just World and Blind,
101 Plan B boards.
MALE SPEAKER: I remember you
telling me one time that they
saw your 101--
whatever, your tape to get
on 101 or something.
And [INAUDIBLE] or somebody was
like, oh yeah we like you.
But I don't know about
your friend Gino.
Am I remembering that wrong?
JASON DILL: There's no way
because Gino was already so
well respected before he even
really hit that scene that I
kind of went on his coattails.
I think I had such a big mouth
when it came down to what my
opinion was that the people that
I did business with were
like, well this fucking little
loud-mouthed kid.
He's so about it.
Like, fuck it.
Throw him out there.
Let's see what he does.
And I think I've been thrown out
there so many times to see
what I can do that I ended
up just having to
become as big as my--
I thought my britches
were, or whatever.
I know how anti-climactic it
sounds, but then I was pro.
I don't really remember.
And then the whole 101 thing
kind of turned into a really
rad thing, though.
Yeah, right after Snuff
was 20 Shot Sequence.
And what happened was
I hurt my knee.
I tore my ACL in half.
Yeah, so that video came out
with a super small part, the
20 Shot Sequence video.
But Natas let me help him
edit that 101 section.
My mom had seen enough of me
around the house and was just
not stoked on how bummed
out I was, I'm sure.
I'm sure she really
felt for me.
And the very first clip
of me coming back is
that line at Flushing.
It's the first time I skated
in eight, nine months.
MALE SPEAKER: What
was the line?
JASON DILL: The heelflip over
the grate with the pipe,
nollie backside [INAUDIBLE]
flat, switch 5-0, switch
frontside 180 out.
And that was the beginning
of Trilogy.
Yeah, my part in that video
was fucking balls
to the wall, man.
I think that was everything I'd
ever achieved to bin was
in that video part.
Like, up until that point, I
think that's everything I ever
worked for.
Finally, like--
Finally, like as gnarly as
Gino's part was in that video,
I felt finally I had
my own niche.
I achieved all my goals at 19.
Anything after that was just
icing on the cake.
By the time that came
out, Natas quit, and
I got kicked off.
So the day Trilogy came
out, I got kicked off.
MALE SPEAKER: But
you're in it.
JASON DILL: Yeah.
MALE SPEAKER: And so--
OK.
Why'd they do that?
JASON DILL: Because I stole
boards because I was--
MALE SPEAKER: Oh, I
heard about that.
JASON DILL: I had no money.
Gino made $1,500 a month
and I made 1,000.
One day we went to roll in the
streets and they were like,
you're not getting
paid this month.
With Trilogy about--
Trilogy master tape, done.
Parts, done.
You're not getting paid.
MALE SPEAKER: How many
boards did you steal?
JASON DILL: 36.
Because then I can get-- if I
had 36 boards I could pay my
rent and get an ounce of pot.
And then I'd just live off Top
Ramen and Kool-Aid like I'd
been doing.
That Memory Screen
blew me away.
If anybody's seen Memory
Screen, it just like--
I remember [INAUDIBLE] like,
you were into it?
Like a little kid, like
that whole first part?
I was like, yes.
Like the [MAKING SOUNDS].
I'd sing the song, that
middle section.
I can't forget to tell you
something that you're going to
think is funny.
You'll probably use
it, after this.
But when I was skating for 23,
I was going to SF a lot,
during that fit shit because
I rode for a
company called C/O Wheels.
C/O was short for cocaine.
So stupid.
What age is that, like 21?
I was like 21 years old, going
to SF all the time, smoking
cocaine blunts, being nutty.
Like, turning into that weird
dude who would just take drugs
when he's with you
and not tell you.
Like, that was never me,
but I turned into that.
It was a really strange
period.
In my 23 ad, it's that ollie
over to frontside tailslide on
that pole, where you have
to do the gap thing.
Henry Sanchez had wrote, Michael
Bolton-ass looking
motherfucker.
And I remember being
so hurt by it.
And then it just being one of
those things like, well fuck,
at least one of the gnarly
dudes wrote it.
Yeah.
And then I remember being--
towards the end of my contest
skating days--
and I just--
I went to a contest in Canada.
And all I did was hang out
with Dyrdek and Kalis.
I came home from that contest
and it said I rode for Alien
Workshop in the new
Slap Magazine.
So I called Chris Carter,
knowing him.
And I was like, hey,
it says I ride for
Workshop in the new magazine.
I just want you to know
I have nothing--
I didn't--
that's not me.
He's all, I know.
And I think he said something
along the lines of like, no,
we OKed it.
That's cool.
And they just knew.
They knew I'd be riding for
Workshop because I tried to
get on Workshop when I
got kicked off 101.
Carter, he always calls
bullshit on it.
But I remember getting
Memory Screen.
It was yellow.
It was a VHS, yellow tape.
I liked Dinosaur Jr. I
knew who they were.
Carter always calls--
no, you didn't.
Fuck.
Bullshit.
You didn't know who--
yeah, pfft.
Just Alien Workshops
is just such a
fucking sick, smart company.
Like, I always adored them.
And so it was a pleasure
to be at Workshop.
It was really great.
But the video that people always
come up to us about is
the fucking Feedback video.
People love that
goddamn video.
And we put Ty through so much
shit making that video.
Because we made that video
right before we put
our Alien part out.
Poor Ty was making that Feedback
video of us, like
totally showing us, showcasing
us in that section.
And we were like, fuck
this shit, Ty.
We want to do our Alien part.
Fuck a Transworld video.
Fuck--
Transworld video--
what the fuck, Transworld.
That's bullshit.
We didn't know what it was
going to look like.
And then that fucking Feedback
video came out.
Everyone had just the
raddest parts in it.
Kids that were born when that
part came out still
come up at a demo.
Feedback.
They love that video.
CHRIS CARTER: Dude, you got--
this is your big video.
This is it.
JASON DILL: OK, OK, OK, OK.
All right.
No problems.
I'm only skating.
I'm just skating.
I swear.
That's it.
That's all.
So far I heard I got the last
part and all that shit.
So [INAUDIBLE]
so psyched.
CHRIS CARTER: You know
what the last part
means, don't you?
JASON DILL: I do!
CHRIS CARTER: That's
the curtains.
JASON DILL: A lot of people
don't believe this, but they
started recording me for about
a year straight without
telling me.
So what you see in
Photosynthesis is a mixture of
conversations me and Carter
had over a year.
And that's not Carter
you see at the desk.
It's just a stock photo they
found of some guy at a desk.
My mom thought that was Carter
for years until she met him.
Photosynthesis took about
two years of work-work.
I think for so long, I always
felt that this is what I'm
going to do.
I'd want to be individualistic,
and I'd want
people to know me for me
and not part of some
big team, or whatever.
MALE SPEAKER: Everyone always
talks about the walking down
the stairs.
JASON DILL: No, I just
thought it worked.
I was trying to film
a line and--
what was it?
Originally, it was
just a backside
heelflip over that barricade.
And so then I started doing this
stupid fucking 360 flip
that I ate shit on so bad up
at the top of the street.
And that spot got demolished
after 9/11.
But what it was-- like, you
cruise down this small street,
and the fakie shuvit over the
bench because I've always
loved that trick.
No one does that very much.
And then to pick
up the board--
I just figured it would transfer
so well to walk down
the stairs.
One, two, three, four, down!
And then I jumped that.
That was a pretty fucking big
gap that was there then.
I was a much younger
man at the time.
It's just part of the video.
And then just the reaction I've
gotten out of that over
the years is just insane.
MALE SPEAKER: So then--
then my brother Joe hit me in
the chin with a crowbar.
I turned around and
talked to Joe.
You know, why you [INAUDIBLE].
It's not necessary.
Don't hit me in the chin.
[INAUDIBLE]
I don't like, OK?
Joe comes over, has a gun,
shoos me in the stomach,
shoots another guy over
there really fast.
Shoots him down.
[MAKING GUN SOUNDS]
Right?
Everybody's freaking
out, going crazy.
I'm like, Joe, stop shooting
everybody, man.
This is crazy!
Those people are going to die!
[LAUGHING]
MALE SPEAKER: I can't take it.