There's a lot of science in this
chipotle sauce, probably.
But that we're not
talking about.
We're talking about the
science of milk today.
And there's some really, really
cool, believe it or
not, colorful science of milk.
Watch this.
I'm Steve Spangler, and I'm all
about making science fun.
For the last 20 years, I've
been teaching ways to turn
ordinary science experiments
into unforgetable learning
experiences.
I have an amazing team who will
do whatever it takes to
affect the way people
think about science.
And to do that, I live
by one motto--
make it big, do it right,
give it class.
Watch this.
See this amazing burst
of color that's here?
In order to understand how milk
does this, you have to
understand something about
the chemistry of fat, the
chemistry of water, polar,
nonpolar, hydrophilic,
hydrophobic--
most importantly, the chemistry
of this amazing
substance called soap.
Well, if you take a look at
the science of milk, it's
really a combination of
fat and water, right?
And all different kinds
of fat-- so that's
fat free or 1% 2%.
If we're going to understand
how this burst took place,
let's just break this component
down and start with
the water component itself.
So in a plate goes just
a little bit of water.
And to the water, we add just
a couple drops of food
coloring so that we can
see the movement--
so a couple drops around
the circle.
And now, the last step is just
a little bit of soap.
We're just using regular
dish soap here.
And I don't need a tremendous
amount so I have a little
portion cup.
And our soap is perfect.
Now, in order to dispense it,
I'm just using a cotton swab.
So a little bit of the soap on
the cotton swab, and now,
watch what happens.
You have to look here
in the very middle.
Watch.
Did you see little burst of
color that was there?
That's it.
That's our burst.
It's very different from the
milk that we had before.
See, the milk had this churning
kind of action.
This does actually nothing
except for that initial burst,
which means that the soap helped
to break up the surface
tension of the water-- that
layer of the water that the
molecules hook together.
So the hydrogen bonding allows
the water to form almost a
skin, so to speak.
And the soap, of course, breaks
that skin and breaks
the surface tension.
But we don't get the bursting.
So it really is not a phenomenon
of soap and just
water here and food coloring.
There has to be something
with the fat.
See, milk is really a
combination of polar and
nonpolar materials.
Polar would be water.
Nonpolar would be the fat.
Now, they say that there's
fat, also called lipids.
Maybe The best way to explain
what nonpolar would be is to
use this model of these
little yellow sticks.
They're called lipids.
See, they're nonpolar in that
they're just these long chains
of molecules, so to speak.
See, fat is nothing more than
a combination of hydrogen
molecules hooked onto carbon.
And this long chain
makes the fat.
See, there's no head and
there's no tail.
It's just this long chain.
And this is what we're going to
use to represent the fat.
Soap, on the other hand,
is a combination
of polar and nonpolar.
And that's why we're using
these matches to
represent the soap.
Look at this.
The base of the match here, or
the long part, is going to be
used to represent the nonpolar
part, very similar to this
part that you see over
here with the fat.
But see the very end
of the match?
That's the head.
And let's call that
the polar part.
Now, water is a polar
material.
It's a polar solvent.
So water now dissolves in
the head of the match.
And the rest of that match there
now wants to attach to
something that it's like.
You've heard the thing "like
dissolves like." Well, it
wants to go attach itself
to anything
else that is nonpolar.
Look and see how it attaches
to the fat.
It's a matter of just
matching this up.
The other part, which is the
polar part, the head, now
washes away in the polar
solvent, which is water.
That's a lot of chemistry to
simply say that this is how
you get clean, but this is
exactly how they made soap
many, many, many years ago.
They took white wood ash,
very alkaline, or
they could take lye.
They would combine that with a
little bit of water and then
add and animal fat to that, a
little bit of salt, mix the
whole thing together, and it
made for this perfect material
that would literally cover your
body, remove the grease
and the dirt, and then wash
away in the water.
But some of you need an even
more scientific explanation of
this hydrophobic, hydrophilic,
polar, nonpolar.
And for that, we turn to our
friends at Crash Course!, who
know exactly what to say.
HANK GREEN: The fact that water
is a polar molecule also
makes it really good at
dissolving things, which we
call-- it's a good
solvent, then.
Scratch that.
Water isn't a good solvent.
It's an amazing solvent.
There are more substances that
can be dissolved in water than
in any other liquid on Earth.
And yes, that includes the
strongest acid that we have
ever created.
These substances that
dissolve in water--
sugar or salt being ones that
we're familiar with-- are
called hydrophilic.
And they are hydrophilic
because they are polar.
And their polarity is stronger
than the cohesive
forces of the water.
So when you get one of these
polar substances in water,
it's strong enough that it
breaks all the little cohesive
forces, all those little
hydrogen bonds.
And instead of hydrogen bonding
to each other, the
water will hydrogen bond around
these polar substances.
Table salt is ionic.
And right now, it's being
separated into ions as the
poles of our water molecules
interact with it.
But what happens when there is
a molecule that cannot break
the cohesive forces of water?
It can't penetrate
and come into it.
Basically, what happens when
that substance can't overcome
the strong cohesive forces of
water-- it can't get inside of
the water-- that's when we get
what we call a hydrophobic
substance, or something that
is fearful of water.
These molecules lack
charged poles.
They are nonpolar and are not
dissolving in water, because
essentially, they're being
pushed out of the water by
water's cohesive forces.
Water--
we may call it the universal
solvent, but that does not
mean that it dissolves
everything.
STEVE SPANGLER: So you get this
hydrophobic, hydrophilic
thing, right?
Fat being hydrophobic, correct,
and the hydrophobic
end of the soap, and then the
head of the match being
hydrophilic, or water-loving--
that's the part that just
simply washes away.
What does all this have to
do with bursting milk?
Well, now you start to see the
alignment of the molecules
that take place in milk.
Well, we're back to the milk.
I selected milk for this example
that has a lot of fat.
It's whole milk--
lots of fat.
Of course, there's water.
So if you can imagine this on
a microscopic level, as soon
as I tough it, you now have the
hydrophobic end-- that's
the long end of the soap--
now trying to hook on to the
hydrophobic end of the milk.
And this moving around
these tails--
kind of whipping around-- is
exactly what you see as the
milk starts to move.
Watch.
See, it's the hydrophobic end.
It's the hydrophobic end of the
soap now hooking onto the
hydrophobic end of the milk.
And you can see the movement
that's in there.
Literally, we're seeing
molecules in motion as the
milk starts to move around,
and of course, realigning
itself so that the hydrophilic,
or the
water-loving end is close
to that of the
water as it moves around.
And you now get to see this
beautiful movement inside just
because the molecules are
chasing themselves around and
realigning.
So we're going to turn this
into a real science
experiment.
It means we have to
compare something.
And why not compare the
different kinds of milk?
So look over here-- fat free
milk, 1%, 2%, whole milk, half
and half, and finally,
buttermilk.
Now, it's really important as
you're doing your comparison
to make sure that all of the
milk is the same temperature.
So we've let all of this sit
out at room temperature so
that we're comparing this.
The real question would be does
it change at all if you
heat it up or if you
get it colder?
Different question at
a different time.
Right now, we're simply
observing the differences in
fat for all of the milk.
And finally, every great science
experiment has to have
a great hypothesis.
So our hypothesis today
has to be which one
will burst the best?
The one with the most fat or
the one with the least fat?
Lock it in and watch this.
Let's start with fat free.
Watch.
1%.
Wow, we get a great
burst on 1%.
All right, 2%.
Here we go.
Wow, even better.
Here's whole milk.
Beautiful.
Table cream--
lots of fat in table cream.
Watch.
Look at this continued
churning.
And finally, who doesn't like
a little buttermilk?
You know, it leaves that kind
of feeling in your throat.
I know some of you have
already tuned out.
Watch.
Nothing.
Well, outside the buttermilk,
which was just too viscous to
move around, the one with the
most amount of fat is the one
that gives us the best bursting,
although, if you
take a look at each one of
these, you do see some
movement, but it decreases as
you go from whole milk, 2%,
1%, and just very, very little
movement at all with
the fat free milk.
What a cool way to understand
the science of polar and
nonpolar, hydrophilic,
hydrophobic, and the science
of soap using something
simple like milk.
Well, it looks like milk,
but it's not.
It's Elmer's Glue.
See, Elmer's Glue, chemically
speaking,
is polyvinyl acetate.
It's a thermoplastic polymer.
It is unusual because it
has a polar part that
dissolves in water.
But it also has a nonpolar
component.
And you know what we can do if
we have something that has a
polar and nonpolar component.
Get the food coloring.
All right.
This one here-- let's start with
a little bit of Elmer's
Glue and even less water.
Now, if I was doing this for
science project, I would
measure this out so I could call
it a 90% solution of glue
or an 80%, whatever it is.
Here, I just want to test the
hypothesis that if we add some
water, that it's going to give
us some pretty good bursting
of those colors.
Watch what happens.
There's the movement
that we wanted.
Look at this.
It's fantastic.
You almost get this combination
of what we saw
with the buttermilk.
Ah, look at the little
fingers that are kind
of coming out here.
Yet you get more movement than
we saw with just the regular
Elmer's Glue.
Maybe the best part of
this is what happens
when you let it dry.
See, normally, you would
just dump the milk out.
But if you allow the Elmer's
Glue to dry, especially on
these plastic plates, you
get something very cool.
Remember, it's not milk.
All of these plates
have Elmer's Glue.
The only difference is the
amount of water that
we put in each one.
And the best part is, over
time, they'll dry.
Well, if there's not too much
water, they'll dry.
And watch what happens
when they dry.
You can literally just
peel them out.
And it looks like this.
Put them under the flashlight
and take a look at this.
You get this beautiful kind of
stained glass window effect.
Well, you have some fairly
simple materials to learn some
high level chemistry.
And if you use the Elmer's
Glue solution, you get a
keepsake that's pretty
awesome as well.
And best of all, at the end of
day, you've got a whole lot of
milk and some cookies
left over.
Who doesn't like
a little treat?
Oh, god.
That's glue.
Higginsworth!
God, that's horrible.
HIGGINSWORTH: Close the door.
Stop wasting energy.
STEVE SPANGLER: Science
of milk.