the great depression in 1929 and came out
of it thinking that there was still goods
in store windows, things in ca..cars in car
lots but people just didn't have the money
to buy things. So he realized it was the rules
of the game that we play by that were so screwed
up... and from when he was very young, he
set out to find an alternative social design
to take care of the problems that we have
today. This is what's very different between
Jacque and other protestors and people who..who
understand that the system is not working
but they do not pose an alternative. I don't
know of anyone else who tries to find the
root causes of the problems and understands
that things cannot be fixed within the monetary
system and the system that we live by today.
So, Jacque has worked.. He's 95 years old.
He's worked since he was very young to..working
with people: drug addicts, alcoholics.. changing
them, joining the Klu Klux Klan and changing
them. Putting his educational processes to
test.. and understanding if he needs to change
the world, he needs to be able to change peoples
values as well. So, he's arrived at a totally
new social design and he backs it up technically!
These are not just words that he's talk about.
If you go to our website: "THEVENUSPROJECT.COM"
You'll see what this..this new world civilization,
this sustainable future would look like. Jacque
Fresco: So I see, eventually, whether The
Venus Project gets off the ground or not,
this is what I see: I see machines displacing
people... and if you displace people in the
automotive industry, where the machine picks
up the car, puts the wheels on.. you're displacing
millions of people. You don't need air conditioning.
You don't need to pay em' for vacations. You
don't need to take out insurance on their
health.. and you don't need all the lights
you need with people working there. So, industry
will put in machines, wherever they can..
but here's the downfall: If you keep doing
that all over the country, people will not
have the money to buy vacuum cleaners, electric
fans, or refrigerators. If you displace most
people by machines, "How are they gonna buy
things?" So, it's a self-contradictory system...
and THIS is the basis of understanding: That
politics was good 100 years ago but it's obsolete
today. Everything that you have in your own,
those of you that have a home... Your television
set, your washing machine, your refrigerator,
your electric lights are all technical! There's
nothing political about that. It's all technical.
If you took away the technology today, you'd
have people pulling boats along the river.
Do you understand that? It's technology that
frees you from things. It's electric air-conditioning
that makes your house tolerable. So, we don't
want to put the technicians in control anymore
than they're in control today. All the technicians
do is build bridges if you're a bridge designer.
If you're an air plane designer, you can work
on air plane designing but you don't tell
people what to do. It isn't that technicians
will rule the world. I'm against that! I'm
against scientist ruling the world! I don't
see any real scientist protesting against
the exploitation of young kids when they work
in factories. We use to hire children that
were 12 years old and put them in factories
and work em' saturday and sunday. It's when
people march to free those kids from those
conditions. "Why do women have to fight for
women rights?" "Why did women have to march
years ago for a public library?" I don't know
why JUST women did but they did march and
they wanted a public library so if people
couldn't afford books, they could have access
to books. Then there's the metaphysician who
really believes that everybody has goodness
within themselves. They really don't have
anything within themselves. If you were brought
up in Nazi Germany as a baby, after Hitler
burned most the books, you'd be a Nazi. If
you're brought up in Australia, you'd say,
"How are ya' mate?!" That would be normal
to the way you speak. If you're brought up
in Germany, "Deutschland Ÿber alles!"..Germany
above all. If you're brought up that way.
So you musn't hate anybody because their all
brought up. "What are American soldiers?"
They are killing machines. They're not taught
anything..anything else. If I had anything
to do with it, I would take ALL the soldiers,
send em' back to the university to become
problem solvers. We have allot of problems
that aren't solved... and that's what we need.
Problem solvers! For every Edison we found,
imagine all the Edison's we never found. I
don't say Edison was good either. He was a
crook also. Crowd Question: "Don't scientist
usually rely on statistics to make a decision?
It seems, uh, usually, its, you know, statistical
analysis and then they draw a conclusion from
that and then, you know, as science evolves
and as we make new sciences, we will again
have like better kinds of statistics or whatever
and then we'll apply those to the new technology
that we develop. So how do we develop a language
that's not subject to interpretation.. or
statistical interpretation?!" Jacque Fresco:
"Scientist today are commercially rewarded
for being chemist or working for the drug
companies or working for the aircraft companies.
They're just as corrupt as anyone else...
and scientist, if they were scientist, they'd
say, "What makes war? Why are we going to
war with Germany? What's the problem? What
makes a man the way they are?" They wouldn't
stay in their field. Today their chemist.
They're scientific in chemistry. Then there's
structural engineers that are scientific in
structures... but they're not scientific in
human relation. They know nothing about it
or little about human behavior. So, I'm saying
there's no such thing as a scientist, YET!
Otherwise, they'd be out here in the protest.
Do you understand? I'm not talking about a
world managed by scientist... but a world
managed by scientific method! That means first
you do a survey of Texas, "How much air able
land do you have?" "How much water do you
have underground?" After you do that survey,
you can estimate how big a city can be built
in that region. If it doesn't have the resources,
it won't work. If you have a population far
above 7 billion, there will not be enough
food to go around and there's gonna be territorial
disputes. Territorial disputes are not made
by bad people or fascists or communists or
socialists free enterprises. They're made
by social conditions called, "The March of
Events". In other words, if a meteor were
coming toward the Earth, I can assure you
that all nations would stop their armies and
navies and share ideas with one another to
try to divert that meteor away from the Earth.
Not because they're good but because they're
all threatened. All nations will join together
on any common threat if they realize it. Crowd
Question: "I'm a mother of 7 children. Which
of my 5 children should not be here so that
way it would reduce the population of the
Earth?!" Jacque Fresco: "Well, all i can say,
if you want a world without war, without hunger,
without poverty, it has to be in accordance
with the carrying capacity of the Earth's
resources. If you go beyond that, you're going
to have trouble. Do you understand what I'm
saying? Crowd Question: "It seems to me what
you're saying is, that you want fewer people
but who are you to designate who the people
that should and should not be here?!" Roxanne:
No, he's not saying that at all. Crowd Question:
"I'm asking for clarification!" Roxanne: You'd
have to listen to know more about the system.
What he's proposing is a system based on the
methods of science to..to produce abundance
for everyone in the quickest time..without
polluting the earth. He's talking about a
system based on..on the well-being of people
AND the environment. He's talking about a
system that does not use money. As long as
you use money, you'll have corruption, greed,
crime, embezzlement. So he's trying to get
rid of the root causes of the problem. We
have enough have goods and resources to take
care of the entire population and even more
if we use it wisely... but what we're doing
today, we're doing mass killings by starvation...
and we're against that. We're saying we have
enough resources if we use science and technology
to the best of our ability without the monetary
system to feed, house, and clothe everyone
on earth. We can do that today. That's what
he's talking about. Jacque: "I'm not against
you. Sometimes a person comes up to me and
he says, "I have 10 children." and then I
say, "What are they for?" "What are they for?"
Just having children is not wisdom! No, I
don't believe in depopulation, I believe in
educating the public. "Why don't you put 10,000
people on the boat?" Cause it'll sink! The
displacement of the boat determines how many
people you can put on it, not Fresco... and
if you wanna take a..take 400 people and put
em' in a spaceship, it won't get off the ground.
You have to figure what the thrust is. How
much thrust you can develop in a spaceship...
and when the government came up to scientist
and said, "Can you put a man on the Moon?",
the first thing they said was, "I don't know."
So i'm saying there is other ways of thinking
about things but you need help. When a man
takes his belt off and whips his kids, "Is
he bad?" No! He doesn't know any other way
to get to them. He says, "Do what your Daddy
says!" The kid doesn't so he whips him because
his Daddy whipped him. He doesn't know! Now
protesting the stock exchange will not change
anything! I hate to tell you this. I wish
it did. I'm gonna try to tell you what we
have to do. To live in a world without war,
without poverty, without hunger and without
most crimes... all criminals are made by this
society, by the monetary system and scarcity
and burdens that are too big for the average
person to handle. There will be no armies,
no navies, no prisons, and no police in a
Resource-Based Economy. Whyyy? Because it's
just like the public library. You can access
any book you want to. Next door to the public
library, we have a camera center, where anybody
in the community, a 7-year old kid can walk
in and say, "I've come to check-out a camera."
Free! No fee involved. Do you understand that?
Just like the public library. Next door to
that you'd have musical instruments, where
anybody, like the public library, can check
out any musical instruments. The Venus Project
is sharing all the world's resources with
all the world's people. A Resource-Based Economy
is using resources rather than money. Making
all things available to all people... and
if you don't do that, you'll have wars, robbery,
crimes of all kinds. Even every criminal is
made by this culture. Once you make things
available, that's the end of crime. Do you
understand that? Not say, "Don't steal!" As
long as you understand that people are made
that way. When you're brought up in Australia,
you say, "I'm Australian and i'm proud of
it." "I'm a Greek and i'm proud of it." That
divides people. If you divide people, you
can conquer them. So what the politicians
say is things the public likes to hear. Scientists,
not all them, some of them. When they discovered
that the Earth is round, they don't say to
the public, "It's a little round and a little
flat." So they get along with everybody. No.
They say, "You're wrong. It's not flat. Here's
the evidence we have to show that it's round."....
and what you have to do is change people.
Roxanne: "We built everything ourselves. Put
in all the windows. Instill the doors. We
Built over 400 models of the future. We didn't
have any outside capital to do that. I did..had
a full-time job in order to support that.
I put all the money towards that. We've put
all the money that we've made in The Venus
Project towards that as well. If anybody knows
us, we work 7 days a week on...on promoting
this direction. So we do have a non-profit
organization now. We are collecting donations
for a major motion picture that we want to
do to show what a re..what life in a Resource-Based
Economy would be like. And we live in a monetary
system. Because we are working towards a Resource-Based
Economy the coun..county does not say, "You're
doing a great job. You don't have to pay taxes.
You don't have to pay your electric bill.
So.." Crowd Comment: "THANK YOU FOR ANSWERING
THAT!"