this episode with
science magic.
I'm Steve Spangler, and I'm all
about making science fun.
For the last 20 years, I've
been teaching ways to turn
ordinary science experiments
into unforgettable learning
experiences.
I have an amazing team who will
do whatever it takes to
affect the way people think
about science, and to do that,
I live by one motto--
make it big, do it right,
give it class.
Take a look at this.
I have two cut-out shapes
that are here.
I don't know what
to call them--
French fries, arcs.
The yellow one is here.
The red one I've cut so
that it's smaller
than the yellow one.
How much smaller?--
hard to estimate.
I don't know--six
centimeters--
something like that.
No camera tricks.
Don't blink an eye.
Watch this.
Bam!
Maybe it's the yellow one that's
small, and it's the red
one that's big.
No, wait, maybe it's the red one
that's small, and it's the
yellow one that's bigger.
That's a pretty amazing
optical illusion.
So it's not actually
a magic trick.
Indeed, it is an optical
illusion, because watch what
happens when you flip
it over here.
They're exactly equal.
One goes over the top like this,
and it almost looks like
they're perfectly equal until
you snap, and watch this.
The red one is bigger
than yellow one--
(WHISPERING) magic.
All right-- easy to make.
It's classic science magic with
a super optical illusion.
Now, you cut these, for example,
out of a paper plate,
so you cut the rim off
of a paper plate.
That would be perfect.
You're just trying to get an
arc that has just a nice
smooth edge that's here.
If truth be told, you can
actually go to Starbucks and
take the little thing that
goes on the outside-- you
know, to keep your hand from
getting hot-- and peel that
apart-- not while somebody's
holding the cup-- and lay it
down, and it gets a pretty good
arc, so you can do the
same thing that way, as well.
The secret is that your eyes
played a trick on your brain.
Watch.
If you haven't guessed it by
now, the arcs are exactly the
same, so you need to make two
arcs, but make sure that
they're different colors.
You could make them out of
plastic if you wanted to.
Like these, this is a material
that you could write on, so
maybe a message could be written
here if you want to
compare two different things.
These are just made out a kind
of plasticy material.
Watch what happens when you put
the first one down, and
this one goes on the top, notice
what your eye does
immediately.
It's a comparison game.
Immediately, your eye compares
this long line here with the
shorter line here, and
your brain says this
is the bigger one.
Now, the optical illusion looks
better even the farther
away you get it, so from
there, it looks great.
Even if it's in the center, it
looks like this one is the
small one and this one's
the big one.
When you trade it out like this,
it's the same illusion,
but you're just switching
it back and forth.
Now, some people will
do it like this.
It's all part of the
presentation.
You could very easily
say this--
the red one is bigger
than the yellow one.
You can actually see that
by holding it up.
See how the red one is bigger
than the yellow one like this.
That's OK, because I can stretch
the yellow one, and
now the yellow one is larger
than the red one.
No, maybe the red one's larger
than the yellow one.
I'm so confused.
The comparison is great.
So what does this have
to do with science?
It's great for comparison,
because you can come to the
wrong conclusion very
easily if you're
not comparing equals.
So, for example, this here, the
bottom one looks bigger
than the top one because you're
allowing your eyes to
compare this long line
with the short line.
If you're coming to a conclusion
in a science
experiment, or you're gathering
all the data, it's
easy to come to a false
conclusions unless you're
comparing the same things.
This happens all the time when
people do an experiment with
multiple variables, and they
get a different result, and
they do a comparison,
and they come to a
conclusion that's wrong--
come to find out they had
too many variables.
You have to be a
good comparer.
Is that a word-- "comparer"?
Just compare things correctly.
So I've got a little treat
for you on this episode.
What happens when you take
magicians and you put them all
together in one place?
Things disappear, and things
float in the air.
It's called a magic convention,
and we're lucky
here, because in Colorado--
in Fort Collins, Colorado--
there are 250 magicians or so
from all over the world that
get together to magish for the
weekend and kind of share
their secrets, and we have some
access to a place that I
want to show you.
So close the doors.
We're going on a field trip.
Open the doors, open the
doors, open, open--
can I have my keys?
Close the doors.
All right, well, here we are
at Magic in the Rockies.
This is one of the premier
magic conventions.
It's like nerd week here in
Fort Collins, Colorado.
Top notch magicians from all
over the country-- people who
play Las Vegas, and people who
work corporate events, and
people that do the birthday
parties and stuff on
television--
they're here, and they're here
to share their magic, and how
they do it, and share it with
other people, so I'm totally
in nerd heaven.
Here we go.
One of the coolest things about
being at a magician's
convention is you meet
the coolest people.
And Gene Turner, from Kansas,
City, Missouri--
is that right?
GENE TURNER: Kansas City, yes.
STEVE SPANGLER: And you
have this finger
manipulation kind of thing.
They call it sleight
of hand, right?--
close up magic.
GENE TURNER: Right.
STEVE SPANGLER: You
do that so well.
GENE TURNER: Yeah, my favorite
thing is to go ahead and
remove these.
It'll sound louder to you, so go
ahead and get those out of
there for you.
Here, you hold-- never
mind, you're busy.
Just go ahead and hold your
hand out here for me.
You can put that one away.
Now, I have two red balls.
My hand's [INAUDIBLE].
I have no sleeves,
actually, today.
I will go slowly, but if you
blink, you will miss it.
Close it tightly--
just one ball.
Put it right up here.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
GENE TURNER: How many
in the hand?
STEVE SPANGLER: One.
GENE TURNER: How many in mine?
GENE TURNER: Now, mine goes
right through your elbow.
My hands are empty.
Check it out.
Just one.
Right.
See, I'm a man of my word.
I said mine would go through
your elbow, and mine went
right through your elbow.
Hands out.
I went too quickly.
I'll slow it down.
Two hands empty.
I'll hold this one.
You hold that one tightly.
Now, this one goes
to my pocket.
It really goes down
there, see?
The hand's empty.
Watch that elbow--
scientific principle--
centrifugal force.
You feel anything go in,
anything leave, let me know.
Put both hands together.
How many red balls
in your hand?
STEVE SPANGLER: Two.
GENE TURNER: Right.
Absolutely.
Now, there are two.
See, this one goes in,
that one goes in.
How many here, again?
I went too quickly.
STEVE SPANGLER: I--I--I
All right.
I'm confused.
GENE TURNER: I don't
understand it.
I don't understand it.
Well, listen, I was going
to let you know,
too, I found this.
I don't know if you've seen
that around, but I'm sorry
about that.
It's just kind of a habit.
We'll go ahead and put
that back on there.
STEVE SPANGLER: He
stole my watch.
GENE TURNER: There you go.
All right.
Do you have anything
in the [INAUDIBL
STEVE SPANGLER: Yes, I have
--pocket over there.
OK, something over there.
That's great.
OK.
Well, I'll tell you what.
I'm going to try to take the
watch again in five seconds.
Time it-- five, four, three--
that was so close.
That was so close.
Now--
STEVE SPANGLER: Can
I have my watch?
GENE TURNER: Oh, no, but
your wallet, I can give
that back to you.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to-- that wallet
came out of this pocket right
down here, but you can put
it wherever you'd like.
STEVE SPANGLER: Gosh.
GENE TURNER: Yeah, oh,
and I'm sorry.
I got the watch again.
STEVE SPANGLER: Ahhh!
GENE TURNER: You're right.
I probably should put that
back on there for you.
STEVE SPANGLER: All right.
GENE TURNER: There Ever go.
Now, I want to make sure
that's buckled,
and on there good.
STEVE SPANGLER: Yes.
You should use--
GENE TURNER: Buckled
through the loops?
STEVE SPANGLER: Yes,
it's buckled.
GENE TURNER: OK, you concentrate
on it, all right?
Bring your right hand
over, and hold this.
STEVE SPANGLER: Ahh!
GENE TURNER: All right.
We'll get started again.
STEVE SPANGLER: Oh!
GENE TURNER: [INAUDIBLE].
STEVE SPANGLER: All right.
I'm putting it on myself.
At a magic convention, just
like any other convention,
there's a trade show
room, right?
So this is called the dealers'
room or the exhibit hall.
So this is where magicians go
around from table to table and
they watch other magicians sell
tricks so that they can
put them in their acts.
And one of the most genius minds
that's out there right
now is a gentleman by the
name of Losander.
And he just does
amazing things.
All you have to do is watch,
and you're amazed.
Welcome.
LOSANDER: [INAUDIBLE]
STEVE SPANGLER: And will you
show me something very cool?
LOSANDER: Yeah.
Check out the chain.
Is it really solid?
STEVE SPANGLER: It is.
LOSANDER: Now, this here,
as you really can see is
electrical tape.
OK, so my plan is very simple.
I take a piece of the
electrical tape.
I'm to going to tie these two
fingers together, and I'm
going to do this as tight
as even possible.
Watch.
Check it out.
Is it really tight?
STEVE SPANGLER: Yeah.
Your fingers are turning red.
LOSANDER: Right, it's
turning red.
They will turn blue so
we have to hurry up.
On the count of three, OK?
One, two, three.
STEVE SPANGLER: I'm standing
right here.
I'm standing in the spot the
magician doesn't want you.
I mean, I'm right
in front of him.
LOSANDER: Yeah, it's all
in there, right?
STEVE SPANGLER: It
is in there.
LOSANDER: Now, for most people,
that was a little
fast, so let's do it again.
Let's pretend we [INAUDIBLE].
STEVE SPANGLER: Wait, hold on.
LOSANDER: Is that
a real thumb?
Check this out.
STEVE SPANGLER: Yes,
it's a real thumb.
LOSANDER: Look, I'm going to
penetrate that thumb for you.
STEVE SPANGLER: Thank you.
LOSANDER: It's going to hurt.
STEVE SPANGLER: It's going
to hurt you, right?
LOSANDER: One, two, and three.
It goes right through.
Here, please hold the chains.
One of these days,
I'll teach you.
Meanwhile, you are the only guy
at this convention who can
actually keep the
electrical tape.
[CHUCKLING]
STEVE SPANGLER: It's
really good.
This guy is good.
The cool thing is you
get to meet a
bunch of cool magicians.
I've known Danny Archer here
for years, and years, and
years-- probably 30 years
doing magic, not only
performing magic, but being
able to teach a
little bit, as well.
And I asked if maybe you'd teach
us a trick, but I want
you to blow us away first.
Show me a magic trick.
DANNY ARCHER: All right, we'll
do a trick first, and then
we'll teach you one.
Do you have some change--
a quarter, maybe?
STEVE SPANGLER: I
have a quarter.
DANNY ARCHER: Do
you have a pen?
STEVE SPANGLER: I thought you
were going to ask for a
hundred dollar bill.
DANNY ARCHER: No.
STEVE SPANGLER: I don't
have that have that.
I have a pen.
DANNY ARCHER: OK, cool.
Here's what's going to happen,
on the count of three, the
coin is going to disappear.
Don't take your eyes
off that coin.
One, two, three.
Oh, you see the quarter didn't
disappear, but [INAUDIBLE].
STEVE SPANGLER: Where's
the pen?
DANNY ARCHER: No, I'm kidding.
Right there.
If you look right there.
There's the--
STEVE SPANGLER: How
cool is that?
DANNY ARCHER: Watch the coin.
This time the coin will
disappear for real.
STEVE SPANGLER: That is cool.
DANNY ARCHER: Do you want
your quarter back?
STEVE SPANGLER: Yeah, I guess.
DANNY ARCHER: Sometimes
they [INAUDIBLE]--
hold on a minute.
STEVE SPANGLER: Look at this.
Get out of here.
[GASPING]
DANNY ARCHER: You
want it back?
STEVE SPANGLER: How in the--
that is totally good.
Now, you're really going to
teach us how to do this?
DANNY ARCHER: I'm going to teach
you how to do that--
really easy to do.
You need--
I had one quarter already
in my shoe.
STEVE SPANGLER: Get
out of here.
DANNY ARCHER: So when I
get up in the morning.
You put a quarter
in each shoe.
You're ready to do
this two times.
STEVE SPANGLER: Have you figured
this out?-- magicians
are liars, so they lie a little
bit, but that's OK.
DANNY ARCHER: We lie a lot.
STEVE SPANGLER: You lie a lot.
DANNY ARCHER: So you [INAUDIBLE]
the coin.
STEVE SPANGLER: So you start
with the coin here.
DANNY ARCHER: One
is in the shoe.
One is in each shoe.
STEVE SPANGLER: And this is
what you borrowed from me.
DANNY ARCHER: I borrowed the
coin, I borrowed the pen.
So I turn my body a little
bit, because I'm going to
secretly leave the pen behind
my ear, and if I did that
here, they would see that, so
I turn my body a little bit,
but I put all the focus
on the pen.
STEVE SPANGLER: And I'm
looking down here.
DANNY ARCHER: And I bent over a
little bit, too, on purpose.
That forces you down
a little bit.
So what I do is I come
here, and I tap my
nail or tap the pen.
And I'll just show you, here
is the exposed view.
I put it behind my ear one--
behind the ear--
two--
behind the ear-- leave
it-- three.
But that all happens when I'm
here, so I come down.
Now I come up a little bit,
and I'm holding this here.
STEVE SPANGLER: I see it.
DANNY ARCHER: So keep
the camera here.
As I start to turn around, and
I point right here, this hand
goes to the edge of
the pocket and I--
STEVE SPANGLER: You just
drop it in your pocket.
DANNY ARCHER: I just drop it
in my pocket, but all the
attention is right here.
Now, I take this off, but
I say, watch the coin.
I have no coin.
I'm tapping my thumbnail just to
make a little bit of noise
right there.
He can't hear it, but-- so
I say, watch the coin.
This time it disappears, and I
just flick this off the top of
the nail for real.
So now the coin is gone.
You give the guy the pen back.
You say, do you want it back?
Now, I didn't have one in both
shoes, but usually, if you do,
I say pick a foot.
STEVE SPANGLER: And see, that's
what blows you away is
that you go, no--
DANNY ARCHER: Pick a foot.
STEVE SPANGLER: --how
did you--
I want this foot right here.
DANNY ARCHER: I stamp
the foot like that.
I show my hands empty.
I come down.
I shake it down like that.
I let them see it
inside the shoe.
Now, a lot of times, they don't
want the coin back.
STEVE SPANGLER: No.
DANNY ARCHER: So you do this
10,000 times, you can buy
yourself a new car.
STEVE SPANGLER: Oh.
All right.
So the deal is is how many
times do you think you've
performed this until you felt
really good at doing it?
DANNY ARCHER: Probably
after 20--
30 times.
I've done it thousands
of times.
It's a great trick to
do when someone
says, do a trick, Danny.
I have none of my props on me.
STEVE SPANGLER: You
can just do it.
DANNY ARCHER: Do you
have a coin?
It doesn't have to be a coin.
It could be a bill, it can
be another small object.
Do you have a pen, a straw, a
crayon-- it could be anything.
STEVE SPANGLER: All right.
Let's challenge our
YouTube viewers.
Here's what I want to do.
You just saw Danny Archer, an
amazing magician, do this.
He taught you how to do it.
I want you to do it.
Get somebody to videotape you
doing it in front of a group
of kids at school, at work,
wherever you are.
Post it, and send it
to us, and we'll
feature it on the channel.
We're going to pick the best
one, and we'll feature it on
the channel.
DANNY ARCHER: [INAUDIBLE].
STEVE SPANGLER: Fair enough?
All right.
OK, that's your homework.
Thank you.
Nice job.
DANNY ARCHER: [INAUDIBLE]
STEVE SPANGLER: All right,
no-- away I'm done, OK.
I'm going to the bathroom.
Don't follow me in.
How many times did I tell you
no, not in the bathroom.
All right?
It's a zero kind of thing.
Hey, Eddie.
EDDIE: What's happening,
Steve?
STEVE SPANGLER: This is
going to be good.
EDDIE: This is a great
convention, isn't it?
STEVE SPANGLER: Do
a trick for me.
EDDIE: [INAUDIBLE].
STEVE SPANGLER: If you're a
real magician, do a trick.
EDDIE: I can do that.
I can do that.
Would you like me to teach you
to the trick or just do it?
This is a great one.
STEVE SPANGLER: Do you know
we're going to be in trouble
for having cameras
in the restroom.
It's just--
EDDIE: It's OK.
It's all right.
This is one of my favorites.
It's the torn restored
handkerchief trick--
napkin trick.
And what you do is before you
start, you crumple one of them
up, and you put it
in that hand.
They don't know about it.
STEVE SPANGLER: So you're
teaching this?
EDDIE: I'm going to show
you how to do it.
This is great, because we're
in the bathroom.
No one's watching.
STEVE SPANGLER: This
is awesome.
You're learning how to
do a magic trick
in the men's bathroom.
EDDIE: So what you do, is
see, now, this looks
a little bit fishy.
STEVE SPANGLER: [INAUDIBLE],
all right.
DANNY ARCHER: This
looks fishy.
See how my hand--
if I say I want to borrow one of
these papers, when you hold
it, it's not so obvious that
there's something in there,
especially if you hold
the other hand
sort of the same way.
You know what I mean?
STEVE SPANGLER: Yeah.
DANNY ARCHER: And you also
need a magic wand.
STEVE SPANGLER: I've
got a magic--
EDDIE: No, no, no.
STEVE SPANGLER: What,
you got one?
EDDIE: I've got a little--
STEVE SPANGLER: Look at you.
All right.
EDDIE: Yeah, I'll tell you,
I'm like ready to go here.
So what you do is you
start ripping up
this paper like this.
STEVE SPANGLER: If somebody
says, let me see a trick, you
just grab a napkin--
EDDIE: --and you just
stick that in there.
They don't know about that.
And you're ripping this up,
and you're doing all this
stuff, and you squeeze
it down.
So they know about this, but
they don't know about that.
STEVE SPANGLER: They
have no idea.
EDDIE: OK.
So you're standing there.
You take it in this hand.
Now, here's the cool part.
When you get the magic wand--
now, check over there-- see how
I'm switching those two?
You just go and tap like that,
and then this blows them away.
You go like that--
STEVE SPANGLER: All right,
so the wand is the total
misdirection.
EDDIE: That's it,
and that's it.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK,
but if you're--
I'm just going to tell you this
from one kind of magician
to another professional
magician, I can see it
in that hand, so--
EDDIE: You can see that?
STEVE SPANGLER: Yes.
But you gotta have-- if you're
doing this at home, you
[INAUDIBLE]--
EDDIE: There's no problem.
STEVE SPANGLER: What?
EDDIE: What you do is
you just go in, tap
that, and that one--
STEVE SPANGLER: Holy cow.
EDDIE: --goes back
[INAUDIBLE]--
STEVE SPANGLER: I have a
feeling we've been had.
[SIGHING]
EDDIE: Huh.
STEVE SPANGLER: What
a surprise.
EDDIE: It's getting
stuffy in here.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK.
Oh, sorry sir.
STEVE SPANGLER: Magicians who
do stuff with money is
fantastic, but it scares me, so
when Sean [INAUDIBLE] said,
do you have some money?--
I thought, I do have a dollar
if you want a dollar.
SEAN: Yes, can I borrow
some money?
STEVE SPANGLER: Absolutely.
SEAN: That'd be great.
STEVE SPANGLER: See, this is
where they ask me can I have
some money.
SEAN: Oh, great.
Oh, it looks like you
have more than--
you actually--
STEVE SPANGLER: I was hoping
that you would pick a dollar.
SEAN: Yeah, well, no,
that's perfect.
Cool.
Now if I could have some car
keys, that would be--
STEVE SPANGLER: Yeah, no, Gene
Turner's got the car keys.
SEAN: All right, so we have
looks like five bucks here.
STEVE SPANGLER: You can
see I'm a big spender.
SEAN: You are, yeah.
But let's face it, you
can't go very far
with five bucks, right?
STEVE SPANGLER: Yes, it's my
allowance for the week, so--
SEAN: The value menu's not
even a value these days.
But this is what I do.
OK, watch.
OK, ready?
STEVE SPANGLER: Yes.
SEAN: Whoosh!
Just like that.
Yeah.
That's $100, $200,
$300, $400--
that's $500 right there.
STEVE SPANGLER: See, if you only
knew where he lived, you
would know what I know, and
that is, I give him five
bucks, he gives me $500,
and the trick is
over, I would assume.
SEAN: Well, let's face it, you
know, because you don't want
to walk around with--
I mean, you want to walk around
with $500, it's just
not a good idea to walk
around with $500.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK, if I've
got five bills, and I'm
walking in here, they're
going to be gone.
SEAN: Have you see this crowd?
STEVE SPANGLER: Yeah,
they're a bunch of
cheaters and stealers.
SEAN: That Gene guy, he'd
totally go for this, which is
why I just carry the ones, and
that way, if I'm mugged, you
know, then I'm only out
five bucks, so--
STEVE SPANGLER: This is--
that's it?
SEAN: There you go.
You can have that.
Get yourself something nice.
STEVE SPANGLER: [SIGHING]
Do you see why it's frustrating
to be at a magic
convention?
SEAN: [CHUCKLING]
LOSANDER: Harry Houdini, right,
in his later years, was
kind of like obsessed with
collecting [INAUDIBLE].
STEVE SPANGLER: Right.
And this is Harry Houdini.
LOSANDER: Yeah, that's
Harry Houdini.
He created this device.
It's like a cabinet-- and
a very simple one.
There is a chalkboard, chalk
hanging on the string.
STEVE SPANGLER: So it's
just a piece of chalk.
LOSANDER: Exactly.
So, of course, we do not want
to necessarily contact his
dead mother--
[CHUCKLING]
but--
STEVE SPANGLER: --because
she would be angry.
LOSANDER: Yeah, she'd
be angry.
If you see a dice, what
number do you see?
STEVE SPANGLER: Like
a regular die?
Number six.
LOSANDER: Number six.
Was that your choice or
did I manipulate you?
STEVE SPANGLER: No.
I just see the number six.
LOSANDER: Right.
This one here is just a cloth.
It has nothing to do with the
trick, per se, but Harry
Houdini used to perform in
complete darkness, so that's
why we're using this to
cover up the cabinet,
OK, just like so.
Now, there was usually a long
meditation involved, but then
he found out, just the simple
word "spirit" would actually
do the trick [INAUDIBLE].
STEVE SPANGLER: Would
you look at that?
Wow.
Absolutely amazing.
I'm here to tell you there are
absolutely no strings.
LOSANDER: And that's quite
unusual because Harry Houdini
could only do this in complete
darkness, but-- ooh!--
sometimes he'd get
carried away.
Gotta be careful.
But that's true to the fact
that he may actually
[INAUDIBLE] contact.
[INAUDIBLE].
STEVE SPANGLER: I'm standing
right here.
LOSANDER: Yeah.
STEVE SPANGLER: You're
amazing.
LOSANDER: Right.
Thank you.
STEVE SPANGLER: And this is why
the people around here at
the table want to have your
secrets, so to speak.
LOSANDER: So to speak, yes.
STEVE SPANGLER: Now you know.
Well, one of the things that
magicians want to do is to
make sure the art is preserved,
and so that's why
they're always attracting
young magicians.
And this young man here, Max
Davidson's, been doing magic
more than half of your life.
So you've been six and a half
years, which means you're 12
years old, right?
Psychic powers.
I can't turn the ones
into hundreds, but
I got psychic powers.
And you have just rope
in your hand.
Show me what you're
going to do.
MAX DAVIDSON: All right.
So this is a cool little
effect with
three pieces of rope.
We have a short rope--
if you check that out--
a long rope--
STEVE SPANGLER: Good,
a long rope.
MAX DAVIDSON: --and
a medium rope.
So if I could just have
the long rope for me.
This is the long rope
right here.
This is the short rope, and then
in your hand, you have
the medium rope.
[INAUDIBLE] see that--
wonderful.
So this is actually
quite interesting.
All we have to do is give the
rope a pull, just like this,
and they change into the
same exact size.
You see, now, the short one is
the same size as the long one,
which is the same size
as the medium rope.
STEVE SPANGLER: I checked them
and they don't stretch.
MAX DAVIDSON: They don't
stretch, do they?
So three ropes is a bit
confusing to follow because
you have two eyes, so we'll
just go with two.
As a matter of fact,
so is two ropes.
That's hard to follow, so
let's just start out
with one, like this.
STEVE SPANGLER: Wow.
MAX DAVIDSON: Now, here's what
I'll do is take the rope and
tie it into a loop,
like this, OK?
I have a ring.
If you could check
that out for me.
It's a solid, good ring?
STEVE SPANGLER: It is.
MAX DAVIDSON: Any holes?
STEVE SPANGLER: No.
MAX DAVIDSON: There's
that one.
STEVE SPANGLER: How
did I know?
MAX DAVIDSON: [INAUDIBLE]
you know that joke.
All right, what we do is take
the knot, just like this.
Place it through the ring.
That's all we have to do.
Give it a blow, and the ring
actually just melts onto the
rope, like that.
STEVE SPANGLER: Wow.
MAX DAVIDSON: Now, it's
really on there.
If you can just give
that a pull.
STEVE SPANGLER: It
is on there.
MAX DAVIDSON: It is.
OK.
So, watch, we can take it
off just as easily.
I'll blow like that, and the
ring is off the rope.
If you want to check that
out again, feel free.
STEVE SPANGLER: The kid's
only 12 years old.
MAX DAVIDSON: Here, let
me show you how I get
the ring on the rope.
This is really cool.
You see, what I do, it's
with the middle.
I just take the middle
off the rope.
Then I take the ring, and I
put it on, and I take the
middle, and I just put
it back on like that.
Now, sometimes the middle won't
come off, so this is
what I have to do, is actually
take the ends off
the road like that.
And that leaves me with an
infinite loop of rope.
You know, it makes no sense.
I've got an infinite
loop of rope.
The funny thing is you can't
really get a knot in an
infinite loop of rope.
STEVE SPANGLER: Wow.
MAX DAVIDSON: --unless you have
ends, which I have in my
pocket, so we'll take those and
stick them on just like
that, so the knot
becomes reality.
Now, here's how you get
the loop of rope.
You just need some static
electricity, so if you get a
little from here and a little
from here, you get that
infinite loop of rope.
Now, you need ends, and I had
those in my pocket, so we'll
take the ends and just put them
on the rope like that.
I'll show you that again
in slow motion.
You just take the ends off the
rope, and then putting them on
is just as easy.
You just give them
a tie like that.
And then they're on the rope.
Now, remember, we started out
with three ropes, right?
So there's one on my shoulder.
The ends go in this hand,
the middle in this hand.
Actually, if I take my fingers
like scissors, just like this,
I can cut the rope into
two ropes like this.
Now, two ropes of the exact
same size change into two
ropes of different sizes, and
then back to one rope.
I'll do that one more
time, except I want
you to cut it, OK?
Ends go in this hand, the middle
goes in this hand.
Take your fingers
like scissors.
STEVE SPANGLER: Like this?
MAX DAVIDSON: Yeah, yeah.
Just cut the rope-- perfect--
just like that--
into two ropes.
Now, what I'm going to to is
change them back to a short
rope, a long rope, and
a medium rope.
This is the short rope
and the long rope.
I'm going to change--
STEVE SPANGLER: This is
the short and long?
MAX DAVIDSON: Yeah, yeah, but if
you blink, you'll miss it.
So don't blink, but you actually
might have already
because the knot isn't in
the middle anymore.
It's actually on the end,
leaving us with a short rope--
STEVE SPANGLER: Look
at this one.
MAX DAVIDSON: --a long rope,
and a medium rope.
STEVE SPANGLER: You
are amazing.
You understand what a
little practice--
the guy blows your mind,
and I'm right here.
All right, cut.
Show me how to do this.
So if you want to try to stump
a magician, you grab them at
the most inopportune time.
You go, show me trick.
And so Chad Wonder, Nickelodeon
Entertainer the
Year, is grabbing a coffee,
and I go, stop, show me a
trick, and so, here
we are here.
And if you can catch them this
way, you know they're good.
All right.
CHAD WONDER: OK.
STEVE SPANGLER: Please,
Chad, show me a trick.
CHAD WONDER: So check
out nickels.
This is a trick about nickels.
So just make sure we
got nickels there.
STEVE SPANGLER: We do.
We've got nickels.
They look like they're
real nickels.
CHAD WONDER: And then
check this out.
That's the important part.
That is the old cap that--
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
STEVE SPANGLER: It's
just a cap?
CHAD WONDER: Well, it's
actually from a gun--
this was the back of a gun--
anyway, long story.
STEVE SPANGLER: I understand.
CHAD WONDER: It fits
perfectly--
hold on.
STEVE SPANGLER: So
magicians tinker
around with stuff, right?
You're always looking for--
CHAD WONDER: [INAUDIBLE]
like this.
STEVE SPANGLER: Where would you
find a cap that goes over
and it goes--
CHAD WONDER: Well, my grandpa
was on a battleship, and these
are the little things
that fell off.
STEVE SPANGLER: Too
much information.
CHAD WONDER: All right,
here we go.
So we're going to do this, and
then you get that right over
the nickels, and then this
is the part where
everybody gets fooled.
I make them disappear
just like that.
See [INAUDIBLE] was--
STEVE SPANGLER: I'm
going to tell you,
I saw you do something.
I saw you kind of slip something
in underneath.
CHAD WONDER: Uh--
STEVE SPANGLER: I mean,
I'm not trying to--
CHAD WONDER: But look--
they're gone.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK, I know
they're gone, but I saw you
shoot something under
your hand.
I mean, I'm not trying to be a
jerk about it, but I saw you
put something under your hand.
CHAD WONDER: Steve, you're
supposed to be helping me out.
STEVE SPANGLER: It doesn't
have to make the cut.
I mean, if you don't
want to do it--
CHAD WONDER: All right, well,
I turned them into dimes.
STEVE SPANGLER: [CHUCKLING]
CHAD WONDER: But,
wait, hold on.
Here's the thing-- the nickels
are still here.
You just have to-- they're
really big
and jammed in there.
Check it out.
Look in there really hard, OK?
STEVE SPANGLER: Look at this.
They are not big in there, and
they're not jammed in there.
CHAD WONDER: Look, I'll
show you why.
I'll shake them out for you.
There you go.
See, it's right there.
STEVE SPANGLER: Why do I think
I fell for this one hook,
line, and sinker?
Now I'm going to get a coffee.
CHAD WONDER: I'll get
one with you.
STEVE SPANGLER: John T. Sheets
is an amazing magician that
does a stage act with doves
that appear everywhere.
But you also are a master of
closeup magic, as well.
And I stopped you and said, show
me something, and you've
got something with quarters.
JOHN T. SHEETS: I do.
I've got a couple
quarters here.
And if you will, take one,
and it's a free choice.
That is a regular coin.
Now, we could use your coin or
mine, but we'll just use this.
If you will, take the pen.
STEVE SPANGLER: I'm telling
you it's real.
JOHN T. SHEETS: It
is a real coin.
So take that and write your
initials on the coin.
Now, you can write it
on one side or both.
It's totally up to you.
Now, what you've done is you've
identified it, so
there's no other coin in the
world that looks like that.
I'll take the pen.
Go ahead and show that around.
Show it to these people.
show it to the camera.
Now, there's no way I could have
made those marks on there
before you got here, right?
STEVE SPANGLER: Not at all.
JOHN T. SHEETS: Perfect.
I'll take the coin.
Now, do you know what
a quarter's
made out of by chance?
STEVE SPANGLER: I don't know.
There's maybe some zinc
in there, you think?
JOHN T. SHEETS: Nickel
and copper.
You know that you can't
[INAUDIBLE], right?
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
JOHN T. SHEETS: What you're
supposed to know the science.
STEVE SPANGLER: I'm
sorry, yeah.
JOHN T. SHEETS: It's all good.
Look, nothing else
in my hands--
just the coin.
Steve, if you will, hold
out your hand, and your
initials are there.
No other coin in the world that
looks like this, but if
you watch--
STEVE SPANGLER: Oh, my gosh.
JOHN T. SHEETS: It's now bent.
The same quarter, the
same initials--
STEVE SPANGLER: I will promise
you, yes, it is.
JOHN T. SHEETS: It's now
a lucky souvenir.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK, you
look at it, ma'am.
FEMALE SPEAKER: That's
amazing.
STEVE SPANGLER: It's
really bent, right?
FEMALE SPEAKER: It's
really bent.
JOHN T. SHEETS: That's
a lucky souvenir, and
that's my gift to you.
If you keep it, it will
bring you good luck.
STEVE SPANGLER: I'm going to
have a lot of good luck.
How does he bend a quarter?
There's a theme of young
magicians here at this
conference, and magicians
have big conferences.
And the Society of American
Magicians--
SAM-- is a big deal.
And they got a hold of this
young man, Tommy Walker, who
is in ninth grade.
Good.
Actually, a student of
my father's, right?
TOMMY WALKER: Yeah.
STEVE SPANGLER: How
cool is that?
TOMMY WALKER: [INAUDIBLE].
STEVE SPANGLER: Will you show
us some cool card magic?
TOMMY WALKER: Absolutely.
Would you take a card?
STEVE SPANGLER: Absolutely.
TOMMY WALKER: All right, go
ahead and memorize it.
Don't show it to me.
Show it to the camera.
STEVE SPANGLER: Got it.
TOMMY WALKER: All right, put
it back in the deck.
I'll bury it in there.
I'll mix up the cards.
Give that a shuffle
just like that.
STEVE SPANGLER: Pretty
fancy work.
TOMMY WALKER: Now, if I just
snap, your card comes all the
way up to the top.
STEVE SPANGLER: No, that's
not my card.
TOMMY WALKER: You're serious?
STEVE SPANGLER: I mean,
I could lie.
TOMMY WALKER: [INAUDIBLE].
STEVE SPANGLER: That's
not my card.
TOMMY WALKER: Could you
hold open your hand?
All right, I'll put
your card there.
Cover it up with your
other hand.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK, but
that's not my card.
TOMMY WALKER: Yeah, we'll
try it again.
It always works the
second time.
Watch.
I just snap.
It comes all the way
up to the top.
STEVE SPANGLER: No, that's--
wait-- that was--
TOMMY WALKER: Take a
look in your hand.
STEVE SPANGLER: That's
my card.
That's amazing.
TOMMY WALKER: Thank you.
STEVE SPANGLER: Wait-- that
happened in my hand.
You put that card--
do I have my wallet still?
You know when you're at a
magic convention, these
magicians take over
the entire hotel.
You'll find them, well, you've
seen them in the bathroom, at
the bar, the front lobby.
Brian Daniel South not only is
a great magician, but he came
up with this idea of teaching
teachers how to do magic in
the classroom.
So if you see a teacher that's
doing magic in the classroom,
pretty good idea that they were
part of your Teach by
Magic program.
So I have to ask you, will you
teach me how to do a trick?
BRIAN DANIEL SOUTH:
I'd love to.
STEVE SPANGLER: Teach our
viewers how to do a trick.
BRIAN DANIEL SOUTH: We're going
to do a real simple
trick with a rope.
And it's not even a trick
so much as it is
kind of a circus stunt.
The idea is that I'm going to
tie a knot in a piece of rope
just by waving it
just like that.
See, that'd be pretty
good, right?
STEVE SPANGLER: That'd be
awesome if you could do that.
BRIAN DANIEL SOUTH: So
if I just do that.
STEVE SPANGLER: [INAUDIBLE]
been working one hand.
BRIAN DANIEL SOUTH: Just
one hand, yeah.
You can even put one hand
behind your back.
I've been practicing this one.
It's kind of new, and that's the
idea is that we can learn
simple little tricks like this,
but it doesn't always
work the first time.
And that's the idea you can
share with your students.
Sometimes you have to practice
and you just wave it, ta-da!
STEVE SPANGLER: Nice job.
BRIAN DANIEL SOUTH: And then
you'll have the knot just like
that, so I like to use this one
with teachers because it
shows how simple magic can be.
It might look like it took a lot
of practice, and a lot of
hard work, and I've been
studying for years how to wave
a rope to make a knot, but the
simple secret was I had it in
my hand the whole time.
STEVE SPANGLER: So that's it?
So all you're doing is holding
it, but all the time, I never
once questioned what you
were doing, so I'm
just doing this thing.
BRIAN DANIEL SOUTH: I have
a rope with no knots.
I had a rope.
STEVE SPANGLER: So what if a
kid's, like, doing this to you
all the time?
BRIAN DANIEL SOUTH: Yeah,
that makes it more fun.
STEVE SPANGLER: Yeah,
that's more fun.
BRIAN DANIEL SOUTH: It's
more interactive.
STEVE SPANGLER: But you grab it
like that, and then all the
sudden, ta-da, but you have to
use your kind of flourish.
BRIAN DANIEL SOUTH: Yeah, you
got to, you know, build it up.
That's what magic's all
about-- the show.
STEVE SPANGLER: Because if you
just do that, then everybody
catches it.
BRIAN DANIEL SOUTH: If I just
said, here, have a rope, and
there's a knot, that's not
going to fool anyone.
STEVE SPANGLER: But if you
could really do it with
sleight of hand,
that would be--
I mean, can a real magician
actually-- is there a weight
in the [INAUDIBLE]--
BRIAN DANIEL SOUTH: That
would be [INAUDIBLE]--
STEVE SPANGLER: --with
manipulation?
BRIAN DANIEL SOUTH:
Well, let's see.
Let's try it out here.
We're going to take
out the knot.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
STEVE SPANGLER: Wait,
let me see.
[INAUDIBLE].
BRIAN DANIEL SOUTH: Oh, yeah,
he's got [INAUDIBLE] sneaky.
STEVE SPANGLER: All right.
There is no knot.
BRIAN DANIEL SOUTH: No knot.
STEVE SPANGLER: I promise,
there's no knot.
BRIAN DANIEL SOUTH: All right,
so we're going to do the never
got [INAUDIBLE] thing, right?
Here we go.
No knot.
Watch.
Just like that.
STEVE SPANGLER: (WHISPERING)
Bam!
See what happens when
you practice?
You get to be that good.
So this is what's so great about
Magic in the Rockies.
You see cool people.
This guy started this.
[INAUDIBLE] is there.
MALE SPEAKER: Steve, you're
exposing magic.
STEVE SPANGLER: No, I haven't.
I've just been showing
the tricks.
MALE SPEAKER: You're not
supposed to-- get the camera
out of here.
You're out of here.
STEVE SPANGLER: No, I'm just--
MALE SPEAKER: Burn the
frickin' tapes.
Out of here-- no.
STEVE SPANGLER: No.
Run, [INAUDIBLE] run!
Get out of here!
[INAUDIBLE].
[MUSIC PLAYING]
STEVE SPANGLER: The microphone's
back here, if you
want me to switch sides.
GENE TURNER: Bring the
keys over here.
That way, again, I don't have to
cross over in front of you.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK, so where
do you want the keys?
GENE TURNER: Just put them in
this pocket right here.
STEVE SPANGLER: So
hold on a second.
I have to find where keys are.
GENE TURNER: Oh, I'm sorry.
STEVE SPANGLER: Oh!
GENE TURNER: I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.