EDDIE ELGUERA: After the skate
camp was over, we started
coming back, and I had
to get back home.
We had been gone all summer.
And then I kind of was moving
in another direction in my
life, and from that time, he
went down to San Diego and
started living there at
the H-Street House.
And he just kind of went
off, and I was excited.
ALPHONZO RAWLS: And after that
summer, he just never even
went back home.
I mean, to this day he just
never went back home.
Sometimes he'd get stranded at
the H-Street House, and so he
would call me, like Alph,
what are you doing?
Come pick me up.
Let's go skate, let's
go skate, whatever.
And so we started kind
of hanging out.
I'd come out and pick him up.
And show him all the local
spots around and stuff.
ERIC KOSTON: I skated
with him a lot, just
those H-Street days.
And we were filming
a lot together.
I was just living at the
H-Street House at that point.
And I was 16, probably still.
ALPHONZO RAWLS: Coincidentally,
here's
something that some people might
not know about me and
Eric, but coincidentally, we
were born in the same hospital
in Bangkok, Thailand.
My mom's Thai, and Eric's
mom's Thai.
I was talking to my mom, and she
said, yeah, I mean, at the
time, that was the only
hospital in Bangkok.
So it was kind of interesting to
find that out years after.
Yeah, I mean, we hung
out every day.
We're close buds.
I mean, he was like,
that was my dude.
You know what I mean?
We hung out every day, and we
just did a lot of things
together, and stuff.
And so we kept each
other motivated to
keep this thing moving.
I actually got sponsored
for skating vert.
I mean, not that I labeled
myself a vert skater, but all
in all, we always skated
everything.
Whatever was available to us.
I mean, back in the days, it
was kind of like that.
I mean, it wasn't like you're
a vert skater or a street
skater, or whatever.
For the most part, everyone
skated everything.
ERIC KOSTON: No, I think skating
with him just helped
me get better on tranny.
When I grew up, in that time,
you skated everything anyways.
You know, you still didn't
have to sort of define
yourself as like a street
or a vert dude.
I just wanted to be good
at everything.
I mean, vert was one of the
toughest things, though, for
me, for sure.
But I want to be good
on everything.
ALPHONZO RAWLS: You know, the
thing that I noticed about
Koston growing up is he's just
one of those dudes that's kind
of good at whatever he does.
The kids these days would
be amazed at how sick
Koston is on vert.
He's gotten more recognition
for his street skating, but
all in all, I mean, he can
really skate anything.
I bet he'd be able to even skate
Mega Ramp if wanted to.
Anything I'd ever seen
him try to do,
he was good at naturally.
But it was almost depressing,
like, I'd be trying a trick or
whatever, and he'd come up
just goofing around.
He's just come through and just
do to manual, or out of a
manual, or something.
He's just that good.
ATIBA JEFFERSON:
I knew of Eric.
Like, I was a huge beyond fan.
Like, Koston was a god.
Koston was my favorite
skater as a kid.
Number one.
His H-Street part, I loved
his H-Street part.
It was like, dude, this
dude's the best.
MALE SPEAKER: Was H-Street
Next the video that you
actually like, went out
and filmed for?
Your first time filming
a part?
ERIC KOSTON: Yeah, yeah.
I remember going out and filming
with Ternasky when he
was still at H-Street,
you know?
Then he broke out and did Plan
B. By then we'd found out Plan
B was being formed.
It's like, yeah,
Eddie told me.
He's like yeah, they're
starting a company.
Ternasky's leaving.
GUY MARIANO: I'm sure like, Mike
Ternasky was really good
with picking out dudes that
still, to this day, are in the
industry, and like some of the
best, you know what I mean?
And I'm sure Mike Ternasky had
his eye on Eric, and wanted
him on the team.
That would have been amazing to
see like, Koston on Plan B.
I've never even thought of that,
but like, just when you
said that, I'm just like wow,
that would be amazing.
AARON MEZA: James Kelch was
like, I'm trying to get on
Plan B. That's why
I was filming.
He wanted me to film him for a
sponsor video, and he said
Plan B was going to be like, the
dudes that are on it, the
people that everybody
knows that are on.
And he said like, also
like Jason Carney.
And I think he said
Eric Koston.
And that's probably the first
time that it had maybe dawned
on me that Eric must
be really good.
MIKE CARROLL: I knew Mike wanted
to put him on Plan B,
and I think he was in the
name of the ams, or
something like that.
But I didn't really know
him that well, so I
was just like, oh.
MALE SPEAKER: But do you think
that was more because you
didn't know him, or more--
MIKE CARROLL: I think it was
more just because I just
didn't really know him.
I just didn't really care.
You know what I mean?
Because I know people have
always given me shit.
Like, oh, you didn't
want him on.
But I mean, that was just more
about, like, I knew Shawn.
I knew Rick, you know?
So I was just like, let's
put these people on.
GUY MARIANO: And especially at
that time, everybody was
really young.
There was like, a lot of shit
talkers and whatnot.
With any person that's really
good at what they do, people
are going to be intimidated, and
they're going to fear it a
little bit.
It was just probably people
jealous that he was such a
good skater trying to hate on
him, you know what I mean?
MALE SPEAKER: Was there talk
of you going to Plan B?
ERIC KOSTON: Yeah.
It was crazy.
I was with Eddie, and we
drove to the contest.
Tony Mag wants me to
enter the contest.
I was like, I don't want
to enter the contest.
I don't want to be pro.
Like, I'm not ready
to be a pro.
Like, if I do this, I'm pro.
That's what it was.
It was like, a contest,
you know?
Ternasky pulls me aside
and goes, hey man.
Don't enter this contest.
I want you to ride for Plan B.
I want you to be an am for
Plan B. There was the pressure
that quitting, being 16 and
like, having to turn pro
all like in one day.
I'm with Eddie.
He wants me to like, just,
you know, say no.
Quit on the spot.
Ternasky's like, Eddie
will understand.
I was like, dude, I can't
do that to Eddie.
I can't, you know?
Like, I can't quit H-Street.
I can't.
EDDIE ELGUERA: Yeah.
It's one of those things that,
you know, when you're that
good, everybody's going
to come at you.
I think what he did was great.
I think he did it
the right way.
GUY MARIANO: Eric didn't just
like, bounce at the first
opportunity to go in this super
team that was being
created, you know what I mean?
That's cool that Eric had some
loyalty at such a young age,
when a lot of people were
bouncing around.
ALPHONZO RAWLS: After half the
crew broke apart and did Plan
B, there was a greater
appreciation for the people
that remained.
For whatever reason, Tony Mag
kind of valued me more than
Koston in regards, to you know,
what he wanted to pay
him and stuff.
And so I think I might have
convinced Mag, if we were
hoping to be a brand for any
more time, you know,
definitely Koston is
the main dude.
Let's give him more money.
ERIC KOSTON: I remember Alphonzo
going to Tony, like
sort of strong arming
him, like, you've
got to pay Eric more.
We're going to get
an apartment.
He was living with his mom, so
he kind of strong armed Tony
to pay me like, $500 a month
so I can cover some rent.
MALE SPEAKER: You were
pro for H-Street.
ERIC KOSTON: I was pro.
MALE SPEAKER: Did you have
a board on H-Street?
ERIC KOSTON: I had a board, and
it was like this horrible,
like greeting card.
It was like, an old lady
all wrinkled up.
It was just a bad
illustration.
And I was like, oh,
this is funny.
This would be a funny graphic,
being a kid.
Tony, should we make
this as a graphic?
And that's how simple
it was back then.
It didn't come out
until I quit.
A few of them leaked,
and kind of got out.
A couple hundred, I guess.
They did get to shops.
ATIBA JEFFERSON: I remember his
first board on H-Street,
though, at the state
shop I worked at.
Had the grandma.
It wouldn't sell, because like
right when that board came
out, he was on 101.
So everyone was like, 101.
And it sucks to this day,
because I wish that I would
have grabbed that board,
not knowing.
ERIC KOSTON: Years ago, Pat
Chanita had come up to me and
said, hey man, I got
one of your boards.
I stole it from Tony.
I got your first
H-Street board.
I want to give it to you.
And Pat Chanita had stolen
it, and he wanted
to give it to me.
And he gave it to me, finally.
It finally got to me.
Yeah, it was sick that he
thought that I would want it.
And I did.
I was like, dude,
yeah, totally.
ATIBA JEFFERSON: It wouldn't
even sell.
We ended up like,
giving it away.
And this is when no one
got a free board.
That was like, unheard of.
I remember my friends from
Deluxe would send me a board,
and I'd be like, oh my god.
I just got a free board.