Next up, we head to Sin City in
search of some of that old
Vegas magic.
This is me in the back of a
pickup truck in the middle of
the Nevada desert.
We were on our way to Las Vegas
for something called the
International Lingerie Show, an
event billed as a three-day
spectacular showcasing the
latest in cutting edge
lingerie design.
Before we left, a friend of
mine, the celebrated fashion
photographer Alice Hawkins, said
I must make a stop at her
friend Mark Hayward's house
in Tecopa, Death Valley.
Mark had spent a lot of time
in the city but found it
overwhelming, and so disappeared
into the desert to
live a life of solitude.
Alice told me he'd have some
sagely advice about Vegas
which would be invaluable
to our trip.
How would you feel if you had
to go to Vegas tomorrow and
walk around the strip?
MARK: I'd feel like
I was in hell.
It's like walking
through hell.
You go into the city, and in
a few hours' time, all your
finest sensitivities
are blunted.
You begin to feel more
and more inhuman.
More like a robot.
Sex is very powerful.
We should always beware and feel
a deep reverence for the
power of sex.
It's the source of all
our creativity.
Either way, it can bring
it to a downfall.
CHARLET: The Vegas economy
is currently ranked
worst in the nation.
Local industry has gone to great
pains to keep the money
coming in, and nowhere is this
more apparent than in the
field of adult entertainment.
The extravagant glamour of
years gone by has been
replaced by a stripped-down
version, where less has
definitely become more.
So I have a bit of a personal
love affair with lingerie
because when I was at uni, I
worked part time for three
years in Agent Provocateur.
I know everything
about lingerie.
There's nothing you
can teach me.
I've got enough knickers
to last me a lifetime.
But maybe where lingerie is at
now has changed, so let's see.
The moment I stepped into the
badly lit exhibition center, I
realized this was about
as far away from
sexy as could be imagined.
So this is Dennis.
He's lived in Vegas
for 11 years.
DENNIS: I've been coming to
the International Lingerie
Show for three years now.
I've attended a lot of the other
adult-oriented shows.
These are some of the samples
that this booth is nice enough
to give out.
And they make excellent
quality garments.
CHARLET: Which pink?
DENNIS: Oh, this pink
right here.
CHARLET: Why?
MARK: Something dynamic
that stands out.
This is Las Vegas, and you want
to be colorful and bright
and make the right impression
in Las Vegas.
CHARLET: Do you like thongs?
DENNIS: I love thongs,
absolutely.
Now for me, a thong
covers a bit too
much, but they're nice.
They're quite fond of offering
you a piece of ass here.
Am I right?
CHARLET: I'm eating ass.
DENNIS: Right here is one
of the newer ones.
They have some of the state
of the art stuff.
They also have devices
for the gentleman.
The pleasure flesh is very
close to the real thing.
CHARLET: Have you ever tried
anything like that?
Do you speak from experience?
DENNIS: Oh, I speak from
a great experience.
CHARLET: This stall seems to
be bona fide lingerie.
This is unusual lingerie.
Is this a bra or underwear?
FEMALE SPEAKER: That would
be crotchless.
CHARLET: Oh, yes.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yes.
CHARLET: Can we talk
about this?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Oh, yeah.
CHARLET: Is this for women?
FEMALE SPEAKER: No, this
is for the boys.
They have quite a
few of these.
They've got an elephant,
they have a candy cane.
CHARLET: Is this to make it--
your bits look less
intimidating?
FEMALE SPEAKER: I just hope
they can fill it up.
CHARLET: This is Andrew,
Mr. Gorgeous.
ANDREW: Yes.
I just got in from a fun
night of partying.
I feel amazing.
I'm here to model my friend's
skin line called Skin Couture,
which is what I have
right here.
CHARLET: It says "Every saint
has a past, every sinner has a
future." What's going
on on your butt?
It says Don't.
Is that a tease,
like oh don't?
Or is it actually don't?
ANDREW: It's don't, like
I'm not easy like that.
Don't.
Get away, I'm not available
like that.
But I like the bathing suit.
CHARLET: Ah.
What is this company that
you're modeling for?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Well, the
company is called Shibue
Couture, and it's the first
strapless panty.
It's a silicone-based
adhesive miracle.
CHARLET: Ah!
FEMALE SPEAKER: Stays on.
Sometimes you like a little
bit of modesty,
just a little bit.
MALE SPEAKER: [YELLING]
$5 samples!
Come and get them!
CHARLET: I thought you
said blow jobs.
So, no blow jobs?
MALE SPEAKER: Well, now that
you're here, we could probably
arrange something.
Can I take a bathroom
break, boss?
CHARLET: Bye!
MALE SPEAKER: All talk
and no action.
CHARLET: I wasn't exactly
impressed by what I'd seen.
If this was how far lingerie
had come, I was depressed.
When three giant plasters
actually constitute lingerie,
I think you've hit
rock bottom.
During the expo, one thing
did catch my eye.
Nestled in between all the sex
toys and crotchless panties
was a poster for something
called the LFL, or Lingerie
Football League.
After making a few phone calls,
we were invited to go
and crash the training session
for local team
the Las Vegas Sin.
ANNOUNCER: Here she is,
first down and more.
Inside the 10, 5, Las Vegas has
scored their first touchdown.
ANTHONY: Over the years, since
I've coached women's football,
I've learned every woman's
different.
We're probably one of few
coaches who really just
understands life.
And we let the women
live their lives.
HEATHER: I really trust what
Coach Hac does with
everything with me.
So if I'm a quarterback slot
receiver, I trust what he does
and I know that it's for
the best for the team.
ANTHONY: As a coach, I have to
look beyond the whole lingerie
aspect of it, and just
look at the athlete.
ANNOUNCER: Look at her go!
She's everything!
She has it all!
She's got the moves, she's
got the speed,
she's got the power!
CHARLET: Is it not ever
a bit impractical?
MADDIE: I've never had anything
been pulled out or
showed out, but I've seen it.
CHARLET: Are your
fans mainly men?
MADDIE: Yes.
They go there for bachelor
parties, big groups of guys.
CHARLET: So it's not as violent,
maybe, as the male--
MADDIE: No, it is.
CHARLET: --equivalent?
It is?
MADDIE: Yeah.
We hit like men, but we
have less padding on.
So it actually hurts
a lot worse.
It sucks.
TAMICA: And I just love the fact
that it allows women to
still compete at a high
level of sports, and
it's extremely sexy.
Because it's still a new league,
there's still a lot of
people who have their doubts.
They'll consider it a powderpuff
league, but it
really isn't.
The ladies out here are really
hard, rough, and just
beautiful and competitive
and it's amazing.
CHARLET: It's very hot.
DION: Yes.
It's Las Vegas.
CHARLET: These are a bit
sexy, aren't they?
DION: Put the right foot up,
right foot up, right foot up.
There you go, looking at her.
And getting ready to run.
Ready?
There you go.
Three steps-- one, two, three.
Go out.
Now go deep.
Go deep.
Keep running, keep running.
Keep running.
Go get it.
Ahh!
What is that?
CHARLET: Didn't you just
think oh, this sounds
like a bit of a gimmick?
These girls are just going to
be flapping around, they're
not into that--
DION: The first group of
girls was a gimmick.
They were really models.
So now you have real athletes
that have ran track, who have
done softball, volleyball, and
now they're learning the game
of football.
CHARLET: How important is the
lingerie to this whole thing?
DION: You bring football
and women together?
Sexy women and football
together?
That's every man's
fantasy, right?
ANNOUNCER: Touchdown, Vegas.
CHARLET: I caught it!
Didn't you see?
ANNOUNCER: One more time,
Vegas just puts on the
exclamation point.
CHARLET: Team on me!
MALE SPEAKER: Team on three.
CHARLET: Team on three!
FEMALE SPEAKER: Say
one, two, three.
CHARLET: One, two, three--
FOOTBALL PLAYERS: Team!
CHARLET: So this is Strings.
Ever heard of it?
Me neither.
But it's actually the number one
manufacturer and supplier
of g-strings to the
Nevada state area.
Apparently, times were tough in
the g-string business, and
ownership had changed hands
several times over the years.
Do you live here?
LEO: Yes, I've been living
in Vegas for
about four years now.
I had to reinvent myself, so
I came out to Vegas, and I
reinvented myself.
CHARLET: How's it doing,
the reinvention?
LEO: It's working well.
I'm still here!
CHARLET: Do you think it's a
better quality of life here?
LEO: It all depends what
you're looking for.
I'm single, footloose,
fancy-free, with no luggage.
There's entertainment here.
Of course, there's family
entertainment, but I'm not
here for family entertainment.
I like a 24-hour city where I
could choose the level of
entertainment that I'm looking
for and [INAUDIBLE] the danger
I'd like to get involved with,
if you know what I mean.
FEMALE SPEAKER: And you can
play with Little Bo Peep!
LEO: Oh, my, yes!
Let's see.
Come on out here.
FEMALE SPEAKER: How
does it feel?
LEO: That's beautiful.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Oh,
it's super cute.
LEO: Oh, that's outstanding.
FEMALE SPEAKER: I just
need my little sheep.
MIKE: We invented
the sexy bikini.
We invented the scrunch.
We changed the way everyone
wears their stuff, and copies
us from Vegas.
The trend in Vegas is less and
less and less and smaller,
because they're all trying to
get the money, which is hard
to get right now because
of the economy.
If they make a lot of money one
night wearing something,
that will become their lucky
set of clothes, and they'll
just wear that every day because
they think it's lucky.
I don't think the guys
in the club really
care what you're wearing.
This is a tiny bikini.
CHARLET: Oh my god, even that
makes me feel busty.
MIKE: That's the new smallest
version we've made.
This was the tiny before.
But this is the new tiny.
CHARLET: Are there are things
that when you started working
here, that you were
selling, that now
people just won't touch?
MIKE: Anything that covers up
too much doesn't sell anymore.
CHARLET: You're the best
g-string maker in America?
CHARLET: 20 g-strings an hour?
CHARLET: So what's her secret?
CHARLET: Congratulations!
That is a g-string.
As fascinating as that
was, it was nearly
time for us to leave.
But before we did, Mike
said I could choose an
outfit from the shop.
MIKE: This one would
look good on you.
CHARLET: OK.
MIKE: You can pick any color
underwear you want, but you
might want to just
go with hot pink.
It all depends on your
bum, too, right?
That dress was made for you.
That's a perfect Vegas night
out dress for you.
CHARLET: After a whole afternoon
learning about the
finer points of g-string
construction, we made our way
back across town for what we
thought was the opening show
of the Las Vegas International
Lingerie event.
After a disappointing trade
show, we were more than ready
to have our minds blown.
ANNOUNCER: Two, two, one,
two, check, two,
two, one, two, two.
CHARLET: So these are the
dancers who are rehearsing for
the show tonight.
They're being choreographed.
And they're all in track suits,
but when we see them
later, they're all going
to be half-naked.
I thought it was going to be
more of a catwalk thing, but
it seems that it's more of
a dance performance.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Look, look,
two head rolls this time.
TAMICA: My name is Jessie, hi.
I'm a model.
This is my first number.
On the inside of this one, you
can hold all of your money!
This one is kind of like an
old time gangster, kind of
Halloween costume.
CHARLET: Where do the
boobs go, Jessie?
JESSIE: I'm not quite
sure where the boobs
are supposed to go.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Not everybody
can do it.
And that sounds kind of mean
to say, but showgirls are
showgirls because they actually
are trained dancers,
and they are beautiful women,
and they are talented.
You're not going to go be an
astronaut unless you're
trained to do it.
You won't come be a
showgirl either
CHARLET: Is there anything
you won't wear?
FEMALE SPEAKER: I mean, there's
nothing I won't wear,
because ultimately somebody's
paying me to wear what they've
asked me to, and I've
agreed to it.
As soon as this is over, we'll
get our check, and we'll race
over to the Luxor and do our
fittings for new costumes that
are going into the
show tonight.
I don't even know
what day it is.
I'm being called.
Sorry, got to go.
CHARLET: Thank you.
The doors have opened
to the punters.
They're flooding in.
It's funny, this is not like--
it doesn't have the same vibe
as a fashion week somewhere
else in the world.
These girls are just fucking
hard workers.
This is just another
job for them.
They're going to go off
and do their next
show somewhere else.
They're all a bit kind of dead
behind the eyes, almost.
But this is Vegas.
I suppose this is
what you get.
ANNOUNCER: Thank you so much for
all the buyers coming out.
You guys look good out there.
I want to thank a lot of support
people that help us
put on this show.
And it's time to party!
[DANCE MUSIC]
CHARLET: And that was it.
This hour-long parade had been
the International Lingerie
Show, what we've come
all this way for.
But at least we'd made
some new friends.
DENNIS: Oh-oh, my friend
[INAUDIBLE] here.
CHARLET: This is an
international lingerie show.
Do you have a favorite thing?
DENNIS: I'll be honest.
Personally, I just like to see
a lot of skin, and I like the
kind of slutty look.
And I also like the very
romantic, beautiful costumes.
And I just thoroughly
enjoy it here.
FEMALE SPEAKER: I liked the
old days when they had fur
coats and jewelry, and
it was classy.
I like that a lot.
It was elegant, it was nice.
It was evening gowns to go
to shows, you dressed up.
And now you can go, and they
wear cut-off shorts.
These two ladies were sitting at
the bar and they're talking
about shopping, and they're
talking about sex and
everything.
And the one lady said, did you
know a guy can tell the size
of your vagina by the
size of your mouth?
And her friend goes,
oooh, really?
FEMALE SPEAKERS:
Viva Las Vegas!
CHARLET: We've just been kicked
out from backstage
because some of the models are
feeling uncomfortable.
So now we're stuck out here in
this really fun corridor.
The whole thing had descended
into a gaggle of middle-aged
women grasping frantically
for free dildos and lube.
Call me old-fashioned, but I
prefer just a little more left
to the imagination.
After only three days in the
city, I felt used and dirty.
My dreams of finding that
old Vegas magic had
fallen wildly short.
We drove back to Death Valley
to our friend Mark's house,
where he and his buddy David led
us through the nighttime
desert to take a cleansing dip
in a natural hot spring
powered by volcanic energy.
I jumped at the chance to wash
away the feeling of having
been at a seedy funeral for
the death of the showgirl
MARK: There's bubbles, that's
gases that are depressurizing
as they come to the surface.
And they set off a frequency
in the water.
CHARLET: Get in.
MARK: It's like DH
Lawrence said.
"tHE dead alive man has become
an enigma of our time, which
it never was before.
He has gone down the slope of
mechanized death, depending on
artificial stimulations that
the city offers until he
himself becomes artificial."
That certainly happened to me.
That seemed to happen
to other people.
They're so dependent on
artificial stimulations to
keep themselves propped up,
they can't bear it.
They just fall apart.
The men are missing out on the
best that life has to offer.
The best that love
has to offer.
It wasn't until I took some LSD
that I realized just how
far away from reality
I really was.
[MUSIC PLAYING]