practice punching the air.
But by the time I was
getting choked out,
I came to an epiphany--
fighting is hard and passing
out is easy.
But if being manly
was painless,
everyone would be a man.
My name is Harry.
And I've been a loser
for most of my life.
I thought I was done with my
awkward phase when "Vice"
hired me to write about
politics, culture, and other
important world affairs, which
should make me cool.
But it doesn't.
I'm still just a weird kid
who creeps people out.
This is "All Around Losing"
with Harry Cheadle.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
HARRY: This is Daniel.
He was in the Israeli
army for 10 years.
And he lives and breathes
Krav Maga.
And this is me.
I'm not very manly or tough.
And I mainly deal with conflict
through nervous laughter.
But I wanted to change
all of that.
And because Daniel is such a
walking testosterone machine,
I thought I could learn some
martial arts from him and
hoped his massive manliness
rubbed off on me.
DANIEL: I was in charge of
the counter-terrorism
division in my unit.
You work under pressure
constantly, so a lot about
psychology.
HARRY: I want to learn how to
defend myself against being
choked out, which isn't
really a problem right
now, but who knows?
Sounds very intense.
Hopefully nothing bad happens.
And I don't get hurt too much.
But I usually do.
So let's see how this goes.
DANIEL: Three, two, one, go.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
HARRY: First, we did some cardio
warm ups, which just
helped remind me how
out of shape I was.
Most of my classmates were tough
guys who looked like
they hung out in saunas and
boxing gyms all the time and
had balls the size of beets.
Even the one woman there was
more manly than I was.
Whew, that's hard work, man.
DANIEL: How do you feel?
HARRY: Tired.
DANIEL: Tired?
Don't even start.
HARRY: I know it's
still early.
Just try not to fall down,
that's what I'm trying to do.
Then, all of a sudden,
it was time for the
punching and kicking.
Punching and kicking, in case
you've never experienced it,
is no fun and it hurts a lot.
But we kept doing it anyway.
I feel there's a lot of stuff
to remember just punching.
All gets out of my head.
[TECHNO MUSIC PLAYING]
HARRY: They played techno music
while they pummeled me.
So it was like being in a club,
only instead of dancing,
I was getting beat up.
So actually, it was
a little less
humiliating than the club.
[TECHNO MUSIC PLAYING]
DANIEL: You OK?
HARRY: Yeah.
DANIEL: You look pale.
HARRY: I'm a little fluid
dehydrated, I think.
Dry mouth.
DANIEL: You lost some color.
HARRY: By the time the class
ended, I was ready to stop
with the running and
the kicking.
But I felt even less prepared
for a fight
than I was going in.
So I asked Daniel for some
pointers, both in
fighting and in life.
If they're in a situation,
what's the one thing you
should remember?
DANIEL: Run fast.
HARRY: Run fast?
DANIEL: Yes.
HARRY: I felt like I understood
Krav Maga and
Daniel's manliness,
at least a little.
But it takes more than one
day to become a man.
It takes two days.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
HARRY: Krav Maga is
really manly.
But it's also a lot of work.
But you know what's
not a lot of work?
Firing a gun.
[GUN SHOT]
Whoa.
And also firing a gun is manly
because guns are basically
just giant, metal penises
that ejaculate death.
I'm here at Cortlandt
Manor, New York.
And I'm going to learn how to
fire a shotgun from a guy
named Joe Izrael, who is,
coincidentally, from Israel.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
HARRY: Joe was a big, quiet,
bearded dude who probably
owned more guns than
I do shirts.
So I was a little nervous at
first and couldn't talk good.
I tried to compliment
his weapons.
But I didn't know what to say.
Nice paint job on that one.
JOE: Excuse me?
HARRY: Nice paint
job on that--
[CLEARS THROAT]
JOE: So what we'll do today
here is NRA basic shotgun
shooting course.
So we're going to learn how
to shoot a shotgun.
And there will be
a written exam.
You don't have to be afraid.
HARRY: It turns out shotguns
are very, very complicated,
like cars or women.
Joe demonstrated how to
hold a gun and told
me stuff about it.
But all I could think about
was how cool it
would be to fire it.
At the end of the class, I had
to take a test with Joe
standing over me like a heavily
armed exam monitor.
But this was the easy part
since I'm good at tests,
unlike fighting, shooting, or
anything else that would help
me survive in the wild.
JOE: This is yours.
Congratulations.
HARRY: Certified.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
HARRY: We ventured out onto the
range, where we watched a
bunch of guys fire
pistols at stuff.
We put on these ridiculous
headphones to cancel out the
incredibly loud noises of
the guns going off.
And although it was definitely
masculine, I had no idea what
I was doing out there.
It didn't seem like Joe
had any idea either.
He kept looking at me like I was
some kind of weird bird.
JOE: This is what you're
shooting at.
HARRY: Wow, OK.
JOE: OK?
HARRY: It looks very small.
JOE: It is.
So grab the gun.
OK, and let's go on station
number three.
HARRY: All right.
JOE: You can now
close the gun.
HARRY: OK.
JOE: OK.
HARRY: And this would
need to be--
JOE: No, no, no, no.
We're not shooting it.
HARRY: OK.
JOE: Just mount the gun,
properly as we've learned.
HARRY: Like--
JOE: You feel comfortable?
HARRY: Uh--
JOE: Don't lie to me.
HARRY: No, no, not really.
JOE: OK.
If it's not comfortable,
it's not right.
Relax.
Relax a little.
HARRY: OK, relax.
JOE: You're very tense.
HARRY: I know.
I haven't fired a gun before,
so I'm tense.
JOE: So many people use this
gun, you couldn't imagine--
HARRY: OK.
JOE: --old retired grandmas,
teenagers, little girls, my
seven-year-old daughter.
HARRY: Pull.
Oops.
Oh, I forgot to cock it.
Pull.
Oops.
[GUN FIRING]
Pull.
JOE: Good.
HARRY: Pull.
[GUN FIRING]
JOE: Good, good.
HARRY: This is more fun than
I thought it would be.
I'm going to get carpal
tunnel from this.
No one's going to believe it's
from handling a shotgun.
Everyone's going to think
it's from jacking off.
JOE: Harry.
HARRY: Oh.
[INAUDIBLE].
JOE: Come stand.
How does this feel?
HARRY: This--
JOE: Huh?
HARRY: Is this a little lighter
than the last one?
JOE: No.
If anything, it's heavier.
It's better suited for you.
HARRY: OK.
JOE: OK.
But I have a lot of youngster
and old, retired people who
pretty much are more comfortable
with the gun.
HARRY: Pull.
[GUN FIRING]
Whoa.
JOE: Blew it off your head?
HARRY: Yeah.
JOE: OK.
HARRY: It's very fast.
JOE: You're way too tense.
You having fun?
You came here to have fun.
HARRY: Is it normal for--
JOE: Huh?
HARRY: Is it normal
for first timers?
JOE: I'm not saying it
happens to everybody.
There are some people who just
come and pick it up, and some
people need more time.
[GUN CLICKING]
HARRY: Oops.
JOE: Oops.
[GUN FIRING]
HARRY: So shooting a gun is
really fun and awesome.
I also learned that shooting
small pink things going really
fast is incredibly difficult.
If a small pink thing attacks
me at high speed,
I'm probably fucked.
But if a person attacks me, I
think I'm going to be a little
more confident because I've
got my Krav Maga skills--
that was a punch.
Actually, now that I think about
it, if someone attacks
me, I'm probably just going to
run away or get beat up.
Yeah.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
JOE: Turn that way.
HARRY: Turn this way?
I don't know how to turn
properly without pointing it
[INAUDIBLE].
JOE: Look, just pick it up.
Now you can turn.
HARRY: OK.
Like this?
JOE: No, you can--
HARRY: What?
Oh, like this?
OK.
[MUSIC PLAYING]