hard as you want, and
no matter how--
Oh.
I'm Steve Spangler and I'm all
about making science fun.
For the last 20 years, I've
been teaching ways to turn
ordinary science experiments
into unforgettable learning
experiences.
I have an amazing team who will
do whatever it takes to
affect the way people
think about science.
And to do that I live
by one motto.
Make it big, do it right,
give it class.
Well, let me start by
apologizing for my
inappropriate conduct.
I'll be better.
The deal here is this, I didn't
do the thing right,
because if you take an egg,
normally, and you put it in
your hand and squeeze, there's
no problem at all.
But this hand would be fine,
this hand is not.
Why?
Because of the ring.
See the ring put pressure at a
certain point and it broke.
Which brings me to thinking this
is pretty cool, if you
make somebody with a ring
squeeze it in their hands, it
will crack on them.
And somebody without the ring,
it won't crack at all.
It all has to boil down to
the shape of the egg.
And isn't nature amazing?
How it knows how to make
this dome shape.
When you look at it like this,
if this doesn't look like a
little piece of architecture,
I don't know what does, with
that archway.
And you look at how it
distributes the weight on
either side, perfectly.
We simply emulate nature in
architecture and it works.
So a long way of saying,
put it your hand
like this and squeeze.
And if you squeeze as hard as
you can, honestly, as hard as
you can, you can't
break the egg.
Because all of that pressure
is being disseminated, or
dispersed, all over
that shell.
Now there are times where I've
done it this way, and tried to
crack it like this.
And sometimes it's a
little easier, even
this one's not bad.
But as soon as the ring goes on
like this and you squeeze,
that causes a small little
fracture and the egg breaks.
And now you know the secret.
But there's other cool
things about an egg
that you need to know.
And it's what the egg
is made out of.
This shell, on the outside, is
made out of a substance called
calcium carbonate.
And, believe it or not, that
substance is easily dissolved
using a simple acid
like vinegar.
Well it's a classic elementary
science experiment.
You take a raw egg and you put
it in a container like this.
And then you pour the vinegar
over the top.
Now, if you're in a chemistry
class you might use something
like hydrochloric acid.
At home this vinegar
is perfectly fine.
There are two strengths of
vinegar, so sometimes at the
grocery store you can get
concentrated vinegar and that
will speed this whole
process up.
But even right now, take a look,
you can start to see the
bubbles forming on the
outside of the egg.
And those bubbles are
carbon dioxide.
So, over time, you're going to
eat away at that calcium
carbonate and you're going
to get a naked egg.
Well, it's going to be naked.
But it's going to be naked
in about a week or so.
And you don't have time to watch
it, even with time lapse
you'd be bored.
So I took the liberty
of making one just a
little while ago.
Take a look at this.
This is a naked egg.
Now it doesn't seem like it,
because we let this one sit a
little bit longer.
But look, it is.
All of that outside shell
has been removed.
And here it is.
But maybe the best way to be
able to see it is to use a
light like this.
You can actually see some of
the shell, right here.
So you see this little
part of the shell?
But I found that it is even
cooler if you take an egg and
you only dip it partially
in the vinegar.
And this is what you get when
you pull it out just
a little bit early.
This is the naked egg, but you
see can see the shell is here
on this side, and
it's completely
eaten away right here.
So when you take a look at
it, take a look at this.
You can actually see the pits
where the vinegar started to
eat into like this.
It's a partially naked egg.
Well now that you know that an
egg is strong, we need to find
out just how strong it is.
So it's time for a test.
And the little set up that
we have here is perfect.
We happen to have
a digital scale.
That's what this is here.
And I got the digital scale
from the same people I was
babysitting the dog from, that
we used the speakers, you
know, for the cornstarch
monsters.
Who would have thought--
[BANG, BANG]
--they got a scale.
So we have a scale.
And on top of that scale we're
going to use the egg crate.
So this will be a perfect
way to be able to
hold it, like that.
And now, we're going
to take a raw egg.
And our raw egg's going
to go right here.
And then we're going to put
some pressure on it.
Well, we'll tare it out.
Here, let me tear it out.
All right, it's at zero.
Perfect.
All right, we're going
to take the tray.
The tray goes on
top like this.
And now we're going to put some
pressure on just a single
egg to see how much
pressure I can put
until it finally breaks.
Watch.
Ugh.
13 pounds, somewhere
around there.
It's not very good.
And see where that pressure
point is?
And it kind of makes sense,
because when this was here,
look at this.
When it was on top, you can see
where that pressure point,
all the pressure was on the
very, very top, there.
So it's no wonder it broke.
It's just like my ring being
able to push into it.
So I think we need more eggs.
So let's go from one
to four eggs.
So if we can support all four
corners sitting over here,
let's see what that
would do for us.
One here.
Here's let's do all four
corners, like this.
So, hopefully, we'll distribute
the weight.
And, hopefully, they're kind
of the same height.
It's pretty close.
Looks like they're all about
the same height.
I'll try to keep the pressure
equal here in the very center.
All right, here we go.
Here we go.
This is good.
[CLUNK]
Shot the back and everything.
It's disgusting back here.
There you go.
Look at this.
Three eggs break.
One's fine.
Just means that the pressure
wasn't the same.
And I probably didn't make
sure everything is equal.
I think what's going to be best
is if I put one here in
the middle and another
one here.
Six eggs, which looks
pretty good.
Tray on top.
Now we just have
to have weight.
I could get people here
at the Spangler
Playground to sit on it.
I don't think they're
going to do that.
I think it's probably a better
idea to get some
books, lots of books.
Books.
Some of my favorite
ones right here.
Look at this one here, I love
this one. "Science Circus."
That's a good one.
"Thanksgiving
Magic," I love that.
Oh, here's one of my favorite
ones, look at this one here,
"Naked Eggs and Flying
Potatoes." I love this book.
Oh, and here's the sequel, "Fire
Bubbles and Exploding
Toothpaste." Just don't know
if they're still--
oh, they are still available.
Where can you get them?
Stevespanglerscience.com.
That's cool, torque.
Check this out--
oh, sorry.
We've got some books and
we need to have eggs.
So here's what we've got.
Here's this whole piece here.
I think that the idea here
is to get six eggs.
And just inspect them
and make sure
they're good at the beginning.
And let's see if we can get them
all as even as possible.
That looks a little high
but maybe we'll be OK.
We're going to say, just here,
two in the very middle.
Hopefully, try to keep things
as symmetrical as possible.
We can see how even
this really is.
Let's see if we're making
contact all the way around,
bingo, and we are.
And take the tray off, because
we want to tare it to know
exactly how much weight.
Perfect.
All right, tray on top.
Let's start adding some books.
"Chemical Demonstrations,"
it's fitting.
The bible for everybody
who ever did
demonstrations in college.
So that's perfect.
Everything is good.
All right, here we go.
Volume two, volume three.
Even though we're just on the
very tips of the eggs, we're
distributing that weight
over six eggs.
So this one goes here.
And how about a classic.
One right here.
This one's a great one.
And how about these here.
Good.
One of my favorite books,
a really hard to find.
This "Mr. Wizard's Science
Secrets," a great one.
All right, this one goes here.
I hear--
I hear creaking.
[CRUNCH]
Thank goodness these two
books were not the ones
that broke the eggs.
All right, 30 pounds.
But 30 pounds and six
eggs, not so bad.
And we were on the very,
very tops of the eggs.
So if you wanted to turn this
into like a science fair
project, you would just simply
relate the amount of pressure,
or the weight, that you
can put on here, to
the number of eggs.
So instead of just doing
six, maybe you try
eight, or you try ten.
Or whatever it might be.
Let's just use a whole tray of
eggs and see how many books we
can get on top.
30 eggs, here we go.
Careful of the first
ones here, so we
equalize the pressure.
All right, that's it,
all the books.
And you can see--
I'm hearing creaking.
But I think it's the creaking
of the actual container
itself, and not the
breaking of eggs.
We are perfectly fine.
The only way we'll be able to
see, is to take all the books
off and lift the tray.
All right, here's
the truth test.
See, I'm pleasantly surprised.
Look at this.
The creaking that I heard was
the sound of this egg carton,
itself, moving, but if you look
at these eggs, we are
perfectly fine.
We got to 59 pounds, total
of 30 eggs, no cracks.
We need more weight because we
want to see what it takes to
be able to break this.
You know what we need?
Not more books.
We don't need bricks.
We need people.
Higginsworth, come here.
No, it will be fun.
Come here.
356, 57, 58, 59, 60.
360 eggs.
Sure, I could have done some
quick multiplication, but why
when you can count?
Because counting is fun.
Here's the deal.
This is the ultimate
egg stunt.
We saw how strong they are, now
we want to see if we can
walk them, because these little
eggs are saying, (IN A
SQUEAKY VOICE) please
walk on me.
Please whatever you
do, walk on me.
And we want to fulfill
their every desire.
So we're going to
walk on them.
But not me.
No, no.
We're going to find something
that you know and you love, my
best friend, Higginsworth.
Come here, Higginsworth.
All right, this is going
to be great.
Sounds good.
Get off the phone.
No, I'm available to
start any time.
He can't start anytime.
I got to go.
Sorry.
So what are we doing?
OK, look.
You're going to walk on eggs.
OK?
So I need you to those
shoes off.
And we are going to
walk on eggs.
Go.
Get them off.
All right.
Let's do it.
Whoa.
Where did you get
feet like that?
Let's not worry about that.
What are we doing here?
Listen, I think you need
to get them wrapped up.
So get some bubble wrap.
I want a nice cushion as you're
going through here.
I don't want these
eggs, breaking.
OK.
Bubble wrap.
Perfect.
Here's the deal, if you make all
the way across, no broken
eggs, you're going to get, in
addition to your $20 this
week, an extra $5.
You're going to find a five.
That is impressive.
OK.
Here we go.
Go.
Nice, I'm helping you,
good job, yes.
This is good.
Perfect.
And it's there.
And look back and see what
a great job you--
son of a [BLIP]
It's the bubble wrap.
Why did you move forward with
the bubble wrap idea?
Bad idea.
I should have had your
actual feet on there.
Can you get the bubble
wrap off, please?
Wow, I can get over
those feet.
Yikes.
All right, this time,
no bubble wrap.
So we replaced all the eggs.
This time, no bubble
wrap, bare feet.
I think it's going to be better
because the feet will
contour to the eggs.
I think it's going to be good.
OK, so here we go.
There you go, good.
Good.
It's OK, keep going, let's go.
There you go.
Go, ready?
And, good, good, good, keep
going, and go, go.
And go, go.
Go go, good.
Go, go.
All right, all right, do you
think we can fix that in post?
Well here's what we just
learned, as big and cool as
these trays are with a total
of 30 eggs, they
don't work at all.
They just don't support
the eggs.
And we had a couple
that cracked.
And then these became
very flimsy.
So if you're trying to impress
your friends, don't be using
these big huge crates.
By accident, we looked at
these smaller cartons.
Look at this, the smaller carton
has a lot more support
for those eggs.
And so we're going to stagger
them like this.
And we think, or at least the
theory is, that this is going
to support the feet
much better.
All right, Higginsworth,
here we go.
OK, left foot on first.
Let's see.
That's it.
Good.
Good, walk through, you're
doing great.
I hear it.
You're doing great.
10 cartons total.
Look at this, 10
cartons, total.
You ready?
Here.
Nice.
Look at that.
All right, there's creaking
but come here and
take a look at this.
We have a couple little
minor cracks, but
nothing that's horrible.
Nice job, Higgins--
You did it.
It's the egg walk.
Thanks, Steve.
All right, you're going to
enjoy your egg walk.
This is going to be great.
And, Higs, the greatest
thing here is, watch.
These are not broken, so--
What am I doing with these?
You can return them.
All right?
To the store?
Get them back fast.
All right.
So, that will be absolutely
perfect.
Or, why don't you make your
mom a nice omelet.
You know how you're pretty
good at making omelets?
All right, so just make
her an omelet.
OK.
This will be great.
How about tomorrow morning
you bring us all some
omelets, all right?
That'll be great.
And just tell her, that
we just used these
a little tiny bit.
So, it's fine.
But I don't want to
waste those eggs.
OK?
Got it?
OK.
Here you go.
Put those in your car.
Taking these back.
[PLOP]
[SIGH]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Damn solar cooker.