Can you achieve balance? I would take people
that believe in nature and let them build
a natural farm, and people believe in science
live in this city. All the cities would be
saner in design, but there'd be different
value systems and you can check them out,
see how it works. If you wanna live on organic
food and you have a community of 40,000 people,
living on organic food, they're all healthier,
but mentally they're not. Physically they're
in perfect shape but mentally, they believe
they've made metaphysical temples and all
that, you know what I mean? So, you might
check out different cultures and say yes they're
all healthy physically, mentally they're aborted.
Do you think you know what I mean? You know
Hitler was a vegetarian don't you? He didn't
believe in eating living things. But his brain
was no better than it was. So if a person
eats nothing but organic food, never had cancer
never had heart disease, but is fucked up
at here, has associative disease, you know
what that means? Doesn't like Swedes, or Catholics,
or gays, that's associate disease. So we don't
measure all of that stuff. A language is an
attempt at controlling the behavior of people.
It isn't a mechanism for controlling behavior,
it's an attempt. People write books cause
they think they can impart their values to
other people, the book is only 1 piece of
the action, and many other things necessary,
conversing with one another, up and back,
disagreements, areas where you're little foggy,
not quite clear. So when I tell you that a
neurologist doesn't know what the problem
is, unless they're social. He has no idea
if he works on the brain there's a study,
how does the brain work? The brain doesn't
work it responds to different cultures. Do
you understand that? Asking a question how
does the brain work? Can not be asked outside
of the culture. You can't do that, it's like
saying, how do we walk? Well, if you lived
on a planet with 1 tenth of gravity, the guy
says let's go for a 20 mile walk you say okay,
because gravity doesn't bother you too much,
but if you live in a planet with 5 times the
gravity of the earth, the guy says wanna walk
a hundred feet? Says that's too much for me,
do you understand by you respond to the environment?
Senators make laws, but they can't change
natural law. They can't change the law of
gravity, at a congress meeting, so it's easier
to go up the steps of the capital. They can't
change natural law, although to a limited
extent we can affect it. So all of us live
within the trap called time and culture. You
know what that means? We live within the trap
called time and culture. So an anthropologist
can't study culture, unless he studies his
own culture, and if he does, he's not gonna
become an anthropologist, becomes a student
of life systems. Maybe, if you know what I
mean? All single professions will disappear
in the future, I've no question about it.
You have to become so general. Encompassing
is a better word than general, cause that
sounds like it's less. I can't use that word
all encompassing. Well, more encompassing,
more encompassing. Emotions get in the way,
because they block you from looking at things
in a more general viewpoint, but when you
like the way you think, that's called arrested
development. You said one time there's no
emotional problems, what did you mean by that?
Well by that I meant there are relating problems,
relating to different things, and you get
hopped up about it, or you get angry, or you
feel depressed, the only way you should feel
depressed, there are real reasons, fairly
depressed if Hitler won the war and they put
you both in solitary confinement, you would
feel depressed, cause there's nothing you
can do about it. If you were around 500 normal
people, they can make you feel depressed.
They can cut you out. But it depends how much
you know about normal people so you don't
let them do that to you. You know how far
you can go, or you think how far you can go.
You'll find out fast enough how far you can
go. When people call up and say what is the
Venus Project? You say have you got 2 weeks?
You can't say this is what it is, oh thank
you very much. It's like answering questions,
you can't answer questions. But you still
have to have a couple of sentences. Yes you
do. Or you can't get around it. If you're
really interested in knowing how people work,
and how they relate to one another and the
environment, get the book, cause you got too
many calls every day to go into detail. After
you get the book, if you've got problems we
can discuss it. You ask a person what do you
want? I want a car. No, they wanna be a certain
place at a given time, that can be done by
television, you know what I mean? You can't
visit your aunt Minnie on a screen full size.
You don't wanna drive to Aunt Minnie's, and
you don't wanna drive to work, you want the
pay cheque. Not every week, when you want
it, right? A guy says I want a job. He doesn't
know what he's talking about, he wants some
money to buy the things he needs. So then
he needs things, not money. You ask a person
what do you want? A decent home, 40,000 dollar
home? 20,000 dollar, what do you mean by decent
home? But in this culture, people really can't
use that kind of logic. They have to think
within. They're incapable. You can give them
a whole new set of tools, and there'll be
people that'll be gunning for you too, cause
you're taking their tools away, or their controls.
So when you say, what does the Venus Project
really think? That's an abstract question,
depends on the situation. Lock your frame
of referent. What? Said lock your frame of
referent. Yeah. A person says what if you
build a Venus Project and a meteor hits it
and destroys it. Then we're fucked. Or we
start over again if we're still around. It's
just a lot of unnecessary aberrant responses.
That's why I would never talk to a psychiatrist,
cause they think they're on the right track.
Although, there are some that know they know
very little about human behavior, you know
there are people like that, that have studied
the field of medicine and really feel that
they don't have much control over health.
And a person says I want a healthy body and
I say what do you want it for? If you're just
healthy so what? I'd rather have a healthy
mind and a warped body. You know what I mean?
But what we talk about is associative systems
that correlate, you know what that means?
With changing conditions.
You know they ask you in school what do you
wanna do with your life? What a stupid question.
What can I do with my life? School doesn't
offer you everything. You got it? You usually
say a healthy associative system correlates
with the real world, but that was good, it
correlates with changing conditions. Yes.
More appropriate huh? Yes. Which is the real
world I guess. But then you've gotta remember,
you're drifting away from the average person,
and you've gotta update your communication,
or try. If you don't work on the people around
you, you will get lost. And they might say
what are you a perfectionist? You know, they
have no other words. A perfectionist is a
guy that died, that's it. You can't be a perfectionist.
You can be particular about things. Just get
away from the holistic words like truth, the
absolute truth, the absolute truth. I said
this before, in order to tell the truth you
have to know everything, to know that which
is true. Okay you guys I'm gonna relax. That
was good Jacque. Thanks Jacque. So that wraps
up this lecture on behavior. He's pretty busy
for a guy his age who needs to be resting
up after about 6 or 7 months of traveling.
He actually has been drawing a lot since he
got back, he did this whole stack in about,
actually 3 times this much but a lot of em
he just rips them up, throws them away. The
usual Venus Project tours which are held on
some Saturdays will resume this month so please
check the website for the dates on those if
you'd like to attend. Since he got back from
traveling he's had a couple of groups, this
particular group was out of Miami and they
have to do with permaculture, and were interested
in the Venus Project. He also had a small
group of 3 or 4 people before them that was
from his original group in Miami when it was
called Sociocyberneering. So thanks for watching
and keep an eye out for more lectures and
other things that we'll be posting soon. Thanks.
There's so much of it.