ELLIOTT BAMBROUGH: We're
in Tokyo right now.
Everyone's well aware of the
subcultures and fetishes that
exist here.
That's inside the city,
happening around me right now.
But outside the city there's
another subculture.
It's called Dekotora.
Basically it's Pimp My
Ride for trucks.
And these huge Transformer-esque
type things
with neon lights and murals
and chandeliers.
And our mission while we're here
is to meet the guys who
started it.
For all these different missions
I'm going to have
someone along with me, who I'm
going to call my co-pilot.
And you're going to
meet her tomorrow.
But for now, I'm going head
round Tokyo and try and soak
this all up.
So I told you guys that we're
going to have a co-pilot along
for the ride and it's
Maggie Stoody.
Can I call you Maggie?
MAGGIE STOODY: You can.
Thank you.
ELLIOTT BAMBROUGH: It's Mags.
What do you want?
MAGGIE STOODY: Oh, it all
looks so appetizing.
ELLIOTT BAMBROUGH: So you want
to be crazy kickboxer
or upset pork man.
What do you want to be?
MAGGIE STOODY: I think I'm going
to go crazy kickboxer.
ELLIOTT BAMBROUGH: It's hot.
It's hot, pre-warmed
pork noodles.
What do you do when you're not
in Tokyo or going out to
discover Dekotora trucks?
MAGGIE STOODY: I
am a Chicagoan.
I travel a lot.
Just got back from Ecuador
a couple weeks ago.
ELLIOTT BAMBROUGH: Sweet.
What were you doing
in Ecuador?
MAGGIE STOODY: Just
bumming around.
And my brother and
I are starting a
small sunglasses company.
And a portion of our profits
go to eradicating vitamin A
deficiency which is a huge world
health crisis that not
that many people know about.
ELLIOTT BAMBROUGH: OK cool.
MAGGIE STOODY: Yeah.
So I know we're on the mission
to find Dekotora trucks but I
have to admit I don't really
know what they are.
MAGGIE STOODY: Dekotora
trucks basically
means decorated truck.
It all starts off these guys,
just ordinary truck drivers,
start a whole new subculture.
In '74, there's a production
company and the guy was
working there, saw one of these
Dekotora trucks, was
inspired and fascinated by it
and started off this whole
sub-genre of movies
about truck guys.
And the first one's called
Truck Rascals.
They formed a group of Dekotora
truck drivers to make
it easier for the production
company.
It really exploded and other
groups started forming around
the country and it became
a big thing.
It's really dwindling.
You don't see Dekotora trucks
in Tokyo anymore.
We're going to bump
into the newer
generation of Dekotora drivers.
MAGGIE STOODY: Cool.
ELLIOTT BAMBROUGH: See them with
their pimped out rides
and just hanging.
MAGGIE STOODY: Cool.
I can't wait to hang.
ELLIOTT BAMBROUGH:
Just hanging with
the big white trucks.
We're on our way to Gunma in
Central Japan, about two hours
west of Tokyo.
We're supposed to meet with one
of the old school original
Dekotora truck drivers.
His name is Taguchi San and he's
been in the scene for the
last three decades.
We're going to find out a little
bit more about the
history of Dekotora and
how it started.
MAGGIE STOODY: Thank
you for having us.
MAGGIE STOODY: Thank you.
ELLIOTT BAMBROUGH: Thank
you so much.
Arigato.
ELLIOTT BAMBROUGH:
We're in Gunma.
Behind me is the Dekotora store,
and this kind of acts
as a truck stop for guys.
There's a diner over there.
Or the guys stop here and they
get a tune up as well.
But this is also where they
get all their supplies for
Dekotora, the lights and the
neons, and the horns.
And we're going to go inside now
and go and check it out.
MAGGIE STOODY: Enormous.
ELLIOTT BAMBROUGH: The
bombardment on your senses
with all the flashing lights and
everything and everything.
MAGGIE STOODY: Whoa,
it's so big.
ELLIOTT BAMBROUGH: From
decorating the outside to the
chandeliers to the upholstery,
anything you can get for the
truck is here in this store.
MAGGIE STOODY: A little
unicorn action for ya.
ELLIOTT BAMBROUGH:
Here's your--
MAGGIE STOODY: Wow!
ELLIOTT BAMBROUGH:
Your finishing
touches, your grills.
MAGGIE STOODY: Look at
these little guys.
It's an enormous key chain.
I already know how I would
do my Dekotora.
Murder out the outside, matte
black finish, and then all
sparkle black on the inside.
[GASP]
These!
Ridin' dirty.
ELLIOTT BAMBROUGH: You can take
your Lil Wayne Dekotora
and you can shove it.
MAGGIE STOODY: I really
would too.
Like you could go grandma's
Dekotora.
ELLIOTT BAMBROUGH: This
is just crazy.
MAGGIE STOODY: So cool.
ELLIOTT BAMBROUGH: The fact that
we have three lined up
and with the sun bouncing off of
them, with all the silver.
MAGGIE STOODY:The bling.
Disco balls.
ELLIOTT BAMBROUGH: And
everything glimmering.
MAGGIE STOODY: It's
so beautiful.
ELLIOTT BAMBROUGH: And
here are the guys.
SEKINO SAN: My name is Sekino.
ELLIOTT AND MAGGIE: Sekino,
nice to meet you.
ELLIOTT BAMBROUGH:
Nice to meet you.
Thank you.
MAGGIE STOODY: Thank you.
ELLIOTT BAMBROUGH: Where do you
even start with getting
the stuff on?
ELLIOTT BAMBROUGH: The murals
on the side, how did he pick
this one out and who
commissioned it?
Who painted it?
ERINA SUTO: He painted
it himself.
MAGGIE STOODY: Wow.
ELLIOTT BAMBROUGH: You
did it yourself?
MAGGIE STOODY: So beautiful.
ELLIOTT BAMBROUGH: Is it rude
to ask him how much he spent
all together?
If he could estimate.
ELLIOTT BAMBROUGH: Does he have
it specifically insured
for that amount?
ERINA SUTO: No insurance.
ELLIOTT BAMBROUGH: Does he have
any idea how many light
bulbs are in this?
ELLIOTT BAMBROUGH: Oh, sweet.
So it's a cool little cabin.
MAGGIE STOODY: Wow.
ELLIOTT BAMBROUGH: So it's life
a home away from home.
TV.
Stereo.
MAGGIE STOODY: Chandelier.
ELLIOTT BAMBROUGH: Imagine the
guys sitting here playing
poker, having a few beers.
MAGGIE STOODY: So maybe they'll
Dekotora our Mini?
We can be part of the club?
ELLIOTT BAMBROUGH: That's
a good idea.
MAGGIE STOODY: Yeah?
ELLIOTT BAMBROUGH: Yeah?
MAGGIE STOODY: All right.
ELLIOTT BAMBROUGH: Thank
you so much.
MAGGIE STOODY: And thanks for
letting us see your truck.
It's beautiful.
Arigato.
[JAPANESE]
[TECHNO MUSIC]
ELLIOTT BAMBROUGH: We've just
been told that the Mini has
now been Dekotora'd so it's time
to go in the workshop and
get it out.
They're going to town
with it, I love it.
Now you guys know a little
bit more about Dekotora.
Right now I'm off to
the next adventure.
[TECHNO MUSIC]