They're scared of the camera,
or something.
This is the mom right here.
I found her in the street.
This is the son right here.
Big old dude right here.
This is my skate contest
at Pedlow.
I was 12, doing a
front lip bro.
I just bought that bike from my
homie's dad, for like $100.
Stoked on that.
Got this bad boy.
Got my diploma, high school
graduate, boy, you know.
Yeah, me and Jeron Wilson
graduated from
the same high school.
Look at this thing.
My dad made this for me.
This is an old board I skated.
I skated until it was completely
fucked right here.
And he just shaved it
off a little bit.
And made this little
piece for me.
Still got it, to this day.
He made this probably like 12
years ago, maybe, when I first
started skating.
This is my dad, Heriberto.
These guitars here are
traditionally from Veracruz.
[STRUMMING GUITARS]
God damn school police.
This was where I tried to learn
how to drive stick.
But it didn't really work out.
My dad called me a little
bitch because I
couldn't drive stick.
[STRUMMING AND SINGING]
We're getting into
Van Nuys, dog.
This is where BVN is,
and BVN, whoo!
You gotta watch out
for those fools.
[STRUMMING AND SINGING]
Woo hoo.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]