Bam!
So I bet you think this is the
part of the show where I'm
going to say, don't try these
experiments at home.
And you're right.
Except there is one experiment
we want you to try.
Just look for the graphic
that's right here
that says, Try It.
That's your signal that
you can try that
experiment at home.
Everything else, off limits.
Look, I've already given you
homework, and the show hasn't
even started.
Well, this is the answer to the
age-old question, what do
you do to crush that can?
Because of course, you
don't want to just
sit here and do this.
Expends so much energy.
Why wouldn't you want to have
this entire set up here just
to accomplish the same thing.
But there's nothing really
cool about that.
All right, so let's see if we
can do it a different way.
So here's what we have, is
we have three cans here.
In each of the cans, I have
a small amount of water.
Now, you could do this on a
burner if you wanted to.
In this particular case, because
we're portable, we
have this little camping
stove thing.
And so now, let's
turn this on.
So the object here is this, is
we want to boil that water.
So when you boil the water in
the can, water when it boils,
goes from a liquid into a gas.
And when it does that, those
little water molecules move
about 1,700 times farther
away from each other
than they were before.
In essence, we're turning
it into water vapor.
And you can see a little
of the water vapor
starting out here.
What we're really trying
to do is to push the
air out of the can.
This is a demonstration
in air pressure.
There's air pushing all
around the can.
If we're at sea level, it's 14.7
pounds per square inch.
It's pushing all over the can.
What we want, is we want to
evacuate the can from the air,
just leaving the water vapor.
This is hot now, it's a gas.
If we could cool it down very
quickly by turning it upside
down and putting it into water
there, we might be able to
allow the air pressure
to crush the can.
So, here's what happens.
I'm going to grab my gloves so
I can just kind of pick it up
and hold onto it.
You want a really, really good
burn on these, so we really
want to see a lot of the water
vapor coming out so we get a
good crush.
All right.
This is looking like it's got
a pretty good burn on it.
We've got water vapor
coming out.
Let's try this first
one right here.
So hold onto the can.
Watch.
Upside down.
Nice.
It's just the pressure of the
air on the outside pushing
against the can.
Watch this one.
Ready, watch.
Bam.
Finally, the last one here.
Here's our tea.
Look at this.
Now when it happens, watch
when we pick it up here.
Look at how much water got
pulled up inside of the can.
No really, I should say how much
water was pushed from the
atmosphere down, and
up inside the can.
See, it's a much better
way to crush a can.
And it's so much easier,
don't you think?
I'm an idiot.
I remember doing this years
ago in a chemistry class.
They had ditto fluid.
So this was a metal can.
So I've kept some of those cans
over the years, it's just
a matter of finding
an empty can.
The trick is not to use a can
that had solvent in it because
you don't want to cook
the solvent.
That could be a whole different
experiment.
I'm not a hoarder.
Look, I just happen to have
this from 20 years ago.
This is perfect.
It's exactly the can that
we're looking for.
So, we'll do the same thing.
We'll put the water inside, then
we'll cap the whole thing
off and see if we can crush this
can using that same kind
of science style.
See the boil that
we have here.
That's we want.
We're pushing all of that air
out, filling the space with
water vapor.
And we should just--
it should be perfect.
Ready?
I think we're good.
Let's turn it off.
Cap this off like this.
Set it here.
And now watch.
You can hear it actually
talking to you.
So unlike the soda can, it takes
a little bit longer.
Imagine all of that air and that
surface area that's there
with that air pressure
pushing on the can.
Let's see what happens if
we cool it down just
a little bit more.
Watch.
Perfect.
This is good, but it's not the
impact that I'm looking for.
And now that we know
how to crush it,
let's just go bigger.
I'm supposed to do TV this
afternoon, so I have a regular
nine news spot this afternoon,
and instead of going down and
doing an experiment, I convinced
my producer to send
a live truck to us.
Since we're practicing it
anyway, I think this looks
totally cool and kind of a
behind-the-scenes of getting
ready to go do the Ellen show.
So it just puts a little bit
more pressure on making sure
this dumb thing works.
And I've got two hours
to make this happen.
With live TV, I mean,
there's no editing.
So I've got to have it crush
in under 60 seconds because
there's just not too much that I
can do to sit there and talk
it through.
So, cross your fingers.
This will be much better.
It's a 55 gallon drum.
We got six of them just to
practice with today because we
just got to make sure that we've
got the timing down.
Take a look at the construction
of the drum, this
is really important.
Notice it's sealed all the way
around, so it's not one that
has a clamp down.
And there's two little places
that could open up.
This one here is going
to remain closed.
We put the water in this one.
So from practice, we know
about 4 liters--
close to a gallon of water--
will go in.
That's going to go up on a
great big, huge turkey--
I don't know, a turkey oven,
you know what I'm talking
about, that you boil the oil for
a turkey at Thanksgiving.
So that's going to boil
this pretty fast.
So we've got a propane
tank off to the side.
Once we have that boiling, that
should be pretty good.
And we can do that kind of ahead
of time and then kind of
wheel that out when we
have to on stage.
The real problem is, I know
this is going to work--
I mean look at this, it's
going to crush--
but I need to do this.
I need to have maximum
implosion, and also I have to
do it within a certain period
of time because they can't
wait like for four
or five minutes.
So that's where these
kind of come in.
I think what we'll do is we'll
take ice water and fill the
four buckets with ice water.
So slowly, we can kind of pour
those over them like this.
Hopefully we can
cool it faster.
We've got to catch everything,
so follow me over here.
A handy dandy kids swimming
pool should be perfect.
So the set up will look
something like this.
We'll throw the swimming
pool here.
Got it.
We'll fill that with three,
four inches of water.
We'll put ice in there so
it's nice and cold.
Then we'll heat this up, boil
it away, we'll find a couple
rods here like this.
Jeff and I will grab it on
either end, we'll pick this
up, set it in there, and then
the stopwatch starts.
I need a crush within
60 seconds.
We really just can't edit
around 60 seconds.
So if I can do it within 60
seconds, it'll be perfect.
We'll see if it happens.
This will give us more than
enough to boil away, and
again, the entire trick here
is to be able to get it to
boil, and to get all that water
vapor kind of coming
out, push all the air out.
We've got to get a really
good, rapid boil on it.
We can do all that backstage or
kind of behind the scenes,
so I'm not worried about that.
It's from the moment that we cap
off the lid and go, that's
when the clock starts ticking.
See, and the situation
is this.
If you need some water, why
wouldn't you just go and get a
forklift first.
So if you want to try
this at home, get a
forklift, number one.
Number two, get a great big
huge pool like this.
Don't use this empty one that's
here and just like a
hose that you could
put into it.
No.
Move it in with a forklift.
And then, hire a union guy like
this to go ahead and just
kind of put it in place.
This is perfect.
Why couldn't you recreate
this at home.
And I would expect that you
would be doing that.
Nice.
All right, see the water
vapor coming up here.
You know, the steam.
You can't be fooled by that
small amount that's coming up.
We need, for this 55 gallon
drum, a great rumble inside.
So we need a lot coming out.
So, we'll see this increase.
Again, it's pushing all the air
out, and it'll be perfect
when we cap it off.
We got to get it burning more.
See the rumble that
we have here?
That's kind of the volume
that we're looking for,
consistently coming out.
I think we're right there.
So we're going to turn the
burner off, then we're going
to put the cap on, and get
it over onto the side.
He's got the tight cap because
we don't want any of that air
coming back in again.
Just going to grab the edges
here, we're going to pick it
up, ready, put it in.
Good.
Now it's starting
to cool down.
Somebody needs to
start the timer.
Let's tip it over.
See, this should do it with
no problem at all.
I think we try another drum.
We'll pull this out, we'll
try another drum.
OK.
I don't know.
[SMASHING SOUND]
That was awesome.
All right.
Well, that worked.
It just took a little baseball
bat hit, we crushed the can.
Unfortunately, we
can't do that.
That's not the whole idea here,
but maybe it's just--
oh my gosh, look at this.
God, that's amazing,
look at that.
Now it's my job to start the
55 gallon drum graveyard.
One down, six to go.
All right, so here's
where we are now.
We're at 200 degrees with this
thermometer, that's just
surface temperature.
We started with two gallons of
water, we're getting a really
good roll here.
Let's use this as a benchmark
and see if it works.
Start the clock.
Yes, let's do it.
OK, so the trick here
is to cool it down
as much as we can.
Hear it talking?
That's not the implosion that
I wanted, so it's a happy
in-between.
So it's either we cooled
it too fast.
And we want that implosion.
So the next one I think we do,
is pour a little bit of water
on it, but just let it
sit and see what
happens with the implosion.
Put it in.
Start the clock.
Nice.
Time?
40 seconds.
Even when you were that
close, it was OK.
All right, we're going for
maximum implosion this time,
and so we've cooked this off.
It's sitting here at about
the 10 minute mark
where we were before.
Same amount of water.
This time we're going to put it
in the ice bath, we're not
going to pour anything on top of
it and see if it will crush
within the first 60 seconds.
If not, then we're going to
pour slightly and see--
right now, I know that it will
crush, I just want a good
implosion to scare
the audience.
I mean to get them excited
about the whole process.
Who am I kidding, I want to
scare the crap out of them.
Getting closer, and closer,
and closer.
And you can hear the can
starting to crinkle just a
little bit.
It's crinkling.
It's even talking to you.
The hard part is--
the hard part is you
have no idea when--
[EXPLODING SOUND]
Bam!
That was a good one!
All right.
Isn't that awesome!
[EXPLODING SOUND]
Bam!
That's how to crush a can.
All right, so with this
particular can, here's what we
could have figured out.
We had too much water
to start with.
We weren't getting the boil
that we really needed, so
fixed that problem.
No problem with capping it off,
that wasn't a problem.
We thought maybe we had to have
the water colder, that
wasn't a problem.
We just have to trust that
it's going to happen.
So, pouring just a little bit
of water on the top starts
that whole process of cooling.
Those molecules are 1,700 times
further away from each
other than they were before.
And funny that outside pressure
wins as the can collapses.
Looks pretty good.
Well, if you enjoyed this week's
episode, go ahead and
click the Subscribe
button here.
You'll be the first to know
when a brand new episode
appears each week.
This button right here will
show you some more cool
science experiments that we
do outside of the show.
This button right here will
take you to last week's
episode just in case
you missed it.
And if you want to see the stuff
that you shouldn't see--
that's the bloopers
and the outtakes--
well, just click this
one right over here.
And if you want to hear me
stop talking, through the
magic of television, just click
this button right here.
Go ahead, click it.
And I'll stop.
[MUSIC PLAYING]