Female Speaker
I'm honored to bring before you
today a group of distinguished
leaders who've helped navigate
our state and country through some
of the most difficult and important
natural resource issues of our time.
These individuals have led in the
US Senate, have led US agencies
including the US Environmental Protection
Agency, the US Fish and wildlife
Service, the Department of State
International Environment and scientific
affairs, have led us as the governor
of the State of Wyoming, have led
us as senators in Wyoming, have led
us as ambassadors to foreign countries,
and led a US commission on financial
responsibility and reform.  They
have led major conservation and scientific
foundations, the Conservation Fund,
and the World Resources Institute.
These individuals have dedicated
themselves to leading through collaboration
which is our topic today.  Through
crossing the divides that occur between
the values and interests surrounding
thorny natural resource issues.
DDT, wolves, spotted owls, salmon,
land management conflicts, agriculture,
energy development and conservation
and balancing those.  They have mastered
and applied for decades the art
of bringing people together and finding
common goals.  From its conception
to our current day activities, these
individuals have helped shape the
Ruckelshaus Institute University
of Wyoming for over 20 years.
All of them have served and 2 still
do, on the board of the Ruckelshaus
Institute, uh and as chairs of the
Ruckelshaus Institute. As holds
true when they helped create the
Institute today the mission of the
Ruckelshaus Institute is to advance
the understanding and solution of
complex environment and natural resources
challenges and support stake holder
driven solutions to environmental
challenges by communicating important
research and promoting collaborative
decision making.  It is a great
honor to bring together Mike
Sullivan, Senator Al Simpson, John
Turner, and Bill Ruckelshaus. Let's
give a warm thanks to their coming.
[Applause]
Mike Sullivan
Thank you very much in the uh in the and
good afternoon ladies and gentleman.
I feel a bit like I'm standing
on a precipice with a boulder and
all I have to do is push the boulder
and watch it roll for a couple of
hours because I don't know how you
could facilitate or moderate
these 3 individuals.  [Laughter]
but every now and then I may, uh, may
step in and see if there is anything
that that I can ask that you might
be interested in and then I think
at the end of the uh session we are
going to have about toward the end
of the session if we could dampenem
down a little we'll have about
20 minutes for you to ask questions
that would be of interest to you.
Let me start by just talking about
the collaborative process for maybe
30 seconds because of we have a a
number of experts in collaboration
and other means of negotiations sitting
sitting  here but uh it was clear
20 years ago when the Ruckelshaus
Institute was formed that the sensitive
issues in Wyoming and and most of
those surround natural resources
and the environment needed to have
some kind of a different forum or
process by which some of these issues
could be resolved.  And uh to the
credit of the University and the Ruckelshaus
Institute and the group including
Al and John and and others, Craig
Thomas who, who helped start it, uh,
we decided to start a a group to
try to focus on a collaborative
process and bring together a number
of advisory boards members who could
provide some expertise not only in
the uh process but in various issues
and act as a forum to help resolve
issues.  Bill Ruckelshaus, uh, generously
gave this time from the beginning
and, and uh we've all been very grateful
for that and we're grateful for him
to make the trip out here into the
wilderness uh for this session today.
[Laughter.]  Uh I was thinking
as Jane and I were driving in from
Casper about the collaborative process
and you know in today's time it seems
like compromise and collaboration
has taken on almost a four letter
word sort of context and and that
has get to be wrong.  There is no
magic to the collaborative process.
It's the way we get along on a daily
basis and I was thinking Jane and
I have been getting along for 50
years collaborating.  [Laughter]
and uh so I don't know that there
is a lot of magic to it but it does
take patience and perseverance.
And uh we have three people some
have more patience than others on
this panel but uh but they've certainly
have been exposed to it.  So let
me introduce John is a Wyoming native
as most of you would know.  He is
from Jackson Hole and Moose uh he
is a long time rancher family ranch
at Triangle X outside of Jackson
and has contributed and served the
public of Wyoming both within the
the state legislature and the Senate.
He was president of the Senate
while I was governor.  And I was
please to have the the opportunity
to serve with him.  Before he went
uh to Washington D.C. to become
director of the Fish and Wildlife
Service, a place where a lot of
collaboration and sensitive issues
exist, uh he he then served as chairman
or director of the Conservation Fund
and uh left that position to become
Assistant Secretary of Motions and
International Environmental and
Scientific Affairs which he is going
to have to tell you what they do.
But I can tell you they do remarkable
work throughout the world with uh
various sensitive subjects and fragile
environments.  Uh John served 19
years in the Wyoming legislature
representing North Lincoln and Sublette
and Teton counties where there are
always controversies.  And he's
remained a partner in the Triangle
X Ranch, a family dude ranch and
outfitting operation in Jackson.
Please welcome John Turner.
[Applause]
Bill Ruckelshaus.  Bill is currently
strategic director of the Natrona
group by way of background he was
a member of the Indiana House of
Representatives and its majority
leader from 1967 to 69.  The president
appointed him uh for the years 1969
and 1970 as assistant attorney general
in charge of the Civil Division of
the US department of justice and
that would cover the two hours that
we have here if he wanted to tell
us about that.  Uh alone uh but you're
not going to get a chance to do
that.  [Laughing.]  He became uh
the United States Environmental
Protection Agency's first administrator
when it was formed in December of
1970 and served until 1973 and I
asked him was it 3 times you were
Environmental uh Protection Agency
director and he said no it was only
2 but he was there in in Washington
so often that I thought he served
under 4 or 5 presidents in that capacity.
In April of 73 he was appointed
acting director of the Federal Bureau
of Investigation.  Just to provide
a little diversity to his to his
interests.  And uh the same year
was appointed deputy attorney general
for the Department of Justice.
He was pres- he was appointed by president
Reagan as the 5th EPA administrator
until 1985.  He's founding director
and board member of the Initiative
of Global Development, chairs the
William D. Ruckelshaus Center at
Washington State Univ- University.
And I suspect that there are five
or ten other very high profile environmental
uh study groups and others including
one you were telling me about about
ocean acidification in Washington
that Bill has been chosen and acts
as chairman or a member because
of the great contribution he brings
to those groups.  He's also a probably
this is the most sterling of his
uh resume he's a board emeritus
member of the World Research Institute
and the University of Wyoming Ruckelshaus
Institute.  [Laughter.]
Please welcome Bill Ruckelshaus.
[Applause.]
Alan K. something something.
[Laughter.]  What can I say that
hasn't been said?  Alan served 14
years, was it, in then 13 years
in the Wyoming legislature.  Uh the
first time as a very baby lawyer
that I ever approached legislature
for anything Al took me under his
wing and I've been grateful and indebted
to him ever since.  He served from
1979 to 1997 as United States senator
from Wyoming.  He was most recently
appointed in 2010 to co-chair President
Obama's National Commission on Fiscal
Responsibility and Reform.  Which
was a small little job he was asked
to do and uh he he he built it into
a really big thing.  [Laughter.]
And uh and we're all the better
for his having undertaken that uh
position.  He taught at the Shorenstein
Center on press politics and public
policy at Harvard University and
served at the John F. Kennedy School
of Government in Cambridge, Massachusetts
the direct as director of the institute
politics where he inoculated the
Harvard campus with his own western
wit and personality.  And I don't
know whether you've noticed but
it's never been the same since.
[Laughter.]  He teaches periodically
at the University of Wyoming and
spends a good deal of time promoting
the University and Wyoming throughout
the country.  He is a Cody boy.
Please welcome Alan Simpson.
[Applause.]
I am going to ask Bill Ruckelshaus
to start and just give a a short
overview of your experience
with collaborative process
Bill Ruckelshaus
I  think it's as good as uh jumping on
point point as any to describe what
collaborative processes are all about.
And why universities could be the center for a
place like the Institute. uh As you all know
we've had trouble in this country
over the last couple of decades
in arriving at decisions.  Uh the
level of civil discourse particularly
at the national level has not been
very high or edifying.  And it gets
in the way uh uh I think of rational
address to our nation's problems.
So we can bring our hands about
that and say what caused it, what
can we do about it, why don't people
treat one another better, but it's more
helpful I think to talk about that
kind of problem within the context
of a of a solution to a multi interest
multi party type of problem.  Which
collaborative processes really work
pretty well for.  Uh use of collaboration
to make decisions is not a new thing
in this country.  We have uh in
Jeffersonian days uh farm raising
exercises and neighbors helping
neighbors uh solve their own problems.
And we were as a nation kind of
founded on that. But one of the problems
with collaborative issues have
today is they compete very strongly
for the judiciary, executive, legislative
branches of decision making.  Which
some of this uh lack of civil discourse
lack of harmony exists today and
it's sometimes hard for these collaborative
processes to break through because
they're dealing with uh dispute
resolution institutions that are lodged
in our constitution.  And it is
trying there.  And there are automatic
sources of funding for these cat
these ways of resolving societal
disputes. Well one of the ways
of of of avoiding that is to simply
let universities with their enormous
capacity for uh for knowledge for
the generation of knowledge for
the uh taking that knowledge and
applying it to the social problems
uh and providing a readout where
people can come together around
their problems and sit at the same
table and listen to one another.
This uh when Alan, it's really
Alan's fault that I got involved in the University
of Washington, uh Wyoming, sorry,
it wasn't your fault and asked me
to come and and help the University
try to sort out what they could
do to make a significant impact on
natural resource kind of issues.
Well we spent a couple of weekends
at it with a very distinguished
board, several of whom are here in
this audience, uh and to try to
figure out what we could do that
would be helpful for Wyoming in
trying to resolve some of their natural
resources disputes. And so what
we decided was the University is
a very good place to have people
gather to come uh in Wyoming, almost
literally lay their guns down at
the door and come in and talk to
one another.
Male Speaker:
Not anymore!
Bill Ruckelshaus
and and really listen to
one another as they discuss
what a problem looked like from their
perspective.  And collaborative
processes give people an opportunity
to not only talk to one another
in a civil way but to listen and
once that once that trust builds
up within one of these collaborative
processes.  So that people began
to talk and listen to one another
real progress starts to be made.
And universities are a wonderful
place to make that happen.  They
have research capacities, they have
the teaching uh responsibilities,
and they have outreach, particularly
in land grant colleges like Wyoming
have uh have uh have have uh an obligation
to reach out into the community
and try to help help resolve disputes.
All of these things are involved
in collaborative process.  The faculty
can be made available to help resolve
difficult scientific questions, uh
they can use the students and graduate
students as uh uh as helpers in trying
to gather information.  In fact
that will inform the discussion but
then they provide this uh uh literally
an arena where people can come together
and talk to one another in a civil way.
Out of that if they're properly
structured, if they're properly
sponsored by the government or the
governor and legislatures and if
the people themselves are desirous
of coming to a harmonized solution
to their problems enormous progress
can be made.  And and issues that
just seemed intractable and been
around for decades can be solved.
We have any number of them in the
state of Wyoming as well as other
states where institutes like this
have been created over the last
few decades. So collaborative
processes hold great promise I think
for trying to get uh at disputes
that seem intractable uh and at
the same time allow us to to come
to a conclusion that is durable
primarily because it is one that
satisfies all the people around
the table they know they've had a
chance to be heard.  They know their
interests have been taken into account.
They figured out how to harmonize
harmonize their interest with those
of the rest of the people at the
table.  So when you get a solution
out of one of these processes, it
is a lot more durable than one where
you end up with a corner of the
legislature where they can be overturned
by such and such proceeding.  That's
seemed way too detailed a
fashion to do what you asked.
Mike Sullivan
I'll uh uh let me just ask you.
because you're most recent work on the
National Commission for Fiscal Responsibility
which might be viewed as a collaborative
process by some.  [Laughter.]
Uh how would you characterize the tenor
of the current public debate
and what does it say about the need or the
uh inability to have collaborative processes?
Alan Simpson
Well first let me uh,
Mike Sullivan
Turn your microphone on?
Alan Simpson
Yes, I uh I see that I've fouled it up.
Mike Sullivan
Here. [Laughter]
Bill Ruckelshaus
There's a screw loose
Mike Sullivan
let me work on it.
Alan Simpson
Oh I have it I have it now.
[Laughter]
Mike Sullivan
Well Alan it's called a switch!
[Laughter]
Alan Simpson
I don't have to take that! [Laughter]
Just quickly, I served in the legislature
with this delightful man and we
he put a bill in to do conservation
easements.  Let me tell you that
was back in the 70s.  You think that
was popular you're goofy.  And we
lost that by one vote.  They thought
I was a commie after I finished that.
[Laughter]
Uh, but my training came,
I'll answer your question,
I was on the Park County Zoning and
Planning Commission in the 60s.
So I know what hell is from the
origins of hell.  We were saying
"if you want to have a two story
purple outhouse on your property,
by God it's America!"  " You will have
have a two story outhouse...." well
I said go ahead but the neighbors
might not go for that. Anyway.
I really came out of that one painted
red. This guy comes to Washington
with a sense of humor. In doing
the most unbelievable mess of things
and I was on the Environmental Public
Works Committee and all I came away
from was admiration for a guy who
could take more flak by the ton
and keep smiling with a great sense
of humor. And this young man
was in the the he represented uh
a client who was being seriously
abused by the Union Pacific Railroad.
And Ed Herschler, a Democrat, and Hellbaum, and
myself with the council of this young
lawyer took on the Union Pacific
and smashed them flat. Don't forget
the statue books were set up so
the Union Pacific could put a
depot in your living room!
Because they got twenty miles on each
side of the track and inter lacking
minerals and surface.  And they
were crowding out the Trona industry.
So I'm always I dunno, I'm perverse.
It's obvious that I am, but back
to your question.  The president
wanted us as co-chairs, we went
to see him which says everything
on the table, he says yes, everything,
including your Obama-care, yep, he
took our commission in and told
us the same thing. And uh we came
out after 8 months with 5 Democrats
and 5 republicans and 1 independent
voting for a package which is tough.
And real and it's about math.
It's not about emotion. And senior
citizens breaking the bed pans in
the hospices and cheating the veterans
and all this junk that you get out
of em. And social security, how
could you ever change retirement
age to 68 by the year 2050, how
will seniors ever be able to, and
I said, you can figure it out somehow.
Anyway. I'm getting a lot of trouble
that way and uh so for the first
3 months we didn't even have any
trust. I was on the Iraq study
group. There was no trust in the
beginning. That was Jim Baker and
Lee Hamil. So finally Herst and
I said we'll just do a 2 person
report, we don't care if you join
or not. Because the first all of
this stuff, the first few months
they say, who is the biggest spending
president in the history of the United
States before this one. The answer?
George W. Bush. Never voted a single
spending billion six and a half years.
So that would light up
the fire but then they'd say this
guy has 3 times worse, car, stimulus,
I mean, 3 months, finally we said,
we don't give a damn how we got here
it's what do we do now.  This trajectory
of debt deficit interest is on the same
course as Portugal, Spain, Ireland all
the rest except we are bigger.  So we
began to talk. If you can imagine
there was a congresswoman named Jan
Shakowski, Illinois, man oh man
I can tell you she's tough.  And
she just raised hell. But she we
said, well, then what's your plan, she
said, I'll do one, I'll give you
a plan. It wasn't something we accepted,
but, if you're going to be in the
game you don't just sit and bitch.
Put your plan on the table. Don't
just sit and say, I compromise is
a four letter word. In fact, in
fact the speaker said when I asked
him about compromise, he said, I
don't know that word.  And McConnel
doesn't know that word, and Harry
Reed doesn't know that word, and
Pelosi doesn't know that word.
But it won't make any difference
when the markets pull the chain
on us.  They don't give a damn who's
running the country, they just want
their money.  They want more interest
for their money when they see a
dysfunctional government.  So it's
sad to watch, it's more bitter than
I've ever seen, breaks your heart,
Ted Kennedy and I used to work together
on immigration and other issues,
uh I didn't care what he did or
how he lived, but he never broke
his promise to me ever, and that's
one tough guy.  Never broke his word
to me.  But we used to just scrap,
knock each other out, it was fun, I
loved it. Anyway it's uh, we're headed
for deep stuff and and and uh I don't
see any prospect of any kind of
cooperation before the election,
and between November 6 and December
31 hang on to your shorts.  Cause
it's going to be a blood bath of
5 to 7 trillion bucks rolling around.
If you go too far one way it's
a recession.  And if you do too little
it's a recession.  We'll see what
happens.  But you've got to keep
your sense of humor.  I try to do
that.  My mother said that humor
is the universal solvent against
the abrasive elements of life.  The
other one is the definition of politics,
and here it is, very short: in politics
there are no right answers, only
a continual flow of compromises among
groups resulting in a changing cloudy
and ambiguous series of public decisions,
where appetite and ambition compete
openly with knowledge and wisdom.
[Laughter]
Tears are streaming down your cheeks!
Male Speaker
That's too profound for me! [Laughter]
Mike Sullivan
Let me just ask John. Uh you were
you were director of fish and wildlife
during uh spotted owl and reintroduction
of the wolf and a number of other issues
that you can remember better than I can.
Uh where do you think the collaborative
process comes in and what issues
does it particularly lend itself to?
John Turner
well thank you mike, and uh what
a pleasure to join you all.  These,
literally, 3 giants up here, and
I want to thank you all for joining
us today, taking part of your time
uh I'm really proud as hopefully
all of you who live in Wyoming with
what's going on in Laramie uh these
days.  Dr. Burke and her staff,
uh the University of Wyoming is really
a great university in many respects
and one of them is in  the arena
of natural resources. Uh thanks
to the gentlemen here and many others
what's going on in the Ruckelshaus
Institute is uh really an example
of excellence for the mountain west
and for the for entire country how
we can come together and build information,
find common ground, solutions to
some pretty thorny issues.  Uh a
superb school of natural resources,
a wonderful conservation corps working
across the state, and now uh uh the
Barry Center on uh Biodiversity
just has great promise for Wyoming
and the future of the West.  Uh.
President Bush honored me by asking
me to join the US Fish and Wildlife
Service uh in 1990.  And uh that
was literally the best job in Washington.
But I was, uh, a foot taller and a head
of hair I think that's I think that's
a Simpson Simpsonite.  But before
I got into the Fish and Wildlife
Service mostly because of endangered
species and uh the wetlands and
a few others, I can recall uh going
to Shirley Basin to reintroduce
uh the black footed ferret which
Jack they found here in Meeteetse,
uh the rarest mammal in the world,
we were down to 18 animals and decided
to roll the dice and look for a place
for re-introduction in the Shirley
Basin and the ranchers there on private
land agreed to work with us to allow
us to reintroduce uh the black footed
ferret. Um and I asked one of
the ranchers, I remember we were
up there to release the first ferrets,
pickups going everywhere, and private
leaving gates open and dust and
biologists setting up all kinds of
crap and I said, why are you letting
us do this?  Here is the most rarest
and endangered mammal on the planet
and you're allowing us to put it
right in the middle of your operation.
He said, well gosh, it's a part
of Wyoming landscape and it's kind
of exciting just don't tell our friends
at the Wyoming stock growers we're
doing this cause of the spotted owl,
the wolf reintroduction, uh I might
make a few comments on wolf reintroduction
because Al's here and his memory's
pretty ripe on this one.  Uh wolf reintroduction
was a national uh interest of course
for decades uh to bring wolves back
to Yellowstone landscape and uh
myself and a few others had the audacity
to think we could come up with a
plan which would meet the interests
of the western states, the cattlemen,
the sportsmen, as well as the national
interest and so working with Alan and
I'm sure he regrets to this day and
Malcolm Wall and Conrad Burns and
Jim McClure, Larry Craig some pretty tough
hombres, we made, we put together a group, call it
a collaborative effort.  Uh we had
ranchers, we had wool growers, we
had uh, local officials, we had people
from game and fish agencies in a
three state region, we had conservationists,
wildlife groups, and we put together
a a pledge, a plan and a pledge,
to Wyoming, Montana, and Idaho that
we would reintroduce the wolves,
which we did, 31 of them into Yellowstone
Park.  Uh and also some in Idaho.
We made the pledge uh at the threshold
would be 10 breeding pair in each
state.  Uh 10 breeding units in
Idaho, Montana.  And once that happened,
then we would turn jurisdiction back
to the states.  Uh and that we would
make a compact with the ranchers
and the livestock owners the big
game interests that when wolves
misbehaved they would be managed
but they would be off limits and
I uh so it was this successful collaborative
effort where the western congressional
delegations were not happy about
this.  But it sounds like as good
a deal as fair a deal for the western
states and the national interest.
And I regret to this day we have
never kept the promise to the people
of Wyoming and Idaho and Utah.
Uh it's great to have wolves back
as part of this landscape but by
Wyoming law we have almost 30 breeding
pair now and 3 times the promise
pacts I think were close to 50 pacts,
in Wyoming uh a lot of people don't
want to recognize that government agents
have killed 1700 wolves since they
were introduced. Why should the
tax payers be these conscientious
agents trying to take of problem wolves.
So unfortunately, the people that
bought into that collaborative effort
to get it done was successful but
the final outcome where we had I'm
sure well intended but misguided
activists and activist judges which keep moving
moving the goal post and uh certain
groups that want to litigate and
so forth.  But I think uh the US
Fish and Wildlife Service tried
to down this wolf since 2002 and
of course that's been for the
court and we'll try again this fall
with a compromise that uh the federal
government, Governor Mead, and others have
tried to put together, uh I think
there's already been court filings
uh there already been court filings
before Fish and Wildlife interiors
even publish the rules for this
fall.  But it's unfortunate we did
not keep our pledge to the West
uh to the western states.  The people,
I got off a plane about a few years
ago, here in Cody.  Ran into a very prominent
lady I won't use here name, I promise
a very intelligent businesswoman
I've been friends with, saw her
in the airport, went to give her
a hug, she just shaken me she backed
away from me, and she said, John,
I can never forgive you for what
you did. I said, What? What are we talking
about, she says, your intr -  reintroduction
of wolves into Yellowstone. I love
Yellowstone park. I go there every
year with my kids and my grandkids
I can never go back to Yellowstone
because of what you've done.  Now
you can say, well that's a little
unreal, but people around the country,
you all do understand the passion
with wolves. The years in the
legislature, I saw a grown man stand
up and break into tears on 2 issues
of my 19 year one of course is abortion
the other was wolves.  So we're
not there yet on wolves, and, um, I'm
sure Alan would have quite a few
comments on them.  Northern spotted
owl probably biggest endangered species
issue facing the country.  Prior
was salmon, uh, Pacific salmon, involved
3 states, uh about 12 million acres,
we established critical habitat on
7 million.  The entire northwest
was fearful, people's jobs, just
wanted to pay off their mortgage,
send their kids to school, uh I think
we found good middle ground uh on
science uh to try to help communities
for the unemployment issues, but
spotted owls was another tough one.  We
did that have a lot of collaborative
efforts, timber companies, communities,
and uh the three states.
Mike Sullivan
What what kind of natural resource issues
in the West are not suitable
for the collaborative process?
Bill Ruckelshaus
It's an important, uh uh, thank
you Mike for asking that because
that's an important thing to remember.
All issues can't be solved by a
collaborative process.  They're
not suited for it.  Uh but and all issues
that for which collaborative processes
are suited aren't always solved
that way because all these processes
don't work.  Sometimes people don't
participate in them and they don't
really participate in good faith.
They want to blow them up and if
somebody's determined to that you
can usually blow them.  But the
the best way from my standpoint to
think about it, areas in which these
collaborative processes work well
are sort of place based uh issues.
And they that sort of defines a
lot of natural resource problems.
Uh, for instance in a watershed
you have a lot of different claimants
for the use of water.  Uh ranging
from wildlife habitat, to fish habitat,
to irrigation, to uh recreation.  Uh
drinking water supply, the conditions
of water quality.  Those issues can
provide people and just proper water
rights that are so well known in
the West, as very emotional issues.
Those kinds of water related and
watershed place based kind of problems,
if you get everybody at the table
and open their minds and get them willing
to talk to one another it's amazing
how much progress can be made.
We have an situation in Puget Sound,
where I now live, and uh a watershed,
and there just huge fights over salmon,
which are listed as endangered in
Puget Sound, and which, so it is
a problem of habitat, where those
fish normally would spawn and breed
and where this uh smolts would uh would originate.
There are huge fights over these
questions.  And there are 14 major
watersheds in Puget Sound.  In
3 of them there have been collaborative
processes, one of which has gone
over 20 years, where the people
are all together.  They have managed
to sit down and talk through all
their desires for the uses of the
water in that sound.  That's where
Mountaineer is located, Ft. Lewis
is there, there are a lot of small
towns, there is an Indian reservation
on the edge of the Squalee River,
that's the river where this uh collaborative
process has been working.  All of
these people have worked out their
their their interests and have managed
to harmonize them.  And they got
more money, and this may not make
everybody in Wyoming happy, but they
got more money in the stimulus program
than all the rest of the watersheds
in Puget Sound put together.
For 2 reasons: they had a plan that
they all agreed to, and they all
went forward and tried to raise money
on it uh from first the federal
government and anyplace else they
could find it.  They have made enormous
progress in that watershed. They have, they've
worked out all their problems themselves
and they all think of the watershed
as their place.  That's where they
live and that's where their children
are going to grow up, and uh
they they find it enormously uh rewarding
that they have been able to come
together. And it's primarily because
a farmer who was a leading citizen
in the watershed and an Indian chief
named Billy Frank shook hands and
said, we've got to stop fighting and
stop going to court stop going to the
legislature trying to get our way and figure
out how to harmonize our interest and they've
done it.  It is it's a marvelous place
to visit because you know almost the
minute you come into that watershed
the people there are all on the same page
pulling in the same direction.
John Turner
it, it isn't going to work if the
key players won't sit at the table.
They figure there's uh either they
can force something that they want important
in their own means or the objectives
they think they can get in an arena
Or I think there are some issues
that are over ripe.  They've been
worked so much and people have beaten
the tar out of each other so long and
it's been in the papers so long that
that trying to find common
ground might be difficult.
Alan Simpson
My, in my, I think I'm correct that
Montana has not yet done a wilderness
bill nor Idaho?  But Wyoming did.
And Herschler was governor.
Malcom and I and Dick Cheney
were in the house and in the
Senate and and John Cyberling
was the chair of the house committee
and he wanted to put he had a staff
member who wanted to rise every morning
at uh face east and transform himself
into some kind of Zeus or something.
I never did figure out what the
hell the guy was doing, but he wanted
to set the whole state of Wyoming
into wilderness.  So we put a bill
to make a city park in Cleveland
a wilderness, and Cyberling then
came over to visit and we began
to talk.  And then the enviros came
and and there was never enough but
we need another 285 thousand acres,
or we need an so finally Malcom
and I and Herschler and Dick got a
big map and we said, bring us
a Crayola.  A big 'ol black Crayola.
And we said, how many more acres
you want? I mean cause you're not getting
out of this room and playing this
game where you get it and then you
go and give it again and then you
go to court. So they said well we
need a hundred and whatever it was
so Herschler looked at it is said,
well we need something down there
in the southwest down there
around Fontanel he drew a
little picture and had acres in it.
Cheney said, well back there behind
Hogadon, we like that up there.
That would look good up there.
Malcolm said, oh I've been waiting
for that around Cloud Peak,
we'll just, hell I said, well
Bob Cat Crick we'll just run something
back over the ridge there.  And
we did and they said, well, they,
and we said, well isn't they the
acreage you wanted, they says, well
yeah, but we have to talk to our
people.  We said, no.  This is it.
You've been hanging around like
poor relatives and now that's it.
[Laughter.]  And so we sent it up
to the President and I to show how
retractable it is, I believe if
I'm not mistaken that Steve Sims
and and Church even tried to do
it.  Conrad and Locke has tried to
do it.  In other words, efforts
between Democrats and Republicans
always cremated by these ropes that
are demanding more and more and more.
It's unbelievable. So I think I'm correct
maybe somebody can correct me
but I don't think either of
those two states, and don't forget
Wyoming leaving off Alaska, the lower 48,
Wyoming provides 44% of the nation's
wilderness.  It's like I said we
gave at the office.  [Laughter]
Mike Sullivan
Well, what a day, I think
what you're saying is that there
are issues where because of the
demands of one group or another you
can never reach the harmony that
Bill talks about.  One of the one
of the questions that occurred to
me today was, and I think it may
be why we can't go anywhere on health
care, nat- nationwide with regard
to the parameters yes or no politics
on that but, has it been your experience
that when you have an issue that
there is a large group that
wants the status quo?
Bill Ruckelshaus
They're they're not going to negotiate
good faith, one of the things you have
to do before you, Alan Alan's decision
is an example of place based. Example except
pl- space was unlimited.  That's no definition
of the space. There's no watershed.
No place that they could identify
with as their place.  And and so
it is important to be able to put
some boundaries on what they uh what
was they're discussing in order
for these collaborative processes
to work.  Uh and you I I have believed
for years, in fact we suggested this
to the congress on environmental
issues, that they should try to get
the before introducing a bill a
member of the committee should try
to get the relevant players around
the table and say, okay, we're going
to work this out, much the way Alan
just described in the wilderness
situation.  And here the criteria
we are going to use is we need an
agreement and if we don't get an
agreement out of all of you it will
be balance because of the balanced group we are
going to go ahead anyway.  So it
forces a decision for a certain period
of time it is a form of collaborative
process.  There's more force associated
with it.  It won't change the decision
of the process itself is normal but if you
don't have everybody collaborating
and somebody says the status quo
is fine they're not a player.  Before
you start one of these processes,
what you have to do whether it is
a university Wyoming or Washington
or any other university or place
where this is going to happen.
You have to do an assessment.  You
have to go out and talk to all of
the people that are going to be involved
and say, are you going to play?
Are you willing to try best you
can to harmonize your interests
with that of others at the table?
And if they say, no, I can get
a better deal in the legislature
or the courts or the status quo
is fine with me, then you don't have
a a a requisite agreement to try
to work things out with a proper group.
Alan Simpson
Think of it this way.
You've got uh the situation, now,
83 guys in the house, and gals,
they didn't go there to limit government,
they went there to stop government.
Well how the hell do you start anything
when you've got 83 people rock bound
that want to stop government?
Merry Christmas! [Laughter]
Mike Sulivan
John?
John Turner
I think the uh idea of rightness
is is there is some merit to it.
I recall in the legislature Alan
mentioned the open space easement gives land
owners another tool at auction where their property
rights uh when we put that in it was the
agriculture interest, a few others
that helped do us in.  Then we came
up with an idea called the Wildlife
Trust Fund that uh the two of you remember
where were going to take mineral
proceeds create a 5 to 250 million
dollars to compensate Wyoming ranchers to
uh to keep the land private property
but uh to provide easements. Again
it was the Ag interests and
we've talked a lot about it
recently with some of their leaders
about how they helped throughout
that and we lost it by one vote in
two sessions.  Wyoming in my opinion
has an opportunity that no other
state has to protect its wildlife,
resources, its open space, its critical
watersheds, its tradition of agriculture
in a way that no other state can
cause both states have screwed it
up and lost it and they're spending
billions to protect remnants where
Wyoming can really mold their landscapes
and partnership with the land owners.
Well now that has all changed uh
the Wyoming land owners all over
the state are forming partnerships
with nonprofit groups, with the
Wyoming trust fund which is now in
place, the NRCS, the University
of Wyoming, it has provided data
and background, and I think that
Wyoming stockholder's agriculture land
trust is now protected 170,000 acres across
Wyoming on a volunteer basis. They're
now the 9th largest land trust in
the United States there are 1700
of them, uh, just down here in Meeteetsee
the uh Epperson family at the Hat
Two Ranch protected a huge 13,000
uh acre easement provided aquidity.
Cash for future generation to help
that family to help keep ranching
down at the Butt Ranch down in Sublette
County.  We just did a wonderful
uh uh conservation easement deal
where they're going to buy the ranch
use the proceeds to buy the ranch
next to them keep both protected and uh
provide easements to help sage grouse,
winter mule deer habitat, moose habitat,
so what's going on with the Wyoming
land owners now?  Using good signs
for priority areas uh people bringing
their resources together part of
the mineral industry has been willing
to put up money to impact to to mitigate
impact in the upper Green.  So the
collaborative effort now is is really
working well.  Uh and we have an
opportunity to do a lot more because
I think now the timeliness is right
where Wyoming ranchers see uh an
opportunity to keep lands in private
ownership to keep ranching protect
public value. uh resources, so
there's great opportunity for Wyoming
based on this kind of collaborative effort
Mike Sullivan
And so many of these issues where there
isn't that self-interest and harmony from
the beginning, you need to have some kind
of a hammer that provides that self
interest.  And it seems to me in many cases
that's leadership.  Whether it's
the Senate committee that says,
we're going to do something.  We
prefer you do it collaboratively,
but if you don't do it we're going
to do it.  Or a governor who says,
this is an issue and we're going
to take care of it.  But as we see
in today's political world, so many
of the leaders, as Al mentioned,
and as we see the elections coming
up even, uh the executive uh nominees,
are going to come in with an unwillingness
to talk about compromise.  Or collaboration.
How do you get the leadership into
a collaborative attitude in order
to move some of these intractable
issues off the status quo or off
of the self-interest issues and
into an area where you can have
some kind of harmonization of the interests?
Bill Ruckelshaus
If I could answer that question
we wouldn't need to have
a presidential election.
How do you get leaders to be leaders?
If leadership is defined as no
give, no compromise, no backing away
from the principle, we ought to
have principles that guide our conduct
but principles don't say you can
never compromise in order to achieve
a greater approximation toward whatever
principle you're trying to preserve.
It may be necessary to compromise
to get there.  And it is clearly
true when these collaborative processes
work it is because leaders in the
various among the various interest
groups that are being represented
at the table come forward and exercise
leadership.  One of the things they
have to do is go back and talk to
the people.  If they're representing
an environmental group, or ranchers,
or whoever it is that that is part
of their uh contingent, they can't
just go in there and represent themselves.
They have to go in there and talk
to their groups and say, here's where
we are, what do you think?  And
then exercise some persuasiveness
and leadership among their own group
to get them to move forward toward
a compromise that will give most
people most of what they want.  If
somebody comes out with everything
they want then probably somebody
else got nothing.  So you're going
to need to have a willingness to
compromise when those groups come
together.  But those leaders have
to usually emerge during the discussion
of the collaboration itself.  And
it's not somebody running for presidential
office it's somebody who is very
unlikely.  They just happened to
be someone with an interest that
uh they have been imaginative enough
to figure out how they can harmonize
with somebody else's interest.
Alan Simpson
I think a a remarkable thing
is the existence of this thing for
18 years.  Uh there were people of
all stripes who were terribly terribly
concerned about hearing about this
operation starting up.  You remember
that?  I do.  Big time.  Well, and
it came from, it, I wouldn't even
name one, all of them were concerned,
what are they going to do uh they're
going to mess around and uh they're
going to get into land use again
and they're going to get into this
and this and water use and all the
things that create high high passion
in Wyoming.  So bad that a member
of I think they had an oversight
outfit in the legislature, our budget
was 5 million bucks out of you know,
I don't know what the hell it was,
a billion and a half or whatever,
and wanted an investigation of this
group and put it in the law.  Now
that's how fun and games this was
when it started.  It's been there
for 18 years.  Let me tell you.
I dealt with people like Robert
Birds, George Mitchell, Al Cranston,
Democrats of the first order, and
George Mitchell, you remember, Bill,
put us all in a room, Democrats and
Republicans, and he said, we're
going to do a clean air act.  And
we're going to do that, we have
a conference and he brought in everybody
one after the other.  What great
patience, it takes tremendous patience,
I do not have that.  I never have
had.  I'll eventually get my foot
in it without question but I'll
stick around.  I've never given anybody
the ice treatment.  That's the worse
thing of all time.  You give the
other side the ice treatment, I'm
not talking to you, it's a good way
to destroy marriages, it's a good
way to destroy anything, destroy
nations, I used to say to Cheney,
why the hell don't you talk to North
Korea and Iran?  Well we don't talk
to Iran.  Well I says we won't have
anybody left!  [Laughter]
And then Dick is a chum of the ages.
He's just one of the dearest guys
I have.  Of course they then chose
the demonize him, sadly enough,
cause he's just he's just he's right.
And that's my personal opinion.
But.  Never the less.  Madness.
To see to see the uh uh uh came
out of came out of that hearing one
night, or the uh conference, and
there were a bunch of guys, all environmentalists,
sitting around like they were sitting
around the fire if there had been
a fire.  And I says, what are you
guys doing out here?  Well we're
figuring out how to beat Chafee
and Mitchell in the next election.
I say, you people are stupid.
If you didn't have Mitchell and Chafee
a Democrat and a Republican to do
the thoughtful patent work, you're
going to get something rammed into
you, that you won't even know what
it looks like.  I mean, uh, you
know, this delisting issue, I have
a word for those people out there.
Keep your word.  I voted for the
delist, I voted for the grizzlies,
and I voted for the wolves on the
basis that when that population
of grizzlies reached 664, that would
be it and it would go into another
plan.  The minute it hit there, it
went to court.  That second.
I don't like that at all.  It's called
lying.  And then the other one was
get to a certain breeding pair, wolves
in this and this and we'll say that's
it.  Principle prey base of wolves
is is an ungulate.  They'll eat
60 ungulates a year, a breeding pair.
Well how many breeding pairs?
I listed all that, I bought that,
Now, here we go. The minute that
hits, I talked to Malloy, not even a hair
before I said, you're as ornery as I am,
the judge.  He said, I know, but
I'm as ornery on both sides.  And
he is.  That's good.  But never the
less, keep your word.  You can't
have anything collaborative or honest
or anything unless you keep your
word.  I don't like people who don't
keep their word and I can identify
their organizations.  I'll still
go talk to them, but I'll ram it
right in their nose, too!
Mike Sullivan
something about the Gazoo, is....
Bill Ruckelshaus
Let me make one point, cause Alan
mentioned there was some concern
when the University of Wyoming started
this effort to encourage collaboration
in the state to resolve some of these
issues.  The university's role is
not to solve the problem.  The university's
role is to cre- to create a a center
where people can come and resolve
their own differences.  They can
provide facilitation, they can provide
knowledge, they can provide scientific
information that will help inform
the discussion, but the university
itself is not uh is using them
as a center for helping and facilitating
collaboration doesn't solve the problem.
I mean if the university comes
down on one side or the other on
one of these issues officially as
the university, they get into a huge
big controversy and become less
successful as the university itself.
But as a neutral form where people
can come together and solve their
own disputes and then the university
steps back and stays out of it, they
perform a very useful function for the state.
Mike Sullivan
So how would you say you get leaders
into the collaborative process, or use
the authority of leadership to get others
into the collaborative process?
John Turner
Well, I think it stops it
starts with trying trying to be a
good listener.  Trying to be humble,
trying to gather information, try
to find people on all sides of the
issue who have a genuine interest
in a solution.  Um, I think today
as we look a lot of the resource use
Alan commented on the legislative
process, uh, I don't know if I can
offer a lot there.  But it seems
like what brings people today together
is maybe a hammer.  It is a regulatory
hammer hanging over people.  It might
be the Endangered Species Act, it
might be 404, uh it might be the
Migratory Bird Act which if anybody
reads it is a hell of a lot tougher
than the Endangered Species Act,
uh so those are kind of hammers.
A land owner might say, yeah, but
there are other kinds of hammers.
It's the income tax or state tax
on my large ranch and I'm having
trouble with a cash flow right now
just to pay off the pick-up and send
the kids to school, uh that might
not be the hammer, but there are
some things you can bring the
land owner which help make that
positive center, uh, fortunately there
things in the tool kit now where
we can provide a equitity cash to
a land owner, which might allow him
to continue the operation.  It might
be an incentive to his kids to hang
around, and so we keep our multi-generational
ranches going, and sometimes I think
collaborative interests work simply
because a lot of people even on diverse
sides want to do the right thing and
if they get a setting that is somewhat
safe, a watering hole, where people
seem like they can be trusted, they
really want to do the right thing.
There are people, there are conservation
people, the land owners, people
in business, in the private sector.
Uh, if you can take away the threats
and they really want to do what's
best for the land or their business
or their interests in the community.
And if you can do that with partners
in a non-threatening way that doesn't
get you at the other end you haven't
given some away, uh I think it really
helps the collaborative process.
Mike Sullivan
Let me ask this.  Uh what in your collective
opinions, are the most sensitive environmental/
natural resources issues that we are going
to be dealing with for the next few
years, and are they are they suitable
for the collaborative process?
Bill Ruckelshaus
There's one that's overriding everything.
And that's the question of climate
change and that is not something
of collaboration, it's a global issue.
I mean you're just kidding yourself
if you think you can get everybody
sit down and work that out. Uh
uh I mentioned to you before when
we started here I'm currently involved
in an ocean acidification panel in the state of
Washington which is to make recommendations
on the first of October.  And part
of the problem is as carbon is absorbed
by the ocean, since the Industrial
Revolution really, it has been building
up and it's about 30% higher today,
the carbon content of the ocean
than it was when the Industrial Revolution
started.  Uh we thought this was
a great thing because it was absorbing
a lot of the carbon that was being
generated by burning fossil fuels,
now we see that it is causing shell
fish to have difficulty forming shells
so that we've got oysters, that
are about a 175 million dollar industry
in Peugeot Sound, uh a good number
of those oysters have been unable
to form shells for the last five
and a half years the the native oysters
grown in the hatcheries are doing just
fine because they can filter the
water and they can take uh they
can provide more alkalinity for it.
But that that's just another aspect
of the same problem, of carbon coming
out of the atmosphere.  What can
you do about it?  You know our our
panel's supposed to make recommendations
in about 60 days and it's not clear
what you can do about it.  Certainly
can't do anything about the global
problem in one state.  Uh but it
is a huge problem and something we're
going to have to figure out a way
to deal with.  Uh through some combination
of of programs.  There's no one
magic bullet to do it by any means.
But we haven't yet gotten ourselves
in a position to uh come to grips
with this issue.  Yet it's it's just
going to really coming at us like
a freight train the longer we live.
John Turner
I think two others that will impact the West,
certainly may not be in the realm of what
Bill said on climate change but it'll
be water, the fights over water here
in the West, as the West and the Southwest face
pretty severe droughts.  It's how
our water comes off in the spring and
Ranchers versus fish versus cities and it'll
be Wyoming against the downstream
states.  And uh the second issue
might be sustainability.  Uh all
of us in our personal lives, our
business lives, our communities,
how are we utilizing resources, how
uh much waste are we generating, how
do we use energy, uh how do we use water.
Uh are we good stewards for the
resources of this country's been
blessed with.  And under the rubric
of sustainability certainly around
the world the access to fresh water
is you know, 2 billion people don't
have access to fresh water.  A child
dies every 15, 20 seconds from water
born disease.  I think we have to
be conscious of this.  2 billion
people don't have access to just
basic energy, you're not going to
have environmental protection or
education or good health care or
economic development, jobs, if you
don't have access to basic energy,
that confronts a lot of the issues
on climate change.  So uh, I think
those are some of the issues that
are going to whirl around
in the days ahead.
Alan Simpson
Climate change is real.
What what's causing it I I
I have, I share some thoughts,
but it's there.  Let's just say it's
there.  To deal with it, I don't
know how you would do it.  Another
one would be in this part of the
world, fracking, fracking with regard
to the oil and gas industry is going
to be a big time mess around uh for
sure.  Few sheds, Um, You know.
Look at today.  We don't even, as
far as I know we don't even have
a fire in Wyoming but we're getting
a whole load from Idaho and Montana
and it's very limited, kind of sad.
But but that's the way that is.
The other one is the ancient stuff
of water. Riparian verses appropriations
So those are real things.
Air quality, uh quality
of life.  Population.  I would think
we've got it figured out that that
your population has doubled since
the beginning of mankind.  And ready
ready 2056, well look at those figures.
How many foot prints will fit on
the face of the earth?  But you don't
hear hear some of the groups talking
about that!  That's critical.  Because,
you know, some civilizations have
disappeared because they ate the
last animal and took the last stick
of wood and used the last resource
and they're gone.  Don't know why
they're gone, but they're gone.
So those are issues that don't get
dealt with cause you're into religion,
and you're into this and you're
into that, it's all shaded into 4
things that I've found in my public
life.  Emotion, fear, guilt, and
racism.  And either pass or kill
or support or get rid of something
using a deft blend of emotion, fear,
guilt, and racism.  It's hell of
a fun place to work.  [Laughter.]
Mike Sullivan
Great place to live too!
Bill Ruckelshaus
Another issue that we we'll
we've got to context issue we have
to think about.  I was born in 1932.
And uh when I was born we had a
little over 2 billion people on
earth.  Last summer we announced
that we have over 7 billion people
on earth.  We have a lot more technology
than we did 80 years ago when I
was born.  We have a lot more wealth, may not feel like it,
not right now in the middle of this
recession, but we have a lot more
wealth globally than we had uh 80 years
ago.  And that's from the beginning
of man's time on earth to 1932 we
had 2 billion people.  Just in my
lifetime we have more than tripled
that.  7 billion people, more than
that now, since a year and a half
has passed.  So then the real question
is in thinking about these ecosystems,
a lot about which we are talking
today, how how do you preserve these
ecosystems,  and these goods and services
of these ecosystems, water, air,
earth, provide us, and at the same
time accommodate the needs of man
and man's desire to be prosperous
within that ecosystem?
Man cannot be seen as separate from the
ecosystem, we are part of the ecosystem.
And if we can't figure out a way to live
consistent with the other living
things that share the space of this
planet with us, and and make it
as possible as we can that those
other living things can prosper
as well, it is ultimately going to
effect us.   So we we need to begin
to think of ourselves not as if we're
going to set aside some wilderness
and never let man in there therefore
it'll make a field of it, that's fine,
but by the same token we are occupying
more and more of the ecosystems of
the world and we're part of it
and we'ver got to figure out how
to be how how to cause man to prosper
and at the same time the other living
things in that ecosystem to prosper as well.
Mike Sullivan
When you have the federal government
owning more than half the land, or
half the land but more than half
the minerals, how do you effectively
get the federal government into
collaborative processes?
[Laughter] Come on Jump on that!
Bill Ruckelshaus
The answer is leadership!  It really is!
There is no reason the people
running the federal agencies that
have so much impact on the land of the West
not be collaborative, not to include
the people that are going to be impacted
by whatever decisions they make,
by whatever changes they make.  You've
got to do that in order to get the
people to where effectively support
every decision you make and if you're
not any good at that you're not any
good at leadership.  You know.
It seems to me that it's absolutely
necessary that part of the federal
official's responsibilities are seeing
as as both listening hard to what
people say or or their intr- interests
and bring those along in whatever
decisions they make so it has
a chance of being durable.
John Turner
I think uh sometimes almost in
the western states get a
little bit of an inferiority
complex, we do too much whining.  Uh
it seems like that's always good
politics. Uh. And yet I think uh with
the right kind of leadership uh
from the governor's office, delegation,
and uh having once been a federal
bureaucrat uh in a federal agency
I think uh those agencies for the
most part have some very good people.
And if we don't start by beating
the tar out of them but working with
the regional directors, working
with the secretaries, uh, on western
issues.  Now, some of those are
going to be fraught with there's
no way that we're going to get an
adequate solution, but I think there's
a lot of examples where the people
in the West under your leadership
and others, and today with Matt
Mead, the right kind of delegation,
bringing in the right kind of people
with with uh our congressional delegation
and so forth, uh I see a lot of
promise in the western states coming
together and finding some solutions.
I see where governor Mead now heads
up an eight state effort on sage grouse,
which is one of those hammers hanging
over the western states, and I think
is is an opportunity where the western
states can come up with a toolkit
and plan a  strategy that would be
way out ahead of what the feds are
looking at.  And thus get a lot of
diverse groups in behind it.
So I think there's real opportunity
if the western states would whine
a little bit less, and uh thoughtfully
uh approach our federal agencies
and take partners with them, the
private sector and uh reasonable nonprofit
groups, I I do feel there's more
middle ground than we sometimes admit.
Mike Sullivan
Thank you, let me just say that
you're talking about the sage grouse.
It seems to me that is an issue that has
lent itself to collaborative processes
both state and federal and it's partly
because there's such a big hammer.
Alan Simpson
I think, I sense that there's more
listening and more transparency in
every one of those laws that we
worked with uh when the federal
government was doing something, that's
our landlord, was doing something
to the tenants.  There was a way to
the tenants to speak, uh and I think
they're listening.  I think I see
that in the Shoshoni force with things
of recent vintage.  I see that with
Yellowstone Park.  We held those
hearings in in Wyoming and Cody.
I think what's happening, when you
have one of those meetings and and
the nut job gets up and starts frothing
at the mouth, people sit for a while
and then they say, why don't you
shut up?  So that we can get on
with the discussion here!  That is, I
I think is is happening and that
I I think is very good.  Listening
takes place, and uh they all have
a process of participation.  And
I think there's I think more listening
going on with what's local of course,
local feeling in the Yellowstone Park.
Sylvan Pass, and ice climbing.  There's
more listening.  I think that's good.
Mike Sullivan
On that positive note,
We're going to open
it up to questions from the audience.
Male Speaker
Tyler Krutzfelf.  I'm a Montana guy.  But on the ...
Mike Sullivan
We didn't beat up on you hard enough!  [Laughter.]
Tyler Krutzfelf
On the uh current topic of coal export,
which would most likely benefit
Montana and Wyoming, there's a cash
being spent on both sides of that
dialogue, by the environmental
community, the face of Washington,
Oregon, and the uh coal community.
Is that issue an example of uh
an uh collaborative opportunity maybe perhaps
for that policy and the Ruckelshaus Institute in
Washington state and Laramie?
Bill Ruckelshaus
The coal export uh issue is is very hot
right now in the state of Washington.
Uh probably too hot to be subject to
collaboration uh Alan mentioned several
hours ago, we've been speaking [Laughter], uh
Alan Simpson
he didn't have a good breakfast!
[Laughter]
he's a bit testy this morning.
Bill Ruckelshaus
He was, I can't even remember what
it was I was going to say.  But that that
issue is probably not right, we mentioned
rightness, for collaboration because
there is too much emotion involved,
particularly in the opposition to
it and I think they are kind
of entrenched right now.  Over time,
if it looked like some kind of export
facility moving forward then
you'd get more in the
mood of beginning to discuss what
form should that export take, and
how many trains should come into
the state, what's going to happen
to the coal dust.  I'm mean, there's
all these kinds of issues being
raised by the opposition to the export,
and I don't think that as of this
juncture they would be ready to sit
down with those who want to export
the coal and really work it out.
I haven't asked them that question,
so I don't know that, but what we
do, and I think it the same thing
is true of Wyoming, in the state
of Washington is do this assessment
ahead of time and ask every body
what they think.  If they're not
willing to sit down, we recommend
that they not try one of these processes.
Because they don't have a very
good chance at working.
John Turner
Well, it's a good question for Wyoming.
I hap I happen to be pretty strong
advocate of coal and in the way of
transparency is one and it's important
to the people of Wyoming. It pays
a lot of our bills, it pays for our
school, it builds our hospitals,
provides money for management of
natural resources.  So coal's pretty
important in the state of Wyoming,
the largest coal deposit that's in
political jurisdiction in the world.
And uh helps light a lot of homes
and and provide energy for businesses
and jobs across America.  So it's
important in Wyoming and I also uh
serve on the Board of Directors
at Peabody Energy, the largest coal
company in the world, and we're
interested in actively exporting
coal.  We're the largest coal miner
in the Powder River Basin, pay a
lot of taxes in Wyoming, uh, but
we're exporting Wyoming coal now,
it's going in barges and we ship
from Houston and the ports.  And
so uh it's going to be an active
outlet for coal from the Illinois
basin, uh, some Appalachian coal,
but especially met coal used for
making steel.  You have thermal
coal and met coal.  Uh if you go
around the world and uh and look
at what's happening, coal's the fastest
growing, uh, energy source now in
the world.  And there's a coal plant
every 2 or 3 days now coming online
in India and China.  Coal is America's
most abundant energy resource, so
it would seem to me rather than trying
to just do coal in which a lot of
groups would like to do, and admittedly
coal is at a disadvantage currently.
with the wonderful finds in
natural gas that's been happening.
shale gas throughout the United States
but the price of coal is depressed.
But US coal is going, if it's not
burned here in the United States
it's for darned sure going to go
overseas.  And if it isn't US coal,
if it isn't Wyoming coal, it'll be
Indonesia coal which is poor ore,
it'll come out of Australia, South
Africa, perhaps Mongolia.  So uh,
I think it's going to be an export
product out of the United States,
whether it goes uh out of Washington
in the Columbia River there's some
pretty advocate groups out there,
uh remains to be seen.  But uh there're
terminals being built in Houston,
there's current terminals there,
so uh we're going to be moving coal
out of the United States in the
export market.  If not us it'll come
from Columbia and other sources.
Bob Lewdel
Um, John, this is a uh, a uh, this is a
uh question uh but but maybe not
really a question.  Going back to
2000 you'll, Bob Lewdel, good to see you, John.
You'll remember in 2000 we were in Missoula
and uh we formed uh, and you were
there representing the Conservation
Fund, and we formed the American
Wildlife Conservation Partners,
and we struggled for 2 days as you
probably recall, and we put together
some uh 30 uh hunter conservation
organizations.  Now we are 50 hunter
conservation organizations.  Uh we
have provided for the uh Bush administration
uh 1 in 2 for wildlife for uh the
21st century.  Buying 1 and 2 for
Bush and buying 3 for uh the Obama
Administration.  We picked out the
most important issues that faced
the uh uh hunting community, the
uh, hunting community, were the first
conservationists founded by the
Boone and Crocket back in 1887.  Uh,
John, uh, we have, uh 50 groups now.
We uh, are are strong and well.  We
work together, NRA, Boone and Crocket
uh, Russell Sportsman's Foundation,
the Isaac Walton League, all
come together.  We have sign
on letters that go uh to uh the
uh uh various uh uh members on the
uh uh US Congress, the administration,
on issues that are important to us.
Uh we uh got the uh uh President
Bush uh to sign an executive order
for a wildlife conference, uh in
2008, as you will remember.  And
that was uh 100 years after Teddy
Roosevelt's first uh conservation
uh summit on wildlife and natural
resources.  Uh.  We are now beginning
to uh engage the environmental community,
and uh it it's kind of interesting,
John, because uh the reason why
they are engaging with us is our
science is better, we're getting
reception from uh uh not only our
our legislators, uh but also uh
from the executive uh branch of government.
And uh the uh environmental community
is uh edging closer to us and uh
we're making overtures, uh, that
uh one would not have thought possible,
you know, 5 or 6 years ago.  So
I just wanted to uh to point out,
because you and I have not had a
chance to talk about that recently,
but to me this is one of the great
uh examples of collaboration uh working
and it's working in a very quiet
way, very effective way, and we're
pretty proud of it and as you
recall, we were there in smoky
Missoula in 2000 and uh here we are some
12 years later and and uh it's been
a very successful and gratifying,
uh, experience and just sort of an
example of, to what the 3 of you
have been talking to uh uh the last
hour and a half.  Thank you.
Mike Sullivan
Thank you, Bob.
John Turner
Bob, thanks for being here, and thanks
for the decades of you being in the
trenches working for wildlife and
collaborative efforts.  And indeed the
partnership, the coalition, the science
they're bringing just out of the Upper
Green, on uh mule deer, and uh fisheries,
and pronghorn migration routes, and
you're, as you continue to be, a
real leader in them and I salute
you.  Uh indeed the sportsman in
this country has been at the forefront
of conservation and putting their
money and their resources into protecting
habitat and watersheds and I salute
you.  And Mike, I'd just like to
say on coal I didn't say, I think
what we all need to do is work for
a lot of the science that is going
on where uh on clean coal where we
can strip carbon uh we ought to
continue it here in the United States
and fortunately the new energy school
in down at the UW has got some will
have some excellent research ongoing.
How do we use coal, to continue
to use it for America's future,
for jobs, income and and in the coal
better, we've stripped most of the
pollution out of coal in the last many
years.  Now the challenge is carbon.
Jack Durnell
I'm Jack Dernell from Meeteetee
Uh, trying to make it as short as I can.
I was enthused to be here today cause
I was with you when we, oh, Ted, and a few
people, when we started this thing
at Laramie 18 years ago I guess.
Time flies, but what got me interested
in it was black footed ferret of
course.  We formed an advisory group,
I said this is chaos, so we formed
it, not knowing what we's doing,
but 14 years later I guess we saved
them.  But during that time Governor
Sullivan uh started some, oh like
with ranchers and management process
where we could bring in advisory people
into the ranch which was not very
popular, and different ranchers could
get all kinds of different groups
to come in and collaborate, on their
ranch, and the wildlife, the rains,
the hydrology, anything that might
pop to mind.  And we also had bureaucracies
that had advisory boards, which me
and several others have served on.
So my question is all about collaboration.
I understand it, I've been in tons
of groups of collaboration, but every
time, I'm not going just to pick
on the BLM, but they had rules, codes,
regulations, that said we could
do this, this this, and this.  I
said, yeah, but we worked for a
total year on the advisory group
uh working out a plan for Wyoming
and Wyoming's BLM plans.  And it
had environmentalists, it had hard
noses like me, ranchers, and we
collaborated and at the end of the day
we had an agreement except for one
thing, and it always came down to that
with the bureaucracy. I said, you
cannot collaborate for Meeteetse
Wyoming, or Evanston or Gillette
or coal or anything else unless
the local people, the social and
the economic system comes down to
them and they have to play a part.
What they did is eliminate our
advisory board in Wyoming so we had
no BLM advisory board.  They just
said, no, can't do that.   We can
do the five that you agreed on the resources.
But social and economics has nothing
to do with resource management.
And it happened time and time and
time again.  And I've collaborated
with the Fish and Wildlife Services
recently in the last 5 years in
DC.  I went there and they came to
me and we did changed ideas and
things like that.  So I understood
them better.  But it still bothers
me.  You gotta have the local people
involved, social, economic has to
be involved, in resource management.
If you don't do it, you're going
to fail.  Do you agree or disagree?
Bill Ruckelshaus
I mentioned earlier, you has to
see all the people as part of
the ecosystem.  They have to
be allowed to prosper just like other
things do.  And the leadership at
the national level has to understand
that in order to make progress against
their own priorities.  And if they
don't do that, it isn't effectively
done, and it is done, as a number, as
Al said recently, it it's been done in a
number of areas and where it's not
done it doesn't work. So that's
really what I mean by leadership
in in those national agencies.
Mike Sullivan
The black footed ferret wouldn't be
here  now except for the actions of
Jack Turnell who was the one that
discovered it on his ranch and
took the time. [Applause]
Okay.  Let's go here.  You notice
I'm favoring the right.
Now figure that one out!
[Laughter]
David Dominc
David Dominc, and uh from Cody.
I used to work under that Bill Ruckelshaus
guy.  Uh, it seems to me that uh
we've heard about the bad guys,
we know who they are, the coal, the
oil, the frackers, etc.  But, uh,
I was at the uh 45th anniversary
of the Wyoming Outdoor Council the other
day  down in Lander, and it occurs to me
that we have these environmental groups,
I think Bob O'Dell talked about
the wildlife people, the hunters
and fishers, but we've got these
wildlife groups in the is state,
Wyoming Outdoor Council, Sierra Club,
Audubon society, of which I'm a
member, Potter Resource Group, Nature
Conservancy, Greater Yellowstone
Coalition, uh and have they ever
gotten together and asked and collaborated?
The word I got from one of the
heads of that was, well we might
if we had something in common.  And
I think that as an environmentalist,
uh that's something uh that our side
out to begin to work on. Thank you.
Mike Sullivan
Well let's leave that there.
[Laughter]
Bill Ruckelshaus
He's right!  I mean, David, it's nice to
see you again.  He was in charge
of the water program when he first
started to come over to the Interior
Department.  And uh the truth is
that environmental groups aren't
any more homogeneous than business
or anybody else.  Uh and uh
they do cooperate often, not always,
and when you can't, when they're
necessary for the decision to stick
and they're not willing to cooperate
then you're better off not starting.
Uh when they are willing to compromise
and work together, real progress can be had.
Male Speaker
I haven't hear y'all mention the
National Environmental Policy Act and
the cooperating part of it.  Especially
where we brought in the county commissioners
and other conservation district
or facts were entered into these
uh uh evaluation processes, NEPA,
to uh, get the facts.  And I think
uh, I think the way you're using
Yellowstone, uh, a number of things
I could go on.  But.  The facts
haven't been considered in a manner
that they should.  That's why I
wanted your perspective on the National
Environmental Policy Act.
John Turner
I think uh the written in the 70s,
uh I think past the Nixon administration,
was a very well intentioned that before we
embark on federal action that we really
look at a comprehensive environment and
social impacts. Uh, I said well
intended because my own personal opinion
is that NEPA's gotten so mired in
processing bulk that it has become
less than user friendly.  Very uh
attuned to activist groups, private sector,
non private, uh can stay involved
in a very complex agency process,
but for average America to get
plugged into what becomes thousands
of pages and uh provide uh
useful feedback to the federal
agency proposing action uh I'm not
saying we throw it out, but I think
it's time we revisited NEPA.  And
see how we can make it a process
that uh Americans across the board
can find where they can plug into
it, uh learn something basic, and
then provide feedback.  It just
seems like NEPA has has grown into
a little a monster in process and bulk.
Bill Ruckelshaus
I think the uh I would agree with
John that certainly that was not what was
intended when NEPA was first passed.
Uh it was introduced by Senator Jackson,
from the state of Washington, and it
was meant that when there was major federal
projects it was restricted to federal
projects, there should be an understanding
of the environmental impact of what
that project entailed.  It certainly
didn't, it has evolved into a monster
maybe, I don't think too strong of
a word, to describe it.  And it
may be that a collaborative process
could be used to take a look at
NEPA and see if it can't improve
it.  Not to abandon the idea of
taking into effect the environmental
impact of what you're doing, but
doing it in a more rational fashion
than exists under existing law.
It really is a a tremendous boon
to consulting firms that do extremely
well by undertaking these 4000 page
reports. To what extent it really
has an impact on development that
has been official versus the cost of
it, is is kind of hard to justify
today. I think I think therefore
I think we should take a look at
how we can streamline; streamline
NEPA and make it work a lot better.
That may be possible if the Congress
were to were to in effect convene
in a convener and convene a group
that could take an honest look at
it and make recommendations for
improvement.  That would be the use
of collaboration that I would think
would be very valuable.
Alan Simpson
I think one of the things that
when I was there became, and uh still
am a delightful friend of C Sanders,
who was the Democrat Secretary of
Interior, earthy, wonderful guy,
and uh, when we went out he said,
god, I came here with the thought
we could get something done.  And
he said that all these groups that
fight everything are all connected.
Their their funding sources are
connected, their families are connected,
it goes deep down into the system.
And I said, really?  He said, yeah.
He got out his little chart.  Then
there was a thing called the same
facts were being generated, and
then a new name would pop up, uh,
Save the Earth Quickly, or Save
the Earth in 10 Years, or Save the
Earth Whatever, just all funded
by this amazing network of people
who hire leagues of lawyers who
are good people.  All lawyers are
good people.     [Laughter]
But it's almost like the old phrase,
you unbuttoned your shirt and your
heart fell out.  Because they have
lost sight of what really is going
on in the world.
Male Speaker:
First of all, I need to thank John
Turner for the fine uh commercial
for the Wyoming Stock Growers' Land
Trust.  John, I hope that earns your
forgiveness for the votes we probably
secured to defeat your conservation
easement legislation 25 years ago.
But uh, one of the issues you
have touched on a little bit here
in the last question.  It seems
that one the real distance
settings to collaboration today is
uh the litigation process and
I don't mean litigation to solve
substantive issues, which hopefully
sometimes the wisdom of our judges
can do, but process litigation,
where it seems to be to some degree
on all sides.  Uh, I might not get
what I want, but I can sure keep
you from getting what you want.
Uh, all I have to do is file a lawsuit
contending that some agency didn't
completely follow the process and
I'll stymie the works for another
4 or 5 years and I'll have the satisfaction
of knowing you didn't get what you
wanted.  How do we address that and
remove that as a distance setting, so
unless there are series legal issues,
we we as whatever side we represent,
can look at an issue and say, my
best bet on getting this resolved or
at least come out to some degree with
something I can live with is through the
collaborative process, not through
uh hiring one of these wonderful
attorneys and showing up in the court room.
Bill Ruckelshaus
One one of the reasons one of the ways
of doing that is an awareness of what
you just said.  We had uh a statement
by Al earlier that rightness was
a problem in trying to solve some
of these things.  Actually when people
have been in court for 10 years
and spent 100s of thousands of dollars
on legal fees, and maybe reach 10%
of the resolution of all of the problems
that exists, that is ripe for collaboration.
People get discouraged after awhile
when they're fighting each other
and not getting anywhere.  And they
have this sense of we're winning
we're winning we're winning we lost,
how did I get there?  And and even
though they have won in the lawsuit
it's probably less than 10 or 15%
of what they need to to ultimately
achieve it.  And once people come to that
conclusion they often look for
collaboration as a way of trying to
resolve their disputes and recognize that
they have to harmonize their interests
with others. which makes it more
likely they'll be successful in
a collaboration than before.  So
issue can be over ripe, they get,
people get so mad at each other they
can't talk to one another, but they
can also get exhausted by trying
the other approaches to uh resolution
of our disputed and be
ready for collaboration.
Mike Sullivan
I think Jim's concern is he just
can't live that long!
[Laughter]
Bill Ruckelshaus
Me either, be we can at least start it.
Alan Simpson
Jim Magagna, uh worked with his
industry in the wool growers,
and it was a privilege to try to
help and launch occasions but this
guy is so steady and he doesn't
get caught in, he's really trying,
and and it is so true it's, I want
to deny you the pleasure of getting
what you want and I know that I'll
probably lose but I know that I can
screw you up for 2 or 3 or 4 years.
What a wonderful trait!
[Laughter]
Boy, it's really out there and
it's so vivid and disgusting, and
they pr- they they they preen about
it.  They're very proud of the fact
that they stomped this by simply
filing the suit and then when they
lose at every level they just keep
appealing and appealing, there's
nothing appealing about them!
Male Speaker
I think Dominic's comment made me
think for a moment that most most
folks most citizens most voters know
what they know about complex issues
from their interest groups that they're
part of, but yet most folks aren't part
of those interest groups.  Most voters and
most citizens are highly confused.
The media is the only way they
learn what's going on and they
don't learn much, because as Al
Simpson has pointed out nationally,
uh uh the media thrives on polarization.
I had a news director tell me one
time, nobody's interested in a message
from the muddled middle.  Well, the
muddled middle is where everything
gets done!  And I wonder if, as
collaboration moves forward, if it did,
if if those who are collaborating did
a better job of reaching out to the
levers of medium.  And talking about
what they're doing, what they're
actually getting accomplished.  If
that might help quell some of the
noisy rabble on the right and on
the left who are uh dragging the
dragging people's confidence in our
political process right into the
mud.  What Al was able to do is Simpson
bowls got the whole country talking
about the possibility, the possibility
that we could deal with the defect.
And it was the first time anybody
did.  You have a yahoo on the right
or the left showing up on the evening
news, you had senator Simpson and
Erston Bowls talking about
what was actually possible.
Mike Sullivan
That yahoo on the right [Laughter]
Panel Member
Depending on which one you have!
Male Speaker
But anyway.  The point, has to do
with trying to the point has to do with
recognizing through the course of
collaboration that outreach uh through
the media uh being aggressive about
it may yield tremendous benefits.
John Turner
But it's really a a superb observation.
Uh the media has a real role to
play.  And uh I've accused of often
being lazy.  And maybe it's just
cause they're spread so thin, but
most of these, many of these resources
issues, are difficult because they're
complex.  And and so to get the information
out correctly, it's easy to do the
sexy thing, get a quote here, get
a quote there.  The public still
doesn't know what in the hell's going
on.  That's one of the things Bill
started out talking how a university
then, can be a pretty good watering
hole just to provide basic information.
Uh on an issue uh the tools,
the issues, the science to date.
So a university can do that.  Plus
a group should try to see that, what
are the facts that we agree on,
the challenges and the opportunities
and then make an effort to get that
to the media, uh and have a spokesman
trusted by all sides that can talk to
the media uh.  It was one of the
most frustrating things I encountered
with the Northern Spotted Owl, which
was very complex.  You turned on
the national news and you'd be interviewing
somebody that was just a bird addict,
that worshiped spotted owls, then
some poor guy afraid he was about
to have his mill shut down and lose
his job.  That became the issue,
how you got all the critical aspects
of uh the spotted owl issue out
to the press.  Getting them to take
the time to look at those issues
it's a good point.
Bill Ruckelshaus
Now I I think it's an excellent point.
And I think there ought to be built
into one of these uh collaborative
process, uh a desire to assess how
do we get this, let's assume we
come to some resolution of the issue.
How do we get that resolution to
and the approach that we took to
get there out in front of the public
in such a way that they see these
problems can be grappled with.
Maybe we don't understand every aspect
of it, but look at these people
who've been fighting each other for
years have sat-sat down and worked out
their differences and have now come
forward.  I don't think that will
happen automatically I think we make
a concerted effort then the process
itself to insure that the results
are communicated we'll have a better
chance of of getting the right kind
of result.
Mike Sillivan
Al, you're an expert at the at the media.
What your response?    [Laughter]
Alan Simpson
I've always had the very sick idea
that the First Amendment belonged
to me too.  And when you knock on
them, then they shriek like gut shot
panthers. It's wonderful to watch.
Because they'll say, it's just the
public's right to know.  I say, yeah,
it's the public's right to know something
that's real.  Uh not rumor and crap and just
garbage, that's the public's right to
know and then, always, I love the phrase
"We stick by our story."  That just
is a ritual, usually with violin
music in the background!  After they've
hammered you flat, all erroneous,
and and fake, and they say, we stick
to our story, our editorial board
has decided that Simpson is a kook
and we've got to drive him out.
Lemme tell you.  An attack unanswered
is an attack believed.  I've always
lived that way, I've always took
them on.  But I tell you, they're
interested in confusion, controversy,
and complexity, not clarity and
lemme tell you.  If you watch stuff,
Charlie Rose and Jim Lair, you have
to bring your own brains to those
sections.  There are staff members
who will not allow their senator
or congressman to do those because
it's twenty minutes.  And their brain
and their mouth is only done for
sound bites!  And they know just
exactly what to use so they can
then go back and say he was on the
news last night, usually babbling,
you know, 30 seconds worth, and you
you couldn't get people to go on,
their staff wouldn't let them go
on Jim Lair or Charlie Rose because
you had to sit there for 20 or 30
minutes and answer questions with
nobody around to shovel papers to
you.  It's a vacuous group.  They're
there for re-election.  We're at a
crossroads now in America between
cowardice and greed.  Cowardice of
the legislators, and greed of those
people who don't want to do anything
to that tax code, and it only helps
really 10% of the American people.
Look like I've never heard of that
stuff in there.  Abandon mine land
reclamation.  Lord save you don't
want to oppose my own delegation, but
when you use it to on the auditorium
at the University of Wyoming, that
ain't exactly mine land reclamation.
So we have to dig into this stuff.
And when you do you get hammered
flat and then the media will always
come up with some wrenching story,
some some probative thing I talked
to a wonderful young gal in Cody
who just graduated from Columbia
Journalism School, that's one of
the best. I said, what are you going
to do now?  She said, I'm going
to be one of the hunters.  I said,
what are you going to hunt?  She
said, people like you.  That's, that's
her new you know she'll do a good
job.  She's bright and and but you
know.  If every person in public
life is an adulterer, a rotten crook,
corrupt, if every person in the
media is a drudge, this guy, that
guy, then we all get tainted with
that.  I would think that unless the
unless politicians and journalists
get together and decide that they
are worthy parts of society, this
society can't exist.  As as long as
people are disgusted with journalists
and disgusted with politicians, you can't
hate politicians and love democracy,
and you can't hate journalists and
love the Second Amendment, the First
Amendment, the whole thing.
Jessica Clout
Thank you very much.
Um I'm actually not really a member
of the public.  I've apologized
to my colleagues, I'm very fortunate
to just have joined the team at
the Ruckelshaus Institute and the
School of Environment and Natural
Resources.  Um and I will be working
on collaborative issues in Wyoming.
Um one thing I just wanted to bring
to your attention and ask you if
you have any experience in this,
and at this point I'm going to sit
down, um, I'm just, did I say my
name?  Jessica Clout. Um, there's
also this idea of collaborative learning.
In natural resources we don't always
have to get to the table with the
expectation that we come to a resolution.
That we, that we make a decision.
We could also just come to the
table to learn.  And I have a lot
of experience in that.  And sometimes
it is precisely the issues, Bill,
that you were mentioning, that might,
you felt were too hot, that actually
might lend themselves to that kind
of approach, a collaborative learning
approach.  Because it it takes the
it takes a little bit of the heat
off.  And it might create an opportunity
for people to just come to the table,
hear each other, learn from each
other, and if a decision can result
from that they'll find out.  But
in the meantime, more is learned
and it's not just the uh the speaking
people, it's it's some of a the people
here we're referring to.  It's not
always the same voices.  And I was wondering
if you'd had any experience with that.
Bill Ruckelshaus
Let me give you an example.  I I think
that's a very good point.  There is a,
there're skeptics, about collaborative
processes who say they're endless and
they never come to a resolution and
they don't come to some final
conclusion, and that therefore I don't
want to participate in.  So you've got
to be careful about that.  But we
had an experience at the beginning
of the Institute, uh it it's been
almost 16 years ago now, but the
Safe Drinking Water Act was coming
up for re-authorization by the congress,
Senator Kempthorne from the neighboring
state of Idaho was the head of of
the Subcommittee on the Environment
and Public Work Committee that was
looking at it, in in order to educate
the board about the nature of collaborative
processes, he took the Safe Drinking
Water Act and said, supposing this
was something we needed to come
to a conclusion about, how would
we do it?  And we spent two days,
I didn't think we'd come close to
resolving the issues in there, and
we came to a conclusion.  There there
were probably 25 people there about
what the Safe Drinking Water Act
Amendment should say.  They were
causing tow towns like Torrington
in a Wyoming to close down because
they couldn't afford the kind of
filtration systems that were mandated
under the law.  We we reach an accommodation
on this a lot of the disparate kind
of people represented on the board.
I took the results to Senator Kempthorne,
uh in the Senate a couple of weeks
later, he said, how did you get
all these people to agree to this?
I said, well we just sat down and
discussed the issues and and everybody
had their mind open, and listened
to one another and talked to one
another, and we came to this conclusion.
He took our recommendations and
put them in front of his committee
and they essentially became the law,
essentially what the Safe Drinking
Water Act says now.  So it is possible
to try something like this and just
for purposes of exchanging information
find you can find common ground.
And then in this case just from
kind of dumb luck, but we were here
and he was ready for something like
this and we presented it to him
with a a a broad degree of a of
a representation and consensus.
He was not able to get on his
committee he essentially used
that and it became the law.
John Turner
I I think the observation on collaborative
learning is is a good one.  I think
anybody we look at in the political
arena, or nonprofit, or industry,
or whatever that's been affected,
maybe by experience they've learned
to listen to other people and work
with them and accommodate them uh
I can think of so many examples
in my life as a legislator where
I had a great idea, and if people
would just do it the way I had figured
it out we'd have it solved.
[Laughter]
Simpson would screw around with it,
or Governor Sullivan, or the stock growers, or
somebody would say, hell no, Turner,
but maybe if you we could accommodate
this or that.  And again and again
I said, you know, if I hadn't listened
and worked, there were things I
hadn't thought of, others' people's
concerns, and one of the good,
great things about the University
Program that we've all been involved
in is collaborative learning in the
University.  And it it really is
something to watch, where you take
a students in diverse a disciplines,
a law student, a kid in energy, a
kid business, uh a kid from wildlife,
uh and and put them together in a
core group and they all have their
own slants.  Somebody's interested
in business, somebody's interested
in engineering, and you and you bring
these kids together, you provide
them a lot of information, and they've
got to solve a real uh resource
issue.  Uh energy extraction in the
Upper Green, or a major highway
or something, and they all gotta
duke it out and learn from one another
and it's a whole semester.  Uh and Dr.
Burke and others can provide more
information, but it's called uh Capstone,
and I've had the opportunity to
just go down and speak to these kids,
and boy they're thoughtful and innovative
and knocking heads and learning from
one another and those are the life
skills that are going to make these,
when they go into the private sector
or government or nonprofit or their
own business, they're going to develop
some pretty neat skills in how to
work with other people.  So collaborative
learning is such a a vital tool in
helping anybody interested in these
processes.  How does that seem?
Alan Simpson
I think the toughest problem
is the people that are there have
seen so many of these things fail,
they in the elephant graveyard,
they say, well, here's Turner, he
showed up, here's Ruckelshaus, Simpson,
Sullivan, they tried that 10 years
ago, just give it up.  You never
want to believe that.  You just
have to use continual perseverance,
keep coming at them, they'll say,
don't appoint another commission,
they've never done anything.  Well
let me tell you I've been on 3 that
have done a lot.  I remember Immigration
and Refugee Policy with father Ted
Hessler, Kennedy, bunch of us.
We did a legal immigration bill and
an illegal immigration bill, didn't
work cause we couldn't get a more
secure identifier, because the right
and the left said, that this is a
national ID card.  That's how you
get things done.  Don't forget.
The triggers, enrage, emotion, and
then you did the Iraq Study Group,
we agreed with every word, 5 Dems,
5 Republicans, the last administration
accepted about 5 of them, since
then 59 of them have been adopted
as to what we suggested you do.
And now this hideous thing that
Furston and I are involved in.
It doesn't matter what you call it,
it ain't going away!  It's out there!
And this country is headed for some
terribly tough time.  To think I
said to Anne, I've never been more
energized, and she said, why is
that, I said, because at 81 now,
I have achieved life's ultimate goal.
I have pissed off everyone in America!
[Laughter/ Applause]
Mike Sullivan
Do any of the panelists have any
that that you have left unsaid?
[Laughter}
Bill Ruckelshaus
I mean, I think Alan is
right though, I think he has
pissed off everybody. [Laughter]
Mike Sullivan
Well....
John Turner
Thank you all!
Mike Sullivan
Thank thanks to the audience. [Apause]
Music