dedicated adults who had
so much left to give.
Three months since
we, as Americans,
began asking ourselves if we're
really doing enough to protect
our communities and
keep our children safe.
For the families who lost a
loved one on that terrible day,
three months doesn't even
begin to ease the pain they're
feeling right now.
It doesn't come close to mending
the wounds that may never
fully heal.
But as a nation, the last
three months have changed us.
They've forced us to answer some
difficult questions about what
we can do -- what we must do
-- to prevent the kinds of
massacres we've seen in Newtown
and Aurora and Oak Creek,
as well as the everyday
tragedies that happen far too
often in big cities and small
towns all across America.
Today there is still genuine
disagreement among well-meaning
people about what steps we
should take to reduce the
epidemic of gun violence
in this country.
But you -- the American
people -- have spoken.
You've made it clear that
it's time to do something.
And over the last few weeks,
senators here in Washington have
listened and taken
some big steps forward.
Two weeks ago, the Senate
advanced a bill that would make
it harder for criminals and
people with a severe mental
illness from getting
their hands on a gun --
an idea supported by nine
out of ten Americans,
including a majority
of gun owners.
The Senate also made progress on
a bill that would crack down on
anyone who buys a gun as part
of a scheme to funnel it to
criminals -- reducing violent
crime and protecting our law
enforcement officers.
Finally, the Senate took steps
to reinstate and strengthen a
ban on the sale of
military-style assault weapons,
set a 10-round
limit for magazines,
and make our schools
safer places for kids to
learn and to grow.
These ideas shouldn't
be controversial --
they're common sense.
They're supported by a majority
of the American people.
And I urge the Senate and
the House to give each of
them a vote.
As I've said before, we may not
be able to prevent every act of
violence in this country.
But together, we have
an obligation to try.
We have an obligation
to do what we can.
Right now, we have a real
chance to reduce gun violence in
America, and prevent
the very worst violence.
We have a unique opportunity
to reaffirm our tradition of
responsible gun ownership, and
also do more to keep guns out of
the hands of criminals or people
with a severe mental illness.
We've made progress over
the last three months,
but we're not there yet.
And in the weeks ahead, I hope
Members of Congress will join me
in finishing the job --
for our communities and,
most importantly, for our kids.
Thanks.