A salaam aleikum.
Louder!
SHANE SMITH: A salaam aleikum.
[INAUDIBLE]
MALE SPEAKER: Bye.
SPIKE JONZE: They
were starting to
open the door to leave.
We are in the Socotra, which is
an island a two hour flight
of the coast of Yemen
in the Indian Ocean.
And--
SHANE SMITH: It's
hot as balls.
SPIKE JONZE: It's hot as--
it's hot.
Yeah, this is a pre-historic
land because it broke off from
the continent of Africa at least
two million years ago,
and so all the has evolved
on its own trajectory.
And so you have incredibly
exotic trees--
SHANE SMITH: We're going to see
the blood tree right now.
SPIKE JONZE: A tree that
bleeds dragon's blood.
We came to Yemen to do a story
on, basically, the truth or
untruth of al-Qaeda in Yemen.
But Shane was like, if we're
going to Yemen, we have to go
to the Socotra.
I don't care, I'll
buy a helicopter.
And so, based on Shane's
demands, we took two days to
go to this pre-historic land
of the lost island.
and--
SHANE SMITH: But since it's
two hours drive in the hot
heat, we decided to do
a Spike [INAUDIBLE]
spend Saturday with.
So how does this dagger
look, shitty or good?
SPIKE JONZE: We're doing the
official, full blown,
deconstructed, "Rolling Stone,"
"Playboy," Shane Smith interview.
We're going to get to know every
inch of your cranium and
body by the end of
this interview.
SHANE SMITH: Are we going
to touch moles?
SPIKE JONZE: Probably.
Your one of the driving forces
behind this whole Vice thing.
SHANE SMITH: Yeah.
SPIKE JONZE: Yeah, why
did you start Vice?
SHANE SMITH: Because I
couldn't get a job.
SPIKE JONZE: Where
were you living?
SHANE SMITH: I was living in
Budapest being a criminal.
And I came back for my
brother's wedding.
SPIKE JONZE: What kind
of criminal?
SHANE SMITH: You know,
buying and selling
money illegally, arbitrage.
SPIKE JONZE: What's that mean?
SHANE SMITH: Buying and selling
money illegally.
SPIKE JONZE: [LAUGH]
SHANE SMITH: And I came back for
my brother's wedding and I
met Saroosh Alvi, who was
just out of rehab.
And I was on acid.
And I was like, oh, you're
from Pakistan.
I'll show you how to throw a
googly, which is the type of
Cricket throw.
SPIKE JONZE: Yeah, how
old were you guys?
SHANE SMITH: 24.
I was 24.
Saroosh was 25.
And then we became
best buddies.
And then we were working at
a place called "Voice of
Montreal." It was a make work
project for Haitian
immigrants and us.
And then, after a while, they
owed us money, and they
couldn't pay us,
so we took it.
And we dropped the O, and we
called it "Vice." And then
that was it.
SPIKE JONZE: So you stole the
magazines from a nonprofit
organization that was trying
to help Haitians.
SHANE SMITH: Correct.
SPIKE JONZE: Dude, that's
kind of not that nice.
SHANE SMITH: Yeah, and we
were on welfare, too.
The government paid for us.
SPIKE JONZE: Wow.
SHANE SMITH: Yes.
SPIKE JONZE: Then what?
SHANE SMITH: So in 1998, when
we came down to the States.
Well so, we were interviewed
by a newspaper.
We made up this story
that Larry Flint was
going to buy us.
And there was something that
someone else, named Conrad,
and then this guy named Richard
Szalwinski, who was
like the richest guy in
Montreal, Richard Szalwinski
read it in the newspaper, and he
called us and he said, who
are you fucking guys?
So we went to lunch at his
restaurant and someone came in
saying, Shane's hung
over or something.
And he goes, oh you drink?
I said, oh, I can drink.
He goes, OK, drink that
bottle of whiskey.
And I drank half the bottle of
Jack Daniels and then had to
sit there at lunch and
negotiate with him.
And so he's like, we talked to
him for the lunch, and he
goes, it's a Friday.
And he goes, OK, I want to
see you guys Monday.
I want to be your partner.
So we went away on
the weekend.
And we know how to
value a company,
we didn't know anything.
And we have the paper
somewhere.
It's called the Price of Vice.
And it's got doodles
all over it.
And it was basically, we're
so stupid, it was like, so
there's three of us, right?
The fourth partner
to come in at an
equal share is $1 million.
So that valued it at $4 million,
and we would get the
$1 million.
Because it was worth nothing.
It was worth, I mean,
whatever.
So he looked at it.
He said that's a lot of money.
He signed it, I don't
know why.
He signed it.
And we just got whisked
off, and all his
minion gave us money.
And they give us $50,000 each,
just to hold us over until we
got all the rest of the money.
And we didn't know what to do.
I remember running in circles
outside screaming at the top
of my lungs.
Because none of us had
ever had any money.
So then he brought us down to
New York for the e-commerce
dot-com revolution thing
in the '90s.
And so we came down, and we were
sort of fascinated with
cocaine, and supermodels, and
street wear, and just shit.
We were like we're so rich,
we're so rich, it's crazy,
dot-com, hooray.
And then obviously, boom.
He had about 25 companies.
And they all went bankrupt.
And we were the only company
that didn't go bankrupt.
SPIKE JONZE: And how did you get
it back from [INAUDIBLE]?
SHANE SMITH: We bought
it back.
That's a long story, but
we bought it back.
We bought it back for pennies
on the dollar.
And it wasn't worth anything.
And then we moved to Brooklyn.
And we just started
from scratch, like
started from nothing.
And so we only really became
Vice when we got back to being
poor, and punk, and started
expanding in our own way, and
having our own voice, and owning
our own company, and
doing it our way.
SPIKE JONZE: Describe the
different periods.
And what the magazine
wrote about.
And what the tone was in the
Montreal years, in the early
Brooklyn years.
SHANE SMITH: In the beginning
we were all about making up
shocking stories.
We made them up.
So that was the beginning, was
sort of like "National
Inquirer" type shocking stuff
combined with, like, hip-hop
and punk rock.
And then when we came down to
the states it was more of,
like, we were drunk at our
Christmas party, and we were
like, look at little
Eric Lavoie, who
was my intern for--
he's only had one job.
He started working for
us when he was 17.
And we were like, look
at that little guy.
Let's do a whole issue on him.
So like every article, every
fashion shoot, every record
review was all him.
And we just loved it.
We thought that was
funny as hell.
And half the people would say,
that's really funny.
fuck you, "Vice," I hate you.
You're full of shit.
And we always said, actually,
from the beginning, either
have people love you
or hate you.
But just don't be in between.
And it's the same thing with all
our good issues, like the
Iraq issue, where we gave the
whole issue over to Iraqis
during the war.
Or the special issue.
SPIKE JONZE: What's
the special issue?
SHANE SMITH: We gave the
whole issue to a group
called How's Your News?
Which is a group
that does news.
They're mentally challenged.
I was really proud of that.
And then when we went out into
the world more, we were like,
oh, there's a lot of bad
things happening.
We have a media platform, and
what are we talking about?
A pair of Nikes that you
can only get in Tokyo
between 2:00 and 6:00.
So we got a little
more serious.
It became more international,
for sure.
Like, when we had two employees
and were in
Montreal, it's different
than having 750
employees in 40 countries.
It's just a different entity.
SPIKE JONZE: What were some of
the pieces that you guys did
that were like turning,
defining points.
SHANE SMITH: A lot of pieces
that made VBS famous were
actually mag pieces.
So like, Gun Markets in
Pakistan, Butt Naked in the
Tupac Army, we shot Heavy
Metal in Baghdad.
I think we do things
in a different way.
We call it immersionism.
So we come here, and
we just travel
around, and we see shit.
And we say, this
is what we saw.
Maybe it's not 100%, obviously,
because you can't
do it all in a couple
weeks or whatever.
And I always used to say, like,
if you're looking at
"Vice" for being news and the
truth, then you're in trouble.
Because we didn't come up as,
like, I'm Jesus on my cross.
We came up as, yeah, it's
totally cool, fucking shoes.
Vice guide to fucking
eating pussy.
you in the ass.
I don't know if you've heard of
a thing called "Jackass."
We were like that.
We're not the best because
we're the best.
We're the best because we're
the tallest of the midgets.
But we want to get back
to being the best just
for being the best.
And that's why we're putting
Viceland, VBS, and "Vice"
altogether as one beautiful
big boy.
SPIKE JONZE: Online.
SHANE SMITH: Online and in
the man, and everything.
We're just going to-- because
we built "Vice" and then we
built Viceland.
And then we built VBS.
And they all are a little bit
separate, but they all have
the same voice, the same
attitude, the same people
working on them.
So we're like, why don't we just
put them all together.