SHANE SMITH: Now because Colonia
Lebaron is so close to
the American border, they're
totally affected by our
immigration policy and, of
course, our war on drugs.
If America sneezes, Mexico
catches cold.
And because of this, they are
extremely interested in
American political policy.
You have narco cartels.
You have a drug route.
You have illegal immigration.
So all of these problems, who
do you think should be the
next president of the
United States?
BRENT LEBARON: Mitt Romney has
a great, great policy.
SHANE SMITH: Now are you just
saying that because you're
Mormon-ish?
BRENT LEBARON: His
ties, his people.
His family lives right across
the mountain here.
You should probably meet them.
BRENT LEBARON: Now, when Brent
says his family, he means
presidential candidate
Mitt Romney's family.
Now, we knew that his father,
George Romney, had been born
into Mormon colony in Mexico,
but not that they still had an
active Romney colony
here in Chihuahua.
So the Romneys still live
here, across the valley?
BRENT LEBARON: Yep, they're
some great guys.
I just really like them.
Golf with them quite often and--
some really cool guys.
SHANE SMITH: Yeah?
BRENT LEBARON: Yeah.
SHANE SMITH: So we went across
the valley to check them out.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
BRENT LEBARON: Nine holes with
two par fives, and two par
threes, and the rest
are fours.
Pretty nice greens, eh?
SHANE SMITH: Beautiful.
How did this golf
course start?
BRENT LEBARON: We just got a
group together that like to
play golf and copied other
golf courses, put in the
sprinkling system.
When the violence started, we
lost quite a few members--
just like in Casas Grandes,
a lot of people moved out.
SHANE SMITH: You play here with
some of the Lebarons from
colonial Lebaron?
KELLY ROMNEY: Yeah, some
of the guys come
over here and play.
SHANE SMITH: And who's better,
the Lebarons or the Romneys?
KELLY ROMNEY: The Lebarons.
[LAUGHTER]
KELLY ROMNEY: I don't know
what they're eating over
there, but--
[LAUGH]
SHANE SMITH: So how long have
the Romneys been here?
KELLY ROMNEY: 1885.
My great grandfather, Miles
Park Romney was one of the
original people that
came here.
Mitt is a relative.
He's a second cousin.
SHANE SMITH: So his dad
was born in Chihuahua.
Yeah, he was born in Colonia
Dublan, about
15 miles from here.
Their family left, and they
stayed in the United States.
They didn't come back.
You know, I remember his father
ran for President of
the United States in '68, at
least he was a candidate.
His citizenship was questioned
because he was born here in
Mexico but he was born
of America parents.
SHANE SMITH: Do you think that
this craziness around the
run-up to the election, is that
bringing too much attention?
KELLY ROMNEY: I think one of the
reasons it's brought a lot
of attention to here is because
of Mitt's position on
illegal immigration.
SHANE SMITH: Now what's ironic
about this is that Mitt
Romney, whose father was born
in Mexico, and would be
considered the poster child of
the Dream Act, actually has
one of the staunchest views on
immigration in his already
conservative Republican Party.
MITT ROMNEY: And I've indicated
I would veto the
Dream Act if provisions included
that people who are
here illegally--
if they go to school here long
enough, get a degree here,
that they can become permanent
residents.
I think that's a mistake.
[APPLAUSE]
MITT ROMNEY: Now, it seems a bit
weird for a person who's
essentially a first-generation
immigrant to have such harsh
views on immigration.
It's kind of like, me thinks
thy dost protest too
much kind of deal.
And his own cousin Kelly who,
although he supports Mitt for
president, thinks that
his position on
immigration is wrong.
KELLY ROMNEY: I think
he needs to change.
Being born and raised
in Mexico--
and especially since NAFTA, I
think that the United States
is partly responsible for
the increase in illegal
immigration that happened.
SHANE SMITH: So America makes
policy then, all of the
sudden, Northern Mexico
gets all screwed up.
KELLY ROMNEY: That's right.
Give amnesty to those that are
out there that are working
legitimately and have a job.
Come up with a guest worker
program and let these people
go out there and work and then
come home and take care of
their family because, basically,
they're starving to
death here in Mexico.
SHANE SMITH: In fact, it's so
bad that, for many people,
there's only really
two options--
one, sneak into America, or
two, work for the cartels.
Didn't some farmers go up from
the farms and go to the
mountains and start
growing drugs?
KELLY ROMNEY: Yeah, a lot of
them have gone into the
mountain areas, and they
grow of drugs.
SHANE SMITH: And now we're
sitting here, going, OK, well,
what are we going to do.
KELLY ROMNEY: What are
we going to do?
Exactly.
I wish Mitt would make
contact with us.
And I really think that
we could help him.
SHANE SMITH: And as I would
later realize, contacting the
Mexican side of his family would
probably be the last
thing that Mitt Romney
would do.
MITT ROMNEY: We have got to
protect our borders and stop
the flood of illegal
immigration.
And I will not do anything that
opens up another wave of
illegal immigration.
[APPLAUSE]
KELLY ROMNEY: When they started
the war on drugs, the
violence just escalated.
To me, this used to be
the most peaceful
place in the world.
But now you keep a close
watch on it.
SHANE SMITH: Have there ever
been any Romneys kidnapped?