innovative strategies to better understand
the brain. And in order to do that we need
new technologies. CLARITY is a great example
of the type of new technologies that will
enable future brain studies.
So prior to this technology, scientists used
methods where they would take thin slices
of the brain. They would put these on glass
slides, process them with antibodies, which
illuminate what chemicals are there. And then
they would have to use a microscope to study
which transmitters are in which locations.
Unfortunately, you can’t see the structure
of a neuron in a brain slice.
So with this technology, they’re able to
look at the entire neuron in a three dimensional
volume. And with this three dimensional structure
intact, you can see where the neuron starts
and what brain region it projects to. In slices,
you can only see what’s in the position
where you started. And what this technology
will allow is to do is not only study what
molecular or single elements of a cell are
located in a neuron, but how those communicate
with other elements in the brain.
So in the recent publication by Deisseroth
and colleagues, they describe not only the
ability to look at animal models – or whole
brains of animals – but also the ability
to look in human brain. So in a post-mortem
brain from a child suffering from autism,
they were able to trace neuronal projections
from a significant volume of tissue. They’re
also able to use the technology to stain for
neurochemicals located in that brain region.
And the potential for this type of research
is great for understanding how disruptions
in neural circuitry are involved in disorders.
It has really transformative potential.
The technology shows us in the video an area
of the brain that’s involved in memory,
the hippocampus. And this video shows the
neurons that are involved in processing memory,
where they project, and what neurotransmitters,
or chemicals are contained in those neurons.
And it shows this in three dimensions, so
you see not only where they start and where
they project and how they might interact to
form memories.
The video through an entire mouse brain shows
us how neurons are connected. So the neural
circuitry – which neurons project to which
areas in the brain, how they might be involved
in giving commands to execute certain functions
that we know about from physiology studies,
but we don’t actually know how they connect
to each other. This technology allows you
to bring those together.