Yeah. You're a good bird.
Take you home, get your Ieg better.
Dear William, thank you so
much for the birthday present.
I'm so happy you remembered,
as few here at the orphanage did.
It's interesting how life
works out, isn't it?
Years ago, when you first joined
my orphanage's outreach program...
...I never imagined we would
become such good friends.
You have enriched my life.
And for doing this,
I'm eternally grateful.
Hope all is going well
on the wildlife refuge.
-Please write again soon.
-How're you feeIing?
I do so look forward to your letters.
Always your friend,
Irena Morawska.
Dear Irena...
...I'm glad you lik e
the American Indian bracelet...
...a true symbol of our friendship.
At the same time, it pains me
that others at the orphanage...
... failed to recognize
your special day.
You're an intelligent, special girl.
So trust me when I tell you this.:
Pave your own path.
Do not wait for others to lead you.
You'll benefit more in the end.
By the way, you've done well with
the track er puzzles I've sent you.
Over the next couple of letters, I'll
send ones that are more challenging.
This one's called a cipher.
Lik e I said, it's more advanced,
but I am sure you'll catch on quick.
William.
Friends forever.
Here's another cipher
for you to try and solve.
Remember Napoleon,
the great general, once wrote.:
"He who fears being conquered
is sure of defeat. ''
I suppose I'm just trying to say
that we can rise above our problems.
The answers are all there
if we look close enough.
-Be strong.
-Watch where you go.
In six months, I will be 1 4
and have to leave the orphanage.
I'm not sure where to go after that.
Still, as you have taught me...
...I can see opportunity in all things.
Mrs. Donata told me she has
big plans for me and not to worry.
Whatever happens, I know that
you and I will remain connected.
Irena.
Anything eIse?
Thank you, Rosie.
Do you know any good jokes?
Guess that means no.
-Cup of coffee?
-Just give me whatever he's having.
Look what the cat drug in.
-You thought you'd never see me here.
-I was hoping I wouIdn't, you know.
But shit happens.
OId Shepherd taIked about the mighty
shit you once did for the government.
But that's in the past.
We're Iiving in the here and now.
You saved my ass a few times,
as I recaII.
I owe you one, BiIIy.
WeII, Iet's just caII it even.
No way.
I' II count to 1 0.
Let's see how far you can run
before I catch you.
One...
...two, three....
The thriII of the chase, Mrs. Donata.
It's aIways a constant source
of amusement to me.
Dear Irena...
...I may have to go away
for a while, but don't worry.
You can contact me in Montreal
at the address below.
It's hidden in a cipher
called zodiac.
Remember Napoleon and be strong.
Ania Brotzcha.
Mata Majerska.
Irena Morawska.
Annoucheka Ravinska.
You've aII dreamed of homes...
...famiIies and a better Iife.
WeII, dreams can come true.
It's my job to expedite such dreams.
PoIand.
If you couId be anything,
what wouId you Iike to be?
A modeI. In a magazine.
A modeI?
WeII, you're not exactIy
modeI materiaI.
StiII....
And you, what wouId you Iike to be?
A good student, sir.
Lord have mercy. What a mess.
How do you want to pIay this?
Doesn't have to be difficuIt, WiIIiam.
Just need to taIk.
WeII, I' II teII you what.
PIay this by the books for me...
...and I' II come peacefuIIy.
Sure. By the book.
It's nothing personaI.
It's just too many Ioose ends.
Cabin's a nice touch.
You know, I buiIt this cabin
with my own money.
GIad to see you saved.
That was smart.
Bring WiIIiam to the van.
Take him.
Put the gun down, Shepherd.
Set it down very gentIy.
Now, get over here.
Very good.
Now I want you to turn around.
It doesn't matter how far
a man runs.
He can't run away from himseIf.
You' re stiII a company man, WiIIiam.
And we wiII find you.
It's time to Ieave, Irena.
My American friend.
WiII you make sure
that he receives this?
Oh, that's funny.
Okay, I gotta go. Bye.
Mr. DeIacroix?
Anything in the box for Lansing?
Let's take a Iook.
I'm afraid onIy one this time.
Dear Mr. Lansing,
we regret to inform you...
... that Irena Morawska will no longer
be able to correspond with you.
Let me have your bag.
Be better for the photo.
AII right.
You can smiIe a bit.
What kind of foster program is this?
It's a speciaI program...
...for very taIented kids.
Good students, Iike you.
What do we have here?
A Ietter from America, huh?
Those are mine.
Burn these.
What do we have here?
I haven't seen a cipher Iike this...
...in a Iong time.
I think we wiII caII her LoIa.
-LoIa?
-LoIa.
I Iike LoIa.
Whenever you're ready.
And just remember to Iook
right into the Iens, okay?
My name is Annoucheka.
When I grow up,
I want to be a modeI.
Go on. You're doing fine. Go on.
A modeI.
No!
AII professionaI modeIs
suffer from stage fright.
WeIcome to PoIand, Mr. Davenport.
Are you here for business or pIeasure?
A IittIe sightseeing.
This doesn't Iook Iike
a modeIIing agency to me.
Annoucheka, what are you thinking?
Be carefuI.
Annoucheka, no. PIease don't.
You can try to run,
but there's nowhere to hide.
And now, I am forced into making
an exampIe of you.
You' re fast.
Not quite fast enough.
Come in.
-Hi.
-Can I heIp you?
I'm WiIIiam Lansing.
I'm staying at the RoyaI HoteI.
I received a Ietter from you
about Irena Morawska.
I'm sorry, Mr. Lansing.
I wasn't expecting--
I mean, Irena said you worked
outside with animaIs.
Did she say that?
WouId you go with me for a moment?
Sure.
This is where she wouId sIeep.
It was aII such a terribIe business.
Irena running away, I mean.
Of course, I caIIed the poIice, but....
-Irena ran away, huh?
-Perhaps there was a boy.
She was at that age.
And Irena was speciaI.
She was speciaI,
but I don't think there was a boy.
NapoIeon.
You don't mind if I caII the poIice?
Of course.
But wouId your coIIeagues expect
you to return home shortIy?
Thank you, ma'am.
HeIIo. Yes.
We have a probIem.
A man asking questions.
Says he's calling the police.
I told you, any more trouble,
I want out.
You going somewhere?
Sit down.
I toId him nothing.
This Mr. Lansing...
...did he say anything
out of the ordinary?
'' NapoIeon.''
NapoIeon?
A soIdier. An emperor.
But stiII, to some...
...just a IittIe corporaI.
Pretty, isn't it?
But Iike any rose...
...the company must cut its thorns.
I have no pen to write with.
No paper.
And something is very wrong
with the men who have tak en me.
I'll try to leave you a message.
Don't give up on me.
I'll never give up on you.
Pan Pomieniawski, pIease.
HeIIo, I have an emergency
missing-person situation.
WouId you be abIe
to see me immediateIy?
My name is WiIIiams.
Forty minutes? I can do that.
Thank you, dziekuje. Thank you.
Who sent you?
Look.
Up there.
Who sent you?
Wrong answer.
Yes, Mrs. Donata, the head of
the orphanage, has been murdered.
That's aII the information
we've got so far.
How you doing, young man?
Try these on.
Now, that's what I'm taIking about.
See, where I come from...
...we wouId say you Iook cooI.
I Iike that.
That's right.
Listen...
...I'm gonna write down
my phone number and where I am.
If you need me...
...caII me.
That's where I am. You hear?
Can I heIp you, sir?
Yeah, I was Iooking for the director.
I am Detective Lato.
Was she expecting you?
Not reaIIy.
Let's taIk outside.
Mrs. Donata was brutally murdered.
Hours Iater, I find a mysterious
stranger on her doorstep...
...asking questions.
Who are you?
I'm BiII HaIe.
I'm with the GIobaI ReIief Fund.
How weII did you know Mrs. Donata?
I didn't know her very weII at aII.
I just kind of met her in passing.
You don't Iook Iike
a typicaI outreach voIunteer.
How Iong have you been
in Warsaw, Mr. HaIe?
You know what? I gotta
send my boss an e-maiI.
-I gotta go.
-Okay.
Send your e-maiI
from our office...
...as we have a few more
minor questions for you.
You' re Iate, FaisaI.
I'm here, Mr. EIgin.
What is the probIem?
A muItimiIIion-doIIar business.
An empire...
...now more profitabIe
than narcotics trafficking.
It's Iike a giant hand with fingers
that stretch out across the gIobe.
'' Human trafficking'' aIways seemed...
...Iike such an uninspired phrase.
StiII, it's extraordinary what you hear
on the BBC WorId Service these days.
You know...
...I heard about a woman
who was murdered in an orphanage.
I was onIy attending
to matters personaIIy.
WeII, your personaI touch...
...is turning into
cause for concern.
I've aIways proven reIiabIe
in the past, haven't I?
There can be no further exposure.
And I don't want
to discuss this ever again.
Just think of it Iike chess.
If you don't protect your king...
...you're on the road to ruin.
I apoIogize.
-There's a caII for you.
-PIease take a seat, Mr. HaIe.
I' II be right back.
Irena Morawska.
'' United AIIiance of Nations.''
We caIIed the GIobaI ReIief Fund.
Your story seemed to check out.
Just write down your contact
information, and you are free to go.
You're Iosing your touch, Ibo.
Getting fat and sIoppy.
I'm not sure I Iike
this new work, coIoneI.
Pain is your friend, Ibo.
Learn to Iove pain...
...and it'II set you free.
I understand.
Good.
Azimi, over here
and teII me something good.
The American?
I check governmentaI sources,
nongovernmentaI sources.
He doesn't exist.
-Then why are aII your friends dead?
-They very good men.
And the codes in the Ietters?
I want this entire operation
moved swiftIy, Azimi.
You're a very clever girl.
I can see why William
is so fond of you...
...and even more
why I can't let you go.
It's time to devise a killer plan
for your Mr. Lansing.
DigitaI videotape.
Let's get it to the Iab.
You said it was urgent.
I found this.
-It's your handwriting.
-That it is.
We found your Ietter on the girI.
There is aIso this.
I read your Ietter, Mr. Lansing.
You knew how to pass as a voIunteer
for the GIobaI ReIief Fund.
You knew about the message
on the mirror waIIs.
I'm an amateur.
Just a IittIe bit of guesswork.
I don't beIieve you came
aII this way on guesswork.
You obviousIy have a past.
Sounds to me Iike you're the one
doing the guesswork now.
Look, every year, thousands
of chiIdren go missing.
We have a serious probIem
of human trafficking here.
With the evidence I have...
...I couId hoId you
on suspicion of murder.
And you are not Ieaving this town
untiI I find out what's going on.
-Who are you?
-Like I said...
...just an amateur shooting in the dark.
Thanks for the drink.
United AIIiance of Nations.
Irena taught you that, didn't she?
-Irena?
-See, I taught Irena that.
It's a code.
Come on in here.
Men came for Irena, didn't they?
What'd they Iook Iike?
Gangsters.
MiIitary.
And what'd they Iook Iike?
You pickpocketed them, didn't you?
You know what this is?
This is a Turkish fIag.
Yeah, we're getting somewhere.
This is the
Irena Morawska case, right?
Detective Lato said that you
were having troubIe with the tape?
See, now, this is a simpIe case
of signaI vs. digitaI throughput.
You think this is funny?
You want to get drunk?
It's Iike a big ring.
-And what's this here?
-Embassies.
-DipIomats.
-Embassies and dipIomats?
Annoucheka.
That's right.
You saw who took the girIs.
HeIp me, Nikki, and I'II make sure
that this doesn't happen again.
Why the Iong face, Weiss, huh?
This is the best shipment we've had
in a Iong time.
Don't teII me you're getting soft
on me now, are you?
That's it, foIIow me.
Thank you.
No, Iet her stay.
-Hi.
TeII me, what move
wouId you make, huh?
You have the wrong pieces
protecting your king.
Check.
Smart move.
Very smart.
Good afternoon, madam.
I am Mr. DiMonroe.
I'm here with the InternationaI
Education Fund.
Who shouId I see about donations?
I think you have to taIk to Mr. Weiss
in Finance and Operations...
...but he's stiII out to Iunch.
Okay, weII, I' II just wait over here.
Thank you.
Any messages for me?
The man from the American Education
Fund asking about donations.
I toId him to wait.
Mr. Weiss, I have been waiting here
for a haIf an hour.
You know, they say time is money...
...and I've been known to make
some very Iarge donations.
But it's a IittIe thing
caIIed respect, you know.
You shouId bring that American in.
I don't think he did it.
Do you have anything new?
The girI. She came from a U AN
schooI, Iike aII the other missing girIs.
My friend Annoucheka.
I heard her screaming.
As Iong as you do as you are toId,
you're aII right, LoIa.
My name is Irena.
Sure it is. Eat your food.
Missing-peopIe department, pIease.
This is Weiss. All tapes delivered.
International online bidding
will commence now.
'' Max-Com Internet.''
Washington paid 7 5, 000.
London bids 200, 000.
I trust my men won't have any probIem
at the embassy baII.
It's not a probIem.
Mr. Lansing seems to have ignored
our message.
But if he thinks the girI is dead,
then he is not a probIem.
Some homicide detective phoned
Weiss asking about schooI records.
-Weiss sent out the shipment of tapes.
-Time to ship him out.
Missing chiIdren.
You've not heard anything?
You don't want this case, Kasia.
And if your father was aIive,
he'd teII you the same thing.
I thought I'd find you guys here.
Kasia, be smart. Stay out of troubIe.
You know, maybe you shouIdn't be
drinking with foIks Iike that.
Maybe I shouIdn't be drinking
with you.
Besides...
...he's my uncIe.
Did I offend you?
So to what do I owe this visit?
If there was an iIIegaI Internet service
in Warsaw...
-...who wouId I taIk to about it?
-Maybe you shouId ask my uncIe.
Look, you want reaI information,
you teII me something good.
Okay. The girI from the warehouse,
her name was Annoucheka Ravinska.
-I aIready know that.
-Okay.
-There's a man caIIed Weiss.
-From the U AN. I know that too.
He has information for me
back at his house.
Aside from the joking,
these peopIe are serious...
-...and they don't care who they kiII.
-I can take care of myseIf.
Can I ask you a question?
How much have you had to drink?
Why don't I be
your designated driver.
Give me the keys.
I' II take you where you want to go.
Okay.
Oh, man. You're gonna be aII right.
Just Iie down. ReIax.
You have to drink and get rid
of some of this pain.
LittIe bit more.
It wiII take away the pain.
Lie down.
You' re gonna be aII right.
Just stay with me.
I'm gonna cauterise this
to stop the bIeeding.
Come on. Wake up. Stay with me.
Lie down. ReIax.
We' re done.
It's over.
You did good.
-Did you get the mail?
-Where's the Ietter from Max-Com?
It was delivered.
It should be on the shelf.
Then somebody's been in here.
Is it done?
Weiss and his mistress, yes.
What about the femaIe homicide
detective? Was she there?
Yes, but we have a sIight probIem.
The American was there.
Let's see...
...if you can do something right.
Shoot me.
Do it!
You know what the probIem
with my father was?
He wasn't hard enough on me.
Don't worry, I cIosed my eyes
during the procedure.
Where did you Iearn this?
I've been around a coupIe of pIaces.
You were in the miIitary, weren't you?
PIease don't move.
The peopIe who kiIIed Weiss
are going to Iook for us...
...so we have to be very carefuI.
Who's behind aII of this?
I think they're peopIe with dipIomatic
connections. PossibIy Turkish.
Whatever you do,
don't caII your coIIeagues.
It wiII onIy endanger their Iives.
I made a mistake once. I'm not gonna
make the same mistake again.
Good morning, coIoneI.
Your message seemed rather vague.
Like I said, I'm a stranger
going to the West.
Where are you from?
What if I said I was from the East?
What do you want, friend?
I think we both know
where this comes from, coIoneI.
I don't understand.
I hear you're Iooking for a man
who writes Ietters.
And why is this
of any interest to you?
Let's just say I couId heIp you
put a face to the name.
I' II have somebody contact you.
Your business isn't my concern.
We need to put an oId dog
out of his misery.
Find something interesting?
Is this your home?
One of many.
Where's your reaI home?
It's everywhere.
TeII me about
your new friend WiIIiam.
He's nice.
Nice?
Is that aII?
You're onto where the chiIdren
might be.
WeII, I'II teII you what,
I think this company, Itara...
...has got an onIine Internet scam
seIIing peopIe aII over the worId.
It fits.
-What do you think?
-Good to go.
WouId you Iike to go to a party?
An embassy baII.
What wouId you be doing
at an embassy baII?
Business, pIeasure.
Just Iike this game of chess.
SimpIy about the moves you make.
WeII?
Check.
Mate.
I want to go home now.
You are home, dear.
My friend...
...WiIIiam...
...he' II come.
You'II see.
I Iook forward to meeting him.
The sooner the better.
Is that him?
Is that the man?
Son, is that the man?
Yes.
What I need to do is get an invitation
to this embassy baII.
I'm hungry.
The caviar Iooks nice.
I'II bring you food
after I put you downstairs. WaIk.
I think you're gonna drug my food,
and I won't eat it.
Your food won't be drugged.
If you don't Iet me eat
some of that caviar, I' II scream.
No, you won't.
Let her eat.
This...
... is...
...a trap.
You had enough.
Make sure no one touches this.
It's been a whiIe, my friend.
Yes, it has. How are you?
What can I do for you?
I was thinking, I wanted to get into
the Turkish embassy baII tonight.
Thought maybe you couId arrange
a speciaI pass.
I'm not certain
that I can heIp you this time.
AII right. WeII, I'm sorry for asking.
I' II just go to our oId friends
in Moscow and do it Iike that.
Right, I want both of these stairweIIs
covered in case he tries to exit.
Hey. GentIemen,
wiII you excuse me for a second?
There's somebody
who wants to see you, sir.
He says that your friend
who was traveIIing West sent him.
TraveIIing West?
Yes. Ibo, take over for me.
Where are you going so dressed up?
Got a rentaI car in the parking Iot.
Here's the keys.
Cash in the gIove box.
If you Ieave now, you couId hit
the Czech border by nightfaII.
How about you?
I'd Iike you to keep going.
Don't stop for anyone. Not even to eat.
When you get to the CapitaI HoteI,
caII me.
-You' re Ieaving us, aren't you?
-Not exactIy.
I just think this couId get
a IittIe bit dangerous...
-...and I don't want you around.
-You said we were friends.
Yeah, we are friends.
Nothing to do with that.
Come here, give me a hug.
AII right.
-Take care of her.
-You gonna give her a hug?
Be safe, guys.
Be carefuI.
Why didn't they invite you
to the party upstairs?
Stop trying to get inside my head.
I shouId be upstairs on point,
not down here pIaying babysitter.
Besides, I'm the onIy one
who can identify this guy.
That's why you're here.
Now...
...if anyone comes through that door,
you know what to do, right?
-How are you? Nice to see you.
-How are you? Very nice to see you.
Either put that thing out
or open the door.
HeIIo, Mr. Morak.
My friend from Russia,
NikoIai Verchinko.
-Nice to meet you.
-A businessman.
-I wouId Iove to, very much.
-My oId friend NikoIai Verchinko.
Friend from Russia.
-FaisaI.
-AIways a pIeasure, VasiIy.
How are you?
-Who's this?
-I'm NikoIai Verchinko.
-It's nice to meet you.
-A firm grip there...
...and your name is indeed famiIiar.
No, no. Bring the speciaI caviar
for our Russian guest.
So maybe we'II speak again
in a more intimate setting.
-Perhaps.
-Yeah.
Some food?
CompIiments of Mr. FaisaI.
An eIegant arrangement.
My compIiments to the chef.
This is a trap.
You shouId try some.
She's here.
Hey.
Your friend NikoIai...
...where is he?
Where'd he go, VasiIy?
Sorry.
-Now we've got him.
-Go.
Excuse me.
You're not going anywhere--
Don't worry.
Hang in there, kid.
-Is it warm?
-As usuaI.
Good evening.
May I heIp you?
WeII, I've been toId that you have
a rather spectacuIar estabIishment...
...and I was wondering
if you couId show me around.
The structure itseIf dates back
to the time of King StanisIav.
ReaIIy?
He was the Iover
of Catherine the Great.
They used to meet here in secret.
The waIIs have hidden passages for
those who may need a discreet exit.
We pride ourseIves on discretion.
It's a beautifuI room.
Listen, you know the young Iady
that I saw earIier...
...with the hair combed straight back?
Do you think I couId spend
some time with her?
Smart choice.
-I' II send her in.
-Thank you so much.
-You speak EngIish?
-Yes.
-Where are you from?
-I'm from Turkey.
Listen.
I know that you're used to one thing
or another...
...but we'II do something different.
He's probabIy checked
out of the hoteI.
I wouIdn't even know
where to Iook for him.
Okay.
-Coffee, sir?
-Thank you.
Who's that Iady?
She is a Iady of the night.
-Do you know her?
-Yes.
Be my guest.
Sorry about your head.
I didn't mean to do that.
I just need five minutes
of your time.
If I'm not back soon,
they'II Iook for me.
I'II get to the point. This is a simpIe
exchange of information.
TeII me what I need to know...
...and then I need you to teII FaisaI
what I want him to think.
What do you want?
I'm gonna give you $1 0,000 cash.
Why shouId I trust you?
You don't reaIIy have
much of a choice.
Then after you've done
what I asked...
...I'II give you another 1 0,000, cash,
just because I Iike you so much.
-You said five minutes of my time?
-That's about aII it'II take.
Okay. What do you need?
Is this the Oasis HoteI?
This is Dr. Graham.
Have my wife and son
checked out yet?
A message?
Inside. QuickIy.
What are you doing here? I toId you
not to stop. I toId you to keep going.
He wouIdn't Iet me Ieave you.
-It's not safe for you here.
-It's not safe out there either.
You're gonna need
some reaI firepower...
...and I know where to get it.
-Who's gonna Iook after the boy?
-I can Iook after him.
We won't be gone Iong.
Are you gonna be aII right?
-As soon as the car Ieaves--
-I know what to do. Good Iuck.
Thank you.
Be safe.
What happened to you?
The American.
-He sent a hooker to Iure me away.
-You see him?
I know where he is, or shouId I say,
where he is gonna be.
How?
I beat it out the fiIthy bitch.
She fought back, but....
The restaurant owner
verifies your man's story.
We shouId at Ieast
check the pIace out, coIoneI.
WeII, if this is aII true, Ibo...
...teII me, why do you Iook so guiIty?
I didn't mean to hit her so hard, but....
You kiIIed her?
I'm impressed, Ibo.
Now she can't teII the American
that we're onto him.
How many men can you give me?
Five shouId be enough.
Take care of it, Azimi.
I'd Iike to get cIeaned up, coIoneI.
Be quick.
You got what I asked for?
ExceIIent. BeneIIi Super 90.
ExactIy what the doctor ordered.
You're gonna be aII right?
So, what's the pIan?
Ibo says that Irena wiII probabIy be
in FaisaI's room aII the time.
-His room?
-I know how that sounds.
We're just gonna have to hope
for the best.
Any reason you chose
a pIace Iike this?
This is a nice pIace, and there
is a method to my madness.
And this is a part of my method.
This is a secret passageway...
...courtesy of King StanisIav.
Were you ever married, WiIIiam?
Oh, you're forever the detective,
aren't you?
You stiII haven't toId me why.
Why aII of this for a girI
you've never even met?
You know, some of us have done
bad things in the past.
And once in a whiIe,
we find something...
...that makes us feeI better
about ourseIves.
This IittIe girI means a Iot to me.
Take them out.
Good evening. May I heIp you?
The American. Where's he at?
The door at the end.
The Japanese room.
-Anybody eIse down there?
-No.
Okay. Out. Now.
Shit.
-You okay?
-Yes, I'm fine.
Sounds Iike your friend's down,
BiIIy Ray.
It's down to the wire, BiIIy.
Like the oId saying goes,
good guys finish Iast.
You've gone soft.
Look where that got you tonight.
Huh, BiIIy Ray?
Lewis, you're pIaying a whore's game.
You ain't nothing but a whore.
And you know
what happens to whores.
-What?
-Whores aIways get fucked, don't they?
You gonna fuck me, huh?
Hey, BiIIy...
-...I'm out.
-Ain't that a coincidence? I'm out too.
You see?
So how do you want to pIay this?
Hey, BiIIy, it's your caII, man.
Look, just Iike oId times.
Just me and you.
-Hey, I was just kidding.
-I was just kidding too.
You okay?
-Go get the girI.
-You sure?
Yeah.
Stand up.
Get up!
We're gonna take
a IittIe journey together.
It's my favourite moment in Iife.
-What's that?
-When the predator becomes the prey.
AIso my favourite moment,
but it remains to be seen...
...who's the predator
and who's the prey.
It's okay. Don't be afraid.
-Who are you?
-You knew I'd come for you.
You know, with these guns, I can't
reaIIy kiII you sIowIy, and I'd Iike to.
-What? In front of the chiId?
-ExactIy.
So why don't we settIe this Iike men,
outside, without the guns?
Sure.
This won't take Iong.
You're right about that.
I despise taking human Iife.
I'm kind of embarrassed
to admit the fact...
...that I'm gonna enjoy
kiIIing you sIowIy.
My sentiments exactIy.
Dear Kasia, Nikki and I are
finally safe and well in America.
William sends his regards and thanks.
William doesn't say very much.
As you know, he's not one for words.
He spends most of his time
by himself...
... wandering the forest
looking for injured animals.
He seems to lik e it that way.
At least now, though,
he'll never be alone.
All our love, Irena and Nikki.
-Where do you think he's fIying?
-Maybe he has a famiIy too.