Tumblr is a good place
for inspiration.
I definitely support Tumblr.
There's the other side, where
people are like, there's no
creativity.
It's just a reblog generation.
But what's wrong with having a
visual identity that's based
on other people?
It's just curating.
Everyone's just being mini
curators, in a sense.
I don't necessarily
think that's bad.
I'm bad at eye contact.
I can get awkward.
But I'll try.
I'll try to keep it here.
[MUSIC - JEROME LOL & JOHNNY
WOODS, "THAT LAUGHING TRACK"]
I was in college and taking a
lot of social media classes
and media theory classes.
And Marcus and I met
on a message board.
We both made music
as solo artists.
And then it was just
a fun experiment.
Let's try to collaborate
on a remix.
And so we did a remix.
It was fun.
And then it kept going,
had a snowball effect.
Why even stop?
People are enjoying it.
It was fun.
It came out of experimentation,
I think, of
can we do an internet group?
Can this just exist online?
But it was cool.
We brought it into
the IRL sphere.
And we played shows in Europe.
It was amazing.
It was really fun.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
I was on this tour with
some friends.
We'd played in Tijuana
on a Saturday night.
So I had no cell service,
nothing.
We were in Tijuana.
We got back to the hotel room
in San Diego at 4:00 AM.
And I just look on Twitter.
Friends of mine are like, great
job Rihanna, stealing
Jerome's visual aesthetic.
[MUSIC - RIHANNA, "DIAMONDS"]
I watched it.
I was like, yeah.
I get it.
I get why people are going to
associate that with some of
the videos I've made.
But I wasn't particularly
offended.
Thinking about the context more
and more, I was like,
this is kind of fucked up.
But then also a side
of me was like, why
wouldn't this happen?
Of course this happened.
This happens with everything.
This isn't the first time
this has happened.
Do you not want it to get big?
I was like, this is
actually cool.
This is the best looking
Saturday Night Live
performance in my eyes.
I loved it.
But taking out of context, if
you have like a 50-year-old
guy who's never seen that
before, seeing that aesthetic
on Saturday Night Live for the
first time, not understanding
where it's coming from, see
it as being problematic.
But Buzzfeed or Buzzmedia, or
whatever that site's called,
they used me as the example.
They could have used--
hundreds of artists have
that same style.
It's not really specific
to me.
Seapunk as a word was
coined in 2011.
That was just a buzz word that
people wanted to assign to
this whole visual aesthetic.
I think what people are talking
about when they say
seapunk is this Tumblr aesthetic
of early web 1.0
art, a lot of water visuals,
and this bright
pastel-y color scheme.
But it's definitely referential
to early web 1.0
stuff, GeoCities, Angelfire,
stuff like that.
But I know I'm not doing it
justice to the people who
really identify with seapunk,
because I don't
identify with it.
But they, I know, have their own
belief system, which you
can read about on
the internet.
Now people like know what you
mean when you say seapunk
aesthetic, or whatever.
But it can be a little
frustrating.
[MUSIC - LOL BOYS, "123"]
This 123 video I did was
like this song, kind
of this club song.
But then the visual
representation of the song
kind of made it into a more
interesting thing.
[MUSIC - LOL BOYS, "123"]
I don't believe in nostalgia,
romanticism.
I think you have to
take that stuff.
And just placing it in this day
and age makes it, I guess,
taking it out of context,
making it fun.
And even if people think
it looks shitty, it's
beautiful in a way.
That style, I think there's a
certain kind of beauty in it,
just on an aesthetic level.
It's nice to look at
that kind of stuff.
Maybe it is because
it's nostalgic.
But it's still make sense
in a modern context.
[MUSIC - LOL BOYS, "123"]
I really like screenshots of
just funny things that happen
online, whether it's a pop-up
ad or just ads in general.
If you take that out of context,
it's like someone
designed that.
Someone designed a pop-up ad.
And so to put it just on your
Tumblr without it being
annoying, it just gives it
a new life, I think.
Skrillex had seen--
my management had showed
him my website,
showed him my videos.
And he really liked it.
He said he he wanted
me to do something.
He had this website he
wanted to do it.
He's just like yeah, make
it anything you want.
It can be like old
GeoCities style.
It could be whatever you want.
We did the whole thing
in two nights.
It was an amazing experience,
and super fun.
It was fun.
We were doing it for Skrillex.
A lot of people got
mad at that, too.
You sold out.
No.
But it wasn't like we did that
and there was this art
direction team.
He was talking to us.
It was a direct dialogue.
And he understands
the whole thing.
This is Santee Alley.
This is where you can find
Twitter chains, Angry Bird
chains, a lot of chains,
internet things.
Do you have any 3D hologram
cases that change?
That's like the club look
of 2013 right there.
[MUSIC - LOL BOYS, "CHANGES
(FT HEART STREETS)"]
Kind of with the last EP, the EP
changes and it was kind of
like the crux.
We were really happy with it.
It was the pinnacle of what we
thought we could do as this
internet group.
[MUSIC - LOL BOYS, "CHANGES
(FT HEART STREETS)"]
I had an idea of doing
a screen shot video,
kind of like that.
I love that people lip
sync on YouTube, and
that's a whole sub-genre.
That's such a niche.
So I wanted to take that, and
place it in like this is an
official music video with
people doing it.
And then the whole like meta
thing of making it on top of a
desktop came to me after.
So then yeah, those people, I
just sent out a mass email of
musicians and friends I
had, seeing if they
were down to do it.
I was stoked, very happy
with the response.
It was cool.
It was really fun to do.
It's fun to collaborate.
They are just as much
directors in the
music video as I am.
Because I didn't know what
I was going to get back.
I said listen to the song.
I didn't even say for how
long do have to do it.
I said listen to this
song, and record
yourself reacting to it.
So some people lip sync.
Some people don't.
I sent them the lyrics.
It was super fun.
It was a collaborative thing.
I plan on doing that with my
next videos, to do something
that's collaborative
with other artists.
[MUSIC - LOL BOYS, "CHANGES
(FT HEART STREETS)"]
I think anything that's on a
computer, if you see it on
your screen, it's on
your computer.
Even if it's on the internet,
it's still on your screen.
So I think you own it.
That's part of why computers
and the internet is great.
Because it's modular.
You can just take whatever
you want.
That's kind of the
whole thing.
If you view the internet as kind
of this collaborative art
project that keeps--
everyone is just
stealing from each other.
And it keeps getting crazier
and crazier and crazier.
I'm OK with that.
That's a fun thing.
It makes it exciting.
[CHATTER]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
I think the persona I project
as Jerome LOL is more of--
it's humor.
It's funny.
But it's still me.
I'm still that every day.
But more and more I thinking
of it in the third person.
I am more careful with what
I'm posting online.
That's kind of the beauty of the
internet, though, is you
get to choose what you want
to broadcast to people.
The more I'm getting into it,
especially since I've gone
solo, the more I view it as this
third person thing, which
keeps me sane for sure.
Because I'm not always a crazy
internet person, I guess.
It makes you super self
aware, I think.
The first time you use Facebook,
you have the option
of, what's your profile
picture?
Even choosing your profile
picture, that's a statement of
how you view yourself.
It's a very self reflexive,
self aware activity.
It's insane, now little
kids are doing that.
I feel like everyone is becoming
self aware in the
past few years.
It's just going to
keep getting more
and more hyper aware.
I've been on vacation where
I have stepped away, but I
really don't like it.
I don't think it's a
physical addiction.
Definitely it's not.
I don't get sick.
And I don't have physical
withdrawals.
I'm not throwing up if I
don't check my email.
It's an obsession, more than
an addiction, I think.
I'm obsessed with
the internet.
I need to see what's going on.
I need to be connected with
those people that I like.
And I don't want to
miss anything.
I'm addicted to the internet
completely.
I'm on it way too much.
But maybe not way too much.
I enjoy my time on
the internet.
I have stepped away.
I have gone on vacation and been
away from the internet
for five days.
It's refreshing.
You come back and then you
realize, I don't need all this
bullshit, really.
But then right away when
you get back into it,
you're back in it.
So I think it's healthy once
in while, to get away.
And to know that you
can get away.
And it's not the end of the
world if you miss a few emails
here or there.
If it's a day where I don't have
anything to do and I'm
just in the studio,
probably 11 hours.
Yeah, I spend about 11 hours
a day on the internet or in
front of a screen.
[MUSIC PLAYING]