Formula One is the most
obvious connection.
But McLaren was also involved
with Can-Am
racing as well as IndyCar.
Founded in 1963 by Bruce
McLaren, a former racer
himself, it's one of the few
brands in the world that
invests itself so heavily
into racing.
JOHN ALLERT: It wouldn't
surprise you to know when you
come to a building like this
that everything we do is about
attention to detail.
But it's not just attention to
detail for detail's sake.
It's always with an
objective in mind.
And 9 times out of 10, that
objective is winning.
We have other businesses where
winning isn't necessarily
being first across the line--
it's about being the best.
But at the end of the day,
everything we do is about
being better than our peers,
better than our competitors.
JF MUSIAL: I have
to ask though.
You look at Bruce McLaren's
vision and
actually what Ron Dennis--
how has McLaren transpired at
after all these years to be
what it is, from those
initial idea?
JOHN ALLERT: I think it's
because it's the shared value
systems that Bruce had
and that Bruce
imparted on his team.
And then when Ron took over,
he had very much those same
values, but then just took them
to a whole new level, was
able to bring in greater
finance.
And that gave us the muscle to
then develop that vision and
take it into other areas.
JF MUSIAL: What I love, though,
is that you stay close
to your racing history.
This is incredible.
JOHN ALLERT: Well, how
can we not stay close
to our racing history?
I mean, our racing history
is phenomenal.
And we've won 1 in 4 of every
Formula One race we've ever
competed in.
JF MUSIAL: Unheard of.
JOHN ALLERT: We've been on the
podium for 50% of every race
we've ever competed in.
So it's a pedigree and a
heritage that we are obviously
very proud of.
We're not an extrovert business,
but we feel very,
very proud inwardly
of that success.
And it's that success that
inspires the current
generation of people at McLaren
to try and take it to
another level.
How do people feel about
all of this heritage?
JF MUSIAL: Yeah.
JOHN ALLERT: They feel
enriched by it.
You can't help but feel
inspired by it.
And it's one of the key
reasons that we
have it all on display.
Your reaction when you walked
in here is no different than
anybody's reaction.
Which is, wow, there's a Senna
car, or there's a Prost car,
or whatever it is.
Everybody has their particular
era that
they get excited about.
And for me just as one person,
to actually see some of the
cars here every day that I've
actually stood on the other
side of the wire from
when I was 12 or 13
years old, I get tingles.
I get goosebumps just
thinking about it.
We've had people break down in
tears seeing some of the cars
that you've walked past today.
JF MUSIAL: Walking into the MTC,
it's as if you're walking
into a science fiction movie--
long corridors with highly
metallic surfaces.
You walk through hallways
thinking Trent Reznor should
score a soundtrack for all the
guests to listen to as they
enter the place for
the first time.
Everything is spotless.
Everything is clean.
You can tell everything is
designed obsessively.
And I'm not saying that
in a cold way.
In fact, the architecture allows
for so much natural
light into the work spaces it
makes you feel awake, alive.
JOHN ALLERT: This building was a
vision conceived in the kind
of mid to late '90s.
JF MUSIAL: OK.
JOHN ALLERT: Ron Dennis always
wanted to bring the kind of
the federation of companies
together under one roof.
We'd grown exponentially over
a period of 20, 25 years.
And we really were wanting the
benefits of being back as one
kind of collective.
JF MUSIAL: Mm-hmm.
JOHN ALLERT: We then wanted a
showpiece both for commercial
reasons, so that we could
explain to people the vision
of what we're all about and
hopefully elicit their
investment in us either as
sponsors, or partners, or in
some cases, investors, but
also to make sure that we
could recruit the best people,
and get the best people to
come and share in what it was
that we were trying to build.
And this facility really
does inspire the
people who work here.
And I think that Ron really was
ahead of time in creating
something that people would just
want to be in, want to be
part of, as well as well
as the success of
the business itself.
To actually come to a
place like this is--
it's an awe-inspiring
environment in which to work.
And it's a little like
going on stage.
You really feel like you have
to up your game when you
arrive here every morning.
JF MUSIAL: It is an inviting
experience, which makes sense.
The MTC opened in 2003.
And Ron Dennis was very
influential in its design.
Inside, you not only have
McLaren Racing but also
McLaren Automotive and the
not so well known McLaren
Electronics.
Walking in here, you look at
this, this is not what I was
expecting at all.
JOHN ALLERT: No, this looks--
JF MUSIAL: This looks like
a scientific laboratory.
JOHN ALLERT: I was just going
to say it looks like a
laboratory.
But it's not.
This is part of McLaren
Electronics.
JF MUSIAL: Got it.
JOHN ALLERT: So this is where
ECUs are actually being
physically created.
I mean, we're printing circuit
boards in there.
That's high-end stuff.
It's not the sexy end
of the business.
But it's very high-end.
JF MUSIAL: Ron Dennis wanted
the building to attract the
best engineers and designers.
But more importantly, he wanted
to keep them there.
Walking the hallways, you can
tell everyone who works there
has a sense of pride to be
working within those walls.
JOHN ALLERT: It's actually--
it's a very selfless culture.
I think we attract like-minded
people here who ultimately
want to win and what to do the
best they can possibly do in
whatever role they have.
But they're selfless people
who want to come
together as a team.
And understand that actually
the old cliche of 1 plus 1
equals 3, that if they can all
come together and be the best
in their particular discipline,
chances are that
we're more likely to
succeed or to win.
And we have a lot
to live up to.
We have 49 years of success.
In the time that we've been in
Formula One, for example,
there have been over
100 Formula
One teams have failed--
have come and gone,
left Formula One.
So this is no place for
the weak or the meek.
And we're reminded of those
sorts of statistics every year
when people either leave the
automotive sector or they
leave Formula One.
And that's part of that pressure
to make sure that
we're being the best.
Because it's a slippery pole.
Either in supercars
or in Formula One,
it's a slippery pole.
And those that aren't near the
top have a real struggle.
[INAUDIBLE]
JF MUSIAL: Now, past the wind
tunnel and the Formula One
work bays, we walk down a long
hallway, all underground, very
James Bond-like.
You then hit a set of stairs.
You go up.
And then you walk into
what is called the
McLaren Production Center.
This is McLaren Automotive.
This is the future of McLaren.
LEE BOYCE: So right now, this
is the north end of the MPC.
This is a VIP area.
This is a hosting suite.
So this is basically where
potential customers, or
dignitaries, or any type of
VIP can come to this area.
And from this area, we lead
directly out onto the
production facility, just
around this corner here.
JF MUSIAL: OK.
LEE BOYCE: And I think
you need to see that.
JF MUSIAL: Let's go
check it out.
So how old is this place?
LEE BOYCE: So we've been
operating in here now for--
JF MUSIAL: Whoa!
Look at this!
LEE BOYCE: --eight months.
JF MUSIAL: And you're in full
production at this point.
That is incredible.
LEE BOYCE: We are flat-out
production.
And we have been now since
the turn of the year.
We have been at full capacity
in terms of our planning
requirements for this year.
And for sure, everything, from
a production point of view is
going absolutely beautifully
at this moment.
JF MUSIAL: This is surreal.
LEE BOYCE: Yes.
JF MUSIAL: It's almost
a [INAUDIBLE] room.
And it mimics the MTC but
on a different level.
Prior to the MP4-12C, McLaren
built my favorite hypercar,
the F1, then after that, the
SLR, which was built right
alongside the F1 cars.
But now, for the new MP4-12C,
it's an entirely new building.
The first thing I noticed there
was that there was a lot
of unused space.
McLaren has been around
for about 50 years.
But McLaren Automotive
is essentially an
entirely new company.
They built the McLaren
Production Center knowing they
would be building other models
besides the MP4-12C.
LEE BOYCE: Actually, what you're
looking at now is the
best part of 20,000 square
meters of floor space on which
we want to produce
the vehicle.
We worked really hard to make
sure that we could integrate
all of the processes that were
absolutely critical to
ensuring that the assembly of
this vehicle was felt on
absolute personal level from an
operator's point of view,
but also gave the customer a
really good feeling that
actually, his ownership
experience didn't start when
he took the car.
It actually started at the
placement of order.
And therefore, if he wanted to
visit this facility, he could
actually come and see his
vehicle being birthed.
All of the technicians feel as
though they're involved in
making that person's car.
So it's not just a vehicle.
They accept that there behind
that is a customer, and a
valued customer.
And we wanted to make sure that
his ownership experience
started right here from the
moment we first loaded any
components into the facility.
If we keep taking a
look down here--
JF MUSIAL: So this is
Phase 1 right here.
LEE BOYCE: So this
is absolutely the
start of the process.
JF MUSIAL: OK.
So this is the MP4-12C
monococque right here.
LEE BOYCE: We didn't want any
feel of industrialization in
the facility.
We wanted it to be a theater.
JF MUSIAL: [CHUCKLES]
LEE BOYCE: It was really
important to us that we create
an environment where everything
felt special and
everything felt personal.
And I think we've
achieved that.
So what you don't see is you
don't see any significant
levels of automation.
You don't see clunking--
JF MUSIAL: You almost
see none.
LEE BOYCE: --chains.
You don't see any conveyors.
You won't see air lines
or anything like this.
It's all very quiet.
It's all very composed.
And it's all very simple
in its execution.
If we take a look at some of the
racking and what have you,
there are a number of components
such as fastenings
and such as brackets and that
where we can clearly hold
quite a decent level of stock
holding lineside.
And as you can see with things
like these front long
[INAUDIBLE], we've designed
some bespoke stillaging to
allow us to--
JF MUSIAL: Just for
these parts?
LEE BOYCE: Just for these
particular parts.
And we have bespoke stillaging
all around the facility.
But I think what's a really
good, tactile thing about what
you're looking at right now is
if you look at the diameter
and the radius of the bespoke
stillaging, it's absolutely
the same as the radius and the
diameter of the racking.
As you could see, this is where
the vehicle's being more
and more progressed through
its build assembly phase.
So the windscreen surround
is going on there.
And the B-pillar carting
is going on here.
So even though we have 100%
confidence in the facilities,
and the equipment,
and the whole
process with these guys--
and we are 100% confident--
that doesn't stop us taking
every single body, and it is
every single body, and
processing them into the
Geometric and Surface
Validation station.
So this is Geometric and
Surface Validation.
So basically, every
single body--
even though we're 100% confident
it's in a good
place, we still want to measure
it just to ensure that
we don't get any quality drift
in the overall body's vehicle
assembly status.
JF MUSIAL: So this whole rig
here is just for measurement.
LEE BOYCE: So everything that
you're seeing here is
absolutely for measurement.
So if we take a lot
of surface points.
We take hundreds of
surface points.
We take hundreds of geometric
points on the vehicle to
ensure that we know that the car
is in a really good place
dimensionally.
The body would exit these
double doors here.
JF MUSIAL: Got it.
LEE BOYCE: Which are closed
at the moment.
Then it will go into-- this
is the paint facility now.
In essence, the vehicle through
this paint facility is
processed across two skids.
The body goes on one particular
skid and all of the
other supplementary panels
go onto another.
This is the single biggest piece
of investment in terms
of equipment in the
whole of MPC.
And so we've pushed all of
the potential suppliers--
with regard to paint
facilities--
hard in terms of making sure
that in their thinking,
they've got absolutely what we
were all about in terms of an
installation.
So whilst all of them could
have satisfied us
technically--
that's not a problem--
we wanted to make sure that
this was right as well.
This was really important for
us to make sure that they
understood our philosophies,
our methodologies, and they
clearly understand that from a
brand augmentation point of
view, whatever they install
absolutely complemented them.
Because what it creates is it
creates a completely different
mindset of thinking for
the technician.
What it demonstrates to the
technician is that we've
thought about their working
environment as much as we have
the product and the customer.
Because if we create a perfect
work environment for them,
they can only ever give their
best of themselves.
And I actually think you get
that natural transfer into the
vehicle there.
And you get an uplift
of in-built
vehicle processing quality.
I'm absolutely convinced
of that.
So what you're seeing here
now is worth seeing.
This is what we call Skid 2.
And it's just had its
base coat applied.
That won't go forward until
they put the clear coat on
those particular booths here.
The whole facility-- even
though we designed the
facility such that if
we wanted to put
robots in here, we could.
And whilst robots have
got great dexterity--
and they have-- and you can put
all sorts of convoluted
and complicated programs into
them, there's nothing more
dexterous than the human.
And what a robot doesn't have
as well, he doesn't have the
eye as well.
It's an application process.
There's nothing emotional
about it.
It's very clinical.
It's just application.
Here, these guys can take a
view on when they think
they've done something
absolutely the
right way or not.
And they've got an opportunity
to do a level of reparation in
the booth should a mistake have
been made or should they
see something on the vehicle,
then they think, oh, that
doesn't look quite right,
there's an opportunity here to
do that reparation.
So [INAUDIBLE]
this is an audit line.
And so basically, when the
vehicle has had its clear coat
put on, it goes into
the oven through
those glass doors there.
There's exits here.
And this is the first point
we do some inspection.
Every single vehicle gets
a full surface quality
inspection.
The great thing about this
facility is we have enough
flexibility in here to always
do a fix the same day such
that it doesn't disrupt
our output
requirements for the process.
So it comes all the way down
this particular facility here,
shuffles across again, and then
goes into the polishing
and final finishing site.
Every single car gets a full
flat and polish so that we
raise the optical aspect
of the vehicle.
So we create a far greater
level of depth
on the color itself.
So you can actually look
into the color.
And you're not just looking
at surface.
You're actually looking
into the color.
FRANK STEPHENSON: Everything you
see on the car, we like to
say it is done for a reason.
Which means that everything that
you see has an effect on
the overall performance
of the car.
And more so also, when they do
say form follows function,
that sounds nice
and everything.
But with this car, pretty much,
it's form equals function.
What looks right works.
What we've done is, of course,
you have the two main intakes
on the front which are for
your inner coolers.
They specifically have to get
a lot of very air in there
very efficiently and do
the job of cooling.
But also, we have what
we call a splitter
right here in the front.
And that creates a lot of
downforce, creates the right
feel for the road
with the car.
This area is very critical
underneath.
If you rub your hand underneath,
you'll feel some,
what we call diblets.
They're little--
JF MUSIAL: Oh, yeah.
FRANK STEPHENSON: --pumps that
actually straighten out the
airflow underneath, things that
you don't even see, but
they're on the car.
I mean, every detail is really
taken to the max on this car.
This is what we called
biomimicry.
There's a lot of influence
from what really works.
Some organisms in the world
use this type of design
feature for purpose basically.
We have had a little bit of
freedom with the headlights.
This is where you can really
start to give the car a little
bit of a unique look.
It's almost as if it's the
eyes of the person.
Eyes do give people a
lot of character.
So we're not really influencing
too much
technology here.
We are using high-tech
Xenon lamps.
But you can see that the actual
form of your daytime
running lamps sort of creates
the feel of the McLaren logo.
JF MUSIAL: Uh-huh.
FRANK STEPHENSON: We let the
light bleed through these
three little slots here
which are almost
like fins or gills--
JF MUSIAL: Gills-- that's
exactly what I was going to--
FRANK STEPHENSON:
--of a shark.
JF MUSIAL: --going to
describe as gills.
FRANK STEPHENSON: And that sort
of-- when you're in the
front, you look back and you see
that, it really gives the
car its own unique look to it.
Another thing that we've really
concentrated on is
keeping the cowl, the back of
the hood, as low as we can for
full optimal forward
visibility.
So we pushed it quite
far down.
That gives us a great
viewing angle from
the driver's position.
And one of the funny things
that you would not really
notice unless you're actually
sitting in the car-- it's very
interesting-- is that the center
point of the wheel is
directly under the highest
point of the fender.
Which means when you're actually
sitting down, you
know where your wheels are
placed to hit the apex.
JF MUSIAL: Because you see it.
FRANK STEPHENSON: Because you
know that the farthest point
you're looking-- or the highest
point-- is actually
the center of the wheel.
So you can really place it--
JF MUSIAL: Interesting.
FRANK STEPHENSON: --precisely
that way.
Really important is actually
this blade that we have here
on the side.
And although it looks kind of
like an element that we sat
down and designed and had fun
with, it really came out of
the computer, out of
what we call CFD,
Computational Fluid Dynamics.
And in our intent to make the
car as small as possible and
center all the weight towards
the center of the car, we've
actually turned the radiators
parallel to the direction of
the car to get the weight, the
mass, all towards the middle.
This blade here has been done
on the computer such that it
generates or actually keeps
the air attached to it.
And it throws it in on
an accelerated curve.
So you get plenty of
coin that way.
So this blade is
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
very necessary.
Of course, it adds flavor
to the car and
makes it more unique.
But it's there for a
reason, as I said.
Another element that I really
like on the car is what we
call the air brake on
the back of the car.
And we don't consider
it a spoiler.
It's not even used
as a spoiler.
It's basically a way
of adjusting the
braking on the car.
So anytime you break
in anger--
JF MUSIAL: In anger--
I like that.
[LAUGHTER]
FRANK STEPHENSON: Well, with
intent to break, I guess, to
slow down--
it goes 90 degrees.
And what happens then is that
the center of gravity actually
moves back towards the back of
the car and puts more weight
on the back wheels so that you
can actually use the breaks in
the rear a little bit more.
A lot of the action is actually
done by the wind
itself, not by pushing it
up but releasing it.
And then lift-- go
up on its own.
One of the design words that we
use a lot on the car is to
actually-- for the language--
is actually to almost, like,
shrink-wrap the surface.
Whereas a lot of cars add
volume, what we're trying here
to do is take away volume.
So you're almost, like,
shrink-wrapping the metal over
the hard points, which are
suspension mounts, or vision
angles, or head clearance
angles, whatever.
So we're trying to minimize,
take weight out of the car, by
reducing the amount of surface
area we have running.
JF MUSIAL: Got it.
LEE BOYCE: So this is basically
the start of the
trim and final part
of the process.
This is where we start
layering the car and
installing it ready for us to
take it to a point of--
JF MUSIAL: No wiring harness?
Wiring harness?
LEE BOYCE: Wiring harness--it's
as simple as that.
JF MUSIAL: Yeah.
LEE BOYCE: So we have the
opportunity of being able to
produce the same amount of cars
in this facility as any
of our competitors with their
levels of industrialization.
You don't actually need that.
And we wanted to create a
different blueprint for how to
build cars.
And if we take a look at these
vehicle ramps here, these are
a standard vehicle ramp.
But we wanted to make sure
that we put some nice
architectural cladding
around it.
And we made sure that we set all
of the services underneath
the tiles as well.
So you do not see any lines.
And that's why everything
is really clean.
And it was really important to
us that we didn't trailing air
lines, and we didn't see
trailing cables.
This is a really interesting
feature in the facility.
Again, same diameter, same
radius, but what's really
interesting here is that all
of the services are in a
trench here.
JF MUSIAL: Got it.
LEE BOYCE: So we have this
trench that runs the full
length of the building.
We have those in three or four
places across the building.
All of the services actually go
feed up through the back of
these tool cabinets there,
so that all of the IT
functionality is fed up
through here as well.
So you don't see any
cables here.
And if you need to use
compressed air or you need to
use single phase electrics,
it's all
embedded within the facility.
And you just don't
see any cabling.
Every single operator is
accountable for his work.
They work with what we call--
we have this little access
swipe system.
So when the car comes into the
facility, every single
operator has to swipe
his card.
If we take a look here--
I won't do it because it means
I'll have to start assembling
parts of the car.
But he would swipe his card
across the reader there.
And then that locks him
personally into that
particular vehicle to undertake
a certain amount of
work on that particular car.
JF MUSIAL: He's responsible.
LEE BOYCE: He's absolutely
100% responsible.
Now, we're getting into
the final stages of--
JF MUSIAL: I'm seeing a bunch
of grease pen on here.
So 248, 248-- so that's how
you identify [INAUDIBLE]
LEE BOYCE: That's how
we identify--
JF MUSIAL: [INAUDIBLE]
LEE BOYCE: Absolutely.
So this particular panel
was painted with
this particular body.
So that we absolutely make
sure we don't get any
inconsistencies with
color matching or
anything like this.
JF MUSIAL: Got it.
LEE BOYCE: And not only that--
we want to make sure that this
particular component is going
to be reset with this particular
door, so we get a
really good fit and finish from
a gap and profile point
of view as well.
LEE BOYCE: JF MUSIAL: Got it.
So what we're doing here now on
this particular station--
this is the geometry
setup lift.
This is basically where we do
toe, camber, ride heights, and
all of that sort of thing in
readiness for when we go into
the dynamic rig.
JF MUSIAL: Cool.
LEE BOYCE: [INAUDIBLE]
This is where we put the
car through its first
real dynamic load.
So we do an engine
fire-up further
upstream in the process.
And this is where we put
the car through some
dynamic load here now.
So basically, we bring the car
up to temperature, check most
of the electrical systems are
working, and all of the brains
in the vehicle are communicating
with each other.
We do some brake activity.
We do some acceleration,
deceleration.
But just generally, put the
car through some immediate
dynamic loads.
JF MUSIAL: Yeah.
LEE BOYCE: So in essence,
vehicle goes through a dynamic
rig into the Monsoon where
we give it a full
saturation of water.
I don't know--
16,000 liters in about 6
or 7 minutes-- it's a
huge amount of water.
Car exits there.
It then gets prepared, ready for
external drive appraisal.
They all leave through
that door there.
JF MUSIAL: OK.
LEE BOYCE: Goes out on its
external drive appraisal where
we put it through some more
aggressive loads.
One of things-- when we were
landscaping the whole
exterior, the outside of the
facility, what was really
important to us was to try
and optimize the land
around us as well.
So we've got cobbled sections
of roadway out there which
allow us to shake and rattle the
car a little bit just to
loosen anything.
Go before we actually take it
on the highways and byways.
JF MUSIAL: Ah.
LEE BOYCE: Obviously, during
the wetter seasons in the
year, the car could come back
with some muck and what have
you on them.
And that's why we just have this
wash down rig here now.
So we just give the underside
a quick wash down and just
make sure that the vehicle
is fully cleaned
before it exits here.
It would sit normally on here
for 45 minutes, just to have a
final drip-dry.
We take a look at the vehicle
after its been out on an
external drive.
And what we do is we're
basically checking to make
sure that nothing has worked
loose, there are no weeps, or
leaks, or anything like that
from any of the joints.
JF MUSIAL: Yeah.
LEE BOYCE: There's been no
displacement of any harness
clips or anything like this.
And everything [INAUDIBLE] is
absolutely how we want it to
be-- a very, very critical
station.
We're getting ourselves ready
to hand the car over to the
auditors with what we perceive
to be a car that is acceptable
for the customer.
The auditors then give it a
really thorough investigation,
an interrogation.
And again, they go to the nth
degree of checking service
quality, checking fit and
finish, checking functionality
of all of the systems.
JF MUSIAL: So that's it.
These cars go to the
customers, right?
LEE BOYCE: These cars are ready
to go to the customer.
JF MUSIAL: So where's--
LEE BOYCE: [INAUDIBLE]
JF MUSIAL: Where's the
car I'm driving?
LEE BOYCE: Unfortunately,
it's not one of these.
But just for you, we have
one back at the base.
JF MUSIAL: Cool.
LEE BOYCE: OK.
JF MUSIAL: Thank you.