have an atmosphere (like on the moon), the
sky would always be dark, even when the sun
is shining. So let’s rephrase the question
- why is space dark?
I mean, space is full of stars - countless
stars which are all about as bright as the
sun, and in an infinite eternal universe,
no matter what direction you picked, if you
looked far enough in that direction, you would
see a star or galaxy. So the whole sky should
be as bright as the sun, night and day!
And since it's not, does the darkness of the
night sky mean that there's some distance
away from us when stars and galaxies just…
stop? A boundary between something and nothing?
An "edge" to the universe?
Not exactly - all of our evidence seems to
indicate that space has no edge. But the universe
itself does - not a spatial edge, but a temporal
one: as far as we know, the universe had
a beginning. Or at least, a time about 13.7
billion years ago when the universe was so
small and crumpled-up with itself that our
standard notion of space and time breaks down.
And since only a finite amount of time has
passed since this so-called beginning, that
means that some of the stars necessary to
fill up the "brightness in every direction"
are so far away that light from them plain
hasn't had time to reach us yet… it's as
if the universe were a big thunderstorm and
we're still waiting to hear the thunder from
the really distant stars.
But wait, it’s better than that - since
light takes time to travel across the universe,
when we point our telescopes at something
really far away, we're actually seeing that
part of universe as it was when the light
was emitted. So when we look at 13.5 billion-year-old
light, it's not that we don't see stars just
because light from them hasn't gotten to us
yet - we don't see any stars because we’re
getting a peek at the universe before any
stars had formed! A star-less universe! Now
that sounds to me like a pretty good reason
why we look up and see a dark night sky.
But… it’s not. I mean, it is true that
we can find points in the sky where there
aren’t any stars by looking past the earliest
stars and thus farther back in time. But even
when we point our telescopes past the earliest
stars, we still see light. Not starlight,
but the light left over from the big bang.
And we detect this “cosmic background radiation”
coming more or less evenly from all directions,
forming a background beyond the stars. So,
I guess the night sky ISN’T actually dark
to begin with.
Right... so if our telescopes tell us that
the night sky isn’t dark, then why does
it look dark?
Here’s a clue to the real answer: when the
Hubble telescope photographed the distant
stars of the astoundingly beautiful Hubble
extreme deep field, it took the picture using
an infrared camera. Why? Well, distant stars
and galaxies are moving away from us because
the universe is expanding. So the same way
a record slowing down lowers the pitch of
my voice, the doppler effect causes stars
moving away from us to become redder, and
the farther away they are, the faster they
move away from us and the redder they become,
until they become… infrared. And then we
can't see them any more. At least not with
our human eyes - and that’s why the night
sky appears dark!
In summary: If we lived in an infinite, unchanging
universe, the entire sky would be as bright
as the sun. But the sky is dark at night,
both because the universe had a beginning
so there aren't stars in every direction and
more importantly because the light from super
distant stars (and the even-more-distant cosmic
background radiation) gets red-shifted away
from the visible spectrum by the expansion
of the universe, so we just plain can't see
it.
Finally! We’ve shed some light on why the
night sky is dark. And why it isn’t.