SIMON OSTROVSKY: We've seen a
lot of settlers, and we've
seen their settlements and their
homes, but we really
haven't got the Palestinian
perspective at all.
And apparently, the Palestinians
are often
attacked by settlers.
So we've come to this town,
Asira al-Qibliya, to get their
perspective on things.
This is the end of the road in
this Palestinian town, so
these houses here are the ones
that are closest to the Jewish
settlement up the hill.
And they face the brunt of the
attacks when the settlers come
down throwing stones.
And the owners of some of these
houses are telling us
that the Israeli army doesn't
do anything about it.
MALE SPEAKER 1:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
SIMON OSTROVSKY: He showed us
videos he'd taken himself of
the settler attacks where you
could see youths come down
from the settlement above the
village to throw stones.
MALE SPEAKER 1:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
The worst thing about it was
that they were accompanied by
the Israeli army, who were
supposedly there to separate
the two groups but were in fact
doing nothing to stop the
settler attack.
MALE SPEAKER 1:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
A few weeks after we visited
Asira al-Qibliya, the settler
attacks resumed.
But this time, two Palestinian
villagers who were throwing
stones and approaching Jewish
youths were shot by the
settlers with live ammunition
during two separate attacks.
Both times, the Israeli
army did nothing to
restrain the settlers.
Fortunately though,
both men survived.
MALE SPEAKER 1:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
SIMON OSTROVSKY: The situation
was obviously very tense and
very dangerous, but this wasn't
the only place under a
fair bit of pressure.
The Migron settlement is one
of the few Jewish outposts
that have received clear-cut
court orders to be totally
dismantled.
This is Migron, an illegal
outpost, and Israel has
ordered all of this to be
demolished in a few months.
So it's got a bit of a
Deliverance vibe going on, not
so much because there's a lot
of hillbillies out here but
they're about to flood
the valley.
Migron has seen some of its
structures knocked down by the
Israeli authorities before, but
this time, Israel's high
court has ordered that the
entire place be destroyed
because it was illegally built
on Palestinian land.
It's a very unusual ruling, and
most Palestinians see it
as a one-off rather than a
reversal of settlement policy
in the West Bank.
I spoke to one of the residents
to find out how she
felt about the impending
demolition.
Do you sympathize with
Palestinian people who also
see their houses get demolished
under Israeli
bulldozers?
FEMALE SPEAKER 1: I see it from
another point of view.
I think it's a different
story.
Here, nobody killed anyone.
Israel destroying a house
for Palestinians
is not for no reason.
Most of the times, it's
because they did
a very wrong thing.
People killing people
and other things.
The story here is that the
families did nothing.
It's not that I don't
feel sorry.
I do.
But I more feel sorry about my
own people that sits under
attacks every day, and we
see it all the time.
SIMON OSTROVSKY: So right now
must be a really difficult
time for the residents of Migron
because the high court
of Israel has stated pretty
finally that by August, they
want all of this to
be demolished.
Do you know what you're
going to do?
FEMALE SPEAKER 1: We believe
that we won't be in the
street, and we work with the
government to find a solution
for this hard situation.
SIMON OSTROVSKY: It's easy to
get bogged down in the legal
details of the status of each
individual settlement, but the
important thing to remember is
that while some sites face the
chopping block, the total number
of settlers in the West
Bank has grown from just 12,000
in the early '80s to
over 300,000 today.
And that figure doesn't even
include a further 200,000
Israelis living in East
Jerusalem, according to the
activist group Peace Now.
Many have begun asking
themselves if it's even
possible for a Palestinian
state to emerge from a
territory crisscrossed with
Jewish settlements.
A couple of miles down the road
from Migron just across a
small valley, we saw a shack
with a couple of teenagers
poking their head out of the
door to see who we were.
It turned out that the
shantytown of [INAUDIBLE]
was yet another unauthorized
outpost.
The place isn't marked on any
map, but already it's been
demolished and rebuilt
a few times over.
These kids were without
any adult supervision.
They told me they've named the
place Strength of Zion.
Wow, it's really basic.
There's not even a floor.
It's just the grass here.
You've got holes in the roof.
It's rained today.
SIMON OSTROVSKY: This has
been totally incredible.
This is the freshest, most
radical outpost that we've
visited so far.
The crazy thing about it is
that the more you talk to
these guys, the more somebody
tells you that God has given
them this land, that there
is no two ways around it.
You start to believe them and
get to the point where you
think a peaceful settlement
is almost impossible.
With so many settlements being
built up on the future
territory of the Palestinian
state, you start to wonder if
Israel is working to make the
two-state solution a reality,
or if it's just telling the
international community what
it wants to hear.
The more Israelis move to the
West Bank, the less viable a
Palestinian state seems to be.
So the real question becomes
whether Palestinians will end
up citizens of a greater Israel
with equal rights or if
they face a permanent regime
of occupation.