TOMMY ANDRES, CNN ANCHOR: Hi, everyone, I`m
Tommy Andres. I`m a correspondent with CNN
Radio, but today, I am filling in for Carl
and hanging out with you for this Friday edition
of CNN STUDENT NEWS.
First up, news from the United Nations Security
Council. The group voted yesterday for stronger
punishments against North Korea. It is a reaction
to that country`s latest rocket launches and
nuclear tests. There has been a lot of tension
between North Korea and other countries over
its nuclear program, so that Security Council
vote may not seem surprising. What is interesting
is that it was unanimous. China, one of North
Korea`s strongest allies, voted in favor of
the punishments. These punishments are designed
to change a country`s potentially threatening
behavior. Sometimes they work. Other times,
they don`t really have much impact.
You may have heard about filibusters in social
studies class. We`ve talked about them before
on our show. They are a way for a U.S. senator
to block or delay a vote. On Wednesday, we
actually saw one. Here is what happened.
John Brennan is President Obama`s nominee
to run the CIA. But the Senate makes the final
call, and Brennan is a controversial pick
because of his connection to the use of drones.
He`s been an adviser to the president on homeland
security and counter-terrorism issues. He
is a big supporter of using unmanned aircraft.
The president has been criticized for his
position on drones, including the possibility
that they could be used to target Americans
who pose a threat to the United States. Senator
Rand Paul wants more answers about the president`s
drone policies. On Wednesday, he used a filibuster
to try and push for those answers.
The way it works is that when you get control
of the Senate floor, you don`t give it up.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
SEN. RAND PAUL, R-KY.: I rise today to begin
to filibuster John Brennan`s nomination for
the CIA. I will speak until I can no longer
speak. I will speak for as long as it takes.
Has America the beautiful become Alice`s Wonderland?
"No, no, said the queen, sentence first, verdict
afterwards. Stuff of nonsense, Alice said
loudly. The idea of having the sentence first?
Hold your tongue, said the queen, turning
purple. I won`t, said Alice. Release the drones,
said the queen, as she shouted at the top
of her voice." Lewis Carroll is fiction, right?
I have allowed the president to pick his political
appointees, but I will not sit quietly and
let him shred the Constitution. I cannot sit
at my desk quietly and let the president says
that he will kill Americans on American soil
who are not actively attacking the country.
Which has previously brought a challenge in
federal court, to the legality of the authorization
to target.
I would go for another 12 hours to try to
break Strom Thurmond`s record, but I`ve discovered
that there are some limits to filibustering,
and I`m going to have to go take care of one
of those in a few minutes here.
(LAUGHTER)
PAUL: I thank you very much for the forbearance,
and I yield the floor.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Mr. President.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Senator from Illinois.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
ANDRES: Senator Paul has gotten some support
and some criticism for his filibuster. He
also says he`s gotten a response from the
White House. Yesterday, John Brennan was confirmed
as the next CIA director.
Next up, authorities at this cat haven sanctuary
are going to investigate a tragic accident
that happened at a California facility. On
Wednesday, an intern who worked with the animals
there was mauled and killed by one of the
sanctuary`s African lions. It`s just one example
we`ve seen recently of the potential risks
when humans and creatures enter each other`s
habitats. When two park workers in Florida
accidentally disturbed a hive, they were swarmed
by tens of thousands of Africanized honey
bees. That species is very aggressive, especially
if bothered. The men were stung nearly 100
times each.
Thousands of sharks swimming offshore force
some South Florida beaches to close. Experts
say the sharks aren`t after people, but going
in the water means you`re entering their habitat,
and in a case of mistaken identity, if a shark
thinks the person is a smaller fish, could
lead to problems. And these iReport images
from Israel show things going in the opposite
direction. All those black specs, they are
locusts and they are migrating north in search
of food. And when they come across farmland,
areas where farmers are growing fruits and
vegetables, the insects can attack the crops
and leave them decimated.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Is this legit? The idea
for an International Women`s Day was suggested
at a conference in 1910. It`s true. One year
later, more than a million people went to
International Women`s Day rallies.
ANDRES: For 100 years, International Women`s
Day has been celebrated on March 8th, today.
The international celebration eventually led
to the creation of Women`s History Month in
the U.S. This year`s month-long theme is about
honoring women in STEM fields. We`re talking
about science, technology, engineering and
math. And women like these.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: When Jane Goodall was
22, she was invited to visit her friend`s
farm in Africa. When she arrived, she was
asked to study a group of chimpanzees. That`s
how she began a career of studying and writing
about chimps that`s helped the scientific
community learn tremendous amounts about the
behavior of these animals and about their
natural habitat.
As a child, May Jamieson loved to read about
science, especially astronomy. She went on
to earn a degree in chemical engineering and
become a medical doctor. But eventually, Jamieson
returned to her love of astronomy and applied
for the science program. On September 12,
1992, she flew aboard the Shuttle Endeavour
as the first African-American woman in space.
A book called "The Sands of Mars" inspired
Donna Lee Shirley`s curiosity about the Red
Planet. Shirley earned bachelor`s and masters
degrees in aerospace engineering and came
to the Jet Propulsion Laboratory in 1966 to
work on the first unmanned mission to Mars.
Thirty years later, she was managing the Mars
exploration program when the Pathfinder and
Sojourner rovers successfully explored the
Red Planet`s surface.
In the late `80s and early `90s, Danica McKellar
starred on the TV show, "The Wonder Years."
What many fans may not know is that McKellar
later graduated from UCLA with a degree in
mathematics. She even helped write a math
theorem that`s named for her. McKellar has
also written books about girls and math, saying
that she`s combining her love of entertainment
and math to make the subject more entertaining.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today`s Shoutout goes
out to Mrs. Slossom`s (ph) U.S. history classes
at Gennessee Valley (ph) Central school in
Belmont, New York. Which U.S. president moved
the start of daylight savings time from April
to March? Was it Lyndon Johnson, Ronald Reagan,
Bill Clinton or George W. Bush? You`ve got
3 seconds, go.
The
earlier start began in 2007 under President
George W. Bush. The reason was kind of the
same idea why daylight savings time originally
started. That`s your answer and that`s your
shoutout.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
CARL AZUZ, CNN ANCHOR: It puzzles the daylights
out of some people. Why have daylight savings
time if daylight is just going to get longer
anyway as the Northern Hemisphere approaches
summer? Well, for one thing, it`s the law.
Before 1966, states had different times and
dates for springing forward and falling back.
The Uniform Time Act was passed to get them
all synched up. But unlike many other laws,
if states don`t want to participate, they
don`t have to. Most of the state of Arizona,
as well as Hawaii, don`t. So if you go there,
they`ll tell you what time it is. The idea
is a lot older than the `60s, though. Ben
Franklin apparently had enough time on his
hands to propose saving daylight, and several
countries took him up on it. Well, they did
about 130 years later. World War I was on,
so daylight saving time was used to help save
electricity. With the sun up later, people
didn`t need to turn lights on until later.
It stopped nationally after the war, and stayed
that way until Congress got around to setting
times for it. But today, daylight saving time
is sleepy time for many Americans, especially
Monday morning after springing ahead. The
Better Sleep Council says people struggle
and slog around in bad moods. SleepBetter.org
says America loses hundreds of millions of
dollars because workers aren`t as productive
until they get used to it. They`re not saying
we should get rid of daylight saving time,
but this sheds light on why some sleepy people
might want to.
Carl Azuz, CNN, Atlanta.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
ANDRES: Before we go, we`re going to get in
a little snowboarding story. Bet you didn`t
think I meant this. That`s Eden Grace (ph)
on the board. When this video was shot, she
wasn`t even 2 years old. And this wasn`t even
close to her first time on a snowboard. Her
parents say she`s been going up the mountain
since she was six weeks old. She learned to
shred before she could walk. If she`s already
this talented at 2, by the time she gets older,
there`s snow telling how good she`ll be.
Time for us to pack it in. Remember to set
your clocks ahead this weekend, and teachers,
remember to share your feedback about today`s
show on our home page. I`m Tommy Andres. Have
a great weekend.