JACOB SOBOROFF: The
conflict in Ukraine
took a dramatic turn
over the weekend
when Russian President
Vladimir Putin stationed
more than 16,000 troops in
Ukraine's Crimean peninsula.
The biggest video in Russia
today is this footage right
here from the ground
in Sevastopol.
The armed troops that
you're seeing are Russian,
and they're demanding
that the guy
on the right, the Ukrainian
officer, turn over his weapons.
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
JACOB SOBOROFF: To
keep us up to date
on what's a very
dangerous situation,
Vice News is posting
dispatches from Ukraine,
including this one from inside
a military base in Crimea.
REPORTER: So we just came over
the wall of the Ukrainian Naval
base.
They've put these
desks everywhere
to make it harder for
people to move through.
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
JACOB SOBOROFF: You can see more
of Simon's continuing coverage
over at Vice News.
And if you want to
get up to speed,
we put together a playlist
for you after the show.
Something we've been
keeping our eye on.
ALEX: Ever been on a
date where the person
doesn't realize it's a date?
It's nowhere near
as fun as this.
Stuart Edge teamed up with
musician Tiffany Albert
and magician Jarek 120
to surprise strangers
near the Santa Monica Pier.
MAN: Oh.
Man, am I starving.
GUY: So, you want to
get married, then?
GIRL: I've kinda bee just
looking for the right guy.
And once he comes along,
why wait, you know?
ALEX: Stuart's been
doing feel-good pranks
like this for a year and a half.
This was just posted and has
almost two million views!
JACOB SOBOROFF: If
there's anything sweeter
than a little old lady,
it's a little old lady
with a heart of gold.
Evelyn's a determined
98-year-old woman
who got her driver's
license back
just so she could
help a friend in need.
EVELYN: She said to me, Well,
if they don't get another bus,
they'll find another
place for me to live.
And she says, I just don't
want to go anywhere else.
I said, Joyce, I'll get you to
the grocery store every week.
JACOB SOBOROFF: Thanks,
Evelyn, for reminding us
that we can never be
too old to be generous.
You guys should check out
some more great videos from I
Like Giving.
And in the meantime, I'm
going to go call my Nana.
NINA: Hey, guys.
I'm Nina Terrero from
Entertainment Weekly.
You know that saying,
I wouldn't date you
unless you were the
last person on earth?
Well, meet my new obsession.
A new web series that put
that saying to the test.
"Bad Timing" centers
around a super dorky IT guy
and the hot girl of his
dreams, thrown together
during the zombie apocalypse.
GIRL: Aaaaah!
GUY: Shh, there
could be zombies!
[KISSING SOUNDS]
I can't breathe,
I can't breathe!
No, no, no, that's a good thing!
NINA: I couldn't
be more excited,
because episode four
officially drops today.
And for more of the
best series on the web,
check out a special video
we made just for you.
The link is the description.
JACOB SOBOROFF:
Casablanca is widely
considered one of the
greatest movies ever made.
But just in case the movie
flopped during testing,
the studio made an
alternate version
and it just hit the internet.
That is the premise behind
PistolShrimps newest video,
which introduces us
to Casablancbot 3,000,
the love interest
Rick might have had.
RICK: Here's
looking at you, kid.
ROBOT: Syntax error.
I do not understand
that sentence.
JACOB SOBOROFF: The two
buddies behind this channel
met in college.
All they want to do was
make absurd videos that
ask questions of famous films.
Like, what if everybody
in The Hobbit had tattoos?
HOBBIT: I really don't think
you should get that butterfly
tattoo on your lower back.
SARUMAN: Always you must meddle.
HOBBIT: It looks
trashy, I think.
SARUMAN: That's absurd.
HOBBIT: Gandalf called
it a tramp stamp.
SARUMAN: He's a foolish fellow.
JACOB SOBOROFF: These guys
have been making awesome videos
since 2008.
They've got over
100 million views.
Hit subscribe right now, go
catch up on all their stuff.
This next video was
sent us via Twitter
using the hashtag
#youtubenation.
A mother filmed her
seven-year-old son
with Asperger's
playing with Sophie
the Sea Lion at the
Smithsonian National Zoo.
And it is awesome.
BOY: Alex, run back and forth.
Go!
Go, go, go!
[GLEEFUL LAUGHTER]
MOTHER: Zachary, come over here.
JACOB SOBOROFF: We want to know
what you guys are watching.
Film yourself
talking about a video
you love, and then post it with
the hashtag #youtubenation.
Now, play us out, Dan Kroll.
[MUSIC - DAN KROLL, "FROM
NOWHERE"]