That creature is us.
All over the world we still use our
ingenuity to survive in the wild places,
far from the city lights,
face to face with raw nature.
This is the Human Planet.
The jungle is nature at its most vigorous,
complex and mysterious.
It may appear bountiful,
but for humans, this is a surprisingly
hostile environment.
Though, through history,
great civilisations have arisen here,
none have stood the test of time.
The jungle refuses to be tamed
and it punishes those
who don't live by its laws.
Yet even today, there are some
who guard the secrets
of surviving in this wild world.
These are the remarkable stories
of the people who call
the rainforest home.
Tropical rainforests coverjust
2% of the planet's surface...
...but they're home to half
of all species on Earth.
The problem is, much of this life
is in the tree-tops,
a world way out of our reach.
Exploiting the canopy's riches from
the forest floor is so challenging,
getting enough protein
is a daily struggle.
The
Matis of Brazil
are highly skilled hunters
but for the past week there's been
barely enough meat to go round.
Benin is hungry and he's determined
today's hunt will be more successful.
Administering tree-frog toxin into
his bloodstream purges his body,
preparing it for action.
The
Matis also drop a noxious
plant juice into their eyes
to sharpen their senses
and focus their minds on the hunt.
Benin and the others summon
the power of the animal spirits.
Hunting canopy animals
from the ground
requires formidable fire power...
...a four-metre long blowpipe,
precision-made to a design
honed over thousands
of years.
Spotting animals in the dense
vegetation is so hard
the Matis rely on hearing
to locate prey...
...and use mimicry to lure them
into range.
They can imitate all ten species of
monkey found in these forests.
(IMITATES MONKEY CALL)
(MONKEY CRIES)
A howler monkey responds.
30 metres up,
monkeys are feeding in a fig tree.
Scoring the darts with piranha teeth
ensures the poisoned tip breaks off
in the victim's body.
Unlike guns, blowpipes are near silent
and can be fired
without spooking the monkeys.
Benin makes the first hit,
and now the monkeys scatter.
Once shot, the monkeys
must be tracked
as the curare-vine poison takes effect.
This monkey's already weak,
but it's hiding, and must be flushed out.
They shoot again.
But it's stuck in a vine now, and
there's no choice but to go and get it.
One down, but it's just the beginning.
As one of the swiftest hunters,
it's Benin's job to pick off
any escaping monkeys.
He shoots another, but misses.
Benin fires again, this time on target.
The monkey finally stops...
...and Benin takes aim one last time.
Eight monkeys. It's been a good day.
But all too often
they return empty-handed.
Hunting in the canopy is so difficult,
people must find most of their food
closer to the ground.
But scratching a living
on the forest floor is hardly any easier.
The complex nature of this mysterious
world is so hard to master,
the lessons have to start early.
Orlando's from the Piaroa tribe
of Venezuela.
He's like any other kid,
only life in the jungle has already
forced him to fend for himself.
But this childhood adventure takes
them deep into the jungle underworld.
As only 2% of sunlight
reaches the forest floor,
surprisingly few plants grow
and this means few animals.
There's less protein here
than in the desert...
and much that is here is poisonous.
Distinguishing dinner from danger
is an essential life skill.
Few creatures have a more sinister
reputation than the one they seek.
The goliath tarantula,
the size of a dinner plate,
the largest spider in the world.
It's hard to imagine
a less appetising meal,
but picky eaters don't last long
in the jungle.
Besides, Orlando says
they're delicious,
and handling dangerous animals
comes with the territory.
From about five years old,
Piaroa children know exactly
where to hunt for spiders...
...and in a couple of hours
can catch enough for a decent meal.
But they have to be careful
of both the huge fangs
and of the hairs they kick
towards any attacker.
If they contact the skin or are inhaled,
they cause a nasty reaction.
Orlando's come off worst.
But growing up in the jungle,
he's used to a little discomfort.
Tarantulas are best served toasted,
like marshmallows.
All the hairs must be singed off
so they don't catch in the throat.
And when they start squeaking,
which is just air escaping from
the joints, they're almost done.
Tarantulas taste a bit like crab
and, with a little seasoning,
they go down a treat.
Orlando's and his friends'survival
depends upon embracing
every opportunity in the forest
Jungle people rely so heavily
on their surroundings,
they become a natural part
of the forest
and form extraordinary bonds
with nature.
Very few people live more intimately
with animals than the Awa Guaja
of the eastern Amazon.
Nurturing a wide range of creatures
from the forest,
the Awa are obsessive pet keepers.
And there are some animals
they cherish above any others.
Like the Matis, hunting monkeys
is vital to the Awa's survival,
providing nearly half their protein.
But this relationship
provides far more than food.