BENNY SOLIS: Florence
was cool.
I saw some pretty historical
stuff and it was really nice.
I actually got to see the world
famous statue of that
one guy, and then I saw
this big church.
I never thought I would
be good enough in
racing to be here.
Well, I'm not thinking about
the race right now.
I'm kind of enjoying what I'm
looking at, but yeah, it's
always in the back of my mind.
But I'm just hoping
for the best now.
[JAZZY MUSIC PLAYS]
STURLA FAGERHAUG: This
is where we're at.
Roggello, Italy.
It's going to be intense.
For the next couple of days, I
think it's going to be a big
ass party around here.
That's what it usually
is here.
KEVIN SCHWANTZ: This is not an
easy place to figure out.
It's difficult.
Lot's of elevation changes.
Lots of different things are
going on that'll make the bike
work really good in one corner,
and the next corner
it's going to seem like--
because it's downhill-- you're
falling away.
It's an easy place to make a
simple mistake, end up running
off the track and
tipping over.
Take your time, find some good
reference points, have fun.
BENNY SOLIS: I mean, everyone's
fast, from first to
the last, they're all
just real fast.
I guess everyone's
competition here.
I want to get top 5 this time.
And I know it'll be hard 'cause
I don't know the track,
but even if I have to lay a bike
down, I want to do what I
have to just to stay in
the first 2 rows.
BEN SOLIS: Sometimes I get
frustrated, 'cause I don't
know what's going on.
Why is he going that slow?
Because I know he can run up
front, but when he's having a
problem, I don't know,
what is it?
BENNY SOLIS: Sometimes
I'm just not into it.
But he tells me I have to be if
I want to be up here doing
what I want.
Jake's over here, and
then he's doing it,
he's getting it done.
KEVIN SCHWANTZ: You're at
Mugello, MotoGP teams are
here, 100,000 fans sitting
on the hillside.
That in itself is
enough pressure.
And a lot of times, the parents
are adding pressure.
Benny Solis, Jake Gagne, Hayden
Gillim, those kids have
their dads here working
on the bike.
It's a certain situation where
the family's been doing their
best to try and get this kid
into a road racing career and
trying to push them along
and help them.
It's kind of make it
or break it time.
MARC GAGNE: Our whole goal is
to stay up, and get points,
and be consistent, and not
to throw the bike away.
You can't do anything on the
ground, you can't win on the
ground, you can't score
points on the ground.
JAKE GAGNE: Having
my dad here--
it's good.
He pushes me a little bit harder
and he knows how to
work on bikes really good.
I like having my dad
here, he's good.
MARC GAGNE: The old days of
daddy and going racing are
kind of over.
Now it's just make sure you get
me there, Dad, I'll take
it from there.
HAYDEN GILLIM: It's easier to
give feedback to him about
what the bike is doing because
we've been racing and working
on bikes together for
8 years, now.
And he's just a really
big help 'cause,
well, he's my dad.
FRANKIE GILLIM: Usually he's
always been real loose and
doesn't really get stressed,
or anything like that.
This year, I don't know
if he is or not.
I just try and make him laugh.
STURLA FAGERHAUG: My dad just,
he usually just says good luck
and stuff before the race.
It's not like he's out there
saying, you have to finish the
race, you have to win this
one, and all that--
think of the championship--
like that stuff.
He just says good luck
and do your best.
OISTEIN FAGERHAUG: A lot of
parents interfere a lot and
tell them do this, do
this, do this--
GURO FAGERHAUG: Yeah,
I know that.
OISTEIN FAGERHAUG: --and get
angry if they crash, and it's
not like that.
KEVIN SCHWANTZ: Whether it's
your father, or whether it's
somebody who's really close to
you, they can be your biggest
supporter at times, but they
can also be your biggest
critic, especially if the kid
has a struggle out there and
maybe has a rough weekend, and
then dad's sitting there, arms
crossed, kind of
looking at you.
BENNY SOLIS: I'm nervous.
I'm always nervous.
DANNY WALKER: One of his
talents, and a natural thing
for him is he's about
as calm as can be.
I'm nervous as get out, I can't
hardly stand still, and
he's over there taking his sweet
time, getting dressed.
What, I still got 15 minutes.
Like it's a day or two.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[MOTORCYCLE ENGINES REVVING]
PETER CLIFFORD: The light,
red lights go out.
Disaster from Fagerhaug, total
disaster from the cup leader.
Well, his practice start wasn't
any good to him at all,
because that's made an absolute
nonsense of him.
[MOTORCYCLE ENGINES]
BEN SOLIS: Basically letting
know Benny his position, what
lap times, and that way he
can see what's going on.
[MOTORCYCLE ENGINES]
PETER CLIFFORD: Back to red
helmet of Sturla Fagerhaug.
He's now up into 13th, he'll
still see that he's got a
chance of getting with the
front runners here.
[MOTORCYCLE ENGINES]
PETER CLIFFORD: 5 abreast across
the start and finish
line for the rookies, and
Fagerhaug is there with the
red helmet.
Pick out #33, Fagerhaug.
It's right there now.
He's on the left hand side.
He's up into third place.
Is he going go for second?
He looks at second.
He doesn't, he backs
out of it.
Kornfeil comes around
the outside.
[MOTORCYCLE ENGINES]
PETER CLIFFORD: Fagerhaug
has the advantage.
Now Kornfeil is traveling behind
him, and really work
with the Norwegian, and
try and get away from
the rest of the pack.
PETER CLIFFORD: Jake Gagne,
still with that third place,
and if anything he has
closed that gap.
He certainly opened
up the advantage.
MARC GAGNE: He's staying smooth
and he's got fastest
lap right now, so--
-How you feeling?
MARC GAGNE: Nervous as
heck, but all right.
It's all good.
It's hard to have as much fun
as I'm having right now.
PETER CLIFFORD: There's 2 men
down, and I didn't say the
falling so I'm not
sure who that is.
It's too focused, and
unfortunately Jake Gagne
walking back.
MARC GAGNE: And he went
down up there,
and so he was walking.
They show them on the camera.
He was pushing, trying
to run up there.
It's difficult to do.
Never been here, so, maybe he
pushed a little too hard.
He'll be fine.
It's time to go to
the next one.
And now he knows he can run with
these guys, so I would
say look out.
PETER CLIFFORD: Weaving across
the track to spoil a
slipstream, it's Sturla
Fagerhaug, and he's
going to take it.
Yes, Sturla Fagerhaug takes
his second victory of the
Rookies Cup season.
[SPEAKING NORWEGIAN]
[BAND PLAYS]
GURO FAGERHAUG: Congratulations.
STURLA FAGERHAUG: Thanks.
JAKE GAGNE: I've had 2 broken
wrists, a broken collarbone,
broken toes, broken heel,
and then just got
knocked out a few times.
They're all really painful.
Breaking bones never feels
good, but you've got
to deal with it.
HAYDEN GILLIM: The crashes
that I know I'm
going to hurt myself--
like whenever I broke my
collarbone, that crash
whenever I high sided--
the 3 or 4 corners before I
crashed, it just felt like I
was dreaming.
And then whenever I crashed, it
didn't even feel like I was
the one crashing.
MARC GAGNE: I love seeing
a good crash.
I mean-- not necessarily
motorcycles--
cars, anything.
As long as they walk away.
Nobody likes to see
anybody get hurt.
But, sure.
Crashing is part of the aura
of racing, and when crashes
occur, it's usually because
somebody's pushing the limit,
and you're going just a little
bit over the edge.
And usually that's
very, very fast.
JAKE GAGNE: If you race
motorcycles you've got to
expect you're going to crash
sooner or later.
You've just got to accept it,
try not to think about it.
Sometimes it can be bad,
sometimes you can walk away
and not even feel anything.
Just depends how it is.
But you just got to learn
to accept it.
KEVIN SCHWANTZ: I think the
certain amount of danger, some
guys are willing to take that
risk a little bit more than
the other, and that's those
guys that can push the
envelope, recover from it, and
still go back there time and
time again.
JEREMY APPLETON: While
motorcycle racing is still a
dangerous activity there are
less broken limbs compared
with what their used to be,
partly because we've built
technology into the suits and
the equipment which aims to
keep riders sliding during the
course of an accident, so
dissipating energy during the
course of an accident.
There are certain accidents
where, inevitably, limbs or
bones get broken because of
the sheer forces involved.
But generally speaking, riders
these days are less prone to
the sort of injuries they
occur through violent,
uncontrolled crashes.
PETER CLIFFORD: A decade or 2
ago, the sport was a lot more
individual then, and a
lot more dangerous.
Now it's more of a team sport.
The team that you ride for and
the people around you matter
more, and it's a lot less
dangerous than it used to be.
You've got to be unlucky to get
very seriously hurt now,
and terribly unlucky
to get killed.
MARC GAGNE: You've got people
out there that are doing
something that 1 millionth
of the population
could possibly do.
Me being on the edge of my
seat, my heart racing--
I mean, I can't go
do it anymore.
But I can definitely get that
feeling by watching it,
especially when you know
somebody or, in my case, I'm
lucky enough to have my
son that does it.