[INTERPOSING VOICES]
FRANKIE GILLIM: Most of the
kids' real close friends were,
I mean, their best friends
were racers.
HAYDEN GILLIM: This race, me
and Mathew qualified crap.
Together, he qualified 19th,
I qualified 22nd.
MATHEW SCHOLTZ: I mean, we all
come out to race, so we all
love the same thing.
So everything's good.
We're all mates.
HAYDEN GILLIM: Him and Sturla
and Jake, we're all buds and
we're all pretty close
off the track.
And we can all cheer each other
up and make jokes and
everything all day long, and
then once we get onto the
racetrack, we're kind
of like a team.
HAYDEN GILLIM: As
in, Pen Islands?
MATHEW SCHOLTZ: Pen Islands.
[SPEAKING JAPANESE]
MARC GAGNE: He's not here
to make friends.
He's said that for years.
I don't come to races
to make friends.
I can make friends any time.
I come here to do my job
and try to win a race.
So considering where we are, we
don't know the tracks, we
know very few people over
here, we don't know the
language, so he's got to grasp
every little bit of
information he can gather and
then try to apply it in a very
short amount of time.
PETER CLIFFORD: The Rookies
Cup is simple and all race
weekends are pretty
much the same.
We start with a free
non-qualifying session, where
the guys can just go out, get
the feel of the bike.
And then we have two qualifying
periods, both half
an hour each, and it's their
best lap time from either of
those two sessions that gives
them their grid position.
HAYDEN GILLIM: I went faster, I
don't know if I did better.
As soon as my dad gets in
here, he'll tell me.
JAKE GAGNE: Felt pretty good.
The bike was working good.
It was a bit windy.
I think I ended up sixth on the
grid for tomorrow's race
so I'm happy.
Hayden Gillim was 22nd and
Benny Solis was 23rd.
BENNY SOLIS: I don't know,
Jake's been doing really good.
But I feel like I should be up
there with him. 'Cause last
year, I was always with him.
Most of the time, I was in
front, and towards the end he
was right there with me.
HAYDEN GILLIM: Last year I raced
some of these guys, and
I was up front with them, and
then this year just haven't
been able to get the bike put
together, and haven't been
able to put together
any results.
And I've only got, like, 10
points out of possible 75.
KEVIN SCHWANTZ: One of the most
difficult things as a
rider is coming here and trying
to stay focused without
getting frustrated
with yourself.
You look at your lap time,
you're 2 seconds or 3 seconds
behind the leaders, that seems
like an eternity as a rider.
You're working with 13-
to 16-year-old kids.
It's another scenario that
throws a big curve ball into
everything, 'cause some kids
mentally are really strong,
and some kids, just the
slightest little excuse they
can think of, then their
attitude goes out the window
and their focus is gone and they
don't even really want to
go riding anymore.
DANNY WALKER: You don't
make excuses.
Everybody from second
on down has excuses
on why I'm not winning.
First guy, you got none.
I'm good.
From second, oh I've got
a ton of excuses
on why I'm not there.
But Hayden realistically
is just too
big, he grew too much.
FRANKIE GILLIM: At 125, it's
about like in America.
You've got to be jockey size.
And Hayden's not a jockey.
They know he has ability from
last year, and AMA, and then
when he came over here during
the rider's club.
He had the pole at Valencia.
GUSTL AUINGER: It's very
hard for the boys.
I can understand this
very much because
they want to win races.
But every result have
some reason.
FRANKIE GILLIM: The only thing
I ever really say to him
before a race is that I love
him, and to go have fun.
Fire it up.
[MOTORCYCLE ENGINES REVVING]
PETER CLIFFORD: So Fagerhaug
goes for the lead.
Beautiful move from
the [INAUDIBLE].
And absolutely superb stuff,
totally unhurried.
Just slides past there.
That [INAUDIBLE]
coming down to the
[INAUDIBLE].
It's Fagerhaug that leads,
it's Marino that
is in second place.
Absolutely superb stuff.
There's what?
There's eight, 10 guys there
crossing the line together.
And this time it's Gagne that
leads from Kent, Fagerhaug,
Marino, Kristiansson, Hiura,
Hook, and Kornfeil.
Fagerhaug is making
his escape.
He started the lap with 8/10
of a second advantage.
It's already, I think, gone
out of effect, and once it
gets past a second, it is really
hard to pull back.
Kornfeil goes up the
inside of Gagne.
But the advantage now
that Fagerhaug has
over Kent is 1 second.
Fagerhaug thrashes
across the line.
Well, what an absolutely
superb race.
And there is Daijiro
Hiura, the Japanese
who finished second.
Brilliant ride from him.
And what a good ride
from Jake Gagne.
MARC GAGNE: He just
did well, man.
He's running right where he
should be, led for a few laps,
so he did awesome, more
than I could expect.
JAKE GAGNE: Towards the
end, it came down
just to the last corner.
And I just made some mistakes in
the middle of the race, and
it kind of caught me, but happy
to be on the podium.
PETER CLIFFORD: Daijiro
Hiura in second place.
[BAND PLAYING]
DAIJIRO HIURA: Yes.
Maybe shoes.
Second.
Yes.
Thank you.
DANNY WALKER: Seen so many
parents where the kid's not
having a good day and they
jump on them and they're
yelling at them.
I'm like, dude, there's guys
making $2, $3, $4 million a
year that have bad days.
Have you never, as
a professional,
ever had a bad day?
If he doesn't have that inner,
burning, driving desire to
pass the guy or be better or
go faster, then you can't
develop that.
FRANKIE GILLIM: 12th.
You did good.
We dropped, again.
HAYDEN GILLIM: I was braking,
then, like, 30 seconds later,
they brake and just freaking
hit everybody
and run off the track.
And then, freaking, they
wouldn't slow down.
Finished 12th, so it was OK.
It wasn't amazing, but starting
from 22nd it was
pretty good.
For some reason, I am horrible
in qualifying and then come
back and get OK positions.
FRANKIE GILLIM: We're just a
day late and a dollar short
every time so far.
We just gotta get up
to pace quicker.
This'll be the last time
you'll see me.
-Really?
FRANKIE GILLIM: I'm out.
I don't have no time
left to get off.
-That was good stuff.
FRANKIE GILLIM: Yeah, it was.
I mean, We improved
a whole bunch.
-Hot out there.
MARC GAGNE: It's not about the
money or the fame necessarily.
In my eyes, and I'm sure his,
it's about going and doing the
best you possibly can.
And if the best you can takes
you to the top, then more
power to you 'cause you
did a great job.
You know, as a dad, I knew he
could be there all the time,
so I say hail to
the Americans.
Podium--
it's all good.
HAYDEN GILLIM: At first it was
just about having fun, and
travel around the world, and
make lot of friends.
Now it's gotten more about money
and everything else.
But I try and focus on
just having fun.
FRANKIE GILLIM: I guess this
year, he's having to persevere
through struggling
on the bike.
He's never had to before.
It's always been natural.
And here, natural ability's only
going to get you so far.
And then from there, you've
got to have knowledge,
maturity in what you're
trying to do.
On the track, off the track, try
to put it all together to
become one whole.