things they've done
and between differently
the million pound chandelier
she's eight hundred unique pieces that
have to be individually hand cleaned
tuesday night
caltech matriz a guy who used to get one
of the few places probably convene on
impulse
in an age of austerity
some gangsta prepared to pay the price
of the small family car
spent one night
state doing it in jewelry lutz
it's six thousand nine hundred dollars
guidelines
grant first-time long history claridge's
is allowed cameras behind its do with
them
we spent enough to resolve stands and
downstairs
following the staff as they provide
luxury too discreet annex casey see in
town
services contracts out every bit
backstop of biking artists
how does tomorrow he's making
with that they're expecting
it's not a blind date
c_a_c_ stay
condemn aunt impeccable attention to
detail
and style you go to enormous lengths to
please
christina regions we might think they're
outrageous spirit
we want to know
good morning claridge's how may i help
you
use your taking the rust ras
yes that's going to be from saint
pancras station sir
offered for the taxing on the character
of the concierge they don't accurate
estimate for him
like so much
notice i didn't say i don't know
polyester yet but that's it you know
that's the uh...
you
never let them hear you sweat
uh... one moment please is great slip
you find out for you
and
wildly
most wonderful tools that we have here
in claridge's but not everyone who
really knows
is called google
and google will answer everything
so we've seen linking uses up here but
worldwide are just typing into google
good morning claridge's how may i have
you
tools to be needing to get stayed the
same species claridge's stylistic
elements nineteen eighteen fifty four
board trains do what you think the
comings and goings you know me
fame street flooding killing tearing up
the hotel has two miles of going to
listen four hundred staffed
unsaid savers thousand helps
and sixty-three
ranji have pics
dot on dot the
because the lobby
embraces everything that has to stop
this
here you know that's the camera that's
the beauty of creating new you can't
feel it when you walked through the
reporting to us that you were entering a
very very special case
at the helm of history british
institutions is forty one-year-old
thomas call
he's the youngest general manager in
hotels history
call mister bosco at mister clinton also
have a very regular visits her family or
surviving coming to the was there for
many years and i really really the
eighty eight deaths so far
they spent a week in paris
so so they have lots of interesting so
it's just that
alone are u
realistically it was a joke
it
quarters lover i know we have to follow
up for you of course uh...
denny's fascinate
is an american designer
the u_n_
it's the second g_o_p_ honestly today
my favorite
david good to get the that account
the piano street cost five thousand one
hundred pounds in ninety and comes with
its own private arkla on cool twenty
four hours a day
to pander every week
okay
well what i would say employees in
philadelphia at noon
what strikes you about this rain when
you come in
you feel like you've stepped back a
little bit like you're in some
following the english
mentioned in the middle of live did it's
beautifully matched
and beautifully done
but it's not force
you have order modern conveniences
cereal to press the button and have the
public come
reach the concierge is the perfect
example
this is clearly the most modern element
to have that instant
espresso
your industry ditional environment and i
think that's
which really
has made this
something quite unique
since pretty special at me and i think
the best of the people com
the best when i say that i mean
the people who
who problems
foreign wobbled this is an exceptionally
large salome he led a field and
that luxury some people to call thing to
celebrate in these times
there's always going to be
luxury
yaar maladies
comes from the island of medium andy's
keeper of the last man operated linked
in london
transporting tragic in class
withdrawing
i received your guests
dreadful toothpastes
in saying this is the best lived in the
world in every single one lived like
this
underneath that
cut the both at this school this is very
nice cool
possess hundred fifteen years old
these beautiful
the queen of spying
indian here last week
the imperative option i know
you've been couple months ago
indian did pull cruise you've been in
this spot because you like to be here
different of this new
mode or not
in like to see tobin displace over here
and uh... do you know that the other
people's really enjoyed this
or
pizza delicate business address in the
united tests
every morning thomas sits down to compel
use the welcome cards
the car crying sessions with kristy
always a big difference
carrot
this weekend snow distinct coming tonics
schools are not the cards because
forgetful
coca-cola
slow fifty-three skeptic
had been an athlete
bandits
and and ask for witchcraft
you too
today is intended to you
sakta chapman xd
expected to begin with
timeframe for when the first and join
the q
who warns written
yes it is
we highways and liza minelli always
everything could be coming to you right
diya aaj
packardbell
and there are really
fifteen the all he and idon't what you
may still be a sc
delivery next email
someone needs to be the gunmen off or
not
it's you know someone needs to happen
the debate over helicopter view you can
not to conduct a will construct
deletions to move
really holding on to you
he wants to do with this
do you find it and using that anyone
says it's in
british
and japan and germany sought to find it
in using its time for them
but but but it's you know it's it's it's
good to see things so that
and sometimes it is a humorous aswell
that's why i don't find it challenging
to to represent a british brad
to them
but yet you know catches the indecency
english what had happened and i'm german
and i can't change that and sent him
doesn't mind anybody
the lamps if you know if you have a
broken lamp
patients to shake
cable is shaking each issue the nuances
i'm sure she shakes transition technical
services which we just
on itself
deputy head of housekeeping and bombs is
one of the few innovation and assist off
she executed joked with obsessive
attention to detail
itself
the best
the flowers
flowers at that time
bomb in a classroom
thought like both missing why has the
same time
simon
they're going to have a closer look at
some of these the same one our heads
the content of your phone calls
commission on civil rights law
he seemed to us
doesn't hurt and send comments
rancorous storage the presents and
happen here
new york
testified
quest colosio list again inside the
backing out because they have them
we had a case that once guests at the
top and he left a lot of money that back
which was just folded slave
and then the next guest who tapped into
the room
to find the money
how's it
it was a lot of the last couple of
thousand pounds
there also have to him and i think for
the future
so that's why
a lawless taking in technology i think
if there they go they found out
they find a lot of money money now
sometimes isn't is lost in a safe
if the guest is not asking flooded
i think is for six months alec
yep the money
they just look at it
yet can be a lot of mine i think it
depends on
undivided
i don't know what i thought oh my god
that's just about two thousand dollars
things like that
that's what's left of the message
and you like this at home
talk
www not stall not its fault
not every dog is left behind
sammy the spaniel has dated the twenty
times at the hotel
minutes concession to come
you walk straight up to do and puts his
new sentences
this is it
sometimes i'd recommend luggage of would
indigestion entered the room
there there was asked
me semi comming to
and then a protected so tell for him in
the total
indices his international concern
and sometimes it takes a long time to
check in a long time to check etc
concedes if you could you see busy
talking to send
the checkout
sammy's truly feared a water bottle
a put into storage
awaiting his next easy
before we can start to send this to get
on with the palestinians and one like
this enough for me that
having to pressure you to do is tell
needs a just get me entertained
medicines didn't state taxes he says
and a happy thank you very much and i'm
quite happy to stay another night school
hole
jewish mummy
was my mistake
with simpson
resend
and to do everything they could get
uninteresting introduced i cannot see
newt week s
how would you if you think you might
can't see it
do whatever she says they want
me too
frustrations weakened state
through my mates three one six
three to one claridge's has eighty three
thousand guests here
as well as mister clinton nine two oh
two
the hotel is used to dealing with people
who demand a whole lot more mistake
final stop
in three days time
they're expecting the arrival of forum
royalty who want to all-time entire
federal
the opposing alot of monies they had a
child extension
level textiles at six o'clock at
presumed security will be on the same
for the post and in
as this room just add really make sure
that we take all the alcoholic products
item
from us and one
fortunate students hope personally and
studio
the whole school will be taken over by
twenty seven
email guests with their women and a
security guard
but many men will be allowed to set for
that
we have to armies
line all these people are still was
cepeda constant
remaking very very soft
barnett banks they
she wants very very soft bat
salvia within their extending the east
park and
video game
there are forty mins on the fentanyl
ten have to be cleared of or funny cute
creates faced the private dressing
renews and dining dreams
so all of us also the fact that
the opening that when it was also on the
whole floor
sin and death of vince gill and mom
peaks and com
they can do that to happen
the other patrons will be turned into
kitchens
we completely cover the contents and
then they will lay
banking tables away around the room
and searches
and sand in the first seven distance
from the senate population
surfaces
to entice weeks will be used just a
story shopping bag
presentation must be perfect
all scuffs attached dot
dripping taps fixed
ethicist investors actually ramsey are
from the top
one-party
is renowned
dot
fucked up
as long as i said about
however
the guests have yet to confirm that
booking
yes
all things
possibly travel travel plans changed
visit london is a paris
physically be the u_s_ or for the arts
maybe they thought they might go skiing
they might go to the skiing resort
you know the schedule itself
peters lives are very very demanding and
very busy
we we have to set them out of our top
tokens they probably have every
intention to stay here on wednesday and
then the date changes team on strange
different plane
different demand for a different city
and they arrive from thursday or a week
later on in the year we deal with it all
the time
sold for one room that's of course
slightly different in comparison to a
hotel
it's taken two days to transform the
third floor into temp requirements
still the booking has not been confirmed
all is well
related to the issue
the royal family finally in my next two
days behind schedule
hadn't met
uh... highness quickly i have too much
now
haven't been to a boom i haven't seen
and i haven't
spoken to are heads in exchange
so it's really not unusual for a ham
form for me not to see certain death one
would think would want
with more than eleven thousand five-star
luxury rooms in london
claridge's faces stiff competition
thomas names he needs to keep attracting
the likes of the guests currently
occupying the third floor
how can people understand
how big a business
para kisi it's the easiest or a relative
he know that all of course companies and
corporations in this world that probably
and turned over more revenue with four
hundred twenty people and then other
such hanover nestle carriages
it's it's it's it's a fifty eight
million pounds
business and and all of a
times
and that is as yet and is there
on mute increase in revenue every year
but yes again you can call the press or
you can
you know i'm probably the one to ask for
more
installed it's what you do to yourself
and uh... it it wouldn't be
it wouldn't be a hefty budget if you
said like you know it was amazing what
we did last year let's just do the same
he would always want to do anything to
do
better integrated more
more than a third of claridge's gets it
from the united states
a couple times a year thomas travels to
new york sumit the most influential
american travel agent
which is really very very important that
the general manager school once or twice
a year uncensored
there's nothing more valuable than
personal contact and that's really
that's really why i'm here
simulink and manages and other details
in line for weeks torches doesn't simply
come outside
known to you
country she's seventy two
fast start
issue travel
father and daughter dylan stacy
croft ultra luxury experiences
fantasy coverage they can be found on
the internet
and you can any get their number my pain
joining fee
recharge honors housing dollars to
become a colleague
and twenty five thousand dollars a year
to stay on as the clinton mass before
you've even made a phone call from the
halloween well it will make one welfare
left
left is a fishing story like colombian
like efficient she wanted a is good
to fish too and they were in africa
we want to make sure she said i want to
make sure eight ke catches a fish
so we had a habit higher frogman
to go do wanted
to put a fish
uh... the hook
he could have fish
but we still had a paper the frogman
he has a heart attack
i'll come back to your itinerary module
with a new yellow hepatitis doing where
london london this is element is like
new york community orchestra
powerful cost less than a positive but
then of course when you meet the press
in when you will see what's going on i
mean that is really a reality it doesn't
quite reflects yahoo out this depressed
that they really don't decide to climb
kicks ass through yeah that's true in a
addresses you know the prez
if they stay in a romance that they are
a technique
talented
that outstanding
thousand and two five or whatever
that's the difference does a
mariel you know that they do say it
saturday realm
discourages and not think certain people
too
it's not a
for everybody at you know they don't
like
baby update us good
who works at the end of the more
contemporary love more money in the next
time
for everybody and yet the smaller
yanmar boutique
how do you ever had to and
clients requesting reams redecorated
overcrowded
and in fact on the day of the baby
you know that one
felt like the color scheme of the ruler
like
so they're going to do it and then
and of course judge imported milna
you know they leave but it back to what
it is
and it mine pain
that if there is important
yet again hot here are my family saying
comments is nestled duty
he knows what's going on in claridge's
even when he's on the other side of the
atlantic
does anything anything happening in
haiti at once
the pretty straightforward
thank you
chincoteague
marriages they sometimes think
you must have thing to happen it just
makes my law
main grain military human-like in the
running of the box and
and sandhogs and how often to boston
everyone
and of course you know the way out of
something that
prep school
building new mobile no
so when that happens and you see how he
will continue unicode
musicians middle-aged women who come
here
meanings and maintenance mangement
do wrong stars can you have any it would
come up with all of you
that will be making threatening
heartbreaking today but last day with
the information to the clean up the
little but but but but
minimal that very well-behaved dogs dont
platitudes rocks dot as a group of
next door
barry
five hundred nights the clients in
claridge's last year
thomas is determined to improve on that
right i think you realize that i have
uh... anything like that
says thank you
action to as a was collapsing again
fortunately
strategy sixty points down
substantially here
uh... so you know people concerned
working well and supply coming into the
market if i was a lot of i'll tell you
that the nervous about all your
competition
they had a lot better and there's a lot
of it collapses lawrence
criterion for season it was a lot of
beautiful roses absolutely have some
people excited so relaxed
your child stay with it i don't see why
they would through a great products
but everybody by season if you look like
when they first opened
that you see i think we always have to
be cautious
do you have to see your email you the
arrest anymore although i have
absolutely no i have to be here as well
as basic give great game you have a
great reputation but more importantly of
great service levels
how much interlock your reward what
point does it become ludicrous spend
that money
that's really the individuals say you
know why there's
one man's ludicrous is another man's
normal so that's really individual thing
you know called
there are certain suites in the world to
go for
i buy hired by date
two thousand dollars for sweep down the
process a cavalier chris
at another person
will pay fifty thousand dollars a night
for sweet i think that it's a
i know what i paid for one night
in the best sellers tera plunge and
provides the four seasons that other
people would have a heart attack
and for that long
fifty thousand dollars
intel missus absence his deputy michael
blonston is responsible for the day to
day mounting for home town
continues but they today
will walk again
price that they are two demands
and specifically what they really are
and that's more proclaiming that sad
the trip consecutively
all hightower's michael
arm on-site part is baar entrance
there's prince on the block dot blot it
do they have housekeeping or by post
from often just our wipe it down
okay great thank you
this whole air it is not the loss i
think that fully paid the same
researcher at the day's and it does need
a bit more of a tough sell so
and that can literally be like that
today
three days ago
wasn't there
everthing on saturday
cabling start
my son was working on it
itself
all units
gail zappa
k
it's uh...
and i'm a little early on there that i
have a lot of stuff
for love
this is a view you call the price on
perhaps you can
we need to know the price that you think
claridge's likes to flirt with these
fashion who cultural connections
and now has an artist in residence
he stays fifty two nights a year
in exchange for drawings
it got all of london
all these things you just thinking
life's going on
all the people were killed
what you think that thinking about you
i hope that if you have to think
employees in the book
entails
he must have done something
he must have done well
artist doing well that's what i want
by title is fashion
artiste in residents and it seemed
residents will that's where we hear
as the bid i keep repeating i'm going to
be recording controlling some of
countries favorite guests on the
with very famous some of them on those
there is an underlying thing about style
within the group of people that we can
control
internationally famous model carmine
gallo receipt cheat
it's eighty one
and she's been staying at clarity since
the early sixties
the one wonderful thing that's still
operative
is that practice comes with the most
discreet
people who see me and my
corollaries my formal night can we look
forward to begin
and they never look at me and it's
always madam sicknesses that they
reported this for you
ministerial treatments of the
poor something for me
she doesn't get how great she is thank
god 'cause she could be a monster
and that sixty six years in industry
that hated him
so it's no wonder she's good at it as i
would say we should be able to be
unit because sixty six to the press
what's your favorite
normal for
i like a lot of them actually but warm
warm for and eighteen on
it's a great deal sweet on the first
floor where you get a bottle or two
you needed to ring the bells and two
people cause it took me ages to be made
by the death or i'm not a person who has
a popular i'm not a person who brings
republic so i would bring down to
reception and also what to do
rather than being
but a great equated digital
people he's having a potluck
i don't want to get used to have people
is dangerous
exceeded its good
people of seven people
there is a great challenge
dynamic challenges
had bagged a non-deductible deals
but i think you know a few game with
people you have to let people stopped
coming soon
beget willing to serve you know
and that i can i
michael lind first came to look at the
hotel in nineteen seventy six
when he was sixteen years old
i grew up in a little village idiomatic
interest in the southwest welland
and at one thousand people and continue
everybody
what's special about this week
this version is one of our is one of
these were my favorite suites it's very
very nice
anything that he's israel was
and sat really don't have
usage groceries or
heads of state
good investment
welcome
what to put all suites
here we have the sitting room
they'd save morgan it's so very nicely
seven we have for the french and marble
f five days here we have said peter
piano
it says here
is piana belonged to reachability carton
of giving someone faber
activated when a free will
burglar
famous place in uganda
simplify
i think i'll be done it in the subject
she was wonderful
electrician's revisions said penthouse
fusion suites
chiseled that incident catwalk for a
straight-a student projects which is
which
and mariah carey should lovely earnestly
she states of status
we famous you can choose your own made
me feel india's
because you're a curious state carriage
is something else
equipments
here's a dining room here e-tickets room
it you can have a few meals here its
ease up to ten to twelve people
if my phone
and his is a bedroom here again you've
called buttons and other sites if you if
you'd like this season to the bottom
because there is no few when you stay
here
he did to lift your name to withdraw my
kids about something
angry unitaf clear that if you need to
come
physical buttons as well
and opinions
thank you very much
morning mister neck is this is your six
forty five wake-up call feel very
welcome
uh... today is going to be cloudy with
some light rain in the forecast and the
highs going to be a partially eight
celsius or forty six right
yet it is sometimes collins was called
the soundboard when they take the
celebrities morris misplace it up and if
there is a lot of your beds
by you get used to the ones that they'll
call you with all the time to play with
arnold schwarzenegger quite a lot so
you'll pick up the phone say good
afternoon claridge's how may i help you
anatolia who is you've got the and what
does he do
christine
it's good for you
set up a little bit about me he had a
new very exciting booking became an
overnight me anti japanese
artists come sort of known as the
britney spears of japan she's going to
be taking into our penthouse for one
month starting on november first on so
if we can all just get it from there is
some self with parent will be more
details to come on that shortly
absolutely and colleen where and who is
who is using
icb corners decision yet
what do you
um... we should racial jordan today
and recently moved to monday
measures of from the mailing to repair
their mandate resolve building tuesday
within a week says we will all martin
work
and that these
graphic with everyone thank you very
much
data
first-class eighties we just heard about
it at eleven o'clock last night
so we don't know i have to get you some
research but she does have a crew of
thirty-five people that she travels that
which he is it one of the preferences
for strategy of causing
um... jacuzzi but also to stay on the
high it's going to stand up and a half
an hour and hav at this point doesn't
have intercourse
photograph
and about four days
out the fifteen-year-old bar
even go to the jacuzzi surrounded by the
original markers
we do not have to do everything i can
real rio a_t_m_ jack pictures exactly
reaction to that yeah wanted them
marketing
infertility coffin starts the new rivals
to fight against the japanese are just
going into the brick enticed
she's actually pre-registered for
arrival on saturday evelyn those
received a memo the clarity steam
has researched in you guessed from
stacey opera who tells you
i was a city emails their children
testing off like specific comments made
by her teams from previous stays
uh... as he instead
going to not sweet without any
pre-authorized each month and then come
to you by their staff they're going to
have not learn scams stressed
any stronger she sent her to that nobody
for any reason goes to that sweet arm
also they had issues there then i cut
top
you know atop falling off
and which
through the whole stayed into jeopardy
so you know you didn't know as obviously
what issues the top and at that time one
thing nearly lost the hotel in taipei
some business
for going to look at the hands of course
he that we have in store it last week
for all arriving on saturday
cancel privileges
wanted to see
who lockers lower more control
associate
makers
sts sneeze ps
six cc's losses for senior citizens
lace surfaces of course is everyone is
telling you this i think that is that if
this is all that
sex life and i think very much cds is
only wants to see this since we are so
someone will have to think that this is
called before she arrives
japanese pop star has arrived to rabin
settled into the six thousand seven
hundred pound tonight intel
win
of course a mechanic and before you
reading room
all the numbers are up here
i can't remember what i had for
breakfast this morning but i can
remember almonds
and how do you have many call
news from the japanese pop artist
not
one i have no i've not spoken to her
once her manager yes he did he calls a
lot of but her herself no on
underneath notions of almost
heavy senior i've not smell
uh... i think it's in a video on youtube
buds uh... whistle
cannot in claridge's coming out of the
law
have you met with japanese pop artist
he's not fun in the penthouse
peacekeeping initiative yes
and csc building here
and is that the fact that real harp and
always lived
and he and the same
this is a good morning good opportunity
for the ellis's very party because just
workin on most of the time
remain a movie
payment etc licensed isn't only
and will email it took a little later on
the justice for all of the gates
hundreds
antiques
jeep-like
she was she was she's
descended
lecture and then
uh... really beetle and
or or to say in the bronx and the
strangest respecting hughes
c have hundreds maybe
because of this error maybe i don't know
it posted allison
what do you think
me big-screen skit
this is the one sixteen central in
clarity yes
lions out
which people pizza army always happy
what i think the but it's the afflicting
because we have the watchmen
would you like to thank
know it
i think i mean i don't believe exhibit
again though what kimberly irwin
repairman liberty
but they're not going but you don't
hello
christmas season is key to the hotel
morris county schools clinics any other
time of the year
i think the train station
down tonight
together
lol
it's a piece of claridge's traditional
did every year the hotel has a famous
designer to build its christmas tree
over the past two years this is being
john galliano
but not this year
another french picture house is being
approached
difficulties with the printouts in the
house of this is an initial strong
buyout out by ourselves and that the
head down the side of thought for a long
time it's a completely after the
different design from anything we've
done before judge you think it'll be
very good thing
but i have to be our last
the idea that the gloves bats
reinventing success working very hard to
state and it's not something very
peaceful customer this is really i've
that had bounced creating a princess
rations
and you know i can
we member of the attraction at the tree
has been over the last few years and i
can really seem to be coming in and
families
under the tree and children just being
super excited entry is obviously not
send just magically appearing into a
week i have some meticulous planning and
getting ready for this to happen but in
essence we half the time frame between
mcknight and six a_m_ so
openly six dollars
victory just has to be reading it has to
be ready in six eight six thirty days
there comes a point when everybody gets
higher than it looks more interested in
coffee sent ten pictures
to watch it
darman his old-line midnight malt
hannah
do you think
elitist
what
wanna
olin
pollution and
scurrying
this year
dash
be determined by i i absolutely love it
and i'm very very cute yes so first of
all what you see if you see amazing big
christmas tree and you came home wall
if we think it's a great stream and then
you're closer and the first thing you
probly discovers the scene around the
tree of mister and missus long time
and his mistress after the christmas
last
leona
failed
okay how much it cost characters
allies
shouldn't that be
well kept secret
how much does magic cost
jack and malcolm in many cases
and has been coming to the hotel for
fourteen years
this year than spend christmas with
their family in the royal suite
jack sold his software company to
hewlett-packard
and only two teen court donations and
google
very happy and very happy life we've had
together
and many many years
and fun
benefit in the times that we expand
characters have been used invite but we
always enjoy there as well
deal with this one hundred reuniting
congratulations to jack and norman
walker on their sixty
first wedding anniversary
entire coaches team
we know so well
they're like family
uh... our first visit
two courageous
wondered
we went up to uh...
character i think it was hard to make
sort of malaysian
and trial that
israel awake at night
the
we we get more leader constantly now
somewhere in there return would go over
there
pink excellent
chairing
and beautiful
that would be mine
defensive about me i will
highlight his career that when they gave
it to your lease to the restaurant to
roll over and say that i think they made
a mistake
hai
okay well let's look at the arrive this
sem
bill davis one um...
steve insisted on that today it's that
americans are coming back tomorrow as
everyone knows so that's uh... pay a lot
of attention that we've had this it's
it's christmas day
looking forward to having them back
today staying for sixteen
so it's the longest day of the day to
celebrate christmas here
damaging so that everybody in your teams
who has joined
after their last day is discreetly being
introduced in twenty dollars to them
they are all in
most regular guests and i think i mean
for forty years in such a special state
so
they should be recognized and no one
do not speak
enough to be introduced exactly
so goods thank you that's among course
mistresses now call coming in for
sixteen nights katrina
one one one
friendly to prepare the facts
for mister meese smoke or
and their classmates organize some
foreign teachers for that or the like
like a wheelchair in the citadel
somebody to the table exits
anything else that we need to everybody
should know cause all young anything
mexican i
the royal suite he's been minute people
panicked for the malcolm's arrival
detailed desperate filed document his
cabinet to returning guests outlying say
every preference from how the big cement
dot and tight securities to where the
fun each year is placed within the read
possessive abt that picture csr
setup of the seating courthouse smokes
and that's the top of her bedroom
it has not had a different way of he's
making of the bed and then the white
part of the family as well
but they are like that at the show up
people
did a lot of
sheets
yet
back next to their windows for me is to
have
and tell you learned on wall
to see it's and blankets should or not
because
and also some political contest at the
time is like a conduit
but she's just on the top
to just make sure that
those pics
because we don't have a great service
effective listening
twenty objections can really going to go
let's close it was a good
competency
just
help
he loves his sweet cost
uh... to rent
status three days five-and-a-half hours
it is a lot of money but i think
you can call easily spend ten thousand
pounds flying to new york
for five or flight
missile become very also
it's a management tradition
it on her rival leases malcolm has
handed in old set of keys to the doors
encourages
the checks and she knows the who tell
better than any of the staff
and connect as on marine nights manager
they're always in the same place and
they have to be in for a long time
because this has been the general and
just ask for a new we meet aspect but
for i think it will be more than fifty
years
this year freaky thank you
yes ameen missus mack was a fantastic
woman and says she has
the grades i think she has a great
spirit and a great sense of humor so if
you can actually see it twenty i when
she gets the ski says s they disappeared
and back
on tuesday of preparation
thomas checks every last detail before
mr mrs malcolm rhyme
but he and let's just wait here for a
moment
so i think i think we should take the
orchids away because that clashes with
the police look it's it's not the same
so we can
just maybe get some
but what i've done nothing moro from
poland or more traditional flawless is
more
and another christmas here range from
fraud
not over his investment
it's a nice day
traditional christmas i mentioned
pretty much
excellence is not cross into the city
this piece is always appeared for just a
little
coffee trawler
mhm airplane
mister o'rourke
always there
and then here is preferred
occurs reading
everything is fifty pat perfectly that's
how you always is
and always has to be like this
just a few fellow changes and then go
with it we need to add some
some amenities like the food better for
the but of course that o_t_a_ yet they
become fresh from the kitchen
one point
lastly
mizuno more than a minute let them enjoy
this is it and i'm sure there will be
many more to come
so here
michael has been sending the malcolm's
since he started working in haiti now
annual deficit cutting the budget
committee from thirty four years have
been hidden
it remembered match
visit is part of our charlie does return
cost was me back
visited the familiar faces coming back
and
ephemeral dad
well i hope so the
ahead
private
the
tearing messy cleaned a stain
the milkens andy's the hotel twice
we're all creatures of habit augusta
greatly over the voters people have
breakfast needs at the same thing the
map is to have the same breakfast every
morning if coffee for two
toasts
wedded to regret toast assisted living
orange is not the most important u
team needs to how much money people
yes
and guess it's amazing
you know it is very difficult times
jacobs charged is sleeping rec great
sheep
but you get used to sit with working
with the collectors he's
because
could be headed
system parts from coffee
for the sole use of next week if that's
the kind profit will
behind
actually cost
won't be in the stomach
mason nicely you know exactly what you
have any idea in mind is like putting a
very lucky
wonders what movie
alleged white papers or s
history you know i heard a dog must have
greg norris
time
the good but does not appear no no
you're stuck with me today
but i was sick for the next three days
for the bata tomorrow
have you ever got jealous fill in the
films never
we would take issue with
noriega failure to do
more power to meet with sam
to prewar freight hartford muddier
north african terms were cast
thank you very much
invariably simpler times every time
someone this issue needs to
creates resend to visit again
so there needs to be at least one memory
that within college and out of business
to create long as he had to create
that's
emotional that's
association with the hotel that will
make this person turned into a regular
guest
wanted more resources go to how few
c_d_-rom percent goes to interest
bank is a very good to talk to connect
due to half measures
twenty happy
plans for a short with you know
we passing through
from which is next monday might
tomorrow mind dumb and bring the science
content so we don't want to for a look
at the brain one strong rome wings
tonight with contract on this frankly
throws himself into what can be allen
alone because he for male daytime
timbers and come to see in madagascar