Let's do this
[Macklemore and Ryan Lewis's
"Can't Hold Us"]
men singing: Hey, hey, hey.
Hey, hey, hey.
What is your sound?
Return of the Mack.
Get 'em what it is what it does
what it is what it isn't.
Looking for a better way
to get up out of bed
instead of getting
on the Internet
and checking a new
hit me, get up.
second singer: If you can't get
what I'm trying to say.
Let me get up.
If you can't read
from the same page.
chorus: I know you want it.
I know you want it.
We came here to live life
like nobody was watching.
chorus:
I hate these blurred lines.
Blurred lines.
Blurred lines. Blurred lines.
Hey, hey, hey.
[Daft Punk's "Get Lucky"]
man: I-I-I, I-I'm a...
I-I-I, I-I'm a...
Williams: I'm up all night
to get lucky.
We've come too far
to give up who we are.
So let's raise the bar
and our cups to the stars.
We're up all night
till the sun.
We're up all night to get some.
We're up all night
for good fun.
We're up all night to get lucky.
Let's stop talkin' and do some walkin'
[music mash-up: Psy's "Gentleman" and Ylvis' "The Fox"]
[Baauer's "Harlem Shake"]
Do the Harlem Shake.
[scream]
Yeah
Rewind, me love rewind!
Trust me, on my
I-N-D-E-P-E-N-D-E-N-T hustlin'
Chasing dreams since I was 14
with the four-track, bussing.
Revelation comes so giving it
back to the people,
now sing this song
and it goes like...
[Ylvis's "The Fox
(What Does the Fox Say?)"]
[humming]
And it goes like...
P-P-P-P-P-P-Pow!
What the fox say?
You wanna change
the world?
You're a goat!
You can do that!
Lewis: Here we go back.
This is the moment.
Tonight is the night.
We'll fight till it's over.
So we put our hands up like
the ceiling can't hold us.
Like the ceiling can't hold us.
Here we go back.
This is the moment.
Tonight is the night.
We'll ride till it's over.
So we put our hands up like
the ceiling can't hold us.
Like the ceiling can't hold us.
[music mash-up]
[waves washing on the beach]
Watch the year's trending videos
at youtube.com/rewind
For Talia Joy
Who Still Inspires Us