I never imagined this is how
I'd be making money.
It's now how I imagined
you'd be making money either.
But when I did imagine it,
you were wearing gold pumps.
Please.
I'm too much of a shoe whore
to even think about these things
touching my feet.
I'm so glad you said "shoe."
What?
How many more
do we have to do?
I don't know, but bridezilla
just invited 30 more guests.
I need to email the shoe store
and ask them to hold
eight more boxes.
No, no, no!
Hey, baby.
What's wrong?
The Internet keeps going out.
Let's see.
It looks like you got a problem
with your reception.
You only got one bar.
Well, how many bars
do I need for Internet access?
Usually two or three.
What? You see, this is what
I'm talking about.
Why would they tease you
with one bar?
You're either on the Internet,
or you're not.
"Here's one bar.
"You're almost there,
not quite.
We'll talk to you when you have
one or two more bars."
It's just cruel.
I'll take care of it
for you, baby.
I'll pick up another wireless
router when I get back.
Thank you, honey.
What y'all doing,
cleaning out your closet?
Please, like I'd wear shoes
without toe cleavage.
Toe cleavage is only important
to a guy
if your toes are a 36d.
Clearly, he does not know
what I can do with my toes.
♪ Are we there yet? ♪
The Rat in the House
S01x05 Original Air Date on June 16, 2010
♪ tell me, tell me, tell me ♪
♪ tell me,
are we there yet? ♪
-- sync, corrected by elderman --
-- for www.addic7ed.Com --
Hey, Troy.
Come on in.
Hi, Mr. Kingston-persons.
How are you feeling today?
I'm good.
Are you looking for Kevin?
Sure, unless you want
to hang out.
He's upstairs.
Hey, dad, do you want
to take me shopping?
No.
Thanks for nothing.
Hey, Gigi,
have you seen my mom?
She's with a client.
Why?
'Cause I want her
to take me to the mall
so I can buy
these diamond earrings
I've been saving up for.
They cost $50.
$50?
Yup.
Oh, baby, those are
your starter diamonds.
I'm not doing anything.
I'll take you.
Really?
Yes.
$50 diamonds.
Exactly.
That is so cute.
Look what I got.
Cool!
What's his name?
He doesn't have one.
But you can give him one,
if you want.
How about...Whitey?
I guess.
It's a bit obvious,
but it works.
You want to keep him for a day?
I can't.
My dad's afraid of rats.
Just keep him in your drawer.
Your dad'll never find him...
Unless he looks in the drawer.
Good idea.
I wish I lived in a drawer.
Well, I gotta go.
My mom thinks
I'm in the bathtub.
Your eyes are really pink.
Little bed...
Hey, dad.
Whatcha doing in here?
I need
a stronger WI-fi signal,
so I'm going to install
this router in your closet.
Oh, do you know how long
you're gonna be in there?
Why? Is there someplace else
you want me to be?
No.
I was wondering if you'd,
you know,
be in there a long time or not,
just in case
somebody was looking for you.
What was that?
What?
I thought I heard
a scratching noise.
Oh, that was me.
My skin's all dry.
Mom keeps taking my lotion.
What is it with the two of you
and lotion?
Is that why
you don't want me in here?
No, no.
Just, my skin's all dry.
Try taking a bath.
That'll get rid of the funk
and the itch.
Good idea.
Bye.
That was close.
Whitey.
Whitey!
Whitey?
Not the pimp walk.
Is that enough bars for you?
Internet in the car.
I am impressed.
But my question is,
does it work in the house?
Excuse me.
I got something to show you
right here.
Bam!
If you're working
on the couch...
You are connected.
If you're working
on the counter,
you're connected.
If...You do...The robot
in the dining room...
You are fully connected.
With bars like this,
you might get fully connected.
Ooh, you're sexy
when you drop your firewall.
Hey, Troy.
Come on in.
Hi, Mr. Kingston-persons.
Hi, Mrs. Kingston-persons.
Hi, Troy.
Kevin's upstairs.
I like the way
you read my mind.
Hey, mom.
Hey, dad.
Hi, sweetheart.
You been shopping?
Yes.
Yes, I have.
Oh, I'm going
to get out of here
before all the,
"oh, that's so cute!"
Look at this, mom.
Bam!
Oh, that's so cute.
Look at this.
Bam!
Oh, and that's not all.
Look.
Bam!
Lindsey, where'd you get
the money for all this?
Oh, I ran into
an old boyfriend,
and we tried to shake him,
but we couldn't.
So we let him buy us
a bunch of stuff.
You're telling me
you let some man buy Lindsey
all these things?
Oh, and my earrings,
and I still have my 50 bucks.
Lindsey, I don't want you
becoming one of those women
who accepts gifts
from strange men.
But, mom--
no buts.
Please go to your room.
Gigi and I need to talk.
Where do you think he went?
I don't know.
He was in my drawer,
and then three seconds later,
he was gone.
Dude, you've still got
race car underwear?
What are you, nine?
Troy, we've got to find
Whitey.
If my dad sees him,
somebody's going to end up dead.
I don't know if it's going to be
him, us, or the rat.
All this talk of rats
is making me hungry.
Does your mom have
pita pockets?
Zee, I don't know
why you're so upset.
My daughter just got
a bunch of free stuff
from some man.
It wasn't just some man.
He was a man I know
who likes me, who I don't like,
who's trying to convince me
to like him by buying me stuff.
I don't think there's
anything strange about that.
I don't want Lindsey thinking
that's how life works.
That is how life works!
That's what's so great
about being a...
Woman.
How about she uses
her other assets
to get what she wants,
like her brain?
Stupid women do not get
free Prada bags.
Gigi.
I don't want Lindsey doing
what you're doing.
I'm not raising her
to be dependent on men.
Is you accepting flowers
any different
from me accepting a trip
to Puerto Rico?
Yes.
In principle.
Okay, are you independent?
Did you buy this house
by yourself?
Are you raising your kids
And you know what?
I am not the one
who goes running to her man
every time she can't get
a signal on her computer.
No, you run to the mall
and let a man buy you
a new computer.
That was one time!
Are you saying
I'm a bad influence?
Yes.
I guess
that's what I'm saying.
You know what?
I don't need
some holier-than-thou friend
judging me on what I do.
'Cause I'm a good person,
Suzanne!
I am not the hypocrite!
Hey, Kevin!
Be cool.
Be cool. Be cool.
Hey, Mr. Kingston-persons.
The Internet is down.
You boys been messing
with the wires?
No.
Can you fix this later?
We were just about to watch
an episode of Mojo Joe.
How you going to watch it
if the Internet is down?
That's okay.
I gotta go anyway.
My mom thinks I'm with the nanny
at the grocery store.
Hey!
What is the matter?
We have a rat!
Nick, it's a rat,
she'lnot Al-Qaeda.Ikes greet
those traps I set out
last night?
All tripped.
That rat is playing tricks
on me.
Yeah, well, you're not
the only one with a problem.
Gigi's not speaking to me.
I don't even know
if she's showing up for work.
I know I'm not.
I'm taking a rat day.
I mean, Gigi crossed
the line, didn't she?
She can do whatever she wants.
I just don't want her doing it
in front of our daughter.
Does our daughter know there's
a rat loose in the house?
Oh, she doesn't care.
She's probably dreaming
of her next trip to the mall.
She better watch out
for those mall rats.
Nick.
Shh, shh, shh!
You hear that?
Oh, my God.
Will you please stop worrying
about the stupid rat?
Baby, rats are not stupid.
Did you know they're not
indigenous to the United States?
They come from Norway.
You cannot be stupid
and get to Seattle from Norway.
Rats are everywhere,
like Carmen Sandiego.
Nick.
Nick!
I am in the middle of a crisis
with my best friend
and our daughter,
and you're on a ladder,
hiding from a rat.
Gigi did what Gigi does.
You know how she is.
I guess.
I just didn't expect her
to be that way
in front of Lindsey.
Look, Lindsey's a smart girl.
Just because she got
a free pair of sunglasses
doesn't mean
she's going to end up
like Lindsay Lohan
or Paris Hilton
or Britney spears--
you know, white women.
Have faith in our daughter.
That's all you got?
"Have faith"?
Oh, are those rat droppings?
Oh, that stuff is deadly.
You could get leptospirosis,
salmonellosis,
trichinosis, tuberculosis.
You can also get a broom
and sweep it up.
Baby, can you get me a broom?
Why don't you just have faith
that the rat won't bite
and get the broom yourself?
Funny.
Come on, baby.
Get me the broom.
Baby.
Babe!
Suzanne!
Your perimeter is clear.
When was the last time
you seen him?
Well, technically,
I haven't seen him,
but I know he's here.
How do you know?
There were bite marks
in my router cables.
And you believe this
to be a rat.
It was either that
or the Indian in the cupboard.
Indian in the cupboard.
Man, I love that movie.
Didn't it have
a little Indian in it?
Yeah, and a little bear.
And the rats tried
to get him.
That was terrifying,
right there.
Look, that's why
I'm telling you:
This thing is smart, man.
Look, I set traps out
last night,
and this morning,
they were all tripped.
That tells me
it was more than one.
Look, I saw this
on Nat Geo.
Did you know that rats can meet,
court, and mate
in less than 3 1/2 seconds?
That's almost as fast
as the Kardashians.
I hate to say this.
Man, I can't help you.
Your whole house
has been compromised.
Now, look.
If we don't find this rat
in the next 24 hours,
it's going to be hell to pay.
I got to get
some heavy artillery.
Hey, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Look, you got a gun, man.
What else do you need?
Do you think
this little, bitty gun
is going to kill a city rat?
You got a lot to learn.
What's that?
Man, I hate it
when he does that.
Hey, Lindsey.
What you got?
String cheese.
Careful not to drop any.
You know there's a rat loose
in the house.
Ew, gross, dad.
You know I hate rats.
That's what I'm talking about.
So what's going on
with you and your mom?
She thinks I'm a tramp
because some strange guy
bought me some sunglasses.
She doesn't think
you're a tramp.
She doesn't want you
accepting gifts
from men you don't know.
Neither do I.
Duh.
Don't you think I know that?
Besides, that's an epic fail.
So what'd you get, anyway?
It's in the dining room.
You want to see it?
Can you bring it in here?
Nope.
Wow, those look expensive.
How much were they?
I don't know.
Rat!
Run, Lindsey, run!
Go, go, go!
Don't look at me like that,
Chuck.
We all have our fears.
I'm afraid of rats,
and obviously you're afraid
of championships.
Hey, Nick.
Marty!
Don't sneak up on me
like that, man.
I didn't.
What the hell is wrong with you?
Man, I can't work.
I can't sleep.
I'm jumpy, edgy.
Another fight
with the missus, huh?
No, we didn't get
into a fight.
There's a rat loose
in the house.
Did you know one pair of rats
can shed
over a million body hairs
each year?
Rats' front teeth
never stop growing.
And if they don't gnaw
on things,
the teeth can get
up to five inches long.
A rat can enter any space
a half an inch wide.
And they can swim as far
as a half mile in open water.
A rat can drop 50 feet
without injury.
They have a 36-inch
vertical jump.
So that means if a rat fell
out of a plane
into the ocean
a half a mile away from me
and I was on an island
up in a tree,
sealed up in a box with only
a half-inch opening for air,
that rat could still get in
and kill me?
Martin!
Oh, my God.
Were you this mad at me?
You took all my hard work
and threw it on the floor?
Yes, I was this mad at you.
But no, I didn't do this.
Nick thought he saw a rat.
Well, what was he going
but no, I dito do,o this.
Embarrass it to death
by making it wear these shoes?
Oh, I'm sorry.
Maybe you don't need my help
because you're
an independent woman
who can do everything herself.
You don't mean that, do you?
No.
And I didn't mean it
when I said that you were
a bad influence.
And I didn't mean it
when I said
you always run to men for help.
And I didn't mean it
when I said
that you weren't good enough
to be around my daughter.
Well, technically, you didn't
say that; I said that.
Yeah, but I let you say it,
and I didn't say anything.
I'm sorry.
I love you.
I love you too.
And, zee zee,
you should know me by now.
I don't do anything
I don't want to do.
Men do nice things for me
for different reasons,
and just because I don't agree
with the reason
doesn't mean
I shouldn't benefit.
I know;
I just don't want Lindsey
to end up like Paris Hilton
or Lindsay Lohan
or Britney spears--
you know, white women.
Lindsey is going to grow up
and be a beautiful woman.
She's going to have to learn
what to take,
what not to take, when and why
and why not to take it.
Hi, sweetheart.
Hey, mom.
Can you return these for me?
Why?
Because I wanted to buy
my own earrings.
Oh, and here's 50 bucks.
No, you don't have to do that.
I know, but I want to.
Well, that is very independent
of you.
Thank you.
Sweetheart, you know,
if you want to keep
the glasses and the wallet,
you can.
Really?
Yeah.
Well, actually, I really
don't like the wallet that much.
So you can take that one back.
What are you doing
with my money?
You didn't buy those earrings,
and I need something
to put in my new wallet.
Did you know rats have
incredible physical memory?
They always retrace their steps.
Where was the last place
you saw him?
In my drawer.
Did you check there?
"Did you check there?"
Whitey!
Do you know
what rats are capable of?
A lot of people think
rats are stupid.
But you don't get from Norway
to Seattle by being stupid.
I know!
Okay, you ready?
Yeah.
All right, let's hit it.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Take this.
What's this?
That's a letter to Suzanne.
If anything should happen to me,
make sure she gets it.
Oh, yeah,
you might not make it, huh?
I'll tell her.
Okay, on my call, all right?
Ready.
One, two, three.
Let's hit it.
I said hit it and quit it!
No, you can't kill Whitey!
He's Troy's pet rat!
No, he's not.
What?
It's not a pet rat.
It's a food rat.
Little boy, you was going
to eat that rat?
I remember when I had
my first rat.
I was in the jungle
of Indonesia.
I took it down
with a glass of Agent orange.
I wasn't gonna eat it.
I bought it to feed
my Uncle's pet python.
Kevin, why would you bring
that rat in here,
knowing I'm scared of them?
I'm sorry, dad.
I wasn't thinking.
You do realize I'm only ten.
Well, I gotta go.
The snake's starting
to get hungry.
So you're just gonna let him
feed Whitey to a snake.
Yeah.
You saw lion king.
It's the circle of life, dude.
Yup, hakuna matata.
What's that?
What?
-- sync, corrected by elderman --
-- for www.addic7ed.Com --