TYLER MANSON: Growing up in
Ventura, California, the
Malloys were pretty much
the hometown heroes.
And Dan, being the youngest of
the three brothers, I sort of
watched closely as he went
through his competitive years
and went from winning major
competitions to completely
giving up competing and dropping
his major sponsors in
order to spend more time at
home working with a local
company, Patagonia, local
board builders, and just
different ideas in terms of
buildings surfboards and what
it means to be a pro surfer.
This is a new car for you?
DAN MALLOY: Yeah, me and my
brother, Keith, have been
experimenting for last couple
years with just trying to use
a little bit less
gas and stuff.
And so we got this
little thing.
I think it's an '82 VW Rabbit
truck, and it gets 40 miles to
the gallon of diesel.
Or we put biodiesel in it.
I think this battery
pack's done.
Round two.
[ENGINE SOUNDS]
TYLER MANSON: Nice.
Nice.
RY CRAIKE: Dan's super mellow,
just absolutely rips.
He charges.
THOMAS CAMPBELL: The best.
He's one of the most incredible
athletes I've ever seen.
One of the best tube riders
in the world, by far.
ALEX KNOST: He's a nice guy.
I think that's probably the most
inspirational thing about
Dan is he's still a cool guy.
And he's been there and done
that for so fucking long that
you think he'd be a total
asshole, but he's
pretty far from it.
DAN MALLOY: So this whole area
is where I grew up and learned
how to surf and where
my family and all
my friends are from.
This is where they blast the
Patagonia surfboards, and this
is the retail store
right here.
So it's really cool to be
working with them, because
it's a part of our community,
rather than working for one of
the surf companies down in San
Diego or Newport Beach, which
I don't really have very much
interest in the scenes down
there and the communities
down there.
And so it's really, really fun
to be a part of something
right at home.
We were really clueless to the
whole surf scene when we were
little kids, and this spot right
here, called Emma Wood,
we thought it was the best
surf break in the world.
We'd just come straight out
of Ojai, turn right on the
freeway, and go right down
here to Emma Wood.
It's a really neat spot.
There's a little wedgie left
and a little right.
There's a little left
right there.
A bunch of the kids surf here
too, so it's fun to paddle out
and check out all the groms,
see who's ripping.
And just a ton of good memories
along this whole part
of the coast.
I think it's called Green Con
Parkway or something, but we
always just called it Summer
Beach because it was one of
the beaches that we would
go to in the summertime.
And it was another place
that we thought was
a really good wave.
And it's fun, but it's not
So this is my brother,
Keith's, house,
and I live here too.
I rent a room from him.
And we have a ton of
surfboards in here.
It's kind of a collection
over our whole lives.
ALEX KNOST: Dan's funny because
he can ride any kind
of surfboard.
MANUEL CARO: You put Dan Malloy
on a piece of wood with
a door handle on it, and
he'll probably still
surf better that you.
CHRIS CHRISTENSON: He was one
of the first pro guys to
really be open to trying
something besides their 6' 2",
6' 3" thrusts.
RY CRAIKE: Dan was definitely
riding some different boards,
some of those wooden ones
and the quads and stuff.
And it looked like they were
going insane for him.
He'd just come flying out of
these pits, just right into
the biggest carve.
ALEX KNOST: It's encouraging,
but it's also
belittling, you know?
He's fucking that good.
KASSIA MEADOR: He just surfs
so well and so insane, and
it's just cool to have people
like that out there surfing
and pushing the limits and
riding different boards.
CHRIS CHRISTENSON: He's a good
enough surfer to feel what
those boards have to offer, and
his mind was open enough
where to put them to
get that feeling.
From one of the first guys
that's showing up in the
videos on that equipment and
ripping them in good ways, and
then both doors just went
boom and everyone came
rushing into it.
TYLER MANSON: What's your
dad's surfing history?
DAN MALLOY: He grew
up in Los Angeles.
When they were 10 years old, he
moved to Topanga He wanted
to learn how to surf.
And one year, he asked his
parents for a surfboard for
Christmas, and he
didn't get it.
So I think he ripped
an old longboard
apart, and made this.
TYLER MANSON: He grew up with
a rough crowd of surfers?
DAN MALLOY: Yeah, he was
actually the youngest of a
crew of guys.
They were called the
Topanga Bombers.
And at that time, surfing
was rebel guys.
And at his high school,
the Beach Boys played.
He said him and his friends, the
Topanga Bombers, all came
with eggs and egged the Beach
Boys off the stage.
And they left and didn't
come back.
And it was right at the
beginning of the dance.
[LAUGHS].
This is that Rich Pavel from
Sprout, the finless one, and
that board is really,
really good.
TYLER MANSON: So you brought
that board to Sri Lanka?
DAN MALLOY: Yeah.
I took that one to Sri Lanka
and surfed it a ton.
That one was shaped for
Kelly, and I still
have to give it back.
He totally knows that I
have it still, and I
need to give it back.
But there's a big ethical
dispute in surfing, whether
you should use jet skis or not
to get into waves, and I kind
of agree with all the
anti-jet ski talk.
But then every once in while,
you can get in a situation
that would be impossible
to get in.
Part of it's just it's loud and
smells like gas, and when
you get a good wave, you don't
feel like the accomplishment--
I don't know.
It's almost just a different
experience.
And on big days, you'll catch
maybe 30 or 40 waves on it
with a jet ski, and if you're
paddling you might only catch
three or four.
But it's like that whole
quantity and quality thing.
Those four waves and that whole
experience are super
quiet and nice and with
a couple friends.
And you don't feel as safe,
but that can feel OK, too.
TYLER MANSON: This is?
DAN MALLOY: Kind of the
latest version of--
Danny Hess and I have been
working on some boards.
Or he's been working on them,
and I've been getting to ride
them, I guess is how
it should be put.
Actually, what I've been riding
the most around here in
the summertime, as far as
shortboards go, are these.
Fletch is also my neighbor.
He lives about four houses up.
He's been shaping me boards for
about three years now, and
this is a model we've been
working on a ton.
And it's coming out
pretty good.
This board is the best
shortboard that
I have right now.
But my dad made about
10 or 12 of these.
They're replicas of the boards
that they use to make and ride
in the '20s or around
that era.
I guess it was from the early
1900s to, maybe, the '30s they
were still around,
I'm guessing.
And they're a replica of the
Tom Blake-style paddle
surfboards.
You got it?
TYLER MANSON: Yeah.
DAN MALLOY: OK.
And it fills up with
water pretty quick.
Oh, I don't know if
there's a cork.
But I think a wine cork fits
in there, so let's see.
This is Tom Blake.
Tom Blake was just this crazy
innovator, one of the people
who set the standard for
the surfing lifestyle.
He was this kind of crazy,
eccentric guy who--
I think, vegan, vegetarian, in
Hawaii, at a time when they
were having luaus and eating
pig and barbecuing and all
this stuff.
He lived in a little tiny boat
by himself and was one of the
first people to go, let's make
the boards really, really
light and, through a bunch of
different experiments, came up
with these hollow,
wooden boards.
And all of the sudden, they were
these amazing tools for
life guarding and surfing.
Everything was better.
And then one day, he put a fin
on the back to see if it would
help him steer a little
bit better.
And that was probably the most
important innovation.
All of the sudden, you could
completely control the board
and go down the line, which was
totally setting everyone
up to get barreled.
[MUSIC - JON WILEY,
"KILL FOR YOU"]
DAN MALLOY: I was riding a 7'
2" Greg Liddle about a week
ago or something like that.
I was just not that much
in the mood to surf.
And those boards paddle well
and are easy to carry, so I
just grabbed it.
It didn't have a fin in it, but
I was just going to go on
my stomach or maybe go on
my knees or something.
I just wanted to get
in the water.
And I got a couple waves and
stood up, and it felt like it
was really going fast.
Even though it didn't have a
fin, the way that it's shaped,
you could really still
go down the line.
So I got all psyched, and it's
the board I've been riding in
the last few days.
Or I've had about four sessions
now without a fin,
and I'm totally having
fun with it.
You've got to concentrate
super-hard and totally focus.
In littler waves like that, you
don't usually have to pay
that much attention.
So on days like today, it's
kind of soft and you can
experiment with different
stuff.
Usually, that's what
makes it fun.
If you go out on board you're
super used to, it can be a
little bit boring.
[LAUGHS].
It depends.
[MUSIC - JON WILEY,
"KILL FOR YOU"]