-The rain just stopped
this morning.
The sun has come up again.
It's another beautiful
day in China.
I guess for cheating last night,
I got what I deserved.
In this whole time on Thumbs
Up, the rooftops, the
abandoned buildings, not one
bite, not one any weird thing
while we were sleeping.
First night in a hotel, I get
a spider bite on my fucking
cheek, on my neck,
and on my ass.
I woke up this morning; I can't
fucking move my leg, or
this side of my face hurts.
It's like I have TMJ.
Not like I would know what
that feels like, but.
[CLEARS THROAT]
The guy's like a
mythical hero.
He comes to a town.
He entertains the locals.
He beats up the bad guy.
He gets the girl at the
end of the show.
I mean, it's like
who does that?
Do they even make people
like that anymore?
Did they ever make
people like that?
We're still trying
to head south.
Try to get a ride
into Changsha.
I woke up this morning, and I
took this painting off the
wall of this hotel.
And I just drew this.
So without further ado, let's
continue this ride.
Thumbs up, China.
[LAUGHS]
[HONKING]
-Thumbs up, China.
we just got a ride in Wuhan,
and we're heading south.
The team is broken up again.
Two now become three.
We'll find out if three's
company or not.
It's a weird one, this one.
Good to have you back.
Wait, wait, wait.
Once again, the entire country's
under construction.
There's these trucks everywhere,
and they're all
driving to one city to the next,
and they don't really
give a shit if we
jump in or not.
So let's find out where
we're at now.
Thumbs up.
These.
Guys are fucking perfect
for each other.
[TRAIN HORN BLOWS]
Ni hao.
What are you kids doing?
Just ran into like the
8- and 11-year-old
version of me and Harry.
And obviously they don't
give a fuck, but--
walk on this side,
you retards!
Good job, Harry.
Great influence, dude.
Train hopping in China's
a little bit
tougher than the US.
They're still trains, but
the people on the
lines aren't as nice.
And we havw to do a lot more
speaking, and there's a lot
more transition, and there's
a lot more barbed wire.
But--
you guys all right?
OK.
-Yeah.
-We're just in this passenger
car train, waiting for it to
start moving.
I don't know if you thought you
were ready for this ride,
this adventure.
You OK?
You seem a little scared.
-Yeah, little bit.
-Little bit?
Don't worry.
You're with Harry and Dave.
We'll take care of you.
We do this all the time.
We're professionals.
We rode the trains and the
cars all over the world.
OK?
You're going to get a little
bit dirty, but don't worry.
Thumbs up, China.
Man, what an ordeal.
It was a real trial by fire for
our damsel in distress,
Sheeka, our woman in red.
First, the Harry beats the
shit out of this pimp.
Then, she doesn't know what
she's getting into.
She pops rides with us in a
construction truck today.
We get off somewhere between
Wuhan and Changsha.
Then we try to hop on a train,
and I turn around, and I see
her eating ice cream.
Didn't work out, so we
jumped off the train.
And then, our luck, we found
a passenger train.
We sat on top, and we
rode into Changsha.
So here we have Harry, AKA
Captain Save A Hoe, AKA Sister
Fucker, with Sheeka and--
bear with us, Thumbs Up.
We're going to do it right, and
we're going to do it just
the way you like it.
Hard and fast.
All right.
-Over here.
Sheeka's [INAUDIBLE]--
-What is this, a hair salon?
-Yeah, I think so.
-Oh, cool.
Hello.
Ni hao.
So you guys already?
-Yeah.
-I'm David.
Panda?
Can you explain to him
our situation?
We come from very far.
We've been on trains, on empty
buildings and abandoned
buildings, on dirty trucks.
And we just need a place
to relax and just rest.
Just please, can we stay here?
Come on, come on.
[CLAPS]
What?
[CHEER]
-All right.
You're the man, dude.
I love you.
[LAUGHTER]
-Yeah, that's awesome.
You understand the road.
Look at that, America,
China, the world.
Nice people everywhere.
All right, this guy's
the coolest fuck.
He's the Panda.
Pandas have been good luck
for us on this trip.
So goodnight.
If you guys are going
to fucking bone,
just go to the bathroom.
Please let me sleep.
Goodnight, America.
Goodnight, China.
Goodnight, the world.
Thumbs up.
-What's going on?
Should we leave?
Here, just go to sleep.
We're still in Changsha
right now.
The further we go south, the
chicks get hotter, but thanks
a lot, Harry, for bringing
sand to the beach.
We're at a park right now.
It's a beautiful day out, and
everyone's just chilling on
the benches taking naps,
texting their
girlfriends, whatever.
This looks like a hotel
right here.
That dude Panda that
let us crash at the
hair salon last night--
cool as hell.
We took bets last night-- what
kind of hairstyle he had under
that white beanie.
And his bangs were right here.
I think his girlfriend or wife
was pissed that he let us
stay, but he put
his foot down.
Anyways, we're just going to
enjoy our in the park a little
bit, and then we'll get
back on the road soon.
[INAUDIBLE]
[LAUGHTER]
-Take a good look at his face,
because in 20 years, he's
going to look exactly
like that dude.
[LAUGHTER]
[INAUDIBLE]
-Bye bye.
-Hands down, Chinese babies
cutest babies
in the whole world.
The language barrier thing is
grinding me down so much that
I've absolutely lost
my patience
with asking for rides.
I just get into strange people's
cars and then just
tell them to drive and
refuse to get out.
This is hitchhiking,
Chinese style.
Once again, when a woman
asks, who can say no?
Especially a woman in red,
damsel in distress.
South.
Thumbs up, China.
First chance she got, I guess
two days with us,
three days with us--
I don't even know--
was enough.
First exit, first rest
stop we got to, she
jumped out of the car.
I guess whatever we
went through--
train hopping, jumping into
strangers' cars, whatever we
put her through--
she wasn't into.
And whatever she had going
on in Wuhan was more
appealing than that.
She jumped out of our car and
was out-- peace out, later.
And I mean, her final words to
Harry were "not a good fit."
So I don't know if she
meant Harry's penis
size or in her vagina--
if their bodies didn't match
or if their personalities
didn't match, but
she was over it.
I don't want to say I
told you so, but.
-[INAUDIBLE]
-I know you think you were going
to help her, but you
probably would have
ruined your life.
You probably would have
ruined her life.
You all right?
-Yeah.
-Dude, we're almost to
the end of the line.
We're almost to the
end of the road.
We're only a few rides away.
I'll buy you egg custard when we
get to the end, all right?
Will that make you
feel better?
-Sure.
-All right, come on.
We got one of the worst but
best smelling rides ever.
Every time we'd try to relax
on that ride, a branch or
something or sap or
bark would hit us.
But it is the first time
in my life I ever got
to ride on a tree.
I felt like a hobbit on Lord
of the Rings, riding that
goofy tree.
But they took that tree far,
and we rode that tree hard.
So just rolling through
this town.
[HORN HONKS]
-One of the best things about
international travel or going
to a country where you don't
speak the language is nobody
knows that.
They don't understand what we're
saying to them, and we
don't understand what they're
saying to us.
But it's a good thing me and
Harry have the dopest
imaginations around, so we
create our entire worlds.
We make our own fun.
We get ourselves off.
We get wet.
And we're not even trying.
That was a gift for the city.
We are in, I think, a town
called Lichang--
Yichang?
-That's right, Yichang.
-I feel really sad right now.
I'm trying to slow shit down.
It's like when you're fucking
a girl, and you're going to
come really fast, 'cause
I see this horizon.
I see the line.
We're almost there.
The trip's almost over.
And I'm trying to hold back
one or two more last pumps
before I explode in a rage.
But I can't hold back.
Let's try to get a
ride out of here.
[HORN HONKS]
-Can I get in?
-[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
-We need a ride, down south.
We're almost there.
We're this close.
Shit, dude.
Anyone have a pen?
-Nope.
Oh wait, here.
Here's a marker.
-OK.
Just go a little bit.
-Let him write something.
-OK, OK.
OK.
Oh OK, I got it.
I got it.
-I think that we understand, but
Dave has an [INAUDIBLE].
-I understand what you're
trying to say to me.
Now let me--
I--
OK.
So you came at me
with that shit.
I can reach all the
way around.
Yeah!
All right, come on.
I can reach all the way around
with both hands too.
All right, come on.
Let's go.
Down south.
-All right!
-Thumbs up, China.
I love you.
We're almost there.
Sit tight.
Be patient.
-All right.
Thumbs up, China.
-Thumbs up, China.
We're on the dirty, nasty
ass shores of Shenzhen.
Today's my birthday.
I turn 33 today.
Don't want any pomp
and circumstance.
I'm with my uncle, Sum
Dum Guy, Harry Kim.
And I'm Someting Wong.
And I guess my mom and dad gave
this to Harry to bring to
me when he came to visit
me from my [INAUDIBLE]
on Beijing.
There's a drawing from
my mother and a
drawing from my father.
And it is a very special day
today, but not because it's my
birthday, but because it's the
last day of Thumbs Up.
And we've accomplished
our mission.
We've crossed the country, the
great nation of China, from
Beijing to Shenzhen.
We did what we've never done.
I don't know what you call the
opposite of kidnapping, but we
went into people's cars,
and we forced
them to give us rides.
Chinese people, I never knew one
word that you said to me,
but it didn't matter because
I understood anyways.
It was all in your eyes.
And so I just want to
say some thank yous.
I want to say to China, thank
you for accepting my uncle
Harry as your chosen son--
first as a mutant dog boy, and
then as the mini-Buddha.
Thank you for letting us
rock out with you--
showing you how to rock and you
showing us how you rock.
Thanks for letting us float down
your rivers and streams.
Thank you for fulfilling my
dream as a vandal for letting
me hit up the greatest wall
in all the world, the
Great Wall of China.
Thank you for letting us find
love, fight for love, and lose
love, and find it
all over again.
Thank you, Ms. Stephanie.
Panda titties rule.
Thank you for letting us help
you demolish buildings.
Thanks for having the fucking
cutest babies
in all of the world.
Thank you for all your rides--
your bulldozer rides, your
donkey rides, your boat rides,
your tree rides.
Thank you to the chicken who
flying drop kicked Harry to
humble his fucking ass.
Thank you for turning even the
shittiest tasting food into
candy for us.
Thank you for creating
fireworks.
Thank you for sharing
your art with us.
Thank you for letting me
share my art with you.
And thank you for letting us
express ourselves through
song, dance, and aerosol.
Thumbs up, China.
We've done it.
We rocked China.
We got to the south.
I mean, if we cross over this
water right now, that means
we're technically
leaving China.
If we stay, I've heard fabled
stories of cities where girls
pimp out the men, which
is my fantasy.
There's ghost towns
with ghost hookers
that give ghost handjobs.
So we come to the conclusion.
Should I stay, or should I go?
This way China.
That way Hong Kong, where
almost everyone speaks
English, and I could fucking
talk to people again.
I think a ghost handjob sounds
good right about now.
So what do you think, Harry?
China?
-Well, there's gambling
in Macau.
-All right!
[LAUGHTER]
-We can't film here?
-Hello.
-Hello?
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE].
-OK, we come with you.
Everywhere we go.
Oh, nasty.
We're like on the nasty, nasty
disgusting shores of Shenzhen.
Just over that mountain right
there is Hong Kong.
That's where Hong
Kong, Macau--
still technically China,
but once we leave, we
can't come back in.
We only have one entry visa.
So we're just wandering.
This dude just was like
yo, what's up?
We got our feet completely
covered in mud.
And he just picked us up,
and he won't talk to us.
But he'll give us a
ride in his jeep.
We take all rides,
so here we go.
Where is this guy taking us?
[PHONE BEING DIALED]
-Calling my host at the
Venetian in Las Vegas.
Hey, Chong.
I'm going to the Venetian
in Macau.
Can you call someone and
hook me up there?
I'm with Harry.
We'll be there in a few hours.
Just give them my card number,
and have us all hooked
up when we get in.
Thanks, Chong.
Thumbs up, China.
Edgar Allen Chong, thank you.
With one phone call to my host
in Las Vegas, the Venetian he
called his friend, the guy that
hired his ass, in the
Venetian Macau.
He sent a hydrofoil to Shenzhen,
picked us up.
And then dude waiting for us
right here in Macau gave us
one of the dopest, sweetest
rides we've ever got in our
life from our driver Ken Kong.
We're in a seven million Hong
Kong dollar car, right Ken?
-Yes.
-Tell us about this car.
Maybach.
In all of Thumbs Up history,
never have we gotten a ride in
a car this expensive.
I can't believe they even
let us in here.
We smell so fucking bad
it's not even funny.
[LAUGHS]
-Thumbs up, China.
Thumbs up, China.
[INAUDIBLE]
Ugh!
We just want to thank you for
ending our trip in the most
nicest ride we ever had.
Thank you.
And I know we smell bad.
We're very tired.
But thank you for ending it in
the most triumphant way.
-Thank you.
-Sometimes in life, the world
looks down upon you when
you're degenerate.
And sometimes when you're
degenerate, the
world praises you.
And just like that, transported
into another
world, straight to our deluxe
suite at the Venetian Macau
overlooking the city, which
pretty much looks like Las
Vegas on Hawaii.
Got my bathrobe on.
Got my bro with me.
China was long and hard.
It was dirty.
It was grimy.
And now we're in this clean
polished world.
We're just going to try to
enjoy it, celebrate it.
Life is good.
Life is sweet.
And I love you, America.
I love you, China.
And I love you, the world.
Goodnight.
Thumbs up, China.
-Thumbs up, Macau Venetian.
[LAUGHTER]
-Oh shit.
[TAPPING OUT RHYTHM]
-Thumbs up.
Yeah!
Monte Carlo to Macau.
You know how we roll.
Just like there's no beginning
and no end to the road, this
journey has no beginning
and no end.
And as long as the road goes on,
me and Harry will go on.
Yeah!
-Yeah!
Heyaw!
-Aw yeah!
[LAUGHTER]
-Yeah!
Oh!
Thumbs up, China!
[GRUNTING]
Thumbs up, China.
[LAUGHTER]
-Thumbs up, China!
Yeah!
Thumbs up, China.
[INAUDIBLE]
fuckers.
Thumbs up, China.
[INAUDIBLE] fuckers.
Thumbs up!
[SCREAMS]