THOMAS MORTON: Hi,
it's Thomas.
We're in Kurdistan in northern
Iraq near the Iran border.
We are hanging out with the
women fighters of PJAK, Free
Life for Kurdistan Party.
[GUNFIRE]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
THOMAS MORTON: This is northern
Iraq, a suburban
paradise of shopping malls,
fast food, and the most
advanced movie technology
on the planet.
Holy shit.
They are so far ahead of us
in dimensional cinema.
It's a pretty far cry from
southern Iraq, probably
because it sat out the war
that's still ravaging the rest
of the country almost a decade
after we started it.
Northern Iraq, also called
Iraqi Kurdistan, is a
semi-autonomous state with its
own regional government mostly
made up of Iraq's Kurdish
ethnic minority.
The Kurds are mountain folk
who live in the overlap
between Iraq, Syria, Turkey,
and Iran, but don't really
belong to any of them.
The Kurdish goal for the last
century or so has been to
carve out a homeland for
themselves, a greater Kurdistan.
Which they've gone about the
traditional way by forming
guerrilla armies, blowing up a
bunch of crap, and generally
making trouble for the countries
whose territory they
consider their own.
So far, the place they've had
the most success is Iraq,
though through no small
help of the USA.
We're on the corner of Texas
Avenue and New Mexico Lane in
the middle of the American
village in Kurdistan in
northern Iraq.
Kurdistan is, kind of, a major
exception to what's happened
over the last 10
years in Iraq.
It's where the rest of the
country has fallen into
bloodshed and divisive fighting,
it's blossomed.
They've had a tremendous
industry spring up here.
There's developments
everywhere.
They're building gated
communities that look like
they're somewhere in Southern
California, and it's nice.
HIWA OSMAN: We are looking to
the West as models for us to
conduct our affairs by.
And what we are seeing from the
ruling parties in Baghdad,
they are looking to East
and to the immediate
neighborhoods.
You go to any other nation in
the region, you will find that
their anti-Americanism
runs rife.
The only nation that accepts
America fully, despite the few
occasions of betrayal
in history,
is the Kurdish nation.
THOMAS MORTON: Throughout their
history, the Kurds have
been particularly adept at
playing their enemies against
each other.
In the '80s, this meant joining
with Iran against
Saddam Hussein which put them at
odds with then Iraqi allies
us, meaning America.
Once Saddam got the upper hand,
though, and started his
infamous Anfal genocide campaign
against them, marked
by mass civilian killings and
the indiscriminate use of
chemical weapons, the Kurdish
rebels went from terrorists to
freedom fighters in
American eyes.
During the first Gulf War, when
George Bush spontaneously
called on the Iraqis to rise up
against Saddam, the Kurds
took this as a sign of America's
full-fledged support
and launched a massive assault
on the retreating Iraqi Army,
which failed miserably.
During the subsequent bloodshed
and refugee crisis,
US military was forced, largely
through bad press, to
make good on their implicit
promise and actually give the
Kurds their support.
To this end, they established
a no-fly zone at the 36th
parallel to keep the
Iraqi Army at bay.
And the rest has been smooth
sailing for Iraqi Kurdistan.
I mean, there was a bloody,
fractious civil war for a few
years over which rebel group
would lead the new country.
But otherwise, Kurdistan has
been doing well for itself and
is generally held up as one of
the few success stories of
American interventionism.
ROBERT BAER: They absolutely
love us.
They give us the oil, they
give us anything.
I mean, we've done more
for the Kurds
than anybody in history.
We beat their enemy.
THOMAS MORTON: While Iraq is
more or less a lock for the
Kurds, Kurds in Turkey, Syria,
and Iran, are still fighting
for independence and even
basic civil rights using
guerrilla warfare and suicide
bombings to their ends.
The US State Department
considers most of these groups
terrorist organizations, which
is a bit confusing considering
their support for the old
Peshmerga guerrillas, who are
now running the show in the
entire Kurdish government.
One of these new groups, PJAK,
was formed in 2004 right after
the American invasion to
specifically target American
enemy Iran.
PJAK has become notorious for
their largely female fighting
force and bears a conveniently
vague relationship with the
also gender equal PKK, who fight
American ally Turkey.
We're on the road from
Erbil to Rania.
Rania is up in the hills.
Today is the eighth or ninth
birthday of PJAK, and they're
having a little festival up
here that we are going
to take part in.
The PJAK birthday party was
being held at a secret
mountain bee farm close
to the Iranian border.
It was technically a media
event, but since having higher
ups from all the major Kurdish
guerrilla groups in one
location made the risk of an
Iranian or Turkish rocket
strike especially risky,
security precautions were
taken that effectively made us
the only media covering it.
So it was kind of like
a personal press
conference just for us.
So we're here.
We just, we've been driving in
the mountains for a while.
This doesn't look like Iraq.
And I think, actually, we're
pretty close to Iran.
PJAK was designated a terrorist
organization by the
Obama administration this year,
which made me a little
nervous that running the
receiving line here might turn
into a personal Hanoi Jane
moment, or moments.
Actually, PJAK occupies a sort
of political gray zone where
you're not allowed to give them
money, but the government
isn't really trying to
stop them from doing
their thing in Iran.
Most likely because the thing
they do kind of ties in with
the things we want
to do, which is,
namely, fuck with Iran.
The Kurdish Independence
Movement
is notoriously factional.
It's your basic "Life of
Brian" alphabet soup.
There's the KDP, the PUK, the
PKK, the KCK, PJAK, All of
whom have the same ultimate
goal but just slightly
different ways of trying
to accomplish it.
We tried to get a guy from the
PKK to explain the whole
spread for us, although
he claimed he wasn't
part of PKK but KCK.
We're not exactly sure there's
a difference, though.
RAJ VALAT: Today, approximately
50 million Kurds
living in four parts
of Kurdistan.
It's the same problem, but
this is in Iran, in
Turkey, or in Syria.
We are one people, and
basically, the solution that
we want to see is democratic
autonomy for Kurds and
democracy for Turkey,
for Iran, for Syria,
for Iraq, as well.
THOMAS MORTON: PJAK's
emergence from the
anti-Turkish PKK seems like a
pretty transparent attempt to
snag American support
while still
fighting one of its allies.
PKK's leader, though supposedly
not PJAK's, even
told the press in its early days
that if the CIA wanted to
use PJAK to destabilize Iran,
it would be a great idea.
Who supports the Kurds?
Like who are your allies
outside of the area?
RAJ VALAT: Our allies
are our people.
And our allies are mountains.
That's all.
THOMAS MORTON: Not entirely sold
on this reply, we figured
spending a day in the mountains
with some of their
female fighters would help
answer the question of who
PJAK's real allies are.