THOMAS MORTON: OK.
THOMAS MORTON: Let's
fall back on our
survival training from--
DON WHITE: I'll see you all out
in the field somewhere.
THOMAS MORTON: All right,
thank you sir.
DON WHITE: Good luck guys.
THOMAS MORTON: OK, so, let's
just cross real low.
THOMAS MORTON: Maybe we
should just make a
fucking run for it.
What we hope right now is that
the Americans still control
the fire base, and that
we can hole up there
for a little bit.
Should we yell, don't
shoot, reporters?
I'm kind of holding my hands
out in a surrender gesture,
which I figure is definitely
in keeping with the kind of
craven in nature of the role
I've chosen for myself.
Maybe if we report a little
louder they can hear our
voices, and I'll call out--
[GUN SHOTS]
THOMAS MORTON: Whoa!
Don't shoot!
Reporters!
Lets go this way.
Well, this is definitely
the base.
NARRATOR: The fire base was
still under American control,
but barely.
The infantry unit had been
whittled down to a skeleton
crew of one GI, and the only
girl we'd seen without
a rice paddy hat.
THOMAS MORTON: Were you the
one who shot at us.
ANNA TOMIC: Yes.
THOMAS MORTON: OK,
that's all right.
I would have done it to.
DON WHITE: There's a
leg infantry unit
working its way up here.
DON WHITE: That's another
American unit working their
way up here.
They should be coming
from that direction.
ANNA TOMIC: OK.
|
THOMAS MORTON: So the soldiers
we were waiting on the
infantry division just rolled
up cool as day.
BILL BURGESS: There's another
patrol out there.
This place is infested.
BILL BURGESS: I'm 4th
ID, 4th Infantry.
THOMAS MORTON: What occurred
to your unit tonight?
BILL BURGESS: Well, think
mainly what we've
got is light VC probe.
They're just trying to find
out how many we've got in
here, and how many are
holding the position.
THOMAS MORTON: Does
this happen often?
BILL BURGESS: Every night, yeah
Charlie owns the night.
All we can do is hunker down and
try to keep the body count
to a minimum.
What's going on back
in the world?
THOMAS MORTON: Not much, there's
a new Doors album
that's pretty decent if you
like that kind of stuff.
How was Korea compared
to here?
BILL BURGESS: The same, fighting
communism, the
insidious evil, love to travel
to distant lands and meet
exotic people and kill them.
THOMAS MORTON: Well
thank you soldier.
I hope this goes well.
Excuse me, we're looking
for a Sergeant Wilkes.
SERGEANT WILKES: That
would be me.
THOMAS MORTON: Is there going to
be another patrol tonight?
SERGEANT WILKES: We're going
to do what's called a RON,
remain over night.
We're basically going to go find
a spot, a hiding hole,
and hide, and lay out in
the field all night.
THOMAS MORTON: Could we
accompany you on this patrol?
SERGEANT WILKES: Are
you gonna talk?
THOMAS MORTON: Huh?
SERGEANT WILKES: Are
you gonna talk?
THOMAS MORTON: Can I talk?
SERGEANT WILKES: No.
THOMAS MORTON: Can I whisper?
THOMAS MORTON: So there's
no talking whatsoever?
SERGEANT WILKES: When we leave
here there won't be a single
word, except for a radio
check every hour.
[ROCKET LAUNCHING]
-That's a rocket!
[EXPLOSIONS]
[GUN SHOTS]
THOMAS MORTON: So VC right at
the perimeter of the base.
There's rockets on the
other side too.
[GUN SHOTS]
-It's a fire [INAUDIBLE].
THOMAS MORTON: Charlie's
fucking everywhere.
Our fire base is under attack.
-Come on you fucking gooks!
[GUN SHOTS]
THOMAS MORTON: This fox
hole right here.
[GUN SHOTS]
THOMAS MORTON: It's kind of
weird because you struggle to,
like, remember to keep in
character, and to, like, make
sure you pretend it's 1968.
And then when the actual fire
fight happens it's as if it is
-Get down on your knees.
Down.
THOMAS MORTON: So we've
basically been under fire for
the last 30 minutes.
And I've kind of had this
suspicion it was four dudes.
We just killed two of them
and then captured two.
And the fire fight
has stopped.
Let's see what happens
to them.
SERGEANT WILKES: The skinny
one's a smart ass.
BILL BURGESS: Oh yeah?
SERGEANT WILKES: Yeah, he's
definitely a troublemaker.
And the other one looks
like he'll talk.
BILL BURGESS: Well,
do it the old way.
Just rub a butt out
on their nut.
They'll tell you how their
mama wipes their ass.
-How many of there are you?
-Two squads?
-Two squads of four?
Two squads of 12?
Two squads of what?
-VC [INAUDIBLE].
-Look, fuck with me
once, I kill you.
BILL BURGESS: OK, I guess
it's time to get
something going here.
Here, take this.
All right you little shit.
You going to start telling
me something.
Want a cigarette?
[SCREAMING]
BILL BURGESS: Talk to me!
THOMAS MORTON: One other thing
that's tricky about Vietnam,
is to make the war accurate,
you have to
make the racism accurate.
This may be true for other wars,
but Kraut and Jerry just
don't carry the same weight
these days as
gook and slant eye.
BILL BURGESS: You been around.
You speak English.
You want another cigarette?
-Fuck a you, GI!
BILL BURGESS: How about
you ear there.
How about that?
[SCREAMING]
THOMAS MORTON: It's a
little bit grizzly.
It looks like two VC soldiers
are coming out of the grass.
Holy shit, no, it's like
four or five, God.
NARRATOR: Actually, this ties
back to a much larger Nam
problem, of whether or not to
re-enact soldier misconduct.
Nobody behaves exceptionally
well in war.
That's the point.
But while it's natural to let
the heroics of, say, Antietam
or the Battle of the Bulge take
center stage over the
concurrent rapes and
field burnings.
The public impression of the
Vietnam War is colored by
things like my Malai and the
Zippo Raids, not exactly the
US Army's proudest moments.
BILL BURGESS: Grab another one
of those grunts over there.
Tell him to come over
here and stand on
this side with a rifle.
This mama-san here's got
NVA equipment on.
THOMAS MORTON: What's
going to happen
with all these prisoners?
SERGEANT WILKES: Well, if they
make a push on it, they become
a liability to us.
So we're going to whack them.
-Speak Vietnamese?
-Speak English?
Speak English?
Speak French?
THOMAS MORTON: Why did you
guys all surrender?
-No ammo.
THOMAS MORTON: Oh, you ran
out of ammunition.
SERGEANT WILKES: Time
for you to go now.
Really sorry, it's been fun.
Get up.
This is where bad
things happen.
Turn around.
BILL BURGESS: I ain't got time
for no courtroom out here.
[GUN SHOT]
BILL BURGESS: You've still got
your little friends out there
popping at us from
the damn trees.
You're going to tell
me something.
I want something.
Give me something.
All right, that's fine.
You got exactly 60 seconds
to let me know something.
If not, I'm going to
give you a little
taste of American steel.
THOMAS MORTON: We've got
a lot of prisoners
kind of lined up here.
They've been sort of taunting
them for a little while.
And now appear to be ready
to execute them,
summarily, which does not--
not really in fitting with,
like, the best of image of US
soldiers in Vietnam.
BILL BURGESS: Cut
the camera off.
Cut the camera off.
THOMAS MORTON: Why do we need
to cut the camera off?
BILL BURGESS: Cut
the camera off?
THOMAS MORTON: Why do we need
to cut the camera off?
We're here of our
own volition.
We're Americans trying
to cover this war.
Keep rolling.
-I tell you what.
You see this?
How about this?
[GUN SHOT]
-Next!
-Anybody want to say anything?
THOMAS MORTON: Did they
just murder someone?
[GUN SHOTS]
THOMAS MORTON: The soldiers
we've been with this whole
time are summarily executing
their VC.
Excuse me, excuse me,
we're filming.
-Ah!
We asked to turn
the camera off.
THOMAS MORTON: What's
going on here?
Shouldn't these people be
turned over to army
intelligence?
-They are being turned over
to army intelligence.
THOMAS MORTON: How
do you figure?
-See, we've got this nice piece
of intelligence right
here-- this SKS.
That's all the Army
needs to see.
THOMAS MORTON: Wouldn't these
prisoners be more valuable to
the army alive?
-I don't see any prisoners.
I just see NVA shooting at us.
THOMAS MORTON: Do you worry
about the effect that these
images will have on the
broadcast back to America?
-I think we're doing
everything we
need to over here.
Doing good work over here.
-Good night, sweeties.
Did you see all those
fucking gooks trying
to get up and leave?
Wow, just running out of here.
THOMAS MORTON: So we just
witnessed a war crime.
You can see there are 1, 2, 3,
4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, VC
soldiers who had surrendered.
Or just-- no, I'm sorry, 12,
summarily executed by American
soldiers out here in
the field with an
utter sense of impunity.
Kind of not a great look for the
American Army, you know?
[MUSIC PLAYING]
THOMAS MORTON: I'm trying to
unpack everything we've just
been through in the last day.
I feel like the reenactment
may have been effective in
really blurring the lines
between doing this for play
and trying to fully recreate the
historical reality of Nam.
On the one hand, it's a hobby, a
way to hang out your buddies
and have a good weekend.
On the other hand, the whole
point of that hobby is to
immerse yourself in the most
awful experience most men will
ever live through, which kind
of hits home at the
fundamental paradox
of war itself.
That is to say, in the words
of William Tecumseh
Sherman, it's hell.
Although, in the words of
Spacemen Three, I think I'll
be in good company down there
with all my friends.
All this reporter knows is that
the things I've seen here
will stay with me until the end
of my days, and forever
haunt my dreams.
From Vietnam in North Carolina,
it's Thomas Morton
signing off.
[CRICKETS]