ARTO SAARI: It's the day of the
crooked eyes after the Day
of the Dead.
That was a good kick
in the nuts.
I'm going to have to
do that again.
Where are we going,
Cabo today?
-I think so, yeah.
ARTO SAARI: Holy shit.
Yeah.
Oh, yeah.
Cabo's not in the itinerary.
But we're trying to stretch it
and make it all the way to the
[WHISPERING]
tip, if possible.
How much longer do you
think the loop is?
BILL BRYANT: It says that
it's 100 to Cabo.
So we would come down that.
ARTO SAARI: That looks
[INAUDIBLE] pinnacle, sort of
there a little, that road.
We might just go straight.
BILL BRYANT: Or we can go--
what Chris was saying, let's
just go to Pescadero, set up
so everybody knows where we're
at, where everything is, and
then just ride down to Cabo.
It's supposed to be--
ARTO SAARI: And then
we can drive up.
On the way up, we
can go, though.
BILL BRYANT: Yeah, you can
do whatever you want.
-Yeah, let's go straight then.
BILL BRYANT: So everybody knows
where the base camp is.
And you can do things
at your own pace.
ARTO SAARI: All right.
Straight down.
-[INAUDIBLE] sit there
and keep driving in
circles if you want.
BILL BRYANT: Right.
You can go up to Sierra
La Laguna if you like.
We're just cutting right across
the peninsula again.
-How long will that take?
BILL BRYANT: All day.
-Really?
HIME HERBERT: All fucking
day, bro.
Seven days of motorcycle
riding.
BILL BRYANT: It'll take
as much as we've got.
HIME HERBERT: And we're
still alive.
BILL BRYANT: It'll
be pinnacle.
HIME HERBERT: My ass is numb,
but my mind is strong.
[ROCK AND ROLL]
BILL BRYANT: I was really
excited to go to a part of
Baja that I hadn't seen.
I'd seen Cabo from a boat.
And I'd been as far
as La Paz before.
But I'd never been in that
stretch in between.
Sometimes you have to pay
attention to the riding so
much that you forget to
stop and smell the
roses, so to speak.
I really enjoyed it.
Pescadero was fun.
[ROCK AND ROLL]
ARTO SAARI: You could retire
there fairly peacefully by
yourself, I reckon.
I think the place is
named after fish.
HIME HERBERT: El Pescadero
means the fish.
ARTO SAARI: El fucking
fish-eria?
HIME HERBERT: Fish-eria.
What's Black Bart's
mean in Spanish?
ARTO SAARI: Black Bart's?
Black Horses.
-What?
HIME HERBERT: What
was it called?
Lord Black's.
ARTO SAARI: Take me to your
biggest skate park.
Take me to your biggest
whatever it is
to skate right now.
The [SPANISH]
in my stomach wants
to roll around.
-I don't see no skate park.
HEATH KIRCHART: Played for the
Chargers and the Colts, that
never skated?
-Yeah.
HEATH KIRCHART: Just thought
the town needed it?
That's the story, right?
-Yeah.
ARTO SAARI: There's no way.
It looked pretty
fucking insane.
It looked like whoever built it
were pretty fucking amped
and a few margaritas deep when
they started digging that, and
obviously digging more and then
pouring concrete on it
and then even building it on
top of the concrete, coping
fucking semi lobbing
down on it.
I mean, it looked awesome.
It was just fucking
full of water.
And you couldn't skate it.
-What are you doing?
HIME HERBERT: I'm doing
a test run.
-You got it.
[LAUGHING]
HIME HERBERT: Oh, god.
Fuck you.
-Want some help?
HIME HERBERT: Oh, god.
I definitely got some
kind of fucking
disease out of this shit.
HARVEY FOSTER: I had fun
skating in that park.
And we didn't do rad tricks
because of the situation.
But I don't know.
I had fun.
It could have been the
worst skate park.
It could've been really nice.
ARTO SAARI: What is this?
HIME HERBERT: It's a helmet.
ARTO SAARI: When life sucks,
you ride the helmet.
I got to go take a poo now.
Because obviously no one--
HIME HERBERT: No one skates
sleeveless anymore.
ARTO SAARI: No one brought
toilet paper to the session.
So you gotta come up
with something.
-Hey, [INAUDIBLE],
please film that.
HARVEY FOSTER: So remote, man.
[DOGS BARKING]
KEEGAN SAUDER: I think it was
when I figured out that there
was a full moon and that
the rental hut,
although nice, was concrete--
and then I found out that the
beach was a half a mile away,
and you can camp
on it for free.
So that pretty much
sealed the deal.
I just was going to go down
there no matter what, even if
it was alone.
And then everyone seemed
to get stoked on it.
-Ah!
-It bit you?
ARTO SAARI: Grab
a seat, fellas.
I found two gods on this
trip, the god of fire
and the god of margarita.
A-fucking-men.
-And that was the story?
-How old were you when you
lost your virginity?
HIME HERBERT: Wait.
How old are you, Harvey?
HARVEY FOSTER: 19.
-No, I was 17.
KEEGAN SAUDER: 18.
Arto, what about you?
-For some reason when I was at
17, I thought everyone--
KEEGAN SAUDER: Viking lord?
ARTO SAARI: 15, I think.
KEEGAN SAUDER: Wow.
I could see boning
at that age.
But I just never had the
balls to do that.
I don't think I could
have pulled it off.
ARTO SAARI: It was like,
I didn't know at
all what I was doing.
It was just like,
[MAKING SOUNDS].
A few pumps.
Oh.
Oh, no.
What happened?
KEEGAN SAUDER: It's pretty rad
that we're at an amazing
beach, full moon, and we're
just talking about dicks.
Fucking typical.
-Were you sponsored when
you went to Munster
when you were a kid?
ARTO SAARI: I got boards
from this local shop
and stuff back home.
-What year was that?
ARTO SAARI: '98, I think.
Somewhere in '98.
HEATH KIRCHART: Wasn't your
hair straight back then?
ARTO SAARI: No.
It's always been
pretty fucked.
I had a Zoo York cap
on the whole time.
HEATH KIRCHART: Zoo York?
ARTO SAARI: Zoo York.
HEATH KIRCHART: I'll never
forget that gap, front board
over the pyramid.
ARTO SAARI: I either
got second or
third, I can't remember.
I think it was me, Chris
Senn, and BA.
But BA won it.
It was like us three.
-You must have been
pretty stoked.
That's a solid entrance.
-Do you get health insurance?
KEEGAN SAUDER: I pay for it.
-He's Canadian.
KEEGAN SAUDER: Oh, in
the US, though.
Because I live here now.
ARTO SAARI: I just got mine
a couple months ago.
I guess I turned into
a pussy head.
KEEGAN SAUDER: We can't talk
about stuff like that.
We're rebels.
ARTO SAARI: We're filming
for the Flip video.
Early on when I got on, my
travel insurance ran out.
I wasn't even living in the
States at the time.
I knocked myself out in San
Dieguito, trying to warm up on
this rail, knocked myself out.
-Is that the one where
you puked?
ARTO SAARI: Yeah, that's the
cartoon out of-- yeah.
-Oh, that was fucking gnarly.
ARTO SAARI: That's
the first one.
And then two months later, I go
to the Vancouver Slam City
Jam, knock myself out
in the contest.
Mike Vallely starts a riot.
Someone steps on my hand or
kicks it or whatever.
And fucking I wake up at the
hospital, my fingers
pointed that way.
My finger is like that.
So there's--
get some beers!
-That's what they're doing.
ARTO SAARI: Get couple.
-[CHUCKLES]
Get couple.
You start using less and less
words in your speech later on,
as Reggie takes over.
Beers.
Couple.
Get.
Warrior need drink.
ARTO SAARI: Eventually, at the
end of this trip, it's just
going to be grunts.
[GRUNTING]
That means let's go or
I got to get gas.
KEEGAN SAUDER: Woke
up at dawn.
Woke up every hour, really,
through the night because it's
camping sleep.
HEATH KIRCHART: You look at
Keegan, and Keegan is just, I
think, the freest
one on the trip.
Keegan would be out
here camping on
the beach by himself.
Keegan is the most adventurous
one of the group.
KEEGAN SAUDER: I just need
to do something physical.
I have to feel drained somehow,
physically drained.
So that day at the beach, the
owner of the surf camp showed
up with boards, surfed
all day.
And then I just figured, we've
been riding for six days.
And we're definitely going
to do that again.
So if this is my one chance to
do something completely the
opposite of being on a
motorcycle, this is it.
[SURF ROCK]
HEATH KIRCHART: He was out there
surfing with people, and
they're telling him their
life stories.
That would never happen to me.
There's like a spot where
20 surfers are.
And Keegan will be in
there, mixing it up.
I don't want to be
in that mix.
I don't want to have to fight a
surfer because I don't know
what I'm doing.
I've been skating
for 20 years.
You'd think if I stood on a
surfboard, I'd look OK.
But I'm just stiff.
[SURF ROCK]
HARVEY FOSTER: Tomas,
I hate surfing.
HEATH KIRCHART: I'm that person
that when I look back
on shit, I love it.
But when I'm experiencing it,
when I'm in it, I'm just kind
of like, all right.
Let's get through it.
HARVEY FOSTER: Just sitting
there with this fucking ball
and chain, trying to
get out there.
HEATH KIRCHART: I've just been
way too [INAUDIBLE] on myself.
That is not how I see it.
Like, I enjoyed this.
I think this is the
best city so far.
There's a beach.
It's free to stay on.
People surfing, there's
beautiful girls
on the beach here.
There's a bar right there.
I'd definitely stay longer.
-Reggie!
ARTO SAARI: Aloha.
Mahalo.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
Surf's up, bro.
[WHISTLES]
ARTO SAARI: Reginald,
how's Harvey doing?
Getting the hang of it?
Harvey Foster, I can tell that
you're cool just by the way
you wear your jeans
on the wave.
HIME HERBERT: Waves
were bitching.
It was two to four, south swell,
peeling like a mango.
So I had to get out there.
Yeah, we had a high
five moment.
We shred the gnar out there.
HARVEY FOSTER: You did.
HIME HERBERT: We.
HARVEY FOSTER: It was one of
the funnest nights of the
trip, funnest nights followed
by one of the funnest days.
That whole thing was
so worthwhile.
I felt funny after because I was
like, man, I was laughing
and having such a good time.
I probably got the
worst laugh ever.
Those guys are probably so sick
of me laughing right now.
Because I was having
a good time.
In this trip, everyone brought
something to the table.
Everyone did.
I don't think anybody
lacked in any area.
HIME HERBERT: I think
collectively, it's an awesome
group of people.
And if one person was missing,
it wouldn't be the same.
I imagine we'll all be friends
or acquaintances for life at
this point, depending who talks
to me after I'm done
with this interview.
KEEGAN SAUDER: It's a bummer
that's it's coming to the end
because everyone's seeming to
really meld together nicely.
Sad to see the trip done because
it's pretty awesome.
But pretty psyched to go home.
It's both, both things.
The end of the road
looks pretty good.
But at the same time, it's
the end of something.
HARVEY FOSTER: Now that we're
going back, I'm kind of like,
whoa, it'd be kind of sick
to stay longer now.
I don't mind staying longer.
HIME HERBERT: You've
reached the end.
So coming back was
definitely weird.
Just because you knew that
the trip was coming--
not to an end because it still
had, fuck, who knows how many
more days until we get back?
That was the first point of
the trip that it was like,
we're on our way back home.
-You excited to go back, Bill?
BILL BRYANT: Yes.
-What do you look forward to?
BILL BRYANT: As Arto would say,
we have hit the apex on
our way home.
We achieved the pinnacle.
ARTO SAARI: I don't know.
As soon as you reach the apex,
and you're going back the same
route, it's just kind of like,
let's just fucking go.
Now it's just like, all right.
-The relationship
is in a slump.
ARTO SAARI: Yeah.
Everyone's sick of each other.
Everyone's heard everyone's
stories.
We need to figure out how to
make it a little bit more
"bromantic." We're going up.
We're going up north.
[ROCK]
-Oh, my god.
[LAUGHING]
[INAUDIBLE]
[ROCK]
HARVEY FOSTER: I'm trying to
get us dinner tonight.
[ROCK]
HIME HERBERT: Get
out of the way.
[SPANISH].
[ROCK]
BILL BRYANT: The new guys, I
think, are generally pretty
alert at first.
And then they have a day or two
of success and start going
faster, getting a little
crazier and
having a little fun.
And that wild west
part kicks in.
And guys are like, pfft,
I can do what I want.
I can take my helmet off.
And then I think that's when you
start getting in trouble.
So we were leaving the old mills
in San Quintin, really
our last day here before we head
to the border on the way
to Ensenada.
And I was rolling up.
And I could see something
up in the distance.
And I thought, oh, it's
one of those guys
stopped for a smoke.
Whatever.
And then I realized it's a bike
laying on its side, and a
guy who's just sitting on it.
And I thought, oh, crap.
This is not good.
At least he's not laying
out in the road.
He's sitting up, which
means he's alert.
And can't be dead if he's
sitting up on his bike.
Because the way the bike
looked was shocking.
You don't see a Harley turned
on its side without some
damage to man and machine.
Had that been a day when
somebody was wearing skate
shoes and a t-shirt, it would
have been a lot worse.
KEEGAN SAUDER: If I hadn't have
been wearing that helmet,
I might be dead.
-[INAUDIBLE]
KEEGAN SAUDER: I took
it off forever.
And then yesterday
I did that skid.
And then Harvey's like, you
should wear a helmet.
So I was like, OK, I'm taking
Harvey's advice.
I was tumbling.
The tank slappers, the
handlebars, it's just like,
build up, more and more.
And then it's [WOOSH].
I could feel that
helmet hitting--
[WOOSH]
I could feel it hitting
rocks and stuff, too.
That would have split
my head open.
Maybe I'll slow down now.
That's the moral.
-All right.
Don't scratch it now.
HARVEY FOSTER: Look at
this stuff, dude.
The holes could be gouges
in your ribs.
KEEGAN SAUDER: There was a
fucking machete sticking off
the back.
-The machete.
KEEGAN SAUDER: What if
it had landed on me?
-I've thought of that
so many times.
Like, dude, there's a machete
right here, sticking up.
HARVEY FOSTER: I said
that to you too.
I was like, dude, are you
sure that's safe?
And you're like, oh, yeah.
It's totally fine.
-All the shit happens.
And you have--
KEEGAN SAUDER: I don't know
how the fuck [INAUDIBLE].
-You're going to be sore.
KEEGAN SAUDER: I got
away with it.
-No road rash.
No--
-Oh, yeah.
Rib cage.
KEEGAN SAUDER: That's
the worst one.
-That would have been all
on the top of your head.
KEEGAN SAUDER: I could've
just been dead.
-That little fucking ball.
HARVEY FOSTER: Because
you rode through it.
You rode through it too.
I'm psyched on you guys
for doing that.
That's a good ride.
I did it too.
[ROCK]
ARTO SAARI: I'll go on a
motorcycle trip to anywhere.
Tierra de Fuego.
That's it, right?
Tierra del Fuego.
The tip of fire.
Alaska's one place
I want to go.
And fucking tip of fire is
one place I want to go.
If you can combine the two,
it would be most apex.
[ROCK]
ARTO SAARI: Or start
from the bottom.
Fuck.
Who knows?
Go all the way up and then take
the Bering Strait across
to Russia, take the Road of
Bones, Mongolia, side by side
Siberian Express, or even
ride on the tracks.
Go to Scando.
Go up Norway all the way
down to Morocco, the
southern tip of Africa.
Retire in Australia.
-Jesus.
-What you just said
there was--
-You're a real go-getter.
ARTO SAARI: Fucking go get her
done while you're at it.
So what's going on with
these beers, anyway?
It's as important as fuel at
this point of the trip.
This is very important.