MATT FARAH: You know, people
talk about the golden age of
muscle cars like it was 50 years
ago, like the last good
muscle car Americans came out
with was in 1969 or '70.
But I disagree.
I think the golden age of muscle
cars is right now.
The new Shelby GT 500
has 660 horsepower.
The Camaro ZL1 has
580 horsepower.
And even this CTS-V wagon
has 556 horsepower.
Now, these two cars behind
me are pretty special.
I mean, underneath, you have
very similar drivetrains.
And it's a testament to General
Motors that they are
willing to make this drivetrain
with either a
Camaro body on it, or a station
wagon body on it,
depending on what you want.
We've come to Texas, and
as we know, everything
is bigger in Texas.
The portions of barbecue
are massive.
The boobies are gigantic.
And a man named John has a small
shop here, and he likes
to build things that
go obscenely fast.
[ROCK MUSIC]
JOHN HENNESSEY: You know, this
whole thing probably started
as a kid, where my dad exposed
me to cars, and if a fast car
was cool, a faster
car was better.
And as I grew up and had my own
car, I bought a 442 Olds
when I was 16.
I bought it with my own money,
and it wasn't a day before I
had the air lid flipped upside
down on the Quadro Dog
carburetor trying to get
more power out of it.
So I've been doing it for a
little over 20 years, started
in 1991 as a hobby.
Hobby got out of control, and
here we are, building probably
300 to 350 cars a year for
clients all around the world.
MATT FARAH: Now, this is
the HPE700 package.
And what you get for that is
707 horsepower and 717
pound-feet of torque.
Now, you probably imagine that
feels great to drive.
But wait till you hear
how it sounds.
Shall we?
The Camaro ZL1 is already
a massive
improvement over the SS.
Not only do you get the LSA
supercharged engine out of the
CTS-V, you also get the
magnetic ride control
suspension, which is just
about the best piece of
hardware General Motors makes.
So good that it's actually not
even really worth improving
for a street car.
If you wanted faster
lap times, maybe.
But the ride is really
good, actually.
I like how Hennessey makes
the power, too.
It's not just crank
up the boost.
Because that--
yeah, you might get one or two
good passes, but once it gets
heat soaked, your car
starts to slip.
It's not cool.
This--
different heads, different
cam, headers, exhaust,
old-school muscle car stuff.
It's not even running that
much extra boost.
All the stuff is made old-school
horsepower way.
[LAUGHING]
Wow!
Lot of blower whine
up front, tons of
exhaust noise out back.
I'm scaring cattle right now.
They don't want no part of me
on the side of the road.
JOHN HENNESSEY: GMLS-based
motors are a
great platform to modify.
So new Corvette, Camaro, SL1,
Cadillac CTS-Vs. I'd say right
now in the last 24 months, more
than 50% of our business
is GM LS small-block
Chevy-based V8s.
They're very easy to modify.
They're very reliable when
they're modified.
We've got the ability to do the
calibration, so they get
great fuel economy.
They drive like stock.
And most of our packages up to
700 horsepower will offer a
three-year, 36,000-mile
warranty.
And I can only do that because
I've got the confidence that
it's going to be reliable
and live.
And the customer's going to be
able to drive it like they
would drive an everyday
stock car.
I can drive around like
this all I want.
And the car's going
to hold up.
It's going to start when
I need it to start.
And if I'm going to buy a
$55,000 SL1 Camaro, put
another $20,00 into it with
Hennessey for all the
upgrades, I'm $75,000
into a car.
That car had better start
when I want it to start.
That was only 4,000
rpm, by the way.
I need it to be reliable.
I need it to get me where
I want to go.
And the good news is, this
package comes with a
three-year, 36,000-mile
warranty.
So when it breaks, it's
on him, not you.
If you've got the money, and
you want to be eating ZR1s,
this basically turns a
Camaro into a ZR1.
JOHN HENNESSEY: Every
car is different.
I look at every car
as almost like a
stock in a stock market.
What potential does it have?
If a new BMW M3 comes out,
and it's 414 horsepower,
whatever's from the factory BMW,
I know, they take their
cars, and they don't leave a
whole lot of meat on the bone.
They tune their cars to where,
when you get it from the
dealer, there's not a whole
lot of upside left.
Whereas a lot of the Ford stuff,
GM stuff, a lot of
American muscle car and sports
cars, typically there's a lot
more room to add more power.
And so, you look at the
LS-based motors.
A Cadillac CTS-V, for instance,
comes in with 556
horsepower.
That platform goes up to 700,
750 horsepower super reliably.
Now, you want to go beyond 700
or 750, then you need to look
at pistons and rods and doing
additional upgrades that are a
lot more expensive.
You can do 1,000 horsepower, and
we'll offer warranty with
that package.
But every package
is different.
It's our job to figure out, how
far can we go that we're
not pushing over the edge
of reliability?
MATT FARAH: John will tell you
that there are no downsides
whatsoever to this package.
And I agree with him, mostly.
You see the exhaust?
It's really loud.
And that's coming from me.
It's really, ridiculously,
ludicrously loud.
It is so loud that I actually
felt bad about driving past
people's houses while
road testing it.
It's that loud.
And then there's a cam.
Now, a cam really wakes
up an LS engine.
You get a lot more
power out of it.
So I understand why
you'd want one.
But you get the uneven,
lumpy idle.
Now, some people love that.
Other people think that in
between gears and while going
between reverse and park and
drive or at a red light, it
makes the car feel rough
and uncivilized.
Now here, it's up to you to make
the choice if that's what
you want from your car.
This car will go 185 miles an
hour in the standing mile,
which, if you recall, is about
10 miles an hour faster than I
went in a bone stock ZR1.
So you know that even if you
can't do it right off the
line, sooner or later
that power will
make it to the ground.
I would advise a set of sticky
tires for this car, though.
Because 707 horsepower and 717
pounds of torque, I'll just
blow them right off.
Now, the bad news for someone
like me is that, this car,
it's hard to see out of.
You can't wear a helmet in it.
It looks cool.
It does.
I'll give them that.
But for me, not so practical.
Fortunately, back there,
we have the model of
practicality.
CTS-V wagon--
seats five, same LSA engine,
same HPE700 package.
You can get it for both cars.
And that means same deal.
707 horsepower, 717 pound-feet
of torque.
And while pretty much everyone
that I know, anyway, would say
that a 700-horsepower station
wagon is extremely cool, I
think we should find out which
one is faster in a drag race.
All right, my favorite
time of day--
drag racing time.
We're done with the road.
So HPE700 Camaro versus
your daily driver.
JOHN HENNESSEY: They both
make similar power.
The wagon actually probably
makes a tiny bit more power
than the ZL1.
The ZL1's a little
bit lighter.
So it's going to be
a close race.
MATT FARAH: And you drive at
your track all the time, and
I've never driven here.
JOHN HENNESSEY: I've
got a little bit of
a home field advantage.
MATT FARAH: Home field
advantage counts.
But who cares, right?
They're both fast.
Let's go race.
MALE SPEAKER: This is
John, me, Thad,
and Tom against Matt.
MALE SPEAKER: Should we stick
our arms out the window?
JOHN HENNESSEY: Yeah, exactly.
JOHN HENNESSEY: Master
control!
MALE SPEAKER: I'm quite
comfortable, how are you?
MALE SPEAKER: I'm great.
MALE SPEAKER: Wow,
that's awesome.
MALE SPEAKER: We just have to
go to the other county.
MATT FARAH: Oh.
OK.
POLICE OFFICER: Go back
where you was.
MATT FARAH: Which county?
MALE SPEAKER: Like 500
feet that way.
POLICE OFFICER: That's Colorado
County, on the other
side of the creek.
MATT FARAH: Really?
POLICE OFFICER: Just
go over there.
That way everybody will
stop calling in.
MATT FARAH: Are people
calling in?
These things are so damn loud.
MALE SPEAKER: No, they thought
we were stealing stuff.
POLICE OFFICER: No, it's
the three cars.
It wasn't noise.
MATT FARAH: Oh, OK.
POLICE OFFICER: It was
the three cars.
MATT FARAH: Oh.
All right.
All right, back across
the creek.
Sure.
No problem.
POLICE OFFICER: You go across
the creek, you'll be fine.
MATT FARAH: OK.
POLICE OFFICER: You won't
hear from us.
MATT FARAH: Then they'll call
someone else, right?
POLICE OFFICER: Probably.
MATT FARAH: OK.