SUROOSH ALVI: We're
in Baghdad.
We're here to interview the only
Iraqi heavy metal band
called Acrassicauda.
We've been following them
for three years.
This is risky, it's dangerous,
people would say it's really
fucking stupid for us
to be doing this.
But heavy metal rules.
MALE SPEAKER 1: Rock
stars, yeah.
MALE SPEAKER 2: If I didn't play
drums as hard as I can,
I'm going to kill someone.
MALE SPEAKER 1: These are our
fans, and most of them either
dead or out of this country--
they just disappeared.
MALE SPEAKER 3: Whoa.
MALE SPEAKER 2: We got the
troops and we got the tourists
outside, and we are stuck
in the middle.
SUROOSH ALVI: The first question
they asked us was
have you guys ever used guns?
And then they gave us these flak
jackets, and they said be
prepared to be shot at.
MALE SPEAKER 4: It's so amazing
that we're still
talking and breathing.
MALE SPEAKER 5: This is what
life looks like here.
[LAUGHING], Maiden rule, dude.
SUROOSH ALVI: We're going to the
practice space right now,
it got hit by a scud missile.
MALE SPEAKER 2: We had a threat,
but we're going to get
you one by one.
MALE SPEAKER 6: If we
go, we go together.
MALE SPEAKER 3: Yeah,
metalheads forever.
MALE SPEAKER 6: OK, we
talk here about a
free country, right?
Where's the freedom?