of "Wuthering Heights."
SPARKY SWEETS: But Heathcliff
ain't bringing his vengeance
to the streets.
JACOB SOBOROFF: To
thine own self be dope.
This is YouTube Nation.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
JACOB SOBOROFF: Virgin Galactic
just released this video.
And all I can say is they
are really doing this.
Their third successful
rocket-powered flight
took off January 10, reaching
a record-breaking height
of 71,000 feet.
What you are about
to see is not CGI.
It is 100% real.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
JACOB SOBOROFF: Soon,
civilian passengers
will be able to reach
an altitude of 62 miles
and travel three times
the speed of sound.
Nearly 600 people
have already ponied up
the $250,000 for seats
on the first flights,
including Justin Bieber
and Russell Brand.
Start saving those pennies,
because the first passenger
flight is set to
take off this year.
ALI: This video has
been blowing up my feed.
A possessed baby cruising
the streets of New York?
What could possibly go wrong?
With over 20 million views, the
most shared video of the day
comes from the same guys who
made that telekinetic coffee
shop prank last October.
[SCREAMING]
ALI: This one's for
the movie "Devil's Do."
I'm pretty sure that baby sat
behind me on my last flight.
JACOB SOBOROFF: This next
video really struck me.
It feels like we're looking
at a young Wes Anderson.
Teenage filmmaker Josh
Ovalie gives a first person
account of his
struggle with ADHD.
JOSH OVALIE: So
it all comes down
to one single, simple equation.
Take the pills, less
tutoring hours, sad Max.
Happy Max, no pills,
more tutoring hours.
Less tutoring hours,
happy Max, more pills--
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
JACOB SOBOROFF: Starting at
over half a million views,
the comments-- you
should go look at them--
are filled with teachers,
parents, students
expressing their admiration.
High schooler Joni Y
writes, thank you, Max,
for making me feel
like I'm not alone.
This dude's rad.
ALEX: Buildings?
This is not the
snowboarding I remember.
This is Dan Brisse's
submission for the X Games
online competition, Real Snow.
Each contestant submits a 60
second video of their best
stunts, and the fans get
to vote for their favorite.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
ALEX: The X Games don't
start until next week.
But if you want, head on
over to their channel.
You can check out a
bunch of other people
who scare the bejesus out of me.
They're jumping
off of buildings.
Who does that?
JACOB SOBOROFF:
"Wuthering Heights"
is a classic tale of love, loss,
and some dude getting crunk
and dropping a
baby off a balcony.
Welcome to the classroom
of Dr. Sparky Sweets.
The newest episode
from Thug Notes
tackles Emily Bronte's
Gothic classic.
SPARKY SWEETS: Ain't
nobody know where
he got them swoll dollars from.
But he's gonna use it to get
back at all them haters who
done [BLEEP] in his [?
cereal. ?] Heathcliff
swindles Hindley
and his son Hareton,
jacks Wuthering Heights, and
treats Hindley like a [BLEEP]
till he dies.
JACOB SOBOROFF:
Dr. Sweet's goal is
to make education fun,
hilarious, and accessible
to everyone.
Thug Notes hasn't even
been around for a year,
but it's gaining a
pretty devout following
with its on-point
analysis of the classics.
He's been praised by
everybody from Huff Post
to the National
Association of Scholars.
SPARKY SWEETS: Only
a jive-ass fool
would bother capping
a mockingbird,
because all them
[BLEEP] do is just
drop next-level beats
for your enjoyment.
JACOB SOBOROFF: Be sure
to check out our playlist
of Sparky's best.
Seriously-- anybody that can
make "Crime and Punishment" fun
is a wizard.
I think we can all
agree there is nothing
more exhilarating than
some great multitasking.
MIKE FALZONE: I submitted this
video because sometimes, it's
fun just to watch a guy try to
play 100 instruments at once.
It looks like he got trapped
inside your high school's music
storage closet,
and now he's just
trying to play himself out.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
JACOB SOBOROFF: Thanks, Mike.
That thing is crazy.
It's called the
American Photo Player.
And it was used to score
silent movies in the '20s.
There's less than 50
of them around today.
If you guys find or create
something you want on the show,
make a video like Mike did,
upload it to your channel,
post a link and a description,
and use the hashtag
#youtubenation.
You don't have to go home,
but you can't stay here,
unless you're going to check
out the links that are below
and the playlists that
are about to pop up.
Now, play us out, That 1 Guy.
[MUSIC PLAYING - THAT
1 GUY, "MODERN MAN"]