show you what a farm looks like, and how they
operate and the conditions that the animals
are under. And I am here with Bob lowe who
is the co-owner of Lowe Ranch. And Bob our
first questions is from Gee L. from kingston,
ON. "Maybe you could post a picture of these
happy 'Family farms' in which you say your
animals are raised with the best care?"
BOB LOWE>> Our farm is 3 generations- my father,
my brother, myself, my nephew, my son. We
just raise cattle the way, the way they're
supposed to be raised, I guess. If you're
a cow, it's pretty idyllic. The mother cows
are on pasture year round. The calves, after
their weened, will go into the feedlot.
JEFF KROL>> And what do they feed on when
they are here?
BOB Lowe: Grass- just grass.
JEFF KROL>> And how big is this area we are
looking at?
BOB LOWE>> Well, this particular field is
320 acres. We've got pastures in the mountains
that are 24,000 acres.
JEFF KROLL>> Wow. That's a lot of pasture
BOB LOWE>> Yeah. hahaha
JEFF KROL>> You mentioned a feedlot. Would
we be able to actually go out and see a feedlot?
BOB LOWE>> We can do that. We have a feedlot
as a part of our operation.
JEFF KROL>> Fantastic.
BOB LOWE>> As you can see, that's my house
over there. It's 200 yards from the feedlot.
I can walk to work. My kids, when they were
little, could come over and see me anytime.
It's important to me that the consumers are
told the truth about where their food comes
from. We aren't trying to gloss anything.
What we do- we are proud of what we do. WE,
what we produce in this feedlot and I wouldn't
try to sell it to somebody else if I wouldn't
eat it myself.
JEFF KROL>> So Bob, where are we now?
BOB LOWE>>Right now we're at the feedlot,
it's another division of our farm. This is
where the calves will come after their weened.
JEEF KROL>> And would this be the average
size for a feedlot?
BOB LOWE>> We're 4000 head capacity. We're
probably considered a medium sized feedlot
in Alberta.
JEFF KROL>> How many months will they actually
be here.
BOB LOWE>> The ones that are going back into
the breeding herd will be here about 5 months.
The ones that will go into the food chain
will be here about 8 months.
JEFF KROL>> Our next question is from Squid
N. "What do you feed your animals?". So Bob,
what is actually in the feed?
BOB LOWE>> We feed a mixture of straw, silage,
grain and a mineral pack. The straw is this.
As you can see it's from a mature plant. This
is barley straw. Silage is just an immature
plant. It is green. The nutrient content is
spread through the whole plant instead of
just in the seed head. The barley seed from
the mature plant looks like this. This is
the milled barley. That just basically means
it's crushed. The reason we do it is to improve
the digestion. We do feed analysis on all
our feed and where it's lacking in vitamins
and minerals we get custom formulated mineral
pack. This is a sample of the mixed ration
that comes out of the feed truck. The silage
the straw, you can see some grain kernels
in there. That's just, that's what the cattle
get to eat.
JEFF KROL>> Our next question is from Emily.
"Does the animal feed contain any antibiotics?".
I'm here with Calvin Booker, who is a Vetrinarian
in Souther Alberta and actually Bob's local
Vertinarian. And Calvin and Bob I'm hoping
we can answer Emily's questions.
CALVIN BOOKER>>So, Jeff some of the feed we
feed animals, Cadilac seed, does contain antibiotics.
Depends on what stage of the production cycle
the animals are in and what particular diseases
they might be susceptible to at that point
in the production cycle. We would look to
on of the licensed anti-microbial products
in Canada to try and prevent and control diseases
that might occur in the cattle population.
Cattle are- in some ways- a lot like people.
They get sick from a lot of different diseases.
Some of those are infectious diseases like
the common cold and others might be metabolic
disturbances or digestive disease like when
we have an upset stomach. For the animal health
products that we use in Canada, their approved
and regulated as to how we can use those by
the Canadian Food Inspection Agency or the
Vetrianary Drugs Directorate Division of Health
Canada. Included in that would be