pregnant and she had decided to have the
baby and she had a little girl that she
logs is happy with her decision
but even though she made that decision
she has to deal with
consequences if people don't
really think about
and not consequences that
the father of the child wants to have
custody
you know we honestly i did forget panel
was blown away by so article
and by the concept so and you know
as she points out an article
thirty-one u_s_ states
allow a man who fathered through rape
to get custody of his case right so that
show
kanu uh...
an issue an unexplained this puts and
extra conundrum among women because
then
their those guys have leverage
and they get into a situation where they
say well you could testify against him
but then i will would want visitation
rights
or maybe i dropped a visitation rights
request if you don't have so far
power
how does that stresses that
under what
muncy
could be states possibly give visitation
rights
for the fathers who got the kids through
rain
i mean you are not a bad parent
my god i can't recall what would you do
anything slightly wrong and i think it
is a way
you're telling me and i know that's an
exaggeration
but you know what's really trying to
find some way press them make their mom
okay
so this is missus knots
and nonetheless the reform say no no
it's ok so cadre person
but apparently thirty percent women
choose to have the kid anyway which on
blown away by can't believe that that is
an incredible statistic tunes different
studies indicate that thirty percent of
women decide to have the baby even if
they were great
but now it is very short standing up my
insurance they wanna make that i
understand that right
but for that
republicans they think no we don't want
you to have that choice a person an
amendment for example and another two
thousand nine uh... acted by the way
paul ryan and eighteen
co-sponsored
would say that
even in a case of rape and incest in
fact the g_o_p_ platform the dangerous
path two days ago
says the u_n_ a case of rape and incest
it doesn't matter you loss happy kid
that two thousand nine act
makes it criminal
if you have an abortion even if you are
right
the so that they know what a mess
the you get raped you have to have the
rapist said
and then if you don't they put new
wordpress
but if you do have the kid
then you're tethered the rapist for
eighteen years you've got a cm over and
over again as it is visitation rights
if anyone different states
for your kid
it's mindboggling
how can anybody both of these people
i know at look as i read this story of
her as an actually you know wait out the
facts
iced x_-rated
asked why this happens like why is it
that we have these laws that protect the
rapist as opposed to those who have been
right threat why would you give these
men visitation rights
and i think it comes to argument that
a lot of you know hateful people liked i
can say about legitimate rate maybe
these guys out there think wealth you
know we don't know if she was
legitimately rapes so why are we going
to take this man child away from him
bingo
anything sebab perspective to date
always look at it from a male
perspective and a very calm and i
wouldn't want my child taken away and
look
and other state rate is what madeleine
panel will be the guide with a quote all
the time we have these crazy rape ideas
abortion ideas for the first place
places obviously marital rape is in town
he says that in his book
so
but you know
and what they always say when they say
america roe versus wade to and how could
be talked about it
when he had agent on this program just
another day saying that you know these
women they offer a lot
and so they could be lying and then you
take away the poor fathers his patients
but look this is not a thing you'd idbi
proving the court of law you know just
said oh yeah i think that guy who did
something wrong
on on twenty investigation rights though
is
proven accord a while imperial
if the jury of your peers and charges
that are at center
but it's because they don't care and out
they don't they are care and also you
have to keep in mind first of all allot
of great is unreported in the u_s_ and i
know weitzman reported it's because it's
tremendously difficult to prove that
you've been raped
okay because of course to you and that
man has to be guilty beyond a reasonable
doubt
and it's difficult when it's a game of
he said she said so even if she said no
even if there was afb you know for
physical altercation with she tried to
push him off
improve that that's a very difficult
thing to prove
so these guys get to continue making
these ridiculous arguments about
legitimate rape
where and then at the same time women
will get raped in guys get away with it
because they know they can get away with
it looks every seven percent country
thinks that
abortion should be believed
some believe additionally your honor all
circumstances
but great majority finishing the legal
under most circumstances you noted
anybody hannah says beyond twenty weeks
you think that it should not be legal
now most people things beyond twenty
four weeks it's our lead others arias
was seventy seven percent of us degraded
it should not be illegal right in all
sorts of only seventeen percent say
illegal under all circumstances
yet but those guys are somehow incharge
now look i was sure you charter graphic
file these are the long's that work
past
to restrict abortion rights
uh... since nineteen ninety five
the have added up to seven hundred and
keen different laws
passable most all by republicans
to take away your rights
in all the different states
since nineteen ninety-five and you see a
big jump to in twenty ten that's when
even the more radical right wing
republicans take over
it's happening all across the country
they're taking away our rights and what
times you don't realize it until you get
run into a situation like this woman did
or for c_n_n_
and then you're
cac bo leaving one
that to you
yet but they warned and they are
and they do it all over the country