Most of the people I know down
here have seen something
bizarre at one time
or another.
No, we don't discuss it a whole
bunch, but they believe.
They think there's something
going on, too.
My partner and I moved to the
San Luis Valley to raise
cattle, did not move here for
UFOs, and didn't even realize
that this was a hot spot of
the nation for sightings.
And I knew nothing about
them anyway.
Well, then I started meeting
some of the locals down here.
And they all had UFO stories--
I mean, one after another after
another, even to the
point where there was a real
estate company years ago that
would make people who bought
land from them sign a
disclaimer saying that they were
aware that there was UFO
activity in this valley.
So anyway, it got to the point
I'd giggle and say, we need a
UFO watchtower, never ever
thinking I'd ever do it.
Well, after four and a half
years of struggling with cows,
because they don't eat
sand really well,
they about broke me.
So I was talking to one of the
farmers one day and I said,
I've had to sell the cows.
I don't want to sell my land.
And he said, you need to put
up that UFO watchtower you
giggled about.
You'd have fun.
It was just going
to be a little
old mom and pop business.
We'd be open in the summer,
closed in the winter, catch
that tourist traffic off the
highway, never thinking we
would ever see anything
from here.
I mean, that was not
even a vision.
Well, from the time we opened,
we started seeing things.
And as of now, and this is
November, we have had 67
sightings from just here
since we opened.
One night we had about
60 people over here.
And there was a couple sitting
up from on the bench.
And the woman jumps
up just screaming.
Do you see them?
They were so high up that if she
hadn't pointed them out, I
would have never seen them.
And there was one here and one
here, and they were moving
remarkably fast towards
the north.
The one in the front stopped,
and it waited for the one
behind to catch up.
And when that one caught up, the
two of them took off, and
there was a streak of light
across the sky.
Another night it looked like a
shooting star, and it was over
here on the other side
of the sand dunes.
And it's coming down.
I'm watching this shooting
star, OK?
And it gets below the peaks of
the mountains, and it lost its
momentum, and it started
to float like this.
Well see, that makes sense
to my weird mind.
But anyway, what didn't
make sense is it went
straight back up.
So it wasn't a shooting star.
So many bizarre things
have happened here
in the last 12 years.
And I tell folks, maybe
you don't quite get
all of this, OK?
But you better have an open
mind, because something's
going on up there in
that cosmos, so we
just don't know about.
And do I believe now?
You betcha.
JAY YOUNG: I've seen some
pretty strange things.
I've seen things that I've never
even heard of before.
I think there's a lot of things
in this universe that
we don't understand, and maybe
we're not meant to.
Elvis.
Here, buddy, buddy.
Oh, there he is.
How you doing big dog?
Hey.
[ALLIGATOR HISSING]
JAY YOUNG: How's my big boy?
Yes.
How's my big boy?
I was born in Texas, but I had
the good sense to move to
Colorado when I was six months
old and been in the valley
almost ever since.
My name is Jay Young, and I'm
the manager of Colorado Gators
Reptile Park.
I've known Judy for quite
a while, I guess.
I went to the UFO watchtower
probably the first
year she opened it.
It was a novel idea.
She knew there was all
these sightings in
the San Luis Valley.
And as she's told you,
I'm sure, she's seen
things since then.
Do you know about Snippy
the horse, right?
First documented animal
mutilation, possible UFO
mutilation, happened here in
the San Luis Valley back in
the late '60s.
And it was a horse named
Snippy the horse.
It was just totally
stripped bare.
But where the meat ended on
the neck, the flesh was
cauterized.
There was no blood in the
horse's body, and there were
no signs of any predators or
anything strange around it.
We just found this horse
with the flesh
missing off of its head.
And we had an ostrich
disappear.
It's missing to this day.
It's been four years now.
Nobody ever saw this ostrich.
So we decided to name
him Snippy, if he
ever does show up.
I think the San Luis Valley
probably draws a lot of
supernatural or extraterrestrial
activity
possibly because of the
geothermal water.
And there's a lot of crazy
people here who probably see
things that they didn't
actually see, too.
And then, the San Luis Valley
draws strange people, so it
might as well draw strange
aircraft as well.
JUDY MESSOLINE: Some say that
its the vastness of the
valley, because it's so huge
and not highly populated.
Others say it's a spiritually
of the valley.
Others say that there's
an E.T. base in
Mount Blanca over here.
Well, all of this sounds
really good.
But it didn't make
sense to my mind.
Then I got a magazine
from Great Britain.
And in that magazine it said
that the majority of their
sightings was where there
were hot water wells.
That makes sense.
From one end to this valley
to the other, we
have geothermal water.
JAY YOUNG: We have very little
atmosphere here at our elevation.
We have very little pollution.
We have very clear skies.
We do a lot of watching just
from our front yard.
Judy built a nice place for
people to go and hang out that
didn't have a front yard here.
JUDY MESSOLINE: The folks who
come here to visit, first
thing I ask is have you ever
had any UFO experiences?
Some will come right out
and say, oh yeah.
But folks have made
fun of them for
relating their stories.
And I said, how can
people do that?
People have these experiences,
don't make fun of them.
DAN: Everyone, whether they're
skeptical or not, everybody
wants to think we're
not alone.
Yeah, I've seen lights in the
sky and objects that seem to
hover and then take
off quickly.
AMANDA: I was up in
the mountains with
my friend near Denver.
And it was the middle of the
day, and we saw something that
was just hovering
for a long time.
It was just like an orb that was
brightening and dimming.
But it was still for a really
long time, and then it moved.
JOE: I just left my house.
I was on my way into town and
had some lights coming over
towards us from where
Blanca is.
And as it was coming towards
us, it seemed to come down,
get brighter and brighter
as it was coming down.
It was a pretty good ways
up there, though.
And all of a sudden, it went
from going straight at us and
took an immediate right and went
off and just disappeared
off into the sky.
KENNY: We have what we call
the mystery lights.
It's lights we see over
top of the mountains,
not moving, not blinking.
So it's not really an airplane
or nothing, doesn't look quite
like a star.
So we don't really know what
it is, so we just called it
mystery lights.
JAY YOUNG: I'm driving up
Highway 17 one night.
I saw three lights
off to the left.
And then they went over
the mountains in
less than 10 seconds.
I calculated it out that there
was no sonic boom from them
taking off, breaking
the sound barrier.
So that was strange.
And then I calculated it out.
They were going upwards of
21,000 miles per hour.
JOSH: I've actually never
experienced anything.
And I've never seen anything
myself in the area.
But I believe it.
In the cities and valley,
there's a lot of stuff going
on, a lot of buildings.
But out here in the open,
you can really see
everything in the sky.
I'm sure there has been plenty
of sightings out here.
There's plenty of room for it.
JUDY MESSOLINE: If
extraterrestrials were mean,
we wouldn't be here, kids.
Because their technology is
so much greater than ours.
We wouldn't be here.
There's a painting over there.
And the woman who did the
painting is an abductee.
She has been abducted
for, oh gosh, since
she was just a child.
And she's 50 now.
And now she tries to make it
a positive experience.
And yeah, she was scared.
But that's human nature.
We're going to be scared
about the unknown.
I used to watch Mulder
on TV and stuff.
But as far as really being into
it, I was a horse person.
I was not somebody that was out
here staring at the sky
all the time.
Now, I wish I would have taken
the time to stare at the sky,
because there's some amazing
stuff that goes on up there.
You look at all the turmoil
that we go through here on
Earth and the changes,
and there has to
be something better.