JACOB SOBOROFF: By
now you probably heard
about the escalation of the
massive anti-government protest
in Ukraine.
Early reports are
claiming more than 20
have died in the
last day and a half.
With so much footage
from the ground,
there is unprecedented
access to protests
like this in the form of
social media and video.
Literally, right
now I'm watching,
with 128,000 other
people, l live footage
from Kiev streamed on YouTube.
The world is watching
Independence Square burn.
This is happening
as 6,000 miles away
another huge
anti-government protest
is taking place in Venezuela.
Tens of thousands of
citizens, and many of them
are students, have been taking
to the streets and online,
calling for the resignation
of President Nicolas Maduro.
They're protesting issues
from freedom of speech,
to corruption, to crime.
Last week the protests
turned violent.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
JACOB SOBOROFF: At
least four people
have been killed
many more injured.
Yesterday opposition
leader Leopoldo Lopez
surrendered himself
to the government.
To get informed about
what's going on in both
of these situations,
you should take a look
at the playlist
we've put together
for you after the show.
ALI: The Jamaican
bobsled team has always
been a feel-good story
around the Olympics.
This year they upped their game
by making their own theme song.
They perfectly timed
this to sync up
with their run in Sochi.
And its racked up
nearly a million views.
[MUSIC - SIDNEY MILLS,
JON NOTAR, GROOVE GUILD,
"THE BOBSLED SONG"]
ALI: They may not bringing
home a medal this year,
but this song is pure gold.
JACOB SOBOROFF: This one is
a favorite around the office
today.
But just a warning,
you might want
to have a Costco-sized
box of tissues ready.
Owen is eight years old and he's
got a rare muscular condition.
Haatchi is a
three-legged rescue dog.
And for the last
year and a half,
they've been best friends.
OWEN HOWKINS: First I met him.
He just laid up to me.
Put his head on my lap.
COLLEEN DRUMMOND: Owen
stroked his head and said,
Hello, Haatchi,
and there was just
like a communication
between them
that I knew they
will ever understand
and there was an immediate bond.
It's like they both knew that
each other were different
and there was a
instant acceptance
of those differences.
JACOB SOBOROFF: Since
this was posted last week,
it's already got
over a million views.
Eric said It best in the
comments when he said,
I think I must have swallowed
a coconut because there's
a giant lump in my throat.
Couldn't agree more.
ALEX: I saw this yesterday
and I immediately
shared it with every
single human I know.
Apparently, so did
millions of other people.
Prepare yourselves.
Wolverine cat is about
to destroy the internet.
And also this guy's house.
[FLY BUZZING, SWORD SWISHING]
The VFX wizard behind
this work of art
is also responsible for
last year's mutant kitty
hit, Cyclops Cat.
Here's a pro tip.
If you want to see you
cat act like Wolverine,
try giving her a bath.
JACOB SOBOROFF: How do you
get an educational message
across to kids in a fun way?
How about epic rap
battles of science?
Science teacher Tom
McFadden collaborated
with the seventh
and eighth graders
to make this awesome video.
[MUSIC - TOM MCFADDEN, "THAT'S
METAL"]
JACOB SOBOROFF: He's been
helping the students get
excited about science for years.
If only there was a teacher who
made algebra fun by using water
slides.
Oh, I would have killed it.
This is the part of the
show where you tell us
what to watch.
Filmmaker Ryant Talbot
tweeted us this video
using the hashtag,
YouTube Nation.
[MUSIC - RYAN TALBOT, "WHAT YOU
FEEL"]
JACOB SOBOROFF: Ryant,
thank you so much.
If you guys have a video
you want to see on the show,
all you gotta do right now is
drop it in the comments using
hashtag, YouTube Nation.
Now play us out.
ZimoNitrome.
[MUSIC - ZIMONITROME, "D IS FOR
DOGECOIN"]