The new year hasn`t seen any new let-ups in
the fighting in Syria. The Middle Eastern
country`s been ripped apart by a civil war.
It started in March of 2011, with the government
of President Bashar al-Assad fighting the
rebels who want him out. Since then the war
has ballooned. Different groups and even terrorists
have joined in. The U.N. estimates that 60,000
Syrians have been killed. And while experts
and CNN correspondents don`t know when this
will end, exactly, they believe it will include
the removal of Syria`s president.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
NICK PATON WALSH, CNN CORRESPONDENT: Will
rebels defeat the regime? There`s very little
doubt that will happen, it`s not going to
be one day, which has a decisive changing
of the flags over buildings in Damascus and
then the whole country turns 180 degrees in
terms with government. But there have been
weeks now of consistent bad news for the regime.
For a week, regime air bases and military
outposts have fallen daily. Rebels now focusing
on besieging the bases from where the regime
projects its brutal force.
Now it affects not only how people feel inside
the regime in the circle, it affects how their
sponsors feel, and, of course, it boosts morale
for the rebels as well, so that real sense
of momentum that`s been in place now for months,
is beginning to meet (ph) around the capital,
and I don`t think any observer at this point
thinks that the Assad government really has
a chance in terms of retaining long term power
over the country.
As the rebels increasingly make more military
gains, the question is beginning to be asked:
will Assad stay on fight to the end, as he
has said or will he go?
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: Yesterday was the first day back-to-school
for the students of Sandy Hook Elementary
in Newtown, Connecticut. They`ve been out
since a shooting happened at Sandy Hook in
the mid-December. Seven miles away, in Monroe,
Connecticut, what used to be a middle school
was converted for them. Teachers spent part
of their Christmas break decorating, putting
in a welcome sign, paper snowflakes sent in
from around the world, the school`s pet turtle
and familiar rugs and furniture so that the
kids would have a smoother transition to the
new place. Counselors and police were also
there to help. The new school, Chalk Hill
Elementary, also has more security. At least
one parent interviewed by CNN says her son
isn`t afraid, he`s just looking forward to
seeing his friends.
On their first day back, one of the first
items of business for congress men and women
was to elect a new House speaker. This comes
right out of the U.S. Constitution, Article
1, Section 2, which says "The House of Representatives
shall chuse" - note the spelling there -- "their
Speaker and other Officers."
The Speaker is the leader of the House. He
or she is also a second in line to the presidency
behind the vice president. The Constitution
doesn`t specifically mention what the Speaker
should do, but today that job includes presiding
over the House, often speaking to the media,
communicating House priorities and representing
constituents back home. The speaker also represents
the majority party in the House, and since
Republicans have control with 234 representatives
to the Democrats` 201, it was certain to be
a Republican. Yesterday, they reelected John
Boehner as House Speaker. He got 221 votes,
and that means he`ll be doing the job for
at least the next two years.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Is this legit? The U.S.
has more tornadoes than any other country.
Totally true. Tornadoes can form almost anywhere,
but the U.S. gets most of any nation.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: It`s not just tornadoes, the National
Severe Storms Laboratory says thunderstorms
in general are most common in America. And
look at these stats from the National Weather
Service: the U.S. gets about 100,000 thunderstorms
a year, 10,000 are severe storms. We get floods,
hurricanes making landfall. It`s part of the
reason why some folks want to climate prove
more parts of the U.S. That`s something that`s
been tried by some cities around the world
with both the wanted success and some unwanted
side effects. It usually involves some major
engineering work, and with that, comes major
fees.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
CHAD MYERS, AMS METEOROLOGIST: You have to
understand where we are in the world, how
our weather is so different here in America.
First of all, we have the Rocky Mountains
to the west, we have a Gulf of Mexico, very
warm water here. And the cold air that plunges
to the east of the Rocky Mountains, and that`s
where a tornado threat comes from: moisture
here, dry air here, cold air here, and that
is tornado alley. Something else we have,
a very large Atlantic Ocean allowing those
big storms, those hurricanes to come in at
full throttle, full speed because the water
is still very warm there. So where do we go
from here? How do we get ready? I guess, how
do we get climate ready? If it gets warmer
and the water does go up, if the ice melts,
and the water in the ocean gets another foot
higher, how do we protect ourselves? Well,
the first place that`s protected itself now,
obviously, New Orleans. They built all of
these barriers, did a very good job this year
at protecting New Orleans.
Now, those barriers did something else - they
blocked the water from going into New Orleans,
but they also really increased the amount
of water that went into Plaquemines Parish.
So you have to watch what you do, because
you just can`t put a barrier around the entire
world and hope that you stop all the water.
I take you over her at Rotterdam, where they
stop the water from coming down the river
with these huge, just big gates right there.
They will close, if there`s surge coming down
from the North. And this is what will be.
Right here. Those two gates right there will
swing together and stop the water from coming
in. Huge projects. I mean significantly big
projects, when it comes to how much money
this could possibly all cost.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Time for "The Shoutout!" Which of the
following objects is three dimensional? If
you think you know it, then shout it out!
Is it a trapezoid, rhombus, cylinder or rectangle.
You`ve got three seconds, go!
A Cylinder representing a water bottle or
the coffee cup on your teacher`s desk is a
3-D object. That`s your answer and that`s
your "Shoutout."
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: We can print any of those two dimensional
shapes on paper at the printer at your home,
like we did right here. You see these shapes.
New technology is making it possible to print
out 3D objects as well. All of these things
were made using a 3D printer. Look at this.
It uses files (ph) pictures and adds layers
of material, usually plastic to actually make
the object. Some companies are already using
3D printers to make medical devices and architects
are printing models of buildings in 3D. You
could check out that shoe we showed you that
last image there. That was made on a 3D printer.
Now the technology has come down in price
for just over a $1000, that means for their
price, you can have a 3D printer in your house.
It will make stuff out of plastic, but some
higher end printers can make small objects
out of metal. The architect in this video
took an idea from nature to try to print bigger
objects - buildings.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
DR. SANJAY GUPTA, CNN CORRESPONDENT: I`m Dr.
Sanjay Gupta. Meet Neri Oxman, she believes
we can one day 3D print our buildings and
she`s using the innate wisdom of nature as
her muse.
NERY OXMAN, DESIGNER, MIT`S MEDIA CLUB: When
you think about other systems in nature, one
often think of the spider web. So, the spiders
are creatures of the environment that generates
silk, they create trailing routes, they capture
their prey, they wrap their prey. So in a
way this spider is a kind of multi-material
3D printer. The spider itself is a kind of
printing machine, only instead of printing
plastics, it prints with silk.
GUPTA: At a lab at MIT`s media lab, she is
experimenting with different printable materials,
everything from concrete to silk.
STEVEN KEATING, RESEARCH ASSISTANT, MIT MEDIA
LAB: With the system we`re hoping to be able
to 3D print buildings with whatever geometry
we want. So imagine that Dr. Seuss looking
curved house would cost the same amount as
a rectangular, box-shaped house.
OXMAN: In the near future, we will be using
3D printing to print buildings, to print houses.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Do you want to know what happiness looks
like? Watch this YouTube clip of an Alabama
football fan seeing what was inside his Christmas
gift.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: I`ll give you a receipt,
just in case.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Oh, I like it.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: What size is it?
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: I like it.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Fit (ph) him. Fits him,
I guess.
We are going to the game, Pa! We are going
to the game!
Look at that (inaudible).
(LAUGHTER)
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: We got to tip our hat to that. The tickets
left the fan of the Tide tongue-tied, He`d
never been to any Alabama bowl game, let alone
a national championship, so his surprise was
Ala-fantastic. You don`t need to be a Bama
fan to hope he has a ball at the game against
Notre Dame
That foots the ball for this week on CNN STUDENT
NEWS. We`ll field more stories on Monday.