I am Nimrod Kamer, a social
climber disguised as a
journalist.
And this is my film,
"How to Make It
#Huge in the Film Industry--
and also Persuade Some Chicks
to Put MDMA up My Rectum and
Leave it on the Shelf."
That morning, I woke up
on the red carpet.
Good one.
Do you want to interview me?
-No.
No.
NIMROD KAMER: You can
ask me something.
-What?
NIMROD KAMER: You can ask
me about my life.
My father is one
of the actors.
-Oh, really?
NIMROD KAMER: Yeah.
-Oh, OK.
Look.
Maybe she's--
NIMROD KAMER: Oh, if you want
to interview me, it's OK.
I'm Joachim Phoenix's cousin.
-Really?
NIMROD KAMER: Yeah, yeah.
-Amazing.
NIMROD KAMER: Did you
see the film?
-Not yet.
NIMROD KAMER: Me, neither.
Hey, I'm the son of the Iranian
director [INAUDIBLE].
Can you take me to
the Excelsior?
Guys, can anyone take
my photo for a sec?
I am the son of one
of the jury.
Yeah, my father is
in the jury.
Somehow they had given me
full accreditation.
I thought I might as well
do a press conference.
NIMROD KAMER: It was imperative
that I make more
friends with large IMDB pages,
and I have long believed that
blackmail can be a great
ice breaker.
I have your sex tape,
by the way.
He was just a friend of mine.
Don't hurt me.
Don't touch me.
Pierce Bros' PA escorted me
to his private suite for a
one-on-one screening of
his illicit sex tape.
I took off with his two
gorgeous nieces.
Later that night, we pierced
each other without protection.