sex, drugs, and rock and roll.
RYAN DUFFY: Hey, I'm Ryan Duffy,
and welcome to "Vice
Today." On this episode, we meet
another one of our weird
and wonderful neighbors from
the internet, sex blogger
Rachel Rabbit White on another
episode of My Life Online.
Then we get another round of
etiquette updates from the
classiest bearded blowhard
we know.
But right now, in the very first
"Vice Today" special, we
head out to LA and give the
paparazzi a taste of their own
toxic medicine.
This is Pap Smear.
PAPARAZZO: This way, please.
William, guys, please.
This way.
PAPARAZZO: Hey, let's wait
'til he come out.
PAPARAZZO: Emma!
Emma!
Down here, please!
[MUSIC PLAYING]
STEVE: I think we can all agree
that paparazzi are some
of the lowest forms of
life on planet Earth.
The ever-growing business of
invading public person's
privacy and the seemingly
insatiable appetite for such
garbage prove that more than
ever people are looking for
glimpses into lives
that seem more
interesting than their own.
PAPARAZZO: I love you!
[MUSIC PLAYING]
STEVE: When "Vice" asked me if
I wanted to write a story
about this profession, I jumped
at the opportunity.
I had to know, were they
just trying to get by?
I decided to go directly
to the source.
Going down Melrose here where
we're going to meet the
photographers, [BLEEP].
I don't know his last name.
And it's probably
better that way.
After asking various contacts I
was put in touch with Peter,
a professional and somewhat
jaded paparazzo who agreed to
give me all the pertinent
details I would need to
capture my prey in exchange
for his anonymity.
What is it?
What is a paparazzi to you?
STEVE: He also said that there
are a select few freelance
photographers, such as himself,
who adhere to a moral
code of sorts.
STEVE: What did you do before
this career as a pap?
STEVE: It sounds kind of like
a stripper being asked to be
called a dancer.
You're not really dancing.
STEVE: He also schooled me on
the paparazzi circuit and its
respective territories.
STEVE: With this information at
my disposal, I was ready to
start my rampage of
invasiveness.
Going to post up and try
to hunt the hunters.
My photographer and I headed
straight for the guitar statue
outside BOA, a popular nightclub
on Sunset Boulevard
frequented by celebrities.
STEVE: We see a huge guitar, and
there's two shady looking
dudes in beanies.
And they look like the
kind of guys that
are willing to fight.
We pulled up two blocks away.
I'm starting to get nervous.
We parked and went over our
plan, which basically amounted
to getting in their faces and
asking increasingly personal
and judgmental questions.
STEVE: A paparazzi is telling
me to not get too
close to the story.
That's funny.
Hey, homie.
How are you?
Please tell us, what are
you wearing right now?
Who are you wearing?
What does your underwear
look like?
Please tell us.
Who are you with?
Do you feel bad when you
go home at night
doing this to people?
Do you like a pinkie in
the butt during sex?
Sir?
When you're getting a blow job,
do you like one single
pinkie in your butt?
I'm not getting the scoop
from you, dude.
We want to know just
one question,
sir, just one question.
Do you smell the toilet paper
after you wipe, sir?
Do you go number two
in the workplace?
Somehow I think in this
interview that you think
you're holding on to some
last shred of what
you're doing is art.
It's not.
You're taking pictures of
celebrities at vulnerable
moments without their
permission.
They don't know who you are.
You guys interview
other people?
How come I'm not allowed
to interview you?
Does this make you feel weird?
If you guys do this for a
living, why are you so pissed
off that we're doing
it to you?
I'm not in your face.
I just have a quick question.
Why are you hiding?
Why is there so much shame
behind what you're doing?
You don't like your
own medicine, bro.
You don't like the way it feels
to you, then why would
you do that to your fellow
man and woman?
You're getting mad at me
following you around trying to
get a hot scoop, and that's
what you're doing.
That'd be like a butcher who's
afraid of eating meat.
Why hide in the bushes at a
restaurant for Paris Hilton's
tit to fall out?
If you're such a photographer,
why don't you go and shoot
waves at Maui, or
why don't you--
STEVE: No.
STEVE: All right, this is Steve
for "Vice" magazine.
I thought we were
going to have a
really crazy story here.
I heard stories of Brazilian
guys that loved to fight.
Thought we were going
to encounter that.
But what we encountered
is a bunch of cowards.
Most of these guys are just
pussies, and they're not down
to scrap or do anything
like that.
So it's kind of fun story.
But it was anti-climatic.
Like, who these guys really are
that you see the pictures
on TMZ, they're a bunch
of scared guys who--
I'm sitting here solo, kind of
like a pussy myself, and they
don't even want to
make eye contact.
So they feel bad about
what they're doing.
It's kind of like grinding
someone to the
ground at this point.
I'm going to just take off.
I feel bad.
Later, guys.
Thanks for playing, man.
Thank you.
Good night.
RYAN DUFFY: Really?
We wanted to call
that Pap Smear?
I had to say "Pap Smear"
on camera?
Pap Smear?
Really?
Next up, we meet sex blogger
Rachel Rabbit White who talks
to us about transsexual stripper
parties, clown
fetishists, and how she
certainly does not talk to her
mom about her job.
RACHEL RABBIT WHITE: Well,
people think that they can
have sex with me a lot.
INTERVIEWER: I'm sure.
RACHEL RABBIT WHITE: Yeah.
People think they can
have sex with me.
And then people also think
I'm a porn star always.
So a lot of times
people search--
I see their Google searches.
Rachel Rabbit White porn.
Rachel Rabbit White porn star.
Where is Rachel Rabbit
White's porn?
People really think I'm a porn
star, and it's very confusing
for them that I'm not.
And I totally understand why
they would think that.
Because a lot of the people that
are blogging about sex
are in the sex industry.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
RACHEL RABBIT WHITE: The name
of my blog is my name, which
is Rachel Rabbit White.
So it's RachelRabbitWhite.com.
I write about sex and gender
and relationships.
And basically you'll see more
journalism style posts where
I'm writing about other people's
sex lives, kinky,
crazy things.
The second is more memoir-type
stuff, and about my own life
and my own relationships.
And the third is advice.
A lot of people ask
me questions about
their own sex lives.
So I record videos where
I try to help them
and give them advice.
OK, so despite what you may
have learned in sex ed in
fifth grade from your school
nurse, I say that you should
take sex advice from a
woman wearing pastels
and shoulder pads.
I think a lot of guys feel
the way that Grant and
possibly you feel.
They just want to
suck [BLEEP].
And why wouldn't they?
Sucking [BLEEP]
is amazing.
OK, can you see me?
So I recently had a reader write
in and ask me for tips
on taking sexy pictures.
Great thing about this shot
is that if you're doing it
actually naked and really
Craigslist style, it makes
your tits look great
no matter what.
So if you don't have any boobs,
kind of like me, it
makes you look like all the
sudden that you do.
I started the blog working
as an intake person
at a donation clinic.
And I knew I wanted
to be a writer.
And I knew I wanted to be
writing, and I wasn't.
So I started the blog to
force myself to write.
This might be interesting.
These are the slutty journals
from when I was 21, before I
was seriously writing.
I lived a pretty textured
existence.
And then I think part of the
reason for starting the blog
was working through my past.
And part of the reason I was
writing about sex is because I
used to have a lot of
sex and was having
all these crazy stories.
And I'm wondering about what
happens when you don't love
somebody anymore and where
does the love go.
Very overly dramatic stuff
that you would
write when you're 20.
But it's fun to have
this stuff.
And it's fun to go back and use
it as writing fodder and
to remember where my mind
actually was when I'm writing
about me, sort of a
character at 20.
And I think why I write about
sex and relationships is
because, for a lot of young
people, that's sort of the
biggest thing that's happened
in your life.
For a lot of young people, their
biggest story is really
that they lost their virginity
or that they
were broken up with.
When you're in your 20s, I think
these are the things
that you're really
grappling with.
And also, just to sort
of educate myself.
I am genuinely interested in
what other people are doing
and understanding what makes
other people tick sexually.
So when I'm writing about
someone else's sex life, like
maybe they like to have
clown sex, I really
don't understand it.
And I want to go out and
understand it and bring it
back to the readers like,
here's what I found.
If I weren't doing stories on
these things I would never be
exposed to this world.
And that's when I feel the most
alive, is when I'm out
getting stories and exposing
myself to this sort of thing
and running around the city.
So I covered an all-transsexual
strip party in
New York City.
So I'm just going to read
you a few of my notes.
The women are in Moulin
Rouge-inspired lingerie,
glitter and garter belts,
dancing and stripping for a
crowd of men.
The men are of all ages, and
slink and hide in the corners
in between approaching the
women as they dance.
I'm introduced to-- and I don't
have her name here.
I'm going to have
to look it up.
She's been throwing trans
parties for a long time.
She says those parties are
completely different.
First of all, this is a
posh club, she says.
There's also more focus
on costumes.
And they actually dance.
So while there's a drag queen
working the door, the place is
not so much for a
queer audience.
The gays don't come.
But even if they did, it might
not work with what the
promoter is looking for.
He tells me that the guys that
come here don't want to see
two men kissing at this party,
that this isn't what they're
looking for.
And this would scare them
and cause them to leave.
And then that's as
far as I got.
I'm not sure what
the fetish is.
I mean, definitely they
want a penis.
And these guys definitely, like
the guy said, they didn't
want gay men there.
They didn't want to be reminded
of the gay community.
They were almost anti that.
It's tough, because I don't
think there's a very good
history of people reporting
within these sort of
marginalized sex communities.
So it's this line I'm constantly
walking where I
admit if someone asks
me if I'm a writer.
And if they ask if I'm
going to write
about this, I say yes.
But I try not to be so snarky.
I really want to learn
why they're doing
what they're doing.
But I'm also honest in my
descriptions of them.
I don't shy away
from the ugly.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
RYAN DUFFY: The combination of
the internet and sex, making
you feel worse about humanity
day by day.
Finally, we get another
selection of bits and bites on
how to be a well-mannered adult
in the 21st century.
This is Etiquette Update
with John Martin.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
JOHN MARTIN: Multi-colored
socks, men's
basketball, being bald--
not classy.
When you're in the bathroom,
don't leave
magazines on the toilet.
Don't leave matches on
top of the toilet.
Breakfast burritos, adults
watching cartoons,
snowboarding, 14-year-olds on
birth control, white socks,
Velcro shoes, hats on backwards,
insulting your
girlfriend at brunch--
not classy.
Number one, don't
go to brunch.
Number two, don't go to brunch
with your girlfriend.
Brunch is for drinking.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
RYAN DUFFY: Hope you enjoyed
another episode of "Vice
Today." If you like the channel,
please subscribe.
And keep an eye out
for new episodes
every Monday and Thursday.
[MUSIC PLAYING]