FRANK CASTRONOVO: But we're
getting our After A Hard Day's
Work drink.
I think we should put some of
these in our pockets, because
when we leave here, we won't be
able to get that anymore.
FRANK FALCINELLI: I've got a
denim jacket that has pockets
on the inside.
FRANK CASTRONOVO: I brought my
jacket with all the pockets so
I can put shit in there.
This is Frank Castronovo
of Frankies Spuntino.
Do you want to do that?
FRANK FALCINELLI: Frank
Falcinelli.
Frank Castronovo.
All right.
Here we go.
Our idea, our concept was just
to attract the least amount of
attention as possible.
That was pretty much it.
FRANK CASTRONOVO: We kind
of fly under the radar.
FRANK FALCINELLI: Yeah, be out
in Brooklyn and just fix up a
place nice and get back to
the stuff that we ate
when we were kids.
In chronological order, our
restaurants are Frankies
Spuntino on Court Street,
Frankies Spuntino on Clinton
Street, Cafe Pedlar, Prime Meats
right next to us on 465
Court Street.
FRANK CASTRONOVO: Last
but not least.
FRANK FALCINELLI: Last
We're in Carroll Gardens heading
over to Roberta's.
FRANK CASTRONOVO: When you want
to feel relaxed, you want
to just kick back your feet,
take off your shoes.
FRANK FALCINELLI: Roll
something delicious.
FRANK CASTRONOVO: We're
going to spread
the joy and the cheer.
They've got sick pizza
here, man.
FRANK FALCINELLI: Cheer's man.
FRANK CASTRONOVO: Prost.
-The Frankie story?
Well, these two guys grew
up together in Queens.
FRANK CASTRONOVO: Probably
like 13.
FRANK FALCINELLI: Yeah,
12, 13 years old.
FRANK CASTRONOVO: Frank went to
culinary school like right
after high school.
And I ran into him.
And I was like, where
are you at, man?
And he was like, I'm
working at Maxines.
And I was like, fuck, I've got
to get out of Queens, man.
How the fuck am I going
to get out of here?
And he's like, oh yeah
you travel a lot.
You could be a chef.
You could work in any country
in the world.
And I always loved to travel
and go places and that was
like my ticket.
Thinking someday, you know
I've got to do something.
Why don't I open a restaurant?
I love to eat.
I go to everybody's
house to eat, man.
I was invited to everybody's
lunch and
everybody's dinner, man.
I thought I was going to be 55
years old and have a little
restaurant with my
wife and my kids.
And we were just going to
have a little thing.
And Frank said, uh uh.
It's happening now.
We're doing it now.
Whoa.
FRANK FALCINELLI: The one thing
that's awesome about
being in the restaurant
business and coming to
restaurants, you can order like
a salad and then you get
40 entrees.
If you're working like 90 hours
and you're incessantly
worrying about your business,
the least you can do is go to
another restaurant and get
a bunch of free shit.
This is like restaurant merch.
They are like, hey, have another
one of my t-shirts.
FRANK FALCINELLI: But
we've got to go
outside and smoke, man.
Where's that smoke
coming from, man?
Oh, my goodness.
And Roberta's crew has now
ingested more THC than they've
ever ingested.
So, we're going to see Mathieu
at Motorino now.
MATHIEU PALOMBINO: Welcome
to Motorino.
And it's a great honor to
have the Frankies here.
FRANK CASTRONOVO: Mathieu
from Motorino--
FRANK FALCINELLI: Is a
classically trained chef.
FRANK CASTRONOVO:
He's like us.
He's more of a classically
trained chef.
We talk food.
And he knows more than
just making pizza.
And he's also similar
to us starting out.
Just kind of doing like very
simple things, but doing them
really well.
Just focusing on the quality of
the product and not trying
to do everything
that he knows.
FRANK FALCINELLI: We share the
same hospitality aesthetic
that we have as far as really
making people feel
comfortable.
A little bit more than buying
them a drink type of thing.
It's just real, you know--
you feel like you want
to be part of that.
And they want to be part of your
life while you're there
and away from there.
And it's just a bond
that carries on.
They call it roasted
mortadella,
but it's fried baloney.
It is.
That's fried fucking baloney.
Yep.
He throws the kitchen
sink at you.
That's the shit right there.
We're definitely doing a lot
of different projects.
But we're trying to keep the
pace steady and even.
"The Frankies Spuntino Kitchen
Companion and Cooking Manual."
That's going to be
out in June.
Somebody's got to be interested
in how to make the
damn gnocchi or how to make the
cavatelli or how to make
the white onion dressing.
It stays true to the fact that
it is a cooking manual.
It's meant to stay on the
kitchen counter at all times
so that's your go-to book.
Getting down with some
delicious, delicious--
Cheers.
Cheers man.
FRANK CASTRONOVO: We're
leaving Williamsburg.
And we're heading back
to Carroll Gardens.
FRANK FALCINELLI: We
kidnapped Mathieu.
The menu is very solid.
And all the dishes--
when you take a dish off, you
get like an uproar and say,
why are you taking that out?
Something basic, like
our meatballs.
That's everything
everybody wants
to know about, meatballs.
So let's make a meatball.
It can't be that hard.
FRANK CASTRONOVO: We're doing
meatballs Frankie style.
FRANK FALCINELLI: Parsley.
OK, two cups of bread.
Plenty.
FRANK CASTRONOVO: We're
making meatballs.
That is some nice looking
browning Frank Falcinelli.
You have to nice and slowly
brown everything with a lot of
love and care.
Tell you, chefs are like, don't
cook with olive oil,
don't cook high-- yeah, you
don't go over a certain
temperature.
Keep it like at 110, 120 like
Frank's doing right now.
All right, Frank.
Let's go grab a bottle
of wine.
FRANK FALCINELLI: Um, let
me read French braille.
Yes, it's very easy in braille.
Ooh, yeah.
FRANK CASTRONOVO: So, bascailly,
this is more like a
hamburger in tomato sauce with
garlic and Parmesan cheese.
It's really tasty like that.
So, here we go.
Now, you can see the meat just
reached tempreture, so it's
still really tender.
You just put a little
sauce around it.
Put sauce on top of it.
Put a little cheese on that.
FRANK FALCINELLI: It
looks good, man.
FRANK CASTRONOVO: It's fresh.
It just got cooked.
Holy shit.
You know people here say,
he's a fucking cook.
Or that's all he does,
but it's a lot more
serious than that.
We're putting food in
people's mouths.
And It's not really about how
great we can be and how
popular we can be and how
much money we can make.
It's really about truly
believing that what you're
doing is something good
and what you're doing
is the right thing.
Because when you die and you're
done, you're not taking
anything with you except what
you did with your soul, how
you enriched it.
And that's why I always feel
like what I'm doing is good
and right and true.
Truthfully, I'd love to go out
being known as like be
Grateful Dead of food.
That would be like
my ultimate.
That's what we're trying
to do here.
You came just in time for
the final doobie, man.