for long journeys to allow us to
begin the first ever crewed
missions beyond the Moon
into deep space.
We'll start by sending
astronauts to an asteroid for
the first time in history.
NEIL DEGRASSE TYSON: There's
an asteroid called Apophis
discovered a couple
of years ago.
That asteroid, on Friday the
13th in April in the year
2029, will come close enough
to Earth to dip below our
orbiting communications
satellites.
It'll be the biggest,
closest thing
ever in recorded history.
If it goes through what we call
the keyhole, which is
where the Earth's gravity is
just right, it will hit the
Earth seven years later.
If it goes through the center
of the keyhole, it will hit
the Pacific Ocean and create
waves of tsunamis that'll
blast clean the entire west
coast of North America.
MIKE GERNHARDT: It is a
statistical certainty that one
day, the Earth will get hit by a
large asteroid, whether that
be in 50 years or 100
million years.
NEIL DEGRASSE TYSON: We pay
for insurance against car
accidents, against damage to
your home, but no one has
organized what it would take
to get asteroid insurance.
In fact, the asteroid insurance
isn't to replace
your home if you get hit by an
asteroid, it would be to have
enough money to do something
about it in the first place.
SAUL ROSSER: My name's
Saul Rosser.
I'm the Operations Director at
Aquarius Reef Base, which is
NOAA's underwater habitat or
research station about four
miles off of Key Largo.
We house six people at a time
about 60 feet underwater.
During this mission, we have
three astronauts, a planetary
scientist, and two of our
technicians living underwater
to work on techniques for
exploring asteroids.
The first habitat was built in
1962 by Jacques Cousteau.
Now 50 years later,
this is the last
habitat on the sea floor.
And this is the only place you
can do this kind of thing.
So they're down there looking
at, how do you translate
across an asteroid, and how do
you work out the details of
moving along in a zero-G
environment, taking samples,
and working across the surface
of the asteroid?
BILL TODD: NEEMO is NASA's
undersea research program--
stands for NASA's Extreme
Environment Mission
Operations.
This particular mission is
focused on going to an
asteroid and living and working
on the surface of an
asteroid, which is a fairly
complex and difficult task.
What possibly could be more cool
and more exciting than
blending outer space and
undersea together in this is
extremely vivid, dynamic,
exciting environment that
there's also risk that you have
to manage, and you have
to really pay attention
to what you're doing?
For me, that's exciting.
MIKE GERNHARDT: So my name
is Mike Gernhardt.
I'm a NASA astronaut.
I've actually flown in space
four times, and I'm the
principal investigator of
the Neemo 16 mission.
So to be perfectly honest with
you, I had my heart set on
going back to the Moon, and I
was hoping to maybe have a
chance to be the crew
that did that.
So when I first heard we're
going to an asteroid and
stopping the lunar program,
that was a big
disappointment to me.
But rather than go off and cry
in the corner, I picked it up
with my team, and we started
working the details of what
it's going to be like to
work on an asteroid.
And it's turned out to be a very
fascinating, challenging
place to work that's really
moved our technologies forward
in a very positive way.
Working and doing space walks
on the asteroid is like the
worst combination of the dirt
and all of that of the Moon
but with no ground
reaction force.
On the Moon, you can walk.
You have ground reaction
force.
On a space station, we're
floating around but we have
pre-engineered translation paths
with handholds and foot
restraints and all these
kinds of things.
And we have none of that
on an asteroid.
So two and a half years ago,
no one had any idea of how
we're going to do
these things.
And we have very systematically
developed the
techniques and evaluated them,
and I think that we're well on
our way to understanding
what those
operations should be like.
So we probably won't land on an
asteroid, but we will touch
the asteroid with
a human hand.
And the way we will do that is
to be on a foot restraint
that's attached to the space
exploration vehicle, this
small vehicle that
flies around.
So we'll fly in close to the
asteroid and then reach in
with our foot on a foot
restraint and grab rocks or
deploy scientific instruments
on the asteroid.
So unlike the lunar landing, we
will probably not land and
attach to the asteroid.
We will fly around it and touch
it with our hands to get
the samples that we need to
understand the geology.
There are all sorts of minerals
on these asteroids
that we can't get
here on Earth.
There's rare earth metals.
There's platinum.
There's precious metals,
things like that.
Without a doubt, there are
economic benefits of mining,
and I think it will come.
It's not 10 years away.
I think it's way more
than that, but
you gotta start somewhere.
By going to an asteroid and
understanding their
characteristics, that informs us
with better techniques for
so-called planetary defense,
where we could either slightly
shift the course of the asteroid
at a distance far
enough away that it doesn't
hit the earth or possibly
percuss it into smaller
pieces.
We don't really know the right
answer for that, but the more
we know about asteroids, the
better informed we'll be to
defend the Earth against an
asteroid hit in the future.
NEIL DEGRASSE TYSON: Well, we're
smart enough, and we
have a space program, and we're
clever enough that we
never have to go extinct
by an asteroid.
We have more choices available
to us than
Tyrannosaurus Rex did.