We are at that time when a great transition takes place.
The society, the way we know it now, is changing very rapidly.
We have to go along with the change that is happening as oppose to fear it and resist it.
We have all heard about 2012, it's doomsday, the world will end, mankind will end.
Some people have got this idea that things will stop,
things will end in a catastrophe, but actually none of the philosophy is saying that.
The agenda seems to be trying to put a negative spin on it
to radiate fear out on the planet as oppose to love.
And love is the glue of the universe.
The more one loves and finds unity in this world and harmony,
the more the blessing will be when that time comes.
When you get up in the morning, the sun will be shining,
it will be just like another normal day.
But what might happen, I feel, could be a great change in consciousness.
A prophesied acceleration of both technology and consciousness is occurring right now
which is right on time with what's been decoded from the Mayan information.
All shall benefit, on different levels, even the unawakened will benefit,
because that's how the universe elevates souls.
What is getting ready to happen is a positive thing,
it is a step forward in an evolution, it's an awakening in consciousness.
If we have a good look at our solar system and how it works,
the moon goes around the earth, the earth is rotating and orbiting the sun.
Now, our sun in turn is orbiting Sirius.
In the great orbit of our two suns, we have turned the corner from the dark ages.
Now they are pulling towards each other, bringing us to a higher consciousness.
So, we are really in just a great time in history to be living.
It is just an amazing time.
The great changes that we will see with our own eyes will be stupendous.
The new world of love is coming.
Life on earth is affected by many cycles,
the light of the day
and the dark of the night
and our yearly cycle of the four seasons.
The stars in the sky are linked to life on earth and greatly influence our existence.
That, which is above, is the same as that, which is below.
As above, so below.
But what if there is a greater cycle that takes thousands of years,
which influences human consciousness?
According to many cultures, much like the seasons that are familiar to us,
human kind undergoes a similar cycle in which consciousness expands and contracts.
It results in great ages of enlightenment and dark ages of misery.
Different cultures refer to this cycle by different names,
including the Yuga Cycle or The Ages of Man.
But one thing is certain,
these cycles were known to almost every ancient culture throughout the globe.
The Hindu Yuga Cycle consists of four ages;
the Kali Yuga or the Dark Age,
Dwapara Yuga, Treta Yuga
and the Satya Yuga, the Golden Age.
During the Golden Age, human consciousness is at its peak
where unity is celebrated and life is lived in peace, love and harmony.
In the Silver and Bronze Ages, our consciousness begins its descend to its lowest point,
the Dark or Iron Age,
in which suffering and ignorance is at its peak and humans are divided and at war.
That is our current Age.
Then the cycle makes its way up again to the Golden Age.
These four Ages influence the rise and fall of civilizations across the globe.
It is believed that we are at that time
when the Dark Age is coming to an end and the Bronze Age begins.
And the cross over it taking place during the galactic alignment
on December 21st 2012.
The mainstream media throughout the globe
depicts this date as the end of the world
in which catastrophic events will extinguish all life on Earth.
The end of the world theory is based on the Mayan Long Count Calendar,
which ends exactly on 21st December 2012.
Although many claim that the Mayans have predicted the end of the world,
there is no evidence to suggest so.
The Mayan Calendar simply resets on this date,
as one cycle ends and a new one begins.
Many believe that the marker left by the Mayan's
indicates a great change in consciousness
as we leave the Zodiac Age of Pisces and enter the Age of Aquarius.
The date has become the most anticipated day in history
and while many are anticipating it with love,
others anticipate it with fear.
What were the ancients trying to tell us?
Is it the end of the world?
Or is it a time of great change in human consciousness?
Man know thyself and you will know the universe and all its Gods.
So when one understand that we are the microcosm of the macrocosm,
the stars that go above and around in various different cycles
then we understand the connection between us and the God.
Individual people by themselves, groups, societies,
the mood of the whole planet - can all be altered, can all be changed
and the reason for that is because the planet, group's, societies
aren't what they appear to be.
They are just another level consciousness.
We are all consciousness.
If consciousness changes to a higher vibration, which I feel is happening at 2012,
then the society, the way we know it now, will not be there anymore.
The old has to go, the new has to come.
Religious traditions are looking forward to this time,
because they know that it will bring
much peace and love and joy and wisdom to mankind.
You become aware of what you really are,
you become aware that you are one with God and that you are God.
Individual little elements or atoms of that devine.
And when one realizes the God within us,
he can see the God within everyone.
Just trust in love, everything else comes.
The universe knows what we need and the solar system knows where its going.
The sun is flying through the heaven taking us to new place,
we can rest assure that we are in good hands.
We have all heard about 2012, it's doomsday,
the world will end, mankind will end,
comets come down and who knows what.
Some of the things to do with 2012 that are out there
are quiet contrasting, aren't they?
To say the least.
People are looking forward to terrible things happening,
there is a lot of fear out there.
Some people have got this idea that things will stop,
things will end in a catastrophe,
but actually none of the philosophy is saying that.
They are saying it's the beginning of something new.
The negative things out there
would probably be better of discarded.
I think that the 21st of December will be an ordinary day in real terms,
except we will all go "Phew" if we make it, okay.. now what?
Oops, it's the 22nd.
Is that the first day of something new?
Or is this a gradual process that's actually been happening?
Well, December the 21st date is one that we don't have to
get ourselves tight up in a knot about,
some of the Mayan information is saying it's actually a window of time
and it started maybe 2007 and is extending out to 2015.
And the clock struck one and everything was sorted,
its never ever going to happen.
It's a gradual gradual process, it cannot possible happen,
suddenly I ate this cookie and all of a sudden "Wow, it all happened."
It's just nonsense.
You won't get anyone to touch someone on the head
and everything will be completely clear.
None of these things are going to take place,
it's going to be an ordinary day, that's what I suspect.
On 21 December 2012, when you get up in the morning,
the sun will be shining or it's cloudy... whatever, and nothing has changed.
It is just another day and you will think 'Where was all this doomsday talk,
comets come down, where is it?'
It doesn't affect us in that way.
It will be just like another normal day. You have nothing to fear.
But what might happen, I feel,
could be a great change in consciousness.
What is getting ready to happen is a positive thing,
it is a step forward in an evolution, it's an awakening in consciousness.
This beautiful awakening is quite a positive thing
so it is definitely not something that we should have any fear about.
The society, the way we know now it now,
will not be there anymore or is changing very rapidly.
People don't believe in the old system anymore.
You are not out chasing the so called dream
that you have been brainwashed to believe you should be anymore.
You are actually doing what your inner self dictates to you.
People start to become aware of who they are
and they start to realize that there is more to life
and they really do want more but not in material things,
they want more in terms of peace and love and no more wars
and no more hunger and starving and all these situations.
So, people are starting to realize that there is a community
of humanity out there.
There is a plan to take us into super consciousness.
Every one of us, for a short brief period of time.
A super consciousness is we merge with the divine,
merge with all consciousness,
for a short period of time we know everything,
we come into the oneness.
We are all facets, experiential facets,
Individual little elements or atoms of that divine.
We are experiencing kind of a tsunami right now in consciousness
and it's about ready, in my opinion, to turn into a tidal wave of awareness.
The Mayans are teaching that beautiful things will happen, wonderful things,
great changes in the consciousness of mankind.
Certainly there is a consciousness shift going on.
A prophesied acceleration of both technology and consciousness
is occurring right now,
which is right on time with what's been decoded from the Mayan information.
The Mayans know that the universe is a loving place,
there is chaos and there is love in the universe
and the love is always correcting the chaos.
So, whatever happens in 2012 will be for the advancement of mankind.
All shall benefit, on different levels,
even the unawakened will benefit,
because that's how the universe elevates souls.
We are choosing between spirit consciousness and matter consciousness
and those choices will influence what direction we take after a transformation.
What is happening at this moment is discussed in all the bibles and mythologies of the world.
The ancient ones knew the cycles, the Hindus call this cycle the Yuga cycle of 24,000 years
in which we go through the Gold, Silver, Bronze and Iron Age
just like we go through the yearly Summer, Winter, Summer, Winter
and the daily night and day.
So we do this in the 24,000 year backward precessional cycle
and we are at what the prophecies say is the time of the harvest
the time of the end,
the end of this wave of evolution of mankind
where certain ones ascend, awaken,
remember who they are and reclaim their divinity.
We have to go along with the change that is happening
as oppose to fear it and resist it.
And when we go into fear and loathing, our body shuts down,
our chakras, our consciousness.
It's possible people in that frame of mind could even get left behind.
On the other hand if they open up and accept it and become a part of it
and they become part of an amazing transformation
that is getting ready to occur.
What is really in fact going to happen is the Galactic Alignment.
In two respects,
if you look at the galactic plane, if you imagine that the galaxy
is a very very thin dish in the heavens.
Well our Sun it's in a cycle of 24,000 years, called precession of the equinoxes
and during that cycle it spends 12,000 years above the equator
of the milky way galaxy, the galactic plane,
and 12,000 years below.
So, our Sun is now sitting below the galactic plane and its popping its head through
and its passing that galactic plane right now as we speak
and on the 21 December 2012 it will be more over then under.
The other aspect of this is that the equinoxes have been migrating
around the heavens through the signs of the zodiac for 24,000 years.
The vernal equinox occurs on the 21st of March.
Now, at the moment on the 21st of March is actually Pisces,
because its the sign that appears on the horizon on the 21st of March,
that sign, is the sign that we are in.
Now we have been in that sign,
the Sun has been in it at the equinox for 2,000 years.
Now it is right at the end of Pisces and the new sign coming through is Aquarius
and the Sun will be in Aquarius for 2,000 years.
Each age is about approximately 2,000 years.
Each age represents a kind of a level of consciousness and at each shift,
there is a shift in consciousness.
That's the symbol for Aquarius, so the age of Aquarius is happening right now.
The age of Aquarius represents a period where instead of spiritually speaking,
instead of worshiping the single God or Guru
or martyr on the cross or whatever you want to have.
Instead of focusing your energies in that way,
the age of the Aquarius tends to look for truth in one another,
in each other, in each individual person.
That's a big shift in the consciousness,
it also represents the onset of technology, but hopefully clean technology.
The Piscean age, is an age of division.
The Age of the Piscean has been true to its name,
we have been very divided.
Coloured people, different languages, different cultures,
different concepts and ideas, we are so divided, its horrific.
We can look forward to an age of harmony with Aquarius,
a greater level  of understanding and unity of consciousness.
And Aquarius is an air sign, it's a fixed air.
So it's nature is quiet different to the mutable water of Pisces.
We have been in a mutable cross for 2,000 years.
The equinoxes and they have been in the mutable signs of Pisces,
this is the March equinox.
Virgo the other equinox
and the solstices have been in Gemini, the solstice of June, June the 21st
and Sagittarius, December 21st.
Now what is happening as the equinoxes move around that clock
and they come into the fixed signs.
What is going to happen is this, the vernal equinox will be in Aquarius,
the autumnal equinox will be in Leo, which is fixed fire.
The solstices will go to Taurus, fixed earth
and the Winter solstice will go to Scorpio, fixed water.
Now, these four signs are the fixed signs.
So the holy cross, the divine cross in the skies will be in situated
in their most natural home - the fixed signs.
Well in this age it have been in Pisces, which is mutable,
and before that it was Aries, which is cardinal.
So, now it gets to be fixed and that is the alignment.
That is what is taking places, because those signs there are very very powerful,
the fixed signs.
They are very powerful in transformation of the human consciousness
and in the bible and in the holly books,
they are the lion, the bull, the man and the eagle.
In Revelation the God is described as having the face of the man,
the face of the bull, the face of the eagles and the face of the lion.
Well that is the fixed signs of the Zodiac, they are going home.
The equinoxes and the solstices are going home
and that is what we are looking forward to.
That is what it means, there is big things happening with 2012.
We are getting ready to evolve at a very fast rate.
The reason this happens is because the center of the galaxy
puts out pulses and their waves.
The reason it does that, is the same reason a cell in your body
puts out vibration within that cell
to make sure that the cell as a whole
is operating on the same page.
To make sure those of us on the perimeter of the galaxy
are in tune with the evolution of the whole galaxy.
Now, I feel, that if you look at these massive transformations
in the evolution of life on the planet,
it is always a positive shift.
It wasn't like at one of the intervals, that all of a sudden
life became more retarded
and started de-evolving or going in the opposite direction.
If there is a wave of consciousness
that is sent out from the centre of the galaxy
and we pass through one of these waves,
then the consciousness on the planet as a whole
begins to expand and vibrate at a higher frequency.
Evolve much faster then previously before.
There is what's called Yugas and Yugas means world ages
and it starts of with what's called Satya Yuga, which means Golden,
then it devolves into Treta, which means Silver.
Then we  go to Dwapara and this means Bronze
and currently we are in the Kali Yuga, which means Iron.
These cycles of Ages go around continuously.
The Golden Age last for 1,768 million years.
That humans live for 100,000 years, that gold is something you eat of
and maybe just discard, like a paper plate today.
The point is that they are very highly advanced souls.
The human earth planet, under the Satya Yuga - Golden Age,
is only occupied by Mystics, serious Yogis.
It is described that the demonic's live on another planet.
So we are separated by space.
Than as we move in to the Treta Yuga - Silver Age, it become 1,296 years,
people live for 10,000 year, they eat of Silver.
and now the demons live on another country on the same planet.
the only the only thing separating is ocean.
Then we come into Dwapara Yuga Bronze age, which is 864,000 years,
or half the length of the Golden Age,
people live for a thousand years,
they have good and bad in the same family.
You can see in the old testaments, that is Bronze age culture, Dwapara Yuga,
so they are living for a thousand years - all the old testament folks -
Noah or Adam - all lived for a longer time than we do.
And then we come into Iron age,
in Iron age we going to live 100, good and bad is in each and every
single one of us, it's not separate now. It is in us.
And we have to become conscious of not to 'fan the flame' of the negative actions.
We have to take some very strict codes of behavior, if you're serious,
I mean you can do anything you want on Earth, but if you are serious,
if you want a ticket  out of the material world, based on this,
we might like the Earth planet, but it's a prison.
We can expect in 2012 to enjoy a much more harmonious world
and high consciousness, because where the sun is taking us
in the 24,000 year processional cycle, is - back to the Dwapara Yuga.
Certain Hindu scholars say that we have already entered Dwapara Yuga
in the 1700's, so about 200-300 years ago,
whereas others tend to say that the Dwapara Yuga has not began yet,
we are still at the end of Kali Yuga.
Nonetheless, in all the traditions, we are at that time
when a great transition takes place.
A wonderful transition, and all the religious traditions are looking forward
to this time, because they know that it will bring much peace
and love and joy and wisdom to mankind.
This is a cycle which continues in its nature and behavior,
but does never come back to the same place.
So we are always growing with this, the feathered serpent, our solar system,
we just have to trust that feathered serpent takes us to greener pastures,
in fact the Mayans tells us that it will, because on the 21st December 2012,
where this galactic alignment is going to occur, then we shall start newer influences
and different influences that we have not seen for a long time since our awakening,
cause we are awakening.
And the dead that shall arise that the scriptures are talking about
"The dead shall rise",
that's not dead in terms of in a tomb and then all of the sudden
you pop up out of the tomb as literal as Christianity is trying to teach,
its talking about - we.. that we have been dead in sleep fullness,
we have been sleeping.
Now, as we learn this stuff, and we remember the symbols now
cause we know what these mean,
they've been lying dormant in the winter of unconsciousness for thousands of years,
and the Romans went destroying the temples of Egypt and defacing their monuments
and the hieroglyphs that they didn't understand,
and the Christians they destroyed the Mediterranean's cultural,
spiritual, hermetic heritage.
Alexandrian the Library was burnt,
in Jerusalem the Temple of the Initiates there was destroyed.
Carthage - you know, she snuffed out all the lights so that she could rule
in the fictional world for thousands of years.
Now as we awaken and we reclaim our dominion, this science is essential.
Astrology is the science of "As Above So Below".
And it is the beginning of understanding of who you are.
When you realize that you are this and you look up and you go
"Twinkle twinkle little star how I wonder what you are?",
and you know what the stars are, they are fountains of life.
Firstly, we have Solar System, Sol being the Sun,
the male energetic in our solar system, and all the planets are regarded as feminine,
generally speaking, dancing with the masculine.
We, as human beings with the human eye can only see the seventh planet.
Five planets, actually - Sun and Moon.
The external planets, or the planets in the outer solar system
cannot be seen by the human eyesight without an optical instrument.
Those seven planets are influencing us daily. And, if you want the proof,
go to your newspaper, and you will see in the weather area "Sunrise" - "Sunset",
"Moonrise" - "Moonset", and in a special little box
the rising of Venus, Mars, Saturn, Jupiter... They are there. It's there.
Now, they've been trying to eradicate astrology,
because the grand Christian church doesn't accept it.
But, actually, they are the only group in the world that doesn't.
The Jews are based in astrology,
you can see the remnants of it in the Christian church with the twelve apostles,
they have replaced the houses of the Zodiac.
And if you go into a Hindu temple, when you firstly go in, on a left,
you'll see twelve constellations as deities,
when you go all the way around the temple
to see all the other persons in the temple, then there's the seven planets.
If it's a bright sunny day when you wake up, it's having a good effect.
If the clouds get between you and the sun, it filters that good effect.
Now for plant life, aquatic or tidal behavior, all feminine life on the world planet
is governed by the Moon.
That's why we call it the Menstrual cycle from the word Moonstral cycle,
and the other word we say is a Luna cycle - Luna-tic.
And the law knows, the police know, and every authority knows
that as the moon moves into its full position,
it has an esoteric effect on humanity.
Many, many more stupid acts will be occurring around the full moon.
Do they affect us? Absolutely. The Sun and the Moon are the strongest.
Sirius B goes around Sirius A, and it takes 49.9 years.
It is so heavy, that a teaspoon of it would be hundreds of tons.
It is spinning on its axis 23 times every minute. This is a sun, this is a star guys,
like it's that heavy... imagine how heavy it is!
And it is so powerful magnetically, that it directly affects our Earth.
In 1989, when this little fella here,
this very heavy hard little fella - when he passed between
Sirius A and our Sun with its Earth going around here,
the spin rate slowed down in '89, losing a full second per day
for a period of several weeks before the event,
and then sped up gaining a second per day for several weeks after the event.
Take note of that men, that's a star that is 8 light years away.
It slowed and sped our Earth.
If we have a good look at our solar system and how it works,
for instance the moon goes around the earth,
the earth in turn is rotating and orbiting the sun.
So, it takes 365 days to go around the Sun.
Now our sun in turn is orbiting Sirius.
Sirius being the brightest star in the sky and in the sector of Cancer right near Gemini,
it is in a binary with our star and every 24,000 years we go around each other
in a clockwise motion.
Sirius and our Sun have been going away from each other
for the last couple of thousand years, and now they've turned the corner,
so they are heading towards one another.
As we reach the outer limits of that orbit,
that elliptical orbit with our Sun and Sirius,
this is where the Iron age is, the Golden age is when they are close to each other
and as they separate they go through Silver and the Bronze to the Iron age.
Well, that affects the consciousness of mankind.
Because we have 100% consciousness when the stars are close to each other,
the consciousness falls to 75%, 50% and 25%.
We have not enjoyed full consciousness for a long time.
And many of the gifts and abilities and powers that we once had.
As we have turned the corner in the great orbit of our two suns - Sirius and our Sun,
as we have turned the corner and they are hurtling towards each other now,
we have turned corner from the dark ages.
We have come out of the dark period,
because the suns have been pulled apart and their influence is weakened
and therefore our consciousness has dropped, and we are in the dark ages.
Now they're pulling towards each other, bringing us to a higher consciousness.
And that's nature.
Nature brings us, ascends, helps us and carries us through ascension process,
so it's all loving.
Even though there is chaos, and there's fear and anguish
and chaotic events occurring around us in our world,
even though that is happening, that's really just the remnants of the dark ages.
So we've turned the corner!
The two suns are hurtling towards each other at great speeds now,
and that's the beautiful part of where we are.
We've turned the corner.
So we are really in just a great time in history to be living, it's just amazing time.
The great changes that we will see with our own eyes will just be stupendous.
We are actually just simply locked into a series of cycles.
And it's the duty of every human being, when there're ready...
to discovery their own awareness, to take control of themselves.
In the book of Daniel of the bible it says that in this time,
many will come to an accurate knowledge of the truth
and they will whiten their robes, and they will turn to the truth.
But it also mentions that many will just go off into the darkness
and continue on the path of darkness.
It's true we are in the dark age right now,
but we are getting ready to come out of it.
And those who identify with the darkness,
those who feel at home and comfortable with it,
yeah they want to keep it that way, they don't want things to change.
They are afraid of light coming in, they are afraid of people waking up.
If everyone starts to find out, what 2012 is really about,
then that's going to accelerate the process even more,
they are going to start catching onto the true of what's happening,
so to suppress the information is part of the 2012 agenda.
The media portrays 2012 as doomsday.
The world will end, mankind will end,
comets will come down, and who knows what.
The agenda seems to be trying to put a negative spin on it.
Britney spears: "Keep on dancing until the world ends,
if you feel it, let it happen, keep on dancing till the world ends"
Song: "Looks like we made it..."
Voice: "Get it on for the end of the world.
New Lynx 2012: The Final Edition."
"A growing number of Americans getting ready for doomsday.
You think that's crazy? Right after the break,
spend a couple of minutes listening to our next guest,
and see what you think then."
"Well, you may have your car, lawn mower
and your family junk stuffed in your garage,
but for one Arizona man it is the staging area for doomsday.
And he is not the only one.
The supplies and tools he needs to survive the Apocalypse,
whichever way it may come."
"People preparing for, basically, the end of days,
and extreme doomsday bunkers.
Jack Jobe is joining us now with more about that."
"Well, there is a phenomena right now among people,
especially because of year 2012,
to take more advantage of being prepared for doomsday-like disasters"
"Thousands are now on high alert, stock-piling food
and building underground bunkers - even in Australia.
And companies are cashing in - they're selling survival items,
like gas masks, nuclear protection suits,
and even food and water tablets"
The obvious question comes - why would anyone want
to take something that isn't necessarily negative
and, even worse, something that is actually a positive thing,
and turn it into a negative thing?
Using it as a means to radiate fear out on the planet, as opposed to love?
The people who got the hooks into this information - disinformation,
misinformation - have really hoodwinked humanity's progress.
So, in the movie for instance, 2012, there's fear and loathing,
and this is so far away from what the potential is.
Cause if you can radiate fear that can keep that frequency,
which is expanding and growing higher, contracted,
that to me suits the 2012 agenda.
Well with regard to 2012, the media is not the place
source for information, it will be misinformation,
and it will be negative... and it is. It's very negative.
And, of course, they are driven by fear, and they love fear,
and the people who control those stations and those networks,
they are happy to generate fear.
"Clips warning viewers about December 21st 2012,
that's the date that many doomsday prophets are claiming
the world as we know it will end.
My next guest Jim Durdan works with survival group
which is planning for this apocalypse.
Jim, how will it happen will it be an object from outer space,
will we destroy ourselves in a nuclear holocaust?
How will it happen in 2012?"
"Well, based on Mayan calendar and the Dresden Codex,
the Egyptians and Mayans had the end times of 2012
as an apocalyptic event."
"Their calendar predicts that 21st of December is when the world will end.
And while that won't stop the most of us from making plans for Christmas,
there are tens of thousands of believers who are preparing for the worst."
"According to one ancient prophecy, the end of the world is only weeks away,
so - are you ready?
It's the ancient calendar that ends on December 21 this year,
in other words - doomsday."
It's not the Mayans telling us this business,
it's westerners interpreting what they think the Mayans were saying.
They see a stela, they see a piece of carving and then they start to interpret.
What a joke. What an absolute joke.
There's been a lot of co-opted, incorrect information out there.
And it's deliberate.
Major media destroy information.
If we had a mainstream media that even vaguely associated itself
with the true meaning of the word Journalism,
none of this would have been possible.
But, the same people that control the politicians, own the media.
And so, the media is not there, just like governments,
to serve the interests and inform the people.
is there to tell the people what those who own the media,
want them to believe.
They see this consciousness happening and they are fighting it
with everything they've got.
And so they are trying to turn it into a negative thing
as opposed to a positive thing which is really what's occurring.
If you take the Mayan perspective,
the Mayans have got a totally different perspective to what we think,
to what we have been taught, but they believe that good things are coming.
"The Mayans themselves never said that world would come to an end.
The only guy who did, the first guy was Jose Arguelles,
who later renamed himself Valum Votan the ancient Mayan God,
cause he turned into a reincarnation of it,
and he in 1988 wrote a book called The Maya Factor,
but the Mayans themselves have said the complete opposite,
they had left behind carvings in stone, saying that there would be
good things happening in the future,
like such and such day after 21st of December."
And the fear for mankind is basically the fear of death,
which we shouldn't have,
because if we continued to teach our original nature religion
and we didn't stop in the advent of Christianity,
we would still know, we would know that death of our body
is just a non-event, because the soul is immortal,
but because we have lost this wisdom and true religion
about the soul and its immortal nature, with fictional religions,
we have fear of death.
There was never fear of death.
The fear sets up a victim - perpetrator - and rescuer cycle,
and we get trapped in that victim mentality or perpetrator or rescuer,
a rescuer is just another victim.
And there's nothing more debilitating, more controlling
and limiting than the "Victim Mentality."
We are encouraged by this manipulation throughout our life
to see ourselves as victims to blame someone else
"Oh, I'm the victim, I'm in this situation because of A, B, C, D...," and on it goes.
And when we are in that state, we are going to stay in that state,
cause when you think you are a victim, the victim vibe goes out,
the victim circumstance goes in.
When you say "Hey, I'm not a victim, I'm in control of my life,
I've created these circumstances I don't like,
therefore I can create circumstances I do."
At that point victim mentality is gone, victim circumstances stop being attracted,
and suddenly people come into your life who were just the people you need
to get you out of the circumstances you don't like,
and if you don't realize what's happening, and most of us don't at the time,
we say "Oh my, mate, I was so lucky - this fella came into my life
at just the right time, this person... I couldn't believe it, amazing luck!"
No. You pulled them in, because your state of being had changed,
and you synced with what you needed to get out of that situation.
We are so in control of our destiny, it's unbelievable,
and yet, billions are persuaded they are not,
and therefore they create a very different reality.
So, if we are in fear, we can attract a reflection of fear.
The fear is a lack of being all powerful,
and so being anything less than an infinite love puts us into a state of fear.
One of first things we subject to is fear.
"You can just fall over and hurt yourself." "I could bleed."
"You don't want to put your hands in that pot, it's too hot."
"There's sharks in the water." All those things - fear.
And this is the greatest stick that anyone can give to controlling a human being.
It's called slavery. Any other name you can call, but nonetheless,
if a person does not have freedom, they have to become some sort of slave.
What we don't want to become is slaves to the media.
There is a machine that's pumping out every day.
They say two things about the paper you can rely on, the newspaper:
The price of the newspaper and the date.
Those two things you can rely on, and then they say "You better check the date!"
This is the way we become, our consciousness is controlled - we wake up
in the morning the alarm goes,
we have X amount of time before we have to be at work.
We know if we leave a few minutes earlier
we will probably have an easier traveling time.
This is all fear. All of it is fear.
I don't want to lose my job. If I lose my job, if I lose my house,
my wife will leave me, my children... It's all fear.
We all live in a world, which, take a step back, deep breath,
look at it again, is utterly, bloody insane.
And we are asked to believe, and so many people do,
that we are somehow at the cutting edge of human evolution.
We are nowhere near the edge of what is possible,
and what is there to be known.
But the norms are very powerful.
Especially, when from cradle to grave, we are constantly manipulated
and confused with contradictory information,
and we are pressured to believe it,
otherwise we get ridiculed or condemned for being different.
"Just look at us. Everything is backwards, everything is upside down.
Doctors destroy health, lawyers destroy justice, universities destroy knowledge,
governments destroy freedom, the major media destroy information
and religions destroy spirituality." - Michael Ellner.
That is where we are!
If you are tricked into fearing by the media
and people talking of weapons of mass destruction,
and all this over and over again,
If you are tricked into going into the fear camp,
then what is actually happening, you are relating to the universe
through your ego, which is easily controlled and easily deceived.
By keeping us involved with fear, it will be very difficult for us to,
let's say, ascend - that's the popular word for that.
The people who control our society, don't want us to go into bliss,
because if our chakras and our Kundalini and other things were all awake,
and we become more divine-conscious, as a super-conscious in awareness,
they have no control of you.
If there is nothing to fear except fear itself, and you drop that fear,
then you have to be in bliss.
If you choose love, the ego subsides,
you wake up and start seeing the reality of what's really going on around you.
The ego only has a very small vision of what actually is taking place and occurring,
and an individual and an ego is very easily controlled,
but a person who is awakening, a person who becomes enlightened,
can't be controlled at all,
in fact there is an old saying that an enlightened being plays with the universe
the way that a child plays with a ball.
Because they see the reality of everything,
they can't be tricked, they can't be fooled.
It's like a spell has been cast on the human mind,
to disconnect us from the full magnitude of who we are,
and the great news is the people who are in control of breaking that spell, is us -
not some external force, us. It's just a choice.
We are now at a time, a wonderful time, when balance is returning.
You just have to have faith - to trust in love - to choose love and to trust in love.
And that that will end up taking you into a much better place.
If you continue to operate out of fear, and continue to operate through the ego,
then you'll continue to be controlled and you'll continue to be scared,
have the shit scared out of you,
and you'll continue to not have a clue about what's going on in the world
and around you, or even inside you for that matter.
The more responsible we become for our actions,
the more harmonious the world will be.
As people begin to awaken and take on responsibility,
we can expect to see a much more harmonious world.
The main thing you have to fear is fear itself.
If you get sucked into fear, it's going to put you out of harmony
with actually what's happening, as opposed to part of what's happening.
If you want to be a part of what's happening,
then you will not obsess with fear.
Governments destroy freedom. This is the great one.
If, you know, people are new to this, this is the first big step:
Governments are not there to serve the people - governments are there
to serve those that control the governments and enslave the people -
that's what they're there for!
Once we realize that,
then a lot of dots start to connect.
"The very word "secrecy" is repugnant in a free and open society;
and we are as a people inherently and historically opposed to secret societies,
to secret oaths and to secret proceedings."
"Its preparations are concealed, not published.
Its mistakes are buried, not headlined.
Its dissenters are silenced, not praised.
No expenditure is questioned, no rumor is printed,
no secret is revealed."
"For we are opposed around the world by a monolithic and ruthless conspiracy
that relies primarily on covert means for expanding its sphere of influence-
on infiltration instead of invasion, on subversion instead of elections,
on intimidation instead of free choice."
"It is a system which has conscripted vast human and material resources
into the building of a tightly knit, highly efficient machine that combines military,
diplomatic, intelligence, economic, scientific and political operations."
It's supposed to be a hidden elite, which own and run the corporations,
they own the banks, they own the media,
so they have got total and absolute control of everything - just about.
They control all the major important institutions of the world.
They subvert organizations, they infiltrate organizations,
they are very very active, they send spies all around the world.
They hack our telephones and listen to our conversations-
we are being spied on by these families.
I'm talking about the real owners now, the real owners-
the big wealthy business interest that control things
and make all the important decisions.
Forget the politicians - the politicians are put there to give you the idea
that you have freedom of choice. You don't.
You have no choice. You have owners. They own you. They own everything.
They own all the important land, they own and control the corporations,
they have long since bought and paid for the Senate, the Congress,
the state houses, city halls, they have the judges in their back pocket,
and they own all the big media companies so they control just about all the news
and information you get to hear, they got you by the balls!
They spend billions of dollars every year lobbying to get what they want.
Well, we know what they want - they want more for themselves
and less for everybody else.
They are not in the spotlight, so to speak,
they are not the world leaders that we see, but they are something behind that.
Leaders come and go, don't they? They are always transient.
But these people do not come and go, they're always there,
and they run the cogs and machine at the highest level - over the ages.
They go back a long, long, long way.
And so they maintain their bloodlines and keep a lot of power and wealth,
and as they inter-marry, they amass more wealth
and more power - against other families.
They own this fucking place, it's a big club, and you ain't in it!
You and I are not in the big club.
By the way it's the same big club that used to beat you over the head
with all day long when they tell you what to believe,
all day long beating you over the head in their media telling you what to believe,
what to think and what to buy.
The table is tilted folks, the game is rigged, and nobody seems to notice,
nobody seems to care.
Good, honest, hardworking people,
white colour, blue colour - doesn't matter what colour shirt you have on.
Good, honest, hardworking people continue, these are people of modest beings,
continue to elect these rich cock suckers who don't give a fuck about them,
they don't give a fuck about you, they don't give a fuck about you,
they don't care about you, at all, at all, at all...
These elite families call themselves, the Illuminati.
Their symbols are always, you'll have an eye or a pyramid or something like that.
that these are bad symbols, these are beautiful symbols
but by using these beautiful symbols they have given them a bad name.
So people associate the pentagram and the hexagram with satanic symbols,
well they are not they are just nature symbols.
We know you are ruthless, we know you are evil.
To David Rockefeller, to the Rothschild representative here,
to the queen of the Netherlands, to all of you.
We tell you, you are not our queens, you are not our kings, you are not our Gods,
we do not belong to you.
We are not your slaves. We stand as free humans have stood since the beginning
of time against the strong man, against the thugs, against the bullies.
We will defeat your world government.
The Illuminati are after world control. They want a New World Order.
A New World Order, a world where the rule of law, not the law of the jungle,
governs the conduct of nations.
When we are successful and we will be,
we have a real chance at this New World Order.
An order in which a credible united nations can use its peace-keeping role
to fulfill the promise and vision of the UN's founders.
I had planned another closing message,
but I feel compelled to say what I am about to say.
Now I risk sounding like a conspiracy theorist.
But it's no longer a theory, what I am about to say is fact.
The secret organizations of the world power elite are no longer secret.
They have planned and are now leading us into a one world communist government.
This is terrorism of the most worst kind, brought on you by our own government.
And it's not going to be a nice New World Order.
It's going to be a fascist dictatorship.
It's going to be hell on earth. Martial law, concentration camps,
but they just want their workers.
They want a very very wealthy rich class and workers.
No smart people, no bottom class, just slaves and them.
But I will tell you what they don't want.
They don't want a population of citizens capable of critical thinking.
They don't want well informed, well educated people capable of critical thinking.
They are not interested in that.
That does not help them. That's against their interest.
If a cow were to someday wake up out in the pasture and realize its fate.
That it's going to end up in a McDonalds hamburger one day.
If it had that understanding, do you think it continued to stay out there and eat grass?
or do whatever the farmer wanted it to do. Hell no!
But as long as that farmer can keep that cow in cow consciousness,
that's not going to happen.
They want to retain the status quo, the way things are,
because they already have the control and so they want to maintain that.
We hear about a whole lot of conspiracies and perhaps a lot of them are true.
Like the idea of fluoride in your water, it affects the pineal gland.
Perhaps that was a deliberate strategy in order to stop people rising their consciousness.
I can give you a long list but you know the food we eat,
the way we are educated, what we are told to believe, all of this plays a part.
They keep us dumbed down. They keep us unaware.
The world has been turned into a maze of confusion.
And its done to keep us from the simple truths.
Because complexity is there to stop us finding those simple truths.
But when you connect the dots, between apparently unconnected people,
situations, organizations, world events, you start to see how they fit together.
Suddenly, this bewildering, confusing world
starts to take on a much clearer dimension.
Because, only by connecting the dots, over, as you will see today,
a vast range of subjects and situations and people,
can you start to see why the world is upside down.
Why it is as it is, and crucially, behind that complexity,
those smoke screens of complexity, is an amazing revelation
of who we are and the nature of life.
When we start to realize, that far from being Ethel Jones, or Billy Smith,
we are all that is, has been, and ever will be.
That is the difference between who we are,
and who we are manipulated to believe we are.
And obviously we are suffering from the effects of the dark ages,
loss of consciousness and as we awaken in these days, which we are
because the spiraling sun is taking us to greener pastures.
I don't think the mainstream media wants everyone to realize
that there is a mass awakening taking place.
But yet everywhere I go and everything I see points to it.
Everywhere I go there is this enormous amount of enthusiasm
and interest in yoga, meditation, not just eastern things but philosophy.
Workshops and things that are about self-awareness.
People are opening their eyes and seeing what's been done to them.
They are finally seeing that they have been sodomized for such a long time
and they are not free.
Just because we have got the freedom to choose what color milkshake
we are going to have, what flavor, does not mean we are free.
That's an illusion, you are not free, it's a police state.
Now, people are waking up to that because they realize that it's just a service.
The banks have a service and that service is war.
The scientist and big pharma have a service and that is to drug you.
Because drugs cost a lot of money and they want money.
The governments are there to deceive you
and to take money from you, via taxes.
The world is turned upside down and people are confused
and the reason this is happening is because of these Illuminati families.
They have done this to us, its deception.
Society has allowed itself to be dumbed down.
I mean we are just as much to blame as they are for allowing it to happen.
But unfortunately there is an awakening happening now
and people are starting to wake up.
People are becoming more conscious of the fact
that we need to change our habits and improve and take responsibility.
That force which is contracting awareness and consciousness,
I think it's starting to get a little bit nervous and a little bit afraid.
Its worried and because it seems like it's up scaling things.
As this consciousness revolution is starting to occur,
its upping the anti on its side of the scale too.
It sees this awakening happening and its very threatened by it
and it does not want it to happen.
So greater and greater measures are taken.
The elites and the power families realize that they are
losing their grip on the system.
The system is collapsing.
So they naturally like every organism are trying to prolong their existence,
therefore they try to keep fear out there and fear out there
but a lot of people are just not buying into it
and the reason being is because our sun is bringing us into the higher essences,
the higher consciousness and therefore we refuse to go back,
we can't, we can just climb up now.
What was a kind of a willing complacent dumbing down,
is now getting ready to turn into a big conflict between the forces in control
who want to keep everybody as they were,
and this consciousness revolution which can't possibly exist
on that level now when their eyes are open.
We don't need their services - war, drugs,
terrorism comes from these people, it doesn't come from "terrorists"
they are the terrorists.
The Illuminati families are the terrorists.
So, all these things and their services - let's just say NO.
But, if you reject that, if you say no to that,
and you say no I choose something better, I choose something higher,
and you start refining yourself, you start living in love, instead of living in fear.
And if enough people catch on and start doing that,
then we'll turn the world into a garden of Eden again
We will defeat your world government.
I stand before the creator of the Universe, and I ask the creator of the Universe
as our founding fathers did in 1776, to lead, guide and direct us
and to give us the power, and the foresight, and the understanding
and the will to stand against your entire agenda,
including, your final plan of world population reduction of 80%.
Why do you put mercury in the vaccines, stannic sodium fluoride in the water? Why?
Why do you put cancer viruses in the vaccines,
why have you used depleted uranium now in four separate nations,
you're arrogant, you have the sickness the elites have had throughout the history.
Darker forces really fear a man who is in touch with his own truth
and is dictated by that,
because they can't control you anymore.
Well, they could very well lose their power base by us becoming awakened,
and so, in order to keep us under control, they promote an agenda of fear.
They are reacting to it because in fact they are afraid.
The Illuminati are afraid of losing all their power,
when 2012 arrives, they know that the energy grid, the evil, negative energy grid
which sustains them, won't be there to support them.
They are standing in the front of a tidal wave saying "I'm not gonna get wet."
They're gonna get wet.
And they're gonna get affected by this consciousness shift too - whether they like it or not.
Our concern is not to worry about the Illuminati at this stage,
our concern is to imbue our lives with bliss and love, because their time is up.
It's over and that's obvious.
It's obvious to the awakened masses now.
They're running for the hills, desperately trying to cling on to their empire,
but we can conquer these, like David conquered Goliath,
by standing up - making a stand, responsibly.
You will and you are failing now.
Your New World Order will fall. Humanity will defeat you.
John F. Kennedy: "Confident that with your help
man will be what he was born to be: free and independent."
There is only one of us experiencing a fractal holographic experience of itself.
Each one of those individuations,
no matter how infinitesimal has got the entire whole within itself.
There is this illusion that were are something else,
but in truth all we are is consciousness observing the manifestations
of consciousness - dance before our eyes.
We are all the same person, watching ourselves from different viewpoints,
from different attitudes, from different environments.
Everything in creation is the same energy, and energy is consciousness.
Energy = Consciousness.
So we are looking at creation being one gigantic consciousness,
one gigantic mind, of which we are all part,
so we're like droplets of water in an ocean of consciousness.
We're individual to a certain extent, but all together we make up the whole.
There's nothing to do in this world of bamboo, but everyone needs a hobby.
You're just here to experience, you're having a good time, right?
But the illusion that we put ourselves into,
can be so powerful, that we can get lost in it.
Every human being is God himself, but he does not understand his true self
and he's constantly engulfed by the influence of his mind,
his intellect, which we call as the great delusion.
He's constantly driven by this great delusion.
The world is like a ride in the amusement park, and when you choose to go on,
you think it's real, because that's how powerful our minds are,
and the ride goes up and down, and round, and round.
It has thrills and chills, and it's very brightly coloured, and it's very loud,
and it's fun for a while.
Some people have been on the ride for a long time
and they begin to question - is this real or is it just a ride?
And other people have remembered, and they come back to us and they say
"Hey, don't worry, don't be afraid, ever, because this is just a ride,
and we... kill those people."
"Shut him up! We have a lot invested in this ride, Shut him up!!"
Look at my furrows of worry, look at my big bank account
and my family - this has to be real."
It's just a ride.
The one energy wishes to experience itself.
But, when it's in the oneness, it cannot experience itself,
it only knows it as a concept.
And so, it does the next best thing - it forgets what it is.
By deliberately forgetting what and who you are,
you can have the experience of remembering.
We are consciousness. Disembodied, no-form awareness, having an experience.
Like a central American shaman said,
"We are perceivers, we are awareness; we are not objects; we have no solidity.
We, or rather our reason, forget this
and thus we entrap the totality of ourselves in a vicious circle
from which we rarely emerge in our lifetime."
And that vicious circle is what the control system wants to keep us in,
cause then we are controllable!
When we say I'm doing some kind of spiritual practice or following spirituality,
what it means is I'm actually finding out who I am.
What am I? Who am I? Where did I come from?
What am I doing here on this Earth? And where will I go?
You're actually demystifying these concepts yourself, by realizing who you are.
Eventually you will get to the point where you will probably experience
the truth of who you really are as opposed to the illusion that you believe you are.
You believe you are this physical body, you believe you are your thoughts or whatever.
The truth of it is, you're the source of all those things - you're the source of your thoughts,
you're the source of your body, you're the source of all your emotions.
You're the place from which all that comes,
but we've been tricked into believing, for whatever reason, that we are these things.
But we're not these things, we're actually the creator of those things.
We are nothing short of divine. We are undifferentiated consciousness.
As we remember who we are, and acquiring more powers,
we are learning that we are co-creators in this experience and what is about to happen.
Enlightenment really means - you become aware what you really are,
you become aware that you are one with God, and that you are God.
Well, like a drop is to an ocean - you put a drop of water into the ocean
and it becomes the ocean - well, that's what we are.
are units of divinity. We are deific atoms - units of God.
And that's what the scriptures say - we are the sons of God.
In that sense - so it's beautiful!
Far from being worthless, we are unique and vital droplets in this ocean
of consciousness that we call God or creation,
this God, as we call it - it's not some guy with a beard sitting in a throne saying
"You've sinned and you shall be punished",
or something out there - it's actually within us, it's around us,
it is everything, it is the consciousness,
that is expressing itself in all the variety of forms that we see.
Obviously, we are at a different level of consciousness to a wall,
but the wall is still God, at a different level of consciousness it's still the same whole.
Doesn't matter which race culture everyone is confined to,
but the same God which resides in me - resides in everyone.
And when one realizes the God within us, he can see the God within everyone.
You never see positive drug stories on the news, do you?
Isn't that weird, since most of the experiences I've had on drugs,
were real fucking positive.
Who are these morons they're finding  that's what I want to know.
How about a positive LSD-story, wouldn't that be news-worthy, just once,
to base your decision on information, rather than scare-tactics and superstitions,
and lies? Just once. I think it would be news-worthy.
Today a young man on acid realized that all matter is merely energy condensed
to a slow vibration, that we're all one consciousness
experiencing it self-subjectively.
There's no such thing as death, life is only a dream,
and we are the imagination of ourselves.
Here's Tom with the weather.
The body is the way our awareness experiences this reality.
If I want to interact with this reality, which is a frequency range,
I have to have an outer shell, we all do, that vibrates within this frequency range,
cause our consciousness is vibrating much too quickly - it's like radio 1
trying to make a connection with radio 2,
on different wave lengths, it's never gonna happen.
So we take on this outer projection we call our body,
and therefore I can pick this up and interact with this reality.
What the control system wants us to do, is to believe that projection,
that vehicle to experience this reality is who we are,
cause then we go from "I am all that is, has been and ever will be,
I'm Charley Smith, I'm Ethel Jones, I've got no power."
It's the whole bottom line of it!
The United States has two satellites, they're called GOES.
The role of these satellites is to measure the magnetic fields of the earth
and send back readings every 30 minutes,
and those readings normally fall within a certain range of data
that scientists are used to seeing.
Well, it was in September of 2001, that scientists began
to see some readings that were off the map, just off the scale
compared to what they had seen in the past.
Then they said, what is happening, what is it that could be influencing
the magnetic fields of the entire planet
to such a degree that we're seeing those big spikes.
That our satellites are seeing, that we never seen these before.
They overlaid the data from the satellites onto a calendar of months and days,
and long behold what they found, is that the spike was occurring precisely
during the time of September 11th 2001, and even more precisely
that the first spike occurred 15 minutes after the first plane
hit the first tower in the World Trade Center.
Now, the reason this is so important to a scientist is because for 300 years
our science have been based on two false assumptions.
The first false assumption is that "Everything is separate from everything else,
that what happens in one place has no effect on what happens anywhere else,
and if it looks like it does, it's only a coincidence."
The second false assumption: "Our inner experiences - of thought, feeling, emotion
and belief have no effect on the world beyond our bodies."
Based on those two false assumptions, that had been accepted for 300 years by scientists,
I can see why there would be a disconnect when they're looking at
magnetic fields of the Earth, spiking precisely the moment the human emotion
of the planet is focused on a disaster.
We live here in Australia, and recently there were two cyclones
in the same year in northern Queensland.
What I noticed when we went and looked on the weather station, on the weather channel,
is the men and women who are telling the public about that thing,
they're saying it could generate into a much bigger storm.
And, so, what's called Focused Human Attention,
is that they drew everyone's mind into the idea that this is going to
generate into a much bigger storm.
And that's what they kept saying.
Until, Focused Human Attention on the storm made it grow bigger.
Now, if we thinking that's not true, then we have to take a look at this gentlemen
who's getting some vessel of water, and he says "Love" and puts a little label "Love",
and the molecular structure all goes into harmony.
And then he gets the same water, puts in a different vessel, puts "Hate",
and everything goes into chaos and stress.
In actual fact in a scientific basis now, if a person,
a scientist is carrying out an experiment,
he has to leave the building, the area - everything.
Because his consciousness is going to affect the outcome of the experiment.
So they now have to carry it out when he is not around,
to get a true result scientifically.
Thoughts are very powerful. If it is a positive thought,
it will travel to the positive collective, if you send out a negative thought,
it will travel to the negative collective around the world,
and it will have a negative effect on the planet.
Almost universally ancient texts and traditions have reminded us
that we are connected - they've said that we are one, that we are part of our world,
that we are part of one another, that we're part of the Earth and the changes in the Earth.
And, what I found is, over the last 22 years as I've travelled nearly
every continent of the Earth, and spoken to people from
so many different traditions and cultures, is that people really want to believe that,
they want to believe and they like to believe that we're truly connected,
but they need a reason for that belief.
Science is now giving us that reason - for our logical mind, to make the connection,
to see how we are related and how we influence the world,
and how by honoring that connection through our hearts,
we literally have the power to influence the very fields of this planet
to sustain life in the world, sustain the health,
the healing and the well being of our bodies,
and it's all about the magnetic fields of the Earth.
In Washington DC, people from all over the world came there to meditate,
and the crime rate dropped dramatically during that time,
proportionally to the amount of people who were meditating - in exact proportion.
I work very hard here in this center, to keep the vibrational rate of this room
at a very high frequency.
Now, it's to the point where people who don't even have an interest in meditation,
come here into this room, there was one person who spent a night
not that long ago, had no interest in meditation and that sort of thing whatsoever,
and a Kundalini awakened in the morning.
He had no understanding of that at all,
he had never even heard the word before.
And so, just by being in an environment which is kept pure, that happened.
Now, take that on a larger scale - if we were as a society - to do that
to the whole planet, then your wildest imagination
couldn't conceive of what is possible in such a scenario.
A person who sits there and meditates quietly,
in very, very strong gravity - they set up a gravity field,
that they're not moving no matter if the building falls down.
They can counter-act the negative effect of many.
A person who is in a negative space, walks into a room with ordinary people,
immediately, the level of energy will come down
and people won't know exactly what it is or why it is that happened, but it happens,
same thing happens the other way around too - you get a bunch of people bitching
and complaining in a group
and one person who's just in an amazing space of consciousness comes in
and the next thing you know the whole group is laughing,
enjoying themselves, having a good time.
Consciousness changes, generally speaking, because of realization,
however, when we're talking about collective consciousness, that is changed by media.
From channel to channel, on the news, and on dramas,
and on every other program,
and all it is - is brainwashing and demonization.
Generally a human being is bombarded with unwanted thoughts
constantly during the day, which depletes his mental energies.
When one is depleted with mental energy, it causes what you call
a drain of one's own mental resources and drain of just our physical energy as such.
Due to which our ability to comprehend and think reduces,
our efficiency as a human being reduces as well.
But, when you do something spiritual and associated with spirituality,
you're constantly gaining positive energy,
so the ability for personality defects manifests less.
The worst weapon in the world is the Television.
And the reason is - it's not the cameras fault, it's done in the editing process.
It's done in the voice-over, in the treatment.
The camera doesn't tell a lie, it only ever tells the truth.
Where the problem with the collective consciousness is - unless it's focused,
Focused Human Attention in the right mood
you may as well be on the battlefield, saying I'm French.
And the other goes on - I'm British.
Hold on, we better all pray to our God, and then we better kill each other.
See? This is called collective consciousness.
The individual consciousness is gone. He fled the battlefield, he didn't want to know.
Individual people by themselves, groups, societies,
the mood of the whole planet - can all be altered,
can all be changed and the reason for that is - because the planet, group's, societies
aren't what they appear to be.
They are just another level consciousness. We are all consciousness.
If consciousness changes to a higher vibration, which, I feel, is happening in 2012,
then the society, the way we know it now, will not be there anymore.
The old has to go. The new has to come.
I don't feel that one thing is going to evolve independently of another.
I feel that in this field of consciousness we live in, things operate in an uniform way
and we are now passing through a period,
in which an acceleration of consciousness is taking place.
Everybody is benefiting from these finer conscious levels that we are arriving at,
simply by means of where the Sun is taking us.
The earth itself is a conscious living entity,
and if the beings living on it choose to raise their frequency,
they choose to live in love as opposed to fear.
The plants will grow greener, the oxygen in the air will replenish,
the pollution will start to disappear - it'll turn literally into a utopia - heaven on Earth.
It's up to our focused attention to create that reality,
but we have to become aware of who's meddling in our minds.
Our mind is our biggest problem when it's not under our control.
Under OUR control.
Somehow we have this wrong idea that we have to do that by going out there and building it.
You don't go out there to build it, you go in here to build it.
You find it in here first, and just allow it to radiate out around you.
And everything else then naturally happens by itself.
As people begin to awaken and take on responsibility,
we can expect to see a much more harmonious world.
It's just a ride. And we can change it anytime we want.
It's only a choice. No effort, no work, no job, no savings of money,
a choice right now, between FEAR and LOVE.
What society would probably like for us to believe is love is like
what we see on the Hollywood films.
Love is actually a state of being.
It's not actually something that you do to somebody else.
If someone loves you and you don't feel love for them, you don't feel anything.
You only feel love when you are radiating love, when you are giving love.
If you love yourself, you feel better in yourself.
If you hate yourself, you loathe yourself. And why do you wanna do that?
Why do you wanna be miserable? Why do you wanna feel bad? Is that good for you?
The worry is just another prayer for what you don't want.
If you want to create what you DO want, focus on the, let's say grandest vision
of the highest version you could possibly imagine.
If you're gonna do anything, make sure you are doing it out of joy and not fear.
If you feel negative, you have no energy,
if you feel positive, you have much more energy, and you can do a lot of things,
you can help many people and yourself.
To choose to love over fear is choosing a state of awareness,
a state of consciousness to exist in, to be in as your reality.
And even when the dark forces come along and try to draw you out of it,
you still love them. Of course, they really hate it when you do that.
And all it is, like everything else, is a choice - a choice between fear and love.
That's all it is!
We can choose to be frightened. We can choose to hate. Just a choice.
Or we can choose not to fear and we can choose to love.
Not love on the basis "I love you if I fancy you darling",
but I love you because you exist.
I love you whatever. I love you without condition.
As the loving component grows,
that becomes more and more contagious, if you like,
and the world tends to become a more loving place, as a result.
The critical mass of the love paradigm grows.
And if you want to change the world, it has to start with self.
Fear, anger, hatred, condemnation,
dictating what other people should be - that's the world we got.
That's the prison.
But Paradise is waiting.
It's a thought, an attitude away, that's all it is, it's a choice away. Love.
We love each other, and love the world,
our lives are fundamentally changed,
and the world is fundamentally changed.
And we are the generations, strange as it may seem
when you survey the world today - we are the generations,
I passionately believe, who are gonna love the world
into the paradise it really should be, and was always designed to be.
Human beings actually are supposed to be eternal,
full of knowledge and full of ecstasy and I'm not talking about the pill,
I'm talking about spiritual bliss, which is the highest frequency,
a living entity in a human body can experience.
Bliss is our birthright. We were made to enjoy love and happiness.
That bliss is always there, there's so much potential for bliss. Right?
It's like a light switch - you go to turn it on,
and you know that the moment you turn it on,
the light comes on and the room fills.
That's what the bliss is like, it's just there waiting for you to just turn it on,
and you can tap into it - as much as you want.
So people are not reminded of that. They are being pulled away by distractions:
"Go to work." "Go to school." "Do this, do that." "Get a career."
And - guess what? The bliss just gets left behind, all the time.
They just leave it behind.
Why not enjoy it? It's there.
God is total Love, and there is nothing else.
And Love is the glue of the Universe.
Now is the time to embrace the Love, and to leave the fear behind.
It's quite as simple as that. Because fear means you have a fear of losing something.
What could that be? All those possessions out there?
All those material illusions or your body?
Well, the body is going to die anyway. It's only a matter of time.
But the one that embraces the love,
is the one that knows that he can never lose.
And when you find that love and you know that you can never lose,
come what may - it may be physical destruction,
and it may be just general chaos and fear,
and anguish attacking us from all corners, but if you remain in love,
you receive all the blessings, so there should be nothing at all to fear
about 2012 and what is coming.
The eyes of fear wants you to put bigger locks on your door,
buy guns, close yourself off the eyes of love, instead see all of us as one.
Here's what we can do to change the world right now to a better ride.
Take all that money we spend on weapons and defense each year,
instead spend it feeding, clothing, educating the poor of the world,
which it would many times over, not one human being excluded,
and we can explore space together,
both inner and outer.
Forever.
We are not governed by any calendar, no event or any such thing.
Every decision you make, takes you in a different direction.
When you make good decisions, all the time, take a moment to breathe,
come into the now, make a conscious decision.
Everything has changed.
The most important things I'd like to say to people is - to know who you are,
reclaim your sovereignty, and learn the science of "As above, so below" -
the macrocosm and the microcosm,
because we are the microcosm of the Universe, of the whole Universe.
Our body is Universe, full of atoms, trillions of atoms, which are stars.
I think we're a part of a greater wisdom that we'll ever understand,
a higher order, call it what you want.
You know what I call it? The Big Electron!
The Big Electron!
"Woooww... Woooww... Woooww"
It doesn't punish, it doesn't reward, it doesn't judge at all.
It just is, and so are we. For a little while.
So, once we know this and we realize what we really are, and who we really are,
then we stand up and ignore, virtually ignore this system of fear
and embrace the love, and nothing, there's nothing that can stop us,
there's nothing that can hurt us,
there's nothing that can cause us to fear anymore.
Whatever we do in our life, please make sure that we sprinkle some spirituality onto it.
When we sprinkle something spiritual onto it,
we also get the benefit of inner peace, inner calmness,
otherwise we get so lost in this world, that we do not know what we want,
and that's a very bad state to be in.
So do take up some spiritual practice every day,
so that it helps you to nurture your mind, nurture your intellect, calms your mind.
Be a sane person in this insane world!
Be the happy person, so that you can help other people be happy.
Otherwise you're a part of the problem yourself,
and that's a worst place to be in.
We left a great place of unconditioned consciousness,
and the purpose of life is to go through this cycle of necessity,
glean all the wisdom that we can from it and return to the cause
much more than we were before. Much, much more.
For those people who have been a victim of the propaganda,
the 2012 agenda to promote fear,
what I would say the best thing to do is - not to get fooled by that,
and your worst enemy is the fear itself.
And to just trust in love.
You are what you think. What you think, you will become.
When the Buddha says that we are what we think,
then I think we would be advised to hold the most positive and grand view
we can possibly have, cause what you think about is what you're going to create.
So every day make it a blissful spiritual day, and share that,
share compassion, share love. Drop the fear.
There's nothing to fear, except fear itself.
It's really true, what my guru and other teachers have said,
that if you want to change the world, you've got to start with yourself.
Changing the world is not something in the future anymore,
"Oh it will be better for the kids."
It's here now, and we are going  to see it happen.
The more one loves and finds unity in this world, and harmony,
the more the blessings will be when that time comes.
And the time is coming, it's a coming,
the beautiful rewards for all those who are poised to receive them.
They are coming.
The new world of love is coming.
As the date approaches, more and more people are becoming aware of its significance.
Is it really a window of great changes in consciousness?
Is that what the ancients were trying to tell us?
When we take a look around the world, we have seen decades of dictatorships collapse,
as humanity united and march the streets in Tunisia, Yemen and Egypt.
Injustices have been exposed by WikiLeaks,
such as the "Afghan War Logs" which uncovered corruption,
murder of civilians, and a multitude of US military cover-ups.
A global network of truth and awareness is uniting mankind
via technology and the Internet - the one last channel left un-filtered.
As knowledge is spreading, people are awakening,
and we are beginning to see a clearer picture of the world that we live in.
Consciousness is shifting right before our eyes.
The people in power may try to negatively influence the outcome of the coming shift.
By creating a world war or collapsing the global financial system.
They may generate enough fear to open the gates to their New World Order.
If that day comes - we need to remember their true agenda,
unite as one and rise in love and compassion.
Crowd: "Troops out now! Troops out now! Troops out now....!"
Crowd : "The people united will never be defeated!", "The people united will never be defeated!"...
What is the pathway forward?
Perhaps we are here right now to define what comes next?
Is it not up to us to act together and build a better future?
A world without suffering?
We have learned that the galactic shift is empowering us to create great change,
and the elites are trying to influence that change with fear.
We have learned that we are fractals of one consciousness experiencing itself
and with the power of the collective we can change our experience
anytime we choose to do so.
When we focus all our devotion and envision a new beginning,
we will create a world of peace,
love,
and harmony.
The time is Right Now. Heaven or Hell on earth is up to us.
And it's only a choice between fear and love.
How this will play out - only time will tell,
as we approach December 21st 2012,
and beyond.
In the seventeenth chapter of St. Luke, its written
the kingdom of God is within man, not one man nor a group of men, but in all men!
In you! You, the people, have the power, the power to create machines,
the power to create happiness!
You, the people, have the power to make this life free and beautiful,
to make this life a wonderful adventure.
Now let us fight to fulfill that promise!
Let us fight to free the world! To do away with national barriers!
To do away with greed, with hate and intolerance!
Let us fight for a world of reason,
a world where science and progress will lead to all mens happiness.
LET US ALL UNITE!!!
It's an endless ocean of bliss.
Part of one vast ocean of intelligent living energy.
It's an energy, it's a force, it's the force of God.
The idea is to be in touch with this energy, to understand it.
It's urging us toward higher growth and toward higher evolution.
Like an electric shock, the Kundalini went right up my spine.
I felt connected to every single living thing, and in fact,
I felt connected to everything in the entire universe and cosmos,
I felt one with it.
Tremendous amounts of love and peace, complete acceptance,
complete love, complete everything.
Absolute truth, absolute consciousness, and absolute bliss.
That's our nature. Our nature is bliss.
When you experience that, you will never be the same ever again.
Don't ever let anybody tell you what God is.
Find out for yourself.
V/O: There is a secret buried inside of everyone.
I believe that is the inherent divinity and eternality
of the being inside the machine.