The following program is brought
to you in living color on NBC.
Captain's log, stardate 6031.2
We are in standard orbit above
the neutral planetoid Babel,
awaiting the beaming aboard
of Federation ambassadors
who have been attending a
crucial economic conference.
One ambassador, however, prefers
an older form of transport....
- You must think I'm hopelessly old fashioned.
- Ma'am?
Well to prefer traveling by shuttle, rather than
having my atoms shooting through space.
I always found that, a very unsettling concept.
Our ship’s doctor agrees with you.
He's a sensible man.
You know, you remind me so much
of someone I knew a long time ago.
Would that be because I resemble my
grandfather -- Dimitri Chekov.
Federation ambassador to Russia.
You mean "from Earth."
Of course...
I knew him as ambassador when I
first went into service for Obsidia.
I liked him very much.
He liked you. He told me so. Many times.
Did he?
Many times?
Yes, ma'am.
[Warning tone]
What the hell?
What are you doing?
Buying time. That debris field might camouflage
our image. He won’t know what to target.
Target?!
His disrupters are armed.
Hold on. I’m going to try something....
Space, the final frontier.
These are the new voyages of the Starship Enterprise,
Its five year mission to
explore strange new worlds
To seek out new life and new civilizations.
To boldly go where no man has gone before.
- Oh My.
- Yes, Ma'am.
Klingon vessel, stand down
or be fired upon!
That was exciting.
Sorry. I hadn’t planned
on any entertainment.
Captain, the Klingon is signaling us.
He identifies himself as
the Dark Destroyer.
- On screen, Lieutenant.
- Aye, sir.
Well, well, well. Lost a little
something, have you, Kirk?
Our sensors had the Shuttle at all times.
But it’s...thoughtful of you to enter neutral
space to see about it. Now get gone.
Ah, but it is neutral space. You have
no authority to order me out.
I just came by to offer a friendly greeting...
get in a little target practice.
If you were friendly, you wouldn’t
have come in cloaked.
We have been visiting quite a few
of your Federation planets lately,
the ones that have failed
and been abandoned.
They make very nice -- and easy --
additions to the Klingon Empire.
Kargh, get out of here before
I run you out under escort.
Mr. DeSalle - Phasers?
Hot and locked on the Klingon.
You hear that, Captain?
I am sure we will see you again, Kirk
-- as our Empire expands.
I think a welcoming committee for Ambassador
Morgan and Mr. Chekov is in order.
Mr. Spock, Bones, your with me.
- Scotty, you have the conn.
- Aye, sir.
Hanger deck secured.
Hanger deck pressurizing.
That was really quite a ride.
- Permission to come aboard allowed?
- Granted, sir.
- You know, you did a wonderful job.
- Thank you.
This way, Ambassador.
- That was a nice piece of flying, Mr. Chekov.
- Thank you, sir.
Captain James T. Kirk, Ambassador.
Welcome aboard the Enterprise.
Thank you, Captain.
I have to apologize for
that little Klingon incident.
My pilot was very skillful. However, I may
have to consider the transporter, next time.
Allow me to introduce you
to my first officer Mr. Spock
Mr. Spock
- My Chief Medical Officer, Dr. Leonard McCoy.
- Ambassador.
If you were injured, or shaken up
in the shuttle, I'd be happy...
Not at all, Dr. McCoy, I'm fine.
However, I would appreciate
some rest in my quarters.
Permit us to escort you to
your quarters, Ambassador.
Mr. Chekov, take the ship out of orbit
and set a course straight for Earth.
- See you later Pavel.
- Lady Rayna.
Let's go, Pavel.
I was never that young.
I trust the Council sessions went well?
Not at all captain, I’m afraid
we didn't accomplish a thing.
That’s disturbing.
[Rayna] The Federation credits system
is collapsing on planet after planet.
[Kirk] Credits aren’t worth the same
from one planet to the next.
[Spock] Resupplying consumables,
in certain sections of the quadrant,
has become difficult where the value
of the credit has been devalued.
Yes, but it’s more than that. The planets
with viable economies can hold their own.
But others, less fortunate, are falling into
economic ruin and will soon be abandoned.
How well we know that. The Enterprise
has assisted in the evacuation
and relocation of two
Federation colonies, so far.
Really?
The Council debated for over three
months and came up with no solutions.
And we won’t meet again
for another six months.
I am not hopeful.
Our Klingon visitor pointed out abandoned
planets are ripe for the plucking.
Yes, by the Klingons or the Romulans.
So, we have economic Chaos, failing
worlds. We must find a solution.
Otherwise, I’m afraid the Federation
will not exist much longer.
- Mr. Sulu, you are relieved.
- Take good care of her tonight Vincent.
Not a bad piece of flying out there, Chekov.
Thank you.
Considering you’re not rated
for helm as well as navigation
Well, it doesn’t matter in the shuttle.
As I demonstrated.
Still, a double bridge qualification means
more when promotions come up.
DeSalle? What’s your phaser firing rank?
Eighty-five.
Ninety-seven.
- Have fun at Dinner.
- Dinner?
Oh really?
With Ambassador... Rayna?
It's a... just dinner.
Captain. I’m picking up a blip.
It’s pacing us.
Can you make it out?
Could be a ship, but it’s just on the
edge of our long range sensors.
All I got was a flash --
solid but unidentifiable.
I want the sensors set for a constant sweep
around the ship. Under a 24-hour surveillance.
If there's something out there,
I want to know what it is.
he told me all the old Russian
folk tales when I was a boy.
But he set them in outer space.
- On alien planets, of course.
- Of course.
I wanted to visit them all,
so I became a navigator.
Very simple.
Dimitri was an inspiring man, wasn’t he.
Do you know that told he told me when I was just 22,
that I could be the Obsidia System ambassador?
He was always so positive. He said he saw
in me all the possibilities, even then.
He was right. He told me
all about you, you know.
Yes, "many times", you said.
I think he was just a little bit in love.
Was he?
Yes.
You know, this is much too complicated a
subject to be discussing at such a late hour.
Perhaps we could do it
on another occasion?
Tomorrow, dinner?
Done.
Slummin’, lad? Not like you
to come down here for a visit.
The navigation system’s showing
a slight deviation off prime.
It’s only a tenth of a degree, but it’s
increased since I noticed it last shift.
I’ll take a look at it.
But it will have to wait a bit.
We’re having a wee bit of a problem
with the manifold pressure here....
Mr. Scott!
Well?
I don’t see how you could have been
shielded from that radiation burst,
but, there doesn’t seem to be any damage.
Then I can return to duty?
Take this shift off. Go back
to your quarters and relax.
Doctor, I feel fine.
Hey, doctor’s orders. And If you decide to
disobey, remember I can pull you in here
for a complete two-day medical
exam. With probes. Just because.
I think I’ll go back to my quarters... and relax.
Status, Mr. Scott.
Do you want the full report or the summary?
The summary will do.
All right then. We've got one
warp engine, one impulse engine.
Full warp will be impossible and
maneuvering will be clumsy,
but we’re working around the
clock to get us back on line.
How long?
As soon as humanly possible, sir.
Best we can do. [Bridge com sounds]
McCoy to bridge.
Kirk here. What is it, Bones?
Captain, report to Sickbay as soon as
possible.
Can it wait?
Now, Jim.
Alright Doctor, I’m on my way.
Mr. Spock, you have the Bridge.
- Stay on it, Mr. Scott.
- That was my intention, Sir.
This shouldn’t be. I mean he was perfectly
fine on the last scan. Yesterday.
Did you miss anything?
Well then why is this happening?
History. On Gamma Hydra Four, he was exposed,
just as we were, to the aging disease.
Back then a burst of adrenaline allowed
him to escape the full effects, but
obviously his body has been harboring
the disease all this time.
And?
He's suffered a massive radiation dose.
It unleashed the disease and...
now the Hyronaline therapy isn’t working.
Prognosis, Doctor.
He’s aged twenty-five years in one day.
Bones, What can you do?
Nothing, Jim. I can't stop it.
No. This has to be reversible.
The ship’s computers can access all the
medical knowledge the Federation has.
I’ll do my best, Pavel. Count on it.
That’s not good enough. You have to
find a cure. There has to be one.
If there isn’t....
You always have an answer.
Lieutenant, maybe you'd better think about
putting a few things in order. Just in case....
I won’t have to.
I’ll report to my station now.
Mr. Chekov, in your condition, I think
it's best that you remain here in sick bay.
Unless, if Dr. McCoy thinks it's all right,
you may return to your quarters.
But I feel fine!
Captain,
I’m picking up that anomaly again. Stronger now.
I’m definitely reading it as another ship.
Spock - configuration?
I cannot make it out, sir. It remains on the
extreme edge of our sensor perception.
Or it could be taunting us
by cloaking and uncloaking.
Klingon? Romulan?
Either is possible.
Lieutenant Uhura, hail that ship.
Aye, sir.
Federation Starship USS Enterprise
to unidentified vessel.
State your planet of origin
and purpose in this quadrant.
No response, sir.
Open a channel, Lieutenant.
Aye, sir.
Kargh, if that’s you – no more games.
As of right now, my phasers are armed,
and they’re going to stay hot.
Close channel, Lieutenant.
Aye, sir.
Mr. Spock, this ship is on yellow alert.
All ship’s eyes and ears are
to remain on that intruder.
I want to know their every move.
If he’s cloaked, sir....
Then he has to uncloak to
fire his disrupters.
Full yellow alert, Mr. Spock, until
and unless I order a stand-down.
Understood, Captain.
I'm young.
Damn it, I’m young,
and this can’t happen!
Why me?
I didn’t do anything.
I was just there.
Everyone else was cured.
Why am I the only one that wasn’t?
I didn’t do anything.
[Door Buzzer]
Who... who's there?
Lady Rayna. May I come in?
A moment, please.
Come.
Pavel.
I'm so sorry.
Funny,
I didn’t hear an announcement
on the ship’s intercom.
Well, you know how it is.
You tell one person in
strictest confidence and it's...
all over the ship in an hour.
It’s only a rumor.
Yes but, Pavel, surely...
Dr. McCoy is searching the
medical files right now.
He always has an answer.
Yes, I am sure he will find a cure for you.
Yes.
Get me the Tellerite information.
Their physiology is only
remotely like a human’s.
Get it anyway.
Of course.
So how are we doing?
We're making progress.
Give me another hour, and I’ll have
the second warp engine on line.
Thanks Scotty.
Sir, the unidentified vessel
is moving in our direction.
Bearing 230 mark five.
Picking up speed.
It's gone.
Cloaked.
Trajectory?
Angle on our starboard bow---
Vessel uncloaking. Two hundred thousand
kilometers and closing fast.
It's Klingon.
Disruptor ports are open.
Red Alert. Now.
Red alert. All hands, man your
battle stations -- This is not a drill.
I Repeat, All hands, man your
Where are you going?
To my station.
You can't.
I’m the best weapons officer
the Captain has.
Pavel, did he call you?
Deflectors.
Shields up, sir. We have full power on
deflectors and phasers.
Shields haev gone sir.
Scotty, when can I have power to maneuver?
Captain, I can give you phasers and
shields or maneuvering power,
but I canna give you both.
- The best you can, as soon as you can.
- Right, sir. I had better get down there.
Phasers targeted. Ready to fire.
He's coming around, sir.
Fire.
Damage to port sections five and six.
Isolating that section...now.
Helm is sluggish, sir. Power down
thirty percent.... Forty.
Sentell, report.
Diverting power to maneuvering.
Uhura, shut off that noise.
Mr. Spock, monitor the reports
and give me a summary
of the damage.
DeSalle. Do we still have
shields and phasers?
Shields at twenty percent. Phasers are down.
We have full photon torpedo capacity.
- Then let’s give him a jolt.
- Yes, sir.
Damn.
Full spread, sir? If he didn’t deviate
from his original course ---
No, Mr. DeSalle. We might need them later,
and we've got a ship to save. Mr. Spock?
Phaser and shield power is compromised,
but we still have power
to maneuver slowly.
Four quarters decks and one engineering
level are damaged. We have lost crew.
Personnel is checking the roster now.
Sickbay is flooded with injured.
And Mr. Scott?
He begs to inform you he generally only
performs miracles on Tuesdays and Thursdays.
Today is Monday.
Very well. Carry on, then.
[Speaker] Deck 6 forward bulkheads totally blown.
[Speaker] Engineering level 3, extensive
damage to decking and overheads.
[Speaker] Four water recyclers are non-
functional, but they can be rehabbed.
[Speaker: Multiple voice reports at once - unintelligible]
Thank you Miss Okuda.
- Does anyone have any good news?
- There’s a wee tad, sir.
We have all our engines back. On the other hand,
two of our generators were damaged by the
hit on Engineering level 3.
If we go to warp, I don’t have enough
power for the phasers and shields.
If we stay here I can give you those.
So we can run, or we can
stand here and fight.
That’s about it, sir.
We’re working on it.
Lieutenant Uhura, send a subspace Mayday
to all Federation starships in range.
We've been attacked by a Klingon vessel,
without provocation. We're able to move,
but we don’t have adequate defenses.
The Federation ambassadors
on board are at high risk,
and we can't protect them
if we are attacked again.
Captain’s log, supplemental. I have decided
to wait at the site of the attack,
hoping my call for help will bring us
an escort of Federation vessels.
Thus far...no response.
Pavel.
Why you wasting your time sleeping?
What the hell?
What indeed.
I’m still asleep. I have to be.
You’re not.
- You’re not an hallucination.
- Not to you,
but, anyone else looked in here
you would be talking to yourself.
I have to see Dr. McCoy.
He will only tell you what you already know.
What? That I’m losing my mind?
Are you? What do you see
when you look at me?
Myself. The way I should be.
I see the way I will be... Would be.
If I was given the time.
Let me tell you something --
that mirror is not our friend.
We could cover it up.
It wouldn’t change the
truth of the matter.
Are we going to admit what that is?
Yes. I
we --
were young two days ago.
Now look at us.
Grandfather’s hands looked like that.
Do you know what I think?
I'm dying
and you're here.
And this is starting to get
very Russian.
- Any response, Lieutenant?
- No, sir.
- Keep sending the Mayday.
- Aye, sir.
- Do you remember...?
- Everything.
[Both together] Tribbles! (laughing)
Billy Claibourne.
I made a hell of an outlaw.
They killed us then.
It was an illusion. If you
don’t believe, it is not real.
This is real
Yes.
Gamma Trianguli VI.
Yeoman Martha Landon.
She was beautiful.
[Together] We were in love.
A planet where there was no disease
and no one ever grew old.
- The Feeders of Vaal.
- Captive to a machine God.
Would you settle now for such a life?
- I don't know.
- You wouldn’t. I wouldn’t!
Harry Mudd.
And all his beautiful ageless...
- androids!
Captain, I’ve got another blip.
Unidentified vessel closing on us fast.
Uncloaked Klingon vessel.
Not the same one that attacked us.
Message coming in, Captain.
It’s from the Klingon.
On screen.
Greetings, Captain Kirk. We
intercepted your distress call.
Come to gloat?
In fact, we came to help.
Really? Then I’ve a great deal for you on
some waterfront property in Riverside, Iowa.
I do not understand the reference.
Just what do you want, Kargh?
On my honor, Kirk, the ship that
attacked you was not Klingon.
Are you telling that me we didn’t see the
vessel that uncloaked and fired upon us?
I can have the visual record
played back for you. Lt. Uhura---
Have you ever seen a magician’s trick, Kirk?
The success of the trick lies in your
seeing what he wants you to see.
And your point is...?
Kirk, I know where my sister
ships are. On my honor,
the vessel that attacked
you was not Klingon.
Based on past history, I can’t accept that.
Sir. Captain Kargh has twice said, “on his honor”
the attack vessel was not one of theirs.
To Klingons, honor is everything --
more important than their very lives.
He harried the shuttle at Babel.
A different time, a different exercise.
I believe he means exactly as he says.
It was not a Klingon that attacked us.
What are you suggesting, Kargh?
I have a proposition for you.
Then let’s hear it.
I am willing to transport
aboard your ship, Captain.
We should conduct our
business face to face.
All right then, prepare to beam aboard.
I look forward to meeting you.
Lieutenant Uhura,
Have Security escort Mr. Kargh to the
Briefing Room, and ask Mr. Scott to join us.
Spock, your with me.
DeSalle, you have the Conn.
Growing up, this was all that I wanted,
to be an officer on a starship.
But once I did that,
It wasn’t enough, just to have
my commission and this berth.
I had to be the best navigator,
the best weapons officer.
Not just the best on this ship --
the best in the Fleet.
We did devote a lot of time to duty.
That was before. I had years to spend,
and now this thief of time in
my body has taken them.
I’ve lost all the things I could have had.
Opportunity,
love
joy,
Life.
I am 25 years old.
I’m not just going to die,
I didn’t get to live!
We both had the same dreams.
Why are you here?
I suppose I want to know...
if this is  all there is, was it worth it?
That’s one of those questions, isn’t it?
Was I a good person?
Did I make a difference anywhere?
Was I worth the time I spent here?
I’d like to say yes.
So would I. But can I?
- You saved Scott’s life.
- Reflexes.
No, you had a choice. You could have
gotten of the way and saved yourself.
Maybe.
Would you have done anything else?
If I knew the cost?
I honestly don’t know.
And what’s left?
We don’t have much time.
I should be on that bridge.
That Klingon is still out there, and I’m the
best weapons officer the Captain has.
Best in the Fleet.
Why not report in?
I can’t! Dr. McCoy won't clear me for duty.
But he will.
Yes.
He has to...
Welcome aboard.
Odd situation we are in,
isn’t it, Kirk?
If we're going to make the most of this,
we had better get started.
Please.
"Anything can be resolved ---"
"-- after a hot glass of tea."
Grandfather’s motto.
But not this.
No.
"Curative properties. Good for the soul."
Can’t cure this problem.
- Do you remember?
- Everything.
I was thinking of Apollo.
Tried to make us worship him. Obey him.
Overstepped his bounds there,
the arrogant ---
Well, he’d been a god.
Have you noticed that never works?
I did. I wonder why.
Because humans have this
stubborn streak in them.
You try to tame them,
bend them, they rebel.
Why aren’t we rebelling
against this thing?
You go into service,
you know you could die.
You hope you won’t,
but you know you can.
If you’re lucky, you’ll live
past your service years,
take your pension and go live on a
nice blue and white planet
in sunshine and joy.
And?
Not "And." - "Or".
You die young and,
one hopes, heroically.
But this...
No heroics. No glory.
No sunshine and joy.
But we’ve done a thing
or two, haven’t we?
Are you ashamed of our record?
Of how we’ve served?
No. I...
we..., did our best.
Yes.
Damn right.
Should we regret?
Not one thing. Ever.
Can you prove no Klingon was
responsible for this attack?
How? Shall I contact our sister ships
and interrogate the captains?
And if I did, would you believe them?
No!
We have to trust your "honor", Kargh.
Why attack the Enterprise so
deep in Federation space?
Why attack your ship at all?
Because, you’re not above causing
chaos where you can, laddie.
Captain Kirk, you understand
we have “ears” on Babel.
We are well aware the economic
conference was useless.
Threatening the Federation ambassadors
aboard is a waste of effort.
They are only going home to report defeat.
Failing fringe planets will be abandoned
and can be taken over by our
invasion troops, if we want them.
The only reason to attack you, is to
place blame on the Klingon Empire.
And who would want to do that?
The Romulan Star Empire.
Possible, Captain. They are
occasional Klingon allies,
but they do not have the same goals.
You would know, of course.
Projections based on past history and
societal ambitions are quite logical.
Or it could be someone else.
Which is why I am offering our assistance.
Cut him loose, Captain. Why would
this Sassenach want to help us?
Because whoever it is,
is an enemy to us both.
You’re on, Captain.
Let’s do this…
together.
Captains log, supplemental.
The Enterprise faces the
possibility of another attack.
This time, however, we
have an unlikely ally.
On screen, Mr. Spock.
This is the ship that attacked us.
It is a perfect replica.
Replica?
Since it could not have been one
of our ships, it must be a replica.
The name? The symbols on the ship?
"Danger Stalker".
And an identifying vessel number.
Before you ask,
there is no such ship in our fleet.
But if the Klingons can
prove it’s not theirs---
The marauder does not intend for
that to happen, Commander Scott.
They can destroy us and
leave enough evidence
the Klingons perpetrated the attack.
The Federation leaps to the desired conclusion.
And we’re in the middle of a war …
Clever. But we’re not
going to cooperate.
Mr. Scott, repair status?
You’re going to owe the entire
Engineering Department a round, Sir.
Both the phasers and
the shields are back on line.
Two rounds, Mr. Scott –
just as soon as we’re out of this.
Gentlemen, now we recall our Mayday.
We're fully operational,
so we don't need any more help.
We can report that this
alien ship is not Klingon.
Baiting a trap.
With a little help from our friends.
-- let’s move.
[Door buzzer]
[Intercom] Pavel -- it’s Rayna.
Come.
I thought you might need some
company. I know I certainly do.
It has gotten lonely in here,
the last few hours.
Shutting yourself off?
Do you mind if I turn up the lights?
No.
I’m sorry if I embarrassed you.
There is not much left to embarrass.
It’s all right. Leave the lights up.
The Enterprise is fully repaired.
The Captain expects another
attack, but we have an ally.
But no one responded to our Mayday.
Someone did.
Captain Kargh of the Dark Destroyer.
You've got to be joking.
No,
that would be a Russian joke.
Oh, Pavel...if ever you were needed,
it will be in the next hours.
That may be all the time I have left.
U.S.S. Enterprise to all Federation
vessels in the Alpha Quadrant.
We're withdrawing our Mayday. We
have no further need of assistance.
There are few similar diseases,
but they’re genetic and
and not induced in the same way.
But similar.
There are no cures for them, either.
I have to report to the captain.
I understand.
- McCoy to Kirk.
- Kirk here.
Captain, I have completed my
final examination of Mr. Chekov.
As we discussed, the
situation has not changed.
My diagnosis remains the same.
Thank you, Bones.
Mr. Chekov -- We’re going to need you.
Report to the bridge.
Was that the wisest decision, Jim?
Maybe not, Spock.
But it was the best one.
You heard the Captain.
How much time do I have?
Honestly.
Damn it, Pavel, I’m a doctor, not a watchmaker.
Soon.
It's all right.
Damn it, man, you saved Scotty,
but you sacrificed ---
No sacrifices.
It was worth it.
It was all worth it.
You can’t know that.
Oh Yes … I can.
Go on. Captain wants you on the bridge.
Klingon vessel uncloaking on the port
bow, one hundred thousand kilometers.
Relative position, 180 degrees mark three.
I have him. On screen.
Long range full perimeter scan...
No other vessels, sir.
[Kirk] Where's Kargh?
[Sulu] Probably ran.
They are targeting the previously
damaged area, Captain.
Shields?
Holding, Sir.
Mr. Chekov?
Forward shields are gone.
Secondary deflectors holding.
Phasers still charged and ready.
Captain!
The hostile is recharging disrupters.
Now.
The marauder has been damaged.
But not enough. He’s coming about.
The marauder is preparing to fire again.
Secondary shields gone.
We still have phasers.
- Any signal from Kargh?
- Negative, sir.
We cannot withstand another attack, Captain.
The hostile has charged torpedo racks.
A strategic hit will stop Mr. Chekov’s aerobatics.
Not likely.
Got you.
Mr. Chekov,
that was the most elegant weapons
demonstration I have ever seen.
Captain, incoming message
from the Dark Destroyer.
On screen.
That worked out well.
You're late.
But in time for the kill.
Kargh, we need to know who they are.
Which is why I offer to board the hostile.
They have dishonored the Klingon Empire.
I want to know who these people are
even more than you do, Kirk.
Very well, Captain. But I expect a
report as soon as you find anything.
Permission to return to my quarters, Captain?
Lieutenant Uhura, have Ambassador
Morgan come up to the bridge.
Sir, report coming in from
Captain Kargh on the hostile.
On screen, Lieutenant.
What is it, Kargh?
As I assured you, Kirk,
this is not a Klingon vessel.
It is a Federation ship modified
to look like one of ours.
but only on the exterior
and in its weaponry.
What’s its origin?
[Kargh and Rayna] Esterion system.
How can you tell?
Well look at him. He hasn’t
even covered his interface.
This whole ship reflects their building
style. Federation, yes --
but with Esterion’s particular touches.
And how would you know?
Captain, I believe I know
what's happened.
Esterion is one of the systems with a shaky
economy, hovering on the edge of collapse.
I don’t understand.
Esterion is known for their engineering
and technological advancements.
They are extremely valuable
for the entire Federation.
Absolutely, but they’ve placed primary emphasis
on combat devices and inventions.
In a Federation of peace, they
face failure on a planet-wide level
because there is no use for their technology.
And they've consistently refused
to change directions or goals,
even though it means
their own economic death.
Their philosophy is that there will always be a
war. All they have to do is simply wait for one.
But how did they get a cloaking device?
Captain, my inquiries into classified records
indicates that Starfleet gave it to them
for reverse engineering after we... ”removed it”
from the Romulan vessel eighteen months ago.
And if they could provoke a war between
the Federation and the Klingons---
A war would fuel their entire economy -- make
them more necessary to the Federation.
But to not them alone.
Who's in on this with you?
We’ve already asked that question.
This one has chosen not to answer it.
What about the others on board?
All dead.
By their own hand, I can assure you.
I can continue questioning---
No. Prepare them to beam
aboard the Enterprise.
They’ll face trial for
their crimes.
And their planetary leaders will join them.
I owe you that courtesy, Kirk --
but only because we stood together this time.
The next time....
Until then, Kargh.
Channel close, Miss Uhura.
Sir.
Mr. Spock we’ll detain the Esterion and
tow his vessel to the nearest Starbase.
Ambassador, I’d like your written opinion on this
situation to go along with my official report.
Of course.
You realize, we may never
discover who else was involved.
You mean, we may never know who all of
our enemies are -- inside the Federation.
Keep it in mind, Captain Kirk.
And look to your back.
Pavel …
We’re almost at Starbase 16.
From there, the ambassadors will be
given transit to their home planets.
Leaving?
In a few moments.
You need a pilot.
- A shuttle.
- Mr. Scott has volunteered.
Good man.
Thanks to you he’s alive to do it . . .
Pavel,
it has been my great honor...
and joy...to know you.
Thank you . . . for bringing me home.
The pleasure
has been mine,
my lady.
Do Svidania …
(Farewell)
Thank you, Ambassador.
There's...
been a steady stream of visitors
through here today.
Sulu...
Uhura...
... Doctor McCoy.
Mr. Scott, he brought me a bottle of vodka...
for...
when I’m on my feet again.
And...
S... Spock.
For
my journey.
I thought I’d take my turn.
Captain and all.
Who’d have thought, I’d live so long,
in such a short time.
I didn’t …
do too badly, did I?
Never.
You had top marks from the beginning.
The bridge will never be the same without you.
You’re the best Weapons Officer,
the best navigator.
... in the fleet.
In the fleet.
[Sad Russian music playing...]
English subtitles by Peter Walker.
www.startreknewvoyages.de
Captain's log, stardate 2683.4
An attempt to rescue the Enterprise
from a Romulan threat,
has propelled Sulu forward,
thirty years in time.
There's a signal. Looks to be Sulu,
but something's nee right.
Mr. Sulu, what was 30 years to you,
was 30 seconds to us.
Something else.
- Alana.
- Who is she?
She's my daughter.
You're Captain Kirk, aren't you?
How did you know?
My father told me
you were impressive...
...and knew it.
You command miracles
and you don't even know it.
I'm starting to.
We now have only 32 minutes,
before our shields collapse.
I don't care who dies--
she lives!
World Enough and Time, with George Takei
www.startreknewvoyages.de