so you think they'd be pretty pro quo
begin but apparently
in a bone to debate with the tea party
or they thought it was a good story line
and uh... they got a new character that
was revealed last week
jack's slacker
and he's a tea party guy and his dad
his at manager co real american phys ed
boulter
and zeb coulter goes out there and talks
about you know
t partylite principles
the nelson said that uh...
by he gets fan mail from rush limbaugh
glenn beck and alex jones
outsourcing prop course the realities
alex is probably fuming about the
conspiracy and obviously the rock chosen
the rockefellers of taken over to the
beat of the all these things are obvious
uh... anyway
mandate
so the conservative fans arm
so melissa closely rates in the deputies
making a big mistake with this jack
swagger storyline
and then uh... marks god or rights in
amused by this
for are you doing does them culture guy
a killer tea party saratoga angle
this a lot of money
military immediately for about a month
right
during your guest i sound like they're
maker is i'm not like
did they wait but data and
that there is no favorite
i see the w_b_ scrapping all over the
tea party right now with the jack
swaggert jimmy not cool law definitely
select out teacup
but here's what's my favorite
with their handle sister bolger
defense bloody the idea that they were
that's funny
but they're checking pilot does arise
that would every where in that direction
you met pads flatness while ago data
liberal that was the bad guy
and think that was funny too
and by the way he's gonna be fighting
jack swagger is alberto del rio
are all heavyweight championship
so the team for a guy
against m_x_ kya
come on house that not fun
the matter with you guys that's fun
drama
and you never know team forty guys maybe
your guide keep them asking guys as and
then you guys can point out something
wrong
the buses dog
so are miss
needlessly reminded us
well john stossel than doctor david
initials
these days wrestling inmates that their
faith which drives me crazy i don't
think that your government
like storylines what is this uh... soap
opera now
all wrestling is the end
in this poor or in print and interest as
well as the one out
okay
uh... everybody's lives is a drama new
store that's a site map in the old days
we just saw solidity view that doctor
david the schultz
uh... irish also still
carrying out a storyline is singled
convincing
what you have a good bit her the odds
are good that i would be a good one
propelled only without the babbitt's
renewing it and apart from the camera
related pretty redneck dot hearing any
part of the top didn't
separate like that all you got
so that's what you knew the interview
was going south
antoine miller direction and he's
rednecks adhered ainit barricaded
sadness
and then what happened next was living
there
i think it's a site
today despite cut
dot
uh... what they are hardly at all but
dot holder
bulky six
now that was terribly wrong of course it
is thrown out a wrestling and he's
probably
your grocery bags and
thank you have a good day router worry
is right
of and dr feel bad for john stossel
and then he had to run away only goof
that i wasn't there
and of course just levels are of course
it was fake except for that one e crazy
mo moment from those schultz
anil
jericho multiple at at fault to this
that we've never shown any interest
before
voice also goes and gets in the bible
walters on it
franchise tax had heard that this
happened here are not until i start that
i
realized the impact of this i'd hope
nobody thinks that this was part of your
story you really weren't because i
understand
all right now that it's been difficult
or you mostly just to watch it
laptop power to protect their what part
of the left and it's just it just makes
me mad armenian orion each year
dr arthur the editor damage but probably
permanent lightyears works
uh... winter a lot of fans of the time
of both of those buyers people talk live
with her
information p it's not about in
and entertaining and then became very
clear and very their own unfortunately
in your case in that part of it to him
happy about it
if it doesn't tell them having trouble
hearing which doctor doctor shields
so the recipe just as a huge libertarian
guide now at very likely republican
voter so im coarsely wrestles with the
republicans are on for a long time now