they had not been
this active in going after government
officials and that outside world at this
level
ever before
so what about how we talking about here
well recently
texas uh... this returning my gma clone
and his wife were killed and just so i
was coming on air sonu report release
that mike mcclellan was shot twenty
times
so that is an execution
no question about it
sane people division is always shot his
wife once so clearly sending a message
former texas district attorney mark
costs
was killed
just under three months ago working on
the same cases indicting
they re brotherhood of texas
now in colorado a different group
kodai apparently part of the present
cheap
compliments
knocked on his door he s is the war
issue and that
and that guy we know about
uh... 'cause he was later in a shoot out
it was killed as well
and uh... that's parle part of it
uh... colorado uh...
two eleven group that's also an area
grouping in the colorado prisons
now we have an inside source uh... from
the president's
therapies for the
daily beast and
he has a very interesting perspective on
this
he says for example four people
have been killed since the beginning of
the year this series of shootings that
appear to be connected
the homegrown
g hottest
of the aryan brotherhood g hyannis
and they are apparently coming now
before i give you more details of what
they're source inside the prison says
get a lot of this right before we came
on air
never seen this in america
prosecutor just quit
an aryan brotherhood case because a
security concerns
it's in texas
u_s_ attorney jay hellman
except out any email to the defense
attorneys saying
short once a
as a security concerns i will no longer
be part of this case
that's basically u_s_ prosecutors saying
no mots
ads audible
leave global
by the way to squeak note
what would happen if it was
muslim jihad
we would be on terror alert
thirteen on main
whatever the maxim is we go to morning
above it
if they killed four people
involving doctor finacial ta is
prison officials
their muslim side dot it almighty god
the whole country would be on fire but
we should be on fire i can't believe
secular government officials
and it appears allegedly
that is the aryan brotherhood so now
more promise of the press
america's harsh judicial system
coupled with a growing national affinity
for u lies in complete isolation the
super max prisons
as a corrections tactic my first choice
in many cases turns men into monsters
this is willie interested
that is a calm whatever in fact as a
play yesterday on the current show on
the young turks
the unmarked quote out from southern
poverty law center
and he said
the very are running thing happened
decades ago when we do you say great in
the presence
it created more racial gangs
including the aryan brotherhood
if you're white anywhere the president
well if you didn't have protection you
were in trouble
it let people more into the aryan
brotherhood
so they got a president they're more
likely to become radicalized
and at some point
they get out of prison
guys imprisoned a runny hw
crime organizations
selling drugs in family math is the
number one
thing that they're selling and then so
when texas
working with federal prosecutors
indicted thirty four this very brothers
of texas guys or that's what all the
sudden hell broke loose
alava marcio
and the second banker is what this
former presidents talking about
inside a jail where sol arch
sold for calling in
there were basically creating monsters
and then releasing them into the world
more from that
performer preserved
many of personal locked up when our
nation embarked on policy
for for-profit
mass incarceration
near then the last century are now
returning in this society
and as predicted by numerous
professionals their sector and more
dangerous
them when they went behind bars
this is a recipe for disaster today and
get on the current show i was talking to
a represents tantrums over from new
hampshire
he made a terrific point
they're trying to block
privatized prisons and introduce it
thing about the incentives
now in a public prison youth
theoretically one do some rehabilitation
now that's been up a bit theory
and not put into practice a lot here in
the u_s_ is another part of our
but inside the private residence
they actually the financial motivation
to make sure
but those people are so bad that they
come back into president
so that that prior presented make more
money
you know they're going to rehabilitation
or their incentivize to create monsters
that then
arr again release into the world
commit more crimes and come back in the
private prisons
the fear among law enforcement is for
the should be
is that now we have dozens upon dozens
if not hundreds
who knows maybe even thousands
of murders chickens
finally coming home to roost
and we're seeing today
and as i said unbelievably some d_a_'s
are now saying i got no interest in
those chickens and i'm wrong over the
hills
i've seen this i have another country's
you had lethal
drug gangs in mexico
this is a different situation and is now
happening here
and these are aryan brotherhood guys
apparently there behind
we gotta get incredibly serious about
this problem
by the way while last final
insult to injury
when president obama first took office
uh... there was a homeland security
report that said
white supremacist groups
huge problem for domestic terrorism
right wing talk show hosts like rush
limbaugh the foxes guys wed
howell aanu how hearing talk about right
wing groups
and possibly white supremacist
no you take that other board of course
what a president mama do as usual yest
are absolutely start
we're down to one person into part of
our ministry because of an alteration of
what parts used
rush limbaugh said
then not dead on the part of the one
person
training white supremacist remiss
they're doing this kind of violence
how's that work it out for us