MALE SPEAKER: This way
after he come out.
PAPARAZZO: Emma, Emma.
PAPARAZZO: Emma.
PAPARAZZO: Down here, please.
PAPARAZZO: Down here!
PAPARAZZO: Get your bag!
STEVEN RANDOLPH NARRATING: I
think we can all agree that
paparazzi are some of
the lowest forms of
life on planet Earth.
The ever-growing business of
invading public persons'
privacy and the seemingly
insatiable appetite for such
garbage prove that more than
ever, people are looking for
glimpses into lives
that seem more
interesting than their own.
PAPARAZZO: I love you!
STEVEN RANDOLPH NARRATING: When
Vice asked me if I wanted
to write a story about this
profession, I jumped at the
opportunity.
I had to know.
Were they just trying
to get by?
I decided to go directly
to the source.
STEVEN RANDOLPH: Going down
Melrose here, where we're
going to meet the photographer,
[BLEEP].
I don't know his last name, and
it's probably better that
way, you know?
STEVEN RANDOLPH NARRATING: After
asking various contacts,
I was put in touch with Peter,
a professional and somewhat
jaded paparazzo, who agreed to
give me all the pertinent
details I would need to capture
my prey in exchange
for his anonymity.
What is it?
Like I--
I don't know, like what
is a paparazzi.
STEVEN RANDOLPH NARRATING: He
also said that there are a
select few freelance
photographers, such as
himself, who adhere to a
moral code of sorts.
STEVEN RANDOLPH: What did
you do before this?
Before this career as a pap?
STEVEN RANDOLPH: It sounds kind
of like a stripper being
asked to be called a dancer.
You're not really dancing.
STEVEN RANDOLPH NARRATING: He
also schooled me on the
paparazzi circuit and its
respective territories.
STEVEN RANDOLPH NARRATING: With
this information at my
disposal, I was ready to start
my rampage of invasiveness.
STEVEN RANDOLPH: Gonna post up
and try to hunt the hunters.
STEVEN RANDOLPH NARRATING: My
photographer and I headed
straight for the guitar statue
outside BOA, a popular
nightclub on Sunset Boulevard
frequented by celebrities.
STEVEN RANDOLPH: We see a huge
guitar, and there's two
shady-looking dudes in beanies,
and they look like
the kind of guys that are
willing to fight.
We pulled up two blocks away.
I'm starting to get nervous.
STEVEN RANDOLPH NARRATING: We
parked and went over our plan,
which basically amounted to
getting in their faces and
asking increasingly personal
and judgmental questions.
STEVEN RANDOLPH: A paparazzi is
telling me to not get too
close to the story.
That's funny.
Hey, homey.
How are you?
Please tell us, what are
you wearing right now?
Who are you wearing?
What does your underwear
look like?
Please tell us.
Who are you with?
Do you feel bad when you
go home at night,
doing this to people?
Do you like a pinky in
the butt during sex?
Sir, sir, sir!
[POUNDING ON GLASS]
When you're getting a blowjob,
do you like one single pinky
in your butt?
I'm not getting the scoop
from you, dude.
We want to know, just
one question,
sir, just one question.
Do you smell the toilet paper
after you wipe, sir?
Do you go number-two
in the workplace?
Somehow I think in this
interview that you think
you're holding on to some last
shred of like, what you're
doing is art.
It's not.
You're taking picture of
celebrities at vulnerable
moments without their
permission.
They don't know who you are.
You guys interview
other people.
How come I'm not allowed
to interview you?
Does this make you feel weird?
Why-- if you guys do this for
a living, why are you so
pissed off that we're
doing it to you?
STEVEN RANDOLPH: I'm
not in your face.
I just have a quick question.
Why are you hiding?
Why is there so much shame
behind what you're doing?
You don't like, you don't like
your own medicine, bro.
You don't like the way it feels
to you, then why would--
why would you do that to your
fellow man and woman?
You're getting mad at me
following you around, trying
to get a hot scoop.
And that's what you're doing.
That'd be like a butcher who's
afraid of eating meat.
Why hide in bushes at a
restaurant for Paris Hilton's
tit to fall out?
If you're such a photographer,
why don't-- why don't you go
and, and shoot waves
at Maui, or--?
STEVEN RANDOLPH: All
right, this is
Steve for Vice Magazine.
I thought we were
going to have a
really crazy story here.
I heard stories of, like,
Brazilian guys
that love to fight.
Thought we were going
to encounter that.
But what we encountered
is a bunch of cowards.
Most of these guys are just
pussies, and they're not down
to scrap or do anything
like that.
So, um, it was kind of a
fun story, but it was
anti-climactic.
Like who these guys really are,
that you see the pictures
like on TMZ, they're a bunch
of scared guys who--
I'm sitting here solo, kind of
like a pussy myself, and they
don't even want to
make eye contact.
So they feel bad about what
they're doing, and it's kind
of like grinding someone into
the ground at this point.
I'm gonna just take off.
I feel bad.
Later guys.
Thanks for playing, man.
Thank you.
Good night.