movies, and I disliked
liked all of them.
I've seen maybe 10
Chinese movies.
I disliked all of them.
-This one's very calm.
It's basically--
THOM DEVITA: Yeah, I don't
care about calm.
I like good acting.
-Maybe it was good to them.
-Yeah.
THOM DEVITA:No.
No, it's not.
I really like film
noir movies.
There's nothing like them.
I like Edward G. Robinson--
nobody like him.
-No, I like him.
THOM DEVITA: He's an actor.
Is he different from
the other actors?
-Yeah, he's good.
THOM DEVITA: I think
he's the best.
-They were good, but a lot
of that stuff was like
over-acted.
THOM DEVITA: No, it's
not over-acted.
-Some of it was.
THOM DEVITA: No.
-It was.
Compared to what they do today,
it was over-acted.
-Marlon Brando changed
that with the--
THOM DEVITA: Oh, that's why I
didn't like Marlon Brando.
I didn't like Marlon Brando.
I'm not a great fan
of Marlon Brando.
[JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING]
THOM DEVITA: I'm not a great
fan of the director of "The
Godfather."
-Francis Ford Coppola.
THOM DEVITA: Yeah, I'm not
a fan of his movies.
ROBERT RYAN: No good movies were
made after the film noir
period, as far as Thom's
concerned.
THOM DEVITA: What you want to
see is Orson Welles in "A
Touch of Evil." What film noir
movie have you seen?
-I saw one about a nun.
ROBERT RYAN: He's definitely
very particular about what he
likes when it comes to
art, music, film.
But he's got great taste.
THOM DEVITA: I hate
rock and roll.
No Rolling Stones.
-Yeah, yeah.
THOM DEVITA: Stupid
Rolling Stones.
-They call--
-You don't like rock-- you
a big rock and roll fan?
-No.
THOM DEVITA: What'd
I tell you before?
I said '20s, '30s, '40s.
That is it.
Everything after 1949--
all popular culture--
went downhill.
I told this to Scott, and Scott
says, you just threw
more than half a century
out the window.
[LAUGHTER]
THOM DEVITA: [INAUDIBLE].
ED HARDY: He's got this
totally rigid thing.
And again, he's 12 years
older than me.
But I've hung out with a lot of
people a lot older than me
that I had a real
rapport with, or
had more common ground.
But deVita just--
that's it.
This is what it is.
ROBERT RYAN: Then no good jazz
music was made after they made
hot jazz, cool.
When it became cool jazz, Thom
stopped listening to it.
-So you don't like
John Coltrane?
THOM DEVITA: No.
-I know.
OK.
Just making sure.
THOM DEVITA: No.
You know who likes
John Coltrane?
People who don't like jazz.
They say, oh, now,
that's nice!
You want to hear some?
Put on that tape over there,
and you'll hear
some real hot jazz.
[NEWSCAST PLAYING]
-Mitt Romney has had nothing
to do with it and--
[JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING]
-Who's this, Thom?
THOM DEVITA: Oh, Earl "Fatha"
Hines on piano.
I used to go listen to this here
on 2nd Avenue between St.
Mark's and 7th Street when
I was 17 years old.
Makes you tap your
feet and dance.
I was born in Manhattan--
lived there for 60
years of my life.
NICK BUBASH: I think he was
born in 1932, and he was
raised on the Upper East
Side in Harlem.
And as far as I know, his dad
had a store of some kind--
whether it was a candy store or
fruits and vegetables, or
something like that.
THOM DEVITA: My father was born
in Sicily, come here when
he was about five.
-That's your first
communion photo?
THOM DEVITA: Yes.
JOHN WYATT: I asked Thom what
he did before he became a
tattoo artist.
And he said in the '50s, he and
his brother were pickers.
They would go to the Upper
East Side on garbage
collection days, that people
would put furniture and other
objects out in front
of their buildings.
They earned about $200 a week,
a piece, and never
reported any of it.
They never had a Social
Security number.
NICK BUBASH: Thom told me that
his first apartment was $25.
And he couldn't get $25 together
every month, so he
moved into an apartment
for $15.
And he couldn't get that
together, either.
He was an artist's model
is what he did.
That was a job he did, I think,
on a regular basis-- an
artist's model.
We have one cover that Hardy
uncovered, somehow.
It was a picture of him, I
think, dressed as like a Cuban
communist or something
like that.
THOM DEVITA:Does this
look like me?
-It does in that photo.
THOM DEVITA: He's a very
realistic artist.
NICK BUBASH: And I can't
remember him ever talking
about having a job.
I think he worked in
a scrap metal yard
for about 10 minutes.
Thom was not a labor guy.
He had a job digging
ditches one time.
He lasted about a couple hours,
him and his brother,
and then they just left the
shovels there and split.
THOM DEVITA: Worked in
scrap metal yard.
I think it was in the Bronx.
Dropped-- was a manhole
cover on my foot.
Just lifting it, and it slipped
out of my hand and
broke my toe.
-And so you went downtown
because you were out of work?
THOM DEVITA: No, I got workman's
compensation.
-Oh.
You went down to be with
the bohemians.
But he was too late.
They were gone.
THOM DEVITA: I was 30
years too late.
1959 or '60.
-All that was left
was the beatniks.
THOM DEVITA: The end
of the beatniks.
-It was the end of
beatnik era.
The beginning of the hippie
era was what was
starting, the hipsters.
There were a lot of social
changes going on,
and things like that.
But things were changing.
ROBERT RYAN: Thom told me that
him and his brother, I guess
they were probably still living
in Harlem at that time,
and they wanted to
go downtown--
go to one of the arty places,
I guess Thom's brother said.
And Thom thought they were going
to see a guy named Arty.
But Thom's brother wanted
to go to the art bars.
I think it might have been in
the West Village at the time.
-Avoid being a square.
Be an in chick with
an out crowd.
Be cool without being cold,
and remain young
and never grow old.
Dig my sermon.
My sermon--
ROBERT RYAN: They were just like
meeting a lot of people
and doing a lot of stuff and
just making good time in that
neighborhood at that time.
ED HARDY: He's had a really,
really interesting life.
And he used to hang his
paintings or his artwork on
the fence around Washington
Square.
I'm very big on the New York
school of painting and stuff
from the mid-20th century.
And de Kooning and all those
guys are my heroes.
And Thom was around that.
He's been doing art forever.
He knew those guys
at the Cedar Bar.
NICK BUBASH: I can remember
him telling stories about
Franz Kline having an argument
with Willem de Kooning about
something, or whatever.
He used to go there and
spend time among them.
THOM DEVITA: I just rubbed
elbows, just was in the same
bar with them.
De Kooning is the only one who
I spoke with, and he'd say
hello to me all the time,
whenever he saw me.
They didn't know I
was a tattooer--
just an artist.
I said I was an artist, then
I became an artist.
-So it's just like kind of like
he was artist, model,
odd-jobber, picker.
NICK BUBASH: Tattooer.
Yeah, exactly.
Just like me.
And how we got into tattooing,
I don't know.
I think it was like a switch was
hit, I think, or maybe--
I don't know.
I can't tell you that.
I can't answer the question.
I recently learned that he got
his first tattoo when he was
17 years old.
Now, I had not known that.
THOM DEVITA: That's
Charlie Wagner.
MALE SPEAKER: Did you get
tattooed by Charlie?
THOM DEVITA: No.
No, I was 17.
That's when I had gone into
Charlie Wagner for
a snake and a skull.
He says he wasn't
putting them on.
ANGELO SCOTTO: You hear stories
about Charlie kind of
hawking, like a barker
at a carnival.
Kind of that hawking, come
here and get tattooed.
He's probably one of the
originators of tattooing in
New York City--
on the Bowery.
You hear stories, oh, I paid a
quarter for this, a bottle of
Sneaky Pete.
The stories were true.
ED HARDY: Wagner was still on
the Bowery, and Thom wanted to
get a dagger done from him.
And Wagner said, I'm not doing
daggers this week.
I'm doing ships.
That's it.
That's on the wall.
It's a done deal.
That's how the tattoo
shops were.
It's like Henry Ford in the old
days-- any color you want
as long as it's black.
He had the market.
He had the fucking cars.
And if you wanted it, that's
how you got it.
THOM DEVITA: So I went
down the block.
I went down the block.
And I got it from Moskowitz.
-The old man, or the--
THOM DEVITA: The old man.
And the next time I went
down, he says the
kid will put it on.
And the kid looked like
he was younger than I
was, and I was 17.
I wanted a Moskowitz.
Then I met him years later.
He hadn't heard that story.
He was [INAUDIBLE].
Figured out [INAUDIBLE].
He says, I remember you.
-Do you find it odd that Thom
started tattooing when he was
in his late 30s?
ANGELO SCOTTO: Well, Huck
Spaulding told me that Thom
bought machines from
him years before--
years before--
and just kept them
in the drawer.
That's what Huck Spaulding
told me.
ED HARDY: He sent away.
He had Spaulding's address.
DeVita would always go,
"Spauldeen." He said, I wrote
away to "Spauldeen" in Albany.
And he gets these machines.
He takes the rubber bands off.
This must be packing material.
I can't get this fucking
thing to work.
So he called Huck.
And then it came out in the
phone conversation.
And Huck said, well, are the
rubber bands adjusted right?
And he went, well, I thought
that was packing.
I took them off.
And the needle's
jumping around.
He probably never got close
enough to watch somebody work.
And people didn't like you
asking questions, anyway.
Most tattooers, if you ask
questions, they throw you out.
-If you ask him when he started
to tattoo, he just
asked, what year did
it become illegal?
ANGELO SCOTTO: 1961,
by Mayor Wagner.
Charlie Wagner started it, and
Mayor Wagner finished it.
JOHN WYATT: I saved a lot of
articles, and this is when
tattooing was banned
in New York.
That's Tony D'Anessa.
It was banned in 1961, allegedly
over a health issue.
And the tattoo artists that were
out of business opened up
in other cities.
ANGELO SCOTTO: And there was
only two places in the whole
state of New York
to get tattooed.
It was Huck Spaulding in Albany
and Stanley and Walter
in Long Island, yeah,
when it was legal.
-There are very few people in
New York in the late '60s and
'70s that were doing tattoos.
There was Tony Polito.
There were the guys
in New Jersey.
NICK BUBASH: Mike Malone
may have been
tattooing at that time.
And then everybody else was on
the outskirts, because it was
illegal in Manhattan.
-Thom was tattooing
underground out of his apartment.
I think he started off tattooing
on 8th Street and
then eventually moved
to 4th Street.
THOM DEVITA: When I was
underground, I worked what was
once a kitchen.
Took out the stove and the
refrigerator, and it's no
longer a kitchen.
ANGELO SCOTTO: He just worked
off a kitchen table.
Everybody started on their
kitchen table.
You're a bootlegger.
THOM DEVITA: I used to have it
on one of my cards, "not for
public display in
New York City."
-Remember the time you were
raided, and you put everything
in trash bags and threw them--
THOM DEVITA: Yeah, that
was another time.
-Threw them out the window--
THOM DEVITA: No, no.
I wasn't raided.
-Or you thought you were
going to be raided.
THOM DEVITA: I thought they
had helicopters above--
-Yeah, they had helicopters.
THOM DEVITA: Above my house.
-Can't remember the story.
THOM DEVITA: I say what,
is this for me?
I threw them down
in the backyard.
And they went into
the garbage can.
So then I go out the front
door, and there's police.
Oh, I said, my God.
What is this?
They were after some rapist.
-Thom thought they were raiding
the tattoo shop.