Newtown, Connecticut, Aurora, Colorado, Tucson,
Arizona - when a mass shooting happens like
we`ve seen in those cities, the issue of gun
control often comes up. President Obama has
said he wants to take action on this, he`s
put Vice President Joe Biden in charge of
coming up with ideas on how to reduce gun
violence. Vice President Biden`s task force
is getting input from people with many different
view points. Yesterday, I`ve met with gun
safety organizations and victims from some
of these shootings. Now, they are pushing
for stricter gun control. Today, the task
force is set to meet with representatives
from groups that support gun rights, like
the National Rifle Association. That organization
says it`s committed to protecting people,
but it thinks stricter gun laws aren`t the
best way to do that. Retail stores that sell
guns are also going to be involved in these
meetings. President Obama said he wants some
concrete proposals from the task force by
the end of this month.
2012 is in the books, and it`s in the record
books, too. Last year is officially the hottest
year ever for the United States. It was also
the second worst for extreme weather: things
like hurricanes, droughts or floods. The average
temperature across the lower 48 states was
55.3 degrees. That beat the old record by
a full degree. Scientists say that when things
get warmer, it raises the chances for extreme
weather. All 48 of those states had above
average temperatures last year, but some set
their own superlatives.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: You`ve got to tell me if
you don`t feel good.
CHAD MYERS, AMS METEOROLOGIST: The warmest
year on record for the United States. Every
here, every spot here in the red, a new record
for the hottest event for any year ever recorded.
And July, 2012 was the hottest year on record
of any month we`ve ever recorded since we`ve
been here.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: In many U.S. States state legislatures
are back in session this week and next. They`ve
got different names in different states. They
may be called the state house and senate.
The legislative assembly, the general assembly,
but basically, they are meeting of people
elected by the states citizens to make laws.
All right, cool, so what - well, a lot of
the things that affect you every day are determined
by state legislatures. They make laws about
your schools and the requirements for graduation.
They decide who can drive and when, they ensure
roads are taken care of and safe. They operate
states courts and they decide how much tax
you pay when you go out to eat or you buy
clothes. These are all responsibilities of
the state, so while we spend a lot of time
talking about the U.S. Congress on CNN STUDENT
NEWS, we want you to keep in mind that your
state law makers pass laws that effect you
as well. It`s part of what`s called "federalism."
It`s a system of government where the same
place is controlled by two different authorities,
so in this case that would be your state government
and the U.S. Federal Government. Each of the
50 states has a governor he or she represents
the states executive branch. Your state courts
are the states judicial branch and the state
legislatures we just talked about make up
your states legislative branch.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: See if you can I.D. me.
I`m a South American country that`s home to
about 28 million people. I border the Caribbean
Sea, Colombia and Brazil. I`m one of the world`s
largest exporters of oil. My president is
Hugo Chavez. I`m Venezuela. And President
Chavez has been in charge of my government
for nearly 14 years.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Hugo Chavez is supposed to stay in charge
of Venezuela`s government for the next six
years. He was reelected to a new term last
year. The country`s constitution says his
inauguration is today, on January Tenth. There`s
a problem, though, Chavez won`t be there.
The Venezuelan president has been in Cuba
for the past month or so, he`s being treated
there for cancer. There was some concern in
Venezuela about what might happen if Chavez
missed the inauguration. The Constitution
there says that if a leader is permanently
absent, there would have to be new elections.
That`s not going to happen. Yesterday Venezuela`s
Supreme Court ruled that President Chavez
will start his new term today even if he`s
not sworn in.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today "Shoutout" goes
out to Mr. Breese`s class at Odyssey Charter
School inn Palm Bay, Florida.
What U.S. State is home to the National Baseball
Hall of Fame? You know what to do, is it in
New York, Ohio, Texas or California? You`ve
got three seconds, go!
Baseball`s Hall of Fame is in Cooperstown.
So if you said New York, you hit out the park.
That`s your answer and that`s your shoutout.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: That Hall of Fame isn`t getting any
new members this year: there were 37 players
eligible to get into Cooperstown on the 2013
ballot. But when the votes came in, no one
was elected to the Hall of Fame. This isn`t
that unusual, it has happened before seven
other times since the Hall of Fame voting
started in 1936. What`s really interesting
about this, this time around is that some
of the players who were eligible for the first
time have been accused of using performance
enhancing drugs. That includes all time home
run king Barry Bonds, seven times Cy Young
winner Roger Clemens and Sammy Sosa, one of
only eight players to hit more than 600 career
home runs. All three have denied using performance
enhancing drugs. The Hall of Fame is voted
on by members of the Baseball Writers` Association
of America. Players need to get support from
75 percent of the voters in order to get into
Cooperstown. One voter said, this year`s results
are a statement on baseball`s so called "steroid
era." He says the concerns about players who
were linked to steroids has hurt the Hall
of Fame chances for some clean players as
well. This is an issue we are talking about
in our blog. So, you are welcome to log on
to cnnstudent.com, to tell us your opinion.
In 2010, Congress passed a law called the
Pedestrian Safety Enhancement Act, it laid
out new rules for certain vehicles. The Department
of Transportation looked at a lot of factors
including the extra costs for car companies,
now they are planning to put these rules in
effect. So why is the government making noise
about cars that don`t make enough?
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
RENE MARSH, CNN CORRESPONDENT: They are green,
fuel efficient, but too quiet and a potential
threat to cyclists and pedestrians. That`s
what the Department of Transportation says
about hybrid and electric cars. The federal
agency just proposed rules that would require
new green vehicles make sounds loud enough
to alert pedestrians and cyclists like George
Abbot.
GEORGE ABBOT, PEDESTRIAN, CYCLIST: I have
the experience going alongside them - and
not, like not realizing that there was one
there.
MARSH: It`s what`s under the hood that makes
this hybrid an electric car so quiet on the
road. This Nissan Leaf also has technologies
similar to what the government wants in all
electric and hybrid cars. Do you hear that
sound? Well, the government believes it could
save lives.
Eddie George sells the vehicles at Dart cars
in Maryland.
EDDIR GEORGE, DARCARS NISSAN: The car is very
quiet, you cannot hear anything, so I mean
you have some people when they are coming
to test drive the car, the car is on.
MARSH: But a flip of a switch and its pedestrian
alert feature turns on. Without the feature,
a much quieter drive.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: I didn`t know that would
help, but I think, you know, again, I think
people would just need to pay more attention.
MARSH: DOT says the sounds would need to be
loud enough to still be heard despite other
street and ambient noises when the vehicle
is traveling under 18 miles per hour.
The National Highway Traffic Safety Administration
estimates their proposal would mean 2800 fewer
pedestrian and cyclist injuries per year.
MARSH: You shouldn`t expect to hear blaring
sounds coming from these green cars, if this
is enacted, it was a lot louder in our piece
because our mikes picked up the sound. Each
company can pick their particular sound they
want their cars to make. For example, the
vehicle we looked at, the Nissan Leaf, the
technology, it was developed with the help
of students at some of the country`s schools
for the hearing impaired. Rene Marsh, CNN,
Washington.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: All right, well, before we go, we`ve
got a beastly tail of mistaken identity: reports
of a lion on the loose in Norfolk, Virginia,
might have given some residents paws - look
at this thing, it`s kind of cute. There was
no need for concern, as you can see. The carousing
cat was actually a dog. Easy to understand
the mix up, though. This labradoodle`s owner
cuts his canine so that he resembles the local
university mascot - a lion. Still, police
called the zoo just to make sure that cats
were in their cages. So it seems like this
time the main event was just the king of the
concrete jungle. CNN STUDENT NEWS returns
tomorrow. No lion about that, we look forward
to seeing you all then.