CARL AZUZ, CNN ANCHOR: I`m Carl Azuz. And
this is CNN STUDENT NEWS. World Series starts
tonight, so good luck to you, Tigers and Giants
fans. We are going to have some serious history
coming up. But first, we are hitting the campaign
trail.
For the top two presidential candidates, the
debates are over, the conventions are far
behind us, the election is less than two weeks
away. So now what? What are they doing between
right this second and election day? In a nutshell,
it`s an all-out sprint. President Barack Obama
and Republican Presidential nominee Mitt Romney
are crisscrossing the country. They are meeting
with potential voters, going on TV shows,
posing for pictures and campaigning in front
of crowds. There will a lot of that, especially
in swing states, where it`s uncertain which
candidate is likely to win. The campaigns
are buying up ad space, so you`ll see more
commercials on more channels, and their running
mates, wives and families are doing all they
can to get supporters to vote on November
Sixth. At this point, it`s anyone`s guess
who will win the election. A CNN political
reporter says Americans will wake up on election
day not knowing who their next president will
be. It makes the campaigning and the candidates
due between now and election day even more
significant.
Our next story takes us to Italy, some people
in the scientific world are stunned about
a court case that just wrapped up there.
Six scientists and a government official have
been convicted on manslaughter charges, and
sentenced to six years in prison. This goes
back to an earthquake that hit the city of
L in 2009. The court ruled that these scientists
didn`t do enough to warn people that there
was an earthquake risk. The trial focused
on a meeting that happened one week before
the quake. City residents had raised concerns
about recent seismic activity. At this meeting,
the scientists determined it was unlikely
that a major quake would hit. Unlikely, but
not impossible. When that major quake did
hit, more than 300 people were killed. Earthquake
experts around the world say it`s impossible
to predict earthquakes with any kind of accuracy,
they say this court ruling could stop scientists
from making predictions in the future. But
another expert says, the case wasn`t about
predictions, it was about communication and
the failure to get information out.
Back in the U.S., the Food and Drug Administration,
the FDA says it`s looking into reports of
a possible connection between energy drinks
and five deaths. The parents of 14-year old
are suing Monster Beverage, which makes Monster
energy drinks. The parents say their daughter
died from heart problems after drinking Monster
Energy on two consecutive days. Law suit says
the drinks had 480 milligrams of caffeine,
that`s equal to about 15 cans of soda or three
cups of coffee. And it`s nearly five times
more caffeine than medical experts say teenagers
should have in a day. The FDA says it hasn`t
found any direct link so far between this
teen`s death and the energy drink. Monster
Beverage says it`s saddened by the death,
but "doesn`t believe that its beverages are
in any way responsible."
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today`s "Shoutout" goes
out to Mr. Tolen`s American Government & Civics
Class at Niles Community High School in Troy,
Michigan.
What is this: You know what to do, is it a
mammal, reptile, a fish or amphibian? You`ve
got three seconds, go!
What you are looking at is a mammal, specifically
it`s a beluga whale, which is sometimes called,
a white whale. That`s your answer and that`s
your "Shoutout."
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Well, here is a fun fact for you. Belugas
are sometimes called canaries of the sea,
because they make this high-pitch chirping
sounds, scientists are saying, though, that`s
not the only sounds that these whales can
make.
(VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: It sounded kind of like a person`s voice,
but muffled, right? That was a beluga. Researchers
think it figured out how to mimic the human
voice after spending a lot of time around
people. What clued researchers in was when
a diver thought someone was giving him underwater
directions, telling him to get out of the
tank. It turns out, he was hearing the whale.
It`s fascinating stuff. The next story today
is about pirates. Not the movies, those are
kind of fun, we are talking about the pirates
involved in some of the very dangerous attacks
we`ve reported on in recent years. Now, according
to new information, there are actually fewer
of those attacks this year. The International
Maritime Bureau says piracy is at its lowest
level since 2008. During the first nine months
of this year, the organization says there
have been 233 actual and attempted pirate
attacks around the world. During the same
timeframe last year, there were 352. The leader
of the group says it`s good news, but he added
that the voters where these attacks happen
are still dangerous, and that there still
needs to be a Naval presence there.
On this day in history, in 1861, the first
transcontinental telegram was sent from San
Francisco to Washington, D.C. It was the first
instant communication from one side of the
U.S. to the other. In 1940, part of the Fair
Labor Standards Act went into effect. It set
the standard work week for American workers
at 40 hours, and in 1992, the Toronto Blue
Jays beat the Atlanta Braves in a six game
to win the World Series. It was the first
time that a Canadian team won the baseball
championship.
Something else happened on this day in history,
and it makes October 24th an annual event.
It`s United Nations Day, because on this day
in 1945, the international organization was
born. The idea for the U.N. came out of World
War II. Representatives from 50 countries
got together to create a charter for the group.
It says the U.N.`s goals are to maintain international
peace and security, develop friendly relations
among nations and work together to solve global
problems. On October 24th, 1945, a majority
of the countries ratified that charter and
the United Nations officially came into existence.
This is Alexandria Horstman, she`s using that
laptop to attend school with little help from
her friends. Here is what this about: Alexandria
is a freshman in Highland, Illinois. At the
start of this school year, doctors told her
she`d have to miss up to three months because
of some medical problem she was dealing with.
Her school uses laptops and iPads, so one
of her friends came up with this idea to carry
Alexandria, using her laptop from class to
class. So she`s not skipping school, she is
skyping school. She is getting better, faster
than doctors predicted. In fact, Alexandria
could be back in class in person this week.
And here is the word to the wise for you:
telekinesis, it`s the ability to make things
move without touching them, so you are using
just your mind. It might sound like a superpower,
and it is for some comic book characters,
but researchers are using telekinesis to help
people who have everyday physical struggles,
like for example, people who are paralyzed.
Take a look at this.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: If you have someone that
can`t communicate, you can completely change
their quality of life by allowing them to
communicate. But the next thing that you want
to restore is mobility. So, the next project
that we took upon ourselves was to try to
be able to drive a wheelchair with mind signals.
I`m the creator and the director of the Georgia
Tech brain lab, which is a research group
that`s devoted to researching and understanding
what kind of control we can have from brain
signals alone.
We were one of the very first labs to control
a wheelchair with brain signals. And we`ve
used a variety of different mechanisms, so
that we might have boxes flashing at different
speeds, and we can tell by brain signal processing
that if you are watching this box that`s flashing
at ten times a second, or this one that`s
flashing at 15 times a second, all you have
to do is pay attention to the one you want.
If you want to turn right, you pay attention
to the one on the right, and we can see, which
one you are looking at by the oscillations
in the brain, how many times a second your
brain is processing it. We can say, you are
looking at the one that`s flashing ten times
a second, and we can turn a wheelchair. Out
most recent wheelchair, one of my master students,
Michael Boys (ph), who is a wheelchair user
himself, reverse-engineered his own wheelchair
to be driven by this - the visual interface,
and he actually drove it around the building
quite a bit. So, that was exciting, and it
gives people control without having to move
a joystick, without having to press a button,
but to be able to move around your own home
without assistance was very important. We
are very focused on providing independence
to people with physical disabilities.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: Some football coaches might not seem
like natural pranksters, but the head coach
at Umass had a good one. He was running a
team meeting last week that was interrupted
by state police officers. They said they had
paperwork for two walk on players, guys might
have thought they were in trouble, but when
they read the fine print, it turns out they
were being awarded full athletic scholarships.
The Youtube video makes one thing clear: the
team might not have the best record on the
field, but that coach is number one in the
college football prankings. Oh yeah, football
puns. We can`t pass them up. We are going
to take a hike and pass them back to your
teachers. I`m Carl Azuz.