BRYAN IGUCHI: Today we're
going to go take some
snowmobiles out and try to build
a couple jumps, or at
least build a jump.
Try and get a couple
jump shots.
Working on a photo shoot
for Volcom right now.
Kind of doing like a little
web edit little
short for the internet.
And then just shooting photos
for a TransWorld magazine
story on Jackson Hole.
KEVIN JONES: Once again, Guch
is taking the early steps.
Like, OK, I'm going to go get
certified to be a guide.
I'm going to spend most my time
with my head in the snow
pit, figuring out what kind of
snow crystal is morphing with
another one, which is all
knowledge that the future of
snowboarding is going to have to
have if they want to go to
these places in the back
country and be alive
to tell about it.
KEVIN JONES: I mean, to this
day, he snowboards more than
anybody I know.
And he loves it more than
It can be a really shitty run.
And Guch is fired up like,
that was so sick.
And you're like, yeah,
I guess it was sick.
[SNOWMOBILE  ENGINE REVVING]
KEVIN JONES: There's nobody,
that I, one, on a stoke level
would want to ride with and,
two, just on an overall safety
factor would want
to ride with.
The guy is just truly
a bad ass.
And there's no one
else like him.
BILLY ANDERSON: We keep getting
older, but they all
stay the same age.
So it's like everyone's coming
up, and they're running into
the same challenges year
after year after year.
And if we can bring authentic
experience to our team, it's
just huge value for us.
I mean, Guch has been there and
lived through his mistakes
and grown from them.
And if we can have those guys
around to mentor the next
generation, it's just going to
make them better people,
better snowboarders.
And that's extremely
valuable to us.
[SNOWMOBILE  ENGINE REVVING]
BRYAN FOX: For me, being on a
trip with Travis, and having
him talk about Iguchi,
is still--
I've never met Bryan Iguchi.
And when he talks about them
it's still like that little
kid, you know where,
that's crazy.
You know that guy.
That's weird to say, because
I'm an adult and that shit
doesn't matter at all,
it's just some guy.
But it's still like you get
that, like, that's crazy.
You casually hang out with this
guy who you still just
hold him on this little
pedestal.
Like, fucking this guy's cool
as shit, no matter what.
BRYAN IGUCHI: Fuck!
VERNON: [INAUDIBLE].
JAKE PRICE: That was
sick, though.
VERNON: Yeah.
JAKE PRICE: Yeah, watching Guch
ride is better than going
and building a jump, Vernon.
Let the other guys do
all the bitch work.
And we'll just show
up and film it.
BRYAN IGUCHI: Want more?
JAKE PRICE: Yeah.
BRYAN IGUCHI: OK.
JAKE PRICE: Or a couple more.
JAKE PRICE: Like I said, we
don't have to build a jump.
We can sit here and
watch him ride.
[SNOWMOBILE  ENGINE REVVING]
KEVIN JONES: The last couple
years I got the ride with
Bryan a bunch.
And it's not about going out
and getting the raddest
snowboarding, although
that is an objective.
But he's done enough to know
that it's about having a good
time out there.
And we went on a camping
trip last year.
And there was not really
any good snow around.
Guch goes and butters out those
cornice and then just
does this Backside
5, and stomps it.
It wasn't like the hugest
thing in the world.
But for the conditions that
we had, I was blown away.
We had some younger
guys in our group.
And I'm like, this guy is like
10 years older than these.
These kids should be up here
riding this, and he should be
down here watching.
But no.
He lapped the thing like 20
times and was just taking what
the mountains gave him.
And that inspired
me once again.
JAKE PRICE: You going
to side flip it?
BRYAN IGUCHI: I'm just
going to go.
JAKE PRICE: OK.
VERNON: You guys ready?
JAKE PRICE: Yep.
VERNON: Ready.
Well, that's a fun
jump, though.
Perfect nice landing.
JAKE PRICE: Heck yeah.
VERNON: You can't
even hear him.
JAKE PRICE: He hit the
pocket that time.
VERNON: Yeah.
BRYAN IGUCHI: I think I've
taken the right path.
And I think my perseverance
with
snowboarding is paying off.
It's like I'm still involved as
a professional snowboarder.
And it's just changing.
I feel more as an ambassador
for the sport.
They want to continue to
support me with my
snowboarding, they want to film
and shoot photos, I love
to go out and ride.
I'll always be out there.
Camera or not, or regardless of
who I'm with, I'm going to
be out snowboarding.
I love it, man.
JAKE PRICE: Yeah, ready.
VERNON: Ready.
JAKE PRICE: Wow, he's on fire.
VERNON: He wants to
keep hitting it.
JAKE PRICE: Yeah, Guch.
BRYAN IGUCHI: It feels good to
be a part of it, and to be
able to offer something and
contribute to younger
snowboarders, and the Volcom
team, and having the guys want
to come out and ride with me,
and be able to help out with
photo shoots, and help get
film shots, and help
just make it happen.
I think it feels good to
be a part of the team.
We going?
JAKE PRICE: Yeah, dude.
BRYAN IGUCHI: I feel weird.
JAKE PRICE: How come?
BRYAN IGUCHI: Just
solo sessioning.
JAKE PRICE: That's awesome.
BILLY ANDERSON: Guch is just
an amazing person.
He's just very humble and
thankful, great energy, and
just a lot of mountain
know-how.
He is just very aware
of what's going on.
And it's dangerous out there,
like with avalanches and just
different snow conditions,
different environments.
Things are always changing
out there, and you need
experience.
JAKE PRICE: Fuck yeah, Guch.
Over 40 and doing, was
that Backside 7?
VERNON: Backside 7
and [INAUDIBLE]?
JAKE PRICE: It's so sick, man.
BRYAN IGUCHI: Want
to get going?
JAKE PRICE: Yeah, I do.
BRYAN IGUCHI: OK.
Well, I'm here, I planted
my roots.
I met my wife here.
I have my son Milo now.
The community and my friends.
It's just home now.
And I'm still continuing to
find new places to ride.
And it's still challenging
and fun.
I think it's a lot of mountains,
a lot of mountains
to explore, a lot of good
riding to be had.
I feel it's every season that
I have new objectives or I'm
discovering new things and
getting to know it better.
BILLY ANDERSON: The doors that
he's opening for younger
riders at earlier stages is just
something that would be
such a bummer if he
wasn't doing it.
And if you had to do that to
get to where he is now, I
don't think he missed
out on anything.
TRAVIS RICE: I guess the one
thing I would say was, beyond
even any of the zones or
avalanche knowledge or any
type of actual thing that he
showed me, more than anything
he just lives his life.
And he answers to truth and
honesty and respect for
himself and the people
around him.
BILLY ANDERSON: When I see
kind of how he's grown up
through it and be able to take
it from a really heavy skate
influence scene and time and
really gone with snowboarding
and transformed into the
mountains, I mean he's really
at a legendary status.
The lock down that he
has on Jackson Hole,
and just his guiding.
And I think he's just about to
revamp this whole thing, which
is his potential and influence
that he can have on
snowboarding.
There's a full second or even
third coming of Bryan
Iguchi right now.
JAKE PRICE: One man demo.
VERNON: Got back.
Several of those were
sick, dude.
BRYAN IGUCHI: Thanks.
JAKE PRICE: That was
fucking awesome.
BRYAN IGUCHI: This is a
fun, fun little jump.
This is fun, you know.
VERNON: Dude, the Back
7 was so sick.
BRYAN IGUCHI: Oh, thanks, man.
VERNON: Man.
BRYAN IGUCHI: This is my
snowboard park, you know.
JAKE PRICE: Yeah,
just like the--
BRYAN IGUCHI: Kind of like
go to fun session jump.
VERNON: It's sick.
That was great.
BRYAN IGUCHI: That cliff up
there is pretty sweet, man.
It reminds me of Mission.
There's a step-down over here,
too, that might be in.
Did those guys go
to the boundary?
JAKE PRICE: Yep.
BRYAN IGUCHI: Cool.
JAKE PRICE: Should we probably
go over and meet them?
VERNON: It that far
over, or not?
More or less, or?
BRYAN IGUCHI: Whatever
you want.
JAKE PRICE: Can we bring
them back and
just have a fun session?
How did you get-- oh, that's
a snowmobiler.
Oh see, that's a 6 slash
right there, too.
VERNON: In the pocket?
JAKE PRICE: Yeah.
VERNON: It's beautiful.
I'd love to shoot
with him there.
JAKE PRICE: You can get up a
little higher and see all the
[INAUDIBLE], too.
VERNON: He's going to be here
in the morning, huh?
Before the sledders come?