to me, Johnny Bonehead.
I'm Mike Shaw here with
Motherboard, and we're here to
respond to the video First
Animal to Survive in Space.
We were really floored
by all the comments--
20,000 and growing.
And keep those comments coming,
we do appreciate it.
I'm very grateful for
the response.
And now let's get to some of
your questions and comments.
"This stuff ain't new.
I saw a special on these things
four years ago on
Discovery Channel.
Why these just coming to
light?" TJtheEditor.
Well, we're just adding
to the discussion.
People want to hear about
tardigrades, they want to hear
about space.
And any time you talk about this
type of topic, it spurs
interest because we all want
to know how we got here.
So let me talk about some of
the science versus religion
comments, I think that
might be interesting.
Jubba explains that the
purpose "of life is to
propagate itself." Hm,
there's an idea.
And chickenfingers123, he
clarifies entropy theory
verses the biblical
age of the earth.
For me, there's really only
one question about the
universe and its origins,
and that is why is
there anything at all?
In other words, why is there
something rather than nothing?
And by nothing, I don't mean
vacuum, or space--
I mean nothing.
So just think about that for
a second, let it sink in.
There is something--
there's matter, there's us,
there's conversation, there's
stars and galaxies.
Why is there something rather
than nothing at all?
All of the great religions, they
all at least attempt to
tell us why there
is something.
Religion tells us why,
science tells us how.
"The dangerous tests on these
animals disgusts me.
Tardigrades need rights,
too." And that was
answered "I know, right?
Maybe tardigrades don't want
to be subjected to extreme
temperatures and being
tossed in space!"
You know what?
You're onto something here.
I don't think they want
that at all, no.
I can't tell you what
they do want, but
they don't want that.
Now, just keep one thing in
mind, that tardigrades go into
kind of a suspended animation
called cryptobiosis, and they
probably don't feel a thing.
So they don't care whether
they're being subjected to
x-rays and vacuum
and radiation.
To them, it's just like
another hot day.
Here's a good one.
"If students consistently come
late to class, it will
detrimentally affect
their tardy grade."
Love that, love that.
One million monologues, you have
a good sense of humor.
And by the way, I used to be in
the hot dog business, but I
didn't relish it.
One of the questions
was "Why talk about
tardigrades from space?
Evidence shows that they're
related to earth creatures."
That's from Philip Hedden.
That's a great question, because
that's very true.
Most of the evidence, especially
DNA evidence which
we have now and we didn't have
in the past, shows that
they're either related to
Arthropods, Nematodes, which
are those little round worms.
Arthropods would be
ticks and water
mites, little tiny creatures.
So they probably are related to
creatures that are on earth.
So the question is, again, did
tardigrades come from space?
If there was a fragment of DNA
that arrived here on a comet
or a meteor and that evolved
into all life, including
tardigrades, then yeah,
tardigrades came from space.
So that's one way
to look at it.
OK, one nice comment which, I
don't know how it was meant,
but I know how I took it.
Danielvincentkelley made
a rather long comment.
And at the end he said "Dude
should have a job packing
vans."
Well, I don't know if he meant
that to be insulting or not.
If he was insulting me,
I'm not insulted.
I think probably he might
have been insulting
people who pack bags.
And this is a really good
comment that hits home.
Because I think, again, it
comes back to acceptance.
And whatever we do in jobs or in
our life, if we can accept
it we'll find that there's a lot
more happiness involved.
And it really doesn't matter
what you do when you're in a
state of acceptance.
That just about wraps it up in
terms of responding to most of
the comments that I could.
And I would just like to say
that I really appreciate the
feedback and the interaction.
I just want to thank you again,
all of you, for that.
And I look forward to seeing
you again sometime.