It would be a film works on its
own as a standalone, and
also lives up to what "Spider"
was, and also works as a
sequel by taking the same
character and has this guy
learned any lessons and what's
he like in his new
relationship.
I like that he's the bad
guy or evil character.
But he's well-intentioned--
this well-intentioned
guy that maims his
girlfriends for love.
A lot of people ask, is the
character in "Bear " and
"Spider," is it based on me?
And I guess, essentially,
I am the guy who
does like to do pranks.
I've never had one go
as bad as he does.
So essentially, it's
an extension of me.
But I'm not really that guy.
He plans this elaborate picnic,
but then can't just
have it be a normal picnic.
He has to surprise her
with a bear suit.
And then beyond that, once she
gets hurt, instead of taking
her and trying to get her help,
he's talking about how
great the bear suit is, which
is ultimately his undoing.
Because "Spider" was in the
city, I wanted to take it into
a different environment.
Initially, my idea was
just to be in the
wilderness of some sort.
I also wanted to do an animal
that was so much bigger than
the last one.
One of the main things with
"Bear" for me was knowing that
the bear suit had to be right.
And I contacted Nick and Paul at
MEG who had done the needle
in the eye effect in "Spider,"
just asking them if they had a
bear suit or if they knew
someone who had one.
When I called them, they were
like, yeah, we have three.
We have a momma bear, a papa
bear, and a baby bear.
And so I went round and I tried
on the papa bear suit.
And it was so far beyond what
I imagined they would have,
and so good.
When I tried it on,
I was like--
just how good the suit was, I
was just like, this film is
going to work because
of the suit.
But again, with the tying them
together, I like the idea that
the quote comes from something
that Jill says in "Spider." As
much as I wanted it to be a
standalone film, I wanted to
tie into "Spider" as well.
So the fact that Jack is taking
a needle to the eye, I
wanted to show some sort
of remnants of that.
And so for people who notice
that he had one discolored
eye-- so Jack now has
one brown eye and
one gray-blue eye.
There's another nod to "Spider"
in here which is a
complete accident that people
think is set up.
But on the end of the bed,
there's a t-shirt with a
spider on it at the
start of film.
And that just happened to be
there on that bed in that
location when we started
filming.
I actually thought
the production
designer had put it there.
And I was like, oh,
that's great.
Where did you get that?
And she's like, oh, that
was just there.
[VIDEO PLAYBACK]
[ROARING]
[SCREAMING]
[END VIDEO PLAYBACK]
"Bear" has a shot in it that a
lot of people it's the first
they ask about is how
did you do the fall?
The fall--
I approached it a similar way.
I did storyboards.
And then I went out and shot
an animatic and had an
approach on how I was going to
do it and then spoke to Mike
Seymour who did the visual
effects on "Spider," and
worked out a plan on how
we were going to do it.
And this time, the fall--
again, it's made up of a
number of shots.
But there was no dummy
in this one.
It's all real.
We essentially set up a rig
like a flying fox from one
tree to another over the cliff
and had her ride the push bike
off the cliff and catch her
10 feet from the ground.
In the shot, you get the camera
going over, the girl
going over on the bike, and the
bike going all the way to
the ground.
Then we set the camera up
looking straight down and had
the same girl without the wires
and rig jump from a
lower ledge at about 10
feet to the ground.
And we dug up the dirt and
put a mat underneath.
So then she could
do the landing.
We showed her the take we liked
best and got her to get
the same body position
as she jumped off to
get the impact point.
And then Mike just joined the
two shots together and removed
the wires and ropes to give,
again, in one shot, the
feeling of someone riding off
the cliff and going all the
way to the ground.
[VIDEO PLAYBACK]
[SCREAMING]
[END VIDEO PLAYBACK]
The reaction it gets from the
audience comes from--
most people are used to seeing
shots like that.
But it usually cuts out
to another angle.
They don't expect it to go all
the way to the ground, which
was the effect I wanted.