eat oysters, and up to 30% of the world's
male population have a part of their penis
removed shortly after birth. The statistics
for Americans are around 70%, or as high as
80% among European-Americans, and the rates
vary with religion and region. By contrast,
the European rates are much lower, less than
20%, less than 1% in places like Finland,
and in Muslim controlled central Asia and
the Mid-East, the rates are nearly 100%.
The faiths of Islam, Christianity and Judaism
practice circumcision as a religious rite,
an obligation of faith, and some African tribes
practice adult circumcision as part of the
rites of manhood. The earliest record of circumcision
comes from ancient Egyptian art, and the Semitic
peoples appear to have adopted the practice
long before the writing of scriptures, suggesting
that wide-spread circumcision pre-dated the
Bible by thousands of years. Alexander the
Great, a Greek Macedonian who was raised in
a non-circumcision culture, was said to have
radically altered the traditional circumcision
practice of the peoples he conquered.
What an odd thing for diverse cultures to
have adopted. I suppose certain early cultures
might have associated foreskin with poor hygenic
practices. In some cultures, circumcision
of young boys was probably a sort of coming-out
party for the genitals, a test of manhood
as well. Some tribal cultures consider the
phallus to be a symbol of fertility or power.
The act of modifying it has an effect on the
perception of the person. That cultural interest
probably became codified in cults and religious
ceremonies, like ceremonial tatooing or ear
piercing or many other body modifications
practiced by world cultures. The genitals
have always been a religious obsession: up
to and including full self-castration by male
priests of Cybele. (sib-ellee). So, although
we associate circumcision with certain religious
groups, the practice seems to predate the
religion, and the cultural practice was co-opted
by priests, rather than invented by them.
I had no idea that male circumcision was such
a touchy subject. Growing up as I did in the
American MidWest, circumcision was a normal
part of labor and delivery. When my wife and
I were discussing our plans with our obstetrician,
we really hadn't discussed the topic together.
In the end, we made a hasty decision to carry
on the tradition in my family: circumcision.
Now that I look back, I regret basing such
an important medical decision on such casual
thinking or lack thereof. However, I don't
think the issue is as clear-cut, pun intended,
as it might appear at first glance. I want
to throw out a few issues that I've been thinking
about. I hope you'll watch the full video,
tell me your thoughts on the topic, and hopefully
start some useful discussion.
My mind is far from made up on this topic,
and I confess the more I learn, the more complex
are the issues and the harder it's been to
take a strong stand on either side. Sometimes
knowledge is the enemy of confidence and vice
versa.
1. Modern infant circumcision methods are
relatively safe and minimize suffering, but
are not RISK-FREE nor painless.
Most circumcisions are done in one of three
methods, the Plastibell, Gomco or Mogen clamps.
All of them are relatively very safe, with
few recorded complications, but there ARE
complications and risks. Not the least of
which is the risk of cosmetic or functional
damage to the penis, minor or serious infection,
and bleeding or hemmorage. These risks are
usually lowest in newborns. Older children
and adults who undergo the surgery are much
more likely to have serious complications.
There've been numerous studies that attempted
to quantify adverse events. If we simply include
any symptom, including redness or bleeding,
the rates range from 2 to 40 percent, depending
on definitions. If the study only includes
serious complications, which would be issues
requiring further medical care, the rates
are usually around 0.2%. That's 2 out of a
1000 circumcisions where the procedure required
additional medical care. Usually these were
a matter of bringing the baby back in to the
doctor, or it could include an ER visit. I
couldn't find any recorded cases of deaths
in my survey of the medical literature, but
I did find an estimate of 1 death for every
500,000 circumcisions suggested by an opponent
of circumcision , Lowell King, in a 1975 report.
I suspect that's a bit high, and includes
cases where the proximal cause may not have
actually been the circumcision. Nevertheless,
there are risks, up to and including death,
though they are very rare.
2. There are some medical benefits to routine
infant circumcision.
In some cases, removal of the foreskin is
medically necessary to prevent more serious
pathology. We could call that medical circumcision,
but I'm talking here specifically about circumcision
of boys as a routine practice.
We can break the topics of benefits into three
categories: STD transmission risk, UTI risk
and severity, and avoidance of rare conditions.
Particularly the HIV risk argument must be
addressed. Foreskin is a favorite target of
HIV infection. It is loaded with the kinds
of cells most easily infected, the Langerhan's
cell, but not protected by a resistant layer
of protein called keratin. We would predict,
therefore, that circumcised men without a
foreskin would be less likely to be infected.
The process should also affect the ability
to transmit the virus, as microscopic openings
in the foreskin allow the virus an easy exit
to the next host.
That's the mechanism or theory behind protective
circumcision, how does that translate into
actual protection? Well, the evidence seems
pretty strongly in favor, although there are
some who disagree. In high risk populations,
like those in East and Southern Africa, it's
very protective. We're talking about 60% or
more reductions in transmission. That could
save millions of lives, and the public health
agencies that operate in the area, like the
World Health Organization, are actively investigating
if the benefits outweigh the risks, and if
circumcision clinics for adults are practical.
If we had an effective alternative for preventing
the spread of HIV, if condom use and testing
were more prevalent, I would say this argument
would be neutralized. However, at the present
moment, circumcision is very effective in
these high risk populations. In lower risk
populations the HIV risk reduction is more
modest.
The protection doesn't just benefit men, it
also benefits women, since the protective
effects are only detectable in heterosexual
transmission. By benefitting women, it can
also prevent newborn children from being born
infected and that saves the lives of little
baby boys.
Similar effects and similar mechanisms have
been identified for several other STDs: genital
ulcers, Herpes, Trichomoniasis and human papillomavirus
infection transmission are all reduced in
circumsized individuals. Chlamydia and gonnorhea
transmission, on the other hand, don't appear
to be affected.
The papillomavirus infection is especially
important, as HPVs are associated with various
cancers, most especially of the cervix, where
it's implicated in nearly 100% of cases. Worldwide,
cervical cancer is estimated to affect 490,000
women, and cause 270,000 deaths annually.
Circumcised men are both less likely to be
infected, and also less likely to transmit
the infection. This may help to save the lives
of women. Vaccines against HPV may change
the cost to benefit equation, but for the
moment, I think this is a point in favor of
circumcision.
Circumcision also reduces the risk of penile
cancer, although the prevalence of this condition
is so rare that it's hard to put much emphasis
on this benefit.
Circumcision reduces the likelihood of a urinary
tract infection by eliminating an area where
infections can form and remain hidden. Since
newborns have a non-retractable foreskin,
it provides a little pocket where bacteria
can lodge and grow. As a result, keeping a
circumcised penis clean and dry appears to
be easier, but this could probably be overcome
by a little extra effort on the part of the
parents.
What kind of magnitude of benefit is seen
in circumcised infant boys? 1% of newborn
boys develop a UTI, and the risk reduction
is about 10 fold. That sounds pretty impressive,
but it means that we have to circumcise about
110 boys to prevent one UTI from occurring,
which probably doesn't quite overcome the
risk of complications from the procedure.
On the other hand, some little boys have a
high risk of UTI due to medical conditions
where urine flows back into the ureter and
kidney, and circumcision lowers their risk
enormously. In these cases, benefits clearly
outweigh risks, and only four circumcisions
are needed to prevent one UTI. If you've ever
had a urinary tract infection, you know that
they are not fun, and can potentially become
quite severe.
Lastly, male infant circumcision can be protective
against certain rare conditions. Phimosis
is a good example, where the foreskin doesn't
become retractible. This is a serious medical
condition, and can require therapeutic circumcision,
or it can sometimes be treated with a simple
steroid cream.
There are other such conditions of the foreskin
that can be prevented by its removal at a
very young age, although the cost to benefit
ratio for these may be questionable.
3. Routine circumcisions are not recommended
by most medical authorities
I'm just going to read the position statement
of the American Academy of Pediatrics. It
typifies the fairly generic statements that
neither condone nor condemn the cultural practice
of circumcision, but don't endorse a purely
medical indication for infant circumcision.
"The American Academy of Pediatrics (AAP)
believes that circumcision has potential medical
benefits and advantages, as well as risks.
The existing scientific evidence is not sufficient
to recommend routine circumcision. Therefore,
because the procedure is not essential to
a child’s current well-being, we recommend
that the decision to circumcise is one best
made by parents in consultation with their
pediatrician, taking into account what is
in the best interests of the child, including
medical, religious, cultural, and ethnic traditions.
"
This is the current position statement, and
it reflects the modern consensus. In the past,
the AAP has taken stronger stands against
or in favor of circumcision, depending on
current evidence and the political environment.
Circumcision has seen a decline in recent
years in the US, and I think the medical community
themselves are responsible for the change,
advising parents about both medical and ethical
concerns of circumcision.
4. The evidence about the negative health
consequences of circumcision is a mixed bag.
One odd thing about being a biologist is that
so much is known about the human body that
we have to specialize in one particular topic.
In this case, as I read through the list of
adverse events associated with male circumcision,
I was painfully reminded of how little I know
about that area of the body, despite EXTENSIVE
personal study and examination in my youth.
Male infant circumcision may have some serious
associated risks, but it has to be remembered
that 1 in 3 men are circumcised and that the
practice goes back into the misty recesses
of pre-history, so the effects must be fairly
rare or non-critical. However, the kinds of
complications listed in the literature required
that I go back to a medical dictionary. Here
are some of the terms I encountered: lymphedema,
urinary fistula, hypospadias, epispadias,
meatus ulceration and glans skin bridges.
Catastrophic events like partial or total
loss of the function of the penis occur once
in every million or so circumcisions done
under modern surgical conditions.
One primary concern is a loss of sexual pleasure.
The tip of the penis is exposed, and over
time the skin might be more likely to become
keratinized, or tougher and thicker, and therefore
a little less sensitive, although most studies
didn't find this to be the case. There is
also some concern about mutual enjoyment of
intercourse, although I didn't find much evidence
for this in the literature, either. In fact,
in some studies the opposite is true, with
surveys of female partners in Africa stating
that they preferred sex with their partner
after he was circumcised.
There are also some who speculate that the
pain and suffering of the procedure, together
with inadequate anaesthesia, has an effect
on the child that translates into psychological
damage. There is a definite effect on older
children between 2 and 6 who are old enough
to be aware, but too young to understand,
called castration anxiety.
All of this represents the purely scientific,
purely medical, pros and cons. This ignores
the most deeply controversial topic, the ethics
and morality of surgical removal of a natural
part of the human body. Here, science is silent.
Is it right for a parent to make such a decision
for a child, one that is permanent and profound,
painful and risky? Does the physician honor
their oath to do no harm, if they perform
this procedure without a medical indication?
I've thought a very long time on this topic,
and I think that my own decision for my son
might not have been justified. I deeply regret
that all this consideration comes now, when
the decision is long past. I don't think he
was permanently harmed, and I don't think
he'll have any problems in the future, but
I wish I had given the topic more thought
at the time.
I am most swayed by the argument about the
rights of the infant to make choices about
their own body. I would prefer if the child
could make this decision. Unfortunately, the
risk of complications of adult circumcision
make it much higher risk compared to infant
circumcision. If the child can't make the
decision at the point where the procedure
is safest, I think the parent usually has
the best interests of the child at heart,
and any decision they make is part of their
legal guardianship. It's not an optimal solution,
but it's one we've practiced in other cases
where important medical or legal decisions
need to be made.
I strongly support the use of anaesthetic
during the procedure, something that is not
routinely done in the US. Some figures suggest
only about 25% of circumcisions are done under
anaesthesia. Maybe I don't understand the
case against, but it seems like preventing
pain and suffering is the least we can do
for the baby boy.
Lastly, I know the topic of female genital
cutting is bound to come up in discussion.
I don't consider the two procedures to be
equal. The closest analog in women to the
male foreskin is the clitoral hood. This is
rarely the only tissue removed, usually the
clitoris is either partially or entirely removed.
This is the equivalent of castration in males,
something not practiced in modern cultures.
I'd like to keep the two issues separated,
but I think it's only fair to allow for comparisons
so long as a proper equivalence is made. I
am strongly opposed to female genital cutting.
I'd like to summarize my own impressions from
research on this topic. I think the medical
evidence is slightly in favor of routine circumcision.
There are no benefits that cannot be obtained
in other ways. The most effective way to prevent
HIV and other STD transmission is still condom
use or abstinence. Condom use is the best
solution. Proper foreskin hygeine, likewise,
can greatly reduce UTI rates in young boys
without the need for surgical prevention.
In the very real world, circumcision is an
imperfect solution, but one that seems to
work. It could potentially save millions of
lives in high risk areas. The medical benefits
are offset by medical risks and possible psychological
or sexual effects later in life, but I still
think the evidence is slightly in favor.
On the other hand, the ethical issues around
circumcision are, on the balance, anti-circumcision.
It seems a violation of the rights of the
child to an intact body, and it seems to violate
core medical ethics to do no harm.
There is also the religious, cultural, or
family tradition to consider. Parents could
be argued to have certain rights to decide
what traditions their children follow until
their age of maturity. This is not an argument
that I find very compelling, so I won't go
any deeper into it.
I look forward to a "robust" discussion on
this topic. Before you start writing your
500 character argument, though, I would make
three requests. One, try to avoid overly emotional
wording and tactics. Two, if you make an assertion
of fact, a proper citation to a source is
much appreciated. Note that links are not
only not allowed in YouTube comments, but
they aren't even proper citations. Three,
and this is the challenge: I would ask that
you avoid using any terms that you'd be uncomfortable
reading aloud to a nice old lady you met on
the bus. Good luck, and be creative. Extravagantly
fictional prizes will be awarded to the best
use of creatively non-offensive language.
I have so many papers to cite that I've had
trouble posting them below. Instead, I've
posted a link to the citations in the under-bar.
As always, thanks for watching.