RYAN DUFFY: Probably could have
gone one slice of pizza
lighter at dinner.
FELIX JEREZ RIVERA:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
RYAN DUFFY: So it's the 13th
year of the Chavez regime here
in Venezuela, and his Bolivarian
revolution has left
the country deeply divided
along political lines.
And despite its egalitarian
aims, the economic divide
between the haves and the
have-nots remains staggering.
Despite all this, in this
election year, the issue that
will decide the future of this
country is violence.
Venezuela has become known as
one of the most dangerous
countries in the world, and last
year alone, Caracas had
more violent deaths
than Baghdad.
With a population a tenth the
size of the United States,
Venezuela last year managed
to record more
murders than America.
An astonishing 19,000
violent deaths in a
population of 29 million.
LUIS CEDENO: If you want to
compare with wars going on in
other countries, they
don't have that
death toll every week.
So we have to ask ourselves,
are we in a state of war?
RYAN DUFFY: With the protection
of Caracas' finest,
we headed to Pitara--
a sprawling slum where a
shocking percentage of the
city's violence happens--
to get a lay of the criminal
landscape.
There's probably two ways to go
to this neighborhood, with
the guys who run it from the
inside, and the guys who
control it from the outside,
otherwise, the guys with guns.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
FELIX JEREZ RIVERA:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
RYAN DUFFY: I was feeling OK
about this until the eight
hundred disclaimers about what
to do when and if we come
under fire, and here's
the evacuation, and
hide under the tires.
And all that kind of made
it a little more real.
We spoke with Luis Cedeno, the
head of Paz Activa, an NGO
that tracks violence
in Venezuela.
LUIS CEDENO: What violence
you would see in Pitara?
You would see gang violence.
When these gangs have a shoot
out, you're in the middle of
the shoot out, you're
going to get hurt.
RYAN DUFFY: The craziest part
is that this isn't organized
narco-violence, this is petty,
you looked at my sister
sideways, street bullshit.
Someone turns the corner and
shoots at him and misses,
either you or I is
going to die.
FELIX JEREZ RIVERA:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
RYAN DUFFY: In Caracas,
living in Pitara
counts as probable cause.
FELIX JEREZ RIVERA:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
LUIS CEDENO: There are actually
little arsenals in
every barrio.
You can go there and you can
actually buy a gun, buy
ammunition, access
to grenades.
You can actually rent the gun
if you don't want to buy it,
and it's a lot cheaper.
FELIX JEREZ RIVERA:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
RYAN DUFFY: Just made a stop
here on the patrol.
Looks like a guy was not just
drunk driving, but actually
drinking while he was driving.
And apparently drinking and
driving isn't a big deal here.
On an average day in Venezuela,
58 people are murdered.
This is my nervous tic.
The entire time we were with
the cops, of the radio was
crackling with reports of
killings all around the city,
and we were soon in pursuit
of an armed suspect.
[POLICE RADIO]
RYAN DUFFY: With over 90% of
crimes in Venezuela going
unsolved, it wasn't quite a
surprise that this call ended
without a suspect.
FELIX JEREZ RIVERA:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
RYAN DUFFY: Has crime in this
area gotten better or worse
over the course of
your career?
FELIX JEREZ RIVERA:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
RYAN DUFFY: Although the slums
have always had problems with
violence, it's only in the last
decade that it has risen
to war zone levels.
So the question is, what
the hell happened
in the last 10 years?
[SINGING]
RYAN DUFFY: Venezuela is
ruled by socialist
superhero, Hugo Chavez.
A man who, at a glance, seems
completely out of his mind.
HUGO CHAVEZ: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
RYAN DUFFY: Despite its third
world crime stats, Venezuela
isn't exactly a poor country.
It's a massive oil industry
produces 2.5
million barrels a day.
Most of which is consumed
by the United States.
And the country has
larger proven
reserves than Saudi Arabia.
Before he took power, foreign
companies like Exxon Mobil
made huge profits from
Venezuela's oil fields.
But when Chavez nationalized
the industry and sent the
multinationals packing, all
those profits went directly
into government accounts.
But despite this, and after 13
years of power, he still
shifts the blame for the
problems of violence and
poverty onto previous
governments.
HUGO CHAVEZ: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
RYAN DUFFY: But in October,
the Bolivarian Revolution
faces its toughest electoral
challenge ever from Henrique
Capriles Radonski who's hoping
to tap into the public's
pent-up frustration
over the violence
issue among other things.
But even with a strong opponent
and his fierce battle
with cancer, Chavez is still
plowing forward with his
socialist agenda.
HUGO CHAVEZ: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
[MUSIC PLAYING]