RYAN DUFFY: How did a group that
started as a small but
wily militia in the '80s
transform itself into a
military and political force
to be reckoned with?
Where did this come from?
MALE SPEAKER 1: It comes
from everywhere.
MALE SPEAKER 2: Imagine you are
Iranian, and offer you to
run a country for one
billion dollars.
Will you take it or not?
RYAN DUFFY: In addition to
shit-tons of guns and millions
of dollars from Iran, they did
it through something they like
to call resistance tourism.
MALE SPEAKER 3: They might want
to leave that one off the
children's part of this tour.
BOY: Hezbollah!
SOLDIER: Please.
Erase this film.
MALE SPEAKER 4:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[CROWD CHEERS]
HASSAN NASRALLAH:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[CROWD CHANTS IN FOREIGN
LANGUAGE]