MALE SPEAKER 2: The best night
is you go out, and you end up
maybe on a plane to Paris
with a beautiful girl.
You want to set the
stage for that.
MALE SPEAKER 3: We invited five
designers in New York.
And they come from different
design disciplines.
Getting the opportunity to
design a kind of vision of the
future club, it's like a
dream for any designer.
We didn't know at all what
this is going to bring.
It's a risk.
On the other hand, we're
there to experiment.
MALE SPEAKER 4: Night club of
the future may not look
totally futuristic.
MALE SPEAKER 5: You have to try
to design something that's
timeless to the best
of your ability.
MALE SPEAKER 6: It's all about
just creating one night
that'll create a lasting
impression for the rest of
their lives, creating a memory
that people will never forget.