It's awesome.
Well, you -- this is a beautiful
day, because it was like a
hundred-and-a-million degrees
here on Monday and it would have
been miserable to be out here.
But we got a perfect day, and
this is a very special day for
the White House Kitchen
Garden because in addition to
harvesting some of the lettuces,
I think we've got broccoli
that's ready.
What else are we going to do?
What's ready?
Are we going to get some
of the rhubarb that we --
we got rhubarb.
You see those big huge leaves?
That's rhubarb.
And it's huge!
It's like an elephant's ear.
So we're going to pick some of
that and we're going to use some
of that food in the White House
to feed the President's family
and our guests.
But we're also going to give it
away to people who need good,
healthy food who
don't have homes.
So we're going to be
able to get a lot done.
But we're also going to do a
Three Sisters planting today
because last week we launched
a special new part of our
"Let's Move" initiative.
Do you guys know all
about "Let's Move,"
what we're trying to do?
Have you heard about it?
We're going to try to make
sure that all you kids grow up
healthy, knowing what to eat,
knowing how to exercise.
It's a whole initiative to work
with people all across the
country to think about how we
eat and how we move our bodies
so that you guys grow up healthy
and strong and able to do well
in school and be
successful in life.
That's what the whole "Let's
Move" effort is about.
But last week we launched a new
component of the program called
Let's Move Indian Country.
And we're working specifically
with young kids in the Native
American community all
across the country.
And this planting is a
special way to highlight that
new initiative.
And this is the first time ever
that we're going to do a Three
Sisters planting here in the
White House Kitchen Garden.
And you all are going to be a
part of making that happen.
Is that -- does that sound okay?
Yeah, yeah, sounds fun?
So we're not going
to talk too long.
I'm going to turn it over to our
special guest, Jefferson Keel,
and he's going to tell us a
little bit about the Three
Sisters planting, and he's
going to do a blessing, okay?
So let's listen up, and then
we'll get to work, okay?
All right, here we go.
I'm going to turn it over.
Jefferson keel:
Thank you, ma'am.
Thank you.
The idea for the three
sisters as we call it,
they are interconnected.
The three sisters are
beans, squashes, and corn.
And they work together to
protect each other and to help
each other grow.
The beans provide protection
or nutrients for the corn,
the corn converts
nitrogen for the beans,
and the squash has large leaves
to protect the beans from animals.
And, of course, the Secret
Service here will protect
these I am sure.
But they work together
to nurture each other,
to help us to reap those and
then help us as we consume those.
So that is what we call -- that
is why we call them the three sisters.
So today we are
going to plant those.
But before that, we always
prepare ourselves and we go
prior to planting,
we go to the creator.
We ask God to bless those.
So I am going to
do a brief prayer.
And I am going to ask for a
special blessing on three things.
One, I am going to ask for a
special blessing on all things
God has created.
Ask a special blessing on the
First Lady and her efforts to
help us to move Native America.
And then for the healing of
Mother Earth and the seeds that
were planted so that that they
can continue to nurture us.
So will you pray with me?
Okay.
(speaking foreign
language)
Father, we thank you for this
beautiful day that you have given us.
We ask a special blessing on
the First Lady and her family.
We ask that you would just keep
your hand on them and guide them
and protect them Lord.
We ask a special blessing on
the seeds that we planted here today.
The corn, (foreign lanuage)
the beans, (foreign language),
and the squash,
(foreign language).
We ask that you would just heal
Mother Earth so that she can
continue to nurture us.
And, Father, I want to ask a
special blessing on the young
men and women around the world
who are protecting our freedoms
that we might enjoy today and
the freedoms that we enjoy in America.
Father, we ask all of these
things in the precious and holy
name of Jesus, amen.
All:
Amen.
First lady Michelle Obama:
All right.
Let's go plant.
You guys ready?
Let's go.
Sam Kass:
We will harvest this lettuce and
then we are going to
pull that rhubarb.
First lady Michelle Obama:
Oh, I love pulling rhubarb.
Sam Kass:
My two water people are over
here with me.
You and I are going
to stand right here.
This one is going to have --
(cross talk)
First lady Michelle Obama:
Okay.
When I cut --
Sam Kass:
All right, guys.
Come over here.
There you go.
First lady Michelle Obama:
Okay.
We have to take all of these.
Sam Kass:
It is so cold.
I need your help now.
Ready.
First lady Michelle Obama:
All right.
We need more baskets.
Sam, we need more baskets.
We are moving.
You want to try?
Sam Kass:
All right.
Here you go.
Is it getting cold?
You can pull out all of those
plants just like those.
All right.
You can put it down here.
You don't need a basket.
You can put it down.
Dig it out.
Child:
I am ready.
I got another half.
I got you one.
I would like to do that one.
Sam Kass:
Put it in there.
Child:
Hi Mommy.
Sam Kass:
It is so cold.
Right in there.
How are we doing, guys?
Good job, guys.
You don't have to put
those in the water.
Child:
Where do I put them?
Sam Kass:
I don't think
they go in the ice.
Sam Kass:
I don't know about the ice.
Look at those.
They are pretty good, huh?
All right.
Dump them in.
Good job, guys.
Look at these.
Come on there.
Dump them in.
Pretty good, right?
Yeah.
These are beets.
There you go.
Good job.
No, those don't
need to go in there.
You can just dump
these right here.
You can put them right here.
Pour them out right here.
There you go.
Great job.
Nice.
Child:
What is that?
First lady Michelle Obama:
What about the little one?
Child:
What are these for?
Sam Kass:
All right.
Take this basket back to
somebody who needs it.
We don't have enough baskets.
Good job.
Child:
Do you need
anymore baskets?
First Lady Michelle Obama:
I think we are good.
Child:
You need a basket?
First Lady Michelle Obama:
I will take that basket.
Sam Kass:
You can sit down here.
Yes.
You need a basket?
First lady Michelle Obama:
You know what, why don't I help you?
Sam Kass:
Awesome.
Perfect.
Keep it in there.
Put it in the basket.
Child:
Look over here.
First lady Michelle Obama:
Okay.
Take it in.
Sam Kass:
You can put these over here.
Good job, guys.
Look at how much food this is.
Sam Kass:
This is amazing, isn't it?
Make sure you shake off the dirt.
Go ahead.
Good job everybody.
Shake off the dirt.
There you go.
Good job.
All right.
Let's see.
This is a basket.
Good job guys.
First lady Michelle Obama:
Whoo-Hoo!
Child:
We are all done.
Sam Kass:
You guys are done.
All right.
This is a giant pile.
(cross talk)
Child:
Hello.
First Lady Michelle Obama:
You pull it straight up.
All right.
So let me show you
how to do this.
Sam Kass:
Oh, good one.
You want to help
with the rhubarb?
Child:
Hello.
First Lady Michelle Obama:
Nice.
You want to help here?
Okay.
Sam Kass:
Good job everybody.
First Lady Michelle Obama:
Nice job.
All right.
You got it.
Just keep it low -- excellent.
(cross talk)
So are you working hard?
You guys
are doing a great job.
Look at that.
You know how to pull it.
You are doing an excellent job.
Excellent.
Just keep pulling.
You can use it as a fan.
Will you fan me?
Child:
Yes.
First Lady Michelle Obama:
All right.
Let's some more.
Keep pulling.
You want to pull
all of them out.
When you are done there
--
Child: Hi, Mrs. Obama.
First Lady Michelle Obama:
Hey guys, how is it going?
Child:
Good.
First Lady Michelle Obama:
You want to take these here.
You guys,
pull that one too.
We are good on that.
Child:
All right.
First Lady Michelle Obama:
You guys need help over here?
Nice.
Child:
What are these?
First Lady Michelle Obama:
Okay.
Oh, my goodness.
(cross talk)
There you go.
You got it.
Child:
I got one.
First Lady Michelle Obama:
Good job.
You know where they go?
Sam Kass:
You are a super star.
We don't need that one.
We don't need that.
We don't need Those ones.
You can go to town.
First Lady Michelle Obama:
Great.
You are going to help?
That work done.
You want to help with us.
Here is more.
This lettuce is different.
That is good.
You okay?
Good job.
We have got more over here.
Sam Kass:
Take turns.
First Lady Michelle Obama:
Use two hands.
Two hands.
Good job.
Jeferson Keel :
Let's do this.
Here you go Sam.
Sam Kass:
Ready?
There we have got a
couple more pieces.
We'll put them over here.
We need more people in the
back and more people in the front.
First Lady Michelle Obama:
Hey, you guys did great.
(cross talk)
Sam Kass:
All right.
That is good.
You can leave that middle one.
Leave that middle one.
That is the seed.
This is where the
seed is going to be.
First Lady Michelle Obama:
You did awesome.
(cross talk)
Sam Kass:
Come on over here, over here.
Do you guys have any idea how
much food you just picked?
First lady Obama:
Goodness.
It was great.
Sam Kass:
It is gone.
It was ravaged.
(cross talk)
First Lady Michelle Obama:
Outstanding job.
Sam Kass:
Everybody in.
Move in, move in, move in.
Photographer:
All right, Everybody.
Look here.
Ready, one, two, three.
All right.
Let me get another one.
(applause)