[GUNSHOTS]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
SHANE SMITH: War makes fucked
up movies, and that is a
fucked up movie.
It's called "Divine
Intervention." It's part of a
new wave of Lebanese cinema
that's coming out of the
violence and the craziness and
the terror that's been going
on there for the
past 40 years.
Now there are a lot of different
political factions
within Lebanon, but we're going
to be concentrating on
the Palestinians, who
are refugees.
They are people without
a state.
And film has become the most
important medium for them to
get their message across.
50 or 60 years ago,
Beirut was much
different than it is today.
It was known as the Paris
of the Middle East.
It was the cultural center
of the region.
It was the artistic hub.
But at the same time, this
part of the world was
radically altered with
the establishment
of Israel in 1948.
The creation of Israel and the
ensuing war caused the
displacement of the Palestinian
people into many
neighboring Arab countries.
But a lot of them settled in
Lebanon in temporary camps and
thought that they would soon be
returning to their homes.
But they're still there today.
Three generations later, they
still don't have a homeland.
They are still refugees.
They don't have passports.
They can't work.
And they're still living
in the same camps.
Today Israel believes that the
Palestinian refugee camps are
a breeding ground for terrorists
and that militant
groups like the Hezbollah hide
their weapons within their
communities.
In 2006, Israel bombed Lebanon
for a month in retaliation for
Hezbollah's kidnapping of
two of their soldiers.
Some of what happened in Lebanon
during the conflict
was documented by civilians.
In fact, the footage you're
watching now is from a DVD
that we bought on the
streets of Beirut.
MALE SPEAKER:
[SPEAKING LEBANESE]
SHANE SMITH: Instead of
succumbing to hatred and
violence, some young
Palestinians have turned to
film making as both a creative
and a political outlet.
And we're seeing fiction, we're
seeing documentary, as
an expression of what it's like
to grow up in a constant
state of conflict.
-[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
FEMALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
-[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
SHANE SMITH: These films are
happening with little to no
funding, basic resources, but
against all odds a small group
of Palestinian filmmakers
is emerging.
Our first contact with
Palestinian filmmakers was
very personal.
We had gone to Beirut to shoot
"The Vice Guide to Travel." It
was a story about a skate
park that was
sponsored by the Hezbollah.
And while we were there, we met
a Palestinian Boy Scout
leader named Ahmad.
And Ahmad lived in the Bourj
al-Barajneh camp in Beirut.
Eddie, our producer, went
to Ahmad's house
to interview him.
And he found out that his dream
was to become a filmmaker.
EDDIE: So I wanted to stop here
because of that poster.
EDDIE: Oh, it's a photo
that they painted?
AHMAD: Yeah.
EDDIE: How?
They shot him?
[MUSIC PLAYING]
EDDIE: I saw some photos
of you with a gun.
AHMAD: Ah.
EDDIE: [CHUCKLE].
EDDIE: No.
AHMAD: OK.
EDDIE: Yes.
EDDIE: You're suffering.
Do you want this generation
of children to be martyrs?
You work with them every day.
EDDIE: What's the next step?
AHMAD: For me?
EDDIE: Yeah.
What can you do?
AHMAD: I'm going to have
a camera soon.
SHANE SMITH: So we went to the
camps, which are incredibly
depressing.
And the thought that Ahmad
wanted to be a filmmaker, and
that we had everything at our
disposal to help him with
that, after spending time with
him and opening up his life to
us, we decided that we
would surprise him.
And we gave him one
of our cameras.
AHMAD: As a Palestinian guy it's
so difficult to get like
a good camera.
I promise I will use this camera
for the peace, and for
nice things.
[MUSIC PLAYING]