so what's fluxes one-on-one when it
comes to race issues
what is the four elicit you must have
what you need to blame black people
using its there
the particular sir
number two immediate axle rights groups
number three
you need to protect corporations would
and a number four
you must use a black man as a proxy for
these effects of course i was like i
said
isn't mentioned three hundred dollars
sneakers on like this is going to be
some sort of like
picked up on the black community are
already any abuse of like it
so in this clip
big building they wait four four four
sold three hundred fifty dollars seekers
our civil rights issue
ice pack share the sticker shock i think
we ought to three hundred dollars
prepare sneakers so when you look at
some of the real problems facing black
america
fourteen point four percent unemployment
six
points higher
than the national average kids are
heading back to school black kids
disproportionately will head back to the
worst schools the most violent schools
with the worse
performing teachers
and this is what
uh... national urban league wants to
talk about the price of sneakers doesn't
make a lot of sense yet as in the
national normally is saying hey you know
what
since you wanted to our kids
and that you tried in these incredible
amounts of money it doesn't help their
poverty doesn't help the situation is
set up
that's what it concerned about it
now you can argue about that whether
that is a legitimate
safety concern itself with its own
but here fox was a major it's not the
corporations law it's not their fault
for overcharging et cetera okay
whose fault is it is the black people's
fault of the terrible schools is that
are set up
idled as the wall street journal
columnist wall street journal also owned
by rupert murdoch who owns this court
jason miley tells me something he's
black
here let's let 'em uh... explain
to use worked out the president of the
national program we says
quote it's insensitive to market of
three hundred dollars shoot to kids and
teens as people are going back to school
and struggling to buy school supplies
this fee is not produce is not read it's
a single pair of sneakers sorry same
it's insensitive sent out their work
they're worried about the feelings
to the extent that this is an issue
establishing record at the black
community this is about bally's
services about culture puts blaine that
puts
conspicuous consumption hadith
industry and threat and the focus needs
to be on the black community to to
rectify that
blaming corporate america is not gonna
fix that problem
that clinton is one way or another you
need to understand the right people to
blame or black people
humpback partridge what you'd have a
legitimate conversation about
they say you know what
list you know as bill cosby tries to do
from time to have any dislike each and i
have history of this error
but try to help
this is not helping people destroy a
national television is saying
it's black people's fault and don't
worry we got a black eye this a but
they're not
done yet
so if it's shifting the blame alan on
this uh...
the cultures and and the sensibilities
of the black community
but he uh... you name the topic you know
obvious she'd make happen schools is not
because you know black kids watch twice
as much television is like it's it's
because standardized tests are biased
great you know uh... tub of black men
are ever filling our prisons
are not because of lack the head here
but because the criminal justice system
is racist
this is all about
shifting blame when it comes to civil
rights leaders and they're not doing
any favors for the people they claim to
represent
perfect point number five
as there is no duty assignment shifting
blaine
usse well you see that civil rights
leaders to black people are sitting way
it's that needs to be and their their in
the ear amazingly talented during this
they do it over and over again and what
with it
it's not like they're trying to help the
black community it's not like boxes as
this huge
lack of your eagerness you're like a
guys hit list let's have an honest
conversation about what's happening
right
no this is the right that there was no
audience
so they got all you have towards those
black kids wasting their money in the
three hundred dollars sneakers
that we found a nice one
and he says it's all their fault the
crime as their fault the schools are
their fault it's all their culture
that's the problem
fall where they would be made out white
culture but i guess of mom's going to
take your money give them out of three
hundred dollars speakers and of course
this is the type of programming that
gives you know individuals in this
country and molly to speak out against
social programs because they'll say
all working on these minorities taking
advantage of social programs like
welfare and food stamps
when at the same time combined the three
hundred dollars sneakers that's what
this is really about at live in the
edison that nobody resist seed in
back-to-back segments and holders how do
you want to thank you and i don't know
alright jr analysis
because they recovered a bit
really in reality what happens is you
have some of them social programs
its actions that
if it's not like
devised by sneakers with
food stamps 'cause as we already know
again and again the which citizen that
could mean the times against it
black folks
aren't too many recipients of
about government assistance obviously we
know that i read it but you know who
cares what will keep
protecting the life
is its debt
mildly white kids can afford through
june fifteen dollars shoes
uh... why parents out there you guys
were aren't cast
the browser three hundred fifty
no nobody can afford that there's
nothing to do black kids but yes
wouldn't miss this poor kids first
people they can afford it
and then you know we know it is the
discrepancies on that but
when it comes to focusing on and on some
of the first clip
because some of the river link isn't
focusing on
that schools
that teaches and and and uh...
violent neighborhoods
acquittal that'll concerns of the time
of the strongly built the first place
the order of the league's ever said his
skepticism runs for president denies
right in his sex is not true immigrate
majority what they do are those topics
right
and generated great point
watson
do a segment on white kids being the
same three hundred fifty
uh... dollars however they don't have a
white guy from west virginia on say hey
you know what
answering what will work struggling to
find any jobs in this community and most
of the federal assistance to the white
people uh... and you know the same time
they're blind the speakers just like
anybody else's
the issue of the not to do that side
this is make the assumption that this is
that you know black kids buying these
expenses sneakers
ending and look what you see this more
white people that black people because
you're my guess is
as a whole lot more white kids by
mistake is that what