Travis Taylor: But will
our remote control
demolition derby end in
victory or disaster?
Rog: [laughing].
Daddy: Uh-oh, look out.
Travis Taylor:
I'm Travis Taylor,
I'm a rocket scientist
in the space and
defense industry
here in my hometown of
Huntsville, Alabama,
where my daddy helped
build the rockets
that sent us to the moon.
Daddy: Have y'all
been drinking
rocket fuel again?
Travis Taylor:
Sometimes big science
moves too slow for me.
So come the
weekend I round up
my best friend Rog.
Rog: Hey.
Travis Taylor: My
nephew Michael
and my buddy Pete
to tackle important
problems with a little
down-home ingenuity.
Rog: Damn it, boy.
Travis Taylor: Right on.
Hey, is there any more
beers in the cooler?
Me and the guys were
fooling around with
remote control toy
cars on a beer can
obstacle course.
One thing led
to another and
before you
know it we had
our own remote control
demolition derby.
Oh.
Michael: Hey
quit that, now,
this is supposed
to be a race.
Travis Taylor: If you
want to be the man,
you got to beat the man.
Look out.
Oh, oh.
Michael gets a little
competitive at times so
when I whooped him at
the RC demolition derby
he challenged me to
take it up a notch,
a real demolition
derby with full sized
remote control cars.
Michael: Yours is
more maneuverable.
If we had real
vehicles I'd be
beating you right now.
Travis Taylor: Now that's
my kind of challenge.
Daddy: You think that's
gonna be easy to do
a real car
remote control?
Travis Taylor: We put
a man on the moon,
we can figure out how to
remote control a car.
Daddy: Well we didn't do
it in the weekends either;
we did it seven days a
week on the mission.
Travis Taylor: Yeah but
that ain't as hard as
walking on the moon.
And Michael, he's
a big RC guy.
We can work on cars.
What could be more
fun than a demolition
derby on the weekend?
Now we just got to
figure out how to add a
remote control
device on a real car.
Oh right.
So we went back to the
garage to figure this out.
You got your steering
column sticks out,
out of your dash.
We were at the chalkboard
working out how we we're
gonna RC up the cars
and putting weapons
and stuff on them.
What if we weld a
blade or something?
What in the crap?
And I look over
at Rog and this thing
crawls out
of his overalls.
I, it's, I, I didn't
even know what it was.
Rog: It's a
little guinea pig.
Travis Taylor: What
are you doing with that
in your pants?
[laughing].
Michael: Yeah.
What's his name, Rog?
Rog: Curly.
Travis Taylor:
He says it's a
hairless guinea pig.
Rog: Feel him.
You know you want to.
Travis Taylor: It
feels like a pig.
It looked to me like
somebody had taken a
squirrel and held it
down and shaved it.
Daddy: What
do they eat?
Rog: They eat carrots
and things like that.
Travis Taylor:
Whatever Rog has got in
them overalls I reckon.
[laughing].
Rog: Yeah, he
done ate it all.
If you ain't
never seen one,
just startling
to look at them.
He's pretty, though,
I think he's neat.
Travis Taylor: We can
put that on the dash.
Well you can pet your
guinea pig we got to
figure out how we're
gonna RC up these cars.
Rog: Let's do it.
Travis Taylor:
We're gonna create a
remote control device
to run a full-sized car.
We'll use a regular toy
remote as the controller;
radio signals will
trigger the servomotors
for the 3 most important
parts of the car,
the gas, the brakes
and the steering.
Once we figure out how
to do it in one car we'll
do it to the second car.
Then we'll crash them
in to each other to see
whose is better in
an RC demolition derby.
Daddy: Great, we're gonna
spend an entire weekend
carefully building two
remote control vehicles,
then destroy them both.
I think there's something
wrong with all these boys.
Travis Taylor: We might
ought to add some stuff
like rockets or some.
Michael: Put some
spikes on it.
Travis Taylor: Harpoons
or some spikes.
Michael: Yeah.
Travis Taylor: Or.
Rog: Put a big manure
spreader on top and
sling crap out.
Travis Taylor: Oh manure
spreader to sling crap,
that'll be good.
Well y'all go figure
out what y'all want to
do to yours and we'll
figure out what we're
gonna do to ours.
We're gonna put
some stuff on ours.
Michael: Uncle
Travis wants to use my
old pickup truck,
Uncle Jessie,
for his remote
control car.
Pete: You know, I
should have brought
a crowbar I bet.
Michael: So if I'm
gonna fight him in a
demolition derby I got
to go for a big gun.
I might have
just the thing.
Travis Taylor: Ah,
that ain't no weapon.
He shows up
with this old RV
that we've used
for stuff before.
That thing's rickety,
it's rotten and rusty.
There's no way it can
hold up to Uncle Jessie.
And I'm telling you
David is gonna kick
Goliath's butt.
That thing's
just an accident
waiting to happen.
Michael: Exactly,
isn't that what you
want in a
demolition derby?
Travis Taylor: Yeah.
Michael: I think that
thing's heavy enough.
If it puts one
good lick on
Uncle Jessie it'll
be over with.
Travis Taylor: I don't
believe you could
ever get a hit on
Uncle Jessie.
Uncle Jessie is
driving around all
over that thing.
You ain't never gonna
lay a lick on him.
Michael: Man,
you're crazy,
that thing's
got a 360 in it.
Travis Taylor:
It don't matter.
You can drive fast
in a straight line but
you ain't gonna
turn real sharp or
it'll flip over on you.
Michael: Hey quit that,
you're gonna tear
something off of there.
Travis Taylor: I ain't
gonna tear nothing up.
Rog: I'm on
team Michael.
This old RV ain't
fast, but it's big.
It's gonna take a
lot to destroy this thing.
Travis Taylor: Come on
lets RC these trucks up
and lets go have
us some fun.
Once we figured out what
we needed I sent Michael
and Pete off to the RC
store to come back with
whatever we needed
to RC up the car.
And in the meantime
Daddy and I and Rog
are getting the steering
wheel off of Uncle Jessie.
Daddy: There you go.
Rog: All right team.
Travis Taylor:
There it is.
Here, go put
that somewhere.
Rog: Hold this, Curly.
Travis Taylor:
You and your pig.
I said somewhere;
I didn't mean throw
it in the back.
Rog: Like you got
particular about the
back of this truck.
Look at all the
crap in there.
Travis Taylor: Go put
that guinea pig somewhere
and do something.
Y'all are gonna lose
'cause all you're gonna do
is sit around and pet
that guinea pig all day.
Rog: Y'all
don't be throwing
nothing back here.
Travis Taylor:
Don't throw it, ag.
You the one already
that threw that
steering wheel
in the back.
Don't leave that pig in
the back of my truck.
Rog: That ain't
your truck.
Travis Taylor: Well
it's gonna be when I
start putting
robot stuff on it.
Rog: Stay with it Mule.
Travis Taylor: We're
gonna steer the truck
with the servomotors
connected to a pulley.
So I'm welding the
pulley wheel directly
to the steering column.
After he got back
with the parts,
Michael started building
the frames that'll hold
the servomotors inside
both of the trucks.
And these are the
parts that will make it
push, pull and turn.
A radio signal from
our control makes the
actuators push the
hydraulic pistons,
which are attached
to the pedals.
Push one lever, the
gas pedal moves and
the truck goes.
Push another, the
brake pedal moves and
the truck stops.
Daddy, here's
something you can do.
Daddy: What do you want?
Travis Taylor: Go out
there and figure how that
right there is gonna
go on like the bottom
of the brake pedal
or the gas pedal.
Daddy: Now I'm
gonna grind in that
brake pedal down.
Travis Taylor: While
you're grinding,
look right here,
I didn't finish this
I don't think.
See if this one will
fit on there flat,
we need to grind
that down some more.
Rog: Y'all are doing all
this for naught really.
Travis Taylor: Why?
Rog: Oh, we're gonna
destroy y'all dude.
Travis Taylor: Oh.
Rog: That RV's gonna
roll right over on you.
Travis Taylor: Y'all
aren't even gonna
lay a hand on us.
Rog: Whatever, we
ain't gonna use hands.
Travis Taylor: Look here.
Michael: Uncle Travis
better be ready
because we got plans
for deadly weapons.
We need to do is get a
piece of angle iron and
take two opposite ones
across and drill them
holes and then we
can just slide a piece
of angle on there
and then we can weld
all the pieces to the
one piece of angle.
We're gonna put a rammer
on the front of the RV,
we're gonna have
fireworks shooting out the
sides to set the
enemy on fire.
And we're gonna hang
big wrecking balls off
each side to hit the
truck as we pass.
We're gonna add spikes
to the wrecking balls
so it's a big mace.
We're gonna get
medieval on this truck.
Travis Taylor: I was
thinking about how
this crash-up
derby's gonna work.
We can't go in reverse
so we're just gonna go
around and around each
other just like an
old pirate ship
navy battle.
So I used that strategy
to design our weapon.
I decided to have
Daddy make some
pirate ship cannons
out of old sewer pipe.
We're gonna mount them
on each side of the truck
and they're gonna
fire beer cans.
Daddy: Too much.
Well now I've
seen everything.
He's got me making a
homemade beer cannon.
I did a little math and I
figured that with about
10 grams of black powder
a 12-ounce beer can
should go just
about 200 feet.
Travis Taylor: This
thing's loaded.
Here's our beer cannon,
let's go see
if it'll work.
Well let me point
that somewhere else,
Daddy, yeah.
All right,
here we go.
Daddy: I'll be
surprised if that
beer can don't rupture.
Travis Taylor:
Yeah we might just
throw beer everywhere.
We got about 10 grams
of gunpowder in this
thing loaded with a full
12-ounce can of beer.
If we're right it's gonna
act like a cannon ball
and blow a hole right
through our enemy.
If we're wrong, well
we may just be covered
with beer and blood
from the shrapnel.
Get on back there
behind an oak tree
or something.
Pete: Yeah.
Travis Taylor: We have
to very carefully
wire the beer cannon
into its trigger,
a 12-volt battery.
We're doing it from a good
distance just to be safe.
Everybody fire
in the hole,
fire in the hole.
Here we go.
And three, two, one.
Holy crap!
Travis Taylor: We're
putting remote control
devices on an old
pickup and an RV.
Plus we're adding some
serious weapons here
because they're going
head to head in an RC
demolition derby.
Fire in the hole,
fire in the hole.
Here we go.
We're adding a beer
can cannon to the
pickup but first we
had to test it.
Three, two, one.
Holy crap.
Pete: Whoa.
Where'd it go to?
Travis Taylor: It
went way out there.
Pete: Yeah.
Travis Taylor: It
went 100 yards.
Pete: That was
beautiful.
Travis Taylor: I'm
walking that off.
Daddy: Well I
said 200 feet.
Travis Taylor: 72 yards.
That's 216 feet.
Pete: On the
nose, Charlie.
Daddy: What's
it look like?
Travis Taylor: Just
ripped the bottom off
of it when it
hit the ground.
Daddy: I'll be darned.
Travis Taylor:
Daddy you can build
the hell out
of a cannon.
Daddy: Shoot beer at 'em,
when all else fails.
Pete: That's awesome.
Travis Taylor: We're
also adding to our
arsenal with old-school
battering rams and
axe blades off
the side of the truck.
This looks, it's nasty.
All right, so put that
right there for a minute.
Now that's got to
get mounted somehow
to that seat change.
Pete: Here's what
I was thinking.
Travis Taylor: Look this
we weld it out here.
Pete: I like that.
Michael: I stole
an idea from that
old movie, Ben-Hur .
We're gonna weld spikes
sticking out of the tires.
If that truck comes
anywhere near us,
we're gonna rip its
tires to shreds.
Travis Taylor:
What are you doing?
Rog: Got me a secret
weapon right here.
We ain't gonna
need that big one.
Curly now he's mad
'cause y'all made fun
of him a while ago.
Tell 'em Curly.
Daddy: [laughing].
Travis Taylor: He
needs him a girlfriend
he can put in there
and ride her around.
Rog: He's looking;
he's out cruising looking
for a girlfriend.
Travis Taylor: Yeah.
Daddy: Yeah, I don't
think anything that
ugly could get
a girlfriend.
Travis Taylor: Well
except maybe another
hairless,
ugly girlfriend.
Rog: Remember that
girlfriend you
had in high school?
Travis Taylor:
Shut up, Rog.
Rog: Look at old Curly.
Travis Taylor: Just
keep on playing
with your hairless rat.
You'll see who's gonna
end up being victorious
when all said and done.
Rog: Can't
believe you got.
Travis Taylor: If I were
you I'd get back to work.
Daddy: Get out
of here, pig.
Travis Taylor: We got
our weapons lined up
but Michael is the
only one of us who
has experience with
remote control.
So we are relying on him
to set up the RC units
for both trucks and
we're getting close
to our first test.
Michael: We've
about got everything
wired up in here.
I've wired it all
to this controller.
I can steer it.
I got my brakes.
And then, I've even
got my throttle.
Travis Taylor: We've
got both the vehicles
completely remote
control ready.
Now we need to test
those things and
make sure
that it works.
So we stripped the
weapons off Uncle Jessie
and got it
ready to roll.
Come here we're gonna
do a test on this thing.
Michael: Hey Rog, why
don't you ride and
be my gear shifter.
Rog: I'll do it.
Travis Taylor: All
right here we go.
Back it up, Michael.
Pete: Are we still in?
Daddy: I hope
it backs up.
Travis Taylor: Put
the car in reverse.
Rog: I guess we could
have figured out how
to put it into
reverse remotely,
but that would
have been a lot
more work, so we
decided against it.
Travis Taylor: Put it
in drive and get out.
Here we go.
Watch out, Daddy, he
might run over you.
We're going
around that tree.
Pete: This
is pretty cool.
Rog: Look at that,
Uncle Jesse, son.
Pete: This
is pretty neat,
there's a truck driving
around the yard
with nobody in it.
And here we are with
a toy remote control,
making it go
wherever we want.
It's like the best
Christmas present
a man could ever want.
Daddy: Michael,
quit ruining my yard.
Rog: [laughing].
He's on it, Charlie.
Michael: Watch this;
see if I can
power brake it.
Daddy: He comes
running across the yard
with tires spinning and dug
a trench across my grass.
Michael: Well you
can power brake.
That ain't the
yard out there.
Daddy: I'm skinning
that boy's head
before this day is over.
Rog: Oh me, Michael's
gonna get a whooping.
Travis Taylor: Oh,
grandma's gonna be
madder than
crap about that.
Michael: I was forced
to hand over the
controls to
Pete after that.
Pete: Charlie, I will not
power brake in your yard.
Travis Taylor: Turn it.
Turn it.
Pete: Oh, hold on.
Rog: Go fast, Pete.
Travis Taylor: Turn
it, Pete, turn it.
You got to turn it, boy.
Pete: I know.
Travis Taylor: Now you
done got it stuck.
Pete: No I didn't.
Travis Taylor: Turn it
back, bring it back.
Bring it back.
Rog: You got to turn
it while it's going
or it's hard to do.
Michael: Yeah, turn
it while it's going,
it's holding
up right there.
Travis Taylor: Come on.
How long is that range,
that thing's got?
Michael: Oh it's
got a long range.
Don't worry
about your range.
Travis Taylor:
Turn it around.
Rog: It's
running in circles.
Pete: It takes a little
getting used to.
Almost cut a
donut with it.
Michael: Do it.
Travis Taylor: No,
not out in the field.
Come on.
Daddy: I do not
want donuts cut.
I am serious.
Pete: Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Travis Taylor: Pete.
Watch out, now.
Be careful,
don't get going too fast.
Pete: Wait a minute.
Oh.
Something's wr.
Travis Taylor:
What are you doing?
Ho, stop it, Pete.
Pete: It won't.
Travis Taylor: Crap.
Oh, turn it off.
Turn it off.
Pete: I couldn't hit the
breaks or the steering.
I guess we lost
the signal.
Travis Taylor: Crap.
Michael: Oh good idea,
now the radiator's blown.
Travis Taylor: Is it?
Michael: Yeah.
Daddy: This
truck's wrecked.
We got a limb big as a
baseball bat sticking
through the radiator.
Travis Taylor: Crap.
Michael: The
truck is toast.
We spent the whole day
putting the RC unit on it,
then it goes out of
control and crashes.
The radiator's destroyed,
water's pouring everywhere
and it's already
overheating.
Travis Taylor:
See if it'll go.
It'll run, 'til
it runs hot.
Michael: This won't go
more than 40 feet now.
Rog: Stay with it, Pete.
Travis Taylor: We
always have to test
the things that we build.
But I hate it when tests
go wrong and tear up what
we just spent all
day working on.
So we got to get
our act together.
And to be honest I don't
know if we can fix this
radiator or even find
a new one overnight.
If we don't,
we're screwed.
Daddy: These
experiments are dangerous.
These guys are real
rocket scientists.
Don't try this at home.
Rog: Oh hell.
Travis Taylor:
Michael what the.
Rog: Hang on.
Travis Taylor: We're
taking full-sized trucks
and making them
remote controlled.
Be careful, don't
be going too fast.
Our first test
was a disaster.
Crap.
Oh, stop it.
Michael: Oh good idea,
now the radiator's blown.
Travis Taylor: Is it?
Michael: Yeah.
Travis Taylor: We spent
the night calling around
auto stores and junkyards
and by a miracle Pete
found a Ford radiator that
would just about fit.
So we worked on
getting it in place,
fixing it to where
the truck could run.
And I think we're
back in business.
Michael: So now both
trucks are ready and
it's time to rumble.
Daddy: We're at
the Fairgrounds,
where they'll let us
use their big field.
We've got two vehicles
and they're each armed
to the teeth and
remote controlled.
These boys are planning
to crash them into
each other over
and over again until
they're
completely destroyed.
In Alabama we call
that a great weekend.
Travis Taylor: We're
gonna knock that RV
right off the road.
We've made our old
truck Uncle Jesse into a
deadly remote
control weapon.
This thing right here
is gonna be like a
can opener, it's
gonna rip that RV
of yours just
right in two.
Pete: That's right,
stem to stern.
Travis Taylor: We're
gonna use these saw blades
to cut your wheels
out from under you.
The thing that's gonna
really take you out,
these beer cans are
gonna go right through
the walls of that thing.
Michael: Shoot, that
ain't gonna do nothing.
Travis Taylor:
They are too.
Michael: Uncle Travis
and Pete might have
beer cannons
but Rog and I
got old fashion
wrecking balls.
We got heavy kegs with
spikes hanging from
each side and spinning
spikes coming out
of each wheel.
We also have fireworks.
There's a whole box of
bottle rockets and
Roman Candles pointing
out of the side of the RV.
We're gonna
shoot em out and set
Uncle Jessie on fire.
Travis Taylor:
Rocket launchers?
Michael: Yeah.
Travis Taylor: Rockets
are just gonna go
off across the
parking lot.
Michael: Yeah.
Yeah, right.
Travis Taylor: You ain't
gonna hit nothing.
Michael: They're
gonna go right through
the windshield.
Travis Taylor:
Especially if you keep
them duct taped
down like that.
Michael: Yeah.
Travis Taylor:
You're just gonna set
yourself on fire.
Michael: Most
of all we've got weight
and speed.
We could ram that little
truck and that'd be it.
Daddy: I told these boys
to take some test runs
before we start the
demolition derby.
Travis Taylor: Go
around and around, man.
Daddy: I want
to make sure we can
control these things.
Travis Taylor:
Go, Pete, go.
Rog: Look at that.
[laughing].
That sucker gets
sideways, Charlie.
Travis Taylor: Go a
little faster, Pete.
Michael: This
thing is deadly.
I didn't realize what
kind of momentum those
kegs would pick up just
swinging on the sides.
One hit from that and
Uncle Jessie is gone.
Rog: Watch that
brush by, Pete.
Travis Taylor: These
guys don't know about
my secret weapon.
It's a little remote
control toy car.
And it's carrying
a fireworks bomb
on its back.
When I need to, I
can have that thing drive
right under the RV and
blow it up from underneath.
It's a remote
control assassin.
Daddy: I'm ready
to see some action.
Travis Taylor:
Let's do it.
Daddy: Let's do it.
Get out here
and let's go.
Travis Taylor:
Let's get it on.
Michael: All right.
Travis Taylor:
It's show time,
it's the David and
Goliath battle royale and
David is about to
kick Goliath's butt.
Daddy: Get
ready, set, go.
Travis Taylor: Get him,
Pete, get him, Pete.
Wait slow down.
All right,
ripped him out.
Rog: Look at the
side of the RV.
Travis Taylor:
We gutted the RV.
First hit, Uncle Jessie
suffers no damage and
we rip a big chunk
out of that RV.
Pete: Oh look at all that
stuff on the ground.
Michael:
That's all right,
we got a big
vehicle and
we can take a lot
of punishment.
Rog: It looks like
we're gonna have to
hit that truck
a lot harder.
Travis Taylor: Bring
her around again,
Pete, quick.
Get him on this side.
I think it's
about time for a
pirate
cannon broadside.
I'm gonna hit
him with the gun.
Daddy: Get it, Pete.
Rog: You can't hit
nothing, Mule.
Pete: Hey, all right.
Travis Taylor: Boom, score
one for the beer cannon.
Pete: Woo.
Travis Taylor:
Yeah, look at that.
Rog: That was nothing.
We took a direct hit
from the cannon and
it didn't do
a damn thing.
We're still in
this fight.
Pete, you can't
catch nothing.
Travis Taylor:
Get him, Pete.
Daddy: Oh Pete,
you missed him.
Travis Taylor:
Get him, Pete.
There you go,
watch out, Pete.
Whoa.
Michael: Oh.
Travis Taylor: Oh.
Rog: [laughing].
We've got hit hard,
but Uncle Jessie was
spewing gas everywhere.
All we need is
one good hit and
we gonna take him
right out of the game.
Daddy: You're gonna
run out of gas, Pete.
Spewing gas everywhere.
Look out.
Pete: Get him.
Travis Taylor: Oh.
[laughing].
Rog: [laughing].
Oh get him,
boom, got it.
[laughing]
Come on, yurk.
Travis Taylor: Whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa,
we're leaking
gas everywhere.
Pete: Oh no, man.
Travis Taylor: Be
careful, be careful.
Rog: [laughing].
Oh.
Pete: God.
Rog: I love it.
Travis Taylor: Looks
like we're both dead
in the water.
But I've still got my
remote control assassin.
There it goes.
All right, here we go.
Pete: At least gonna get
rid of the evidence.
Rog: Woo.
First the fireworks
started taking off.
Put your safety
glasses on.
Then they hit
the gasoline.
Daddy: Uncle Jessie
was a good old truck.
Travis Taylor:
Uncle Jessie was a
good old truck.
Rog: Oh.
Michael: Get, get back.
Travis Taylor: You
didn't leave Curly
in there, did you?
Rog: No, no, no.
Curly's at home, safe.
Travis Taylor: We proved
that in a weekend we could
not only create a radio
controlled full-size car,
but we could destroy that
thing real good too.
Now that's redneck
ingenuity.
Rog: It's time
to go, boy.
Curly, come on, dude.
Oh crap.
Mamma: What are you
looking for, Rog?
Rog: Uh, oh.
[laughing].
I sent Curly in
here to cool down.
Come here, Curly.
He don't come
when he's called.
Mamma: Well what you
calling him for?
Rog: I don't know, I
ain't never lost him.