VALERIE VARGAS: We're in
the big, red circle.
Did you see the kangaroos
in there?
And the wallabies?
STEWART ROBSON: Hello.
VALERIE VARGAS: How
cool is he?
STEWART ROBSON: You want
to go on the slides?
You know you do.
VALERIE VARGAS: Can you imagine
getting a hug from one
of them, how awesome
that would feel?
It would wrap around your
whole entire body.
MALE SPEAKER:
STEWART ROBSON: I can't really
remember, to be honest.
She'd probably need
to jog my memory.
MALE SPEAKER:
STEWART ROBSON: Oh yeah.
We were working together then.
We were friends, and
we were whatever.
And she was blind drunk.
Horrendous.
I remember telling her, if you
were a man, I'd knock you out.
Because she's a mean drunk,
really horrible.
And then, well why are
you being an asshole?
And her answer was, I
fucking love you.
A few months later,
we were together.
VALERIE VARGAS: The lion's
voice is the deepest and
loudest of all cats.
How low is your voice compared
to a lion's roar?
Pop your head through the hole
and growl as low as you can.
Go on.
STEWART ROBSON: I'm
not going to roar.
VALERIE VARGAS: Go on.
STEWART ROBSON: Ahh.
VALERIE VARGAS: We were friends
just before he started
to be serious about wanting to
tattoo, and before he actually
started tattooing.
By then we were talking every
other day swapping stories
about what's going on with me.
And I really liked
his work online.
He had a couple of websites
with some of his work.
And it was like, hey, would you
mind just doing a little
black tattoo?
And he did it.
And we just stayed in touch.
So it was a lovely journey,
friendship wise.
And then when we got together
it felt like, right, this is
where it really begins now.
STEWART ROBSON: I absolutely
love the head, the tail--
yeah.
VALERIE VARGAS: [INAUDIBLE]
STEWART ROBSON: Yeah,
absolutely.
Every element about it is just
more the position of where
he's off to.
VALERIE VARGAS: Well let
me draw it first.
And then I'll let
you have a look.
STEWART ROBSON:
VALERIE VARGAS: He doesn't like
the claws, the way the
angle of them goes.
STEWART ROBSON:
VALERIE VARGAS: He's always been
very good at doing that,
telling me why something is
wrong, not just telling me
it's wrong or why does that
look like shit, you know.
STEWART ROBSON: That's
how we ended up
getting together, really.
Because it worked really well.
She helps me with drawings,
I help her with drawings.
And she went, why is that tiger
you drew cross-eyed?
And I'm like, I didn't fucking
notice it's cross-eyed.
And so we can help each other.
Maybe I focus more on
composition and flow, and she
focuses more on detail.
And Valerie can characterize
a mood and a feeling and a
character in a tattoo.
And a lot of people don't
make a character.
They either make it angry or sad
or whatever, but there's
no character there.
She's known for faces.
But she also does a
characterization with eagle,
snakes, and narrowing an eye,
and maybe a larger pupil or a
smaller pupil.
And she understands
that stuff.
VALERIE VARGAS: I'm just so
happy that I like his work, he
likes my work, which means that
we have mutual respect.
I've said to him before, kind
of jokingly, if you sucked I
wouldn't have half as much
fun in this relationship
as I do, you know?
It's really cool to watch over
his shoulder and just be like,
how did you do that?
That's amazing.
And I love it.
STEWART ROBSON: I don't think
either of our work would be as
accomplished without
each other.
All right, Dragon Man.
VALERIE VARGAS (OFFSCREEN):
The Dragon Man.
STEWART ROBSON:
VALERIE VARGAS (OFFSCREEN):
Shut the fuck up.
It doesn't need a wave at all.
STEWART ROBSON: It says,
[INAUDIBLE] in
the water above it.
VALERIE VARGAS (OFFSCREEN):
Ugh.
Shut up.
You're just making
my life harder.
MALE SPEAKER: You're
not a fan of waves?
VALERIE VARGAS: I can't draw
water to save my life.
I'm generally quite a grumpy
sod, to be honest.
You know, I don't know if it
comes through or what.
But I think the more I hang out
with people the more they
see it, definitely.
STEWART ROBSON:
VALERIE VARGAS (OFFSCREEN):
Where?
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
VALERIE VARGAS (OFFSCREEN): If
you're going to say here, I
don't want it there.
STEWART ROBSON: No, no, because
that'll take up space.
You need a cloud in here.
VALERIE VARGAS: Really?
STEWART ROBSON (OFFSCREEN):
Yeah, in that little bit.
Because that's just an
empty hollow there.
That's all.
VALERIE VARGAS (OFFSCREEN):
No, I'm not
gonna do a cloud there.
VALERIE VARGAS (OFFSCREEN):
See, Stewart?
STEWART ROBSON (OFFSCREEN):
DANTE DIMASSA: We all say that
Stewart's under the thumb.
You know, I'm married, I have a
child, and the one who wears
the pants in my house
is my wife.
It might not look like that, but
that's how a man's life--
not a man's life.
You know, when you get married
you sign up for that.
That's how it is.
So it's all right.
And Stewart knows that.
Stewart knows how to
handle Valerie.
STEFANO C: I mean, I
know many couples
that are both tattooers.
So there's always
the team work.
And I guess it does help.
I mean, having satisfaction from
work makes you go home
and have a positive love
life or relationship.
It's obviously a full-on
tattoo life.
VALERIE VARGAS: You're going
to have to get a spider web
for this one.
I think that would be nice.
Either that, or get a spider
web, actually, on the ball of
your shoulder.
STEWART ROBSON: There's
not much outside of
tattoos in our lives.
And things have fallen by the
wayside that aren't tattoos,
or that we can't soak
up information
from to use in tattooing.
But then, tattooing has
given us so much.
Our relationship is due to
tattooing, our friends and the
opportunities that arise.
It's given us our lives,
and we enjoy our lives.
So keep feeding the beast.
STEWART ROBSON (OFFSCREEN):
[INAUDIBLE] neck.
VALERIE VARGAS (OFFSCREEN):
They always look
like they're drunk.
STEWART ROBSON (OFFSCREEN):
He's pissed.
He's not happy.
VALERIE VARGAS: You think so?
Yeah?
Green dragon, some purple,
some yellow, some red?
MALE SPEAKER:
VALERIE VARGAS (OFFSCREEN):
Really?
Because I thought I'd draw
a peacock on you.
MALE SPEAKER:
VALERIE VARGAS (OFFSCREEN):
Oh, that's
definitely not green.
Oh, no, no.
That's definitely
turquoise blue.
That's not green.
Like that kind of green.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN): OK.
VALERIE VARGAS: Basically, since
I got into tattoos in
2004 with my apprenticeship,
I've just not stopped.
And I'm catching up now
with the fun stuff.
And I keep reminding myself I'm
a 30-year-old woman, I'm
not a 15-year-old girl.
I need to learn to drive, I need
to learn to do things.
I barely know how to cook.
And he kind of jokes about
it, but he's very
serious at the same time.
Like look, when we finally
settle into this flat, I'm
going to take you to the
supermarket, and I'm going to
teach you how to shop
for food and stuff.
Because I don't know how
to shop for food.
I literally go, I want
a sandwich right
now, I'll buy a sandwich.
And then what do
I eat tomorrow?
I'm really bad like that, so
he's going to help me a little
bit, be a bit more
domesticated.
That's a sexy fish.
Would you not agree?
STEWART ROBSON: A sexy fish?
VALERIE VARGAS: Yeah.
Oh, look at that dude.
How awesome is he?
STEWART ROBSON (OFFSCREEN):
It's just nice to grow
alongside someone, as well.
It's super cool.
I guess we're still
growing together.
She's still developing.
It's really cool to see that.
And I'm still developing,
and she's really
supportive of that.
Yeah.
VALERIE VARGAS (OFFSCREEN):
It really works for us.
It's not for everybody.
A lot of people do go,
how do you do it?
How do you live together, go
to work together, work the
same days, and hang out together
on your days off?
I don't know.
It works.
Can't hug you with this?
STEWART ROBSON (OFFSCREEN):
I know, bags everywhere.
VALERIE VARGAS: You
having fun?
STEWART ROBSON: Yeah.
STEWART ROBSON (OFFSCREEN):
[INAUDIBLE]
A little bit.
VALERIE VARGAS: What
do you want?
STEWART ROBSON: Just
stand there.
[INAUDIBLE]
VALERIE VARGAS: Hang on.
Yeah?
Enough?
STEWART ROBSON: You hate having
your picture taken.
VALERIE VARGAS: I hate having
my picture taken.
STEWART ROBSON: [INAUDIBLE]
VALERIE VARGAS: Yeah, he loves
having his picture taken.