150 years ago,
the business corporation was a
relatively insignificant institution.
Today it is all pervasive like the
church, the monarchy
and the communist party in other
times and places;
the corporation is today's dominant
institution.
This documentary examines the nature,
evolution, impacts and possible future of
the modern business corporation.
And you should give them a narrow
legal mandate
what has allowed today’s corporation
to achieve such extraordinary power
and influence over our lives.
The beginner inquiry scandals
threaten to trigger a wide debate
about the lack of control over big corporations.
"I think there is an overhang..."
"over the market of distrust..."
"there is a 95%, 100%, a huge
percentage of the business"
"community are honest and reveal all
of their assets,"
"their compensation programs are robust"
"but there are some bad apples."
The media debate about the basic
corporating principles
of the corporate world was quickly
reduced to a game to follow the leader.
"I still happen to think the United States
is the greatest place in the world to invest."
"We have some shakes up that are
going on because of a few bad apples."
"Some people call me a bad apple,"
"well, I may be bruised but I still taste sweet."
"but I may be the sweetest apple on the tree."
"These are not just a bunch of bad apples!"
"This is just a few bad apples!"
"It's not just a few bad apples!"
"We got to get rid of the bad apples!
You can start with Tyco!"
"Bad apples!"
"We know all about WorldCom!
- Bad apples!"
"Xerox corporation!
"Arthur Andersen. - Bad apples!
ENRON obviously! - Bad apples!"
"K-Mart Corporation!"
"Their car is getting a little
more full."
"I don't think it's just a few apples
unfortunately,"
"I think this is the worst crisis of
confidence in a business..."
What's wrong with this picture?
"Can we pick up a better metaphor
to describe"
the dominant institution of our time?
Through the voices of CEOs, whistle
blowers, brokers, gurus and spies,
insiders and outsiders, they present
the corporation as a paradox,
an institution that creates great
wealth but causes enormous
and often hidden harms.
I see the corporation as a part of
the jigsaw in society as a whole,
which if you remove it, the picture
is incomplete
but equally if it is the only part,
it's not going to work.
A sports team, some of us are blocking
and tackling,
some of us are running the ball,
some of us are throwing the ball
but we all have a common purpose
which is to succeed as an organization.
A corporation is like a family unit;
people in the corporation work together
for a common end.
Like the telephone system, it reaches
almost everywhere.
It is extraordinarily powerful.
It is pretty hard to avoid and it
transforms the lives of people,
I think, on balance for the better.
"The eagle, soaring, clear eyed..."
"competitive, prepared to strike
but not a vulture..."
"noble,  a visionary, majestic..."
"that people can believe in and be
inspired by;"
"that creates such a lift that it soars."
"I can see that being a good logo
for the principal company."
"Okay guys, enough bullshit!!"
Corporations are artificial creations;
you might say they are monsters trying
to devour as much profit as possible
at anyone's expense.
I think of a whale, gentle, big fish
which can swallow you in an instant.
Doctor Frankenstein's creation has
overwhelmed and overpowered him
as the corporate form has done with us.
"The word corporate gets attached
in almost..."
"you know, in a priority of sense to..."
"and it gets married with the word
agenda  and one hears a lot"
"about the word corporate agenda
as tough it is evil,"
"as though it is an agenda which is
trying to take over the world."
"Personally, I don't use the word
corporation,"
I use the word business;
I would use the word...
"I use the word company.
I'll use the word business community"
"because I think that is a much fair
representation"
"than zeroing on just this word 'corporation'."
"It is funny that I taught in the
business school for as long as I have"
"without ever having been asked
so pointedly to say"
"what I think a corporation is."
It is one form of business ownership.
It's a group of individuals working
together to serve a variety
of objectives the principle one of
which is earning large,
growing, sustained, legal returns
for the people who own the business.
Hi there, this is Mark Achbar,
I produced and co-directed the corporation
and this is the official shareware
version of the film.
I am proud of the fact that hundreds
of thousands of people
have already downloaded and shared
this film.
If I had a dollar for every download, well...,
I probably wouldn't be making this appeal.
More than 200 people worked on
the film, the DVD, and the website
over 8 years.  If you support the film,
please support the filmmakers too.
You can make a contribution, large
or small,
even a couple of bucks would help
at www.thecorporation.com.
All rights reserved.
http://www.geodirect.co.nr/