IAN ST. PE: VBS.
Vice, Black Lips,
Israel, tour--
what month are we in?
June?
June.
Let's do this.
[MUSIC PLAYING - THE BLACK
LIPS, "COLD HANDS"]
IAN ST. PE: We're in the biggest
Israeli radio station.
ALL: Hi, we're The Black Lips.
You're listening to KZ
Radio with Quami.
QUAMI: Black Lips, [HEBREW].
So thanks.
Thanks, guys.
BLACK LIPS MEMBER (OFFSCREEN):
Yeah.
JARED SWILLEY: Thank you.
QUAMI: Yeah, it's great
having you here.
We've been waiting for a really
long time for that.
JARED SWILLEY: Oh, yeah.
We've been waiting a long
time to come here.
COLE ALEXANDER: Yeah.
JARED SWILLEY: You know, we
were really surprised that
anyone over here knew
us, so it was cool.
QUAMI: OK, so what's next.
JARED SWILLEY: This is
called "Dirty Hands."
QUAMI (OFFSCREEN): Yeah, it's
your biggest hit in Israel.
JOE BRADLEY (OFFSCREEN):
One, two, three, four.
[MUSIC PLAYING - THE BLACK
LIPS, "DIRTY HANDS"
QUAMI: Thanks so much.
The Black Lips.
Have fun during the rest
of your stay in Israel.
And you have two
more shows in--
JARED SWILLEY (OFFSCREEN):
Jerusalem--
QUAMI: Jerusalem.
JARED SWILLEY: And Haifa.
QUAMI (OFFSCREEN):
And Tel Aviv.
JARED SWILLEY: And Tel Aviv.
[MUSIC PLAYING - THE BLACK
LIPS, "LOCK AND KEY"]
IAN ST. PE: OK, so we're
in Israel right now.
And as you can see, it's
a lot like New York.
There's a lot of Jewish
people, a lot
of kids with guns.
And one better part is instead
of swimming in the Hudson
River, we're going to
the Sea of Galilee.
Right?
Yes.
[MUSIC PLAYING - THE BLACK
LIPS, "LOCK AND KEY"]
IAN ST. PE: Now, we're in
Tiberias, the Sea of Galilee,
and we just found out that
there's no beds tonight.
We thought we were going
to a kibbutz,
but it's just a porch.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN): Oh
yeah, did you mention we're--
IAN ST. PE (OFFSCREEN): Yeah.
We're staying on the
fucking porch.
So we have to--
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
We're sleeping on
the god damn ground.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
How's that for Israeli
hospitality?
IAN ST. PE: It's great.
The hummus today
was top notch.
But god damn, they should have
told us we're going on a
camping trip with no sleeping
bags or tents
or blankets or anything.
JARED SWILLEY (OFFSCREEN): Yeah,
I'm going to baptize
Cole tomorrow.
He needs it.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
He does.
JARED SWILLEY (OFFSCREEN):
He needs it.
JOE BRADLEY: [INAUDIBLE]
JARED SWILLEY (OFFSCREEN):
He needs a cleansing.
He smells so bad right now.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Yeah, there he is.
IAN ST. PE: Hey, Cole.
MALE SPEAKER: Hey, Cole.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN): Cole,
are you ready to get
baptized tomorrow?
COLE ALEXANDER: Oh,
yeah, yeah.
JARED SWILLEY (OFFSCREEN):
I'm gonna baptize you.
COLE ALEXANDER: Jared's
gonna baptize me?
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
It's time.
COLE ALEXANDER: Comes a
time in a man's life.
MALE SPEAKER: All right.
This is day one.
IAN ST. PE: We're The Black
Lips, and we're here at the
Sea of Galilee, getting
holy with you.
MALE SPEAKER: Word.
[MUSIC PLAYING -
THE BLACK LIPS]
[MUSIC PLAYING - THE BLACK
LIPS, "VENI VIDI VICI"]
[CAR ALARM]
[MUSIC PLAYING - THE BLACK
LIPS, "VENI VIDI VICI"]
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN): Can
we just talk about that
fucking wooden deck situation
for a second?
JARED SWILLEY: Well, we
kind of got kidnapped.
I think they were trying
to show us a good time.
They said they had a private
beach, and I thought a private
beach meant there was a house
that goes with it, but I guess
their parents just
own a porch.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
It was dark.
JARED SWILLEY (OFFSCREEN):
No lanterns.
Not one pillow.
I think two blankets.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Two beers.
JARED SWILLEY (OFFSCREEN):
Yeah, like four
beers between everybody.
It was awesome.
[MUSIC PLAYING - THE BLACK
LIPS, "OFF THE BLOCK"]
COLE ALEXANDER: We are here at
the Jordan River, the place
where Jesus was baptized
by John the Baptist.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN): And
what's going to happen to you?
COLE ALEXANDER: I'm gonna have
my ass baptized by Jared.
FEMALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Yeah, why not?
PRIEST: Well, I'm not bequeathed
to this area, so I
cannot baptize--
FEMALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
No, it doesn't matter.
PRIEST (OFFSCREEN):
[INAUDIBLE]
sacrament.
Yeah.
FEMALE SPEAKER: OK,
I'll pray for you.
[INAUDIBLE]
if you only need a
piece of paper.
JARED SWILLEY: I don't
know what to say.
PRIEST: I accept Jesus in the
name of the Father, the Son,
and the Holy Spirit.
FEMALE SPEAKER: You're ready.
OK, [INAUDIBLE] yourself.
[INAUDIBLE] here.
This way.
Clean?
COLE ALEXANDER: Why?
I'm trying to become baptized.
FEMALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Hurry up.
They always say something.
Dip yourselves into the water.
Come deeper.
COLE ALEXANDER: Say it loud,
into the camera.
FEMALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
OK.
Lord, bless those two
[INAUDIBLE] in the name of
Father, Son, and Holy Spirit.
Bless them and change
their life, Father.
And now you.
OK.
Hallelujah.
Now you.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Excuse me, guys.
Please, you cannot go like
that in the water.
JARED SWILLEY: Sorry.
MALE SPEAKER: You're offending
people, I'm very sorry.
You have to have appropriate
[INAUDIBLE].
You're offending people
like that.
People come from all
over the world.
JARED SWILLEY: I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
MALE SPEAKER: I hope
you have a good
ceremony, but do it properly.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Thank you.
PRIEST (OFFSCREEN): I'll give
you a blessing here.
Almighty God, I ask of you, that
Cole Alexander to open
his heart up completely to Jesus
Christ, the Father, Son,
and the Holy Spirit.
May he receive your grace today
to truly be a disciple
of Jesus Christ and reject
sin and accept the
Kingdom of God forever.
In the name of the Father,
the Son, and Holy Spirit.
COLE ALEXANDER: Thank
you, Father.
PRIEST: You're welcome, Cole.
COLE ALEXANDER: Does this guy
look like Jesus or what?
PRIEST: He does.
[MUSIC PLAYING - THE BLACK
LIPS, "BAD KIDS"]
JOE BRADLEY: We're here with
Jesus at the River Jordan.
It's a great day for baptism.
Great day for friendship,
forgiveness, fellowship, and
most of all, Jesus.
[MUSIC PLAYING - THE BLACK
LIPS, "BAD KIDS"]
LIPS, "I SAW A GHOST"]
COLE ALEXANDER: Hello, we're The
Black Lips, and we're at
the Dead Sea.
JARED SWILLEY: We're 400
meters below sea level,
meaning this is the closest
place to hell on
earth you can get.
It's good for your skin.
It makes you look good,
makes you feel good.
JOE BRADLEY: Smell good.
Make love good.
[MUSIC PLAYING - THE BLACK
LIPS, "SEA OF BLASPHEMY"]
COLE ALEXANDER: Where's
the mud?
JARED SWILLEY: I'm gonna have
that shit all over in my body.
I'll put it on my cock.
Fuck this, dude.
[MUSIC PLAYING -
THE BLACK LIPS]
[LAUGHING]
IAN ST. PE: We're making
our skin smooth.
COLE ALEXANDER: We're in
this medicinal mud--
mud hole with trash
and minerals.
JARED SWILLEY: We're smoothing
our skin, the Dead Sea '07.
Spring break.
JOE BRADLEY: '07.
'07.
JARED SWILLEY: Keeping
it young.
JOE BRADLEY: Keeping it black.
COLE ALEXANDER: Bringing new
meaning to the term "wigger"
in the 21st century, homeboy.
JOE BRADLEY: [INAUDIBLE].
IAN ST. PE: Peace.
The stuff on the skin feels like
that hot oil stuff that
you put on your girl and
she puts on you.
This feels good.
IAN ST. PE: Do we look
relaxed and smooth?
You're god damn right, we do.
This was amazing, amazing.
COLE ALEXANDER: Better
than a Hollywood spa.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN): Yeah,
you're gonna end up like
Paul Mitchell one
of these days.
[MUSIC PLAYING - THE BLACK
LIPS, "WORKIN'"]
DAVE HAMNAHEM: Yeah, OK.
So let's have a short
introduction.
Jared on bass, but
today on guitar.
JARED SWILLEY: Hey.
DAVE HAMNAHEM: Ian on guitar.
IAN ST. PE: Sup.
DAVE HAMNAHEM: Joe on drums.
JOE BRADLEY: Player.
DAVE HAMNAHEM: And
Cody on guitar.
COLE ALEXANDER: Hello.
DAVE HAMNAHEM: OK, so you want
to tell us how's your
impression from Israel
up until now?
Do you have an impression?
JARED SWILLEY: So far,
it's been amazing.
We just came straight
from the Dead Sea.
We've been down there today.
DAVE HAMNAHEM: Straight to
the radio, you mean.
JARED SWILLEY: Yeah, yeah,
straight to the radio.
DAVE HAMNAHEM: And how was it?
JARED SWILLEY: That
was incredible.
We floated a lot, and we covered
ourselves in mud.
[LAUGHTER]
DAVE HAMNAHEM: Who writes
the lyrics for you guys?
COLE ALEXANDER: We all do.
DAVE HAMNAHEM: But for this
song specifically?
JARED SWILLEY: Cole.
COLE ALEXANDER: I wrote the
lyrics for that song.
I was in Los Angeles, and I
was with these people, and
they were smoking crack.
And then this lady was a model,
and she was telling me
how her son's teacher had died,
and she didn't want have
to tell him because he
liked the teacher.
JOE BRADLEY: One, two
three, four, five,
six, one, two, three--
[MUSIC PLAYING - THE BLACK LIPS,
"HOW DO YOU TELL A CHILD
THAT SOMEONE HAS DIED"]
COLE ALEXANDER: See
you, Dead Sea.
IAN ST. PE: See this view?
I want you to look at it and
tell me there's no God.
Amazing.
[MUSIC PLAYING - THE BLACK
LIPS, "FAIRY STORIES"]
IAN ST. PE: Man.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
What is it, like
10:00 in the morning?
IAN ST. PE: This is great.
Yeah, it's like 10:00 in the
morning, and we're doing the
tonight show.
Fuck, I'm tired.
I'm tired.
We're going to do
a little on-air
performance for Israeli TV--
their Jay Leno.
What's his name?
FEMALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Lior Shlein.
IAN ST. PE: Lior Shlein.
That's what we're doing.
FEMALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
The show called Ha-Layla.
IAN ST. PE: Ha-Layla.
Eat your heart out.
COLE ALEXANDER: I think it's the
first time we're ever been
on a legitimate television show,
except for the local
news network.
With a seven point rating,
is that what you said?
MALE SPEAKER: 7%.
COLE ALEXANDER (OFFSCREEN):
7%.
MALE SPEAKER: 7 or 8.
JARED SWILLEY: We got
like 400,000 people.
It's a lot.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
No pressure.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN): Joe,
are you ready to do this?
JOE BRADLEY: I was born ready.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Yeah.
JOE BRADLEY: Came out
of that womb ready.
IAN ST. PE: Party time.
All right.
[MUSIC PLAYING - THE BLACK
LIPS, "BAD KIDS"]
[CHEERING]
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
What is that smell?
JOE BRADLEY: What is
this bullshit?
A nigger can't even
sing in here.
Can't see, can't breathe.
Don't feel good, look good,
don't smell good.
What the fuck is this shit?
I can't see.
Smells like somebody opened
up their butthole.
up their asshole in here.
[MUSIC PLAYING - THE BLACK
LIPS, "BURIED ALIVE"]
SUROOSH ALVI: What was it like
playing at a kibbutz?
JOE BRADLEY: Well, at a
kibbutz-- it's kind of like
this commune.
But I think they're all just
most just lazy, [INAUDIBLE]
looking for cheap rent or
something like that-- or at
least that was somewhat
of the vibe.
But it was open every single
night until like 11:00.
They got cheap beer and they
don't make any money.
When we played, they
had this tradition.
They burn this whole frying pan
up of pine cones and let
all the smoke fill that
tiny-ass room
when we were playing.
The window was right
next to me.
Eyes were closed.
I could feel the smoke billowing
and filling my
lungs, second and second,
losing breath
and breath and breath.
And we were like, what
the fuck is that?
It's like, oh, it's
our tradition.
And I was like, well, it's
our tradition to breathe.
[MUSIC PLAYING - THE BLACK
LIPS, "BURIED ALIVE"]
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN): Well,
now we're going to the
other side, so you can--
COLE ALEXANDER: We're going
where no Israeli
has ever been before.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN): To
play to the Palestinians.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
I'm not nervous at all.
I think everybody's gonna
be really nice.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN): Yeah.
Yeah.
They will be.
COLE ALEXANDER: Hello.
We're The Black Lips, and we're
here in Bethlehem about
to play a rock and roll show.
We got our friends here.
This is our friends here,
drinking juice.
All right.
[INAUDIBLE].
JOE BRADLEY (OFFSCREEN):
One, two, three, four.
[MUSIC PLAYING - THE BLACK
LIPS - "BOOMERANG"]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
JOE BRADLEY: Hey, were
The Black Lips.
We're here in Bethlehem,
in the West Bank.
Just did a little bit of
busking, not for money,
though, just for fun.
The kids were into it.
We got some mint tea from
some local shop owners.
JARED SWILLEY: And now we have
bragging rights to say that
we're the first and only
punk band to ever
play in the West Bank.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Yeah.
JOE BRADLEY: West side.
IAN ST. PE: West Bank's
the best bank.
JARED SWILLEY: We're the
West Bank's first
and only punk band.
COLE ALEXANDER: West
Bank ballers, '07.
Peace out.
[MUSIC PLAYING]