MALE SPEAKER 1: The games of the
30th Olympiad in 2012 are
awarded to the city of London.
[CHEERING]
[MUSIC - GEORGE EVANS, "IN THE
GOOD OLD SUMMER TIME"]
MALE SPEAKER 2: I'm pretty
excited about the Olympics
FEMALE SPEAKER 1:
Really excited.
MALE SPEAKER 3: A moment
in history which
will never be repeated.
FEMALE SPEAKER 2: There's
nowhere else in the world that
could do it justice.
MALE SPEAKER 4: The whole of
Great Britain will celebrate.
FEMALE SPEAKER 3: I'm not sure
the people who are angry about
the Olympics are being
very patriotic.
And for me, the Olympics
is not about politics.
JOE ALEXANDER: The mayor is
trying to introduce us as
being anti--Olympics.
But really all we're trying to
do is save our community.
DOLORES JOHN-PHILLIP:
We weren't included.
It's almost like we're
the forgotten people.
IAIN SINCLAIR: It's going to
be completely deranged and
crazy for a period of time.
MALE SPEAKER 5: It's important
because it's the one event
that unites the world.
LEAH BORROMEO: Hang
on a minute.
Who's paying for this?
MALE SPEAKER 6: I don't think
our generation's really fussed
about the Olympics.
MALE SPEAKER 7: I'm really
excited for the
Olympics to be in London.
MALE SPEAKER 8: It's
just Olympics.
It's nothing that special.
[MUSIC - GEORGE EVANS, "IN THE
GOOD OLD SUMMER TIME"]
EDWIN DENIS CLAYTON: My name
is Edwin Denis Clayton.
I'm 83 years old.
And I think since 1960 I've
seen 13 Olympic Games.
My first Games was in 1960,
and what gave me the great
passion to go again was the end
of the Olympic Games, at
the closing ceremony in Rome.
There was a big sign and a big
announcement that said
arrivederci, and we would
meet again in Tokyo
in four years time.
And that brought tears to
my eyes, and I said
yes, I shall be there.
The games came first always.
I wanted to see the one
more and the one
more and the one more.
But no, as I can't get tickets
this time, I can't
actually see it.
Eight years ago, we knew
that the games were
going to be in London.
And I thought well, in eight
years' time, I could well be
in a wheelchair.
And so I thought, well, even in
a wheelchair I could still
get to the London Games.
So that is a big
disappointment.
Although I'm never depressed and
I'm never down hearted, it
just appears to have knocked
off the enthusiasm.
[SOFT PIANO MUSIC]
IAIN SINCLAIR: We're standing
now not really more than a
couple of hundred yards from
the main Olympic site.
And yet you're already dropping
into another world.
A strange mix of decaying
industrial grunge with
elements of the country, with
the wilderness-- the real
wilderness that was untouched.
This was a zone that was
dangerously dirty.
It was where there were
two landfill dumps.
There was a factory making
luminous watch dials.
There was a small nuclear
reactor that belonged to Queen
Mary College.
The tarmac that we're standing
on now is actually being
re-branded as the Olympic
Greenway.
And in reality what
it is is Joseph
Bazalgette's sewage outfall.
So it was a thing that
was functional.
It was carrying the sewage out
of London and therefore
helping to alleviate cholera and
all the diseases that were
making London intolerable with
stinks and smells, and
creating something viable
and useful.
And that is being cosmetically
doctored with tarmac that's
turned it into an airport
runway, or a motorway.
And so in a sense you have the
entire panorama of cultural
and social history visible and
available as a post-industrial
theme park.
MIKE WELLS: One of the things we
discovered at Games Monitor
was that radioactive waste had
been buried in the cesspit of
a house that had previously
stood on our site.
We were living on the estate.
These clowns, the Olympic
Delivery Authority-- the ODA--
came on to the landfill site and
started excavating, taking
no precautions for
the existence
of radioactive waste.
They were excavating for months
before finally, we
don't know why, they called in
radiation protection advisers.
The first day they were
on site, they
started finding stuff.
They had to trace back where
it had been excavated from,
and they actually traced
it back to the
bowl of the main stadium.
And I'm not claiming this site
is so hot that you're gonna
get your testicles fried or
something like that, but there
is a problem.
IAIN SINCLAIR: The interesting
thing about the Lower Lea
Valley was that it
was a borderline.
It was an area for people who
lived in the density of East
London to come into and
escape and explore.
All of it was lost.
All of it was not supported.
All of it drained away in the
promise of creating this brave
new world, which is actually
an extension of an enormous
Australian shopping mall.
Instead of a park for the
people, we've actually created
a toxic wilderness.
BORIS JOHNSON: I have every
confidence that when people
come to London in 2012, they're
going to find a city
that is very different.
It is a city that is changing,
and changing the whole time.
Virtually every single one of
our international sports were
either invented or codified
by the British.
[CHEERS AND JEERS]
BORIS JOHNSON: They were.
And ping pong was invented on
the dining tables of England,
ladies and gentlemen,
in the 19th century.
It was, and it was called
whiff-waff.
MALE SPEAKER 9: Hello.
I'm Boris Johnson.
Come on through to our
whiff-waff party.
[TECHNO MUSIC]
MALE SPEAKER 9: Here we are in
central London for the big
whiff-waff--
pre- Olympics whiff-waff
tournament.
FEMALE SPEAKER 4: I think
it's nice to have
it on our home turf.
It's great to get
everyone here.
But I think that everything
is going to collapse.
The infrastructure, the
transports, I think it's going
to be an utter nightmare.
But I am going to the whiff-waff
event, so I'll have
to stick it out.
MALE SPEAKER 9: I
think humor--
I hope-- and a really, really
shit opening ceremony.
That's my expectation.
FEMALE SPEAKER 4: I think people
that may disagree with
his policies or principles
still, I think, like him for
his sort of hearty guffaw and
his charisma and his color,
his wayward hair, his ridiculous
cycling, and that
he's a little bit different.
BORIS JOHNSON: Our Olympics
will give that East End of
London the huge regenerative
boost that it needs.
LEAH BORROMEO: The kind of
trouble making I've been
involved in with regards to
the Olympic Games has been
getting the truth out, and has
been trying to bust the myths
that LOCOG-- the London
Organizing Committee of the
Olympic Games and the ODA--
the Olympic Development
Authority--
have been trying to put out.
One of the biggest myths that
LOCOG has been trying to sell
about the Olympic games is
that it's going to bring
regeneration to London and
to the rest of Britain.
Regeneration is when preexisting
community remains
in an area.
And you bring in more schools,
you bring better hospitals,
you bring in better
public services.
And you generally make
life smiley.
It's not--
as what's happening in the
London borough of Newham, and
lots of parts of Hackney and
parts of East London which are
most affected--
directly affected by the games,
where people are being
taken from their neighborhood
and then being told to leave
that community, so that
you can then build new
condominiums, built a smacking
new shopping center and bring
in a completely different
economic class to
up the area a bit.
But what happens to all
those families?
They get sent as far as places
like Stoke, or they get sent
to Essex, or they get
sent elsewhere.
But they're--
just basically means
that they're no
longer Newham's problem.
And they're no longer the
problem or the issue.
JOE ALEXANDER: We're very
close to the Olympics.
We've been pretty much in the
building site when it was
being constructed.
And some people have been
complaining of dust-related
illnesses and stuff like that.
Of course the council
ignored that.
[CONSTRUCTION NOISES]
DOLORES JOHN-PHILLIP: We've put
up with all the noise, all
the dirt, all the grime.
And nobody has ever said to
us, hey, you can have
subsidized tickets, or it would
be nice for you to come
and visit, seeing as it's
right on your doorstep.
Absolutely nothing,
no mention of us.
It's almost like we
just don't exist.
And it's sad, really, because
it's right on your doorstep,
and you should be able to enjoy
it and be part of it,
but we're not.
JOE ALEXANDER: We're up
in Denison Point--
I think it's floor 17 or 18--
and the council have
leased the top five
floors to the BBC.
Initially they said that the
blocks had asbestos in, so
they're not fit for purpose.
It's not safe.
But it's safe enough to
build media suites.
Community's been dispersed,
you know?
And this is why they did it.
They wanted the BBC, wanted to
have these lovely views and
sing praise to the Olympics.
Which is probably not a bad
thing except when you have to
factor in that just down here
you see all these houses and
all these people are going to be
kicked out of their homes.
And many of them have lived
there for 40 plus years.
This community's nearly
half a century old.
Lately gentrification--
especially when it comes
to regeneration--
is about wholesale land grab.
About moving communities away
from where their homes and
where they're used to, and
effectively just dismantling.
It's like social cleansing.
I think what the Olympics does
is it speeds the process up.
I think it was already
happening, but the Olympics
has given it an extra boost.
And it's helped it to kind of
like a move lot quicker.
DOLORES JOHN-PHILLIP: Because
it's like now, oh, because of
the Olympics we're regenerating,
you know, we're
doing up East London.
Always been a very poor borough,
and so forth, and
they're throwing money into it
as if to say, oh look what
we're doing for you.
No, they're not doing it for
us, the people like me.
It's not for us, because they
don't want us here.