THOM DEVITA: This one
is not for sale.
MALE SPEAKER: Oh, OK.
THOM DEVITA: Isn't that
a great photo?
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
THOM DEVITA: The black
and white one.
No gloves, ink, and blood.
MALE SPEAKER: When did you
start wearing gloves?
THOM DEVITA: I kept thinking
I should be wearing gloves.
And one day, a girl who was
working for Ed came up.
And she looked in
my little room--
I had customers outside--
and she looks in, and she
says aloud, no gloves?
I sent Fred out for
a box of gloves.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
JOHN WYATT: People would come
into the shop with a
preconceived notion.
For example, a lot of the
Hispanic men wanted Jesus
Christ or the Madonna.
And Tom felt like tattooing
something Japanese.
And he would invariably talk
them into, instead of Christ,
a Japanese demon head, or
instead of Madonna, a woman
that looked like a hooker.
I met Thom in about '73, '74.
And I went into this apartment
around Washington Square Park.
Ed was tattooing a Kirin on
the back of Thom's thigh.
And I was just blown away.
I never saw anybody like Thom.
Here's a man with a whole
body suit, practically.
And I thought, I'm going to have
to photograph this guy.
He's so interesting.
And I said, can I have
your phone number?
And he said, yes,
it's H-E-V-T--
they were all letters.
He didn't think in
terms of numbers.
I felt that Thom was
not acting strange.
I felt that's truly who
he was, that he
was somewhat primitive.
That he's lived in sort of an
isolated way and wasn't part
of the mainstream and didn't
care about that.
One of the entertainment
qualities to hanging around
the shop was you never knew
what was going to happen.
There was a character that
showed up with a peace pipe
claiming to be an American
Indian, although I think he
was a Latino.
There were just so many
different characters there
that it was like going to a
Fellini movie every time you
went there.
ED HARDY: Thom had the weirdest
assortment of people
around there.
His crew was just very
eccentric like
New York street life.
It's like when you read
Burroughs in the stories when
people like Junkie and some of
those guys are rolling lushes
in Times Square.
It's just a complete old school,
New York underworld.
JOHN WYATT: It was a diversity
of customers.
Later on he had Chinese gang
members coming to him.
Customers would be coming in and
out all day, all the time.
So, I was there.
And they would usually call from
a payphone, say they were
in the area.
And then usually if Fred Klausen
was there, he would go
down the three flights
to answer the door.
Fred Klausen was a
friend of Tom's.
And he was there almost
all of the time.
He drew a lot of the
flash that Tom had.
He was a pretty good artist.
NICK BUBASH: And that allowed
Thom the time
to just do the tattooing.
I remember he paid Freddy $30 a
day, because he would always
say I'm doing this
one for Freddy.
I do one a day for Fred.
ED HARDY: He was just like
Tom's right-hand guy and
gopher and did a lot of
stuff for him and
drew some of the flash.
He was just around.
I mean, it was like everything
in deVita's, it was just
really amorphous.
THOM DEVITA: They always used
to say, I was the only
tattooer with a butler.
That was Fred.
NICK BUBASH: He answered
the door.
He was very soft-spoken.
THOM DEVITA: And Bink saw his
first tattoo on Fred, which
was my tattooing.
It's when he was a little kid.
And that was the first
tattoos he ever saw.
NICK BUBASH: Oh, because Binks
lived near where Fred lived.
ROBERT RYAN: He grew up in the
town I grew up in, Point
Pleasant, in New Jersey.
I might have been 10
years old in the
supermarket with my mother.
And I saw this really
dynamic person.
He had this really long beard
and tattoos all over his arms.
So, the first tattoos I really
saw, the first heavily
tattooed person I saw
were deVita tattoos.
And later on, I met Fred.
I got to see the tattoos that
blew my mind when I
was 10 years old.
I got to see in person.
So cool, and so strong,
and so personal.
NICK BUBASH: I think Binks
inherited all of Fred's stuff,
all of his journals.
THOM DEVITA: Oh, yeah.
He used to write journals.
NICK BUBASH: Freddy
kept journals, I
guess piles of them.
THOM DEVITA: And then he died.
And he gave them all to
Binks before he died.
ROBERT RYAN: Before he passed
away, he left me his whole
collection of journals.
So, there's actually hundreds
of them, which pretty much
span the course of 1966
to about 1994.
It's just cool to really get--
you know, a guy that I knew
pretty well, to really see where
he was at when he was my
age and younger, it's
really cool.
And it's weird that we were kind
of these kindred spirits.
It's strange.
I go through here.
A lot of these notebooks could
have been mine, reading some
of the writings and some of the
stuff that he collected.
Here's a good Fred
one I could read.
"I look up to no man in
adoration as I did before.
Now I know I am as strong or
stronger than my past Gods.
I meet them as equals where it
makes no difference if I don't
meet them at all.
I have my own contentment
to keep me company.
The world opens up in front of
me without any effort on my
part."
They're really, really a great
insight onto Freddy's
personality, and also the time
that Thom and Fred were
hanging out in New York.
I don't think that they were
necessarily part of a scene.
But they were kind
of the scene.
And the whole Eastern Buddhism
thing that was kind of
catching on in New York
City at the time, they
were there for that.
You talk to Thom about it, and
I don't think he was as into
it as Freddy was.
But I think that it was more
Thom was friends with Tyler,
and also his neighbor.
Tyler was an anarchist that
had started his own church
down in the Lower East Side.
He would do tattoos according to
the phases of the moon and
certain lunar holidays.
He was definitely a
far out character.
ED HARDY: My friend Vale did an
interview with him in one
of those "Tattootime's."
He has this
whole phalanstery thing.
And it was based on a
combination of mainly
esoteric, Tibetan-Buddhism,
[INAUDIBLE]
stuff, and astrology.
And he did these
insane things.
He was a phenomenal, phenomenal
person, really just
out there, really brilliant,
a real genius.
NICK BUBASH: When you became
a member of the Uranian
Phalanstery, you went
downstairs.
Dick took your photograph
with a Polaroid.
He wrote your name
on it backwards.
In other words, I
was Kcin Hsabub.
And then he tacked it on the
wall in the phalanstery, which
was an old synagogue.
Talk about bizarre.
This Reverend Dick did this.
This is a mantra.
That's "Om Mani Padme Hum." This
is from a gravestone, a
Tibetan gravestone.
Then the rest of these
things are deVita's.
All this stuff, all these tribal
things he put on in the
early '70s.
THOM DEVITA: I'm the first
to do the heavy,
what they call, tribal.
I'm the first to do that.
NICK BUBASH: This thing
here he found--
it was a carving on a
stone that he found
on the ground somewhere.
And he brought it home.
And he rubbed it with
ink and pressed it
on a piece of paper.
And he got this design
out of it, this
geometrical design here.
And then he tattooed it on me.
ED HARDY: He did
a great thing.
He put on a lot of elbows that
was off some kind of thing on
the street.
And it was just like, well,
that's a good design.
That's a good design.
It was so important.
That's why in a lot of ways,
like I say, when I went in his
place, it the first time it
really lit my head up.
Because I got so deep
into tattooing.
And it took a long time to break
it through, and go, oh,
these other things could
be great tattoos, too.
And deVita was like the past
master of that stuff.
It was mainly like Zuni things,
Rainbird designs and
stuff, like black
graphic designs.
Cliff was on that big and really
realized how great it
could look.
THOM DEVITA: He was a better
salesman than I was.
ROBERT RYAN: But people could
argue that you were the first
person to do tribal tattooing
in the United States.
THOM DEVITA: Yeah, but if they
were to ask me 10, 20 years
ago, I would have said
it was Cliff.
ROBERT RYAN: But Cliff would
have said it was you.
THOM DEVITA: But Cliff said it
was me, and I believe him.
Yeah, that's Pueblo
Indian design.
SCOTT HARRISON: Was that
on somebody's arm?
THOM DEVITA: What?
SCOTT HARRISON: This design?
THOM DEVITA: Ah, yes.
You looked at my work.
SCOTT HARRISON: A lot, a lot.
THOM DEVITA: It can't be a lot,
because I'm not in that
many magazines.
Yes.
SCOTT HARRISON: He was one of
the first American tattoo
artists to do large-scale
tribal work at all.
It was like him and Cliff Raven
were some of the first.
And he was doing those big
Rainbird patterns that you can
see in that article.
I'd seen him in the white
"Tattootime," the art from the
heart issue.
In the article, Ed made a point
of really focusing on
how Thom's shop and his
environment that he created
was really an organic
part of New York.
The Lower East Side at that
time was, obviously, this
super dense, sensory overload,
kind of place with graffiti,
and all sorts of people
hanging out
with stuff going on.
And how his shop was kind of a
nexus for all these social
forces that were in New York and
congregated there and met
in this weird somewhat surreal
environment that Thom had
created that could contain it
and let it flow through.
NICK BUBASH: Absolutely, he
was blown away by the fact
that Thom had filtered his own
life experience through these
tattoo designs, in a sense, and
turned them into a whole
different vision.
He was a visionary.
But people generally did not
come by, I don't think, until
much later.
They didn't start to appreciate
what he had done
and what he was doing until
much, much later.
I mean, years and years later.
He never traveled much.
Thom stayed put, pretty much.
Occasionally, he would go out
to California to visit Ed.
Occasionally, he would
go to Hawaii.
I mean, you could count
them on three fingers.
But then later on in life,
he started going to the
conventions.
Pretty much after he retired
from tattooing, that's when he
started going to these places.
Because then he would go and
sell his art work is what he
was doing when he wasn't
tattooing anymore.
He needed to make an income
somehow, and that's how.
And he would do a little
bit of tattooing.
But he had gotten married.
And Jenny took a job with IBM.
So, they uprooted everything.
And he figured he would just
open up a tattoo shop there.
In fact, he did open
up a tattoo shop.
He opened up a shop in
Newburgh when he
was 60 years old.
But then nobody knew where
the hell he was anymore.
But there was no business
to support the shop.
He couldn't do it.
I said, you're opening
up a tattoo shop.
You're 60 years old.
He said, yeah, and I'm coming
back again when I'm 80.
I remember him saying that.
THOM DEVITA: I'll show these
guys some of my new flash.
NICK BUBASH: Yeah, you want to
see some of his new stuff?
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah,
I would love to.
THOM DEVITA: My last flash.
This is a rubbing from
a tattoo stencil.
And this is meant to be put
on a chest this way.
NICK BUBASH: I love the new
black paintings that he's
doing, the black paintings with
the colored drawings,
colored rubbings, and
stuff like that.
Boy, they're just super,
really beautiful stuff.
THOM DEVITA: That's a beauty.
And All the outline is rubbing
and then it's filled in.
NICK BUBASH: He takes the filler
out of those notebooks,
like the black piece of paper so
you can put a piece of art
on both sides of it.
And he takes that piece
of paper out.
It's kind of thin and black.
And that's the thinness
he needs to get a good
rubbing off of it.
He wanted me to send
all the fillers
out of all my notebooks.
I said I'm not going to do
it, forget about it.
THOM DEVITA: I call these
the creative rubbings.
MALE SPEAKER: Creative
rubbings?
THOM DEVITA: Yeah, from
tattoo stencils.
ROBERT RYAN: So, when you first
started making rubbings,
Thom, was it from when people
would share designs with you?
THOM DEVITA: Yeah.
ROBERT RYAN: Before
copy machines or
anything like that?
THOM DEVITA: Right.
SCOTT HARRISON: I was
getting rubbings of
all his acetate stencils.
When I was doing that, he saw
that, and he did a rubbing.
He added--
I think it was either a Virgin
Mary or a Jesus--
he added a Koi.
He just rubbed the
Koi right on top.
And that's when the stencil
rubbing thing started.
And so then he started doing
a lot of that on paper.
And he showed it
to Nick and Ed.
And then they were
like, oh, wow.
I think Ed said, there it was.
It was in front of our faces
all these years.
And he just brought it out,
like you could do that.
Make these crazy things
with the stencils.
ROBERT RYAN: That's the beauty
of Thom deVita is that he
doesn't change.
He's doing what he does.
He's making deVita artwork
every day.
And the trends come and go.
And he's still doing
what he does.
He's kind of like--
I don't want to offend him,
because I know his religious
beliefs-- but he's like the
Buddha of tattooing to me.
He's just there doing
his thing every day
with it, not affected.
MALE SPEAKER: You've got
a lot of artwork.
THOM DEVITA: Some days
I don't do anything.
Some would say it gets out of
hand that I work everyday.
I'm always working just so I got
40 years of work behind me
with no outlet.
So, it looks like I just
recently done it, because I
keep repeating myself.
The tattooers, they're
into prints.
I think prints are the thing.
A lot of people are like that.
They got them fooled
with prints.
Not only tattooers, but all the
galleries, they sell prints.
When I do sell a print, if it's
a print, I work on top of
it, disregard that the
print is there.
It's what I do that's
important.
ED HARDY: In terms of the art,
I mean, none of us were
selling any art.
None of us were doing--
we were just all tattooing.
And, of course, I was totally
open to the idea of it,
because I came out of a
fine art background.
Then when we put that show
together in Chicago, that "Eye
Tattooed America," I thought
that would really do it.
The show got a lot
of attention.
The show traveled.
NICK BUBASH: And it was a show
of primarily tattoo artists
who are also fine artists.
So, I don't know how many people
were in the show, like
30 people maybe or something
like that.
It was quite a few people.
SCOTT HARRISON: It was one of
the first big art shows of
tattoo art.
At that time, even if you
weren't very selective,
finding tattooers who were going
to do some art to be in
a gallery show would have
been difficult.
NICK BUBASH: Thom had
a hell of a show.
SCOTT HARRISON: And the "Eye
Tattooed America" show, I
mean, it was unbelievable.
It was this giant wall
of [INAUDIBLE].
I mean, he sent 300 pieces.
So, he sent his whole shop.
The shop is this organic
part of his
aesthetic, or his house.
I mean, what is less like
deVita's aesthetic than a
piece of art floating
symmetrically in a white space?
I mean, that's the opposite
of what he does.
So, I mean, obviously,
he stole the show.
ED HARDY: It was a really
beautiful show.
Just his perceptions are
so completely unique.
And that's, all these years,
we've been trying to get the
high art world to
recognize him.
And he's just so out there.
And if people didn't understand
the vocabulary of
tattooing and the cultural
context of tattooing, they
just didn't know where
to place it.
They didn't know what
to do with it.
I thought deVita would
make a big hit there.
But these art people
would come in.
And they just didn't
get deVita's stuff.
NICK BUBASH: No,
you know what?
I never expect anything.
I think by that point, I had
already learned not to expect
anything, you know?
JOHN WYATT: This is one of my
favorite pieces by Thom.
The Koi, the colors in it, the
brush strokes, I think, are
just beautiful.
But I've shown his work
to painter friends,
and they were astounded.
They're saying, who
is this guy?
He's a genius.
Look at these brush strokes.
Here's a guy that doesn't have
an art education and is just
going by intuition.
And it's genius.
He's really under-appreciated.
He really should be shown
in a major gallery.
THOM DEVITA: Did I show you
these yet, these landscapes?
NICK BUBASH: These
little vignettes.
THOM DEVITA: Do you want
to see 100 of them?
MALE SPEAKER: Sure.
THOM DEVITA: Come here.
NICK BUBASH: Wow,
look at them.
It's beautiful.
Can you imagine how beautiful
these would be if they were
all lined up, like
all in one--
THOM DEVITA: Yeah, going
down the slope of the--
NICK BUBASH: Of the
Guggenheim.
Yeah, down the Guggenheim.
One right after another.
No, I don't think he fits in.
And I think that's probably why
he should be recognized.
JOHN WYATT: I don't know what
label anybody could put on it.
But it's very different than
what I've ever seen before.
THOM DEVITA: This is
one of my boxes.
The box is a fruit box
from the supermarket.
Oh, I had this in the
library art show.
SCOTT HARRISON: In Newburgh?
THOM DEVITA: In Newburgh.
I've been showing there
for about 10 years.
And I've won about three
or four ribbons.
JOHN WYATT: We all want to see
him somewhere that he gets the
fame that we feel he deserves,
and the recognition, and the
appreciation.
But I think he might be
content the way it is.
SCOTT HARRISON: First of
all, he's 80 years old.
How much do you want an
80-year-old man to work and
hustle and try and start at the
bottom of the art game?
I mean, that's absurd.
He does it because that's
what he does.
He is a true artist.
He makes it if no
one looks at it.
We didn't get to the full
resume of his art shows.
Because some of the art shows
that he participates
in have been at--
I think it was called the
Newburgh Arts Festival, where
they have the amateur
art shows.
And he would go.
And he would set up
his little table.
And he would have exactly what
you see in his house, or
whatever, these super
interesting,
rough montage things.
And he would just sit there with
the old lady who did the
color-by-numbers painting
and whatever.
He would just sit there.
THOM DEVITA: The show's
started already.
I wanted to count how
many people come in.
So, we had to go, and
they still come in.
FEMALE SPEAKER: This
is so cool.
So, you're ready?
THOM DEVITA: Yes.
FEMALE SPEAKER: To
give your spiel?
THOM DEVITA: What spiel?
FEMALE SPEAKER: The
history of Thom.
THOM DEVITA: To who?
FEMALE SPEAKER: To everybody.
So, this is you here
doing this?
THOM DEVITA: Yeah.
CAROLINE: What is your name?
THOM DEVITA: deVita.
CAROLINE: Steve, mine's
Caroline.
And you live in Newburgh?
THOM DEVITA: Yes, my
name is deVita.
MALE SPEAKER: deVita.
CAROLINE: deVita.
OK, what's your first name?
THOM DEVITA: Thom.
CAROLINE: Thom deVita.
MALE SPEAKER: I think people
have been waiting for you to
come down from the hill.
SCOTT HARRISON: I've been
trying to get people to
appreciate Thom for so long.
And now it's like when those
tattooers came in yesterday
and were like, oh, just
wanted you to know we
really respect you.
It just touched me.
And it was also like, where the
fuck have you guys been?
MALE TATTOOER: How you
doing, Mr. deVita?
It's an honor to meet you.
THOM DEVITA: Thanks.
MALE TATTOOER: Yeah,
definitely.
I've been wanting to come and
visit you for awhile.
So, it's pretty exciting.
THOM DEVITA: Where's your
shop in [INAUDIBLE]
Falls?
MALE TATTOOER: Right
on Main Street.
It's called Graceland Tattoo.
THOM DEVITA: Yeah, we pass
by there sometimes.
See, if I was walking, I would
walk by a tattoo shop.
Because I usually don't
go into them.
Because nobody knows who I am.
MALE TATTOOER: We do.
THOM DEVITA: I doubt it.
If I had walked in, you would
have known who I was?
MALE TATTOOER: Oh,
I would have.
FEMALE SPEAKER: He would know.
MALE TATTOOER: Well, I guess
you'd be surprised at how many
of us know you and
look up to you.
I know I do.
SCOTT HARRISON: I just want
Thom to be happy.
And I don't think that--
I mean, I'm sure he'd be happy
to have a museum show.
But he's a very grounded guy.
It would just be another event
in his week if he had a museum
show, I think.
I would like for people to keep
his mind entertained a
little bit.
THOM DEVITA: Six months later
they'd come back and
want to cover me.
SCOTT HARRISON: I would like
to see Thom engaged in the
tattoo world as much as he
would like to be and have
people who respect him to talk
to him and just give him some
kind of integration
into the world.
THOM DEVITA: Here you go.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Beautiful.
I love it.
Thank you.
THOM DEVITA: All right,
thank you.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Thank you.
THOM DEVITA: This is taking
longer than I thought.
SCOTT HARRISON: Because your
method is very slow, Thom.
THOM DEVITA: I thought
it would be one hour.
I'm tired.
SCOTT HARRISON: You're tired,
it hasn't started yet.
THOM DEVITA: Put ghost cat.
SCOTT HARRISON: You
got nine hours.
THOM DEVITA: Here.
SCOTT HARRISON: This one?
Where are we going?
THOM DEVITA: Why you got
to keep asking me?
Just put them up.
SCOTT HARRISON: Because as soon
as I do it under my own
direction, you're going
to make me take it
down and move it.
THOM DEVITA: He don't want
to make any decisions.
MALE SPEAKER: I think he
knows the consequences.
SCOTT HARRISON: I'm not getting
paid managerial salary.
I'm just a day laborer.