so they sent the panic it throughout
this talbot when in fact politico has an
article titled paul panic seizes i waste
abolition
quotes inside article ours so damning
for what this that was friend
thinks of outsiders like ron paul one
actually overturn their apple cart
uh... so they talk to one republican
after another look at these closures
becky beach
along tomorrow republican who helped
president
george h_i_v_ bush and george w_ bush
she says
it would make the caucuses mostly
irrelevant if not entirely irrelevant if
all winners
she continues you would have a very
damaging effect
because i don't think he could be
elected president i'm booked iowa and
national public unease
wouldn't think he represents the will of
the voters
so not only does iowa caucus become
irrelevant iran paul wins
but she says
that if he wins it doesn't even
represent
feelings but the real milo bombs let
alone the nationalist
but how can i represent them
phillies iowa voters every trust voted
and he came in number one
the establishment is so deathly afraid
of ron paul
that anytime that he is
got any advantage they want to minimize
it
in obliterated
firstly was coming in
atherton some of these uh... polls is
out there like a high just a friendly
guy comes unplugged secular make
anything of it second out doesn't count
as ron paul is a lot of active
supporters on the ground when although i
had a lot of actors words on another
level off at all bob i had to absorb
llama
broad walton irrelevant rotate
i tell you as a hundred times over
totally disagree with the ron paul on at
least half of those issues
on social security on the income tax i'm
getting really part of education i don't
agree with them
but this is a right
in telugu i_d_ even if he wins he will
be comes in number one
not only is it dot calvo isn't although
on board i will cut is becoming relevant
but that the bhosale just bali
but do you need
it's absurd but it goes on such as one
person
his house speaker cried paulson
uh... i don't think any candidate for
burning the process in that fashion
hopes the caucuses
in anyway referring to ron paul's
fervent supporters on the ground
but that's about all caucuses about
people are talking about a candidate who
shot the caucuses
we've only been doing this for her
decades everybody knows or that's what a
caucuses
anytime anybody else wins
they'd all look at that they've got a
real momentum then side people on the
net
all hallways in alabama won the primary
was because he does so well in iowa
and the national presently huge stake
out a bit and i think you're right to
now when rob was about two and i'm now
it's pervert in the process
to actually win the caucus
crocs are mind-blowing so uh... politico
summarized by the way a what is that new
short version of what the republican to
do ron paul wins ignore him anyway
if he was losing then are tempted these
one day you know right
did just don't want him to drop off our
on call
this is the interest in the same corrupt
politics
that has been going on in washington
robert that's why this bothers me is
that a panic disease not to take away
their money for their that they're black
money they like what while we get with a
cold or money being corrupt rotblat
let's do it
so here is that
governor terry branstad the governor of
iowa quote
people had a look at who comes in second
and who comes in third
alter christ sake
and he continues government-run
seagram's metro because in a strong
second it definitely helps im going to
new hampshire and other states
what we do it that way when ron paul was
coming a second or third being the
center of the rosy relevant iran balls
first know that what's relevant is
coming second author
this is a joke by his i've never seen a
joke this it grotesque
wages and this combo
who could possibly say who wins is
irrelevant the most important thing is
to go that far
piece we work
this gifted death of ron paul
uh... finally like in the nineteen th
paragraph of this political article
by fire exit quote
this is doctor paul's hands on the most
authentic principal came in the race
might go quietly philip
paul's campaign chairman joseph it
outside of can appalls campaign there's
not one positive things that about the
leading candidate in iowa from the
entire party okay
uh... when they ask doug rosalie
republican lawyer and brent said advisor
uh... how uh... severe old
warned it would be appalled
one he said it would be quote
a moral wound
look at how much this that was really
scared to death of ron paul
they're like old day and the doctors
coming he's gonna throw throw over
terrible crime said no don't you don't
get to take money anymore
and is due to the beating of your
daughters
reading these quotes makes me wanna
campaign for ron paul
totally thoroughly
and that we disagree with them i'm
probably more than fifty percent
of his issues
here's at ten oh one he had not done yet
i love this one
sam clovis
he he's a local talk shows he says i
think up all win would be devastating
for the state of iowa and the caucus
process
now you ready for who her clothes and
supporting us that
rick sent or
now that's
you get that
rick sendo chance of winning the overall
the national uh... into eric candidacy
for the republicans insofar lower than
ron paul's
so if they are excuse was all rob hall
can win over on national race for the
republicans that's why we think it would
hurt the iowa caucuses and make them
irrelevant if you want i will talk this
well how could you possibly say
that every state or wins it'll be better
now would be worth some of that logic
because it isn't about ron paul
effect on the highway caucuses it's
about is if
endemic corruption
but they're all pumped up
though i don't know i don't think i
think your boss doctor ballpark village
what went down that reject was ralph
corrupts sellout all patients
mexicano people going
repairing that running autos i think i
think it is not even god don't do it to
us doctor weir u_n_ aid
while you covering the process by weight
critical finally conserve activists
hammer scott
she's bypassed a co-chair right so she's
got it
force in this race but nonetheless
another quote just like the others i
think your pervasiveness
to see the process
hijacked
would be a concern for those who
consider the pot or we have
are being first-in-the-nation
so when michelle bachman was leading the
repair polls in iowa
it was the greatest thing in the world
and of course she deserved it
but if ron paul wins he is hijacked the
prize process
and still not quite there but the more i
read this stuff the more i think
uh... you know what
maybe some bigger chances with tucker on
for
because of this ellison is this deathly
afraid of them he's certainly must be
doing something right