MIKE HUTTLESTONE: You carry on.
BEN EBBRELL: So here,
we've got 3/4 bottle
of pomegranate juice.
Reduce down in a pan with a
couple of tablespoons of sugar
until it becomes really,
really syrupy and sweet.
BARRY TAYLOR: Mike, have
you done this before?
BEN EBBRELL: Apply and smear.
MIKE HUTTLESTONE: There you go.
Not bad.
BEN EBBRELL: Job done.
Now, for the actual cocktail--
I'll leave that to one side.
Baz, 50-50 pomegranate juice.
Why?
Because it's tropical and
every Valentine's drink
needs to be pink-- so 50-50.
BARRY TAYLOR: Of
course, it has to be.
How much?
BEN EBBRELL: 50-50,
so that's fine.
Equal measure of
ginger ale, and that's
there for the fiery kick.
MIKE HUTTLESTONE: Yeah.
Fiery passion-- also
important to a relationship.
BARRY TAYLOR: What are
you getting at, Mike?
MIKE HUTTLESTONE: I'm
talking like I'm an expert.
[LAUGHTER]
BEN EBBRELL: It's all
about balancing flavors.
There we go.
And then perhaps a
little bit of a cliche,
but we've got to pop a cork.
There we go.
MIKE HUTTLESTONE: Don't
aim it towards me.
BARRY TAYLOR: [INAUDIBLE]
impress the date by--
BEN EBBRELL: And we've
crushed up some ice.
Our ginger and pomegranate
in over the ice.
BARRY TAYLOR: Look
how pretty that is.
MIKE HUTTLESTONE: Mm-hmm.
BEN EBBRELL: And then
finish it with the fizz.
BARRY TAYLOR: Ben, did you
make this one for yourself
rather than your date?
MIKE HUTTLESTONE:
This is what he's
going to be drinking by
himself on Valentine's night.
BEN EBBRELL: Beautiful.
Every Valentine loves
a perfume fragrance.
BARRY TAYLOR: Indeed.
BEN EBBRELL: So here,
we've got some basil.
It might sound weird.
MIKE HUTTLESTONE: Yeah.
BARRY TAYLOR: A little bit.
BEN EBBRELL: So basil with
ginger, absolutely beautiful.
That can go in there.
Top it right up now
those bubbles have died.
BARRY TAYLOR: Be generous.
BEN EBBRELL: And finish
it with a pincher
berry, or a physalis fruit.
And that just sits
on top of there.
MIKE HUTTLESTONE: Nice.
BEN EBBRELL: Basil, pincher
berry, pomegranate, ginger,
champagne-- that's
our YouTube Crush
cocktail for your
Valentine sorted.
BARRY TAYLOR: Look.
How easy is that?
MIKE HUTTLESTONE: But
if you missed any of it,
you can check out the full
recipe in the description box
below.
BEN EBBRELL: Here.
Have a taste.
I'll crack on, make some more.
BARRY TAYLOR: Boomtown!
[MUSIC PLAYING]