n the last lecture we were talking about some
mathematical models for facility location.
Today we are going to be talking about the
problem of layout planning. If you recall,
the hierarchy of location problems is the
next important problem where the objective
is to determine the related positioning of
different departments. In this lecture we
look at the basic issues that are involved
in the layout planning exercise. We shall
look at a generic procedure known as systematic
layout planning to develop a layout of a plant.
What are the objectives in plant layout? When
you develop a layout for a manufacturing plant,
what are the typical objectives?
There could be many objectives some of them
are listed on this slide for instance one
objective could be to minimize the investment
and equipment. Somebody might say how layout
will influence the investment in equipment?
Obviously if you do not duplicate equipment
and you have a streamline layout then you
could minimize the investment and equipment.
The layout has considerable effect on the
investment in equipment. It also helps you
to minimize the overall production time. You
can utilize the existing space most effectively
with proper layout. A proper layout should
provide for employee convenience safety and
comfort. You should try to maintain flexibility
of arrangement. Layout generally tries to
minimize the material handling cost. It also
tries to minimize the variation in types of
material handling equipment for instance a
good layout could try to standardize the kind
of material handling equipment that it uses,
for instance you do not expect forklift trolleys
of very different sizes to operate in the
same shop floor, you could expect standardize
equipment. Generally the plant layout could
facilitate the manufacturing process and it
could also facilitate the organizational structure,
because what could happen is that you are
trying to place different kinds of equipment
and trying to segregate different types of
operations. Therefore it will tend to facilitate
the organization structure as well. Let us
have a brief idea about different types of
layouts.
Brightly speaking we can talk about the product
layout, a process layout or mix of these two,
which is called a mixed layout or the layout
by fixed position. Let us see for instance
as to what are the features of each of these
different types of layouts. The product layout
is essentially one where a product enters
the line and one side and you keep on performing
different operations on the product. Finally
finished products come out in the outside.
So, all assembly lines for instance are typically
examples of product layouts. The idea here
is that the layout is dictated by the product.
Whatever operations are required on the product,
they are laid out in either straight line
or in U mode or in serpentine time mode or
in any other mode but the essential thing
are that all the operations are to be performed
on the product or performed in sequence. From
the raw material you ultimately get the final
product. This is the typical feature of a
product layout. In fact when you are talking
about product layouts you tend to generally
resort to products layouts when the volume
of production is large and for instance and
you have a dedicated product, you are not
changing the product design that frequently.
Another kind of layout is a process layout.
Essentially a process layout is something
where you have different departments that
are A B C D E F. Each of these departments
houses machine which are similar in character
though these machines are not identical. For
instance A could be all the lathes. So lathes
with different features are in the lathe shop,
this could be a milling shop, this could be
a grinding shop and so on. Each shop has different
types of machines clubbed together and what
happens is that a particular product depending
upon it is requirement will move from one
department to another to another till finally
the product is produced. The major advantage
of this type of layout is the product variety
that it can handle unlike the product layout
which typically handles the single type of
product. You can make a variety of products
in this particular layout and of course what
will be the major problem here? The major
problem obviously is B is large number of
products moving here and there. So there will
be a lot of confusion in terms of movement.
There will be lot of delays as product weight
and move to different departments therefore
the production time generally tend to be large
in such situations. So you could try to have
the situation where you have both the product
and the process layouts mixed, so it is a
mixed layout. Mixed layout is a very common
layout in industry, for instance what could
happen is if you go to a factory like Maruthi
ute for instance, you could find that the
final product is being produced as an assembly
line. So it is a product layout. But the various
components which go into the product are actually
being produced in a process layout in different
shops. So you invariably have a mixture of
both the product and the process layout in
various organizations. Of course one can also
talk about a cellular layout or a group layout
which is something that is generally suited
to a situation where you have a predictable
variety of products to make and the idea is
that you try to group products into product
families, part into part families and these
individual parts are part family is then subjected
to processing in individual cells. The basic
idea is that in a cell, the processing sequences
are almost uniform, so the modification behind
the cellular layout is that we try to get
advantages of both product layout and process
layouts, that means you get the variety of
the process layout and you try to get the
speeds by this grouping of parts which are
all then processed in various kinds of cell.
Then we talk about layout by fixed position.
In a layout by fixed position what happens
is that the layout is determined by the size
of the product, for instance this is true
for special structures of a ship building
or for assembly of an aircraft depending upon
the type of the aircraft, you have different
machines, different pupil keep coming and
moving. In all these cases what was happening
was that the job was moving and the machines
was stationary here. The job is stationary
and the machines are moving. There is really
not much to choose as far as the layout is
concerned, this is governed by the shape of
the product itself. If you are building a
ship, the shape of the ship it itself will
dictate the layout and machines will come
do the welding operations of the riveting
operations and go back. Then somebody else
will do the painting and this is what it is.
We are looking at this layout design problem.
It is important to note how this problem is
actually affected by other decisions pertaining
to the product, the schedule and the process.
You see that the layout design problem which
we are trying to a address is governed by
the product design, the process design and
the schedule design. The product design means
what you have to make that determines the
layout. How you have to make it means the
process that you have selected for making
the product. So this will term in the various
machines and equipment that you need. Schedule
design which talks about how much you need
to make. So this is essentially a decision
that comes from marketing forecasting of the
man which tells you how much how many pieces
you need per day. The product process and
schedule constitutes the basic information
that you need for layout design. Mind you
it is not only layout design which is linked
to this but these decisions in and sales are
also related to each other. To call the choice
of the product will also determine what process
to take. Choice of the process will also determine
the schedule that you have to follow and so
on. So in the layout design process, we are
here primarily talking about the layout of
process layout. In the layout design process,
you need inputs from the product, the process
and the schedule that is the important thing.
If you try to compare for instance what could
be the features of a product layout in this
category? You find what is the product layout?
Product layout is a situation where the input
is some raw material and it is being processed
in different works station and sequence till
finally the final product comes out here.
So in a situation like this you have smooth
and logical flow lines. You need to have very
small in process inventories because the part
which is processed here will immediately go
to the next machine, so there has to be very
little in process inventory here.
Total production time per unit is short. There
is a reduced material handling because the
parts directly move from one workstation to
the other. So it does not have to be transported
in trolleys and tracks to other departments.
There is little operator skill and the training
is therefore simple production, planning and
control and there is less space for work in
transit and temporary storage. These are some
of the features of a product layout.
Let us look at the process layout. Now what
is our basic concern in this particular session?
A process layout is a collection of departments
A B C D E F which are housed in maybe different
rooms or different buildings. Therefore the
advantages are there is better utilization
of machines, hence fewer machines and needed.
Why this is happening is because here you
have a lathe that is a special purpose lathe.
So all jobs which require processing on that
special purpose lathe will come here and get
the processing done and go away. Whereas if
the same thing was to be done in a product
layout, you will have to duplicate the machine
at whatever operation it came.
If you need a lathe here, after ten operations
you require the same lathe, you duplicate.
So generally, better utilization of machines
and fewer machines are needed in a process
layout. There is a high degree of flexibility
with regard to equipment or manpower allocation
for specific tasks. What this means is if
a job comes to a department of the milling
machine, there is often a choice. It can be
put in either machine 1 or machine 2 or machine
3 because they are all capable of doing the
operation. It can be given to definitive operators
depending upon their skills. You have this
flexibility with regard to both equipment
and manpower allocation for specific tasks.
Comparatively low investment in machine is
required, this follows from one. There is
greater job satisfaction for the operator.
Why is there a greater job satisfaction for
the operator because the operator who is working
in a particular department during the day
handles variety of jobs, different types of
jobs unlike an operator who is working on
a product layout, who could be sitting on
a machine and operating a pedal. So you operate
a pedal maybe 250 times a day and that is
the end it is life.
Here there is greater job satisfaction for
the operator and specialized supervision is
also possible here. Why specialized supervision?
because the supervisor for the lathe section
nearly spent 10 years in the lathe section
and become a supervisor and in our knows the
ins and outs of all the machines which are
there in this particular shop. If you talk
about the product layout on a line there are
different machines manufactured by different
manufactures and having different features.
It is impossible for one particular individual
to be an expert of all those machines. The
kind of supervision that he will be able to
give is only general and not specialized.
However the process layout has some limitations
and we should be aware of those limitations.
Since longer flow lines usually result, material
handling is more expensive. Obviously a part
has to go from here to here. It has the first
weight then somebody has to load it on to
a trolley and then the trolley has to go.
The trolley may weigh in that department;
somebody unloads it and so on.
So longer flow line used result material handling
is more expensive. In fact the general objective
function in designing a layout of this type
is one of the major objectives to minimize
the material handling cost. Production planning
and control systems are more involved in such
systems. Total production time is usually
longer. Large in process inventories take
place because material might be stored up
in different departments without being processed.
Space and capital are tied up by work in processes
and because of the diversity of jobs in specialized
departments, higher grades of skill are required.
This is also another feature because quite
often if you need somebody to operate a grinding
machine, you could at least expect that he
has done an ITI diploma and has put in three
years therefore he can undertake to operate
such machines. All these operators operating
this machine would generally be pupil who
have higher grades of skill unlike an operator
on a product line because on a product line,
if you even select a man from the street,
all you has to do is to press a pedal 250
times and that practice can be given to him
in half a day and therefore training people
and product for operating product layout is
generally much easier whereas here it will
be much more difficult. Let us look at this
chart which is called a P-Q chart and essentially
what we have said is consider a situation
where we have to make a large number of products,
P is the product variety and we arrange these
products in the descending order of the quantity
that you need. What really happens is that
this product is the first one to be made in
large quantity. This product is to be made
in lesser quantity and so on. So we have products
which are arranged in the descending order
of the air quantity. Now this chart which
was suggested by Muether, gives an idea of
the situation under which you should use different
types layouts. For instance what you said
is once you got these products lined like
these, the products which are here, that means
for products for which the varieties low but
the quantities are high, those are the products
for which product layout is more suitable.
I mean you set up assembly line, and on this
end here where you have a large number of
products but the quantities are electively
smaller. So it is a large amount of variety
but low production quantities. This is the
situation where a process layout is recommended
and in between these two categories when you
have intermediate variety and intermediate
production quantity, generally you could use
a combination layout which is the product
of these. The idea here is only to give you
an overall intuitive feel when a product layout
and process layout should be selected. Product
layout is most appropriate when you are having
less number of products to produce in large
quantities and the process layout is used
when you have large variety but to be produced
in small quantities. This summarizes the features
of product and process layouts in that sense.
Let us now look at the process of designing
a process layout. Normally when you talk about
layout planning we are generally talking only
about process layouts because product layout
is generally fixed by the sequence of operation.
So, there is nothing much to design except
to ensure that you have the space to layout
those machines.
There is a procedure which is called systematic
layout planning SLP. SLP procedure of Muether
was proposed way back in 1961 where we gave
a general framework for how these process
layouts are to be designed. You might wonder
as to why a procedure developed so long ago
is still being talk about. You talk about
something when it is still useful. The zero
invented so many years ago is still useful.
But the point here is that the systematic
layout planning procedure of Muether has suddenly
become important because this has now become
the basis for many of the computerized layout
planning algorithms which are available. In
the next class we shall be talking about some
computerized layout planning procedures. Those
procedures are actually base their inputs
and operations on the SLP procedure. We look
at the SLP procedure in this class to understand
what all is required. The first in that required
is to input data and activities. What is the
kind of data or activity that you have to
input for this particular problem?
There are three kinds of data that you need
to input, the product data, the process data
and the scheduled data. The input to the process
of planning a process layout is essentially
inputting this kind of data about the product
the process and schedule and from this input
data the first step that is done is to identify
the flow of material. The second step is to
identify the activity relationship based on
step one and step two. We develop what is
called a relationship diagram and then this
relationship diagram is converted into what
is called as space relationship diagram. In
order to develop the space relationship diagram,
you have to compute in step 4, the space required,
match it with the space available, that means
if you find that the space required is 4000
square feet you must make sure that 4000 square
feet of space is available. So it is just
to check in that direction and then you develop
the space relationship diagram in step six.
This space relationship diagram is then subjected
to modifying considerations and practical
limitations which you may not have considered
in the entire process so for. On the basis
of space to develop the layout alternatives,
you evaluate these alternatives and pickup
the best layout alternative that you have.
So this is the brad framework and it is a
very systematic framework for a problem like
designing a layout. You can see that you can
divide this framework into three different
phases. Up to here is the phase of analysis,
up to step five is the phase of analysis,
where your analyzing your data, finding out
the flow of material activity relationships,
depending upon the activity relationship diagram,
the space required and the space available.
Once the analysis part is over you search
for the solutions. So from the space relationship
diagram, you are developing layout alternatives,
so you are searching for alternatives solution
and then once you have searched you have developed
these solutions, you have to identify which
is the best so it is the selection of the
solution. Search followed by selection, preceded
by analysis is the general order of this particular
algorithm. The one reason why it is popular
is that it provides a framework for intensive
exactly what is to be done. When you are developing
computer program you must tell the computer
exactly what is to be done and that is why
this framework has been used in layout planning
exercise. This is the SLP procedure of muether.
We will try to illustrate this procedure to
a sample problem so that you get an idea of
what exact or how the layout operations can
be done. Just to give you a feel if we are
to organize production as a product layout
essentially what it means is that you have
to start from the raw materials stage.
You have different types of products. You
go to the saw department, you go to the milling
department, you come to inspection one and
then do this operation here and then final
operation here and you come out and similarly
what we are trying to say is every departments
which are laid out core also be laid out so
that you are trying to facilitate a product
layout for three different product. Now we
in this particular scheme of things have essentially
used these three symbols.
The circle represents an operation being done
like machining operation or mettle removal
or grinding whatever a square represents and
inspection and a inverted triangle of this
nature represents storage. This is a convenient
way of representing the types of operations
which are required here. Let us assume that
we have a process layout for the same thing,
so what we have is, we have these different
departments, raw materials, storage, saw department,
where saw is done of the material, the lathe
department, the drilling department, the milling
department, the inspection the packing and
finish goods and here again we have different
products which we try to move. So these products
move according to their needs. There is a
lot of criss crossing so typically this is
the kind of thing it happens in a process
layout.
These crosses I think are supposed to be the
centralized of these individual departments,
if your raw material stored, this is the center.
If this is the one, these are the centers.
We need them later. Let us suppose that we
are trying to work on this particular process
layout and we are maybe trying to evaluate
this process layout. We are trying to find
a better layout by using SLP. We will see
how we can do that. So the operation could
be something like this. This is out input
data for the problem. We are saying essentially
that they are three products A, B and C which
we want to manufacture and the processing
sequence of these products is this first goes
to saw, then mill then inspect then turn,
then mill, then drill then inspect then package
and similarly for this and similarly for this
that means we know for each product the processing
sequenc
We know the information pertaining to the
product, what is the product and how it is
going to be processed? Product and the process
information is available to us for these three
products, then we would also like to know
the schedule information to how much is the
demand for each of these products. What my
happen is that these products may be considerable
in size, this maybe a small costing, this
maybe a much bigger thing, this maybe a smaller
thing and so on.
In order to take care of that aspect we are
simply standardizing the material flow required
in the plant to pallet loads per day, that
means how many trolley loads per day will
be needed? What we are saying is that as far
as product is concerned we required eight
pallet loads per day in terms of production.
This might be something like 160 products
or whatever it is. We are talking in terms
of pallet loads. Similarly B requires 3 pallet
loads which maybe 300 components so whatever
could be different and C could be five pallet
loads per day, so we are using a common unit
for measuring the material handling of these
products throughout the plant. This is essentially
our schedule requirement. Firstly, how many
trolley loads of A, B, C must be produce per
day in the factory? We need information about
the processing the products the processing
and the quantities. This is the input to it.
What we are going to do is we are going to
actually construct what is called a from-to
chart
and from-to chart is actually a convenient
means of reducing a large volume of data into
a workable form.
By inspecting the data displayed in the from-to
chart the layout analyst can identify the
departments having large volumes of movement.
So let us try to do it for our example,
What we find here is let us say we construct
this information, from-to chart is actually
a square matrix. In the matrix we have listed
all the departments, raw materials, saw lathe,
drill mill inspection packaging and finish
goods, and same departments here and so on.
What we are trying to basically find out is
what is the total movement from this to this
so it is a from-to chart it is very much like
a distance chart, which is say what are the
distances from one pair of cities to another
pair of cities? For instance what you find
is everything begins from the raw materials
stage, so you have the total movement which
will take place form raw material to saw.
What you are saying is let us look at this
requirement. This product A will go from raw
material to saw C, will also go from raw material
to saw, but B will go from raw material to
drill, it does not go to saw, so as far as
this is concerned product A and C will make
a movement from raw material to saw and you
can easily find out what is the total movement
of raw materials of product A and C. So A
trolleys are moving and C is five trolley
loads are moving, so 8 + 5 is 13, that how
you get this figure of 13 and similarly for
the other entries in this particular chart.
So it shows that the total movement which
takes place from raw material to saw, 13 daily
they will be 13 trolley loads moving from
raw material to saw and from raw material
to drill 3 will be moving and as far as this
movement is concerned from milling to inspection
16 will be moving and so on. This from- to
charts shows the number of materials handling
trips per day between all the departments.
Now what is the idea? The idea is that those
departments which have a large amount of movement,
especially these departments should be as
close to each other, the layout is possible.
They should be as much as possible, close
to each other and for those departments which
do not have any movement, need not be that
close. So from this from-to chart we can we
can make a common like this. Normally the
from-to chart is used to analyze the flow
in process layouts. The item movement that
occurs over some specified period of time
is totaled for all products and entered in
the from-to chart as shown in the next figure.
What do you like to simply show is this information?
In this figure which is also from-to chart,
the previous chart was total flow or material
handling material flow taking place between
all pairs of departments. This particular
chart is the information pertaining to the
distances between the various departments.
You are asking me about the centers in that
layouts, so if you are now talking about this
layout, we look at the centralized of each
department and find out what is the distance
from the centroid of one department to the
centroid the other departments. On that basis
we can construct a diagram of this nature,
which should show that the raw material to
drill department is 72. Note that the various
distances between all pairs of departments
are listed here. This particular matrix could
be either symmetric but it is not necessary
that it be a symmetric. The distance from
one department to another need not be the
same as the distance from the same department
back to cell if there are unidirectional flows
and so on. If you are permitting all kind
of flows, then this maybe the same. Whatever
be the distances they can be accommodated
and this is the distance matrix, so we have
a flow matrix and we have a distance matrix
which we have constructed. An important thing
to note here is that the distance matrix can
be constructed only if you have a tentative
layout.
So it is for that tentative layout that we
have made the distances, so then what we do
is we multiply the two matrices element by
element. Now we have the total material handling
effect. This is the total loads multiplied
with distance which we had in the previous
matrix. We have two matrices; we multiply
that so this is the total material handling
effect. You will have these entrances here.
We can sum up the rows; you will get 424 which
is the material handling effort. Total material
handling movement from the raw material is
424 units and total material handling movement
to the saw is 208. So this is the to and this
is the from, in terms of total material handling
effort and a zero in a particular column shows
that this is a source and a zero in a particular
row shows that this is the sink, obviously
because what is happening is that everything
flows from the raw materials store. It is
a source, there is nothing coming to it and
the finish goods is last operation. So that
is where you have, and nothing goes out of
it. If you sum up these values, this column
or this row, the total value is 4032. So it
shows that the process layout which we are
at the movement investigating has a total
material handling effort of 4032, this is
significant a development because what have
we done? We have been able to quantify the
material handling movement for a layout and
this is the likely objective function for
that particular layout. We are able to say
that the total material handling effort for
this layout is so much. Clearly we could use
this information to evaluate different layouts.
Plant one, plant two, plant three, each one
we can calculate the distance matrix will
be different the load matrix will be the same.
You will get different material handling figures
which is like the objective function values
and you can choose a particular layout which
in fact has the minimum material handling
effect and in fact this is one of the basic
logic that is provided in the development
of craft which is a computerized relative
allocation of facilities technique which we
can talk about in the next class.
We can plant a layout by following these steps
is something like this. Suppose these are
the departments which are to be placed in
a layout, the foreman office, the conference
room, the parcel post parts, shipment repair
and service area, servile area receiving testing
and general storage, first thing that you
can do is apart from the material handling
effect, we were initially talking about box
number one in the SLP procedure, i.e., development
of the flow of materialism in the various
types. We are not talking about box number
two, where you are trying to develop activity
relationships for these things. What you can
say is for each pair for instance you can
say that as far as repair and service parts
is concerned its proximity two, for instance
the conference room is unimportant, so we
give a U rating here so this is the significant
of the U. You have various ratings. Normally
what we give is we give typically the ratings
A E I O U and X. A means it is absolutely
essential to locate the departments close
to each other for instance, this is A, it
is shows that parts shipment and general storage
is absolutely essential to have them close
to each other so you have an A rating. E means
that is essential but not absolutely essential,
so for instance service area and testing is
essential to have them close to each other.
I is important so for instance here the conference
room in the foreman room is important to have
them close to each other because you can call
them for conference, O ordinary close nesses.
You have an overrating between the repair
and service department and the parcel post
and U is unimportant that they be close to
each other, for instance conference room it
is unimportant that it is close to parcel
post or parts shipment and so on. X means
it is highly undesirable to have these two
departments close to each other. You do not
see that here. What may happen is for instance
you might have a boundary; you might not want
that to be close to your air condition metrology
shop. You can give X rating; it is highly
undesirable to have these things there. What
is really important is given this ratings
for these are giving the general preferences
that you may have for locating certain department
close to each other or not. You accommodate
those priorities that you have in the form
of these ratings, these are called activity
relationships. The numbers are normally given
because a factor say E might, you might have
a number of reasons 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 which you
document.
(Refer Slide Time: 43:18)
‘Might’ refers to for what reason we identify
E. When you are documenting this, the numbers
are also clear here.
We talk about these ratings:
Absolutely essential
Especially important
Important
Ordinary closeness OK
unimportant
and X is undesirable.
When you are giving any rating it could be
for various reasons for which you get a code
like flow of materials, ease of supervision,
common personnel, and contact necessary and
convenience or something else. When you give
a rating you might see whether it is for this
reason or that reason whatever that is the
idea. On the basis of this information we
can develop what is called an activity relationship
chart. This is what an activity relationship
chart looks like. We have these departments
from 1 to 10 which you can talk about, so
each square represents a department 1, 2,
3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10. After being represented
by a square, you identify what kind of a rating
you want to get between these departments.
Mind you the rating can also consider the
material handling effort which you computed
in step one. You can have various types of
situation. It should be one line here, two
lines here, three lines here and four lines
here that is it and X U is no relationship
and X rating could be wave V diagram. What
will happen is for instance between one and
three there are three lines. It means that
there is an E rating between 1 and 3.
Similarly for the others what will happen
is that the number of lines between a department
actually shows the a affinity between these
departments that is the related desirability
of different departments to be close to each
other is stronger if the bond is stronger
and the number of lines show the bond. You
are basically getting an idea of which department
should get close to each other to this. This
is called an activity relationship diagram.
Here we assumed that the same size was there
for department particular to calculate the
requirements of each department. So what will
happen is typically how we will be able to
do that for different departments? say if
this is the saw department you know that this
houses the equipment, the Amstrong hack saw
and there are 3 of these the machine center
dimension for each of these in feet in 10/9.
The total machine area requirement is 190
per machine and the total process area required
is because there are 3 machines 570 square
feet.
You can find out immediately the amount of
machine area that you need for this department
called saw, similarly in the mill you might
have different types of machines. You have
a plain mill - 5 of them, vertical mill - 7
of them, hand mill- 4 of them. You know the
department sizes of the machines center requirements,
area of which department and the total area
corresponding to each of these machines. This
exercise can be done for the calculation of
the production space.
We do it for each department in the same manner
and at the end of it we have been able to
find out the total at that mean, the final
area requirements the total square feet required
is now 3931. This is the space required only
for the machines, so normal practice in factory
design is to add 40 percent space for aisle
that is movement within the department. 40
percent aisle space of this is 1572. The total
production space required is 5503 that is
how we calculated this space and we also know
the space requirement of individual departments
as a consequence. We have so far not considered
non productive activity space, this is only
protection space.
You will have to add the requirements of the
non production activity space for storage,
office, locker rooms, foreman maintenance,
and tool crib and so on. This total area comes
out to 1448 square feet in addition to that
you already had. We have to add to the earlier
area production area 5503, this additional
space 1448 and get the total requirement of
6951 square feet of floor space required in
total.
This is the activity involved in calculating
the space from the production requirements
and the non production requirements. What
is then finally done is we have the activity
relationship diagram. The activity relationship
diagram of each department was shown as a
square; this is called a space relationship
diagram. We did the calculations for the space;
each department is shown propositional to
its size. This department has a size of so
much.
This department has a size of so much and
so on. This was a bigger department and it
has a size of 1750 and so on. You represent
these departments in terms of sizes propositional
to the areas. What is the problem now? If
you can imagine that these individual blocks
are cut out of card board with various things,
you could shift them around and try to range
them in the form of a layout and you could
then ultimately get a layout. This is basically
what may of the computer programs do. They
begin with this diagram as an input and then
by shuffling around these departments, generate
a layout. Obviously there are infinite possible
combinations. You have to look for a best
combination and best means. What is your objective?
The objective could be anything; generally
the objective is a material handling effort.
If you are using activity relationships, you
are trying to maximize the material handling
and other factors also. What you do is you
can give some weightages to A E I O U X, some
marks and ultimately develop a layout for
those particular boxes.
Finally what we do is we can develop a plant
layout by shuffling these departments. Ultimately
this shuffling leads to what is called a block
plan. So this is the block plan. We show department
1 should be here, 2, 3, 4, 5
We actually solved the plant layout problem
for this particular case by developing a block
plant which looks like this. Finally when
we look at what we have tried to do in this
particular lecture, we have seen that the
objectives in different types of layouts whether
you talking about process layout, product
layout or mixed layout or even cellular layouts,
the objectives are different. Therefore the
ways of handling these layouts are all different.
Systematic layout planning is a systematic
procedure for designing process layouts and
basically we looked at this procedure in this
particular class to identify how systematic
layout planning can be done for process layouts.
From-to charts measure material handling effort.
A step by step procedure for a sample layout
was done and the major advantage of this particular
systematic layout planning procedure is that
it is a precursor to computerized layout planning.
Therefore in the next class we will try to
look at some of the computerized layout planning
procedures that are available for handling
the layout planning problem course. This will
constitute a basis for doing the exercise.
Thank you