CARL AZUZ, ANCHOR, CNN STUDENT NEWS: Hi Everyone,
I`m Carl Azuz, news out of South America leading
off today`s show. Hugo Chavez, the longtime
leader of Venezuela has died. Chavez was born
in Venezuela in 1954. In 1998 he was elected
president, the youngest one in Venezuela`s
history. He was reelected in 2000, 2006, and
2012. Chavez was controversial. He spoke out
against the United States and other countries.
He had been fighting cancer in recent years,
traveling to Cuba for medical treatments.
Venezuela`s vice president announced the death
of Hugo Chavez yesterday afternoon.
Next up today, we`re turning to Wall Street.
A new record set yesterday by the Dow Jones
Industrial Average. The Dow, not the entire
stock market. It`s a group of about 30 major
stocks, but it gives an idea of how the entire
stock market is doing. Here`s a look at the
last several years. In 2007, the Dow started
dropping, it bottomed out in 2009, and it
started going back up. Yesterday, when the
stock market closed, the Dow was at a new
all-time high. The Dow is one factor that
experts use to figure out how the entire country
is doing.
The Dow is doing well, but the economy is
still struggling. What`s the deal? One possible
explanation is that investors don`t have a
lot of opportunities to make money in other
ways, so the stock market is kind of the best
game in town.
At the start of this week, we reported on
a sink hole that formed underneath a house
in Florida. Workers have finished tearing
down that house and now we can see the actual
hole. That`s it. About 20 feet wide, more
than 50 feet deep. This opened up underneath
a bedroom and swallowed one man up. In that
same report in Monday`s show, we talked about
how and why sink holes show up in Florida.
This one formed on Monday, just three miles
away from the first sink hole. It`s not as
big; 12 feet across, 4-5 feet deep, and it`s
between two houses. So it didn`t cause any
damage.
David Mattingly had the chance to go inside
a sink hole. This is what he found.
DAVID MATTINGLY, CNN CORRESPONDENT: A massive
sink hole, carved out of solid limestone by
drops of water.
So this is what a sink hole looks like from
the inside.
JERRY BLACK, GEOLOGIST: From the inside, yes,
before you fill it up with sand and dirt.
MATTINGLY: And if someone were living right
on top of this, they would be at risk?
BLACK: Yes.
MATTINGLY: Geologist Jerry Black says Sunshine
State homeowners might be surprised to find
out just how common these are.
BLACK: Rain water turns to ground water and
that`s what`s naturally acidic. That`s the
device that dissolves the limestone and will
help create these cavities.
MATTINGLY: What is unusual about this sink
hole is it`s easy to get inside. Called "The
Devil`s Den," it`s open to tourists for viewing
and diving.
And dive instructor Prince Johnson takes me
under for a look. I find that this seemingly
placid pool of water is anything but.
PRINCE JOHNSON, DIVE INSTRUCTOR: The water
has gone down considerably because of the
aquifer, but it has also risen. When we`ve
had hurricanes and tropical storms, it has
risen 45 feet.
MATTINGLY: Forty-five fee?
JOHNSON: Forty-five feet.
MATTINGLY: So the water`s constantly going
up and down?
JOHNSON: Up and down.
MATTINGLY: Depending on drought and hurricanes.
Down here, it`s easy to see how fluctuating
groundwater has silently wreaked havoc. I
passed by limestone boulders as big as cars,
sitting on the bottom. And these same forces
are still at work compounded by the demand
for fresh water.
Perhaps most striking to me, how appearances
of this sink hole are so misleading. A single
beam of light reveals the cavern is even bigger
below the waterline, with tunnels and passageways
carved deep into the darkness. But most disturbing
could be the view from up top. The round opening
is deceptively small. Little indication of
the cavern that`s just beneath my feet.
Until a hole like this opens up, there`s really
no warning is there?
BLACK: Correct. It is that random and that
sudden. And it could happen obviously overnight
or any time.
MATTINGLY: It can, and it does. With thousands
of sink holes opening up in Florida every
year.
David Mattingly, CNN, Williston, Florida.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today`s shoutout goes
out to Ms. Fuzi`s world history class at St.
Gabriel`s Hall in Audubon, Pennsylvania.
Which of these terms is a synonym for "truce?"
You know what to do. Is it acrimony, coup
d`etat, armistice, or dilettante? You`ve got
three seconds. Go.
Truce and armistice both mean an agreement
that ends some kind of hostilities or fighting.
That`s your answer and that`s your shoutout.
AZUZ: One example, the armistice that was
signed on July 27, 1953 it stopped the war
between North and South Korea. Now, North
Korea is threatening to end that truce.
Here`s the history. The Korean peninsula split
into North and South after World War II. In
June of 1950, the North invaded the South.
That was the start of the Korean War. The
U.S. supported South Korea, China supported
North Korea. Hundreds of thousands of people
died. Here`s the interesting part: the fighting
stopped in 1953 with that armistice. There
was never a peace treaty so the Korean War
technically never ended.
Nowadays, North Korea is a closed society;
it doesn`t have a lot of contact with the
rest of the world. It does have a bad relationship
with some nations including South Korea and
the United States. Some of that has to do
with North Korea`s controversial nuclear program.
The U.S. is leading an international effort
to punish North Korea for a recent nuclear
test it did, and the North says that`s why
it`s threatening to get rid of the 60- year-old
truce.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
JOHN KERRY, UNITED STATES SECREATRY OF STATE:
North Korea keeps choosing to make belligerent
and reckless moves that threaten the region,
their neighbors, and now directly the United
States of America.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: The border between North and South Korea
is called the DMZ. It stands for the Demilitarized
Zone. It`s a tense place under the best of
circumstances, which is what Paula Hancocks
looked at while she was there.
PAULA HANCOCKS, DEMILITARIZED ZONE: Here in
the DMZ you can see a North Korean soldier
just across the border. They often come out
of that area to see what is happening on this
side, the South Korean border. This is the
joint security area. It`s basically where
all of the negotiations have taken place between
the North and the South since 1953. Now, the
blue huts behind me are half in North Korea,
half in South Korea and the border itself
is obviously very tense. You can see the South
Korean soldiers facing off against the North
Korean soldiers, and a very inauspicious border.
The concrete slab that you can see in the
middle there, just a few inches above the
ground is effectively the border between North
and South Korea.
So here we are in one of the huts in the joint
security area. This is basically where all
of the negotiations take place, half in North
Korea, half in South Korea. Everything has
to be completely equal and you can see at
the moment it`s being monitored by South Korean
soldiers because it`s the South Korean side
that`s letting people in.
This is called checkpoint three along the
DMZ and you can see how close we are to the
demarcation line. These white stakes that
you can see is effectively the border between
North and South Korea. So just beyond that,
beyond those trees you can see a building
there. This is one of the buildings that obviously
the North Koreans could be using to monitor
South Korea just as here on the South Korean
side, they`re monitoring the North Korean
side.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: See if you can ID me.
I`m an endangered species that`s been around
for millions of years. My hundreds of teeth
come in handy since I`m the largest predatory
fish on the planet. Despite my name, the only
part of my body is my underbelly.
I`m a great white shark and I can move through
the water at up to 15 miles per hour.
AZUZ: One scientist said that finding a great
white is like looking for a needle in a haystack.
Researchers got their hands on one recently.
They found it about 200 yards off the Florida
coast. Researchers tried to haul her into
this at first, but then realized they`re going
to need a bigger boat. Once they landed her,
the scientists had 15 minutes to do about
a dozen things. They checked to see if she
was pregnant, collected blood samples, and
tagged her with a satellite transmitter to
track her movements. They`re hoping to learn
more about these sharks and to increase public
safety. If a tagged great white gets too close
to shore, the scientists will call authorities
who can warn people on the beach.
San Francisco`s Bay Bridge doesn`t get as
much attention as the Golden Gate. Then someone
came up with this bright idea: it`s a combination
of art and technology. Twenty-five thousand
lights spread out across the nearly two mile
bridge. If it looks like they`re shifting,
they are. The artist set up a program that
lets him control each light individually.
He can run the whole thing from his laptop.
The lights will be on every night for two
years. If the artist has something else planned
for then, then this display is just bridging
the gap. At any rate, the Bay Bridge won`t
be in the Golden Gate`s shadow for a while.
This story`s not funny, the puns aren`t that
great, but it makes sense as a before we go
segment we try to focus on the lighter side
of things.
It`s lights out for now, we`re back tomorrow
for more CNN STUDENT NEWS.