Yeah.
Oh, [INAUDIBLE].
DANNY KASS: If you go to the
US Open and you've been
practicing a run for three
months, and you've landed it
for two months straight.
Well then, you know what?
You're running it good enough.
Because it's got to be something
that you come up
with that's just there.
You got to feed off the crowd of
the energy to really do it.
And I did it.
I did my first ever frontside
1080, after a
cab 1080 in the 2002.
And it was a time where I think
a lot of people thought
that the sport really
wasn't going to
progress much further.
And when they saw this young kid
from Jersey just kind of
pushing and pushing, I think a
lot of people really realized
that it was time to shit
or get off the pot.
-This is Danny Kass
[INAUDIBLE].
Cab 1080.
Yeah!
JAKE BURTON: I think Danny Kass,
he just epitomizes what
the Open's about, which
is amplitude,
technical tricks, and style.
TOM MONTEROSSO: Take any pro
snowboarder that's alive
today, any big name
pro snowboarder.
Chances are at some point they
either went to the US Open or
competed in the US Open.
I remember in the early 2000s
when Danny Kass went on his
crazy winning streak.
Once he won the US Open, which
is one of the last contests of
the year, that's when it was
like, holy shit, Danny Kass is
hands down the best pipe
rider in the world.
The whole thing was a huge,
huge win for anybody.
ROSS POWERS: I always looked at
it like, I want to just go,
put on the best show I
can, have the best
time, and go for it.
And nowadays in snowboarding
there's so many events that it
gets all the top riders
together, kind of end of the
year battle.
Everyone's been working
hard through the year.
What tricks do you got?
Throw them down.
TODD KOHLMAN: Just with the US
Open being like the longest
running event in snowboarding,
and keeping it an open where
people can sign up and then
work their way up to ride
against the big riders kind
of has a soulful feel to
snowboarding.
Just back to the roots.
BARRY DUGAN: They were pros.
You kind of knew who was going
to show up and contend.
But there was always that
mystery about what teenager or
tween was going to show
up and throw down.
JASON FORD: Not only has it been
an iconic competition for
Vermont and the East Coast, and
all the people that drive
four or five hours
to attend it.
But it's been good for
snowboarding, because having a
US Open title, or win, or even
a podium has been, for many
people, a highlight
in their career.
TOM MONTEROSSO: You didn't
really have a lot of events on
the East Coast that
you could go to.
It was the US Open every March
where you could see
[INAUDIBLE].
Jamie Lynn would make
an appearance.
Mike Michaelchuk, Jim Rippey,
Daniel Frank, all these icons.
KELLY CLARK: The people who
drive up from Jersey all night
and sleep in their car to come
watch the US Open, it's almost
got like-- what do
you want to call?
Like a cultish following.
PAT BRIDGES: Just like kind of
like a meeting of the tribe.
And you had all these college
kids, and ex-ski racers, and
sort of like burnouts, drop
outs, kind of people who
wanted to be a part
of a fringe group.
SETH NEARY: I remember being at
the gondola and seeing Noah
Salasnek and Chris Roach, and
just being completely
starstruck.
I mean, like holy shit,
these dudes are here.
One hand you're kind of
like fanning out.
But at the other side, you're
like competing.
You want to compete against
them and win.
ANDY COHGLAN: Back then it was
just a straight shot downhill.
I had Vans high top checkered
shoes on.
Man, was it scary.
You're just on this old--
this stuff.
It just made it so
much harder.
JAKE BURTON: It was sort of
a daredevil type scene.
Probably the appropriate word.
And table upside down for
the starting gate.
And it was wild because in the
beginning, it was like downhills.
I don't know, it's sort of
where we were at, just
charging down the hill.
DONNA CARPENTER: If you were
willing, you were welcome.
I do remember the first
woman rider.
And she cried at the top for
like 20 minutes until we
talked her into going.
So it was very intimidating.
I mean, it was these
alpine courses.
They were icy.
We didn't have great
equipment.
ANDY COGHLAN: The US Open was
really important for Jake, and
he took it over from Paul Graves
who ran the first one
in Woodstock, Vermont,
in '82 and wasn't
going to do it again.
And so Jake, kind of out of
necessity, was trying to find
a way to expose snowboarding
to the world.
JAKE BURTON: The freestyle thing
hadn't really happened.
And a lot of people look
back and say, why not?
But it was a necessary time
for snowboarding.
We had to develop boards,
riders had
to develop the technique.
And we had to develop product
that you could get down the
hill on, and turn right, and
left, and stop, and do all
those sort of necessary
functions.
ANDY COGHLAN: It was great.
I mean, especially when Burton
started making the halfpipe, I
think the whole sport
really progressed.
And the media really started
to cover it.
TERRY KIDWELL: It was
1988, they had
their first half pipe.
And I was like surprised.
We get out there and
they have this huge
backhoe digging the pipe.
That's the first time I've ever
seen a piece of equipment
digging the walls for
us, probably the
best pipe to date.
I mean, it had to have been.
Jake always put a lot of effort
into having that event
be the event of the year.
JAKE BURTON: We had Craig Kelly
riding for us at the
time, and he was a phenomenal
pipe rider.
I can remember that first year,
Terry Kidwell won it.
And he and Craig would
just go at it.
And it was an incredible
competition.
It was super fun to see.
ANDY COGHLAN: It was
also a kind of the
changing of the guard.
Because that was the year that
all the young guns were
supposed to win.
Terry Kidwell won the halfpipe
and I won the downhill.
So the two old guys ended up
winning for one more year,
until the young guys came the
next year and took over.
MIKE HAYES: As soon as they
introduced the halfpipe,
that's when we started to
see the crowds show up.
Basically, the whole event
started to gravitate towards
the freestyle events just
because that was the real
crowd pleaser.
It's a lot more fun to watch
the halfpipe than it is to
watch some slalom races.
And so eventually they phased
out the alpine events, and
that's pretty much
when I retired.
They retired me.
PAT BRIDGES: I mean, it used
to be like an underground
where you'd hear the Stratton
pipe got cut,
and you'd go there.
And then, part of the mythology
of the Open was the
fact that not only was it open
to competing, but once that
last competitor dropped
in for the finals,
that pipe was open.
And it was mayhem.
CHRIS COPLEY: As an announcer,
it was really tough.
Because we would have to say,
all right, hold the course.
They're cutting to a commercial
right now.
And so everyone's standing
around going, what--
come on, man.
It broke up the whole
flow of the event.
And then, like a couple dudes
were like, hey, I don't care.
I'm just bombing it.
And they would just cut under
the fence and charge it.
And the crowd would
go so berserk.
HANNAH TETER: People loved
to see the [INAUDIBLE]
in between.
It just adds the fun element to
it and the non-seriousness
effect kind of goes away,
which is nice.
JAKE BURTON: Not that anybody's
encouraging
anybody to do it.
I mean, you've got to have a
certain amount of balls.
Abe Teter, I think, probably
gets the best career poacher.
I mean, that guy just
always went huge.
And people loved to see him
ride, so nobody ever
complained about it.
BARRY DUGAN: It was to see who
was going to be king and
queen, that's for damn sure.
But it was to have a lot
of fun doing it.
And be within touching distance
and getting the high
fives from the crowd, and being
able to hear that roar
and walk through the crowd and
be at the same parties with
the athletes.
I think that's the legacy
of the Open, is being
the best of the best.
TERRY KIDWELL: There are a lot
of big events around the world
from the past to the present,
but I think US Open has stood
the test of time.
I'm super stoked to
hear they're going
into their 30th year.
That is super cool.