people whether they're Dos--
CAT MARNELL: Or Don'ts.
FAT JEW: Why don't you
focus on women a
little more right now?
CAT MARNELL: No, I do like
women, which is why I don't--
Yeah, I should find some Dos.
FAT JEW: OK.
Some Jews?
CAT MARNELL: I like making
fun of men--
FAT JEW: OK, that's great.
CAT MARNELL: --much more.
But in terms of like--
FAT JEW: That's great.
CAT MARNELL: Do.
Hands on hips, yes.
FAT JEW: It's Asian Gilligan.
CAT MARNELL: Hey,
Power Wheels.
FAT JEW: Hey, wigger.
CAT MARNELL: Wigger!
FAT JEW: That's a Do.
Is Mazda Miata Japanese for
homosexual transporter?
That's a do.
Well, you came out to LA to work
in the film industry, and
you ended up with a menu
balanced on your head.
That's a Don't.
CAT MARNELL: You look like
one of those extras on
"Entourage."
FAT JEW: You guys are
planning a murder.
We're not allowed to say that.
That's a Do.
Looks like a gay
Son of Anarchy.
Cut it.
Yeah.
Cut it back-- no, back
the other way.
Cut it.
You're a Don't.
Look at this woman with
pink Juicy pants.
That's such a Do.
Philip Seymour Hoffman.
Chubby dude with
a boogie board?
That's DO, caps lock!
Are you able to take out jean
shorts that fit from that ATM?
CAT MARNELL: Denim
clamdiggers?
Don't.
FAT JEW: You're a
definite Don't.
Is this guy wearing a Joker
basketball jersey?
CAT MARNELL: And pumping hard.
FAT JEW: And pumping hard!
Hey, Joker!
You ready to pull away
if he tries to beat
the shit out of me?
Joker basketball jersey!
Yes!
You're a total Do!
Anyone with a vagina
is scared of you.
Odd future?
How about no future?
Linkin Park Incubus t-shirt?
Yeah.
Why does everyone have
cargo pants on?
Male model or caterer?
CAT MARNELL: And he was wearing
the hair equivalent of
a tail feather.
FAT JEW: Damn, Jamaican with a
mustard face drinking a V8?
Do.
CAT MARNELL: Interracial
couple's always a Do.
This is the future.
FAT JEW: This is what that
dream was all about, huh?
If your hat is so floppy that
you have to hold it up, you're
a fucking idiot.
This is the kind of Latino
guys who loves Spiderman.
He'd wear a silk Spiderman
button-down.
CAT MARNELL: Why is he carrying
so much stuff?
FAT JEW: This guy's
seen some shit.
That's a Do.
CAT MARNELL: Uh-huh.
Men are always sexier
with a cigarette.
FAT JEW: That guy looks like
he was a fucking watchtower
guard at Birkenau.
[CAT LAUGHS]
FAT JEW: You still
think he's sexy?
Oh hell, yeah.
CAT MARNELL: Weed bandana?
Do.
FAT JEW: Oh my god.
Everything about you is great.
Nice tiny ponytail.
It's like a little waterfall
of terrible.
Dude, I'm going to ignore your
deep leathery face, your
horrible unfunny sign, your
coral necklace, and your
horrible life.
And I'm just going to
focus on your Crocs.
You're a Do.
Despite--
against all odds, you're a Do.
Look at this fucking big
floppy-titted, man-shouldered
fucking hippie monster.
First of all, this woman
is like a female--
look at her chest.
Her sternum is insane.
She may have glossed up, too.
She looks like Jon Gruden, Renee
Zellweger, and Jeffrey
Tambor with a wig.