likes, shares, and comments.
I'm going to throw
to the package.
[MUSIC - LINDSEY STIRLING AND
PENTATONIX, "RADIOACTIVE"]
[MUSIC - BOYCE AVENUE FT.
FIFTH HARMONY, "MIRRORS"]
[MUSIC - WALK OFF THE EARTH FT.
KRNFX, "I KNEW
YOU WERE TROUBLE"]
[MUSIC - JAYESSLEE,
"GANGNAM STYLE"]
[MUSIC - THEPIANOGUYS,
"TITANIUM/PAVANE"]
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: All right.
The winner is-- the winner's
name is in the cake.
REGGIE WATTS: Is in the cake?
It looks like white
card is the winner.
Nope.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN:
The winner is--
BOTH: Lindsey Stirling and
Pentatonix, "Radioactive."
[CHEERING]
REGGIE WATTS: We want
to present this to you.
This is the award for
the award that you won.
LINDSEY STIRLING:
Oh, my goodness!
REGGIE WATTS: It's a
representation of the award
that you won.
LINDSEY STIRLING:
It's beautiful.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Yeah.
It's amazing all that you've
accomplished, truly it is.
It's great.
LINDSEY STIRLING:
Well, thank you.
And a big shout
out to Pentatonix
who won this award with me!
REGGIE WATTS: Yea, yea!
LINDSEY STIRLING: Awesome.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: How
long have you been playing?
LINDSEY STIRLING:
I've been playing
since I was six years old.
REGGIE WATTS: I knew you
were going to say that.
LINDSEY STIRLING: You knew it?
REGGIE WATTS: Suzuki method?
LINDSEY STIRLING:
Suzuki all the way!
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Really?
LINDSEY STIRLING: Yeah.
You, too?
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: No.
LINDSEY STIRLING: OK.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: Only
the first couple albums.
REGGIE WATTS: Where'd
you learn to dance?
LINDSEY STIRLING:
Actually, I was
self-taught through
watching YouTube tutorials.
No joke.
JASON SCHWARTZMAN: What?
REGGIE WATTS:
You're pure YouTube.
LINDSEY STIRLING: Exactly.
You know what?
I owe everything of my success
and this award to YouTube.
I was the artist that
everybody wanted to change,
and YouTube allowed me to be
true to my passion, allowed
me to be true to my
values, and true to myself.
So, thank you, YouTube!
Thanks for all the fans,
and thanks to Pentatonix!
[APPLAUSE AND CHEERING]