on the nuclear facilities
of this country.
MAN: For the Yellowstone
super-volcano.
MAN: Civil unrest following
a dirty bomb blast.
NARRATOR:
And protect themselves...
MAN: Boo-yeah!
NARRATOR:
...from what they perceive
is the fast-approaching
end of the world as we know it.
GIRL:
Thomas, don't give 'em the gun!
Don't give 'em the gun, Thomas!
NARRATOR:
Next, we go inside the lives
of three committed preppers
who have devised
extensive plans...
MAN: We've got dinner.
NARRATOR:
...gone to great lengths...
GIRL: There's no toilet.
Toilets were made for a reason.
Use them.
NARRATOR: And made
huge personal sacrifices
to ensure their very survival.
MAN: It's great to have
healthy pets
because you never know when
you're gonna need to eat 'em.
NARRATOR: The experts
will assess their preps
to see if they have
what it takes...
GIRL: Hello.
NARRATOR: ...to survive.
MAN: Contact, rear!
Need some covering fire!
NARRATOR:
This is "Doomsday Preppers."
Lucas Cameron
is a farmer in Tennessee.
He's spent his entire life
living and working
on the same tract of land.
He, his wife Nikki,
their son Jonathan,
and his parents,
Mike and Brenda,
are all God-fearing Christians.
Lucas even works
for the local ministry.
But when Lucas turned
to the good book for guidance,
he found more than just a path
to spiritual salvation.
He found stories
of the wrath of God
and of men who were
preparing to endure it.
LUCAS CAMERON:
Scripture's full of preppers.
Noah built an ark,
and it saved his family.
Joseph made sure
to put granaries in Egypt,
and it saved not only
his family, but all of Egypt.
I intend also to put back
so that I can save myself
and my community.
I'm preparing
for a global earthquake
described in Revelation.
Cut 'em off!
My life is different
to most people,
because as they go about
their days carefree
and never think about
what may happen tomorrow,
the thought is always
in the back of my mind,
and I make certain to prepare
for what is to come.
There's nothing
more important to me
than prepping
because the scripture instructs
me to do so for the "end days."
In the very near future,
the events prophesied
in scripture
in the book of Revelation
will come to life.
There will be
a great earthquake,
greater than one ever has been
since the foundation
of the world.
NARRATOR: Lucas believes
this great earthquake
won't strike out west,
but right under his feet,
along the New Madrid
fault system.
Parts of Tennessee
and several other states
lay within the fault zone,
the most active seismic area
east of the Rocky Mountains.
In 1811 and 1812,
a series of nearly
8.0 magnitude earthquakes
tore through the New Madrid,
creating huge landslides
and fissures
that ripped across approximately
45,000 square miles
and caused parts
of the Mississippi River
to run backwards.
Lucas believes this was nothing
compared with what's to come.
LUCAS: In the days following
the earthquake,
the chaos will erupt.
Many people
will turn to lawlessness
as a means for survival
because they've not
took the time
to make proper preparation.
NARRATOR:
To prepare for Armageddon,
Lucas and his friends and family
have begun fortifying
the family farm,
spending around $50,000
to turn it into
a compound he calls...
the Alamo.
LUCAS: We call it that
because that is the place
we look to for protection
and our final holdout
when these events
start to take place.
This place is to be here as
a beacon of hope for many others
and to also help light the way
for our community in recovery.
NARRATOR: To help get the Alamo
ready for doomsday,
Lucas and his family
have been recruiting others,
with the goal of forming
an elite prepping force.
They call themselves
the Seven Trumpet Preppers.
Each member has been
hand-selected by Lucas
for a skill set
he believes will be vital
after a mega-earthquake.
LUCAS: Everybody's in charge
of a certain task.
Kevin has seen
the worst side of war
and knows exactly
what it means.
KEVIN: I win.
LUCAS: He's in charge of
security during the daytime.
LUCAS: Brian is
a night-shift worker now,
and he's very accustomed
to the nighttime,
and he will be in charge of
the night-shift security watch.
My dad, he's been a farmer
for all his life.
He's had plenty of skills
in growing crops
and beef production.
NARRATOR: If a major rupture
within the New Madrid
fault zone occurs,
it could leave more than
2.5 million homes
in the central U.S.
without power.
So Lucas is turning to another
of the Seven Trumpet Preppers,
Scott,
to ensure the Alamo has abundant
alternate energy sources.
LUCAS: Me and Scott
have known each other
since we were children.
Scott assists me
in power projects
and in fabrication
of the materials that we need
for those things.
SCOTT: If they have an idea,
I try to make it possible.
I try to build it
as cheaply as I can
and make it practical.
LUCAS: As far as energy
is concerned,
I have no intention to ever use
gasoline or diesel again
once these events
begin to happen.
Wood gasification
is my only intention
of having a power source.
NARRATOR: A gasifier can convert
materials such as wood
into a petroleum substitute
by burning the products at
a temperature above 450 degrees.
LUCAS: We're gonna set this up,
and then we'll start
sliding the boxes in.
Alright, this one goes
in the top slot.
The other one goes
in the filter area.
NARRATOR: Lucas was able
to construct his gasifier
out of ammo boxes and old scrap
materials worth less than $200.
LUCAS: Gas that's released
from charring the wood
will go to the filter,
and then that will
filter out the liquid from it,
and then it will go
to the generator,
and we can fire up
the generator off of it.
We want a lot of heat.
I want this thing
to look like pit barbecue.
Once you get to 451 degrees,
we're going to start
making wood gas.
We're almost there.
MAN: Yeah, we're getting there.
LUCAS: Looks awesome.
Looks awesome. I love it.
MAN: C'mon, buddy.
We got it running.
LUCAS: As this runs,
you can power a battery charger
off of this unit.
And you can have
an unlimited amount of power
as long as you have wood
to power the generator.
NARRATOR:
Lucas is also constructing
a vertical wind turbine,
which they'll use
to charge batteries.
LUCAS: This vertical axis
wind turbine that we built
was made out of stove flashing
and some flat bar.
This is a vehicle AC motor
and squirrel cage.
It can be very useful
in a situation where
you need portable power.
NARRATOR: When it comes to food,
Lucas already has 5 goats,
20 chickens, and 40 cows
ready for doomsday.
But finding a way
to keep all their stored food
secure through an earthquake
is another one of Lucas'
current top priorities.
So he
and the Seven Trumpet Preppers
are trying to make their
storage area earthquake-proof.
LUCAS: I'll hold it
while you cut on her.
What we're doing today
is securing the shelves together
with L-brackets.
This will stop the sway
in the shelves
when an earthquake comes
and also help to stop them
from falling over
and spilling our stored product.
Also on the back,
they're being affixed to the
wall and the concrete block
so that no food falls out
or is busted
from coming off the shelf.
NARRATOR: Lucas' plan
is to stock these shelves
with 3.5 years' worth of food,
which he believes will be
enough to last a group of 20
through the worst
of a New Madrid quake.
LUCAS: My wife Nikki takes care
of most of the food dehydration
so that we can have them
stored on the shelves
if we ever need them.
WOMAN:
Barbeque sauce with chicken.
NIKKI: Oh, that's my favorite.
WOMAN: Beef enchilada.
LUCAS: This is one
of our food caches
that we're putting MREs
and rice stores back.
And this will be
not only to benefit us
but some others nearby,
neighbors in the community,
just in case things
get terribly out of hand.
GRANDMA: Why is there
not brown rice up here?
NIKKI: Because
the white rice keeps longer
than the brown rice.
NARRATOR: Although he believes
this storage area
within the Alamo
will survive a massive quake,
Lucas has also concealed another
400 to 500 pounds of food
in two different hidden
locations around the farm.
LUCAS: We've been very careful
to divide our food stores up,
not only for OPSEC,
but for the fact
that if for some reason
one of them was lost,
we would have plenty of other
food at other locations.
NARRATOR: Lucas is storing
enough food for 20 people
because he has a master plan
to expand his ranks
and create
a formidable prepping force.
But when it comes
to new recruits,
Lucas is very demanding.
LUCAS: To have someone
on my safe list,
they would've had to done
something for me in my past.
This would have to be
trusted people I've known
and have done only good deeds
toward other people.
NARRATOR: And his newest
potential member
may not be able
to handle the stress...
MAN: Contact, rear!
NARRATOR: ...of being
a Seven Trumpets Prepper.
NARRATOR: Lucas Cameron
is preparing
for a biblical earthquake
along the New Madrid
fault system
by turning his 26-acre farm
in Tennessee
into a safe haven for himself,
his family, and his neighbors.
LUCAS: I spend thousands
of dollars a year prepping.
This farm has everything we need
for whenever the great
earthquake takes place.
NARRATOR: Lucas fears
that some of those who
have not prepared as he has
will turn into marauders
in the aftermath
of a great quake,
and descend on his Alamo,
looking to plunder his preps.
So to ensure he always has
enough ammunition
to combat
the threat of looters,
Lucas plans
to manufacture his own.
Today, he and his father, Mike,
are teaching Lucas'
7-year-old son, Jonathan,
how to reload ammo.
LUCAS: The reason it's important
to know how to do this
is because one day,
whenever you can't get ammo,
you might need
to make it for yourself
so that you can hunt
or protect yourself with it.
My son, Jonathan,
is 7 years old,
and I intend to teach him
all that I can.
MIKE: Every time you come down,
come all the way down.
Very good.
All right, now,
that starts the crimp.
Congratulations! Your first
loaded 12-gauge shell.
Let's see it.
Got to make sure that
the primer is always flush.
LUCAS: It's crimping good.
What's the only purpose
guns are good for?
JONATHAN: Killing people
that are trying to kill you.
MIKE: Guns are just weapons.
They're like a carpenter's saw.
But we like 'em, don't we?
All right.
NARRATOR: To bolster the ranks
of the Seven Trumpet Preppers,
Lucas is now looking for other
trustworthy local preppers
who can bring
specific skills to the group.
LUCAS: There'll be those
that take care of security,
those that take care
of the farming operation,
and others that will
be in charge of things
such as power supply.
NARRATOR:
One potential new candidate
recently moved
only 35 miles away.
Kevin O'Brien
is a father of four.
He regularly
takes his family camping
in the wilds
of eastern Tennessee.
KEVIN O'BRIEN:
All right, everyone out.
We got camping to do.
NARRATOR: His children
don't particularly enjoy
these camping trips.
KEVIN: You like camping.
You excited to camp?
WOMAN: She's never excited.
KEVIN: No, you don't like
camping, do you?
WOMAN: Manual labor.
KEVIN: I know.
NARRATOR: But Kevin insists
on coming back again and again.
That's because this isn't
a typical campsite.
This is their new home.
KEVIN: We moved
from Florida to Tennessee
to avoid worldwide destruction
from the effects
of a pole shift.
GIRL: Hello.
NARRATOR: Last season
on "Doomsday Preppers,"
Kevin O'Brien
moved his entire family
from Jacksonville, Florida,
to the remote hills
of eastern Tennessee
in an attempt
to escape the apocalypse.
KEVIN: I think
I owe it to my family
to do everything I can
to keep them safe
and out of harm's way.
NARRATOR: Kevin was determined
to get his family out of Florida
because he thinks
it will wind up underwater
in the event of
a catastrophic polar shift.
KEVIN:
When the polar shift happens,
we're going to see
rising sea levels,
earthquakes, volcanoes,
tsunamis bouncing off
coasts back and forth.
Entire countries
might be underwater.
Florida might find itself maybe
where Alaska used to be.
NARRATOR: But not all of Kevin's
family shared his beliefs,
or his desire to uproot
and move 540 miles from home.
WOMAN: Are you looking forward
to moving at all?
GIRL: No.
WOMAN: Not at all?
KEVIN: Our oldest, Hailey,
she's getting
into the teen years,
doesn't want to uproot
and leave her friends behind.
WOMAN: A lot of our family
thinks we're crazy.
A lot of our friends
think we're crazy.
HAILEY: Well, we are crazy.
NARRATOR: Despite
their kids' protestations,
Kevin and Amie
packed up their belongings,
along with their 2,000 pounds
of food, ammo, and energy preps,
and set out
on a nine-hour journey
from Florida to Tennessee.
But nearly a year
after their move,
the 130-acre plot of land
that was supposed to become
their prepper paradise
is still just an empty lot.
KEVIN: Prepping costs money.
The move up to Tennessee,
you know,
kind of put us
in a hurt locker a little bit.
We put a nice chunk of change
down for the land.
We don't have the cash on hand
to build a house ourselves.
NARRATOR: Instead, the O'Briens
have been renting a house nearby
and making regular camping trips
to their land
to get their kids
used to the area.
KEVIN: Camping once again
to kind of get used
to the property
and know our way around.
HAILEY: There's no toilet.
There's no shower.
No sink.
And it's terrible.
Toilets were made for a reason.
Use them.
KEVIN: It'll be fun.
You'll enjoy it.
It'll grow on you.
We'd like to build
a really solid home,
probably out of
reinforced concrete--
bulletproof, waterproof,
fireproof, earthquake proof,
and ultimately,
pole shift proof.
BOY: When are we getting
the house built?
KEVIN: Hopefully
in the next six months,
if all goes according to plan.
My real main fear now
is just am I gonna be able
to get the things in place
that I want to have in place
by the time something happens?
NARRATOR:
Not having enough money yet
to build his prepper dream home
hasn't slowed Kevin down.
Even with limited resources,
he still spends
20 to 25 hours a week
filling their rental house
with preps he thinks
they'll need for a polar shift.
AMIE: We have enough rice
to last forever.
But the thing is
Kevin doesn't even eat rice.
He hates it.
Everything goes to prepping.
There's no leisure.
I don't think we've ever really
been on a family vacation.
We've gone to see his family
in New Jersey for a funeral,
and Kevin counts that
as vacation.
I wish that Kevin
could find a balance.
You can still prepare for all
the bad things that can happen
and still enjoy your life now.
Just go to a movie with us,
or play a game.
NARRATOR:
But instead of movie night,
tonight, Kevin's
quality time with the kids
is showing them how to make
first-aid kits
for their bug-out bags.
KEVIN: It's important
for each of you
to have your own first-aid kit.
In case we get separated,
you've got your own supplies.
NARRATOR: Kevin believes
that after a polar shift,
hospitals will be overrun,
and medical supplies
will be scarce.
KEVIN: Pull out your Band-Aids.
NARRATOR: So he's been
stockpiling first-aid supplies
for months.
KEVIN: We're gonna
put these in the metal tins
because they won't get crushed
as easy inside the bag.
And once the lid's
snapped on them,
it'll be pretty close
to waterproof.
Hey, if you want to be up
all night doing this, fine,
but otherwise
let's pay attention
and we can move on
to the next thing.
BOY: Our friends...
if we talk about
pole shifts and stuff,
they would think,
"They are crazy."
KEVIN: All right, so everyone
put your lids on them.
We're all done. Good job.
All right!
Now that we've got that done,
I've got a little present
for you guys.
NARRATOR: While Kevin
believes Tennessee
is much safer than
Florida overall,
there are two nuclear plants
in the state.
KEVIN: Gas masks.
GIRL: Can we try it on?
NARRATOR:
Both of which he believes
will be vulnerable to meltdown
during a polar shift.
KEVIN: You've got
the nuclear accident
as a result of the tsunami
over there in Japan.
The mask filters out any kind
of harmful radioactive debris.
And after like a polar shift,
you're gonna want
stuff like that
if you have to go out and about.
GIRL: Hello.
HAILEY: Hello.
I believe
a polar shift will happen.
I just don't believe
it'll have any effect
on our geographical locations,
and I honestly don't think we
have anything to worry about.
NARRATOR:
Since Kevin's not getting
his family's full support,
he's on a mission to connect
with other like-minded preppers
willing to help him survive
a polar shift.
LUCAS: How we doin'?
NARRATOR: But when he hooks up
with Lucas'
Seven Trumpet Preppers online
and tries to join their group,
the initiation test may be
much more than he can handle.
LUCAS: Cut 'em off!
Cut 'em off!
NARRATOR: Kevin O'Brien
has moved his wife
and four reluctant kids...
AMIE: Are you excited to move?
GIRL: No!
NARRATOR: ...540 miles
from Florida to Tennessee
because he fears
the world is about to end.
But his family believes he may
be taking his prepping too far.
AMIE: I don't think
Kevin understands
that this is kind of like
a lonely lifestyle.
You don't have a whole lot
of people to talk to about it.
My kids don't want people
knowing that we're preppers.
They get embarrassed.
NARRATOR:
With only grudging cooperation
from his wife and kids,
Kevin's been looking
outside the family
for the support he craves.
He's created a website, hoping
to find like-minded locals.
KEVIN: If I have to make friends
all over again
and meet new people and network,
I might as well
try to meet fellow preppers,
so this website kind of is a way
to bring preppers together.
We're up to 152 preppers
as members.
It makes you feel
really not alone.
One of the first people
to join was Lucas.
NARRATOR: Unlike Kevin,
Lucas Cameron already has
a tight-knit prepping group.
They call themselves
the Seven Trumpet Preppers.
LUCAS: As a community
of preppers, we do many things.
We store food together,
we do operational security
training together,
and we make sure
to be medically prepped.
NARRATOR: Kevin's asked Lucas
if he can join
the Seven Trumpet Preppers
and work together
to survive the apocalypse.
KEVIN: Lucas has got a whole
community going over there.
I will actually be
going out to his place,
out to his farm to meet him.
LUCAS: Welcome to
my humble abode, neighbor.
NARRATOR:
Today, Lucas has invited Kevin
to visit his compound
for the first time.
LUCAS: You got the whole army
with you today.
KEVIN: Yeah, I brought the clan.
LUCAS: Hey, how we doing today?
KEVIN: It was nice to kind of
be invited to go out over there
and see what they had going on
and then swap ideas.
NARRATOR: But today's meeting
isn't just about
making new friends.
Before deciding whether or not
to admit the O'Briens
into his group,
Lucas wants to test
their defensive skills
and make sure they can
carry their own weight.
KEVIN: So you guys are already
loaded and ready to go, huh?
LUCAS: Hey, we're...
Take your time, neighbor.
KEVIN: All right, here we go.
NARRATOR: As Lucas' group
assesses the O'Briens'
performance on the gun range,
Kevin is eager to prove
that he and his family
can bring valuable skills
to the table.
KEVIN: Thanks for having us over
and letting us fire some rounds
off in the gun range
and, you know,
we're kind of new to the area,
so we want to get to know
other preppers in the area.
NARRATOR:
But the Seven Trumpet Preppers
want Kevin to understand
that becoming one of them
requires more than just
proficiency with a firearm.
BRIAN:
Eventually, you will learn
how each of your people walk.
At a distance, you're like,
"Man, they all look the same.
Who is that?"
"That's so and so,
'cause I can tell
by the way he's walking."
You learn how
they carry themselves.
That's important details
to pay attention to.
NARRATOR:
Lucas still isn't convinced
Kevin is the right man
for the job.
In his opinion, the true measure
of a Seven Trumpet Prepper
is how much he's willing to give
to protect the group.
LUCAS:
For Kevin to make the cut,
he would have to prove to us
that he'd more than willing
to take up
and help protect this place
if in need or in a threat.
NARRATOR:
So Lucas has arranged an event
that will not only test
Kevin's defensive skills,
but his own group's
security training as well.
LUCAS: We're gonna have
a mock raid on the farm
and test
our operational security.
Do you want to be part of that?
KEVIN: Yeah, that sounds
real interesting.
LUCAS: Awesome.
NARRATOR: Lucas has invited
the prepping experts,
David Kobler and Scott Hunt
from Practical Preppers,
to conduct a mock raid
on the Alamo
during one of their
nighttime supply runs.
DAVID: We're going to evaluate
his perimeter today.
We're going to see how he reacts
to some hostile forces
coming against him,
see if he reacts properly,
see if he actually
if he's proactive
and he comes after us
to make sure he's secure.
Nighttime is the hardest thing
to do an operation.
It's hard for us to sneak in,
but it's also very hard for him
to defend his property.
NARRATOR: Practical Preppers
don't know the terrain,
but they're equipped with
the latest in night vision,
communications,
and tactical gear.
Lucas' team
has home field advantage,
but none of Practical
Preppers' modern technology.
LUCAS: We're runnin' tonight
with no coms
so there won't be no chatter.
It's just all yell commands,
voice commands only.
NARRATOR:
Practical Preppers' objective
is to get within
a 4-foot perimeter.
They believe anyone able to get
that close in a real attack
would be able to kill
the inhabitants.
SCOTT:
If we get close to his home,
his location, where his wife,
his children, his supplies are,
then he has lost,
he's lost the battle.
NARRATOR: It will be Kevin's
responsibility during the attack
to drive up
to receive the food transfer
and act as watchman.
KEVIN: So what's the game plan?
LUCAS: We don't know exactly
where they're gonna hit from,
but it's gonna take place
during the transaction,
while we're loading you supplies
to help your community.
MAN: So mostly
just stay with the vehicle.
Let us be security team.
KEVIN: I'm kind of the outsider.
They've know each other
for a very long time
so they really don't know,
you know, what I'm all about.
So, they're gonna get to see
how I react
under a, you know,
stressful situation.
NARRATOR: As the sky darkens,
Kevin takes his position.
LUCAS: Contact, rear!
Need some covering fire!
NARRATOR: But in the heat
of the moment,
will he earn his stripes,
or crack under the pressure?
NARRATOR: Kevin O'Brien is
in the midst of a combat drill
that will determine
whether or not
he's accepted into Lucas
Cameron's prepper network.
Kevin's assignment:
protect the food transfer
from ambush.
With the help
of night-vision goggles,
Practical Preppers'
assault team
is creeping toward the compound
under cover of darkness.
Lucas' team
attempts to take away
Practical Preppers' advantage
by sweeping the area
with flashlights
to counteract
their night-vision goggles.
But this also gives away
Lucas' team's positions.
DAVID: I see a guy with
a flashlight in the front.
Let's go.
We knew exactly where they are.
They thought
they had the advantage
by using that flashlight
and shining it out there,
but it's also
a huge disadvantage.
If we find out
where their security is,
we can take advantage of it.
LUCAS: Contact, rear!
Contact!
LUCAS: Need some covering fire!
NARRATOR:
Knowing his responsibility
is to protect the vehicle
during the chaos,
Kevin holds his position.
LUCAS: Cut him off!
Cut him off!
NARRATOR: But as Lucas
calls out instructions
to his other teammates,
his gun jams,
and he's left helpless.
LUCAS: Son of a bitch.
Jam! Jam!
DAVID: Let's go!
Take 'em! Take 'em!
NARRATOR: Practical Preppers
take advantage
of the equipment failure
to breach the 4-foot perimeter
and stop the supply transfer.
DAVID: We made it far up.
We made it all the way
to the house
and actually used their house
as cover for us
as we shot at them.
[bleep]
LUCAS: Outstanding job.
KEVIN: What'd you guys think?
DAVID: Night vision
gives us an advantage.
Communication
So definitely invest
in some radios.
I mean, night vision
is pretty costly,
but radios--
you can easily do those.
SCOTT: I think the main lesson
is we got too close.
And so they need to back up
their nighttime perimeter.
Putting up some alerts
around the perimeter,
they would have
picked us up a lot sooner
and we would have never
gotten to that vehicle.
LUCAS: I definitely
learned a lot
from this experience
as a whole.
KEVIN: Yeah, it was definitely
a learning experience,
and it was great practice,
a good trial run.
And I think we all have
a lot of takeaways
that we're gonna learn from,
you know, moving forward.
NARRATOR:
Even though Practical Preppers
succeeded in taking the Alamo,
for standing his ground
during the confusion
and protecting the truck,
Kevin earns
the ultimate accolade:
acceptance from Lucas'
Seven Trumpet Preppers.
LUCAS: I feel like the moment
that you pulled up,
and we done,
we done a good shift.
I think as a whole, all of us
think that you made the cut.
Appreciate you.
KEVIN: All right. Thank you.
Glad to be in.
NARRATOR: For Kevin,
finding acceptance
in a prepper community
has helped his family
begin to feel
like bugging out to Tennessee
was the right move.
KEVIN: I really feel
we're in the right place
because we're finding out
there's a whole lot
of preppers up here.
And we're finding
more and more every day,
so starting to network together
and kind of help each other out.
AMIE: All right, Hailey,
get your little chick.
HAILEY: Here he is.
AMIE: Yeah.
And what's your chicken's name?
HAILEY: Nugget.
HAILEY: I do believe they're
doing it because they love us.
You know, they're our parents,
they want what's best for us,
and I am looking forward
to having a house to live in
on our property.
It'd be nice to actually have
somewhere to call home.
AMIE: Alright, that's enough.
If the world goes to hell,
they will absolutely
appreciate our prepping.
If not, I don't know.
Maybe they'll look back and say,
"Well, you know,
they were crazy,
but they were just doing it
so that we would be safe."
I don't know.
You never know.
Hopefully they will.
NARRATOR: Kevin and Lucas,
the experts
at Practical Preppers,
have reviewed your preps.
Kevin, the fact that you are
starting to raise chickens
is a step towards
a re-supply plan,
but to ensure your family's
survival long-term,
you should also plant
a vegetable garden.
KEVIN: Once we got out there,
one of the first things we were
gonna do was put a garden in.
NARRATOR:
Lucas, your prepper network,
food preservation methods,
and power sources
are all impressive.
But your communications plan
is completely inadequate.
You should invest in radios
for all your team members.
LUCAS: I believe that is
a very fair assessment,
and that is something
that we are making
a number-one priority right now
and will be investing in
in the very near future.
NARRATOR: To determine how long
you could initially
survive a catastrophe,
Practical Preppers
has scored your preps
in five categories
of 20 points each.
Kevin, cultivating food
on your property
will greatly enhance
your re-supply plan.
15 out of 20 points.
Lucas, your food re-supply plan
is excellent.
19 points.
Water:
Kevin, 12 points;
Lucas, 13.
Shelter:
Kevin, you need to
transition from a tent
to a more permanent
bug-out structure.
11 points.
Lucas, you should have
a bug-out location
in case your compound
gets overrun.
13 points.
Security:
Kevin, 13 points;
Lucas, 16.
Kevin, reaching out to Lucas
shows that you recognize
the importance of community
in surviving a disaster.
This gives you
11 X-factor points.
Lucas, your ability to stretch
your food supply through farming
gives you 13.
Kevin, your total score
is 62 out of 100.
Lucas, your total score is 74.
Your initial survival time
is 14 months.
Kevin, you have 9 months
initial survival time.
KEVIN:
Oh, harsh. 62 out of 100.
I know we do have
some weak areas.
Obviously building our house
and getting out on the property
and getting everything
we have planned underway
is gonna hugely impact,
you know, our score
and knock it up several notches.
LUCAS: Our water
and communication issues
will be resolved shortly.
As far as a bunker goes,
we don't need one because
we meet our enemies head on.
KEVIN: We've been real busy
since the film crew
last came out.
We've moved to a bit
of a prepper's paradise
only about five miles away
from our bug-out location.
It's got a pond out front
stocked with fish.
It's got a wood-burning stove.
We're always adding
to our food preps.
We just extended
our chicken coop.
So, keeping busy as always.
Take care.
LUCAS: We took care
of some of our issues
that we had with our preps.
As far as communication goes,
we've gotten
some walkie-talkies.
We've also began construction
on a hand pump for our well
so that our water situation
will be better in control.
NARRATOR:
The Earth's magnetic poles
have been known
to switch places.
The last switch happened
roughly 780,000 years ago.
But there's no evidence
a magnetic pole reversal
has any impact
on the Earth's geography.
Earthquakes
on the New Madrid fault
occur once every 500 years
on average.
Scientists believe there's
a greater than 1 in 50 chance
that the New Madrid fault
will unleash a major earthquake
in the next 50 years.
Native American prepper
Snake Blocker
plans to survive doomsday
by becoming one with the land.
No storage space full of food,
no backup water supply.
But when he tries
to teach his new wife
the Apache way of prepping,
it may spell trouble
for the newlyweds.
SNAKE BLOCKER:
Do you actually see
the baby wasp right in here?
SNAKE BLOCKER:
You want to try it?
MELISSA: Not right now.
[tribal singing]
NARRATOR: In the mountains
outside Denver, Colorado,
Apache Native American,
Snake Blocker,
regularly honors his heritage
by taking part
in traditional ceremonies.
SNAKE BLOCKER: Dancers ready?
NARRATOR: Today, he's attending
a blessing and cleansing ritual,
a symbolic circle of balance,
strength, and unity
in which all are equal.
Emulating
his ancestors' way of living
is central
to Snake Blocker's life,
as is upholding
their traditions,
like interpreting
Apache prophecies.
Over the past 15 years,
Snake Blocker has had
a profound recurring vision,
which he believes
is a warning from God.
SNAKE BLOCKER: I found myself
kind of in a distant land.
Death was showing me
that this was his plan...
And his destruction
for the world.
The U.S. economy will collapse.
Look at how much debt we're in,
trillions of dollars.
The value of the dollar
is decreasing day to day.
Paper money
is going to be worthless.
People are going to go to
stealing, pillaging, rioting.
You're gonna see
the United States
go from middle-class
society to slums.
Nobody knows
the time or the day,
but it's guaranteed to happen.
Aaaah!
I'm preparing
for economic collapse.
It's real important for me
to utilize my wisdom
that I've gained
from the Apache heritage
and the Apache traditions
and applying it
to today's situation.
NARRATOR:
But Snake's new wife, Melissa,
a school teacher
and trained opera singer,
has not yet fully embraced her
husband's prepping lifestyle.
SNAKE BLOCKER: If I was single,
it doesn't really matter.
I'll adapt and survive.
But my greatest fear is being
separated from Melissa, my wife.
NARRATOR: So today,
he's decided it's finally time
for Melissa to get on board
and experience
what he has planned
for life after doomsday.
MELISSA BLOCKER: He is so...
so very prepared
with everything, you know.
And change for me is usually
a little bit slower.
SNAKE BLOCKER: I need to be a
responsible husband to my wife.
To have the strength
and the symbol of the snake,
I too must be strong
for others around me.
NARRATOR: Unlike many preppers,
Snake Blocker hasn't been
stockpiling food and water
at some remote safe house.
There's no trailer full of food
waiting for them,
no barrels full of water.
Instead, he intends
for them to travel light
and live off the land, like
his nomadic Apache ancestors.
SNAKE BLOCKER: The Apache
is always on the move,
so they learned to adapt
in a variety of terrains.
The great spot is to get
to higher elevations.
Number one,
you're away from the city.
Number two, the higher upstream
you go up in the mountains,
the more pure
that water is gonna be.
NARRATOR: Because he plans to
keep them always on the move,
they'll need to be able to drink
water wherever they can find it.
SNAKE BLOCKER: Thirsty, hon?
NARRATOR: But bacteria
thrive in water.
And waterborne diseases
kill close to 3.5 million
people each year--
the equivalent of almost
the entire city of Los Angeles.
SNAKE BLOCKER: Use this straw,
get a little sip of water
and hydrate.
NARRATOR:
So Snake Blocker considers
their water filtration straws
invaluable.
When water passes through them,
activated carbon
blocks parasites
like Salmonella and E. coli.
SNAKE BLOCKER:
Give it a try, Melissa.
Got to stay well-hydrated.
Filtration straws will keep us
going for a while.
NARRATOR: Convincing Melissa
to drink from a muddy puddle
is one thing;
getting her accustomed to eating
what he can find in the hills
is another.
SNAKE BLOCKER:
You want to basically
be able to survive on your own
through the means
of hunting, fishing.
NARRATOR: But in the wilderness,
Snake Blocker's experience
is that it can take
up to three days
to find any animals for food.
So he wants to train Melissa
to be willing to take
what they can get
when resources are scarce.
SNAKE BLOCKER:
You're trying to hunt,
but you're unsuccessful
for up to three days.
Then you find food, you've got
a little bit of nutrients,
and then it might be another
three days without food,
and that tends
to be the pattern.
In the meantime,
you can rely on insects,
and that will help your body
and sustain your muscles
to help you continue the hunt.
Look, Melissa, over here.
We got an anthill.
It's kind of nice, actually.
Just using my hands, if I didn't
have a shovel or anything.
All you got to do
is put your hand out,
and the food comes to you.
NARRATOR:
There are roughly 1,700 species
of insects in the world
that are edible
and which can provide calories,
protein, and vitamins.
Ants, in particular, can be
high in protein and low in fat.
SNAKE BLOCKER: So take it,
you smash them.
That way they don't bite
your tongue when you do it.
You want to
crunch them right away,
just in case
they still are alive
and they will pinch your tongue.
I swallow it.
MELISSA: What do they
taste like, hon?
SNAKE BLOCKER:
There's a tiny bit of juice
that comes out
from their guts
and really doesn't have
a whole lot of taste to it.
MELISSA:
That would gross me out.
SNAKE BLOCKER:
You want to try one, Melissa?
MELISSA:
No, I really don't want to.
SNAKE BLOCKER: I always like
to lean over boards like these
'cause you never know what
you're going to see under there.
I've caught
some snakes, lizards,
all kinds of insects under here.
Nice.
MELISSA: Ooh.
SNAKE BLOCKER:
So that's the first time
I've seen a wasp's nest
under a log.
We'll see if we can kill them
and eat their young.
You actually see the baby wasp
right in here.
MELISSA: Okay.
SNAKE BLOCKER:
You want to try it?
MELISSA: Not right now.
SNAKE BLOCKER:
All right. I'll try it.
It's not going to bother me.
I'm not going to vomit.
A little more
nutrients in there.
You can actually
boil this entire hive here
and eat the entire thing
just like that.
You do what you need to do.
NARRATOR: Because of Melissa's
reluctance to eat insects,
if Snake Blocker expects them
to be able to survive
a potential doomsday
by living off the land,
he's going to have to find
more palatable food sources
for his wife.
MELISSA: Getting hungry.
NARRATOR: But in the mountains
of Colorado, keeping Melissa fed
is going to put all his Apache
hunting skills to the test.
NARRATOR: Denver prepper,
Snake Blocker,
is training his newlywed wife
how to survive life
after an economic collapse
by taking her from
their comfortable home
and out into the wild.
Unlike other preppers
who might spend thousands
of dollars stockpiling food,
Snake Blocker believes
their key to survival
is by following
his Apache heritage
and living off the land.
SNAKE BLOCKER: It doesn't matter
what tribe you're from.
Our ancestors
always told us be prepared.
They would train without fear,
and they would train
to never give up.
NARRATOR: When trying to survive
off only what he can hunt
in the mountains of Colorado,
Snake Blocker knows one can
go days without a kill.
But his new wife, Melissa,
isn't used to being
without food for that long.
MELISSA: Getting hungry.
NARRATOR: So Snake is focusing
all his Apache hunting skills
toward trying to find
their dinner.
SNAKE BLOCKER:
To use a bow and arrow
takes a high level of skill.
Cool, got a rabbit.
It's a fat little guy.
NARRATOR: A hare's lifespan
is between one and five years,
but they can have litters
of five kids at a time,
making them
a more abundant food source
than large game.
SNAKE BLOCKER:
We've got dinner.
MELISSA: Yay!
NARRATOR:
Because they've bugged-out
with precious few supplies,
Snake's survival plan
depends on being able
to find what they need
in the environment around them.
And that includes
shelter from the elements.
SNAKE BLOCKER: This is like
a native ceremonial area.
It may be used periodically,
but for now it's not being used,
and we have
quite a few resources we can use
to build a shelter.
NARRATOR: Snake also finds
an animal's jaw bone,
which he turns into a tool
for skinning their kill.
MELISSA: I'm not used to seeing
a rabbit being skinned.
SNAKE BLOCKER: A little
more scraping here,
make sure it's nice and clean.
In a survival situation,
you got to do things
safe and quick.
NARRATOR: Snake Blocker
now needs to rely
on another Apache skill
he was taught
to ensure they can cook
the day's catch.
SNAKE BLOCKER: What I'll do
is I can take a branch
that's slightly bowed,
I can take strings,
tie it up to each end
so it looks like a mini bow.
NARRATOR: A bow drill,
one of the most ancient
fire-starting techniques,
works well in most environments.
SNAKE BLOCKER: Kind of almost
like playing a violin
where you're just going
to saw it back and forth
and back and forth.
NARRATOR: Friction heats
the wood dust to 800 degrees,
producing a smoldering coal.
SNAKE BLOCKER: I can do
the kindling here.
Alright.
You getting hungry, babe?
MELISSA: Yeah.
SNAKE BLOCKER: God creator
and rabbit spirit,
thank you for blessing us
with your meat.
All right, dig in, babe.
MELISSA: It's pretty good.
A lot better than the ants.
SNAKE BLOCKER: You actually
want to eat the eyeball.
Push it...you're able
to pop it out.
Actually it comes out
fairly clean.
The connective tissue
already burnt off.
The good's in here.
MELISSA: You can have
the other one, too.
SNAKE BLOCKER: Next time
you're trying one.
MELISSA: All right.
It's a deal.
SNAKE BLOCKER: She's seen the
importance of these skill sets,
she's appreciating it,
and she's accepted it,
which is great.
I always called him paranoid,
but I just realized,
you know,
the importance
of being prepared.
It brings a new priority to it,
just to make sure I'm prepared
to be able to do
what needs to be done.
SNAKE BLOCKER: People rely
too much on the government
to protect them,
especially in the U.S.
The people that
are gonna survive
are gonna be the people
who have alternative methods
of supporting themselves.
NARRATOR: Snake Blocker,
Practical Preppers
has assessed your preps.
Your nomadic bug-out strategy
will ensure
that you will always be able
to find food and water.
However, your straw filters
are only designed
to filter 20 gallons.
SNAKE BLOCKER: I do have
several water filtration straws.
We can filter up to about
500 gallons worth of water
directly from the streams
or ponds, or even toilets.
NARRATOR: Also, hunting is
incredibly time-consuming.
We recommend setting
snares or traps
to augment your food supply.
Practical Preppers
has scored your preps
in five categories
of 20 points each.
Food:
if you don't bring
supplies with you,
you will be limited to what
you can hunt and harvest.
6 out of 20 points.
Water: 9 out of 20 points.
Shelter: 8 out of 20 points.
Security: 15 out of 20 points.
Your knife skills will help you
survive with limited resources.
For this, you receive
10 X-factor points.
Your total score
is 48 out of 100.
You have four months'
initial survival time.
SNAKE BLOCKER:
Well, based on that evaluation,
I disagree with it.
I'll be able to survive as long
as needed, as long as I live.
The score should be much higher.
Having a secondary bug-out
location in the mountains
is ideal.
Melissa and I
have been expanding
our secondary bug-out location
at her parents' house.
Here we have a natural spring
that bubbles out of the ground,
extra portable
water storage containers,
set up the spigots on them
so we can actually get
a good amount of water supply.
We added hens and chickens.
That way we're able
to get supplies
for both the meat
and for the eggs.
NARRATOR:
In spite of the recent recession
and European debt crisis,
most economists believe
a near-term depression
is unlikely,
and the odds
of a global collapse
that would result in
a severe breakdown of society
are remote.