in his name is doctor joseph master
apollo and he is a creationist
he believes that uh... scientists have
absolutely no proof of that aleutian and
that no scientists can't disprove the
literal interpretation of genesis so
he's creating this so-called mini trial
where he will i'd choose all listen
potential judges
and the scientists that would adn
debate him
wud agree on one of the judges on the
list
and then they would go ahead and debate
and if the scientist wins he gets ten
thousand dollars
how okie
the so the sign this might have probable
being
orders for reuniting saying okay
genesis definitely didn't happen there
was no talking snake it's i don't know
how you disprove that
it's from his the creation of skin
pigment stability is so-so r_t_c_
student of us would but how in the world
is this guy i think he's gonna win
his case
where he's gonna prove the genesis did
have
at ok self
i reread genesis today
in the first after dot creates man-woman
right but then a second chapter what
happened that when he created because
all of the site in adams light yellow
like ten one one and bright
dot offers animals in adams like man i
really into the animal's i'd like a
female companion was afraid what initial
female companion sheila disappeared
and and dot like i decided to go to
sleep under review rebuffed retreat a
woman
desperate corporate
and apparently people are living like
nearly a thousand years at that time
i want so i know that that would be
really difficult to prove uh...
scientifically but that we again so we
come back to the guy who's good for the
winter though who knows
proving this literally have
okay you have a parking state
yet you're gonna
you know that goes with the opposing
years old
and by the way so we have today is
arguing to your right to know in all
these different cases is a copy of the
like insects
bridal
is set
will leave you with a legally doses that
so we all started inserts
haven't even had kids in the kids have
sex
emigrated ups u
but they didn't get mad at the rate
but all the good wishes for the bible
too
story about how they
so some this is a guy that believes in
the literal interpretation of that now
said like a billion times
uh... but
is yours again to say about scientists
he says may abolitionists are not stupid
people there bright
but they are bright enough to know there
is no scientific evidence they can get
uh... in a mini trial
uh... and you know he as as a contest
rules state that evidence must be
scientific which means it is objective
valid reliable and calibrated
is an interesting thing to say because
what kind of scientific evidence are you
gonna provide
on the job
there's a little thing called miracles
wouldn't do it
yet responded