I address you tonight,
not as the President of the United States,
not as the leader of a country,
but as a citizen of humanity.
We are faced with the very gravest of challenges.
The Bible calls this day Armageddon, the end of all things.
And yet, for the first time...
in the history of the planet,
a species has the technology...
to prevent its own extinction.
All of you praying with us need to know...
that everything that can be done to prevent this disaster...
is being called into service.
The human thirst for excellence,
knowledge,
every step up the ladder of science,
every adventurous reach into space,
all of our combined modern technologies and imaginations, even the wars that we've fought,
have provided us the tools...
to wage this terrible battle.
Through all the chaos that is our history,
through all of the wrongs and the discord, through all of the pain and suffering,
through all of our times, there is one thing that has...
nourished our souls...  Mom, that salesman's on TV.
and elevated our species above its origins,
and that is our courage.
Dreams of an entire planet are focused tonight...
on those 14 brave souls...
travelling into the heavens.
That man's not a salesman.
That's your daddy.  And may we all,
citizens the world over, see these events through.
Godspeed and good luck to you.
Freedom crew. Independence crew.
How ya feelin'?  Uh, good, you know.
I mean, considering I've never been this scared in my entire life. I You know
Listen. Once you get up there, you're gonna be on your own.
If anything should happen, I just wanted to  I know, Harry.
I'll, uh, try not to disappoint you.
Take care of yourself, kid.
Freedom's on the bridge. Attention in the firing room.
Oxidizer loading is complete. Independence's on the bridge.
Attention all personnel. We are T-minus two hours to the programme goal.
Hey, Harry.  Yeah, Rock?
You know, we're sittin' on four million pounds of fuel, one nuclear weapon...
and a thing that has 270,000 moving parts...
built by the lowest bidder.
Makes you feel good, doesn't it?  Yeah.
How ya doin', Oscar?  Great.
I got that excited, scared feelin'
like 98 percent excited, 2 percent scared.
Maybe more. It could be 2 It could be 98 percent scared, 2 percent excited.
But that's what makes it so intense, is it's so confused. I can't really figure it out.
Will you make mine really tight, 'cause I don't want to fall out?
I mean, almost to the point of cutting off circulation.
Ow.
It must be a comfort to know that if the space programme goes under,
you can always get a job at Helga's House of Pain, huh?
All right. Flight directors on with the go/nogo for launch.
Retro. Booster.  Go flight.  Go flight.
Ecos. Trajectory.  Go flight.  Go flight.
FIDO. EVA.  Go flight.  Go flight.
CAPCOM Freedom. CAPCOM Independence.  Go flight.
Go flight.  All right, ladies and gentlemen, it's pucker time.
Independence and Freedom, this is Kennedy firing room. We're T- minus one minute.
All crew members, close and lock your visors.
Independence, this is launch control. Be advised, we're in a smooth count.
T minus 31. You're go for autosequence start.
P.L.T.s, perform your A.P.U. prestart.
Okay, gentlemen, you're our warriors up there. God be with you.
You're already heroes. Just sit back and enjoy the ride.
We're T minus 20 seconds.
Ten. Nine. Eight. Seven.
Four. Three. Two. One.
We have main engine start.
We have booster ignition.  We're going.
And liftoff.
Freedom, this is flight deck.
Roger, Freedom. You're looking good.
We have go for Independence.  Three. Two. One.
Independence, we have booster ignition.
We have liftoff.  We are cooking, Houston.
Houston, the tower is clear. They're all yours.
Heads up, everybody. They're ours now.
All engines are go.  Keep a sharp eye out on both of 'em.
Start roll manoeuvre.
Two good roll programmes.  One down.  Independence, we have max cue.
Roger, Control. We are a max cue.
S.R.B. sep
We are singleengine, press, demigo.  Copy, press, demigo.
Houston, this is a kickass ride!
Freedom, this is Houston. Main engine cut out on schedule. Out.
Freedom, stats are good.
Independence, telemetry is up and running.  Oh, my God.
This is space! 'Course, we're just in the beginning part of space.
WeWe haven't gotten to outer space yet.
Roger, Houston. We have a visual on the Russian space station. Initiating retro burn.
Gentlemen, remember the Russian space station has been up there for 11 years.
Most of us don't have cars that old.
Now, the cosmonaut on board has been on that tin can for 18 months, alone.
So don't be surprised if he's a little... off.