Hey Jamie, Jamie, we've got our first present
for our first anniversary.
Ahh wicked, a birthday present. And it smells
like bacon dude.
Ah it does smell of bacon. What's this, I
didn't even know they made these.
It smells kind of heinous as well.
Ohh.
We should, play it.
Yeah we totally should, I found a VCR.
Oh I don't even know how to work it any more.
I can't wait to see what's in it.
Haha! Baking a cake or what?!
Yeah, yeah.
When are we going to eat this bad boy?
Err you know it's a birthday cake.
Who's birthday cake?
Err, you don't know him.
I don't know him?
No.
I don't know him? But you know him?
Yeah, I've got friends.
It's for Jamie Oliver isn't it?
It's not for Jamie Oliver, why would you say
that? Why do you think it's for Jamie Oliver?
I see some of these organic ingredients and
when do we every cook with organic.
Jamie Oliver's the type of guy to into a box
and tell you it's organic chocolate cake.
If you think that's a good guy the continue
making this cake but at least let me put my
old big mac inside.
Alright we're mailing this badboy all the
way to JO across the pond.
That's some good cake. We're bakers now Josh.
Happy Birthday and um I hope this bacon's
good by the time it gets to you.
Ahh, thanks very much man. Epic Meal Times
you're the bomb. Cheers guys, I'm going to
go and sort this out.
Over to you brother.