EDDIE HUANG: The guards
have arrived.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Kenting is the southernmost
part of Taiwan--
oceanside property right here.
And where we're at is
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE],
which is the most famous
place for seafood.
We're going to eat some
fresh seafood.
We're going to party
with the surfers.
And tomorrow morning, the locals
are going to try to
teach the kid how to surf.
Ready.
I'm hungry as a motherfucker
right now.
-[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[CROWD CHEERS]
[DANCE MUSIC PLAYING]
EDDIE HUANG: Your
man's A Swey.
He's the hombre with the
blazer and no shirt on.
Oh shit, baby!
Oh, shit!
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
A SWEY:
EDDIE HUANG:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
A SWEY:
EDDIE HUANG:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
A SWEY:
EDDIE HUANG:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
A SWEY:
EDDIE HUANG: Jeff.
Jeff is the pioneer of
Taiwanese surfing.
A SWEY:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
Check the wave.
We've got to check the size.
Check the wind.
Check the people.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
EDDIE HUANG:
This guy is looking
for bikini.
These guys looking for bikini.
[LAUGHTER]
EDDIE HUANG: Did you want
to be a surf ninja
when you were a kid?
Surf ninjas was the
hardest shit ever.
This is 7-11's finest.
We usually don't support
big business.
But we didn't have much time.
A SWEY:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
EDDIE HUANG:
[LAUGHS]
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
A SWEY:
EDDIE HUANG: Dude,
I like that.
This dude just finesses, like,
five hundred years of beef,
out of a Volkswagen.
A SWEY: My shop.
Open!
EDDIE HUANG: Yo, look at this
aspirational painting they
have here--
giant badonk.
A Taiwanese man can dream.
Yo, I feel like a 30 NT
cheese pork sandwich.
They gave me the extra, extra
beginner RV board.
Like, I could fall three
times on this board and
not fall in the water.
This is fucking housed.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[LAUGHS]
He said usually when he teaches
people how to surf,
it's a four-hour class.
But he has to compete
in an hour.
So basically, I'm
going to die.
A SWEY:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
EDDIE HUANG: OK.
I feel like you're having
second thoughts now too.
Like--
[LAUGHS]
[EXCITING MUSIC PLAYING]
-You OK?
Eddie, are you OK?
EDDIE HUANG: Yeah!
Woo!
Aaah!
When I saw the southern
Taiwanese coast, I was just
like, this is it, B.
You kind of, the first time you
get up, realize why people
love surfing, why they fucking
come out here every day, 6:00
AM and do this.
It's like that first time you
have a soup dumpling, the
first time you into,
like, fucking
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE].
There's those things that you
can't replicate the first time
it happens.
You really can't explain.
It's just--
woo!
To the gods.
This kiwi is wild and crazy.
Oh my god.
Jan's in the background fucking
asking about every juice.
Yo, my dude, my dude, for real--
like, as a Latino, we
like guava.
I love guava, you know.
I'm very, like, heavy
in the guava game.
But, like, I want to see how
dope, like, the Taiwanese
guava game is.
Because I see, like, you have
white guava, and we usually--
Latinos, you know.
[LAUGHTER]
JAN: Wow.
Yeah, yeah, exactly.
EDDIE HUANG: For real, this
is like a Taiwanese Corona
commercial, B.
-Next up on "Fresh
off the Boat."
EDDIE HUANG: We just made a
quick pit stop at the famous
Taiwanese hot springs.
And it smells like Ava
Devine's butt hole.
She ate a cum burrito.
That bitch is disgusting.
[LAUGHS]
Let's go, dad.
-Whatever.