>> ELECTRICITY POWERS JUST ABOUT
EVERYTHING IN OUR LIVES.
BUT WHERE DOES IT COME FROM?
AND HOW DOES ELECTRICITY WORK?
WE'RE STANDING BY TO ANSWER YOUR
QUESTIONS.
STAY TUNED.
"D4K" IS NEXT.
>> HI, I'M JOAN CARTAN-HANSEN,
WELCOME TO "D4K."
THE PLACE FOR SCIENCE.
>>> BEFORE WE GO TO YOUR
QUESTION, LET'S LEARN A LITTLE
BIT MORE ABOUT ELECTRICITY.
WHEN YOU TURN ON A LAMP,
ELECTRICITY FLOWS.
AND TURNS IT INTO LIGHT AND HEAT
HEAT.
THE ELECTRICITY WE USE IN OUR
HOMES AND SCHOOLS STARTS AT A
POWER PLANT.
HERE IN IDAHO, A LOT OF
ELECTRICITY COMES FROM
HYDROELECTRIC POWER.
THESE PLANTS USE WATER TO TURN A
TURBINE IN A GENERATOR, WHICH IS
BASICALLY A BIG MAGNET
SURROUNDED BY A COIL OF COPPER
WIRE.
AS THE MAGNET SPINS IT PRODUCES
ELECTRICITY.
NOW ELECTRICITY DOESN'T DO YOU
MUCH GOOD UNTIL IT MOVES.
ELECTRICITY FLOWING THROUGH
WIRES IS CALLED AN ELECTRIC
CURRENT.
ELECTRICITY JUST WON'T FLOW
THROUGH ANYTHING.
SOME MATERIALS CONDUCT
ELECTRICITY BETTER THAN OTHERS.
ELECTRICITY CAN'T GO THROUGH
PLASTIC OR RUBBER, THOSE THINGS
ARE KNOWN AS INSULATORS.
THINGS LIKE METAL WIRES ARE
CALLED CONDUCTORS.
ONCE ELECTRICITY IS GENERATED AT
THE POWER PLANT, IT FLOWS TO
YOUR HOME OR SCHOOL OVER WIRES.
ALL THE WIRES TOGETHER ARE KNOWN
AS A GRID.
POWER COMPANIES ACROSS THE
COUNTRY WORK TOGETHER TO MAKE
SURE THE POWER GRID IS FULL AND
FLOWING.
THAT WAY WHEN YOU TURN ON YOUR
TV, ELECTRICITY POWERS IT UP.
YOU CAN FIND ELECTRICITY IN
OTHER PLACES.
IN 1752, BENJAMIN FRANKLIN
PROVED THUNDER CLOUDS CONTAIN
ELECTRICITY.
YOU KNOW IT AS LIGHTNING.
STATIC ELECTRICITY IS AROUND ALL
OF US.
IT'S CAUSED BY FRICTION, LIKE
WHEN YOU RUB TWO SURFACES
TOGETHER.
HAVE YOU EVER BEEN SHOCKED?
THAT'S STATIC ELECTRICITY.
THERE'S ELECTRICITY IN
BATTERIES, WE EVEN HAVE
ELECTRICITY IN OUR BODIES.
BUT DON'T FORGET, ELECTRICITY
CAN HURT YOU, TOO.
DON'T GET NEAR DOWNED POWER
LINES, DON'T PLAY WITH ELECTRIC
WIRES IN YOUR HOUSE, AND STAY
INSIDE WHEN THERE'S LIGHTNING.
ELECTRICITY IS A FORCE TO
RESPECT.
>> AND JOINING ME NOW TO ANSWER
YOUR QUESTIONS ABOUT ELECTRICITY
ARE JOHN GARDNER, PROFESSOR OF
MECHANICAL AND BIOMEDICAL
ENGINEERING AT BOISE STATE
UNIVERSITY.
HE ALSO LEADS THE ENERGY
RESEARCH INSTITUTE.
AND KIP SIKES, OPERATION
ANALYSIS AND DEVELOPMENT MANAGER
FOR IDAHO POWER.
THANK YOU BOTH FOR BEING HERE.
APPRECIATE YOU JOINING US.
JOINING US HERE IN STUDIO A AT
IDAHO PUBLIC TELEVISION ARE THE
STUDENTS OF THE THIRD, FOURTH
GRADE CLASS.
THANKS FOR BEING HERE!
LET'S GO TO YOUR QUESTIONS.
>> HI, MY NAME IS JOEL AND MY
QUESTION IS, HOW MUCH --
WHAT ABOUT ELECTRICITY DOES THE
AVERAGE U.S. PERSON USE IN A
WEEK?
>> JOEL, THE AMOUNT OF
ELECTRICITY, THE AVERAGE
HOUSEHOLD USES IS JUST THINK OF
A HORSE.
WE THINK IN TERMS OF HORSEPOWER.
SO ON AVERAGE, A HOUSEHOLD USES
1.6 HORSES EVERY SECOND.
SO JUST THINK OF THAT AS A
CONSTANT HORSE RIDING AROUND,
THAT'S ABOUT HOW MUCH
ELECTRICITY YOU'RE USING ALL THE
TIME.
>> BRIAN ASKS, HOW DO CLOUDS GET
ELECTRICITY?
>> SO RYAN, I ASSUME YOU'RE
TALKING ABOUT LIGHTNING THAT
COMES FROM CLOUDS.
THIS IS A NATURAL PHENOMENON
THAT HAPPENS AS THE CLOUDS MOVE
THROUGH THE AIR.
THE ATOMS AND MOLECULES IN THE
AIR AND THE WATER AND THE CLOUDS
HAVE FREE ELECTRONS AND THEY GET
EXCHANGED AS THE CLOUDS MOVE
THROUGH THE ATMOSPHERE.
AND THE ELECTRONS BUILD UP ON
THE CLOUDS, AND THEY NEED
EVENTUALLY AFTER A LITTLE WHILE
HAVE TO MEET --
NEED A PLACE TO GO.
AND THEY'LL GO TO THE CLOSEST
SPOT THAT'S OF A DIFFERENT
CHARGE LEVEL, AND THAT'S USUALLY
WHY LIGHTNING WILL HIT A TREE OR
A TALL HIM.
IT HAPPENS IN THE ATMOSPHERE AS
A COURSE OF EVERYDAY EVENTS.
>> MY NAME IS MEGAN AND MY
QUESTION IS, HOW DOES
ELECTRICITY TRAVEL?
>> MEGAN, THE WAY ELECTRICITY
TRAVELS IS REALLY THERE'S MORE
THAN ONE WAY TO MAKE IT TRAVEL.
BUT NORMALLY WHAT WE THINK OF
TRAVELING THROUGH A CONDUCTOR OR
A WIRE IS THE ELECTRONS WILL
BOUNCE ALONG AND PUSH EACH OTHER
ALONG.
BUT ANOTHER WAY TO MAKE
ELECTRICITY TRAVEL IS WHAT WE
HAVE IN A LOT OF THE TECHNOLOGY
THAT WE USE TODAY.
IT'S CALLED A BATTERY.
SO ELECTRICITY CAN BE STORED AND
MOVED AROUND AND TRAVEL THAT
WAY, BUT REALLY FOR ELECTRICITY
TO FLOW YOU NEED A CIRCUIT,
WHICH MEANS IT HAS TO BE A
COMPLETE CONNECTION CIRCLE ALL
THE WAY AROUND TO THE SOURCE.
>> MY NAME IS CHARLOTTE AND MY
QUESTION IS, WHEN WAS
ELECTRICITY DISCOVERED?
>> SO WE'RE NOT SURE.
I THINK IS THE SHORT ANSWER TO
THAT QUESTION.
BUT THERE'S A LOT OF
EXPERIMENTS, A LOT OF
UNDERSTANDING ABOUT ELECTRICITY
THAT CAME ABOUT IN EUROPE IN THE
1700s.
SOME OF THE SCIENTISTS WHO DID
THIS WORK IN THEIR LABORATORIES
HAD THE NAMES THAT WOULD NOW
COME ALONG WITH ELECTRICITY.
SO THERE WAS AN ITALIAN
SCIENTIST NAMED VOLTA, AND WE
NAMED VOLT AFTER HIM.
ANOTHER FRENCH SCIENTIST NAMED
AMPIER WHO GIVES HIS NAME TO
CURRENT.
SO THERE WAS A LOT OF
EXPERIMENTS, STARTED MOSTLY WITH
STATIC ELECTRICITY, WITH PIECES
OF GLASS AND VARIOUS KINDS OF
PLASTICS AND WOOL AND COTTON AND
THINGS TRYING TO FIGURE OUT HOW
TO MAKE THOSE LITTLE SPARKS THAT
WE NOW SEE WHEN WE RUB OUR FEET
ACROSS THE CARPET.
AND THAT EVOLVED OVER TIME.
SO IT WAS OVER HUNDREDS OF YEARS
FROM THERE TO CREATING A MACHINE
THAT IF YOU TURNED, COULD MAKE
ELECTRICITY.
AND THAT'S --
WE CALL THAT A GENERATOR, AND
THAT HAPPENED THROUGH TO
PROBABLY THE BEGINNING OF OUR
ELECTRIC GRID, THE MODERN
ELECTRIC GRID, WHICH WAS THE
LATE 1800s WITH OF ALL PEOPLE
THOMAS EDISON WAS THE FIRST ONE
TO CREATE ELECTRICITY, PUT IT ON
A GRID AND SELL IT TO PEOPLE IN
NEW YORK CITY.
>> IS THAT GRID IN USE TODAY?
WAS IT THE ONE DAMAGED SO BADLY
BY SUPER STORM SANDY?
>> NOT EXACTLY.
SO THAT ACTUALLY OPEN AS VERY
INTERESTING PIECE OF OUR HISTORY
OF TECHNOLOGY.
BECAUSE EDISON CREATED THIS GRID
USING A GENERATOR THAT CREATED
DIRECT CURRENT, OR D.C. CURRENT.
THERE WERE OTHER SCIENTISTS,
OTHER ENGINEERS WHO THOUGHT THEY
HAD A BETTER IDEA AND IT WAS
GEORGE WESTINGHOUSE AND 96
LA TESS LA AND THEY THOUGHT IT
WOULD BE BETTER TO USE
ALTERNATING CURRENT.
AND THERE WAS A BIG FIGHT FOR
DECADES.
THEY USED PUBLIC RELATIONS AND A
LOT OF PRETTY NASTY TACTICS.
YOU THINK OUR POLITICS ARE BAD,
YOU SHOULD READ ABOUT WHAT THOSE
GUYS WERE DOING.
IN THE END WESTINGHOUSE WON AND
WE HAVE AN A.C. GRID BECAUSE OF
THAT.
BECAUSE THE TECHNOLOGY WORKS
BETTER FOR THAT.
THOUGH THERE'S SOME PEOPLE
LOOKING AT D.C. AGAIN THINKING
THERE MIGHT BE THINGS THAT WORK
BETTER FOR THAT TOO.
>> TYLER ASKS, HOW DOES
ELECTRICITY END UP IN
EVERYBODY'S HOMES?
>> TYLER, THE WAY ELECTRICITY
GETS TO YOUR HOME IS THROUGH A
SERIES OF WIRES.
IT COMES FROM A GENERATOR
OBVIOUSLY AND THAT HAS WIRES IN
IT, AND WHERE IT'S PRODUCED THEN
IT'S MOVED THROUGH THE SYSTEM,
IN MANY CASES BETWEEN STATES, OR
THROUGHOUT THE REGION.
AND THE GRID AS IT'S CALLED, THE
ELECTRICAL GRID, IS A CONNECTION
OF ALL OF THESE WIRES THAT MOVES
ELECTRICITY AROUND THE WESTERN
UNITED STATES, AND THOSE WIRES
CONNECT ALL THE WAY TO THE
COMMUNITIES THAT YOU LIVE IN,
AND THEN WIRES ALL THE WAY TO
YOUR HOUSE.
SO THE REALLY NEAT THING IS,
IT'S ALL TOUCHING WIRES, IF YOU
COULD GET REALLY SMALL AND CRAWL
INTO THAT OUTLET, YOU COULD GO
TO ANYONE ELSE'S HOUSE THAT HAS
ELECTRICITY AS WELL.
>> HI, MY NAME IS YOSHI, AND MY
QUESTION S. HOW FAST CAN
ELECTRICITY TRAVEL THROUGH
WATER?
>> THAT'S A GREAT QUESTION.
AND THE ANSWER IS YOU KNOW, LIKE
A LOT OF THINGS, IT DEPENDS.
IF IT'S PURE WATER WITHOUT ANY
IMPURITYING, THE ELECTRICITY
WON'T TRAVEL THROUGH IT AT ALL.
IT CAN'T, BECAUSE IT ACTS AS AN
INSULATOR.
BUT SMALL IMPURITIES LIKE WE
FIND IN TAP WATER OR THE WATER
IN OUR RIVERS, IT WILL CONDUCT
ELECTRICITY.
AND THE MORE IMPURITY AND
PARTICULARLY THINGS LIKE SALT
ARE REALLY GOOD AT CONDUCTING
ELECTRICITY.
AND IT WILL ALLOW MORE AND MORE
ELECTRICITY TO MOVE THROUGH IT.
BUT AS WE MENTIONED EARLIER,
WHEN ELECTRICITY FLOWS, IT
PRETTY MUCH FLOWS AT THE SAME
SPEED, WHICH IS CLOSE TO THE
SPEED OF LIGHT, WHICH IS VERY,
VERY FAST.
>> OWEN ASKS, WHY IS IT WHEN YOU
RUB YOUR FEET ACROSS THE CARPET,
YOU MAKE ELECTRICITY?
>> WELL, OWEN, I THINK WE'VE ALL
DONE THAT AND SNUCK UP AND
SHOCKED SOMEBODY, BUT THE WAY IT
WORKS AGAIN IS STATIC
ELECTRICITY.
BY RUBBING YOUR FEET ACROSS THE
CARPET, YOUR SHOES ACT AS
INSULATORS, AND AS ELECTRONS
BUILD UP ON YOUR BODY, YOU GET
ONE CHARGE OF ELECTRONS ON YOUR
BODY THAT'S DIFFERENT THAN
SOMEBODY ELSE.
SO THE MORE YOU RUB, THOSE
ELECTRONS TRANSFER TO YOU, AND
CAN'T GET OFF OF YOU.
UNTIL YOU REACH TO TOUCH
SOMETHING.
AND THAT ZAP AGAIN, WHEN YOU
SHOCK SOMEBODY, BECAUSE YOU
BUILT THAT UP, THAT'S A LITTLE
MINI-LIGHTNING BOLT IS WHY IT
HURTS.
>> HI, MY NAME IS KENDALL AND I
WOULD LIKE TO ASK, HOW DOES
TIDAL POWER WORK?
>> THAT'S A GREAT QUESTION.
TIDAL POWER IS SIMILAR TO
HYDROELECTRIC POWER THAT WE'RE
MORE FAMILIAR WITH IN IDAHO.
THE WATER IS HELD UP BY DAMS,
AND IT GETS HIGHER AND HIGHER
ABOVE THE LEVEL OF THE RIVER.
AND WE USE GRAVITY TO MOVE THAT
WATER DOWN TO THE LEVEL OF THE
RIVER AND WHILE IT'S ON ITS WAY
THROUGH IT SPIN AS TURBINE THAT
GENERATES POWER.
TIDAL POWER, SOMETIMES THE TIDES
WILL RISE AND FILL THE WATER
BEHIND A DAM, THEY'LL CLOSE THE
DAM OFF, AND THEN IT LOOKS JUST
LIKE A HYDRODAM.
SOMETIMES IF THE TIDES ARE
COMING IN THROUGH A SMALLER AREA
LIKE A RIVER, LIKE OUTSIDE OF
NEW YORK CITY, FOR EXAMPLE, THE
EAST RIVER, THEY'LL PUT
PROPELLERS UNDER WATER, ANCHORED
TO THE FLOOR OF THE RIVER, AND
THE TIDE WILL MOVE PAST THE
PROPELLERS.
THEY LOOK LIKE LITTLE WIND
TURBINES, JUST LIKE THE ONES WE
SEE OUT THERE, JUST SMALLER.
AND THE FLOWING WATER MOVES THE
PROPELLERS, THE TURBINES, AND
THAT TURNS THE GENERATOR.
BOTH OF THOSE METHODS ARE BEING
USED.
>> RYAN ASKS, WHAT CREATES THE
ELECTRICITY IN SOLAR PANELS AND
LIGHTNING?
>> WELL, RYAN, THE WAY
ELECTRICITY IS CREATED IN SOLAR
PANELS, THEY'RE BASICALLY SAND,
OR SILICON.
F AS THE SUNLIGHT HITS THEM THE
ELECTRONS GET EXCITED, BUT IT'S
A LITTLE MORE COMPLICATED THAN
THAT IN THAT THEY HAVE GATES
ALSO.
THAT ONLY LET THE ELECTRONS OUT
IN ONE DIRECTION, AND THAT'S
WHAT CREATES THE CURRENT.
THE ELECTRONS BOUNCE OUT OF THE
SOLAR PANELS.
NOW, LIGHTNING IS A LITTLE
DIFFERENT IN THAT IT'S ACTUALLY
STATIC ELECTRICITY.
SO JUST THINK OF WALKING ACROSS
THE CAR EXPET RUBBING YOUR
SHOES.
AS CLOUDS RUB AGAINST THE EARTH,
OR THE ATMOSPHERE, IF YOU WILL,
CHARGES CAN BE BUILT UP THAT ARE
DIFFERENT BETWEEN THE CLOUD AND
THE EARTH.
AND ONCE THAT GETS STRONG
ENOUGH, THERE'S ENOUGH
DIFFERENCE IN THE ELECTRONS, THE
POSITIVE AND NEGATIVE CHARGES
THAT IT WILL --
WHAT WE CALL IONIZE THE AIR,
THAT'S THAT BIG ZAP THAT ALLOWS
THE ELECTRONS TO GO THROUGH THE
AIR DOWN TO THE GROUND TO
BALANCE OUT THE CHARGES AGAIN.
>> HI.
MY NAME IS CHRIS.
MY QUESTION IS, HOW MUCH
ELECTRICITY CAN TIDAL POWER
PRODUCE?
>> THAT'S A GREAT QUESTION.
THERE'S LOTS OF AREAS IN
RENEWABLE ENERGY WE DON'T KNOW
MUCH ABOUT YET.
AND TIDAL POWER IS ONE OF THEM.
THE MOON'S ORBIT CHANGES THE
LEVEL OF THE OCEANS TWICE A DAY
THROUGHOUT ALL THE COASTAL AREAS
OF THE WORLD.
AND IF THE CONDITIONS ARE RIGHT,
WHERE WE HAVE HIGH TIDE AND THE
RIGHT KINDS OF HARBORS OR
INLETS, WE CAN BUILD DEVICES
THAT CAN HARNESS THAT ENERGY.
WE DON'T --
THE ANSWER IS NOT VERY MUCH.
WE DON'T DO VERY MUCH OF THAT
RIGHT NOW THROUGHOUT THE COUNTRY
OR THROUGHOUT THE WORLD.
BUT IT'S AN AREA, AN EXCITING
AREA OF RESEARCH AND A LOT OF
HOPE TO DO THAT IN THE FUTURE.
>> IF YOU TRAVELED AS FAST AS
ELECTRICITY, YOU COULD GO AROUND
THE WORLD EIGHT TIMES IN THE
TIME IT TAKES TO TURN ON A LIGHT
SWITCH.
>> HELLO, MY NAME IS MOSES AND
MY QUESTION IS, WHAT PROPERTIES
OF METAL AND BONE MAKE THEM SUCH
GREAT CONDUCTORS OF ELECTRICITY?
>> MOSES, WHAT MAKES A GOOD
CONDUCTOR IS SOMETHING CALLED
FREE ELECTRONS.
IN OTHER WORDS, IT'S MADE UP OF
ATOMS THAT HAVE A WATT OF --
A LOT OF ELECTRONS THAT CAN MOVE
FROM ATOM TO ATOM WITHOUT A LOT
OF RESISTANCE SO THAT THEY CAN
MOVE EASILY, BUT JUST LIKE A
PIECE OF METAL OR YOUR BONE, IT
DOESN'T MEAN ELECTRONS ARE
MOVING THROUGH THERE CONSTANTLY
RIGHT NOW, IT TAKES A DIFFERENCE
IN VOLTAGE TO MAKE THEM MOVE.
IF YOU CAN PUSH THE ELECTRONS
AND THEY'LL MOVE EASILY, THAT'S
WHAT MAKES A GOOD CONDUCTOR.
SOMETHING THAT'S AN INSULATOR IS
WHERE THE ELECTRONS ARE BOUND
VERY TIGHT TOGETHER AND DON'T
MOVE.
SO EVEN IF YOU PUSH ON THE
ELECTRONS, THEY'RE GOING TO STAY
IN PLACE.
>> WHY DO THEY NEED A?ID
BATTERIES?
>> ELIZABETH, THE REASON THAT
YOU HAVE ACID IN BATTERIES, OR
WHAT ARE CALLED LEAD ACID
BATTERIES, ARE THE ACID CREATES
A FLUID THAT ALLOWS ELECTRONS TO
BE STORED IN IT.
IT'S ACTUALLY AN ICE 0 TAUPE.
--
ISOTOPE.
SO THE ELECTRONS CAN MOVE FREELY
THROUGH THE FLUID, BUT JUST LIKE
THE IMPURITIES IN THE WATER, IF
YOU DIDN'T HAVE THIS ACID IN
THERE, THERE WOULDN'T BE ENOUGH
ELECTRONS OR IONS TO EXCHANGE
WITH THE METAL PLATES IN THE
BATTERY.
SO THE ACID REALLY IS A WAY TO
STORE ELECTRONS UNTIL YOU
COMPLETE THE CIRCUIT AND ALLOW
THE ELECTRONS TO FLOW.
>> MOLLY ASKS, HOW DOES
ELECTRICITY TRAVEL THROUGH
WIRES?
>> WELL, MOLLY, THE WAY
ELECTRICITY TRAVELS THROUGH
WIRES IS MUCH LIKE WATER GOES
THROUGH A GARDEN HOSE.
IF YOU'VE EVER EXPERIENCED THAT.
THE ELECTRONS ARE REALLY THE
ELECTRICITY THAT'S MOVING
THROUGH THE WIRES, AND THEY BUMP
ALONG FROM ATOM TO ATOM IN A
CONDUCTOR.
THE ELECTRONS ARE FREE TO MOVE.
SO THEY PUSH EACH OTHER ALONG
JUST LIKE WATER GOES THROUGH A
GARDEN HOSE.
>> MY NAME IS CANNON, AND MY
QUESTION IS, WHY ARE THERE SO
MANY DIFFERENT ELECTRONS THAN
JUST THE ONE BY ONE INCH PIECE
OF MAGNET?
>> THAT'S A GREAT QUESTION.
IT ACTUALLY IS A HARD ONE TO
UNDERSTAND, BECAUSE ELECTRONS
ARE VERY, VERY SMALL, AND
THEY'RE IN EVERYTHING THAT IS
AROUND US.
EVERYTHING --
EVERY MATTER, EVERYTHING THAT'S
MADE UP OF STUFF IS MADE UP OF
ATOMS, AND ATOMS HAVE THREE
KINDS OF THINGS --
PROTONS, NEUTRONS, AND ELECTRONS
AND A LOT OF ELECTRONS.
SO IF I UNDERSTAND YOUR
QUESTION, WHY ARE THERE SO MANY,
IT'S BECAUSE THEY'RE SO SMALL.
THEY'RE SMALLER THAN ANYBODY CAN
SEE.
EVEN SMALLER THAN OUR BEST
MICROSCOPES CAN SEE.
SO IT'S A LITTLE HARD TO GET
YOUR HEAD AROUND THAT, BUT IT'S
A HUGE NUMBER OF ELECTRONS.
>> ZANDER WOULD LIKE TO KNOW
WHAT IS THE DIFFERENCE BETWEEN
STATIC AND REGULAR ELECTRICITY?
>> WELL, STATIC ELECTRICITY IS
KIND OF WHAT STATIC MEANS.
IT'S NOT MOVING.
SO IT'S JUST A DIFFERENCE IN
WHAT WE CALL POTENTIAL, OR WHICH
IS VOLTAGE, SO STATIC
ELECTRICITY DOESN'T HAVE ANY
CURRENT OR NO ELECTRONS ARE
MOVING.
SO NORMAL ELECTRICITY IS WHEN
THE ELECTRONS ARE MOVING, AND
IT'S THE MOVING OF THOSE
ELECTRONS THAT DO --
DOES WORK, OR IS USABLE.
SO STATIC ELECTRICITY IS KIND OF
LIKE A BATTERY.
IT'S THERE, IT'S READY, BUT IT'S
NOT DOING ANYTHING AT THE
MOMENT.
>> HI, MY NAME IS CLAY.
MY QUESTION IS, HOW LONG UNTIL
THE WORLD RUNS OUT OF FOSSIL
FUEL TO BURN TO MAKE
ELECTRICITY?
>> CLAY, THAT'S A GREAT
QUESTION.
YOU'RE NOT THE ONLY ONE ASKING
THAT QUESTION.
THAT'S A QUESTION THAT WE'RE
ASKING OURSELVES AND WORLD
LEADERS ALL AROUND THE WORLD ARE
ASKING ALL THE TIME.
UNFORTUNATELY THE ANSWER IS WE
DON'T REALLY KNOW, BECAUSE
FOSSIL FUELS ARE BURIED DEEP
UNDER THE CRUST.
WE KNOW WHERE WE HAVE FOUND THEM
IN THE PAST, WE KNOW WHERE
THEY'RE EASY TO GET BUT WE'RE
FINDING MORE.
BUT I THINK THE MOST IMPORTANT
ANSWER TO THAT QUESTION IS THAT
THEY WILL EVENTUALLY RUN OUT.
AND FINDING OUT WHAT TO DO TO
MAKE ELECTRICITY TO POWER OUR
SOCIETY ONCE THAT RUNS OUT IS
PROBABLY THE MOST IMPORTANT
QUESTION OF WHAT IS LIKELY TO BE
YOUR GENERATION.
AND I THINK KEEPING ASKING THAT
QUESTION IS THE BEST THING WE
CAN DO.
>> AUDREY'S QUESTION IS, WHY
SHOULDN'T YOU PUT RUGS OVER
POWER CORDS?
>> THIS IS A VERY IMPORTANT
QUESTION.
IT'S REALLY ABOUT SAFETY.
IF YOU PUT RUGS OVER POWER CORDS
AND WALK ON THEM, JUST WALKING
ON THEM CAN BEBD THEM AND BREAK
THE WIRES OR POSSIBLY DAMAGE THE
INSULATION THAT IS AROUND THE
WIRE THAT KEEPS THE ELECTRICITY
IN THE WIRE.
SO THAT COULD START A FIRE IF
THE ELECTRICITY COULD GET OUT,
OR SP IN THE BEST CASE, IF YOU
BREAK THE WIRE BY WALKING ON IT,
THEN THE CORD WON'T WORK
ANYMORE.
>> FROM CAMERON, IS IT POSSIBLE
TO HAVE TOO MUCH ELECTRICITY
WHEN YOU CHARGE AN ELECTRONICS
DEVICE?
>> CAMERON, HAVING TOO MUCH
ELECTRICITY CAN BE AS BAD OR
EVEN WORSE THAN NOT HAVING
ENOUGH.
SO WHEN YOU'RE CHARGING AN
ELECTRONIC DEVICE, THE REASON
YOU'RE CHARGING IT IS THE
DEVICE'S VOLTAGE IS LOWER THAN
IT NEEDS TO BE AND IT DOES
HAVEN'T ENOUGH ELECTRONS STORED
IN IT.
AS YOU'RE CHARGING IT YOU'RE
MOVING ELECTRONS INTO IT.
BUT AS YOU DO THAT, THE VOLTAGE
IN THE DEVICE COMES UP.
SO IT WILL START TO COUNTER
BALANCE AND THEN THE ELECTRONS
WILL QUIT MOVING BACK AND FORTH.
AND SO THAT'S WHEN IT'S CHARGED.
THE IMPORTANT THING HERE IS TO
PLUG IT INTO THE RIGHT VOLTAGE.
IF I PLUG IN SOMETHING THAT
REQUIRES 12 VOLTS LIKE A CAR TO
SOMETHING THAT'S SUPPLYING 100
VOLTS, THAT'S GOING TO BE TOO
MUCH ELECTRICITY TO CHARGE THE
DEVICE.
>> CADEN ASKS, HOW DOES A
BATTERY STORE ELECTRICITY?
>> A BATTERY STORES ELECTRICITY
THROUGH A CERTAIN KIND OF
CHEMICAL REACTION.
DIFFERENT BATTERIES HAVE
DIFFERENT KIND OF CHEMISTRY, BUT
THERE'S TWO DIFFERENT CHEMICALS
THAT WHEN THEY REACT TOGETHER,
WHEN THEY'RE PUT IN CLOSE
CONTACT, WILL PUSH ELECTRONS
AWAY AND MAKE THEM AVAILABLE TO
TURN ON YOUR FLASHLIGHT OR RUN
YOUR CELL PHONE.
THE SAME THING HAPPENS IN
REVERSE.
IF YOU PUT ELECTRICITY INTO A
BATTERY IT REVERSES THAT
REACTION AND TURNS IT BACK INTO
THOSE OTHER TWO CHEMICALS.
SO IT'S A GREAT WAY TO STORE
ENERGY, AND THEY'RE STORING IT
IN A WAY OF CHEMISTRY AS OPPOSED
TO ELECTRICITY.
>> ABBY WOULD LIKE TO KNOW, WHEN
YOU PUT JUMPER CABLES ON A CAR,
CAN THE CAR RUN AGAIN?
HOW DOES THAT WORK?
>> THAT HAPPENS.
THE REASON YOU USE JUMPER CABLES
IS BECAUSE THE BATTERY IN YOUR
CAR THAT YOU USE TO START THE
CAR, HAS DIED ORS HAS RUN DOWN,
MAYBE YOU LEFT THE LIGHTS ON, OR
IT GOT COLD AND THE CHEMISTRY
GOT AFFECTED OR THE BALTIMOREERY
IS JUST OLD.
SO WHEN YOU --
TO GET THE CAR STARTED YOU NEED
THAT ELECTRICITY STORED IN THE
BATTERY TO TURN THE STARTER
MOTOR THAT TURNS THE ENGINE AND
GETS IT GOING.
SO WHEN THE BATTERY IS DEAD, YOU
CAN'T TURN THE STARTER MOTOR.
SO JUMPER CABLES LET YOU HOOK UP
YOUR BATTERY TO SOMEBODY ELSE'S
BATTERY, YOU'RE USING THE OTHER
BATTERY TO START YOUR CAR.
AND THE RECHARGE YOUR BATTERY A
LITTLE BIT.
BUT ONCE YOUR CAR HAS STARTED
IT'S GOT A GENERATOR THAT WILL
RECHARGE THE BATTERY.
IF ALL YOU DID WAS LEAVE THE
LIGHTS ON THE BATTERY WILL
RECHARGE AND YOU'LL BE FINE.
AND IT SHOULD WORK AGAIN FOR A
WHILE.
IF THE REASON YOU M TO USED
JURNER CABLES IS BECAUSE YOUR
BATTERY WAS OLD, YOU PROBABLY
WILL HAVE THE SAME PROBLEM AGAIN
NEXT WEEK OR TOMORROW AND SO YOU
NEED A NEW BATTERY.
>> HELLO.
MY NAME IS 0 EXPWREN MY QUESTION
IS, WHAT IS THE MOST EFFICIENT
ELECTRICITY GENERATOR?
>> OWEN, THERE ARE LOTS OF
DIFFERENT WAYS TO THINK OF
WHAT'S THE MOST EFFICIENT
ELECTRICITY GENERATOR, BECAUSE
THE GENERATOR ITSELF IS JUST A
WAY TO CONVERT ONE FORM OF
ENERGY INTO ELECTRICITY.
SO YOU CAN CONVERT IT --
CONVERTING WIND INTO ELECTRICITY
IS TAKING PHYSICAL FORCE FROM
THE WIND AND TURNING SOMETHING
THAT THEN GENERATES ELECTRICITY,
WHEREAS THE FALLING WATER,
BURNING FOSSIL FUELS IS ANOTHER
CONVERSION.
SO WHEN I USE HEAT TO CREATE
STEAM TO TURN SOMETHING, THAT'S
MUCH LESS EFFICIENT THAN JUST
TURNING IT WITH OTHER MECHANICAL
FORCES.
SO THE EFFICIENCY AS WE TRY TO
MEASURE IT, IS THE TOTAL ENERGY
IN VERSUS THE AMOUNT OF
ELECTRICITY OUT.
AND THE MOST EFFICIENT ONE THEN
IS THAT LOSES THE LEAST AMOUNT
OF ENERGY CONVERTING IT TO
ELECTRICITY.
>> IF YOU GET SHOCKED, WHAT
HAPPENS TO YOUR BRAIN?
>> THAT'S A GREAT QUESTION.
OF COURSE THE IMPORTANT THING IS
TO NOT GET SHOCKED, BECAUSE
ELECTRICITY CAN BE VERY
DANGEROUS.
AND IT DEPENDS WHETHER THE
ELECTRICITY TRAVELS THROUGH YOUR
BRAIN OR NOT.
USUALLY MOST PEOPLE GET SHOCKED,
IT TRAVELS THROUGH YOUR ARMS OR
LEGS AND IT CAN DISRUPT THE WAY
YOUR HEARTBEATS OR IT COULD
CAUSE BURNS ON YOUR FINGERS OR
OTHER PLACES WHERE THE
ELECTRICITY ENTERS AND LEAVES
YOUR BOY BODY.
YOUR BRAIN HAS A LOT OF
ELECTRICITY IN IT, THAT'S WHAT
HELPS YOU THINK, SO IT CAN
SCRAMBLE THAT A LOT.
EVEN SMALL AMOUNT CAN MAKE YOU
UNCONSCIOUS OR CAUSE A LOT OF
PAIN.
>> HIGH NAME IS IRIS, AND MY
QUESTION IS, DOES HAIL AFFECT
POWER LINES WHEN IT'S HAILING?
>> IRIS, THE WAY HAIL CAN AFFECT
OR ANYTHING FALLING OUT OF THE
SKY, WHETHER IT'S FROZEN WATER
IN TERMS OF ICE OR HAIL, OR EVEN
THE WIND THAT MIGHT COME WITH
THE STORM, IS THE POWER LINES
ARE SUSPENDED ON TOWERS.
AND IF ENOUGH THINGS HIT THEM
WITH ENOUGH FORCE, THEY COULD BE
DAMAGED OR BROKEN, OR THE
INSULATORS COULD BE.
SO IF A POWER LINE FALLS ON THE
GROUND, YOU WANT TO STAY AWAY
FROM IT BECAUSE YOU DON'T KNOW
IF IT STILL HAS ELECTRICITY OR
NOT.
BUT THAT'S ONE WAY THAT STORMS
OR THE WEATHER CAN KNOCK DOWN A
POWER LINE.
>> McKENZIE ASKS, CAN WE EVER
RUN OUT OF ELECTRICITY?
>> ANOTHER GREAT QUESTION.
I THINK THE BETTER WAY TO ANSWER
THAT IS TO THINK ABOUT WHERE
ELECTRICITY COMES FROM.
SO THERE WILL BE THINGS WE MAKE
ELECTRICITY FROM, LIKE SOLAR
ENERGY, OR WIND OR HYDRO, THAT
IS BY DEFINITION RENEWABLE.
IT KEEPS COMING BACK.
SO WE GET SNOWPACK IN OUR
MOUNTAINS TO FILL OUR
RESERVOIRS, AND THAT WILL BE
AVAILABLE TO MAKE ELECTRICITY
NEXT YEAR AND THE YEAR AFTER
THAT AND YEAR AFTER THAT.
AS LONG AS WE'VE GOT WATER ON
THE PLANET AND IT RAINS, WE'LL
BE ABLE TO MAKE
HYDROELECTRICITY.
AS LONG AS THE SUNSHINES WE'LL
BE ABLE TO MAKE ELECTRICITY FROM
THE SUN.
WHAT WE WILL RUN OUT OF ARE THE
FOSSIL FUELS THAT WE DEPEND ON
FOR ABOUT HALF OF THE
ELECTRICITY, TWO-THIRDS OF THE
ELECTRICITY WE USE IN THIS
COUNTRY.
AND I THINK THAT'S SOMETHING
THAT WE NEED TO BE ADDRESSING,
AND WE ARE.
WE'RE DOING A LOT OF RESEARCH IN
HOW TO MAKE THE RENEWABLE
ENERGIES MORE RELIABLE AND LESS
EXPENSIVE.
>> WHY DID YOU BOTH DECIDE THAT
YOU WANTED TO GET A JOB DEALING
WITH ELECTRICITY?
WHAT WAS IT MA THA MADE YOU WANT TO
DO THIS FOR A LIVING?
JOHN?
>> WELL, I'M A PROFESSOR OF
MECHANICAL ENGINEERING.
AND SO THAT'S NOT SOMETHING YOU
OFTEN ASSOCIATE WITH
ELECTRICITY, BUT I'M VERY
INTERESTED IN ENERGY AND HOW
SOCIETY USES IT AND HOW WE USE
IT AS A SOCIETY.
SO WHEN YOU START GOING DOWN
THAT ROAD YOU IMMEDIATELY GET TO
ELECTRICITY.
BECAUSE THAT'S PREDOMINANT, THE
MOST VALUABLE, THE MOST FLEXIBLE
USE OF ENERGY WE HAVE.
SO OVER THE LAST 10 YEARS OR SO
MY CAREER HAS SPENT TIME WORKING
IN THE AREA OF ELECTRICITY.
>> FOR ME GETTING INTO
ELECTRICITY WAS KIND OF A
NO-BRAINER IN THAT MY FATHER
WORKED FOR THE ELECTRIC UTILITY
AS WELL.
BUT WHAT REALLY INTERESTED ME IN
ELECTRICITY IS MATH.
BECAUSE I LOVE MATH SO MUCH,
ELECTRICITY, YOU CAN'T SEE.
SO THE WAY WE UNDERSTAND
ELECTRICITY IS THROUGH USING
MATH, AND EQUATIONS, AND THAT
ALLOWS US TO THEN SIMULATE OR
RUN COMPUTER MODELS OR THINK
ABOUT HOW IT WORKS AND JUST
DISCOVER HOW TO USE MATH FOR
SOMETHING THAT NO ONE CAN SEE.
AND BESIDES, IF YOU CAN'T SEE
IT, NO ONE CAN PROVE YOU WERE
WRONG, CAN THEY?
>> THE FOLLOW-UP TO THAT IS
ALWAYS, IF SOMEONE WANTS TO DO
THAT FOR A LIVING, WHAT SHOULD
THEY STUDY IN SCHOOL?
>> DEFINITELY TO GET INVOLVED IN
ANY ENGINEERING FIELD, BUT IN
ELECTRICITY OR ENERGY,
UNDERSTANDING MATH IS VERY, VERY
IMPORTANT.
BUT ALSO THE SCIENCES.
NOW, IT'S ALSO IMPORTANT TO
RECOGNIZE IT'S NOT JUST PHYSICAL
SCIENCES THAT WOULD BE PHYSICS
AND CHEMISTRY, THOSE ARE VERY,
VERY IMPORTANT.
BUT ELECTRICITY IS ALSO A VERY
USEFUL IN BIOMEDICAL AS WELL AS
BIOLOGY, BECAUSE OUR BODIES RUN
ON ELECTRICITY AS WELL.
SO UNDERSTANDING ELECTRICITY IS
PART OF UNDERSTANDING YOURSELF.
>> THAT'S ABSOLUTELY RIGHT.
I THINK IT'S ALSO IMPORTANT NOT
JUST TO BE ABLE TO PARTICIPATE
IN YOUR MATH COURSE AND DO WELL
IN MATH, BUT ALSO TO BE CURIOUS.
AND THE KIND OF QUESTIONS WE
TALKED ABOUT TODAY ARE EXACTLY
THE RIGHT KIND OF QUESTIONS.
IF YOU'RE WONDERING ABOUT HOW
ELECTRICITY WORKS, KEEP ASKING
THOSE QUESTIONS AND LOOK FOR
THOSE ANSWERS.
>> I'M SORRY, WE'VE RUN OUT OF
TIME.
THANKS TO JOHN AND KIP FOR
JOINING US THIS EVENING.
AND ALSO THANKS TO NADINE
CHAFEE'S CLASS FOR PROVIDING US
WITH QUESTIONS.
>>> YOU CAN LEARN MORE, WE'LL
ANSWER MORE QUESTIONS ABOUT
ELECTRICITY ON OUR "D4K" WEB
ONLY.
AND EACH WEEK CHE OUT MY
SCIENCE BLOG FOR THE LATEST
SCIENCE NEWS FOR KIDS.
AT IDAHOPTV.ORG/D4K.
THANKS FOR JOINING US.
WE'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"D4K."
>> DO YOU HAVE A SCIENCE
QUESTION?
>> YEAH!
>> DO YOU WANT TO WIN SOME
PRIZES?
>> YEAH!
>> WHEN YOU SEND USA QUESTION TO
USE ON "D4K," YOU AND YOUR CLASS
ARE ELIGIBLE TO WIN DVDS AND
OTHER PRIZES.
LAST MONTH'S PRIZE WINNER WAS
LENA FROM MRS. McCAMERON'S
CLASS AT GRACE JORDAN
ELEMENTARY.
IF YOU WANT TO SUBMIT A
QUESTION, CHECK OUT THE "D4K"
WEBSITE FOR THIS SEASON'S TOPICS
AND SEND IT IN.
YOU CAN SEND IT AS AN EMAIL OR A
VIDEO QUESTION.
RECORD IT ON YOUR WEBCAM OR CELL
PHONE AND IF YOU'RE AN EDUCATOR
WE'LL LEND ACAMERA.
FIND OUT THE DETAILS ON HOW TO
SEND IN YOUR QUESTION AND HOW TO
WIN ON THE "D4K" WEBSITE.
THAT'S IDAHOPTV.ORG/D4K.
"D4K."
THE PLACE FOR SCIENCE.
Captioning Performed By
LNS Captioning
www.LNScaptioning.com
>> IF YOU WANT TO LEARN MORE
ABOUT THIS TOPIC OR WATCH OUR
VIDEOS CHECK OUT THE "D4K"