The classic way of talking
about an EVA suit is a
spaceship for one.
So how is it possible for two
guys to make space suits that
historically have been built
by whole teams of people?
How is it possible?
Maybe we shouldn't
be doing this.
My name is Ted Southern.
We are here at the Final
Frontier Design studio.
NIK MOISEEV: [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
TED SOUTHERN: I moved to New
York and told people I wanted
to make body armor for a living,
and that was really my
goal in life.
And I was lucky, within about a
year of living here, to find
a costume shop, Izquierdo
Studios in Chelsea, that
actually did make body armor.
And 10 years at Izquierdo Studio
taught me a lot of
different things about a lot
of different materials.
I still do costuming
now independently.
I got started making wings for
Victoria's Secret, and I'm
still doing that now.
I actually see a lot of
commonality between costuming
and space suits.
You're obviously building
for the human body.
You want something to be
comfortable and functional.
I suppose, on paper, I would be
the creative one coming up
with crazy ideas and Nik
would keep me in line.
But sometimes it's the
other way around.
With space suits, it's
a longer process.
There's generally a little bit
more money involved, a little
bit higher technology.
But I really see it as a
continuum, and there's a great
deal of relation.
And Nik and I were competitors
in the 2007 Astronaut Glove
Competition, which is part of
NASA's Centennial Challenges,
sort of like the X PRIZES.
The challenge was to redesign
a space suit glove to have
lower torque and higher mobility
than NASA's current
technology.
With the glove, it's been
a consistent problem.
It's sort of the weak point of
design for a space suit.
It is the most functional part
of the suit, and a critical
part of astronaut efficiency.
Neither one of us won in 2007.
And I gave you a ride
back to New York
City afterwards, right?
NIK MOISEEV: Right.
TED SOUTHERN: And kind
of never thought I
would see him again.
But he kept in touch through
email, and we decided to
become partners for the 2009
Astronaut Glove Competition.
And we outperformed NASA's
current technology and won
some money.
We won second place and formed
an LLC from there.
So here at Final Frontier
Design, we are working
specifically on IVA suits now.
We're trying to meet a market
demand in the new commercial
space industry for launch
and reentry suits.
TED SOUTHERN: This is a vacuum
chamber glove box.
It pulls pressure out from
inside this chamber and mimics
that pressure differential you
would have inside a suit.
The gloves are obviously really
important to test on
their own as much as possible,
because it really is the human
interaction with space.
It's how humans get work done,
is with their hands.
But we can go in here and try
different tests for dexterity.
One of the ones that I
think is particularly
hard is this peg board.
Last time I was at the Johnson
Space Center, we used their
vacuum chamber glove box,
and inside they
had a Rubik's cube.
So I felt like I needed a
Rubik's cube in my vacuum
chamber as well.
So this is what we call the
Frontier Prime, it's our first
full-body pressure garment.
This suit was a collaboration
between the two of us, Nikolay
built the outer garment.
So this is what we call
the 2G suit, the
second generation suit.
The real advantage of this suit
is it's almost entirely
single layer.
So it is a challenge for two
guys to be making space suits
when historically it's been the
dominion of crews of engineers.
But we've made a lot of
accomplishments so far.
Obviously, we started with
gloves, which are one of the
most specific and heavy-designed
parts of a
space suit.
And we've made a great deal of
improvements over the years in
not just our gloves, but
obviously we've moved on to a
whole suit.
We're testing at levels that
NASA tests at, as far as
leakage rates, as far as range
of motion, as far as cycling,
as far as torque.
TED SOUTHERN: It's low weight.
It's low mass, which is a huge
driver in space travel.
There are generally considered
to be two
kinds of space suits.
One is an IVA suit, which is
sort of a launch, reentry, and
docking suit.
IVA is Intra-Vehicular
Activity.
The EVA suits, Extra-Vehicular
Activity, are a lot more
complicated.
They have life support generally
on their back.
They have enclosures over the
pressure garment that protect
from thermal extremes,
micrometeoroids, sometimes radiation.
Even before Americans were
going to space, they were
going to very high altitudes
where they needed protection
from the extreme environment.
And I think the most classic
case of-- the pioneer of that
is Wiley Post.
He's an early aviator who did
a lot of experience with
pressure garments.
He had a distinct advantage
because he only had one eye,
so he could turn the visor of
his helmet to one side and get
good peripheral vision.
He used pretty crude and
rudimentary things-- squirrel
fur and really thick rubber and
very restricted mobility--
and was very dependent on the
capsule that he was in.
NIK MOISEEV: [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
TED SOUTHERN: Obviously, with
NASA, space suits improved
quite a bit.
The Mercury suits were much
more anthropomorphic and
functional, but we didn't
see EVA until Gemini.
The Apollo suits that went to
the Moon were even a great
deal more functional than the
Gemini suits who only saw
limited EVA.
-I like to skip along.
-Not me, boy.
Skip.
-Well, whatever you call it.
NIK MOISEEV: [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
TED SOUTHERN: Today's current
EMU has a really
long lifespan on orbit.
It's capable of 8 to 10 hour
EVAs, through a great variety
of sizes of people.
There are females and males
who are doing work
in space suits now.
So it's come a long way since
Wiley Post for sure.
-Wave for the camera.
That's good.
All right.
NIK MOISEEV: [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
TED SOUTHERN: So I'm pretty
excited about the waist belt.
We really need to
work on that.
NIK MOISEEV: I am
so hungry that--
TED SOUTHERN: Are you hungry?
But we just ate.
So in June of this year, June
of 2012, we launched a
Kickstarter campaign to help
us support our new company,
and to really sort of announce
that we're ready to build a
flight-certified suit.
So thank you for your
Kickstarter support.
All right.
NIK MOISEEV: Give me five.
TED SOUTHERN: We were
successful.
We reached our funding goals.
But I think more importantly
than that, we got customers.
We got press.
We got people aware
of our project.
We are working now with
Zero2Infinity, which is, as I
mentioned, the Spanish
high-altitude balloon company.
I think it'll give a lot of
validation to work at altitude
and to test these suits in
flight before they start going
on rockets.
So we're really excited
be working with them.
It's exciting for us to be
around in this time where the
commercial industry is just
starting to exist.
I think there's a lot of very
optimistic people saying next
year we'll fly.
It's a long wait, but I think
it's really exciting that it's
actually happening.
And I think once the industry
gains a little bit of
traction, it will really
expand quite quickly.
It's part of human destiny
to move beyond Earth.
It may take a long time,
but I think that
it's part of our future.
There's a great William
Burroughs quote where he says
human beings are not destined
to remain human beings any
more than a tadpole is destined
to remain a tadpole.
We will evolve.
We will move on past Earth.
NIK MOISEEV: [SPEAKING RUSSIAN].