No one denies this.
My name is Sam Barclay.
I'm from Major League Eating.
We are the world body that
governs and sanctions all
stomach centric sports.
And coming up in a matter of
moments, on that very stage,
is the Smoke's Poutinerie third
annual World Poutine
Eating Championships.
There is no bigger stage
in all of world sports.
TIM JANUS: My name
is Tim Janus.
They call me Eater X. I'm
the number three ranked
competitive eater on the planet,
and I'm here for the
Smoke's Poutinerie World Poutine
Eating Championship.
I didn't do a lot for this
contest, mainly because we
don't have a Smoke's Poutinerie
in New York City.
If you're going to practice,
which we don't do very much
anyways, it really helps to
have the exact food you're
going to be eating
in the contest.
I think we're going to
be duking it out.
It's a capacity contest, but
speed is the name of the game.
It's a very quick food, so at
the end it's going to come
down to who has more
room left.
And we're all pretty big
eaters in that sense.
JIM REEVES: Hi.
My name is Jim Reeves from
Buffalo, New York.
They just call me Buffalo
Jim Reeves.
I love this contest.
I've done it all three years.
This will be my third
year doing it.
I'm currently ranked number
18 in the world.
I'm the current world record
holder over watermelon.
I've eaten 13.22 pounds of
watermelon in 15 minutes.
I'm pork rind eating champion of
the world, 50 hamburgers in
8 minutes and 100 whole
jalapenos in 8 minutes.
The first National Buffalo Wing
Festival, 10 years ago,
my brother-in-law was in
from out of town, he
dared me to do it.
I did it.
I did pretty well.
Poutine is one of the most
difficult foods to eat,
absolutely.
People don't think so, because
everybody loves french fries,
but the reality of it is
they're really pasty.
And when you try eating them
fast, all that dryness and all
that pastiness starts to gum
up your mouth, just like
peanut butter does.
So it's actually more difficult
than eating hot dogs
or hamburgers.
BOB SHOUDT: My name's Bob
Shoudt, Notorious BOB.
Most people go for
the gold stuff.
This is real pine, though,
I went for pine.
I've always been eating in
eating contests all my life.
I'm 45 years old.
Once you start getting money
to eat, you keep eating and
keep getting money.
This is a cool trophy here.
So you want to get your picture
taken with that trophy.
It kicks ass.
You've seen the trophy,
you know it kicks ass.
LARELL MARIE MELE: My
name is Larell Marie
The Real Deal Mele.
I'm ranked number 30 in
the world of MLE.
I think now that women are
more aware of competitive
eating it's becoming a
lot more equal field.
It's not just the men anymore.
The women are having equal
opportunity and awareness.
So it's not become disgusting
anymore.
It's something cool
to be doing.
And especially if you
can beat some of the
guys, it's even better.
MICAH COLLINS: They call me Wing
Kong, or the Candyman.
I am from Philadelphia,
Pennsylvania.
I'm 13th in the world
right now.
It started as a bad joke
and a lot of beer.
I actually hold the world
baked bean record--
5 pounds, 4 ounces
in 58 seconds.
This morning I did about nine
pounds of cabbage with about a
gallon of water, so that flushed
everything through and
I feel great.
I'm ready to go.
I'm stretched out and ready.
SAM BARCLAY: Let the
contest begin.
TIM JANUS: I tied for
second today.
I'm happy.
I feel like I could eat more.
It's great poutine.
I was a little conservative with
the water, so I have a
lot of space left.
But I'm happy with
the results.
It was a good contest.
BOB SHOUDT: Second place.
I'm proud of that.
It's a good contest.
I really wanted to be next to
that trophy at the end, but
it's something to shoot
for next year year.
I have to stay hungry
and focused and come
back strong next year.
JOEY CHESTNUT: I'm Joey
Chestnut, world champion
competitive eater, ranked
number one in the world.
Today I was able to come out
champion of the poutine eating
championships and dominate the
field and take home the
poutine eating title
to California.
Today I was just eating
with my left hand.
If I had to drink something I
would drink with my right.
But I'm left handed, so I was
doing all my real eating work
with my left hand.
And I just try to get
into a rhythm.
You get into a rhythm, breathe,
swallow, do the same
thing over and over again.
I had somebody behind me,
yelling at me, coaching me,
yelling at me every time
I slowed down,
which always helps.
Besides some awesome trophies,
I'm walking away with two
grand cash.
Even if there was no cash
involved, I'd love to come
here and win it again.