-Leo got pulled over.
[LAUGHTER]
POLICE OFFICER: We were getting
phone calls, doing
things that weren't real smart,
weren't real safe.
You know, in a group like
this, everything kind of
sticks out.
Enjoy your ride and have a
good time, but don't do
anything crazy, OK?
Thank you.
GROUP: [IN UNISON]
PATRICK O'DELL: Hello,
welcome back to the
"Epicly Later'd" show.
This episode is the mild ride,
which is Ruca's Vespa tour.
And we went from Los
Angeles to San
Francisco, back to Los Angeles.
And it was a really mellow tour,
like mellow demos at
like Derby Park in Santa
Cruz, and, like,
just real mellow stuff.
And so this is it, the
Mild Ride Tour.
-[INAUDIBLE]
Devouring its future.
Hey, Sean, Jimmy.
We're on Treasure Island at a
Navy base, so call me back.
All right, bye.
PATRICK O'DELL: Have you
been here before?
KEEGAN SAUDER: Uh, no.
I've never been to
Treasure Island.
PATRICK O'DELL: What
are you building?
JOSH HARMONY: Getting
that Vespa in here,
so we can get launched.
-Ha!
JOSH HARMONY: So you're
just going to stop.
Maybe you should, like,
turn to the right.
-I'll do it, but I'm
going to turn.
Yeah, I'm going to turn,
but I'm going to stop.
I'm not going to go anywhere.
[APPLAUSE AND CHEERS]
-Is this urine?
-That's definitely urine.
Urine throw.
[CRASH]
[LAUGHS]
Urine!
PATRICK O'DELL: You know this
is a mature skate tour.
ETHAN FOWLER: Of course,
yeah, in all ways.
JOSH HARMONY: If by mature you
mean totally awesome, then
you're right.
AUSTIN STEPHENS: I don't know.
I don't know how to sum it up.
I don't know, it's been
really silly.
These things are
kind of silly.
It just got banged
up a little bit.
But I think they kind of
have to expect that.
If you're lending out like a
group of Vespas to a group of
skateboarders, it's kind of
maybe somewhat expected.
That's just the--
it's just the edge of
the world right now.
KEEGAN SAUDER: Yeah.
AUSTIN STEPHENS: There's
no ocean down there.
It's just completely clouds and
just universe out there.
PATRICK O'DELL: How was
this drive so far?
AUSTIN STEPHENS: Well, pretty
beautiful, as you can see.
-[GROWLING]
KEEGAN SAUDER: Just slide
around and shit.
Just go until you loop out.
ETHAN FOWLER: Yeah.
KEEGAN SAUDER: Board almost
hits you in the face.
PATRICK O'DELL: What
about Ethan?
How long have you known him?
KEEGAN SAUDER: I think I
met him three years.
He is one of my favorite
skaters.
I looked up to him 10
since I was about--
you know, when that first stereo
video came out, I was
like 14, 15, so yeah,
he is kind of--
he is Ethan Fowler.
To me, he's fucking sick.
[CHEERING]
PATRICK O'DELL: What about
the other night.
Were you in the hotel room?
Oh yeah, you were in
the hotel room--
KEEGAN SAUDER: Yeah, yeah.
PATRICK O'DELL: --when he
was like ranting and
philosophizing.
KEEGAN SAUDER: Yeah, well, he'd
had a couple road pops,
so the conversation
was flowing.
ETHAN FOWLER: We went
to Burnside.
My first time at Burnside
was on a
fucking eighth of mushrooms.
I got it, dude.
It was the most satisfying
demo of my life.
PATRICK O'DELL: Today?
Really?
ETHAN FOWLER: Yeah.
It was fun.
KEEGAN SAUDER: It was
a fun session.
ETHAN FOWLER: It was.
KEEGAN SAUDER: It was
like a session.
It wasn't like a demo.
ETHAN FOWLER: Exactly.
That's what I'm saying.
KEEGAN SAUDER: This happened.
Hello.
ETHAN FOWLER: I think that's
seriously the longest I've
skated at a demo in years,
multiple years.
I told you that.
KEEGAN SAUDER: You
said eight years.
ETHAN FOWLER: Serious, and
I'm not even kidding.
KEEGAN SAUDER: You said it was
the first time you'd skated
more than 10 minutes.
ETHAN FOWLER: I swear to God,
that's not even a joke.
Like, it was a good time, like
goofing about, you know?
It still was fun.
[IMITATING CHARACTER VOICE]
Did I tell you about the one
time I'm at that computer, and
the last time I talked to that
girl was a bad time.
KEEGAN SAUDER: Are you doing
Sling Blade right now?
ETHAN FOWLER: Yeah, right?
Yeah, it was good, huh?
KEEGAN SAUDER: That was
so Sling Blade.
ETHAN FOWLER: Yeah.
[IMITATING CHARACTER VOICE]
Man, I'll tell you one time--
every time I took that liquor,
I came down a bad man.
PATRICK O'DELL: Hi, welcome
back to the show.
At the end of the Mild Ride
Tour, I started interviewing
Ethan a lot.
I think on the tour, I
forgot who he was.
Maybe with the beard,
I couldn't remember.
And then I'd see him skate-- and
I was like, damn, that's
Ethan Fowler.
I don't know.
He's just a real influential,
stylish skater.
I've been following his career
for a long time.
So I just met up with him and
started asking him these
questions just to sort of do
like a little retrospective of
Ethan Fowler's pro career.
So that's what this is.
The Ethan Fowler episode.
PATRICK O'DELL: Oh, don't
let him eat the mic.
ETHAN FOWLER: He ain't
gonna eat it.
Looks like Henry Rollins.
PATRICK O'DELL: I interviewed Ed
the other day, and I asked
him about you.
And speaking of Rollins, he said
when he first met you,
you were, like, really into
Rollins and vegetarian.
ETHAN FOWLER: Yep.
And a stint of veganism
as well.
PATRICK O'DELL: Really?
ETHAN FOWLER: Indeed, yeah.
It's kind of weird for a
14-year-old kid, I think.
I don't know.
PATRICK O'DELL: How
did you meet Ed?
ETHAN FOWLER: My buddy Dave
that I skated with was, I
guess, buddies with
Jerry Fowler.
I don't know what, but I'd just
gone skating with him,
and then Jerry mentioned
it to Ed.
And I don't know, but we just
ended up at the Huntington
High School.
[CHUCKLES]
And skating around and shit.
And, I don't know.
I guess Ed was into it.
ED TEMPLETON: Yeah, we we're
just skating a lot back them.
I mean, he was like a rad
kid to skate with.
And he was not just, like,
a typical stake kid.
He was interested in music,
and art, and stuff.
So it was kind of fun to be
around a kid who was into that
kind of stuff.
He was super young.
I mean, he was like, 15 or 16
when I first sponsored him.
And he was just like
beyond incredible.
ETHAN FOWLER: And then Ed called
and said we'd like to
have you on board.
So I said, I don't know.
I mean, OK, turn me pro,
and I'll ride for you.
And he goes, OK.
So that was that.
PATRICK O'DELL: No way.
ETHAN FOWLER: Yeah.
PATRICK O'DELL: [LAUGHS]
So wait, how old were you?
ETHAN FOWLER: 15.
PATRICK O'DELL: That's funny
is that you were just like,
make me pro.
ETHAN FOWLER: Yeah.
PATRICK O'DELL: That's
pretty cool.
ETHAN FOWLER: Yeah, it worked
out, I guess, you know?
ED TEMPLETON: And then the weird
thing happened with us
is, his parents moved to
Iowa City, and that was
devastating for him.
His skate career was
just starting.
He's 16 years old.
But his parents are going to
move the some butt-fuck town
and take him away from
California and the whole skate
scene and stuff.
ETHAN FOWLER: Yeah, the whole
family picked up and split and
went to Iowa--
well, except for my brother,
who was of age.
And Ed had offered to take me
in, kind of like a guardian
and all that, so I could
further my career.
But Mom wasn't having
that, so--
ED TEMPLETON: You know, don't
worry, I'll be a good dad.
And she was super pissed.
I mean, she just got up and
said, how dare you.
Fuck you.
And like walked out
of the room.
And I was just sitting there
like, oh shit, I really, oh,
this sucks.
ETHAN FOWLER: Yeah,
yeah, she was mad.
It'd be an uncomfortable thing,
your teenage son going
to live with his employer
buddy skate friend.
ETHAN FOWLER: Which I ended up
doing anyway, I mean, that
was, like, inevitable.
TOBIN YELLAND: I had never
met Ethan Fowler before.
I had driven across
the United States.
Thomas Campbell had
come with us.
And he had the idea to stop by
his friend Ethan's house, who
was, at that time,
16 years old.
And he was a really amazing
skateboarder.
And Thomas' idea was to stop
by his house, say hello to
him, and shoot a bunch
of photos.
And maybe we can use him for
Big Brother, you know, a
magazine article or something.
ETHAN FOWLER: They were coming
through from New York, and I
had met before and shot
with Thomas and stuff.
And we got along good, so they
came through to shoot weird
Iowa spots.
And then they were splitting and
said, well, we've got an
extra seat.
You want to come?
And I said, well,
yeah, but I do.
And so I just had my shit in
my backpack, like an extra
pair of shoes and a shirt.
And I was like, OK, let's go.
And so I went to the bank and
took out all my money and just
got in and split.
And that was it.
End of story.
PATRICK O'DELL: Didn't
you tell your mom?
ETHAN FOWLER: Yeah, I was
there for three days.
I called and said I live
in San Francisco now.
DAVE CARNIE: Yeah, one of the
first times I met Ethan, it
was his birthday.
And me and Tobin went
over to his house.
And he was kind of weird.
He just seemed-- he was
just kind of odd.
He was, like, playing jazz,
and playing his drums, and
listening to jazz music really
loud, like really crazy jazz.
And he was drinking whiskey.
I remember that.
And he was only 15
or something.
And I was doing speed
at the time.
And so I offered
him some speed.
And he was like,
oh, fuck yeah.
And like, I didn't know
he was 15 at the time.
And then I learned later that
he was drunk on whiskey, he
was high on speed, but before
all that, he had dropped two
hits of acid.
I don't know, obviously,
I like that
kind of thing in people.
So we had a good time
that night.
ED TEMPLETON: So that's
it, you know?
I mean, basically, he was in
our video during that time.
That was the time we filmed
for Toy Machine Live.
So yeah, a lot of that footage
from that period was like
Ethan in his new phase, coming
from Iowa City, and you can
see him in the video smoking
cigs and wearing cool vests
and things.
And within weeks of him being
in SF, I get a call from him
saying, I'm running
for Stereo.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHRIS PASTRAS: Ethan just
oozed style, man.
We always used to say,
like, it was as if he
was born for Stereo.
But I kind of had this vision
of like, man, I want to get
like some skate company going
where it's all, like, solid
skating, with big tricks, and
not all the board hitting the
ground at the same time as
the dude or whatever.
When he came along, it was
like the golden child of
Stereo basically.
And we gave him two weeks
to film that video part.
And him and Tobin came back with
this part, and they went
out like four or five times.
Like the Stereo video was like,
this is what happens
when you leave the house
with a skateboard.
PATRICK O'DELL: Did you film
a lot of his Stereo part?
TOBIN YELLAND: Yeah, I filmed,
probably, most of it.
And as well as, like, I filmed
most of the video.
And that was really fun.
He's just like a prodigy
skateboarder.
So he just came to San
Francisco, started filming for
his part, and just, basically,
kind of, like, made every
trick that he tried.
And he was just in this like--
this kind of mode, just being
like Superman skateboarder.
KEEGAN SAUDER: Skateboarding
was kind of shit back then.
You know, small wheels, creeping
at a curb, just doing
the stab and wiggle, where
you don't even ollie.
You just like, uhh.
And then, I don't know.
These guys were skating
fast and smooth.
It was kind of like a precursor
to Eastern Exposure.
Like it was the start of skating
getting good again.
JAKE PHELPS: Chris Pastras and
Jason Lee were in this very
same office.
And they were going, looking
through their Ethan Fowler
footage, and they were like,
man, we fucking--
we got lucky on this kid.
Because he was 15, he won
the world championships.
You know, I'm not worthy,
you know?
He did a couple three flips and
some flat grounds, some
front boards, some big spins,
and people were like--
in a contest, unbelievable!
Which is all normal now, but
at that time, it was all
really pretty earth
shattering.
Ethan, I think he was
an amazing skater.
He told me some really funny
things in life, I think.
He goes, Phelps, man--
you know, this is when he
was the slicked-back
fucking teen wolf.
I was like, all right,
what is it?
And he's like, everyone
else is all trying
to flip their board.
Man, I just want to
ollie everything.
And he had supreme
ollie powers.
ETHAN FOWLER: But that
was the whole idea.
Like, I don't think anybody on
that team was even remotely
interested in sitting there for
three hours trying to get
some insane thing on
a curb that they
would make once a year.
But no, at the time, I
don't think it was--
I mean, it was well received
in small circles.
But, like, for the most part,
it was like, whatever.
You know?
Who are these goofballs?
PATRICK O'DELL: More like
contemporary videos, like--
CHRIS PASTRAS: Virtual
Reality.
PATRICK O'DELL: Virtual
reality.
CHRIS PASTRAS: That was the
one we were up against, I
think, in terms of timing.
And the first girl video,
I think, had come out.
Yeah, for sure Stereo definitely
always got a strong
reaction, one way
or the other.
That's for sure.