AARON ROSE: [SYNTHESIZED VOICE]
Hi, I'm Aaron Rose.
Barry McGee is a San
Francisco-based artist.
His drawings, paintings, and
mixed media installations take
their inspiration from
contemporary urban culture,
incorporating elements such as
empty liquor bottles and spray
paint cans, found wood
and scrap metal.
His work has been featured in
solo exhibitions at the Walker
Arts Center in Minneapolis, the
Prada Foundation in Milan,
Brandeis University's Rose Art
Museum, and the Watari Museum
of Contemporary Art in Tokyo.
We sat down with him recently
for this rare interview.
In recent years, your work has
become much more conceptual.
[ELECTRONIC MUSIC PLAYING]
AARON ROSE: [SYNTHESIZED VOICE]
The geometric panels,
for example.
Where does the inspiration
for the
geometric/conceptual work come from?
BARRY MCGEE: [SPANISH-ACCENTED
SYNTHESIZED VOICE]
I became bored of the
faces and imagery.
I had been waiting for
my encounter with
abstraction for some time.
It was very slow coming.
It was and is a slow-motion
car crash for me.
I'm still spinning
out, waiting for
impact, to some degree.
AARON ROSE: [SYNTHESIZED VOICE]
What is it about San Francisco
that interests you?
BARRY MCGEE: [SYNTHESIZED VOICE]
Well, there really is no city
like San Francisco.
There are so many different
economies running right up
against each other.
It has changed quite a bit
in the last 10 years.
But somehow, it still retains
a solid population of freaks
and anarchists.
What can be better than an aging
transvestite anarchist?
AARON ROSE: [SYNTHESIZED VOICE]
Do you think the city has
had an influence on you?
BARRY MCGEE: [SYNTHESIZED VOICE]
Yes, it has.
But I'm starting to let other
environments slip in also.
AARON ROSE: [SYNTHESIZED VOICE]
McGee is also a graffiti artist
working on the streets
since the 1980s, where he is
known by the tag name Twist.
His trademark icon, a
caricatured male figure with
sagging eyes and a bemused
expression, recalls the
homeless people and transients
who call the
streets their home.
It communicates the artist's
strong empathy with people who
have been left behind by
contemporary society.
Rather than being another
graffiti artist who does
things in galleries, I've always
considered your work to
be much more about the
history of graffiti.
Would you agree?
BARRY MCGEE: [SYNTHESIZED VOICE]
Well, there is a great
history of graffiti
and graffiti writers.
I only take part in a small blip
in the scale of things.
Galleries are boring.
You know that, Aaron.
That's why there is so much
graffiti on the streets.
This trend of graffiti in
galleries will pass, and
something truly more horrific
will replace it.
All artists: Please
get back in the
safety of the galleries.
AARON ROSE: [SYNTHESIZED VOICE]
What is the difference for you
in working at a gallery, in a
museum, or on the street?
BARRY MCGEE: [SYNTHESIZED VOICE]
One is boring.
One isn't.
AARON ROSE: [SYNTHESIZED VOICE]
What do you think about
the art world?
BARRY MCGEE: [SYNTHESIZED VOICE]
It is really great.
The energy is really good,
with lots of fresh young
upstarts moving in
every month.
How else would we
have met, Aaron?
AARON ROSE: [SYNTHESIZED VOICE]
Destruction seems to be a common
thread in your work.
What is it about chaos that
inspires you and your artwork?
BARRY MCGEE: [SYNTHESIZED VOICE]
It takes a lot of work
to destroy something.
I've worked the last 25 years
building, day in, day out.
They painted over everything
I built.
Even my oldest rooftop graffiti
masterpiece from the
late '80s is gone.
Destruction is all around us.
They can't destroy me.
I've only just begun.