MALE SPEAKER: Whoo!
MALE SPEAKER: You gonna go to
a strip club in Portland?
ALEX OLSON: No.
MALE SPEAKER: Why not?
ALEX OLSON: You can't ask
me that question.
I have a girlfriend.
MALE SPEAKER: John, you hyped
to go to Portland?
JOHN ALDEN: Yeah, I'm hyped.
It's gonna be fun.
MALE SPEAKER: What's
good about it?
JOHN ALDEN: Well, you
already went and
got ones at the store.
MALE SPEAKER: I made that up.
JOHN ALDEN: You know
what's good.
MALE SPEAKER: I made that up,
but what's the best place?
JOHN ALDEN: I'm planning Union
Jack's right by our fucking
hotel, it's the shit.
MALE SPEAKER: What about--
JOHN ALDEN: Mary's
Club's good, too.
MALE SPEAKER: It's
on your shirt.
JOHN ALDEN: Been repping the
shirt the whole trip.
MALE SPEAKER: You gonna go to
a strip club in Portland?
ANDREW ALLEN: Fuck, man.
MALE SPEAKER: Greased
lightning.
ANDREW ALLEN: Yeah.
I'll be there.
For a second.
I actually won $40 today
playing dice, so.
Yeah.
MIKE CARROLL: Yes.
I just don't know if tonight's
the night.
MALE SPEAKER: Why not tonight?
MIKE CARROLL: Tonight?
Tomorrow's the demo.
MALE SPEAKER: Glad you
could make it, man.
MALE SPEAKER: Thanks.
MALE SPEAKER: So hyped.
So hyped.
MALE SPEAKER: You stoked
for the first demo?
MIKE CARROLL: Yeah.
I just don't know where
my board's at.
MALE SPEAKER: You excited
to join the tour?
ERIC KOSTON: Yeah, totally.
I wanted to take a cab right
into a campground.
Unfortunately it didn't
work out that way.
MALE SPEAKER: Dude, you
can smell the sawdust.
MALE SPEAKER: I can smell it.
FRANK GERWER: Am I supposed
to even be on this course?
Holy shit.
FRANK GERWER: This
is his fist demo.
ROBBIE RUSSO: Yeah.
MALE SPEAKER: First demo?
FRANK GERWER: Feel the heart.
Boom, boom, boom.
MALE SPEAKER: You never
skated a demo?
ROBBIE RUSSO: No, I just
don't know what to do.
FRANK GERWER: Just do what you
usually do when all these
people aren't around.
For me, that would be nothing.
ROBBIE RUSSO: That
would be nothing.
FRANK GERWER: Are you nervous?
ROBBIE RUSSO: Naw,
not that much.
I just don't know
where to skate.
Where am I gonna skate?
Fucking big ass rail.
JOHN ALDEN: Oh, this is Robbie's
first demo, huh?
Wow, I didn't even
think about that.
I'm gonna have to have
a little heart to
heart with the kid.
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
JOHN ALDEN: Make sure he's
on track, make sure
he's not too nervous.
Try to suss out some weird spots
for him to get weird on.
Not seeing too much Robbie
obstacles here, but--
MALE SPEAKER: 10-foot corners.
JOHN ALDEN: Yeah.
Yeah.
Well, I mean, they've got
concrete on the ground, but
not so much on the trannies.
MALE SPEAKER: Did you
win anything?
ROBBIE RUSSO: I did a split
on a ledge for once.
MALE SPEAKER: Hey, kid.
Are you the little guy?
MALE SPEAKER: Are you
the little guy?
What's your name?
ROBBIE RUSSO: Robert.
MALE SPEAKER: What's
up, Robert?
MALE SPEAKER: Robert!
Can I have your autograph?
MALE SPEAKER: Can I
have a signature?
ROBBIE RUSSO: For what?
MALE SPEAKER: Can I
have a signature?
ROBBIE RUSSO: Can I use your
pen after you're done?
RICK HOWARD: I saw him
signing his first
autographs ever, too.
MAX SCHAAF: Was it?
Did you catch it?
RICK HOWARD: This is his
first demo ever.
MALE SPEAKER: That's insane.
RICK HOWARD: He was
on the demo.
MAX SCHAAF: He signed
the wrong name.
RICK HOWARD: I didn't
know what to do.
I was like, do what
you usually do.
JULIEN STRANGER: And he didn't
know that there was a ball
back there, either.
MALE SPEAKER: Tony, your demo's
in the other room.
TONY MIORANA: Oh, is it?
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah, why
aren't you skating?
TONY MIORANA: Because there's
Body right there, and there's
like, [INAUDIBLE]
right there.
It's going off in here.
This is where some fun stuff's
gonna happen right now.
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah!
[CHEERING]
MALE SPEAKER: Right
here, right here.
MALE SPEAKER: Who's your
favorite skater out there?
ROBBIE RUSSO: Mike
[INAUDIBLE].
MALE SPEAKER: Mike.
MALE SPEAKER: [INAUDIBLE]
not here.
That's here.
MALE SPEAKER: I know, well--
MALE SPEAKER: Alex
Olson's here.
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah, Alex
Olson, definitely.
MALE SPEAKER: Alex Olson.
Hey,
RICK HOWARD: Alex is chilling.
MAX SCHAAF: No, he's skating.
RICK HOWARD: He's ripping.
MAX SCHAAF: He'll throw
out little like--
RICK HOWARD: Little teasers.
MAX SCHAAF: Teasers.
[INAUDIBLE].
[CHEERING]
MALE SPEAKER: Which skater
do you like here?
MALE SPEAKER: Sean Malto
and Eric Koston.
MALE SPEAKER: Sean Malto's
the shit, yeah!
MALE SPEAKER: What happened?
SEAN MALTO: I had to hard
flip the stairs.
Dude, it sucked, too.
The park was getting so fun.
[CHEERING]
MALE SPEAKER: Frank,
how come there's no
chicks in the VIP room?
FRANK GERWER: Was I
in the VIP room?
MALE SPEAKER: This is the
VIP room right now.
FRANK GERWER: Oh, that's
why there's no chicks.
MALE SPEAKER: Power
to the stick.
Over there?
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah,
because it--
JOHN CARDIEL: All right, let
me see what graphics--
let me see whose boards
are what.
Who's doing what?
MALE SPEAKER: Black label.
JOHN CARDIEL: I'm going
to have to go
with the label board.
Sorry, bro.
MALE SPEAKER: Hey, can
I have that one?
JOHN CARDIEL: No disrespect,
but that's the way
it goes, all right?
That's the way we roll.
MALE SPEAKER: What are
you doing, John?
JOHN CARDIEL: Giving
away boards to the
most thrashed boards.
MALE SPEAKER: What are those,
your old boards?
JOHN CARDIEL: No.
MALE SPEAKER: These boards
from the van?
JOHN CARDIEL: Everybody
else's boards.
MALE SPEAKER: How's it going?
ALEX OLSON: Tired.
It's kinda crowded.
I don't know.
Everyone's skating
the [INAUDIBLE].
Not so nice.
I'm not good at the
[INAUDIBLE].
I like watching Andrew.
He's fun to watch.
MALE SPEAKER: Who's your
favorite skater
out of the guys here?
MALE SPEAKER: Eric Koston!
MALE SPEAKER: Koston.
MALE SPEAKER: Eric Koston.
MALE SPEAKER: Portland!
ERIC KOSTON: Dude.
It's just too much.
This is just too much.
All the cameras.
Human hallway.
MALE SPEAKER: I'm
filming Preston.
ERIC KOSTON: I'm
claustrophobic.
This is phenomenal.
It's for the kids, so I'm gonna
keep them here a little
longer so they buy more shit.
Basically, the longer they're
here, the more money they
spend, right?
MALE SPEAKERS: Koston!
Koston!
MALE SPEAKER: All right,
what's he doing wrong?
MALE SPEAKER: He's going
on the wrong side.
The whole feng shui of this
trick, and you're going this
way on the right side
of the rail.
It's a lot, just mentally
makes it work.
Eric Koston likes to
challenge himself.
Do it on this side,
he'll do it.
MALE SPEAKER: Koston!
MALE SPEAKER: He said this kid
gave him like, the gnarliest
motivational speech.
Hey, what did you tell him?
MALE SPEAKER: Huh?
MALE SPEAKER: What did you
tell him to try to
get him to do it?
MALE SPEAKER: I said if he
doesn't get it, Sean's gonna
get his wife, his dog,
and his house.
And his [INAUDIBLE].
MALE SPEAKER: And then
when Sean landed
the trick, he said--
MALE SPEAKER: Oh, I said do it
right now, or you're a bitch.
MALE SPEAKER: What
did you tell him?
ROBBIE RUSSO: Do it for cribs.
[CHEERING]
MALE SPEAKER: There's an
American Apparel store on
like, 12th and Burnside.
MALE SPEAKER: I think
I went there today.
MALE SPEAKER: You can
just get geared.
MALE SPEAKER: And I think
I just got it today.
MALE SPEAKER: Sick.
MALE SPEAKER: From the same
place you got it.
MALE SPEAKER: You guys were
just kicking it, huh?
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah, I got this
sick ass [INAUDIBLE] jacket.
MALE SPEAKER: Dude, I
live downtown, man.
I know where all the fucking
sickest spots are.
MALE SPEAKER: What's
that shirt about?
MALE SPEAKER: Oakland.
MALE SPEAKER: Dwight,
look at that.
You see the back?
MALE SPEAKER: Oakland.
MALE SPEAKER: The lines?
MALE SPEAKER: Let's
see what I got.
MALE SPEAKER: Cardiel
got this one.
Pete got this one.
MALE SPEAKER: It's only the
dudes that are fucking in the
master's division.
30 and up.
ERIC KOSTON: This was made
by my friend Lorenzo.
And it's a grown ass
man fan t-shirt.
I mean, everybody rips, but I
think everybody has to be over
30-years-old to be on this thing
that and just fucking
ripped, so.