First up, we are looking at President Obama`s
first news conference since he was reelected
to a second term. The president took questions
from the media for about an hour at the White
House yesterday afternoon. One topic that
came up, the so-called "fiscal cliff". It`s
a set of spending cuts and tax increases that
could go into effect soon. The president and
congressional leaders are considering ways
to avoid that cliff. President Obama was set
to meet with business leaders after yesterday`s
news conference to talk about the issue. He
said he wants input from everyone.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
BARACK OBAMA, PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES
OF AMERICA: I`m open to new ideas, if Republican
counterparts or some Democrats have a great
idea for us to raise revenue, maintain progress,
make sure the middle class isn`t getting hit,
reduces our deficit, encourages growth, I`m
not going to just slam the door in their face.
I want to hear idea - I want to hear ideas
from everybody.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: We are going to leave Washington now
and head over to the Middle East, specifically
Gaza, one of the territories at the center
of the conflict between Israelis and Palestinians.
The violence between those two groups has
been increasing recently. Yesterday, Israel
launched air strikes against what it said
were terrorists targets. Palestinian officials
said there were at least 35 strikes in an
eight-hour span of time. At least nine people
were killed in the air strikes, and that includes
the leader of the military wing of Hamas,
that group controls the Palestinian government
and the U.S. classifies it as the terrorist
organization.
Israel said its air strikes were a response
to increased rocket attacks from Gaza. One
of those rockets hit a shopping center in
southern Israel yesterday. Both sides, Israel
and Hamas, say they are defending themselves
against attacks from the other side.
Finally, we are going to head all the way
over to Australia. Some people made their
way to the northeastern part of the country
this week, and they went there to see this:
a total solar eclipse that was visible over
Australia`s northern territories. According
to NASA, this kind of thing happens on average
about every 18 months. But that`s in different
spots around the world. This parts of Australia
might not see another full solar eclipse for
375 years. So, what exactly is going on in
a solar eclipse? It has to do with orbits
and shadows. Solar eclipse happens when the
Moon, while it`s orbiting the Earth, passes
directly in front of the Sun. That casts a
shadow on the Earth surface. In the outer
part of that shadow, the penumbra, part of
the Sun, is blocked. In the inner part, the
umbra, that`s where the eclipse is total.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today "Shoutout" goes
out to Ms. Chapman`s English class at Daniel
J. Savage Middle School in Modesto, California.
Newton`s first law, which says an object in
motion will stay in motion unless acted on
by an outside force, describes what concept?
Is it inertia, gravity, acceleration or thermodynamics?
You`ve got three seconds, go!
Newton`s first law of motion is sometimes
known as a law of inertia. That`s your answer
and that`s your "Shoutout."
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: An everyday example of inertia: you
are driving a car down the street, and another
one stopped in front of you. Your car will
stay in motion unless an outside force stops
it, so either a break or the other car. Now,
there is some new technology out that could
help avoid the accident. The National Transportation
Safety Board says this new technology should
be required on all vehicles. It could help
prevent some accidents, it could also drive
up the cost of a car. Sandra Endo now takes
a look at how this technology works.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
SANDRA ENDO, CNN CORRESPONDENT: This is what
federal safety officials want to avoid.
Oh my gosh! Ah!
A new technology could help. I got behind
the wheel at the Insurance Institute for Highway
Safety to see how collision avoiding systems
work. This car automatically brakes when it
comes too close to the car in front.
Wow! That is freaky! And it completely braked
on its own.
DAVID ZUBY, INSURANCE INSTITUTE OF HIGHWAY
SAFETY: It prevented a crash.
ENDO: The sensors and cameras installed in
the vehicle can detect more than just cars:
at a faster speed, watch what happens.
ZUBY: And a pedestrian out in front of us.
ENDO: Oh my gosh! A! Oh my gosh! I hit him!
ZUBY: You hit him!
ENDO: Oh no!
ZUBY: But not too hard. He probably just fell
over.
ENDO: Oh, I didn`t.
ZUBY: And at a higher speed, we wouldn`t -- we
wouldn`t avoid the crash, and that would be
a crash, but because of the braking, the crash
would be at the lower speed then it would
be without the system.
ENDO: The National Transportation Safety Board
Wednesday added collision avoidance technology
to its list of most wanted safety improvements.
It wants states to mandate these systems,
now available in luxury cars in all cars.
DEBORAH HERSMAN, NATIONAL TRANSPORTATION SAFETY
BOARD: We know that hundreds of lives can
be saved, and hundreds of thousands of injuries
can be prevented if the technology improves
and you can avoid these runoff the road, rear
end and also the side departure, the lane
departure collisions.
ENDO: Other safety systems on the market include
blind spot indicators, directional headlights
and an alert when a driver drifts out of the
lane. The insurance institute says, the automatic
breaking system is effective. The lane departure
warning system hurts rather than helps. But
it`s unclear, why.
ZUBY: They don`t seem in this earlier data
to be preventing crashes, which is a disappointment.
Transportation safety officials say, once
the kinks are worked out, the technology could
further reduce the number of fatalities, which
has been decreasing from year to year.
ENDO: Oh my gosh!
Despite the increasing number of drivers on
the road.
ENDO: Wow! That was scary!
(END VIDEOTAPE)
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Is this legit? Coral
is an example of an igneous rock.
No, in fact, it`s not a rock at all. Coral
is alive and it`s a type of animal.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Coral is a living species, it`s also
an endangered species. And a museum near Cancun,
Mexico is trying to help out in a couple of
ways: The art work is designed to help develop
new coral: and the artist who created it is
hoping his design will pull some of the attention
away from existing coral, to kind of give
those reefs a rest. Nick Parker has more on
a green project beneath the dip blue sea.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
NICK PARKER, CNN CORRESPONDENT: Welcome. To
an underwater world and mysterious figures
frozen in time.
This unique museum off the coast of Cancun
has nearly 500 sculptures sunken in up to
ten meters of water.
A growing tourists attraction, it`s also a
vital frontline in conservation as it diverts
divers from Mexico`s fragile coral reefs.
It`s a labor of love for British artist Jason
De Caires Taylor who began the project in
2009.
JASON DE CAIRES TAYLOR, SCULPTOR: I was a
diver, and I`ve been diving around the world
in various places, so I had this vision that
I always wanted to create this underwater
sort of seascape, and I was also looking into
the conservation element of it that it could
be used to create an artificial reef, started
off like a pilot project in Grenada. It started
off quite small, we just had a few pieces,
and slowly grew.
PARKER: The project called "the eye" of Cancun`s
Marine Park officials who were trying to restore
the region`s reefs damaged by 2005`s Hurricane
Wilma.
JAIME GONZALEZ, NATIONAL MARINE PARK: And
we thought that by implementing this project,
will become an icon for Cancun.
PARKER: Taylor has staggered the deployment
of the statues over a few years, so there
are some that cleaner than others.
The visual evidence of nature gradually taking
over, he has titled "silent evolution." Crucially,
the statues are made from a ph-neutral material
to attract fish and coral. And the cement
is high grade, to withstand strong currents.
TAYLOR: The world`s coral reefs are facing
extreme pressures from all sides. Issues to
do with water quality and global warming are,
you know, some of the biggest problems. This
project, obviously, can`t combat that. But
what it kind of help to do is raise some awareness
about the state of our reefs and draw people`s
attention, to, you know, the underwater scene.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: All right, we are going to wrap things
up today with a little museum matchup. Guess,
which one is real, and which one`s a work
of art. OK, it`s easy to tell them apart.
They do look eerily alike, even this guy`s
girlfriend was a little freaked out by the
resemblance when she ran across this painting
during a visit to a museum.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
NIKKIE CURTIS, MAX GALUPPO`S GIRLFRIEND: I`m
giggling like crazy, and it`s dead silent
in those museums -- and I go, do you see this
guy?
MAX GALUPPPO: I`ll be honest, at first I didn`t
-- I didn`t think it looked like me.
I feel goof for 450 -- I`ve got to-- I`ve
got to admit.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: The painting was made 450 years ago,
I guess when you are waiting for your long
last twin to show up, you have a lot of time
to just hang around. And while the guy might
have tried to brush off the resemblance at
first, eventually, he had to come to grips
with the art truth. Of course, the whole thing
has gone viral. So, if he was looking for
a little online attention, this is a big twin.
And while sometimes it`s difficult to come
up with the pans at the end of show, with
art stories, they just come easily.
That`s all for CNN STUDENT NEWS. I hope you`ll
paint us back into your schedule on Friday.