quite native to Jamaica.
Got a pot, got a banana, let's chop this up
just to help it break down. I want to go two
bananas. These are the guavas. Let's give
it a little peel. It's like mixture really,
of a pear and an apple.
You don't have to take any of the seeds out
like you do in a pear, just put the whole
lot in. Two of these, that's all I need. Boom,
in it goes. Banana and guava.
When it comes to putting in your vinegar and
sugar it's all about balancing. So the sugar
for the sweetness and the vinegar for the
sharpness.
Caster sugar, two heaped tablespoons I reckon
in there so far. Right I've got white wine
vinegar here. I'm going to put about 50mls
in. All this is doing is really loosening
it up and adding that acidity to it. Let's
pop the heat on.
Lovely. Keep an eye on it because it will
take literally minutes. Little bit of water
in there. Now I'm just going to mash it up
a little bit. I just want to see the consistency
and if I need to add any more vinegar or water.
Let's have a little look.
Sweet, acidic, the banana hasn't had enough
of a chance yet, it's not quite ripe but once
I blitz it up. Boom, we'll be there! Wonderful.
I'm going to let it tick away, when it starts
boiling, give it a minute.
Can you see there? It's just enough liquid
just to keep it all together.
Spot on, the guava's coming through, little
bit of banana now and that acidity from the
vinegar is not as harsh as it was before.
So that's ready.
if you haven't got one of these blenders,
don't panic you can have it quite chunky if
you like. If you've got a potato masher or
something like that or a ricer. Put it through
that.
Good. I want it really smooth, so I'm going
to put it through a little sieve first you
know what I mean. Oh yeah!
Now I'm going to let that cool down and it
will be ready to go beautiful.
That's my banana and guava ketchup complete.
Wonderful west Indian fried chicken, wow.
Ketchup we made, banana and guava. Little
bit of that on top.
Mmmm, that ketchup's banging. If you can get
your hands on some guava go for it guys, it
really is worth it.
Mate, I'm off.