particular visit.
(laughter)
I'd like to think it's because
everybody is excited about the
Korea Free Trade Agreement, but
I suspect it might just have a
little bit to do with your
Lions beating up on my Bears.
(applause)
All right, all right, all right.
(laughter)
Don't get carried away now.
Not to mention your Tigers
hanging in there last night.
(applause)
As you can see, President Lee
is a pretty good politician.
(laughter and applause)
He knows how to get
on your good side.
(applause)
Today I brought a good friend
and one of our closest allies,
President Lee of South Korea.
Some of you may know, President
Lee has got a remarkable story.
He grew up a little
ways from Detroit,
but he embodies that same spirit
that Detroit is all about.
Through sheer grit
and determination,
he worked his way from
the humblest beginnings.
The South Korea of his
childhood was an extraordinarily
poor country.
But he worked his way
up, worked his way up,
went to school while
cleaning streets,
and eventually went on to run
a Hyundai machinery plant --
so he knows a little
bit about cars --
then the whole company, and
ultimately was elected the
President of the
Republic of Korea.
And this is a country that's
staged one of the world's
greatest economic comebacks
that we've ever seen.
So President Lee knows what it's
like to go through tough times.
He knows what it's like when
folks have counted you out.
And he knows what it's like
to make a big comeback.
So with that, I want to welcome
President Lee to Detroit and
have him say just a few words.
(applause)
President Lee:
Thank you.
(speaking in Korean)
(as translated in English)
Folks, I'm a little bit
shorter than President Obama,
so I'm going to
adjust the microphone.
(laughter)
I hope you'll understand.
(speaking in Korean)
(as translated in English)
Well, first of all,
ladies and gentlemen,
it's a great pleasure visiting
your factory here in Detroit
along with one of my closest
friends, President Obama.
(speaking in Korean)
(as translated in English)
Well, folks, as you know, the
global economy is going through
some tough times, and so there's
one thing on the minds of both
President Obama and
I, and that is jobs.
It is about creating
good, decent jobs,
and it is about
keeping those jobs.
And this is what keeps us awake.
(applause)
(speaking in Korean)
(as translated in English)
Ladies and gentlemen, before
I came here to see you,
I just had a brief tour given
to me by the members of this
factory and I heard
about the history,
and I also heard about the
danger of how this factory was
on the brink of being closed.
But now, as you can see, we
have so many people here,
like all of you here working
here and earning a good living.
And I think more than anyone
else here in this factory,
I think it's President Obama
who's the happiest man to see
this factory being so
energetic and enthusiastic.
(applause)
(speaking in Korean)
(as translated in English)
Ladies and gentlemen, it was
three years ago when I first met
with President Obama, and back
then I still remember how we
talked about a lot of things.
And one of the things that was
on President Obama's mind was
how to revive the U.S.
automotive industry.
Because we all know that the
U.S. automotive industry was,
and is, the leader in the
world, and President Obama was
concerned what he can do to
revive Motor City and the United
States automotive industry.
And we talked a lot about that.
And, folks, I know a few things
about automobiles because back
when I was in the
private sector,
I used to build cars myself.
So I know a thing or
two about automobiles,
and I think perhaps this was
the reason why President Obama
raised the subject.
But we talked a lot about
how to revive the U.S.
automobile industry.
(speaking in Korean)
(as translated in English)
Ladies and gentlemen, President
Obama just briefly talked about
my past, how I really worked
hard throughout my life.
And I was once just like you
-- I did work in factories,
and I was also in the
boardroom, as well,
as a CEO of one of the
largest companies in Korea.
But one thing I learned
throughout my experience in my
life is this: During
times of challenges,
when you're faced with
difficulties and if you want to
create good jobs and
maintain these good jobs,
there's only one thing and the
surest way to do that is for the
workers and for the
managers to work together.
It is about
cooperating together,
and that is the surest way to
ensure good jobs and for you to
keep your jobs.
(applause)
(speaking in Korean)
(as translated in English)
And, ladies and gentlemen, we
are here with President Obama
because when I was a worker I
knew that, more than anything,
for all of us to enjoy good life
is for all of us to have a good,
decent job.
And I know how important it
is for anyone to have a good,
decent job.
And the factory here --
as I was looking around,
I felt once again how important
it is for all of us to work
together because I know that
three years ago GM Korea and GM
Orion, you guys worked together
to set up this factory.
And today, you are building
models here and you're
manufacturing cars
that three years ago,
GM Korea and your company
has been working together.
And that is the reason
why I came here,
so I can see with my own eyes
the good work that all of you
are doing here.
(applause)
(speaking in Korean)
(as translated in English)
Folks, when I was President, as
soon as I became President of
Korea, I visited a GM Korea
factory not once, but twice,
which was quite unusual for the
President of Korea to do so.
But I came here today -- and as
I watch the factory and I took
on a tour, I was very, very --
deeply impressed by the way
you're operating this factory.
I was impressed by the
fact that this factory is
very pro-environment.
You take care of
the environment.
Also you've adopted the
latest IT technology so that
efficiency is up.
You have the highest standards,
and you're building excellent
cars here in this factory.
And I am confident that this
factory is going to continue,
and it's going to
make good cars,
and your lives are
going to be good.
And I'm sure -- and I'm
confident in the future.
(applause)
(speaking in Korean)
(as translated in English)
Lastly, folks, I just want to
say one thing before I go.
(speaking in Korean)
(as translated in English)
As you know, the KORUS FTA
will soon be implemented.
(speaking in Korean)
(as translated in English)
I know, folks, that some of you
here may think that with the
implementation of the KORUS FTA,
that somehow your jobs may be
exported or go somewhere else.
But let me tell you one
thing -- that is not true.
(applause)
I am here with President Obama
today because I want to give
this promise to you, and that is
that the KORUS FTA will not take
away any of your jobs.
Rather it will create more
jobs for you and your family,
and it is going to
protect your jobs.
And this is the pledge
that I give you today.
(applause)
(speaking in Korean)
(as translated in English)
Soon, folks, Motor City is
going to come back again,
and it's going to
revive its past glory.
And I have all the confidence
in the world that you are going
to do that.
(in English)
Thank you.
(applause)
President Obama:
Give President Lee a
big round of applause.
(applause)
All right.
Well, thank you, President Lee.
Thank you, to everybody who
has joined us here today.
A couple of people I
just want to mention.
First of all, the CEO of General
Motors, Dan Ackerson, is here.
Where is Dan?
(applause)
There he is.
The UAW President, one of the
key people who helped make this
agreement possible -- that
is my dear friend, Bob King.
(applause)
And my U.S. Trade
Representative,
who spent a lot of long nights
with his Korean counterpart --
Ron Kirk is in the house.
(applause)
I just want to follow up
President Lee's remarks with a
few words about what the Korea
Free Trade Agreement will mean
for American jobs and
for the American economy.
In the last decade, we became a
country that was known for what
we bought and what we consumed.
And a whole bunch of goods
poured in here from all around
the world, and we spent a lot of
money and took on a lot of debt,
in a lot of cases,
to buy those goods.
But it didn't necessarily
produce a lot of jobs here in
the United States.
So when I took office, I was
determined to rebuild this
economy based on what this
country has always done best --
not just buying and consuming,
but building; making things,
selling those goods
all around the world,
stamped with three proud
words: Made in America.
(applause)
And that's why one of the
first decisions that I made as
President was to save the U.S.
auto industry from collapse.
(applause)
There were a lot of politicians
who said it wasn't worth the
time and wasn't worth the money.
In fact, there are some
politicians who still say that.
Well, they should come tell that
to the workers here at Orion.
Audience:
Yes!
President Obama:
Because two years ago it looked
like this plant was going to
have to shut its doors.
All these jobs would
have been lost.
The entire community would
have been devastated.
And the same was true
for communities all across
the Midwest.
And I refused to
let that happen.
(applause)
So we made a deal with
the auto companies.
We said if you're willing
to retool and restructure,
get more efficient, get
better, get smarter,
then we're going to
invest in your future --
because we believe in
American ingenuity.
Most importantly, we
believe in American workers.
(applause)
And today, I can stand
here and say that the
investment paid off.
(applause)
The hundreds of thousands of
jobs that have been saved made
it worth it.
Audience:
Yes!
President Obama:
An American auto industry that's
more profitable and competitive
than it's been in
years made it worth it.
(applause)
The taxpayers are being repaid.
Plants like this are
churning out groundbreaking
fuel-efficient cars
like the Chevy Sonic --
the only one of its kind that's
made and sold in the United
States of America.
(applause)
And for folks who
haven't tried it,
you've got to sit in that car.
There's a lot of room in there.
(laughter)
Felt -- even for a pretty tall
guy like me, I felt pretty good.
They took away the keys, though.
Secret Service
wouldn't let me --
(laughter)
-- I checked in the dash.
It wasn't there.
Now, here's the thing.
We live in a global economy, and
that means most of the potential
customers for American companies
like GM won't just be here in
the United States; they'll
be all around the world.
And the more goods and
services we sell abroad,
the more jobs we
create here at home.
(applause)
In fact, every $1 billion in
exports supports thousands of
American jobs.
And that's why I've set a goal
of doubling our exports -- and
that's a goal that
we're on track to meet.
That's why we worked
with Panama and Colombia,
as well as South Korea, to
resolve outstanding issues with
these trade agreements, and
that's why I pushed Congress to
pass them as soon as possible.
(applause)
Now, Korea is one that
is critically important,
because understand Korea
has 50 million people;
it's one of the fastest-growing
countries in the world.
It's one of our closest allies
and our closest friends.
And -- President Lee and I
talked about this when we had
dinner the other night -- our
trade is basically balanced
between the United
States and Korea.
They buy as much stuff from
us as they sell to us --
and that's how fair and free
trade is supposed to be.
It's not a one-sided
proposition.
(applause)
That's how trade
is supposed to be.
And I know President Lee
doesn't mind me saying this,
even though he's a Hyundai guy.
(laughter)
If Americans can buy Kias
and Hyundais from Korea,
then I know Koreans should be
able to buy some Fords and
Chryslers and Chevys that are
made right here in the United
States of America.
(applause)
The other thing
that happened was --
this took a little longer than
some people expected because I
wasn't going to sign
just any trade deal.
President Lee wasn't either.
We had to work hard to
reach an understanding.
It was like a scene
from a GM dealership,
where folks are negotiating
about the heated seats and the
extended warranty, and you're
going back and forth and trying
to figure how does it fit
together so that it works
for everybody.
But when all was said and done,
President Lee and I walked away
with a trade agreement that
is a win-win for both of
our countries.
(applause)
Here in the United States, this
trade agreement will support at
least 70,000 American jobs.
It will increase exports.
It will boost our economy by
more than our last nine trade
agreements combined.
And as I said, the good thing is
we've got a balanced situation.
It's not just a matter of folks
sending a bunch of stuff here.
Koreans are also buying
American products.
That's what makes it a win-win.
(applause)
And by the way, I also held out
on sending this agreement to
Congress until they promised to
renew a law called the TAA --
Trade Adjustment Assistance --
that helps American workers
who've been affected by global
competition so that they are
able to help transition.
(applause)
Now, it's because of
all these benefits --
it's because of all these
benefits that this trade
agreement won the support
of business and labor,
from automakers
and auto workers,
from Democrats and Republicans.
That doesn't happen very often.
And it was good to finally see
both parties in Congress come
together and pass legislation
that is good for the American
people -- an agreement that will
not only build on our strong
economic relationship that's
been existing for years to come,
but also promises, as
we've seen at this plant,
the capacity for us to exchange
ideas and technologies and
systems, which will improve
productivity on both sides.
Nearly a decade ago, when a
Korean business named Daewoo
Motors went bankrupt, it was
General Motors that stepped in
and saved that company, which
is now known as GM Korea.
And years later, it was the
engineers from GM Korea who
helped make the
Chevy Sonic possible,
and the collaboration with that
company that's helped save this
plant and these
17,050 -- 1,750 jobs.
So on a larger scale, the closer
economic ties between the United
States and Korea are going
to lead to more jobs,
more opportunity
for both nations.
(applause)
Already, Korean investment
-- and by the way,
it's not just in
the auto industry.
Already, Korean investment is
creating jobs here in Michigan,
with LG Chem planning to make
lithium ion batteries in
Holland, Michigan; and Hyundai
manufacturing suspension modules
in Detroit; and Mando opening
a new research and development
center for brakes
and steering in Novi.
In Korea, American businesses
are going to be pursuing those
same investments
and opportunities.
So it's truly a win-win
for everybody involved.
So I just want to say thank
you to President Lee for his
cooperation and
for his leadership.
I want to thank the members of
Congress who fought so hard to
get this done -- especially
the delegation from this state.
I want to especially thank the
people of Detroit for proving
that, despite all the
work that lies ahead,
this is a city where a great
American industry is coming
back to life --
(applause)
-- and the industries of
tomorrow are taking root,
and a city where people are
dreaming up ways to prove all
the skeptics wrong and write the
next proud chapter in the Motor
City's history.
(applause)
And that's why I
came here today.
Because for every cynic that's
out there running around saying
it can't be done, there are a
whole bunch of folks that are
saying, "Yes, we can."
(applause)
Yes, times are tough.
Times are tough and they've been
tougher in Detroit than just
about anyplace else.
But we've made it through
tough times before.
We do not quit.
We've rolled up our sleeves.
We remembered our history.
And we said to ourselves there's
nothing that we cannot do when
we're willing to do it together.
You are all a testimony
to the American spirit.
(applause)
These cars are a testimony
to the American spirit.
And if we can take that same
spirit and apply it across the
board to all the
challenges we face,
there is nothing
that we cannot do.
God bless you.
And God bless the United
States of America.
Thank you.
(applause)