According to a report by the United Nations, since 1947
more than 150 million people have been witnesses to UFO
sightings throughout the world. More than 20,000 of those
have been documented landings.
A Roper poll conducted in the United States reported that
70% of the U.S. population believe that the government is
not telling the public everything it know about UFOs and
extraterrestrials.
We're dealing with the biggest
story of the millennium.
Visits to planet earth
by alien spacecraft.
Successful cover-up
of the best data.
Bodies and wreckage!
For 58 years.
The bottom line is
I don't believe
the claim of the
Air force that...
all sightings can
be explained.
This is the
biggest secret
in the history
of the human race
and particularly in
the history
of modern
government.
We are being engaged
as a planet and
as a species by
other beings.
The Canadian government
is how I actually proved
that the U.S. government was
covering up their collection
of UFO sightings
and records.
America and Britain
had made it very clear,
to allot of countries who have
the same sort of sightings
and the same resources,
that this is something that
they better
not let out.
Not until we
say it's OK.
If we would get off
of this 'ego-trip',
this western scientific 'ego-trip',
we would not become the virus
of the universe
that we are.
Nobody really
wants us out there.
The dependence on oil
could be ended over night.
We're being slowly conditioned to
understand that there is life
outside this planet and
that we probably live in a
universe and a galaxy,
teeming with life.
I had my own UFO sighting and
said, well, case closed.
There's nothing like seeing
one for yourself
to end the debate.
Are we absolutely sure that we
are not alone in this universe?
We invite you now to come
with us upon a great
and wondrous journey.
An adventure, perhaps,
into your very own
past
present
and future.
See and hear the real stories
and most importantly
be introduced to
the actual individuals
who have volunteered to come
forward to speak the truth.
Do Flying saucers exist?
Are extraterrestrials real?
Is there a government cover-up?
For nearly 60 years,
denial has been the only
official position of the
governments of the world,
relative to UFOs,
alien abductions
and extraterrestrial
contactee reports.
Endless debates
have raged over the
thousands of documented
cases, that have been
brought forward without
official recognition.
Some have been
monumental incidents
involving 100's or even
1000's of people.
A flying disc crashed.
The debris and alien bodies were flown to
Wright Field Air force Base, in Dayton, Ohio.
A triangular shaped object
illuminated the entire
forest with white light.
The object had a
pulsing red light on top
and a bank of blue
lights underneath.
It left ground traces, and
radioactive anomalies.
This was a multiple witness
sighting by military personnel.
100's of reports
of lighted objects
frequently described as
enormous and triangular in shape.
Air force F16s chased
many of these objects.
The Belgian government cooperated
with civilian UFO investigation.
A huge V shaped object
hovered over Phoenix
for 10 to 15 minutes,
observed by tens of
thousands of people.
Hundreds of objects
appearing alone and in clusters
appear throughout Mexico,
observed by tens of
thousands of people.
Flying saucers are real.
On the Blackvault you
can download documents
that prove that the United
States Air Force bases
have been breached by
UFOs, (their restricted airspace.)
That missile silos have
mysteriously been shut down
due to UFOs hovering
over the base.
I think you download
that and you read it,
err, you conclude,
yeah, OK. UFOs pose
a national security threat
to the U.S. government.
In 1952 I was
an 8th grader
and old enough to
read for myself
the big screen
headlines that July about
UFOs flying over
the nation’s capitol,
and the air force planes not
being able to catch them.
They're there, and
they're paying attention.
Incidents happened in the
Soviet Union before it collapsed
Incidents happened all
over the northern U.S.
at I.C.B.M. bases,
where they came down
hovered over the silos
and played hell with
the electronics.
Pictures were taken.
Hundreds of witnesses
watched them.
It's highly classified,
you'll never hear about it.
except from whistleblowers
and bigmouths like me!
While I was attending
Northrop Aeronautical Institute
and working for
Douglas Aircraft in
El Segundo, California.
I had heard about George
Adamski in one of the
Sunday newspapers.
He had his story and
his pictures of contacts
plus pictures
of his ships.
Well I had, by that
time, seen so many
during the day
and the night
that I felt
I would like to go up
and meet this gentleman.
On the weekend he
would entertain people
who had come
to see him.
Military people,
engineers, scientists.
People from all
walks of life.
He had taken some
beautiful pictures of the
scout craft as well
as the carrier ships.
I went up
to see him.
He had a 6 inch
telescope that he used
to take the pictures
of the flying saucers.
And in using that scope,
when I had finished
I was just about to take
my eye off the eyepiece
when there was a
blue/white streak
that went by
and I jerked my head up to
see if I could see it and I didn't.
I looked at his 15
inch telescope dome
which was a couple of
hundred yards from his house
and there was a BIG
flare of blue/white light
and then it kind of closed
back down, no noise.
At first I thought it was
an explosion, but it
was a little
slower than that.
And there was an
elliptical flying saucer
Looked to me like it was
hovering above the ground.
So I heard it
increase its frequency
and it got brighter
and brighter,
and it was really
pretty hard to look at.
And it shot
straight up,
until it looked like
one of the stars.
If you've ever been to Mount
Panama at night, on a dark night,
boy they're
big and bright!
And it stopped for an instant, and then
it shot over the horizon over San Diego.
We have more than 1 witness
who have been involved in the
tracking of these
objects on radar.
and many
people say,
well look if this
stuff is real,
why are there
no radar reports?
I said, we have them!
We actually have
the radar tapes!
From the
F.A.A.!
This is not just UFOs,
and this is not just not
being visited by
guys from other planets.
I was to learn later that
our security,
our intelligence
people,
our military people,
concluded and learned,
we're not merely dealing with
inter-planetary visitation.
We were being visited by
guys from other star systems.
Which, technologically we
know what that means.
They're not just from another like planet
like Venus or Mars or somewhere!
These guys are
from other stars.
I’m convinced after
studies since 1958
that the evidence
is overwhelming
and planet earth
is being visited by
intelligently controlled
extraterrestrial spacecraft,
in other words, some
UFOs are alien spacecraft.
Most are not, I don't
care about those!
Most isotopes
aren't fissionable,
I don't care about
the ones that aren't,
if I'm going to
build a reactor!
If somebody who had the
clearance to carry nuclear weapons
or launch nuclear weapons
saw these objects
over a nuclear facility
and reported it, and have
documents to prove it happened
this is dispositive
that's what someone who
is wanting to look into this
who says, well, could this really
be true and I don't know about it?
They need to look at that,
and we've assembled it.
We have a 600
page book of
top secret documents and the
transcripts of these witnesses.
We have videotape.
So I began watching the newspapers
for any newspaper reports,
I started buying magazines that
had a UFO article in the magazine
and collecting these and
from those I would
get names and addresses.
And I often called the people
that wrote the articles to get them.
Then I would go interview
those people myself,
and if they
took pictures,
then I would try to get
a copy of the pictures.
and frequently did!
And then I
began,
trading the pictures that I already had
with other people that had pictures,
to get more
pictures, and
eventually built a library
of pictures, probably
the largest in private
hands in the world
its over 4000,
pictures of real UFOs.
Now, if I can collect
that many alone,
as a single individual
working by myself,
how many pictures do you
think the government has got,
when every government employee
is a potential investigator,
and every agent is a
trained investigator,
all collecting and contributing
to the government files
they must have
hangers full of pictures!
What Air force manual
10-206 says is that
a U.S. Air force pilot,
who sees a UFO.
Has to report it in a
particular way and manner.
They outline in this form,
exactly how to report it.
They say, list
the size.
The shape.
Direction of travel.
How big the
object was.
What were the
wind conditions like?
And you go
through this big form,
and say, you know,
your UFO sighting.
The manual then
goes on to state
that you have
to forward this
to the NORAD installation.
This is that one Air
force base that claims
Oh no, we haven't collected
these things since 1969.
The problem is
that this form
was last updated in
October of 2004.
In 1977 I proposed and
became a director of a
proposed extraterrestrial
communications study
done in conjunction with the
Jimmy Carter Whitehouse.
Jimmy Carter, of course,
had had a close encounter
with a UFO, in the company of
10 members of the Leary
Georgia Lions Club in 1969
while he was running
for governor of Georgia.
While he was governor
of Georgia in 1973,
he had filed an official
UFO report, it's now
on the internet, so
everybody can see it.
The 1976
U.S. Presidential campaign
was extraordinary,
because it was waged
between Jimmy Carter,
on the one hand, he's
had a close encounter.
And the first campaign,
waged on a platform,
which included a
disclosure plank, of sorts.
Jimmy Carter was asked,
on various occasions,
and this is documented.
Once elected,
would he open up
the extraterrestrial
UFO files.
And he said:
YES
HE WOULD.
We have over 450 military
and intelligence witnesses.
Some are, they
range from,
Generals and Brigadier Generals.
To Air Traffic Controllers and
Strategic Air Command personnel,
in the Air force.
To civilian people
in the F.A.A.
The Federal Aviation
Administration.
To Astronauts and Cosmonauts.
And it's an enormous database of,
of people who have up close
and personally seen
UFOs or worked
in those projects,
in their capacity as a
government or military person.
Even with the massive
amount of pressure
governments can exert to
maintain the ongoing cover-up,
people continue to
come forward and tell
what they have
personally experienced.
Whoosh! - Like that!
15 miles in a
fraction of a second.
I disengaged the autopilot
to push the nose
over because
we were on a
collision course.
And when I did,
I just saw it head-on. It
was 300 feet in diameter.
We knew that, but we
had only known that
because somebody was
telling us, 300 feet in diameter!
So at that time, I
heard a hell of a noise!
and I said to Fred,
What the hell
was that?
He said:
Well, the navigator and
the radioman ducking,
fell, hit their head,
one hit, hurt their arm,
they were scrambling on the
deck, so a hell of a noise!
I thought it had hit
us underneath!
So I said, well, where
in the hell did it go?
And Fred said, it's right
over to the right.
I couldn't see it,
so it drifted far.
About 5 miles away,
It never got
to the altitude
that we were at.
A few hundred
feet below.
I begin to
watch it, well,
we knew then it was
a friendly encounter,
it just wanted
us to see it!
So then I went to engage
the autopilot again.
The magnetic compass
was going like this!
and the Bird Dogs, which
is a directional finder,
Two of the Bird Dogs are
pointing right at this thing,
just vibrating like this!
And it was allot of the
electrical things in the airplane,
that went haywire!
So, I told Fred
Did you see that coming?
He said, as it was coming
closer it was doing this!
And so, I went back to the
vacuum operated desk
The whole airplane was vacuum operated
and hydraulically operated controls,
so I'd go back
to that side.
So then we'd sit there
and watch it for a while,
because it just paced
us, stayed with us!
And so the other crew
knew how to land
the large engines
so I was sent back
and they came forth.
Al Jones,
which was the Regional
Plane Commander,
took my seat.
And was still there.
He was watching it.
And as I was
walking back off,
he decided he was
going to chase it!
And so he disengaged
the autopilot!
When I get
back off,
I wanted to see how the
passengers were doing.
They were all on
the right hand side.
they could see it
underneath the wing!
And then I
thought, Oh hell!
I recognized the
doctor back there
He was a
psychiatrist
out of the Thesdon
Naval hospital.
Plus a lot of
other things.
So I said, I had better
talk to him first.
Carnet would say:
Did you see what we
saw back there Doctor?
And he grinned at me and
looked at me straight in the eyes,
and he says,
yeah that was
a flying saucer!
I didn't look
at it!
I don't believe
in such things!
When I was
16 years old
I was walking down the
street in Arlington, Virginia
and saw 7 red light type
UFOs over Washington,
that made headlines
around the world,
and, since then,
I have seen
8, alien vehicles
on 8 occasions.
The sightings I've had,
are more,
things flying right by,
or blueish green orb things!
I've had 5 sightings.
I've never reported them.
Because I don't
need the grief.
But the trick is,
you know
you can't mention
the company name
or be a company
uniform.
Two of my friends,
excellent pilots, one of
them was a famous pilot,
and yet, they
both got fired
for doing interviews
like this,
but they were in uniform.
Since I've been
a child
I'm looking up
into the sky thinking,
is there more than
just us human beings,
in this huge
universe?
Now I do believe there
is more life forms.
Different life forms.
And more
dimensions
than we
can perceive.
I've had several
sightings.
Probably, the
closest sighting,
would have been,
back in 1974.
I was
driving back,
between Ottawa
and Montreal,
going towards
Montreal.
I remember going
on the highway,
and we came
within, literally,
probably, several
hundred feet
of a huge,
huge ship!
And at first...
you know, we were
driving away here,
and I'm thinking,
Am I really
seeing this?!?!
And we slowed down.
And sort of
peeked out.
and an enormous,
enormous ship,
I would have
to say,
that it was 2 or
3 times the size
of a 747!
And it completely, silently
glided over, across the highway
and we saw it go
off into the distance.
So there was
no mistaking
that that was not
anything at that time
that would have existed
conventionally or militarily.
I was a Lieutenant from
the Bulgarian Air force.
My plane was
the MIG 21.
What I believe?
I believe there is
much more going on
than we can see
with our naked eye.
Being in the 3rd Battalion,
7th Marine regiment,
we were pretty active, we
were on the East coast
in an area called,
'The Punchbowl'.
Which is just down the road
from Heartbreak Ridge.
We had a lull in
the fighting, so,
we just sat around
and played poker.
And somebody
looked up and said,
What the heck is that!?
and we all looked up.
and there was err, it look
for all of the world,
like a chrome
hubcap,
sitting up
above us.
And if you
looked at it
it kind of had a
watery, shimmery look
and a little bit of a
blueish white periphery.
And from time to time,
it would appear to be
elliptical and
sometimes circular.
So I imagine it was
rocking a little bit.
There was just
a hint of a dome
sometimes on it.
Well we
watched it,
and our Colonel came
out and took a look at it,
and he made
a phone call.
Pretty soon, 4 F86 D model,
saber jets came out,
and they tried to
get to the object,
and it appeared that
they hit some barrier,
which you
couldn't see,
because they would
stall out and do a
one and a half turn spin and
then pull out at the bottom.
The flying saucer
finally decided to leave,
and it got very,
very bright.
And it was pretty difficult
to look directly at it.
But it rose straight up and
it went through the overcast.
Now, when it went
through the overcast,
there were three black rings that
radiated from the flange of the craft,
and went from the
flange of the craft
all the way over the horizon,
with no sound at all.
And what it
looked like was,
somebody dropping a pebble
into a glassy pool of water,
and the rings were
spreading out.
In January of 2005.
5.24pm, I was driving south on
Interstate 25, south of Denver.
and I see this
black object,
coming up the road,
above the road, in the sky.
and I thought, that's
curious, what is that?
As I get closer,
as we close,
I see that it is a,
solid
object.
I thought it might have been
Canadian geese, for a start,
I thought it might have
been a piece of plastic,
blown up in the
breeze, like a kite.
But I could see it
was a solid object
it was not affected by
breeze in anyway.
It was flying on
a straight course.
It looked black, it may
have been some color
but because it was
silhouetted against the sky,
it looked very dark.
It looked like a plank.
It looked like a board.
An oblong
shape.
It was
bizarre!
It had a couple of little bumps
on the leading edge, on one end,
and I thought,
well if it's just junk,
that would be
random, perhaps,
it certainly wouldn't
be symmetrical,
and I looked at the
other side, and sure enough
it had the identical bumps on
the other side of the leading edge!
So it was an
anomalous object,
Could I identify it?
Heck no! I couldn't
relate to it!
It had no sweepback, no
anhedral, no dihedral.
It didn’t have any
external power plants,
no wings, no
tail empennage.
flight control surfaces or
probes.
A search of the term
'Fastwalkers' on the internet,
immediately reveals references
that 'Fastwalker' is a codename,
used by various government
agencies to refer to UFOs or
as they are
sometimes called,
Non Reference Targets.
Craft that I recorded that
did the 180 degree turn
down on this
portion of the screen.
They're called 'Fastwalkers',
because of their speed.
The whole episode took about
half a second to perform, or less!
And we're
talking milliseconds!
And that kind
of lets you know,
that it's not an earth
satellite that we're looking at,
because it's
moving so fast.
Plus the fact,
our satellites don't
change direction,
180 degrees without changing
speed, or 90 degrees.
And I have seen
many of the shadows
go up and do a 90 degree,
right across the screen.
Sometimes, you'll
see 3 or 4 objects
in formation, looks
like formation flying,
and one will branch off to the
left and one will go to the right.
Somebody coined
the phrase, 'Fastwalker'.
It's appropriate.
The Fastwalkers are
these very rapid moving,
electrogravidic and anti-gravity
discs and craft of various shapes.
The N.S.A. actually for a
long time called these E.T.Vs,
Extra-Terrestrial Vehicles,
and from the military who
have tracked these objects,
they've been called
Fastwalkers because,
as apposed to 'Slowalkers',
which are satellites.
Because they move
at enormous speeds,
for example, they've been
tracked at going 10's of
thousands of miles per
hour in the atmosphere
and making a right hand turn
without decelerating.
Well, you can't do that
with a conventional system.
You have to correct
the gravity and mass inertia.
and that's what
these things are doing.
So these have
been tracked on,
dedicated and classified
radar systems.
Occasionally, people who
are on an ordinary system,
will pick
them up.
Today, the internet is
literally alive with websites,
that are filled with
detailed reports,
many of which, include
convincing videos,
and pictures of unknown
crafts and alien like creatures.
I live in Phoenix,
Arizona.
I am a sky watcher,
a UFO hunter.
I have a website called
www.cnufos.com
I’ve had an interest in
UFOs my whole life.
But officially that started
on April 15th of 2004,
when I walked my dog
in the middle of the night,
looked up in the sky and
saw some strange lights.
I've got over 200 UFO
video clips on my website.
I'm more interested
in the day footage.
Now, the day footage
is completely different
because that's
harder to dismiss.
You know, so I would have
to say every other month,
it seems like I'm
catching something.
And I go out
everyday.
Pretty much, 6 days a week,
a couple of hours a day.
You know, you add all those
hours up and that's allot of time.
Just to catch one
thing for 20 seconds!
But that's more than most
people see in a lifetime, so,
I think that's
better than nothing.
Well I'm involved in the
political resolution of the
I prefer to
call it,
the Truth Embargo that
the government have imposed,
on the facts regarding the
extraterrestrial presence.
That presence has
been established, I think,
many times over
by the citizen science research that
has been going on since the 1940's.
The government did studies, but
they were primarily for show.
and the issue from a government
standpoint has been managed,
very intensely,
since 1947,
at minimum!
Managed in a
sense that,
the government was
going to deal with it,
but deal with it within the
national security structure,
and never acknowledge that
there is anything to this.
But in fact
there is!
We are being engaged as
a planet and as a species
by other beings.
Possibly multiple
species!
This has just been proven
beyond any doubt at all,
by anyone who reads
the research who isn't
compromised
by being,
either an
idiot or,
an employee of the government
management of the issue,
can only arrive
at one conclusion.
The evidence is
overwhelming.
Videotape.
Daylight discs.
Night time discs.
Photographs.
Direct pilot sightings
by the thousands!
Millions of sightings
around the world.
There are testimonies from
direct government involvement,
and of course, you've
got an entire contactee
body of evidence
that is now,
in the tens of
thousands of reports.
Now, like
never before,
astounding events are transcending
national and geographical boundaries,
currently happening
in Brazil and Mexico.
Unprecedented
UFO sightings,
are sweeping the entire area
of south and central America.
Does the key to
understanding,
UFOs and aliens,
and their relationship
with each of us,
laying being able
to simply perceive
what is in a
higher spectrum?
Like seeing the
infrared range,
or other dimensional
frequencies?
Images gathered from
infrared cameras in Mexico
and special cameras
used in Brazil
seem to indicate that
the aliens and their crafts
may in fact be
all around us.
Jaime Maussan is one of
Mexico’s foremost journalists.
Internationally known
and respected,
for more than three
decades of journalistic work,
his investigations and
reporting in the UFO field
have made him an icon to
UFO researchers, worldwide.
Jaime's weekly network
television show,
60 Minutes,
in Mexico, reaches millions
of people each week,
and regularly carries segments
on the subject of UFOs.
This flap has been
recorded on video.
It means that we
have evidence to prove
that something is
really happening,
in the Mexican
Republic.
The video camera
has become,
the most important
instrument,
to really capture
this new reality.
Even the
Mexican Army,
the Air force
in Mexico,
recorded UFOs.
The video was
given to me,
and I released
that to the world!
In that case,
that happened,
on March the
5th, 2004.
The soldiers were able
to record something that
they couldn't see
with their own eyes!
and that's
amazing!
That was the
first time,
someone recorded
something, that
they were
not able to see!
With Jaime Maussan,
aboard a plane
coming from San Antonio
to Mexico City, flying,
over a place
called,
San Luis
Potosi'
to film a UFO,
following the plane!
It was the detected
by the radars
and they have
everything on film.
So, for us it
is normal.
Maybe because we
are searching for it.
Maybe because we are trying
to look for this reality.
Maybe they are
following us!
I don't know, but it
happened to me,
that at least 50
times! Maybe more!
There are objects that we
cannot see with our own eyes,
but
THEY
ARE
THERE
They are
watching us.
In the last months,
in Mexico,
after thousands
of videos,
we have been registering some
of the most spectacular videos.
You can see hundreds
and hundreds of objects
making formations,
and flying together
exactly, the same
thing that you can see,
in the military
video.
These formations moving
at the same speeds,
in the same
direction,
at the same
altitude.
As the more one researches,
the more one discovers,
that literally 10's of thousands of
very credible people of every age,
occupation,
and nationality
are claiming,
that they have
had personal contact
with either aliens, or
interdimensional beings.
Credible researchers now say
that as many as 60 different species
of intelligent, super
conscious beings,
have been interacting with
humanity for millions of years.
Physically, they look,
they're humanoid.
Their skin is as white
as a piece of paper.
Throughout much
of their adult life
they are the same
height that I am.
5'11, 6 feet tall.
Their eyes are perhaps
twice as large as ours.
They're typically blue
eyes with white pupils.
Although, when they get
older, especially the men,
their eyes take
on a pink shade.
Their eyes stretch further around the
sides of their head than human eyes do.
And their ears
and their nose,
are only about half the size
of human ears and noses,
and their ears lay back along the side
of their head more than a human does.
Their lips are not as
prominent as humans,
and they don't have teeth,
they just have ridges,
because they are plant
eaters, they don't eat meat.
How can we know for sure,
exactly how many
extraterrestrial races
are visiting us or
interacting with humanity?
There are
different sources,
disclosing some
of that information.
I find one of the most credible
to be whistleblowers.
People who have worked in
these various secret projects,
who in some way
have kind of,
been given information
that gives them an idea,
of exactly how
many races are here.
One of those
sources is a,
Sergeant who worked in the,
for 22 years in the Air force,
Clifford Stone.
And he was involved in
these top secret projects,
that involve the
retrieval of crashed discs.
And in that process he was able
to get quite a bit of information on
how many extraterrestrial
races are visiting us.
And he came up
with the figure of 57!
Others have come
up with slightly more.
Another prominent
whistleblower,
a former employee
of the C.I.A.
is John Lear.
And he talks about,
over 60 races,
that are visiting
the Earth.
On one night I saw
between 200 and 300,
different tall,
white individuals,
there were so many,
I couldn't count them!
Lined up along the mountains
to the east of the lawn,
where the ammunition
bunker was.
On the night that the tall
white lady known as Pamela
was supposed to
finish her final exam,
to be head of the
technology transfer team,
to go into
Livermore.
In amongst those two or
three hundred tall whites,
That's just an
estimate, because I,
I couldn't, there was a crowd of
people and I couldn't count them all.
There were also American
Air force personnel,
nobody below the
rank of Colonel.
There were others like
a four star General.
A three star
General,
There were
several of them.
There were also several
American government people,
in civilian clothing
over there.
Could it be possible that our
universe is not only immense,
but that it
is full of life,
and that there is a great
diversity of this life,
spread throughout
own own local galaxy,
and even our
solar system.
Equally outstanding is the recent
revelation by the government of Brazil,
of their intent to turn
over the official UFO files,
dating back to as early as
1954, to the people of Brazil.
Well, the Varginha
case is probably the
best well documented
case that we have in Brazil,
and probably
in the world.
You know that over 80
witnesses came forward,
first hand witnesses
came forward,
during the first weeks, and they
are still coming after it happened
during all of these
years we still
keep getting witnesses that
come forward and tell us
pieces of the big story, that
we know already, in comprises,
the capture of at least,
two alien creatures
in Aselo, Varginha.
We know for a fact, because
we have it all documented,
plus the witnesses have
confirmed and cross confirmed
that one alien was captured
in the morning of that day
which was a Saturday.
About 10.30
by a Fire Department and some
personnel from the Army.
Another creature was
seen, on the same day
by middle-afternoon,
by three girls.
It was them who called
attention of all the city
to the fact that, strange
creatures had been seen.
Because when the first one was
seen and captured in the morning,
it didn't draw
too much attention.
but in the afternoon when
the girls saw another creature,
and then, spread
the word to everybody,
We saw the devil!
That's what they
thought they saw.
That night of the Saturday,
January 20th 1996
that second creature, probably
the same one saw by the girls,
was also captured. By a police car,
actually a military police car.
with two policeman inside.
The one who was sitting in the
passenger seat was Marco Eli Chereze,
and he was lucky enough to be
the one, who spotted the creature
and grabbed it with
his bear hands,
got back to
the car,
put the creature
in his lap,
and took it
to hospital.
25 days after that, he
died, on February 15th,
of some bacteria
attacks,
proving that his
immune system,
was absolutely
destroyed.
Army personnel and authorities
kept it all secret for lots of time,
until the UFO researchers
started protesting,
along with
the press,
and we gave so much
pressure, that eventually,
information was
released about it.
The exobiological aspect that
the probability of life out there
has actually increased
over what it was in 1950.
and the err, indication
that there may be ways
of traveling faster
than the speed of light.
So hey, they can get
here from there!
It doesn't mean that they
are coming in 5 minutes,
or they're coming every
hour of everyday, but you know,
they might be able to
traverse just huge distances,
in a period of weeks or
months or something,
instead of spending hundreds
or thousands of years.
Well, look at
the UFO sightings.
Maybe they provide the
answer that they are here!
There was talk in the War Room,
about a study that was underway.
And this study became
initiated in 1961,
as the result of an
event that occurred,
early February,
in 1961.
Where a flight of UFOs were flying
from the Soviet sector to the east,
over the Warsaw pact, towards
the west, over the NATO lines.
These, objects were very
high and were very fast.
They were in formation.
They appeared to
be circular in shape.
And they were obviously
under intelligent control.
They came in a formation
of what appeared to be,
almost 100
of them.
And they flew
in formation,
at a high rate of speed
from the east, over NATO
over the channel, southern
coast of England, where they turned,
flew north and disappeared from
NATO radar over the Norwegian sea.
We found out that the
Soviets had gone on alert.
The Warsaw pact had gone on alert
because they had picked them up.
All of our Air force and radar
sensory devices picked them up.
NATO thought those objects
belonged to the Russians.
We found later that the Russians
thought they belonged to us.
Both forces, were
to find out later,
that they didn't
belong to any of us.
That they belonged
to somebody else!
And of course, the
BIG question is:
Who the hell do
they belong to?
Who are they? What are they?
Where are they from?
They demonstrated
incredibly high technology.
They were not jets.
There were no contrails.
They were circular,
they were metallic.
They were in formation.
They moved, obviously,
under intelligent control.
NATO - SHAPE.
Supreme Headquarters
Allied Powers,
initiated a study
in 1961,
which was underway
when I arrived in 1963.
To determine what the
hell these things were!
Some experts now claim,
that societies exist
in our universe, at every conceivable
level of social and spiritual development.
Societies and civilizations
that express themselves
in countless manners of
physical forms and spiritual ways.
Have great wars and conflicts
occurred within our own Solar System?
Does our true planetary
past include rebellions
and disputes that have raged
throughout our heavens?
In our distant past,
have massive spacecrafts rained
destruction down from the heavens?
Ravishing continents and
destroying advanced civilizations?
GENESIS 6:1
When men began to increase
in number on the Earth,
and daughters were
born to them,
the sons of God saw that the
daughters of men were beautiful,
and they married any
of them they chose.
The historical
record is plain!
This has been a phenomenon that has
been around since our recorded history.
The Vedas, the Hindu Vedas, which are
among the oldest writings in the world,
talk about the flying Vimana's,
and how that they were used to launch
weapons, and blow up cities and
all this stuff,
you know,
Again, we've got Ezekiel, and it
just goes all the way back.
So they've been
here all along.
If their game plan was like an
Independence Day type invasion,
where they were going to blow up
everything and eat everybody or whatever,
It would have happened,
long before now!
My main question was:
Is God out there too?
If God is on this planet,
is he out there too?
and those questions were
answered by reading the bible.
And that really set
me on this journey,
to understanding the
abduction phenomenon.
What is the
reasoning for this?
Who is doing this?
And all those questions
that we all ask.
We think of aliens and
we think of angels as,
you know, divine beings,
that we have no idea of,
and we don't see and we don't
communicate with on a daily basis.
But it is not only the
bible and other holy works
that are filled with references
to UFOs and extraterrestrials.
Drawings, paintings, stone
carvings and even coins,
reflect strange humanoid like
creatures and their flying crafts.
Serious researchers now
say that the real question
is not whether there
are abductions occurring,
but are the abductions
to help, or to harm us?
And they Greys were authorized
to, sort of like a Noah's Ark,
to develop a full
genetic and DNA bank
of all flora and fauna
on this planet, so as to
replant it, centuries down the
road, after the catastrophe.
Can you imagine,
any President,
whether it be Bush or Clinton or whatever,
standing before the public, and saying, yes,
I am aware that we have this
joint program with some aliens,
to upgrade our
biological computers.
To build better bodies to house
our souls in future incarnations.
You can't talk
about things like that!
He wouldn't be able to do the
job that we hired him to do.
What we know of the
reptilians by a number of
abductees, contactees and
also whistleblowers is that
there seems to be
allot of evidence supporting
the existence of this race of beings,
on the planet for
thousands of years.
In other words that we might consider
them to be an indigenous Earth species
an advanced, non-human species, that has
lived on the Earth for thousands of years,
and actually may have
played quite an important role,
in the genetic manipulation
or engineering,
which supposedly has happened
when it comes to humanity.
There are various groups,
individuals, species,
who from time to time, come and
visit this planet, and ZOOP around,
and I think that to try to ascribe any
one particular motive to them is err,
tantamount to us looking up at the air
at a Boeing 767 aircraft and saying:
Are those people
good or bad?
You know, you
just can't ask that.
It's just, it's a group of people,
a group of intelligent beings
some of them are good, some
of them are not so good.
But I will say this, I don't think there is
any reason for great fear and anxiety.
Most recently, two new terms have emerged
that also describe human/alien interaction.
The most widely used
is the word Experiencer,
for those who have had some
sort of experience, good or bad.
and Participator, which has been coined to explain
the cases where the individual may have been
an abductee originally but has
transcended the situation by now,
volunteering to participate
with his abductors.
My contact with extraterrestrial
intelligence occurred,
when I was aboard my sailing boat
in Hawaii, in the Honolulu harbor.
and it was early one morning, it was
about 5am and I had gotten up early,
and I had gotten a cup of coffee
and I had gone back to my bunk
and I was just laying
there completely dressed,
trying to err, just look at the beautiful
sunrise that was occurring through the
large skylight above my bed,
and then suddenly, the most
incredible energy enveloped me,
and the whole room began to, like
glow and glisten and a beautiful woman
materialized right
next to my bed!
And at first I thought I was
dreaming or hallucinating,
and I said, you can't be real!
And she said, well I am!
and I said, well why are
you here? And she said,
I'm here as a representative of a group of
friends that want you to come to a briefing.
The room was lit up completely,
but my eyes were closed.
I knew somehow, not
to open my eyes!
There was something telling me:
Don't open your eyes because you
won't like what you're going to see!
Eventually, I did open my eyes,
because I could hear noise in the room,
there was like a scuffling on,
the floor, I opened my eyes,
there were three, small,
grey beings with big black eyes
and big heads, and very
skinny, spindly limbs,
They pulled me up
out of the bed,
and then with one behind me and
one each side of me holding my elbows,
walked me
towards the window.
And I'm thinking, well the
windows are closed guys,
so you had better open
them before we go any further!
So there was this rationality and
irrationality going on at the same time.
I boarded what could
be called a saucer.
It was some type of an
interdimensional vehicle,
that took me to the
briefing that was occurring
on a planet, a local planet
here in our system,
it was Jupiter.
And the whole planet just
radiated with the energy.
And I spent time there with
these incredible people, or beings,
and I got a glimpse of mankind’s
destiny or future, as it was possible.
And as we approached the
window, I closed my eyes.
And as I did, I
felt this stickiness.
It was like, it was a
stickiness and a feeling
of something being pulled
very slowly across my face.
It wasn't painful, it was
just very, very weird!
The next, I opened my eyes, because
I felt cold, I felt wind on my face,
and I was aware that I was now floating,
outside of the window, 3 stories up
looking down at the car park, with
a very bright light above my head.
I couldn't really see
what was above my head,
I was just aware of
this very bright light.
One little grey on each
elbow, I was aware of them,
and we floated
up into the craft!
And people have said: Well,
then you were abducted!
And I said, no, I
went very willingly.
And they've also asked,
how can you tell if you were
to meet an extraterrestrial?
And I would have to
say, the energy field.
Because, when they're
in your presence,
they absolutely resonate at a
frequency that is so much higher.
It can only be described as dealing
with them could be described as ecstasy!
I had been taken in the middle
of the night, while I was asleep,
I was asleep through the whole
thing until all of a sudden,
I felt some pressure
going up my nose,
and it startled me so much,
that I opened my eyes.
And when I opened my eyes,
I saw this large headed being,
with grey skin, large black eyes,
and small other features,
that was looking
down at me.
He had long fingers that he was
using to hold this instrument,
that he was using to
shove up my nose!
I feel knowledge is power.
And some day,
maybe next week,
maybe tomorrow,
maybe in 5 years from now,
we're going to get all of the proof
we need that somebody exists.
Hey an E.T. might show up and
I might actually get an interview!
The point is, that the more that
we know about this subject,
then the less legend
can take over.
If you see a craft hanging near you,
don't get out of the
car, don't stop the car.
Don't see what's happening.
If you see one
coming towards you,
you don't have to be an
abductee, if you don't want to be!
They go away, evidently.
We have 10's and 10's
of people telling us:
Listen, I don't want to do that
anymore, and they let them go.
What we call abductions, or
certain categories of abductions,
took place as a result of an authorized
genetic upgrade of the human race.
trying to get us out
of our war-like ways,
and act-illogically
ecocidal ways.
The indigenous
reptilians seem to
have a very strong interest
in the biosphere of Earth being
stable, that it's not
jeopardized unduly,
and some who
have kind of,
analyzed what the reptilians have been
doing, or had some kind of interaction,
believe that this is because, the
reptilians view humanity as a resource,
and they don't want that resource to
damage itself, or damage the biosphere.
They had about 18
scientists and all had been
working on various
stages of the project,
gathered around a big oval table
in Los Alamos Headquarters,
with Edward Teller, the head of
the Atomic Energy Commission,
sitting at the
head of the table,
One of the aliens, on the opposite side of
the table from my engineering friend,
put in a white shirt and slacks
so he would look less alien,
but he still had his alien, bigger
head and bigger eyes, black eyes,
and he was sitting
in the conference,
he could understand everybody
else because he was telepathic,
and the only way he
could communicate though,
was with the signs that he had
developed with my engineer friend,
to answer the question.
But here was a man, an
alien from another planet,
sitting in a
conference, in 1968
in Los Alamos Headquarters,
on the progress of learning
how to bridge the gap,
between the alien
technology and ours.
They were going to suggest
to the American generals,
additional technology
exchange projects,
and I think they were using
me as the test guinea-pig,
to take me onboard
the scout craft,
and then they could
test my reaction,
to what I was impressed with
and what I wasn't with.
My life changed and I was
never, ever quite the same.
So, the study itself, was not as
complete as it could have been.
They concluded what
they wanted to conclude.
1: There was not
a threat involved.
2: They weren’t
the Soviets.
3: The evidence was overwhelming,
they were extraterrestrial.
4: There were four
groups involved.
Four different groups.
And they were
all humanoid.
But they were
not human.
Only one of the four was what
we consider to be human.
One group out of the four
looked so much like us,
I mean, almost
identical to us,
these guys could have
put on a suit and a tie!
The females,
because we encountered
some of them as well.
They could have put on a
dress, suit and tie, coat or jacket,
sit down with you, next
to you in a restaurant,
sit next to you
in a theatre,
and you'd never know!
These extraterrestrials, they
have a body like ours.
and these extraterrestrial vehicles,
I’m using this in a large sense,
or the people inside the craft -
It's very difficult,
because they make themselves
seen and known to people on Earth,
so it's probably logical that
they are inside a craft,
instead of coming from
somewhere else without a craft.
They will have to have
a soul like we do.
They'd have to have
some kind of body,
otherwise they
would be angels.
How can countries, one of which
actually borders with the United States,
be having UFO visitations
by the hundreds,
when other major nations of
our world insist, that they are not?
And even more
importantly,
how can these countries'
governmental policy,
both official and
otherwise be,
that they never have
had UFO or alien contact?
The only logical
explanation,
is in fact that governments
are willing to lie.
For the past 9 years I have
been researching into the,
United States government files,
on what they have on
the UFO phenomenon,
and all sorts of
different conspiracies.
And I've reached
183'000 pages,
of government documents
on the internet!
There is a political block,
what I call a
'Truth Embargo',
instituted by
the government,
that they are not ready
to formally acknowledge,
this "presence".
Anything that involved
absolute proof,
like hardware and bodies,
were siphoned off completely
into another track.
They just can't allow information
to come out overnight,
so people would
be perturbed
and actually demand that
something be done about it.
They stonewall it, deny it,
lie about it, for, you know,
30 or 40 years,
and then finally just announce it
as if it's fact and everybody goes,
yeah, OK!
It's clear we're dealing
with a cosmic 'Watergate'.
Meaning, some few people
within major governments,
have known since
at least July 1947,
when two crashed flying saucers and several
alien bodies were recovered in New Mexico,
that indeed, some
UFOs are alien spacecraft.
The government setup
Project Bluebook, the Air force did,
in order to investigate
this subject on a,
let me say,
a low level.
Researchers,
mostly, regular citizens,
have proven without a doubt
there's an extraterrestrial presence
and we're being engaged,
the evidence is overwhelming.
In some cases, you can actually
point to where the Air force explanation
completely contradicts,
what’s inside the
sighting report itself.
The word UFO is actually
a disinformation term,
that was invented after they
knew that they weren’t unidentified,
and they knew
they didn't fly!
So it's sort of a,
mind play.
When we had first
evidence of E.T. visitation,
and hardware and so on,
and so on came along,
the U.S. government
took the attitude,
that they couldn't
release this
to the general public, because it had
extreme implications for defense.
We don't want our enemies
to know that we've got one,
because then they
might try to get one.
To the extent that we might be able
to back-engineer the technology,
we don't want to err,
tell somebody else that we're
trying to do such a thing.
Gus Grissom, who was probably
the person that I was closest to,
felt that they
were Spam in a can,
and that the Astronauts were
just a public relations campaign,
for a secret military program
that was spending much more.
The military space program was getting,
you know, was
a gleaming jewel,
compared to the junk that
N.A.S.A. was getting at the time.
You can get a certain amount of
information out through the large media,
but it's very superficial
and very brief,
that's what we've found.
The in-depth sort of, disclosure
of what's really going on,
who's behind it,
what the agenda is,
that is almost
always stopped,
or if they try to do it,
it gets turned into
something ridiculous.
I almost hate the
term UFOs because,
they really aren't
unidentified to
the people that know what's
going on, or the researchers too.
allot of people that
have the answers,
felt it was safe to
come out of the water,
so they're putting out their
information on the internet,
and, you know,
disguised or whatever,
but, so these other
agents who say they're
scanning all the time to
counteract what's
being said by other people from
Intel to think it was safe to OK,
they can put this out, or they feel
like it's the right thing to do now.
You know, enough is enough.
Mankind has a right
to know type of thing.
When I worked for Douglas, I was
assigned to the Douglas Skyrocket.
They wanted me to wire up a
camera out on the wing tip
to look through a course
window, back at the canopy.
So that they could monitor the
pilot, to see what he was doing.
While I went through the
hanger, which was secured.
Well, there were two gentlemen in
there, and they introduced themselves.
One was Naval Intelligence,
and the other one was C.I.A.
And I started working, doing
my job, wiring up the camera.
Well they sat around and talked
and it became very apparent to me,
that they were there
for that purpose, to talk!
They knew about all my
flying saucer experiences,
all the way from Korea!
They told me, Intelligence,
the C.I.A. Intelligence group,
had three intelligence digests.
Flying saucer photographs,
and witness documentation,
from all over
the world!
And they said that I should probably
try to get those three copies,
and that's when I
wrote to Admiral Freeman,
and wasn't able to get
the documents, incidentally.
In addition to that,
they told me
that I should,
tell people about what
my experiences have been.
They said tell
everybody you can!
Because they can't!
They were not
aloud to talk about it.
There is this curtain of ridicule
that's been drawn up around the,
UFO phenomenon,
and as long as that curtain
of ridicule holds solid,
the scientists
will be afraid to
contribute to anything,
to looking into UFOs.
And part of that curtain of
ridicule involves the fact that,
hardly any decent papers have gotten
into the refereed, scientific literature.
So that curtain of ridicule may be
slightly opened up now that they have a
paper that they can refer to if they feel
like writing their own papers on UFOs.
The secrecy has invaded, like
a cancer, many institutions,
including the media, the
government and corporations.
I got into more and more
controversial and exotic subjects,
and I found myself a
journalist without a journal!
There is definitely
very tight control,
over the flow of information
of certain topics,
through our corporate
controlled mass media.
They seem to take it upon themselves
to be the gatekeepers of information.
Part of this information that
they are keeping from us,
is the just absolutely
immense wealth of
information, concerning
the UFO phenomenon,
and the fact that it can
be tracked and documented,
all the way back
through history.
The only institution
that is more corrupt,
than what I'm
describing as this rogue,
transnational, cleptocracy,
is the major media.
More worse than the congress,
worse than the Whitehouse,
worse than anything at the normal
level of clearances at the Pentagon,
is big media.
Big media does not report
the truth about these things,
because they
are not free to.
And we think in the United
States and in the western world,
we really have
a free press,
we have a free press on
everything that's non-important,
on the really important
issues, it's very controlled,
and this is the most
important issue.
This is the biggest secret in
the history of the human race.
The known modern
history of government.
And they have co-operated
with keeping the secret.
How is this
cover-up contained,
and maintained through
international borders,
and if it is, are their
motivations the same?
The best guess
is that,
since America has such
overwhelming economic power,
the only worse thing than
America being mad at you,
is for America
to ignore you.
So many countries economies
depend on America, that I think
that they take their orders
from America in some ways.
When it comes to
the cover-up,
I think that's
one of them.
The U.S. government is not only
pressuring the Brazilian government,
but it's making pressure
over almost all countries
that are some how aligned politically,
aligned to the United States.
Now, all south America, except
maybe for Chile and Venezuela,
who has Chavez,
who is a rebel!
All the rest of Latin America,
is very aligned to U.S. politics.
So, all these countries,
will do just exactly,
what the U.S.
President tells them,
it is, keep this
under wraps!
Recent media polls show that over 100
million people in the United States alone,
believe that there is some
form of extraterrestrial life.
45% believe that the Earth has been
visited by extraterrestrial beings.
Nationally known journalists continue to
turn a deaf ear to the public’s demands
for true investigative
reporting on a daily basis.
Accepting instead, the dribble of denial
from numerous government agencies as fact,
while refusing to interview
the legions of researchers,
who have made serious
scientific investigation,
of UFOs and alien
contact, their life's work.
What else are the governments
of the world, not saying?
What if there is positive proof
that UFOs do in fact exist?
What if that proof has
existed for years, but
has been hidden neatly within the fabric
of a system of lies and grand deception?
We need to be very concerned
about the way in which this whole
area has been managed by the
national security agencies responsible.
By maintaining secrecy, keeping
people in the dark, it means that
we really don't know
whether this secrecy, and
withholding the information,
withholding the technologies,
from the general
public arena,
is really for the best
interest of all of us.
The problem has been
since the early 1950's,
and err, I have the
government documents!
The United States government
has instituted a policy
of denial and control
over the information.
Nothing happening
there folks!
And if somebody persists
in saying, but I saw it!
Then they
are ridiculed.
You got a screw loose,
something’s not right with him!
This is absolutely
just unconscionable,
in a country that pays lip service
to freedom and individual liberty.
Because there have
been so many people,
whose lives have
been wrecked,
whose families have
because of this policy
of denial and ridicule,
over a phenomenon that has
happened worldwide for centuries!
Disclosure has a very
defined definition. It means,
the formal acknowledgement
by the governments of the world,
of the extraterrestrial presence.
As fellow inhabitants of planet Earth,
we live in a rapidly changing world.
The advent of modern communication
networks and the internet,
has made maintaining
the UFO cover-up,
a difficult and demanding
undertaking.
Brian Vike of HBCC UFO, has the number
1 UFO website to send information to.
Him and Rense
and UFOCasebook,
are the three places that I always
send my footage to because,
they will only put verified
sightings on their site,
they just won't
put junk up there.
And I know they get over 3 or
4, up to 10 million hits a month!
For over half a century,
the United States,
Great Britain and a
host of aligned countries,
have been able to maintain
a vast web of secrecy
over what is actually
happening worldwide,
relative to aliens, or what
are generally known as E.B.Es.
Extraterrestrial Biological Entities.
But that is rapidly changing,
and disclosure,
the lifting of the
truth embargo,
is now taking place.
I'll be getting over
500'000 hits this month.
But the interesting
thing about that is,
that a couple of thousand of those
hits each month, are from the military.
As far as sharing information on the
internet, that is the best way to do it,
and probably
the safest way.
Only because, I know I've sent DVDs to
people and they haven't received them.
And I would email them and say,
look, I'm going to send you a DVD,
can you analyze it for me, and let
me know what you think this is?
2 weeks later, they'll email me
and say, well I never got it!
I'm just waiting for that day, when
they come knocking on my door
and want to talk to me about it,
but uh, until that day, I think,
I think they know who I am, I
think they know we're here. I think,
this is the way it's going to
be done from here on out.
Because the military
definitely doesn't want
to talk about it anymore!
Everything at night to them
is a flare or an airplane.
On the contrary, we have all this
evidence that shows otherwise.
Like a dawning of a new day, the internet
is quickly sweeping away the darkness.
The truth will not be stopped.
We're in this
strange reality,
which we're caught
between two worlds,
between 2 paradigms.
And the bridge between,
or the door between these two
paradigms is what is now called,
'The Disclosure Event'.
Recently in
Washington D.C.,
a press conference was held in
conjunction with an international event,
The X-Conference
Where a panel of eminent scientists
and researchers broke the silence,
and spoke out and called for
a full international disclosure
and an end to the truth embargo
relative to UFOs and extraterrestrials.
If I was an 'in-the-know' person,
high up in government or finance,
and I knew about the
extraterrestrial issue,
and I knew about some
extraterrestrial technology,
and I knew what it could
do when it was released,
my position would be this:
Let's keep that technology
under wraps as long as possible,
while we sell as much of
the rest of the oil as we can,
for as much as possible.
And then we'll all
take that money,
and we'll use that to own
the extraterrestrial technology.
Alright.
The point is. There's always people
'in-the-know', and 'out-of-the-know'.
Sometimes it's about stuff, you
know, you're in or you're out.
But there are some things you can't have,
the 'in-the-know' and 'out-of-the-know'.
Basically, what we're
calling on today,
is for the government
of the United States,
to take the issue of
extraterrestrial life,
where it has been
stuck in conflict,
for the last 60 years, and take it out
of the military intelligence agencies,
and put it into the
department of education,
and the scientific departments,
where it belongs.
Take it out of the
threat scenario agencies,
where it is funded as
a potential threat,
and put it into the opportunity
agencies, where it is funded as
a matter of education and advancement
of knowledge, for mutual benefit.
There is an overwhelming
mass of proven,
real,
government documents,
that have been released
largely, through the
Freedom of Information Act,
that show decades
of, for example,
airspace violations.
Very sensitive
places by objects,
doing what appear
to be, the impossible.
We have these documents
from the 1940's.
We have them
from the 1950's.
We have them from the
1960's, 70's, 80's and beyond.
So these airspace
violations continue.
They are provocative.
They are at times,
seemingly confrontational.
You have pilots who
have been going,
who have been charged
with going up to get these things,
and they have described
them at times, saying, yes-
it appears to be a metallic
disc shape, there it goes!
I began on this topic by trying to do reverse
engineering on gravity control devices in 1968,
but now I'm officially looking
at leaked question documents.
Some of the documents
tell an amazing story.
One of the leaked
documents started with F.D.R.
and F.D.R. had setup,
through Vannevar Bush,
the committee called the non-terrestrial
science and engineering committee.
These were the guys, after the recovery
of a crashed flying saucer in 1942,
who were given the parts and were
told to figure out how they worked.
They came back to F.D.R. in
1944, and asked for money.
And he said: No, we got to win
the war first and beat the Nazis.
And then in 1947, it was
Vannevar Bush who went to
President Truman, who didn't
know about all of this, and said,
by the way, we have these craft, we could
do some reverse engineering in order to
improve our country, to improve our
culture, to improve our standard of living,
and that was when
the money started to flow.
July 2002, right here in
the Washington D.C. area,
there was, yet again,
an airspace, jet chase.
By 2 F-16 jet interceptors,
which were chasing, a 'blue-ish'
object, right outside D.C.
My opinion right now is, the person
who is going to wait for hard evidence,
is going to be left behind
when the delouse comes.
Exopolitics offers a
bridge out of:
The permanent warfare state.
The permanent warfare economy.
Out of the permanent
warfare industry,
into transforming the
permanent warfare industry,
into a co-operative
peaceful space age society,
integrated with
universal society.
So I began to look outside of
the, kind of, conventional sphere,
I began to explore theories,
for what it is that really is
driving international politics.
And so then I came up with
this area of an undisclosed,
extraterrestrial presence that
is kept from the general public.
So that really did help me
understand what was going on,
and what is driving
international politics.
What's important is the
structural blinders,
and the structural
belief patterns,
paradigm,
if the Exopolitics
model can come in,
and establish itself as
the dominant paradigm,
such that, structurally,
within Academia,
the Earth is no
longer flat!
It is now round!
Intelligent life no longer ends
at the geostationing orbit,
the universe is now,
highly populated.
It's that sort of sea
change that we need,
to unleash the huge
public investment,
and private explosion of
creativity and co-operation,
to turn our spaceship around,
to be able to survive,
the environmental
pressures,
that are coming now,
which have been the result
of the embargo that
we have been under.
Are we, the people of Earth, on the
verge of technological destruction?
Has our use and
testing of nuclear weapons,
already triggered an inter
dimensional countdown,
that is now
moving us as a planet,
towards some kind of
interstellar intervention?
Even though there's clearly no
evidence, I want to emphasize this,
that these extraterrestrial
civilizations are hostile towards us,
I think they're very
worried about our hostility.
I always turn
this on it's head.
Because most of
these sort of,
documentaries, you know, always
like alien invasion and all this stuff,
No, no, no, no, no, no!
The issue is, if they were
hostile, we would know it by now.
It's clear to me, that what's going
on is that they're very concerned
that at the time that humanity
reached the ability to go into space,
early space exploration, the 1950's,
we also had already developed
weapons of mass destruction
and thermal nuclear
hydrogen bombs and stuff.
And that the co-incidence of that,
the coming together of those 2 things,
put a big red
flag over Earth!
And so, if you look at the databases
from the 50's, 60's, 70's, on forward,
not only in the United States,
but in Great Britain,
in the Soviet Union,
and in China,
that wherever we had space,
aerospace and nuclear facilities,
there were allot of these
so called, UFOs, being seen.
These groups, that
are interested in us,
at least seem to show
some benevolence,
I think, would probably
step in and keep us
from blowing the hell out of
ourselves, if push comes to shove.
The onset of the whole UFO
phenomenon, beginning about 1946/47
I don't think it's
co-incidence that
that coincided with our
development of nuclear weapons.
And I think, that out in the
universe, they were horrified.
They said, oh my God, the
kids have found the matches!
Well they don't want us
to destroy ourselves,
and they don't want us
to destroy this planet,
and yet they're
prohibited from directly,
intervening in our
affairs and our evolution,
so I think that we've got crop
circles, and animal mutilations and
abductions and sightings, and
increasing sightings and all like that,
so that it's not directly impacting on
us and yet over this conditioning period,
we are coming to understand, that
we're not the only ones in the universe,
and I think they're trying to kind of,
boost us up the evolutionary ladder,
so that we can grow to be full class
members of the intergalactic community,
instead of destroying ourselves through our
petty bickering wars, and nuclear holocaust.
Like a dawning of a new day, the internet is
quickly sweeping away the darkness.
The truth will
not be stopped.
We're now seeing this wall of censorship
cracking apart in the United States.
Just recently, we had a
major T.V. network special,
and I found it absolutely amazing
because, Peter Jennings of A.B.C., flat,
just very matter-of-factly
told a national audience
that the Robertson
Panel, of the 1950's,
and the Operation Bluebook,
Project Bluebook, of the 1960's,
were not really scientific based investigations,
they were just public relations efforts,
to try to get people not
to be thinking about UFOs.
So in other words, all you folks out
there who are old enough to have been,
seen all the newspaper reports on the
Robertson Panel and heard what Bluebook said,
It was just hogwash,
never mind!!
The non-human intelligence presence,
has been here for a long time,
that, Colonel Philip Corso said
there are 57 different races,
and that some accords were made
to talk about their presence,
whether it be Hollywood movies or
whatever, including the A.B.C. special,
that if it isn't done soon,
they will probably do it!
Extraterrestrials are not
a national security issue!
They're an educational and
social issue for our society.
And they may
be a spiritual issue!
When I retired
from the military,
I went to work for the Federal
Emergency Management Agency,
and I worked with
them for 14 years.
So I've got 42 years of
government service behind me,
and throughout
all those years,
I had the very highest security
classification you could have,
Top Secret.
When I was in N.A.T.O.
in 1963, through 1967,
I had Cosmic
Top Secret,
Which was and still is, the
highest level of security in N.A.T.O.
That's how I got involved
in this, this crazy UFO field!
Through the 1950's, 60's and 70's we
referred to aliens as extraterrestrials,
but now that science has
been catching up with us,
to a certain degree,
we have changed our
definition, of an alien.
It's probably more accurate to
call them extra dimensional beings.
Because that would explain their
ability to traverse vast distances.
They operate in
more dimensions,
I mean, even the current
theoretical model of the universe,
is upwards of
30 dimensions!
So we're living in a multi
dimensional universe.
And so it's not uncommon to theorize
that we're going to encounter beings,
that operate in more
dimensions than we do.
And that would explain allot of
the phenomenon related to UFOs.
How they're able to appear and
disappear, move very fast,
do all the things that the
E.T.s do, walk through walls,
have remarkable
psychic abilities,
and communicate
telepathically,
It would really go a long way to
explain the phenomenon surrounding it.
What looks like magic to
us, can really be explained,
through extra
dimensionality.
Are any of us really prepared
for the kind of paradigm shift
that would come with
not just disclosure,
but with contact and communication
with intelligences from other worlds?
Is it possible,
that as a species we have
reached the point that our minds
actually filter and generate
acceptable constructs,
which all too often become
our day to day realities?
There is so little of your reality
that is really based on truth,
that it is just,
stunning!
I heard that there are
other worlds that are inhabited.
and Father
Rapile answered,
Would you believe that it would just be our
tiny world that would be giving glory to God?
There has to be many more
worlds, many more planets,
that exist, with inhabitants that would
be giving glory to God, it is not just us.
If I told you
that uh,
you know, the very nature
of the Moon and Mars
and most of the planets
in the Solar System
is being kept from you
for specific reasons,
to make you think that
you're completely alone,
and that these planets
can't be colonized.
Back in the 1950's,
the big question was:
Do they come
from Mars?
Or do they come
from Venus?
And by the 1960's and 70's
we had gotten a little more
sophisticated in our
intellect and in our thinking,
and the question
became:
Well, do they come
from Alfa Centauri?
or Zeta Reticula 4?
You know.
Now up to the day, and we've
gotten even more sophisticated,
and now the
question is:
Do they come from
another planet?
Or do they come from
another dimension?
Or are they perhaps
time travelers?
Do they come from
another time? OK.
And in my study
of all of this,
I have kind of come to the
conclusion that the answer,
is, YES!
The more you know about this
field, it becomes almost paralyzing.
Because the more you
know, the less you know.
The more you know, and the more
open minded that you are about this,
the more you realize that every
answer you find, just leads to,
you know, a thousand
more questions.
Vast sums of money are being siphoned
through these different agencies,
into the coffers of the C.I.A., which then
forwards this money onto the D.O.D.
and this money is funneled through the
D.O.D. and goes into the Black Projects,
which the D.O.D. has
direct oversight over.
So the C.I.A. is kind of like the
bagman, that collects the money.
It goes to the Department of
Defense, that actually administers
how this money is going to be
spent on different Black Projects.
So, the size. How much
are we talking about?
I think the best indication for just
how much we are talking about here,
are the auditing irregularities that
the Inspector General of the D.O.D.
has himself identified.
He identified, in 3 years, it was
1998, 1999, and the year 2000.
In those 3 years,
he identified,
on average, 1.7
trillion dollars,
could not be
accounted for,
in the Department
of Defense budget.
In other words, this was money
that was being moved around
in ways that could
not be accounted for.
And I think, what that indicates is,
the true size of the Black budget.
We're looking at
an infrastructure,
that is funded
by as much as,
1.7 trillion
dollars a year.
Now when you consider that
the whole D.O.D. budget, officially,
is just over 400
billion dollars,
We're talking about
a vast infrastructure,
that is,
Four times greater than
the entire D.O.D. budget!
As Jack Nicholson would say:
You can't handle the truth!
Is it possible that ancient
and secret societies exist,
that have always had the
real, but hidden information?
And have they, as a result of
their ongoing familial knowledge,
been manipulating
and governing,
virtually all countries down
through the centuries?
Researchers point
to the Illuminati,
and the power elite and
their use of propaganda,
as carried by the
mainstream media.
Many believe that these powerful few
actually control almost all information,
by implanting false knowledge and
beliefs into our human collective reality.
Essentially, everything that you would
want to know has been covered up.
From the electro genetic
magnificence of your DNA,
being a spiritual
antenna to the creator,
to the most amazing, perfagering
mystery score mathematics,
that is essentially
freeing to humanity,
in essence, also
very, very clear,
that everything in our
world, is a divine creation,
where as the math is the expressive
tool of the creator for creationism.
The United States government,
the leader of the free world,
is totally controlled
by a wealthy oligarchy,
a small, handful
of people,
that are just
super rich.
Most of them are not
even in government.
But they tell the
government what to do.
These are the people who
are behind the UFO secrecy.
They don't care if you know
there's E.T.s out there,
but if you know
then you will know that
there is alternative technology.
And this could
upset the monopolies,
over energy, fuel, transportation,
communications, pharmaceuticals.
And that's what
they don't want.
After all,
who would continue to pay all these
ever increasing prices for gasoline,
that’s polluting
the air,
choking us all,
killing our kids.
Why would we do that if we knew,
beyond any shadow of a doubt,
that there was non-polluting
energy sources out there?
This is what
it's all about.
It comes back to the
old journalistic adage.
Follow the money.
Everything has been
covered up.
Toxicities of the
pharmaceuticals.
You're not learning the
truth about vaccinations.
You're not learning the truth
about various medications.
The pharmaceutical
industrialists,
which I prefer
to call the,
Military Medical Petrochemical
Pharmaceutical Cartel!
Essentially has control of the
media, the mainstream media.
And so it has control
over the mass mind.
And as a result of those
powers that they assert,
people are not given
factual information
upon which to make
informed decisions.
They're given
propaganda.
And as a result, the choices that
people are making are genocidal.
And I say genocidal with a
strict definition, meaning,
the mass killing of people for economic,
political and/or ideological reasons.
And those pharmaceutical
industrialists are
intimately connected to those people
who wish to control populations.
They've published literature
of what their intent is.
Not only how best to control populations,
why populations need to be controlled,
but ultimately, affecting the technologies
that are in place to do just that
Currently, a 50%
reduction in general,
of the planets population has
been targeted for illimination.
The Disclosure Project is oriented
towards putting together
credible government documents
and these witnesses, so that
there is an undeniable case made
that this is real and not fictitious.
It started really in 19...
the early 1990's.
After I had briefed President Clinton's
first C.I.A. director of this problem.
It was made very clear to me
that the executive branch,
of the U.S. government, did not
want to do this because,
I'm quoting.
"The President was concerned he
would end up like Jack Kennedy."
And I'm not kidding.
That was said to me by
President Clinton's closest friend.
Could it be that much of
what we believe is illusion?
Is it possible that the history of human
civilization is not as we have been told?
Have we as people, been
purposefully dumbed down?
And, have our governments only
served to strengthen the bonds,
that bind us to
our ignorance?
Not only of our past, but of our
present and potential future?
Officials in these agencies no longer
represent the best interests of humanity,
but are now representing the interests
of a particular extraterrestrial race,
that they have been
compromised by.
So we pay a heavy price if
we don't make this open.
If we don't bring in transparency
and accountability,
into this
whole process,
it means that we don’t
know whether or not,
those that are
behind the policies,
are actually implementing
these policies for the best
interest of humanity,
which is what they claim,
or for the best interest of a
particular extraterrestrial race.
Some of the questions
that we must ask include:
Are there bases
on our moon?
Are there structures
and life forms on Mars,
and many of the
other local planets?
Have our governments made deals
and treaties with other life forms,
that affect the future of
all of us on planet Earth?
These people will continue,
zipping through our atmosphere
checking our nuclear
plants and so forth and so on.
They have never
been hostile.
They pose no air security
problems, whatever.
The Air force knows this and the Air force
has made statements to that effect.
That UFOs pose
NO threat.
THEY ARE HERE.
Not just the Greys, but the
others, who look and act like us.
Perhaps they are
here to instruct us.
To help us safeguard
our planet.
Definitely rules and regulations
are governing everything.
And the councils have
the history books
of all the planets
and all of the records.
So when a planet reaches the
point that it can support life,
That's a very momentous time
in the history of that planet.
At that time, the planet
is given it's life charter.
We're dealing with
a BIG, BIG story.
It's not just them.
As I've said, if it
was that simple,
it would have probably
been out some time back.
It's really about us.
It's who we are, what we
are, how we came to be.
and where we might
end up going, sometime.
Life is never allowed to just
simply spontaneously develop.
If it did, it would
be very chaotic.
If we could integrate,
I call it the spiritual, but
the esoteric or whatever.
But I mean true esoteric, I
don't mean religion necessarily,
because there is a difference I
think, between religion and spirituality.
To produce a thinking,
intelligent human being,
would have taken
millions more years,
than what's happening
by normal evolution,
than it would
have taken.
and it would have still, not
of got to the point we are now.
They create life on other planets, because
this is the way they were created.
By what they called the Archaic ones,
the ones' from the very beginning,
have been doing
this forever.
Mankind was developed as
a species, as a spiritual being.
And I think we've gotten so far
away from who we really are,
that it's very hard for us to
go back there and digest,
that maybe we have
cosmic brothers and sisters.
We fight among
ourselves for diversity.
I mean, if anybody walks in
here and looks totally different
we fight among ourselves.
Now I'm thinking,
oh my God!
What are the E.T.s that are
involved, thinking about,
the way we handle ourselves, with
people that are so different from us,
They're probably scared to death to appear
because of what we might do to them.
We have not handled
diversity very well.
One day, I would hope
that the people of Earth,
would stand up and
extend their hand in friendship
to these people, we have never
done that here on this planet.
You know, we've
shot at them.
We've done everything. We've fired
radar, we've fired lasers, everything.
We need to say.......Hi!
There are other extraterrestrial
groups who are human looking,
such as the Pleiadians, the famous
Pleiadians of Billy Meyer and others.
And they are much more intent
on trying to assist humanity, to
become free of this kind
of manipulation from,
other races, that really try to
use humanity as a resource.
Let's think about it.
You can't say,
whoopee! Star kids!
These wonderful advanced
children have been transformed by
contact with people
from the stars,
when in the same breath you say,
there's no such things as UFOs.
The question of UFOs
and extraterrestrials,
most people just think
is something entertaining.
In reality, it's something
that is central to
how we're going to be able
to go forward as a civilization.
Because that
issue involves,
sciences, technologies, energy
and propulsion systems,
that could give us a
whole new civilization.
It's terribly important the
whole thing come apart,
because it's
all one package,
and it's part of
our bright and very,
I think, hopeful
future.
And I think of these star kids
growing up and being our leaders.
Our presidents, congress
people, senators.
University professors.
Leaders in medicine and
science and so forth.
I think what brilliant and expansive
future we're going to have,
but we have to get from
point A to point B, and
this cover-up is just stultifying
us in a very painful way.
Is it possible that an
intergalactic federation exists,
and that this collective
of different member beings,
are in the process of
offering the people of Earth,
membership in a
federation of planets?
Most importantly for all
of us and our children,
some of these
researchers say,
that acceptance of their invitation
to federation membership,
would end all war,
starvation and dependency upon
fossil fuel based energy systems,
for our entire planet.
Part of the problem with the
UFO cover-up coming apart;
You've got to uncover the
whole thing at the same time.
You can't half
uncover it.
People who try, they
only look stupid!
but, they are doing it for us,
they are praying for us!
We are the lowest of the
category in the evolutionary scale.
He really believes that humanity is the lowest
of the category of the evolutionary scale.
With all the proof that he gave
you of the ecological problem,
of the war problem,
of the, choosing evil
problem, and all that.
This is his belief system.
We all have a responsibility to find out
what the truth is about something like this.
People have to take responsibility
for looking into what the truth is.
We've put together the
means, for people to do that.
Now, people have
to take the initiative.
And we need all
the help we can get!
I would ask people to
help us network this to,
anyone and any
institution that can help.
The reason this is so
critical, is that-
We've reached a point
in our civilization,
where, for us to go
forward, as a people,
we're going to have to end
this kind of illegal secrecy.
And we're going to have to allow this
information and these technologies,
to get out and begin to fix
many of these large problems.
I've always believed
our destiny is in the stars.
That's a hope that I have.
Generations yet to
come, will travel out there.
And we'll become a
part of that community.
That's a dream that I
won't live to see, but,
it's a dream I hold dear.
That we'll make it.
That we will survive
as a species.
Because I think
we've got some,
I jokingly say, we have some
good friends in high places.
Text: WTC-SWE