All right, we've got the rope over.
For Tim,
having the ability to be an expert tree climber and taking his
six foot seven frame up into a tree and
sitting in a cramped blind and waiting for
seven or eight hours for a bird to show up
and get the images,
there are very few people on the planet
who probably can do that.
A good example of that is the work that we did
on Greater Birds-of-Paradise.
All right,
here’s the lek right here.
See these branches right here;
this is the main display perch
and secondary perch there.
And there’s my blind over there
where I’ve been shooting from.
And right here is
my leaf camera.
So now we had
two ropes
up two different trees and the first thing
Tim had to do was climb the tree in the dark,
get the camera set up,
climb back down,
go over to the other tree,
climb that tree, get in, set up his big camera,
set up the laptop, plug everything in and basically
pray that it all was going to work because there
wasn’t any more opportunity to climb back down
and fix it if it didn’t work
because the sun was coming up
and the birds were coming.
Ever since the beginning of the Birds-of-Paradise project
I've been sort of dreaming of a shot
where I could see a bird in the foreground
and be looking out over the rain forest
in the background.
And I saw the shot download to my
laptop and I said, “That’s it”.
I just knew I had it.