people begin to worry about their aging process
but they don't understand that you're picking
up NEW bits and you can handle a situation\'85Would
you rather be 17 again? (audience: No way\'85)
or would you want the value system of when
you were 17? See? You know what I mean, its
not worth a shit. Now, it must be something
quite interesting as people keep looking back
to their youth, how much they've really missed.
Or how little they've learned in time. What
they've been doing is going around in a barrel,
you know what I mean? In a motorcycle continuously.
And then they lost the ability to do that
and they went downhill and their income is
less and they were invited to less social
affairs and back here they keep thinking about
a motorcycle in the barrel, those were the
big days. So they get older and older and
they can hardly ride a motorcycle now and
they're still over there\'85. I was telling
some of the people here about my family, they
lived through the depression and they actually
never did travel much and then once they went
to Atlantic City for three weeks. Boy, for
twenty years thereafter, "did we ever tell
you about the time we went to Atlantic City"\'85.You
know, there's nothing there but ocean, board
walk\'85they didn't do anything unusual. But
they remember that and a lot of people in
scarcity remember that in the early days.
But you meet kids today, 17, they've been
to Paris and England and France, y'know\'85"I
was in California.." stuff like that. The
world is shrinking, people move around they
drive across country, they go to Yellowstone
National Park many times and it doesn't mean
anything. And how do you talk to people that
have locked on to that that have lived through
the last depression. Are you, will you be
discriminating against them..you just say
"I don't place much value on that kind of
conversation". You say "do you like honesty?"
I would say "it's the only way to be"\'85"Then
I don't place any value on your conversation"
People don't want honesty, what the hell's
honesty? Honesty would be the most offensive
kind of behavior you can think of. Diogenes
found an honest man, the guy to tell him "you're
never going to find anything resembling an
honest man". To be honest you'd have to know
EVERYTHING about EVERYTHING, to be that certain.
You know if someone asked you to tell them
the TRUTH, you say "I'm not that wise. I can
only tell you a little bit of what I know
about a given subject". Some of you may not
understand that. No one can tell the truth.
The truth would mean, that the judge in convicting
somebody was a victim of circumstances and
he was very angry at the person who committed
the crime because his values had no bridge
to understand the physical forces that caused
that person to commit that crime. Whereas,
Clarence Darrow said that the man who commits
the crime is the same as any other man except
the circumstances they were raised under were
different and it led them to that conclusion.
He didn't get mad at people. And so, how do
you deal with all those things? And do you
want to? Sometimes its better for you to collect
a lot of books, know a lot of things, learn
a lot of things, as much as you can, and go
to areas where you can share SOME of those
things on physical anthropology, you meet
with these people and then the physical anthropologist
and you share what you can with them. And
you talk with electronics people about electronic
subjects and engineers about engineering subjects.
But I find that if you deviate too much from
the subject you lose contact. If you surpass
your friends in electronics then you can't
visit them anymore. You find this, that the
people you were very close to 10 years ago.."I
don't know what happened but I became a loner\'85"
What happens is that people are not that interesting
to you any more. You don't place a value in
the subjects they cherish. I don't know what
to say when someone says "come on over to
the house, it's my baby's birthday". "Well,
put the baby in the other room and we'll sit
down and bullshit"..I used to say to my brother
"come on over but leave the kids home". He
knew what I meant but he didn't like it. He
didn't like it, do you understand what I mean?
How'd you get to be an uncle? What's an uncle?
Is an uncle a thing where you get a blood
transfusion if you need it? Is an uncle any
physical referential thing that can serve?
Just a victim of certain values, "this is
my nephew"\'85well, maybe that person was
switched in the hospital, maybe you took the
wrong kid home. Maybe it's NOT your nephew.
I don't even know if my kids are my kids,
I really honestly don't know that. They may
be, they may not be, but it doesn't matter.
You treat all kids\'85you don't have to worry
about that. I don't want Fresco stamped on
the thumb. Besides my daughter doesn't have
Fresco..( ?) Doesn't serve, the idea (?)
Now Ford of course, he's a smart guy. You
buy a truck and you carry a label on the back,
Ford. You're a living billboard for the Ford
Motor Company. I don't want his fuckin' name
on it, I paid for that truck, I want Fresco's
great visions\'85or whatever the hell I've
got to sell on the back of that truck. But
there are people that drive trucks with the
names of companies. They are intruding, I
can send them a bill, because they have posted
their name on my truck without asking\'85wouldn't
get anywhere. But, some people do that, they
can't do it in architecture I don't think
they ever have a "Louis B. Schmidt Home".
I don't think I've ever seen that. I've seen
buildings called Rockefeller Center, I've
seen things like that. But if I buy the building,
you tear down the name, people can't find
you anymore. So they buy a corporation and
sometimes they buy the name, it might be your
company, John's company. And everybody knows
it and they buy a lot of stuff from that company.
And some people when they buy you out they
don't want to change the name. And if somebody
later finds out that John's company became
the most corrupt company in the world, they'd
pull their friends away from you. You said
"but I'm no longer affiliated"..doesn't make
any difference. Isn't that interesting. That's
the sad thing about people. And if you found
out I've been married for 20 years and my
wife was a prostitute. The neighbors are not
going to invite me over. I said "i didn't
know that". And so they have a certain set
about those things, "they are bad people".
I don't even know how to wrestle with it,
or even know where to begin. And is it worth
beginning? Alright, before i get on with the
subject I want to talk about with you tonight
I just want to say that when I went back to
New York and all the relatives came over,
my mother was about 80 years old, and I "poisoned"
them; I hit them with thousands of different
values and their kids were there and my sister
came out and said "don't you use that kind
of language in my home". So I said "well I
can leave now" and all the relatives said
"No, it's a good idea for the kids to hear
that.." and they voted her out. And she went
back into the kitchen and started to cook.
But she was invited in, she wasn't kept out
of things. Now, no one turned and said "don't
you have any respect for your sister?" I don't
even know what respect means. I say that the
reason that I talk to you, my relatives like
this is cause I respect you. That's hard to
understand. You know "Fuck that shit" to my
relatives and I say "I respect you, I don't
conceal that, I must trust your ability to
handle this linguistic difference". So respect
is the ability to say to somebody "I've got
bleeding piles" \'85I don't care about your
piles, then why do you ask me how my floppy
eyelid was? Aren't you concerned about my
health? \'85say, "well, I've got a headache".
People, that's all they wanted, give them
an aspirin. Says I've got an infected ear\'85must
be very painful. But very few people walk
around saying "I've got an infected asshole"..I
used to say years ago to my wife "I've got
to take a shit" she said "don't tell me just
go do it"\'85And so she says "I'm going out
to hang the laundry on the line" or "I'm going
out to get a quart of milk"\'85"we want to
share all things" she says "but not that".
So you run into a lot of problems and I just
want to briefly say this. It's the story of
driving the car to the garage and you say
to the mechanic once in awhile (?) You talk
about everything and anything without (?)
You can't confront the judge and say "how
do you make that decision?" He's got a book
in front of him that tells him what decision
to make. He's not interested in other concepts
and ideas. You can't get up as the free American
thinker. They'll say I don't hold..that point
of view I consider it obsolete. (audience:
?) Ah, now you're communicating. That's real
semantics. You buy the guy, you buy the judge
or you put the congressman in there. You don't
have to tell him every week what you want,
he knows what you want, cause he gets the
check. If it stops coming he can't operate.
We're going to talk about biochemical conditioning
and learning without experience. And theres
a possibility of that and it has nothing to
do with the word experiments, or the dna.
It has to do with something like this. In
the learning process of all organisms there
is an input device; you pick it up from your
nose your eyes your ears your tongue, and
they all come into the brain and there are
all kinds of cross associations. But if you
could impart information into people, if you
could do this. Put two electrodes on the head
of the person and play information into the
brain you will not have the cross associations.
You'll have a glass and you'll have milk and
you'll have milk in the glass, but how come
it's put in the glass as a container and why
you selected that will not be known. But if
you pipe that in, you'll have a file on milk,
glass, drinking milk in glass and there will
be very little cross associations. Here's
how you understand it, lets assume that due
to shock Ben lost his ability to walk. He
just can't walk, he saw some horrible condition
and he's unable to walk. So we stick two electrodes
into the muscle in the spinal area and we
play the walking cycle into his legs. They
say "how is he walking"\'85.he says "believe
me I really don't know" and there he is walking.
And a lot of people think because you can
walk that you know how you walk. Even people
that can walk don't know how they walk. They
don't say "there's a discharge at\'85(etc.)"
They don't know that, they don't know how
they walk. If you turn to a person and say
"can you see? I've been blind for years" and
a person.."yeah, with my eyes". That's no
fucking answer. People think I'm answering
questions. How do you learn to walk with crutches?
He says "like this.." And even in books on
semantics there's no information. So the question
is "what is learning?" Now, does a person
who can't do any weaving weave a blanket?
If I connect an electrode to the hip and transmit
to the brain and nervous system and they start
weaving, they're amazed, as amazed as you
are. And so you say "how do you do it?" Says
"I don't know I've got some thing connected
to my head" and then you say "stop doing that,
scratch my back" and the hands won't do that
if you're playing that loop. And if you play
a walking loop and decide not to walk you
go right on walking. I don't know if you've
ever had a high voltage thing put in your
hand\'85(?). In the early days, an electrician
trying to see if something is alive would
go like that\'85if it was alive his hand would
close on it, on a wire like that. And he'll
die and so if they do they'll hit it like
that and reflexes the other way\'85 (?) And
if a guy is working on an electrical system
and he's down on his knee and he makes contact
these muscles contract and I've seen a guy
crack his head on the ceiling. He'd never
jump that high, 250 volts right up to the
ceiling\'85clunk. Say "how'd you do that?"
He doesn't know how he did it. Alright, they
don't know the difference between conditioning
which moves a muscle or a reflex, artificial
reflex. Let's take a Frenchman who can't speak
English, let's assume we can do this\'85run
an electrode to the brain and \'85(?) He doesn't
know what he's saying. Neither does a Frenchman.
If you turn to a Frenchman and said "give
me a cup of coffee" in French\'85 said what
do you mean by a cup of coffee? You know a
cup of coffee\'85doesn't know what that is
either\'85(?) Alright when you learn to ski
you don't learn about how you learn to learn
to ski. You just get on the skis and the guy
says "turn your toes in and lean when you're
going downhill this way or that way, or you
want to turn, jump\'85" they give you the
gross reflexes necessary for that. But if
they gave you a description of all the muscles
involved in learning to ski; you gotta learn\'85
So I want to say something about the learning
process. It is not so much that we really
learn but we're stimulated to simulate parallel
verbal behavior and verbal behavior that others
require of us. Like if you hold up a dog a
little while and feed it then put your hands
under it and feed it, pretty soon it gets
up and you say to the dog "how do you do that?"
The dog doesn't say "well come on in the other
room and I'll lay it out". Alright its the
same thing with love, hand holding, we don't
know what it is, cause they never grabbed
us when we were young and conditioned us to
a method of analyzing the kind of conditioning
that's being superimposed upon us. And the
more books you read that are quite different
from the cultural views that are established
something happens in your head. You get a
different kind of set. And so you hear different
views and you reject it right away. You don't
get conditioned cause you hang out with a
screening process. The stuff comes in and
bounces off. I'm sure you've read a lot of
books and said "hogwash" and so\'85(?) You
know what I mean by developing a screening
process? Alright so you can be conditioned
by certain people if they have the elements
to condition you, and you can condition certain
people. And if you succeed in getting a guy
to read Loeb or a gal to read Loeb and other
books and "Tyranny of Words" and many of the
books that you like, it doesn't mean that
the rest of the mental set is going to be
able to file it in the appropriate regions.
}