it's proving citadel dominates the
granada skyline
it's great walls have thirty-seven
gigantic towers
and it took over a hundred and fifty
years to fail
but the alhambra is more than just a
military strong
it's a pleasure palaces
exquisite courtyards
up blood-soaked see a terrible get the
entry
and to the most famous surviving
monument to muslim engineering
in the western world
granada southern spain
in that thirteen century this tension
city lived under muslim rule
the point where the great granada plane
rose to join the mountains of the sierra
nevada
godding over that junction
is the magnificent fortress known
as the alhambra
it was intended to that site to make
military statement
said that it is the powerful
it's not just a fortress
it's suspect
tucked in a network of policies
each one different
by a succession of salt
across a hundred and fifty years each
new ruler has development house because
controller and you have to melt
these promises is surrounded by an
exquisite suite of darkness
combined who
risen from tunis fed by fresh mountain
watched over
via brooding fortress designed to
intimidate
yet for all its beautiful bravado
the alhambra it's not too triumphalism
monument
it was born of fear
twelve thirty eight eighteen
the muslim world of being under attack
from christian crusaders for over a
century
the five hundred year old muslim empire
in spain
we shrinking under pressure from the
rising christine kingdoms in the north
it's an old friend as the president
aristede question
south plains anti anything i think
century's most definitely a period of
diet crisis firmness limp out
dr amira bentsen describes this turning
point in the history of muslim spain
they faced pressure test email
and then add up on indecent part of what
became staying
the empire
and it was in ny period if collapse that
we see local lads
like mohammed first an acid density
beginning to combat anisha for
themselves
not much is known about muhammad it
denies he had before he enters granada
he was just one of the many minus
sultans warren over the scraps of the
fading muslim empire
when cast steel advanced on his northern
territories
he headed south
and took over granada under
circumstances
curtis shrouded in mystery
easy opportunistic leave act
an enterprising individual who's making
best use of the political circumstances
at the time two tries to cheer the any
chance of very existence
including renata
once they're muhammad climbed a wooded
slopes about granada
in search of a location to build the
fortress
in which he could safely on his family
and the nationals from kristina paris
he heard of a force built up from thirty
years and a half hour previous testing
and climb to the hill to investigate
before him the ancient arab casa lsac
thomas a beacon hill
framed by the mountains of the sierra
nevada
it was the perfect site for a fortress
in his mind's eye he conceived grow
before him
muhammad had found his ideal location
decide because he historical wasteful
forties
because is sucky
nearly lost on the media fight don
antonio audit went out
isn't experts in the architecture of the
alhambra
he believes the chill griffey if the
area
is perfect for a stronghold
unhindered back
are desires he's of sierra nevada so
no report in to dickey's will be fine
muhammad instantly recognized the sites
defensive possibilities
she started to outline the citadel if
his dreams
the first step was to rebuild the
existing fortress known as the outcomes
of god
into a stronghold large enough to
support his troops
this would goddess suite of palaces
surrounded by luxurious gardens
that would form a royal quarter
on the northern side of the hill
undecided township
colder medina
housing the hundreds of people needed to
run this royal bastante
encircling it would be a gigantic
perimeter walls
dotted with dot talents to fight off
marauding attackers
the first he needed to build the
watchtower
defensive towers would form an integral
part of muhammad's concept for the
alhambra
the basic building block of each town it
was a square chamber repeated at every
level
these chambers would be filled with
faulted arches
that led light flood through the
interior spaces
the first hour muhammad would build was
the tolerated and i think that known as
the watchtower by the locals
this brooding giant was bigger than
anything granada had seen before
it sent a message to both muslim and
christian alike
it was a statement to the people off or
not
lasted realistic trying to say we can
defend you
but remember that we are you live
and that we are powerful on that week
dominates you as all subject
service watchtower needed to be strong
enough to hold off any attackers
wild bill this constructed the rest of
the alhambra
for this to work
muhammad wanted it positioned on the
extreme weston tip of the should be
cahill
where it would act as the unka for his
plans new fortress
here it would be surrounded by steep
slopes on three sides protecting it from
attack
as it dominated the granada plane
constructing a huge tower on the
precipice
using nothing but primitive tools
would not be easy for the builders
but the solution to that problem they've
right beneath their feet
they were building that fortress on
almost sheer drop
great for defense
and a gigantic gash in that steep slope
reveals the amazing substance that made
the alhambra possible
beneath the tolerate eleven civil
engineer at mcad investigates a seam of
this red rock
paula secrets to the construction of
this place only
is this material here
it is the famous alhambra conglomerate
an extra-special ai and sandanistas
c_n_n_'s love it
get it by some weight
clapton's is the client
starts getting sticky
service material becomes moldable
and they use this stuff
to make that
it gave the builders of ready-made
source of materials onsite
this sped up the construction timetable
and kept them close to the fortress they
were building
it's kalo also gave the stronghold it's
name
the madina alhambra
which means
red city
this amazing early cement allowed the
builders to lay a strong concrete base
for the great watchtower without having
to quarry and transport huge amounts of
stone
thought there was a serious flaw in the
bill
his design
the core of the tower was supported by
tears of options
the full weight of the building resting
upon them
halfway through construction
the builders realized that the arches
were not strong enough to take the mood
muhammad's first hour could collapse in
on itself at any minute as an extra
means of support
they filled in part of the basement to
provide a solid foundation for the
talent to rest on
that hasty repairs
failed to fix the problem
muhammad's fortress was in danger
falling down
britain
the alhambra sinning watchtower the
story that i think that was in trouble
passage builders began to erected
supplementals it was clear that the
lower levels were not strong enough to
support them
edmica explores to find out why
uh... this area
was misleading or for a national news
who were brought here a series of
options that he didn't believe he broke
up
is on his own shootings and vicinity
you know this has nothing to do this
when the structures working for women
who happens to losses in revenue
the structures in distress
there is a
although it here
is very substantial structural crack
roman war our problems what or waiting
on the wall
right away to the floor
is incredible if you're in the hands on
moral issues is that this for me
this one here
postpone the away from this one here
lungs crack for the question is what
post is for one more
the weight of the tower was crushing the
options that were holding it out pushing
it out of shape and cracking its walls
soledad when the spending cuts that they
were
isn't going to go up
here your honor the arch
and turned into a wall something that
was also someone said
muhammad's builders brick topped the
options to provide the crucial support
needed but the interior of the talent no
longer or any resemblance to its
original design
the sultans vision of auction spaces
with a varied into play of light and
shadow
has vanished entirely
in its place is a brutal monument to the
needs of the age
those needs
were defensive
muhammad's great watchtower looks out
over the plains of the sierra nevada
with the distant hills of the kingdom on
the horizon
covered by martin city today
the watchtower once looked out over the
wind farm land
gear it's ideally cited to form the
heart of the great intelligence network
that god's muhammad's kingdom
and the sultan house in need of such a
network
by twelve forty five just seven years
after he took over granada muhammad has
already lost his northern territories to
the christian advance and his army is
too small to win them back
this is not a man who is surviving on
the basis of
military might
and those days are long gone he
surviving on information
and on his relationships
as professor didi fairchild rock als and
those
the alhambra scanned tinued existence is
dependent on the good intelligence
needs information he needs to know when
enemies are approaching
and he needs to know what's going on to
gather this information
the installs a network of signal towers
designed to warn him of the christian
advance
this network a fork lifts was known as
talia asks
they were part of a vast information
gathering system etc dot it intelligence
from people who passed through the area
providing early warning of christian
troop movements
signals warning of impending attack
would be transmitted from the top of the
tower by means of special may replace
all fun
from there
they race from talent to talent
traveling into the kingdom towards the
alhambra
until ultimately they arrive on the roof
of the alhambra swatched our whether a
warm the sultan of impending attack
in twelve forty six
messages from his signal towers
tell muhammad at the christian king
fernando of castio has taken high-end
sixty six kilometers north of granada
it's a major blow
muhammad realizes that he cannot stop
the caste indian entrance
he needs more time to complete his
fortress
he strikes a deal with fernando in
return for guarantees of his own
autonomy
muhammad not only gives up and
he helps fernando cc bill
it's a clever move
but it's also an admission of weakness
lots of people were shocked eddie had in
effect abandoned high-end
the reason he kicked back with to
protect the city of print not a he felt
that this was that cost that had to be
paid to protect the enclave he created
muhammad knows the uneasy troops might
break down at any moment he wants to
ensure that he citadel
is secure is quickly as possible
to do that he must finish the outcomes
about fortress which will house the
troops guarding the alhambra
the plan is to build a triangular consul
conquered upon three towers
from here
a gate house in the back wall provides
access to the rest of the alhambra
have working with the naturally
occurring alhambra conglomerate the
builders use molds to arrest its three
me two thick walls k thing about me
conglomerate diseases that you can build
and this war he shows exactly how they
did it
basically what you do is you build
yourself a mold
yes his big panels joined together by a
series of timber polls and you can see
where the polls would have gone here the
compulsory that put it in the panels in
tied in together and then you're
throwing a conglomerate through the
water
and you're an all-white pounding it and
forcing
particles of the conglomerate together
and really tight concrete light convicts
they leave the letter dry
then climb up onto it and repeat the
process
but the engineers know that there's a
significant downsides to this method of
construction with water and win the
stuff gets blown away i'm what you're
looking at here is that your edited
surfaced out of the many years has lost
its strength
and to prevent that happening what they
did
was their plight at alignments and stock
of which is what this finishes his
sister's bicyclists and mix that would
lying
and a bit of water and applied like a
plaster
that's much much better than swart
and in the job would be done
in this way the walls and buildings that
made up the outcomes about
could be erected swiftly and efficiently
under the defensive chateau victoria del
evento
looking down from this watchtower the
ground plan of the buildings that once
filled the outcast of dollars still
visible
this driving miniature township
houses the troops that got the sultan
and the people who look after them
the central street in the heart of the
aisle kassebaum past five warehouses
and thirteen private houses
tarry
kilns
store houses
and a bakery supply the populations
needs
the out kassebaum he's tina with life
and rising above them all of the great
defensive towers that overlooked the
fortress
sultan mohamed must've wandered through
his stronghold and felt that his dennis
d could find in the pc kua
thought there was more to the alhambra
than just a fortress because beyond the
elk as a pa p plans a suite of palaces
that will eventually how's the sultan
and his family
along with gardens
and a mini township to support them
the alibi how population of not only
easel continents family but of course
his followers
answer rents and gardens of large
population that lived in that palace
so one can think of that happening
intercity probably win as many as five
thousand people living there
in order to sustain this population
the alhambra is threaded with darkness
i'll call you know that all of us will
love money regardless of the other
number are designed to recreate
annoyances
don antonio mountain peak a has studied
the landscape of the hour hambrecht
index
for him
the gardens have a dual purpose
suddenly sensed the sensation of being
in that would be a similar space and at
the same time a pro to the states
fundamental
before
so the gardens of the alhambra we
designed for practicality as well as
pleasure
to grow food as well as flowers
there is just one problem
there is no source of freshwater on the
sabhi ko
it's issue drawback for a stronghold
expected to feed and water as many as
five thousand people
the nearest water source is the river
that flows just to the north of the site
the case
has a severe drawback
cause if you've been here in the
thirties century
revert dot i would've looked pretty much
like it does today the small babbling
brook making its way through granada
the basic problem amit has
towards down here
an immediate out there
to make the alhambra viable
its builders must divert an entire river
up onto the mountain of mohammed
and
making a river float back onto the
alhambra is issued challenge
but muhammad and his engineers must find
a way to make it happen
because without it he cannot transform
these new citadel
into a self-sufficient oases have gotten
some farmland
he needs to carry gallons of water to
the gardens he's planning
to do this
he missed threat the alhambra with
irrigation channels
and this is not an easy task
it's easy to forget in the modern world
how significant war stories
in the historic environment how
difficult was to get hold of
cc imaginary community on tocqueville
and computer tomorrow for water
hundreds of feet above the water
supplies most obvious
the local residents
confronted with its plaguing the obvious
and clever thing we would use the there
what
to some point when it was actually above
them
eleni energy of the river itself bring
water to them
but there is no natural lake about the
alhambra
so they create one
muhammad's engineers constructed down
the path the alhambra
which will build up enough water
pressure
to feed into the citadel
six kilometers from the alhambra dawn
antonio has found the downs at the
engineers created
before but i'm a fan of hillary we find
ourselves that israel battled exact
point for the first man seeking mohammed
the first ordered the construction of
attempt to divert water from the figured
that the other way
based and created reservoir system
capable of providing enough water to
fill in olympic sized swimming pool
hand free five sec
to the alhambra popular
it's hard to believe that this was dot
fi handle most eight hundred years ago
but the ny six martin concrete scheme
liza truly ancient design
d'amato what is he still has the same
sign this letter to the
the only thing that has changed since
the in metairie
every year who know me big time
there are two frontgate of that
one of the gates about what is the flow
into the debate that often the opposite
side of the doubt
tell us what it into that it that way
water from this reservoir flows into a
brick line to come out
known isn't perfect here
this ultimately feeds the alhambra
but diverting the river darrow is just
the start of this mammoth project
the canal builders still have to
overcome a major obstacle
polygamy
the reservoir sits in a valley between
three hills
so in order to reach the alhambra
muhammad's engineers need to build a
water channel six kilometers long
that winds through the hills above the
fortress
this has to carry the equivalent of
seven thousand olympic sized swimming
pools
everyday to support the alhambra is
growing population
and will only work if it flows down hill
at a constant gradient
so how can this happen
when there's a hill in the way
this solution is approved one
instead of going over the high ground
they decide to go through it
the builders dega time about one meter
wide and two meters high through the
hillside towards the alhambra
and the natural stability of the
alhambra conglomerate
in shows that there's no danger of
collapse
it must have taken the months to borrow
a channel into the hill next to the
alhambra
known as the hen iran if it
but there is still one great problem
that must be solved
the alhambra sits on a completely
different hill
muhammad's engineers must find a way to
get the water from one hill
to another
to get water from the hill of the henner
arafat next to the alhambra
into the alhambra itself
muhammad's engineers need to cross a
fifteen meet again that separates the
two hills
the solution
and packwood out
and this is where the water from the
tarifa arise if the alhambra
comes across here
and in the old days it used to go across
the us if you have a yahoo which was a
channel which took it all the way into
the center of the alhambra
the icici every alan formed a lifeline
for the alhambra sit it out
from here water flowed to every part of
the alhambra
it provided fresh water for the populace
fed the multitude of water features in
the darkness of the sultans
these cartons were designed to symbolize
the kingdom of granada
over which the self mushrooms
the gardens had a practical function as
well
they were designed
to create an oasis in the heat of the
granada sound
islam originated in the bed sets in an
environment where water was its premium
and the ability to provide warts and for
how quartet
leading eight not to be something
at sixteen eighteen title kal
in fact it's more than desirable
it's of crucial importance
playing wants is very important but i
wasn't affected
he needed to perform ritual conditions
in one eighty standout humber at what
that is ready completely still
even when you have still pulls water is
flowing into those schools
and filling out again
and it's very important in terms of
ritual purity that whole waters of the
continues flowing
to keep the water pure
muhammad's engineers must create a
system that will prevent sediment from
soaking up the channels
their ingenious solution can be found
dotted all over the alhambra
shallow pool
that's designed to slow the watered down
searching the waters coming
zooming down the channel carrying all
this and pieces
and comes to an area where its wide
indeed
was slow slow it down
and uh... stilts and sends them to slow
down for tomato
in this way
the water for the alhambra stockman's
will be kept constantly fresh
too much water can be a fat thing
if the system over loads
it can back up
blocking the channel and stopping the
water from flowing freely
to prevent this from happening
muhammad's engineers decide to install a
safety valve
any excess water that might overload the
icici ac
is funneled along the side channel
that diverts it into an overflow system
built into the walls
and this is where it comes up
the war starts off opinion pam brown
comes down in the park
through they sell for
dumbest travel and joins up with the
river borrowed it
the engineers may have been genius lee
solved the problem of too much water
but not the problem of too little
and it soon became apparent that during
dry seasons
the alhambra could exhaust its water
supply
at the summit of the header aliphatic
stands their solution to the problem
a massive set of russia flies
visa positioned on the high ground so
that gravity can insure a constant flow
of water defeat the gardens
to get the water up to the stress of
lies muhammad's engineers harness it
donkey to a mechanism of interlocking
wooden gears
when it walks in a circle
it turns up horizontal we'll
this in turn rotate sick care attached
to a water wheel
which dips a line of buckets into the
ethic here below
and deposits the water into a reservoir
above
in this way the alhambra zen ginny as
we're able to realize muhammad stream
of an oasis of gotten surrounding the
palace complex protected by his fortress
but muhammad himself will not seen his
dream come to fruition we he dies in
twelve seventy three before his life's
work is complete
behind him
he leaves one great project unfinished
the prime reason he has built a fortress
here in the first place
the nazri palaces
this is the heart of the alhambra
in the one hundred years that followed
muhammad even as he is dead
his successes completed the great
perimeter wall that surrounds the
citadel
began to construct the palace complex
the courthouse his dynasty
each palace is unique
build one after the other by a
succession of sultans
each internet tended to want to feel the
need house or at least renovate existing
passes to make that and mark
so you end up with a sequence of
different buildings
gradually fill out the space
intellectually create a whole network
palisades
we being
the alhambra complex itself
together they form one of the most
impressive palace complex is still
standing in europe today
this is what the alhambra was designed
to protect
but there is one particular palace
designs not just to protect
but to intimidate
thirteen thirty three
a century after its foundation
yusuf the first comes to the throne of
the alhambra
he inherits the mantle of sultan at a
high point in granada is long-running
conflict with the caste indian
christians
who occupy much of spain
iranian he said the fast in the annie
fourteen centuries all the first
highpoint
off the kingdom
uses the fast allies that marini dynasty
in north africa
and appears to be in quite a strong
position vis-a-vis the christian
kingdoms
to the north
alongside his new allies the marines
yusuf launches an attack into custody in
territory
trying to regain some of the land his
forefathers have lost
however granada is ascendancy short
lived
just seven years later king alfonso of
cast steel defeats the muslims of the
battle of the river sound at all
forcing u since allies the marinis
to withdrawal from spain for good
this may explain why the last active use
of strain
is to build a shoots defensive tala the
biggest yet on the alhambra is north
wall
but already accommoda s
this massive tala stands forty five
meters tall
it forms the centerpiece of the brand
new palace
that use of decides to build
in order to shoe horn it into the new
palestinian
usace architects have to extend an
existing tower on the north wall
they shift the existing sentry walk for
the north onto a new wall and extend the
tower another twelve meters out
but use of isn't thinking of defense
he's thinking of his image
his talent
is designed to make a statement
use of the first has just suffered a
terrible defeat
he decides to build a monuments that
will reinforce his power and involve
ability
in the eyes of his people
by building this tyler yusef stamps his
authority in his kingdom
but yusuf isn't just trying to impress
his own people
he wants to establish he's been from
ability in the minds of his christian
enemies the great hall in the palace of
the com artists is compensating for the
way for lack of of military strength
because he has to rely on political and
diplomatic negotiations he needs very
impressive space in which to conduct
those
thousands of tourists aruba wellness by
the same sense of all that christian
ambassadors must have felt
when they came to me to sell
because the interior of the complex is
designed to make an impression
this is uses grand palace
at its heart the glory that is the whole
of the ambassadors
everything in this overwhelming room
is designed to impress
any visiting ambassador would have been
struck by the sheer scale of the
alhambra
the entire edifice is calculated to
convey an impression of supreme
invincibility
the complex stock homework contains
repeated arabic inscriptions
in praise of allah
almost one my arm and that's right
which is there is no comparable thought
can you see that repeated over and over
and over again
proceedings seventy five feet about
contains more than eight thousand
individual pieces of cd word
painted to resemble
the seven happens of islam
victimized ally is
a microcosm of even if x and sultana can
control it
he is in a sense in control of universe
which is quite a bold statement intimate
he had made a central challenge the
usace architects have to face
they had to impress any ambassador kim
entered this room with the power and
presence of the south
to do that
they needed to focus all
all the attention in the room onto the
sultans thrown in
it's a very striking manipulation of
space to emphasize the fact that you set
the fast
is there enough importance and power and
then he said to be in control of this
indent
to do this the alhambra stock index had
one thing that could help them
mathematics
when the classical world collapsed the
mathematical knowledge used to build the
great monuments of greece and rome was
collected by muslim scholars
and passed down through the muslim
houses of wisdom
at the time of the alhambra
l all of the learning company
and later the woman's
is incorporated into islamic mathematics
they don't reject it because it doesn't
threaten their religion
so here we have this classical legacy of
mathematics
that is not only and how did that then
improved upon
span a muslim architect issues two units
of measurement inherited from classical
architecture
called the russia sheet coder
it was about sixty two centimeters long
than virtually all of the alhambra is
based on this unit of measurement
this late at the heart of the alhambra
st sign
so to create a space that will overwhelm
visitors with the importance of their
sultan
uses architect's design a ground plan
eighteen russia she koto square
they defied the room along its
horizontal in diagonal axes
using strength
fame all count four ninety degree oxfam
wall-to-wall
a straight line between the end points
of the socks creates an off together
this allows them to create a larger
square sitting diagonally across the
original
which marks the location of the central
windows at the entrance
equal actual triangles drawn from the
center of the walls create the perfectly
proportioned width of these windows
very intimidating experience to walk
into the hall of the ambassador's and to
see the full time
position there
century man in that space
generate behind him hannah ran up on
city
and nothing i thought all thought his
territory
how it must have been very impressive
enough that then calculated to
intimidate
for beating both on the inside and the
outside
the tower seems to have done its job
no one dared to attack the alhambra
while yusef was on the throne
in fact he sits down for
would come from a completely unexpected
source
for with great beauty comes great pain
and before the alhambra ca truly fowler
including geo one of the most traumatic
events in its history
nineteenth of october thirteen fifty
four
more than a century after the alhambra
sf ambition
use of the first is preparing for his
daily press
as he does uh...
he is attacked by a deranged slave
capt
command and staff seemed to death
yusef was just thirty six years old
his death paves the way things and on
the defense
to create what may become
the alhambra is greatest monument
just five years into his red
accord chin tries to assassinate the new
south
muhammad flees from his own people
and seeks refuge with granada is oldest
enemy
the christian king of castio
despite his nickname pedro the crew
helps muhammad win back his throne
petr cruel and how much effect really
had a friendship with respect to some
extent instead
intellectual and artistic interests
one could imagine that the team and kate
at had attending friendship beyond the
politics
of here and i think that just underlines
the point that we shouldn't think of
christians and muslims is always at
loggerheads
his friendship with mohammed will change
the alhambra forever
like many spanish kings
pedro is profoundly impressed by the
beauty of muslim architecture
so when he builds a new palace in
seville
he models it on the muslim packing
and when my husband finally
is returned to the throne and goes back
to granada
he spent several years in the company of
another architectural
fan
discussing architecture any brings many
ideas that were developed incidental
back-to-back on that with him this is
very interesting because it means that
the building that we consider the high
point of islamic architecture in spain
always adapt to a christian pallets
insecure
when he returns to the alhambra
muhammad is determined to outdo petraeus
masterpiece in seville
and his triumphant response will be an
architectural tour defaults
with its magnificent courtyard in
breathtaking ceilings
muhammad deficits palace who proved to
be more beautiful
more sophisticated
and more accomplished than the muslim
style masterpiece of his powerful
christian mister
under the reign of muhammad the fish
the age-old rivalry between vannatter
and cast steel takes a radically
different costs
frank status friendship with picture of
casting
military confrontation transforms
into an artistic competition
muhammad commissions the exquisite
palace
and of course of the lions
which seeks to emulate in surpass the
beauty of cadres palace in seville
surfaces
uh... different part thereof
more publicity otherwise
because the test influences so both
islamic atleast ten architect at the
same time
the court of the lions
for many people is the high point of
mastered architecture in the high point
of islamic architecture in spain
it is spatially complex
marie s refine and it brings it all
together in one exquisite space
pia is the crown jewel of the alhambra
built according to a set of rectangles
each related to the other
once again muhammad's architect issues
geometry different effect
when we look at the facade what we see
pain bytes with used to form a school
where
which defines the next level up then we
take the diagonal on that score squeeze
through to the tickle the point the end
of the diana hits the becomes the next
flow within do exactly the same in the
dying from the school
so what you're getting is is the very
precise relationship between one story
high in the next
in accordance with
recruits
elvis looks right to ask because why the
greek architect has come down to us
defines our
sense of beauty nuclear group buildings
and i feel right was because of
presenters
beautiful artefacts
despite these western influences
the palace of the lions remains a
resolutely eastern building
let me say today we don't really see it
as it was
before wondering
program the central balloting
were actually bumpin
the flower beds were in circled by the
sounds of the sultans wives which
overlooked the central garden
you'd had people sitting around the
edges of the court on costanzo pockets
picking
i'd just saying the talks appliances and
shrubs and trees
these rooms contain the palaces most
spectacular tranship
an exquisite form of decoration
known as more cut-outs
with absolutely unique to islam
it's hard to explain where comes from
it's hard to even understand it when you
see it it is so gasoline it it confounds
the senses
you have a sense of it is not wait there
in that it's hard to leave and almost
seems to me is a senior cabinet because
of the interplay
like to say all of these small price
like helen
and again
it's mathematics that creates this
astounding intricacy
hasn't exactly on a trip to the patent
which uses triangles and rectangular
blocks to create its effects
the variety of cuts in the past two work
creates different geometrical shapes
cataracts
the uses set into the wall of the
building with clay
ready for painting plaster work is very
complex
not only because the constant play
between solid and void but also it was
originally paid it it was bright red
bright blue so would have been a very
vibrant scary
the painters use exotic pigments among
them bluegrass you right
extracted from lancaster nasty line in
afghanistan
which cost as much as cold
it's as if the walls of existence had
been completely changed
because overhead is this vault
you cannot comprehend you actually
cannot understand
spatial dimensions are
there is no explain out there that you
can focus her eyes it is
an extraordinary sensory experience
this was to prove the high points for
the muslim kingdom of granada
because a century after muhammad unpaved
roads artistic alliance
but different kind of partnership
would signal the alhambra stand for
in fourteen sixty nine the christian
kingdoms of cast steel and arrogant
unite under ferdinand and isabella
sick historic alliance creates the
kingdom of spain
unmarked suv brutal new phasing
christian policy towards granada
this crusade
on new year's day fourteen ninety-two
after ten long years of war
granada
last muslim bastion in spain finally
compete relates to the christians
among those in the spanish company
witness the surrender
is a sea captain
seeking royal sponsorship for a voyage
of discovery
to the new world
is christopher columbus
the alhambra is new catholic masters
would soon stamp their own mark onto the
complex
in the center of the fortress
king carlos the faith began building a
huge squad
palace
with a circular courtyard
it stands in marked contrast to the
architecture of its nazri predecessor's
it l two mclean
nothing can detract
from fact explicit beauty
if one compares the alana
stone houses of europe
it's just another world entirely
no wonder they want the concord ma it
was a absolutely beautiful and unlike
anything that existed in europe at that
time
a fortress first
a pleasure palace second
and now a place of wonder for tourists
from all over the world
the alhambra still stands today
as a testament to the genius and beauty
of muslim oxfam decide