no stranger to full-on
water wars.
Basically, whoever controls
the water in California
controls the future.
Currently the dominant player in
the state's big agriculture
is Paramount Farms,
which is owned and
operated by Stewart Resnick.
Stewart's goals have recently
aligned very closely with
Governor Jerry Brown's.
WALT GRAY: California's water
war is heating up.
The governor has just unveiled
a new $14 billion plan to
build two tunnels underneath the
delta, transferring water
from northern California
to southern California.
The governor says his plan will
create a reliable water
supply and still maintain
a healthy
ecosystem in the delta.
Not everyone agrees.
EMERSON ROSENTHAL: That's
why we came out west.
We wanted a firsthand look into
the newest chapter of
California's water works.
So, our first job was to meet
Congressman John Garamendi,
who has been fighting
Jerry Brown's water
proposals since the '70s.
JOHN GARAMENDI: This proposal
goes back at least 40 years.
Jerry Brown, in the 1970s, when
he was governor, wanted
to build this system, got it
through the legislature.
I and several other folks
decided that was a bad thing
and we fought it.
We had a referendum.
And now he's back.
He said it very clearly, I'm
going to do it this time.
What are you going
to do, governor?
You're so determined to relive
your old life that you want to
destroy this thing?
You want to build a system that
would destroy the largest
estuary on the west coast of
the Western hemisphere?
Is that what this is
all about, just so
you say I did it?
It's the north versus
the south.
It's the war of water
in California.
It's been going on since the
gold rush, and it's continuing
to this day.
ADAM KEATS: This area right here
is the point at which the
water leaves the public realm
and enters the private realm,
so to speak.
The equation is solely focused
on big, Southern California
agribusiness.
Huge mega-corporations that are
some of the largest farm
interests in the world,
producing big-money crops.
And that's the primary thing
driving this thing.
And no one has a right
to own the water.
It doesn't mean you can totally
deprive the rest of
the state of its access
to the water--
and when I say rest of the
state, that includes the fish
and the birds and the animals.
Early on, in the early 2000s,
mid 2000s, we noticed huge
declines of fish species
in the delta.
6 million splittail were killed
in one count, and
14,000, 15,000 salmon.
Instead of having the power in
one interest, the San Joaquin
Valley farmers-- and that's
primarily one company,
Paramount Farms--
instead of having one big boy
controlling the whole game,
have the state control it, and
have the state control with
very strict rules, in terms of
who gets water, when they get
water, why they get water.
And include in that mix all
the birds and fish in the
environment and ecosystem
up here.
But you can answer all the
questions just by figuring out
where the money is, who's
making the most
money off the deal.
EMERSON ROSENTHAL: Moving large
amounts of water from
one place to another
isn't anything new.
But the water from the San
Joaquin delta is already
spoken for.
By law, farmers who have lived
here in the San Joaquin Valley
for over 250 years still
maintain priority rights over
the delta's water.
They get it first, and their
livelihoods depend on it.
RUDY MUSSI: My father
was a farmer.
I farm with my brother,
and I've done that
for the last 50 years.
All this proposal does is just
steal the water from one area
and ship it to another area.
The reasoning changes
all the time.
At first, it was to enhance the
aquatic species out here.
Well, the Academy of Science
said the peripheral tunnels or
canal won't enhance
the species.
So then they said, well, we'll
do adaptive management.
So, in other words, we're going
to build this and then
we'll figure it out
how to work it.
We fought this battle in 1982,
and I think my dad fought this
battle in the '50s
and the '60s.
It's always been somebody trying
to steal our water.
Anytime there's a finite amount
of water, there's
always somebody that doesn't
have it that wants it.
And don't get me wrong.
We don't mind sharing any
surplus water, but
don't take my water.
I depend on it for
my livelihood.
EMERSON ROSENTHAL: Right now,
we're heading into Clarksburg,
where we're going to film where
they want to begin these
new tunnels.
Sacramento River, chilling
on a private levee.
Snuck out here so we can
see it for ourselves.
If Jerry Brown's peripheral
canal proposal goes through,
they'll take two large tunnels
underground, right under here,
and 9,000 cubic inches of water
per second will be taken
from Sacramento River all
the way down south.
And basically, all the farmers
out here are completely
dependent on this water.
Potentially, that could
all end as quickly as
shutting off a faucet.
John Herrick is one of a number
of lawyers working to
stop the Bay Delta
conservation plan from approval.
Along with a number of
colleagues, John's been on the
job for about 30
years already.
JOHN HERRICK: Their proposal is,
we're going to improve the
delta by moving our intake.
So their plan is to make the
delta better by having less
fresh water flow through it.
It's that nuts.
EMERSON ROSENTHAL: Why does
the Department of Water
Resources and the Department of
the Interior want them to
have those water rights?
JOHN HERRICK: That's an
interesting question.
I don't know.
One of the things that should
be separated, but isn't, is
the fact that the Department of
Water Resources is a seller
to the contractors.
So large amounts of money go
from the people who want the
water, exporters, to
the department.
That connection of buyer-seller
has resulted in
the Department of Water
Resources following the
desires of their clients,
their buyers.
In our opinion, although we
haven't figured out a way,
there are people that
should be put in
jail for these things.
EMERSON ROSENTHAL: All right,
so basically, all of the
proponents of the peripheral
canal have pointed us in the
direction of the Department
of Water Resources.
But unfortunately, after we
set up an appointment with
them, they claimed that they
heard some things about us and
decided to cancel our 2
o'clock appointment.
So it is 10 o'clock now.
We figure we might jump in,
because we have to hear from
their side, and their reasons
behind wanting
this peripheral canal.
Yeah, we're doing
an interview.
How's it going?
-Oh, you know.
I work for state parks.
How good can it be?
-This too shall pass.
-It's entertaining.
EMERSON ROSENTHAL:
Uh, yeah we did.
For 10 o'clock, originally.
The secretary was sharp enough
to divert us away from the
building and not let
us talk to anybody.
But we got some good pizza
recommendations, so we're cool.
Once we got back to New York, we
realized that after all of
our appointments were canceled
with the Department of Water
Resources, the Natural Resources
Agency, and the
chemist who helped back the
proposal's science, we didn't
have a single statement from
the proponents of the plan,
let alone a positive one.
So we tried again.
OK, so I just found the list
of all of the supporters.
This is everybody who
is a proponent of
the peripheral canal.
Let's see if we can
talk to somebody.
[PHONE RINGING]
-Financial Resources Agency,
this is Kim, how may
I direct your call?
Hi there.
My name is Emerson Rosenthal,
and I'm calling on behalf of
Vice Media.
OK.
Can you hold for just
one second?
Let me see if there's
somebody available.
Hi, this is Nancy Vogel,
director of public affairs for
the department.
Hi, you've reached [INAUDIBLE]
with Paramount Farms, please
leave a message and I will
return your call.
We had someone here in the
office that covers Bay Delta.
They're not in right now, you
can leave a message--
Were you the woman that
sent us to that
really great pizza place?
Yes.
That's me.
OK.
Oh good, you guys liked
Zelda's, after all?
Yeah, it was delicious.
Just one second, let me see if
there's somebody available.
Will you please hold for
just one second?
One moment.
Thank you.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
EMERSON ROSENTHAL: The only
response we got was an email
from the governor's press
office, with a link to their
press release.
In the meantime, the governor's
been hard at work
pushing the proposal past a
legislative vote, in spite of
the opposition.
JERRY BROWN: This proposal
balances the concerns of those
who live and work on the delta,
those who rely on it
for water, and those who
appreciate its beauty, its
fish, waterfowl and wildlife.
EMERSON ROSENTHAL: So we'll have
to go with that as their
official statement.
And with all lines of
communication cut off between
the designers of the plan and
the people asking questions,
the Bay Delta conservation plan
is quickly becoming an
imminent reality in the haze
of California politics.
Will governor Jerry Brown win
the water war he's been waging
since the '70s?
Is this a new precedent for
controlling water in America?
In the words of Detective Walsh,
in perhaps the most
famous film about California's
water, "Forget it, Jake.
It's Chinatown."
[MUSIC PLAYING]