on national geographic annexed super interesting
in revolutionized ruffles
move environmental revolution abruptly it's
been over the tea party guys roadside population
in america %uh grows shouldn't baffles right
of a sudden reason why this problem different
is because
the prosecutor there and men can go there
and sleep with the prostitutes
okay okay so far so good %uh approved a there's
a catch them and of course
every road has account
%uh right
as a prostitute and the male art you know
getting it on its broadcast live on the internet
now people subscribers to this %uh portent
p twenty three dollars a month to watch it
so that's how the prostitutes are able to
make their money
okay well at least %uh world listens okay
%uh they make three thousand euros per month
each prosecute so they they get %uh salary
instead of getting paid per client
and and that couples also get paid because
people remarks that couples if you come in
so please paying except as an interesting
perfect bob but then you can buy your own
dvd it's ever set
for this obviously leads to
now faces i know you know i was really interested
in %uh proposition right bob but let's
it's you remember this
and
europe
here you couple choice ours or our lessons
are you couple three choices birthday
hold on hold
you didn't have you with us actually mendez
%uh if u apoyo point levitoff took a look
at the big that's eleven document let's keep
it real mrs
you know i'll pay you do this one time
you talk about a forever
that's ever says that
lab result lesser life ok oregon over for
a about we broadcast on
they didn't have right
life that way but you don't twenty five thousand
divinity it's your money separate out
applying needed by a hat forty-five boxes
laying around
fighting if it's a five hundred
but but but
unison you know correct but money isn't mind
incidents and a half to take one
if
really
wow
i think that's gonna be a mistake i think
it would be dot dot that would be out of time
that's exactly whether a setup this big sister
brought election is going to ask you something
and everything
live again in the state prisons going to be
a mistake if i were to do something like that
could have a woman and that's going to be
everywhere you want to make a big deal about
it
but he said is likely to make a big deal about
it but you can win
people really like
what got you see what role this is from the
young turks
he's got a sex tape is unbelievable
like they're not only about the eva members
for
but that protected packaging
the everybody would save me to leave amended
split everyone but anyway that's not the point
is an important point is your mom sleazy let
me i i hope he does but you know everybody
knows that your mom was right and all your
%uh boys watch that all of the uncles everybody
wants it
if they're brings up a new business crazy
though
in the obtaining your kids have gone ahead
and i'm thinking
that way
i think the reason why i didn't think he'd
be a big deal is because
if we have got a mail celebrity aiden a sex
tape no one really makes a big deal about
the case but if there's a female celebrity
unit everyone
breaks out and it's posted
it every single traveling in america now of
course it's because who do you
would be able to make more video about congrats
sex they've or that
was that never
curly hair from say by the bell
%uh oracle
that the other fell three straight right is
free trade appointee disenchanted for the
past open right here in point yahoo so that's
what everybody said he was appointed electricity
here met nobody's interested one night shift
break so we don't know what that shit out
of that he's a loser right %uh it so it totally
backfired because we want to say that so that
we all i think you've got to tell you what
is it argos critique now not all but we wanted
to see an enemies
and of those distribution
webcam let's keep it
okay
all right so anyway the the whole point of
all this is
they're under a good idea
because yeah i mean you may twenty five hundred
for eva mendez but
most guys alot and eva mendez and i will needed
to be twenty five hundred there because they
wanted bucks and two hundred bucks she's hot
you know that they do i get who gives a shit
nope republic of was you know find out
that they did that
so what i did that
you know it's your
i don't feel like this is going to attract
the worst kind of men
but the problem
on and i think it'd be great shape
i think that absolutely worst back
b_w_b_ related matters business for the sake
may become in their beauty like paula gobi
layers
alot of free prophet in those early days off
the street from vienna cobble together twenty
three bucks right and then extra buck for
earlier big mac or something they want to
know it was a good word at all
and i think all plus a life that you know
that sounds a little shaking certainly
yeah i would opt for
prosecution expiry
okay atlanta if i ready to go to that route
yes maybe eight ish
it is happening they do the club frankly about
a foot nature cannot be delivered you can't
come in
you
if to use that one of the better look at the
pastor of the matter that it should be considered
it's a little discovered banality
%uh by the way all europeans
please please bring it down just mass