out from a fellow You Tuber, Jim Chapman,
over there.
Hello, how are you?!
I'm engaged to a beautiful lady, Tanya, she's
also on You Tube. She does makeup tutorials
and also sort of fun, cute videos. And she's
just delightful to behold.
This will be our eighth valentine's day and
I need something to impress her that might
get me lucky later.
Ok, so we've got a beautiful meal.
We're gonna do marinated, seared tuna with
a nice spaghetti with a simple tomato sauce.
Perfect for Valentine's Day. Let's do it!
So grab your pestle and mortar. I want a nice
pinch of salt Jim.
Ok
That's for seasoning and to give a nice bit
of abrasion.
Like it, good word.
What is it?!
Abrasion.
Yes, very nice. We're gonna grab a wad of
basil and we're gonna make a basil oil.
I think actually when she sees me doing this
anyway I won't even need to cook anymore.
She'll just come in and go - Wow!
That's my boy!
Job done!
So, olive oil. A couple of good tablespoons.
So half the zest of a lemon goes in, just
about 3 or 4 strokes. Just the juice of half
a lemon is probably more than enough.
I only want you to put half on this tuna.
And then I'd keep this for sort of drizzling
on the end because it's fresh and alive!
Sustainable fish! We do not want to be using
Bigeye or Bluefin tuna. So Yellowfin or Skipjacks
are really, really good to use. We are gonna
do something very special. Jim, I want you
hold that pack and smash it like a man on
that board.
This is where it's all gonna go wrong isn't
it?!
Dominant!
Yeah! That's what I'm talking about!
Yeeeeah!
Wooooah!
Next, 200g of tomatoes. We're just gonna cut
them into half.
Once upon a time, I cooked
naked for my wife. I was like you. I was young,
vulnerable and looking for love. And not married
yet. And I actually cooked whole sea bass
in my new oven. As I opened the door to check
my sea bass, a jet of hot steam shot into
my penis, my whole night was ruined! So that's
a warning!
Or wear clothes when you cook!
Or just wear pinny.
Yeah.
So we've halved our tomatoes, good job. We
want some garlic, just a couple of cloves
of garlic each.
Tell us all about your channel.
So essentially what I do every week, on a
Friday, I'll upload a video where I embarrass
myself in some way.
So people basically tune in to see you squirming
at your own sort of self...
Yeah, self-loathing, self-pity, that sort
of stuff.
Ok, it's time to cook the Tuna.
A lot of people think that Tuna has to be
cooked all the way through.
No I don't like it like that, bit tough.
A little bit pink is good.
Let's make a two minute tomato sauce. I wanna
go in with a whole pinch of fennel seeds.
Go in with some olive oil, garlic, grab a chilli.
So I reckon about half a chilli is going to
be good for you and your Mrs. And then go
in with your tomatoes as well. Now if we look
in the pan now, see I'm just gonna turn this
Tuna over.
Oh yeah!
Beautiful!
So tuna on, sauce on, pasta's on with a nice
pinch of salt, nice pinch of pepper.
If you look in this pan, see how we're just
softening up those cherry tomatoes.
We've had about a minute and a half on each
of these Tuna so here's your one. And like
a piece of meat, we're gonna let that rest.
Now Jim, if you can get a little bit of that
lovely, fresh basil oil. Divide up our pasta.
Just grab some basil and just tear a little
bit, or chop a little bit through. You don't
need much.
Right at the last minute.
So we're gonna just drag that onto a plate.
But I think it's quite nice to have this as
a share plate.
Yeah, then there's more chance of you getting
that sort of Lady and the Tramp moment isn't there.
Yes! and are you gonna make this for her on
Valentine's Day.
Yeah! Yeah, that's the reason I'm here.
Ok, so over here we're just gonna tear that
open and you see how that's blushing in the
middle?! That's what we want.
And we can just tear that up and it gives
you more surface area to have that lovely
marinade.
So Jim look, you've done a great job mate.
I'm very proud of myself.
You're good!
I've entered manhood.
So how are we gonna test this?
I dunno, you know?!
Hmmmm...
You are the best! No, you are the best! I've
made this meal for you because I love you.
Because I love you.
And you are gonna get to try every single
bit of it!
Ha ha ha
Why do you look nervous?
I'm petrified!
We're just doing role play here alright?!
I'm scared! Behind your eyes it looks like
you're curious!
Up you go, with confidence.
Up, across, nailed it!
Mmm, wow!
Pasta's very good Jim.
I'm impressed with myself.
A really nice plate of food, well-cooked my
friend!
Thank you very much!
And to all my lovely subscribers, if you haven't
seen Jim's channel then click on the link
below and you'll get to see him do some funny,
whacky and some very honest things, every
Friday.
We also filmed a video over on my channel
with Jamie and if you've come from that then
why not subscribe to this channel because
it's really, really great, he's a nice guy
and he makes amazing food.
And it's free so just subscribe!
Do it!
Take care guys. Happy Valentine's Day!