UNIDENTIFIED BOY: Hello, Mr. Feniz. Great
(inaudible) humanities class.
UNIDENTIFIED GIRL: And we are from this international
school in Bangkok, Thailand.
UNIDENTIFIED CHILDREN: At CNN STUDENT NEWS.
UNIDENTIFIED GIRL: Take it away, Paul. Wow.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Fridays are awesome. I love starting
with I-reports like that one from Ms. Tiffany`s
class. I`m Carl Azuz. This is our March, 1st
edition of CNN STUDENT NEWS. It`s also a deadline
for the U.S. government. About $85 billion
were set to be eliminated from the federal
budget, unless Congress and the president
can agree on the way around these automatic
spending cuts. That`s not expected to happen,
even though none of the politicians really
likes these cuts. Here`s the basic problem:
the government spends far more than it takes
in. But neither the executive branch, nor
the legislative branch has total control over
what the government spends money on. And they
disagree on how to tax and how to spend. So,
these cuts are set to kick in the lower government
spending, and one big question is, are most
Americans going to notice?
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
TOM FOREMAN, CNN CORRESPONDENT: If you would
listen to only the White House, you would
have the sense that we are going to a sequestration
nation pretty soon, and that everybody would
be hit in all these different areas: food
safety and education and our tax returns or
national parks - everything - and this seems
to be true. If you are the right person doing
the right thing, you in fact may see an effect
here. For example, if you are in a military
town, and you rely on military business, you
might see an impact fairly soon. If you are
at the airport waiting for the right flight
at the right busy time, you might have a delay.
If you are waiting on unemployment benefits
and the check comes in lighter than, you expect,
that would also be a real effect on you fairly
soon, but notice I`m talking about specific
groups of people doing specific things. The
broader picture of the whole country may be
different, and to address that I want to talk
about one of the hardest things that came
up today, Eric Holder speaking up, and he
had this point to say in the middle of today
where he said, look, we will be less safe,
if our budget adjusted (ph) cut next year
from 27 billion by 1.6 billion, to 25.4 billion.
If these cut happens the nation will be less
safe These are his words. And this is why
he says that: because he says, there will
be furloughs at the FBI we`ll have fewer people
looking into crimes and trying to prevent
crimes. ATF inspections of things like gun
permits, all of that, will be knocked down
a little bit, there will be fewer people to
man the prisons, so prison will spend more
time on lockdowns, there will fewer grants
for local law enforcement. All of this will
make things less safe in the country, according
to him.
This is the budget, if it gets the sequester.
$25.4 billion for next year. That`s much it
would get. But look at this; this is a graph
of funding for the Justice Department for
the last 11 years. And if you`ll notice, when
you look at this graph, in fact, that line
would be right about here. So, in fact, for
the past 11 years only the past three years
has the Justice Department had more money
than they would have under the sequester.
So, does that mean that all these years we
were less safe? When the national crime rate
was steadily moving down during that period
of time? These are the tough challenges out
there, because in many ways, as Democrats
in the White House say, all these cataclysmic
things are going to hit if the sequester comes
in. I think Republicans maybe betting on the
idea if a few weeks pass, a couple of months
pass, and the public doesn`t notice it, because
of things like this, then they are going to
be able to turn around to the White House
and say, you were just trying to scare us.
You said a lot of things, and we haven`t seen
it come to pass.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: At 2:00 Eastern, yesterday afternoon,
the doors of a papal retreat closed. It signified
the official end of Pope Benedict XVI papacy.
And it followed a day of good byes. In this
last public appearances, Pope Benedict said
he was a pilgrim beginning the last leg of
his pilgrimage on earth. In his last tweet
as pope, Benedict wrote, "Thank you for your
love and support. May you always experience
the joy that comes from putting Christ in
the center of your lives. This is historic,
in part, because it`s the first time in 600
years that a papacy has ended in retirement
rather than death. At cnnstudentnews.com,
we posted yesterday`s explainer on how the
Catholic Church will choose its next leader.
Next up today, a bit of bad news from the
Governors Highway Safety Administration: driving
death among American teenagers apparently
increased in 2012. The jump was almost 20
percent over the year before. Researchers
aren`t sure why, but they`ve known for years
that moto-vehicle accidents have been the
leading cause of death for U.S. teenagers.
The overall rate is still lower than it was
five years ago, according to the researcher
who led this study. But if the goal is to
decrease the number of driving related death
every year, this is a setback. Different states
have different laws and limits on driving
ages. Would you accept stricter teen driving
laws, if it meant the possibility of fewer
accidents? If you are on Facebook, tell us
what you think at Facebook.com/cnnstudentnews.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Todays` "Shoutout" goes
out to Ms. Colizzi`s students at Maple Valley
High School in Vermontville, Michigan. What
event is celebrated every year on March 8?
You know what to do, is it International Women`s
Day, Saint Patrick`s Day, Flag Day, or Teacher
Appreciation day? You`ve got three seconds,
go!
it International Women`s Day has been celebrated
on March 8th, for nearly a century. That`s
your answer and that`s your "Shoutout".
We`re still one week away from International
Women`s Day, but today marks the start of
women`s history month. In fact, one led to
the other: International Women`s Day goes
all the way back to the early 1900s. The idea
came up at an International Conference of
Working Women as a way to raise awareness
about issues affecting women around the world.
So, fast- forward to the 1970s. Women in the
United States were planning a new event to
celebrate the accomplishments of American
women. They picked March because well, that`s
when the international celebration was already
taking place. Believe it or not, women`s history
month didn`t start up as the whole month.
At first, it was women`s history week. In
1987, Congress expanded the celebration to
the entire month of March. Every year, the
national women`s history project picks a thing
for women`s history month. This year, it`s
women inspiring innovation through imagination.
It`s specifically honoring women in the fields
of science, technology, engineering and math.
But women`s history month is designed to honor
women in all walks of life. And that`s what
we`ll be doing throughout March.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Teachers, your turn? How are we doing?
We`re looking for and considering all of your
comments at cnnstudentnews.com. Please, swing
by today, tell us what you think of this show.
First known use of the word "robot" in 1920
in a play. First use of the word "robotics",
1942 in a story. The actual machines are used
all over the map today in science, industry,
medicine, war. But up until now, anyway, they
have mostly featured moving metal parts. Say
hello to Saul Griffith, and what could be
the next generation of robots.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
SAUL GRIFFITH, CO-FOUNDER, OTHERLAB: If you
think about everything, all of the consumer
products, every machine the humanity has ever
made, it`s, you know stiff and rigid. There`s
a completely grained space of soft machine.
Robotics industries are most concerned with
the number of degrees of freedom.
SANJAY GUPTA, CNN CORRESPONDENT: Right.
GRIFFITH: And how much it costs for each degree
of freedom.
Here`s a way that we could really transform
the cost of robotics. We`ll eliminate all
the (inaudible), we`ll eliminate the pins
and the bearings and the joints. And we will
sew you a robot out of fabric, and use pressurize
fluids to make it work. And it will reduce
the cost of robots a hundred fold, and it
will make them (inaudible).
The gray (ph) behind me, for example, weighs
one or two pounds. Yeah, it is the size of
your and fully pressurized than I couldn`t,
you know, lift a human an arm`s leg.
GUPTA: Wow.
GRIFFITH: There`s no hinges and bearings there.
It`s all done in this tensile fabric, so it`s
really built like a lot of biological systems
that are - this works much more like a fish
or a shark than it does like a robot.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: We`ve talked recently about a couple
of snowstorms that have hit several states
in the U.S. Here`s some I-reports from a student
in Iowa: drifts and shovels. Look at both
the beauty and the work, associated with winter
weather. A teacher from Texas sent us another
one you probably haven`t heard about, that`s
herd as in cattle, some of them got loose,
possibly when snow covered over their fences,
and they just mooed on down the road.
And a look at the fun side of snowstorms comes
from Kansas where some high school friends
spend four hours building a 13 foot Franken
snowman. And it`s all pretty good, but this
last I-report today is the icing on the snow
cone. Some students at Wale (ph) University
in Texas apparently made the most of their
snow day, building, shaping, slicing and sculpting
a miniature at Mount Rushmore. The glasses
detail are Mr. Roosevelt. Snow problem, when
someone volunteered his own. It`s enough to
make fans of U.S. history melt. And never
did George, Thomas, Teddy and Abe look so
cool. Of course, it`s neither as permanent
nor as detailed as the real one. That sculpture
rocks. But as long as the snow stuck around,
people thought it was pretty chill. And the
fact that George Washington had wooden teeth
might have kept them from chattering in all
that cold. That`s all for CNN STUDENT NEWS.
I`m sorry, we`ve run out of time. In the future,
I`ll just have to rush more. See you..