for every Oscar
winning movie ever.
Cracked posted this
almost four years ago,
and it still holds up.
MALE SPEAKER: Differences
are surfacing between us.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Accusations
about your sexuality.
MALE SPEAKER: Suspicion
that a character once
thought trustworthy
may not be trustworthy.
JACOB SOBOROFF: It's almost
at two million views.
From the music to
the characters,
if there was an Academy Award
for Academy Award parodies,
this thing gets it.
CARLY: We all know that "Captain
Phillips" is up for an Oscar
for Best Picture this year.
I'm the captain now.
Am I right?
But did you know that it's
not the only film made
about modern piracy?
"Fishing without Nets" handles
the subject matter completely
different, and is told
entirely from the perspective
of Somali pirates before
they reach the boat.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CARLY: This film is
a great companion
to "Captain Phillips."
I definitely recommend
going and seeing both,
but not if you ever want to
feel safe on a boat again.
ALEX: How do you
like your Oscars?
With facts?
How do you like your facts?
With numbers?
I've got you covered.
Check it out.
Alltime10's has Oscar
facts and numbers.
Littlest-known Oscar
facts, like did
you know Marlon Brando sent a
Native American woman to refuse
his Best Actor award
for "The Godfather"?
Well, I thought all the facts in
this "Little-Known Oscar Facts"
video we're going to
be well known facts.
Turns out they're all
little-known known facts.
Whoa.
Way to go, Alltime10's.
EARNEST: "Gravity" is up for
10 Academy Awards tomorrow
tonight.
Framestore, the company
behind the space magic,
just posted this
behind-the-scenes look
at how CGI played into
the making of the film.
They actually
animated every shot
before they even
brought the actors in.
I love this because it feels
like a Blu-ray extra feature
without having to buy a Blu-ray.
Also, if you're like me and
you haven't seen "Gravity,"
it's just a good way
to quickly catch up
before tomorrow night's show.
ALI: So earlier
this week, I brought
in a video that was one of
my favorite new discoveries
of all time from a
channel called Dos Padres.
And they have made a video
where they recreate scenes
from each of the best picture
nominees for the Academy
Awards.
MALE SPEAKER: Do
you trim the fat?
MALE SPEAKER: Do I trim--
yeah, I trim the fat.
I stay lean.
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah,
how many times a week?
MALE SPEAKER: Three
or four times a week.
MALE SPEAKER: I myself, I trim
the fat at least twice a day.
MALE SPEAKER: Wow.
MALE SPEAKER: Once in the
morning, along with my eggs,
and once at lunch, right before
I slip myself into a nice BLT.
ALI: It really comes through
that they are real movie lovers
and I just think they're
wonderful, and silly,
and brilliant, and
I'm a huge fan.
STEPHEN: My partner
Patrick and I just
posted this to our channel.
Our friend, Oscar-winner
Luke Matheny,
claims to know every
best picture winner ever,
so we put him to the test.
This is for real.
He is amazing.
Best picture 1969"
LUKE MATHENEY:
"Midnight Cowboy."
PATRICK: Correct.
STEPHEN: Best picture, 1984.
LUKE MATHENEY: "Amadeus."
LUKE MATHENEY: He's correct.
STEPHEN: Best picture, 1985?
LUKE MATHENEY: "Out of Africa."
PATRICK: Correct.
STEPHEN: If you want
to see true passion,
watch Luke's acceptance speech.
It's beautiful.
LIZZIE: I love the Oscars.
I wait all year for this.
I host my very own
tiara and pajama party.
I've won every year.
Can't wait. iJustine is
also hosting her own Oscar
celebration this year.
She will be hosting a live
feed from the red carpet
with StyleHaul.
IJUSTINE: We will be
streaming the live red carpet
pre-show at 2:30 Pacific,
5:30 Eastern, on March 2.
I cannot wait to
see you guys there.
LIZZIE: iJustine is great.
She's been around forever.
She's got almost
two million subs.
If you're not
familiar with her, you
should definitely check her out.
And I already know who will
be winning the best costume
at my Oscar party, because
I'm the only one there.
JACOB SOBOROFF: While you're
waiting for the show to start,
we've put together a great
Oscar-themed playlist for you,
but before we go, hey,
man, who do you think's
going to win best song?
EARNEST: It may sound crazy
what I'm about to say--
[MUSIC - "HAPPY," BY PHARRELL
WILLIAMS]