your sense of kindness
and generosity.
Now Lil Bub, of course,
is a star cat.
For many of her fans, Lil
Bub's face and demeanor
represent kindness
and positivity
in the face of adversity.
She also snorted a few
times in reverse.
Why would you do that?
Now we all understand that the
winter holiday season is one
of the most fun times
to party.
And in that spirit of inclusion
and warmth, we ask
you to donate to your
local animal shelter
this holiday season.
[SINGING]
I'm dreaming of a
white Christian.
As precious as Lil Bub is, she
takes a lot of care, a lot of
resources, and a
lot of energy.
So find it in your heart to
donate, have a happy holiday,
and enjoy the preciousness
of this beast.
How do you even exist?
How tender is your paw?
Lil Bub.
[HOLIDAY MUSIC PLAYING]
[MEOW]