mysteriously winding down - this is
Genesis Week.
[Music]
And a welcome to this episode of Genesis
Week, the weekly program of creationary
commentary on news, views and events
pertaining to the origins controversy,
proudly brought to you by CORE Ottawa -
Citizens for Origins Research and
Education, and exclusive right here on
youtube.  Showing the glory of God in the
Creation, and broadcasting from the
Justice League Satellite, now that the
Justice league no longer exists and the
organization was going into receivership,
we got their space station hideout for a
song and a dance! We bring you the
information the anti-creationists don't
want you to see or hear.  One of the most
talked about shows in Science and
Technology on youtube.
You can find us at wazooloo.com or
genesisweek.com, or click the
ever-so-convenient subscribe link up top,
and don't forget, you can also peruse
other episodes by following the links in
the upper corners of each episode. I'm
your host, Ian Juby
I discussed the fishy story of fishapods
last week - the alleged history of the
fishees growing legs and walking up onto
land and becoming amphibians -
tetrapods.  A wonderful story, complete
with an alleged fossil ancestral tree!
So now we look to this weeks report of a
find of bizarre, legless amphibians which
live predominantly underground.  Although
they are called Caecilians, rest assured
they have nothing to do with Italy.  The
report discusses finding a whole mess of
these strange creatures nesting in
Northern India.  Now this is not the first
find of ceacilians, they are well known,
just not in India.
However, you'll recall the convoluted
history of evolution presented last week,
which has now gotten even weirder:
according to the evolutionism myth, fish
grew legs, walked up on to land to
become four-legged amphibians which
diversified into all kinds of other land
creatures - including cows, dogs,
cheetahs, apes and humans....while many
other organisms decided to go on strike
and never evolve, while still yet some of
those four-legged amphibians
mysteriously decided they were better off
without legs, and evolved into these
legless amphibians.  And so the
evolutionism myth takes another bizarre
twist in its just-so story.
So obviously these legless amphbians
have been quite successful without legs,
so why did the fish evolve legs in the first
place?  If there was an advantage to legs,
then why did these amphibians de-evolve,
losing their legs?
In the end, the answer is irrelevent,
because Evolution will simply make it fit -
answers or not, because evolution
conforms to whatever evidence it is
presented with, because it is not science.
You are certainly welcome to believe
evolution, just please, don't call it
science.
General Electric released details on its
stunning new thermal-imaging technology
last week, along with a report in Nature
Photonics.  Researchers were studying
the wings of butterflies, and made a
surprise discovery.  The Morpho butterfly
glistens with a stunning, beautiful blue.
It's what causes this colour that caught
the eye of researchers and inspired the
design of an electronic eye.
Examined under an electron microscope,
the researchers discovered the surface of
the wings were covered in an array of
tree-like nanostructures.  This "forest" did
several things: It refracted light,
enhancing blues and removing other
colours of light.  That was already
interesting, but what they also realized
was that this forest expands and
contracts with temperature, which alters
what colour of light is enhanced or
removed.
Taking this tip from the butterfly, GE
engineers then set out to design a camera
that "sees" temperature - thermal imaging
- based on what they learned from the
butterfly wings.
The results are stunning - with the
camera able to see temperature
differences less than 0.2 degrees Celcius
- and with incredible speed - a response
time of about 1/40th of a second.  To give
you an idea of just how fast that is,
consider that this video is a series of
different pictures, every picture on the
screen for a fleeting moment - 1/30th of a
second.  In less time then it took for you
to see this subliminal message ***********,
the GE thermal camera has taken millions
of temperature readings and recorded
them!.
But of course, even though the camera
was intelligently designed, why is it so
hard for people to believe the butterfly
was also designed?  Such intricacies in
the butterfly wing have no apparent
evolutionary purpose.  Yet it is within the
character of a Creator God to make
things that are just plain pleasing to the
eye, which He also created.
A baffling mystery was revealed this week
in National Geographic magazine: The
European Space Agency's Venus Express
orbiter has been mapping the surface of
Venus. A problem arose when the
photographic maps did not line up with
the photographic maps taken by NASA a
mere 16 years ago.  After checking, double
checking and triple checking, the planet's
features almost seemed to have moved
12.4 MILES from where they were last
seen!
It would appear that the rotation of the
planet is slowing down - and dramatically
so.  Venus is already an odd-ball in our
solar system with a retrograde rotation - it
spins in a direction opposite the majority
of planets.  This is already a fatal problem
for the naturalist theories of the origin of
the planet. But now to discover the
planet's spin slowing down? And
dramatically so at that!  It remains to be
seen exactly what is going on here, but
one thing can be said: If this change in
spin rate is consistent, it poses
astronomical problems for an old universe
- pun intended.  The farther you go back in
time, hypothetically the faster it was
spinning - to the point where forces would
rip the planet apart long before you hit
the alleged age of 4.6 billions years old.
We'll follow this story with interest.
[scary, dramatic music]
Wahoo! Mail for me?
[beeping sounds]
Hmmm...I forget - are you supposed to cut
the red wire or blue wire first?
Or I could just pull the detonator...
[dramatic, scary music]
WilliamTyndale1 made a comment on last
week's show, the likes of which I hear
often:
OnceForgivenNowFree also expressed
the exasperation so many feel when
reading the skeptical comments:
It should be noted that I frequently get
similar comments from non-Christians
and non-creationists.
Interestingly, I was having a discussion
with my friend Shannon this week, and
she made a very interesting observation
which I think is quite accurate. She had
seen some studies written up on road
rage - how people can become absolutely
insane from their rage - completely
irrational, emotional, even physically
violent.  Normal people who suddenly lose
all control of reason or rationale.  This
study apparently concluded that people
considered their cars an extension of
their person, and thus violating your car's
personal space was a very personal
violation against themselves.
In like fashion, Shannon I think correctly
deduced that some people
subconsciously consider evolutionism
theory an extension of themselves - for
whatever reason.  And thus when
evolutionism is questioned, it becomes an
attack on their person, and they respond
with a completely irrational, unreasonable
reaction akin to road rage.  I don't want to
pick out examples from the comments,
because I have no interest in publically
humiliating people, but the very irrational,
illogical, yea even stupid comments that
are persistently and consistently made,
are made by people that I would not
consider stupid.  Why? Look at the
comments - they're in a rage. An
irrational, illogical, unreasonable rage.
One lady on twitter responded to my last
video response to the living dinosaur with
"Ian, he's only going to rub your nose into
the dirt even more. You have no chance
of winning against him. None!"
Umm.....who said anything about
"winning?"  Such comment is emotional,
personal, irrational - such people are only
interested in "winning" - whatever that
means. Personally, I'm interested in the
truth, not "winning."  So let the skeptics
rage.
PaulChartley wrote in:
Thanks for writing in.  However,
apparently you are unaware that fossil
footprints are very seldom found with the
track maker. Of all of the dinosaur
megatrack sites in the world, I only know
of four that had some dinosaur remains
contained within the track bearing layers,
for example.  I am unaware of a single
body fossil found anywhere in the
Coconino sandstone, though there are
innumerable fossil tracks scattered
throughout the layers.  The lack of body
fossils has nothing to do with the
legitimacy of the tracks.  Police at a crime
scene who see human tracks can
positively identify that it's a human, even
if they don't have the human who made
the tracks.
Johnbgroovy wrote in:
Excellent question, but you're mixing
things up there. For example, the same
comments could be applied to evolution:
What practical benefits for humanity has
evolution produced?  You could also ask
the same question for the science of
paleontology.  What are the benefits to
humanity? The science you are referring
to uses physics, chemistry, etc... applied
to the here and now. Both Creation and
Evolutionism are attempts to explain the
past - it's totally different.  Paleontology
and aspects of Geology also have this
limitation.
In fact, evolutionism has been detrimental
to scientific research - medical research
in particular.  For example: Eugenics. Or
Junk DNA and vestigial organs.  The
original, evolutionary interpretation for
these things was that they were useless
leftovers from our evolutionary history.
We now know that all of the alleged
vestigial organs have purpose, as does
the alleged "Junk DNA."
Creationary thinkers would claim that any
DNA has purpose - there is no such thing
as useless leftovers. There may be
broken DNA or organs, but creationary
thinking would inspire, not hinder
scientific research. As a result of
evolutionary teaching that things like the
tonsils were useless leftovers, doctors
cut them out of patients quite
regularly.....until the discovery that a
tonsillectomy left you prone to polio, and
paralysis.  Evolution has HINDERED
scientific process.
The difference here is how your
worldview affects how you do science.  In
this case, one world view expects useless
leftovers, and deters scientists from
seeking the purpose of useless leftovers.
The other worldview would say that
everything had purpose and was part of
the overall design, thus compelling
scientists to seek out the purpose and
design.  Creationary thinking looks to
nature as DESIGNED, with the intention of
copying the Designer's ideas - because
He is such an incredible designer.
A very lengthy discussion about stasis
went on last week, and I must give kudos
to Youtuber Fusion840 who attempted to
explain the significance and obvious case
for stasis in the fossil record to people
who would not listen nor believe.  Hey - at
least you tried!  But the discussion was
ended and summed up so nicely in one
sentence by Answersquestions1:
You nailed it!  Thanks to everyone who
wrote in comments.
Well that's it for this week, I'm your host
Ian Juby, I hope you'll join me next
Thursday for the next episode  Please
subscribe up above and use the
convenient "share" button down below to
post this video on twitfaceplus page, or to
embed it in your blog or website!  Let us
remember the words of our Creator, the
Lord Jesus Christ, who said : I am the
Way the Truth and THE LIFE, no man
comes to the father but through me." See
you on the flip side.
[music]
Production Software was provided for
Genesis Week by the Big Valley Creation
Science Museum, located just 25 minutes
north of Drumheller, Alberta. In the heart
of the dinosaur badlands, the Big Valley
Creation Science Museum was built from
the ground up to give credit to our
Creator, portraying the scientific evidence
showing that creation is the faith that fits
the facts, and that evolution is the faith
that the facts have failed.
Visit BVCSM.com for more details.