comments.  This is Genesis Week.
[Music]
And a welcome to this episode of Genesis
Week, the weekly program of creationary
commentary on news, views and events
pertaining to the origins controversy,
Brought to you by CORE Ottawa -
Citizens for Origins Research and
Education, and exclusive right here on
youtube.  Excellence in pirate
broadcasting, we we bring you the
information the anti-creationists don't
want you to see or hear, and we show the
glory of God in the Creation.  Every single
show has been in the top ten most
discussed videos of the week in Science
and Technology on youtube.
Remember you can punch in
wazooloo.com or genesisweek.com, and
you will find us, or click the
ever-so-convenient subscribe link up top,
and you can also peruse other episodes
by following the links in the upper corners
of each episode. I'm your host, Ian Juby
MSU scientists reported in this week's
edition of Science magazine that they had
observed alleged "evolution" in viruses in
the lab.  Right off the bat, we need to
address the sticky problem of just what is
"evolution" - how do you define it?  There
seems to be not much doubt these
scientists are using the very weak
definition of evolution as simply change
over time.  However as I pointed out in
CrEvo Rant # 41, this definition makes a
great presidential campaign slogan, but
fails miserably to describe evolution, as it
would include the evolution of the bicycle
and languages (which are both
intelligently designed), and also include
things like genetic entropy - which is the
opposite of evolution, but definitely
change over time.  There is also the
problem of viruses not even being
definable as "life" based on the
evoutionary definitions of life. So already
the application of this research to
evolution is in question.
This alleged "evolution" was rapid and
dramatic, with the virus undergoing four
mutations that enabled it to attack E-coli
bacteria.  So - does this help evolution?
Not really.  First of all, some may get
excited over this, believing that the first
life on earth was perhaps a virus. In fact,
the Canadian Museum of Nature used to
state this specifically in an audio exhibit.
However, viruses can't reproduce -
viruses take over the reproduction
system of living cells to reproduce.
Therefore viruses couldn't be the first life,
because they need other life to exist!
Secondly, As Dr. Michael Behe pointed
out regarding the Science paper,
As Behe pointed out in his review on the
Evolution News website, the virus in the
experiment wasn't the only thing
"evolving."  The bacteria that were being
used as the target by the predator virus
were also rapidly changing in defense.
This is well known in bacteria actually.
Cells, such as the bacteria, have
receptors in their skin which link to
various biochemicals for signaling.
Viruses "dock" to these bacteria using
these receptors, thus infecting the
bacteria. But there are many different
receptors, and viruses can only dock to
specific receptors.  When the bacteria
detected that the viruses were docking to
one receptor, they destroyed the
receptor.  The virus then changed to be
able to infect the bacteria using a sugar
called mannose that the bacteria brings
into the cell.  The bacteria recognized the
infection, and destroyed the system
which makes the sugar, and thus the
virus couldn't infect the bacteria.
In the closing words of Behe:
Contrary to what most think, viruses are
actually an important part of life, and part
of the big-picture system that produces
variety critical for life. Viruses actually
carry disease resistance from one
organism to another.  Viruses that cause
harm are actually evidence of something
gone wrong.  This was a perfect world, but
just like you can ruin your car by
disregarding the specific instructions in
the owner's manual written by the creator
of your car, so does disregarding the
specific instructions in God's owner's
manual - the Bible, has caused problems
throughout all of earth.  An excellent
article dealing with the subject of viruses
and life by Dr. Jerry Bergman is available
on the trueorigin website.
The British Museum of Natural History
had a short article on the horseshoe crab
- allegeldy true proof of evolution, seeing
as how it hasn't changed (according to
the evolutionary timescale) in 450 million
years, and has survived 3 of earth's major
extinctions!  This article was a perfect
propaganda piece, putting all the spin in
just the right places.  As I mentioned
briefly just a moment ago - if you ask the
majority of evolutionary thinkers to define
evolution, almost all of them would say
"change over time."  I disagree with that
vague definition, but it is useful in this
case to make my point: Evolution requires
change over time. The horseshoe crab,
and countless other organisms in the
fossil record, have not changed over time
- this is called stasis.  But did that slow
them down from heralding the Horseshoe
crab as proof of evolution? Oh heck no!
The last paragraph is actually entitled "A
strange evolution?"
This article is a classic example of just
how flexible evolution is.  No matter what
the evidence is - evolution twists,
contorts and distorts itself to fit the
evidence.  Uh folks - a "theory" that
explains all evidence, even contradictory
evidence, is not science.  Such a theory is
clearly not falsifiable, and therefore not
science.  Instead, the horseshoe crab
provides powerful evidence of creation -
with organisms reproducing faithfully
after their kind, exactly like the book of
Genesis says in its first chapter.
Institute for Creation Research reported
on one of their research projects in this
month's "Acts and Facts" - the study of
telomeres in the middle of DNA chains.
Your DNA strands are clustered together
into 23 groups called chromosomes.
Chimpanzee DNA is clustered into 24
chromosomes.  This causes a dilemna for
evolution, because the great apes and
humans are supposed to have a common
ancestor - but yet how does a 23
chromosome sperm fertilize a 24
chromosome egg?  It can't!  So the
evolutionary thinkers - a certain Dr. Miller
in particular, have proponed the idea that
somewhere in human ancestry, there was
a fusion of two ape chromosomes into
one chromosome - specifically,
chromosome #2.  Of course, he glosses
over the point that you have to have the
exact same chromosomal fusion in a male
and a female, at the same time, and in the
same place, and they have to mate!
If you'll recall, DNA is a string of chemical
letters - G, C, T and A.  The end of the
DNA strands in Chromosomes contain a
long repeating sequence of TTAGGG;
usually this sequence is repeated
thousands of times to mark the end of the
strand, and is called a telomere.
So Miller went on record at the
Anti-Intelligent Design Kitzmiller /Dover
court case to say that the human
chromosome 2 is actually two fused ape
chromosomes - and claims it's proven
because there is a telomere sequence,
right smack dab in the middle of the
human chromosome 2, exactly where we
would expect that the two chromosomes
fused!  The anti-creationists have become
quite arrogant with this alleged "fact" all
over youtube, posting videos with bold
titles like "how to shut up pesky
creationists."  Well alas, not only does this
NOT shut me up, it grants the creationary
community the perfect opportunity to
show just how incredibly wrong, and even
deceitful, the anti-creationists can be.
In the August 2011 Journal of Creation,
Doctors Tomkins and Bergman dropped a
nuclear bomb on the claim of
chromosomal fusion. In fact, I'll have a
rant hopefully coming out shortly just on
this subject.  Tomkins and Bergman
showed conclusively that there is zero
evidence for a chromosomal fusion - for
example: that alleged telomere sequence
in the middle of the human chromosome
2? It was in completely the wrong place, it
is not a telomere because it is too short,
and almost every chromosome has these
pseudo-telomeres in their middles.
Contrary to what the ever-so-reliable
wikipedia says, the sequences on either
side of the pseudo-telomere do not match
the DNA sequence of chimpanzees, as
would be expected. There's much more to
this, but I will simply refer you to my blog
post here, Tomkins wrote a brief laymans'
synopsis here, and of course, the
technical article here.
It is now being discovered that these
pseudo-telomeres have, of course,
PURPOSE!  Gee, that's what the
creationists would say!  ICR has
commissioned a research project looking
into the purposes of these
pseudo-telomeres.
Hot off the presses, and heating up the
anti-creation community, Indiana senate
has approved a bill allowing the teaching
of creation in the science classroom.
While the NCSE and ACLU get all hot
under the collar over this, the reality is
that any teacher is already permitted to
teach creation in the classroom!  The US
supreme court ruled on this years ago.
What the supreme court concluded was
that school boards were not permitted to
force their teachers to teach creation -
which frankly, I would agree.
But as this story unfolds, I would like to
point it out to viewers to keep an eye on
what happens over the next little while.
Notice how quickly lawsuits will come out
of this. Why? Because evolution must
hide from scrutiny and questioning - but
there's only one place it can hide: behind
judges, lawyers and school policies. This
is Anti-science, as true science welcomes
scrutiny.
[Dramatic, scary music]
Wahoo! Mail for me?
In episode 4 of Genesis Week, I reported
on alleged multicelled yeast being
produced in the lab.  Youtuber Tubenotme
wrote in suggesting that I clarify a point:
in that show I had stated that the action
of the centrifuge had caused the
clustering, which is not what the original
article said.  To clarify, I was aware of this,
but I do still think that the extreme
G-forces did more than just sorting, I
think those forces actually did contribute
to the production of the snowflake
clusters, even if the authors disagree.
A writer going by the name
Son_of_the_only_wise_god also wrote to
me privately:
Thanks for writing in, that is a significant
point.  Multicelled organisms have cells
specializing in different jobs.  The
snowflake yeast cells did what yeast did
best - because they were still yeast!  I
agree this had nothing to do with the
evolution of multicellular life.
In amongst his childish name-calling and
behaviour, Lawilson still insisted on
taking me to task on the Paluxy tracks,
showing just how little he knows about
them:
Sure - but please note neither Ken Ham,
nor anyone else from AIG has ever
actually spent time in the Paluxy, as I
have.  Let us also remember the task force
assembled by the Twin Cities Creation
Science association, who published their
conlusions in the book "Texas Tracks and
Artifacts."  After examining the evidence
presented for and against the human
footprint interpretation, this team of
scientists concluded that they were
genuine human footprints.  AIG and other
creationists are apparently unaware of
this book, or have ignored it - as has the
anti-creationary community.
Morris retracted his original book
because of errors in his book, and AIG
and other creationists have decided not
to use the Paluxy evidence based on
Kuban's alleged "research" of the Paluxy
tracks, and in particular, the red-stained
dinosaur tracks.  Kuban proponed that the
human footprints were actually the result
of a dinosaur walking on its heels -
metatarsal impressions.  For some
mysterious reason, Kuban never
mentioned in any of his reports that
apparently the dinosaur's heels were
dislocated, because the position of the
"heel" in each of the Taylor Trail tracks
changed position as you go down the
trail!  Apparently the dinosaur's heel feel
off and made its own trail, with the  6 track
landing squarely in the left toe of a
dinosaur track from another dinosaur trail
going in the opposite direction!  This one
track alone not only destroys Kuban's
hypothesis, it raises a disturbing
question: Did Kuban not see this
red-stained dinosaur track, when he went
there specifically to study the red-stained
dinosaur tracks? If so, what other crucial
evidence did he miss?  Or did deliberately
leave out crucial information in his
report?  In either case, Kuban has
demonstrated that his "research" is
invalid and untrustworthy, and so is the
NCSE who apparently never bothered to
check Kuban's "research."
Oddly enough, Kuban did mark the claw
impressions of that particular dinosaur
track on his map.  So I will let the viewers
draw their own conclusions about what
Kuban did and did not know, and what he
did, and did not, report.
Kuban also never seemed to notice that
the dinosaur footprints and human
footprints erode differently - the human
footprints become eroded into a
depression, while the dinosaur tracks
become raised - it's differential erosion.
Clearly the dinosaur and human tracks
were made at two separate times.
Lastly, lawilson has claimed that the CT
scans of the Delk track were invalidated -
which they never were. The skeptics,
such as wilson, just choose not to believe
the evidence. And yes, progress has been
made - in fact, we've had some 6 fossil
human footprints, one carved human
footprint, and a carved test rock, all
scanned on an industrial CT scanner.
Basically, with the exception of one of the
fossil tracks which could not originally be
scanned on the medical scanner we
originally used, the industrial CT scans
showed exactly what the Glen Rose
medical scanner showed....only in higher
resolution.  So no, the CT scans were
never invalidated, contrary to what
lawilson would like to believe.  I will be
producing a video showing the scans
which number over 10,000 images.
Equestions took lawilson and multiple
others to task in a very long series of
posts regarding the Delk track, which I'm
just going to repeat here because it is
very meaty and he hit the nail on the
head:
Man, I wish I could buy you a coffee!  If
you send me your mailing address, I'll
send you a Tim Horton's gift card, how
about that?  For more informaiton to see
exactly what it was they were talking
about, the Delk track video is right here,
in which I explain the CT scans performed
on the Delk track, and why they verify
that both the dinosaur and human
footprints are genuine tracks.
Thanks for writing in - it only violates the
establishment clause if it forces teachers
to teach creation - or any specific religion.
You'll notice that the NCSE and others
fight to even keep questioning of
evolution out of the schools.  Questioning
is good science!
I had a number of complaints from
youtubers mentioning that several
comments were being marked as "spam".
I'd like to respectively ask people not to
do this - I simply do not have time to sit
there and monitor all comments, and
un-spam them. Especially because some
people were actually appreciating the
debate and getting their opponents
comments marked as spam.
I'd also like to ask your opinions as
viewers: it's been suggested I moderate
the comments, which to date I have
avoided doing, for several reasons.  What
do you think? Should I moderate and
delete abusive comments?  Should I turn
off comments after a week? Give me your
opinions in the comments down below.
Well that's enough for this week, thanks
for watching, and thanks for sharing this
video with your friends using the
convenient "share" button down below.
I'm your host Ian Juby, reminding you of
the words of Christ who said "I am the
way, the Truth and the LIFE - no man
comes to the Father but through me."
We'll see you next Thursday.
Production Software was provided for Genesis
Week by the Big Valley Creation Science
Museum, located just 25 minutes north
of Drumheller, Alberta. In the heart of the
dinosaur badlands, the Big Valley Creation
Science Museum was built from the ground
up to give credit to our Creator, portraying the
scientific evidence showing that creation is
the faith that fits the facts, and that
evolution is the faith that the facts have failed.
Visit bvcsm.com for more details.