>>Tony Voellm: So with that, I'd like to introduce
our first speaker of the day. Mark Trostler
is an O'Reilly author, well respected in the
community. He has written a book on testable
JavaScript. He was born in Southern California.
He says he is going to live there until he
dies. I told him please don't do that anytime
soon. And with that, I'm going to hand it
off to Mark, and so here you are.
[ Applause ]
>>Mark Trostler: Thanks. I don't know about
well respected in the field. I don't know
where that came from, but....
Okay. So my name is Mark. I work at Google.
I'm an SET with Google help. I'm actually
based in Irvine.
Yes, I have this book Testable JavaScript.
O'Reilly was supposed to send out a bunch
of copies but they failed, so they said find
me afterwards and I'll collect emails and
if you're interested in the book, I can get
you a free e-copy.
Okay. So when we talk about testability, before
I even jump into this, we heard a lot about
testing and automating your testing and I
think Simon yesterday said something really
great which was you can't sort of bake in
testing and maintainability and all of this
stuff after the fact. It needs to be there
from the very beginning; otherwise, you're
not going to get the benefits of automation
and easy testing and all this. So it's really
important that from the very beginning, your
applications don't just come in at the end
and try to test something.
Really try to be present at the beginning
when these applications are being developed
and architected so you could have your say
about how maybe they should be built to make
your jobs and our jobs much easier down the
line when you need to test these things.
Okay. So when we talk about testability, these
are sort of the standard things that get thrown
out. We want loose coupling and tightly focused
methods, and all this other good stuff. No
surprises, and all that. And I hear these
and I see these in a lot of presentations
and when I talk to people, and that's great,
and I don't think anyone disagrees with any
of these things, but rarely do we talk about,
okay, how specifically do we actually achieve
these things? What do we need to do in our
applications that actually have loose coupling
and tightly focused methods and all this other
stuff?
Sorry.
So the way we get there is using interfaces
and not implementations. And what I mean by
that is, and what a lot of this presentation
is about, is we talk a lot -- there's a lot
of talk, especially in the JavaScript community
and probably in Java as well, about hiding
data. I want to make this private. I want
to make this protected. I'm going to use the
module pattern or closure to hide variables
or properties and methods from you.
And when you start talking about what you're
hiding versus what you're exposing, I think
you've already sort of lost.
And so what I mean by that is when you program
and you test to implement to interfaces and
not to implementations, your life becomes
a lot simpler. You can swap implementations
very easily. You can work, end test, end code
all in parallel, and you will see what I mean
by when I say all this stuff, and you can
write the test one time, hopefully, and then
as you implement different functionality,
your tests don't have to change, or change
very little.
I don't know -- we have some bonus slides
that have slipped in here so I'm just going
to ignore those.
So when I talked about interfaces in JavaScript,
the first reaction is, JavaScript doesn't
have interfaces. Well, it sort of does, and
we can fake it by creating an object like
this and defining a bunch of empty functions
or methods. And when I do this, what I've
done here is I've essentially created an interface.
Here is an interface for a user repository.
It provides some -- all the basic functionality
that I need to get and set and deal with users.
Everyone's application, most applications
have users. You need a way to store them somewhere,
somehow and then retrieve them back later.
So here we create a simple interface that
can get and set and query and do these other
interesting things to a user repository.
And what's great when I have an interface
like this, besides the fact that it's very
sort of self-documenting is when I write my
tests, I write tests to the interface. So
here you could see I'm passing in a repo object.
I don't care what this repo object, how it's
actually implemented. I just care about its
interface, the save and the get methods. So
I'm going to write a test here that I'm going
to save a user, and them I'm going to call
get and get the user back, and then I'm just
going to verify that the user I saved is actually
the user I returned. And this is all via the
interface, not via some implementation that
is buried somewhere in the object.
So now when I want to actually have an implementation
of that interface in JavaScript, it looks
something like this. First I have a constructor
function which takes parameters specific to
that implementation. So here I'm using the
redis data store to implement the user repo
interface, and it takes some host port options,
sort of injected, as we'll see, dependencies
into the constructor, and then I have any
-- I have my redis client here, and then later
on I set the prototype of this constructor
function to be the interface itself. So here
I'm sort of declaring to the world that I'm
going to implement this user repo interface.
And then finally on the prototype I go ahead
and define all the methods that the interface
says I need to define. Get, save, query, delete,
you know, whatever.
So in this way I've sort of created a JavaScript
object that implements my interface.
So what we've got here is we have an object
that's acting as an interface. There's no
initialization you could do on this object.
This object can only be used by implementations
to actually get work done. The interface itself
does nothing.
The implementation itself has a constructor
which takes specific parameters that are injected
into it to actually create the object, the
implementation.
And then I sort of state my intention to the
world that, hey, I'm going to implement this
interface by setting my prototype equal to
it.
And then finally, in the actually implementation
object, I then go ahead and I override all
those interface methods, and now I have an
actual implementation of that interface.
And what's great here is now when I need to
test this thing, I've already got the tests.
I just create a new object of this specific
implementation of the user repo interface,
and now I just call the test method it, and,
great, I do my save and my get and hopefully
it all works, and now I've just tested my
implementation.
So time goes on. My application is growing.
Redis turns out, oh, crap, that was a bad
idea to use redis. We actually need to use
Amazon S3. No problem. Very simple. All we
need is a new implementation of our user repo
interface. Going to call this one user repo
S3. It has a constructor. It takes parameters
that are injected into the constructor for
what we need for this specific implementation.
I'm going to announce to the world that I
am also going to implement this user repo
interface, and then I'm going to go ahead
and actually create the methods that actually
are going to implement that interface, the
save, the get, the whatever. Hey, I've already
got the test for this thing. All I need to
do is wire up a new Amazon -- sorry, user
repo S3 object, run it through my tests that
I've already created that I've already created,
and I could tell easily, quickly, if this
thing actually works or not.
Which brings us to our first principle of
the day, which is the single responsibility
principle that says every interface essentially
should just do one thing and one thing only.
Which leads us to the second principle of
the day, which is no object should be forced
to depend on methods and functionality that
it doesn't use or need.
And we saw that in our user repo interface.
It just deals with saving and getting users.
There's nothing else in there. There's no
extra functionality that I might or might
not need later.
Which finally takes us to our first pattern,
which I'll just call it the interface pattern
here. When we bring all this stuff together,
we have the single responsibility principle.
We match sets with gets, and what I mean by
that is if you have -- if your interface has
a way to take something in, it should have
a corresponding method to get the thing back
out.
I see this a lot with logging. There is a
method on the logger to log something, and
then it goes away, and there's no way to get
it back. The only way to get it back later
is you have some other way to maybe query
the database later to actually read the logs.
That's sort of dumb. You should have something
in the interface, if you can set it, you should
be able to get it back.
You end up with more smaller interfaces versus
a couple really big interfaces that try to
do everything. You really want a lot of small
focused ones.
And then of course we want the interface segregation
principle. We want our interfaces just doing
one thing, one thing only, not any extra functionality
in there.
And when you write tests and when you write
your application, you just look at the interface.
You don't look at the implementation. That
interface we saw, the user repo interface,
it's an object. It's a self-documenting. Here
are all the methods on it. Here's sort of
what they -- the parameters that they take.
That's the only thing you should be looking
at when you're programming and when you're
testing.
Okay. So we've created a bunch of nice interfaces.
We've maybe gotten some implementations of
those interfaces. Now it's time to actually
use this stuff.
What we don't want to do is just turn around
and in something that actually needs our user
repo is to call new. Because what we've done
is you've tightly coupled your implementation
to the thing that needs it. So here later
on when I switch from redis to S3, I need
to go through all my code and find out all
the places where I sort of got this user repo
redis object that is now very tightly coupled
here and replace it with the S3 object. Not
only that, any parameters that this thing
needed to be created, I need to somehow switch
to now being the S3 parameters instead of
these.
So we don't want to do this. This is the sort
of definition poster child of tight coupling
when you do something like this.
So what you do want to do is pass the dependent
in in the constructor just like we saw for
those interfaces earlier when we were creating
implementations. You pass these things into
the constructor.
And then later on, we just sort of save off
a copy of it, and then later on, in class,
we'll use the interface methods of this user
repo object. And now my controller doesn't
care, doesn't know, doesn't want to know whether
it's redis, it's S3, it's MySQL, it's whatever
the heck you decide it should be later, because
these things change, and they do, this class
does not care, doesn't know. It's just programming
to the interface.
Which brings us to the next principle. The
Liskov substitution principle has a big impressive
sounding name which is something which is
pretty simple intuitively, which is any objects
that implements the same interfaces, they
can be swapped out at will. So as we saw earlier,
I have my user repo S3, I have my user repo
redis. I can swap them out to my user controller
class. My user controller class has no idea,
doesn't care, shouldn't have to know, doesn't
know. That's all thanks to the Liskov substitution
principle. A great phrase.
So when you pass in all your dependents to
a constructor, you end up with something called
constructor injection. A very fancy name for
just passing in all your dependents to a constructor.
And what's great about constructor injection
is it makes all of that object's dependencies
very explicit such that you can't even create
this object until you have all of its dependencies
passed into it. You can't create an object
that's sort of half created and then later
on you need to remember to call, like, an
init method or set something else up over
here. You can't even get this object at all
until you've actually passed in all of its
dependencies in the constructor.
This also gives us this nice loose coupling
that everyone agrees is a great idea that
lets us swap out implementations at runtime
or whenever you need to, essentially, to get
very loose coupling.
There are a couple exceptions to this rule,
and we're going to talk about those in a little
bit. Runtime dependencies being the most common.
When we talk about constructor injection and
we say you can't create an object until you
pass in all of its dependencies to it, the
first thing you would think about is, well,
crap, that doesn't seem to help me. Now the
object that -- now I need to know all of the
dependencies of any object I need in order
to create that object. And that sort of puts
all the onus on me. And that doesn't seem
to make sense.
Well, you're right. You shouldn't create objects,
in fact, should you very rarely, if ever,
create objects during the normal course of
the running of your application.
What we want to do here is, we want to create
all of our objects up-front at the very beginning
of -- before your application even runs, create
all your objects, create all your dependencies,
and then sort of kick your application off
once you have all of your dependencies and
all the objects created from this giant object
graph.
So what we've got here is, we really broke
our application into two distinct phases,
if you will. One is at the very beginning
at a place called composition root, if you
want a fancy phrase for it. You create all
the objects your application is going to need
for its entire life. You sort of follow this
object graph, and you create all these objects.
And then you create sort of the highest level
one, and then you kick it off and hit "start,"
and then off it goes.
So we create all of our objects at the very
beginning, and then we, if the first phase,
and then in phase 2, we actually use the objects
in our application runs, and it's all right.
Now, in a Web application, composition root
isn't necessarily when the entire application
starts up, say, with the Web server or something
like that. There's also the request cycle.
For instance, a user object, you don't know
who the user is specifically until the request
cycle starts and you've sort of retrieved
your session. You're like, oh, the user is
Mark. I'm going to create the user object
Mark that represents him.
So it's okay for your composition root to
be, you know, scoped at a request cycle as
well as from the very first time your application
starts up.
Okay. Great. So we want to create all these
objects at the very beginning. Well, then
what creates all the objects?
Well, there's lots of different dependency
injectors or inversion of control containers,
whatever you like calling them. Those are
the things that are -- actually create your
objects for you. And you can use sort of one
off the shelf. Certainly there's many for
Java. There's a lot for JavaScript as well,
it turns out. cujo, cujojs is a really popular
one. Do it yourself, that's a DIY dependency
injection. You can also do it yourself. And
the idea is, at the very beginning of your
application, at the composition root, whether
that's during the request cycle or when your
application first starts up or when you first
push all your client-side JavaScript to your
browser, this object depends on these three,
these three objects depend on these eight,
these eight depend on these 24. Finally, at
the very bottom, you have a set of objects
that don't depend on anything else. So you
create those first. You walk your way up your
sort of dependency graph until you get to
the very top, and then you've created everything.
And that's what these dependency injection
or inversion of control containers are really
good at, are walking that object graph to
create all your objects for you.
AngularJS, open source Google project, does
dependency injection as well.
So there's -- you have lots of -- you have
lots of options here of what you want to use.
Okay. So you've created these sort of self-contained
objects, and they just do one thing, and they
do one thing only. And that's great. And then
the question is, well, what about this other
stuff that I might want to do? I might want
to do logging. I might want to do caching,
all these sort of cross-cutting concerns.
And the question is, how do we sort of weave
these cross-cutting concerns into the fabric
of our application here?
We don't -- we know we don't want to pollute
our interfaces with logging or with any of
this other stuff, because you might need it,
you might not need it. Not all classes might
want logging. So how do we bring all this
stuff together?
Well, let's first look at what we don't want
to do. And what we don't want to do is what
we saw earlier, which is just sort of, you
know, create new versions of this stuff within
a specific implementation. So within my userrepo
redis implementation, I don't want to just
turn around and call, you know, new logger
or new profiler. Again, this tightly couples
us to those implementations. And it makes
things a lot more difficult to test when you
have this stuff sort of buried within the
object itself. It's a lot harder to mock out
and stub this stuff out.
So you say, okay, well, I want to pass some
stuff in maybe to the implementation. And
this is on the right track in that we're using
constructor injection. But there are a lot
of problems with this approach as well.
For one, the single responsibility principle
here is, now we have a specific implementation.
Userrepo redis is now sort of baked in logging
and profiling. And when I want to use the
userrepo redis object and maybe I don't want
profiling and I don't want logging, I'm sort
of stuck here.
So what I mean by that specifically is, you'll
end up with code something like this method
that's implementing the save interface method.
You sort of put all this extra junk in here
that not all users of this class might need.
Here we've got logging, we have profiling,
and then in the middle of all that, we're
actually going to reach out to redis to save
the user. And then we're going to do some
more logging and more profiling. And the problem
here is, in our next implementation, userrepo
S3, I've got to remember if I want logging,
profiling, I've got to pull all this code
out of there and I've got to put it over here.
And as I said earlier, not everybody -- you
might not want logging and profiling all the
time whenever you're using this object.
So the solution to this problem is -- like
the solution to almost all problems, is, we
want to keep the different functionality separate.
We want to maintain the single responsibility
principle. We want to keep -- we don't want
to put in any extra functionality into our
implementation here that some classes might
not need.
So what we want to do is create an interface.
So here is a logger interface. You see it
just has two methods here, a log method, and
then, a way to get the log back out once you've
put the log in.
And here's a simple implementation of that
interface. Here's an implementation that's
going to log to a file. You can imagine one
that would log to a database or log to a remote
logging somewhere else. I have my implementation-specific
constructor that's going to take a file. Here
I'm announcing to the world that I am going
to implement the logger interface. And then
I go ahead and blow through all the interface
methods and implement them for this specific
implementation.
So quick aside here. One thing that makes
JavaScript really nice is, we can sort of
do whatever we want with the objects. A lot
of sort of built-in reflection.
Here's just a quick method called mixin. And
what this method is going to do -- and we'll
see how we use it on the next slide -- is,
we're going to sort of take all the methods
from base class and automatically embed them
sort of from the base, and we're going to
automatically add them to a different object.
So we're just going to blow through all the
properties in our base object. And then if
we find one that's a method and that doesn't
already exist in the -- in our current implementation,
we're just going to stick it on the current
object. And we'll see how we use this in a
second.
Well, let's just look at how we use this thing,
actually.
Okay. So let's get back to our initial problem
here, which is, we want to sort of have logging
with our -- with our userrepo. So here's how
we do it. We create something called a decorator.
And here is a specific implementation of one,
a userrepo logger. And the idea of the decorator
here is, it is going to also implement the
userrepo interface, but it's going to have
logging baked into it.
So, again, here I have a constructor which
is being injected with its dependencies in
this case. It has a dependency of another
userrepo object. We don't care which one,
because it's just going to -- we're just programming
to the interface. And a logger object. Again,
we don't care which one, because we're just
going to deal with the interface.
Now we're going to mix in all of the original
repo's original methods into this class. And
this is really just sort of a helper which
lets me not have to define all of the save,
the get, the query user, the delete user methods.
If I don't declare any of those off our prototype,
then they will just fall back to sort of the
inner repo's version of those methods.
And then, finally, I actually am going to
implement the save method here. And what I'm
going to do here is, I'm actually going to
take the logger, and I'm going to do my logging.
And then I'm going to sort of hand off responsibility
for the actual repo saving to whatever repo
was passed in to me.
And so here what I've done is I've sort of
intercepted or decorated the save method with
logging. And what's great here is, the inner
repo, whichever one I happen to pass in, userrepo
redis, userrepo S3, or whatever, has no idea
that logging is happening. And the logging
has no idea about the userrepo. They're not
mixed in any way. Only through this decorator
class.
So when I want to create one of these things
at the very beginning of my application, using
my dependency injector and my container, I
create whichever implementation of userrepo
I want. Here in this case, the redis 1. I
create whichever implementation of the logging
I want. Here in this case, the file one.
And now I've got another userrepo that, thanks
to our good friend, the Liskov Substitution
Principle, says I can now use this userrepo
anywhere I was using a userrepo before, and
now I get logging for free without having
to, you know, mess up my original userrepo
redis or S3 implementation.
Okay. So we talked about -- we wanted to do
profiling, too. Remember that?
So let's again go through this same kind of
deal here. I'm going to create a profile interface.
It does a start and a stop. And then, of course,
it has a way to get it back out, too, once
we've stuck it in. Here's a very simple implementation
of that interface. Here's my constructor function,
which has implementation-specific parameters,
none in this case, announcing to the world
that I am going to implement the profile interface.
And then, finally, I'm going to go ahead and
actually implement all of those methods there.
Here's just start, stop.
One can imagine, of course, other profiling.
What if you want disk space profiling, what
if you wanted CPU profiling? No problem, just
create another implementation of the profiler
interface and you've got those.
Again, I'm going to create another decorator
for this one, going to call it userrepo profiler.
This one in its constructor function takes,
again, an inner repo, it takes a profiler
interface. I'm going to mix in everything
from the userrepo into this current object.
Again, this is just sort of like a convenience
so I don't -- so this object doesn't have
to implement all of the interface methods
if it doesn't want to.
And then, finally, I'm going to sort of intercept
or decorator the save method of the userrepo
interface. And in this case, I'm going to
do -- sort of start my profiler, then I'm
going to delegate to the inner repo to do
any actual saving, and then I'm going to stop
the profiler. So now I have a sort of profiling
userrepo.
And then, finally, we're going to put the
whole thing together here to get an all-seeing,
all-knowing, all doing logging and profiling
userrepo object. So first I'm going to create
a specific implementation here. I'm going
to use the redis one. For grins, I'm going
to use the time implementation for profiler.
I'm going to use the logger implement- -- the
file implementation for logger. And now I'm
going to sort of create my -- here's my profiling
userrepo object. And then here's my logging
profiling userrepo object. Because I've been
programming to interfaces, I can -- and because
of our good friend the Liskov Substitution
Principle, I can use this userrepo prof object
anywhere I can use a userrepo object since
it implements that interface. So I'm going
to use that to pass into the userrepo logger
object. And now, at the very end here, I have
a userrepo object that can be used anywhere
a userrepo object could be used. But this
one has logging and profiling built into it.
And at no point have I sort of violated any
of our principles of keeping things separate.
And what's great is, I can test the heck out
of my logger implementation. I can test the
heck out of the profiler implementation. And
I don't need to mix them. I don't need to
have that kind of testing also when I'm just
testing the userrepo interface as well.
Okay. So just a quick note on tests here.
There's a couple ways to test decorators.
One is, you sort of mock out the -- sort of
the part that's doing the decorating. Then
you just sort of call your save method on
that object, and then you verify your mocked-out
object.
The other way is to sort of create the whole
thing and sort of mock out everything. And
so this is more like if you don't trust the
fact that when you put all of this stuff together
it's actually going to work like you think
it is, you can -- you can do tests like that.
The previous way is, you've sort of tested
the two in -- all the interfaces in isolation,
and you can just run them through your normal
userrepo test that we saw earlier, that save
that's just saving to the -- you know, that's
just using the interface methods.
So they're really easy to test, and these
decorators are obviously -- are very easy
to mock out as well.
Which brings us to our second pattern, which
is the decorator pattern, which is what we
just saw. And the whole game here is, again,
everything we just saw, you create a constructor
that sort of takes an inner version of the
interface and any other objects it needs that
it's going to decorate the interface with.
Then you want to sort of mix in the inner
objects methods into your decorator objects
so you don't have to implement all the interface
methods if you don't want to.
And then, finally, you go ahead and actually
implement the interface methods that you want,
using -- using the decorator, using the other
object you passed in the logger, the profiler,
to actually do the work that you want the
decorator to do.
And I say in there optionally, because it
turns out you don't actually need to call
the inner interface if for some reason your
decorator decides it doesn't need to. And
the sort of the canonical example here is
caching. You don't want to build caching directly
into your implementations. You can write a
caching decorator that in the save method
or in the get method, it would look to see,
hey, is this object already in my cache that
I'm keeping locally in the decorator? If so,
I don't need to delegate it all to the inner
repo. I can just return the object I've already
got.
Okay. Last bit I'm going to talk about here
is, what about runtime dependencies?
And sort of the example here is, I've got
a dating site, awesome Web site. People come,
they try to find their matches for who they
want to go out with. And there's a couple
different criteria they can use to determine
what they want to use to find their matches.
They can use do we share the same likes? Do
we like to do the same activities? Distance,
how far away are they from me. Or anything
else you can think of.
And the idea here is that when the user comes
to the site, they sort of have a pulldown,
and it's up to them to select how they want
to find their matches, one of those three
things.
Well, the thing is, you don't know what they're
going to pick; right? So you can't sort of
create a user controller object or something
at the beginning with one of these fine match
algorithms, because it's up to the user to
pick it. You don't know what it's going to
be.
So the first step here, of course, is to create
an interface called findmatches. This is given
a user ID. It's going to return a set of matches
for them.
And then we're going to go ahead and create
some implementations of this interface. Again,
here's -- that "F" is just short for function,
because there wasn't enough room on the slide.
So I have a constructor function here. Here's
one for distance. Here I'm going to say I
am going to implement the find matches interface,
and then I have some other objects here. I've
got one for activities. I've got one that's
going to find your closest matches for likes
and whatnot.
So here's the crux of the problem here, is,
in my user controller, I don't know what you're
going to pick. So I don't know which find
match sort of implementation to inject here.
So I could inject all three. That's sort of
-- that's clunky, doesn't smell right. What
about if I come up with a fourth? You know,
a fourth one later. Then I've got to make
sure I add it there. What if there are other
things that need sort of a dynamically injected
findmatches?
So the solution here is an abstract factory.
So I don't want to get too bogged down in
the terminology "abstract factory." That sounds
crazy. That sounds like something you need
in Java, not something you need in JavaScript.
Isn't JavaScript supposed to free us from
all of this?
Well, when I say "abstract factory," all I'm
talking about here is, it's an object that's
going to take a runtime value and return a
dependency. That's all I mean here.
So to create one of these abstract factories,
just like everything else, I'm going to have
an interface. I'm going to call this one findmatch
factory. It just has one method, a get match
implementation. And you can see it takes a
type. And this type, say, is just a string,
likes or activities or distance. And it's
going to return to me the implementation I
need, the findmatch implementation I need,
to actually find the matches that the user
has requested.
So here's a quick implementation of this interface.
Again, I have my constructor. In this case,
it's going to take a userrepo object. I have
a -- I'm here, I'm broadcasting to the world
that I am going to implement the findmatch
factory interface. And then here is my get
match implementation actual implementation
of it. And you can see there's something slightly
strange here which should make you sort of
recoil, is that there's -- new's in here.
Whenever you see "new" in code, you should
get a little bit scared.
But it turns out for factories, it's okay.
It's okay to call new here. This is the whole
point of this object. You don't have to do
it this way. You can also pass these sort
of three or more implementations in via the
constructor. It's sort of up to you how you
want to do it. But the idea here is, I'm going
to take a type, a runtime value, and I'm going
to return an actual implementation.
So in this case, I'm going to switch on the
type, and depending on which one they selected,
I will return you the correct implementation
for that type.
Okay. So what happens here is, in my user
controller, what I'm injecting into its constructor
is the abstract factory. That's the whole
game here. So here I'm injecting in the abstract
factory. I save it off for later, and then
-- so here's a constructor. Here I'm saying
I am implementing the controller interface.
And then in this method here, where -- that
finally boils down to when the user has actually
selected their type, I know what type they
selected, I know what the user is. Now I reach
out to my factory that was injected to me,
and I say, aha, okay, I've finally got the
type. Give me the object that matches this
type. It does. And then now I can call the
interface method matches, if you remember
from the findmatch interface, to actually
get the matches that the user requested, whether
you get it by distance, or likes or activities,
whatever they wanted.
What's great about abstract factories is,
they're really easy to test. You know, all
-- they're not doing very much. Right? They're
just translating from a type to an object.
So a dead-simple test is just to iterate over
all of the known types and make sure you got
the object back that you expected.
And they're really easy to mock out. So when
we want to test the user controller, mocking
out an abstract factory is really simple.
So here's a -- here's an implementation of
our abstract factory for test. It has a specific
constructor that takes a mocked-out match
version and what the expected type was. I
say I'm going to implement this interface.
And then the get matching implementation just
sort of returns the mock, plus it checks to
make sure that the type it got passed was
what was actually expected.
And then you can go ahead and inject this
mocked out or test version of the abstract
factory into your user controller.
Which brings us to our final pattern of the
day, which is the abstract factory pattern.
And the game here is, as we just discussed,
I'm going to take a runtime value and I'm
going to return to you an actual object for
that runtime value. The factory implementation
itself has created a composition root, along
with all the other objects. And you inject
the factory instead of injecting, you know,
the actual, you know, findmatches object into
the constructor of any object that needs to
deal with this runtime value.
And then, finally, you use the factory at
the moment when you actually need it to get
the actual dependency that you needed.
Okay. So to sort of tie a bow on all of this,
what we really like to see when we're talking
about testable JavaScript or, really, testable
probably anything, is we like composition.
Inheritance is a little more stifling. Composition
allows us to really easily mix and match pieces
that we need without sort of sullying our
implementation objects or our interfaces.
We want to program and test to those interfaces.
Again, we talked about -- I talked at the
very beginning about hiding data, making stuff
private, putting, like, an underscore there
to make sure people know that, hey, this is
private, don't touch this. Using interfaces,
it's just here's the interface. That's what
you've got. That's it.
You don't have to worry about hiding as much.
Again, we want to create lots of small interfaces,
because we've seen how easy it is to mix and
match them together. And it's significantly
easier to test small interfaces and to mock
out small interfaces than it is big, hairy,
complex ones.
We're going to decorate and intercept for
those cross-cutting concerns. We're going
to constructor inject all of our dependencies,
even the runtime ones, using abstract factories.
And here's our abstract factories for the
runtime dependencies.
And, finally, there's really, unfortunately,
only one way to actually ensure testability
of your code. And that is to write the tests
first. Because then you're guaranteed to have
the tests up-front. But if you follow, you
know, all of these patterns and these principles
I showed you, maybe you could try to get away
without writing the tests first. But why would
you want to do that?
That's all I've got.
Thank you very much.
[ Applause ]
>>Tony Voellm: Thank you, Mark. That was fantastic.
And thank you for bringing back my childhood
fears with the cujojs.
For those of you who don't know Cujo, it was
this giant German shepherd that's rabid, attacks
his family. They're stuck in the car. Everybody
dies. It's a terrible movie. So years of Beethoven
and Disney has fixed this, but I'm going to
have to watch that movie tonight.
>>Mark Trostler: Sorry to take you back down
that road.
>>Tony Voellm: Questions? We have two mikes
in the aisle, like we did yesterday.
So I see one live question.
When you ask your question, state your name,
your company, and your question. Or you can
delete other parts if you don't really want
to state your name.
So with that, go ahead, please.
>>> My name is Alec Monroe. I work at Arc90.
I noticed one piece that wasn't injectable:
The redis client or the S3 client.
Wouldn't that become an issue when you were
trying to do something live and you didn't
want to actually -- or trying to test something
and you didn't want to actually have to be
talking to S3?
>>Mark Trostler: That's a good point. Because
when I was looking at the slides, I was, like,
you could just inject the redis object itself
into the user redis repo. But sort of the
idea of the user redis repo is, it's talking
to redis. So that's sort of a -- you know,
like, a piece of that object that can't really
be abstracted away.
But using, you know -- programming to the
interface, it's really easy just to create
a mock. So if you don't really want to talk
to redis, it's really easy just to create
a mocked-out version of userrepo that, you
know, is just checking to make sure, like,
did I get this? Was that what I expected?
And whatnot?
>>> So use a different repo in that case?
>>Mark Trostler: Yeah, just use a different
repo. Since you're programming to the interface,
it doesn't matter what the interface is.
>>Tony Voellm: With that, thank you. If you
have other questions, I'm sure you'll be around,
Mark.
>>Mark Trostler: I'll be around. This is a
good question on the Dory, too. But --
>>Tony Voellm: It's a fantastic question.
It says -- it's about, you know, performance
concerns if you have ten seconds, ten seconds
here.
>>Mark Trostler: So the idea is -- so the
question is, well, if you create all your
objects up-front, isn't that a performance
problem or something like that.
Turns out it's really not, since you're going
to be creating all these objects anyway during
the course of your application, it's better
to create them up-front and then you have
less of a performance issue throughout the
rest of your application.
>>Tony Voellm: Good answer. All right.
Thank you. All right.
[ Applause ]