"Rudder" is spelled with two Ds.
- Thanks, wingman.
- Yeah, sure.
Whoa, bandits!
Crack shootin', Danny.
Crack shootin', Rafe.
- Land of the free.
- Home of the brave.
Great flyin',Dad!
Come on.
I'm gonna teach you how to fly.
I get the front!
No, you take the back.
I'm bigger,
and I should be in front.
I'm older,
and I'm teachin', so no.
Wow.
It's like we're really flying.
Yeah, I did it lots of times.
Come on, you man the guns.
I'll give her some throttle.
We gotta get those
dirty German bandits.
Oh, gosh!
- Hang on!
- Make it stop, Rafe!
I've seen my dad
do this lots of times.
Don't worry!
Rafe!
Oh, my gosh! We're flying!
We're flying!
Whoa! Uhh!
Wow.
My dad's gonna kill me.
Come on.
Yes! Whoo-hoo!
We flew!
We flew! Yes!
I'm a pilot!
- I know!
- Yeah!
We flew.
- You no-account boy!
- Daddy-
I done told you,
you spend time playing...
with this stupid boy
can't read...
you ain't never goin'
to amount to nothin'!
He ain't stupid, Daddy!
Daddy!
Ohh!
Come on!
Uhh!
Get on back home. Now!
Get on up.
You got work to do.
Come on! Come on, get on home!
Uhh!
You let him alone!
Daddy, no!
I will bust you open,
you dirty German!
What'd you call me?
I fought the Germans in France.
And I fought 'em
in the trenches.
And I pray to God
no one ever has to see...
the things that I saw.
You're my bestfriend.
Daddy, wait!
Daddy, wait.
Adolf Hitler...
builds the German
military machine...
and drags
all of Europe into war.
But even while France
falls to Hitler...
America still refuses
to join the fighting.
- Where's McCawley and Walker?
- Still training, sir.
Alright, Danny.
Now let's show 'em how to fly.
We're gonna play chicken.
You ready?
This ain't the farm,
and these ain't no cropdusters.
I'm not playing
chicken with you.
Now don't be a baby.
I'll tell you what-
- I'm not doing it, Rafe.
- Well, I'm coming right at you.
You can turn, or you can hit me.
It's up to you.
What the-
Oh, boy.
Why you always
bustin' my ass, Rafe?
Which way you goin'?
I guess I'll go right.
No, uh, left. I'll go left.
OK, we're goin' left, right?
Ri-uh, right. Right?
Right like we're goin' right,
or right like we're goin' left?
Well, now you got me
all mixed up!
I don't know.
Make up your mind.
God, Rafe, we're going right!
Righty-tighty!
Aah!
- Whoo-hoo!
- Whoo-hoo-hoo!
Those are some smooth aces.
Did you say something?
'Cause let me tell ya,
those farm boys are grounded!
Yes, sir, an entirely
unacceptable use...
of m-m-military aircraft, sir.
- Get my hat.
- Yes, sir.
Get those hedge-hoppers
in Doolittle's office.
After two years of training...
you believe that
a $45,000 airplane...
is there for your amusement?
No, sir.
I was just trying...
to keep my edge, Major.
And when you did
the outside loop last week...
what did you think that was?
Honing your skills?
That's not training, McCawley.
That's a stunt.
And I personally
consider it to be reckless...
and irresponsible.
Major...
How could that be,
when you're famous...
for being the first man
in the world ever to do it?
Don't get cute with me, son.
No, sir, I don't mean
to be disrespectful.
I just think that-
well, I-
It is reckless
and irresponsible...
if you're just doing it
to be a show-off.
But I was doing it to try
to inspire the men, sir...
in the way that
you've inspired me.
I believe the French
even have a word for that...
when the men get together
to honor their leaders.
They call it an homage, sir.
- A what?
- An homage, sir.
That's bullshit, McCawley!
But it's very,
very good bullshit.
Thank you, sir.
McCawley, you remind me
of myself fifteen years ago.
Which is why we need
to discuss this.
Have a seat, son.
The British have accepted you
into the Eagle Squadron.
You're on your way
to England tomorrow...
if you still want to go.
Huh. Wow.
Just a few British pilots
are all that stand...
between Hitler
and total victory in Europe.
They're gonna need
all the help they can get.
Yes, sir.
Well, I'm on my way.
Just for the record...
I'm supposed to ask you
to reconsider.
Sir?
Sooner or later
we're gonna be in this war...
whether we like it or not.
And I'm gonna need
all of my best pilots.
So it's my duty
to ask you to stay.
Major, what would you do?
If it was me...
I'd go.
Get out. Am I going bald
right back here?
Ooh!
Man, I am one good-lookin'
son of a bitch.
Don't you ever die.
Die. That's exactly...
the concept
you gotta work tonight.
You put a drop of this clove oil
under your eyes...
and you let 'em sting
and well up.
You get your nurse alone,
take a breath...
let her see your eyes glisten...
and say, "Baby,
they're training me for war...
"and I don't know
what'll happen...
"but if I die tomorrow,
I want to know...
"that we lived
all we could tonight. "
Come on, guys!
We got nurses waitin'.
Come on, before the rest
of his hair falls out.
How could you do this?
Well, Doolittle assigned me.
He wanted me to get some real-
real combat training in.
Well, guess what?
It's not training over there.
It's war.
Where the losers die,
and there aren't any winners-
just guys who turn
into broken-down wrecks...
like my father.
Yeah, I understand that, Danny.
But I feel like
I got a duty to go.
Don't preach to me
about duty, damn it.
I wear the same uniform you do.
Now, if trouble wants me,
I'm ready for it.
But why go looking for it?
God, Danny, come on.
I'm gonna be twenty-five.
I might as well be an old man.
They're gonna have me bein'
a flight instructor.
I don't wanna teach
loops and barrel rolls.
I wanna be a combat fighter.
Hey, come on!
The nurses can't
d- d-dance by themselves.
Let's go.
If the call of duty
means seeing 150 men...
in their underwear every day...
we are here to serve.
I can't believe it.
Saturday night
in New York City.
Do you know what they're doing
where I come from?
Nothing.
Cow-tipping.
Well, that's why
you joined the Navy, hon'.
To get out of that dusty
little town and see the world.
May I remind you, Barbara,
we're Navy nurses, not tourists.
I joined to do
my patriotic duty and...
to meet guys.
Me, too.
Girls, we're gonna have
so much fun tonight in the city.
You've gotta tell them
the story, Evelyn.
What?
Oh, come on. Tell us.
Oh, it's such a long story.
We got time.
I saw it happen.
Well, it was
about four weeks ago...
What do you think
is b-b-better?
All in the one cheek,
or spreading them out?
OK.
Fusco, Anthony.
You all right, buddy?
Sweetie, do you really
have to do this?
I'm not gonna get yellow fever
in my barracks.
No? If you'd rather,
she can do it.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Just gimme a minute.
Honey, the government
says stick 'em, we stick 'em.
Uh!
Hey, Red, you alright?
Eye exam number four?
Listen, Doc, I have passed
a dozen medical checks.
You write that,
they won't let me fly.
Sorry, son.
I'm gonna fail.
They're gonna
take my wings away.
No, they won't. Just relax.
Read the bottom line, please.
Just keep practicin'
the bottom line.
And don't worry.
I'm right behind you.
J- L-M-K-P-O-
Next.
Ma'am.
J- L-M-K-P-O-E-T-X.
Eyes like an eagle, ma'am.
Slow down, flyboy.
And, instead of the bottom,
read the very top. Both eyes.
Yeah.
"C"- sorry, "J."
Ahem. "C"...
- "W."
- "Q."
- Uh, "Q."
Uh, "'Q."'
Read the bottom line
again, please.
But read it right to left
and every other letter.
"E."
Heh. "'X."'
- X-E.
X- E, ma'am.
Ma'am, I know how this looks.
I'm sorry, Lieutenant,
I really am.
But Army and Navy
requires 20/20 vision.
Oh, i-it's-it's not
a problem with my eyes.
I mean, I can see.
I mean, I can hit a running
rabbit with a $3.00 pistol.
I got a problem with letters,
that's all.
Well, maybe after
some schooling...
you could come back
and take the test again.
No, I had schooling.
I mean, I-the teachers
just never knew...
what to make of it.
It's just letters.
I mix 'em up sometimes.
That's all.
I mean, I just get 'em
backward sometimes.
L- look here. Uh, my-my math
and-and spacial reasoning...
and my verbal scores
are all excellent.
But you barely passed
the written exam.
Yeah, but he did pass it.
So, is it my turn now?
- No, you'll wait your turn.
- Yes, ma'am.
Ma'am, I-I'm never gonna
be an English teacher.
But I know why I'm here.
To be a pilot.
And you don't dogfight
with manuals.
You don't fly with gauges.
I mean, it's all about
feeling and speed...
and lettin' that plane
become like a part...
of your body.
And that manual...
says that a guy who's a slow
reader can't be a good pilot.
That file says I'm
the best pilot in this room.
Ma'am, please,
don't take my wings.
Well, I felt so bad.
Evelyn, rotate to station three.
I had no choice.
I passed him.
- Good.
- Uh-huh.
So, then this
cocky pilot comes back.
- Say, fella, are you enlisted?
- Yeah.
"Yeah"? Boy,
you're talking to an officer.
Yes, sir. Sorry, sir.
- Give me that file.
- Yes, sir.
- Parade rest.
Ma'am, I didn't get
a chance to thank you.
Drop your skivvies.
Ah, oh, OK.
Just like this?
That's fine.
He did have
a very cute butt.
You know, I know
you didn't have to pass me...
and you did. And I just-
I didn't think
you'd understand, and you did.
You know, you still
haven't said thank you.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Why'd you do it?
I mean, I'm just curious.
You're like my hero now.
Actually, my father was a pilot.
And, um, I've seen
first-hand what happens...
when a pilot loses his wings.
You know what?
Your father's my hero,
then, too.
Infact, as an officer,
I think it'd by my duty...
to take my new hero's
daughter out tonight...
Just to-aah!
Gosh, did I poke too deep?
I think you hit the bone there.
You are so mean.
What? So is-
is there any chance...
that you might,
kind of, sort of...
you know, like me, or...
Oh, how did you guess?
They never taught us...
how to deal with this...
feeling.
Wh-what feeling?
Well, it's kind of like... this.
Ow!
Well, he was getting fresh,
so I poked him again.
All right, Romeo.
I want to get this over with.
Hold on a second.
Miss...
I really, really lick you.
What did he mean?
Like you.
I didn't mean to say that.
And I just, um...
I just want to ask you, please,
if I can donate dinner.
He started
to act very strange.
Or, well, buy you dinner.
This isn't your chart.
Whoa.
No. That's the, uh, this,
uh, fellow over here's.
I think he left.
Have you already had this shot?
Yeah, well, once... already.
Well, I wanted-
I mean, can I ask you out?
No!
And he just went wham!
Unh!
Oh! What'd you do to him?
Poor guy.
Hey!
Oh, my God.
Are you OK?
Uh, yeah.
I'm fine. I feel great.
This is just standard
precautionary... thing.
Look, I got some, uh,
genuine French champagne...
from France.
I thought, you know,
maybe we could celebrate.
Celebrate what?
Oh, I don't know. Uh, well,
you being my hero, for one.
OK. Why not?
So, uh, ahem...
I wanted to thank you.
And I just wanted to, uh...
put your mind at ease
about passing me...
because I really do think
you did this country a service.
I mean, I'm-
I am a great flier.
And if you have a fault,
which you obviously don't...
it's modesty.
No. If I have a fault,
it's candor.
You are just so-
Uhh. Cork just got away from me.
God, oh, it hurts.
It hurts something fierce.
I'm sorry.
- Ohh...
- Oh, it's bleeding.
- God.
- Oh!
- Ohh!
- Lay still.
I ruined everything.
- Oh, it hurts.
- Ow! It's cold.
- It'll stop the bleeding.
Yeah. I can't breathe.
Lay still.
You are so beautiful it hurts.
It's your nose that hurts.
No. I think it's my heart.
And then I kissed him.
Oh, Evelyn.
That's the most romantic story
I ever heard.
It's been the most romantic four
weeks and two days of my life.
Oh, I'm so jealous.
Hello, Lieutenant.
- It's good to see you.
- You, too, Lieutenant.
Pick a hand.
It's beautiful.
What's in your other hand?
Mine.
Well, it took me six hours
to fold these.
Oh!
I want you to meet my friends.
Rafe, this is Martha,
Barbara, Sandra-
- Hi. I'm Betty.
- Hi.
Would you happen
to have any friends?
Huh. Take your pick.
Hi.
Whoo!
We ever get in this war
and somethin' happens to me...
I can't tell you how good
it makes me feel to know...
that someone as sweet
as you will be there...
to nurse me back to health.
Good, but we're not
in the war yet.
- Ahem.
- OK. That was a bad line.
Hi.
I'm-I'm Red.
Red-
S- s-s-s-strange.
Heh heh.
Your last name's Strange?
Yeah. She's all yours, soldier.
No. It-it's Winkle.
Red is such a ladies' man.
Do you always stutter?
No. Only when I'm-
She's totally buying it.
- Nervous?
- Yeah.
Why can't I get
something like that?
Hello.
Hi.
Danny seems kind of shy
around the girls.
Tsk. It's not that he's shy.
He's just, ahem...
a little unsure of himself,
you know.
His old man used to
run him down a lot.
Get him in a plane,
he's sure of himself.
He's like my brother.
He's like my best friend.
He's my right hand.
Which at the moment is
a long way south of my waist.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I guess I lost
a little altitude.
Yeah, I guess you did.
Excuse me.
You and me, we got to talk.
So, the rumor is the Navy's
shipping us to Pearl Harbor.
Well, won't be so bad.
It's about as far from
the fighting as you can get.
You'll get a sun tan.
So maybe the Army'll
post you guys there, too.
You... are a super special woman.
And, and, well...
Well, they're-
they're training me...
to be a big bad warrior,
and, well...
So, I mean, you never know
what might happen tomorrow...
or... or any day
after that, you know?
So...
God, we need to make
tonight super special.
Why are you crying?
I guess it's the thought...
that I might not ever
get to see you again.
Dry your eyes, toots.
Tonight, you're mine.
I don't want to be
with a crowd tonight.
I just want to be
alone with you.
Well...
How does New York Harbor
by moonlight sound?
Ohh! Heh heh!
Are you gonna be
a bad influence?
Of course I'm a bad influence.
Let's see if we can
commandeer this vessel...
'cause we're, uh, officers
of the U.S. Government.
Not for long, we won't be.
One day, we'll take a trip
on a boat like that.
Would you like that?
We'll be dressing for cocktails
and walk into the grandsalon.
No one's talking about war.
They're just dancing
to Cole Porter.
- I'll have to get a tux.
- Yeah.
Come on. There you go.
All aboard.
- You're out of your mind.
- Oh, yeah.
Careful now.
Here, sit down.
Now let's see here.
Ah! There we go.
See, this is as close as I
could get you to your ship.
So, at least I tried, right?
Actually, you know what?
This is better.
Yeah, it is.
God, you're pretty.
What's gonna become
of us all, Rafe?
Well, the future's not
exactly in our hands, is it?
No. I guess you're right.
- Aah!
Oh, my God!
Are you all right?
Yeah, are you?
That was not part of the date.
Watch your step.
Oh, thank you.
Evelyn!
Guys, come up! Come on up!
Come up! We're in 321.
There's something
I got to tell you.
Well, you got no secrets
from me, Lieutenant.
I've seen your medical chart.
Here we go.
This can't be good, or it
wouldn't be so hard to say.
Yep.
I got to go away.
We're all going away.
Yeah...
but I'm going to the war...
tomorrow.
I'm flying with
the Eagle Squadron.
It's an outfit the British
started for American pilots.
I don't understand.
You're in the U.S. Army.
How could they order you to go?
They didn't order me.
I volunteered.
Huh.
But I passed you.
I let you through.
And now you volunteer...
for the most dangerous place
you could go?
It's not your responsibility,
not your choice.
Flying's the only thing
I ever wanted to do.
I mean, everything in my life
has led me up to this point.
Meeting you.
I love you.
I love you so much.
Let's go inside.
All right. Wait a minute.
Wait a minute.
Just-I-I can't do this.
This just-it's not right.
I'm sorry. I just-
See, I can't do this.
I mean, I mean, I can.
I- I want to.
I'm not trying to be noble,
you know.
Or not saying
I know what would happen...
or just-
I need to stop talking.
I just-I just don't want-
I just don't want it
to be like everybody else.
I don't want you to have
anything about tonight...
that you regret.
I mean, it's been the most
incredible night of my life...
and I don't want to ruin that.
Oh, you couldn't ruin it.
If I had one more night to live,
I'd want to spend it with you.
See, that's what I want
to come home to.
That's what I want to have
to think about and dream about.
I want to know that
the best part of my life...
is still ahead of me.
Look.
Don't, um... could you...
not come see me off?
Because, uh... saying good-bye
to you once is hard enough.
Here.
Take this.
Why?
You think it looks good on me?
I will come back.
I thought you said
you told her not to come.
Yeah, I did.
Why you looking for her then?
It's my test.
If I tell her not to come,
and she comes anyway...
then I-I know she loves me.
All aboard! Track 57!
If, uh, anything
happens to me...
I want you to be the one
to tell her.
All right?
You just make sure and come back
for the both of us, all right?
OK.
See you when I get back.
Yeah.
Good hunting, Rafe.
Evelyn!
Evelyn.
Hey!
She loves me.
The German Luftwaffe...
relentlessly bombards
downtown London...
while Churchill's
Royal Air Force...
is in a deadly struggle...
to maintain control
of the British skies.
This is a real mess.
Lieutenant McCawley
reporting for duty, sir.
Good.
We'll get you settled
into your quarters.
And then introduce you
to the crate you'll be flying.
If y'all are patching up
bullet holes here...
maybe we ought
to skip housekeeping...
and get me in an airplane.
Two didn't come back, sir.
We counted only eleven.
Are all Yanks
as anxious as you...
to get themselves killed,
Pilot Officer?
Not anxious to die, sir.
Just anxious to matter.
This is yours.
Good chap.
Didn't die till he'd landed
and shut down his engine.
Please be seated, gentlemen.
I'm afraid I'm in a bad mood.
Churchill and Stalin are
asking me what I'm asking you.
How long is America
going to pretend...
the world is not at war?
We've increased food and oil
shipments, Mr. President...
and as far as I know-
What they really need
are tanks, planes...
bullets, bombs,
and men to fight.
But our people think
Hitler and his Nazi thugs...
are Europe's problem.
We have to do more.
Send the Brits and Russians
more of our ships...
and anti-aircraft weapons.
And keep cannibalizing
the Pacific Fleet?
What choice do we have?
We're building refrigerators
while our enemies build bombs.
This is so exciting.
You know there's about
one hundred ships on Pearl.
How many sailors per ship?
It depends.
More on a battleship than a sub.
But say, on average... 2,000?
Then there's the flyers,
the marines, base personnel.
I'm still working on
the sailors.
Girls, I think the odds
are in your favor.
Yeah, like 4,000 to one.
It's paradise.
See you on the beach, boys!
We're in Hawaii!
Hey!
You're not supposed
to paint titties...
on the side of my airplanes.
And if you do,
don't make 'em lopsided.
They were lopsided, Earl.
Look, it says right here.
"Never ride waves amongst
rocks or submerged pilings. "
See, it says
you shouldn't do that.
How do you know they're
submerged if they're submerged?
Gooz, what in the hell
are you doing?
Just trying to fix
this surfboard thing.
He keeps taking chunks off
his nose on the rocks.
On my day off, I'm working
on my new invention-
the Gooz Cruise Fin.
I'm gonna be a rich fella.
Every surfboard in
the nation's gonna need one.
Yeah? Well,
you're gonna need a broom.
Check out these new recruits.
Hi.
Aloha.
Y'all pilots?
We're working on it.
It's a lot of switches
and stuff.
Pride of the Pacific.
Who are you?
Terrors of the skies.
Welcome, ladies.
Hi.
I have to deal with
toasty sun burnt fanny...
before I can show you around.
Ow!
Dear Evelyn.
It's different than I thought
it would be here.
It's cold-
so cold it goes deep
into your bones.
There is one place
I can go to find warmth.
That is to think of you.
I just wish I could be
back there with you.
It's not easy making friends.
Two days ago, I had a beer...
with a couple
of the RAF pilots.
Yesterday,
both of them got killed.
Dear Rafe.
I miss you so much.
It's so strange to be
half a world away from you.
I'm right on his tail!
Got one!
Every night
I look at the sunset...
and try to draw the last ounce
of heat from its long day...
and send it
from my heart to yours.
Family?
Girl, sir.
The girl.
A lot of people
frown on the Yanks...
for not being in this war yet.
I'd just like to say...
if there are many more
back home like you...
God help anyone who goes
to war with America.
Atten-hut!
Attention on deck!
Admiral Kimmel...
Commander-in-Chief,
Pacific Fleet, on deck.
Sharp presentation, Captain.
Thank you, Admiral Kimmel.
For four months now Washington's
been blowing pink smoke...
about the threat from Japan.
Could make us lose
our fighting edge.
I'm determined
not to let that happen.
With your permission, Captain.
Admiral, urgent,
from Washington.
I'm supposed
to keep this fleet...
battle-ready
to take on the Japanese...
cover half the damn globe.
Now they want me to transfer...
another twelve destroyers
to the Atlantic.
Don't they know what
we're facing out here?
They feel Europe
is the greater danger.
I'm assuming these risk
assessments include Hawaii?
Pearl Harbor is too shallow
for an aerial torpedo attack.
We're surrounded by sub nets.
All we need worry
about is sabotage...
so we bunched
our planes together...
to make them easier to protect.
Distance is our ally, Admiral.
You analysts got it
all figured out, don't you?
The smart enemy hits you...
exactly where
you think you're safe.
Incoming!
I fixed the hydraulics
and electrics, sir...
but the oil hoses
still need attention.
Just crank it, Ian!
God speed you, sir.
Red section, take the bombers.
Blue section,
look out for the fighters.
Bombers dead ahead.
Let's drop in
and give 'em a reception.
Red Two, follow my lead,
high side.
Go right at the lead bomber.
Following you, Red One.
Good hit! Good hit!
Red One, coming around,
reset for the kill.
I have the middle bomber.
Hammer down!
We got him.
Nice shot, Red Two.
I got two M.E.s dead ahead.
I'm on him.
I'm on his tail.
Hammer down.
I got one of them!
I got another one.
Red One, you got fighters
all over your tail!
I'm under fire!
I'm taking fire!
Red One, get out of there.
Pull up! Pull up!
Argh! I got an oil leak.
Can't see a damn thing!
I can't bail!
My canopy's stuck!
I can't bail out!
He's on my tail, Red Two.
I'm hit! I'm hit!
Mayday! Mayday!
Oh, my God.
I'm no good at church.
What do you mean, sweetie?
When I'm up there getting
my slate wiped clean...
I'm thinking how
to dirty it up again.
Wow, this from a virgin!
I got to inventory supplies.
Kill me now.
Could you be any more boring?
Don't bother.
Sunday, she writes Rafe...
ten pages instead
of the usual five.
Gosh, I wish I was in love.
Hey, sweetheart.
She hates me.
Good to see you, Red.
Good to see you, too, Betty.
You wanna come for a ride?
Come on.
Yeah, I'll be your chauffeur.
That-a-boy! Be a mad dog!
You hit pretty hard...
for a cook.
All right, Walker,
who you got?
I'll take the cook.
Why? You don't like money?
Come on! Get out there now!
- I'll put five on it.
- Done.
Against a mechanic?
That guy craps rivets.
How's it feel up
from the engine room?
Sunlight botherin' you?
Ow.
Man, he's getting all busted up!
Move! Move!
Come here, we gotta talk.
Get down here.
He can't hurt us.
He can hurt us.
- He cut us. We bleeding.
- Bleeding?
That's a scratch. See this?
This is the hard-earned
greenbacks...
of every pot-scrubbin'
chop in this fleet.
Now if we don't win...
Teeny here has to find
another battleship!
I'm not going back
to the Arizona empty-handed.
Don't worry about the money.
I'll send that
smug engine-fixin' snipe...
back below decks where he belong.
We the man!
He slapped your mama!
Be a son of a bitch!
Look at this!
All right, Dorie!
That's enough. That's enough.
- Oh! Where's my money?
- Nah, fight's rigged.
We're rich! Ha ha ha!
How'd you get this?
Boxing.
Did you win?
Yes, ma'am.
What do you get for winning?
Respect.
So, why do you have to fight
with your fists to get respect?
I left my momma in Texas...
and joined the Navy
to see the world...
become a man.
They made me a cook.
Not even that.
I clean up after
other sailors eat.
Two years, they never even
let me fire a weapon.
Well, let's hope
you never have to.
Yes, ma'am.
You take care,
Petty Officer Miller.
You, too, ma'am.
You know,
he taught me to fly.
I always knew that no matter
what trouble I got into...
I'd never be in it alone.
He'd be there with me.
He was always pushing me
to be better and faster.
He told me
you were a great flier.
It was the same night
he told me...
he'd volunteered
to go to England.
Volunteered?
He... he told me
he'd been assigned.
He was always
trying to protect me.
But you know what?
I look at myself in
the mirror in this uniform...
and I still
don't know who I am.
I look like a hero...
but I don't feel like it.
Rafe...
he always looked the part,
didn't he?
He couldn't wait to be one.
To Rafe McCawley.
The best pilot...
and the best friend
I ever knew...
or ever will know.
To Rafe.
THUR Look at this.
The Japanese...
are flooding the Pacific
with radio traffic.
Everywhere from the Panama Canal
to southeast Asia.
There's no logical pattern,
Captain.
No. There's always logic.
They know we read their mail.
They're trying to make us think
their fleet is moving south.
I'm not buying it.
Something, something's up.
Otherwise, why would they take
the trouble to bullshit me?
Evelyn, I signed for
these letters for you today.
They're from England.
They're from Rafe.
I'm sorry, Ev.
You know how long
it takes mail to get here.
Hurry up!
Show time, boys! Come on!
America still
awaits Japan's response...
to peace proposals.
Ambassador Nomura
arrives in Washington...
in what could
hopefully guarantee...
continued peace in the Pacific.
On the British front,
Churchill declares...
"Give us the tools,
and we will finish the job. "
The RAF has fought
bravely against...
Hitler's ambition to rule
the skies over the Channel.
Victory does not come
without sacrifice.
Evelyn!
- Danny.
- Hey.
Some comedy, huh?
Yeah.
It's been a while.
I've been logging
a lot of flight hours.
I kinda been avoiding you, too.
Yeah.
- Look-
- Do you-
Do you want to?
Sure, yeah.
I remember
one time when I was...
like, seven years old...
I was always building
gadgets and things.
He wanted me
to build him some wings...
so he could fly like his daddy.
I told him you can't fly
without some kind of engine.
But he wouldn't listen.
"Danny, never mind that,
just build 'em anyway. "
So I did.
And I'm up there...
strapping these big ol' wings
on his back...
that we made
from paper and glue...
and these massive silk bloomers
that we stole.
He looked so stupid,
and I told him...
"You can't jump off the barn
in these. "
And bam!
He busted his leg on a backhoe.
God, I miss him.
Yeah. But don't you think...
that Rafe wasn't
back up there next day.
Cast and everything...
telling me to make some
adjustments on those wings.
Check this out!
Crossroads of the Pacific.
Tahiti-1,700 miles!
All right!
Say, Betty...
W- wou...
- No, Betty! Get up!
- What's going on, Red?
- Stand up, please.
- What do you mean?
Just stand up.
Stand...
Oh! Ha!
Betty...
Red, come on!
We got a dinner reservation.
Can I get a minute?
What's the matter, you sick?
Can a guy propose?!
Oh! Thank you!
Am I talking too much?
Sometimes I do that, I'm sorry.
Hold up!
Look at this.
Hello!
OK, let's get out of here.
OK.
I guess I should go.
Don't let it be three months
before I see you again.
I had a good time.
Yeah, me, too.
Do you want me
to walk you home?
No, I'll be fine.
No... of course.
- Good night.
I was just wondering if maybe
I could come by some time...
get a cup of coffee
or a piece of pie?
What am I doing?
OK.
Oh! You were asleep. I'm sorry.
Danny?
Is something wrong?
No! Nothing's wrong.
No problem. Hi!
It's just Danny.
I... just... you...
you forgot this.
Oh... thanks.
It was good of you
to take the trouble...
to drop it over... now.
I... well, I thought
you might need it.
You know...
maybe tomorrow morning.
If...
not that you wear this
to work, but...
No... it's a hankie.
Right, right. Yeah.
Listen, I was thinking maybe...
I could come by some time...
if I gave you a call,
could I come by?
Once, maybe...
if you're not busy?
Yeah, maybe.
- Maybe?
- Maybe.
OK, all right.
Thanks.
Good-bye. Good night.
You are such an idiot!
Did you have fun last night?
It wasn't how it looked.
And if it was,
it'd be all right.
It's been months.
It's time to move on.
I am moving on.
Ev, don't lie.
All I know is, I hear you crying
when you think I'm asleep.
When my dad left...
I was too much
for my mom to handle...
so she sent me
to live with my aunt.
I thought my life was over...
But you don't know
where it's all gonna lead.
If I hadn't run away
and lied about my age...
and enlisted in the Navy...
I wouldn't have met Red, and...
now he's my fiance.
Oh, God, I can't
get used to that word.
- It's only been twelve hours.
- Oh, Betty!
Little Betty
beat us all to the post.
And this is ward three.
As you can see, no patients.
Welcome to Hawaii.
Come on, I'll show you the bar.
Sandra, new recruits to torture.
Come on. Excuse me, ladies?
Hi!
We're gonna wait two years
until I'm nineteen...
and Red can buy me a ring.
Rafe sent his best friend
to tell you...
so you would be OK,
so you can move on.
You gotta go on living, Ev.
Red!
Whoo! Sorry!
Bye, Rafe.
The Japanese Fleet is missing.
They're operating
under radio silence.
This footage was shot
four days ago on October 28th.
We're sending
scout planes in wider vectors...
all over the Pacific,
but they get nothing.
They could be anywhere in here.
I don't understand how
two whole carrier divisions...
can just disappear.
Clear!
Aw, we're all over the page.
We got one wall-eyed
and one pigeon-toed.
Anthony, tap in number six.
All right.
Gooz, tap in number three.
Hey. We got a visitor.
Oh... that ain't
no Navy issue uniform, eh?
Danny, it's Evelyn.
Jesus!
You alright?
Yeah. Yeah.
No.
I think I'm fallin' for her.
Wow. You know,
I saw this coming.
I didn't want this to happen.
It just kind of did.
Can't help it.
Well, Danny,
she's gotta be with somebody.
It might as well be you.
You telling me
if you were dead...
and you saw your best buddy
doin' your girl...
you wouldn't come back and beat
the living crap outta him?
- Tony, back off.
- I'd be back so fast.
Danny's being a better friend
taking care of her himself.
I got a girlfriend.
That's great.
Come on, fellas.
Let's split.
Danny, whatever happens now
is just about you and her.
You gotta try
and forget about Rafe.
Be careful, alright?
Ladies... cloud the mind.
- Thanks, Gooz.
- You're welcome.
Hey, Danny.
Where's everybody going?
Just bein' discreet.
Does it seem like everybody's
acting a little strange?
No. Nah.
Right.
Well, maybe-maybe a little.
Yeah.
Well, people in this outfit...
have way too much time
on their hands.
Oh, yeah.
I just hope they don't think
there's been something...
goin' on between us,
that's all.
Oh, no. I mean, no.
That would be...
embarrassing, right?
Forgot my wrenches.
That would definitely
be embarrassing.
Yeah.
Ha. Forgot my wrenches.
Hey. He really
doesn't have to leave.
No.
I, uh, I'm just goin'
out with the girls, so...
I guess I'll see you later.
- Yeah.
- All right.
Yeah, all right.
I'll see you around.
Shit.
Evelyn.
Have you ever seen
Pearl Harbor at sunset?
Of course.
Well... from the air?
You know, I could get kicked
out of the military for this.
- Really?
- Yeah. Stay down.
The Hawaiians called
this harbor Wai Momi.
It means "water of pearls. "
It's so beautiful.
My dad took me up
a couple of times.
Just don't do what he did.
What do you call it
when you flip over?
A barrelroll?
Yeah.
I won't.
Aah!
- Oh!
- Ha ha ha ha!
- Oh, God.
- What do you think?
I like that.
Hey!
That plane was supposed
to be back here an hour ago!
Quick, hide
in the parachute hangar.
My heart is pounding.
Danny, last night...
No, that's terrible.
Danny, we need
to talk about this.
Sir. Evelyn!
- Danny.
- Hey. Hi.
Hi.
I didn't sleep a wink
last night.
I had to see you.
Last night was crazy,
I know, but...
I'm not sorry. Are you?
I don't know.
Danny, I had a wonderful
time last night. I-
It's just all too fast.
Listen, Evelyn, I was just down
at the beach this morning...
and I watched the sun rise...
and I knew that everything
was gonna be different.
That this was the start
of something new.
In this place, in this moment.
And I don't care what
anybody else says, you know?
How can I not feel this way?
I kinda like you.
Oh, you do?
You have your tie on crooked.
Everything's
gonna be all right, OK?
gonna be all right.
Do you have any airtours going
through the valley of Oahu?
You do?
Aloha.
This is KGMB in Honolulu...
on another beautiful
fall day here in paradise.
We have enough information.
We are returning home.
Do you ever wonder...
if this war's
gonna catch up with us?
Nota whole lot.
Every moment we're not together,
you're up there training for it.
Yeah, well, I'm training
for moments like these...
'cause I have no idea...
how I'm gonna get this car
out of the sand.
Evelyn, can you please
come out of the bathroom?
You've been there for an hour.
Evelyn! What are you
trying to do, look like me?
Are you OK?
Yeah.
What's the matter?
No, you-
D'oy.
They call it the vacant sea.
None of the major sea lanes
go through it...
and you can bury the entire
land mass of Asia there...
and nobody would know.
From there,
they could attack anywhere.
Our last signals intercept...
indicate that the Japanese
taskforce is heading south...
towards the Philippines
or southeast Asia.
But Captain Thurman
of Naval intelligence here...
has his own theory
about the missing ships.
Sir, I believe
they'll try to hit us...
where it'll hurt us the most-
Pearl Harbor.
It's over 4,000 nautical miles
from Japan to Pearl.
That's a long distance
to steam a navy, Captain.
Your theory is based on what?
Well, it's what I would do.
That's not exactly
hard evidence, Captain Thurman.
Well, Admiral,
if I had hard evidence...
we'd already be at war.
Sir, we can read
their diplomatic codes...
faster than they can type them.
But Captain Thurman's
cryptology team...
is still trying
to crack the naval codes.
The intercepts have missing
words and garbled lines...
so to explain the decrypts,
we have to try to interpret...
what we think
they're trying to do.
Interpret?
You mean guess.
They use
their informed intuition, sir.
We guess.
It's like playing chess
in the dark.
Any rumor, troop movement,
ship movement...
spine-tingle, goose bump,
we pay attention to it.
When I was in
the Asiatic Fleet...
the locals used to try
to get outside of a problem...
to try to see the inside.
Well, I see a strike on Pearl.
It's the worst thing
that could happen.
A blow to Pearl
would devastate...
the Pacific Fleet's
ability to make war.
So, sir, you would have us
mobilize the entire fleet...
at the cost
of millions of dollars...
based on this spine-tingling
feeling of yours?
No, sir. My job is to gather
and interpret material.
Making difficult decisions...
based on
incomplete information...
from my limited
decoding ability...
is your job, sir.
Then break the damn naval code,
Captain...
so I can make a better decision.
Aye, sir. We are trying.
I wonder if we shouldn't put
the Pacific Fleet on full alert.
In case the optimism...
of the "Honolulu Advertiser"
proves unfounded, gentlemen...
what are General Short
and the Army...
going to do
about protecting my ships?
Within a ten-mile radius
of your harbor...
we have fighterplanes
here at Wheeler...
bombers at Hickam, and
a trainingstrip at Haleiwa.
We've recently established
a radar station here...
that can detect planes
125 miles out.
Which is a month old, Admiral,
and untested.
I've seen
these new radar screens, Major.
There's no way of telling
whether they're ours, theirs...
or a flock of damn birds.
I'm intercepting
a call from Tokyo...
to somewhere close by Pearl.
There's a call from Tokyo.
They say they don't know you.
Hello? Hai.
It's a local dentist.
He can see Pearl Harbor
from his office.
Are there many sailors around?
Uh, the dentist
says that the flatships...
are not in port.
They're talking about
the weather.
He doesn't seem to know
who he's talking to.
Hello?
Hello? Moshi moshi.
That was a strange call.
Admiral,
may I speak to you in private?
Why would a spy use a phone?
They know we tap
all international lines.
Our listeners feel
it's probably not code talk.
It sounds like someone in Japan
is sneaking around...
asking a local citizen
the location of our carriers.
Well, that makes me feel
all warm inside.
Get the FBI on it immediately.
Have we found
the goddamn Japanese Fleet yet?
No, Admiral. The bases are
looking all over the Pacific.
So the entire fleet could be
rounding Diamond Head...
and we wouldn't know
a thing about it.
Get on it.
I'm alive.
This is the first
I could get word out.
Jepense qu'il est mort!
ll estencore en vie.
I told you I'd come back.
Here, sit down.
Sit down. Come here.
It's OK.
It's all right.
You're real.
Yeah.
I wished for this every day.
I know. Me, too.
Every second. So did I.
I thought you were dead.
They said you were shot down
in the sea.
Yeah, I was.
I was in the ocean.
It was so cold.
I missed you.
I got picked up
by a French fishing boat...
and I was in occupied France,
and I couldn't get word out.
And I'm just-I'll tell you
all about it, I promise.
But I'm fine. I'm OK.
And I'm here now.
Evelyn...
I just wanted to see you.
You're so beautiful.
I love you.
Hey, it's OK. It's OK.
Evelyn, Evelyn. I'm back.
It's OK. I won't leave you
again, I promise.
Rafe, you died.
And so did I.
I know, but I'm-I'm-
It's fine now. I'm back.
We're together.
I mean, we are together...
right?
I don't know where I am.
Rafe.
Stay away.
This is Radio Honolulu...
playing the sweetest music...
on the sweetest island
in the Pacific.
It's a beautiful
December 6th...
with beautiful music...
Raaaaafe!
Oh, Goddamnit.
There you go.
A real live ace!
Whoo!
An ace is only five.
I shot down six M.E.s.
And I got two smokers, too.
They don't count them.
Of course, I got shot down
myself before they could pin me.
So you got back
from behind enemy lines, huh?
What's that combat like?
Were you scared?
Hey! One at a time.
Well, them Luftwaffe boys
can fly pretty good.
It's not like,
you know, training.
They're, uh...
Danny.
You know, they're all about
tactics is what it is.
See, the Nazis, right,
they're faster than you are...
so they'll disappear and
they get up in the soup...
and they'll throw like
a roll or a hammerhead...
and they'll come around
on your high side...
shoot you from behind-
like some Americans will.
Hey...
Gooz, you're lookin'
at a real live ace.
Well, let me give you
the shirt off my back!
Whoo!
Aloha! There you go!
I'll take it from you.
I can see how y'all been
spending your time out here.
Hey, Rafe,
we gotta talk, all right?
I got nothin' to talk
about with you. Here.
Why don't you have a drink?
I'll make a toast.
To returning from the dead.
Wasn't all I expected,
but, well, that's life.
To my best friend
and loyal buddy Danny...
for keepin' up the war effort
back here at home.
Ahh.
You know, where I come from...
somebody makes a toast to you
and you don't drink...
that's sayin' something.
All right, Rafe.
That's how it's gonna be.
To you.
Hey, you guys need to spend
some time alone, I think.
Aw, hell, no, Red.
Come on.
No, no, no.
We're celebratin' here.
Me over there fightin'...
almost gettin' killed...
my friend Danny back here...
lookin' after my interests
for me.
Y'all know Danny
was even good enough...
to look out for my girl for me
while I was gone?
We thought you were dead, Rafe.
And it gutted us both.
And we were just tryin'
to get on with our lives.
Life is good, ain't it, Danny?
You know, you're a rotten drunk.
You always have been.
Well, you're a lousy friend.
That's a new development.
You left her to fight
somebody else's war...
and you made damn sure
that I didn't go with you...
and we thought
that you were dead-
I almost did die,
you little son of a bitch!
And her face was the last thing
that went through my mind...
so don't stand there and tell
me to act like it's all right!
Yeah, Rafe, well, I stayed.
I stayed,
and you made sure of that...
and some things changed.
And I hope
you can get used to that.
Oh, I have to get used to it?
All right. We'll see
how I can get used to it.
- Whoa!
- Hey!
Get used to that, boy!
Hey, hey!
And that's my left hand, too!
Hey, hey, hey! Hey, come on!
Melee at the Hula-la.
Send M.P.s!
- Aah!
- You called me a lousy friend?
- Get your hands off!
Aah!
Ow! Shit!
Come on, Danny!
Let's go get 'em.
Let's move out!
Oh, no. They're gonna
throw us in the brig.
Let's get outta here.
Oh, shit.
Rafe...
you're the only family I got.
When you were gone...
it was the loneliest
I'd ever been.
The same for her, too.
Oh, boy, now you're really
breakin' my heart.
If you hadn't gone,
none of this woulda happened.
Oh, so it's my fault, I guess.
Damn it, Rafe.
I just know
there's got to be some way...
we can work things out
so that...
things could be right
between me and you.
I just don't see how
it could ever be the same.
Revered father...
I go now to fulfill my mission
and my destiny.
I hope it is a destiny...
that will bring honor
to our family...
and if it requires my life...
I will sacrifice it gladly...
to be a good servant
of our nation.
Hey...
we got a large haze.
That's too big
to be planes, right?
Is that what you wanna do?
Knight to knight five?
Boom! Wrong move.
Lieutenant,
radar's picking up...
a large return
moving in from the northeast.
Hang on.
Relax.
It's a flight of B-17s
coming in from the mainland.
Nothing to worry about.
A heck of a lot of B-17s.
Good shot, Hop.
This better be good, Commander.
One of our destroyers reports
having fired and sunk...
enemy submarine attempting
to enter Pearl Harbor at 0653.
It's 7:20!
We had decoder delays, Admiral.
Relay this to Washington.
Recall the staff.
"Failure...
"'Peace talks...
"useless. "
Thurman here.
Tokyo transmitting...
to their embassy
in Washington-
"Discontinue use
of your decoding machine...
"and dispose of immediately.
"Special emphasis
on destroying important parts. "
Do you read that?
Acknowledge.
Admiral...
Naval Intel intercepted
a transmission from Tokyo...
to the Japanese embassy
in Washington...
instructing them to break apart
all decoder machines...
and burn all secret documents.
The Japanese
are expecting a war.
Should we?
Warning of possible...
Japanese aggressive movement
in any direction.
"Broken relationship.
Hostilities imminent. "
But where?
Did you ever lose a fight,
Miller?
I been lucky so far, Captain.
From what I hear, it ain't luck.
Ship's proud of you, son.
Ha ha ha. Yeah! Ha ha!
Why the hell's the Navy...
doing practice this early
on a Sunday?
- Aah!
- Get down!
Go, go, go, go!
I'm with Navy newsreel,
and I can tell you one thing-
them ain't Navy planes!
All hands,
man your battle stations!
We're being bombed!
Get up! Get up!
Jesus Christ!
Man your battle stations.
Another dumb drill.
All hands,
man your battle stations.
- What the heck was that?
- It's a bomb!
Move, move, move!
Son of a bi-
From outside!
Get me the engine room!
My God.
Take cover!
Down! Down!
Report battle stations!
Manned and ready!
Man your battle stations!
This is no shit!
They just sunk the Arizona!
General quarters!
All hands,
man your battle stations!
This is no damn drill!
Go! Go!
They look like Japs.
I didn't even know
the Japs were sore at us!
Danny, you just get me
to a goddamn airplane!
Holy God!
This is good
footage. Did you see that?
Holy cow!
I hope
there's still an airfield left.
Hurry up!
What in the world?
Look! So many!
Everybody to the hospital!
Why's the Navy
always buzzin' us?
shut up, Red!
- Oh, man, come on.
- Red, it's too early.
The Japs are here!
What the hell?
Let's go! Let's go!
- Get corpsmen to the bridge.
- Aye, Captain!
Repair says third deck
is flooding port side!
Yaah! Uhh!
Get up!
Get up, you cowards!
Get up there and fight!
Move it!
Take cover!
I got you, Captain.
You radio for air cover!
Initiate damage control!
Find my X.O.
Tell him to assume command.
And you make sure the gunners-
Everyone's where
they need to be, Captain.
You trained us well.
Captain...
Aah!
Go, go, go, go!
Let's go! Let's go!
Everybody move!
Get the ammo
for that fifty cal!
Get that fifty cal!
Let's go! We gotta get-
Come on, man, we gotta
get this thing loaded up!
- Aah!
Let's go! Let's go!
Come on!
Danny,
get me into a damn plane!
Come on!
Get some ammo up here!
We need some men on these guns!
Sir! The captain says
you're in charge, sir!
We need more ammo! Now!
Send up ammunition
for the five-inch guns!
Medic!
All of 'em, now!
Aah!
Aah! Aah! Aah!
Come on!
Aah! Come on!
Come on, you sum 'bitch!
Aah!
Aah ha!
Oh, yeah!
I need a doctor!
Somebody help me!
Get to the supply room!
Get everything out!
- Aah!
- Planes incoming!
Cut 'em down!
Come on, come on!
Get 'em away from the windows!
The mattresses!
Get 'em against the wall!
Take cover!
Is everybody all right?
Can you stand? Can you stand?
Hold your fire!
Get to the gun! Hurry up!
Get down, Danny!
Aah!
- Earl!
- This is Walker!
We need to get those planes
fueled and loaded right now!
What's going on
out there? Huh?
Danny,
what the hell's that noise?
You guys doin' target practice
or something?
I think World War II
just started.
Go, go, go!
- Billy!
- Run!
- It's gonna blow!
- It's a dud.
It's a dud!
Come on, get down!
Danny!
Danny, are you all right?
I'm all right!
Come on, let's go!
Gooz, come on, man!
We're sinking! We're sinking!
Stay together!
Close the hatches!
- I can't swim!
- Just hang on!
Let's move it now!
Joe! Go! Go!
We're gettin' outta here!
Get in the car!
Get in! Get in!
Come on, let's go! Go!
Get out of the way!
Come on!
Where's this place we're goin'?
We got a small mechanic runway
about ten minutes away.
Hasn't been hit yet.
We got Zeros on our six!
Duck!
Help us!
Aah!
We're trapped.
Try it! Try the door!
Aah!
Oh, my God! I'm going under!
It's sucking me back!
The current's too strong!
They're shootin' at us!
I don't wanna die!
This is it.
Get us out of here now!
How bad?
It's still not over, sir.
An entire fleet at anchor.
My God, my God...
Barbara, fill every syringe
you can find with morphine!
Fill up the kitchen!
Are you listening to me?
Over there! Over there!
We got a bad neckwound here!
Surgery! Move!
Get him to surgery!
Oh, God.
In here!
He's still bleeding!
Another hemostat!
Hurry!
Give me a hemostat now!
Damn it, hurry!
Gimme another hemostat!
Another suture! Hurry!
Give me a-
Oh, God, I'm so sorry!
Doctor!
Here! Aah!
Am I gonna die?
Nurse!
Don't leave me!
Doctor! Get over here!
My fingers
are plugging his artery!
Doctor, what do you need?
Focus, look at me.
What do you need?
- Hemostat.
Here. All right, look at me.
You're going to be all right.
I need more ammo!
I need more ammo, ladies!
Earl! We good to go?
- Mostly, but-
- Get down!
- Shit! Get cover!
- Jesus!
- Come on, you guys!
- Earl, get in here!
Sergeant!
We need more than a shotgun!
You got any other weapons
for coverfire?
Inside that ammo locker!
- Come on!
- Move it!
- Go! Go!
- Get the guns out!
You said the planes
are mostly ready, but...
but what?
She's down, she's broke,
she's shit.
I got four left.
One's good, two need ammo,
one needs fuel.
Fall out
and load up in the bunker!
Let's go! Get down!
- Move!
- Get ready to roll this thing!
Get down! Now!
Anthony, Red, you stay here
and man the fifty-caliber.
Gooz, get to the next bunker
and lay down some coverfire.
Planes.
Should we fire?
Stay down! God damn it!
Hold your fire!
Stay still! Nobody fire!
Oh, God, oh, God, oh, God.
They don't know we're here.
- Stay down.
- Fire?
No, God damn it,
stay down, stay still.
Don't fire.
Oh, God.
I don't see any ordnance.
I think they're going home.
No. They'll be back. We still
got planes on the ground.
Pilots, listen up.
Get all the speed
you can on the runway...
don't get on the stick
till the very end.
In the air, stay low
between the buildings.
You see any Zero
on your tail...
wipe him off, don't freeze.
Just keep moving.
Try to separate 'em,
take 'em out one by one.
P-40s can't outrun Zeros,
so don't try.
We have to outfly 'em.
We got high-level bombers!
They'll bust this hangar
wide open!
Grab the fifties! Let's move!
Move! Move!
Go, go, go!
Zeros!
Take cover! Take cover!
Aah!
- Get down! Get down!
- Let's go! In the box!
Aah!
Danny!
Come on!
Come on, buddy!
Leave him, he's dead!
He's dead!
They're kicking our butt.
Get to the airplanes!
Go, go, go!
Run! Red, Anthony, let's go!
Come on, help me!
Goddamn belts!
Let's go! Come on!
Knock 'em dead.
Quick! Get in! Put this on!
They're coming around.
Bring 'em out! Let's go!
Red, get out of here,
God damn it! Go!
Come on, let's go.
Joe, get out the way!
I'm rollin'!
Clear! Go!
Oh, God. Planes!
Come on, help me!
Hey, Joe! You got three Zeros
behind you!
Turn! Turn!
Oh, God!
Aah!
Oh, shit.
What are you doing? Get going!
Danny, start that thing up
and get in the air.
I'm not much good without
a wing man. I need you!
I got you!
Let's do it!
It's real tight, Rafe!
Real tight!
Hey, Rafe, I'm not sure
we have enough runway!
Get your airspeed up
before you leave the dirt!
Don't freeze. Don't freeze.
I don't think
I'm gonna make it over!
Come on! Come on!
We did it! I'm up!
We got Zeros behind us!
How many you see back there?
We got five on our six!
Take it down to the deck, now!
We gotta split 'em up.
You take left, I'll take right.
Earl, get some guns
in that goddamn tower!
OK! Let's go! Into the truck!
Danny, I got three on my six.
Whoo!
Stop! Stop! Let's go!
Let's go! Move it!
Move it, Red!
- Let's go!
- Gimme the fifty!
Let's go! All right!
I still got
two behind me, Rafe.
Yaah!
Son of a bitch!
Whoa!
Earl, God damn it,
get some guns in that tower!
On the tower.
Going ten stories up.
It's a long son of a bitch.
Rafe, they're all over me!
I can't get them off me!
Danny,
I still got three on my tail!
Keep jinking it!
Don't let them get a handle!
I can't shake 'em!
God damn it.
Danny, let's play chicken
with these Jap suckers!
I'm with you.
Jesus!
- I'm coming right at you!
- Don't brake till I tell you.
Not yet! Not yet!
Come on!
Go left! Now!
- Whoo! We got 'em!
- Ha ha ha!
Set up over there!
Come on, load it!
We're on the tower.
I got one on my tail.
I'll bring him right by you.
He's comin' around!
Let's get this Jap sucker!
Hold your fire. Here he comes.
You better be cocked and locked
when I come by!
Hold your fire!
Fire!
Whoo! Good shootin', boys!
Nice shot, Earl!
Let's head over
to battleship row!
I'm with you!
Let's go do some business.
I'm going after 'em.
Rafe! I got him!
- P-40's!
- Yeah!
They're pulling
into the clouds!
We ain't gonna let these
sons of bitches get home!
How do you like someone
shooting back at you?
Oh, I'm on your ass now!
Yeah! I got one!
Come on!
God, come on!
Come on, stay in there!
Whoa!
I got you, you son of a bitch!
Who taught you how to fly,
Lieutenant?
He did.
I have to amputate here!
I have to amputate!
You're not gonna die!
I got you.
Hold onto this...
Sandra,
we're running out of morphine.
Find some way to mark 'em...
So we can keep track
of who's got morphine already.
Tell me about your ship.
What ship are you from?
It's not marking.
Have you got a marker?
Use my lipstick!
Put "M" for morphine.
- We need a tourniquet!
- Tourniquet!
Where are the clamps?
There's nothing left!
- Evelyn!
- Here, use this.
Go outside.
There's too many to help.
Sort them out.
Only those that can be saved
you bring in.
I can't...
No, please,
I need you to do it!
Go! Go!
Aah!
Don't look at anyone
without a mark!
I told you, stand back!
Keep 'em outside!
Come on! Let's go!
Wait here.
Don't touch me, you Jap!
Get your hands off me!
Get him into critical.
- Get him off me.
- Critical, frontward!
How bad am I?
You're gonna be just fine,
sweetheart.
- I don't wanna die.
- You're not gonna die.
I've got your hand.
Do you have enough morphine
to make him comfortable?
He won't make it.
Line the critical up!
Get him morphine.
Take him over there!
Burn victims by the tree!
I just found her!
I don't think she's breathing.
No, she's dead. Take her-
Oh, God.
Are you sure, Ev?
Check her again.
She's dead.
Take her over there!
But you've gotta be sure!
She's dead!
Go back to work, Sandra.
I don't know what to do!
Over here!
Admiral?
From Washington.
"Attack by Japan
considered imminent. "
They're only an hour late.
How can we help?
We need blood. Come on.
Remember, son,
hold on to your faith.
1,500 cartons over there.
"'Today you will be
with me in paradise...
"so fear not. "
Fear not, my son.
You are a man truly blessed.
You will die
in a state of grace.
Remember, pain is temporary,
but glory is forever.
Hold on to your faith, my son.
You'll be with God, the saints,
and the angels soon.
I absolve you of your sins...
in the name of the Father,
the Son, the Holy Spirit.
Innomine patris et fili,
et spiritus sancti.
Amen.
Go with God, my son.
We've got men trapped
everywhere in the harbor.
We need help
from anybody who can move.
There's somebody in here!
Get somebody down here!
They're cutting through!
I hear somebody!
Get some guys up here!
Pull!
Get us out!
It's filling with water!
Get an airline in here!
We need the air hose!
What can we do?
It won't cut any faster!
- Cut him out!
- Aah!
Yesterday...
December 7, 1941...
a date
which will live in infamy...
the United States of America...
was suddenly
and deliberately attacked...
by naval and air forces
of the empire of Japan.
It is obvious...
that planning the attack
began many weeks ago.
During the intervening time...
the Japanese government...
has deliberately sought to
deceive the United States...
by false statements...
and expressions of hope
for continued peace.
The attack yesterday
on the Hawaiian Islands...
has caused severe damage
to American military forces.
I regret to tell you...
that over 3,000 American lives
have been lost.
No matter how long
it may take us...
to overcome
this premeditated invasion...
the American people,
in their righteous might...
will win through
to absolute victory.
Because of this unprovoked,
dastardly attack by Japan...
I ask that the Congress
declare a state of war.
Is it true...
men are still trapped alive
inside the Arizona?
We can hear tapping
from inside the hull.
We're doing everything we can
to get to them...
but they're
forty feet below water.
We've been trained to think
that we're invincible.
And now our proudest ships
have been destroyed...
by an enemy
we considered inferior.
We're on the ropes, gentlemen.
That's exactly why
we have to strike back now.
We'll attack the Marshall
and Gilbert Islands, sir.
I mean hitting the heart of
Japan the way they have hit us.
Mr. President...
Pearl Harbor caught us unawares
because we didn't face facts.
This isn't a time
for ignoring them again.
We have long-range bombers,
but no place to launch them.
Midway is too far,
and Russia won't allow us...
to launch a raid from there.
Admiral?
Navy's planes are small.
They carry light loads
and have a short range.
We'd have to get them within
a few hundred miles of Japan.
We'd risk our carriers,
and if we lose them...
we'll have no shield
against invasion.
Does anyone in this room
think victory is possible...
without facing danger?
We are at war.
Of course there's a risk.
But consider the risk,
Mr. President.
If the Japanese
invade us right now...
they would reach Chicago
before we could stop them.
Gentlemen...
most of you did not know me
when I had the use of my legs.
I was strong and proud...
and arrogant.
Now I wonder,
every hour of my life...
why God put me into this chair.
But when I see defeat
in the eyes of my country men-
in your eyes, right now-
I start to think that
maybe he brought me down...
for times like these...
when we all need to be reminded
who we truly are-
that we will not
give up or give in.
Mr. President,
with all respect, sir...
what you're asking
can't be done.
- Mr. President!
- Get back, George!
Get back.
Do not tell me...
it can't be done.
Japan continues
its military conquest...
throughout the Pacific.
But, back home...
millions of American workers
band together...
bringing factories to life
to avenge Pearl Harbor.
Mr. President, we have an idea
how to bomb the Japanese.
Sir, it's risky...
but it's bold.
- Who are you?
- I, sir?
Captain Low, Mr. President.
He's a submariner.
He came up with this idea.
I like sub commanders.
They don't have time
for bullshit, and neither do I.
Fire away, gentlemen.
And where is God in all this?
Our enemies believe
a divine wind protects them.
But we see our friends
laid out here before us.
Hey, Captain.
Lieutenants Rafe McCawley,
Daniel Walker.
Yes, Major?
You're both going stateside.
Fly out in two hours.
What for, sir?
Ask Colonel Doolittle.
Yes, sir.
You're packing.
Orders.
What kind of orders?
The top-secret kind.
The dangerous kind.
I can't find Danny.
Is that why you're here?
Looking for Danny?
Probably saying good-bye
to his squadron.
We've been assigned
to Doolittle.
I wasn't looking for Danny.
I couldn't have you go away...
without you
understanding something.
Yeah. You don't have
to explain anything.
I do, because you're acting
like I didn't love you.
Evelyn,
loving you kept me alive.
I should've died over there.
When I was in that water,
I made a deal with God.
I told him I was sorry...
that I knew I'd been a fool
for leaving you...
trying to go over there
and be a hero...
and I promised I'd never ask
for anything again...
if I could just see you
one more time.
And you know what?
It was worth it.
You kept me alive, Evelyn.
You brought me home.
So I'm gonna stand by
my end of the deal.
I'm gonna walk away.
And I won't ask you
for anything.
But I just want to know why.
Just tell me that, will you,
please? Just tell me why.
Rafe, I'm pregnant.
Oh, my God.
I didn't even know until
the day you turned up alive.
And then all this happened.
I haven't told Danny.
I don't want him to know.
All he needs to think about...
is how to do this mission
and get back alive.
Rafe, all I ever wanted...
was for us to have a home,
grow old together...
but life never asked me
what I wanted.
Now, I'm gonna give Danny
my whole heart...
but I don't think I'll ever
look at another sunset...
without thinking of you.
I'll love you my whole life.
I'll see you on board.
You know, the only thing
that scares me...
is that you might love him
more than you love me.
I love you, Danny.
And I'll be here waiting
for you when you come back.
Follow me.
Colonel.
Congratulations
on your promotion, sir.
I heard what you did.
We can explain that, sir.
Explain what?
Whatever it is
you heard about us, sir.
You mean the hula shirts
you were flying in?
Or the seven planes
you shot down?
You're both being awarded
the Silver Star...
and promoted to captain.
Is that the good news,
sir, or...
You're just about
the only pilots in the Army...
with combat experience.
I need you for a mission...
I've been ordered
to put together.
You know what top secret is?
Yes, sir.
It's the kind of mission
where you get medals.
But they send 'em
to your relatives.
Top secret means
you train for something...
never done before
in aviation history...
and you go without knowing
where you're going.
You do it on that basis
or not at all.
I'll go, sir.
I'll go, too, sir.
By the way, the Brits sent
over your personal effects.
Thank you, sir.
There's only one more thing.
Leave your goddamn hula shirts
at home.
Dear Rafe...
It's so strange
to be this far from you...
but you should know this-
every night...
I've been looking
all over for you.
Danny, this...
this ain't no time
to leave things unsaid.
Now, we gotta face facts here.
The fact is, we just both love
the same woman.
She's the first girl I ever
felt this way about, Rafe.
I couldn't help what happened
any more than you could.
This is different,
though, Danny.
Evelyn already lost
the man she loved once.
I just don't want it to see
that happen to her again.
Guys like us got no choice.
This is war.
She knows that.
Danny, don't do this.
Don't go on this mission.
You got nothing to prove.
You've been protecting me
since we were kids.
Yeah, well...
you do tend to need it
from time to time.
The mission I'm asking you
to volunteer for...
is exceptionally dangerous.
Take a look at the man
beside you.
It's a good bet
that in the next six weeks...
you or he...
will be dead.
Everyone brave enough
to accept this...
step forward.
Your grandmother
could take a B-25 off...
on a mile-long runway.
Well, I'm gonna train you
to do it in 467 feet.
Because at 468 feet...
you're dead.
And once you get it up...
you'll learn to fly it
like a fighter...
thirty feet off the ground.
I want you to say hello...
to Lieutenant Jack Richards,
Navy Aviation.
He'll help us
lighten these fat ladies.
Dump that ash can.
See that bomb sight?
Get rid of it.
Colonel, he's crazy!
- The lady's fat!
- Listen to him.
She's fat.
We want a skinny lady!
Max power!
Get up, get up!
- Damn!
- How the heck-
Damn!
They just keep
rolling past that line.
Maybe it's a bad idea.
No, they're too heavy.
We gotta get drastic.
This armored plating goes.
I'm sure, I'm sure.
Lose it like a skirt, son.
Release brakes!
Come on, come on!
- God!
- Put every man on the line!
Let's show these boys
how this thing is done!
Come on! Max power.
Well, if he can do it...
Well, gentlemen,
now I can tell you...
that we're going to Tokyo.
And we're gonna bomb it.
That comes
as a special request...
directly from
President Roosevelt.
The Navy'll sneak us about
400 miles off the coast...
and we'll launch
from the carrier there.
Has that been done before?
Taking Army bombers
off Navy carriers?
- No.
- OK.
Any other questions?
Well, sir, is it even
possible to land...
a B-25
on an aircraft carrier deck?
That won't matter.
As soon as we're airborne,
the carrier heads for Hawaii.
But without them,
where do we land?
I have a phrase
I want you to memorize.
Wo shimeiguo ren.
It means "I am an American".
In Chinese.
Ain't gonna be any easier.
That's three feet shorter
than our practice runway.
- Fellas?
- Sir.
Sir.
Secretary of the Navy
gave me these.
What are they?
Friendship medals
the Japanese gave us...
when they were pretending
to want peace.
What'll you do with them?
Wire them to the bombs
and give them back.
So what's going on?
Well, sir,
we only have sixteen planes.
So?
When the Japs hit us,
they had more than 300.
How much difference
can we make?
It's not that we're afraid,
sir.
But we might die, and
we want to know what it's for.
You know, at Pearl,
they hit us with a sledgehammer.
This raid,
even if we make it through...
it'll only be a pin prick...
but it'll be straight
through their hearts.
Victory belongs to those
that believe in it the most...
and believe in it the longest.
We're gonna believe.
We're gonna make
America believe, too.
Colonel? I need a minute.
- Excuse me, Major Jackson?
- Yes?
Do you remember me?
Oh, sure I do.
I'm sorry.
I've been meaning to thank you.
Well, maybe you can.
When the news comes in
about the Doolittle boys...
I want to be
in the command post.
I'm sorry. I don't know
what you're talking about.
How the hell
do you know about this mission?
Let's call it
an inadvertent disclosure.
Some flyboy you're dating
shot his mouth off.
Actually,
it's about two pilots.
I know they're going
into great danger.
I just want to be there
when the news tells us...
if they've lived or died.
Most officers would have
thrown you in the brig.
Most nurses
wouldn't keep their fingers...
plugged in your artery.
I can't promise you anything.
Hey, Red,
you think they picked us...
to do this
'cause we're young and dumb?
Come on, Gooz,
we're the tip of the sword.
In honor of our trip to Japan...
I got us some victory cigars!
- Yeah!
- There you go.
Put that in your insidepocket,
next to your heart.
You know, Jack,
we may lose this battle...
but we're gonna win this war.
- You know how I know?
- No.
Them.
'Cause they're rare.
And at times like these,
you see them...
stepping forward.
There's nothing stronger than
the heart of a volunteer, Jack.
My friends
in the war department...
don't want me
to lead this raid...
because they say
I'm too valuable.
They don't want me
up in the air...
flying with the men
that I've chosen...
that I've chewed out, cussed
out, pushed to the limit...
and that I've come to respect.
They want me to stand
on the flight deck...
and wave you off.
Well, I don't see it that way.
So I'm going with you.
We take off
tomorrow afternoon...
drop our fire,
and head for China.
Our mission
is to hit military targets...
aircraft and tank factories.
Colonel, you've given us
homing beacons...
but you said China is
overrun with Japanese troops.
What if the beacons
are switched off?
Bring her down
any way you can...
and do your best
to avoid capture.
What if we have to bail out
over Japan?
Well, in that situation,
I can't tell you what to do.
What would you do, Colonel?
I wasn't built
to be a prisoner...
so I would have
my crew bail out.
I'd find the sweetest
military target I could...
and drive my plane right
smack into the middle of it...
But that's just me.
I'm forty-five years old.
I'm an old man.
You guys have your whole lives
ahead of you...
so what you do is up to you.
The mission will launch
in a couple of hours.
You'll stay right in here.
Here. Stay here.
Don't talk to them.
They won't talk to you.
Pretend to type
the information we pass you.
That's it.
This is Orphan Annie
from Radio Tokyo.
To all the lonely boys
in the South Pacific...
watch out-
the enemy will get you.
Maybe she's right.
Japs transmitting!
Captain, radar reports
Japanese patrol boats.
- Range 400 yards.
- How many yards?
400 yards and closing, sir.
Richards, Japs!
400 yards! Let's go!
Admiral Halsey's ordering
the cruisers to open fire!
We gotta sink these Jap boats
before they give us away.
Go to general quarters!
Go, go, go, go!
Oh, my God.
This can't be good!
All hands,
man your battle stations.
Japs one mile away.
They reported our position.
Supposed to launch
400 miles away. How far are we?
624 miles.
- Jesus!
- What do you want to do?
Colonel, I don't know
if the planes...
can carry enough fuel
to make it to China.
Now. We launch now!
Army pilots! Man your planes!
Man your planes!
They're shooting at something.
- Let's go!
- It ain't a drill!
Colonel!
We're too far out to make it!
They need more fuel,
but they can't get too heavy!
Strip everything out of
this plane you don't need now!
Start pre-flight! Let's go!
Add ten cans of fuel
for each plane!
Every plane!
Let's go! Move!
Guys, get up there!
Lose those suitcases now!
- What's your favorite gun?
- What?
You want off this deck,
give me a gun now!
It's still too heavy!
Go to the kitchen,
get some broomsticks.
Cut 'em down, paint 'em black,
and bring them here.
We'll put a broomstick
where this gun was.
What are you doing
to my plane?
Tell your crew to take a piss
before they take off.
We got broomsticks
for tail guns.
Yeah.
Maybe it'll scare 'em.
You take care of yourself
up there.
Yeah, I will.
Danny, be careful, you hear me?
I will.
I'll see you, Rafe.
Rafe!
We're the tip of the sword!
- Turning on one!
- Turning on two!
All right.
You ready for this?
- Superchargers low and latched!
- Low and latched.
We're full into the wind!
More speed! More speed!
Are you nervous?
No-yes, sir. Yes.
When did you find religion?
When you assigned me
to this mission, sir.
Do me a favor.
- What's that, Colonel?
- Pray for both of us.
Tell me when!
Let's go!
Max power!
Oh, please.
Come on! Come on!
Yeah!
Way to go!
Jesus, that was short.
Move 'em up!
Full power, here we go!
Pull back!
Ha ha ha!
Come on, here we go, here we go!
We made it!
From Berlin, Rome, and Tokyo...
we have been described...
as a nation of weaklings
and playboys...
who hire British,
Russian, or Chinese soldiers...
to do our fighting for us.
Let them repeat that now.
Let them tell that to
General MacArthur and his men.
Let them tell that
to the soldiers who today...
are fighting hard in
the far waters of the Pacific.
Let them tell that to the boys
in the flying fortresses.
Let them tell that
to the Marines.
That's Japan, fellas.
Tighten up back there!
Man your guns!
We're in the enemy's backyard!
Look alive back there.
I see coastline.
Heads up, boys! Heads up!
Man your guns back there.
I'm cocked and locked!
Get ready, suckers!
Approaching
targets for bombing raid!
Open bomb bay doors.
Ripley,
you gota target in sight?
37 degrees!
Target in sight!
All right, boys,
let's knock their clocks off!
- Drop your ordnance!
- Bombs away!
One away!
Two away!
Three away!
Four away!
We caught 'em by surprise!
- Dropping ordnance!
- Bombs away!
...factory.
- Whoo!
- We got it!
We hit our targets!
Good job, raiders!
God! Jesus-what? Shit!
We got flak everywhere!
Go down there and get Gooz!
I want everyone to separate!
- Clean that up!
- Yes, sir.
Try and clean that up!
They're shooting flak at us!
We gotta get out of this shit,
Gooz!
- We got a fire!
- Tail's hit!
The electrics!
We got a fire back here!
I gotta short this out!
Get into the clouds,
Danny, right now!
God damn!
Red, go check that out!
We're getting covered!
Just hope they don't hit a prop!
Unh!
I'm hit!
They're tearing
this plane apart!
Red, take it up, 800 feet.
Aah!
I think Theo's dead!
Theo, wake up!
Theo!
Get into the clouds,
Danny, right now!
Get up in that soup!
We're gonna pull out of this,
Gooz!
Thank you, George.
What is it, General?
Colonel Doolittle had to
advance his execution order...
by twelve hours, Mr. President.
There will be no homing beacons.
The plane carrying them
crashed en route to China...
and our bombers
may lack the fuel...
to reach the mainland, sir.
So our boys are flying blind
on empty tanks.
God help them.
We're still not
getting a signal.
All ocean and no land.
Homing in on nothing.
How many cans of fuel
we got left?
These are all empty!
Is this all you got?
That's all we got, Red.
Rafe! You better pray for land!
Break radio silence.
I'm sorry, gentlemen.
You're all brave souls.
The bravest I've ever had
the privilege of flying with.
But we're on our own.
This really was
a suicide mission.
Engine one's fluctuating.
We'll lose it any minute.
- Rafe, you gotta prime it.
- I am. How about now?
I see the coast.
I see the coast!
Copy that, Rafe.
We're gonna make it.
Danny, follow me.
We can make this.
I can see the coast now.
We're only a few miles out.
We gotta find
a soft landing spot.
I'm pushing up on two.
Hold on
for a hard landing!
I see rice paddies.
We'll bring it in right here.
Oh, God, engine one's dead.
We'll lose engine two
any second.
We can make it in. Easy.
Pull it back, glide in on fumes.
Japs!
We got Jap patrols
all over the place!
Japs! Land somewhere else!
Strap yourselves in!
We're coming in hard!
We're a deadstick.
Get outta the nose!
Hold on, boys!
We're going down!
Watch the trees!
Everyone all right?
I'm OK! I'm OK!
Where's Ripley?
He's dead.
Watch for Japs!
- Jap patrols!
- Take cover!
Who's got magazines?
Got em!
Gotta get up into those hills,
find the Chinese!
They got us pinned down!
- Danny!
- Rafe! Rafe, no!
Danny!
Rafe, you don't have a chance!
God damn. Danny!
Come on!
Gooz? You OK, man?
Danny? Aw, shit, Anthony.
Gooz! Can you hear me?
- Yeah.
- Come on.
Danny.
Easy, easy, easy.
I've had better landings.
You saved us back there.
I got something in my neck.
- Let me pull this out.
- Where's Gooz?
He's fine.
He's right over there.
Rafe!
Grenade!
Danny.
Danny!
Danny! Oh!
- Hold on!
- Rafe!
Hold on, now. I got you.
You're all right.
I'm not gonna make it.
Oh, yes, you are.
Yes, you are. Now look at me.
Rafe, I'm so cold.
I'm so cold.
You're all right. Hey.
Hey, Rafe?
Can you do me a favor?
What?
Can you have someone else
write my name on the tombstone?
You're not gonna die.
Look at me, listen to me!
You ain't gonna die,
you hear me?
Danny.
Danny, you can't die.
You can't die. You know why?
'Cause you're gonna be a father.
You're gonna be a daddy.
I wasn't supposed to tell you.
You're gonna be a father.
Please.
No. You are.
Danny.
Danny?
Please, please!
Please.
God.
Please, Danny.
Hold your fire!
They're Chinese.
When the action is over
and we look back...
we understand
both more and less.
This much is certain.
Before the Doolittle raid...
America knew nothing
but defeat.
After it, there was hope of victory.
Japan realized for the first
time that they could lose...
and began to pull back.
America realized
that she would win...
and surged forward.
It was a war
that changed America...
...and the world.
Dorie Miller was
the first black American...
to be awarded the Navy Cross.
But he would not be the last.
He joined
a brotherhood of heroes.
That's for all the raiders.
World War II for us
began at Pearl Harbor...
and 1,177 men
still lie entombed...
in the battleship Arizona.
America suffered...
but America grew stronger.
It was not inevitable.
The times tried our souls...
and through the trial,
we overcame.
Hey, Danny...
how'd you like to go flying?
Come here.
When I think back
on these times
And the dreams we left behind
I'll be glad
'cause I was blessed
To get to have you in my life
When I look back on these days
I'll look and see your face
You were right there for me
In my dreams
I'll always see you
Soar above the sky
In my heart, there'll
always be a place for you
For all my life
I'll keep a part of you
with me
And everywhere I am
There you'll be
Well, you showed me
how it feels
Feel the sky with in my reach
And I always will remember
All the strength
you gave to me
Your love made me
make it through
Oh, I owe so much to you
You were right there for me
In my dreams
I'll always see you
Soar above the sky
In my heart,
there'll always be
A place for you
For all my life
I'll keep a part of you
with me
And everywhere I am
There you'll be
'Cause I always saw
in you my light
My strength
And I want to thank you now
For all the ways
You were right there for me
For always
In my dreams
I'll always see you
Soar above the sky
In my heart,
there'll always be
A place for you
For all my life
I'll keep a part of you
with me
And everywhere I am
There you'll be