sending prices sky-high,
literally, literally, taking
the grass from its own roots.
Now you've got your Con-Dem nation,
Liberals noshing Tories
like altar boys picking dimps up.
Have we had a national
fucking stroke or what?
Is revolution a word,
or was it never?
Anybody watching needs to know,
we cope better than average
with irony in Chatsworth.
Well, for fuck's sake,
we live in Manchester
and they charge us for water.
I wandered lonely as a clown,
necking mushrooms rarely found.
This green and pleasant land
in ancient times...
Yak, yak, yak, yak,
yak, yak, yak, yak, yak!
It's not theirs any more.
This is our England now.
Party!
Can someone please
explain the criteria for a lie
to be a little white lie?
Whose standard
are we measuring this by?
Why don't we have labels
for other sizes of lies?
Lies that are off-white,
or darkening shades of grey,
until in the end they turn to big
dirty pitch-black abominations?
Uh-oh!
Uh-oh. A big rub.
Wow!
It pains me to admit it, but I never
thought she'd be this good.
Er... need to change
the barrel, yeah?
What for?
Jamie!
Oh, shit.
Are you taking the piss?
Mam! Mam, leave it, leave it.
Paddy?!
Get in!
He just couldn't go quietly,
could he?
Lady Diana had less people
lining the streets.
God rest her soul.
When did he die?
Right?
What are you doing?
Whoo!
I'm surprised
they weren't wearing balaclavas.
Ooh, that's a pretty one.
It's fucking lovely, Mimi!
All right, mate? How's it going?
Hiya.
All right?
How's it going, man?
Hey, I thought the IRA
gave all their guns to the filth.
Yeah, well,
plenty slipped through the net.
Shane, cheers, mate.
Good stuff.
See you, love, take care.
Nice weapon. Ha-ha-ha.
Talk about drawing attention, though.
He's not stupid.
Now the police think he's dead,
he can start all over.
So, where is he?
Got off to Thailand, didn't he?
He'll be sipping cocktails
on a beach somewhere in Koh Samui.
Or hanging out with some underage
brass in Patpingpong.
Yeah!
Ah, fuck this.
Hiya, Mimi.
Hiya.
Fill your boots, lads.
'A Moss Side man has been
arrested on suspicion of arson.
'The arrest follows
a three-month-long investigation
'of a suspected firebomb attack
on a house in...'
I need pushing to Chesney's.
Well, why can't he take you?
He's got to further his education
so he ends up nothing like you.
Oh!
Oh! Spare the fucking rod, Patty.
This is the 21st century.
You can't buy a flagon of mead
in the Jockey, you know.
And live rent-free as well?
Well, helping out covers that.
Tinned food and chip shops?
Tight bitch.
How many fucking brain cells
is that gonna help me batter?
Take a look around, Frank.
All those child benefits, long gone.
Carl looks after me.
Occasionally. It's my money
that keeps you going.
Plus, I couldn't trust you
with any more than a tenner.
It was a one-off.
You would think I'd risk bankrolling
such disgusting behaviour
at Lillian's again?
It's a proven timeless cure
for lovesickness.
Even if you can't get it up?
You should never have driven Libby
away. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
If you'd kept it in your pants,
she'd still be here.
'We want you to ring in
and tell us your ideas...'
Cigs, please, Ches.
And some green papers.
Hiya!
Chesney!
How long have you been there?
You need to speak up, love.
I'll have you for discrimination.
Doubt it.
Keep your pork faggots!
Hey, little man.
Procession was a bit OTT,
wasn't it?
You just practise looking sad.
Like the tears of a clown.
How's business?
Demand's definitely there.
I could do four parties tomorrow
if I had the staff.
Staff?
Shit. I have. I've double-booked.
Relying on other people
can be hard work.
I thought you were supporting me.
You know I am. So, then,
why do you keep avoiding me?
I love what you're doing.
Lend us 500 quid, then.
It's cheap for a reason, Karen.
No, no, it's not cheap
when you see what it can do.
You look after me
and I might show you what I can do.
What's up with you?
Not still missing Libby, are you?
Oh, fuck me! Hello!
Vernon Francis doesn't lose any kip
cos the latest split-arse
can't deal with the heat.
Everyone can see right through you!
Tell me, do I look bothered?
Don't feel sorry for him.
You all saw how he treated her.
25% off any of the girls
except Marcie and Mandy.
They've just been vagazzled.
Swarovski.
Oh!
Do I look like some low-life punter
with zero self-respect?
No offence, of course.
Suit yourself.
Ah!
Oh! This bloody pub!
She'll be perfect.
I just need two more now.
You've got no chance.
Where there's a will...
I'm sick of it! How am I supposed
to get in and out on my own?
Now what are you whinging on about?
Your toilets.
You couldn't swing a cat in there.
Oh, yack, yack, yack.
Buy a drink or shut the fuck up.
If they're too small
I'll have you for discrimination.
Whoa! Fucking...
Dr Quinn, Medicine Woman.
Lower than a rattlesnake's clout.
Oh.
Agreed!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
What are you doing?
There's nothing worse.
Grasses make me sick.
I haven't done anything!
And there's nothing for you to do
if you're already barred.
Oh!
Back at the gaff, Strangelove!
I know they weren't together,
but Mimi has just lost her husband.
That Scouse bitch
shouldn't speak to me like that.
They're gangsters!
More plastic than
a Tupperware party.
I remember when
Manchester had real villains.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Old-school QSG?
Those old fuckers wouldn't last
ten minutes on the streets today.
You don't mess with the Maguires.
Half-breed tinkers? Don't scare me.
Here. Read that bit.
"2.2 by 1.8..."
Mm-hm.
Er...
"With a minimum turning circle
of 1.5 metres."
Right, come on.
That's it there.
See?
Knew it! Miles out.
Pass me the phone.
It's about time somebody stood up
to those bullies.
Sorry for your loss.
That's every police station
in South Manchester.
Something wrong with your legs?
What am I supposed to put the ale in?
Do us a favour, will you?
Collect some glasses.
I've done a lot worse
for a lot less.
I'm gonna go lie down
a minute, yeah?
Why can't you juggle like that?
Because that knobhead
was born a clown.
Karma police.
Paddy Maguire, bang to rights.
Hey, what's the odds
on old nick-nack Paddy-whack
drifting off all peaceful
with a smile on his napper?
Fucking no chance.
Chuckie ar la.
Bet half of him's not even in there,
know what I mean? Vroom!
Think he is chopped up?
What happened
to you chatting me up?
What's the point
if you won't let me do anything?
Gaz Sharpe gave me this just
to watch me bend over from behind.
I only want a kiss.
A kiss is actual contact. Intimate.
Even prostitutes don't do that.
I'll have to work out
what it's worth.
What do we want?
Toilets!
When do we want them?
Now!
What do we want?
What the...?
When do we want them?
Now!
What do we want?
Toilets!
When do we want them?
You're having a laugh.
What do we want?
Toilets!
When do we want them?
Now!
What do we want?
Toilets!
When do we want them?
Get the fuck away from my pub!
They're disabled!
So, they should know better!
You stupid bitch!
This is a peaceful demonstration!
Someone call the police!
Jamie!
Get away from me, you lunatic!
You'll get nicked
for being on the premises!
Leave her alone!
Jamie!
Jamie, do something!
Mam!
We don't need any trouble
with that coffin around.
We'll do it.
Someone sees sense.
You'll change both toilets?
Men's and women's.
And a ramp?
And am I still barred?
No.
It's the right thing to do.
Jamie! Jamie!
Jamie?
Jamie!
Jay!
Wonder how he really died.
Probably had a heart attack.
Bit young. My cousin's
got one of these.
You don't break
into gangsters' houses.
I think I just worked out
what a kiss might be worth.
A picture of Paddy on your phone.
Letitia!
Wait!
What happened?
You tell me. You fainted.
Oh.
Jamie?
Ah, isn't he funny, Jamie?
Ha-ha-ha!
Oh.
They've sent me under ever since.
And I thought you were
a big, hard, fearless gangster.
This can't get out, Karen.
Course not.
I'm serious. Any sign of weakness
and people pounce.
Tony Soprano went to a shrink.
Karen.
OK. I get it.
Surprise!
Karen! Don't!
Shh. OK. OK.
It'll be OK.
Please!
I promise. It'll be all right.
See?
Just let it go.
Karen, please, I'm fucking
begging you!
Shh. This'll work. Don't be scared.
Come on.
No!
OK.
Are you some kind of pervert?
You owe me.
You didn't even get a photo.
What if I got something better?
Are you stupid?
We could sell it.
We? Leave it out! What if it's...
The trigger's a bit...
What are you doing?
Get away from here.
Outside. Just now. Two shots.
Quickly!
Should never have left Longsight.
You all right?
That's all that matters.
How would I know if anyone
was out to get us?
Could be kids fucking about.
Why would we have enemies?
Just part of the investigation,
Mrs Maguire.
I'd like to know which grass
reported this bullshit, though.
These things dig right into my tits.
Fucking Gunchester.
Give me the Dingle any day.
That was every wrong 'un in town
and nobody's owning up to firing
a gun. Our enemies are lying low.
Right.
Well, go on.
The police.
Ah, now they really are
taking the piss.
Not commiserating for Paddy.
Mental Macca got killed last night.
They haven't got a body, though.
No. But half of his brain's
left splattered on a wall.
How do you know anyway?
He wouldn't take no for an answer.
We had no choice.
Is nothing sacred?
It's an empty coffin!
With your father's name on it!
It was a lot less messy
than chopping Macca up.
The bizzies just said that
whoever killed Mental Macca
is shooting at us.
Why would they say that?
The bullet casings they found
are from the same gun.
Bollocks. They can't be.
Maybe it's their idea of a joke.
Oh, funny. Very fucking funny.
Yeah. Do you want to rearrange?
OK. Bye.
What's up?
Another cancellation.
What's wrong with you?
Nothing.
I just need to check something.
Oh, aye? What have you done
with our daughter?
I paid her off.
You'll teach her bad habits.
She'll need plenty,
if she's to get what she wants.
I know what you want.
Oh!
And the warriors climbed off
the unicorns, and dived into
the crystal pool.
Which made their shorts
go all see-through.
And all the children
lived happily ever after.
What's Mental Macca doing
in there?
Ah, whoa! What have I done?
Where is it?
What?
The gun.
I thought we'd sold them all.
The one with my prints on it.
Ahh!
That Afro was the only reason
you went out with me.
Is that what you reckon?
My comb at an angle.
Tacchini tracksuit.
Break-dancing at West Wythy
with Jason Orange.
I sure picked the right one then.
I could spin on my head
better than him.
Only cos you had more padding.
Round two upstairs?
Mm.
I'll be waiting.
Bye!
I'm delighted the landlord
has seen fit to cater to our needs.
It's about time more people stood up
for what they know to be right.
Three cheers for Patty! Hip-hip!
At least they're spending.
We'll take to the road
and show no mercy for any business
that fails to meet
the basic levels of support
needed by everyone in this
community.
How was it?
Not bad. Come on, over here.
Always knew you were a clown, Micky!
So, who got the best tips?
What happened?
Hoo-hoo!
Who wants to see some magic,
kids? Wanna play?
Ooh. Ha.
Ooh. Ha-ha-ha-ha-ha! Oh!
Ha-ha-ha-ha-ha! Oh!
So, no-one got paid?
I had to pay them. Compo.
But I'll cover it.
Do you know how much this gear costs?
We'll do better next time.
Please, Karen. I love my job.
Me too.
Must be true what they say.
Old Dr Time can heal all wounds.
With the help of a crushed-up Viagra
and a gram of Charlie.
Jamie, get Patty
whatever she wants.
A single malt.
Pint, Mimi.
Your fetid little maggot
back in working order, then?
Y'on about?
Libby's better off
away from such filth.
Lest we forget, your own daughter
fucked off on you as well.
Because you filled her head full
of romance and turned out to be
a gobshite.
Ah. And has she been in touch
with her dear old mum to tell her
how she is?
Treat her to a coffee?
Let her know
where the fuck she's even gone?
Son?
Where is he?
Aidan!
I'm on the radio in a second.
That's nice.
Are you listening to your favourite
great auntie on the wireless?
You're my only great auntie.
Record it for us.
Did you get it back?
It wasn't there
and they're not saying anything.
You two getting it on yet?
I'm on the radio in a minute, Carl.
Yeah, nice one. I need a few Z's.
Had another late one.
'..mathematics and science
in older children.
'The Government's latest drive
to raise standards...'
Aidan! It...
Carl! It's about to start.
'That's all the news.
But now, here's the weather.'
Someone come and just turn it up!
'..sunshine mainly in the afternoon.
Generally southeasterly breeze
with warm temperatures,
'highs of 20 to 22 degrees Celsius.'
'I'm delighted
the landlords have seen sense...
'time more people stood up
for what they know to be right.'
'Three cheers for Patty. Hip-hip!'
'Hooray!
'Hip-hip!'
'Hooray!'
Hey, look, everyone. Here's Patty!
We heard you on the radio, Patty.
Give her what she wants.
Whisky.
Again.
No gratitude
for getting your mates in?
A sheet of plywood and a brick?
I know. Wish I'd have
thought of it earlier.
And again.
Patty! Come and join us.
Yeah, come and have a drink.
Yay! Too right,
you should go and celebrate.
Children of the revolution!
Chorlton nil, wheelies one,
eh, Patty?
No, it's a wonderful day,
my sister of Shankly.
Especially when the drinks
are on those close to you.
Ha-ha-ha.
Well done, Patty.
Well, aren't we popular?
What do you want
to keep your mouth shut?
80/20 on the disability benefit.
No chance.
Huh... Hey, everyone! Come on!
Big cheer for Patty!
Yeah, party, party!
Whoa! Ha-ha!
Ha-ha-ha. Your call.
Ha-ha.
Yeah, come on! Drinks all round!
Wheelies! What's your pleasure?
Come on!
One...
two, three, four...
five... Look at that one!
..six.
Cheeky f...
Oi! Leave it alone!
Chatsworth's my patch.
Yeah? It's a free market.
Fucking...
Come on, lads.
That's got to be worth 50 quid.
Cheers, Tony. Here y'are,
do you wanna leave us your numbers?
We might be able to
get you some business.
That'll come in handy.
No, I'm really sorry. No, I can't
make Cody's birthday party.
It's very important. Sorry.
No word?
Maybe the filth
are playing games with us.
Why would they?
Because that's the sort of bullshit
they pull.
Would the police fire a gun
through your mam's window?
Well, somebody has,
and it's doing my head in.
Silver lining. I am cutting down
on all the clowns around here.
Falling down the stairs the day
before your daughter's wedding?
That's right.
All the way down?
I needed an operation, didn't I?
Impeccable timing.
She was too good for him.
Oh, too good for all of them
if it means leaving you.
180 a week disability
is no lottery win.
Hey, keeps the wolves at bay.
Stop showing off. Drawing attention.
People know
I can't stand the sight of you.
Clean off, mate. Clean off.
No...
All right, boys, grab a plate.
I've made plenty.
Here you go.
And yours, Mimi. I just laid it all
out on a plate, didn't I?
Changed man. Virtually went down
on my knees. And still she went.
She always thought
she was better than she was.
And then she threw it
all back in my face.
I've seen women like her
all my life.
She just wanted respect.
She's taking us to the cleaners,
Frank.
Oh, well,
she's blagged lesser men than you.
Real mover and shaker.
You see where Libby got it from.
Don't badmouth my daughter in public.
The teeniest bit of effort, that's
all she needed to make, Lillian.
Me, me, me.
Why do you really think she left?
You wouldn't have dared.
She wanted to give it another go
with you.
No matter, I begged and reminded her
you're nothing but
a useless piss-pot.
So, you told her
that you could walk?
Maybe I needed to come clean.
Just so she'd fuck off?
Unburden myself of a hateful lie.
And if knowing the truth helped her
to find the strength to move on...
And I've been running after you
like a busy cunt for four months?
Mm.
And for what it's worth,
you'll carry on.
Oh?
Oh.
Er... excuse me! Oi, oi!
Um... fellow Jockeyites! Get on this!
Tss! Fwk! Christ!
Don't do it!
Yeeh!
Is this a blagger I see before me?
Frank.
You taking the piss?
She can, you know.
As and when requested.
Yeah, I saw her! Go on, show 'em.
Rambling madman.
Oh!
What did you see?
What did I...
Ooh, listen to me on t'wireless.
Oh. Tut-tut-tut!
Tut!
Tut-tut-tut! Splat.
Do you enjoy reminding me
I'm a cripple?
Now, now, Patty. Trades description.
That's what I try, try,
every morning.
Because I pray for a miracle
every night.
And one... one time in a thousand,
I get the strength to force myself up
and manage a whole second
suspended on my feet.
Before...
always fall back down again!
Leave her alone, you bully.
She's suffered enough.
Oh, you're good.
Come here, you fucking fraud.
Frank! Careful!
No!
No wonder fucking Libby left.
That's enough!
OK. OK, OK. Right, OK.
Whoa!
Frank! I'm warning you!
You lying, twisted,
piss-stained old fraud!
You soft-arsed bone-idle tramp.
Libby's gone for good!
Frank, come on!
Aah!
Fuck!
Help!
See! See! She can feel it.
I told you!
Whoa!
Leave her alone!
Oh!
Oh, my God.
Here, he's right.
You...
Oh!
She can walk.
Hallelujah!
Oh, for fuck's sake.
How braindead can you get?
Hope it was worth it.
So, what about Micky and Lillian?
I haven't got the bookings
and this stuff costs a bomb to hire.
It wasn't cos I was smoking weed?
I'm just not ready to expand.
Whatever it is, don't do it.
I know she knows
I know they've got it.
Maybe they haven't.
Maybe it fell through a hole.
Like I wouldn't have felt it.
A hole in the floor?
What are you doing?
You still owe me a kiss.
You owe me a photo.
When did you get that?
Last night.
Well, send it me, then.
Kiss first.
Standing.
Look, I've told you.
Kelly hates guns.
All I'm saying is she's capable.
She lies for a living.
What's that supposed to mean?
She tells nonces
she loves them all day long.
Karen's no angel.
Well, go on.
She knew you were selling guns too,
you know.
Hey, she never even
goes round there.
I know for a fact
Kelly did not take that gun.
By my reckoning,
that only leaves you.
Whoa!
You gonna give your new boyfriend
a kiss?
Get off me!
Again. Where's the gun?
I don't know what you mean!
Look what we do to people.
Do you think we give a fuck
if you go in the groundas well?
Have it your way.
No! No, stop it!
Stop! I took it home.
You. You better hope
they haven't sold it.
Check upstairs.
Who's a lucky boy, then?
Aah.
So, you wanna play with fire,
do you?
No!
No! No!
Oh! Oh!
Oh!
Get'em off!
More! More! More!
We've already done half an hour over.
That's all you're getting! Get off!
Get 'em off!
Nobody said anything about this.
Like you didn't know!
Karen!
This party's over.
Get the door.
You're not going anywhere.
Bit of a prick teaser, are we?
Get it out for the lads. Yes.
Hey, hey, hey, give us that!
It's his treat.
Let him fuck you!
Karen!
Come on,
most strippers do a bit more, yeah!
Do you know who I am?
Some potless dirty bitch?
Karen Maguire.
Wit woo.
Whoa! That's a big one.
Where's that going?
Up your fucking ring piece,
if you're not careful!
What did you do that for?
Hit him as well!
Get off.
That's a heavy water pistol.
You reckon?
Ah! My leg!
That's what you get,
you fucking cunts!
Karen?
You OK?
What happened?
It's all right.
Come on, tell me.
Just come here.
Dad always said you were at it.
What's up with you?
Don't you dare waste that!
Think you can fix things
with a full English?
He's not been right for days.
Hey, don't...
OK, I'll take 50-50
on the disability benefits.
You've got nothing on me any more.
You sure about that?
No chance.
Well, grassing never sits easy.
But DSS, like pit bulls,
get a sniff of blood.
20 years of false claims?
They are going to want a big chat.
I'd say half each seems fair.
Keep your pathetic threats, Frank.
Someone's beaten you to it.
Time to pack your bags.
You looking at,
you fat, lazy bastard?
You wouldn't be in here
if it wasn't for me.
She's full of shit, her!
Like I don't know it.
Who backed her trip to Lourdes?
Bottom line, it's down to
her you're even in here.
Oh!
The kid from Cincinnati, he say yes!
Heh-heh-hey-hey! Who'd Adam and Eve
it, eh? The luck of the Irish.
Burn the slag.
I said leave it!
O blest Lord, Creator God...
in you all things
are rendered pure...
by you are strengthened to endure.
O blest holy hand of God,
all things are sanctified by you...
adorned, enriched,
you make them new.
I'm at a funeral.
Go on, Patty!
Go on, girl!
Squaw Valley, California, 1960.
I was to be the first Irish
winter ice-dancing Olympian.
Then I got pregnant with Libby.
What, at 15? Fucking...
Welcome to your spiritual home.
My country.
The Olympics.
Oh, imagine.
And because you didn't get
to fuck about on ice skates
it's all right to steal
your daughter's life?
What was your excuse,
you useless parasite?
Oh, well, yeah, you got me.
Guilty as charged.
I stole Libby's heart,
but you know when you're like that,
colours are brighter,
birdsong's clearer.
Until the novelty fades away
and I'm back in the arms
of the only constant.
My only true love.
Am I a lesser man?
This mother-child thing?
Whoosh! Nurture, shelter, protect.
That's instinct, yeah?
It's instinct. Natural.
Then, with love and prayers,
you set them free.
Too right.
Amen.
Just a thought.
I'd booked a termination.
At an underground clinic
in Liverpool.
Oh, fuck off.
Abortion was still illegal.
Now you need to button it.
But the worst storm in a decade
stopped the ferries for a week.
Daddy found out, locked me
in my room for a month.
I wanted to get rid of her then...
and I don't need her now.
Well, I hope it was worth it.
I don't need anybody.
'At what point does
withholding the truth become a lie?
'I bet politicians are given books
to guide them on that.
'At what point in the lie you've just
created is it too late to back out
'and telling the truth
would do more damage?
'When you have to keep it going
'because you know that even if you
manage to keep that lie going
forever,
'it will eat you up so much inside
you won't want to live anyway.'
Home deliveries. Good idea. I've got
a bit of stock needs shifting.
I don't want to get involved
in any illegal shit.
Let your driver take the flack.
Not over, is it?
Between you and the running man?
We've been acting out our fantasies.
Oh, yeah. Oh, yeah.
Mm.
Like butter wouldn't melt.
Police just pulled me.
Luckily, I hid that lot
somewhere else.
Avril, we need to talk.
You arrogant piece of shit!
Morning!
Hiya!
Ring the police, Ches.
Tell them about your paedo tendencies
while you're at it.
D'you want some sex?
You were seen kissing her.
I knows my place, master.
Aah!
Subtitles by Red Bee Media Ltd, MemoryOnSmells
www.addic7ed.com