This is for my daughter, Hannah, and
more importantly for all her friends on
Facebook who thought that her little
rebellious post was cute... and for all you
parents out there that think your kids
don't post bad things on Facebook. Well I
want to read you one I took off my
daughter's Facebook wall that she
thought she was being smart by blocking
her parents from being able to see it.
Hannah, you were grounded for about
three months for doing something very
similar to this, and I would've thought that
with a father that works in IT for a living,
you'd have better sense than to do it
again.
But I just spent about six hours yesterday
fixing your computer for you, upgrading it
for you, and spent about $130 on
software.
And today, I ran across a Facebook post
that you didn't think I'd be able to see.
Since you want to hide it from everyone,
I'm going to share it with everybody.
This is called "To My Parents" by the way.
"To my parents, I'm not your damn slave.
It's not my responsibility to clean up your
shit. We have a cleaning lady for a
reason.
Her name is Linda, not Hannah.
If you want coffee, get off your ass and
make it yourself.
If you want a garden, shovel the fertilizer
yourself. Don't sit back on your ass and
watch me do it.
If you walk into the house and get mud
all over the floor that I just cleaned, be
my guest, but clean it up after you're
done getting shit everywhere.
I'm tired of picking up after you. You tell me
at least once a day that I need to get a job."
[laughs] And I love this part.
"You could just pay me for all the shit that
I do around the house!"
Seriously, are you kidding me? I'll get to
that in a minute.
Every day, when I get home from school,
I have to do the dishes, clean the
counter tops, all the floors, make all the beds,
do the laundry, and get the trash.
I'm not even going to mention all the work
I do around your clinic.
And if I don't do all that every day, I get
grounded.
Do you know how hard it is to
keep up with chores and school work? It's
freakin' crazy. I go to sleep at 10 every
night because I'm too tired to stay up any
longer and do anything else.  I have to get
up at 5 in the morning to get ready for
school. On the weekends, I have to sleep
with my door locked so my little brother
won't get me up at 6."  That part is true.
"This is all true!  And I'm tired of this
bullshit. Next time I have to pour a cup of
coffee, I'm going to flip shit!  I have no
idea how I have a life.  I'm going to hate
the see the day when you get too old to
wipe your ass and you call me asking
for help. I won't be there.
Signed, your pissed kid, Hannah."
I'm going to address a couple of these.
We have a lady that cleans the house for
us, as a favor to trade off some services.
She is not, and you will never again refer
to her as a cleaning lady. That lady works
harder in one day than you ever have in
your life.  Pay you? For the chores...
seriously?! Pay you for the chores that
you're supposed to do around the house?
You come home from school, and you
have a list of chores that are on the wall
because you can't remember them if you
don't.  They are sweep the living room and
kitchen floor. Which total will take you
about 3 minutes. If the counter tops are
dirty, wipe them down, which takes about
a minute. If the dishwasher is full and
been run, empty it and put the dishes
away. If it's not, just be sure all the
glasses and stuff are in the dishwasher. If
you have any laundry of your own, do it.
And if your bed is unmade, do it. You
don't have to do my laundry. You don't
have to make my bed. You don't have to
make the guest bed. You have to make
your own bed. Once a month or so, I
guess you probably have to make the
guest bed.  Pay you for chores? Are you
out of your mind? You are 15, going on 16
years old. You want things for your
laptop. You want a new battery. You want
a new cord. You want a new camera. You
want a new phone. You want a new iPod.
But you won't get off your lazy ass to
even look for a job. The only job you've
applied to is the one I made you apply to
because I got the application for you.
[Crumples up paper]
You've been too lazy to even carry that
back. When I was your age, I'd moved out
of the house, lived on my own, went to
college while in High School, worked two
jobs, was a volunteer fireman, and still
went to school. Your responsibilities
include waking up on time, and getting on
the bus. That's the end of your
responsibilities each day. You don't have
that hard of a life. But you're about to. I
warned you months ago, about what
would happen if you did something like
this on Facebook again. The last
time you were grounded, and quite frankly
I've forgotten now, but it was for
something fairly childish and stupid. We
took away the computer, that kind of
thing, no cell phone, no Facebook. And I
told you, if it ever happened again, that it
would be a lot worse. And I was really
close that day to putting a bullet through
your laptop. Now this time, I just spent all
day yesterday, blew half my day,
upgrading your laptop.  Putting new
software on it. Spent about $130 in
software to get everything the way you
wanted to have it for school. You don't
have to worry about buying a new laptop
battery. You don't have to worry about
buying a new power cord. You don't have
to worry about buying a new camera.
Because you probably won't be using any
of them, until probably college. I don't
know how to say how disappointed I am in
you, and how disrespectful you were to
every single adult in your life, but kid, you
got it easy... way easy.  It's about to get
harder. It's about to get a whole lot harder
today. Because you're not going to see
this and for all I know, you might not ever
see it. But as soon as I'm done, I'm going
to post this on your Facebook wall. So all
those kids that thought that it was cool
for how rebellious you were can see what
happens. And all the parents may get an
idea to boot up their own kids ass. There
were more curse words in that one post,
just ridiculous. Not happening.
Disrespectful to me, your mother, your
step-mother, your family, your friends,
and yourself. So, I'm going to put a stop
to it right now...
[Picks up the camera]
That right there is your laptop.  You see
it's out here on the ground. This right
here is my .45.
[fires gun]
That was the first round.
These are exploding hollow point rounds,
and you have to pay me back for these
too, because these are about $1 apiece.
[fires gun repeatedly]
1..2..3..4..5..6..
Oh yeah, and after that comment you
made about your mom, your mom told me
to be sure I put one in there for her, so
[fires gun] that one is for her. And if I got
one left... [fires gun]... I got two left...
[fires gun]... now I'm out.
So, just for the record, whenever you're
not grounded,
whatever year that happens to be,
you can have a new laptop
when you buy a new laptop. And when
you pay me back $130 for the software I
spent on yours yesterday. Hope you've
enjoyed your little fiasco on Facebook.
Hope it was worth all this.
Have a good day, y'all.