I really like to eat sweets
all the time.
I'd rather do it all day, every
day than anything else.
And so I'm just going to
jump in and do it.
And I'll figure the
rest out later.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHRISTINA TOSI: We have a very
fun afternoon planned.
We take having fun
very seriously.
My name is Christina Tosi.
I am the chef and owner
of Momofuku Milk Bar.
We serve mostly sweet items.
They're sort of kooky baked
goods with an American
perspective.
But we also have a lot
of savory breads.
And we now have five stores
in New York City.
We're most known for our cereal
milk, which is the
flavor of what's left in your
bowl after you eat all of the
cereal out of it.
So the pretzel milk is the milk
that we're the most proud
of right now.
Most of the flavor of
the pretzels is
actually on the outside.
So you're sort of just washing
that salty layer off of them.
For me, it's like the ultimate
salty, malty,
sweet flavored milk.
We've made ice cream
with it, like a
pretzel-flavored ice cream.
But when you have a really good
burger, it's not like
it's the first burger
you've ever had.
But you still want to talk
about it like it's a
revelation.
And that's what good food is.
And then, of course, we have
pork buns, which are the
Momofuku staple.
If you know the name Momofuku,
you probably
have had a pork bun.
Long ago, when Dave Chang and
I were first coming up with
the foundation of what Momofuku
Milk Bar would be, we
said that it would be like Dairy
Queen with pork buns.
We like to use our formal
foundations in cooking and in
baking and sort of give it to
you as a customer in a really
easy, approachable way.
You ladies ready?
The foundations of Milk Bar come
from four of my favorite
people in the whole wide world,
Courtney McBroom, Helen
Jo, Jaime Dessecker,
and Jena Derman.
They help run the kitchen.
They help run the Milk Bars.
They help do everything big
and small in between.
They're sort of like
Wonder Women.
Yeah.
First we're going to go to Dairy
Queen for breakfast.
On our way to Dairy Queen, we
started off with some jello
shots that Jaime cast in these
orange rinds and then cut up
like they were little orange
slices that you would eat
after a crazy soccer match.
Jaime, these are ridiculous.
-Breakfast of champions.
CHRISTINA TOSI: Cheers.
ALL: Cheers.
CHRISTINA TOSI: And
we also made some
kimchi Bloody Mary's.
Being part of the Momofuku
family means having kimchi in
house all the time.
And for me, the kimchi Bloody
Mary was clutch on the way
over to Dairy Queen.
-Cheers to--
CHRISTINA TOSI: To kimchi
Bloody Marys.
-To kimchi Bloody Marys.
CHRISTINA TOSI: To Dairy
Queen for breakfast.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
-Oh.
-Hey, how are you?
Good.
JENA DERMAN: Do you guys
have the fryer on yet?
CHRISTINA TOSI: Oreo
CheeseQuake.
JENA DERMAN: Just checking.
HELEN JO: Just checking.
HELEN JO: Our priorities.
CHRISTINA TOSI: You want to get
the chicken strip basket?
COURTNEY MCBROOM: Yeah.
CHRISTINA TOSI: May I have a
mini Blizzard with Oreo,
Butterfinger, Heath,
and cookie dough?
I have a very strong opinion
about what goes into a
Blizzard-- as many mix-ins
as possible.
There must be Oreos.
And you have to eat it
all in one sitting.
All right.
Which one did you get?
JAIME DESSECKER: I mixed
Butterfinger and
Turtle Pecan Custard.
COURTNEY MCBROOM:
What's yours?
Just straight Butterfinger?
CHRISTINA TOSI: Mine's Heath
Bar, Butterfinger, Oreo,
cookie dough.
Thank you.
COURTNEY MCBROOM: You got to
do fries in the Blizzard.
CHRISTINA TOSI: I don't
like eating ice cream
when it's too cold.
I like letting it melt
a little bit.
And you got to go
salty French fry
straight into your Blizzard.
I'm also really into
the CheeseQuake.
Why didn't we come up with
the liquid CheeseQuake?
I think Dairy Queen also has a
sense of humor in the way that
they name some of their menu
items, which I really relate
to for obvious reasons.
And making a Blizzard from
scratch is like the ultimate--
I think-- experience, in terms
of what's my mood.
Do you think I could make
a Blizzard with you?
MIKE: Sure.
CHRISTINA TOSI: Can we do Oreo
and Strawberry Cheesecake?
I've never made a Blizzard
before, so getting Mike to
agree to let me behind the
counter to really show me the
one, two, threes of a Blizzard
was like the ultimate
experience.
Awesome.
Thank you very much.
All right.
We got Oreo Strawberry
Cheesecake.
JAIME DESSECKER: Whoah.
HELEN JO: Wow.
CHRISTINA TOSI: What.
My first Blizzard.
How are you guys feeling?
Ready for a Michelada
in the beach?
By Mike.
Thank you.
See you soon.
To the beach.
Ooh, it smells like
kimchi in here.
They should make air fresheners
that smell like kimchi.
We're going to the beach.
Maybe we should practice
our beach
volleyball with this sick--
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
CHRISTINA TOSI: Spike.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHRISTINA TOSI: Here we go.
[SQUEALS]
Hi, Chris.
CHRIS HIEW: Hi.
CHRISTINA TOSI: Hi, Martine.
Chris and Martine and Beans
the dog met us at the Far
Rockaway [INAUDIBLE].
Bud.
Come on.
Don't be stubborn.
For me, going to the beach on
the off-season is the best way
to sort of let loose
and chill out.
Because it's sort of like the
beach belongs to you.
I really love spending time at
the beach and sort of just
kicking up sand and letting
loose, or just
sort of dicking around.
[LAUGHING]
We made this last night with
some leftover kimchi Bloody
Mary liquid, and lime juice, and
some kochukaru salt, and
then some Brooklyn Lager.
I'm going to serve it up.
So I think the perfect
beach snack is a
pastrami and rye croissant.
It's got a little Russian
dressing, some sauerkraut
stuffed in.
It's easy to eat.
Sand can't get in it.
[LAUGHS]
The perfect beach snack.
Cheers.
-Cheers.
CHRIS HIEW: Cheers.
ALL: Cheers.
CHRISTINA TOSI: Beans,
don't get too drunk.
HELEN JO: Beans, it's spicy.
Watch it.
COURTNEY MCBROOM: We
should have a sand
castle building contest.
CHRISTINA TOSI: How about who
can build the tallest in a
certain amount of time?
COURTNEY MCBROOM: OK.
CHRISTINA TOSI: Part of
my personality is very
competitive.
Go.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHRISTINA TOSI: I will die.
I will throw myself in
front of traffic
trying to be the best.
Oh.
They're totally fucked.
Let's go.
JAIME DESSECKER: Wait.
We're going for the tallest?
CHRISTINA TOSI: Yes.
-They're building a moat.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHRISTINA TOSI: It maintains
that working hard and kicking
butt and pushing yourself,
but also not taking
yourself too seriously.
JENA DERMAN: Five, four,
three, two, one.
Hands down.
Step away from your castle.
CHRISTINA TOSI: I think
it's fairly obvious
who the winner is.
Clearly ours is the tallest.
You know, it's fun to
be competitive.
It's fun to be like who's going
to scoop cookies the
fastest today?
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHRISTINA TOSI: After the beach,
we to decided to head
to Randall's Island Golf Center
for a little game of
putt-putt golf.
All right.
Losers can go first.
[LAUGHING]
Oh, losers first.
Please.
Duck pin bowling and putt-putt
golf were the foundations of
my childhood.
So whenever I see a putt-putt
golf course, I can't stop
talking about it until I get out
of the car and can hit the
putt-putt golf course.
Dave Chang met us there.
Most people don't know that when
he was a kid, he was sort
of on the road to becoming a
professional golf player.
He was one-handing some
putt-putt holes, which I
thought was pretty intense.
Where'd you get those hot
putt-putt golf kicks?
Just a little something
you picked up?
COURTNEY MCBROOM: Yeah.
CHRISTINA TOSI: Courtney got
the first hole-in-one.
We had a little friendly
wager.
I owe her $20, I think.
Damn it.
COURTNEY MCBROOM: You can put me
down for one on this hole.
CHRISTINA TOSI: Some more
friends started arriving.
Danny from Mission Chinese and
Steve from Asia Dog ended up
joining us at Randall's Island
with the hot new Taco Bell
tacos wrapped in the nacho
cheese taco shell.
DANNY BOWIEN: We went and we
got 40 of the Dorito tacos.
CHRISTINA TOSI: Why
did you do that?
We have too many.
DANNY BOWIEN: Because
you have to try it.
Because we were talking
about it yesterday.
Do you guys want to eat
one now, or what?
CHRISTINA TOSI: Yes.
COURTNEY MCBROOM: This
is insanity.
CHRISTINA TOSI: So good.
JENA DERMAN: This
is ridiculous.
CHRISTINA TOSI: I've been making
nachos with Doritos,
nacho cheese and cool ranch
mixed for years.
Someone has a hidden camera
in my apartment.
[LAUGHING]
I feel like we should give up
on putt-putt and just start
tailgating.
JENA DERMAN: Right?
That's why I'm trying
to like, let's get
back to this apartment.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHRISTINA TOSI: Oh, this is
going to be delicious.
[LAUGHING]
DANNY BOWIEN: Look
at that thing.
That's amazing.
CHRISTINA TOSI: OK.
Can I get--
Can somebody sous
chef me please?
DANNY BOWIEN: What
are you doing?
What do you want?
You want these in here?
COURTNEY MCBROOM: We're going
to take care of you later.
CHRISTINA TOSI: For a proper
tailgate, I feel like there
has to be some sort
of chips and dip.
We're very big on chips and
dip in our kitchens.
So we brought ranch dip and
potato chips and we made a
sick seven layer dip with
tortilla chips.
For me, a good tailgate
has warm food.
So these are kimchi
quesadillas.
They're tortillas with a little
bit of shredded cheddar
cheese and our home-made
kimchi, Napa cabbage.
COURTNEY MCBROOM: So good.
CHRISTINA TOSI: We decided to
bring our favorite throw
together sandwich, which is
a grilled cheese sandwich.
But instead of sandwich
bread, we use
two of our corn cookies.
And we make a ham and cheese
grilled cheese sandwich.
The last time I was at a
tailgate it's because I was
going to a Redskins game.
And my stepbrother made us show
up to the stadium at 7:45
in the morning.
And we got so shit-faced
my sister was trying to
roundhouse kick me.
Shit-faced at 10 o'clock
in the morning.
And then she got mad at me
because she fell on the ground
and couldn't beat me up.
[LAUGHING]
That was the last time I
tailgated, the one and only
time that I think I properly
tailgated.
We were having a blast.
We were all sort of
kumbaya-ing around the tailgate.
And all of a sudden, this woman
at the Randall's Island
Golf Center called the cops
on us because apparently,
tailgating is not legal
in their parking lot.
They weren't having
us anymore.
So we packed up and
got out of there.
We wrapped it up.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[INTERPOSING VOICES]