Fillet.
Look at these beautiful bad boys man. Oh they're
so good! And for half the price of Filet Mignon,
of Fillet. We're talking the rump, the bullet,
the Cogal. Rump fillet man, Dutch Cogal. You
gotta spit the G.
Haha.
First make sure you take your steaks out of
the refrigerator at least 60 minutes before
you cook them. You want them to be room temperature.
These things are thick and it's gonna take
a while.
Now come over here, we're gonna get our butter
rocking.
We've got our knife, stick it in the butter.
There we go.
Mmmm, it's like a Popsicle full of heart attack.
There's our unsalted butter, we're gonna let
it melt down and the fats from the butter
is gonna give us that caramelisation on the
meat.
And in the meantime we're gonna sort out the
steaks.
And that is with Sea Salt. You want them to
melt onto the meat and right there is pepper.
Now, I used to use pepper but sometimes pepper
can go acrid. They actually burn onto the steaks.
We're gonna put the pepper on at the very
end when we let the steak rest so just salt,
real simple man.
So do one side then turn them over. There's
a lot of surface area to rock and flavour.
Butter is melted, let's get the steaks on
the grill.
Oh yeah!
You guys ready?
Here we go. You want a nice fierce, hot heat.
Proper hot heat. Feel that, oh yeah!
Two steaks on the grill, we're gonna give
them a minute then flip them.
So basically you wanna sear the outside and
keep it all juicy inside man.
We want a beautiful flavour on the outside
and the char.
That's one minute up, time to flip.
I cook my steak a minute a side, three flips.
I like my steak medium-rare.
Shake your rumpa.
Oh that's a minute, sorry.
Right we've just done both sides, now we're
doing the perimeter man, sealing all that juicy
flavour man. I might even work a couple of
tongs dude 'cos I'm doing two steaks at once,
look at this. Ambidextrous! I'm going lefty,
I'm going southpaw.
Alright we've sealed all the sides, now it's
the turn of the herb brush.
So if you wanna know how to make this, just
click on the herb brush.
Ok, so we're gonna dip the herb brush into
the butter and then we're gonna splash flavour
onto the steaks. And you see a bit of flare up.
That's good man. That's gonna help us
give a beautiful char on the steaks.
Once you've hit it with the herb brush, flip
it and hit it again for another minute.
We're gonna kiss the steaks hahaha. So much
flavour!
You know what, our steaks are good. The amount
of time you've used to cook your steaks, you're
gonna use the same amount of time to rest
your steaks. Let all that moisture and that
juicy goodness come back into that muscle
so that when you cut it open it's just juicy
and beautiful.
I can see you guys like, come on I wanna eat!
Uh uh, you gotta rest them, okay?!
Ok, so we're gonna take them over to the indirect
side of the BBQ and we're gonna let them rest
for about 4 to 5 minutes alright.
When they're resting, you add the pepper.
You get it on both sides.
Let's get our steaks off the grill and mange!
And we've got a beautiful, medium-rare cook
rocking here just the way I like it.
That is perfect. Look at all those juices
right there. Oh my goodness gracious.
Oh man these are beautiful. One for the camera
guy.
You know what, I always eat first and I feel
bad because you gotta film it all dude!
So listen, this goes to you.
Alright, ready, 1,2,3. Ha ha, right?!
I'm happy to sit down.
This rump fillet steak is perfect on its own
just with the herb brush and the butter and
the salt and the pepper but if you wanna pimp
it out, I've got this beautiful Chimichurri
sauce. You can drizzle it on there, give it
a bit of a tang, with the garlic and the coriander
and the parsley. Oh and that vinegar will
just set it off!
If you wanna learn how to make the Chimichurri
sauce click on the jar now. Just do yourselves
a favour and click on it man. Chimmichurri,
beautiful on meat.
That's it for DJ BBQ's Ultimate Steak.
What do you guys want me to cook man? You
guys asked for that one. I wanna hear from
you guys in the comments below. Do it! And,
also make sure you click on this thing if
you haven't subscribed already.
I'm DJ BBQ and I am out of here.