who came down from the heavens.
Always you have someone
who is descending from the sky
with loud noise,
with thundering,
with fire, with smoke.
They would have come the most
powerful and magical place
possible... from the stars.
NARRATOR: But just who were
these mystical beings that
ruled the skies with
supernatural powers?
David CHILDRESS: You could
wonder if these tales of Zeus's
thunderbolts, Thor's hammer,
if these weren't real weapons.
NARRATOR: Did our ancient
ancestors create the gods from
their own imaginations?
Or did they simply report
events they believed to be true?
GIORGIO A. TSOUKALOS: Our
ancestors misinterpreted
extraterrestrials as gods,
because that is was the only way
that they could explain away
what they witnessed.
NARRATOR: Millions of people
around the world believe we have
been visited in the past by
extraterrestrial beings.
What if it were true?
Did ancient aliens really help
to shape our history?
And were the gods of
our ancestors actually visitors
from other worlds?
Sync by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com
NARRATOR: Truva, Turkey.
For over 150 years, this small
city has been the center of one
of the greatest archaeological
finds in modern history: the
possible discovery of the
legendary city of Troy.
In 1868, amateur archaeologist
Heinrich Schliemann, set out to
find what he believed was the
city that served as the basis
for the Trojan War, as described
in one of the greatest pieces of
classical literature, Homer's
epic poem, the Iliad.
Written in the eighth century
BC, Homer's Iliad tells the
tale of a great war, born of
feuding and jealous gods.
While most scholars believed
the story of the Trojan War was
a work of fiction, Schliemann
was determined to prove the
myth was a reality.
Richard RADER: Heinrich
Schliemann's discoveries rocked
the archaeological world.
Armed with his copy of the
Iliad, basically, he just
decided that he was gonna find
Troy.
And so he went and just dug a
big hole, and when he went, he
discovered the real Troy.
NARRATOR: But if Homer's
story of Troy was true, what
would it say about other Greek
stories and myths?
Might those also be true?
Did powerful gods and goddesses
actually exist?
And, if so, where did they come
from?
Hellas, also known as Greece.
Each day, thousands of tourists
visit temples and monuments
built to honor the gods of
another age.
The Acropolis...
Delphi...
The Parthenon...
The Temple of Apollo.
These ancient sites reflect a
powerful reverence for beings
that supposedly ruled the world
thousands of years ago.
CHILDRESS: When you look at
many of the mythologies around
the world, they have these
stories of gods coming down from
the sky.
RADER: There's a beautiful
description of the way that the
gods move, like, when they kind
of come down to the Earth.
You get the sense of them
gliding down, but the way that
they move is kind of beyond
time.
It just kind of happens.
NARRATOR: If the ancient
Greeks invented the stories of
gods as a primitive attempt to
explain their universe, how can
we account for similar deities
found in widely different
regions and cultures around the
globe?
Was it mere coincidence?
Or was there a common origin
for these gods, who supposedly
traveled to Earth from the
skies?
Jason MARTELL: The earliest
civilization we have, 3800 BC,
the Sumerians actually give us
visual descriptions of these
beings and speak of this time
that they lived amongst their
living gods.
They called their gods the
Annunaki and that term simply
meant "those who from heaven
come to earth."
RADER: Mythology is chock...
full of these episodes of gods
coming down to earth.
I mean, because mythology is so
interested in the relationship
between gods and humans, there
is necessarily gonna be a lot
of communication, and communion
between the two of them.
NARRATOR: In his 2000 book,
Odyssey of the Gods, Erich Von
D Niken argues that the world's
sacred books are full of
descriptions, not of gods, but
of supernatural beings
interacting with humans.
Von D NIKEN: Some thousands
of years ago, when our
forefathers were still
primitive, some
extraterrestrials descended to
our planet.
And because of misunderstanding,
like of technology, our
forefathers thought that these
extraterrestrials must be some
gods.
NARRATOR: Mount Olympus.
Greece's highest mountain.
According to ancient myths,
this site was the home of the
gods.
(thunder crashes)
It was here, on Mount Olympus,
that Zeus sat on his throne and
determined the fate of
mortal men.
TSOUKALOS: Whenever we have
references to Mount Olympus, it
is described to be this
magnificent palace on top of
Mount Olympus allegedly, and the
temple walls were always
gleaming of gold, or gleaming
with silver, and a lot of little
lights that they described as
jewels.
Well, if you look at that
from modern perspective,
what if that place... Mount
Olympus... wasn't necessarily the
top of a mountain, but it was,
in fact, a spaceship, because it
is described how sometimes there
was a big rumbling with Mount
Olympus, and the entire top
lifted off.
NARRATOR: But if Mount
Olympus was home to alien
visitors, could Zeus have been
their leader?
According to both the Iliad and
the Odyssey, Zeus was often
depicted as wielding a
lightning bolt.
CREMO: It appears to be a
very powerful weapon because he
could destroy whole cities with
this thunderbolt weapon of his.
NARRATOR: Similarly, Zeus's
brother Poseidon, the God of
the sea, was armed with a
trident.
CREMO: He was able to create
tsunamis, tidal waves with this
weapon.
The trident weapon of Poseidon
seems to have been something
more than just a pitchfork.
TSOUKALOS: So is it possible
that the lightning bolt and
the trident is some type of a
direct energy device?
NARRATOR: Arguably, one of
the most important of the Greek
gods was Apollo, who rode the
skies in his chariot of fire.
Von D NIKEN: Apollo first
was the teacher of the young
Greeks living there.
He teach them how to make
buildings on the mountain, on
the hillside.
He teach them how to make roads.
He teach them in astronomy.
NARRATOR: Centuries later,
when Rome ruled over Europe and
the Mediterranean, from the
first century BC until the
seventh century AD, the Romans
paid homage to gods similar to
the Greeks.
Zeus was now known as Jupiter.
Poseidon was called Neptune.
But Apollo was known to both
the Romans and the Greeks.
Coincidence?
Or, as most ancient astronaut
theorists believe, was it the
historical account of powerful
beings that came to Earth
thousands of years ago?
(neighing)
MARTELL: We know that the
extraterrestrials more than
likely are the source of what
they call gods.
How did they get here?
More than likely in some type of
craft.
Philip COPPENS: What we map
into our myths and our legends
are incredible stories,
incredible events, and any
extraterrestrial being, any
ancient alien who has come here
on Earth, will be written down
into this account because it is
such an extraordinary event that
it'll be marked forever.
NARRATOR: But if the stories
of Greek and Roman gods are
true, can evidence of their
existence be found in other
parts of the globe?
And, if so, where did they go?
NARRATOR: On the northwest
coast of France, just South of
Brittany, lies one of the e most
important prehistoric sites in
Europe.
At the seaside village of
Carnac, over 3,000 megalithic
stones are placed in rows over
two miles long.
The Carnac stones were hewn from
local rock formations and
erected between 4,500 to 2,500
BC, at the end of the Stone Age.
They are the largest collection
of standing stones in the
world.
CHILDRESS: Archaeologists are
baffled by the many megaliths at
Carnac here.
It's clearly a massive
construction project with blocks
of granite weighing 50 to 100,
to even up to 350 tons.
Legends here say that giants
built Carnac, but you have to
wonder, what is the real purpose
of these giant megaliths, and
why would prehistoric people
have moved all of these massive
stones and placed them in the
many alignments here at Carnac?
CREMO: Thousands of large
stones have been arranged in
very interesting patterns.
They're arranged in intersecting
lines that form triangles that
could only be visible from above
the Earth.
These arrangements of stones
may have been a way of
communicating with
extraterrestrial beings.
NARRATOR: The ancient Greek
poet Pindar spoke of a mystical
land called Hyperborea, far to
the north, where the sun shined
24 hours a day.
Legends claim that Apollo
visited Hyperborea, traveling in
his chariot of fire every
20 years.
TSOUKALOS: Apollo would tell
to the Greeks, "Okay, I've got
to go see some other people.
"I've got to go and teach them."
And they're, like, "Well, where
are you off to?"
And he's, like, "Well, I'm
actually going to a place that's
beyond where the north wind
comes.
It's the land of the
"Hyperboreans."
NARRATOR: Although mainstream
archaeologists speculate that
the Carnac stones are most
likely tomb markers, ancient
astronaut theorists believe
these stones are intentionally
laid out in a unique geometric
formation.
Von D NIKEN: Many
speculations existed since
centuries, and only a few years
ago, in France, they started to
photograph this whole French
Brittany by helicopters.
And when they put the pictures
together, all of a sudden,
someone realized, hey, this is
not coincidence.
The distances of the lines are
always the same... 2,860 meters.
Or exactly the half of 2,860
meters.
The angles are always the same.
It's Pythagorean triangles.
It's all a gigantic
geometrical pattern.
From Stone Age, which
is impossible.
Our Stone Age people had no idea
of Pythagoras' triangles.
Pythagoras was about 420 BC.
NARRATOR: Even though the
geometric arrangement of the
Carnac stones predates the
Pythagorean theorem by more
than 2,000 years, one question
remains:
Why were the stones arranged in
such a precise pattern?
CHILDRESS: The Carnac stones
are one of the few things on the
planet that can actually be seen
from space.
And they're a perfect marker for
any kind of aerial vehicle
looking down on the Earth.
Many of the tourists w who com
here to Carnac claim that they
can actually feel the energy
emanating from these granite
megaliths.
How did these ancient people
know about this energy?
Is it possible that they were
able to use this energy to even
move and erect these giant
stones?
Von D NIKEN: I am of the
opinion that they were made on
purpose.
The extraterrestrials told our
ancestor: do this and this.
It's not the extraterrestrials
who made the stone lines.
It's the humans who made it,
but by the order of the
extraterrestrials.
NARRATOR: But were the Carnac
stones a signpost for an ancient
astronaut called Apollo, as he
flew his spacecraft high above
the land?
CHILDRESS: If the Greek God
Apollo was really some kind of
ancient astronaut, it's possible
that the stones here at Carnac
were a directional finder
pointing the way to the far
north, to the Hyperborea of the
ancient gods.
NARRATOR: Over 1,000 miles
north of Carnac lies
Scandinavia, home to an ancient
people called the Norse.
The Norse were tribal Germanic
people who lived in what is now
known as Sweden, Denmark,
Iceland and Norway.
Norse legends record the
triumphs of great warriors with
advanced weaponry, sophisticated
combat techniques s and
navigational p prowess.
Like the Greeks, Norse mythology
includes supernatural beings,
other worlds and powerful gods.
But like the Romans, could the
Norse myths refer not to
different gods, but the same
gods as those depicted by the
ancient Greeks?
CHILDRESS: There are a number
of similarities between Greek
mythology and Norse mythology.
And many of the gods are, uh,
almost identical.
And they do much the same thing.
(thunder cracks, rumbles)
NARRATOR: Descriptions of the
Viking God Odin... the God of
war, death and knowledge...
and the Greek God Zeus, bear
striking similarities.
Jonathan YOUNG: Zeus and
Odin are both sky father gods.
They travel through the skies
in chariots because they are
akin to the solar, uh,
divinities.
The precursor to many, uh,
religious beliefs is sun
worship.
The ancients knew that life came
from the sun.
So that is a great mystery and
a source of great awe.
COPPENS: What you're getting
there is not just some minor
deity, but you really are
nailing it down to one of the
chief deities.
This is a very important
character.
And so whoever is behind Odin
or Zeus is obviously a person,
or a divine entity, which is
shared by these cultures.
And it's clear that whoever
inspired the myth of Zeus or
Odin is somehow somebody who had
an extremely important
contribution to make to both
civilizations.
So this entity was definitely
known throughout Europe.
NARRATOR: Ancient alien
theorists also point to
similarities between the
sophisticated weapons possessed
by both the Norse and the Greek
gods.
Among Odin's weapons was a spear
that never missed its target.
The Norse God Thor, God of
storms, strength and fertility,
wielded a powerful hammer.
TSOUKALOS: Right there we
have a correlation, a
connection, because not only
does Zeus have the thunderbolt,
but what does Odin have?
And Thor?
They have a hammer.
Thor has a hammer with which he
can smash things, destroy
things, and, you know, the
hammer idea is pretty close with
the description to the lightning
rod that Zeus has.
CHILDRESS: So you have to
wonder if these tales of Zeus's
thunderbolts, Thor's hammer...
if these weren't real weapons,
just like we have today, where
we have directed energy-beam
weapons, or are developing some
kind of literal thunderbolt
coming out of a spacecraft.
(weapons zapping)
(wind whistling)
NARRATOR: But such
similarities are not limited o
the Greek and Norse myths.
In India, the ancient epic of
the Mahabharata describes
visitations from gods that
possessed the advanced
technology of space travel.
Von D NIKEN: There you can
read, some thousands of years
ago, gigantic cities surrounded
our planet.
They used the word "cities,"
because they had no word for
"mother spaceship."
And of a sudden, out of these
cities, smaller spacecrafts
came out.
Of course, in ancient India,
they had no word like
"spacecraft," so they called it
"Vimana."
>> NARRATOR: The ancient texts
of the Hebrew Bible also
describes a prophet who traveled
the skies in a sophisticated
machine.
>> Von D NIKEN: Who is Enoch?
He was the seventh antediluvian
prophet in the Old Testament,
including the Torah of the
Jewish community.
Enoch is only described with two
phrases, that's all.
And it says that the Lord took
him away in a fiery chariot
into the heaven.
>> NARRATOR: But technology was
not the only characteristic
these ancient deities had in
common.
According to legends, the gods
enjoyed intimate relations with
humans.
But if aliens did choose human
women as their sexual partners,
what was their motivation?
And just what was the outcome of
these very close encounters?
NARRATOR: Ancient myths are
full of stories of gods
descending to Earth to mate with
humans.
CHILDRESS: According to many
sources, including Norse
mythology, Greek mythology and
even the Bible, we have the
stories of the sons of God,
or actual gods, from Mount
Olympus or Valhalla, and
they're coming to Earth.
They find, uh, the daughters of
men attractive.
TSOUKALOS: When all these
encounters happened, and when
women slept with those gods...
which can be found in multiple
texts all around the planet...
that those women actually had
sex with extraterrestrials,
not with gods.
'Cause gods do not exist.
(thunder crashing, rumbling)
NARRATOR: According to
Homer's Iliad, the citizens of
Sparta were renowned for their
heroic warriors and their
beautiful women.
Zeus, the Greek God of the sky,
admired a human named Leda.
One afternoon, while Leda walked
alone in an orchard, Zeus
changed into a swan, enveloped
her in his powerful wings, and
made love to her.
Only later did Leda realize she
had been impregnated by a God.
CHILDRESS: When you look at
Greek mythology, and many of the
mythologies around the world,
they have these stories of gods
coming down from the sky, and
have sexual intercourse
with these humans, and, in a
sense, create a new breed of
human.
NARRATOR: The offspring of
these couplings were described
by the ancients as demigods, or
half-gods.
Experts suggest demigods were
supernatural hybrid beings of
human and alien origin.
Ancient Greeks believed these
beings were exceptional...
and destined to perform
extraordinary feats.
COPPENS: It is a tradition in
many civilizations that there
were certain human children
who were somehow not human, but
somehow had a connection to the
stars, to a realm beyond Earth.
And this specialness seems to be
there from birth, and it somehow
seems to involve a DNA
component, which maybe science
needs to look at, and needs
to study.
NARRATOR: Some of the oldest
accounts of gods and humans
interbreeding can be found in
ancient Hindu texts.
CREMO: In the ancient
Sanskrit writings of India, we
find this account:
A Queen named Kunti mated with
a celestial being, an
extraterrestrial, who was known
as the sun God.
The product of this mating was
Karna, one of the heroes of the
Indian epic, the Mahabharata.
NARRATOR: Perhaps the most
famous demigod is the Greek
hero Heracles, also known as
the Roman Hercules.
Heracles was half-man/half-god,
conceived in the union of Zeus
and a mortal woman named
Alcmene.
Mainstream scholars have often
dismissed the tales of demigods
as fantasy.
(thunder crashing)
But ancient astronaut theorists
believe they reflect actual
living entities.
CREMO: These types of
accounts in the ancient wisdom
traditions have a modern
equivalent in accounts of alien
terrestrial hybrids, which is
part of the modern UFO alien
abduction type of account.
It's remarkable that we find,
in these modern reports, exact
equivalents in the ancient
accounts.
That suggests that we're
dealing with realities here.
We're not just dealing with
imaginary stories.
NARRATOR: Ancient astronaut
theorists say the term "star
children" is another way to
describe the offspring of
humans and ancient
extraterrestrials.
They claim that in the early
traditions of nearly every
major world religion,
"star children" correlate to
supernatural beings known as
"gods."
TSOUKALOS: "Star child" is
an often-used reference in
ancient texts when a woman had
a quote, unquote "divine
interaction" with one of the
gods, often resulting in a woman
being pregnant without having
slept with anyone.
You know, is such a thing even
possible?
Yes, it is.
Today, artificial insemination.
That's what happens today.
You no longer have to have sex
in order to have babies.
We have the exact same
description thousands of years
ago, where women, without
sleeping with anyone, all of a
sudden became pregnant, and the
question is how is that
possible?
NARRATOR: Did aliens that
came to Earth in ancient times
use advanced fertility
technology?
CHILDRESS: Within Greek
mythology you have many strange
stories of centaurs, uh...
cyclops, weird genetically
human, uh, half animal
creations.
And you have to speculate,
at least to a point, that
there's a possibility of
strange genetic engineering
going on here, and creating
what are literal monsters in
the past.
CREMO: In some of the
writings of ancient
civilizations, we see accounts
of mating between
extraterrestrial beings and
humans, producing monsters or
giants or other similar types
of beings.
And why is that?
I believe it's because it has
actually happened in the past.
NARRATOR: Could these ancient
tales of enormous creatures...
half human, half beast...
be rooted in truth?
And if so, is there any
evidence these giant hybrids
really existed?
NARRATOR: Lovelock, Nevada.
In the early 1800s, local
legends passed down by the Piute
Indians told of a race of
giants who were exterminated by
their tribe.
It is said this was done by
trapping the giants in a cave,
shooting arrows at them, and
then starting a large fire at
the mouth of the cave.
Evidence of the slaughter lay
undisturbed until the early 2h
recenty.
CHILDRESS: Lovelock Cave was
first discovered by local
ranchers who were looking for
bat guano to use in their
fields.
NARRATOR: In need of
fertilizer for their crops, the
ranchers removed nearly ten
feet of guano-enriched soil
from the surface of the cave.
They found up to 40 or 50 people
inside this cave.
One was allegedly seven feet,
seven inches tall.
They all had long, red hair and
were literal giants.
NARRATOR: If these skeletons
were the remains of the
legendary red-haired giants,
were they visitors from distant
continents?
CHILDRESS: Throughout the
19th century, many giant
skeletons were allegedly
discovered in the Midwest, also
in parts of California and
around Death Valley.
And the skeletons here, found at
Lovelock, are one of the few
that were really excavated by
an accredited university.
NARRATOR: Archaeologists from
the Nevada Historical Society
and the University of
California believe the cave was
occupied from approximately
1500 BC until a few hundred
years before white men appeared
in the Nevada territory.
75 miles from the cave site,
a local museum has preserved
several skulls that some
believe are recovered remains
of the giants.
CHILDRESS: Inside this
cabinet here, are three skulls
from the Lovelock caves.
When you first see these skulls,
they seem to be pretty much
normal-looking skulls.
However, it's when we really
start to compare the jawbones
with this modern dental
impression of a normal adult
male, that we see that these
jawbones are unusually large.
And these are, really, the
skulls of giant people who were
perhaps seven, even eight feet
tall.
One of the odd things with these
skulls is that they're not
actually put on display here at
the museum.
And they're kept hidden in this
cabinet.
Now, we don't know if that's
really, uh, just out of, um,
respect for, uh, Native
Americans, or whether there's
really something unusual about
these giant skulls that they
don't want them to display.
NARRATOR: Are the Nevada
bones evidence of a race of
giants that existed all through
early human history?
If so, could the giants be the
descendants of
extraterrestrials?
According to the Hebrew
Testament, one such giant
appeared in the valley of Elah
2,500 years ago.
Each morning, for 40 days, a
Philistine giant over nine feet
tall challenged the Israelites
to a fight.
His name was Goliath.
COPPENS: David and Goliath
is one of those episodes
in the Bible where you
wonder what is going on.
Is it t just a metaphor or are e
dealing with a fundamental
interpretation?
And in that sense, Goliath has
to be a giant creature.
The question then is: "He cannot
be human. What is he?"
NARRATOR: David's stunning
triumph over Goliath was
considered a mere fable,
until archaeologists turned up
evidence that suggests this
confrontation really did happen.
On the outskirts of
Tell Es-Safi, Israel, scientists
discovered a moat that may have
once protected the Philistine
fortress.
Nearby, they found shards of
pottery inscribed with the name
Goliath.
Tests indicate the pottery is
from the same time period as
described in the Bible.
Ancient astronaut theorists
claim this is unmistakable
evidence of extraterrestrial
giants in biblical times.
And they say there is much more.
The most common megalithic
construction known is the
dolmen.
Believed to be burial chambers,
they are found throughout
Europe, the Middle East, South
America, and Asia.
Could these mega structures be
the ruins of giants?
COPPENS: Archeology likes
to use the word "dolmen," but
they were formerly known in
folklore as "giant's graves."
FATHER William FULCO: A
dolmen is shaped like the Greek
letter "pi" with the top on it.
And they're made of enormous
blocks of limestone.
And even today, it's...
We are marveled that anyone
could construct those things,
and wonder how they got the top
on top of the uprights.
And those were built during the
Middle Bronze Period, which is
roughly 2000 to 1500 before the
common era.
So seeing things like that,
people questioned, those
must've been made by giants.
I mean, ordinary people could
not have done that.
COPPENS: Are we dealing with
metaphors or are we dealing
with hard evidence?
Are these physical creatures
which somehow roamed the earth?
And I think, on volume, we have
to accept that some of these
were real.
The question, then, is how did
these genetic freaks come about?
TSOUKALOS: One of the main
tenets of ancient astronaut
theory suggests that a long
time ago, extraterrestrials
changed our genetic makeup
through a targeted mutation of
our genes, essentially in the
lab.
So they took a couple of human
beings, altered their DNA, then
reinserted those people back
into the population, so through
procreation, those people would
pass on those new genetic
alterations to the entire
population.
NARRATOR: Ancient astronaut
theorists suggest the evidence
points to one conclusion, that
aliens changed the genetics of
early human DNA.
COPPENS: For an alien being
to work with DNA is so easy
that just creating a new type
is not at all that difficult.
Even today, we have the
capability to create new types
of animals.
The question is, were we
created as such, as well?
NARRATOR: But what reason
could extraterrestrial visitors
have had for populating the
Earth with mixed species and
monstrous hybrids?
Were they the result of some
kind of scientific experiment
gone terribly wrong?
Did ancient aliens have some
reason to experiment with human
DNA?
NARRATOR: The Galapagos
Islands, off the coast of South
America, are known for their
unique biodiversity.
In 1832, a naturalist named
Charles Darwin came to these
islands to observe and record
several species of animals not
seen before.
The result of his studies
formed the basis for his
controversial book, The Origin
of Species.
In it, Darwin proposed his
theory of evolution, which
held that all life evolved over
time, through a process of
natural selection.
But even Darwin's theories
could not explain the
developmental gap between apes
and man.
There was, it was believed,
a transitional species that had
to exist, one which became
referred to as, "the missing
link."
>> TSOUKALOS: Homo Sapiens have
been around for 300,000 years.
And only in a few thousand
years, our brain size
essentially tripled.
Now, that does not jive with
ordinary evolution.
You need time.
A very long time.
However, today, biologists
cannot quite put a finger on
how our brain volume tripled in
a very short time period.
That is still a mystery.
>> NARRATOR: Could it be, as
many ancient astronaut
theorists believe, that ancient
aliens had a hand in
jump-starting human evolution
on our planet?
>> COPPENS: Science has been
unable to find the missing link,
and maybe that's simply because
Earth is unable to offer that
missing link.
Maybe the missing link is not
of this Earth.
Maybe the missing link is
somewhere outside,
extraterrestrial.
>> NARRATOR: In 1996, medical
science took a giant step
forward when geneticists
successfully cloned a sheep.
This revolutionary technology
marked a significant
advancement in our
understanding of DNA.
But could extraterrestrial
visitors have also possessed
knowledge of genetics?
>> MARTELL: In the Sumerian
records of mythology, they
explain how they genetically
engineered the first human
being.
And so, it's very possible that
extraterrestrials did
genetically engineer us.
>> COPPENS: More and more
creatures are being discovered,
as s science goes along, in
little caves, or on little
islands, whereby DNA evidence
clearly shows that something
else has been happening.
We're probably gonna get to
hard scientific fact that
something interbred with humans,
on certain occasions, certain
moments in time.
>> NARRATOR: Could the giants
and monsters described in the
ancient myths be examples of
genetic mutations?
And if so, what purpose might
they have served?
>> CREMO: There are actually
accounts in the ancient
Sanskrit writings of India of
how, in their original attempts
to produce...
living things in the universe,
the gods, or the
extraterrestrial beings, made
mistakes and produced different
types of monsters and giants
and things like that.
>> Von D NIKEN: Why should the
so-called "gods" first make such
mixed creatures?
What's the purpose of it?
Did they observe a lion, and
they say to themself, "Why don't
we mix the strongness of the
muscle of the one animal with
the heat expellant, uh, skin of
the other animal, to use it at
some other planet, which is
different Earth?"
So they start to make breedings.
They start to make mixed
creatures.
>> NARRATOR: Scholars and
archaeologists generally agree
that sometime around 3000 BC,
during the Megalithic Era,
mankind took a quantum leap
forward with regard to
civilization and use of
technology.
According to myths and legends,
human beings gave credit to
their gods for giving them
this knowledge.
But if the gods were, in fact,
alien visitors, might mankind's
quantum leap forward have had a
more intergalactic origin?
>> COPPENS: It is clear that
something affected multiple
continents on this planet
around 3000 BC.
The pyramids began to be built
at that moment in time.
Why?
What was that imperative?
Was it a global imperative?
Yes.
Was it an imperative which came
from outside of this world?
Yes.
>> NARRATOR: If aliens
intervened to speed the
advancement of human beings, is
it also possible that they have
influenced mankind at other
critical junctures in history?
And, if so, could they have
continued to monitor us,
even today?
>> MARTELL: It's very possible
that, if there was some type of
genetic intervention,
by an extraterrestrial race,
on humanity, they would be very
interested to see their
experiment progress.
>> Von D NIKEN: I am often
asked the question, "Iit not
ridiculous to believe that
extraterrestrials should, in a
way or other, look similar to
us, or even think similar
to us?"
No.
The question is wrong.
They are not, by coincidence,
similar to us, but we are
similar to them, because we are
the product.
>> NARRATOR: But if alien
beings did interbreed with
humans, why?
Was it to save their own
species?
Or, perhaps, hide the genetic
traces of their presence here
on Earth?
Could there even be aliens
living among us?
Sync by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com