ALEJANDRA GAITAN:
So hi, everyone.
I just saw this video
of a dog--
FEMALE SPEAKER 1: --at
a vet's office--
MEGAN LEE HEART: --giving
the person behind
the register a receipt.
ALEJANDRA GAITAN: It's
just really, really--
MEGAN LEE HEART: --cute.
FEMALE SPEAKER 2: So,
anyways, yeah.
TIM SAVAGE: There's a trend
happening on YouTube right now
which, basically, is just a
bunch of fat-titty girls
making stupid-ass reply videos
to everything that comes out.
MALE SPEAKER 1: They're
flipping everywhere.
Even on this video, because it's
about reply girls, there
will be about five down here
to the left of me.
You look down at the related
videos, there will probably be
some reply girls there.
THE LUCHADOR: They
do shitty videos.
They're completely terrible.
TIM SAVAGE: Just these girls
yapping nonsense for long
enough to fit an ad in so
they can make money.
THE LUCHADOR: People take hours,
and hours, and hours to
produce a quality video
and original content.
And they just pretty much watch
it, reply, and they get
100 times what I would get
in views-- and like this.
MALE SPEAKER 1: The end result
is almost painful to watch.
MALE SPEAKER 2: Oh, hey guys.
MALE SPEAKER 3: Oh,
it made me so hot.
MALE SPEAKER 4:
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
ADOLF HITLER: [SPEAKING GERMAN]
ALEJANDRA GAITAN: Peace and
love, guys, see you.
Thank you very much
for watching, bye.
Now, in case you don't me, I
am the Reply Girl, probably
one of YouTube's most hated
personalities right now.
[SPANISH]
When I started YouTube-ing, I
was below the poverty line,
and I really, really, really
needed a way to get out of
that situation.
Hi guys.
My first month, I made enough
to pay a cellphone bill.
And I worked so much.
Well, it's very simple.
You go on YouTube and
you look for the
videos that are trending.
I like those that are, like,
random and funny.
Good morning, Senor Luchador.
I brought you breakfast with
lots of lots of bacon.
[SCREAM]
THE LUCHADOR: Alejandra, well,
to be honest, she is my
girlfriend's sister.
And [INAUDIBLE] she's
my YouTube mentor.
And we can offer that service.
[INAUDIBLE] service of having a
studio with a green screen,
and having like interns.
ALEJANDRA GAITAN: Well, the
thing is that-- what you're
putting at stake is your
skills and your time.
What I'm putting in stakes
is my money.
So if it doesn't
work, OK, fine.
You wasted your time.
But me, my money's going to be
gone, and I'll be screwed.
THE LUCHADOR: Alejandra actually
pretty much convinced
me to start making videos
on YouTube.
ALEJANDRA GAITAN: Hey
guys, I just saw--
THE LUCHADOR: Reply
Girl, Reply Girl.
I need some advice.
Haters are trying to get at
me, and you know what?
I've got to go break their
necks one by one.
[GRUNT]
Well, what happened was that
she showed me her check.
And it was a nice check.
For what she does, it was a
very, very beautiful check.
ALEJANDRA GAITAN: I always
wanted to be an autonomous
worker, or have a company,
or make money on my
own, be my own boss.
And I just never knew what,
exactly, I wanted to do to
make it happen.
I just knew I want
it to happen.
I studied programming.
But it didn't work out very well
because I'm not a very
good programmer.
And yeah, I also did
some babysitting.
But that's about it.
THE LUCHADOR: I tried doing
replies myself.
And believe it or not, it's
a harder job than
you think it is.
It's long.
It's boring, tedious,
it's annoying.
I mean, it's not a fun job.
And the haters, people out there
who are hating on reply
people, and, like, oh you
know, what they do is
brainless--
you know what?
Do it yourself.
If you don't like it, don't
do it and don't watch it.
Simple as that.
First times that these haters--
they're posting
videos and threads about finding
her address, her IP
address, and knowing
where she lives.
I've seen posts on
YouTube, people
actually posting an address.
They thought that they found her
address, and they posted
it everywhere.
What kind of a bad person are
you to take a hated person's
address and post it
to the public?
So some crazy person comes over
and sees the address and
does something that they're
going to regret
later on, you know?
Oh Jesus.
If only they knew.
I'm waiting.
ALEJANDRA GAITAN: Like, I mean,
I know you are going to
interview Megan, but you
shouldn't do it because she
has tried to destroy me and to
destroy everybody else that
has done replies.
MEGAN LEE HEART: Look, the
Reply Girl, Alejandra--
shut up.
Drop it.
It's getting out of hand.
THE LUCHADOR: Megan understood
that Alejandra and all the
other reply people
are competition.
So the way to get them off
YouTube is to threaten them,
send death letters, try to hack
them, try to find their
address to go and send people
to do things, which is
completely unethical.
ALEJANDRA GAITAN: They leave all
sorts of comments, like,
I'm going to rape you.
We're going to go to your house
and slit your throat.
THE LUCHADOR: Vicious.
When you talk about,
feline, cat crazy--
vicious, you've got that side.
ALEJANDRA GAITAN: What's
this expression--
a dog that barks too much
but that doesn't bite?
TIM SAVAGE: Now a couple of
weeks ago I had a video about
the reply girls.
And the craziest thing to me was
they could not understand
how someone could watch their
videos and think that they
were stupid and annoying.
For those that are initiated
with the character, and what
I'm trying to do with satire
of white trash America, and
that kind of thing-- probably
1 out of every 10 comments
that I get personally is, I'm
going to fucking kill you.
When I worked in radio, I had a
couple of hate calls a week.
But online, I get a couple of
hate comments a second--
every second.
The anonymity of the internet
gives people that feeling of
power that they can do
whatever they want.
And they don't understand
the responsibility.
I understand, she's just
somebody that's trying to make
it, you know?
Not even make it, but,
like, make it by--
And, of course, a little
bit of attention.
Who doesn't like attention.
ALEJANDRA GAITAN: So this is
a video of me modelling.
Look, let's be honest here--
that's just the way, sorry
to say it, male brain in
particular interprets
certain images.
One cannot deny it--
sex appeal, it's a winner.
I don't think it can
open, actually.
No it doesn't open.
If I was earning good money,
I would move out.
But since I can't, I'd rather
stay here in safety.
I actually have lots
of clothes.
It's amazing.
Due to the fact that I'm living
in this house, I can
only wear certain types of
shirts, even if I do have a
lot of clothing.
Let's just say family
conflicts.
They're too sexy.
ALEJANDRA GAITAN: I can see
it bothers her a lot.
She expected us to follow the
traditional way and to, what
can I say, get a job, work all
of your life, and then, at the
end of your life, when you are,
like, useless, retire.
Whose happiness is
more important?
I pick mine over hers.
My father is back in Latin
America because we were about
to immigrate, and he kind
of just hooked up
with another girl.
So--
At the beginning, we used to
talk like once a month.
But as years passed by, I think
it was, like, twice a
year, and then it
was once a year.
And it's been like six to eight
months since I don't
talk to him, so--
THE LUCHADOR: Her traffic
went completely shut.
It went down like crazy.
The way that the YouTube
algorithm is
changing her business--
also changing everyone's.
ALEJANDRA GAITAN: One day,
without warning, I saw this--
poof.
And I was, like, Jesus,
Lord, mercy.
What am I going to do now?
I plan to keep on YouTube-ing.
And in the future, I'm not
really sure what I would do.
Oy.
Hello, Pollux.
You know what's funny, people
think that I'm this party
animal, that I go out and
have fun and enjoy and
do this and do that.
But no, in reality I'm
a very lonely person.
And I like to stay in my room.
I almost never go out.
And I'm just OK here,
in my house.
Kind of--
I don't know.
I wonder if it would have been
better if he had just, if we
would have just broke.
But you never expect your
boyfriend to die and to die in
such a way.
He was a kind man.
He was a kind man, sir.
He was a good boy.
And well, I don't know if I'll
look for somebody, or if I'll
just stay alone, you know?