CARL AZUZ, CNN ANCHOR: That was an enthusiastic
intro, and credit goes to Ms. Bamer`s (ph)
students for today`s hello. Glad to have all
of you, middle and high school students out
there watching as CNN STUDENT NEWS kicks off
its Tuesday, November 27th broadcast.
Starting in the U.S. northeast today, we`ve
talked about how the recovery from Superstorm
Sandy is going to take a while. There are
thousands of people who can`t get back in
their homes, miles of pipes have to be reconnected,
mold, as we show you yesterday, has to be
dealt with. And bills.
Everything from cleanup costs to unpaid bills
from people who had to evacuate. Those are
piling up. These were few of the issues brought
up yesterday, during a state hearing in New
Jersey. Officials there are trying to get
a handle on two things : how to pay for reconstruction
efforts and what kinds of plans can be made
to better protect the area if another storm
hits.
Meanwhile, New York has gotten $27 million
from the federal government to hire about
5,000 unemployed New Yorkers for work on Sandy
cleanup projects. The job will be full-time,
but temporary. New York`s governor and New
York City`s mayor are asking for more federal
money to make additional repairs in their
state.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today`s first "Shoutout"
goes out to Mr. Weisbeck`s senior government
class at Timber Lake High School in Timber
Lake, South Dakota.
Lewis Hamilton, Dario Frachitti and Juan Pablo
Montoya are all known for their roles in what?
You know what to do. Are they all involved
in auto racing, theater, horse racing or Congress?
You`ve got three seconds, go!
All three of these guys are involved in auto
racing. That`s your answer, and that`s your
"Shoutout."
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: And you can add Tristan Nunez to that
list. At 17 years old, he`s around your age,
he is one of the youngest auto racing champions
ever. And what better spokesman against distracted
driving than someone who wants to race cars
for a living? Victor Blackwell joins us now
with the tale of two talents: one about a
driver, one about somebody who is hoping that
one day, phones and driving will disconnect.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: All right, drivers! Come
get in line over here, please!
VICTOR BLACKWELL, CNN CORRESPONDENT: Race
car drivers on a race track. No big surprise.
What might surprise you is that the favorite
to win this race is just 17-years old.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: And you have half the field
this side, half the field this size.
BLACKWELL: He is Tristan Nunez from Boca Raton,
Florida. He started racing go-carts at 13.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Just do what you know.
BLACKWELL: And then graduated to this at 15,
before he was licensed to drive through his
neighborhood.
TRISTAN NUNEZ, TEEN RACECAR DRIVER: My mom
and myself actually feel safer driving on
a race track with professional drivers than
driving on the regular roads with people who
have no idea what they are doing.
BLACKWELL: He revs up to above 150 miles per
hour around this track.
(on camera): At that speed, there can be any
little distraction.
NUNEZ: Yes,
BLACKWELL: It can be - and injury could be
death.
NUNEZ: Fatal.
BLACKWELL (voice over): Actually, that can
happen at any speed.
Before the start of the racing season, a little
distraction off the track nearly created a
major problem.
NUNEZ: I was with my mom in the car, and we
almost got into accident because she was face
booking, emailing, whatever. Distracted.
DIANE NUNEZ, MOTHER: We almost reared-ended
somebody, and he, you know, that`s when we
really - it really hit us, you know, and he
is like, mom, you`ve got to put the phone
down.
BLACKWELL: So Tristan and his mom, Diane Nunez
had an idea: to inspire other people, especially
young people to put the phone down, by branding
his car the "don`t text and drive car."
DIANE NUNEZ: And we put all over the car,
and put in on a suit and then put it on the
Web site and just took off.
BLACKWELL (on camera): And you`ve got the
bracelet because when they raise up there,
their hand ...
NUNEZ: Their hand ...
BLACKWELL: ... with the phone.
NUNEZ: With the phone, they see it, exactly.
BLACKWELL: Yeah.
NUNEZ: So, I mean - it just serves as a constant
reminder not to do it.
BLACKWELL (voice over): Hundreds of teens
have pledged to not text and drive, some had
even signed Tristan`s car as part of the pledge.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: It`s just distracting.
It`s - you get caught up in another world,
completely separate from what you are trying
to do.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: There is not really a lot
of teenage race car drivers out there, so
it was - it was definitely good for them to
go on to a teenager`s car.
DIANE NUNEZ: I know we are not going to stop
it, but at least it`s going to bring more
awareness to people.
BLACKWELL: Tristan was the big winner on this
day at Road Atlanta (ph).
NUNEZ: I would be here.
BLACKSTONE: And he tells teens to look up
to him. The key to his success on the track
is the same key to staying safe on the road.
NUNEZ: You have to have 100 percent focus,
you can`t lose your focus for any - any reason
at all.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Time for "Shoutout Extra
Credit."
What game was invented by James Naismith?
Here we go. Was it basketball, Monopoly, Mario
Bros. or American football? Another three
seconds on the clock and go.
While teaching phys. ed at a YMCA in 1891,
James Naismith invented basketball. That`s
your answer and that`s your Shoutout Extra
Credit.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: So James Naismith invented it, Michael
Jordan mastered it, Wilt Chamberlain holds
the record for the most point scored in a
single NBA game. That`s 100. But as far as
the most point scored in a college game- go,
that record has stood at 113 sine 1954. At
least until this sophomore dunked it. His
name is Jack Taylor (ph). He goes to Grinell
College in Iowa. He`s 5 feet 10, a shooting
guard, and he recently had a game that was
so amazing that Kobe Bryant and LeBron James
tweeted about it. 138 points. That`s the new
record. That`s what Taylor netted in a single
game. CNN Soledad O`Brien spoke to him about
it. How he managed to put up so many points
and how that was unusual, even for someone
as talented as Taylor.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
SOLEDAD O`BRIEN, CNN CORRESPONDENT: I guess,
congratulations first are in order. You were
averaging roughly 23 points per game before
the big game. What do you think happened that
day?
JACK TAYLOR, GRINELL COLLEGE BASKETBALL PLAYER:
Yeah. I think it was - I think it was kind
of once in a lifetime thing to happen. Coming
into the game, I knew I was going to get more
shots than usual. But I definitely hit more
shots than I though that I would and at half
time I had 58. My team and coaches kind of
gathered around me and we were going to get
me the ball every time down the floor. So,
this record won`t be possible without my unselfish
teammates.
O`BRIEN: You know, it`s interesting, because
some people give me a little flack about the
selfishness thing. Stuart Scott On ESPN said
this: "Not a big fan of Jack Taylor`s 138-point
in Grinell win. He took 108 shots, including
71 3`s. Just say that out loud. Now say "team"!
He`s basically insinuating that you were - were
a ball hog, how do you respond to that?
TAYLOR: Yeah, I mean I definitely was a ball
hog ...
(laughter)
TAYLOR: But my teammates kept getting me the
ball. When I would pass it off to them, they
were trying to get me the ball right back,
because they knew I was hot.
And in the second half, we started going for
the record when - when my shots were falling.
So, it was a team effort to get me the ball,
and they kept encouraging me to shoot, which
only gave me more confidence.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: You`d need more confidence to attempt
a record like that. I don`t think I could
score that much just shooting hoops on my
own.
So, 138 points is 138 points, or is it?
There is no disputing what Taylor score, but
as you just heard, some people do dispute
whether he should be recognized for how he
did it.
On out blog at CNNSTUDENTNEWS.COM we are talking
about this. We`d love to hear your opinion
on whether Taylor was a ball hog or a basketball
star?
Please, on that blog, it`s first names only,
please include only your first name.
Before we go, we`ve got some interesting images
for you of Santas getting in shape. It`s the
Santa Claus festival in Sydney, Australia
where it`s actually summer now, so St. Nick
could show off his lack of a tan. The run
benefited children in need, it`s called a
Claus for a Cause, and some, as you just saw,
swapped the sleigh for skis. Fireworks tried
to outshine the Rudolph, one Santa used a
water jetpack to do that. Launching the rocket
that smacked into and then lit up this massive
Christmas Tree. You could say it was sheer
Santamonium, an incomparable Santabration,
a seriously Santalizing scheme to set the
stage for the Christmas season. The advent
of this puns can leave you in a holi-daze.
So we are just going to wish you a merry Tuesday.
Look forward to bringing more news down the
chimney tomorrow. For CNN STUDENT NEWS, I`m
Carl Azuz.