You want a drink, fucker?
PATRICK O'DELL: Yes.
JON LONG: I got Jameson.
PATRICK O'DELL: No, I'm OK,
I'll have some later.
I got to film.
Hi, welcome back to the show.
This episode is about a New
Year's trip we took to Mexico.
We went to Spanky's dad's house
who has a really cool
surf shack overlooking
the ocean.
Oh, and also Jerry Hsu came
along on this trip.
And you might know Jerry from
his part in the Enjoi video,
which I think is one of the best
video parts of all time.
And we're going to ask him
a little bit about that.
The rest is just home movies.
It's just a little bit of video
from our vacation in
Mexico for New Year's Eve.
JON LONG: We're Kilometer 55.
I probably don't want to say
that, I probably want to say
Kilometer 85.
JERRY HSU: I don't
know, it's just
gangster beachfront property.
It's actually just a
converted trailer,
but it's pretty awesome.
No electricity.
MALE SPEAKER: None of
our phones work.
JERRY HSU: None of
We make quesadillas.
CHRIS SHONTING: It's
fairly amazing.
There's a surf spot in
every single-- well,
left to right direction.
When the tide goes out you can
prod animals in the sea in
tide pools.
MALE SPEAKER: He's so bummed,
there he goes.
Ah!
Dude, you popped it!
It's leaking.
CHRIS SHONTING: There was a
guy catching octopuses out
there earlier and just kind
of smashing them.
MALE SPEAKER: Whoa!
KEVIN LONG: Pulled out an
octopus, beat it with his
metal stick, and then ripped off
one of the limbs, and then
threw it in his bucket
and kept going.
MALE SPEAKER: Calamari.
MALE SPEAKER: I'm going to take
all of this footage of
Jerry walking on the beach
and I'm going to put
on really sad music.
CHRIS SHONTING: Little
delicate genius.
When he falls on a skateboard,
I start crying.
You feel like you're going to
see someone die if he falls,
because it's always
the worst fall.
Yeah, he bounces back-- like,
I've see his chin explode and
I felt it right in my nuts.
You know, you just land and
like your feet, your
board's just gone.
JERRY HSU: Ah!
God!
Fuck!
CHRIS SHONTING: I'm always
freaked out, but I'm amazed.
I don't know.
JERRY HSU: No, I haven't skated
in like-- well, I've
skated, but I've been taking
kind of an extended vacation
for like a year.
Yeah, everyone was like, you
should just take a break.
And I was like, all right.
Yeah, it's kind of weird.
I actually--
the last six months of
it was really when I
did the most of it.
For like a year and a half I was
just like, la de da, blah,
blah, blah.
But then the last six months
is always like, OK, every
single weekend just
destroy myself.
[GROAN].
God!
[SCREAM].
MALE SPEAKER: Whoa!
Ah!
Jerry!
JERRY HSU: All the big cheeses
and stuff, they're like, OK,
your part's pretty cool
but we need like
the last, last thing.
And I was like, OK.
So I went and I tried it
one day and I got hurt.
[SCREAM].
And I was like, fuck,
I'm hurt.
And it was like the last
month I could film and
I got hurt on that.
And then for like one month
straight I was just
thinking about it.
Like, oh man, I got to
go back and do that.
And I was super scared that I
was going to jump down it once
and just be like, can't do it.
I don't know.
Probably like 20?
25 or something?
But I don't know.
I never really think about
how many tries
it takes to do something.
I kind of just zone out.
Ow!
[SHOUTS].
MALE SPEAKER: Oh!
[WHISTLE].
Come on, Jerry, right
back at it.
Get this thing.
JERRY HSU: Matt, the brand
manager, he was stressing out
because he made the video.
And then he turned to me and he
was just like, well, just
go do that fucking trick
down those stairs.
And I got so mad, and I was
like, I'll show him.
I'm going to do that trick.
MALE SPEAKER: Do you have any
New Year's resolutions?
JERRY HSU: No, I should probably
start skating again.
EVERYONE: Four, three,
two, one.
MALE SPEAKER: Happy new year!
[CHEERING].
FEMALE SPEAKER: Happy
new year!
JON LONG: Paddy, me boy.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Happy
new year, Jon!
JON LONG: Happy new
year, fucker.
PATRICK O'DELL: Happy
New Year's.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Happy
new year!
MALE SPEAKER: Happy new year!
JON LONG: What's
yours, fucker?
PATRICK O'DELL: I
don't have one.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Happy
new year, Johnson!
CHRIS SHONTING: Mr. Long, he's
one of those dudes that's
honestly epic.
There's no posturing
into epicness.
Or no becoming epic over the
course of the day, by the end
of the day being epic.
It's kind of like, wake
up and just be epic.
I don't know.
I'm impressed.
JON LONG: I'm going to
tell you a couple
things about Spanky.
Here's my beef with the kid.
I wish that he let kids
know that he was
really good at school.
He never graduated.
I could give a rat's
ass about that.
I don't care about that.
But he was really good, he's
passionate about life.
And his family is all passionate
about life.
And that's what I'm trying
to say here.
That's what he does and
that's who he is.
And in that comes this place
and these people and you.
And that's passionate
about life.
OK, I'm getting philosophical
here.
Hey.
KEVIN LONG: Hey, fucker.
JON LONG: This is the--
FEMALE SPEAKER: The build up.
JON LONG: This is my friend,
my bro, my friend.
KEVIN LONG: Guys?
JON LONG: I've never told you
that, but you know what?
You're like my fucking
best friend.
KEVIN LONG: You're
my best friend.
I love you, dad.
JON LONG: I love you,
son, and I mean it.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Speech!
PATRICK O'DELL: You guys,
I love you guys.
And I want you to know that,
look at you and look at us.
You son of a bitch.
My resolution is no
more black ass.
Because I feel that when I
cheated him, it's no more.
MALE SPEAKER: Some more?
MALE SPEAKER: A s'more?
MALE SPEAKER: S'mores?
Is that what he said?
FEMALE SPEAKER: S'mores!
JON LONG: Those are
like Patrick, do I
have a tale for you.
PATRICK O'DELL: What's that?
JON LONG: You want to do it in
Spanish, English, or Irish?
PATRICK O'DELL: English.