CARL AZUZ, CNN ANCHOR: First up today on CNN
STUDENT NEWS, this Florida resident was in
his bedroom last Thursday night, suddenly,
the ground underneath opened up and swallowed
him. A sinkhole about 20 feet wide and 50
to 60 feet deep formed underneath Jeff Bush`s
room.
His brother Jeremy talked about what happened
when it started.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
JEREMY BUSH, VICTIM`S BROTHER: I heard a loud
crash like a car coming through the house.
And I remember my mother screaming, so I ran
back there, and tried going inside his room,
but when I turned the light on, all I see
was this big hole, real big hole.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Jeremy Bush jumped into that hole to
try to save his brother, but he couldn`t find
him. And officials called off their search
on Saturday, partly because of the same reason
why workers began demolishing the house. The
sinkhole was expanding, and there were concerns
that house might collapse at any time. Sometimes
sinkholes are smaller, they might cause the
ground to sag or cause or cause a small panda
form. Other times, they can be huge, like
this one you`re looking at it right now from
Guatemala.
Or the great blue hole, an underwater sinkhole
off the coast of Belize. Florida actually
gets a lot of sinkholes, and that`s because
the ground across a lot of the state is made
up of limestone, a sedimentary rock. Nick
Valencia explains how that can lead to this
sinkholes.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
NICK VALENCIA, CNN CORRESPONDENT: How do sinkholes
form? Let`s break this down for you here.
Sinkholes are usually a naturally occurring
event. Now, what happens is, rain water, that
heavy rain water sorts of sits on top of that
bedrock sanding clay. If you take into account
Florida`s landscape, but it gets a lot of
that very porous limestone. It allows the
rain, this acidic rain to sort of percolate
down into this oil forming this cave like
-- cave like sinkholes here.
And also, sometimes, it`s drought that causes
these caves-like formations. And that`s further
punctuated by that heavy rain that sort of
sits on top of there, causing this to open
up and perhaps, some of the scariest scenarios
in Florida, is that you cannot predict sinkholes.
It`s highly expensive to predict them yet.
To use very expensive equipment and it`s really
tough to pinpoint where these sinkholes are.
In fact, it`s so common about the currents
in Florida.
All of these little blue dots freckled up
and down the state of Florida are past instances
of sinkholes. Now, here, where it happened
on Thursday night in early Friday morning
in Hillsboro County at the Bush residence,
this is the place that the Florida Department
of State says is susceptible to abruptly forming
collapse sinkholes. It`s an area that`s dominated
by them, an area that`s had problems with
sinkholes in the past.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Just the facts -- Affirmative
Action aims to improve opportunities for women
and members of minority groups. It started
as a way to help people who had been discriminate
against in the past. Critics argue that it
uses reverse discrimination to accomplish
its goals. Affirmative action policies have
been used in employment and education.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Abigail Fisher says Affirmative Action
is the reason why she didn`t get in the University
of Texas. She sued the school over its admissions
policies, and the case went all the way to
the U.S. Supreme Court. The decision on it
could come out today. Joe Johns breaks down
the details of the case and some of the arguments
on both sides.
Abigail Fisher dreamed of going to the University
of Texas at Austin for most of her life. After
applying, she didn`t get in, attending Louisiana
State University instead. But the rejection
from U.T. led Fisher to file a lawsuit against
the school claiming she was squeezed out,
unfairly denied admission because of her race.
She is white. She said in a statement, "There
were people in my class with lower grades
who weren`t in all the activities I was in
who were being accepted into U.T., and the
only other difference between us was the color
of our skin."
Whether race should be part of the application
process at the University of Texas is the
issue before the Supreme Court. Edward Bloom
recruited Abigail Fisher to file the lawsuit.
EDWARD BLURN, PROJECT ON FAIR REPRESENTATION:
The most important question is, should a university
judge a student by his or her skin color when
it comes time for admission. And the answer
is no.
Here`s how the admissions process at U.T.
works: the top ten percent of each high school
class statewide gets in automatically. For
those below the top ten percent, like Abigail
Fisher, who was in the 11th percent, the university
uses what it calls, a holistic review where
race is one of many factors considered. One
that University President Bill Powers says,
doesn`t get much weight, and didn`t play role
in Fisher`s rejection.
BILL POWERS, PRESIDENT, UNIVERSITY OF TEXAS
AT AUSTIN: We take ethnicity as one of many,
many factors in our holistic review to make
sure that the three quarters coming in under
automatic admission, that we add to that with
a quarter coming in where we can work for
these other characteristics including diversity.
BRADLEY POOLE, PRESIDENT, UT BLACK STUDENT
ALLIANCE: I think she`s fighting the wrong
fight.
POWERS: Minority student leaders on campus
like Bradley Poole, agree with Powers that
the process is fair, despite Fisher`s claims.
POOLE: Seeing as race is probably one of least
the parts of the holistic review process.
I feel like it`s harping on the wrong -- on
one of the things that -- on the easiest thing
that she could have -- she could have win
against.
POWERS: Others take offense that the lawsuit
implies some minority students are less deserving
of admission than the white counterparts.
CATHERINE RODARTE, STUDENT UNIVERSITY OF TEXAST
AT AUSTIN: To hear people saying that some
of us, Latinos, got in here easily, and the
only reason we got in here is because of the
race. That`s really disappointing. We worked
just as hard as anyone else to get here to
U.T.
POWERS: But conservative groups siding with
Fisher argue it`s not just about getting in.
The U.S. civil rights commission says studies
show that using racial preferences can hurt
minorities by starting them out near the bottom
of their classes.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today`s "Shoutout" goes
out to Mr. Brown students at Clinton High
School in Clinton, Michigan.
Nairobi is the capital of what African country?
You know what to do. Is it Kenya, Tanzania,
Uganda or Zambia? You`ve got three seconds,
go!
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Nairobi is a capital
of Kenya. It`s also the country`s largest
city. That`s your answer and that`s your "Shoutout."
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Nairobi is a unique place. There is
a national park, about four miles from downtown
where zebras, rhinos and giraffes run free.
The park also had predators. 13-year old Richard
Terrere (ph) lives in a farm near the park.
He says that at night lions from the park
used to eat his family`s cattle. When he noticed
when people walked around with flashlights,
the lions stayed away. That gave Richard an
idea: first, he set up a solar panel that
charged a battery during the day. That powered
what you`re about to see, these lights right
here at night. Richard made the lights flash,
so it looked like someone was walking around
with the flashlight, and that`s been keeping
the big cats away.
Next up today, the NFL combine gives players
a chance to show off their skills to pro-teams.
Lauren Silberman was at original combine yesterday
making history as the first woman to try out
for the NFL as a place kicker. Our Women`s
History Months coverage rolls on with some
other sporting famous firsts. Back in 1977,
Janet Guthrie was the first woman to drive
in the Indianapolis 500. Julie Krone displayed
a different kind of horse power becoming the
first female jockey to win a Triple Crown
race. Babe Didrikson Zaharias broke golf`s
gender barrier in 1938. She was also an Olympic
gold medalist in track and field.
Ila Borders makes the list twice. The first
female pitcher to win in men`s baseball game
and the first woman to earn a college baseball
scholarship. In 2002, Lisa Leslie threw down
the first slam dunk in the woman`s pro game.
Ten years earlier, Manon Rheaume manned the
net for a post-season hockey game with the
Tampa Bay lightning. And in the tennis match,
that was known as the battle of the sexes
-- Billie Jean King beat Bobbie Riggs head
to head in 1973. Whether it`s as individual
or part of a team, what do you think about
women competing in traditionally male-dominated
sports? Sound off in our blog at cnnstudentnews.com.
And teachers, we`re always looking for your
feedback. Head to the resources box on our
home page, tell us what you thought about
today`s show.
You might have known that the Iditarod is
called the last great race on earth. You probably
didn`t know that most competitors cover about
110 miles a day. It`s not much if you are
driving, but if you are driving a team of
sled dogs across the Alaskan wilderness in
frigid temperatures, it`s much more intimidating.
It starts in Anchorage and ends in the remote
town of Nome, Alaska. Recalling a time around
the year 1900 when dogs sleds were used to
get supplies and mail there. Planes have been
doing it since the 1920s, except in 1925,
when there was an outbreak of the disease
diphtheria, and pilots couldn`t get through.
Then in temperatures far below zero, sled
dogs were called on once again to get medication
where it was needed. The story became so famous
that a statue of a lead dog Balto was put
up in New York. It`s still there today. The
modern Iditarod route changes from year to
year. It crosses miles of ice and two mountain
ranges. And it required teams to rest, provides
dog food at race checkpoints, and has veterinarians
and advisers to ensure that mushers and their
dogs are kept safe along a trail that used
to be anything but.
It`s always good to know the races and dogs
are watched over when they embark. It helps
keep the whole race from going downhill. And
we tried to come up with a pun on Iditarod,
but it just didn`t amount to mush. CNN STUDENT
NEWS sets off again tomorrow. See you then.