STEVE SPANGLER: Higginsworth.
HIGGINSWORTH: Sorry, Steve.
STEVE SPANGLER: I'm Steve
Spangler, and I'm all about
making science fun.
For the last 20 years, I've
been teaching ways to turn
ordinary science experiments
into unforgettable learning
experiences.
I have an amazing team who will
do whatever it takes to
affect the way people
think about science.
And to do that, I live by one
motto, make it big, do it
right, give it class.
All right.
Dog's in.
Door's locked.
We're set.
Just look around for people,
make sure we're OK.
Ready?
Run.
Go.
Go, go, go, go, go.
Higgins, I thought you
got the dog inside.
If you don't have speakers of
your own, sometimes you can
borrow your neighbors,
especially if you're
watching the dog.
You just have to
be responsible.
Higgins, get the dog back in.
-(YELLING) Doggie.
It's not going to
be a good day.
What I love about today is a
combination of old and new.
You're going to do a classic
experiment using corn starch
and water where we make this
non-Newtonian fluid.
We're going to put a little
twist on that, which makes it
kind of fun.
And that's why you're going to
need to have all the other
things that I was
talking about.
And especially these speakers
that we just bought over here.
And even though Higginsworth
broke these, this one will be
just perfectly fine.
It's just gonna need--
[EQUIPMENT CRASHING TO GROUND]
STEVE SPANGLER: OK.
But these here are going
to be perfect for
exactly what we need.
Big mixing bowl, corn
starch, you're going
to need paper towels.
And you're going to need
to have some--
water, because it's
going to be messy.
Start with the corn starch.
All right, what we're actually
making here is considered a
non-Newtonian fluid.
And more about that when we
start looking at the thickness
of the mixture.
But again, I'm not going to
dump the entire thing.
I'm gonna leave just a little
bit there, because I'm going
to want to be able to, if it's
too runny, add just a little
bit more without having
to bust open
another box of corn starch.
If you haven't played with corn
starch just by itself, it
has this crazy property just
without water, almost squeaks
in your fingers.
As soon as you add water, you're
just kind of working it
in, and waiting for it
to be almost the
consistency of honey.
So just small batches of
water and work it in.
The only way I found to
do this is to work
it with your hands.
When we talk about a
non-Newtonian fluid, it means
that it doesn't obey the
rules or the laws that
Isaac Newton set out.
And he talked about viscosity.
Now, viscosity is the thickness
of a material.
So, for example, honey or
ketchup has a high viscosity,
water has a very
low viscosity.
And it said that the only way
that you can change viscosity
is with the temperature.
However, you're going to see
here in just a minute, and as
you're playing with it you can
see, that this almost becomes
like a solid when you
put force on it.
And it's a liquid when
you allow it to flow.
That's why they call it a
non-Newtonian solution.
Let's see if this is
just about right.
I think it's perfect.
When it has this consistency
right here, you know that
you've got a perfect batch.
So make sure that the batch is
good before you move on.
And now it's time for
the slap test.
So you're going to take the
mixture and pour the mixture
out onto a tray.
This is perfect.
It flows like a liquid.
And the only way that there's
a change there, is with the
pressure or the stress
that you put on this.
So normally, if you would take
a liquid like this, this
liquid here, and you slap it,
it would go everywhere.
I think it's going
to be a solid.
Watch this.
That's awesome.
See, what we've actually made
here is a suspension.
You have a finely dispersed
particle, that's the corn
starch, dispersed in the liquid
that's there, and it's
kind of holding it in place.
It doesn't last for
a long time.
So you can't make a mixture of
corn starch and water and
leave it for weeks and weeks.
It'll actually settle
out and become
almost hard like concrete.
So you really only have a life
expectancy of maybe four or
five hours as you're
playing with this.
It's impossible to take your
hands out of it and to
understand that you've actually
made something that
defies Newton's laws
of viscosity.
It's a liquid, and behaves like
a solid at the same time.
All right, back to
the bowl you go.
Look at the shear factor
that's there.
It literally--
you can break off of a piece.
And you want to know
the best thing?
The place that you do this, a
friend's home, will look like
corn starch for the
next five weeks.
Here's a cool thing to try.
Just take a small amount
and actually roll it.
You can actually roll it.
It feels like it crumbles,
or will roll into a ball.
And the moment you stop,
it just simply flows.
It really is amazing.
All right, we're going to need
to have an amplifier.
This a pretty good opportunity
for you to head to your local
thrift store and just
find something.
I would not damage any
really, really good
equipment doing this.
So we're just using
an amplifier.
I've hooked up the speaker in
the very back of the amplifier
to these little clip leads that
you see here because I
have a surplus speaker.
So we just found a speaker
cabinet at a thrift store that
was damaged, and for $5.00,
found the speaker.
By doing this enough,
you're actually
going to ruin the speaker.
Look at this.
You can see that I've
ruined the cone.
The cone has become detached
from this as we've vibrated as
hard as we're gonna vibrate
it here in just a second.
So don't use your
best speakers.
Or, don't use your speakers.
Black lead to the black,
red to the red.
And now we need tone.
So I'm just going to make sure
that these stay separated and
don't touch.
And now we need a
tone generator.
It's as simple as a free
app on your phone.
All right, I just downloaded
a tone frequency generator.
So go to your app store
and search for a
tone frequency generator.
This was free.
And this just produces
these tones.
[SCALE OF TONES]
STEVE SPANGLER: Now you need to
take the tone generator and
plug it into the amplifier.
Perfect.
[TONE]
STEVE SPANGLER: Even with
a bad speaker, it
sounds pretty good.
We're going to send the sound
through the speaker, but I
don't want to ruin the
speaker necessarily.
So I want to be able to cover it
with a small amount of this
Saran Wrap here.
So this will keep the corn
starch away from the cone.
And now we're going to take
some of our corn starch
mixture and pour it right here
onto the Saran Wrap that's on
top of the cone.
We want to be able to cover
the entire speaker, but we
don't want too much.
That's just about
enough, I think.
So we're gonna start
with 1,000 hertz.
It's that tone that you've heard
on video before, you
know that beeping sound.
Even though we're pumping it
through at a pretty loud
volume, it's not doing anything,
or affecting the
corn starch at all.
[LOUD TONE]
STEVE SPANGLER: Now we need to
bring it a little lower.
[VIBRATING NOISE]
STEVE SPANGLER: Ah,
that's perfect.
That's what we're looking for.
Watch this.
As it starts to move,
look at this.
It starts to behave almost
like a little monster.
That's why they call
them "corn starch
monsters." Look at this.
Look at the movement here.
Literally, it takes on a mind of
it's own as it wiggles and
moves its way up, behaving like
a solid and a liquid at
the same time, spraying
everywhere.
But even this silly little
speaker here that's not that
good does a pretty good job.
Wonder what it would look like
if we had a great speaker.
While that little speaker was
good, the neighbor's big
speaker, the speaker
that we bought,
is going to be awesome.
Now, we don't want to
ruin this speaker.
And so here's what
I'm trying to do.
I want to cover it up with
some plastic, you can see
we've done that.
A little bit duct tape
around here.
And now, the corn starch goes
right in the middle.
Who am I kidding?
This will ruin the speaker,
because just the mere weight
of this on the cone will start
to tear the cone away.
So do not use a good speaker.
And we got it from the thrift
store as a joke.
So say you want to turn this
into a science fair project.
It's very cool.
You just have to have
a question.
So the question might be, at
what frequency can you vibrate
a non-Newtonian fluid
to give you the
best corn starch monster?
Pretty good.
You're going to have to download
the app and try to
experiment on your own.
20 hertz is awesome.
Just between you and me.
But experiment.
All right, we're at 20 hertz.
Watch this.
[VIBRATING NOISE]
STEVE SPANGLER: You start to see
a little bit of distress
right here.
And then you start
to see it move.
You notice that this big
speaker is good.
But cranked up with 100 watt
amplifier, this is about the
best I'm getting here.
So sometimes bigger is not
necessarily better.
It is cool, but it's not giving
us the corn starch
monster that we really want.
So while this doesn't produce
the best corn starch monster,
you can vary the frequency and
actually see the pattern that
different frequencies make.
It's kind of an interesting
observation, especially since
you have the tone generator.
[VIBRATING NOISE]
STEVE SPANGLER: Well, if we want
good response, we have to
move to the sub-woofer.
This is perfect for that
low base response.
I think it's going to give
us exactly what we want.
[VIBRATING NOISE]
STEVE SPANGLER: Sounding good.
This is just the perfect
consistency.
Just thin enough to vibrate,
but to still give you that
nice non-Newtonian property.
[VIBRATING NOISE]
STEVE SPANGLER: You've got to
play with the frequency,
because you're gonna get just
the perfect frequency to give
you the greatest corn
starch monsters.
Look at them start to move
up here, kind of
dance their way around.
We need more.
We need color.
All right, a little bit
of food coloring.
So here's some food
coloring here.
Let's just see what this color
here, whether or not it'll
shoot up and make
some changes.
All we're looking for
are some changes
in the little patterns.
And we think the colors
are gonna make
this look pretty good.
[VIBRATING NOISE]
STEVE SPANGLER: Ah, you can
start to see these changes
right here.
Take a look at this.
That's awesome.
These incredible colors that
you get just mixing.
It sits right in here.
[VIBRATING NOISE]
STEVE SPANGLER: That's a cool
corn starch monster.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
STEVE SPANGLER: OK, if we just
put these down, it'll be just
fine, I think.
Come here, dog.
Come on, come here.
HIGGINSWORTH: Steve.
That's not even the right dog.
STEVE SPANGLER: That's fine.
They'll never know.
OK, come here.
Come here, dog.
OK.
Stay right here, OK?
You stay here.
You watch after the speakers
and your owner.
OK, stay there.
OK, run.
Stay there dog, stay there.