[MUSIC PLAYING]
MALE SPEAKER 1:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
[SOVIET ANTHEM PLAYING]
ALISON SEVERS: In 1979, the
Soviet army entered
Afghanistan, engaging in a
brutal 10-year conflict which
kick-started the Afghan
opium trade.
It was sold all over the world
to help fund the fight against
the Soviets, but the main
customers of the opium were
the Russians themselves.
After the fall of the Soviet
union in 1991, Russia's heroin
problem continued to grow.
So much so, that in 2011, the
country has become the world's
biggest consumer of heroin.
[MUSIC CONTINUES]
ALISON SEVERS: With a southern
border more than 4,000 miles
long, we're talking about a
patrol area greater than the
distance from New
York to London.
It's no wonder the drug trade
is out of control.
We travelled to the small
Siberian city of Novokuznetsk,
which lies just over the
Russian border with
Kazakhstan, and is
on the front line
of this heroin epidemic.
Once a Siberian industrial
powerhouse, now this city has
fallen into decline, with 20%
of its population allegedly
addicted to heroin.
We'd heard stories about
ex-addicts building coffins to
bury their friends, and
religious cults disguised as
rehab clinics.
Worst of all though were rumors
of a new moonshine drug
called krokodil that has some
terrifying consequences.
Nowhere are Russia's
drug problems more
evident than here.
We've come to an area where
there's a lot of derelict
building that are being squatted
by addicts as a place
to use and to live.
Everywhere I look around
me, there are syringes.
There's more syringes here
than I've ever seen in my
entire life.
MALE SPEAKER 2:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ALISON SEVERS: Why are
you hanging out here?
MALE SPEAKER 2:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ALISON SEVERS: This area is
called Zavodskoy and was once
the purpose-built
housing estates
of the Soviet workforce.
Now, these imposing tower blocks
are just empty shells.
These young men have been
living in this abandoned
building for two months.
MALE SPEAKER 3:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
MALE SPEAKER 4:
MALE SPEAKER 5:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
MALE SPEAKER 4:
MALE SPEAKER 5:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
MALE SPEAKER 4:
MALE SPEAKERS:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
MALE SPEAKER 3:
MALE SPEAKERS:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
MALE SPEAKER 3:
MALE SPEAKER 4:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
MALE SPEAKER 3:
MALE SPEAKER 4:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
MALE INTERVIEWER: When was the
last time you went to see a
doctor or a hospital?
MALE SPEAKER 3:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
MALE SPEAKER 6:
MALE SPEAKER 3:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
ALISON SEVERS: Sasha Pelikhov
works for an organization
called Regenerate Russia,
which helps rehabilitate
heroin addicts in
Novokuznetsk.
Sasha explained to us that there
might be more to the
drug trade than just
making money.
SASHA PELIKHOV:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ALISON SEVERS: There's a widely
held belief that a
phenomenon called
narcoterrorism
fuels the drug trade.
It's said that Afghan terror
groups help expediate the
supply of heroin to Russia in
order to both profit from
their former invaders and also
weaken the population by
poisoning them with heroin.
This is what's known as
the Golden Crescent.
It's the route that heroin
takes from northern
Afghanistan, throughout Central
Asia, and into Russia.
Sasha told us that the center of
the local trade was at the
food markets just outside
the city center.
It's where trucks from
Kazakhstan are offloaded with
heroin for distribution
around Novokuznetsk
and the wider areas.
We were told to approach this
place with extreme caution,
and not to get out of the car.
As we drove slowly through the
market, we noticed gangs of
men doing business next
to their trucks.
Many of them bore Kazakhstan
license plates.
It didn't take long
to get us noticed.
All of a sudden, someone spotted
our cameras, and
people started beeping their
horns and yelling.
MALE SPEAKER 7: Why are
people beeping?
MALE SPEAKER 7: Yeah,
everyone's
checking us out now.
MALE SPEAKER 8: Yeah, let's
just get the fuck out.
MALE SPEAKER 7: Let's get
the fuck out of there.
Let's go.
ALISON SEVERS: There's two
pretty snazzy cars behind us.
Those are the first snazzy
cars I've seen
since we've been here.
Probably going to follow
us and kill us now.
The vans have got along the
right-hand side of the number
plate, had KZ, which means,
obviously, the cars have been
trucked in from Kazakhstan.
MALE SPEAKER 9: It doesn't
mean Kool Zines?
ALISON SEVERS: No.
It doesn't mean kool zines.
It means fucking naughty
heroin trafficker from
Kazakhstan.
That's what it fucking means.
Well, there's still a car
that looks the same.
Or maybe all the cars
just look the same.
OK.
We lost the cars and headed back
to meet Sasha somewhere
safe, or so we thought.
MALE SPEAKER 10:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ALISON SEVERS: It kind of just
feels like walking into a
forest in the middle of Siberia,
plus a lot of very
angry dogs.
That one actually did that
whole, like, err, I'm going to
fucking kill you thing.
After about five minutes of
walking through Vorstadt, we
met this guy.
Sasha told us he was salvaging
scrap metal, which is the most
common way for heroin users
to fund their addiction.
MALE SPEAKER 11:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
MALE SPEAKER 11:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
[DOG GROWLING AND BARKING]
MALE SPEAKER 9: What is it?
ALISON SEVERS: Because I can't
see where the syringes are.
They're fucking everywhere.
Opposite the rehabilitation
center, there's just a
deserted building where there's
syringes all over the
floor, and, like, empty
bottles of this stuff.
ALISON SEVERS: What's this?
Sasha.
MALE SPEAKER 12:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
SASHA PELIKHOV: What
is in Tropikamid?
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ALISON SEVERS: Sasha explained
that the eyedrops were one of
the main ingredients of a new
drug called krokodil, a kind
of moonshine heroin.
Krokodil is so called because it
turns the user's skin scaly
and eats them from
the inside out.
SASHA PELIKHOV:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ALISON SEVERS: That woman walked
past us earlier when we
were on our way out
to the brothel.
And Sasha told me the she's on
the road, which mean she's a
working prostitute.
She's just walked past now.
She's met up with a guy, and
she's going to go have sex
with him down there.
Brilliant.
That's completely depressing.
Fucking hell.
With high volumes of drug
addicts comes high volumes of
prostitution.
And Novokuznetsk is
no exception.
What was worrying here was
how young the girls were.
So over there, I can
see two girls.
One of them looks about 14, and
they've been talking to a
succession of men who are
stopping in cars at the side
of the street.
And in fact there's so much
going on here with crime and
drug use, you'd expect to see
police cars and ambulances,
but I haven't seen
any of them.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
NATASHA: [SINGING IN RUSSIAN]
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ALISON SEVERS: The Russian
government offers very little
support for addicts.
There are no local state-funded
rehab centers,
and so the void has been
filled by private
organizations.
They range from centers like
this one, where the addicts
provide volunteer work to pay
for their treatment, to
evangelical churches that
have been accused of
running like cults.
OLEYSA: [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ALISON SEVERS: I heard
a lot of people died.
OLEYSA: [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
NATASHA: [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ALISON SEVERS: Oh.
ALISON SEVERS:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
NATASHA: [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
[CHOIR SINGING]
ALISON SEVERS: After we left
the girls, we went to visit
the priest of the main
orthodox church in
Novokuznetsk.
I had to wear a head scarf
in order to be
able to talk to him.
Spasibo.
MINISTER VASILY:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ALISON SEVERS: So this is the
bit that we bought in the shop
in your church.
And it says, Christian sects,
how they're servants of the
anti-Christ.
Is this relevant in this city?
MINISTER VASILY:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
YEVGENY: [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ALISON SEVERS: This
is Yevgeny.
By day, he's a funeral director,
and by night, he run
the Novokuznetsk branch of Teen
Challenge, which is an
American Christian charity that
now has missionaries and
centers in over 70 countries
around the world, and it's
growing rapidly.
He told us to come along to
meet his congregation in a
remote part of the city which
was an hour drive up a very
steep hill.
And when we arrived,
we found this.
[RUSSIAN ROCK MUSIC PLAYING]
ALISON SEVERS: This is the
sleeping room for the
brotherhood here at Teen
Challenge, which is Yevgeny's
church group
[SINGING IN RUSSIAN[
ALISON SEVERS: This is a
rehabilitation center for
people involved in Teen
Challenge, which is an
American church that's
come to Russia.
And now Yevgeny practices
their doctrine.
I think that Teen Challenge
is a cult, to be honest.
MALE SPEAKER 13: Today, I
live here six months.
Father, Son, and Holy Spirit.
Jesus Christ help me.
[SINGING CONTINUES]
MINISTER VASILY:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
[SINGING CONTINUES]
[APPLAUSE]
WORSHIP LEADER:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ALISON SEVERS: This is Sergey.
We met him begging outside on
the street, and he said most
of the people he knew
have been affected
by heroin and krokodil.
SERGEY: [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
SEREZHA: [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ALISON SEVERS: Later that night,
Sergey took us on a
tour of local pharmacies to show
us how easy it is to pick
up the ingredients
for krokodil.
So these are 24-hour pharmacies
that we're going to.
You can do this any
time of the day.
SERGEY: [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ALISON SEVERS: Sergey said he
knew someone who could cook
the krokodil for us.
He promised to meet us again.
That was the last
time we saw him.
ALEXEY: [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ALISON SEVERS: Alexey is the
pastor of an independent
church that reforms heroin
and krokodil addicts.
ALEXEY: [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ALISON SEVERS: Alexey took us
to meet his friend, whose
family has been destroyed
by krokodil.
With a drug that can kill it
users so quickly, it's very
rare to meet survivors.
LYUDMILA: [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
MISHA: [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
SERGEY: [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ALISON SEVERS: And you
been taking krokodil?
SERGEY: We have, yeah.
MISHA: [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ALISON SEVERS: When did
you start taking it?
MISHA: [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
SERGEY: [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
LYUDMILA: [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
ALISON SEVERS: I felt quite
helpless leaving Lyudmila's
house, but nowhere near as
helpless as she must feel.
Her health, home, and family
life have been totally
destroyed by krokodil, a drug
you can just work out how to
make with the help of
internet forums.
President Medvedev has talked
about closing down the
websites that are providing
this information, but the
internet seems harder to
police than the border.
I can't see any way out for
these people if they're
relying on that.
Drug users are developing new,
terrifying ways of consuming
opiates faster than the
government can decide on any
form of policy.
The church and the sects aren't
the answer, but sadly,
they seem to be the best hope
these young people have in a
city that really does feel
like it's been forgotten.