Captain's log, Stardate 6010.1
While in the midst of a ship wide systems upgrade
The Enterprise has been ordered to depart star
base 37, in response to a nearby distress call.
While there, I had the dubious honour of greeting
the new admiral assigned to this sector.
Our time together, fortunately, was brief.
At last, we were underway.
Although I have mixed feelings knowing
we are more than half way through
our five-year mission.
With Sulu at Starfleet for command training,
the promotion of Mr Chekov to head of security,
and the return of my former yeoman
as a newly commissioned officer,
it seems the more things change,
the more they stay the same.
Uhura, have you made any
contact with the colony?
Negative Captain, I am no longer
receiving the distress signal.
There is an unusual amount of
interference on subspace.
- Captain, you wanted to know...
- Not now Rand. Mr Spock, any readings?
Nothing yet, sir.
We are still too far out.
- Mr DeSalle, what's our ETA?
- 17 minutes to orbit, sir.
- Mr Scott?
- Aye sir, I can give you more.
- Increase speed to Warp 7.
- Aye, sir.
Captain, long-range scans available now.
Sensors indicate massive energy discharges.
The readings are off the scale.
DeSalle, go to maximum Warp.
Lt Uhura, sound red alert.
Chekov, bring phasers and
photon torpedoes online.
Phasers and photon torpedoes
armed and ready, Captain.
Anything, Spock?
I am at a loss to explain, Captain.
Sensors reveal two alien vessels,
then they simply vanished.
Two vessels?
Could they have been working together?
- Unknown.
- Uhura, anything from the colony?
Subspace channels are clearing.
I am receiving a transmission
from the colony, now
- On screen, Lieutenant.
- Aye sir.
This is Captain James T. Kirk
of the starship Enterprise.
Are you in need of assistance?
I'm Cal Strickland, director of this
research colony, here on Primus IV.
You sure took your sweet time,
responding to our emergency.
Well we're here now.
What's the nature of your distress call?
We have the situation under control
now, no thanks to you.
We assumed this outpost was
to be under your protection.
Director, it is.
Now what exactly happened here?
A short time ago, a large object appears
in orbit, randomly firing at the planet.
All attempts at communication
were unsuccessful.
Director Strickland, could we please
review your sensor data,
as it may contain additional information.
I'll transmit what we have.
Of course, by now we are not
too concerned by a return visit by
this intruder, thanks to the Onabi.
The what?
The Onabi. At least that's
the name we were given.
As soon as the Onabi appeared,
this intruder fled.
I'll have my chief medical officer
coordinate with your people
and beam down anything you might need.
In the meantime, we will remain here in orbit,
in case there is any more trouble.
Don't worry, Kirk. Fortunately, as long as we
have the Onabi patrolling this sector.
we feel reasonably sure that we
won't be calling on you anytime soon.
At least not if we need anything in a hurry!
Mr Chekov, cancel the red alert.
Spock, analyse the sensor data.
See if you can determine the
intruders course out of this system.
- Rand, you take care of that.
- Yes, sir.
In the meantime, I will be in
my quarters with a headache.
Here we go again.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the new voyages of
the Starship Enterprise.
Its five-year mission, to explore strange new worlds.
To seek out new life and new civilizations.
To boldly go where no man has gone before.
Captain's Log, stardate 6011.2.
We are continuing our investigation
of the mysterious intruder,
who has been attacking ships and
outposts throughout this sector.
I am frustrated by the lack of information
we have gathered thus far.
That, and by the fact that
there is nothing to do but
wait for the Onabi or
the intruder to reappear.
Captain, I do not recall previously
viewing this representation.
What Spock?
The musical composition you have on display.
Oh, you mean the hymn.
That belonged to my brother Sam.
My mother gave it to he and Aurelan
when they left for Denova.
What is it Spock?
I do not understand the words.
'Amazing grace, how sweet the sound
that saved a wretch like me?'
'I once was lost but now I'm found,
was blind but now I see. '
Well Spock, it is about us. It is about
what we are supposedly doing out here.
Extending compassion to those
in need, saving the lost.
Helping those people who can't help themselves
and asking nothing in return.
But, the song would seem
to indicate a deity.
Were not the religious
conflicts of your world,
what led your species to
the brink of destruction?
- Yes, but it is the ideal that survives.
- Then the hymn is still relevant.
I shall endeavour to study it further.
- Your move, Captain.
- Come.
- Beware Romulans bearing gifts.
- Why Bones? Romulan Ale!
You are aware, doctor, that Romulan ale
is illegal in federation space?
I only use it for medicinal purposes.
Now this looks familiar.
I will have in check-mate
with his next move.
Spock, you play the most irritating
game of chess in the galaxy.
Irritating, doctor?
Check-mate.
Sure you don't know what irritating is?
The fact that my father
married a human female...
- It's terrible having bad blood like that..
- He may learn to enjoy it, some day.
- Kirk here. Go ahead, Lieutenant.
- Captain, receiving a message
from Starbase 37. It's Admiral Leslie.
Admiral Leslie. Any relation to our Mr Leslie?
- It's his father.
- He has got to be adopted!
- Highly unlikely, doctor.
- Go ahead Lt, put him through.
Admiral. To what do I owe this pleasure?
Don't get cute, Kirk. Just what
the hell is going on out there?
- Sir?
- I just got a transmission
from Cal Strickland, the
director of Primus IV.
Yes, Admiral and about that situation...
Cal Strickland is one of the federation's
most brilliant research archaeologists.
And he is my friend.
Imagine the shock that I felt when the
very Starship I sent to protect him
is nowhere in sight.
Now you listen to me, Kirk.
You find out who's responsible for this,
or you are going to be watching
storage consignments of grain
for the next two years.
Do I make myself clear, Captain?
As clearly as can be expected...
What was that?
Don't cross me, Kirk.
If you think for one minute,
that you can push this admiral around
you have got another thing comÖ
Captain, I am receiving an urgent distress
signal from the transport tug, Al Rashid.
They are under attack near
the Klaxor-disturbance
by a ship matching the description
of the intruder at Primus IV.
Go to Red-Alert. Mr Scott, divert all ship's
power to the engines. I want Warp 8.
Lay in a direct course to the Al Rashid.
I am on my way.
- What about the Admiral?
- I am sure he will call back.
Red-Alert. All hands man your battle
stations. This is not a drill.
- Report.
- We are closing fast on the Al Rashid.
- She is reporting that she is under attack.
- The Al Rashid reports a second vessel
moving in to position.
They're challenging the intruder.
The Onabi, I presume.
- Are we within visual range?
- Coming in range now, sir.
On screen. Slow to one half impulse power.
Put us between...
My God!
- Sir, something is jamming the signal.
- Spock, any readings?
The intruder vessel no longer appears on sensors.
and the smaller ship is moving off.
Plot an intercept course.
Try to hail them.
There is no answer to our hails, sir.
- She is going into Warp.
- Lock a tractor beam on to her, Scotty.
Aye, sir.
That's got her. She's slowing.
Still no answer to hail, sir.
Mr Scott, can you get a lock
on anyone on board?
There is a lot of interference sir,
but I have got a lock on something...
Alert the transporter room.
Mr Chekov, have a security team standing by.
Mr Spock, you have the con.
Transporter room, stand-by.
- Do we still have a lock?
- Aye, sir.
Energize.
- Recalibrating. Stand-by.
- What's the problem?
It's these circuits, sir. We have barely
tested the new transporters.
These reading are like nothing
I have ever seen before.
Remind me not to use that contraption... ever!
- Greetings, sentient beings.
- Bones, how do you read that thing?
Whatever it is, it doesnít
register on my tricorder.
Please do not interrupt when I am speaking.
Captain,...
Thank you.
What was that?
As I was saying: Greetings, sentient beings.
- I am Captain James T...
- Captain, the circuits have activated themselves.
Someone else is beaming aboard.
- Mr Chekov, secure the room.
- Aye, Captain.
Oh, was I supposed to wait
until that thing was done?
I just have no patience.
How is everything, dear?
- I am Ohn.
- Now, Mr Chekov!
Force-field activated, sir.
Oh, that is so cute. Look Ohn,
a force-field. Shall we play?
I am Onabi! You must release me!
Mr Chekov, take our guest
to the brig to, get a grip.
I will be there later to question her.
The brig? Oh, I would love to go there.
Captain, this is going to be so much fun.
Take me, my Russian!
What the hell was that?
Chekov, keep the force-field on that thing.
Lt Uhura, I would like you to come
down to the transporter room
- and have a look at our guest, Ohn.
- Aye, sir.
- Mr Chekov, you stay here and... help.
- Aye, Captain.
These readings are useless,
we have to lower the force-field.
In a way, it's beautiful.
Uhura! No!
- ... only Vulcans, now you will die.
- Go to the side, Mr Chekov.
And now, I will deal with you, Lieutenant.
Scott to sick-bay. We have a medical
emergency in the transporter-room.
Please respond immediately.
Captain's log, stardate 6012.4.
The Al-Rashid has received repairs and
is continuing on her resupply mission.
We have taken Onabi into custody
and are holding her for questioning.
Sir? I have Captain Jeffries online.
On screen, Lieutenant.
Captain, is everything alright over there?
What the hell was that thing, Jim?
It came at us out of nowhere.
We're not certain. It's not the first time,
that we have heard about this intruder,
but it was the first time
that we were able to see it.
Now, if you hadn't shown
up when you did...
Our sensors indicated a second ship
for a moment. Did you read that?
We did. We were able to
bring the pilot on board and
we think the two might be
connected in some way.
We hope to get some answers,
to all of this, soon.
Alright Jim. Well you take it easy out here.
That ship of yours is getting quite a reputation.
So it would seem. Is there anything else
that we might be able to do for you?
No, we're fine. Besides, we need to
get back to Starbase 24 as it is.
- Safe travels, Matt.
- Same.
How are Chekov and Uhura, Bones?
Pretty shook-up, Jim. They described
seeing visions of the ship, the crew.
Some pretty wild stuff.
Whatever it was, it happened when
they came in contact with Ohn.
A device with the ability to project
holograms and induce hallucinations
should be considered an
extreme hazard, Captain.
Hallucinations, maybe. But I have
got two people in sick-bay,
who swear what they saw really happened.
What I want to know is who this Onabi is.
Spock, have we learned anything
from the sensor data?
Nothing of use, Captain. The intruder ships
seem to have appeared out of nowhere.
Could they have been
using a cloaking device?
Unknown. It does appear, Onabi
drove the intruder ship off.
If that's the case, she did indeed
save the colony and the Al Rashid.
Do we have anything
definitive on this intruder?
If our scanners are to be believed,
the size of the intruder vessel is
- two hundred times that of our own.
- Two hundred times?
We could quite literally beam the
Onabi Ship aboard the Enterprise.
While the intruder could beam us into theirs.
Nothing like being in the
middle of the food chain.
Logically, there is another possibility, sir.
One could assume the intruder is merely
a projection, created by our guests.
- For what purpose?
- Perhaps to gain whatever reward is offered.
Or, she could be trying to
destabilise the sector
and turn the neighbouring planets
against the federation.
Do you two just sit around all
day and make this stuff up?
Talk about 'paranoid'. Intergalactic plot...
Really doctor, your lack of reasoning
seems more on par with...
Gentlemen, Gentlemen, please. We need to
start working on getting some answers.
Then, Captain, may I request permission
to question the prisoner?
Spock, that is one emotional woman down
there. I'd better question her, Jim.
What she needs is some
good old southern charm.
Doctor, your dismal record with emotional
women, has already been established.
Why you green-blooded, inhuman son of a...
I think perhaps both of you
should question her.
I am sure that between the two of you,
you will discover who this intruder is
and how Onabi managed to
drive him off three times now.
Well?
Aye, sir.
Yes, sir.
- Lower the force-field.
- Aye, sir.
Well, Spock - Say something?
I would say the young lady might
be getting chilled by now.
What?
Captain, our guest has managed to escape.
This is the Captain: We have an intruder alert.
I repeat. All decks, intruder alert.
Ms Rand, you have the bridge.
Sir?
You have had the proper training, haven't you?
- Yes, sir.
- You are fully qualified?
Yes, sir!
Then I mean now, you have the bridge.
I'll be in security.
- Maintain position, helm.
- Aye, Captain.
Pavel, it's good to see you
on your feet again. Report.
Captain, all stations report secure.
There is no sign of Onabi.
Mr Spock, take charge. When you
find her, report to me immediately.
I'll be in my office.
- Aye, sir.
You men check section 4. The rest
head aft. Check each room.
What's wrong, Captain?
Am I not to your liking?
Then perhaps something more like this...
I am reading an unknown energy source.
From inside the Captain's office!
Well don't just stand there Spock.
Do something.
- Chekov!
- I'll apologize later.
How is she, Bones?
She'll be out for a while.
Move her back to the brig.
Take maximum security precautions,
and let me know when
she comes around.
Aye, sir.
It seems a little strange that
a phaser set on stun
was enough to disable her
after all we've seen.
Yeah, it does not make any sense, Jim.
But all my readings suggest that
she is truly unconscious.
- Perhaps it is another ruse.
- Oh, playing possum, eh Spock?
Not an unreasonable
conclusion, doctor.
Well I'm through playing games.
It's time we get to the bottom of all this
before a certain Admiral has
our collective ass. Gentlemen.
Lt Arex, report to main engineering.
Ensign Capek, report to the bridge
Scotty, if you don't sit
still, I can't finish.
Aye lass, it's fine.
It's just a wee bit sore.
You asked me to come down here.
Now do you want me to help or not?
Aye. Go ahead.
There, done.
Ah, Christine, that feels
much better. Thanks.
Now go on and make sure,
Uhura is resting.
Aye.
With this ring, I thee wed.
Captain's log, Stardate 6013.7
There has been another incident
with the device known as Ohn.
Just got back from sick bay.
Christine still hasn't come around. She was
attached to that Ohn thing for a long time.
But fortunately there doesn't appear
to be any permanent damage.
- Well how about Uhura?
- Back on duty.
Makes you wish we had a
ship's councillor on board!
Captain? I'm growing rather bored in here.
Can we please move on?
Lower the force-field.
- Ah, Captain Kirk.
May I first apologize for my previous antics?
I meant you no harm.
Nor we to you.
We simply want to learn more about you
and about this alien intruder that
seems to be menacing this sector.
- Yes. The Mot-nahp.
- The what?
The Mot-nahp, Doctor.
I most despicable menace.
I have roamed the galaxy since
before your sun burnt hot in space.
But soon my journey ends.
- So you can destroy this Mot-nahp?
- Destroy? No...
But contain the Mot-nahp, I can.
And once contained, the menace shall end.
I must say, this all sounds rather epic.
But there's just too many
aspects that don't add up.
Your vessel is simply too small to
drive off an intruder of this size.
Do not believe what only
your eyes tell you, Captain.
I think you'll find,
not all is as it seems.
Angles and ministers of grace...
Scott to the Captain.
Kirk here. Go ahead Scotty.
We are discharging energy
into the disturbance.
There's no reason for it, but
it's happening sure enough.
Where's it coming from?
Instruments read that the discharge
began near the Warp nacelles.
I'll have to take the mains
offline to run a full diagnostic.
Alright Scotty, I'm on my way.
- Aye, sir. - Kirk out.
Onabi, I am going to have
to ask you to wait here.
If you do not release me,
you will be sorry.
The only thing he's sorry about
is pulling duty in this quadrant
Status report, Mr Scott.
We've had to take the mains offline.
The ships running on battery power only.
At our present rate of power consumption,
we can maintain shipís status for 3.24 hours.
This should not be occurring.
It is my theory there is
no actual power drain.
Are you daft, man?
The indicators show otherwise.
Would you care to elaborate, Mr Spock?
Due to the nature of Ohn, this
could be some ploy to make us
believe there is a power drain
when none actually exists.
But for what purpose?
Perhaps to give Onabi
a chance to save us.
Mr Spock, you've been able to mind-meld
with intelligent machines before,
Is there any chance you
can make contact with Ohn?
Captain! Considering the effect the
contact with Ohn has had so far,
do you think it wise to
deliberately touch that thing?
While the risk is great, the danger Ohn
could pose to the Enterprise, is greater.
Captain, I believe this is our best course
to understand what has been happening.
Mr Scott, Spock and I are going to deal with Ohn.
Rand, maintain our position, here.
- Aye, sir.
Scott to engineering.
I need a team to assist me
near the main junction circuitry
at the matter/anti-matter chamber.
Ohn, this is Captain Kirk.
Yes, Captain. Mr Spock
may touch my mind.
It is impressive that you knew of
our goal before we told you, Ohn.
How did you come by this knowledge?
I guess we are just going to have to
get this knowledge for ourselves.
Be careful, Spock.
Ohn, stop what you are doing!
Spock!
Captain, with your permission, I shall now discuss
these fuel equations with the engineer.
Mr Spock... welcome aboard.
I have been, and always shall be, your friend.
Live long and prosper.
No.
Don't you remember?
Ship... out of danger?
You saved the ship. You saved us all.
Don't you remember?
- No - Yes
I love Italian food, and so do you.
Yes.
I thought I was going to die.
Not possible, you were never alone.
Don't believe them, don't trust them!
- They are dying.
- Let them die!
It was... fun. Oh my...
Spock.
Gentlemen. Captain Kirk is alive.
Oh, are you alright, Mr Spock?
I am undamaged. Physically.
How did you get down here?
Can you explain what just happened?
Those images were of no
memories that I ever recall.
Ohn gave you a gift, Captain.
Do you not recognize your own ambition?
I fail to see how answering in
riddles will accomplish anything.
Those images that were shown
to us, were they the future?
The future is not written, Mr Spock.
As to what you saw,
I have no control over Ohn.
No control over Ohn? Then that means that
that thing is a danger to the Enterprise.
Captain, do you not see, we are the same?
Ohn is younger, but we are the same.
The threat is not from us, Captain Kirk.
The threat is from without.
We have found no physical
evidence of your intruder.
In addition, it is highly probably that Ohn
is directly affecting ship operations.
That in itself is reason enough to consider
that both he and yourself, the true threat.
You believe me to be a threat?
You have no idea what's out there.
The Breen, the Cardassians,
the Hirogen, the Dominion!
I'd have tried to make friends!
Get ready, Captain.
None compare to the Mot-Nahp.
We don't respond well to threats, Onabi.
All hands, man your battle stations.
This is the Captain. Report!
Captain, the intruder has
returned and is engaging.
I am on my way to the bridge.
I hope he's up to the game.
- Report!
- Sir, shields are at 50%.
Another few hits like that and
we will lose them altogether.
I've ordered Mr Scott to bring
the mains back online.
What's she doing up here?
Just keep her out of the way.
Mr DeSalle, course 213 mark 4,
three-quarters impulse power.
Aye, sir.
Lieutenant Uhura, anything?
Negative, sir. Hailing on all channels.
- They're coming for another pass.
- Hang on!
Take evasive action!
Get us out of that things line of fire!
Aye, sir!
Captain, we'll not survive another hit like that.
We've got batteries only.
- Scotty, I need emergency power.
- Aye sir, I'm working on it.
Captain, I'm receiving damage reports from
all over the ship. Medical teams are responding.
Captain, if we maintain this course,
we'll enter the Klaxor disturbance.
Our shields and sensors will be useless.
And so will the Mot-nahps.
Take us in, Mr DeSalle.
Aye, sir.
Aren't we going to fight?
This isn't a fight we can win.
This is about survival.
Take us as far in as we can go, Mr DeSalle.
Aye, sir. Entering the Klaxor disturbance, now.
Spock, anything on the sensors?
Negative. As I warned,
sensors are inoperative.
Communications are
down as well, Captain.
- Mr Scott, report.
- The mains are back online.
Seems there was nothing wrong
as Mr Spock suggested.
What was that?
The Mot-nahp is trying to
determine your location,
by setting off anti-matter
charges within the disturbance.
That means his sensors are down, too.
Spock, can you track where that
weapons fire is coming from?
Our deflector-screens are
directing particles in such a way
that we may be able to get a general
idea of where the intruder is.
- How general?
- Within a kilometre.
It would appear I owe you an apology.
None needed, Captain.
Of course, what you do next
will determine your fate.
With a word, you will either
doom or save your ship and crew.
Let me help.
Rand, do we have enough power to transport
Ohn and Onabi back to their vessel?
Barely, sir.
Funnel all ship's power including life
support into the transporter-room.
Sir?
Do it! It may be our only hope.
Mr Spock, would you please escort Onabi
to the transporter-room? - Aye, sir.
Anything Rand?
Too much interference, sir
You performed rather well,
while in command.
You kept your head in a crisis.
That's the first major test
every commander has to face.
Knowing whether or not you'll rise
to the occasion, or freeze - well done.
Thank you, Captain Kirk.
- Uhura, raise the transporter room.
- Aye, sir.
- Transporter-room. Report.
- Spock here. We are almost ready.
Onabi is communicating with Ohn, now.
One could describe them as
being happy to see each other.
We are ready now, sir.
- Mr Spock, peace and long life.
- Live long and prosper.
Seven years... what a waste!
Ohn?
- Well done, Mr Kyle.
- You too, sir.
Transport complete, Captain.
Very good Spock. Now get
back up here on the double.
Affirmative.
Captain, I'm receiving a very weak
signal from Onabi. It's audio only.
Let's hear it, Lieutenant.
Captain Kirk, if you'd be so kind
as to move your ship to 127 mark 3,
I think we can get this taken care of.
Mr DeSalle, lay in a course.
That course will take us back to
the edge of the disturbance, sir.
Go, DeSalle!
Sir, the intruder is right on our tail!
Mr DeSalle, bring us about, Chekov
fire phasers and photon torpedoes!
Firing all phasers, torpedoes away!
There's no effect, sir!
Uhura, jettison the log buoy.
Signal all hands to abandon...
- Captain, look!
- Stand by, Uhura.
Spock, are the sensors back online?
Affirmative, sir.
I'm reading no sign of the intruder...
...or of Onabi.
- Can you track her course?
- Relaying coordinates to helm, now.
DeSalle, follow that ship.
Warp drive is down, sir.
Scotty, report.
Aye, the mains are down
and this time for certain.
It will take several hours to repair, sir.
So that's it?
It's over?
It would appear so, Rand.
At least for now.
- Mr Spock, anything from the sensors?
- Negative, Captain.
Looks like Onabi had one
last trick up her sleeve.
Ms Rand, have Scotty begin
damage control and keep on him.
Don't let him fool you with those
factor-of-four time estimates.
- Aye, sir.
- You have the bridge.
Lt Uhura, encode to Starfleet command
my past week's log entries.
Mr Spock, your with me.
- Aye, sir.
Repair teams report to Mr Scott
in engineering, immediately.
All hands stand down from Red Alert.
Captain's personal log, stardate 6014.3
We continue to clean up our battle damage
and repairs to the warp drive are nearly complete
The ship and crew have performed well,
during this rather unique mission.
What's that you are playing, Spock?
It sounds familiar.
A hymn, doctor, from old Earth.
The Captain recently introduced me to it.
I find the tune, most comforting.
What do you remember,
anything specific?
Images mostly, Bones.
There's just nothing concrete.
If it was indeed a glimpse at our future,
perhaps we should re-examine
some of our methods.
One possible glimpse, Spock. Onabi said,
the future is not yet written.
Maybe what we saw was
just one possible outcome.
Perhaps as the hymn says, 'tis grace
that's brought us safe thus far', Captain.
That's it Spock. You've got it!
Well, there's hope for him, yet.
Of course, on the other hand by changing -
what was it Spock, our methods?
That could be what causes
what you saw to come true.
The doctor makes an
almost logical deduction.
it would appear the timeline
has been altered, already.
Was that a joke, Spock?
Is seemed like a joke.
I am still puzzled as to the
nature of the intruder.
If not a holographic image, they could be
a major threat to the federation.
Well, maybe what we saw was
the vision of a future invader.
God, I hope not. But I wouldn't mind
running into Onabi again.
Gentlemen, that is for the future to decide.
A future, I hope, with
many possibilities.
Captain Kirk, Admiral
Leslie is calling on subspace.
He insists on speaking with you.
Put him through, Lieutenant.
Captain?
Admiral, I was just about
to send you my report.
Fine, Kirk. In the meantime, let me tell
you about your next assignment.
Oh, we're all ears, sir.
You will proceed to the following coordinates
and rendezvous with two robot cargo ships.
carrying a shipment of grain
to Sherman's Planet.
Admiral, may I just say on our behalf...
Oh no Kirk, oh no, wait.
There's more...
Oh, boy.
English subtitles by Peter Walker
www. startreknewvoyages. de