the first Nobel Prizes were awarded and about
15 seconds ago you started watching CNN STUDENT
NEWS.
Our first story on this Monday edition of
our show: every 48 minutes someone in the
U.S dies in a car wreck that involved a driver
who is either drunk or in some way alcohol-impaired.
It works out to more than 10,000 deaths every
year. Police say Jerry Brown Jr. is one of
them. He was the linebacker on the Dallas
Cowboys practice squad who was killed in a
car crash early Saturday morning. Brown was
a passenger. Police say the car he was in
hit a curb, flipped and caught on fire. Officers
believe alcohol was a contributing factor
in the crash. Cowboys nose tackle Josh Brent
was behind the wheel. He`s been arrested on
suspicion of intoxication- manslaughter. Brent
and Brown were teammates in college, too.
Brent pleaded guilty to a DUI charge in 2009
while he was in school. The charge he is facing
now could lead to a $10,000 fine and a potential
prison sentence of two to 20 years.
Every month the U.S government reports on
the national unemployment rate and the number
of jobs added or lost. For November, 146,000
jobs added. Unemployment at 7.7 percent. That`s
a drop from the month before. And it`s the
lowest the unemployment rate has been in nearly
four years. These numbers can be a little
tricky. The unemployment rate only counts
people actively looking for a job. Experts
say that`s the main reason the rate went down,
is because some people just gave up and stopped
looking. The big number to keep in mind - 12
million. That`s how many Americans were counted
as unemployed in November.
The state legislature in Michigan is getting
ready to vote on a right to work law. A big
part of this story has to do with labor unions.
Right to work laws say that workers don`t
have to join unions or pay union dues. People
who support these laws say they can make a
state more attractive to businesses and can
bring in more money for the state economy.
Critics of the laws say that they make unions
weaker and can keep wages lower for workers.
On this map, the states in blue have a right
to work law. There are 23 of those, including
Indiana, which just passed its legislation
this year. Poppy Harlow got the perspective
from both sides of the debate over the possibility
of a right to work law in Michigan.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
POPPY HARLOW, CNN CORRESPONDENT: A labor representative
told me this legislation is anti-worker, saying
that it gives workers less of a voice. What
do you say to that?
GOV. RICK SNYDER (R ), MICHIGAN: That`s backward.
This is about being pro-worker. Again, giving
workers the choice, the freedom to choose
- that`s fundamental.
JON HOADLEY, WORKING MICHIGAN COALITION CAMPAIGN
MANAGER: So, Governor Snyder`s legislation
is anti-worker, it`s going to end up, you
know, being a devastating blow to the middle
class here.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Is this legit? The flu
virus is pathogenic. Absolutely. Being pathogenic
means that the virus causes or can cause disease.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: And there`s a lot of that going around
this year, according to the Centers for Disease
Control and Prevention. For the first time
in almost a decade, the CDC says flu season
has arrived early. The region hardest hit
so far has been the Southern U.S. You can
see how flu activity is spreading on this
map, and you`ll notice the first states to
turn red are in the south. The CDC recommends
that people protect themselves by getting
a flu shot, a vaccine that helps you avoid
catching the flu. But how effective is the
vaccine and how can you the flue in the first
place? Those are a couple of questions I recently
asked CNN`s Dr. Sanjay Gupta.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: All right, you know, students -they
are touching the same desks, the same door
knobs, the same books. How easily communicated
is the flu through touch?
DR. SANJAY GUPTA, CNN CORRESPONDENT: Not as
easily communicated as if you have direct
contact with somebody, but it still can be.
There are some, you know, bacteria out there
that they basically when they hit the air,
they die. With the flu virus, oftentimes,
it can live on a surface for a period of time.
So, doorknobs, for example, a big area of
concern. Desks, as you mentioned. Areas where
people touch their hands a lot. You got - I
mean these areas need to be cleaned.
AZUZ: All right. Is it simple as washing your
hands to get the virus off of them?
GUPTA: Yeah, you know, it sounds almost ridiculously
simple, when you put it like that. But, yeah,
I mean washing your hands can basically protect
you from not only transmitting it to yourself,
touching your hand to your own nose, but also,
you know, giving it to somebody else. It goes
a long way toward doing that and the more
times you wash your hands is better.
AZUZ: All right, let`s say you and I are in
journalism class, and you start sneezing and
saying you are not feeling well. I`m sitting
right next to you. How concerned do I need
to be?
GUPTA: The likelihood, still, even in the
situation like that, is still low, thankfully,
that you are going to get the flu. But, you
know, it`s higher than if you hadn`t been
exposed at all. So, you know, this is a message
I think certainly for people who are sick
and are potentially contagious to stay home
and that`s a big thing. And also, for people,
who are in those situations, to make sure
they are, again, washing their hands often.
AZUZ: With what symptoms should a student
stay home? Like you wake up, you are not feeling
well. At what point should you say I`m not
going to school?
GUPTA: Yeah, you know fever is going to be
one of the things that`s going to be a hallmark,
and usually when you talk about a fever above
101.3, 101.4, that area, that`s really a true
fever. If you have some of the classic symptoms
including sore throat, but also specifically
muscle aches or something that distinguishes
flu from a regular cold. You should probably
stay home with both, that`s when you can tell
the difference.
AZUZ: How effective is a flu shot?
GUPTA: Flu shots can be very effective, you
know, there`s numbers that vary every year,
but it`s in the 70 to 80 percent range, and
it`s not a 100 percent, but it is - it is
pretty good and really the best thing that
we have.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: See if you can I.D. me.
I`m an award that was first given out in the
1930s, I`m named for a former director of
New York`s Downtown Athletic Club. I`m considered
the most prestigious award in college football.
I`m the Heisman Trophy. And some of my most
recent winners include Tim Tebow, Cam Newton
and Robert Griffin III.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Tebow won the Heisman as a sophomore.
Newton and Griffin were both juniors, and
a lot of seniors have won it over the years.
Now, if we were doing the story last Friday,
we would have said that no freshman had ever
won the Heisman Trophy. Then, this guy came
along. Johnny Manziel, quarterback for Texas
A&M University and this year`s Heisman Trophy
winner. He is the first freshman ever to win
the award. Manziel, whose nickname Johnny
Football, took home the trophy Saturday night.
He passed and ran for a combined 43 touchdowns
this season and accounted for 4600 yards of
total offense. That is the southeastern conference
record.
Next up, the python challenge. It runs January
12th through February 10th in Florida`s Everglades
National Park. Grand Prize is $1500. All you`ve
got to do is find these snakes and kill them.
Florida wildlife officials say they`re turning
to the public for help because they don`t
have a good strategy for the python problem.
The contest, which is real, involves an online
safety training course. Organizers suggest
some human ways to deal with the snakes. They
also say the contest isn`t just about killing
snakes, they also want to educate people on
how the python is affecting Florida. Now,
John Zarrella explains exactly what kinds
of problems these snakes are causing, and
how they got there in the first place.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
JOHN ZARELLA, CNN CORRESPONDENT: In his laboratory
Skip Snow keeps in plastic bags what you could
call "the kill:" alligator claws, the hoof
of a deer, a great blue heron, all found in
the stomachs of captured Burmese python.
SKIP SNOW, EVERGLADES NATL. PARK BIOLOGIST:
And it may take us a long time, years, if
not decades, before we fully understand what
the nature of the impacts of Burmese pythons
are in the south Florida.
ZARRELLA: What`s already clear is that some
Everglade species are disappearing, and disappearing
quickly.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Raccoons were such a
problem that we actually had to put a policy
in place to try to manage them.
ZARRELLA: No policy needed now. A study shows
pythons, which simply aren`t supposed to be
here, are likely responsible for nearly wiping
out several creatures. There may be as many
as 100,000 pythons slithering through the
Glades. How did they get here? Bought as pets,
when they got too big, owners got rid of them.
No one would have guessed just a decade ago,
snakes in this river of grass might upset
the balance of nature here forever. John Zarrella,
CNN, Everglades National Park.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: We are going to be honest: today`s Before
We Go segment may not pass the sniff test,
but it depends on how hungry you are. That`s
a bottle of perfume, and yes, you are reading
that right - it`s made by Pizza Hut. Smells
like it, too, supposedly. Piquant pepperoni,
malodorous mushroom. Mostly just smells like
a dab of dough. The company is making a limited
supply, free bottles for around 100 people.
If they decided to make more, they`ll probably
just manufacture it down at the old factory.
You may think oh, the pizza sounds odious,
or you may think this perfume idea makes sense
-- who knows for sure. If it becomes a big
seller, everyone`s is going to want a piece
of that pie. For CNN STUDENT NEWS, I`m Carl
Azuz, have a great day.