SHANE SMITH: So after traveling
across Siberia on
one train, deep into the middle
of nowhere, we switched
to another train going
even deeper into
the middle of nowhere.
And finally, after two and a
half very drunken days on the
train, we arrived in Tynda,
where the North Korean
administrative camp was.
So we just got to Tynda.
Some say it's the worst town
in all of Russia--
the most depressing.
And we're actually going to try
to go to the office that
runs all the North Koreans in
the region and see if we can
ask them some questions.
We met this cop on the train.
He seemed liked a nice guy.
He got the thugs away from us
when things got a bit drunk-y.
And so then he's offered to
help us, which is good.
Because when we went to the
hotel to check in, we
didn't check in.
Why?
Because the FSB, who used to be
the KGB, are asking about
us, saying, let us know
when they check in.
So the lady said, I'll let them
know, but I'm letting you
know that I'm letting
them know.
So we're like, OK, we won't
be staying there.
So we stayed in an apartment
where the water
smelled like gasoline.
And now we have a cop that we're
going to bring with us,
so we seem more official when we
go meet the North Koreans.
We just got here, and
we see posters
of Kim Il-Sung already.
And also it says here that they
will lay their lives down
for the revolution of the great
leader, Kim Jong-Il.
What are we waiting
for, by the way?
SIMON OSTROVSKY: For one of
the bosses of the camp.
SHANE SMITH: Look, he's got,
like, a Kim Il-Sung pin and
everything.
SIMON OSTROVSKY:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
MALE SPEAKER 1:
SIMON OSTROVSKY:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
MALE SPEAKER 1: Hi.
SIMON OSTROVSKY:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
MALE SPEAKER 1:
SIMON OSTROVSKY:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
MALE SPEAKER 1:
SIMON OSTROVSKY:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
MALE SPEAKER 1:
SIMON OSTROVSKY:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
MALE SPEAKER 1:
SIMON OSTROVSKY:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
MALE SPEAKER 1:
SHANE SMITH: So the North
Koreans don't want us to go
into the North Korean camp?
SIMON OSTROVSKY: They don't
want to go into the north
Korean camp.
SHANE SMITH: That's
very surprising.
So we came out here to the
outskirts of Tynda and we
found the North Korean
Administration Camp Number Two.
Surprise, surprise, they
won't let us in.
But we're going to go deeper
into the interior to find the
actual work camps and
see if we can talk
to some of the dudes.
So we're leaving on a one-car
train to go to the north
Korean camps.
It's a one-car train.
That goes into the middle
of nowhere.
[TRAIN WHISTLE]
SHANE SMITH: So this is our
chief of police, and he's
breaking in to the North
Korean camp.
Oh shit, We're literally
getting caught
looting right now.
SIMON OSTROVSKY: We should
get the vodka.
[MUSIC PLAYING]