EDDIE HUANG: Raw
since day one.
UNCLE LUKE: You gotta
practice safe sex.
No, no, no.
EDDIE HUANG: Oh, really?
UNCLE LUKE: Don't listen
to that shit.
[LAUGHTER]
UNCLE LUKE: That's why
I got a new platinum
condom coming out.
EDDIE HUANG: All right,
we wearing condoms.
UNCLE LUKE: Yeah, Luke Condom.
EDDIE HUANG: I'm wearing
Luke Condoms.
UNCLE LUKE: The platinum ones.
EDDIE HUANG: Luke Condoms,
Luke Condoms,
platinum Luke Condoms.
UNCLE LUKE: Don't listen
to that shit.
EDDIE HUANG: Uncle Luke
platinum condoms.
Let's go.
UNCLE LUKE: Let's go
to Rolexx, man.
EDDIE HUANG: Let's go.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
EDDIE HUANG: Yo, we just landed
in Miami, and the Miami
episode is the last episode
of "Fresh Off the
Boat," season one.
So savor it, enjoy it, marinate
on that shit.
And we're going to give you
something extra heavy to chew
on. 'Cause you're out
in Miami, there's
one person to see.
You don't know who that person
is, get the fuck out of town.
Tell Uncle Luke I'm
out in Miami, too.
All right.
So we at Club Lexx with one of
the soldiers watching the
smokers here.
Sosa, you already know.
Show them the "Scarface" hat.
Let me see what you're
working with, man.
SOSA: All right, we got a--
EDDIE HUANG: Bang.
Oh, St. Louis ribs.
Look at that.
Yo, you're definitely-- he's
snapping for you right now.
Look at this.
Do you know what temperature
you keep this at?
SOSA: Sugar Ray, what
temperature we
keep this at, baby?
SUGAR RAY: Like 350.
EDDIE HUANG: 350?
SUGAR RAY: Yeah, but you
don't want no fire.
You just want the pure smoke.
EDDIE HUANG: Yeah, yeah,
yeah, definitely.
So they barbecuing at
a little bit of a
higher temperature here.
It's going to seal
in the juices.
It probably won't fall off the
bone like you do when you have
a lower temperature.
That's mean.
It's just a different
style and technique
of doing these ribs.
Work.
So what's in this?
SUGAR RAY: Well, it's a mix of
carrots, potatoes, onions,
green peppers, Scotch
bonnet peppers.
EDDIE HUANG: OK.
EDDIE HUANG: Wow.
You know, every culture has a
stew just like this, that was
sustenance for hundreds
and hundreds of years.
And you could find tradition,
you could find history, you
could find culture, you could
find sustenance anywhere--
even outside of a strip club.
Especially outside
of a strip club.
Chicken souse.
UNCLE LUKE: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
EDDIE HUANG: What up, Luke?
What's good?
UNCLE LUKE: How you
feeling, man?
EDDIE HUANG: Chilling,
chilling, man.
Been waiting to eat
these ribs.
This shit looks good.
UNCLE LUKE: You hit the
right spot, man.
EDDIE HUANG: Definitely.
Thank you for putting
us on, Miami.
UNCLE LUKE: Did you order?
Let's order.
EDDIE HUANG: No, let's order.
I'm gonna do it the
way you do it.
UNCLE LUKE: This is the
world-famous chef right here.
This is where you get real
ribs, cooked to go.
EDDIE HUANG: Yup.
I want that "Banned
in the USA" shit.
UNCLE LUKE: Exactly.
Exactly.
EDDIE HUANG: Yup.
UNCLE LUKE: The American
way, baby.
All right, hold on, Spike Lee,
you getting this wrist action?
EDDIE HUANG: So I want you
to see, when you eat this
chicken, when you eat barbecue
chicken, you want to look for
that red smoke color
to it, right?
That means it's smoked properly,
when the chicken's
got that redness to it.
All right.
Same with ribs.
Ribs smoked probably will
have a red ring to it.
SOSA: We got slabs already
seasoned, ready
to go on the grill.
Two hours, meat ready to go.
EDDIE HUANG: They got
this to a science.
That shit is good.
When they told us that we were
doing the Miami episode, and
they were like, who do you
want to see on the show?
I said, you cannot go to Miami
and not see the Mayor.
As a kid, you always, like,
informed my life.
Because first, you had
to the half-Chinese
dude in 2 Live Crew.
UNCLE LUKE: Yeah, yeah.
EDDIE HUANG: And I fuck
with that, right?
And then on the second level,
I fuck with Miami.
You were the Mayor.
And free speech.
You know, you put everybody
on with the free speech.
But then third, when I got
older, in law school, it came
back to Uncle Luke again with
Acuff-Rose, 'cause he has the
seminal case on the
parity exception.
Lawyers owe you one.
UNCLE LUKE: Yeah.
Yeah, yeah.
EDDIE HUANG: Everybody in the
music industry owe you on.
So much respect, man.
UNCLE LUKE: Hey, man,
appreciate it.
Appreciate it.
EDDIE HUANG: You a legend, So
we had to come see you.
UNCLE LUKE: You know,
yeah, yeah.
I appreciate you coming down.
Hey, you see the cars,
the line of cars?
That's for the barbecue.
People go above and beyond to
get this barbecue here.
-Aw, man, I come way from West
Palm Beach to do that, you
know what I'm saying?
Come over here and get some good
souse, some good sauce.
-I come way from Miramar.
-I fuck-- hey, look here,
friends go up, let's come down
at the end of the day.
-Oh, man.
I don't know how much cocaine
they got in the souse, man,
but it's something to see.
-Top notch, man.
I come down here all the time.
-That's, that's what
I come here for.
Damn them strippers, I
came for the food.
-Best in town, man.
-Best in town.
-That's what's up.
UNCLE LUKE: I mean, they making
so much money, they
getting ready to open
up their own
restaurant right over there.
They building it right now.
Yeah, no, these guys
came a long way.
I remember when they first
opened up over here.
EDDIE HUANG: How long ago?
UNCLE LUKE: What is it?
SUGAR RAY: Six and
a half years.
UNCLE LUKE: Yep.
EDDIE HUANG: Wow, six and a half
years, under this tent?
UNCLE LUKE: Yep.
EDDIE HUANG: That makes me
happy, though, 'cause a lot of
times, the people that have
these carts and the small
businesses, they never
get to take off.
So that's great to
see them prosper.
UNCLE LUKE: Freaky
Red in there?
-Yes, sir.
UNCLE LUKE: OK.
Tell her her Daddy out here.
[LAUGHTER]
UNCLE LUKE: Why you got your
pants down and everything?
-Hi, Mister!
UNCLE LUKE: So you go
kiss her [INAUDIBLE]
and look at her pants down.
EDDIE HUANG: And the
pants is down.
-I love him.
I know his--
[LAUGHTER]
EDDIE HUANG: Turn up.
-Uncle Luke, I know all about
that penis over there.
Big Daddy.
[LAUGHTER]
EDDIE HUANG: Shit.
After barbecue, the other thing
down South, you eating
barbecue, you know you
need some fish fry.
UNCLE LUKE: Oh, yeah, yeah.
You gotta get the conch.
This guy here specialize
in the conch.
And people come from all over
the place, miles around.
He really opens up at 12
o'clock, midnight.
EDDIE HUANG: Oh, he starts
at midnight?
UNCLE LUKE: Yeah, midnight.
Yeah.
EDDIE HUANG: Wow.
So it really is that
aphrodisiac food.
UNCLE LUKE: Exactly.
Conch Daddy!
You do a lot of chopping
tonight, Conch Daddy.
EDDIE HUANG: Conch
Daddy, thank you.
UNCLE LUKE: Hey.
Oh, baby.
And then when you finish this,
you can go get any woman,
aphrodisiac, lay up all night.
EDDIE HUANG: Look
at this conch.
I'm-a bite into it
so you can see.
Usually conch is rubbery
like octopus.
UNCLE LUKE: That's right.
That's the key.
EDDIE HUANG: It just
goes like that.
You hear that snap?
UNCLE LUKE: That's when
you know it's fresh.
EDDIE HUANG: Crazy.
I mean, I knew you would know
what was up, but this is
beyond expectation.
UNCLE LUKE: Hey, I'm a food--
being that I'm a former
chef, I always gotta
find the good food.
EDDIE HUANG: You were telling
me, you were a chef before you
were a rapper.
UNCLE LUKE: Yeah.
While I was cooking, my
night job was DJing.
EDDIE HUANG: OK.
UNCLE LUKE: So I DJed, and
then I started bringing
concerts down.
So I started making
more money.
Then, I mean, the money--
going to work at a day job
didn't mean nothing, so
eventually I just stopped
doing that.
EDDIE HUANG: That's the thing
though, for a lot of artists,
a lot of entrepreneurs, when
they're trying to get their
shit poppin', you work
in a restaurant.
UNCLE LUKE: You work
EDDIE HUANG: Easiest thing
to do is work shifts in a
restaurant.
What's that, fried snow crab?
I gotta taste one.
I gotta try one of them.
UNCLE LUKE: I hope this ain't
y'all first day shooting,
'cause y'all gonna be fucked up
for the rest of the week.
You'll be running over here.
No, this guy--
EDDIE HUANG: This is crazy.
UNCLE LUKE: Conch Daddy
is the best.
-122nd and 27th Avenue.
And we also got National Tires,
my main man, too.
EDDIE HUANG: You know what's
funny, is when people tell
chefs, oh, you a chef, just
do the chef thing.
You got this, you got
the tire shop.
I do everything.
You've got to get paper
every which way.
UNCLE LUKE: Fucking producer.
[LAUGHTER]
UNCLE LUKE: I done took you
out to the mountain-top.
You're always supposed
to get me last.
EDDIE HUANG: Yeah.
UNCLE LUKE: You supposed
to get the king last.
EDDIE HUANG: No, but we needed
a key to the city.
UNCLE LUKE: Hey, man, only
way I could give you
the key to the city?
EDDIE HUANG: Yeah?
UNCLE LUKE: I do it at my
man Conch Daddy's place.
And here it is.
You got the stone crab key
to the city, baby.
EDDIE HUANG: There we go.
UNCLE LUKE: There it is.
Fried live, laid to the side,
get your body right.
EDDIE HUANG: Thank you.
Thank you, Luke.
Let's get up in the Rolexx.
UNCLE LUKE: Let's go.
Let me take you on in, make sure
the girls take care of
you real nice.
EDDIE HUANG: Yup.
I appreciate it.
UNCLE LUKE: Don't have no
sex with nobody in here.
EDDIE HUANG: No?
No sex in the champagne room.
UNCLE LUKE: With this
raw dog stuff.
EDDIE HUANG: No raw dog.
Only with the Uncle
Luke condom.
UNCLE LUKE: Yeah.
The platinum one.
EDDIE HUANG: OK.
On the next episode of "Fresh
Off the Boat"--
-This boat symbolizes, really,
you know, you're out there,
you're trying to make
a living, you know--
this shows you real life.
This is real life, here.
And then, of course, it also
symbolizes a journey.
We came over here.
But at the end of the
day, this is how
things are being done.
-Good job, Chef!
That's delicious, man.