And on the third day, there was
a marriage in Cana of Galilee.
And it came to pass that all
the wine was drunk.
And the mother of Jesus said unto the Lord:
"They have no more wine".
And Jesus said unto the servants:
"Fill six waterpots with water. "
And they did so.
And when the steward of the feast
did taste of the water from the pots,
it had become wine.
And they knew not whence,
it had come.
But the servants did know.
And they applauded loudly in the kitchen.
And they said unto the Lord:
"How the hell did you do that?"
And inquired of him
"Do you do children's parties"
And the Lord said:
"No".
But the servants did press him, saying:
"Go on, give us another one!"
And so he brought forth a carrot.
and said:
"Behold this, for it is a carrot. "
And all about him knew that it was so.
For it was orange,
with a green top.
And he did place a large red cloth over
the carrot, and then removed it
and lo, he held in his hand, a white rabbit.
And all were amazed, and said:
"This guy is really good!"
"He should turn professional. "
And they brought him on a stretcher
a man who was sick of the palsy.
And they cried unto him:
"Maestro, this man is sick of the palsy. "
And the Lord said: "If I had to
spend my whole life on a stretcher,
I'd be pretty sick of the palsy, too!"
And they were filled with joy.
And cried out:
"Lord, thy one-liners are
as good as thy tricks.
Thou art indeed an all-round
family entertainer. "
And there came unto him a woman called
Mary, who had seen the Lord and believed.
And Jesus said unto her:
"Put on a tutu,
and lie down in this box. "
And then took he forth a saw
and cleft her in twain.
And there was much wailing
and gnashing of teeth.
But Jesus said:
"Oh ye of little faith!"
And he threw open the box and lo,
Mary was whole.
And the crowd went absolutely bananas.
And Jesus and Mary took a big bow.
And he said unto her:
"From now on you shall be known as Sharon,
for that is a good name for an assistant. "
And the people said unto him:
"We've never seen anything like this.
This is great.
You must be the Son of God. "
But the Lord said:
"No. I am he who comes before. "
And they were amazed, and said:
"Master how shall we know
the true Lord. "
And jesus said:
"By his name shall you know him. "
And he shall have a very religious name.
And he shall be call Paul.
And Daniel, shall he be call'
Paul Daniels!
They cried.
And the Lord said:
Yes.
Something like that.
Here endeth the lesson.
Well now, Mr. Perkins.
It was good of you to come in.
I realise that you're a busy man,
but I didn't think this matter could be
discussed over the electric telephone.
No. No, absolutely, Headmaster, I mean,
if Tommy is in some sort of trouble,
then I'd like to nip it in the bud.
Well, quite frankly, Tommy is in trouble.
Recently his behaviour has left
a great deal to be desired.
Dear.
He seems to take no interest in
school life whatsoever.
He refuses to muck in at
the sports field.
And it's weeks since any master has
received any written work from him.
Oh, dear me.
Quite frankly, Mr Perkins, if he
wasn't dead, I'd have him expelled.
I beg your pardon?
Yes, EXPELLED!
If I wasn't making allowances for
the fact that your son is dead,
he'd be out on his ear!
- Tommy, is dead?
- Yes. He's lying up there in sick bay now,
stiff as a board and bright green,
and this is, I fear,
typical of his current attitude.
You see, the boy has no sense
of moderation
one moment he's flying around
like a paper kite,
and the next moment he's
completely immovable.
And beginning to smell.
Well, how did he die?!
- Well, is that important?
- Why, yes, I think so!
Well... Well... Well, it's all got to
do with the library, you see.
We've had a lot of trouble recently with
boys taking out library books
without library cards.
Your son was caught, and I administered
a beating, during which he died.
But you'll be glad to know... You'll be glad
to know that the ringleader was caught,
so I don't think we'll be having any
trouble with library discipline.
- You see, the library card system...
- I'm sorry...
...was...
- You beat my son to death?
- Yes, yes, so it would seem.
Please, I'm not used to
being interrupted.
You see, the library card system
was introduced...
Well, exactly what happened?
Well, apparently, boys were just slipping
into the library and taking the books!
No, during the beating!
Oh, that? Well...
well, one moment he was bending over, the
next moment he was lying down, I mean, er...
- Dead?
- Mmm... deadish!...
Mr. Perkins, I find this morbid fascination
with your son's death
quite disturbing. What I'm talking
about is his attitude!
And quite frankly, I can see
where he gets it from.
Well, it wasn't me that beat
my son to death!
Well, that was perfectly obvious to me
from the first day he arrived here.
I wondered then, as I wonder now,
if he might not have turned out
a very different boy indeed
if you had administrated
a few fatal beatings earlier.
- Are you mad!?
- I'm FURIOUS!
In order to accommodate the funeral, I had
to cancel afternoon school on Wednesday!
- This is preposterous!
- Yes, it is.
Or at least, it would be...
if it were true.
- ... What?
- I've been joking, Mr Perkins.
Pardon me, it's my strange academic
sense of humour.
- I've been pulling your leg.
- Oh, thank God!
I wouldn't cancel afternoon school
to bury that little shit!
Alright, come on, settle down please.
Answer your names.
Anus.
Arsebandit.
Bottom.
Clitoris.
Where are you, Clitoris?
Dodo.
Enema.
Fistup
Come on, grow up please.
Genital.
I'm sorry, Genital.
Herpes.
Still with us I see.
Imadick.
Imadick!
Enema, you know Imadick don't you?
Jaculation.
Myprick.
Has anybody seen Myprick?
Come on!
Somebody must have seen Myprick!
Very well.
Remind me to beat Myprick a bit later.
Nicenquick.
Ontop.
Pube.
Ahhh, Myprick! So good of you to turn up.
Yes. Well now that you are here Myprick,
perhaps you'd like to find a seat.
Bottom, squeeze Myprick in there
somewhere will you?
Rigid.
Our Russian exchange student,
Suckmeoff.
Tightfit.
Upyours.
Vulva.
Yourprick.
And Zipper.
Zipper?
Absent.
Now then boys, the headmaster
has asked me...
...to speak to you this
morning on the subject of smut.
All members of staff have noticed an alarming
increase of the use of silly humour
and puerile innuendo about the school.
Rigid, Fistup, Bottom,
Out!
There have been some disgusting
doodlings on the walls of the lavatories.
Sit up straight Ontop.
One or two unpleasant health
magazines have been found.
If you fall asleep Ontop,
I shall be VERY annoyed.
And Mr Hardon tells me that...
...there has been a great deal
of sniggerin in his biology class.
Tightfit, for heaven's sake,
leave Yourprick alone!
I don't care, Yourprick had no business
poking into your desk in the first place.
I will not put up with this kind
of behaviour boys,
and neither, must I warn you will
Mr. Gripbighardcock.
This is a school for the sons
of gentlemen,
and the theory is that oneday you
will become a gentleman too.
That is with the exception of Genital, who
appears to be turning into a ferret.
So there will be an end to this
second form toilet humour
where so much conversation is
devoted to smutty double entendre.
Dodo Suckmeoff Nicenquick,
detention Saturday.
Right, I'm going to the staffroom now,
but if I come back and catch Herpes in the
corridor like the headmaster did yesterday,
then there'll be trouble!
Do you have ever one of those days
when everything seems to go wrong?
I did, and unfortunately,
it was my wedding day.
And three men in
particular were to blame.
It all started with the priest.
I now pronounce you man and wife...
well done.
You may now kiss the bride...
Nice one.
All right, please be seated everybody.
I'd just like to say a few words
before the communion.
You know, a lot of prospective
brides ask me these days,
"Father, what is the church's
attitude towards fellatio?"
And I tend to reply by telling
them a little story
about the first time I was
asked that question.
It was a couple of years ago,
a young attractive bride to be
came up to me after the service
and asked me just that question.
"Father, what is the church's
attitude towards fellatio?"
And I replied, "Well, you know,
Joanne, I'd like to tell you,
but unfortunately,
I don't know what fellatio is!"
And so, she showed me.
And ever since, whenever anyone
has asked me the question
"Father, what is the church's
attitude towards fellatio?"
I always reply,
"Well, you know, I'd like to tell you...
but unfortunately,
I don't know what fellatio is!"
Next, came my trusted best man.
Um, all right, er... right, well...
huh-huh, huh-huh, right, erm...
ladies and gentlemen and fellow survivors
of that stunning stag party...
how did those two girls get
under the table
and what the hell were they
up to with that toothpaste?
Er... er, right, well,
erm... well, er... when,
just before I left the house,
huh-huh, erm, this afternoon,
huh-huh, I said to myself,
you know,
the last thing you must
do is forget your speech.
Er... mmm, well and sure enough, erm,
erm, when I left the house... whoops!
Ha-ha, er... mm m,
the last thing I did... ha-ha, yes, you
guessed it, well, was to forget my speech.
So, erm... so it's all ad lib, I'm afraid.
Er... er, er, er,...
right, well, well, well,
dear me, well now, now,
when should I begin,
haha-ha, I'd like to begin now.
Huh-huh, er, right, well, well, well,
I've known the groom ever since we first
went to school together at the age of eight.
And you know, he hasn't changed a bit.
Erm, well, that's not quite true, of course.
He didn't have his beard then, huh-huh, erm,
and I'll tell you this, he wouldn't
have been able to do
whatever he was doing last night
with those two extraordinary,
extraordinary, erm... extraordinary
how little people change, isn't it?
Huh-huh, yes, erm... er, although,
I know I changed a great deal
because I used to be an absolute ass,
always bleating things out when I shouldn't,
for instance, this afternoon.
I'm sure I wouldn't have been
able to resist
mentioning the bizarre sight that
greeted my eyes
when I opened this man's bedroom door
earlier this morning, er... mmm.
Yes, but, but, erm, enough of that, huh-huh,
he started making gestures
at me now, which I think,
huh-huh, means he wants me
to cut my speech short, erm.
So, suffice to say that I'll think he'll
make a ripping husband, erm...
then, I think his wife, ripping, too.
Huh-huh. And I can only hope that, that the
dress will hold out, er, huh-huh, erm... so,
so, I'd like to propose a toast,
erm, to go with the pate,
huh-huh... erm, huh-huh, to the groom and
to his lovely horse, erm, wife, huh-huh.
It's all, it's all starting to come back
to me now, huh-huh, erm,
And I just to know that their marriage
will be as happy and satisfying as I was
when I paid off those two prostitutes
earlier this morning... cheers! Huh-huh...
And finally, my loving father-in-law
provided the perfect end to a perfect day...
Ladies and gentlemen
and friends of my daughter.
There comes a time in every
wedding reception
when the man who paid
the for the damn thing...
...is allowed to speak
a word or two of his own.
And I should like to take this opportunity,
sloshed as I may be,
to say a word or two about Martin.
As far as I'm concerned,
my daughter could not have chosen a more
delightful, charming, witty, responsible,
wealthy, let's not deny it,
well-placed, good-looking and fertile
young man than Martin as her husband.
And I therefore ask the question
"Why the hell did she marry Gerald instead?"
...because Gerald is a sort of man
we used to describe at school
as a complete prick!
If I may use a gardening simile here,
if his entire family may be likened
to a compost heap
and I think they can
then Gerald is the biggest weed
growing out of it.
I think he's a sort of man people
emigrate to avoid.
I remember the first time I met Gerald,
I said to my wife
she's the lovely woman propping
up that old lush of a mother of his
either this man is suffering
from serious brain damage
or the new vacuum cleaner's just arrived.
As for his family,
they are quite simply...
...the most intolerable herd
of steaming social animals
that I have ever had the misfortune of
turning my nose up to.
I spurn you as I would spurn a rabid dog.
I would like to propose a toast
to the caterers.
And to the pigeons who crapped on the
groom's family's limousine at the church.
Er... as for the rest of you around
this table not directly related to me,
you can sod off.
I wouldn't trust any of you to sit
the right way on a toilet seat.
Welcome back to the Oliver Theater Awards
and we come now to the award for
Best Actor of the year.
And the nominations for this year are:
Al Pacino for
"Death of a Salesman"
Kenneth Branagh for
"Richard III"
And then two actors both in
the same remarkable new play,
"Stench" by Harold Barkworthy.
And the nominees are John Daniels
in the role of Mr. Trotter.
And David Forbert in the role of Mr. Gannet.
Now, these are four fine actors and
I’m sure they all agree
that the point is not to win,
but to play the game...
And the winner is...
John Daniels!
Oh, SHIT!
Unfortunately, John is unable
to be with us tonight.
So I would like to ask his co-star David
Falbert to accept the award on his behalf.
David!
David?
Perhaps you’d like to say a few words?
Thank you Vanessa.
Ladies and gentleman, what a
delight it is to accept this award
on behalf of my close personal,
acquaintance,
John Daniels.
John cannot unfortunately
accept it himself
because he is in Hollywood.
staring in his first major film role...
with Meryl Streep.
I am however, NOT in Hollywood,
not having been offeredeven a minor
role in a 8mm pornographic movie!
But what a delightful object
it is that John has won.
Although I am sure I will very soon
receive one myself,
when I next buy ten gallons
of petrol at a Texaco.
So what is it that Johnny has got
that makes him stand apart from
other actors of his generation?
Well, I think we all know
the answer to that one...
syphilis!
And what a great and heart
warming thing it is.
That he has already started passing it on
to a whole new generation of young actors.
Of course, to win an acting award is
always a great honor,
but to receive one here in the heart of
London’s famous West End
on an occasion such as this
HUGELY diminishes that honor.
What could be more dull than the sordid,
back-slapping sessions
where has-beens in tuxedos hand over
to even OLDER has-beens in tuxedos,
awards for plays that closed the WEEK
before the opened,
because the audience were
clamoring instead for tickets to
Andrew Lloyd Webber’s LATEST
re-arrangementof Evita,
to suture vocal range of Kylie Minogue.
Therefore, I cannot say what a delight it is
that John has wonthis award instead of me.
And I should like to announce my
retirement from the acting profession,
in order to begin a lifetime of work
amongst the mentally handicapped.
In which capacity I look forward
to meeting all the members
of the judging panel,
very soon.
Ashes to ashes.
Amen!
We are gathered here today
on this beautiful autumn morning
to pay our last respects to
Thomas Fairclough,
Richard Mason
and Harold Walker.
Tom, Dick and Harry.
As they were known to all of us.
Three stout fellows of our community
who will be sorely missed.
Tom, sadly, was blind
an affliction he bore with great fortitude.
Especially considering he was also deaf.
His only power was that
of speech and song.
And we all recall his enormous voice.
Joining lustly in hymn singing.
Of course, being blind and deaf,
Tom never actually knew what
hymn he was singing,
which seemed appropriate because we never
knew what hymn he was singing, either.
In fact, if we had to be frank with each
other, Tom didn't actually know any hymns.
Thus it was with deep gratitude
we recall the day when
Colonel Grant, using only sense of touch,
through the medium of a clenched fist,
actually broke through to Tom
and got him to SHUT UP!
Leading guidance through
the darkness of life,
Tom was lucky to have
a friend like Dick.
Dick had perfect eyesight, and would gladly
lead Tom wherever he wanted to go.
Unfortunately since Dick was deaf,
he couldn't actually here where
Tom wanted to go!
Yet, like Tom, Dick never complained
about his afflictions, did he?
Well he couldn't.
He was dumb;
but, blessed with gift of vision,
though stone deaf,
he was a tremendous fan
of Olivia Newton-John.
Being such an idiosyncratic pair,
deaf to the world about them,
Tom and Dick were to have the permanent
companionship of Harry.
Harry could literally here a pin drop.
Though, being blind and dumb,
he could neither see to pick it up.
nor warn anyone else not to stand on it.
So, as individuals, they were
sadly afflicted,
but together they were in possession
of all of God's senses, weren't they.
And it is together, that we remember them.
Together, at their job, checking eggs
at the battery farm.
Dick would look for the cracks,
Tom would complain to the foreman,
and Harry would do the listening
to Radio One.
Likewise in the evening when
they have returned from work...
...they all sit on the big red couch.
Dick watching the television,
Harry listening to the television
and Tom insisting that is time
to buy a television.
Sadly as we all know,
three days ago, their peaceful
lives were ended.
Dick saw the combine harvester
Harry heard the combine harvester,
but neither could cry out.
Tom, who could have cried out,
never had the faintest idea what hit him.
And so, they were all harvester together.
Blended into oneness, at last.
And now we trust are in heaven, as happy
as any, with that immortal host.
Dick will see the Angel's choir,
Harry will hear the Angel's choir,
and no doubt, Tom will ruin it
for everybody.