NECKFACE: Should I go away so
you can say some stuff?
PATRICK: No, that's fine.
NECKFACE: Hi.
Welcome back to the Epicly
Later'd Show.
This episode, our special guest
is Neckface, who is
standing right next to
me with a skull.
Does a lot of writing
on walls.
What else do you do?
NECKFACE: I skate.
[LAUGHING], I skate.
I paint.
I just do whatever makes
me happy, and makes
other people bummed.
Zero trans fat.
PATRICK: Is it a bunny?
NECKFACE: No, it's a bat.
These are bat ears.
PATRICK: Those look
like bunny ears.
NECKFACE: No, it's
a bat, dude.
So it's like I'm Batman, and
I'm hiding my identity.
If I have this on, they're like
oh, there's Neckface.
When I take this off, it's like,
oh, some random dude.
My real face is my mask.
This is Neckface.
See all those people
on the train there,
everyone on the train?
They don't know who
you're filming.
I pass by cops all the
time, every day.
Every time I pass by them,
they have no idea.
But if they knew, [LAUGHING].
So I'm riding on this
bridge, right?
I'm just looking at the city
like everyone else does.
But not everyone else
sees what I see.
Buildings, buildings, buildings,
oh, two billboards.
Right there.
One of them was the one
for Neckface Begins.
For me, I want to make
people laugh.
I want the person who is just
bummed out, like, man, fuck
that girl, like, fuck this
place, like, I'm never going
there again.
Just so bummed, the person's
so bummed out, right?
And then he sees my thing on
the streets, and it says
Neckface, beat your kids.
And if I bring a smile to that
guy who's been so bummed out
the whole day, or a whole
week, then that's
like, I feel psyched.
It's just like growing up, just
being a bad kid, doorbell
ditching and kicking other
people's trash cans over, this
is what I was meant
to be, I think.
King Diamond is like my
dad, my father figure.
He's rad, man.
King Diamond is like when
you're trying all these
flavors of Gatorade, and you're
over all these Gatorade
flavors, and then you finally
find the fucking Riptide Rush.
And you're like, what?
This Gatorade's fucking sick.
That's who King Diamond is.
To me that's who he is.
I was digging through all these
little whatever things.
And I found King Diamond, and
that's the guy for me.
The dream that I just had of
me turning into a bat and
flying away makes sense.
PATRICK: Is this your
inspiration board?
NECKFACE: It is my inspiration
board.
And I need to change it.
This is a squishy face.
It's a doll.
Somebody made that.
It's Eddie, from Iron Maiden,
who's actually
coming out of a shirt.
That's not a graphic.
That's him coming
out of a shirt.
This girl gave me a whole bag
of stuff for my birthday, a
bunch of random stuff
from her house.
And this guy was in there.
That's where that
guy came from.
My parents didn't care
about me watching
rated R movie, or something.
So I was watching all this
crazy shit, like Freddy
Krueger and Nightmare on Elm
Street and Jason, and all that
stuff at a young age.
And it's just really like
a comic relief.
[EVIL CACKLE]
NECKFACE: If I see a old lady
fall down on the street, it
may not be violent, but she
fell down on the street.
Of course I'm going to laugh.
Oh yeah, this is a new style,
using watercolors.
Trying to take the beautiful
water colors, that everyone--
oh, they're so pretty,
watercolors,
paint a rain forest.
And then I get the watercolors,
and then I just
fuck it up.
I just mess it up and make
this fucked up guy here,
taking your water color and
creating a mess out of it.
PATRICK: You went to art
school for a while.
NECKFACE: Yeah, I went to art
school for two years and
realized that it sucked dick.
So I dropped out.
PATRICK: Those are
the originals?
NECKFACE: Yeah, these
are the originals.
I don't know what the
fuck that is.
I think that might be
on Terry's board.
Braden has this tattooed
on his arm, that guy.
This one is on Terry Kennedy's
board, too.
Devil slam dunking, nobody knows
that the devil plays
basketball.
I'm doing the same thing I've
been doing for years.
And it's like, finally people
are like, oh, his
art's pretty cool.
Maybe we'll give him a show.
But it's like the whole
world against me.
Like, fuck that guy, he sucks.
I'm not going to be like,
OK, everyone hates me.
I'm going to stop.
No.
No fucking way.
I'm going to still be
out there, even if
you hate me or not.
PATRICK: How did you learn
how to papier-mache?
NECKFACE: Not even elementary
school.
Like where you have to make the
balloon, and then you put
the papier-mache over it.
And then you pop the balloon,
and the thing still stays,
because it's dry?
Like that.
I think I learned more in school
in the early years than
in the later years.
Because in the later years,
I didn't give
a fuck about school.
So I think if you're a teacher,
you should teach the
kid as much as you can in the
beginning years of school,
than towards the
end of school.
Because the end school sucks
when you start figuring out,
fuck school.
I like skateboarding.
I'm not going to go
to school no more.
Thar's what I think.