DAVID CHOE: We did it.
After years and years of
traveling, I finally completed
all 50 states.
Alaska, mission accomplished.
I've been to all the states.
This is the last one.
Years on the road.
It's pretty exciting to come
to a new place you
haven't been to.
We had our first casualty
on the road.
After more than 24 hours of
riding in a plane with Andrew,
him showing off doing flight
tricks and stuff, at some
point he was either rough play
with the hat or while we were
ghost-riding the whip, this
is what happened.
So we gotta fix that.
That's like cutting
Samson's hair.
And when we stopped to refuel,
we got Harry a new shirt.
Wardrobe change.
We still got the
tag back here.
HARRY KIM: Oh, yeah.
That's cool.
DAVID CHOE: So let's
get rid of that.
I feel good.
The air's clean.
The air's fresh.
We're in the land of
the midnight sun.
And as the sun doesn't
set over Alaska,
here goes day nine.
Thumb's up, America, it's the
coldest it's ever been on our
entire trip.
Just a doing a little
bit of graffiti like
I'm a teenager again.
And I think someone saw me,
someone called the cops.
So we're trying to find
a place to duck out.
Let's go.
DAVID CHOE: [INAUDIBLE]
get this.
Um, we're just cruising
Alaska.
We've never been to
Alaska before.
We're just coming to town
to play our music.
What are you doing?
DAVID CHOE: Can you see
what you're doing
with that mask on?
You're getting your hair--
MALE SPEAKER: [INAUDIBLE]
my hair cut.
DAVID CHOE: America, we just
found a guy getting his hair
cut by a robot.
It's about 3:00 in the
morning right now.
Hey, how about this?
My friend plays you a song,
you cut his hair.
Hey, let's go.
Let's go check out this shit.
Oh my god.
Um, wow.
What's your name?
MARK WILLIS: My name's
Mark Willis.
DAVID CHOE: I've Dave.
Nice to meet you.
MARK WILLIS: Nice to meet you.
DAVID CHOE: This is
my buddy, Harry.
HARRY KIM: How you doing?
MARK WILLIS: Just getting
hammered tonight,
getting my hair cut.
What are you guys up to?
DAVID CHOE: Hopefully,
we're about to get
Harry's hair cut too.
You guys ready to
hear some music?
DAVID CHOE: Oh, shit.
Hi.
MALE SPEAKER: Hi.
DAVID CHOE: Oh.
DAVID CHOE: OK, sorry.
Is this your room?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yeah,
you can come in.
DAVID CHOE: Can we, can we?
DAVID CHOE: This place
is awesome.
You guys, you guys look like
a very crazy couple.
MARK WILLIS: Well, you know.
CORNELIUS: We've
been told that.
MARK WILLIS: Heard that
a few times before.
DAVID CHOE: You, you guys seem
very comfortable with who you
are as people.
MARK WILLIS: Oh, we are.
CORNELIUS: We like to have
nude [INAUDIBLE] parties.
MARK WILLIS: We don't care.
DAVID CHOE: You don't--?
Well, listen.
You guys seem very open
to a lot of--
I can't believe--
can we see what you look
like under there?
CORNELIUS: I love it.
MARK WILLIS: Yeah.
Yeah.
DAVID CHOE: OK.
America, we've just unmasked
Optimus Prime.
Can you cut Harry's
hair, and then--
CORNELIUS: We can do that.
DAVID CHOE: OK.
Yeah, let's do that.
Um, we have a really good
cocktail going on here.
We have Cornelius making
a bleach cocktail here.
CORNELIUS: Oopsy doodle.
DAVID CHOE: We have Andrew here,
who is the manager of
the hotel here, who was a
little bit upset with us
making a lot of noise outside,
but now he's definitely part
of the party.
We got our fella here, who's
making his own movie now on
his cell phone.
MARK WILLIS: This is
probably the--
might be the second most
greatest thing I've ever done.
But I'm glad I'm a part of
it, and this is awesome.
DAVID CHOE: What--?
MARK WILLIS: Let's keep going.
DAVID CHOE: You want
to keep going.
CORNELIUS: 'Cause this
stuff doesn't work if
you wait too long.
DAVID CHOE: OK.
CORNELIUS: It dies.
Let's get it going.
CORNELIUS: All of it?
Or do you want--
HARRY KIM: Just give me--
MARK WILLIS: What the fuck?
That's pretty gnarly.
CORNELIUS: Who wants
to hold the cup?
DAVID CHOE: All right.
So I thought we had
weird shit.
We get in here, you guys have
huge, black fake boobs, an
Optimus Prime mask, and just
like weird shit over here.
Like--
tit sandwich.
Here's a good one.
Ye olde chastity belt.
Oh, wow.
That looks painful.
I really didn't know what we
were going to do once we got
to Alaska, but I have to say,
it's crazier than Reno.
It's wilder than Tijuana.
It is the wackiest place I've
ever been on the planet.
Harry looks like a pig in
shit, he's so happy.
Jesus.
Harry, she's fucking doing your
hair, like fucking play
her a song, man.
MARK WILLIS: Now, you guys can
crash here if you guys like,
but we gotta be out
of here by 8:30.
DAVID CHOE: Oh, shit, you
guys have two rooms?
MARK WILLIS: Yeah,
we got two rooms.
We gotta be out of here by 8:30
because we have Sunday
school in the morning.
DAVID CHOE: You're going to
Sunday school tomorrow?
MARK WILLIS: Yeah.
I teach Sunday school.
DAVID CHOE: You teach
Sunday school
MARK WILLIS: Yeah.
DAVID CHOE: Oh--
MARK WILLIS: From fourth
to sixth grade.
DAVID CHOE: You think, uh, you
think I could-- me and Harry
could come visit you at Sunday
school if we find time?
MARK WILLIS: Have you accepted
the Jesus Christ in your name.
DAVID CHOE: I have accepted
Jesus Christ in my name.
MARK WILLIS: Do you love him?
DAVID CHOE: I do love Jesus, and
sometimes I wonder if he
still loves me, but.
Oh my god.
What the fuck is wrong
with you, dude?
Wow, you can really see your
hair changing color.
It's going to be like a
weird orange color.
CORNELIUS: We can also
put more on--
DAVID CHOE: Oh, shit.
Your face is orange now,
for some reason.
And now your hair's
turning orange.
If you don't mind me saying,
your wife is very attractive.
When you guys are having sex,
are you wearing the mask, or
she wearing the mask?
CORNELIUS (VOICE OF OPTIMUS
PRIME): I wear it.
DAVID CHOE: Don't worry
about shit, man.
Life--
life's too short to worry about
any bullshit, dude.
I mean, you're a young guy.
How old are you?
MARK WILLIS: I'm 30.
DAVID CHOE: See, you're
a young guy.
You got the whole world open.
Like what are your
hopes and dreams?
What do you want to
do with your life?
MARK WILLIS: I want
to climb Mt.
Everest.
That's my goal.
DAVID CHOE: You'll
totally do it.
MARK WILLIS: I'm not
even kidding, dude.
That's my goal.
DAVID CHOE: You totally
do it, man.
MARK WILLIS: I'm not
even kidding.
I want a child of our own.
Go to Costa Rica.
Run down the beach.
Roll in the sand naked and play
in the ocean with you.
DAVID CHOE: Dude, you're
all right, man.
I like you.
You're a cool guy.
Let's get some sleep,
all right?
We've got a long day ahead
of us tomorrow.
MARK WILLIS: Are we gonna,
are we gonna--
DAVID CHOE: It's cool, man.
Just go to sleep.
Let's go to sleep.
MARK WILLIS: All right.
DAVID CHOE: Let's
get the lights.
MARK WILLIS: All right.
DAVID CHOE: 10 fuckin' days.
Thumbs up, America.
10 days on the road.
Sorta speechless right now.
Truth is stranger
than fiction.
I mean, you can't
write this shit.
This guy's got a
whole new look.
I mean, the nicest, strangest
couple we ever met let us
crash in their extra
bedroom last night.
Said he had his 7 o'clock Sunday
morning school class,
but I don't know if he
was full of shit.
But we woke up and
they were gone.
And we have some new additions
to the family.
We have the Optimus
Prime head.
They forgot their black fur
coat, which had an iPod
charger in the pocket.
And some black tits.
It's a brand new
day in Alaska.
The sun is shining bright.
There's bears out there.
There's Eskimos.
Just when you thought
the trip was getting
a little bit boring.
Come on, America.
Early bird gets the worm.
Let's get going.
What's up, America.
We're in Anchorage right now.
We're here with--
DANIEL: Daniel.
DAVID CHOE: Daniel.
Daniel is a German.
DANIEL: I'm an immigrant.
DAVID CHOE: He's a
German immigrant.
And he's been here
for how long?
DANIEL: Five months now.
DAVID CHOE: And the five months
you've been here, what
can you tell us about
living here?
What's the good stuff?
Bad stuff?
DANIEL: Don't go to Anchorage.
DAVID CHOE: Don't
go to Anchorage?
DANIEL: Make it out of it.
Take your first night and
get out of it, go to the
countryside.
See the beauty of the country.
[INAUDIBLE].
DAVID CHOE: Now I heard
stories about--
I don't know if it's the North
Pole, but I heard stories
about a North Pole.
Have you heard anything
about that?
DAVID CHOE: There
is North Pole.
It's the town to go, man.
Santa Claus there 365.
Little lads running around
randy, it's Christmas every
single day.
It freaks your little
sister out man.
Freaks it out.
DAVID CHOE: Oh my god.
All right.
We gotta find Santa Claus.
We heard he's-- we also heard
that he's a vampire
that eats the elves.
DANIEL: Absolutely.
Do me one favor.
Kick him in the nuts, if
you meet him, for me.
DAVID CHOE: Kick him in
the nuts for you?
DANIEL: Kick him in the nuts.
DAVID CHOE: Daniel,
you're a champion.
DANIEL: Pleasure meeting you.
DAVID CHOE: Nice to
meet you too.
Fucking bullshit, man.
That's the difference between
having a penis and a vagina.
Those girls fucking were on
the street hitchhiking for
less than 30 seconds before
they got picked up.
Let's get the fuck out
of here, Harry.
Thumbs up, America.
We just jumped into a minivan
on a cargo truck.
What a lot of people don't know
is when you see those
cargo trucks that are filled
with cars, trucks, BMWs,
Mercedes, the doors
are always open.
So when they pull up to rest
stops, it's really
easy to jump in.
Our guy's taking a mean dump, so
he hasn't come out yet, so
we'll just lay low till
we get going.
But these usually
go pretty far.
So thumbs up, America.
What a ride.
You need to fucking
get his tail.
HARRY KIM: Yeah.
We need a tail.
DAVID CHOE: We gotta fucking
make it into another hat.
Come on.
Come on, Foxy.
[DRUMS]
DAVID CHOE: Thumbs
up, America.
Ninja grappling hooks.
HARRY KIM: Yeah!
DAVID CHOE: Wait, how are
you gonna get down?
HARRY KIM: Slide.
I don't know.
It's easier to come up, man.
DAVID CHOE: Come down.
HARRY KIM: And there's like
nails all over this shit.
Dude, I'm just gonna
slide, man.
DAVID CHOE: You're not gonna--
you're gonna break your--
HARRY KIM: Just catch me
when I get down there.
DAVID CHOE: You're gonna break
your legs, you dipshit.
Harry, grab the fucking line and
grapple down, you retard.
Do you think there's a hospital
anywhere near here?
Harry.
Grab the fucking rope
and come down, man.
Grapple down, bitch.
HARRY KIM: I really don't want
to grapple down, man.
DAVID CHOE: Get it
stuck on there.
OK.
Good morning, America.
It was a miserable
night in Alaska.
We found out the only real
vampires out here are fucking
mosquitoes.
I took a piss last night
next to Harry.
We got no less than
four mosquitoes
bites each on our cocks.
Our cocks are bumpy with
mosquito bites.
The good side is they're now
ribbed for your pleasure.
Meaning girls.
Arrrr.
[HISS]
Fucking raining and miserable.
We slept in a fucking
rusty shovel.
Fucking ride or die.
HARRY KIM: [HISS]
DAVID CHOE: Fuck, man.
Nature's so beautiful.
There's only one way
to catch a fish.
That's with a fucking
ninja star.
Welcome, America, to
Dave Choe's Death
Star Training Camp.
HARRY KIM: Got it!
I got one!
DAVID CHOE: Unnh!
HARRY KIM: Yeah!
Yeahhhhhhhhhggh!
Arrrrrghghhhh.
DAVID CHOE: This is how we
catch food out here.
Fucking wilderness.
Look at this motherfucker.
We're in the middle
of nowhere.
I went fucking so far to get
this fucking ap-- hey, I was
going to give this to you.
Anyways, I went so far to get
this fucking apple and I'm
starting to eat the apple, and
then this fucker shows up and
he's all looking for food, so
I'm gonna give it to him.
Hey, I'm going to give
you an apple.
You don't want the apple?
Moose!
This'll be a delicious treat
for him when he gets it.
I'm gonna try to throw
it next to him.
Bullwinkle!
Eat the apple.
It's good.
It's delicious.
Eat the apple.
I fucking gave you my apple.
Fuck the moose.
We're relatively close to
a city called Fairbanks.
It's in Alaska.
And I guess we just found
home for tonight.
Hopefully there's nothing
crazy going on in here.
Hello?
There's a garage.
HARRY KIM: Hello?
DAVID CHOE: Anyone home?
[KNOCK]
DAVID CHOE: Hello?
Anyone home?
[KNOCK]
DAVID CHOE: Hello?
This shit's fucking
freaky, man.
HARRY KIM: What is this?
This is nuts.
[KNOCK]
HARRY KIM: Yeah.
Good as any.
DAVID CHOE: All right.
This is home for tonight.
Um, the whole "Thumbs Up" crew
has not been really taking
care of themselves, health
and food-wise.
And so although it's not on
film, every member of "Thumbs
Up," including me, Harry, the
cameraman and the crew, have
all shit in their pants at
least once on this trip.
At least once.
We've been mostly staying in
construction sites and
abandoned warehouses.
We stayed in a fucking crazy
rundown house that had a bunch
of shit, like sleeping
bags and stuff.
And it smelt like fungus.
And I was worried about
Harry's lungs, so.
[BREAKING GLASS]
DAVID CHOE: We have one more day
of this amazing adventure
to hunt down Santa Claus
in the North Pole.
We will find this
motherfucker.
But who knows what the
day holds for us?
We have no idea what
will happen.
Everyone out here looks like
a scary Russian vampire.
So we don't know what's
going to happen.
Stay tuned, America.
Thumbs up.
Here we are, trying to get
a ride to the North Pole.
I'm out of fucking
paint, dude.
North Pole?
We've been out here for a little
bit and not having much
luck, so we picked up this
gigantic Spider-Man hand,
which we're filling up.
All right, look.
Check it out, America.
This is what's going on.
See this kid?
That's me and Harry on this
trip, just full of life, full
of excitement.
What's going on right now is we
got the classic Spider-Man
pose, shooting the web.
And you fold the pinkie back and
the pointer finger back,
and what do you got?
You got thumbs up, America.
So that's what we're going
for right now.
A giant hitchhiking fist.
[SIREN]
HARRY KIM: Oh, we got--oh,
shit We got a ride.
DAVID CHOE: All right.
Get in, get in.
Thumbs up, America!
HARRY KIM: Thumbs up!
DAVID CHOE: Thumbs
up, bitches!
HARRY KIM: Whoa, whoa, whoa.
DAVID CHOE: We love you!
Almost there.
Thanks for the lift, Ralph.
HARRY KIM: This is it.
DAVID CHOE (SHOUTING):
North Poooooooole!
All right, thanks, Ralph.
Have a good time.
Here we are.
HARRY KIM: Yeah.
DAVID CHOE: North Pole, bitch.
Our cameraman doesn't give a
fuck because he's Jewish and
grew up worshipping Hanukkah
Harry, but we're in Santa
Claus's house right now.
Ralph, who refused to be on
camera, definite convict,
definite, definite felon.
Nice guy anyways.
HARRY KIM: Little shady.
DAVID CHOE: Wanted to give
us a ride but didn't
want to be on camera.
It's all right.
Anyways, elves, Santa, reindeer
steaks, all that
goodness awaits us ahead.
Let's go.
North Pole, bitch!
Yeah!
HARRY KIM: North Pole.
DAVID CHOE: Thumbs
up, America.
North Pole!
He's making a list.
He's checking it twice.
He's gonna find out who's
been naughty or nice.
Santa Claus, we're coming
to your town.
What the fuck?
Fuck!
There's no David.
There's no Harry.
I don't even know if I want to
see this fucking guy anymore.
A lifetime of disappointment.
Go see his ass?
HARRY KIM: No.
DAVID CHOE: Let's go see him.
HARRY KIM: That could
be his naughty list.
DAVID CHOE: All right,
let's go.
He's a technically a reindeer,
but check out his gigantic
moose knuckle.
Let's go see Santa.
FEMALE SPEAKER: He's OK.
MALE SPEAKER: [INAUDIBLE]
smile, bud.
FEMALE SPEAKER: He's OK.
SANTA CLAUS: [INAUDIBLE]
where y'all from?
SANTA CLAUS: Sure.
Where did you come from.
DAVID CHOE: We hitchhiked
all the way from
Mexico to come see you.
SANTA CLAUS: Hitchhiked?
DAVID CHOE: Yeah.
HARRY KIM: Yes.
DAVID CHOE: And we're
very hap-- can
we give you a present?
HARRY KIM: Yeah, we wanted
to bring you--
DAVID CHOE: It's
nice and cold.
HARRY KIM: A little special
something to
warm up your holidays.
SANTA CLAUS: Oh.
We'll put it right over
here right now, OK?
DAVID CHOE: OK.
Thanks, Santa.
SANTA CLAUS: Thank you.
DAVID CHOE: I was a little
disappointed 'cause in 1984, I
didn't get the present
that I wanted.
MRS. CLAUS: Oh, dear.
DAVID CHOE: And I feel like
that was probably the best
I've ever been my whole life.
SANTA CLAUS: Well, I'm sorry.
Maybe something happened
during the transit.
Maybe I left it at the
next door neighbor's.
MRS. CLAUS: Could be.
DAVID CHOE: All right, that's--
OK.
But I'm not for holding
a grudge, so.
SANTA CLAUS: [LAUGHS]
So what part of Mexico
you from?
DAVID CHOE: We came
from Tijuana.
SANTA CLAUS: Tijuana, Tijuana.
MRS. CLAUS: Welcome.
HARRY KIM: We came right
across the border.
SANTA CLAUS: That's right.
That's good.
DAVID CHOE: We got stopped in
Canada, and then we got to
ride on a flying sleigh.
SANTA CLAUS: Well,
that's good.
Who's this gentleman
DAVID CHOE: Oh, he's
our buddy.
He's coming along with us.
You're sort of the wizard
at the end of the road.
SANTA CLAUS: [LAUGHS]
DAVID CHOE: It's been
a long journey.
Time to go home now.
SANTA CLAUS: Merry Christmas.
HARRY KIM: Merry Christmas
to you.
MRS. CLAUS: Thank you.
DAVID CHOE: Nice to meet you.
MRS. CLAUS: Thank
you for coming.
SANTA CLAUS: Nice to meet you.
[INAUDIBLE]
Nice to meet you, sir.
Nice to meet you.
DAVID CHOE: Nice to meet you.
MRS. CLAUS: Nice to
meet you too.
SANTA CLAUS: Thank you.
DAVID CHOE: Are there
elves around?
SANTA CLAUS: Not today.
DAVID CHOE: Oh, OK.
Love the belt buckle.
Hey Santa, next time you're on
your sleigh and you see us
guys on the side of the
road hitchhiking,
can you pick us up?
SANTA CLAUS: I'll do
that, I'll do that.
DAVID CHOE: Thumbs up,
thumbs up, Santa.
SANTA CLAUS: OK.
Have a good one.
DAVID CHOE: Thanks, Santa.
Thanks for [INAUDIBLE].
HARRY KIM: Thank you.
SANTA CLAUS: You're welcome.
DAVID CHOE: I'm like a little
bit, like starstruck.
I feel like I just met Jesus
Christ or something.
HARRY KIM: No, he's
a great guy.
DAVID CHOE: That was
the real deal, man.
I feel like such a jerk for
like, yelling at you, yelling
at the Canadians, yelling
at anybody.
I just want to be a better
person from now on.
Let's see how long it lasts.
My feet are tired.
HARRY KIM: Let's party with
Santa tonight, though.
DAVID CHOE: My thumbs
are tired.
It's time to go home.
Let's head back home.
HARRY KIM: I think we should
kick it for a little
bit and then go.
DAVID CHOE: Harry, I'm trying
to fucking do the ending
monologue right now.
Will you quit fucking
it up, dude?
HARRY KIM: I think we should
do the fireworks here.
DAVID CHOE: That--
Jesus Christ, dude.
We could just do all that shit
and edit it in later.
Why do you keep interrupting
me, man?
HARRY KIM: In front
of Santa Claus.
DAVID CHOE: Fuck, man.
Fuck you.
Jesus.
Thumbs up, America.
I'm sorry I yelled at you.
I'm sorry I screamed at you.
Thank you, Mexicans, for
showing us your dick.
Mexicans, thanks for the corn.
Thank you, America, for leaving
us alone in the
backseat with your babies.
Thank you for giving us rides.
Thank you for giving
us plane rides.
America, thanks for letting us
crash in your backyards.
Thanks for making out with
Harry in every city.
Canadians, thanks for nothing.
Thank you, America, for letting
us use your entire
nation as a backdrop for the
most bitching music video, for
me and Harry rockin'
the nation.
America, we're tired.
Thanks for riding
along with us.
It's time to go home.
America, don't fuck
with Santa.
He's got a huge fuckin' dong.
I seen it.
Santa's got a huge
moose knucle.
[MUSIC - FUCKED UP, "DAVID
COMES TO LIFE"]
DAVID CHOE (SHOUTING):
Thumbs up, America!
HARRY KIM: Yeahhh!
DAVID CHOE: Thumbs!
Up!
Bitch!
HARRY KIM: Thumbs
way the fuck up!
DAVID CHOE: Thumbs
up, motherfucker!