urges
al four point five million year old
planet still involving
discounted shift in class
neurons
and glaciers grow and risky
the earths crust is carved in numerous
and fascinating wanes
leaving a trail of geological mystery
behind
in this episode
an investigation into california's san
andreas fall
greatest fault line on earth
eight hundred miles long
this a police car on the landscape this
fall and earthquake
after
but for now is waits quietly
defund russian
stress to strike someone suggests
branch
percent interest false is one of the
most dangerous geological features
california's greatest sins and millions
of our citizens live in constant parel
since records began
there've been thirty march persuades
along the san andreas
word
now america's geologists corrupted
texans a warning of a potential disaster
the major damage has been done
the fall of two thousand eight
more than three hundred scientists
calculated what a major earthquake would
do
to southern california
weird dot aerobatic seven whited kept
all part of a actually avocado
it never happened
definitive scientific report presented
to politicians was code named shankar
your forecast thousands of deaths
means of dollars of damage
in the city of los and
makes a crucial to investigate
the most important question
will the next big bertha
san andreas fault
the latest preparations for disaster of
the climax of an investigation that
started more
hundred years ago
in the aftermath of the great san
francisco perth quake of nineteen oh six
earthquake struggle on wednesday just
before dawn
contractual via forty five-second
igniting fires the rage unchecked for
the next four days
twenty eight thousand
ten the entire city destroyed
and more than three thousand people
one in a refund for the population
for the magnitude of seven point eight
it's in the top twenty
most americans strongest preference
greek sentences to reflection
known understood working made
distribution
native american it's explained of
earthquakes and shots from a battle
between warring spears
latter-day explorers couldn't understand
the shocks the destroy their mission
one spanish mission every room
yet
speakers shop around me from explosions
or under the grounds friends
three hundred years later
and sciences still made little progress
refugees in the ruins of san francisco's
still blamed earthquakes on mysterious
underground explosions
so just three days after the earthquake
the state of california asked one of the
world's most famous geologists
andrew lost from california state
university to investigate what had
destroyed the city
he and a team of twenty five scientists
began collecting damage evidence
this city and surrounding countryside
there were roads that had balked
rail tracks that had twisted
the most startling evidence of all
that came near the town of police barren
county to the north of san francisco
this picket fence haddon eight-foot get
in the middle
before the earthquake it was a solid
boundaries
it's dividing two feet
when he recreated what had happened
lawson realize the full length add fuel
to the park
and torn the fence into
plotting the other
as on a map around san francisco
surprising have
because connecting the dots
drew a straight line
and that every point
the birth
the same way
on the coast to the north
this line of weakness was the culprit
they were searching for
south of san francisco the suspect line
ran under the family
the laguna dicen andreas
so now the earthquake perpetrator atlast
had a name
professor lawson who a decade earlier
had identified cracks in the earth here
as a harmless rift now re christened it
san andreas fault
in modern-day san francisco the
buildings the roads in the railways have
long since been repeated
but if you know where to look evidence
of the nineteen oh six point
still be found
geologist charlie paul files in the
footsteps of loss in st seeking signs of
the habit from nineteen oh six
he finds it on the cliffs that muscle
rock twelve miles south of san francisco
the class is not here by accident by the
very good reason why this witness here
half a mile or so love the short face
apparently fell off
in the nineteen oh six earthquake and if
you look down below us is big located
block on that's near the present-day
short line and isn't she s
anymore
on this and this fall the san andreas
fault is up
about quarter mile offshore airports
that's one of the major crustal
junctions sab on the side of north
america
modern computers canal trace how damage
weeks read out across the city
and that can points where the quake
originated along the san andreas
it was offshore about two miles out to
sea from the golden gate bridge
so to continue tracking the fault of the
investigation must head out to sea
marine geologists use remote operating
vehicles many submarines to map the
season
what you see is subtle variations in the
photography of hypocrisy that would not
naturally lineup
for there might be a line on the ocean
floor the is higher or lower on one side
and you can
use various
to determine that this actually is a
fall
instead of some of the process
running south across the sea there
the san andreas finally runs out of
ocean
and hits the land
this broken line of rocks stretching
infancy marks where the sender andreas
hits land twelve miles south sent
well here are a lot for walk enforce
actually standing on the same day at
fault right now and
uh... yes there was an earthquake i
don't know what happened
right here but i want one of the year
this pacific coastline
where clips crumble slowly into the sea
is the boundary between two the earth's
massive continental plates
separated by the san andreas fault to
vast separate blocks of the earths crust
fly directly alongside each other
here at the continent of north america
by slightly on top of the adjacent
section of cross which holds the pacific
ocean
join can be seen
with these lower darker rocks are
overlay by light colored said amenorrhea
rocks
is what type of everybody
body out more than a hundred million
years amazing to walk bodies that that
are not someone anyway they brought
together
the fault line was exposed to geologists
when the cliffs collapsed here in the
nineteen oh six earthquake
but back then
nobody understood how and why
two different types of rocks
when next to each other
until around forty years ago
when the answer
finally with the
by the theory
affly tektronix
all hearing showed that the earths crust
consists of separate moving plates on
which the oceans and continents it
uh... around two hundred million years
ago they have the pacific ocean played
collided with north america
and started sinking underneath the
lighter com
professor geophysics more sober studies
that process called subduction in his
laboratory at stanford university
for many millions of years prior to the
existence of the senators fault the
pacific plate was some ducting beneath
north america that
fortunately was dying down
uh... that process went on for well well
over a hundred million years so a
tremendous amount of activity was
occurring
as the unstoppable force of one plate
methionine object of the other they were
forced to change direction
about twenty million years ago
claim options were such that the pacific
going to have to start sliding north
with respect to north america and no
you know there's a principal
motion is the sliding process between
the complex and twenty million years ago
the san andreas fault was born
inflates the crushed different types of
rock together
just this year
atlast the investigation knows what it
is dealing with
the san andreas falls is eight hundred
miles long
emerging from the seat at north of point
arena
in northern california
and running down to the solvency
the evidence is coming together
from the nineteen oh six earthquake such
as the picket fence that was torn apart
fruit
but the land was moved
connecting the dots identifies the
screen
the san andreas falls
muscle rock
uncovers different plates of the earths
crust on either side fault
but investigators still
need more information about how off
san andreas has spawned birthplace
the past
it might help answered the all-important
question
well the san andreas strike again
to discover when the senator is fault
will strike again investigation needs to
know about ancient earthquakes that have
struck along the fault line
that there's anything wrong
here in california to particular
challenge that some of her lawyers
written records were from the missions
and from the early explorers only dating
back into the eighteenth century here
whether parts of the world we have a
quick history going back no one
the investigation will stream of the
fifty miles south of san francisco two
industries
where the san andreas may have been
active for thousands of years
karen
this crucial evidence here about
prescription patient eyes
this creek used to four straight across
the center is fault here
but several earthquakes form natural
there
am where the san andreas falter wedges
up here in front of me
that created a small pond and now we're
looking at the dr sentiments about time
that record
the history of earthquakes and that
tells us quite a great deal about the
past behavior the san andreas fault
some of the twins are so small without
notes detective work gets in town and
dusty among tiny cracks insightful that
sometimes we can find out about the past
behavior in the san andreas fall by
looking at the tiniest details
at the bottom of this year old ajun
party
mugs sediments collected above a fine
line of pebbles
then denver's wage shifted the land
upwards on one side of the vertical for
one
service where was originally flat and
then
and subsequent earthquake it was broken
lying there so honest tiny fracture
strand of the senator is false
but finding proof that this is the site
of an ancient earthquake is only part of
the story
i've not needs to know how long ago it
happened
the bear rock layers of no help in
dating is find but just above the
fracture line of the rocks he has found
the evidence he needs
here
a bush was burned by a prehistoric
wildfire
and that remnant of carmen is why you
see this black stain on the side of the
trend toward
the key to unlock the needs of the rocks
is carbon fourteen
moment radiocarbon
its molecular structure means the carbon
fourteen is a more unstable isotoner and
other forms of carbon
it's absorbed by growing plants and
radioactivity decays loan rates after
the plant dies
so measuring carbon fourteen and
vegetation burned in a wildfire reveals
how long ago those plants died
dates the rock in which the carbon is
found
and through this week and reconstruct
the evidence of the past earthquakes
radiocarbon dating is true
persuasive than happening on the line of
the senate race
styles interview
the particular small earth
quake investigated by hand
is around
three-and-a-half
it happened at a time when the last time
you know
drying out
the investigation moves to an even more
remote desert spots
victories oakley
one hundred sixty miles north of los
angeles
here lies of dried up which takes and
unusual course
coming down on the hill frequent takes
his son sharp turned to his writings
a few hundred feet later it makes a
deeply on ninety degree turn to the left
the creek
crossed the line of the san andreas
police literally geologists were
mystified
wanting it'd been in this way
the scientific harini
women the nurses studies on the ground
nowadays but not has an advantage you
can take through the air
vault workout go planet opera type fire
caused by repeated wakefield along the
long line of feels marking the course of
the san andreas footnotes spots the
puzzling thing
instead he's seeking
potluck
wicket opa-locka robert here at the top
already prayed ahead did however old op
caliber daughter right there
five o'clock o'clock right there
fitness aerial view of the creek that
shows that the river once flows straight
on across the full
but little by little this series of
earthquakes along the san andreas drag
greenaway from its original horse
recreating how the land and move still
have not
to parts of the creek had traveled more
than three hundred feet apart
guard plated apathetic wait a minute
barbed wire
or creekside required stop that
because mcallen straight across called
medoff advertise
earlier investigators had already
radiocarbon dated the land on each side
of the folks here
revealing that it took three thousand
years to change the creeks position
so knowing the distance and the time it
took to do with let's hope not calculate
the average the with which the to land
masses are moving past each other
three hundred feet
in three thousand years
look for decades
just over a cage
year
but this was never is
one each year move
reality
was a series
so if you small jobs
whenever tension builds up enough but
remix and moving planes overcome
friction between the rock
the land of garner support
it's an important moment for the
investigation
knowing how fast the land is moving not
only reviews the stress that's building
up
will also on the wrist personally
percent interest falls is getting a bit
sequence
long dried up part
revealed this site danger earthquakes
from prehistoric fire provides the tix
dinner with them
how fast the plates are moving along the
san andreas
now investigation has a new districts
all
people and along the san andreas is
moving one inch every
causing earthquakes
then why
one small town along the fault
investigation has discovered how fast
the land is stretching straining along
each side of the san andreas bombs
wish it would help established when that
ever-increasing stress will soon have
the land apply
next major earthquake
but there's a problem
one part of the fault line just doesn't
fit the pattern
the small town of hollister is unique
along the san andreas fault system
it's never had an earthquake
investigation was going to find out why
hollister has a population of thirty
seven thousand there
and what not
is quite the way it should be
and there are plenty of clues
suggesting that the
and must be moving here
but cracks
christopher way out of line
and out of shape
walking through the hollister wish can
see anything that man has built that was
laid out in a straight line
may have a johnny and that the every
year it changes a little bit of
progressive saying
was losing add up toward conclusion
even without any risk with reverses this
town in the heart of the senator is
system
still slides imperceptibly slowly and
effortlessly along
in one sense that the image that you see
here for share it with the creeping
yourself
is clearly for under control whatever
geologist if you start playing that out
for tens of thousands or hundreds of
thousands or millions of years the
consequences of that become enormously
for many years creeping ground that
moves without earthquakes remained in
unsolved mysteries
then
the investigation moved one hundred
miles south
to another small community
wendell and also creeps along
diligent parkfield has a population of
just thirty seven people and a brief
which spanned right across the san
andreas falls
the bridge separates the pacific plate
on one side
from the north american place on the
other
and agreed railing have started today
i am i right now i'm pacific tori
arnaud west side of the standards for
the sender's comes off before i could
add here or
and right across that
field right under the bridge
read or by the quarter-million transpose
the men are more
the middleman
the movement here around the bridge is
strikingly similar to the slow breeding
ground of hollister
but there is one important difference
here in parkview every couple of decades
uh... this village does have birthplace
they just little tremors
but they're big enough to be recorded on
earthquake monitoring seismographs
that's why the village proudly boasts of
being the earthquake capital of the war
but it's perhaps more accurately called
the earthquake study capital because
scientists are fascinated by the fact
that earthquakes here follow-up
predictable pattern
earthquakes policed right without
warning
patrol of death and destruction made
worse because nobody knew they were
coming
so scientists are desperate for any
clues that might help predict when an
earthquake could happen
and here in parkfield
the earthquakes happen with astonishing
regularity
on average every couple of decades or so
minor quakes happen here eighteen fifty
seven
eighteen eighty one nineteen oh one
nineteen twenty two nineteen thirty four
and nineteen sixty six these after the
sixty six earthquake investigator set-up
a network of monitoring instruments to
see if the fall gave any warning
before the next birthweight arrive
they expected it sometime between
nineteen eighty eight and nineteen
ninety-three but it was late
months of waiting
stretched in two years
this but still
scientists wages
until finally in december two thousand
four
a long-awaited earthquake arise
and was cost on phil
from a now slightly warned and damaged
camera a
the earthquake moving may not have seen
that impressive
but the instruments collected a massive
information
the data didn't after all helped with
earthquake prediction
but it did pinpoint where the earthquake
started underground
which told investigators where to look
next
deep down under the parkfield
countryside
starting slightly to one side of the
falls
the aim was to mandolin and staff into
the very heart of the senate race
three years of drilling long cords of
rock were extracted
in the exact spot
quaker kern
this was the first time teamleader
geologist mark so back had ever seen
rocks from the center of the senate race
what we're looking at here our course
from the active san andreas fault from
and up to about two miles
for the earth science community
these are like moon rocks
as we were trying to assume these course
we had a great
do you love
truly difficulty the san andreas fault
was literally fighting back
after nine weeks of attempting to
recover the colours in the middle of the
huge lightning storm
almost the same directly out of
hollywood with the thunder and lightning
the scores
inferences
since it was a tremendous feeling of
satisfaction
uh... the lightning and thunder just
made it that much more dramatic
and were all wearing gloves
we want equal marketers to affect the
core
and that the war was that you touch the
core as little as possible there
along with this
it's artist you're off
reality was recruitment lifestyles and
it was just such a remarkable thing to
be actually looking at the san andreas
fall
for the very first time
early on got potential
buried within the rock courts they found
a vital clue about the way that lands
lives along the san andreas
bouncer pen tonight
serpentine isn't unusual
rock type it was originally formed i had
a base in the ocean crust an exit wound
up onto the continent but the reason
that september ninth
so interesting is that extra penny is
very
usually alternative helpful i was the
water slide and reinforcements
talcum powder is very slippery
accounts crystalline structure
stall sliding flat plates makes it one
of the slippery a strong sounds of
silence
that helped could well be
uh... lucky mineral in in deciding how
the full is actually working in in
central california we see that the
secrets of the slipping san andreas fall
is actually the walks themselves
metallic explains the tiny earthquakes
in parkfield
nobody's yet drilled to investigate the
rocks that hollister
but scientists suspect the top is
presently
cracks in the wall chill the land creeds
in hollister
an abandoned the bridge reveals the same
creeping ground
in a nearby town
extracted from the fall contains
repentant
leading investigators to the softest and
slippery is minimal
lubricate some parts of the fall
the investigation is having success but
one crucial question remains to be
answered
with the san andreas fall
do next
the investigation into the san andreas
falls is trying to predict when and
where its next major earthquake almost
right
so far the only certain prediction is
the far distant future of the san
andreas
looked twenty million years ahead
if the plague movements continue to
follow their pattern los angeles www end
up becoming a suburb of san francisco
predictions on a short time scale far
more difficult
if you would ask the question
can we predict earthquakes my answer
would be no because i know what your
question really meant
milk and we predicted earthquake is an
approach certain fault at a certain time
that we can specify in the future and we
cannot do that but there are many things
we can't predict we can predict which
faults are likely to produce the big
earthquakes weaken verdict
helping the earthquakes are likely to be
then we can even predict a probability
of the earthquake occurrence over some
period of several decades
predictions are most crucial where the
san andreas runs to the south of l_a_
here in the picture of the valujet
geological evidence of earthquakes
stretches back fifteen hundred years and
more
and they follow our regular pattern
major earthquake strikes herewith
monotonous regularity every two hundred
years
but the latest with is long overdue
there hasn't been an earthquake here for
more than three hundred years
that's a concern
because parts of the san andreas fault
system run straight from fear towards
the city of los angeles
defaults will transmit earthquake shocks
in a straight line
towards california biggest city
geologist fury fiato regularly monitors
on the ground and on either side of the
fault line
p lines up his g_p_s_ equipment
precisely over a series of metal tags
fixed into the ground
this information is crucial for
estimating
how fast the full flexibility and what
is the rate of fiction malaysian of
strain in the crust in other words how
close the crossed is brought to failure
by uh... slipped of the full cadets
repeated alter precise measurements
reveal that land here on the surface
hardly moves at all this is a problem
because deep underground
stresses and strains are still building
the could fall there's little doubt that
the fairly high speed elders deformation
was growing and growing anger always
talking
xxx miles on the ground default is
moving to this more than in usually
doesn't
which tells the opposite side of the
century since the last week the surface
should have shifted three hundred inches
twenty five feet some more
but few can since
so sooner or later something's gotta
give free alcoa knows what's that's
something will be
trucks concerts
and uh... one example
this typo frock which is called the
granite and this is in fact the rock
out-of which most of the earths crust is
made
a microscope reveals the crystalline
structure of the granite
the crystals make the rock stuff
but they have a hidden weakness
bonds between they suddenly crack under
stress
basically wants those materials
solidifies
uh... it is able to uh... arm
crack and the sheared
on the fourth surface and liberal
behavior of resources what wise behind
the physics of prescription
granite rocks underline all the san
andreas fall of right field the rocks
under greater stress than anywhere else
because it's so many centuries since a
major quake occurred
and now we're already three hundred
years on it and so it is not
uh... the strain them all the strain
that has being accumulate in the fault
at this point
as very close to the maximum strain of
this fall has ever seen through its
uh... of geological record and this is a
full dennis couple of generating great
destructive earthquake
tiago believes becoming quake could be
the big that people have been talking
about for years
that's
because of the population density in
southern california
when the last huge quake occurred three
hundred years ago
los angeles was just a tiny spanish
mission community you within one hundred
people
now it's america's second-largest city
with almost eleven million people living
in the earthquake bomb rebel
metropolitan area
people in california
probably experienced the smaller
moderate size earthquake every year
giving the moving in your house but it's
really actually kind of fun there is no
major destruction
people just along with their life
how much bigger events on the other hand
are quite a bit different story
with the threat to los angeles becoming
ever clearer
the investigations nearing its
conclusion
repeated g_p_s_ measurements in the
desert reveal evidence that stress is
building up
while examination of the rocks of the
crust show they may not take the strain
all the evidence points towards a
potentially huge earthquake
building up
southern california
and new experiments suggest the coming
plague
could be far worse
ever imagined
there is new urgency in the
investigation into the san andreas falls
as revealed by recent evidence compiled
by three hundred america's most
respected scientists
they warned that los angeles will be
devastated for major quake strikes along
the southern section of the fall
while there hasn't been a major quake
for hundreds of years even small ones
can still be deadly
but the northridge earthquake which
struck this l_a_ suburb in nineteen
ninety four
luxury along an offshoot of the main san
andreas fall
the quake was only a magnitude six point
seven
considered moderate on the scale of
earthquake measured
but it's still killed seventy two people
and injured twelve thousand
and new evidence suggests mother nature
might have a lot more in store for los
angeles
scientists have long known that
earthquakes generate several distinct
sets of ways
the travel at different speeds each
spreading damage and destruction out
from the epicenter
modern city buildings in birthweight
prone areas like california engineer
companies such way
now do research by geophysicist
professor our results suggests that the
senator is may offer a new and even more
deadly threat
resigned his research is how birthrates
rupture along straight lines faults
just like the san andreas where it
approaches los angeles
he creates his own many earthquakes
representing the san andreas fault by
hairline crack in the thick transparent
block
this special material shows up internal
stress lines when it's a bit violation
and the earthquake
is triggered by a tiny explosion
st
and dot
and it's not always began after we have
a threat
people from high speed camera capturing
ten million frames a second
reveals a startling in newly discovered
phenomenon
this frozen picture
reveal stress line speeding along the
many san andreas in the milliseconds
after the explosion
patrol into the left of this train is a
previously unrecognized type of
shockwave racing along the rupture line
from the earthquake center
on a microscopic scale it looks and
moves exactly like the sonic boom
produced when the supersonic aircraft
such as coddling
breaks the sound barrier
because we also see microloans
lines that i needed to fund up to fix
are from the kids
airplanes
and just like a sonic boom
you can be dangerous
the same sense that we hear this morning
uh... from the cargo
you're going to see this funny
from that
the danger comes because many high-rises
just aren't built to cope with extra
stress from this newly discovered tight
shop
so if you are in all of the indian for
example
abuses wondering
you would like to relate some damage
very soon after that
based on ground shaking callers ago on
it actually is coming
the high-speed wrote to the resigned his
call synergy
happen where forbes running in a
straight line
which might help explain the one hundred
year old miserable surrounding the great
san francisco void
natural disaster which launched the
entire san andreas investigation
the overwhelming tan
san francisco has long seemed
surprisingly out of proportion
to the seven point eight magnitude
and there's a particularly straight
section
the san andreas approaching san
francisco
so many scientists now believe but the
damage was greater than expected because
nineteen oh six quake had traveled as
super sheer speed
of greater concern to modern emergency
services is not what happened a century
ago but what could happen
tomorrow because there is a similar
street section of false aggressed
heading straight towards los angeles
and here's the super show your first
with develops on that line and than the
consequences could be disastrous
all of the investigations warnings about
the senate race came together in the
fall of two thousand eight
with the biggest earthquake drills ever
held in california's if this rather
quick would have happened in reality
it would have been buildings coming down
the you know that there would be no
watertown certainly areas sets within
six says it's all about
but but but the real chance of los
angeles soon being hit by a massive
birthplace
the best scientific consensus now warns
that there's a ninety nine-percent
chance
of a major earthquake in southern
california within the next thirty years
to better understand the threat to l_a_
the geologists produced their study
joint experts in charge of the city's
disaster plan
and none of them doubt that the big
quake is coming
there really isn't even a question of s
anymore
the shaking is going to be a severe for
two to three minutes
and is gonna stop
many had that moment of silence about
that happens before you start hearing
car alarms
although the selling out of the
the study estimates that in a juror's
within the l_a_ metro area
would cost two thousand deaths fifty
thousand injured
and two hundred billion dollars of debt
figure out how corporations developing
and the blocks will be on fire
and
that's the kind that there's an era that
we're looking at the
this factor of disaster california's
people in cities motivates the search to
unravel the secrets of the san andreas
full
all the evidence
finally did
jennifer
nineteen oh six disaster chokeholds
eight hundred miles
different types of rock at muscle rock
provide clues to how the fault was
created twenty million years ago
the riverbed
middletown explains why some parts slim
without major quakes
fertile ground rocks reveal a threat to
los angeles
recent lab experiments uncover new and
more danger
earthquake shockwave
one goal
has eluded rock detective
the greatest fault line on purpose
with the sleeping san andreas
come to life once again
that could be anytime
was the only certainty
is that nothing is certain
you need ever evolving story
delivered