[SPANISH GAME RADIO BROADCAST]
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
ADRI MURGUIA: Faustino
Barrientos embodies the
timeless lifestyle of the
Chilean gaucho, the more
isolated equivalent of the
North American cowboy.
Bringing settlers into Patagonia
was a challenge.
And in 1937, Chile started
handing out land claims to
each colonizer who could clear
120 acres of forest in an
effort to make the
land fertile.
Although construction of routes
to Patagonia land made
the gauchos more accessible,
we heard that Faustino had
moved far beyond the last
stretch of the Pan-American
Highway to Peninsula La Florida,
where he continued
living in complete isolation,
like the original settlers.
Faustino is rumored to be living
alone on his land for
the past 46 years, removed
from civilization and
technology as if time had
never struck Patagonia.
We set out on a journey to find
Faustino Barrientos--
from New York on a cold
winter night.
We had about a dozen bags with
us and had no idea of what we
were getting ourselves into.
What we did know is it will take
us four days of travel
time to reach him.
We caught an 11 hour
flight to Santiago.
We had a layover, and
then got on a
shorter flight to Balmaceda.
There we met our crew, gathered
our gear, loaded the
truck, and drove to Cochrane,
which took five hours.
We spent the night there and
headed out to Port Yungay in
the morning to catch our
ferry to Rio Bravo.
It had taken us two days
to get this far.
And we weren't even
halfway there.
It was impossible to imagine how
you would ever get here by
horse rides from Santiago, like
Faustino had probably
done in the past.
Patagonia's a region at the
southern end of South America.
The area covers about one-third
of both Chile and
Argentina and is home
to a rich and
mostly untouched ecosystem.
It's an important fresh water
source, which also makes it
one of the least polluted
places on earth.
On our third day of travel, we
finally arrived at the end of
the Pan-American Highway, which
was built to connect
remote communities
in the region.
Its final stretch reaches
Villa O'Higgins, a town
formerly only accessible by
plane or horse ride, which is
why it's called the "Last
Frontier of Chilean
Patagonia." With a population
of roughly 400 people, it's
considered a stomping ground for
explorers and scientists
heading towards the South
Patagonian Ice Field, which
doubles as deepest lake
in the Americas.
While we were in O'Higgins, we
visited Faustino's brother to
get a better idea of what
to expect from him.
FLORIDO BARRIENTOS SANCHEZ:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
ADRI MURGUIA: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
FLORIDO BARRIENTOS SANCHEZ:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
ADRI MURGUIA: [SPANISH].
It seemed that Faustino
had a bad reputation
throughout the town.
There was even a rumor
that he had attempted
to shoot his nephew.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
MISAEL TISNADO BARRIENTOS:
ADRI MURGUIA: After learning
that Faustino not only
disliked other people's company,
but also had tried to
kill one of his family members,
we're more than
concerned about staying with
him on a deserted piece of
land without escape routes or
forms of communication with
the outside world.
But we continued on our
way to find him.
Since 2005, this boat started
taking tourists on glacial
expeditions and contributed to
bringing civilization closer
to those who lived out
here in isolation.
It was appropriately named
Robinson Crusoe.
I made it.
We're in Faustino's land.
We were told to walk straight
from the shore towards the
mountains and we'd
find his home.
I don't know if we're
walking in the right
direction, to be honest.
As the boat took off in the
distance, we realized how
isolated we really were.
We walked for about a mile
until we finally spotted
Faustino's retreat.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS: