THOMAS MORTON: Hey,
it's Thomas.
We're in Belgrade, turbofolk
capital of the world.
Turbofolk is traditional
Yugoslavian folk music played
over some of the most violently
aggressive techno
ever recorded, and made for
criminals by criminals.
Where Western pop stars' run-ins
with the law generally
start and end with stuff like
drugs and drunk driving, it
isn't uncommon for a turbofolk
star to be arrested with a
trunkful of smuggled cocaine
or machine guns.
Turbofolk started in the
roadhouse bars dotting
Serbia's highways before
migrating to the city and
becoming the country's biggest
export after war crimes.
Kornelije Kovac is like the
Serbian Elton John.
He's also the closest thing we
could find to a turbofolk
expert without having to talk
to the Serbian paparazzi.
[SPEAKING SERBIAN]
Under Tito, folk music was
deemed too kitschy and
embarrassing for
state support.
So folk singers had
to get their money
from another source--
the Serbian Mafia.
As Yugoslavia fell apart in the
'90s, gangsters bought up
state assets and even led their
own armies in the wars
with the breakaway republics.
They channeled their plunder
into the music they loved, and
overnight, folk turned from
funny country songs about
drunk husbands into turbofolk,
an ear-shattering
million-beats-per-minute
celebration of sex, money,
boob jobs, brand name crap, and
astonishing levels of tackiness.
The queen of the '90s turbofolk
scene was a Serbian
teenager named Svetlana
Raznatovic,
better known as Ceca.
Ceca's songs became the
soundtrack to the wars in
Bosnia and Croatia, and Ceca
herself even traveled to the
front lines to entertain
the Serbian soldiers.
On one of these trips, she fell
in love with infamous
Serbian warlord Arkan.
Following the war, the two
were married in a garish
ceremony Serbian newspapers
described as a fairy tale.
The marriage was broadcast on
state TV, sealing Ceca as the
new queen of Yugoslavian music
and making the marriage of
turbofolk with organized crime
about as literal as it gets.
Arkan was killed in 2000, and
three years later, Ceca was
arrested for having
a cache of assault
rifles in her basement.
Ceca's still under house arrest,
but in her wake, a new
generation of turbofolk
stars has sprouted.
Goga Sekulic is one
of the potential
heirs to Ceca's throne.
Her 1999 breakthrough single,
"Panties," led to quick
success as well as numerous
body modifications and
follow-up hits like "Boy Toy"
and "Sexy Businessman."
We met Goga at the studio of
Pink TV, which is like
Serbia's answered to MTV
but a lot trashier.
It's been the career springboard
for all of
turbofolk's major stars.
Basically, it's turbofolk's
Factory of Dreams.
THOMAS MORTON: Balkan women, in
general, are a little bit
intimidating and often
tall, but Goga's
like, another species.
She looks like--
like a tan Navi.
GOGA SEKULIC:
[SINGING IN SERBIAN]
THOMAS MORTON: After the show,
we headed to Goga's studio to
watch her record
her new album.
GOGA SEKULIC: [SPEAKING SERBIAN]
THOMAS MORTON: Did she say
"Sexy Businessman?"
[MUSIC PLAYING - GOGA SEKULIC,
"SEXY BUSINESSMAN"]
THOMAS MORTON: Great.
What's it about?
Besides a sexy businessman?
GOGA SEKULIC: [SPEAKING SERBIAN]
GOGA SEKULIC:
[SINGING IN SERBIAN]
GOGA SEKULIC: [SPEAKING SERBIAN]
Good, huh?
THOMAS MORTON: Yeah.
MALE SPEAKER: [SPEAKING SERBIAN]
GOGA SEKULIC: [SPEAKING SERBIAN]
THOMAS MORTON: While Goga took
a beauty nap, we had some
drinks with her manager and the
Serge Gainsbourg-looking
dude to get ready for a rare
Tuesday night performance at
Belgrade's Klub Mistique.
KORNELIJE KOVAC:
[SPEAKING SERBIAN]
THOMAS MORTON: This place is
hopping, for a Monday.
THOMAS MORTON: All the girls
are so tall here.
It's freaky.
Yeah?
Oh, OK.
We're in Republike Square in
Belgrade and we are head to
Klub Mistique.
And we are hauling ass.
GOGA SEKULIC: Yes.
THOMAS MORTON: Yes.
Everything-- everything
here is beautiful.
It's great.
It's just, it's very--
everybody is here
very forward.
I like it.
GOGA SEKULIC: [SPEAKING SERBIAN]
MALE SPEAKER: Especially her.
[HORN HONKS]
GOGA SEKULIC: Crazy men!
THOMAS MORTON: Before hitting
the club, we went to pick up
Goga's entourage.
We met our friends at a bar in
a neighborhood nicknamed
Silicone Valley.
Get it?
MALE SPEAKER: Please.
[INAUDIBLE].
THOMAS MORTON: I'm gonna make
this picture so much shorter.
MALE SPEAKER: Uh,
in the middle.
All the way in the middle.
THOMAS MORTON: I'm gonna look
like I'm kneeling right here.
GOGA SEKULIC: For you.
THOMAS MORTON: Aw.
Thank you.
These are beautiful.
Not quite real.
FEMALE SPEAKER:
[SPEAKING SERBIAN]
GOGA SEKULIC: [SPEAKING SERBIAN]
MALE SPEAKER: [SPEAKING SERBIAN]
THOMAS MORTON: Those are some
pretty nice fake roses.
GOGA SEKULIC: Crazy.
MALE SPEAKER: Where's
middle finger?
GOGA SEKULIC: Oh my god.
MALE SPEAKER: [SPEAKING SERBIAN]
GOGA SEKULIC: [SPEAKING AND
SINGING IN SERBIAN]
[BOY SINGS ALONG]
THOMAS MORTON: That
kid's psyched.
GOGA SEKULIC: Oh my god.
Come on.
THOMAS MORTON: These all--
these all the paparazzi?
The place kind of looks like
your standard tacky nightclub,
but everything's amped up to
beyond ridiculous levels.
The music is playing at
mind-altering volume.
The lasers shoot directly
in everybody's eyes.
Someone kept throwing stacks
of napkins at us.
Each of the club's several
floors was packed with
towering, fake-titted women and
men who looked like the
personification of murder.
A photographer kept recognizing
everybody in
Goga's extended entourage--
not from the music industry.
From news reports about
the Serbian Mafia.
At one point, Goga pulled me to
the railing and said, oooh.
Below us, two dudes were beating
the shit out of each
other amid an army of
security guards.
It's one thing watching drunk
dudes fight in a bar in New
York, but when it's two Serbs
in a club swarming with
criminals who've been drinking
all day, the stakes seem a
little higher.
We just left, and it's even
crazier fuckin' outside than
it was in there.
I just stepped on a dude's
foot who looked like--
it looked like he fought an
instinctual response to
fucking, like, shiv me.
This was great.
This is like, this isn't
like New York clubs.
This is insane.
All I did was drink brandy and
listen to music that was like,
felt like it was being punched
into my face the whole time.
GOGA SEKULIC (LAUGHING):
We are happy people.
THOMAS MORTON: That
was insane.
The push in turbofolk right now
is to clear out the trashy
past and go legit, which is
incidentally the same process
the entire country
is going through.
Ideally, this means finally
clearing out all the
corruption that's entrenched
itself on every level of
Serbian society since the
breakup of Yugoslavia.
But in probability, it means
sweeping 20 years of very ugly
history under the rug.
Then shooting it.