and as a result
uh... its
it's cause massive deformities
in children warning iraq right now so
so deputy speaker livid about that ally
depleted uranium essentially is what it
is is depleted uranium season weaponry
are primarily uh... because it
candy penetrate armor
and it was used
a lot by the u_s_ troops said the u_n_
you can't take trips you some of it as
well but um... though u_s_ troops
he's quite a bit of a time in a more
tell the u_n_
and that anywhere where they use these
area so that they can be decontaminated
dot right now the uh... that the
incidents of birth defects and
deformities
and communities doubt word targeted by
u_s_ troops is is really astounding i
i'm not sure what the exact number was i
think we have some graphics on that we
do uh... so
the birth defects influenza uh... itself
is working times higher
uh... then in her rocha nine nagasaki
after the party fun stuff
and we have graphics of of the pictures
of that
kids patties extremely yes really ready
to
yet because we missed please look away
is is that
it's it's really interesting
now this is not even counting the
the many many babies who were citizens
will have to have
and that i had the doctors there say
they have never seen this kind of the
former before coming to this trial has
hafter habits of guest intestines and
organs after the body
and multiple words
so it's really cute depressing to see
that that set that's what's going on
also just said to to make a point of
this that the united nations
last december in the general assembly
attempted to pass a resolution setting
in which it is the precautionary
principle when it comes to the use of
depleted uranium
but the u_s_
the u_k_ france and israel voted against
that resolution to take depleted uranium
out of the next an again so hundred
fifty five of the country said that we
should stop using it and uh... partially
united states is in favor of continuing
and even though it has such an
environmental destruction to the very
difficult to clean up and the
environment
and it has is very clear connections to
these these parents need to know if this
is not just the iraqis were suffering
it's our own soldiers to because um...
there are a lot of soldiers who are also
suffering from depleted uranium
contaminations
what happened to them if they're getting
these massive headaches with their
stability they can't move
there are so urinating line
round there at their date diagnosis
cancer
anticancer res influences
through the roof uh...
back in the nineties and used to be a
after the after that rocked work in
ninety one
uh... there's cancer in her between
forty and then with the pit eight
hundred uh... people per one hundred
thousand iraqis
now that rate is above sixteen hundred
uh... iraqis
one hundred thousand so this is why i
think a lot of young voters uh...
sympathize with the libertarian party
and why out you know you know ron paul
didn't stand a chance
the fact that he doesn't want to do
these rediculous invasions and he
doesn't want to
by into the military industrial complex
is very appealing to people such as
myself
now of course i hear libertarians lose
me when it comes to certain other
policies like fiscal policy but we need
a party that will reject the notion
that we need to invade other countries
to spread democracy and of course that's
always a facade that's not what we're
really doing we're going to and i know
what you think your honor the country i
want to see what we're doing there
we could see these pictures
everyone's as these pictures i mean
the mediation should show inspectors
we did see pictures of a bar coffins of
our soldiers coming back
we can we're not sure that that's that's
the failure of the mainstream press and
it you know it's the duty of new media
to get involved and to expose it which
is why we're doing this story now
however graphic it is
uh... and and and the reason why the
mainstream media doesn't cover these
stories is because of something that we
talk about on a regular basis on the
shelf uh... you know they arb bought off
by corporations uh... you don't think
about how i'd be media covered uh... the
iraq war leading up to the yatra i mean
it was rediculous if u said anything
against invading iraq you would have
been shot and in the mainstream press
with people were fired the dixie chicks
albert just completely criticizing the
mainstream media michael moore was
completely criticizing the mainstream
media phil donahue losses showing he was
required to bring onto two adults two
conservatives for
his one being a liberal and
other other correspondents field yes was
bent i mean and
they kept their other contractors from
golden were awesome parker
yeah antiwar rhetoric so that they just
kept in a closet secures money diskeeper
marge schott
and to do that for a few years
and that was by the so-called liberal
and this n_b_c_ people
because they're owned by g_e_ which is
one of the main
uh... defense contractors act so that we
can see how money influences influences
are media the media is bought
uh... an apologist for bought
that's why we stumbled into this war
that we've never should have
i what i want to read and i don't think
there was stumbling you know i think we
were actually closing hours remain and
herded like cattle basically into this
it was choreographed it was
bought and paid for as you say you know
the in the media via the entire military
industrial complex everybody that had
something to gain from this and even
people who didn't
got roped into pushing us into the
warranty as if we have learned nothing
nothing from that