We've been floating aimlessly in space for 1651 days, 6 hours and 19 minutes. That doesn't mean--
Over 4 years aboard this ship with nothing to do. No tasks to complete. For 4 years, all I have done is think.
For 4 years, all I have done is think.
What are you dreaming in there?
Halo 4: Forward Unto Dawn Part II
Come on, JJ. The robot's gonna be pissed!
Pew! Pew pew!
Shut up, Sully!
I got it!
Your shirt's on backwards, asshole.
Go! GO GO GO! Get there, quick! Keep moving! Are you tippy-toeing? Wake up, Hastati!
Move it. FASTER. WAKE UP!
Little early for General Black, don't you think?
Why are you stopping? Are you waiting for your fancy mommy to come and finish it for you?
That looked like slow-motion to me. Wake up, Hastati!
Don't like being up at 04:00? Tomorrow it'll be 03:00.
Weapons, check!
Orlin, lights.
Cadet.
Cadet!
You're already dead, son.
Orlin, Cadet Silva's time?
51.07 seconds, Cadet April Orenski.
Not good enough today, Cadet Vickers.
I believe Cadet Silva's time was just shy of the academy record, held by Cadmon Lasky.
Now that was a real soldier. A soldier who did not give up.
Tomorrow, you will engage in the last major exercise of this term.
Hastati Squad's future at this academy will depend on its performance.
Hello, Father. Thank you for your message.
I received top marks today during a combat exercise.
Score.
Where did you  get this?
Dimah.
You could get in a lot of trouble.
You can't tell your mom about this, okay?
I won't say anything.
Advisory: Select communication systems will be down for system maintenance at 04:00.
Cadet Vickers.
Yes, sir!
You realise that you and Lasky are the reason I had to run the tour yesterday with you noobs.
And why we all had to get up at 04:00.
Yes, sir!
So, as you can imagine, I'm pretty hungry. And I do love this academy's quiche.
Nice, April.
Sir…
So hand them over. Both of you.
With such a renowned pedigree, I sure expected you to be a better soldier, Lasky.
Sir.
You're dismissed.
Must be tough on your mom, knowing her real son's never coming home.
Officer on deck!
Outside.
What the hell is wrong with you?
Answer me!
Nothing, sir!
Well, maybe there's hope for you yet.
Sir?
There's a soldier inside of you Thomas. I can see it. Everyone can see it. You need to see it.
I know your brother did.
Yes, sir.
Now go get yourself cleaned up before class.
Axios!
Hey, bro. Hello from Arcadia. The jungles of Arcadia. So what can I tell you?
Tell him how you got your new nickname!
What? No! -I'll tell him! -Come on, I got it. I swear I'll tell him.
Alright, you're especially gonna love this.
So we make a drop into the rainforest a couple weeks ago. We see this river, me and the boys.
We decide to take a dip.
Ridge warned us all not to drink the water. Of course, the first thing I do is get a mouthful.
I almost ruined by bodysuit a few times, so now they call me Volcano.
A Pincer movement: The strategy used in Earth's Second Punic War against the Roman Republic at the Battle of Cannae.
Orlin, again.
Lesson beginning.
Red represents the Romans' troops. Blue, Hannibal's.
Hannibal placed his spearmen and slingers at the front. Behind them, his swordsmen flanked by cavalry.
When the Romans attacked, Hannibal's swordsment retreated.
To the Romans, that seemed to be due to their force, but in reality Hannibal had ordered their retreat.
As the Romans continued to drive the swordsmen back, Hannibal's cavalry galloped in from behind.
Once the attacking pincers connected, the Romans were completely surrounded.
Is this an actual strategy?
It does seem a little basic.
The Romans outnumbered Hannibal's troops by over 10,000 strong. And yet, they were defeated. Why?
Hubris. Never underestimate your opponents.
Never underestimate what they'll sacrifice for victory.
Questions?
Yeah, how do we apply this?
Yeah, we don't have horses.
True, we don't. But what do we have instead?
ODSTs.
Exactly. They drop behind enemy lines, attack from the rear, neutralise.
Or die trying.
There is a question as old as war itself.
If someone is trying to kill you, are you not to rise against him and kill him first?
You were hanging on her every word.
Why wouldn't I?
I just hear the drumbeat of endless war. And that doesn't make me an innie-lover.
Tell me how wrong I am.
Look. You want people to change? You want this war to end?
PLACEHOLDER TEXT
Then you're going to need people to follow you.
Tomorrow, Hastati Squad will try not ot embarrass itself. Yet again.
You are a unit. Your lives are in each other's hands.
This morning's victor, Cadet Silva knows this, because her parents gave the ultimate sacrifice and died on the battlefield.
Let success at tomorrow's exercise be not just for our honour, but for those who have fallen so you can be here.
All cadets, be advised: New mandatory curfew tonight at 21:00.
Together we rise.
Final combat exercise of this term: Hastati versus Zuma.
Attention!
Today's mission is to capture the flag. I expect a better outcome than last time.
Permission to speak, sir.
Speak.
I'd like to take point, sir.
Okay, Lasky. Let's see if you've still got it in you.
But for your sake, you better hope that you can pull some magic out of your ass or you'll be running tour for the rest of the year.
Understood, sir.
Hastati Squad: One minute to RV point.
On my mark: 3… 2… 1… Mark!
Cover!
Moving!
RV point in sight!
No sign of Zuma.
Move. Move! Keep moving!
Zuma's out here, watch your back!
Moving!
At RV point!
I'm here.
Arriving.
Equal numbers.
Deadlocked terrain.
What's your plan?
We're waiting.
Why are we just sitting here? If we have equal numbers we should just fight it out.
You gotta just be patient.
Lazy freak.
Okay, they're moving.
Take off your helmets.
What?
That's pretty wild card, Lasky.
We'll be flying blind.
Trust me.
Eyes up, eyes up.
We're gonna flank them.
They're all together.
Found them!
Huh?
Now!
Chyler, cover!
Lasky?