'I wonder what kind of socks
Sophie wears.
'Do women wear socks? Well, yes,
sometimes is the answer to that.
'Socks before or after trousers, but never
socks before pants - that's the rule.
'Makes a man look scary, like a chicken. '
'He just does not give one solitary shit. '
'Yeah, take that, big Suze.
'Your toilet-seat regime is over.
'Ah, freedom! '
'Brown for first course,
white for pudding.
'Brown is savoury,
white's the treat. '
'I'm the one who's laughing
because I love brown toast. '
'There he is. '
- Dr J!
- Good morning, Mark.
Sorry I didn't hook up
with you and Super Hans...
- 'Wedge of ballast, then bed again. '
- Barbara pops up. "Is the file ready?"
'It's a bit like the crusher in Star Wars
but red hot.
'What if Mum and Dad
were trapped in one
'and I had a hook to rescue one of them -
who would I pick? '
I didn't get a chance to tell you
the good news.
We need a clerical assistant
and I've swung you an interview.
- Uh-huh.
- 'Clerical assistant?
'I can't be a clerical assistant.
I'm a musician.
'You wouldn't ask the Chemical Brothers
to do your laundry. '
So is tomorrow at 11 all right?
Tomorrow at 11.
Yeah, sure. I'll set the video.
- 'Don't joke. '
- 'I'm not. '
It's a damn good company
and it'll be the two of us together -
Jez and Mez, the El Dude Brothers.
It's just the music.
It's really starting to hot up.
You know how much
I respect your music. It's just...
Super Hans got a bass loop
for our track that is so good
that when he tried turning it off,
he physically couldn't do it.
I'm on your side.
Every artist needs his patron
but, you know, there's a limit.
Oh. The rent.
I'm not some kind of land baron
trying to milk his cash cow.
- It's just...
- Don't worry, you'll get your milk.
- This track's a banker.
Somethin' Stupid)
- Everybody needs a Somethin' Stupid.
- Sorry?
The guy who wrote that,
he's probably up to his neck
in penny loafers and blue pool tables.
- Right.
- Blimey, what's God up to?
- 'So let's do just a... '
- Just in case the song doesn't work out,
maybe you'd better fill this out
and fax it over by three.
Hmm.
Think about it.
And have a great day. Yeah?
- See you tonight.
- Yeah, cool. Have a good one.
- You, too, mate.
- Bye, mate.
'Work-shy freeloader. '
'Tight-fisted cock-muncher. '
'Next time I have breakfast,
he'll make me sit a fucking exam. '
'I wonder what
Sophie's flirty cartoon will be today? '
- 'I really should ask her out for lunch. '
- Can you hold that?
'You bastard. '
Thanks Third floor?
'I mean, what's the worst
that could happen? She could say no. '
'Actually, that would be terrible.
It would destroy me if she said no. '
There is a notice
about only riding the lift to the first floor.
You're wasting mine and other people's
time, not to mention...
Oh. Er, OK.
'People like him should wear stickers.
Their cars have them.
'Oh, yeah. Great idea, Adolf. '
- Morning, Mark.
- Hey, Sophie.
- 'Go on, ask her! '
- Sophie, are you...?
I mean, would...?
How's your day going thus far?
Have a nice shower or bath?
- Why? Do I smell?
- God, no, you don't.
I mean, you smell nice -
not that I've smelt you.
Oh... See ya.
Later, potater.
'Oh, potater. What have I become? '
'Super Hans said he'll be here
in 20 minutes. Means I've got an hour.
'I bet Mark's got some porn here
somewhere. '
'OK, where's today's cartoon? '
'Mm, not bad.
'No discernible romantic overtones.
'OK, pen, let's flirt with Sophie... '
'Mark's got no conception.
He thinks I'm so...
'But I'm busting my creative balls here,
day in, day out.
'No, but it's all,
"Where's the money? Where's my rent?
"'The rent, Mr Jim Morrison? Mr Keats?"
"'No, you don't like the attack dog,
do you, Mr Keats?"
'Hold on...
I think I've struck the motherload! '
'What the hell is that?
'That is very gay. That's what that is.
'Come on, go crazy!
You're hungry like the wolf. '
"'Fantasy Figure Modeller. "
'Jesus. Maybe this is his porn. '
'I'm giving her a love heart.
'Yes, that's... good.
'No, no, it's not good. It's terrible.
'Think "crazy horse", think
"in your face". What would Jeremy do?
'Yeah, that's it.
'Loves the Nazis. Yeah, crazy love.
'Nazi love. I'm a nutter! '
'I'm a dirty hobbit
and she's a sexy elf
'so she might be...
"'Ohh! You dirty hobbit.
Take off my bodkin and my jerkin. "
'Oh, yeah...
'Pixie ears.
'But that sword.
What if she was a hobbit slayer?
'I'd just use my enchanted amulet.
'Yeah. Yield to me, hobbit-slayer.
'You will touch my magic cock. '
'? And then I go and seal the deal
'? By doing something wicked
like this cartoon?
'Swastika love.
'It's bloody mental. '
- So what do you think?
- I dunno.
- Yeah, it's zzzhhhh! In your face.
- It's just...
I don't like it.
No, well, I do.
- I just don't.
- Oh, right. This is it, is it?
- The end of the Hair Blair Bunch.
- We are not the Hair Blair Bunch.
- Whatever. Spunk Bubble.
- Momma's Kumquat.
No, it's not. I never agreed to it
being Momma's Kumquat.
Look, if this is John and Paul, 1970,
then I need money for the equipment.
This is like your whole
Balearic bullshit, innit?
One minute, it's all, "I love ya, man,"
the next, it's, "Where's that 50 quid?"
- I'm just saying I need money...
- Listen, mate.
Shit is as shit does, my friend.
Look, this is bullshit.
We can't just let the Hair Blair Bunch go.
We are not the Hair Blair Bunch!
'A bloody swastika. That is
the single worst single bloody idea ever.
'I mean, a swastika!
'It's gone. It's happened.
'Oh, yeah, do what Jeremy would do.
Thanks, Jeremy. You tit. '
'Yeah, perfect plan. "I want
to fax this off. Oh, Toni, I feel tired. "
"'Let's just both lie down on your bed. "
'Hope she gets out the bong,
not the cafetiere. '
I was wondering.
You're an urban, switched-on lady.
You've probably got
a fax machine, right?
A fax machine?
Right, like I'd have a fax machine.
Have you just come from the 1980s?
It's like The Spaceman And King Arthur,
but in reverse.
Yeah. I've just got
this crappy job application.
Right. OK.
Tell me something, Jeremy.
Have you ever tried washing up
without using washing-up liquid?
What? Has Mark been talking to you?
Could you clean a pot or a pan
without using a scrubbing brush,
a sponge or a scouring pad?
- I don't think so.
- So what you're saying is
these products are essential -
products no one could do without?
Well, you're kind of
making me say that but...
The first thing to say is that this is
definitely not pyramid selling, OK?
Right. Good.
What's pyramid selling?
'Enter the pit of Sarlak,
little crisps.
'She's ignoring me.
'Of course, she's ignoring me.
I sent her a swastika.
'Jesus! This is the worst thing
to happen to anyone ever and...
'Relax, Mark.
You're not Hitler in his bunker.
'He was really under the cosh.
'Mind you, at least he had a girlfriend.
OK, enough mooning.
'Let's strap on the nosebag
and eat some serious work. '
I mean, does that look like
a pyramid to you?
Clearly, it's not a pyramid. It's a pie.
And... it's like a big, lovely club
with free money for everyone?
- It sounds great, but...
- Free money for everyone.
Ha! Look out the window.
That'll never happen in this old world.
No, see, the early birds
are going to find their bird table
covered in money pie.
- Right...
- But the Johnny and Sally Come-Latelys,
they get a slice of the pie
but then they look closer
and - oh, dear - it's only pastry.
Boo-hoo, Johnny and Sally.
Are you with me?
'Blown it with Sophie.
Who's next?
'Big Suze?
'Never met her.
Not necessarily a disadvantage.
'Why don't I ever get
this fucking thing fixed?!
'Every night... Ah, it always comes out
eventually. Fuck it. '
- Hey, Mark. Liked the cartoon.
- Oh, I'm so... You did?
Yeah, it's meant to be me and Barbara
from Personnel, right?
And... she's handing me
this heart of holiday pay
but in the heart, it's just...
- Race hate?
- Exactly.
That's so Barbara. She's such a racist.
Huh, huh. Right. Exactly.
Listen, Sophie, I was wondering
if I could get your home number.
I mean, for work, in case I need to
swap a shift or... That is, if you don't...
No, I don't, if that's what you want.
'She's actually writing it. '
There you go. See you later.
Oh, hang on. This isn't enough numbers.
Oh, no, it is enough numbers.
'Oh, God, I hope she doesn't mind
about my balls. '
'One step out of line. The slightest hint
of maverick behaviour and you're out. '
Exactly. If it's such a bad thing to do
things by the book, there'd be no book.
'Must keep an eye on him if
he gets it. JLB doesn't need a maverick. '
- So anyway, things went rather well -
- I bet he did it.
Oh, what? Just because he's black?
No, I mean, not because...
- He was at the garage at the beginning.
- I know what you meant.
Anyway, in the end,
I got Sophie's number.
We know he's the only one
with the key to the lock-up.
So do you think I should give her a call?
I probably should.
- I don't know if I should.
- Maybe you should.
OK, listen, if God's doing mountains
or sky or water, I'll call.
- If he's doing trees or critters, I won't.
- All right, let God decide. Ready?
Yeah, sky!
Right, here goes.
'And with a large brush,
I'm gonna... '
'The following names were
presented to us by temping agencies. '
- Answerphone.
- Ah, you see!
He did do it, but for a nice reason.
Who's the racist now, Mark?
Er, Sophie. If you heard that,
please ignore it. I'm not a racist.
Far from it.
Anyway...
It's good to hear your voice.
I know it's only a recording
but you have got a bloody nice voice
and...
God, I just called up to say hi and then...
? Then I go and spoil it all
by saying something stupid like...
? I like you?
I mean, not that.
But anyway...
I noticed that the paper in
the photocopier is running a bit low so...
I know it's not really your job but...
You know, so... See you tomorrow.
Fuck, fuck, fuck, fuck!
- Oh, fuck!
- Oh, my God.
- Jesus!
- I've really fucked it. Have I fucked it?
Maybe it was charming.
- It was the behaviour of an oddball.
- No, not an oddball. A maverick.
You may not play by the rules, but...
by Christ, you get results.
Come on, let's go and have a drink.
Forget about it.
Have you forgotten about
the phone call yet?
- No.
- Right.
How much washing-up do you think
you could do without washing-up liquid?
- I'm sorry?
- Exactly. And friends and colleagues?
Everyone needs cleaning products
and that's never gonna change, right?
- Why are you talking like this?
- Very interesting question.
The first thing to say is
that this is not pyramid selling.
- You're doing pyramid selling?
- Not pyramid selling.
- I can't believe you're pyramid selling.
- Listen, it's not, it's network marketing
and it's a guaranteed money-making...
- I've seen the charts.
- Oh, the charts.
- You didn't tell me about the charts!
- Are you trying to piss on my bonfire?
I'm trying to protect you from...
pissing all over yourself.
I'm not about to piss
all over myself. I'm...
I'm pissing... into the big time.
- You're still coming to the interview.
- Well, I thought...
Listen, Jeremy. You don't understand.
Nothing you want will ever happen.
That's the real world. Your hair isn't red.
People don't walk on stilts.
Maybe somewhere, you can earn a living
drinking margaritas through a straw
but in this world, you've got to turn up,
log on and grind out.
But if you get in early...
Come Friday,
you will owe me three months' rent.
You're coming to the interview.
OK.
'I'll come to the interview,
all right, but I won't be getting the job. '
What?
Er, nothing, just...
something funny.
Can you...?
'Maybe she did find it charming.
Yeah, maybe.
'Just work out her... I could say
Jeremy had a gun and made me sing it
'because he's a crackhead
and he does that all the time.
'Yeah, that sounds great - me in my
crack house. You can be a crack bitch
'and sit on my... Shit!
'Shit, piss, poo, pants, bollocks.
Yes, blitzkrieg! I'm in the Ardennes!
'You can't touch me in the Ardennes,
concealed in the cupboard.
'Everything's OK in the cupboard.
I'm safe in the cupboard. '
Mark?
- You're in the stationery cupboard.
- That's right, Jeff.
OK... Right.
Well...
- I hope you're having a good time.
- Yeah, well...
Hi, Mark.
Hi... Sophie.
I'm just in the cupboard right now.
- About the message, we'll talk later, OK?
- Er, yeah, fine.
'Here we go. Operation Come Over
Like An Unemployable Freak. '
Jeremy Osbourne?
Hi, I'm Barbara.
Do you want to walk this way?
Right you are.
I might wobble
because I'm a bit pissed from last night
and I don't want to get your hopes up
cos I must say...
- I'm only really here because...
- Obviously you know Mark Corrigan.
- 'Oh, shit. '
- Mark would be one of your managers.
'Must be careful. Don't want the job
or to piss off the land baron. '
'He looks like crap. '
We have to make sure
we've ticked all the boxes, so to speak
and kept everything above board.
So if I can outline the basic requirements
of the role you'll be undertaking.
You'll be responsible for updating
and maintaining the filing system.
That may not sound important
but the truth is...
'Shit, what's she talking about?
Nod. Look serious.
'I'm Di, she's Bashir. '
...whole company communicates...
'He'll be able
to pay off the Blockbusters fine,
'plus I'll be able to order him around.
'Not horrible, just...
"Jeremy, could you file this for me?
"'Jeremy, could you take that for me?
"'Jeremy, could you suck this for me... "
Jesus! Where did that come from? '
It's a valuable asset.
Do you have any experience in this field?
Er, I've done quite a lot, actually.
I mean, not formal filing
but alphabeti-pi-cising the videos,
doing the spices...
I'd want to build on that experience
in a professional zone.
Sphere. I meant sphere.
'God, that sounded amazing!
Don't accidentally get the bugger. '
We're doing great.
So, I see you used to be a nurse.
Wouldn't filing be a bit of a step down?
Yeah, I suppose it would, actually,
although I'm looking for something
more relaxing.
Challenging. He means, challenging.
- I expect Jeremy knows what he means.
- Yes, right.
No, challenging is right
but a bit more of a relaxing challenge.
More like doing a crossword
than a tracheotomy.
- Right.
- 'Oh, shit.
'My natural bloody charm's
only swinging it. Got to do something. '
- Are you OK?
- What?
- It's just a thing I have.
- What thing?
Facial spasming.
Facial spa... You do not have...
- I do... sometimes.
- Well, er...
I guess that's everything. Jeremy,
is there anything you'd like to ask?
Yes, Barbara. Yes, there is.
How much washing-up do you think you
could do without any washing-up liquid?
- No, Jeremy.
- Where's this...?
- It's a unique business opportunity.
- It's pyramid selling.
- It's not pyramid selling, Mark.
- It is.
- You're making a fool of yourself.
- You're pissing on my bonfire!
- There is no bonfire!
- Because you keep pissing on it!
Sheesh. This is low. This is really low.
Yeah, well, at least I don't fancy
elves and pixies.
What does that mean? I literally have
no idea what that is supposed to mean!
OK...
Well, thanks for coming in.
We'll be in touch.
'Well, that was a fucking disaster.
I want reparations - brutal reparations!
'I want the Rhineland.
It's going to be 1919 all over again.
'Fuck the inevitable backlash!
'OK. It's OK, Mark. Later.
'Now, calm.
'Calm, honest and mature. '
Hi, Sophie.
Hey, Mark.
I just bumped into your flatmate.
- Oh... yeah?
- He kept talking about washing up.
- Very funny. Like Jim Carrey.
- Huh. Yeah, I know what you mean.
'Get your tanks off my lawn, Jeremy. '
But listen, Sophie...
About the message last night.
I want to kind of come clean really.
It's a bit embarrassing but...
Well...
the thing is...
Jeremy, sometimes, for a laugh,
makes me say things with a bread knife.
- He's obviously not a crackhead but...
- Uh-huh. OK.
Yeah.
Look, you don't have to...
About the phone message,
- you don't have to be embarrassed.
- I don't?
- No, it's just one of those things.
- Is it? It is?
Oh, right. Fantastic.
And... you haven't told anyone about it?
Of course not.
- Oh, thank you, thank you, thank you.
- 'Calm down. She's not Pontius Pilate. '
Yeah, well, you know...
The truth is...
The truth is I suppose...
I like you.
That's why I said the song. I like you.
Is that such a crime?
Should I be hounded to the ends
of the earth just for liking you?
I like you and if you can't handle it,
you can just...
you know...
fuck off.
No, no, I think I can handle you liking me.
Good.
Right, excellent. OK.
Bye.
Hi, Mark. Thanks for bringing in Jeremy.
He was quite the find.
Er, yeah...
Right, I'm really sorry.
I mean, I thought it would be a good...
that he might... but...
Hey! Hey, there!
Feeling better now, are we?
Fully recovered?
Hey, I see you!
I see you!
He used to have a limp!
I mean, he pretended to have a limp.
He's a faking little pegleg!
Hi, Jeff.
'Well, fuck you if you're
not doing small talk. I'm not helping.
'Let's die together. '
? And then I go and spoil it all
by saying something stupid like
? I like you?
? And then I go and spoil it all
? By saying something stupid
like I love you
? I can see it in your eyes
that you despise the same old lies
? You heard the night before
? And though it's just a line to you
For me, it's true
? And never seems so...?