affected people on an individual level. Plus,
we`re going to take a look ahead the next
Tuesday as the presidential campaigns make
their final push. I`m Carl Azuz. This is CNN
STUDENT NEWS.
When you`ve lived through something like Sandy,
how do you balance the need to emotionally
recover with the need to get back some sense
of normalcy? A lot of people are struggling
with that question right now.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: You can`t describe it in
words, because there is nothing -- nothing,
all you see is burnt out rubble. That`s it.
Burnt out rubble.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: You know, it is no words
to put on what happened here, but we -- we
got to start over and bring back this community.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: You take a lot of stuff
for granted, I think until you get to this
point, and then now it`s -- you just want
to get back to it, you know, you want everything
back that you complained about a week ago.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: I just want to get back
in there, get the kids back to school and
things like that, get our life back.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: In New York and New Jersey, people are
trying to get back to their normal routines,
but things aren`t normal. This line, it`s
for a bus. With huge sections of the subway
shutdown, bus service is trying to help now.
Some people said it took four or five hours
to get to work on Thursday. And how about
checking your email or sending a text? Millions
of people still didn`t have power on Thursday,
couldn`t even charge their phones. Some of
the ones who did, were offering it up to neighbors.
They set up charging stations, running extension
cords and power strips out of their homes
for anyone to use, the sign of community coming
together as it tries to recover.
On our blog, it`s cnnstudentnews.com, jobs,
the economy and education top your list of
election issues.
Priscilla is concerned about all three. "With
the prices of everything going up, including
college, it is really going to be a challenge
to attain a higher education."
Carol says, "... there are enough jobs for
the people who have just graduated college.
I am worried I won`t be able to support myself
when I graduate."
Max writes," ... education should be the top
concern. If we have a good educational system,
we will be able to make jobs and help the
economy at the same time."
Some folks like Joshua had a different take,
the biggest issue for him is deficit reduction.
As a large deficit could lead to a default
on our debt.
Jabari also notes the debt, saying, "new ways
to try to fix it might not help."
Austin writes, "It`s the high price of fuel.
I think that if the price of gas were lower,
more people would have jobs ..."
And Brittany feels that Obama and Romney should
talk more about what will happen when schools
have to fire teachers because the school is
low on money."
People who think jobs are the number one election
issue, might focus on a government report
that comes out every month. It updates the
national unemployment rate and says how many
jobs were added the month before. The latest
numbers come out today, and they are the last
ones coming out before Tuesday`s election.
You could be sure the presidential candidates
will be talking about this report and hoping
it helps them gain some support on Tuesday.
We looked at Governor Romney and President
Obama`s economic policies earlier this week.
Today, as we wrap up our series on the candidates`
positions we are focusing on foreign policy.
That covers a lot of issues, so we are going
to cover two of them today. First one, the
war in Afghanistan. President Obama has announced
the plan that would have U.S. combat troops
out of Afghanistan by 2014. Governor Romney
has said, he supports gradually pulling American
forces out of Afghanistan, but he`s criticized
the president for announcing the timetable.
Next up, Iran. When it comes to that country`s
controversial nuclear program, the U.S. presidential
candidates share a lot of the same basic ideas.
Neither one wants Iran to be able to develop
a nuclear weapon. Both support the idea of
using sanctions, punishments against Iran
and neither one has ruled out the idea of
using military force against Iran.
We have a ton of resources on the presidential
election on our home page. Go to cnnstudentnews.com,
check out the election resources bin.
We are in the home stretch of this presidential
campaign. For some folks, it feels like it`s
going on forever. It`s this idea called voter
fatigue. That after months and months of the
speeches and the rallies, the media coverage
and especially the ads, some people are just
worn out. Presidential candidates have been
making political ads for decades, but they
haven`t always look like the ones we see today.
Watch this.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: You like Ike, I like Ike,
everybody likes Ike.
DARRELL WEST, BROOKINGS INSTITUTION: The way
that candidates communicate with voters tells
us a lot about the politicians, but also about
ourselves.
JOHN F. KENNEDY: This is candidate John Kennedy.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: President Johnson.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Jimmy Carter.
WEST: So, it`s an amazing lens on American
culture and on American politics.`
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: This time, vote like your
whole world depended on it.
WEST: The biggest difference in ads that we
see today is really in the editing. Today,
we have a much faster pace, they splice different
images together, there is much greater sophistication
in the production that lies behind contemporary
ads.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Eisenhower answers America.
WEST: The first presidential election where
TV ads played a role was 1952, Dwight Eisenhower
pulled together footage from press conferences
and basically had "Eisenhower Answering America."
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: This historic moment is
brought to you by Citizens for Kennedy.
WEST: 1960 is really considered the first
television election, that was the first election
where we had TV debates between Kennedy and
Nixon, ads also were seen as very prominent,
because it was a wave for Kennedy to basically
contrast his youthfulness with Nixon experience.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: They understand what peace
demands.
WEST: 1964 was a very interesting election,
and it featured a lot of attack ads.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Four, five, six ...
WEST: There was a famous ad called "the daisy
ad", incumbent president Lyndon Johnson had
a little girl in a meadow pulling petals off
of a daisy and in the background you have
the countdown, and at the end of the end,
there is a nuclear explosion.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Nine, eight, seven, six,
five ...
WEST: By today standards, it seems remarkably
tame, because we`ve seen a lot more vicious
and personal attacks on individuals. But when
that ad aired, it actually only aired once
on network television, the public outcry was
so strong that Johnson took down that ad and
never aired it again.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today`s "Shoutout" goes
out to Mrs. Golden`s U.S. and world history
classes at the Augusta Fells Savage Institute
of Visual Arts in Baltimore, Maryland. Who
painted this famous artwork? You know what
to do. Was it Leonardo, Michelangelo, Donatello
or Raphael? You`ve got three seconds, go!
You`re looking at Michelangelo`s masterpiece
on the ceiling of the Sistine Chapel. That`s
your answer and that`s your "Shoutout."
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Michelangelo`s masterpiece is celebrating
a big birthday this week. In 1512, exactly
500 years ago, it was finished and open to
the public. The different panels on the Sistine
Chapel ceiling show people and events from
the Bible. The most famous one is the creation
of Adam, which shows the arms of God and Adam
reaching out to each other. The painting has
survived centuries of war and severe weather.
But now, it`s facing a new threat, one that
comes from an unexpected source.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
BEN WEDEMAN, CNN CORRESPONDENT: Today the
greatest threat to this priceless art comes
from those who flock to admire it. About 5
million people visit the Sistine Chapel every
year, that means 5 million people with sweat,
with heat, with dust.
The number of visitors is expected only to
grown in coming years. The Vatican is planning
to upgrade the current climate control system
for the chapel, but officials are hesitant
to turn tourists away.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: We don`t have to wait till next Tuesday
for election results, thanks to some presidential
prognosticators. Like the Redskins rule. If
the team wins its last home game before the
election, the person or party in power stays
there. Road team wins, expect a victory for
the White House challenger. Has that ever
been manipulated before? We`d be worried about
pass interference.
If football is not your cup of tea, try coffee.
711 is selling Obama and Romney cups of java,
those results will be hot off the presses.
Halloween may be over, but some people think
they can predict the presidency based on which
candidate`s mask sold more. On election day,
they`ll face reality. And the squirrel can
tell us the outcome based on which dish it
eats from. Some of these ideas seem a little
wacky, that squirrel one is downright nuts,
but hey, listen, it`s not scientific, it just
food for thought. One thing we can predict,
we will be back on the air next Monday, so
we hope to see you then, and that you have
a wonderful weekend. Bye now.