always kind of the greatest
form of creation.
Being able to take an idea from
that very tiny amount of
energy, being this idea
in your head, and then
formulating that into
a fully functional
three-dimensional product.
Take that a step further, I
always kind of wanted to
design the ultimate three
dimensional object, right?
And so designing space vehicles,
to me, was like that
ultimate form of creation.
It's like, what's the bad ass
thing you could design would
be a spaceship.
And NASA really was kind of
the final frontier for me.
My name's Evan Twyford, and I'm
a habitability designer at
NASA's Johnson Space Center.
We in our group do conceptual
design for
NASA's human space flight.
A lot of these projects are
coming down as major kind of
campaign level design projects,
where they're saying
hey, we're doing a mission
to the moon.
We're working on a pressurized
rover.
We've got this idea, and
we want you guys to
help us make it happen.
Starting off with sketching
and rendering, very
conceptual.
Take it to a full scale mock
up phase out of wood, foam
core, low fidelity materials.
We use those to kind of sketch
out the volume of how big the
vehicle might be, and how it
would feel on the inside.
Part of what we'll do when we're
designing a habitat is
we'll look at how the corners,
how the edges are treated.
What type of paint schemes
are going to go inside.
There was actually an issue with
one of the colors that
they had painted on the
International Space Station,
where one of the hatches was
like a salmon color.
And the crew really disliked
it, so we try to
avoid salmon now.
And then working out the details
in a CAD system on the
computer, and developing a fully
functional prototype.
And the type of design at NASA
that we do kind of crosses the
line between fine art
and engineering.
So it's a lot more problem
solving, though, which is what
makes it really exciting.
So this is the SEV, the Space
Exploration Vehicle on the
chassis, gen 1B.
For interior design for space
vehicles, there is certainly
the problem of confinement,
which is a psychological issue
for crew members over time.
So we have to deal with ways of
designing environments and
designing products that will
reduce the effects of feelings
of confinement in space.
So this is the interior of the
SEV rover gen 1B, and most of
the interior design elements was
a product of our team, as
well the robotics team that
we've been working with on
this vehicle for some time.
And we've kind of been charged
with making the interior of
the vehicle more comfortable,
more luxurious, if you can
call it that.
Seeing as most of us haven't
actually been to outer space,
it can make things very
difficult sometimes, because
everybody has a different
opinion, or different
assumptions that they're
making about what that
experience is like.
So it's a very testing and
evaluation intensive work
environment.
So we have to do whatever we
can to ensure that these
products will work in their
intended environment.
So sometimes that means flying
products, or mock ups on zero
gravity flight in the
parabolic aircraft.
Sometimes it means going out
into the desert and testing
them in a very harsh, kind of
desolate environment that
might be similar to what we
would encounter in space.
There's always that kind of
thing with designers between
are you going to be like, a
stylist, or are you going to
be a problem solver?
And you can look at a product
and say this accomplishes
exactly what we need it to
accomplish, and that's what
makes it beautiful, and that's
what makes it successful.
It's a very pure design problem
that we're dealing
with, which is to create
products and environments that
the crew will find useful, and
will make them successful and
productive in their
daily routines.
MALE SPEAKER: Go for
main engine start.
T-minus 10, 9, 8, 7, 6, 5--
All three engines
up and burning.
2, 1, 0, and lift off.
The final lift off
of Atlantis.
EVAN TWYFORD: The shuttle
program and the International
Space Station were started in
the '80s as sort of a longer
term analog for human space
flight, and establishing a
permanent human presence
in space.
To start to learn more about
how humans would behave and
interact in longer term space
flight scenarios.
I've kind of felt like a lot of
people in general are maybe
not as excited by the
International Space Station,
or by the shuttle program.
Or at least not as much as they
were maybe in the '80s,
when the shuttle
was brand new.
I just hope that we can really
re-engage people in the right
way, and get people excited
about space flight.
Because this next generation of
space vehicles is going to
be the most bad ass that
we've ever seen.
[ELECTRONIC MUSIC PLAYING]