SHANE SMITH: So this is the
scene of a film that the
General Kim Jong-Il directed?
MR. KIM: Yes.
He likes the film very much.
SHANE SMITH: The first thing
you realize is this isn't a
film studio, it's a museum.
No one's making any
films here.
It's yet another shrine
to this guy.
[SPEAKING KOREAN]
SHANE SMITH: So, the North
Koreans believe that he
invented the whole concept of
multi-camera shoots in 1964.
In fact, they believe he's so
great at making films that
they made a film about how great
he is at making films.
MALE SPEAKER: Visiting the
filming [INAUDIBLE]
he taught the cameraman and
actors how to shoot and act.
This resulted in the creation of
masterpieces that teach man
the truth of life and destiny.
SHANE SMITH: And my favorite
thing is, if you're a little
unsure as to what exactly Kim
Jong-Il did on this film, what
was his role, there's a list.
[SPEAKING KOREAN]
SHANE SMITH: So he
gave on-the-spot
guidance how many times?
[SPEAKING KOREAN]
MALE SPEAKER: 350.
More than 350 times.
SHANE SMITH: He came here 350
times, but he gave 11,000
phone calls?
[SPEAKING KOREAN]
SHANE SMITH: We got it now.
The General Kim Jong-Il
came here 350 times.
He gave 1,770 directions, but
also 11,890 guidances.
And these are all of those
things categorized here.
I'm not going to ask what 8941
is, because when I asked what
the 11890 was, it caused
quite a stir.
It's kind of like Twentieth
Century Fox or something.
They took us rapidly from
room to room to room.
Some rooms we could shoot,
some rooms we couldn't.
I don't know why.
We could shoot the camera room,
but we couldn't shoot
the Soviet Mixing Board.
No more shooting?
MR. KIM: From this moment.
SHANE SMITH: From this moment?
OK.
They've got recreations of their
meals that they used to
eat when they were filming
in the 1960s.
[SPEAKING KOREAN]
MR. PAK:
SHANE SMITH: He played
the guitar?
MR. PAK:
SHANE SMITH: But he
saw the guitar?
MR. PAK:
SHANE SMITH: He was giving
on-the-spot guidance with this
camera, and they kept
this camera here.
Can I look?
MR. KIM: Yes.
MR. PAK: Yes, you can.
SHANE SMITH: Thank you.
So I'm looking into the same
camera that the General Kim
Jong-Il looked through.
I can see things.
I can see marvelous things.
So this is kind of like their
equivalent of [INAUDIBLE], the
Wild West town.
And they'll have the saloon
and whatever.
This is their equivalent to
make Asian history films.
And do they have a Japanese
or American street?
MR. KIM: Yes.
There is the Chinese street,
the Japanese street, and
European street, and also
the [INAUDIBLE]
street.
SHANE SMITH: Can we see
a European street?
MR. KIM: They are
repairing now.
SHANE SMITH: Repairing it?
MR. KIM: If they see a
disliking to see you.
SHANE SMITH: They don't
want to see us?
MR. KIM: Right, they don't
want to see you.
SHANE SMITH: OK.
MR. PAK:
SHANE SMITH: We have to go?
SHANE SMITH: They're
now kicking us
out for some reason.
We asked to see the European
street and the American street
which they blow up when they
blow up America, but they
won't let us see it.
And now we have to
go [INAUDIBLE].
But we're on the film set
in Pyongyang Studios.
When we finally got into the
film studios in North Korea, I
expected to be taken to a sound
stage, or see people
filming, making movies.
But we just got another
museum.
It was a facade.
And like the Arirang Games,
it's just a show.
And you realize they're
doing all of this
for the Dear Leader.
It's Nero.
As Rome is burning, we
need the spectacle.
The DMZ, the People's Library,
the Juche Ideals, the Arirang
Games, it's just a bunch
of sound and fury
that signifies nothing.
MALE
SPEAKER: