in an elementary statistical course
that would let you do this;
but if you really
studied carefully,
you'd know that they
don't let you do this.
A really principled frequentist can't
produce a probability distribution...
- The conclusion we want to point out
when we think about valuation
is the fact that means are scarce.
I alluded to this already that
as finite beings we can't will
our ends to be attained.
- A statistical description of the
government's net-of-interest surplus.
- ...deflation, I think that yields
could drop to say, less than 1%
on the 10 years and less
than 2% on the 30 years...
- ...that would effectively be a takeover of
monetary policy by the Congress.
- Oh, hello!
Daunting, right?
Might even make you feel stupid.
Perhaps it's no wonder then,
while even with the ongoing
economic failures across the world:
inequality, increasing
poverty, debt collapse,
bank failures,
unemployment rising,
very few today seem to
be able to understand,
let alone discuss,
modern economics,
outside, of course,
the delegation game
where the only attempted
solutions people know
is the mere shifting around of
the deck chairs on the Titanic,
assuming some new politician, central
bank policy, or corporate legislation
is going to save the day.
Some years back, after coming to the
conclusion that our politicians,
legislators, and established authorities
just might be provably incompetent
when it comes to the truly intelligent
management of our society,
I started to look for questions
and answers on my own,
asking those questions about things
that many today either seem to take
for granted, ignore or even worse,
assume that they have no capacity
or business investigating at all,
since our credentialed
authorities in control
must be smarter, more informed.
It's a sad staple of
modern culture, you know,
the old "Relax, turn on the
TV, keep going into debt,
and pump out a bunch of
kids while you're at it,"
but most importantly,
keep showing up at those jobs
which you have likely already
fooled yourself into believing
serve some legitimate social role.
Remember, the 1% of the world
that owns 40% of the planet's wealth
did not get that way with you
understanding how the world really works.
Nevertheless, and such
cynicism aside (I'm sorry),
I decided that I
needed to start again,
if you will, and ask some
fundamental questions
about stuff most have simply
written off and forgotten.
If you were to take a poll today of
our species, asking what truly are
the most fundamental questions that
pertain to human survival and prosperity,
such as, I don't know, what really
supports human life, how food grows,
what energy is, what creates and
reinforces good public health,
what defines a useful or
detrimental belief system,
you can rest assured, that the vast
majority would have more concrete answers
about baseball statistics, fashion trends,
sitcom plots, and religious scriptures.
Not to demean the cultural pleasures
and creativity of expression
that creates enjoyment in this life,
but we have a distortion of priority
that has proven incredibly detrimental
to the future of our sustainability
on this planet,
where the majority facing
clear mounting problems
not only doesn't understand what the
root of such problems really are,
they don't even know
what questions to ask;
and today, there is no greater
destructive ignorance at hand,
than the vastly delusional concept
known as modern economics.
It is in this fundamental context
that I found the most interest.
What is an economy?
Where does its foundational
premise come from?
What are we relating to exactly?
How is societal organization
finding a benchmark for itself?
Is there a benchmark?
What are we doing?
Why does the discussion of this
subject appear to be so elitist
in its vocabulary and orientation?
Is it really that complicated?
I became so tired of being
called ignorant of the subject
by self-proclaimed
experts I've challenged,
I decided to take it upon
myself to read the entire
macro-economics curriculum
of Harvard University
from the undergraduate
to the PhD level,
along with all the staples of influence:
F.A. Hayek, John Maynard Keynes,
Ludwig von Mises; and I'll tell
you what, I'm really glad I did
because I had some very poor
judgments that needed correction,
not so much regarding my
views about economics,
but that life is short,
and I wasted an enormous,
unforgivable amount of time
reading this outdated,
overly-intellectualized gibberish.
[Glass Breaking] Ah, shit!
Bob, would you take care of that please?
The fuse panel.
Be careful man, it's not...
[Explosion][Bob screaming]
As the following
episode will detail,
modern economics is not
true economics at all.
It's a mere ideological philosophy,
built upon a series of presuppositions
that have been given the
illusion of permanence.
There is absolutely no relationship
to the scientific integrity
of our knowledge of the environment
built into this model.
The monetary-market system
of religious belief
is at the core of the vast majority
of ecological and social imbalance
we see in the world today.
Sadly, it is in the face of
normality, so many look past it.
We might begin to see that this
principal notion and practice
is truly a problem in
society, and to me,
it is at the heart of
a culture in decline.
Earth: Curious little ball of
rock, gas and water, isn't it?
Hard to believe this little bubble of
chemical elements floating in space,
basically powered by the sun,
could give rise to our colorful,
yet rather troubling
super-monkey species,
a species often appearing pretty serious
in its interest to destroy its habitat,
though I should say pretty serious
in its interest to destroy itself.
- What is democracy?
- It's got something to do with young
men killing each other, I believe.
- Excuse me a second.
Bob, what the hell was that?
The cut away, it wasn't funny.
It was just depressing.
Couldn't you find some guy shooting a
bottle rocket out of his ass or something?
You know what our demographic is
and the point of the show, right?
Okay, well please.
Anyway, perhaps our
immaturity is just a phase,
a tragically comedic rite of passage,
no different than children
that need to be burned
by a hot stove in order to
realize they shouldn't touch it,
or what the physics
behind it may be.
Nevertheless, the history and
characteristics of this little orb
can be scientifically described
with a good deal of accuracy:
A couple of billion years old now,
a composite of gas and dust
that resulted mostly from
a large chemical reaction long ago,
likely an exploding
star or supernova;
and over millions of years this dust clustered
into relatively big chunks of rock,
a pronounced gravitational
field emerged,
our chemical elements
were slowly reorganized,
and conditions emerged to
enable water and an atmosphere,
which is what bred the first
single-celled organisms;
and so went the slow
process of mutation
into the very amusing
circumstance we have today: us.
Of course, you are free to believe
whatever creation story you like:
a rib from Adam, alien cross
pollination, primordial ooze.
At the end of the day, the utility
of such knowledge is quite small.
In fact, our little
monkey brains
might never have a complete
picture of something so complex.
Yet what we do know is that the
universe is governed by laws,
not moral or religious laws,
but laws that were around
long before we ever evolved
a brain to understand them.
Laws that very clearly point out
that we either adapt to them
and respect them, or we
suffer the consequences.
Such is the true face of God:
the Laws of Nature.
In many ways, the
history of our universe
is the history of our
understanding of it,
and we have come a
long way as a species
with respect to how we organize
our lives around these rules.
Likely the best example
of this adaptation,
or in many ways lack thereof,
is how we think about economy,
the foundation of our social survival.
Many thousands of years ago,
our super-monkey brethren
began to discover how to engage nature.
We went from being completely
at the mercy of the habitat,
gathering our food
with some hunting,
living and migrating around the
natural seasonal regeneration,
to an agricultural revolution,
learning how to cultivate food,
create ever [more] sophisticated
tools to ease labor
and in effect, learn how
to mimic nature itself.
In fact, this new awareness and
ever-increasing understanding
to harness the processes
of nature to our advantage
is what has led to the vast
technological innovation we see today.
If nature is doing something,
odds are we can understand how
through these dynamic scientific principles,
from artificial intelligence today
which works to emulate actual
neurological processes,
to molecular engineering
which uses the atomic logic
to manually recreate material objects.
And now, ever-important blood
shifting erectile dysfunction drugs,
which if you have being
watching TV recently,
must be the most epidemic health
crisis in the Western world today.
Since this revolution, human
society became less nomadic,
slowly merging into cities,
and systems of labor
specialization began to rise
along with means for exchange.
Barter is a common example.
You need some eggs?
Maybe give some firewood you chopped up
in exchange for the
dairy farmer's work.
Yet, such practices became cumbersome
and impractical after a while;
so the idea of using
some rare fancy rocks,
like gold and silver as a medium of
exchange, eased these transactions
through a system of pricing goods
in terms of their relative value.
This gave birth to what we know today
as the adjustable price system
which, through the public's aggregate
patterns of exchange and production,
creates a crude, yet
semi-workable logic
where the prices of goods reflect
the balance of supply and demand,
otherwise known as the market or market value.
Let me explain.
When you stumble into the mall
and buy the 85th generation
iPoop 4G mp3 colostomy-bag
camera phone waffle maker,
you are creating economic signal information
that is used to calculate demand,
local and regional preferences,
and other resulting data
in concert with the millions
of other impulsive consumers
who, having also likely
bought the 84th generation
just two months prior
for twice the price,
creates an aggregate flow
of input data and feedback
that allows for an ostensibly rational
regulation of resource allocation,
production, distribution, labor
requirements, and of course
price consensus in the market based
on perceived supply and demand,
not to mention the general
data of how the marketing team
can screw you over
even more later on.
This mechanism is partly
what the ultimate high priest
of our current economic religion,
Adam Smith, was alluding to
with his 'invisible hand' notion
of causality in the free market.
And in many ways he
was on to something.
It does work in a limited
context and a crude way.
In fact, in the 1920's an economist
named Ludwig von Mises put forward
the still high-standing claim
that without the price mechanism
economic calculation and
rational resource allocation
and general organization
would be impossible.
He called it 'The Economic
Calculation Problem'.
However things are much different
today than they were 200 years ago
when Adam Smith published
his 'Wealth of Nations'
or when Ludwig von Mises made his
criticism of central planning.
The fact is the argument has changed.
The economic debate now is
what is actually sustainable and
progressive for the human species,
not to mere mechanics of
the movement of the money.
While it is true the
price system might allow
for the basic calculation
of supply & demand data,
to help rationally allocate labor,
preference, distribution and the like,
it ignores the real
operational factors
that relate to true,
efficient earthly management
hence the true
definition of economy
which is:
optimized efficiency on all levels.
For instance, there is no consideration
for optimum resource allocation
based on the material's
most efficient purpose.
Rational allocation of
resources is not rational
if the most conducive use of those
natural materials, scientifically,
is not directly considered and
brought into comparison. [REJECTED]
There is no consideration for
the organizational efficiency
of technical production itself,
and all you have to do is
analyze the waste machine of globalization
to see this insanity at work.
There is also no consideration for
regeneration needs or recycling protocols:
a true requirement for responsible
rational resource use on a finite planet,
nor is there any true production
or distribution efficiency
in any optimized
scientific sense
as such a means is, as will be
described more so in a moment,
also counter to the inherent logic
of the market system itself.
These, coupled with many
other serious parameters
needed for a truly efficient economy,
are simply ignored or, even worse,
assumed to be inherent to the
price mechanism's function
when they clearly are not.
You see, the price mechanism's
concept of efficiency
translates the subjective
mass interaction of consumers
into the narrow assessments of regional
demand, production and distribution.
It has nothing to do with how or why the
methods of industry are what they are.
Such factors are left up to
the whim of the producers
operating for profit alone,
completely decoupling
from the natural regulation of
scientific principles of sustainability.
Aww, man!
You see, at the core of
'The Economic Calculation Problem'
is really the argument that
we are completely irrational,
that we can't possibly be organized in
a way that is structurally efficient;
we are too insane, essentially.
Therefore, we have to have
a general economic anarchy
to organize our society and
there's no other way around it.
(*Bullshit!*)
Again, today is very different than
it was prior, and a quick review
of modern computer programming
and systems engineering
will tell you that not only can
the algorithmic intelligence
of our sensory and measurement
technology today,
coupled with synergistic
computer calculation,
orient all the previously existing
factors taken into account
by the price mechanism
as we know it,
the truly relevant yet missing
factors for optimal efficiency
and sustainability could be
brought into the equation.
This would be the making of a true
economic calculation for industry,
not the crude truncated data
put forward by price alone.
So, coming back to our
household, the Earth,
what is this thing really? It's a system,
a system of symbiotic laws.
At the core of all
principles of sustainability
is recognition of the largest order
system we can find, for reference.
The price mechanism on the other...
[crash]
Bob, what was that?
Jesus Christ, Louie!
Bob, why didn't you tell
me Louie was here already?
Ladies and gentlemen, we have a special
guest here on Culture in Decline,
our local logic guru,
Louie-the-Logic Gremlin.
Louie has a severe impatience for
anything illogical, and he works to...
OK. Bob, you've got to get the goddamn
Demo-Publican back in his cage
or Louie is going to freak out...
Oh, shit! Cut the camera!
Sorry about that ladies and gentlemen.
As I mentioned,
Louie here gets a little frustrated
when it comes to anything illogical
and the Demo-Publican is
sort of his mortal enemy.
Anyway, Louie, since we have you here,
I want to ask you a few questions.
Is the free market actually
a good basis for sustainability
for the human species?
Well, what about infinite
wants and human needs?
How do we calculate
such complexity?
Thank you very much Louie,
I appreciate that.
Well, there you have it, folks.
However, logic aside, opinions about our
economic system range dramatically.
So, to gain some public consensus
on the issue, we now go live
to our New York 'Culture
In Decline' correspondent,
Big Scotty D, who is
live on Wall Street.
Thank you, Peter. This is Scotty D, in
front of the New York Stock Exchange.
Today we're here
in New York City
just to try to talk to some people on
the street and find out a little bit
about what's going on in the
world perception of economics.
Culture In Decline:
Man On the Street
Sir, do you want to
talk about the economy?
Would you like to talk
about the economy?
I really suck at this,
but I don't think people want
to talk about economy either.
However, there was one guy who
was willing to talk to me.
- What do you feel is the
definition of economics?
Standing here in front of Wall
Street, I'm just curious.
What do you think economics is?
- Well, I would say that
economics is, is really just
just based on money, the
things that's going on,
you know, from over
here by Wall Street.
It's just money that
makes the system ...
generate throughout NY city and
for everybody in the world.
But it's just mainly a money thing,
which makes the world go round.
I know what you are thinking.
You're thinking
"What is this guy talking about?!"
But in reality, he probably
knows as much about economics
as I know about interviewing
people on the street.
And, seems like most of us
really don't know what the
economy is all about anyway.
Back to you, Peter.
*Man On The Streets*
Is it me or have
you noticed that
there is more for sale in
the world than ever before,
and I'm not referring to
goods in your local store.
Today, the market
rational is that
everything is for sale
and nothing is sacred.
Need some cash? Why don't you rent out
your forehead to commercial advertising?
Or better yet, why don't you
buy the life insurance policy
of your elderly neighbor,
and when she dies
you can get nice payout?
Yep, it's legal!
Or maybe it's the little
things that make you happy.
So, rather than put that
blow-up doll in your car
to use the car pool
lane (hehehehe),
just buy it, like you
can in Minneapolis.
Or maybe you have an itch to slaughter
that endangered black rhino in Africa.
Well, you can.
Costs you about $150,000,
but hey, it's there. '150,
boy, I can't wait
to eat that rhino!'
Or more seriously, maybe your kids
are not excelling well in school.
Well, the market has a solution.
Pay them!
Pay them to read and get good grades,
like they do in Dallas, Texas.
But perhaps that is overkill, because
by the time they hit college age
most prestigious universities will
look the other way for admission
once a nice hefty donation is
made for that new library wing.
Want to serve your country,
but are tired of all those
pesky UN war rules and poor pay?
Just join the growing legion of
private military contractors
who are slowly replacing the
US military in general.
Or how about love?
Need a date, but don't want
to wade through all the fog?
Women will now go on dates with the
highest bidder on some dating sites.
Forget chatting, just fork
out a couple hundred bucks
to entice the woman of your choice
to allow you to pay for her dinner.
I am sure it will be a
long lasting relationship.
Or perhaps most important,
does your business need a law
passed to secure profits?
Well, just hire a lobbyist
to influence Congress!
As the prior episode of
Culture In Decline denoted,
there is nothing in the
political and legal spectrum
that is not clearly for sale.
In fact, why do you think the
court system allows most offenses
to be cleared with
monetary funds?
But even if you do something really
bad and you are stuck in jail
don't fret, because
in some cases
you can about pay 80 bucks
a night for a nice upgrade
to a clean quiet jail cell in
a nice area of the prison.
You name it, you can buy
it, and nothing is sacred.
143 years after the passage of the
13th Amendment of the US Constitution
and 60 years after Article 4 of the UN's
Universal Declaration of Human Rights
banned slavery and the
slave trade worldwide,
there are today more slaves
than anytime in human history,
trafficking about 30 million
for various profit schemes.
But, what about ethics,
you might ask?
Well, what about it?
Ethics and morality
continue to be redefined by the
economic ethos of the day,
and when a Wall Street trader
makes millions of dollars
betting against the currency and
hence prosperity of another country,
I can assure you he is
sleeping like a baby at night,
and why shouldn't he?
He is simply doing what is rewarded
and reinforced by the
economic system-at-large.
The market's inherent psychology
has nothing to do with anything
except its own perpetuation.
When you hear politicians tell you that
they are invading some poor country
to bring freedom and democracy,
you need to understand what
those words really imply.
The freedom they bring
is market freedom,
and the democracy that they bring is
the democracy of purchasing power:
the freedom of using
money for influence,
the freedom to, in fact,
restrict the freedom of others.
However, let's get back
to this technical stuff.
Putting aside the distortion
of market rationale
that now puts
everything for sale,
putting aside the false premise
that the price mechanism
actually properly calculates
the true attributes
of a sustainable and
efficient economic practice,
and putting aside the basic
value system disorder
radiating out of the overall
basis of unfolding,
let's now take a little quiz.
Welcome to modern Economics 101.
Question 1: If you
lived on a planet
with finite resources and
an expanding population,
would you encourage an economy based
on the need for growth and consumption
to keep everything going?
Correct answer: No.
The fact that our economy literally
requires constant consumption and growth
to keep GDP afloat
and people employed
is the hallmark of not an
economy, but an anti-economy.
Question 2: If you
were a producer
would you make goods to be as
durable and adaptable as possible
given the finite nature of resources
in an interest to maximize
labor productivity?
Answer: Yes.
Today it's the opposite,
and not only are all goods
inferior the moment they are made
due to the cost-efficiency needs for
corporations to remain competitive,
most companies also engage in what
is called planned obsolescence
which deliberately reduces good quality
to encourage repeat purchases
for more profit.
Question 3: If you were a
socio-economic planner,
would you encourage everyone
to buy one of everything,
hoarding that personal
property, protectively,
even though many goods
are used infrequently?
Answer: No.
That would be inefficient.
The reality that goods are only as
relevant as their use would be realized
and hence a system
of shared access,
not blind restrictive
universal ownership,
would be the most rational
manner of unfolding.
Question 4: What
about incentive?
Would you push a cut-throat,
competititve environment
where everyone it is out for
themselves or their little group?
Correct answer: No.
Knowing what we know today
about the competitive mentality
and how it creates abuse,
along with the reality that collaboration
and the sharing of information
is truly the driver of
progress on the social level,
competition would be seen as the
most limiting of arrangements
as a philosophical practice.
Question 5: What would be
the basis for reward today?
Would you require every human to
submit to each other for labor
as to achieve the
means for survival?
No. That would be crude
and counter-productive,
given the state of technology.
Modern technical capacity has the
ability to increase productivity
beyond anything known
in human history,
not to mention secure more safety
and efficiency in general.
To push human labor for income
in the face of this tool for
vast improvement is just absurd.
Final thoughts: If we were to
take a step back and reflect upon
how our human family is behaving
across the world today,
from Western materialism
to Islamic extremism,
from nuclear war to necrophilia,
we are faced with a dark, yet
extremely entertaining reality.
The very real fact [is] that
we are monkeys in the wild,
barely out of the
jungle on this planet
in the words of the late,
great George Carlin,
inching out of the
Dark Ages, in fact,
from a period of deep fear and
confusion with respect to who we are,
what we are doing, how
we relate to each other,
not to mention how we relate to
the habitat that spawned us.
On one side of the spectrum we have
a vast spectacle of human conceit:
stubborn ignorance, so much
so that if you are like me,
sometimes you wonder why
we should try at all.
That maybe this species
deserves everything it gets
and its fate as an
evolutionary cul-de-sac,
a failed genetic mutation, might be
an ideal hope for this universe.
Cynicism aside however,
it's easy to see that there is a
growing change in the minority
which will slowly become
majority if we let it.
An awakening is
happening, an awakening
where people have stopped
imposing their traditional ideals
and various ideological
baggage on the world,
and instead are
starting to listen,
listening to what the tools of
our ingenuity have afforded us,
listening to the message
of nature itself.
If there is any context which
needs a serious intervention
with respect to the natural
laws that govern us,
if there is any context where we
need to simply pay attention,
prepare to drop all of our prior
assumptions and change accordingly,
it is in the economic context.
Economics is not just some
arbitrary abstraction
for processing and
distributing resources.
It is an underlying value molder that
programs us into modes of behavior
that extend into all
areas of our psychology.
It is the active global religion
whether people like it or not,
and for those of us that wish to
see reason triumph over dogma,
we have a long, long road ahead.
Advocates of the free-market
model of economics will tell you
that there is no other system
possible to calculate society,
that the competitive
basis is the only way
to incentivize our
primitive culture.
They will tell you that reduced
economic interference of government
is the key to preserving the true
integrity of the market economy
and also preserve our
so-called liberty,
which they say would
be quickly corrupted
as tyranny and
oppression must occur
if any type of collaborative, designed
economic practice was applied.
They talk of the
'true' free market:
a utopian ideal that
claims the invisible hand,
if allowed to run without interference,
would alleviate the poverty,
deprivation, abuse, corruption,
conflict and inefficiency
so common in the world today.
Well, as with all religions,
delusion is common,
because today the market is
actually more free than ever
with the state being nothing
more than a parent corporation
working to assist its commercial
subsidiaries which support it.
Everything is for sale, and
no one is accountable.
All natural laws and physical realities
that would comprise the basis
for true technical
earthly efficiency
and awareness and reasoning
that, if allowed,
can literally transform
the world into a place
with vast abundance and
prosperity never before seen,
have been buried and dismissed,
only to be overshadowed by a
certain kind of efficiency,
market efficiency, an efficiency
that tracks money and money alone,
an efficiency that is
literally decoupled
from everything that supports
and secures life itself,
an efficiency that is
circular in its reasoning
as it has no recognition of
the physical laws of nature,
the laws of nature, which are, in
fact, the only real true government
and regulatory system that
has or will ever exist.
But then again, who
is to say it matters?
Maybe we should all
just take it in stride.
Maybe this reality
show of humankind,
this satirical tragic parody
of itself, to be sure,
doing all it knows, maybe
this is the way it is
and our brains, our
genes are messed up,
and we are just waiting
for the final laugh track
when Spaceship Earth slams into
that psychological brick wall.
I guess time will tell.
And until then, sit
back, grab some popcorn
and keep watching the greatest
reality show of all time.
And until next time,
I am Peter Joseph,
an agent and victim of
a Culture in Decline.
Would you like to talk
about the economy?