'The novelist Aldous Huxley
once wrote
'that most human beings
behave as though
'death were no more than
an unfounded rumour.
'But what happens when you realise
the rumour is true?'
'Let's face it, none of us,
'until it hits us in the face,
think we're going to die.
'I can still sort of picture
the consultant's room.
'He said, "Well,
I've got some bad news for you.
'"We think you've got
motor neurone disease."'
'As we film this, Richard Chell
has only months to live.
'His comfort lies
in his religious faith.
'For him, death is not the end.'
Death, to me,
the actual process of dying,
is not something I'm scared of.
For me, it's going through
a door into another room.
What do you mean by that?
I'm a Christian and therefore
I do believe in a life after death.
I do believe that this life
is just part of a process,
and that there's another part
of that process to complete.
I know very well your feelings
about on religion and the rest of it.
But I would say
having a view that is finite
is a bit like having half a meal.
It will leave you hungry
at the end of the day.
But, of course,
the existence of hunger
doesn't mean that there's food.
No, but it means that there's a need.
And I would argue that
there is a food.
If you faced a situation where,
like myself, say,
you were suddenly saying,
"Well, look. Death is fairly close
and you're going to die."
Do you think you would feel
any differently?
Or are you clear in your own mind,
if that was the situation,
"I know exactly how I'd respond
and exactly how I'd feel"?
'It is a fair question.
'I follow reason
and I don't believe in God.
'But this series is not about
whether God exists or not.
'It's about
a more difficult problem -
'what, if anything,
can take God's place?
'Religion has shaped
our understanding of life
'for thousands of years.
'Ideas of the soul,
'sin,
'and the afterlife
are hard to shake off,
'even for non-religious people
like me.
'As more and more of us
realise there is no God,
'what happens as we leave
religion behind?'
I have to believe there's a plan,
and that God is going to
accomplish something through this.
I suppose Jesus is
an unpaid babysitter.
It's like, "If I'm not watching you,
Jesus is."
So do you think that we,
in the West, are too materialistic?
I think so.
'In this film, Death,
'religion has traditionally
been thought to bring comfort
'at the end of life.
'But does it really?
'What can science
and reason tell us?'
How does someone like me,
who has no religion, face death?
'Varanasi, India -
'one of the oldest cities
in the world.
'It has a macabre speciality.
'Its main business
is the industry of death.
'Every year, a million
Hindu pilgrims visit Varanasi,
'dragging with them
some 40,000 corpses
'to be cremated
on the banks of the Ganges.'
This the holiest place
in the whole of Hinduism.
This is the place where Hindus
aspire to come to die,
to escape from the cycle
of birth and death and rebirth.
It is the most amazing scene.
It's probably been going on like
this for centuries, even millennia.
It looks as though
there are ashes down here
in the river, swirling around.
'As an atheist for whom death
is a full stop,
'I suppose I shouldn't feel
sentimental about the carcasses.
'They are ex-people
who have ceased to be.
'Yet I find something
a little bit shocking here.
'The partially-burnt corpses...
'..the locals casually searching for
'precious metals
in the burnt remains...
'..and the rejected dead.'
Although this is
clearly steeped in religion,
there's a surprising lack
of evident reverence or solemnity.
The people standing around
the funeral pyres
are doing the job of work
in a pretty matter-of-fact way.
'But there is a kind of logic behind
the apparent lack of reverence.
'In this religious tradition,
the flesh is no longer important.
'What matters here is
releasing the spirit or soul.
'This is where religion
plays its strongest card.
'The body may not live for ever
but the soul does.
'On the face of it,
it's a comforting idea.
'And a challenge
for an atheist like me.
'If you want to hear the challenge
starkly expressed,
'you can go to a place like this
in Kansas City.'
Hello, I'm Richard.
'This Catholic hospice,
Alexandra's House,
'is for babies who die
within hours of birth.'
These are clearly fatal disorders.
Babies perhaps with anencephaly,
Potter's Syndrome,
where they have no kidneys,
severe genetic heart disease.
So, they're all going to die.
They're all going to die.
And so, the normal recommendation
by the medical profession
would be probably be an abortion
at that point, would it?
Yes.
This may, you know,
be hard for some people to see.
These are many of our babies
for whom we've cared,
some who have lived here,
but all of them that we've cared for.
And so this is leading us up
to where the families stay.
This is where the parents stay.
'Over the last 11 years, Patti Lewis
'has helped the families
of over 500 babies
'who have died within these walls.'
Do you think their mothers are ever
going to meet their babies again?
Yes.
I think the mothers believe that,
too,
and the fathers and the siblings.
'I do sympathise with the desire
to meet again
'somebody whom you've known
and loved.
'But a newborn baby?
'I feel very sorry
for these parents,
'but still, reality may be raw.
'But we have to face it.
The baby was born on Saturday,
7/9/11.
Which was yesterday.
Yeah.
And she came into the world at 6pm
and she lived 30 minutes.
And those 30 minutes seemed so short
and so precious.
We held her and loved her and...
got to give her a little bath and
put her in her christening outfit.
We baptised her.
The family was there with us,
and it was a very precious time.
Can you talk us through
when you first found out
that there was a problem
with the baby?
We found out in January that we were
expecting and it would be our third.
And we were overjoyed.
And we go in for our ultrasound
and find out
if it was a boy or girl.
She did the scan
and told us there was no kidneys.
No kidneys? Right.
That was the first time that
we had heard that diagnosis.
And she called it
a "lethal pregnancy".
So, that's when you sort of
went into shock, is it?
More so, yes.
Did it occur to you that
the total sum of suffering would be
much less if you drew a line under
it then and restarted you life?
You've got to restart your life now.
Why did you decide to go on
for the remaining months?
Well, there's hope in everything
and God can do great things.
So, you were hoping for a miracle?
Hoping for a miracle,
but if it wasn't,
it was still going to be precious
and it's a baby and it's a life.
It's not my decision to
terminate that. It's not my choice.
I carried it and loved it and can
feel it move every single day and...
And also the 30 minutes or so that
we got to spend with her was worth,
I didn't have any of the pain,
but I would say it was worth
all of the trial of getting to
where we were.
And not only did we get to
spend 30 minutes with her
we got to be with
her for, like, 12 hours,
she wasn't with us spiritually,
but we got to hold her.
And you took photographs? &gt;
Oh, yes.
We have one that we
have printed off.
She was beautiful,
she was perfect and everything...
&lt; She looked just like her mom
even down to her fingernails.
Yes, beautiful.
I wouldn't have changed
it for anything.
Do you think you will ever
meet the baby? &gt;
Oh, of course, there is
great hope in that.
We will meet the baby,
it's in heaven with God.
'I feel for Runae and Lee.
'They sincerely think they are
gaining reassurance
'from their faith.
'So now, I need to understand how
this relationship
'between death and religion has
evolved to be so strong.'
Religion denies death is real.
It sets up, instead,
the forbidding prospect of eternity
either in heaven, or worse,
in hell.
For me, what's frightening
is not death itself but eternity,
whether you're there or not.
Yet people still reach instinctively
for religion and its rituals
when it comes to the end.
Why?
It's a very, very artificial
situation.
We see the person lying down.
Unless you're intimately acquainted
with someone,
you don't really see them lying down
and they may well be dressed
in their own clothes
lying down with their eyes closed
in an artificial situation
that they're inside a wooden box.
Now, all of these things
bring a surrealism,
but despite that,
people are very, very focused
on the fact that the last physical
connection they have with that person
is lying in that coffin, and that's
what they're saying farewell to.
So why do people go on
with these strange rituals?
It's the business of walking away
from the funeral and feeling,
"That was well done,
we liked what they've done for us
"and we feel that we laid someone
we cared about very deeply to rest
"in a very dignified
and meaningful way."
And even if the beautiful oak coffin
is then burned or buried,
somehow you feel you've given
the person a good send-off.
Very much so.
More and more of us have no faith
in God but we cling to the rituals.
Even in secular
woodland burial sites,
we find death brings
illogical superstition.
It is fascinating
to see people thinking of themselves
as part of this place.
They're anticipating
their postmortem identity.
So that when people talk about,
as they can in this place,
facing any direction,
so some want to look up the hill,
some want to look down the hill,
some want to look towards the sun,
they are buried
in different spatial directions.
'Douglas Davies is an anthropologist
'fascinated by the fuss
and trappings surrounding death.'
Do you think a part
of what's going on
is a reluctance to believe
that the dead person is really dead?
Yes. One lady, her father
used to farm around here.
And so he's been buried
looking up towards the hill,
cos he used to shoot rabbits up
there and the like,
and to her,
this is dreadfully important
because the relatives, too,
are thinking about their dead
after they've died.
Yes.
'I find I'm not immune
to these notions.'
There's a place in Cornwall
where my mother's family come from
and where we used to spend childhood
holidays called Dollar Cove.
And I think I'm right in saying
there's a little tiny church
more or less on the beach,
more or less built in the sand,
and I've sometimes fantasised
about being buried there
somehow with the sea crashing in
and the tide coming in and out.
What is the allure
that would be there for you
in a location for your body?
It's totally illogical.
It's pure sentimentality.
I suppose there's no rational
defence for it whatever.
One should say, "Just stick me
in a dustbin bag and throw me away."
But you don't want to be
in a dustbin bag?
No, that's right,
and it is pure sentiment.
We are sentimental animals...
Yes, absolutely.
..as well as social animals.
So why do even atheists like me
carry around
this sentimental baggage?
When did these illogical thoughts
first develop?
As a child, I don't think I worried
about God looking down at me
and seeing what I was doing.
I worried about ancestors.
I worried about my great uncles
and great aunts
looking down from heaven
and seeing everything that I did.
Childish, perhaps, but don't
let's be too quick to dismiss it.
Hello, Iggy. Whoops.
CHILD LAUGHS
He doesn't want to come out
and play.
(OK, OK, there we go...)
'From an early age, we start to
believe that there's more to us
'than just our physical bodies,
'as this experiment reveals.'
Shall we give him a little tickle?
He's very sweet, isn't he?
This is a fake machine
to fool children
into thinking live beings
can be duplicated.
MACHINE BUZZES
There's Iggy.
And there's Iggy.
As scientists, we seem to be
committed to the view
that if you could take a person
and make an exact copy,
molecule by molecule,
that copy would have exactly
the same thoughts and memories,
would be the same person.
But intuition rebels.
We seem to want to believe that
there's some essence of ourselves,
something that would not go across
with all those molecules,
something that a religious person
might want to call a soul.
This is an attempt to look at
an old philosophical problem,
which is, imagine
if you could copy anything,
and in these experiments, rather
than getting children to imagine it,
we produce a machine
which looks as if it can duplicate
and copy anything,
a bit like a photocopier
for objects.
Now there's two.
It made two.
We've shown in previous studies
they can believe it can copy toys
very easily, but the question is,
would they really extend that
to something like a living thing,
like a hamster?
Shall we tell him your name?
Do you want to whisper?
And so what copies over
is the body of the hamster,
the ideas of a hamster,
the memories of the hamster?
We believe the intuition is that
the physical object can be copied,
and therefore the physical
body can be copied,
but we're not so sure that children
think the mind can be copied.
Just like adults, they have this
sense that maybe the mind
is different to the physical body.
The reason this is so interesting
is because if you believe the mind
is separate to the physical body,
then it means if the body goes,
then maybe the mind can stay on
and exist.
And this allows for all sorts of
notions of spirits and the soul,
as being something entirely
untethered to the physical world.
Yes, disembodied ghosts after death
or surviving death in other ways,
the soul goes on.
So these young children believe
bodies can be copied but not minds.
Shall we have a look?
One...
Two.  Two.
They are already thinking there's
something in charge of each being
that is unique.
Something like a soul?
Did this hamster see your picture?
(Yes.)
Does it know what your picture is?
(No.)
Does this hamster know your name?
Does  this  hamster know your name?
(No.)
Evolutionary psychology suggests
that we have evolved
a sense of separate mind or soul
because it's useful to us.
Because the experience
of being in control of your body
is so pervasive, you just feel
that you've made a decision,
you'll have a cup of coffee,
you feel like you're driving
this very complex machine.
Yes, you certainly do.
If you didn't feel that you wouldn't
be very well adapted to the world.
No, that's right.
To be a fully functional animal,
which is what our ancestors were,
hunting and feeding and running
and escaping from predators,
you need to feel like a soul
that's in control of the body.
This is one reason why
it's so hard to shake off
the religious way of death.
We are programmed to believe
in something like a soul.
Now, of course,
I don't believe in a soul
but I, too, have the feeling
that there is some sort of essence
of Richard Dawkins
that makes me who I am...
..that gives me
my unique personal identity.
'To understand more about this,
'I need to look at the role
our memories play,
'with the person who's known me
longest ?
'my mother.'
So what have we got here?
We've got, um...
Your first birthday party.
First birthday party.  Yes.
Well, I've no memory of this at all.
That's presumably me, is it?
Yes, that's you.
In a little dress that your granny
sent out from England.
'Our memories are hugely important
to our sense of who we are.'
That's Kilimanjaro.
Oh, yes.
You used to like saying words
like Kilimanjaro.
Oh, right.
'But our memories lull us
into a false sense of certainty.
'They are fallible,
riddled with errors.'
Another early memory
was being stung by a scorpion.
Yes, we were miles,
absolutely miles from anywhere,
and you suddenly jumped off
your chair without your shoes on,
which you weren't allowed to do,
and stepped on a scorpion...
..and Ali,
our African boy,
rushed in and got your foot and
squeezed it and sucked it for hours.
Gosh! Good for Ali. Yes.
Well, not hours but...
And you were screaming. We had to
hold you while he sucked your foot...
Yes. I...
My memory is slightly different.
My memory is that
I was walking along the floor
and I saw this creature
walking across...  Yes.
..and I thought it was a lizard.
Really?
And I didn't step on it,
I put my foot in the way of it
to let it crawl over my foot.
Well...you jumped off your chair...
Mmm. I don't remember the pain.
Don't you? Isn't that interesting?
Cos that was the terrible bit.
We think back to our first memory,
our first big adventure,
and it's almost as though there
was a movie camera in our head
recording every detail.
But that's not the way it is.
That's an illusion.
What we're remembering is a memory
of a memory of a memory,
of perhaps the real thing.
A man may wear a wrist watch
when he's 20
and the same watch when he's 50.
It's the same watch
but it's not the same man inside.
Every atom in his body has changed,
has turned over.
I'm not the child I once was.
The child I once was is dead.
So the physical cells
that once made me are long gone
and my memories are more tenuous
than I would wish.
The connection between younger
and older Richard Dawkins
isn't as strong
as I might like it to be.
And I think this is why
the religious idea
of something permanent,
the soul, is so plausible.
Now I want to explore the reality
of why we die.
Religion still dominates
our thinking about death.
If we get rid of God, what's left?
I'm on a voyage to tell you
the extraordinary truth
that science reveals about death.
According to evolutionary science,
death is not something
to be overcome at all.
It's a necessary part
of the picture.
'I'm joining the scientists on board
'Bangor University's
research vessel on the Irish Sea.'
Is that alive?
Yeah, yeah.
So where do you put that?
'They are studying the lifespan
of a species of clam
'called Arctica Islandica.
'They may look rather ordinary
'but they have one attribute
that is really quite amazing.
'These clams are among the
longest-living animals on Earth.'
Save that one or not?
The reason why we are
so interested in this
is that this is a very
long-lived species.
We can pull it up from the wild
and assign a year - almost to
within one year - how old it is.
Basically, the shell grows
in incremental steps.
Each ring is an annual ring, so
the growth is very much like a tree.
Can you guess from this one
how old is it?
There's a size growth curve. This
is probably 80 to 150 years old.
The oldest of them
reach what sort of age?
Around the UK,
it's around about 220 years.
Up in Iceland, in the far north,
they'll hit 350, 400,
maybe even 500 years.
Only recently, this research team
found a clam that had lived
for more than half a millennium.
It's amazing to think that some of
these clams that we're dredging up
were born before Darwin,
even before Elizabeth I.
So, why do they live so long?
Any evolutionary explanation
of why aging happens
has to do two things.
It has to be able to explain
why you see aging in many species.
It also has to be able to explain
why you see
enormously long lifespans
or possibly no aging
in a very few species.
And the clams, I think,
may be an example of this.
You've seen them and
handled them for yourself.
They have enormously thick shells.
I don't think there are
very many things down there
that can actually bite through them.
And so they can sit around
and they can just carry on
producing offspring
once they've reached
a certain size.
'These clams are continuing to
pass on their genes to
'the next generation,
even at 200 and 300 years old.'
So, from the evolutionary point
of view, it is not just that
the individuals are well protected
against being eaten.
Because  they're
well-protected against being eaten,
it's a good gamble
to stay alive a long time,
because you've got
a good chance of reproducing later.
Whereas something like a salmon
has a very poor chance
of reproducing again,
so it might as well throw everything
it's got into one big gamble now.
That's exactly it.
There is no point
in spending resources
to make a body that
will last 400 years
if your chance of making it
through the night is pretty slim.
So, evolutionary science tells us
a lot about ageing and death.
The clams are able to reproduce
when they are hundreds of years old,
and so long as they are
able to reproduce,
their genes keep them alive.
We need to see death from
a gene's eye point of view.
Our bodies are survival
machines for genes.
Once our genes have got us
to reproductive age
and copied themselves into
a new generation,
our bodies have less purpose.
Time bombs inside us go off.
We age. We die.
So, rather than looking upon
ageing as a wearing out of the body,
perhaps we should see it as a
side effect of how our genes work.
Even extraordinary exceptions
throw light on this truth.
This is Irving Kahn,
a financial trader
on New York's Madison Avenue,
who has come to work
every day since 1927.
Irving is 105 years old.
Do you remember
the Wall Street crash?
Oh, yes.
I came just at the time.
About three or four months before
the peak, the summer of 1928, '29.
And that was one reason
I didn't like the business.
&lt; Yes.
Because I came here,
went to the exchange on Wall Street,
and found, after a week on the floor,
that it was like working in a casino.
&lt; I can imagine.
A gambling house.
I understand that, not just you
but many members of your family
are extremely long-lived.
Yes, my brother Peter is about
103 or 104.
I'm 105.
I have limited renals
and limited hearsight -
and I hope, the right
number of marbles.
You have got a lot of marbles,
I think!
What about your sister,
how old is she?
She's 108.
Mr Kahn, is it possible to
give us an idea
what it feels like to be your age?
It's much better
and it's much worse.
So, why do some people's genes
keep their bodies going
for so much longer?
The curious case of Irving Kahn
and his family
has intrigued scientists who are
trying to answer this very question.
When we ask our people, why do
you think you live to be so old?
One of the things they're saying,
"Hey, it's in my family. My mother
was 102, my grandfather was 108."
Irving can show that he has four
other siblings that lived to be 100.
The study looked at
500 aged Ashkenazi Jews,
like Irving Kahn,
from the same geographical area,
whose environment and genes
can be easily compared.
For Irving, and especially
for his sister, Helen,
she's been smoking for 95 years,
two packs for 95 years,
which shows you that if you smoke
for 95 years, you live a long life!
I know it doesn't!
I can assure you that that's true.
And Irving has smoked
for about 30 years in his life.
So the point here is that
our centenarians, as a group,
did not interact
with their environment
the way the doctors
tell their patients,
that you have to watch your weight,
you have to exercise,
you shouldn't smoke
and you should drink
one cup of alcohol a day
and all the things we know to tell
them. It doesn't matter for them.
So, for some,
lifestyle and environment
don't play as large a role
as we've been told.
But if Irving's genes hold
the secret to long life,
why hasn't evolution given us
all genes like his?
If there are genes that increase
longevity out into the hundreds,
why didn't natural selection favour
those genes in our ancestral past?
Well, I will tell you,
there is something very upsetting
in this sense in our group.
First of all,
a third of the centenarians
in the world don't have children.
OK, so I don't know, is it
having children, raising them,
rearing them, I don't know what?
But the point is that there is
some exchange between
reproduction and aging.
But also, in my study,
the centenarians had less kids
at a much later age
than my control population.
So, if the control population has
three to five kids on average,
our centenarians
are 1.7 kids on average.
And so, if you
are thinking that way,
we're losing longevity genes, right?
Because in every generation,
we populate more
with kids of the people
who don't have longevity genes
than have longevity genes.
Our genes appear to trade
long life for reproduction.
Longevity seems to be connected
to later reproduction
or no children at all.
So how long we live and why
we die are dependent on our genes.
And I'm about to look my own
genetic code straight in the face.
Advances in genetic science mean
it is now possible for me
to get my entire genome decoded.
There's something very personal
and intimate about it as well.
This is something that is
absolutely unique to me,
there's never ever been,
in the history of the world,
nor will there be again
a genome which is the same as mine,
or the same as yours,
or the same as anybody else's.
This new science
is still in its infancy.
I'm going to be one of just
a dozen people in the world
and the first person in Britain
publicly to have
their whole genome sequenced.
What we're doing here
is very new for us, actually,
and it's actually
very exciting for us.
We're taking a genome of
a healthy person and we are asking,
what can we learn about that person?
It is your most important bit
of information about you,
is your genome sequence.
But on a serious note,
of course, we may find information
in your genome that has clinical
or health implications.
Yes, I have thought about that.
So, let's go, let's go and do it.
OK.
It'll just be a little scratch
as the needle goes in.
'Having my blood taken is only the
first stage in a complex process.'
OK, so we're almost there.
This is the most painless
blood test I've ever had.
'Having my genome decoded
is, in effect, a way
'of narrowing down how and when
I'm going to die.
'My journey to understand death
has become personal.'
You have roughly 100 mutations
which have been reported as being
associated with a disease.
'I may be one of a handful
of individuals in the world
'to have their genome sequenced,
but before I find out my results
'I'm off to meet the man
who was first.
'And he isn't just anyone.
'He's one of the two men who made
this new science possible -
'James Watson.'
Well, it's certainly
a very beautiful thing.
'Together with Francis Crick,
'James Watson discovered that genes
are digital codes
'written on DNA molecules.
'Watson and Crick's names
will live forever.
'And Watson isn't shy about it.'
So now I realise, I am,
except for Hawking,
the most famous scientist alive.
Oh, wonderful, yes.
I turned out to be helped by people
looking at my DNA.
In what way?
It revealed that I have a genetic
polymorphism which metabolises drugs
and I have one which acts
very slowly.
So if I take, er, beta blockers,
it stays in my system for a week
instead of going away for a day.
So I've been given them for,
you know,
to help control my blood pressure
and I went to sleep!
Watson took a personal risk
in making his genome available
for study, exposing all its
imperfections to public scrutiny
for the sake
of advancing genetic research.
Do you get great pleasure
from ideas?
No, I get pleasure
from understanding.
Yes. So understanding,
everything falls into place
when you understand?
Yes, you move from...
It's understanding, er...
that gives you happiness and I think
it's one of the unique human features
because it's not limited to me
but it clearly,
you know, when you're able to
find out how to do something.
This, for me, is what is
so thrilling about science -
understanding things,
such as how the DNA molecule
underlies all life on Earth.
It's because Watson discovered
the structure of DNA,
over half a century ago, that today
I'm able to have my genome analysed
and understand what makes me live,
and how and when I might die.
Today is a very special day for me.
In 50 years, lots of people
will be able to say this,
but today I'm one of very few people
who's had
their entire genome sequenced.
Today is the big day
when I get to see the results.
So Richard, it's a long time
since you were in Oxford
and we took an armful of your blood.
We've had a team
busy working since then,
trying to extract the DNA
and reconstruct your genome.
We take these fragments...
'To understand my genes,
'Gil McVean matches them against
the human reference genome -
'a composite of anonymous donors
'that took ten years to decode
and construct.'
What we're really interested in
is not saying where you agree
with this reference
but finding places where you differ.
In that,
we find over four million differences
between your genome
and that reference.
We have about 50,000 variants
that we have seen in you
for the very first time,
completely new to science.
'It is extraordinary that this
enormous quantity of data
'reveals incredibly precise details
about me.
'Elements of my private world
'that I've never shared with anyone
before, or known myself.'
You have a classic European mutation
that means that you've got
runny earwax.
Another one which means that you can
smell asparagus in your own urine.
You've got another one that
means you can taste broccoli.
They sound frivolous,
but at the same time they probably
point to an evolutionary process
and that's probably to do with
your ability to detect toxins.
Plants have different toxins
across the world.
There are local adaptations to toxins
that you need to be able to recognise
to survive.
'Buried in my genome
is the story of my own survival,
'but also clues about how I may die.
'Do I have ticking time bombs
in my genetic code?'
You have roughly a hundred mutations
which have been seen before
in clinical settings
and have been reported
as being associated with a disease.
Having these mutations doesn't mean
you'll definitely get the disease,
it just alters your chance
of getting that.
These are the variants
that you carry
which have been associated with a
whole range of common disorders.
Everything from cancer
through to type II diabetes
through to schizophrenia.
Let's just take an example of this.
If you zoom in on chromosome 11,
you've got a mutation
which the literature tells you is
associated with, or causes porphyria,
which is the disease that people
hypothesised for a while
caused the madness of King George.
It's a nasty disease.
You would know if you had it.
You should have
a 70% chance of getting porphyria.
'So I've dodged that bullet,
but there are other threats.
'It's so impressively precise!
'My genome reveals that if I smoked,
'I would have been
in the most high-risk group
'for developing lung cancer.'
Your genotype doubles your risk
of getting lung cancer
but actually the way it does it
is through doubling your risk
of smoking in a particular way.
So this variant influences your risk
of getting lung cancer
because it changes the way
people smoke.
They smoke deeper breaths,
they smoke closer
to the end of the cigarette.
What it actually does
is change your smoking habits.
How fascinating! So it's picked
up as a gene for lung cancer
but the method of transmission,
the method of effect
is via smoking behaviour.
Exactly. This raises the question
of whether you've ever smoked.
Do you like the smell of wood smoke?
No, I've never smoked.
That's good, but don't take up
smoking is my advice.
It seems to me
to be utterly astonishing
that it's possible for scientists
to take an individual
and to detect these millions
of digital pieces of information
to actually read it out
as though it was a computer disk.
Well, here it is then. Here is
your genome. Look after it!
Thank you very much!
I'm delighted to have it.
Thank you so much for all the work
you and your colleagues have put in.
I mean, when I look at this,
this little box here,
what it contains is all the
information necessary to make...
not quite me,
to make an identical twin of me.
And I think that's an astonishing
thought.
Thank you very, very much for this.
It's been a pleasure.
As we come to learn more about DNA,
our relationship with death
is bound to change.
And as more of us
have our genomes analysed,
will we be able to avoid
those ticking time bombs
contained in our codes
that killed our ancestors
after they reproduced?
This is my genome, my whole genome.
And strangely enough, portions
of my genome are behind that door.
Behind there
is the Dawkins' family vault.
This has been the Dawkins' church
since the 1720s
and in there are 20 of my relations,
many of them my ancestors,
and they have contributed
some of the genes
that are inside
this little silver box.
At the top,
next to the top there,
Henry Dawkins, and then three down,
his wife, Lady Juliana Dawkins.
They are my four greats - my great,
great, great, great grandparents.
One-64th of the genes
inside this little silver box
come from Henry.
The bottom of this column here,
the middle column, is another Henry,
his son -
he has contributed one-32nd part
of the genes inside this hard disk.
Unfortunately,
the door can't be opened.
It hasn't been opened since,
I think, 1919.
They've lost the key,
nobody knows how to open it.
There are some slots in there
that I should never occupy
unless they can get the door open!
What would be rather nice
would be if we could somehow post
this disk in there
to rest alongside my ancestors.
But the genes, the set of
instructions inside us, don't rest.
Just as they have come
from our ancestors before us,
so too do they march on
into our children
and their children's children.
Our genes are a kind of archive
of the remote past.
They go through us
to the remote future.
Henry Dawkins may be
my four greats grandfather
and he's put some genes in here,
but my two hundred million
greats grandfather was a fish
and, by the way,
the same fish was your two hundred
million greats grandfather too.
Amazingly, even he
has put some genes in here,
and they, too, have a chance
of going on to the remote future.
Our genes are, in a sense, immortal.
That's not comforting in the way
the soul is supposed to be,
but it is a wonderful thought
and it is true.
We may argue about whether
we have an immortal soul
that survives our death, but one
thing science tells us for sure
is that if there's anything
that's immortal in our bodies,
it is our genes.
Subtitles by
Red Bee Media Ltd
Best watched using Open Subtitles MKV Player