23 states, nearly half the country. On Monday
afternoon, that`s how many were under some
kind of warning or advisory for wind related
to Hurricane Sandy. This is the view of Sandy
from the international space station. It`s
huge. All that white stuff, that`s Sandy`s
wind field. If that were a country, it would
be the 20th biggest country in the world.
But you really start to understand its power
and intensity when you are on the ground.
The rain is torrential, and the wind - yesterday
it was consistently blowing at about 90 miles
per hour. Then, there is something called
the storm surge. That`s the combination of
a storm and high tide. You see those waves
off the coast of Massachusetts? Storms like
this drive those waves higher, some areas
were expecting a storm surge 11 feet above
normal high tide. That could lead to severe
flooding.
Some officials say that the damage from Hurricane
Sandy could be unprecedented. One government
model says we could be looking at more than
$7 billion in damages, and that`s just from
the wind. When it comes to storms that make
landfall in the northeastern U.S., this is
the one all the others get compared to. The
Long Island Hurricane of 1938. One of the
things that experts look at when they are
measuring hurricanes is the low pressure reading.
Usually, the lower the pressure, the stronger
the storm. The 1938 hurricane had a low pressure
reading of 946 millibars. Sandy`s low pressure
reading -- 943. I asked CNN`s Chad Myers about
the comparison between these two storms.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
CHAD MYERS, AMS METEOROLOGIST: The problem
with this storm call is that people took it
as a category one. It had the pressure of
a category two or three, the wind field of
a category one hurricane, but yet the surge
of a category two or three. When it got north
of Cape Hatteras, and kept getting stronger,
the pressure of this storm was deeper, it
was a stronger storm than the 1938 storm that
just rolled right over Long Island. This was
always a dangerous storm, we knew it in the
pressure. Sometimes you just can`t tell people,
hey, it`s a cat one, take cover, because they
say ah, it`s just a cat one, we don`t care.
This was much, much more than a category one
hurricane.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: All right, thanks, Chad. There is something
else going on with Hurricane Sandy that could
make its impact even worse. It`s the possibility
that this could turn into a super storm. Now,
let me show you what we mean by that. There
is Sandy spinning off the East Coast, and
that high pressure system is keeping it from
moving out into the Atlantic. Then there is
this cold front moving in from the west. What
happens is that when the cold air and the
warm air meet up and make Sandy more powerful,
and you can see there, it keeps the storm
in that same area, just sitting right over
that part of the country. When it`s all said
and done, Sandy could end up affecting up
to 60 million people. Some states have mandatory
evacuations, thousands of people spent the
night at shelters like this one. Hundreds
of thousands of people lost power, and school
was canceled for millions of students. We
heard from some of you on Facebook and Twitter
about that.
Hurricane Sandy is even having an impact on
the race for the White House. President Obama
and Republican presidential nominee Romney,
both altered or canceled campaign events yesterday.
Instead of next week`s election, they were
focused on the storm and the people in its
path.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
BARACK OBAMA, PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES
OF AMERICA: We anticipate that there are going
to be a lot of trees down, a lot of water
and despite the fact that the power companies
are working very closely with the various
state officials and local officials to make
sure that they are bringing in as many assets
as possible and getting those ready in preparation
for the storm, the fact is that a lot of these
emergency crews are not going to be able to
get into position to start restoring power
until some of these winds have died down.
MITT ROMNEY, REPUBLICAN PRESIDENTIAL CANDIDATE:
We faced these kinds of challenges before.
And as we have, it`s interesting to see how
Americans come together, and this, this looks
like another time when we need to come together,
all across the country, even here in Ohio,
and make sure that we give of our support
to the people who need it.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Campaigning is on halt for the hurricane.
The election is still going to happen, it`s
just a week away, and what we are going to
do this week is look at where the candidates
stand on some of the issues. Today`s topic
is education. During his first term in the
White House, President Obama launched a program
called "Race to the Top". It offers money
from the federal government to states for
coming up with plans to meet national standards
and improve teacher quality and plans to turn
around low performing schools. The president
also supports the development of charter schools.
Governor Romney`s education plan is called
"A Chance for Every Child." He also supports
national standards, but he said that education
policies should come more from the state and
local level rather than from the federal government.
Governor Romney`s plan also focuses on choice.
He said he wants to give some parents the
ability to choose where their kids go to school.
Yesterday, we looked at the electoral college,
the system that determines who wins the presidency.
We looked at some scenarios for both Governor
Romney and President Obama to get enough votes
to win the election. One other possibility
came up at the end of that report yesterday.
A tie. Now, Josh Levs looks at what could
happen.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
JOSH LEVS, CNN CORRESPONDENT: It could happen,
and it would throw the race into confusion
and controversy. What if President Barack
Obama and Mitt Romney tie in the electoral
college with 269 votes each? There is an amendment
for that. Here is how it works. In January,
the new House of Representatives would choose
the president, with each state getting one
vote. Republicans will almost surely have
the majority in that vote and choose Romney.
But not Paul Ryan. The vice president gets
decided by the Senate. If that`s still in
Democratic control, Biden would almost surely
win. So, thanks to the electoral system, we
could have a Romney-Biden White House.
But there is also another possibility. Let`s
go back to that electoral college tie. These
are the votes electors are expected to take,
based on the votes in their states. But they
don`t all legally have to. Some states don`t
have laws to punish faithless electors who
go their own way. So, if there is a tie, expect
swayable electors to suddenly become very,
very popular to some, and a source of anger
to others.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today, "Shoutout" goes
out to Mr. Uselding`s social studies classes
at St. Frances Cabrini Catholic School in
West Bend, Wisconsin. Which of these U.S.
military branches was established last? Here
we go, was it the Army, Navy, Air Force or
Marines? You`ve got three seconds, go!
The Air Force was established as its own military
branch in 1947. Before that, it was part of
the U.S. Army. That`s your answer, and that`s
your "Shoutout."
AZUZ: OK, I`ve heard of a chain-linked fence,
a white-picket fence, even a defense. But
a space fence -- that`s a real thing. The
Air Force has been in charge of it for decades,
but the fence needs some repairs, about $3.5
billion worth. The space fence program is
a series of radar signals. What they do is
track space junk. Some pieces are as small
as a soft ball, others are as big as a bus.
And it`s good to have a heads up if one of
those is heading towards the International
Space Station or satellite that carries TV
signals or cell phone service. The Air Force
tracks about 20,000 pieces of space junk,
but it`s estimated that there are ten times
that much junk floating around out there.
The military wants to restring the space fence,
so to speak, before something slips through.
Washington State University head football
coach, Mike Leach, hasn`t posted anything
on Twitter in a couple of weeks. And hopefully,
his players haven`t either. Because if they
do, and coach Leach finds out about it, he
says they`ll be suspended from the team. The
coach banned his players from using the social
media service last week. The school`s athletic
director said some players posted inappropriate
tweets. He described them as vulgar. Some
Washington State students think this is a
good decision, since the players represent
the school; others think the coach shouldn`t
be allowed to take away a player`s right to
use Twitter.
What do you think of the coach`s decision
to keep players off Twitter? Do you agree
it will help prevent distractions, or do you
think it stifles their speech? Cnnstudentnews.com
is the place to tell us.
Before we go, we know a lot of you out there
have gangnam style. We also know that the
leader of the United Nations doesn`t. Well,
not a lot. Here you see him next to international
pop star Psy. Now, Psy tries to show U.N.
Secretary General Ban Ki-moon a little gangnam
style. Ban falls off the horse. He admitted
he was a little jealous of Psy. Ban says he`d
have to relinquish being the world`s most
famous Korean. Of course, in the U.N. workplace,
Ban`s more focused on ergangnomics (ph). And
you can`t really blame the performer, because
he reached for the moon, and with moves like
that, the Psy`s the limit. OK, I`m done. We`ll
see you tomorrow, on CNN STUDENT NEWS.