generation of tattooers.
The next generation of tattooers
that grew up with
the internet, and with
computers, are
different from me.
You see, I didn't grow
up with that.
You have access to the internet
wherever you are.
Even now, you do a great tattoo
with your iPhone, boom,
stick it up on your Instagram.
You've barely finished it.
But everybody [INAUDIBLE]
my shop does this.
Everybody's young, that's
what it is.
My opinion is that everybody
has an opinion.
And the internet is a great
place to air your opinion.
A lot of time people
don't give a
fuck about your opinion.
Just keep doing the work.
This is my opinion.
If you want to validate yourself
as a good tattoo
artist, and you choose the
internet to put your work out
there, put it out there.
Don't give a fucking opinion.
Do you know what I mean?
Because that's only
your opinion.
Again, that's my opinion.
STEFANO C.: Dante, or Danny, as
many people know him, I've
known him for a long time.
He's a [INAUDIBLE]
He's got his own fetish for
denim and [INAUDIBLE]
He wants to look cool.
MALE SPEAKER: I can't help but
look at myself in the mirror
wherever I am.
MALE SPEAKER: Yep,
I love myself.
[LAUGHTER]
STEFANO C.: He's like a very
good friend of mine.
He took me down on his
protective wing.
Didn't come for free.
I had to work very
hard for it.
Yeah, but he gave me the chance
to get me [? in the ?]
shop.
But through him, I had
the chance to see
lots of good stuff.
[INAUDIBLE]
DANTE DIMASSA NARRATING: The
great thing about Frith Street
is that we end up showcasing
really young tattoo artists
that have a lot of talent.
DANTE DIMASSA: This is Frith
Street, everybody.
It's just gone that way.
We showcase young talent.
STEFANO C.: Now it's
me, Jordan Teear.
There's Emiliano Liberatori,
Valerie Vargas.
There's Stewart Robson, Oliver
Macintosh, and Miles Champlin.
DANTE DIMASSA NARRATING: Frith
Street contributed to what's
tattooing in London, or
in England, is today.
DANTE DIMASSA: There's been a
few key shops over the last 10
years that have done a lot
of great, great work.
But also a lot of key artists.
We're fortunate right now that
we're flavor of the month.
So I suppose the right people
wanted to be involved in here
and I think the hard work.
That's what counts.
That's what might of made
it like this, I think.
VALERIE VARGAS: We've always
discussed amongst ourselves
that Frith Street feels
a bit like boot camp.
You come here, and if you're
open, and you work hard, you
will be exposed to anything
and everything
that's good in tattooing.
STEWART ROBSON: It's where
young tattooists come.
And they get whipped,
and broken, and
driven into the ground.
And then you come out a
stronger, better soldier in
the end of it.
STEFANO C.: Frith Street
has been like a kind
of stage for people.
You are definitely in the
place where you got a
spotlight on you.
And you get busy because
there's a big
demand in the shop.
So you try out different
things until you
get on your set style.
DANTE DIMASSA NARRATING: You
see, with Stewart, for
example, Stewart kind of knew
what he wanted to do when he
came and worked here.
I don't think Valerie knew
what she wanted to do.
She hadn't quite yet
found her groove.
VALERIE VARGAS: This will have
to be Stewart's, actually.
I don't think it's mine.
Yeah, it weighs a fucking ton.
He just did everything, tribal,
black and grey, Japanese.
Girls.
Traditional.
Coverups.
Magpie.
Sharks.
That's my chess piece
that he did for me.
So frickn' painful.
What is this?
Nah, this is Stewart's as well,
again doing everything.
Lettering.
Japanese.
So fucking good, honestly.
STEWART ROBSON: I think
Valerie says
she looks up to me.
And I think it feels like
I'm justified in
speaking about it.
But I think she probably just
feels like she's more of an
apprentice, or she's certainly
less experienced.
But, maybe that's because I'm
more used to analyzing my
thoughts, while she works
more gut instinct.
But having someone to look up to
allows her to just run wild
with her instincts, because she
knows that there's someone
there to catch her
if she falls.
Not that she ever does fall.
But that mental safety net has
helped her kind of really get
somewhere, I think.
VALERIE VARGAS: I've always
had some sort of website.
And I had just drawing,
sketches,
ramblings on my blog.
Nothing exciting.
I just did a couple of
commission pieces.
This is basically what somebody
that doesn't know
what's going on tried to draw.
And they can draw.
I mean just because you can
draw, doesn't mean you can
tattoo, know how to
draw for a tattoo.
This is from a girl, actually.
She stands in my mind as being
the first customer that was
like, I just like the way
you do your thing.
Can you kind of do
something for me?
And we came up with
these designs.
They were the first designs
that I thought, I'm liking
where I'm going now,
rather than just
blindly stumbling along.
I think being at Frith Street,
and very quickly falling into
some sort of category, meant
that I've not really done a
lot of everything else.
And when you only doing one
style, one thing, for a period
of time, you're going to get
better quickly, to understand
things quicker, and you
can develop quicker.
STEFANO C.: I remember Valerie
coming to the shop.
[INAUDIBLE]
is [INAUDIBLE]
She didn't have a set
style at the time.
Obviously, she wasn't tattooing
for a long time.
And then that she came
in with a portfolio.
And I remember seeing
a couple of pinups.
It wasn't what she's doing now,
obviously, because the
evolution of tattoo work starts
whenever you find
yourself comfortable
in a place.
And I guess she did find Frith
Street as a place to settle
down and start doing whatever
she does now.
VALERIE VARGAS: Frith Street,
we hit the ground running.
It was so busy.
We were booked up weeks for
a couple weeks at a time.
It was crazy.
I didn't know what
I was doing.
It was just so scary.
And I wanted to impress Dante.
And I wanted to make sure that
he felt like he had done the
right thing by giving not only
me a job, and Stewart a job,
but a couple a job.
STEWART ROBSON: When we first
come down to Frith Street,
definitely the first six months,
anything in life was
just [INAUDIBLE]
VALERIE VARGAS: The technical
aspect of it, how it feels on
the skin, and the tension when
you stretch your hand, and
everything.
All that stuff, came
very slowly to me.
But again, having a friend
that only had the best
interests at heart to help
me, really built up your
confidence.
STEWART ROBSON: And we were so
focused on trying to make
tattooing work, we were both
in our first five years.
In the first five years,
you're an infant.
You're busy soaking everything
up, and trying to learn, and
trying to just cope
with tattooing.
VALERIE VARGAS: The busier it
got, the better my technical
ability got, as well.
I do think that my drawing and
my design work developed ahead
of that, however.
But I managed to catch up
fairly quickly, I feel.
STEWART ROBSON: She started
really digging back in to old
tattoo times, and looking
at Ed Hardy's work form
the '70s and '80s.
And then she realized that Ed
Hardy figured out the stuff
she was trying to do almost
before she was born.
And he nailed it.
So then she used that
as a starting point.
She spring-boarded off that and
see where she could go.
And I think that's when her work
matured, and the style
shifted into a more
adult style.
VALERIE VARGAS: To me there
is certain things that are
tattoos that look
like tattoos.
And the quintessential tattoo
design is either a rose or a
skull, for me, really.
And if you have neither, then
you can't call yourself
tattooed, yet.
Really.
I don't think.
I think the turning point for
me was a nesting doll.
It was one of the first
ones I ever done.
I remember a lot of people
begun bringing that.
They would print it, and bring
it, and wanted me to do it.
A few months after that, like
two or three months, that's
when I noticed I was getting
busier, booked up for three to
four months.
STEWART ROBSON: She tried to put
a barrier between all the
phone calls that would
come every day.
Every single day there'd be
maybe 10 to 15 people, I want
to get tattooed by Valerie.
But they didn't want
little tattoos.
They wanted big three, four,
five session tattoos.
And there's not enough time
in the day to tattoo that.
And then 10 people,
10 new people.
So she had to have
a waiting list.
And then she didn't
really want that.
VALERIE VARGAS: I know that I'm
booked up till October.
So--
hello, hello?
If you get back in touch,
whenever you want to get
tattooed, you might have
to wait a few months.
Or you might--
STEWART ROBSON: She's finally
got through that.
It took two or three years
to get through that.
And for someone who's only been
tattooing five or six
years, that's a long
portion of your
career to be in demand.
VALERIE VARGAS: No.
You don't want to go underneath
this, do you?
STEWART ROBSON: I'm good.
I've got a hat.
STEWART ROBSON: We've spoken
to Dante about
our long-term plans.
VALERIE VARGAS: And we were
thinking, what happens next?
If we want to settle, if we
want to have a family?
Are we going to stay
in London?
Are we gonna stay
at Frith Street?
STEWART ROBSON: Dante's
been so great to us.
So trusting with his time and
letting us develop the way we
needed to develop.
VALERIE VARGAS: He gave us
this huge chunk of trust.
And what did we have
to do with it?
We just made it work for
all three of us.
STEWART ROBSON: And been
supportive in personal
matters, and in business,
and in tattooing.
VALERIE VARGAS: And really, for
the person that has given
us, technically speaking, the
keys to the rest of our life.
STEWART ROBSON: As well as owing
everything to tattooing,
we owe everything in
tattooing to Dante.
VALERIE VARGAS: And that's
part of the reason why I
helped my mother move from
Scotland to London.
STEWART ROBSON: And really
London, and Frith Street, is
the best place for us.
VALERIE VARGAS: We finally made
the decision that, yup,
this is where we're
going to be.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Oh my God.
Holy shit.
VALERIE VARGAS (OFFSCREEN):
Yeah, we still got to do the
bum cheeks.
We're leaving that to last.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
Aha, aha ha.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
That's
another reason I cancelled.
VALERIE VARGAS (OFFSCREEN):
Ha ha ha.
Yeah, yeah.
Ha ha.
Oh shit, bum cheeks next.