VALERIE VARGAS: I didn't like
being different at school.
I don't think any kid really,
actually fully enjoys being
different at school.
I've got a really old drawing
that I did of my mom when I
was like 10 or 11.
That's pretty cool.
Where the fuck did I put it?
I hope I didn't put it away.
That's my mom.
I do remember just copying
things very early on, from age
three or four, and my mom was
always putting it up on the
fridge and stuff.
It just always kind of made me
really happy and really proud
that she liked what I did.
That sounds really sad, but I
didn't really like playing.
I just really liked drawing.
So, to join in, she would draw
with me, and whenever she drew
with me, if she drew girls--
I only found out after getting
into tattoing that the way she
draws girls are very much
like Jerry pin-ups.
Because tattooing designs in
general, in magazines and that
stuff, so it's pretty cool that,
if she was asked to draw
a girl, she'd just
draw a pin-up.
And then, yeah, that
just carried on.
And, we never really
thought I was ever
gonna do anything else.
There was never a
question of it.
And tattooing found
me, thankfully.
And, this is the way now.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
STEWART ROBSON: There's kind
of different elements to
Valerie's style.
There's that kind
of fantasy side.
But then, there's the more
tattoo-ey side, the way she
can just do a really pretty
version of some old flash.
She's careful of doing something
really cute, or
something really tough, or
something really beautiful, or
something--
she never does anything ugly,
but, she can make a witch look
cool, or a demon look cool.
But it's still beautiful.
VALERIE VARGAS: Personally,
I like to base it on
traditional.
I do enjoy putting a
little bit of extra
detail here and there.
Bold lines, lots of black
shading, bright colors.
I really enjoy doing
bright colors.
I'm not a fan of it when people
say, oh, can you make
it look old.
I'm like, the brighter
the better.
STEFANO C.: She's a very
good illustrator.
She knows how to put it down.
She ended up with her drawing
skills to create what she got
at the moment, which is
something pretty unique.
VALERIE VARGAS: Could
you hold this?
Trying to close the
both and I can't.
OK, I'll close that one
if you hold this.
My name is Valerie Vargas, and
I tattoo at Frith Street.
It's a little tiny shop
in a basement in
the middle of Soho.
It's a really nice team
we have, I think.
We all really enjoy each
other's companies.
We're good friends.
And we all respect each
other's work.
DANTE DIMASSA: I want to say
we're a street shop.
This was the idea behind having
the shop the way it is.
But we're not a street shop.
We do a lot of big work.
We do a lot of custom stuff.
The majority of the
stuff is custom.
I can't remember the last time
we've tattooed something
straight out of a flashbook
or whatever.
I think we tend to more--
it's not our scene, but we
tend to a lot of the--
we tend to a lot of kids.
Yeah, show him your front.
Don't be gay.
It's the shop that people want
and come and get not
necessarily a particular tattoo,
but they get a tattoo
that's theirs.
How old were you when you came
and worked at the shop?
24?
25?
VALERIE VARGAS: No, no.
DANTE DIMASSA: Younger?
Older?
VALERIE VARGAS: Well, I've
been here five years in
August, so, 25?
26?
25, 26?
Yeah, you were only
but a young spring
chicken when I met you.
DANTE DIMASSA: Valerie kind of
came with Stewart, really.
The person who got the job
offer was Stewart.
I hadn't planned on giving
Valerie a job, but we knew
that she had a lot of promise.
I had always said to myself,
I wasn't gonna employ a
boyfriend-girlfriend scenario
here, but it seemed the
natural choice to get Valerie.
VALERIE VARGAS: We try and make
sure that the grievance
is dealt with before
we get to work.
Yeah, that's fucking rubbish
to work with, you know.
I mean that's probably the
reason why Danny almost didn't
give us a job together because
he had at one point.
Nobody can stand our company
by each other, so I think
that's the only reason
we work out.
I tattoo next to Stewart
Robson, of course.
Always.
We seem to be a bit of a
kind of double deal.
Like if you're gonna have me,
you're gonna have to have him,
and so forth.
And we really do enjoy talking
over work, and like if I'm
tattooing, he's tattooing, we'll
shout over at each other
or talk to each other's
customers, so.
I really enjoy working
next to him.
STEWART ROBSON: Sometimes she
gets a little annoying.
It's like having your own
conscience in front of you.
And you can't just ignore it.
It's there, going, come on,
you need to do this.
VALERIE VARGAS: Are you
doing any shading in
the curly bits, or?
STEWART ROBSON: I'm not sure.
VALERIE VARGAS: Like
as a black and gray
shading, or color, or?
STEWART ROBSON: There's some
sort of there, so I might just
leave that one.
VALERIE VARGAS: I think you
should a full Indian disco
ball cut-out.
I don't think she's
coming back after
this once you do it.
STEWART ROBSON: But I was
always impressed by her
drawing skills.
She's always so good
at drawing.
Particularly figurative stuff.
The shape of a female body,
and the way that all the
joints fit together.
It was impressive.
VALERIE VARGAS: All
right, here.
Just got one more rose to do.
And then we'll be done today.
DANTE DIMASSA: I don't wanna
say Valerie does our
traditional tattooing, because
it's far from being
traditional.
Nonetheless, the
idea, the way--
I suppose the execution
is very traditional.
VALERIE VARGAS: I think
you deserve a
pint of some chocolate.
DANTE DIMASSA: The designs that
Valerie does are still
rooted in with good, solid,
long-lasting tattooes.
She makes it work
very, very well.
She's just done a back piece,
a Rock of Ages back piece.
I really liked that tattoo.
I'd be proud to have that.
I like the lack of space,
do you know what I mean?
I like the lack of space.
When you look at it, it looks
like it's breathing at you.
I don't think she would want
to say, my style is
traditional, or my style is--
I think her style is a mix of
many styles put together.
Jack Rudy, Scott Sylvia,
Tim Lehi, Chris Conn.
She's taken everything
from those people and
made things her own.
VALERIE VARGAS: I started
tattooing right after Chris
Conn pretty much
quit tattooing.
I had seen a couple of his
tattoos in older magazines.
I didn't connect his name, so
I wasn't really aware that
this guy had been doing all
these paintings that I really
liked as well.
And then when it all clicked in
my head, I was like, oh, my
god, this is amazing,
you know.
And can I get tattooed by him?
Oh, no, I can't.
Never mind.
I collected quite a few
of these prints.
I've got the one that he
did for Revisited.
With all the girl
heads and stuff.
And I'm sure any tattooer worthy
soul has that somewhere
and references heavily.
And even though I've always
enjoyed doing girl heads, it
was that print that I really
got it drummed into my head
what makes a successful
tattooed lady head.
All the little tricks and
everything, and I just took
that and ran away with it, and
had my own style emerge.
I'd like to think anyway.
Ooh.
Voicemail.
Hello?
Hey, so what's going on?
Yeah.
Yep.
That's OK.
I can do that.
I honestly don't get tired
of doing girl heads.
People always ask me but--
I love it.
STEFANO C.: There was a time,
like a couple of years ago
that she was doing lots of
girls, doing everything.
Like doing like the hand holding
something, doing
something, lots of
face expressions.
VALERIE VARGAS: I did these
two on the back
of calves on a girl.
I didn't do this one.
She didn't like that one because
she thought it was too
much like this one, so I did
a different one, with more
jewelry and different hairstyle
and slightly
different facing.
Again, they're the
bane of my life.
I get so many people wanting
exactly those guys.
It's like, you can't have
exactly the same thing.
That's not how it works.
STEWART ROBSON: It's awesome
to see someone just grab a
style and wrestle with it and
twist it and turn it into
something else.
The thing that maybe sets her
apart from the Chris Conn
school of tattooing is
each one of the faces
she draws is different.
Because there's a different
mood, and she's really--
I think that came from her
animation schooling and her
love of animation.
She'll watch all Disney
animations endlessly.
She'll watch Robin Hood again
and I can't stand it.
VALERIE VARGAS: At art school,
I was studying animation.
And it was weird, because I
always felt like the art kid
and then I moved to Dundee to
study art, and then obviously,
you're not the art
kid anymore.
You're just one of
the art kids.
I wanted to do 2D.
I've always enjoyed drawing and
right at the time I was
learning and I was in that
course, 3D started.
Toy Story had just come out
like the year before,
and that was it.
That was the beginning
of the end.
And to actually use a computer
as your primary source of
creativity--
ugh, no, not for me.
I want to get stuck into
something and physically be in
charge of it and not having to
do it through another medium
which, again for me--
tattooing is just perfect.
You will sit here, and I will
cause you pain, and you will
pay me for it.
SPEAKER 1: OK.
And I'll be thankful for it.