John s a guy who goes and finds where it s
unevenly distributed, too. Tells the story.
Brings back empirical data about it, and tells
us what matters about it. I think he s really
important for this crowd because he s going
to tell us about the way our work needs to
change. Our work, anyone in an organization
who really wants to be relevant and perform
well. As you can see from the program, he
has quite a distinguished background. He s
held top positions, leading consultancies,
such as McKinsey and Boston Consulting Group,
and he s currently serving as a co-chair of
the Silicon Valley-based Deloitte LP Center
for the Edge, and he s doing a lot of original
research to develop new points of view on
corporate growth, but the latest of his books,
which is down here cause I just had him sign
it, co-authored with John Seely Brown and
Lang Davison, is The Power of Pull from which
he will be pulling some of his ideas for today.
So I think it s critical for us to listen
to him because he s going to tell us what
needs to change about how we need to work.
As mentors of your acts, you re already in
a potentially powerful position as being someone
who spends time with customers and spends
a lot of time looking at the behaviors they
have. There s an interesting stream of data
that you cross and pull into your own organizations
and see how the organization is actually doing
work to serve these customers. These are two
critical points of data, but I caution that
if we don t spend time listening and paying
attention to what John has to say, and the
realizations he has about the nature of how
our work should change, we could potentially
be marginalized and really left behind those
who are really performing well and better
than us in the UX business. So please listen
up, and I d love to invite John Hagel III
to the stage. John Hagel III: Hi. It s great
to be here this afternoon. I m particularly
privileged to speak a group that s at the
leading edge of experience design. It s somewhat
intimidating, though, because I confess I
come before you without any slides whatsoever
or any visual aids whatsoever so I am the
experience here. It s clear that I m not a
designer. I m a simple business guy. I think
I m what many of you refer to as the suits,
and I don t think you re referring to the
fine cut of our tailored suits when you use
that term. ll just start by saying that I
m in awe of what you ve accomplished over
the past decade. Moving the design mentality
mindset skill set from the design of products
and services to the design of experiences
of the users of those products and services
helps to more effectively pull out the real
potential value of the products and services
they re dealing with, but as impressive as
that is, I want to suggest that there s another
wave of opportunity ahead, and that is to
design experiences that help all of us to
pull out the full potential of ourselves,
and not just the products and services that
we use. What if we could apply the tools and
principles of experience design to help each
of us to more effectively drive more rapid
waves of learning and performance improvement
by working together? I want to illustrate
that opportunity by going back in time to
the beginning of my career. As Brandon mentioned,
I started a long time ago at Boston Consulting
Group. Boston Consulting Group is a strategy
consulting firm. They basically built their
reputation on one chart, one visual aid, and
it was called the Experience Curve. What the
Experience Curve did was describe how performance
improves, and it started by looking at the
semiconductor industry, and looked at operating
performance improvement in the semiconductor
industry over many, many years, and it had
a very distinctive pattern to it, and over
the years BCG applied this analysis to industry
after industry everything from Japanese beer
to toilet paper. All of it follows the experience
curve as a way of describing how performance
improves in markets and industries. So it
s a very accurate description of performance
improvement, but it has one distinctive characteristic,
which I think is important to highlight here,
which is it s a diminishing returns curve.
The more experience you accumulate in a marketer
industry, the longer and harder you have to
work to get the next increment of performance
improvement. It may help to explain why many
of us are feeling increasing stress in the
markets and industries that we operate in.
But what if there were an alternative? What
if we could turn the experience curve on its
side and generate increasing returns, rather
than diminishing returns? What if performance
improvement accelerated as the number of participants
expands? Now that would be powerful, but what
would it require? Well, I suggest it requires
a lot of things, and it starts with a major
shift in our beliefs and our practices. It
s a key dimension of what we ve described
in The Power of Pull as the big shift, and
as a result, I think it requires a shift in
design focus so let me amplify a bit on that,
and when I talk about shift in beliefs, I
m talking about a shift in our view of where
and how economic value gets created. The shorthand
way we have of capturing that is saying we
re moving from a world of stocks to a world
of flows. And what do I mean by that? Well,
I m referring in this case not to stocks that
are traded on the stock market, but knowledge
stocks, what we know at any point in time,
and it turns out if you ask any executive
and really probe as to their basic beliefs
of what s created economic value, the basic
assumption is, first of all, you have to acquire
some proprietary knowledge stocks, and then
you have to, aggressively as possible, protect
those knowledge stocks from anybody else getting
access to them, and then as efficiently as
possible, extract the value from those knowledge
stocks. Huge corporations were created in
the 20th Century around this set of beliefs.
Enormous wealth generated around this set
of beliefs. We make the case that, in fact,
we re shifting from a world of knowledge stocks
to a world of knowledge flows, and the reason
for that is, if you think about it, anything
you know today has more and more rapidly depreciating
value. What we know today has a very limited
shelf life. The shelf life is shrinking over
time, and the only way you can create economic
value in that kind of environment is to find
ways to more effectively participate in a
larger number of more diverse knowledge flows
so that you can refresh those knowledge stocks
at an accelerating rate. Fundamentally different
view of what s required to create economic
value. Now in this context I m actually very
intrigued. I ve just recently encountered
a set of design theories that are known as
constructal design theories generated by two
people: Adrian Bejan and Sylvie Laurent, and
what they ve done is they ve built a design
perspective based on what they call a constructal
law that they ve observed now in playing out
across physical environments, biological environments
and social systems. And essentially what the
constructal law says is that in order to survive,
systems have to evolve greater and greater
access to the currents that flow through them.
Whether we re talking about riverbeds, trees,
the design of our lungs or our cities, it
turns out they all obey this constructal law.
Systems that survive and thrive are those
that evolve most rapidly and effectively to
enhance those flows within those systems.
So I think two interesting implications from
this perspective: one is that the whole emphasis
on system design is on enhancing flows. That
really is the mark of a successful system
and experience within the system, and it s
also an emphasis on evolving systems, not
static systems because the emphasis here is
these systems are continually evolving, and
if they re not they re in trouble, and they
re continuing evolving along a certain pattern,
which is how do you more effectively generate
and support the flows within the system. So
what would it mean to design the systems we
live and work in to continually evolve our
ability to experience more and more flow,
especially the flow of people and of ideas?
So that s one shift: the shift in beliefs
from stocks to flows. There s a corollary
to this, which is a shift in practices. If
they were fundamentally changing in terms
of where the source of economic value is,
it stands to reason that the practices we
use to create economic value are going to
have to change in a significant way as well,
and the way we capture this is the notion
of moving from a world of push to a world
of pull. Again, if you go back in time to
the 20th Century, the large companies that
succeeded in the 20th Century were operating
on a push model. Basically said the key is
to forecast and predict demand, and then make
sure that all the right people and resources
are in the right place at the right time to
meet that demand. Again, huge multinational
corporations created with this push model,
enormous wealth created. On the other hand,
if we re living in a more uncertain and more
rapidly changing world, that kind of push
model becomes more and more challenging, more
and more problematic, and the questions is
then, well, what s the replacement? What s
the option? Well, we argue that it s all about
pull practices. Now many of you, when I say
pull, are going to have a certain mindset
or image of what I mean by pull. I want to
kind of expand that, hopefully. I think it
probably expands by talking about three levels
of pull that are becoming increasingly important.
There s one level, which is probably the most
obvious, which I call access. It s simply
the notion of how do I more effectively access
people and resources when I need them or where
I need them? It s basic search functionality
that Google offers. It s the shift from push-based
media to pull-based media so you can pull
the media you want, experience at any point
in time wherever you want it. Now that s a
powerful of pull, but it s just the first
level. I haven t even begun to tap into the
opportunity around pull, which comes starting
with the second level, which is the notion
of attraction. Here s the challenge: In a
world that s more rapidly changing, you don
t even know what to look for, what questions
to ask, what to search for. The only way you
re going to survive and thrive in that kind
of world is by attracting people and resources
to you that you never even knew existed, and
we ve all had the experience of serendipity
an unexpected encounter. You run into somebody.
You start up a conversation. Start talking
about some of the issues you re dealing with,
and my God, they offer some insight that you
d been struggling with for months. Enormously
valuable opportunities. Now when I talk about
serendipity, most people respond, Yeah, but
that s pure luck. Now there s nothing you
can do about serendipity. It just happens.
All you can do is be prepared for it when
it does happen. Well, in fact, we make a very
strong case that you can shape serendipity.
You can increase both the probability and
the quality of those unexpected encounters
by making choices about where you spend your
time and how you spend your time. Significant
potential to affect that serendipity, that
ability to pull that second level of pull,
but there s a third level that s even more
interesting, and this is the one I focus on
in the context of this discussion around design
challenges and opportunities. The third level
of pull is what I call achieve. It s the notion
of pulling out of each of us, and out of the
institutions we work in the full potential
that resides within us and within those institutions.
It gets to the notion of learning, more rapid
learning, more rapid performance improvement
by using those first two levels of pull and
adding some additional elements on top. That
s where the real power of pull comes in, is
if you can tap into that in a world of increasing
pressure, that s the opportunity to shift
from diminishing returns to increasing returns.
But the key question is how do you design
systems and experiences that provide us with
those scalable pull experiences? It s not
just with a few friends or coworkers, but
to really be successful we talk about the
notion of scalable pull. How do you do this
in a global basis where you can draw out people
and resources, not just in your local workplace,
but around the world, wherever they reside?
Now I confess I don t have the answers to
these questions that I m posing. I don t think
anyone does at this point. That s partly why
I think they re such interesting questions,
but I m hoping to intrigue and tease enough
of you that you ll start to come up with the
answers to the questions, and I don t have
the answers, but I think I can frame some
of the questions that need to be answered,
and in particular I want to focus on two dimensions
of the design challenge: one having to do
with platforms and the other having to do
with pathways, and I think they re both important.
In fact, one without the other becomes not
very interesting. s what are the platform
designs that would accelerate scalable peer-to-peer
learning? How would you think about a scalable
platform to do that? What are the design elements?
And then how can we design the pathways that
will help us get pragmatically from where
we are today, which is nowhere near scalable
pull platforms, to that big opportunity that
s out there? So let me just spend a minute
on the notion of platform designs. What would
platform designs have to do? We all know that
teams are incredibly rich environments for
accelerated peer-to-peer learning. If you
re a part of a high-performing team, you re
going to learn very rapidly and dramatically
improve your own performance in the process,
but there s a big challenge with teams. Teams
don t scale. As soon as teams get to a certain
size, they begin to disintegrate. They begin
to fall apart. So if you re looking for scalable
pull in the sense of more rapid performance
improvement and learning, teams alone are
not the answer. They re part of the solution,
but the question then becomes how do we embed
teams in increasingly rich platforms that
scale by encouraging the formation of even
more teams, and also connect with and learn
from each other across teams? That begins
to look like a scalable pull platform. Now,
as Brandon mentioned, I look for early instances
of some of these things in action, and so
I want to share a couple of examples of the
opportunity that s playing out in some domains
that are not very central to business, but
I think the opportunity is to learn from those
environments and apply design principles into
business. So one example of where some of
this scalable pull platform is emerging is
online in a video game that most of you, many
of you at least, may be familiar with called
World of Warcraft. It has 12 million participants
on a global scale 12 million and it s rapidly
growing, continuing to grow. Most of those
12 million participants are organized into
high-performing teams. If they re richly connected
across teams, they call them Gills. Through
rich networks of discussion forums, video
repositories, all kinds of resources that
can help the members of these teams learn,
not just within the team, but across teams,
very interesting network layered on top of
teams to make them even more successful. There
s another example that we ve spent a fair
amount of time with and we talk about in the
book, which is extreme sports. In particular
we ve spent a lot of time looking at big wave
surfing as an area of extreme performance
improvement, and it turns out big wave surfers,
by definition, are very much tied to local
physical environments. They re not on the
Internet playing games. They re on surf breaks
wrestling with very, very challenging waves
as they come. So they re deeply grounded in
their physical environment, but the scalability
of the learning comes from the opportunity
to layer on top of that physical experience
participation in virtual environments, and
again, learning from each other regardless
of where these surfers are located. South
African surfers communicating with Australian
surfers communicating with Hawaiian surfers,
all of them using the same kinds of facilities
discussion forums, video repositories. They
study videos of each other to learn the practices
that are emerging in different local areas,
and the social relationships that have emerged
around those exchanges of information. So
those are a couple of interesting examples
of the kinds of platforms that are emerging
that create scalable pull in the sense of
learning opportunities, more rapid learning,
more rapid performance improvement as more
participants join in. Really interesting opportunity
in a business context. I mentioned there was
a second design challenge, though, which is
not just the platforms. It has to do with
the pathways. Anybody who starts talking about
these kinds of scalable pull platforms in
front of an executive is going to get a bleary
look on the face and say, Well, wait a minute.
I m over here. You re talking about something
that s way out there. How they hell am I going
to get out there? So if you don t design a
pathway that helps people to move in a pragmatic
way from where they are today to where they
need to be, it s going to be a very short
conversation. So in that context I want to
tell a bit of a story around a company that
we found very interesting in the context of
pull. It s a company I think most of you are
probably familiar with. It s in the software
business and it s called SAP. SAP was at one
time a highly entrepreneurial company. The
founder of it, Hasso Plattner, amazing guy,
very curmudgeonly guy, very passionate about
the software technology and work that he did.
He became more and more concerned as his company
grew and scaled because, as it grew and scaled,
it started to take on more and more of the
kind of bureaucratic tradition-bound risk
averse, not invented here kinds of cultures
that many of us are familiar with in large
companies. So he said, ve got to change this.
And what he did was he went out and he bought
a company, and he bought the company not particularly
because the company was great, but because
he wanted the guy who was the founder of that
company. It was a guy by the name of Shai
Agassi. Not many of you may be familiar with
Shai. He made Shai a very senior executive
of SAP, but he said, m not going to put you
in charge of the core part of my business
because if I do they re going to kill you
over there, and you re a really nice guy.
I don t want to see you killed. So what I
m going to do is I m going to put you in charge
of a part of the business that s on the edge.
It s a new product that we re introducing
called NetWeaver. It s generating a very limited
amount of revenue and no profit so nobody
is going to pay attention to it over in the
core of the business. You ll have degrees
of freedom out there that you wouldn t have
if you were in the core, and he said, I want
you to use that platform as an opportunity
to redefine how we work together and how we
can get to more accelerated performance improvement.
What Shai did was he created a platform called
the SAP Developer Network, and initially it
was a very simple platform. It basically was
an environment you could come into, an online
environment, where if you were a developer
working on this NetWeaver product and running
into programming issues, as many people would,
you could pose the question and see if anybody
else had had an experience that was equivalent
could help you work your way through the problem
you were wrestling with. Really simple. Basically
a discussion forum, but incredibly powerful.
And it turns out now SAP Developer Network
has about two million software developers
actively participating on this network, and
again, it s growing at a very rapid rate.
It s scaling. And it has generated enormous
productivity on the part of these software
developers, and the initial focus of the platform
was actually software developers outside of
SAP. It was software developers in third-party
channels, software developers in the customers,
not the SAP developers because the SAP developers
had this mindset that how can you possibly
learn from anybody outside our company. You
know, we re an incredibly successful company.
Well, it turns out over time more and more
of the SAP developers have migrated out into
this developer network because word has spread
that it s an amazing productivity tool. You
can develop more rapidly, learn more quickly
as part of this network than you ever could
working on your own or working as part of
your local team. So very interesting progression
over time. I tell the story because I think
it illustrates a number of elements of pathways
that are going to be important to realizing
this opportunity to create scalable pull platforms.
One of the pathways is the notion of starting
with a very simple transaction in these environments.
There s often a temptation to go out with
very elaborate kind of learning environments
and performance improvement environments.
This was a simple question and answer discussion
forum: Pose the problem. See if anybody else
has an answer to it, and then move to using
that to build reputation and relationships.
What happened was that as people started answering
the problems, they developed a reputation.
They actually got points. SAP awarded them
points for each successful answer that was
delivered, and they built a reputation around
those points. Interesting sidelight, it turns
out that a lot of software recruiters had
figured out that if you re looking for a software
developer with real talent in certain areas,
go into the SAP Developer Network and look
at those reputation profiles, and you ll find
people who are really successful at answering
some really challenging problems. So it turns
out even though those people offering answers
were not getting any monetary reward directly
for their answers, they were getting some
more and more attractive job offers as a result
of having done that. More motivation to contribute
even more. And by the way, I should say at
this point the average time to answer a problem
that s provided on the SAP Developer Network
is about 17 minutes from the time it s posed
to the time the problem is resolved 17 minutes.
So it s a very, very successful platform in
that regard. But what s happened is then you
ve got a third level of progression and evolution,
which is the notion that over time, as a result
of this reputation and the relationships that
emerge, because people were seeking each other
out as they saw each other s reputation in
certain areas, teams stated to form and took
on more and more challenging application development
initiatives, not just solving a problem with
their current coding efforts, but actually
came together from around the world to develop
entirely new applications, again, based on
the reputation and relationships that they
had built as part of this environment. So
it s an interesting progression. It says start
with very simple kinds of transactions and
build on that over time so you get these relationships
emerging and more interesting learning environments
begin to surface over time. There s a second
dimension to the pathway, which is that the
model that Shai used here, as an entrepreneur
in the software industry, he was a big proponent
of rapid iteration of software development,
and so the notion of deploying this network
in very short increments, getting it out there,
watching how people behaved on these networks
and what kinds of things were working, what
wasn t, and then doing another iteration based
on that was a very powerful way to learn from
the participants and not simply spend a ton
of money upfront trying to figure out what
they would need. So that s a second dimension.
A third dimension is this notion of starting
on the edge. You know, there s a big question
of how do you get change to happen. If we
re talking about scalable pull platforms with
large enterprises, that s really hard to accomplish
given the deeply held beliefs and practices
that drive the core. Most of the cores of
our companies are push-based cores, and so
the notion of not trying to change the core,
but going out to an interesting edge and driving
change from the edge, and by the way, not
bringing that edge back into the core. So
they would have killed the developer network
if they tried to bring it back into the core.
What they were doing was creating more and
more incentive and motivation to pull more
and more of the people in the core and resources
in the core out to the edge and scale the
edge even more rapidly around a very different
set of practices than had prevailed within
SAP at the time. There s another dimension
of the pathway which I think becomes extremely
important to drive the movement, and that
s the notion of performance metrics to measure
progress, and I think what s particularly
interesting about this opportunity for more
rapid performance improvement is it almost
by definition suggests a set of metrics to
say how are we doing. Is performance actually
improving as a result of participation on
these platforms? And what can we learn from
either the fact that it s improving very,
very rapidly or not improving as much as we
d like? How would we tweak it so that we can
actually get more rapid performance improvement?
So it involves really focusing on what are
people trying to get better at in these environments?
What is the performance improvement goal or
objective? And how would you measure progress
in the performance improvement? So at this
point it s not just the learning. You can
t measure learning directly, but you can measure
the outcome from the learning, which ought
to be performance improvement in whatever
domain. SAP was relentless in measuring this
notion of time from question posed to answer
received as a measure of performance improvement
within this network. And then, finally, there
s a fifth dimension of the pathway, which
is building passion, and I think if anybody
is trying to design an environment and set
of experiences to drive more rapid performance
improvement and more rapid learning, you ultimately
need to focus on how do you build, generate,
catalyze, nurture passion among the participants.
The key participants in the SAP Developer
Network are deeply passionate about the work
they re doing on that network. They re not
doing this just because there s monetary opportunity.
They are intrinsically engaged in what they
re doing, and having an impact with what they
re doing and having an impact with a broader
and broader range of people with what they
re doing. There is real passion. So if we
get it right I think there s really significant
opportunity, but I don t want to just position
this as an opportunity. I m going to suggest
that the reason I m optimistic this challenge
is going to be addressed is because it s an
imperative. It s not just an opportunity.
We re going to have to do this. It s not a
choice. It s not something that s nice to
have if we have some budget left over. It
s essential to succeed in an increasingly
competitive business world. Why do I say that?
Well, one of the things that we talk about
in our research for The Power of Pull is we
asked a fairly simple question, which we thought
had been certainly asked and probably answered,
which was just a question of how are we doing
as companies. How are companies doing? Not
just in the most recent quarter or the past
year, but over a long period of time. How
are companies doing? To our surprise, perhaps
not so much shouldn t have been a surprise
given the very short-term focus we increasingly
all have, that question, to our knowledge,
had never been asked, much less answered.
So what we ended up doing was looking at all
public companies in the United States, not
just a sample, but every single public company,
and we looked at it over a long period of
time. We went back to 1965 to today, and we
asked the question, how are they doing? Now
to measure performance, and this may be a
bit controversial, and we can certainly talk
about the pros and cons, we ended up focusing
on return on assets as our measure of performance.
It turns out if you look at return on assets
for all public companies in the U.S. since
1965 to today return on assets has collapsed.
It s collapsed by 75 percent over that time
period. It s a sustained erosion. There is
no sign of it leveling off. There s absolutely
no sign of it turning around. So I think it
suggests that the management practices and
the management institutions we have today
are fundamentally broken, and if we don t
crack this opportunity around more rapid performance
improvement and more rapid learning, these
companies are going to go out of business.
And when I go into corporate boardrooms these
days, I m struck by how often, how frequently
I hear the metaphor or the image of the Red
Queen from Alice in Wonderland. You know,
executives talk about feeling the Red Queen
Effect. And I actually push back on that and
I make the case that the Red Queen actually
had it pretty good. The Red Queen ran faster
and faster and she stayed in the same place.
We re running faster and faster and falling
farther and farther behind so I think the
Red Queen actually had it much better than
we do. So I don t think we have a choice about
this. I think this is becoming more and more
of an imperative. If we don t figure out how
to learn faster and how to accelerate performance
improvement, and how to go from that diminishing
returns environment to an increasing returns
environment we re going out of business. Return
on assets, by the way, if you just follow
the current trend line, which, again, has
been playing out for 40-plus years, reaches
zero somewhere around 2022 so that s not a
sustainable outcome. Something will change
over this next decade in order to address
that. So I want to end just by focusing on
the opportunity. Again, I don t want to end
on a negative note. I come from Silicon Valley.
We re inherent optimists. I mentioned earlier
that the opportunity here was this notion
of increasing returns; that you get better
faster as more and more participants join
in, and that s a real exciting and powerful
opportunity, but I think that s just the tip
of the iceberg. The one thing that strikes
me when I hear discussions of increasing return
is the classic example that people use to
illustrate increasing returns, is the fax
machine, and that s the notion if you have
one fax machine it actually has negative value.
You had to pay money to get it and you can
t do anything with it so it s actually a negative
value. As more fax machines get added in and
connect to each other, the value goes up over
time exponentially for all those fax machines.
But there s a really interesting element or
detail in that story or in that example, and
that is that as fax machines increase in numbers
they are not changing in terms of their basic
performance. It s simply a function of adding
and connecting more fax machines together,
and that is a powerful form of increasing
returns, but there s a second forum, which
is what if each of those fax machines were
getting better in terms of their performance
and functionality, their design, by participating
in this broader network. Then you get a second
increasing returns curve higher, steeper than
the previous one. So it s a very significant
opportunity. I think that those of you who
can take on this design challenge and can
crack the really difficult problems, I don
t want to in any way trivialize the challenges
to creating these pull platforms are going
to be on the edge of a whole new way of design
activity and practices. But one final thought
just to kind of put this into an even broader
context is that rather than focusing on sustainability
as a world, I think we should be taking on
an even greater challenge. It s something
that a friend of mine, Jean Russell, calls
thrivability rather than sustainability. Sustainability
has a notion of sustaining what we have. Thrivability
has a notion of how do we generate more and
more sustainable prosperity from the limited
natural resources that our planet has been
endowed with. So I don t think it s just our
business that depends on learning faster by
working together, but it s our planet. It
s our entire world. If we don t figure out
how to drive that kind of more rapid learning
and performance improvement, we re increasingly
challenged as a planet. We either have to
be satisfied with less and less or we have
to face the consequences of depleting resources
that are not replaceable. So I think we need
to design these new experiences for all of
us, not just for the companies that we re
in today. Thank you very much. Brandon Schauer:
So John has a little bit of time for some
Q&A, and I want to kind of kick it off. I
think one of the challenges for this group
is that we re poised between what we hear
from customers, what we see from customers.
They being somewhat our platform for learning,
as well as the organization, and the organization
representing much more of the core that we
re struggling with day in, day out. I think
I can see examples from our industry where
one organization is moving ahead of another
because of their ability to create a learning
platform with customers, as well as within
the organization. I heard a talk about a year
ago by one of the creative directors at Electronic
Arts. His story was of how they originally
started Madden football franchise interface
based on what TV looks like, but then they
tested it with customers and found out people
don t really like the way the television is
illustrating the experience of football for
people. The scores were too big; they took
up too much of the screen. You couldn t really
see the action, and so by passionately testing
and improving this interface, they were actually
starting to see that football was following
the way Electronic Arts was presenting football
through gaming because TV doesn t inter-test
necessarily or they don t do it in the same
way. So we can see how one organization starts
to build another or beat out another if this
case is TV versus gaming, but I guess my question
is, what have you found seem to be the linchpin
ideas or changes that an organization can
take on to start moving towards this platform?
One of them was going to the edge. Are there
others that we, as people who often are kind
of the middle of the organization, trying
to push things forward? Are there other tactics
we can start to employ? John Hagel III: Well,
it s a great question. I think that there
are many different approaches, and they hinge
on the particular environments. I would say
that one of the reasons I m optimistic is
I do think many companies, if not all, have
kind of made this transition from a very narrow
product-centric view of their offers to much
more of a sense that those products, if they
re going to be successful, have to be situated
within a context in the customer, and that
you have to really kind of cross the table
and understand what is the customer actually
trying to do with these products and services.
What are they trying to accomplish with them?
And so broadening your horizon to look at
the context, and I would say that if you ve
gone that far there s, I think, a logical
next step, which is for most situations customers
are trying to use these products to get better
at something else, something broader that
they re trying to do. What is that something
better and how can you create design experiences?
And I think one of things, at least from my
experience, is particularly important in this
context, and there is a barrier for many companies
to address this, but too often companies think
about the user experiences, the mantra of
one-to-one relationships, and increasingly
I think if you re really committed to helping
customers get better faster using the products
and services that have been provided to them,
and I hasten to add it s not just getting
better at using the product. It s getting
better at whatever task or work they re trying
to do where this product fits into that experience.
If you re really committed to doing that,
you re going to need to bring in other people,
other participants, at least other customers,
and potentially other companies to be more
helpful to those customers so that they can
get better faster using those products or
services. So, again, I think one of the hooks
here is this notion of there s been a trajectory
of progression. Understanding customer experiences
is broader than just the direct interaction
with the product, and then taking it to that
next step of saying what if, and I think often
I find the what if exercise is a pretty interesting
one to really put in tangible terms what would
the opportunity be? What if the customers
could take our products and services and get
better faster on a particular dimension? How
would that drive their continued purchase
of our own products or the pace of adoption
of our products? And, by the way, that was
one of the key metrics SAP used to measure
the progression here, was rate of customer
adoption. As they deployed this developer
network, one of their key objectives, clearly,
was to get more of the NetWeaver product into
the enterprise, and so that was a key measure
and it was something that spoke to the very
traditional core executive if you could communicate
in tangible terms that the pace of adoption
was going up, and show how the kind of interactions
that were occurring on this developer network
most likely contributed to that, you got the
attention of the core. That s something they
can relate to versus learning and relationships
and these more qualitative kinds of terms.
Brandon Schauer: One last thing before I turn
it on to the audience, why will push not work
in the new environment you see? John Hagel
III: s not to say it won t ever work. I think
at the end of the day if you really pushed
me on it I would say that everything we do
is some blend of push and pull technique so
it s not to say push will completely disappear,
but I do think that in a world that is increasingly
uncertain, and it s not just uncertain in
small ways. Many of you are familiar with
Taleb s Black Swan concept. I think one of
the interesting consequences of a more connected
world and a more competitive world, connection
and competition together actually produce
some very interesting results. One of them
is extreme events, cascades that go out of
control and go in ways we never would have
expected. Who would have expected Egypt, Tunisia
would be but that s becoming more and more
frequent. So it s not just the small unexpected,
We missed our forecast by 20 percent this
quarter. It s these eruptions, and if you
have those kinds of eruptions, and you don
t have access to pull platforms where you
can quickly adapt to those environments and
hopefully prosper in them, you re going to
be increasingly challenged so I think that
s a key reason. Brandon Schauer: All right.
Question from the audience? Audience Member::
You gave a framework access attraction achieve,
and I was a little bit vague about that, and
then you gave the example of the developer
network, but it resonated with me and I understood
it, and I wonder if you could just connect
that framework to that example so that I can
get those pieces. John Hagel III: Great question.
So access is simply one of the things they
had as part of the software developer network
was a lot of kind of frequently asked questions
repositories. So you could access, you had
a problem, you could go search through the
frequently asked questions and often get an
answer to your question. Second level of attract
is much more this question of, as these reputations
were being built on this network, people were
seeking out others in the network because
of that reputation, and the person being approached
had no idea that these other people existed,
much less that they had interests that were
kind of related to theirs and they started
getting into really interesting discussions
and building relationships around that. So
that was attraction. You re attracting people
that you never even knew existed as a result
of the reputations that were being built and
the problem solving that you were doing for
others. And then the third level is the notion
of achieve, pulling out our full potential,
learning faster. I think what s happened over
time is this environment has become an extraordinarily
rich learning environment. I mean the productivity
of the software developers has shot way up.
That s the motivation for more and more of
these developers to join this network is because
they know that anytime they run into a problem
they re going to get an answer pretty quickly,
and they ll just be able to learn not only
from the answer, but move faster in terms
of their coding and learn faster as a result
of that. They re learning faster because they
re connecting with each other and engaging
in really interesting discussions around broader
software development issues, and they re learning
faster because they re coming together in
teams and actually working together to develop
new software now in ways they never would
ve done in the past. So hopefully that helps
to clarify it a bit. Brandon Schauer: I think
I saw another hand. Could you step by the
mic over here? Audience Member: So great talk.
John Hagel III: Thank you. Audience Member:
And I have two questions: one is on a really
small scale. I m curious about where you see
anonymity fitting into the pull model, and
then the second question is do you have any
predictions and/or hopes for what you talked
about? John Hagel III: A lot of hopes. I have
very few predictions. Who is it that said,
s very hard to predict the future, especially
if it s in the future, or something like that?
In any event, I think that your first question
was around anonymity, and I ve been involved
in the online environment for a long time.
I actually wrote a book 15 years ago now I
think on virtual community; it s called Net
Gain, and over that time period this whole
question of anonymity versus identity has
really been a continuing discussion. I come
from the camp that both are going to be appropriate
and relevant at different points in time.
I do believe that over time there s more and
more value in persistent identity, being able
to what s the right word? Being able to build
a reputation that is sustainable. Now you
could do that with persistent anonymous identity,
an avatar, a made-up name. On the other hand
I also am a strong believer that at the end
of the day the people who are going to learn
fastest and improve performance most rapidly
are going to be those who find ways to connect
with each other, not just in virtual environments,
but in physical environments, and it s going
to be very hard to preserve anonymity if you
really believe you re going to end up having
to actually engage in a physical space with
these people. I mean you could do it. I m
not going to say it s impossible, but I do
think that that s more and more of an opportunity.
So no predictions. My hopes, you know, obviously
I do think if we are able to harness this
design challenge and create these environments
and experiences where people can learn faster,
I think it has many different effects. I mean
I haven t had a chance to really talk about,
for example, what s going on in Africa and
places like India using these kinds of environments
where these very remote villagers are learning
from each other across villages and into the
cities in ways that would have never been
possible before. I was at TED last week, and
one of the speakers gave an incredible discussion
of what s going on in the favelas in Brazil
in terms of connectivity, and actually there
s higher connectivity now in the favelas than
there is in the more affluent parts of Brazil,
and it s precisely because these people recognize
that by coming together and connecting they
re going to learn faster, and a huge motivation
to do that. So I m very hopeful that it will
both broaden the access and prosperity that
we ve achieved in certain parts of the globe,
and that ultimately it will help us to not
just respond to the increasing pressure and
stress that we re all feeling, but actually
help us to thrive and get to new levels of
rich experiences. So I m very hopeful at the
end of the day. Audience Member: Thanks for
the great talk. Most of your examples are
focused kind of within the organization. I
m wondering kind of within the enterprise
or kind of businesses connecting, perhaps,
to one another, how you see pull working between
businesses and their customers and how that
relationship has changed. John Hagel III:
Actually, the primary example I gave, SAP,
was actually with customers and with third-party
channels. That was the primary focus of the
SAP developer platform. It wasn t an internal
platform, and I actually believe, going back
to the question of how do you get change to
happen in large companies, it s easier to
change at the interface with the customer
than internally. We have such rigid policies,
procedures, processes within the company,
and customers, fortunately or unfortunately,
don t like rigid policies, procedures and
processes so if we re going to be successful
in engaging with them and building deeper
trust-based relationships with them, we re
going to have to figure this out, and so I
believe it s going to get figured out first
at the customer interface and then be brought
into other parts of the company, but that
is where the change will occur. And again,
part of it is just the incredibly increasing
competitive pressure we re all facing in terms
of how do we expand our relationships with
our customers and generate more revenue and
profitability from them, and that that s the
economic driver that s going to make this
work. Audience Member: So kind of going back
to the example that you were using at SAP,
you talked about the access kind of being
the initial sort of core, and then as people
participated and these reputations and so
forth, that it snowballed. So I have kind
of two questions around that: one is what
kind of greases that wheel because conceptually
it s easy to get your arms around, but until
you have the reputation how do you get the
people to come? Was there an actually promotion
around that? Like how did they get that going?
And the second is, in our litigious society
and how historically law has really been behind
technology, how do we navigate that with liability.
We re in the healthcare industry and so there
are a whole lot of issues around sharing and
learning and that kind of stuff. So I m interested
in your thoughts on that. John Hagel III:
Yes. It s a great question. I think that in
terms of how it gets going, again, it s hard
to generalize. In the SAP example it was this
simple process of they took some very narrowly-defined
areas of the NetWeaver platform and created
some discussion forums where people could
just come and ask a question, and so that
was the starting point. One of the issues
you face with these kinds of platforms is
the empty room problem. Right? You create
this discussion forum and you go in and ask
a question. It s an echo chamber. Nobody there
to answer, to talk with you about it. So you
got to be thoughtful, first of all, about
how you populate these arenas initially, potentially,
with some people within the company, but some
lead customers who you ve identified or engaged
with in other contexts; draw them in so that
they become part of the resource that can
be drawn upon. And I just want to broaden
it a bit in the sense that I can t resist
telling a story but one of the people we profiled
in the book, The Power of Pull, is a guy by
the name of Yossi Vardi. Some of you may know
he s a very successful Israeli entrepreneur.
He goes to conferences. I d say six days out
of seven he s at a conference somewhere in
the world. It s all over the world, but what
s really interesting about him is he never
goes into a conference, into a session. He
pays the money; he s there, but he never goes
into the session. He finds a sofa outside
the room and he just sits there, and as he
sees interesting people wondering through
the hall he kind of calls them over and says,
Who are you? Let s talk, and he strikes up
these conversations, and he s a master of
serendipity. s choices like that, I mean,
in terms of design that you, in fact, put
sofas out there, seats out there where people
can connect with each other and start talking,
start conversations. It s really basic things
like that. I just want to finish with a brief
story because it s such a great one on so
many levels. It s actually a guy here in San
Francisco, who many of you I m sure know,
Chris Anderson, who s the editor of Wired
magazine. On the side Chris has a startup
in, of all things, drone aircraft technology,
unmanned aircraft. It s been his passion all
his life, and he decided he was going to set
up this company, and as he set it up he got
more and more anxious because he has absolutely
no technology background himself, and so he
said, How can I do this startup without any
technologists? So he went out and back to
the levels of pull he started with the first
level. He went on a very systematic search.
He went out to all the logical suspects Carnegie
Mellon, MIT, Berkeley, Stanford, Caltech.
Searched ruthlessly through all the PhD programs
to see if he could find anybody who had the
profile of skills and experience that he was
looking for. Nobody. Nothing came up. He was
really frustrated. One day he was in a discussion
forum online discussing drone aircraft technology,
and he struck up a conversation with somebody
he had never encountered before, and the more
he got into the conversation, the more excited
he became. He said, This guy knows more about
drone aircraft technology than anybody I ve
ever met, and he finally asked the question.
He said, Where did you get your PhD from?
And there was kind of this awkward silence
on the other end of the discussion forum.
The guy evaded the question, and they went
on in the conversation and the more they talked
the more excited Christ became, and he ultimately
got enough trust with the guy to probe and
find out who and where he was. It turns out
he was at the time a 19-year-old high-school
graduate in Tijuana, Mexico. Who would have
thought to look among high-school graduates
in Tijuana, Mexico to find the CTO of your
tech startup? This guy, now 23, is the CTO
of Chris startup; has moved to the United
States. But I think it s a great example of
serendipity in action. You often don t know
where to look for the people who are going
to be most valuable to you, and if you don
t participate in environments that help you
to have those unexpected encounters, you re
going to be increasingly challenged. Thank
you. [End of Audio] [Vimeo-210831897] Keynote_John
Hagel III_MX 2011 Page PAGE of NUMPAGES www.verbalink.com
Page PAGE of NUMPAGES hC`p [Content_Types].xml
u$Nw @8Jb _rels/.rels theme/theme/themeManager.xml
sQ}# theme/theme/theme1.xml G$$DA :$BR si-@R
r,[L bX*x KfN1 ,tV@ .EML M .c =<R8 (F{\ O/<o[
62Hp !Uq7 GvxY @JyBw>6K 0i1; P0!Y ?sE/ ?J&l
p)af theme/theme/_rels/themeManager.xml.rels
6?$Q K(M&$R(.1 [Content_Types].xmlPK _rels/.relsPK
theme/theme/themeManager.xmlPK theme/theme/theme1.xmlPK
theme/theme/_rels/themeManager.xml.relsPK
<a:clrMap xmlns:a="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/drawingml/2006/main"
bg1="lt1" tx1="dk1" bg2="lt2" tx2="dk2" accent1="accent1"
accent2="accent2" accent3="accent3" accent4="accent4"
accent5="accent5" accent6="accent6" hlink="hlink"
folHlink="folHlink"/> "^('E2 BoP.E2 Keynote_John
Hagel III_MX 2011 Verbal Ink Normal.dotm Chelsa
Robinson Microsoft Macintosh Word Verbal Ink
Keynote_John Hagel III_MX 2011 Title Microsoft
Word 97-2004 Document NB6W Word.Document.8