To go feel which one is closest. Some do, I don't doubt that.
There are many religious people that go to different Churches and stop at the one nearest to their values.
That's what all people do. And if they all pick primitive things, your culture needs an overhaul.
If we still go to war, you know. I think in the motion picture "Things to come" - somebody said to Dr. Cabal
or the guy in charge that they're at war - "Still at it, eh?"
See, there were some comments which normal people did not react to in the film, at all.
They couldn't react to it. They have no background to react to it. They found a bunch of scientists running things
and it just didn't look right. They'd look like - the answer was H.G. Well's friend said "it sounds like fascism."
Now this system would sound like fascism. Cause Fresco lays out the schools, the buildings, the cities.
Only because not enough people are into that yet. But there will be more people laying it out as they get into it.
Edison taught people how to use the electric light. How to build generators. Or people that made generators
for Edison taught people to make generators.
But the average person did not get it up and say "I don't want any generators, they're not god-given."
There were some people that said that. They'd never use generators - they're out of business.
So - presenting idea's is not the answer. Preparing people's attitude to be able to hear new idea's -
so when they listen to you, they say "I don't know enough about the subject to make a decision; I think
I'll going back and read up on it, and come back next week. Very few people do that.
Sure, you'll find evidence among some academicians to support some of the concepts.
But not enough. I hate to use academicians, cause they climb up on the back of innovators.
But I do understand reliance on academicians to help support the project. But that isn't real.
I think people had to learn from the Wright Brothers - "How to build airplanes."
If they built the first flying machine, the army said - the army was the first to order 5 airplanes from
the Wright Brothers for surveillance. They attempted - "War tank is better for shooting", airplanes could only
carry a rifle. Before that, they threw bottles, and stones at one another in the air. Did you know that?
In the old days? Cause the airplane couldn't carry a cannon, it could only carry a rifle.
The guy would stand up from cover, and try to shoot the other plane down. And then they had a gun way above the
wing, so that it would clear the propeller. Then somebody invented a synchronous machine gun that
shoots between the rotation of the blades. Did you know what I'm talking about? You don't?
There's a bump on the camshaft. You know what that means? The camshaft turns the propellor -
and that bump operates the machine gun [imitates machine gun] between where the blade is.
Otherwise, they shot off the propeller. Do you understand that? So, its the invention of the machine gun
at the pilots eye view that enabled him to shoot down more planes. When the guns are on top, its only
an approximation. Do you understand? They're on the top wing, above the height of the propeller, or out
on the wings, which didn't give you a good view.
So, invention compensates for human insufficiency.
But we have a lot of inventors making things that are useless too.
A house should be a public library, a school, intercommunications systems, not just a home;
with a laptop, the house is becoming more than just a place to sleep and eat. In the future, it'll be
a place with your built-in gym, and everything else, if you can afford it. Or, if the society can make a house -
the better-integrated people aren't interconnected to a richer society.
People say "Will everybody be uniform?"
If they were technically uniform it would be useful; non-technically it would not be useful.
There's nothing the matter with uniformity. All architects, and all engineers have to pass a standard exam
which is okay, for competence, you know. But if you know of technicians that advocate aspects of
The Venus Project, great. Technicians eventually will do that. But remember - they bring with them some
of the primordial slime. Cause they don't come from an environment that's objective, or scientific, yet.
A scientific world is in the early phases of the scientific method. Academia is not The Venus Project.
Nor is it science - as its used today. They wouldn't work on bombers if they were part of The Venus Project.
They wouldn't work on weapons. They wouldn't be patriotic if there was such a thing as a science.
I'm sure there are, I'm sure they're having a tough time, too.
I'm sure there's some scientist must come to some conclusion similar, but not all join together.
Its very rare for someone to have the identical environment I had. Very rare. No, they don't come to
the same conclusion. Most scientists believe in free will.
I asked them. Don't forget, I've met a lot of scientists. "Do you believe in free will?" - "Of course.
I scored high in my school." - That means something else, it means that they have a different environment.
But they don't look at it objectively. They feel they're achievers if they get a Nobel Prize.
They feel good about it, rather than share it with other labs. You know.
They don't have a scientific attitude yet. It isn't here yet.
And if somebody advocates it, then you build a following.
And a following does not give an interpretation of Darwin's theory of evolution. There are people that
do that too - say "there's no evidence." If there's lots of evidence, they don't know what evidence means.
If the evidence is that the trees of a million years ago are different than the trees today. They evolve;
they change. Not necessarily for the better. There were poisonous snakes during the time of dinosaurs.
I'm sure they were different than the snakes of today.
But all animals seem to undergo change according to digging into the ground.
I don't think people will study too much of the past, except that nations, took over other nations, took
their wares, but no species by Patrick Henry, or anybody else. Cause they couldn't say anything relevant.
I don't listen to most political speeches. Cause they don't say anything. They rarely say "we can improve
automotive production by sharing idea's with different companies." They don't say that.
I don't find enough evidence to identify with peer groups. Do you know what I mean?
I'm not saying they don't exist. I'm sure there are people out there in the scientific world that would
jump onto this. But some scientists may say "Have you heard about The Venus Project?" - "Oh, that guy
is self-made. Never heard of him making any contributions."
You know. They might do that. I don't know what they do. But, I can't concern myself with what they do.
So here I'm proposing something. I wish that a lot of doctors at the same time said "Wash your hands."
It was only one guy. And they say "What's your basis for that?" They didn't all have microscopes in the old days.
So he showed them germs on the skin. That was when the real change came. With the microscope.
But, there were people that even said "Well, how do you know they cause disease?" They were always present
when a person had eruptions on the skin. That type of bacteria. When they had visual problems,
they found the bacteria that was responsible. They always found similar bacteria on the eyes, on the hands,
on the genitals, sexually transmitted bacteria were the same. Do you understand what I mean.
But it wasn't until the microscope that uniform agreement can be established. It could not be established
by debate. No matter how - unless the doctor was very important. Most doctors listen to the established
leader of a system. We have no established leaders.
All I'd like to do is get the ball rolling, take it from there. But before I get the ball rolling, I want to get
the idea's out on education, on learning theory, on how the brain is influenced by environment.
If I can get that out, that's a good safety measure to control values, more so.
I'd like to get "I don't know" out there too, more so.
"I don't know." "I don't know enough about it to make a decision."
www.thevenusproject.com
Subscribe - Like - Friend - Fav - Thanks!