CARL AZUZ, CNN ANCHOR: A warm welcome on this
Thursday, March 7, especially for anyone who`s
dealing with this frosty reception. A winter
storm? Yes, another one hammered parts of
the Midwestern and Northeastern United States
this week. Power outages, schools and businesses
closed, flights canceled. Chicago had a record
one-day snowfall on Tuesday. CNN`s Ted Rowlands
was there.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
TED ROWLANDS, CNN CORRESPONDENT: And this
is not only in Chicago. Of course, it`s hitting
the Midwest, Minneapolis, North Dakota, getting
in excess of a foot of snow, and the system
is heading east.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: We`ve gotten our yardstick
out, and at least where I am, I`ve measured
from place to place where it looked like the
snow was untouched, about six inches of snow
so far. Right here in downtown Winchester,
although that`s by no means a scientific reading.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Many airlines canceled.
A number of flights, hundreds, in facts, and
where I`m at Dulles is a big hub for United
Airlines as is Chicago`s O`Hare airports.
So, United is taking a big hit. They canceled
about 700 flights.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: The highest waves during
Sandy were maybe 40 miles an hour, but this
time we are talking about 12 to 15 foot seas.
Now, you can see the damage that is still
pretty clear about what happened during Hurricane
Sandy. Look, so many houses still have been
destroyed or are heavily damaged.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Is this legit? Members
of OPEC, the Organization of Petroleum Exporting
Countries, are all Middle Eastern nations.
Not true. OPEC includes countries from Africa
and South America, too.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Like Venezuela, a country of more than
28 million people that`s in the northern part
of South America. Oil is huge part of Venezuela`s
economy. It`s one of the biggest industries
in the country, that`s responsible for roughly
95 percent of all the money that Venezuela
earns by selling products to other nations.
Venezuela`s in the middle of seven days of
mourning. The country`s long time leader,
Hugo Chavez, died this week. His casket was
moved to a military academy yesterday. That`s
where his state funeral is scheduled to happen
tomorrow. Venezuela will set a date to elect
a new leader in the next 30 days. During this
time, as President Hugo Chavez`s supporters
argue that he gave Venezuelans the sense of
national pride. His critics argue that Chavez
ruined this country`s economy and restricted
people`s liberties. Controversy plays a large
role in Chavez`s legacy.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
HUGO CHAVEZ: Victoria! Victoria!
AZUZ: He relished being at the center of controversy.
So, it`s no wonder his friends and foes had
very different takes on the Chavez legacy.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: He`s made Venezuelans
feel proud to be Venezuelan again. And not
as something, I think that really no other
leader has ever done in that country before.
In fact, they were doing the opposite.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: He`s destroyed the economy
and centralized all power in his hands, decimated
the democratic institutions in the country
and left Venezuelan democracy in even worse
shape. So it`s a pretty negative legacy.
AZUZ: Chavez`s rhetoric often aimed at the
United States or at multinational corporations.
It invoked the promise of a socialist utopia,
but Hugo Chavez had what most other Latin
American leftists did not - oil. Venezuela
has the largest oil reserves in the world,
along with Saudi Arabia. That oil wealth enabled
Chavez to offer up free education and healthcare
in his own country. The price of his socialist
agenda - Hugo Chavez himself, presidential
term limits were abolished. Even his critics
admit, he could have gone on winning elections
indefinitely. His biggest failure maybe his
success, a legacy of one. Friends and foes,
the Chavez legacy is filled with both.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: See if you can I.D. me.
I`m a type of vehicle that`s been around for
more than 100 years. My name comes from a
Latin word that refers to a combination of
things. In my case, that`s internal combustion
engine and an electric motor. I`m a hybrid.
A vehicle that runs on fuel and electricity.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Volkswagen is coming out with a new
hybrid car that the company claims would get
the equivalent of 261 miles per gallon. Considering
that the standard Toyota Prius gets around
50, this is significant. But this doesn`t
mean that the XL 1, as it`s being called,
will get you across the country without stopping.
Between battery and diesel power, VW says,
it will go about 310 miles total, which is
about 90 miles less than your average sedan
on a full tank of gas. But the XL 1`s engine
only needs about 2.6 gallons of diesel to
fill it. So, a fill-up at today`s prices would
cost about 11 bucks. It`s incredibly aerodynamic,
significantly more so than a Chevy Corvette,
for example, and it certainly looks futuristic.
But it`s not fast. It will take over 12 seconds
to get you from zero to 60. Its top speed
will be about 100 miles per hour, though,
of course, none of us would ever drive that
fast. It`s also not expected to be cheap,
and it may not even be available in the U.S.
But Europeans, who want fuel mileage bragging
rights and can still afford the car, may have
something to brag about.
One week ago, we told you about Jhaquiel Reagan.
While he was walking to a job interview, he
made an impression on a local restaurant owner
and got a job there. It is a great story about
one person`s work ethic, but it`s not the
end of the story, and it`s not the end of
Jhaquiel`s impressive display of character.
WXIN`s Kent Erdahl picks up the story.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
KENT ERDAHL, WXIN CORRESPONDENT: Jhaquiel
Reagan has met a lot of people since setting
off on a ten-mile to a job interview days
ago, an interview that he wouldn`t even end
up needing after meeting the owner of Papa
Ru on his way.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: I`m thinking to myself,
here`s a kid walking almost ten miles in ice
and slush and snow for the hope of a job at
minimum wage, just like the kind of story
your parent used to tell - my parents used
to tell - uphill both ways in the snow.
ERDAHL: Jhaquiel`s stories also now stuff
of legend - he`s been immortalized in his
own editorial cartoon and seen his picture
pop up on stories he can begin to translate.
JHAQUIEL REAGAN: People all over the globe
see me. It`s really crazy.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: The story, as one of my
customers put it, is redefining viral.
ERDAHL: That`s because it`s generated more
than just likes on Facebook. It`s created
a new life for Jhaquiel.
REAGAN: It really has changed quick. Like
I went from sleeping on the couch to sleeping
in my own house - in my own apartment.
ERDAHL: You see, before meeting his new landlord,
Jhaquiel was homeless and living with friends.
He also didn`t have a phone.
REAGAN: I was trying to get a hold of you
last night.
ERDAHL: Now, he is taking calls from the Chicago
Bulls organization. They contacted him after
seeing a certain hat on TV.
REAGAN: They gave me some tickets to the Bulls.
I was really impressed. It`s awesome.
ERDAHL: As we showed you last week, Jhaquiel
also received a free bus pass, though he hasn`t
had to use it much after meeting plenty of
coworkers who have offered to give him rights.
REAGAN: I really appreciated. Really grateful.
ERDAHL: Jhaquiel`s story didn`t just give
him a job. In fact, they`ve gotten so much
good publicity here at Papa Ru, that they`ve
actually had to hire additional stuff to keep
up with all the extra demand.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: We`ve got five new permanent
hires.
ERDAHL: Some of them spend time answering
phones.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: My cashiers have turned
into receptionists.
ERDAHL: Fielding dozens of donation requests
for Jhaquiel.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Each slip is an individual
contact of a person with a name and a number,
and they want to help financially, each of
these slips.
EDRAHL: In fact, so many donations have come
in that Jhaquiel decided to create his own
foundation, saying half the money will go
to help disadvantage people find work. The
other half will go to him, but he`ll be sharing
it with the most important people he`s met
in the past days.
REAGAN: 25 percent of my half is going to
Papa Ru employees. Because they have been
working their fingers to the bone while all
of this has been going on. The restaurant
has been more busy than it has ever been.
And, you know, they really deserve it, you
know.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: Are teenagers getting tired of Facebook?
Just about everyone who tweeted me about this,
said yes. A couple of new reports say Facebook`s
younger users might be leaving for other sites
and apps like Twitter, Snapchat and Instagram.
Facebook still gained millions of users last
year, and the company owns Instagram, but
many teenagers are turned off by the number
of parents on Facebook and privacy factors
in it, too. Graham said on our Facebook page,
he is posting less because he worries about
colleges or potential employers seeing it.
Students on Facebook can talk to us there.
Teachers, you can talk to us at cnnstudentnews.com.
Please let us know your thoughts on today`s
show.
Something you may not know about me. I can
juggle - not well. So already I thought this
Youtube video was impressive. But watch this
guy`s left hand and listen closely.
You noticed what`s going on there? Every time
he catches the cube, he is moving its pieces.
The only way I ever solved a Rubik`s cube
was by taking the stickers off and moving
them around. This guy is doing it one-handed
while he juggles. Show off. We`d suggest like
a mic drop, but it doesn`t look he ever drops
anything. We are going to grade that performance,
but we didn`t have a good Rubik for it. He
posted that video right before Valentine`s
day. You might think that`s puzzling, but
it was just in time for Cupid, and if he ever
takes his show on the road, I just hope he
stays safe, because it can be a real juggle
out there. I`m Carl Azuz, enjoy the rest of
your day.