He likes to party down.
Frankie.
[INAUDIBLE].
[SPEAKING]
Clean.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN): Frank,
how come you're like
last man standing,
first one up?
-[INAUDIBLE]
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
He never went to sleep.
It's just that easy.
[LAUGHTER]
-Ah.
[SHRILL SCREAM]
-I didn't [INAUDIBLE] the
whole thing, man.
-Hey, no dice?
-I don't like this hat.
-You don't like this?
Not feeling it?
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN): If
you guys could do a trade,
like a Girl rider for
an Anti-Hero rider,
who would you trade?
-Ooh.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Definitely trade Mikey for
somebody.
-OK, we're definitely
giving Alex up.
It's going to be a tie between
Frank and Robbie.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
I'll take Robbie.
He's got more time.
-Get rid of the Porkchop
and take--
we got Spike, man.
-All right.
-Trade?
Malto, he's got more
life on him.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
For who?
Who you going to get rid of?
-We've given all but me.
I'll trade me for Malto.
-Myself for Robbie.
-I trade myself for Malta.
-So that means you're basically
trading the whole
team.
-You're putting yourself
on Girl.
-Yeah.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
I already tried that.
[INAUDIBLE]
-I'd trade Mike for Julien.
MIKE (OFFSCREEN): You can't
trade me because I already
traded you.
All right?
ALEX (OFFSCREEN): --same
company maybe.
-I traded your ass.
I guess me and Alex are
back on the same team.
That sucks.
-We'll take Johnzo for Spike.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Hey, you guys.
[CHEERS]
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN): Yours
is a little different
than what I've asked everyone
else, but if you could trade
one skater from Real for
a skater from Girl,
who would you trade?
-I don't [INAUDIBLE]
Carol, and they can
have Bujnits.
-Colin for Bob.
-Alex for Julien.
Get the real deal.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN): Can I
ask you a serious question?
-Serious question?
Is this the time or
the place for it?
OK, what?
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN): If
you could trade one skater
from Anti-Hero for a
skater from Girl,
who would you trade?
-All right, let's--
shit.
It's like a chess match.
So you want to take an equally
strong piece, if you know
you're going to lose one.
I don't have an answer for
that, honestly, dude.
The mixture of people here
is like-- there's nothing
interchangeable about anyone.
Sorry, no answer.
-I wouldn't trade
anybody, dude.
And if you say I have to,
I'll just quit skating.
-OK, wait, fuck that PC
answer last time.
We'll go Andy Roy
for Sean Sheppi.
Tomorrow.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
O'Dell, you're entered, 5150.
Here's your number.
Oh, wait, you're 88, sorry.
Whoa, mistake here.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN): Did
our team captain sign us up?
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Yeah, you guys
are all signed up.
Where do we got you, Spike?
Oh, we got your number
right here.
Man, we didn't put too much
thought into these, so it's
nothing personal if you're
offended or something.
-Sweet.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
There you go.
-[INAUDIBLE] appropriate.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
All right.
Julian hooked up a race.
Time trials.
-I already ate shit a
couple times because
I'm not that good.
I'm in the race, and I think
it's going to be a pretty
sorry performance,
but I'm psyched.
I'm glad to be included.
[INAUDIBLE] race is
about to start.
Julien's announcing.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN): One
lap to pick up speed, and then
your second lap is
the timed one.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Does that [INAUDIBLE]?
[SCREAMS]
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN): Ooh!
What number are you?
-1999.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
[INAUDIBLE]
France?
-I don't know if that means
I'm party boy or
skater of the year.
I don't remember what
year I got it.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
I got 88.
I think it's Heil Hitler, is
where the line comes from.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN): One of
my favorite things probably
was being totally surprised when
we went to do the time
trials, and we pulled up
at the skate park.
Nobody said anything.
We didn't know, and
we just got out.
And, well, Julien and whoever
else helped him [INAUDIBLE],
thankfully, had all the numbers
for all of us to be
pinned on our backs, and we
had that little race.
And it felt like we
were BMXing or
doing something different.
You know what I mean?
It didn't feel jokey or weird.
It was like, dang, this
is really fun.
Why would we not do this?
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN): Wow.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
[INAUDIBLE] try to follow
[INAUDIBLE]?
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Yeah.
Where's the starting line?
-[INAUDIBLE]
That's the starting point, and
the time's on the second lap.
[CHEERS]
-After you.
Go.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
[INAUDIBLE], go.
[INAUDIBLE], have you guys
raced here before?
-We did last summer.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
All right.
-It was such a weird
little park, and we
just started racing.
Seemed like the best
use to put it to.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Yeah.
It's amazing.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Hawthorne.
Yeah, we're just going to do
best time out of three runs.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Having some fun?
Yeah.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Just rank it from there.
All right, six six, six,
on the course.
8.65.
Next up.
-[INAUDIBLE]
my imagination because
he's short, but I
think he's the fastest.
-8.69.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Yeah.
-It's neck and neck.
Tony, Robbie, it's going
to be an intense final.
-[INAUDIBLE], too.
-Is he?
-Yeah.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Alex, who do
you think's got it?
-[INAUDIBLE], for sure.
[INAUDIBLE]
like, the person to
beat is Trajio.
If you can beat him,
you're good.
So that's who I was going for.
He won, though.
[CHEERS]
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
-That's it for the first annual
official Northwest Time
Trial Class.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN): First,
second, third place.
-Six, six, six.
-Epic time trial.
Here you go.
This is for participating.
Second place, Alex Olson.
Third place, Robbie Russo.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Robbie!
-A water.
Where's the midget at?
-[INAUDIBLE]
-Huh?
[LAUGHTER]
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
That's not good.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN): Yeah,
it's really good, man.
It's a good bump.
There's like a marsh
in the background.
My collar's all mellow.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
You like this spot?
-Yeah, it's pretty cool.
I ain't got shit
on it, though.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
[INAUDIBLE], Brian?
[CHEERS]
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
There's a bunch of that
footage you don't even see
of everyone slowly
starting to skate it.
It was a rad session before
even the cameras came out.
[CHEERS]
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
[INAUDIBLE], Get a
[INAUDIBLE], Frank.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Yeah, Frankie!
-What we're doing here is
called street style.
Any kid can pick it up.