SUROOSH ALVI: The next morning,
we joined the police
on a raid of Orangi Town, an
area reported to be a popular
hideout for the Taliban.
As Americans have escalated
drone attacks in the tribal
areas, the Taliban
have increasingly
moved to the cities.
And Karachi, with its huge
Afghan refugee population, is
the perfect place to blend in.
CHAUDRY ASLAM: [SPEAKING URDU]
SUROOSH ALVI: Now, I'll admit
that I don't know a lot about
police tactics, but I couldn't
help but notice that this
operation lacked the element
of surprise.
You've got hundreds of police
officers with sirens blaring,
and again, every television
crew in town.
None of the cops seemed too
worried about walking into a
potential showdown with some
of America's most wanted.
It wasn't quite the crack team
we were expecting to be
conducting this kind
of operation.
Deputy Tariq Malik was
designated as our official
tour guide for the operation.
TARIQ MALIK: [SPEAKING URDU]
SUROOSH ALVI: So I feel like I'm
on the set of a cop movie
right now, the kind of buffoon
cops that nobody
wants to work with.
They get the shitty
assignment.
So we headed it into the back
alleys of Orangi Town to find
some Taliban, Sunni extremists,
or any other kind
of bad guy that was still dumb
enough to be there after 300
members of Karachi's finest
came rolling through.
So this is predominantly an
Afghani and Mehsud tribe
neighborhood.
Here is a 4.5 million person
slum that you can't control.
So when the Taliban want to
hide-- when things are going
too hot in the tribal areas-
they'll come to a place like
this and blend right in and
no one knows they're here.
Jihadis--
that's what they're
hunting for--
the new gang in town.
Our friend, Deputy Malik, seemed
more interested in
texting than catching Taliban.
Do you think anyone
will shoot at us?
TARIQ MALIK: Eh?
SUROOSH ALVI: Will anyone
shoot at us?
TARIQ MALIK: Yeah.
SUROOSH ALVI: Will they shoot?
[INAUDIBLE].
SUROOSH ALVI: OK.
SUROOSH ALVI: We'll fight back.
OK.
You'll protect Jason?
TARIQ MALIK: Yeah, yeah,
SUROOSH ALVI: OK, good.
I'm responsible for him.
TARIQ MALIK: Yeah,
[INAUDIBLE].
We are responsible.
SUROOSH ALVI: The cops stopped
and searched the first vaguely
religious looking guy they saw,
only to come up empty.
So we continued on.
We're going house
by house now.
MALE SPEAKER: This guy
in the white has his
finger on the trigger.
SUROOSH ALVI: Yeah, I know.
I know.
He actually seems serious about
this whole thing, which
makes me think that they might
actually pull some criminals
out of this.
They can't not with
all this weeding.
But then I started thinking,
what if we do run into some
hardcore Taliban and
shit hits the fan?
How am I going to explain
this to Jason's mom?
I'm sorry, Mrs. Movica, but your
son, he was shot while
embedded with the Karachi
police force.
He was hunting down
Sunni extremists.
Just another day
at the office.
I was beginning to
figure out Deputy
Malik's policing strategy--
no camera left behind.
SUROOSH ALVI: I mean,
this is a pure show.
This is pure media cop show for
all the networks tonight.
When I go on these shoots,
I don't want to end up
surrounded by guns,
it just happens.
Why are there so many
dudes with guns in
everything we film?
How do you know when you
find the Taliban?
SUROOSH ALVI: Right.
And what are you looking
for right now?
Those specific Taliban
members?
SUROOSH ALVI: Killers.
You're looking for
the killers.
SUROOSH ALVI: And then
what are you going
to do with the killers?
SUROOSH ALVI: When you
find them, you're
going to arrest them?
SUROOSH ALVI: Of
the kidnappers.
We continued waltzing through
Orangi Town, looking for
"killer type peoples." And
then they found him--
straight out of Central Casting,
a proper suspected
Taliban member, turban
and all.
SUROOSH ALVI: Deputy Malik
was like a proud papa.
TARIQ MALIK: [SPEAKING URDU]
SUROOSH ALVI: The media were
happy, so the cops were happy,
and they called it a day with
one nine millimeter pistol and
a guy in a turban safely
off the streets.
SUROOSH ALVI: [SPEAKING URDU]
MALE SPEAKER: [SPEAKING URDU]
SUROOSH ALVI: Some guns that
they confiscated from the old
guy that looked like he might
have been in the Taliban.
I highly doubt he was
in the Taliban.
MALE SPEAKER: Did you see
how that happened?
SUROOSH ALVI: Yeah.
He was smiling.
He was smiling a bit.
MALE SPEAKER: That
was all set up?
SUROOSH ALVI: Yep.
MALE SPEAKER: All the kind of
mocking of the situation
aside, this is a really
dangerous neighborhood.
SUROOSH ALVI: Yeah, exactly.
Watching what was supposed to be
a sensitive anti-terrorist
operation get turned into a
media circus, I couldn't help
but think that it was no wonder
the US didn't want to
involve the Pakistanis in the
raid on Bin Laden's compound.
It would have been broadcast
on live television, and Bin
Laden would have vanished into
thin air, kind of like any
actual Taliban that may have
been in Orangi Town.
Ugh.
The gangsters, when they kidnap
people, this is where
they come and keep them, because
no one would come out
here to look for
them, because--
I mean, why would they?
It's brutal.
MALE SPEAKER: [SPEAKING URDU]