now charter schools are not private
schools are still publicly-funded
however they do not have uh... union
representation and uh... you know they
don't abide by the same rules that
certain public schools too
their companies like amazon and
microsoft that are really finding this
push for charter schools and a lot of
times when the media talks about this
they make it seem as though uh... you
know these corporations are doing it
because they're really want to case
reforming really care about the children
well-coached but is david sort of points
out perfectly of course it's all about
the money now cos like uh... amazon and
microsoft have tablets that they want to
sell to these school districts to these
charter schools of core
of course
all turns out they have a profit motive
why didn't see that coming huge profit
motive so
some might argue well cap public schools
signed contracts with these corporations
and you know do the same thing knelt
there are certain rules that prevent
public schools from signing contracts
with microsoft or amazon
but with charter schools as i've
mentioned they don't necessarily have to
abide by the same rules so these cup
corporations are hoping that they can
cash out big time by getting these
charter school society's contracts and
by the way some might argue well
technology is good it's gonna improve
the education of these young people but
not so fast studies indicate that a lot
of these charter schools on average do
not perform better than our public
schools to so that i was really
surprised but it's not always assume
that the charter schools we're gonna do
that honestly
uh... and parties is that we've been
competition and i believe that he in
diversity so
if you ever want to give a speech trying
different ways
i thought that
the cream would rise to the top and you
see what works and what does it and that
on average the charter schools would be
available schools dot was proven wrong
that's not what happened
but this story begins to explain
part of the reason why
because this is the reason why there is
some of the rooms not all the rules the
some of the rules of the public schools
now we take away those
rose what winds up having trouble
schools
well these for bridges come in they go
by this by that by this by that
forget the rules committee begin date
but it turns out the charter schools
wind up being totally inefficient
yes in fact the administrative costs
uh... are extremely high a relatively
speaking in charter schools
uh... so that's really a big problem in
david sort of points to that perfectly
but uh... of course i would berber doc
is also getting in on the action which i
thought was really interesting so let me
read you are a small part of davis read
this piece
he says the los angeles times reported
that music american eight donated a
quarter million dollars to the reform
slate
that's the same news america that is the
for-profit education technology arm of
rupert murdoch's newscorp it's the same
news america that was recently died
trumpeted by the new york times for
rolling out it's an expensive tablet
that will be targeted at middle school
children that is if the company can
convinced the school board candidates
that'd under rights to divert money away
from firing teachers and into the news
america's coffers
if you are well public corporations
unlimited rain in all of our affairs
will they do removed
who's the rules to their kind of like
this
they have to they their charter is make
every single red set you can
okay that is you only obligation
ecstasy showed us knew that he will be
removed
and they will have a new one
that's why we need the government to
look out for its citizens
to represent its citizens had to put a
check on corporations knowing that that
is the nature of corporations say hey
wait a minute up to protect the citizens
sewing at a balance here i think you
should have corporations but the way the
ballots but that balance has been taken
away because of corporations also
figured out hey you know i can make the
most money
right after the government
mhm iso
i think after the government you set up
a system
where the politicians absolutely depend
on you to get reelected
as we told you i believe yesterday on
the show
therebetween race in the senate
stat ten and a half million dollars
has an average guy in town
with democracy red than at any time at
the only way to invest in a race
is if you play ball with these guys
this is how you play ball and this is
how we destroyed our system of
government our schools and everything
else involved
so we gotta fix the system of hope is
worse for