ROCCO CASTORO: In Florida, I
can sell you a gun on the
street, and it's completely
legal.
How are you going to keep track
of all these guns that
people are just selling and
trading between themselves?
[GUN SHOT]
ROCCO CASTORO: Welcome to
Sarasota, Florida, home to
Siesta Key, the number
one beach in the
United States of America.
It's also home to more guns than
you can possibly imagine.
And we're going to go shoot
them, talk about their laws,
and get ready to blow the
shit out of everything.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
ROCCO CASTORO: Every year,
there are over 30,000 gun
deaths in the United States, a
country with 5% of the world's
population and 50%
of its guns.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
ROCCO CASTORO: The almost
unfathomable national tragedy
that happened on December 14
was the latest and most
horrific example in a string
of mass shootings that have
occurred in the United States
over the past 30 years.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
ROCCO CASTORO: And this time,
there will almost certainly be
a massive legislative shift
on the national level.
How wide-sweeping it will
be remains to be seen.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
ROCCO CASTORO: I was born
and raised in Florida.
And based on my years of
experience trolling around
with some of its most
interesting, valiant and
despicable residents, I can
assure you that many wholly
sensible and productive
Floridians of
all stripes own guns.
And yeah, a lot of scumbags
have them too.
One of the good guys is
Philadelphia native, Eddie
Cacciola, a 32-year-old
former Marine.
Eddie moved to Florida
five years ago.
Before that, he served as a
combat engineer during the
first wave of Operation
Iraqi Freedom.
EDDIE CACCIOLA: It
was pretty scary.
They were shooting Scud missiles
over our heads, just
lobbing them in our direction.
They were blowing up before.
They probably blew up more
of themselves than us.
ROCCO CASTORO: Following
President Obama's 2008 defeat
of Republican nominee, John
McCain, many firearms dealers
in Florida and throughout the
nation reported a massive
uptick in background checks for
concealed carry permits, a
clear indicator that gun sales
were spiking nationally.
The stockpiling also resulted
in an ammo shortage.
By February, 2009, the Orlando
Sentinel reported that 9mm,
.45 caliber, .38 caliber, and
.22 caliber bullets were
becoming scarce.
They also reported that local
Walmarts in Apopka and
Kissimmee had confirmed that
these types of ammo were on
back order.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
ROCCO CASTORO: We're outside
Survive Anything.
Inside, you will find everything
you need to survive
earthquakes, which, as far as I
know, have never happened in
Florida, zombies, which again,
as far as I know, have never
happened in reality, and
an assortment of other
apocalyptic scenarios that
you need to prepare for.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
EDDIE CACCIOLA: People
were more
concerned about the elections.
People were very concerned about
what Obama's going to
do, what Romney was going
to do, what they
had done in the past.
ROCCO CASTORO: A 2009 Gallup
poll reported that as many as
41% of Americans believe that
Obama would, quote, "attempt
to ban the sale of guns in the
United States while he's
president," as in all guns.
[VIDEO PLAYBACK]
-Preserve, protect and defend
the Constitution
of the United States.
-Preserve, protect and defend
the Constitution
of the United States.
-So help you God?
-So help me God.
-Congratulations,
Mr. President.
[CHEERS]
[APPLAUSE]
[END VIDEO PLAYBACK]
EDDIE CACCIOLA: The day after,
I went out just to see the
availability of stuff.
There was people in and out of
there with bags of anything
they could grab.
And then I stopped at a local
gun shop, The Bullet Hole.
And about every fifth person
that walked in there was
talking about how they're
coming to
take all of our guns.
MICHAEL CREA: I just think it's
a big election scare.
And it happens every
four years.
And people get worried about
what could happen.
ROCCO CASTORO: Takes a lot.
MICHAEL CREA: No problem.
ROCCO CASTORO: Have
a good day.
MICHAEL CREA: You too.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
ROCCO CASTORO: OK,
I think we should
probably get out of here.
[VOICE ON WALKIE TALKIE]
ROCCO CASTORO: Apparently,
Walmart gets freaked out when
you try to buy over 2,000 rounds
of ammo at one time.
So we went with the next best
and more expensive option,
visiting one Sarasota's
many gun stores.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
JOHN BUCHAN: It started
between a partnership.
We actually put a patent on a
100-round drum magazine to fit
a Glock pistol.
And we were marketing
gun shows.
These used to only fit dual-feed
AR-15s, AK-47s.
We converted it so it will fit
a Glock, changed some inside
parts, different housing.
The first part you're going to
see, it's in a chassis system
called a RONI.
ROCCO CASTORO: Well,
that's impressive.
JOHN BUCHAN: You'll see a
second fire sequence.
And that's just in the
Glock pistol alone.
Naturally, those are not
available to civilians.
ROCCO CASTORO: I
would imagine.
JOHN BUCHAN: I don't
sell them.
Can't sell them and won't
do anything with them.
ROCCO CASTORO: But you
have the patent.
JOHN BUCHAN: On the drum.
ROCCO CASTORO: On the drum.
ROCCO CASTORO: Have people been
buying more ammo or more
guns than normal?
JOHN BUCHAN: Oh, there's an
increase in sales in both.
ROCCO CASTORO: Yeah.
Yep.
And why do you think that is?
JOHN BUCHAN: Personal
protection, fear of, maybe, I
don't know, government
regulation, banning weapons,
banning certain types
of weapons, banning
ammunition, taxing it.
People are stockpiling it.
People are buying it.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
ROCCO CASTORO: Why would someone
buy that weapon?
JOHN BUCHAN: Long distance
shooting, competition.
It's just fun to shoot.
ROCCO CASTORO: How
far will that go?
JOHN BUCHAN: At a mile and a
half, a .50 round has got more
punch than a .44 Mag does six
inches from your chest.
ROCCO CASTORO: At a
mile and a half.
JOHN BUCHAN: In a
ROCCO CASTORO: Well, thanks
so much, John.
JOHN BUCHAN: Yeah.
No problem.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
ROCCO CASTORO: So two Walmarts,
one gun store later,
we got all of our
needs for today.
Walmart was pretty
accommodating.
But every time you go, it's a
kind of a crap shoot, right?
EDDIE CACCIOLA: Yeah.
Sometimes they'll have
everything you need.
And that's when you've
got to buy it up.
Other times, you've got to buy
something you don't want.
ROCCO CASTORO: I'm going to go
through a little bit of what
we got here, Federal
[INAUDIBLE]
for a 9mm Luger.
EDDIE CACCIOLA: Then we got
a couple of boxes of .45
Federal, some .410
shotgun shells.
A big box of .45 auto,
250-round count.
ROCCO CASTORO: Rifle slugs for
the shotguns, Magtech, Cowboy
Action Loads.
EDDIE CACCIOLA: And 1,000
rounds of .223.
This for the AR?
ROCCO CASTORO: How many people
are we shooting with?
EDDIE CACCIOLA: Four
and then some.
ROCCO CASTORO: Beautiful fall
Florida day, hot as shit.
The Federal Assault Weapons
Ban was passed under the
Clinton administration
in September, 1994.
Sunset provisions set the ban to
expire in 2004, and it did.
[VIDEO PLAYBACK]
-From my cold, dead hands.
[CHEERS]
[END VIDEO PLAYBACK]
ROCCO CASTORO: Since then,
lawmakers like Senator Dianne
Feinstein of California and
Congresswoman Carolyn McCarthy
of New York have attempted
to institute revised
versions of the ban.
Did you do anything
for Veterans Day?
EDDIE CACCIOLA: No.
I tried not to do too much.
ROCCO CASTORO: Tried to relax?
EDDIE CACCIOLA: Yeah.
I figure it's my day.
I don't have to do shit.
ROCCO CASTORO: Yep.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
ROCCO CASTORO: So with several
thousand rounds of ammunition
loaded into Eddie's truck, we
headed to a local range on the
outskirts of Sarasota.
EDDIE CACCIOLA: Yeah.
It's convenient.
I like shooting outdoor.
I don't really feel comfortable
in indoor ranges.
ROCCO CASTORO:
EDDIE CACCIOLA: It's that, and
there's a lot of new people.
And there's just a lot of safety
that goes into it that
people just have no clue.
You don't want to be in close
quarters with somebody that
doesn't know what
they're doing.
ROCCO CASTORO:
EDDIE CACCIOLA: No.
Deer doesn't taste that good.
And it's kind of boring hunting
something that's not
going to shoot back at you.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
EDDIE CACCIOLA:
ROCCO CASTORO: Big Nick, one of
the guys we shot with, he
had a pretty nice AR-15.
He bought it at a garage sale.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
ROCCO CASTORO: That's
pretty standard
practice here in Florida.
No real paperwork was exchanged,
as far as I know.
And he got the gun for cash,
brought it home.
It was about half price.
And we just shot it here
all day today.
That's how easy it is to
get a gun in Florida.
What types of weapons are
illegal in Florida?
JOHN BUCHAN: We have certain
categories that you have to
have certain permits for.
I've got a suppressor
on a gun on a wall.
You have to fill out a form.
It goes to ATF.
It's a $200 tax stamp.
They do a background check.
They send you the stamp.
You're allowed to own it.
ROCCO CASTORO: OK.
And what are some of the
other classifications?
Like a Class 3 license,
what would that mean?
JOHN BUCHAN: Well, fully
automatic machine guns, fully
automatic weapons is a whole
different license.
Transferring those weapons,
there's regulations for all of
that stuff.
And those regulations are
pretty stringent.
And they are enforced.
MICHAEL CREA: Everybody in
Florida owns an assault rifle.
If you try and send the
National Guard in, we
outnumber them.
ROCCO CASTORO: [LAUGHS]
MICHAEL CREA: And the National
Guard is not going to come to
our house and take
our guns away.
JOHN BUCHAN: I've always
wondered why it is so
difficult to get a group of
people in Washington to sit
down, maybe hook up with some
people from the NRA, and set
up districts and set gun laws
that are made by gun owners
and people in the firearms
industry.
Those laws would work.
[VIDEO PLAYBACK]
-When freedom shivers in the
cold shadow of true peril,
it's always the patriots who
first hear the call.
[END VIDEO PLAYBACK]
ROCCO CASTORO: In 2004, the
Department of Justice released
an assessment of the decade-long
ban that said, if
the ban were to be reinstated at
a future date, its effects
on gun violence are likely to be
small at best, and perhaps
too small for reliable
measurement.
The report also stated that
assault weapons were rarely
used in gun crimes even
before the ban.
A dissenting study carried out
by the Brady Center for Gun
Control alleged that data
provided by the ATF showed
that the number of violent
crimes in which assault
weapons were used dropped from
4.82% to 1.61% during the ban.
An ATF spokesperson later said
that his organization could,
in no way, vouch for the
validity of that claim.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
ROCCO CASTORO: John is one of
Florida's approximately 7,000
Federal Firearms License
holders.
The process for obtaining an FFL
and what types of weapons
can be bought and sold by those
who are issued them is
largely defined by 1938's
Federal Firearms Act and the
gun Control Act of 1968.
The ATF issues and oversees
licensing criteria for
dealers, pawnbrokers, and
other people who have
legitimate business with guns.
But the agency's oversight
largely stops at the
licensee's counter.
JOHN BUCHAN: Well, first
things first.
When you open a store up, ATF
gives you the first right to
decline a sale to any individual
for any reason.
And we practice that here.
We've turned gun sales down
because of something that we
just sensed.
The person that acts skittish
when he's filling out the
questions and asking you a lot
of technical things on it and
checks yes to one of the blocks,
not happening here.
And somebody that comes in to
try to buy a weapon and you
know the gun's not for them,
because the boyfriend's
standing right there.
And he's picked out the
gun and he wants this.
But she wants to fill
the form out.
Totally illegal.
Not happening here.
The kid that walked in here
had his hat turned around
backwards, had all the jewelry
on and decided to grab one of
the shotguns and wheel it around
on his hip and act
like, say hello to my little
friend and I've got to have
one of these, not
happening here.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
ROCCO CASTORO: After me and the
boys exhausted most of our
ammunition, we packed up the
weapons and drove to Sarasota
Trap Skeet & Clays, about a
half mile down the road.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
'BIG' NICK COLELLA:
ROCCO CASTORO: Shortly after
arriving at the range, we were
joined by Eddie's 12-year-old
son, Shawn.
EDDIE CACCIOLA:
ROCCO CASTORO: He came to spend
some quality shooting
time with his dad, an American
pastime older than playing
catch in the front yard.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
ROCCO CASTORO: So with this
shooting, it's better to keep
both eyes open?
Some people?
EDDIE CACCIOLA: Yeah.
Some people say that, on the
skeet and trap, it's better to
keep both eyes open.
You couldn't shoot an AR
with both eyes open.
ROCCO CASTORO: Yeah.
Yeah.
Of course.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
EDDIE CACCIOLA:
He's known about guns and the
safety rules, probably, five
years prior to him ever
picking one up
and shooting one.
If the guns are there and he's
there, the sooner I teach him
about the safety, the
better off I'd be.
ROCCO CASTORO: Shawn, as
it turned out, was
a crack clay shooter.
SHAWN CACCIOLA: Pull!
[MUSIC PLAYING]
EDDIE CACCIOLA:
ROCCO CASTORO: I shuddered at
the thought of how accurate
Shawn might be behind an AR-15,
imagining a future with
remote control drone soldiers
piloted by preteen
sharpshooters.
[VOICE OF JOHN WAYNE]
He's a good shot.
ROCCO CASTORO: Pull.
Smell the gunpowder.
Nice.
In between stations, I finally
got a chance to speak with
Steve, the fifth member of our
party and a former Army medic.
Where were you deployed?
STEVE NORTON: Baghdad.
ROCCO CASTORO: Did you treat
a lot of gunshot injuries?
STEVE NORTON:
ROCCO CASTORO: Since you came
back from your deployment, did
it change your appreciation
for weapons at all?
STEVE NORTON: No, not at all.
I've always loved weapons.
My dad was special forces.
He taught me at a young
age about shooting.
And before I could own my own,
he gave me a couple of books I
had to read.
ROCCO CASTORO: Are there any
aspects of the law that you
think are a bit overreaching
or under-reaching?
STEVE NORTON: Probably
not too bad.
ROCCO CASTORO: Yeah?
STEVE NORTON: As long as you
do the proper paperwork
in the right way.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
ROCCO CASTORO: On January 16,
Obama announced 23 executive
orders he could enact without
Congressional approval, in an
effort to curb gun violence
and reinforce existing
firearms laws.
These actions include signing a
Presidential memorandum that
requires Federal agencies to
make relevant firearms
purchasing data available to the
Federal Background Check
System, launching a national
safe and responsible gun
ownership campaign, providing
schools with resource officers
and counselors, and instituting
more severe
penalties for gun trafficking.
[VIDEO PLAYBACK]
-As soon as I'm finished
speaking here, I will sit at
that desk and I will sign
a directive giving law
enforcement, schools, mental
health professionals, and the
public health community some of
the tools they need to help
reduce gun violence.
[APPLAUSE]
[END VIDEO PLAYBACK]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
ROCCO CASTORO: High Noon, like
many other gun shops in the
state, offers Concealed Weapon
Permit Certification classes.
They are overseen by Tom
Dusseau, a local police
officer, former Marine, and
private military contractor.
TOM DUSSEAU: Well, essentially,
the state of
Florida requires that you take
an NRA approved course.
But what a lot of the
instructors are lacking is
the, say, for lack of a better
term, the real life experience
when it comes to being
involved in a
confrontational situation.
You look at the weapons and
how other people perceive
them, and that's what it is,
it's perception, when you have
a list of people, politicians,
whatever the case may be,
picking weapons to put on an
assault weapons banned list,
just because they look evil.
EDDIE CACCIOLA: You can make
anything look badass.
Some have a wooden stock.
Some have a composite stock.
Obviously, the composite stock
looks like somebody's coming
to hurt you.
And the other one reminds me
of my grandfather's rifle.
TOM DUSSEAU: Does that make it
a war-type or assault weapon?
Not really.
It's a design.
After the first election when
Obama was elected, I was
teaching Concealed Weapons
classes in
the state of Florida.
A big class prior
to the election
was eight to 10 people.
After the election, every time
I'd walk in there, there was
25 to 30 people.
The people are running
in panic.
They know the restrictions
are coming.
They come out and they buy a
large number of firearms.
And then they just put
them in a safe.
They don't carry them.
They don't use them.
They just buy them.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
-24-year-old James Holmes
walked into a theater--
Holmes was heavily armed--
and opened fire.
-20-year-old Adam Lanza, who
died of a self-inflicted
gunshot wound to the
head, this was the
work of a lone wolf.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
ROCCO CASTORO: On a Saturday
following the shooting of 28
people at an elementary school
in Newtown, Connecticut,
Virginia State Police processed
4,166 background
checks for concealed and
assault-type weapons, a 42%
increase from the same
Saturday in 2011.
On the same day, Colorado, a
state still reeling from a
string of recent shootings,
also processed 4,200
background checks, the highest
number since the
program began in 1999.
The fallout resulting from the
shooting at Sandy Hook
Elementary has led to a 19%
rise in background checks
nationwide.
According to the FBI,
approximately 2.78 million
background checks were recorded
in the month of
December 2012 alone.
That's a 39% rise from
the previous month.
In recent years, there has been
much renewed attention
paid to some of the more
nebulous aspects of many
states' gun laws.
Particular attention has been
paid to what is called the
"stand your ground" law, the
guiding principle behind
"stand your ground" being that
any person in public, if they
feel as if their life has been
threatened, has the right to
shoot that threat
dead on the spot
without any duty to retreat.
"Stand your ground" became a
household phrase following an
incident in Florida in which the
threat in question was an
unarmed, black 17-year-old with
nothing in his pockets
but a bag of Skittles.
That boy's name was
Trayvon Martin.
There are currently 24 states
with "stand your
ground" laws in effect.
New research indicates that
states with "stand your
ground" laws have a 7% to 9%
higher homicide rate, compared
to states without such laws.
Another aspect of firearms laws
currently under scrutiny
in Washington is the ability to
purchase certain types of
weapons at gun shows, pop-up
shops, or through private
sales between citizens.
[VIDEO PLAYBACK]
--when as many as 40% of all
gun purchases are conducted
without a background check.
[END VIDEO PLAYBACK]
MICHAEL CREA: In Florida,
I can sell you
a gun on the street.
And it's completely legal.
JOHN BUCHAN: You run into a
lot of that at gun shows,
outside in the parking
lot, the side deal.
But yes, it is legal
to do that.
MICHAEL CREA: You know, I could
have bought a gun from a
guy who had it for 40
years, sold it to
10 different people.
They're not going to
trace that back.
How are you going to keep track
of all these guns that
people are just selling and
trading between themselves?
EDDIE CACCIOLA: One
came right here.
And the other one I met in a
gas station parking lot.
ROCCO CASTORO: Did they
just hand it to
you out in the open?
EDDIE CACCIOLA: We put it in
the back of my pickup truck
and tactfully looked it
over and made sure
it was what it was.
And he had a gun and I had
cash, so we made a trade.
So I'm here looking on Florida
Gun Trader, see if there's any
local deals to be had.
Let's see.
What have we got here?
[INAUDIBLE]
Yeah, this guy's real close
to where we're at.
[PHONE RINGS]
[MALE VOICE ON PHONE]
Hello.
Yeah.
How you doing?
EDDIE CACCIOLA: Good.
Does it come with anything?
[MALE VOICE ON PHONE]
Just some [? [INAUDIBLE]. ?]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
ROCCO CASTORO: So earlier today,
you found this Sig
Sauer P238 Blackwood
with night sites
on Florida Gun Trader.
And the guy got in
touch with you.
And we're about to go meet
him in a parking lot.
EDDIE CACCIOLA: Yeah.
ROCCO CASTORO: And
I don't know.
How shady of a deal, on
a scale of 1 to 10,
would you rate this?
EDDIE CACCIOLA: 9 and 1/2.
ROCCO CASTORO: 9 and 1/2?
[LAUGHS]
EDDIE CACCIOLA: Yeah.
Buying a gun at 10 o'clock at
night, a little suspect.
ROCCO CASTORO: Yeah.
You can't go to restaurants
after 10:00.
Buying a gun, kind
of interesting.
What did the guy say to
you on the phone?
EDDIE CACCIOLA: He wants $550 at
the minimum, and as long as
I'm a Florida resident.
ROCCO CASTORO: And that
just means you've got
to show him an ID?
EDDIE CACCIOLA: Yeah.
ROCCO CASTORO: And
he wants cash?
EDDIE CACCIOLA: Yeah.
ROCCO CASTORO: OK.
I'm going to ask you to ask him
for a receipt, maybe hint
at that you may have some
priors, but you don't know.
Are you OK with that?
EDDIE CACCIOLA: Yeah.
ROCCO CASTORO: Are you
going to be carrying?
EDDIE CACCIOLA: Probably.
ROCCO CASTORO: [LAUGHS]
So let's go do this.
This is kind of weird.
[LAUGHS]
EDDIE CACCIOLA: All right.
ROCCO CASTORO: Within 30
minutes, we were posted up in
a Lowe's parking lot,
waiting for our
sketchy deal to go down.
EDDIE CACCIOLA:
[MUSIC PLAYING]
ROCCO CASTORO: How'd
it go down?
You met him, shook hands.
EDDIE CACCIOLA: We just shot
the shit for a minute.
ROCCO CASTORO: Yeah?
EDDIE CACCIOLA: And then got
down to business, showed me
what he had.
ROCCO CASTORO: Did it
feel like you were
making a drug deal?
EDDIE CACCIOLA: Kind
of, actually.
ROCCO CASTORO: Yeah?
Yeah?
[LAUGHS]
Why don't you show
us what you got?
EDDIE CACCIOLA: A little Sig
P238, a little compact carry
piece, perfect for,
maybe, the pocket.
ROCCO CASTORO: Put it in your
belt or something like that.
It's a nice weight.
EDDIE CACCIOLA: He didn't
ask me for anything.
ROCCO CASTORO: Not even an ID?
EDDIE CACCIOLA: No.
ROCCO CASTORO: Didn't
even ask for an ID?
EDDIE CACCIOLA: No.
ROCCO CASTORO: What kind of
guy did he seem like?
EDDIE CACCIOLA: Ah, a
little questionable.
ROCCO CASTORO: A
little quacky?
Did he think that was weird?
Did he hesitate at all?
EDDIE CACCIOLA: He was
a little hesitant.
ROCCO CASTORO: But then he was
like, fuck it, I got the cash?
EDDIE CACCIOLA: Yeah.
He was like, ah, OK.
Once he signed his name and I
signed my name, he said this
is a legal binding contract.
ROCCO CASTORO: Is it notarized?
[LAUGHS]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
ROCCO CASTORO: Just like
abortion, gay marriage, and
other hot-button legal issues,
it is nearly impossible to
convince someone that
his or her opinion
about guns is wrong.
Even if somehow, in some
bizarro dimension where
martial law has been declared,
the same people will keep
stockpiling more and
more, until they
are no longer available.
Outside of stricter regulations
on background
checks and keeping guns out of
the hands of the mentally
disturbed, there is no easy
answer to the firearms debate
that will make everyone happy.
[MUSIC PLAYING]