Well thanks very much.  Today is a really
an exciting opportunity.  Indeed,
that was very energizing, the last session.
We hope to carry that forward and add a little of,
a little bit of clarity, to the vector
that we're on.  I truly think that this is
a unique moment in history.  We are retiring the
space shuttle. We've, uh,
been transitioning the international space
station from one of assembly, to operations
and utilization.  And using that as a
cornerstone of our human space
flight operations and activities to go
beyond low Earth orbit for,
uh, for the duration.
And so, um,
I think it was a fitting introduction
about rising
to the occasion.  And, so what I'd like to do
is, I've got a great couple of
folks on the panel.
I encourage you to take a look at the bios
if you're interested, on page 43
of your, uh, of your
notebook.
Garry Lyles, 35 plus years in the
in the business,
doing everything from systems
integration through program management,
to, uh, leading
most recently, our analysis
of alternatives.  Leading the
study teams looking at our
critical next decisions, looking at
in an objective, thorough
and absolutely complete way.
Uh, our future
heavy lift launch vehicle,
and the space launch systems
options that we're looking at.
He is truly a quintessential
engineer and uh,
and just an asset to the agency.
And, uh, following his,
uh, following his talk
uh, we'll have Maria.
Maria Collura, she is the Deputy Director
of the Space Transportation Planning Office.
Engaged in
our critically important
activities associated with
commercial crew, uh,
to both the international space station
and low Earth orbit.  She has just,
uh, come off
the, uh, the highly
energized and much-anticipated
CCDev-2 announcement.
And so, I think she'll give you some great
insight into that.  Collectively,
these things will help
outline and add some clarity
to the path that we're on.  But, this
is a path that's not yet fully written.
It's one that we are indeed looking to
you, and to share with you
the current status.  So, much
like we wove
a little bit of storytelling
into the past.  I'm going to tell you a
little bit of the why.  Same thing from an
integrative perspective.  I'm going to tell you some of the how
and then it's about participation.
So, we'll do the
engage part last.
Um, I'll start off.
I'm going to give you a little bit of perspective,
kind of a scene setter, here.
And then, I'll dive into my specific pitch.
It's going to be on the human exploration
architecture team.
Some of the near-term work that we've been doing,
and, uh, and the results of that.
As well as the, uh, as well as
the steps ahead.  So, essentially
this just gives you a little snapshot of the vision.
Talk about the budget context
and the capability-driven exploration,
talk about what that means.
Talk about this human exploration framework team, give you
a little bit of insight into
uh, the game plan, our concept
of operations.  Also, talk about
affordability which is a fundamental driver,
much like safety
and, uh, performance
and mission execution.  Talk about
the HAT, which is the follow on work
and I'll wrap it all up.
So, you know, it was an interesting
comment on the organization chart. [ Audience Laughter ]
Well, you, know why I put this one in here,
is, we have about 32 plus direct reports
to the administrator, right.
And, essentially the point I'm trying to make with this
is we have a huge
amount of people engaged.
Every facet across the spectrum:
from people, resources to
to infrastructure, to budget,
to dealing with Congress and the White House,
to the performance, to the missions
to the design people, the safety of the mission assurance,
the engineering and everybody in between.
And it's a ten center effort.
This is what NASA is about.
This is, what is
uh, this is the group or the
body that we have to engage.
Plus, you bring in Congress, and
Congress is not a monolithic body.
We've got the 111th, which passed
the Authorization Act of 2010
in bi-partisan fashion,
signed by the president.  But now,
we have the 112th, and that's a whole
new ballgame.  And, if you, you know, just watch
the political theater playing out.  You've got
the White House, you've got the OMB--
the Office of Management and Budget,
the OSTP.  All the different players,
plus the industry stakeholders,
international, other governmental agencies,
and, uh, and academia.
Add that all to the mix and you
wonder why it's a little bit challenging
to get some decisions.  Everybody has a voice.
And, boy, for ten people in a room
you'll probably get 11 or 12
different opinions, because as people go around
they actually change their story a little bit.
So, that's kind of the soup, or
kind of some of the dynamics that we're playing with.
Um,
and we've got a clear vision, you know,
from our newest release of the
2011 strategic plan.
NASA's strategic goals are
those six listed there.
And, I highlighted in blue the first one:
Extending and sustaining human activities
activities across the solar system.
That's a real big driver for our exploration activities.
But, so too is blending in
a tight synergy with the science side.
You know, developing the technologies
and the capabilities that are necessary
to not only enable and
expand these capabilities, but also
to add huge value to
back here, terrestrially
on the planet Earth.
And, uh, to our national and international economic future
as well as benefiting
all of humanity.  Tying in
our programmatic and institutional
capabilities is ever
more important, given the scarcity
and constrained resources that we have.
And, finally, it's about sharing this.
Uh, not only engaging people
in a two-way fashion,
but sharing this awesome,
and this is the best sense of the word,
message and future that we do have together.
So, essentially the budget overview
for exploration systems.
So, we've got a little under $4 billion.
So, if you can't do something with $4 billion,
something is wrong, right?
We've got a heck of a lot, a heck of a lot of
opportunity here. We do have, uh,
and you know, everybody, uh everybody
is concerned about,
about the, uh, about the, dollars, but this is
really $240 million
above what we, uh, what our FY11
authorized level was.
It does fund
a really diverse portfolio across
uh, across
a broad portfolio
of capabilities.
ISS is at the corner piece of that, for human space flight ops.
And, uh, and
it's also designed
specifically to maintain US
leadership and to engage
in beyond low Earth orbit,
or beyond LEO capabilities
and development for the future.
It also has a
strong underpinning in developing
and leveraging the
commercial space industry.
And that's for safe and affordable access
to the international space station,
and also helping to enable
the broader activities beyond.
That also includes the
Space Launch System and the Multi-Purpose Crew Vehicle
for, uh,
our destinations and
multiple destinations beyond low Earth orbit,
as well as, uh, as well as
the other activities.
So, that's a little snapshot. This is the quick overview,
Essentially, this
budget enables us to work, uh,
certainly.  We already talked about ISS
being highly leveraged, both
in a utilization sense for exploration benefit.
We are looking
to identify those quick
those, uh, those quick
wins as well as the longer-term
set of technology
and research capabilities that will allow
us to conquer challenges in environmental
control and life support systems.
Irradiation.  Extended duration of radiation.
Extended duration micro-gravity experience
or countermeasures.
And, so those are some of the critical
drivers as well as
propulsion and habitation
and dealing with the, uh,
dealing with the delay and disruption tolerant communications capabilities that we'll be
needing for extended beyond low Earth orbit exploration.
Likewise, it will
allow us to aggressively pursue those human
research and life support
and habitation things that we talked about
for technology capability
development perspective.
And, very consistent with the
national space policy, this
is all about huge partnerships
with not only inter-agency folks,
but internationals,
academia and industry.
And by industry, we're talking new space,
old space, we're talking
non-traditional space, we're partnering with
people like Google and Caterpillar,
John Deere, and
GM and Ford, and
Apple and
people across the community that
you don't always consider traditional aerospace players.
So,
little bit of a snapshot as to what
and why.  I think all too often
we throw out, hey, multi-destinations.
We've got high Earth orbit, geosynchronous orbit,
Lagrange points.  Why?
What's compelling about them?  Well, essentially,
we've got a lot of opportunities for
assembly or repair.  They're an excellent
location for, uh,
space, or, uh, telescopes
large, uh, larger
uh, large aperture telescopes.
Looking at Mars and its moons,
essentially, perhaps a horizon
destination for humans
at least in the relatively near term.
You know, is there a life beyond Earth?
You know, how did it evolve?
And, I think from there, uh,
it holds a special place
in many peoples, uh, many peoples
psyche.  Likewise, the moon,
uh, our nearest
uh, our nearest, celestial
body there, we can see a lot
that is covered up by the, uh,
by the environmental impacts here
on the Earth.  It's a great historical
record, uh, with the
rich discoveries of water,
and uh, and all the near-term
other exciting discoveries that we've
just begun to unravel with the Moon.
Um, we OK?
OK, uh, I think,
that, uh, I think given the fact that
it's just three days away as well
holds huge potential
commercial, uh, promise.
And, uh, as we look at Near Earth Asteroids,
NEAs, um,
we have some compelling science
questions.  Everything from
how did the solar system form?
To, uh, helping to
gain some insight into planetary defense.
We know that, uh,
uh, throughout
history, uh, Earth has
uh, the planet Earth has seen some, uh,
seen some impacts
so, as we seek to better understand
what we can do to, uh
both potentially mitigate that or
understand the dynamic, I think all of
that is relevant.  So, that kind of
gives you a little snapshot there.  This is kind of
a picture of how it all weaves together.
Here we are at the international space station down at the bottom,
looking at our new, uh, our new
low Earth orbit missions and as we
extend out in kind of a crescendo of
capabilities.  This is really what a
capability driven, uh, framework or
capability driven exploration
is about.  It's about building the
capabilities and the technologies such
that you can go beyond in an iterative,
or, stepwise fashion, and you
don't have a single path.
So, we have, uh, we can leverage
uh, the, uh,
GEO/HEO Missions, looking at lunar flybys,
lunar surface, uh,
"Min," and "Full Capability" Near-Earth Asteroids,
Phobos/Deimos, and Mars.
And, you see along the way,
what, uh, what each, uh,
what each new plateau affords.
As, uh, keeping
consistent with kind of the quick overview,
I wanted to provide you some insight into,
we call these "budget themes."
When we go up and brief Congress,
uh, with the President's budget, we
talk in each of these theme areas.
And, so that's why it's going to perfectly dovetail with
uh, what Garry and Maria
are gonna talk about.
Essentially, we've got, uh, this theme
The Human Exploration Capabilities budgeted
$2.8 billion for FY12.
Essentially, uh, that
does include labor, and uh, essentially,
that includes $1.8 billion
for the Space Launch System
and, uh, roughly a billion dollars for
the Multi-Purpose Crew Vehicle, and
the ground ops, uh, kind of
an amalgam between ground ops and
21st Century, that enables that.
So, that gives you a little snapshot there.
Uh, right now, as we
uh, and Garry,
I won't spend hardly any time on this
uh, because he will do an awesome job
at it, and I mean awesome,
cause he is incredibly thorough.
Um, as we look at a Reference Vehicle
Design that we communicated
in our early, our early chats,
it was 100
metric ton, or pardon me a
70 to 100 metric ton evolvable to
130 metric ton launch
vehicle.  Built and derived from
the Ares and Shuttle hardware,
with the capability to lift the
Multi-Purpose Crew Vehicle.  So, you see
essentially, what the Reference
Vehicle Design was,
as we submitted.
But, we've got, uh, we've had, uh
a huge amount of work that's gone on since then.
Next slide, uh, is
looking at the Multi-Purpose Crew Vehicle.
Again, we're looking
beyond low Earth orbit,
a variant of the Orion, essentially the
block 2, for those of you that were familiar with it.
And, essentially, this is looking at a
requirements-based, or requirements-driven approach.
Uh, and we're making some final decisions
uh, this summer, we're going to
be communicating that to Congress in what we
call the 90-day report.
And, uh, we'll be building that into the budget,
budget activities and
also the programmatic implementation.
On the commercial side, and
this is a beautiful, this is a beautiful kind of
image showing, uh
a whole bunch, or a
a whole host of potential applications
but, we've got about
$850 million
slated in FY12,
and that includes the labor.
Providing not only,
looking for safer and reliable transportation
to the, uh, and affordable
commercial systems for both
cargo first, and then crew to
the international space station
and low Earth orbit.  We are
transitioning, um
from, we're completing
some of our milestones or our
capability milestones based out
to, uh, to uh, starting to
generate, uh, to generate
a broader industry capable
of supporting the, uh, the crew
uh, the crew needs and
the transportation, traffic flow
challenges of the international
space station.  So, Maria
will do yeoman's work
in outlining that. Uh, as we look at
exploration, research and development
theme, essentially
we've got, uh, we've got
just under $300 million going to this.
It includes the Human Research Program, as well
as our Advanced Exploration Systems.
And, those are, uh, those
are some of our what we call "skunk works,"
or lean or rapid prototyping,
some non-traditional
uh, if you will type approaches
at NASA.  We've done several
prototypes along this line
things like the Robonaut 2,
uh, the hab and habex
and, uh, what used to be called
the Lunar Electric Rover, now the
Space Exploration Vehicle, the SEV.
Those are all examples of prototype
uh, approaches that we've done
each one is a little bit different, but all carrying that
principle, we've got about
63, well not not about,
we have 63 submittals in
as part of this year's, uh,
effort, and those are all getting
reviewed as we speak right now.
Um,
as we look at, uh, with
the Office of the Chief Technologist, OCT,
Dr. Bobby Braun, we are
sending what used to be the majority
of our exploration technology development
program.  We're sending that over to
the Office of the Chief Technologist to
to, uh, to do that work as part of a broader
agency portfolio that will
still remain critically important
as those are mission enabling
and mission critical for
our exploration missions.
Uh, and, for
'12, we're taking a little breather
on, uh, on the uh
Exploration Precursor Robotics
activities, but then in '13
we have a, uh
a blended funding line between exploration
and Science Mission Directorate
for, uh, for those in the
sum of $30 million.
Um,
This just gives you a little bit more,
we already talked about
a risk-based approach to the international
space station, leveraging
what we can there, but also
the ultimate goal is to have much
longer, outside the
Van Allen radiation belt capabilities,
so that we can do these extended
mission durations of perhaps
a year or more.  So, that's a critical driver
and, uh,
the people part of it are
truly a daunting challenge,
but also a huge opportunity.
Uh,
looking a little bit at how we're shaping
that up, ISS utilization.
Developing space biomedical capabilities,
looking at, we talked about radiation
safety for the crew, and then
uh, very much akin with, uh,
with, uh the national
engagement,
harnessing the collective brain power
of not only our national research community,
but a very robust and
integrated international space research
community.  One that is
leveraging not only traditional partners,
but, personally, we, uh,
we've done a lot more with
Korea and other countries like that.
Smaller, burgeoning, uh,
blossoming, uh
space agencies. So, we're
looking to leverage and enhance those kind of
uh, partnerships.
And, uh, looking a little bit at
Advanced Exploration Program review, we already
talked some of that
this is the Robonaut 2, depicted in
the middle there.  Essentially,
we're looking to engage our
great, our great
and experienced workforce, and do more hands on
work here.  Uh, smaller
procurement dollar,
more intense civil servant
leveraged approach.
Um, we are looking
to ensure that we reduce
risk, lower our life cycle costs,
and validate some of the unique con ops.
So this is where we're allowed to take a little bit more risk.
We're allowed to
have some smart failures, as long as
we're learning from these, and, uh,
I think this is a strong step in the right direction.
And, changing the
paradigm, making us more agile and
more responsive, but most importantly
dealing with the critical need that we're going to have
from these systems in this, uh, in this
increasingly, uh,
challenging, uh, budgetary environment.
This is a doable solution.
Alright, we already talked a little bit about
that, I won't spend too much more on that.
We are using analogs in a
large way.  We're using ground tests,
flight tests, uh, we're using
final DTOs aboard the space
uh, space shuttle and also the
space station.  So,
that's kind of the scene setter,
What I'd like to give you now is a quick
snapshot into
our human exploration framework team,
talk about some of the context there.
So essentially,
I think
over the past couple of days, you've seen
just how profound and complex
and challenging and how
team oriented
uh,
truly bold, human
space flight systems
developments and operations are.
They transcend political cycles,
they transcend generations,
and yet,
we've had 24 teams since '69 who have
studied and done blue ribbon studies.
And yet,
when we kicked off this, our
charter had
six words that were different from the
1989 90-day study.
And one might go,
"Well, are we just doing infinite Do loops
on studies?"  The answer is no.
We were guided by a lot of the, uh,
a lot of the policy and legislation
of the day, but the whole purpose
is to create an integrated human space flight
architecture that really
helped us make smart decisions. Not only
as an agency, but as a country
and as a global community
uh, to, uh inform our
strategy and so that's what I'm going to tell you about.
Share a little about that.
Context -- I think you have to
have a context in the political
sense.  We had the Augustine Committee in '09,
In '10 we had the National Space Policy,
very directive toward
international partnerships, US industrial
base, inter-agency collaboration
and cooperation, commercial
engagement.  As we look
at the Human Exploration Framework Team,
we did, uh, we did two different
groups or two different phases of that.
Along, uh,
during, right in smack dab of the middle
of the second one, we had the NASA Authorization Act,
that was passed.  And, you know
it states that the long term goal is to expand
human presence, permanent human presence
beyond low Earth orbit, and to do so
involving our IPs,
our international partners, as practicable.
Along there, we also have this
ongoing effort, but we also now have
a continuing resolution
that we just got passed,
uh, for FY11.
So, essentially, this body
I think people, I think people
thought that we had the ability to
or were setting the
absolute concrete plan.  No, essentially
what we were doing is
doing the work to cue it up so that the
agency, so that the Congress,
so that the White House, can
have informed, uh,
informed set ups, and we can
make those smart decisions
in a timely fashion.  And, I think
the number one thing that people
are looking at is, "Hey, what is our
path, and let's all
get on board and start executing
that, because we are truly at a critical
time in history."  So,
um, a little bit of guidance.
This is a huge word chart.
Many of these are so vetted,
so scrubbed, by
folks that it's just not even worth trying to
change them. I'll just hit the highlights
Essentially, affrodability has gotta be a huge driver
Second one, I think
many, especially in the younger generation
here, will resonate with the second one.
We gotta reward value
conscious performance, take prudent risk
assumption, look at bold innovation,
harness the can-do attitude.
We've, we're an agency
of can-do and we need
to continue and build upon that and evolve.
Um, this,
this stems all the way from
the very newest
ranks, our 10-week, uh,
our 10-week people, all the way
to our, our senior
executives, all the way to
the administrator and the associate administrators
taking that bull by the horns.
And, we need to build and
apply on everything that we've learned over
the past 53 plus years of human space
flight experience,
yet still seek out new innovative ways.
So, marry the best
of both and then leverage our
assets and our people appropriately.
But, that doesn't mean
that we keep everything, because
we have a huge
resource burden, and we need to be
smart and have that requirements driven.
So, here's, here's a couple of
the principles.
Do a routine cadence, and do a routine cadence at
first.  So have it, keep it
sold, if you will.  Have it be a
regular set.  Build upon those
capabilities, we already talked about that.
It's gotta fit within the budget.
That's almost like a "duh."  We can't
be, uh, we can't developing
plans that aren't
executable, given the fiscal constraints that we have.
And, it's not gonna get that much better.
But, that doesn't mean, I mean
we still got, uh,
$18.485 billion,
um, going for us.
We can do a heck of a lot
for that. We've got to leverage
the international space station, we've got a $100 billion
asset.  Just the prudent, right thing to do
and we can use it as a stepping stone with our
international partners as well.
We gotta have a balance here between execution
and technology development,
leverage commonality and evolutionary approach.
Uh, we gotta, you know,
this fight between humans and robots,
that's, that's, that's
that's a fallacy, we gotta have both
and optimize the best.
And then, uh, we gotta leverage
our non-NASA capabilities, whether
they be the DOD or the Department of Energy
or academia, or industry.
And, we gotta stop
having NASA unique
supply chains and new facilities
such that, we
carry the burden of those solely.
So we need to look
in a smart sense there.  And then, develop
the best practices, wherever
uh, we see those.   Uh, truly to be
world-class, you gotta be, uh,
you gotta be a world-class adopter.
So, HEFT, essentially,
we got together, we did a
we, uh, we established a framework
uh, it's called the
capability-driven framework.
And essentially, it's all geared to do one thing:
to weather the political and economic
dynamics and to actually achieve
a cohesive, long term
multi-destination, integrated
approach to human space flight.
And, so I think
we'll explain how we believe that this does
create a safe, affordable and sustainable
approach to that.
It was hugely iterative, we did
lots of technical design and reference missions,
you cross those with investment strategies
it shows the options.  It's not
just one single path.  Somebody mentioned,
you know, "Could we have multiple paths
and maybe all are viable?"  Well that's absolutely true
here.  And, as we look at that,
we developed, "What do you need to go do those?"
Those element catalogs are
the resultant of that.  Then we looked
at the cost and the schedule to
develop each of those, both the development,
the fixed and the recurring, the production
and operations, looked at the phasing.
And, really, ultimately,
that yielded an integrated
program schedule and flight manifest.
Was it ever right the first time?
Absolutely not.  Why?
Because it needs to be optimized
and iterated.  And when we usually saw
that budgets spit out, the raw
budget numbers in terms of a sand chart,
it didn't all fit in the box.  So that's why
I say up at the top, it was highly iterative.
Yet, from this,
we distilled out, hey, what are our
key technology priorities?  What are our key
stakeholder concerns?  How did we meet those?
And we, you know, we checked our homework
along the way.
So, this capability-driven framework
that resulted out this is,
it said, "Hey, we're going to use these common elements
these things that we developed, we're not gonna just
go one destination and
and have the stuff not be applicable
or, or, have it be a
dead end.  No, we're gonna look at
that across all the design reference
missions and see where, see where
we have commonality."  Turns out,
as we look at the con ops, the contingencies
and aborts are actually driving
of the, uh, of
many of, uh many of the
requirements here.  So, it's not just the nominal missions,
it's actually going to do them
and looking at the aborts and
contingencies as the key drivers.
And, ultimately, we, this allows
us to play with the
cost and the schedule,
phasing a bit.
Essentially, in the past, we
haven't had an ability to say "Hey,
as you get increments or decrements in budget
what does that do to you?"
We used to have, OK you get a
10% budget, what does that to your
plans to go to the Moon.  Well,
it'd bad, but how bad?
Now, we have a prioritized list
where we say, "Hey, as you decrement the budget,
here's the priorities, we already
have the list.  Here's what we won't be doing.  Is that
acceptable from a political ramification
or from a national end resultant?"
Or, similarly, or conversely,
as you, as
you say, "I'd like to go to
do this, or as we increment
the budget, what's available,
what can you do?"  We will show
with already preset
priorities, "Hey, here's what we'll do,
here's what we can deliver for that."  So, it's a great
kind of contract, uh,
so from the financial sense
it's a great way to have
more ability to
communicate exactly what you give and get.
This is,
this is kind of a very tough
chart.  It shows the whole
enchilada.  You see out there in red
Mars missions is the ultimate horizon
destination.  What you see is
in blue is each of those
candidate, uh, those candidate destinations
in a multi-destination
exploration approach.
The white things are the key capabilities
that you need to get there.
So, in terms of Multi-Purpose Crew Vehicle
and a heavy lift launch vehicle,
uh, needed for going beyond
low Earth orbit.  Likewise,
you might get the
I'll point this out, you might get the impression
see this crew EVA Block 2 Suit,
you might get the impression that that's only
applicable for the Moon because of this
this, single way to
look at it. So, we made another one,
versus here as you see in purple, this
EVA suit, that planetary
surface suit is actually applicable to
the Moon, Near Earth Asteroids and
Mars as well, so you see it kind of segregates
by transportation architecture,
and destination architecture.
So this gives us the flexibility to go to multiple
places.  But, at the same time,
I think a common criticism is
"Well, this is a path to nowhere, is it not?
I mean, if we don't have a single destination,
aren't we looking at,
at, you know,
nothing or chaos?"
And, that's not true at all.  Essentially,
what we're trying to show
is that, by investing in these
capabilities and technologies
we can enable multiple
places and depending upon
the, uh,
political or economic or national will,
we can go get
uh, we can go achieve
um, these
mission objectives with this approach.
Uh, notionally,
this just gives you a snapshot of some of the architecture.
You know, people always say,
"You're talking fairly, uh,
fairly high level."  These are just a snapshot--
notional pics of some of the elements
uh, across all the
multi-destination approach, that uh,
we looked at.  You see the launch vehicle, the crew vehicle,
the cyropropulsion stage
solar electric propulsion, a lander,
Mars surface systems,
the two different types of suits, launch and entry
or planetary, uh,
a notional depiction of a space
exploration vehicle, uh,
and some robotics, uh,
and then a kick stage.
This, uh, these charts are all public
but what I wanted to show you, soup to nuts
across the top, low
Earth orbit, all the way to Mars surface.
Kind of a crescendo of increasingly
challenging, uh,
destinations or capabilities.
Down on the left
is a range of technologies
that are needed.  What you see is
is white -- we pretty much non-applicable
we don't need to do tech dev there,
veruses in the green, we absolutely do.
You see, that first four columns
you got a nice, we got a nice column there
not a lot of, not so much green,
well, that's kind of a, that's kind of a
good check, we already went to the Moon,
we did a lunar surface stay for less than
seven days.  But, as you extend beyond
that it shows you that indeed,
we gotta do
for Near Earth Asteroids, longer duration lunar
surface stays and
Mars, we've got a lot of investment to do.
And, so this a, it's a
compelling driver for that.  This shows the same,
just a little bit more technologies.
But, we're using
the international space station as the
cornerstone of our human space flight ops.
It's a great test bed, it's great for risk reduction,
building off those partnerships.
And, here's how we're going.
We're taking that framework,
these are a lot of the elements, or
the building blocks that it takes to get there,
these are the cross-cutting systems or
capabilities that we need to have,
in order to enable those.  And, here's how
we're getting them through technologies, research,
science.  And, it's the melding of
of, the Science Mission Directorate's work
it's the melding of the
Office of the Chief Technologist's technology development work.
ESMD and SOMD, as we
merge through the human exploration and
operations directorate, that's how it's all
gonna work.  And, it's all about
partnerships.  And, these are not just international,
but also inter-agency and commercial.
Ones that expand, or
allow us to do things that we wouldn't have done
otherwise, or enable
meaning, if an international
partner brings something, we might have planned it
but, it might have been for 10 or 15 years
down the line.  If they bring it, we'll be able
to do that sooner.  To those that
enhance smaller agencies.
Uh, new
and developing countries
uh, they can each play a role
and there's a piece of the puzzle for everyone.
Um, this is
emblematic of some of the themes
and the common goals.
Essentially, these are the five themes
that the 14 countries who participate
in the international space exploration
coordination group are
working together on.  These are what they agree on.
Exploration is about a
sustained presence, for extending human
frontiers, uh, new knowledge
in science and technology, economic
expansion, global partnerships, and
inspiration and education.
And those below,
also further refine,
um, further refine
and reflect the collective
um, objectives of the international community.
Um,
I think all too often people say,
"Well, you know, give us some examples."
Well, those are the 14 countries.
Uh, each of their symbols
uh, displayed up above.
And they do include
Russia, they do include China,
Japan, Europe,
you see Korea,
and several other nations.
From an inter-agency perspective,
we're working with the Department of Defense
the intelligence community, the FAA
Department of Energy, National Science Foundation
Department of Homeland Security,
uh, NIST, you name it.
Um, and those are a couple of examples
of how we're working. Same thing
on the commercial.  We talked about the
traditional aerospace, the entrepreneurial
and the non-traditional
previously.
So, we already talked about
afforability being a big driver.
We're looking at that soup to nuts.
We're applying the
skunk works capabilities.
We're looking at our insight and oversight,
our contracting models, our requirement
systems, our governance.
Across the board, Dan Dumbacher and
team are trying to really
embrace this in our traditional development
as well as trying to adopt
new ways of doing things.
Um, we met
with 25 different industry groups,
or businesses,
we took their inputs, and this is
kind of a smattering
uh, a smattering of their feedback
and results.  You know,
test and fly often,
systems engineering is critically
important, push decision authority
to the lowest level, maintain aggressive
schedules, manage,
keep it simple.  And, you know, I think this
resonates with some of the other things that you've heard.
And, I think the bottom
line is, that if we have
some focused and realistic and stable requirements,
with capable, and
connected, and properly incentivized teams
and schedules--
NASA does its best work
it seems
on challenging schedules--
that helps all precipitate low cost,
highly successful results.
So, key takeaways
out of HEFT.
Uh, capability-driven framework is
probably one of the major efforts
uh, NASA-wide transformational changes
is gonna be important, and I think we
have the leadership who is
ready to embrace that and
has been.  Um,
engaging in that
activity fairly vigorously.
Um, SLS
and MPCV are the core
first elements.
We do need to invest in some of our long term
capabilities.  Robotic precursors
are necessary if we're gonna actually go to
a NEA.  Um,
this is a fundamental change
but I believe it's, uh,
it's the right approach.  And not
so ironically, uh,
when we briefed the Russians
after 18 months of studying
uh, recently unveiled, I briefed this for
two and half hours, they briefed their
two hour deal
And they said, "Hey, we have a capability driven
framework and we want to work collaboratively."
And, I was actually shocked.
And, I talked to, uh,
I talked to, uh, talked to their folks afterward
and they said, "Why would you be surprised?"
We have the same political and economic
dynamics, this is just a reflection
of that and it's probably the modern paradigm
going forward, because no agency,
no single entity, can afford to
do beyond LEO exploration, uh,
alone.  And, so, last but not least,
uh,
this last one is a
Bryan O'Conner-ism, our
Chief Safety and Mission Assurance Officer.
We gotta have compelling, overarching mission
goals necessary to justify
the risks we're taking and the resources we're
laying out.  And that's
what it's all about, is laying that long term vector--
boots on Mars, sustained human
presence.  So,
In the next
3 minutes, I'll just say, OK,
that's HEFT.  Now we've been continuing
on, we had a framework-- human exploration
framework-- now this is
the human architecture team
this is what's building it.  It's
cross agency, multi-disciplinary.
We're working the international,
we're working the multi-destinations.
Um,
Recent activities have been
helping, uh, refine the requirements for
SLS and MPCV.
We are working on a margins policy,
and this is not the programmatic margins policy,
but the architecture wide
approach. We've, uh,
we've been refining our international
exploration road map, for the
reasons I mentioned previously.
And, we're updating our technology prioritization.
This shows you how
we've got now a
cycle, a cadence of, this is an
ongoing, evolutionary
uh, sustained architecture
effort for the agency.  We're meshing up
with the program milestones and the
international milestones. And,
you, know, this is what we've done over
the past, we're now looking at a crew of four
for all missions, but
geoservicing mission.  Why?
Because we get more international
offsets there, because we get a two person
EVA capability,
uh, by doing so.
We've been looking at crew
access to geostationary
LEO for servicing missions.
We've been looking at, uh,
at a balance of heavy lift and
and, uh, expendable launch vehicles.
And so, a balance between commercial and government.
We've looked at, uh,
some of our Near Earth Asteroid
missions and we've also looked at a little bit of the
Phobos/Deimos.
These, these
are the design
reference missions.  This is a total org chart.
It's intended to be put in there
because you see everything
in vivid detail is, uh.
We've got one for
low Earth orbit utilization,
uh, HEO/GEO vicinity
with and without
predeployment of assets and resources
there.  Uh, lunar vicinity,
low lunar, lunar surface,
uh, minimum and
full capability, Near Earth Asteroids
all the way out to Mars landing.
And you see the ones, that uh,
we've been emphasizing and
uh, and not, based upon the coloration.
So, um,
this is what's ahead.
We're working on currently
our min equipment lists,
we're looking at the impacts of the
uh, this four person crew
uh, taking a look at those driving
priorities, uh, for the
technologies, focusing on the
destinations ahead.
I don't think I need to spend any time
on that.  We now have
both destination and
element leads.  So this means, we've got
a person or a couple of people who are
bellybuttons for each one of these.
So, it
helps address the challenge that
this isn't just, this
isn't just a chaos and a
destination to nowhere.
We have specific focal points who
own all the work, so we have
one-stop shopping for
Near Earth Asteroids or Moon,
or Mars and, uh,
we have a single bellybutton that
we can leverage on those.
Plus, we have elements leads for each one of these,
so as we look at developing commonalities,
strategies, or as we look at
saying, "How can we leverage the development
dollars we're spending?"
We'll have a single bellybutton to push on for that.
And, so, getting back to
engagement.  We have
a ten center team.
These are some of the people you see for the destination
in Space, Lunar, Near
Earth Objects or Near Earth Asteroids and
Mars.  And,
likewise, for the element team support, you can
see each one of those functional areas
and the people.  But, these are just
the focal leads and I highly encourage
every single one of you guys
to engage: young, middle
old-- everybody.
Uh, this is our future.
This is how we collectively
uh, harness that going forth.
So, bottom line is, we are
we are absolutely
looking forward to a robust future.
Our best days are not behind us.
We've had some incredible ones,
but our best days are before us.
And it's about extending and imagining
and bringing to fruition
uh, a
sustained human presence beyond a
low Earth orbit.  We've got the bucks to do so.
It's not unlimited dollars, but
that's a great thing.
It's enough to get the job done and we need to
go do it.  We need to be safe and
affordable.  We've got some significant
progress.  We're not starting from
scratch.  We're kick and start.
We've kick started at building off
of shuttle, station and constellation.
Um, and, uh,
our next challenge is to
execute.  And, I think
that brings, uh, I think that brings
uh, everything into bright
focus. So,
um, I would just like to say is,
is the prospects for the
future I believe are truly awesome.
And so, with that, I would like to
um, turn it over next to
Garry, who will give you
uh, a very detailed
and no doubt, riveting
set of insights into the
SLS game plan.
[ Audience applause ]