[PEOPLE SHOUTING]
JACOB SOBOROFF: The
world's biggest party
is going on right now.
Carnaval kicked off last Friday.
Millions of people
converge in the streets
of Brazil's major cities for
five days of nonstop dancing,
partying, and
parades before Lent.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
JACOB SOBOROFF: If you want
to be a part of the action,
you're in luck.
YouTube Carnaval is live
streaming four hours
of events and concerts from
Salvador every single night.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[FANS SHOUTING]
JACOB SOBOROFF: Guys,
tune in right now,
because it all
ends on Wednesday.
We got a playlist for
you after the show,
with even more Carnaval fun
from all across the country.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
EARNEST, SR.: In
honor of Carnaval,
I give you this Brazilian
masterpiece, quite possibly
the largest stop-motion film
ever made-- in square miles.
Using everything from street
signs to garbage cans,
several graffiti artists
painted works of art
all over Sao Paulo, then pieced
them together for this film.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
EARNEST, SR.: 21st century
art set to 1950s music
is a beauty unto itself.
Head over to Rodrigo's
channel so you
can see this and the other
great videos he's made.
JACOB SOBOROFF: A young pelican
swims ashore after a storm
and is taught to fly by a human.
Separated from his
family, the people who
found him literally ran up
and down the beach flapping
their arms to show this
little guy what to do,
and then this happened.
[MUSIC PLAYING, SOUND OF
PELICAN'S WINGS FLAPPING]
JACOB SOBOROFF: This
video was just released.
It is so majestic, so
beautiful, we had to share it.
CARLY: I'm a huge fan of Laci
Green because she answers
all of the questions that
the rest of us weenies
are too afraid to ask.
In her newest episode,
she enlists the help
of a friend to
discuss what sex is
like for people
with disabilities.
OLIVIA: There is
actually a fetish
for people who
have disabilities.
It's called devotees.
Or if you want to be
more specific for people
who use wheelchairs, it's
called a chair chaser.
But at the same time,
if you remove the person
from the disability and if
you just note the disability,
what is the relationship about?
CARLY: Laci's been an incredibly
positive force in the community
since 2008, and she currently
has the top sex ed channel.
Her work is definitely
something that
is very near and
dear to my heart.
If you're not familiar with
it, head over to her channel
and check it out.
You've got a lot of
catching up to do.
JACOB SOBOROFF: Cub reporter
Steve Goldbloom is desperately
trying to get the story,
and I do mean desperately.
The latest episode of
this mockumentary series
follows Steve as he investigates
the online dating scene.
STEVE GOLDBLOOM:
I understand we're
going to set up
a profile for me.
RACHEL SELIGER: We are going
to set up your profile.
[CAMERA SHUTTER NOISE]
STEVE GOLDBLOOM: Yep,
that's an odd one.
RACHEL SELIGER: How
tall are you, really?
STEVE GOLDBLOOM:
I would say 6'2".
RACHEL SELIGER: Be honest.
STEVE GOLDBLOOM: 5'11".
Nice to meet you.
LEAH: Oh.
STEVE GOLDBLOOM:
You look lovely.
LEAH: I don't like oysters.
STEVE GOLDBLOOM: Oysters
are great. [COUGHING]
Thank you.
LEAH: Thanks.
STEVE GOLDBLOOM: It was fun.
LEAH: Oh, what a nightmare.
STEVE GOLDBLOOM: Ah,
you still have our mic.
JACOB SOBOROFF: The series is
centered around the technology
start-up scene, and last episode
he focused on ride-sharing apps
like Lyft and Uber.
And somehow he managed to
steal a Tesla along the way.
STEVE GOLDBLOOM: If
wanted to try driving--
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah, you
could totally do it.
You should try.
STEVE GOLDBLOOM: I'm
an excellent driver.
[CAR HORN BLARING]
STEVE GOLDBLOOM: Sorry.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Steve?
STEVE GOLDBLOOM: Yeah.
[PASSENGERS SINGING]
[SHOUTING]
STEVE GOLDBLOOM: God!
I see him.
I saw him.
JACOB SOBOROFF: They're
posting new ones every week.
Make sure to
subscribe to keep up
with Stevie G's
in-depth investigations.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
BENJAMIN CRUTCHER:
Hey, Youtube Nation,
are you guys looking for a
video of a woman tap dancing
while playing the saxophone
inside of a bubble?
Well, Dreamy Sax is
the video for you.
[SAXOPHONE DANCE MUSIC PLAYING]
JACOB SOBOROFF: Thanks, Ben.
Believe it or not,
that's actually
an ad for an event
planning company in India.
We need you guys right
here on the show.
Film yourself
talking about a video
you love and then post it with
the hashtag #YOUTUBENATION.
Finally, we just
want to take a moment
to celebrate an
animator that we love
who just reached
half a million subs.
Play us out, Domics.
[MUSIC - THE DIRTY TEES, "MORE
COWBELL"]
Thanks, everyone.