KEVIN JONES: So here we
are in this crazy
place, Red Rocks, Colorado.
And we're at the "TB20"
premiere.
MIKE HATCHETT: TB is
Totally Board, and
20 is our 20th film.
Feel like we accomplished
something there, and feel like
that was a major, I
guess, milestone.
Whatever-- sounds kind of cheesy
or whatever, but to get
to 20 years, I'm happy to be
able to actually work in the
snowboard industry
for 20 years.
TRAVIS ROBB: When you
hit a 20-year
thing, it's a big deal.
It's more about everybody at
this point that's ever been
involved, ever put
effort into it.
That's really what the
movie's about.
DAVE HATCHETT: I honestly never
envisioned that Standard
Films would last this long.
And we have definitely outlasted
every other film
company out there.
We were before they
all started, and
we're still there now.
JIM RIPPEY: Standard films is
notorious for getting up
early, and getting onto those
obstacles, and getting out
there and getting the shots.
And it takes a lot
of hard work.
And that's a big part
of their success.
KEVIN JONES: There wasn't
6,000 film crews
like there is today.
If you wanted to have any kind
of living back then, you had
to make it in Standard
Films, period.
[CHEERING]
MIKE HATCHETT: Yeah, so we're
here at Alpine Meadows, and we
got a triple line built--
three jumps in a row.
Kind of like a rhythm section,
like a moto section.
So we're lucking out,
killer weather.
25 foot of snow base
here still.
Record snow year
here in Tahoe.
Could be sick.
GJERMUND BRATEN: This
is the line I'd like
to pull a Four Loko.
I had a Four Loko at the
after party last night.
-Did you?
Ooh.
GJERMUND BRATEN: Killed me.
MIKE HATCHETT: One person
should shoot right here.
This is cool.
I like this.
GJERMUND BRATEN: I was so stoked
to get invited to shoot
with Standard.
It's especially big because it's
"TB20," and that's kind
of a big deal.
[MUSIC - MEAN JEANS, "STEVE
DON'T PARTY NO MORE]
[CHEERING]
JEREMY JONES: I feel like
Standard Films not only had a
huge influence on snowboarding
but in action
sports movies in general.
DAVE HATCHETT: If it's
snowboarding, we show it.
We're not a freestyle company.
We're not a big mountain
film company.
We show rails, we show park, we
show backcountry booters,
we show it all.
JEREMY JONES: Putting all their
energy on getting the
best riders, filming them all
season, and whittling down
their stuff to three-minute
parts where you just show the
best stuff, and really
letting the
snowboarding do the talking.
[MUSIC - MEAN JEANS, "STEVE
DON'T PARTY NO MORE]
-Yeah!
MIKE HATCHETT: Yeah, Gulli!
Nice work.
That was sick.
When I got out of school, I
imagined myself as a fashion
photographer or a commercial
photographer, shooting fruit
and toothpaste or
whatever-- cars.
I was going to be in the
studio with a flash.
I wasn't thinking about
shooting snowboarding.
And then Dave invited me out
to go rock climbing.
And he takes me climbing for
the day, and I'm kind of
checking their scene out.
I'm like, how long you guys
staying here for?
Two months.
Two months?
In your car, living
in your car?
That lifestyle never
occurred to me.
Then he invites me out
to go snowboarding,
which I'd never done.
Got hooked on that pretty
much instantly.
DAVE HATCHETT: I just told him,
man, you've got to come
up here and check
this sport out.
This is going to be awesome.
It's really, really
fun, and it's so
much funner than skiing.
And you're going to really dig
it because it's like surfing.
MIKE HATCHETT: I think
by the third weekend,
I'm like, fuck school.
I'm getting out of here.
I'm going to go live in
my car for two years.
DAVE HATCHETT: Mike and I
started this film company
called Fusion Films, which was
kind of a precursor to
Standard Films.
And we really just--
we went in the backcountry,
because we
needed to get footage.
And the ski resorts will just
get chopped up so quick, and
it just wasn't aesthetically
that rad to film.
So we were just looking across
the street from Donner Ski
Ranch, and we just knew it was
all virgin, untracked powder,
and it was a lot easier to work
back there and get shots.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
DAVE HATCHETT: It was is just
the very first times that
anyone filmed snowboarding in
the backcountry or anywhere.
So we kind of got this idea,
I'll be the rider.
Mike will be the
cinematographer.
We'll get some friends of ours,
and we'll all just be
together, and we'll
make this movie.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
DAVE HATCHETT: The movie
came out pretty good.
It was a pretty fun
to watch movie.
At the time, it was
cutting edge.
And financially,
it just bombed.
We just didn't sell
enough videos.
And then we tried to get
sponsorship again the next
year, and it didn't happen.
MIKE HATCHETT: After we had made
"Totally Board," I worked
for Fall Line Films
for two years.
And Dave and I--
Dave was filming
with Mack Dawg.
And Dave's like, dude, you and
Mack Dawg should start your
own company.
Jerry and Artie aren't
treating you very
good at Fall Line.
And it was his, actually,
idea.
You guys should put the big
mountain stuff in with the
freestyle, and we should
make a movie.
JIM RIPPEY: So they basically
said, hey, let's meet the
minds, and let's create
something together that brings
both aspects of snowboarding.
You go to Alaska and get your
big mountain riding.
We'll mix the best of that big
mountain riding with all the
jibbing and freestyle
park type stuff.
DAVE HATCHETT: We were just
pretty much just sitting in
the house one day, and I said
hey, let's send out a proposal
and see if we can kind of try
and do what we did with Fusion
Films, but let's just do it
in a new environment.
Maybe we can get sponsorship
this time.
And within a week, we raised
about $80,000 through Wave
Rave and Burton and several
other sponsors.
And that was kind of when
Standard Films was born.
That year, we made Standard
Films' first movie, "TB2--A
New Way of Thinking."
This season at Lake Tahoe is the
season I've been waiting
for all my life.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
TOM BURT: It turned out that
most of the areas that people
ride were developed by us.
Almost everything was
new, besides for--
there's a handful of backcountry
skiers who had
been skiing things, but not
necessarily like what we were
looking for as far as steeper,
more technical lines.
DAVE HATCHETT: Me and Tom Burt
were some of the first guys to
ever jump the I-80 drop, which
is a big famous drop that all
the film crews race to now.
It's a big 50-foot, pretty
good sized drop.
And all throughout the Tahoe
backcountry, we definitely did
several first descents, and we
were certainly the first film
crews to go out there and work
certain areas and certain
circs and ride certain lines,
without a doubt.
JIM RIPPEY: The Hatchetts were
basically filming the kind of
stuff that I wanted to ride
anyway, so it fit perfectly.
I like to ride freestyle and
ride in the parks, but I also
wanted to go to places like
Alaska and get on the steep
stuff that really got
my adrenaline going.
JEREMY JONES: They were really,
at that time, defining
how to shoot skiing or
snowboarding in Alaska.
And a lot of the stuff that
they developed over those
years is just kind of second
nature in that whole big
mountain scene.
DAVE DOWNING: I mean, I saw
"TB2" when it came out, and it
blew me away.
The whole thing blew me away--
the Alaska footage.
Terry's whole part is, like,
five minutes long and it's all
at Squaw Valley.
And it's just crazy.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
TRAVIS ROBB: Along the way, all
those guys did something
that stuck with the people and
inspired them to pursue board
sport culture.
DAVE HATCHETT: We definitely
became recognized as one of
the biggest film companies in
the industry for quality of
cinematography and the quality
of the writing.
So that's something that
Standard Films will always be
known for, is just a really
high-quality product.
JEREMY JONES: Part of me is
pissed off at those guys
because they did hold such a
high standard that it was like
you could do something amazing,
but you let go of
your grab too early, and it's
on the floor, because it
wasn't just perfect.
[MUSIC PLAYING]