Cave Hotel
Is a large and commodious establishment
capable of entertaining 500 guests.
It is constructed on the cottage plan
and the rooms are furnished in a style equal to any first class hotel.
It is the beau ideal of a fashionable summer resort
in the South.
A magnificent ball room is attached to the Hotel.
Curious Sand-Stone Rock
Excavated near the cave about 15 years since,
and now to be seen in the hotel yard.
Path Leading to the Mouth of Cave
Is about a quarter of a mile in length
extending from the hotel
through a gorge in a dense wood.
Visitors generally supply themselves with stout branches from the trees
to assist themselves in their explorations of the rugged paths of the cave.
Out for the Last Time
This is a picture of the gentlemen who conceived
and executed the project
of Photographing the cave,
with the reflectors and etcetera used.
Mouth of the Cave
is 194 feet above Green River,
125 feet in height by
30 in width.
In summer visitors experience a sudden change of temperature when
they stand on the embankment
above the entrance
and a cold blast rushes out from the cave,
the temperature is invariably 59 degrees.
The scene, looking down towards the immediate entrance,
a distance of 100 yards
is picturesque in the extreme
and impresses the beholder
with a feeling of awe at the contemplation of the subterraneous
world beneath his feet.
Mouth of the Cave
This view introduces three well know guides.
The one on the right is old Mat,
he has acted in the capacity of guide for the last 30 years.
Gothic Chapel
A mile from the entrance is a large room
from the ceiling of which hang gigantic stalactites, extending to the floor.
It is represented here as it appeared when lightedup with magnesium light,
the glare of which may be seen behind the columns on the right.
Column of Hercules
Is also in the Gothic Chapel.
It is formed by the union of stalactites and stalagmites
is eight feet in height
and thirty in circumference.
The length of time necessary to form such a column
may be inferred from the fact that it takes fifty years to form
an incrustation no thicker than a wafer.
The Altar
In the foreground is a cluster of columns called the Altar,
at which a romantic marriage took place between two parties
whose union on the face of the earth
was prevented by family interference.
Devil's Arm Chair,
In Gothic Avenue is a large column about 500 yards beyond the chapel.
There is a niche or seat
and which one of the guides maybe seen sitting.
The ceiling of Gothic Avenue
singularly beautiful
as the stalactites assume the most fantastic shapes.
In the niche of this column
the celebrated Jenny Lind rested for some time
during her visit to the cave.
End of Gothic Avenue
The avenue terminates about a half mile beyond the chapel
at "Elephant's Head" and "Lover's Leap."
The former is a large stalagmite
shaped like the head of the animal after which it is named
and the latter is a rock projecting 16 feet
over a black abyss.
Wandering Willie's Spring
trickling down from the roof and the wall of rock
on the left hand side of the Main Cave
beyond the Rotunda and Methodist Church.
It is named after a country violinist who wandered away from his party,
had his lamp extinguished
and was found lying asleep beside the spring.
On the left will be observed some names of visitors
cut on the rock.
The spring is about half a mile from the entrance.
Standing Rocks
Are fifteen feet in length and many tons in weight
and evidently fell from the roof of the cave
at a time when the entire cave was filled with water.
They stand in a upright position
and are 3/4 of a mile from the entrance.
Entrance to Rocky Hall
Looking from Main Cave.
A few feet beyond Standing Rocks
to the left of Main Cave is Rocky Hall.
It is reached by ascending a few steps on rocks piled up at the entrance.
Giant's Coffin
Is an immense rock 40 feet long,
twenty wide and eight high,
which has been detached from the avenue against which it rests.
On the left
beneath the coffin may be seen a narrow passage
which leads into Deserted Chamber.
Giant's Coffin presents a gloomy sepulchral appearance
when lighted up by the glare of the magnesium light.
It is on the right of Main Cave,
one mile from the entrance.
Entrance to Long Route,
Is on the left of Giant's Coffin and so narrow and low that visitors
have to stoop almost to almost to the ground in passing through it.
On the right may be seen the end of Giant's Coffin.
By some it is supposed that the water receded from the main cave
through this passage.
Deserted Chamber,
Is a dreary looking room about 100 feet in length.
The guide in the picture is entering the chamber
from the narrow passage beneath the Giant's Coffin.
In Wooden Bowl Chamber
adjoining this apartment
curious looking Indian bowl was found.
The Indians used long reeds
filled with deer's fat
as torches to guide them through the cave.
Gorin's Dome
Is 200 feet high and 60 wide.
It is reached by descending from the Deserted Chamber
to a narrow rugged causeway called the Labyrinth, passing over a small bridge
and ascending a ladder.
The far side appears like an immense curtain.
When there is a rise in the subterraneous rivers,
the floor of the dome is covered with water
in which eyeless fish are caught.
The view is taken half way between the roof and the floor.
It is called after one of the former proprietors of the cave.
Bottomless Pit and Bridge of Sighs,
Are on the main route to Echo River
and mile-and-a-half from the entrance
The pit is of a immense depth and over it
is thrown a substantial wooden bridge,
across which visitors pass
in the long route and
towards Pensacola Avenue.
The pit presents a sight of awful sublimity
hen its steep sides are lighted
up by the guide.
View From Bridge of Sighs,
Shows a part of Shelby?s Dome overhanging the terrible pit.
It is wild and dreary beyond conception.
The dark avenue to the right is inaccessible to human footsteps,
that is supposed to lead a vast distance
further into the bowels of he earth.
Beyond The Bridge of Sighs,
This view represents two of the guides, just having crossed the bridge towards Reveler's Hall.
They are facing the Bottomless Pit,
overhanging which is the rock in the foreground.
Pit Beneath the Bridge,
Here are the steep sides of the Bottomless Pit
far below the bridge.
The view was taken from a narrow ledge of rocks overhanging the fearful chasm.
The rock on the right projects 30 feet
and extends from the brink of the pit
to 50 feet below the bridge.
Wild Hall,
Is in Pensacola Avenue.
The floor is strewn with immense rocks
that have become detached from the roof.
The cliffs on the left are called the Snow Cliffs,
as they seem to be covered with flakes of snow.
It is two miles from the entrance.
Snowball Archway,
Is also in Pensacola Avenue.
The ceiling of white gypsum looks as if it was covered with snow
and presents a most beautiful appearance.
Symmetry of the natural buttresses which project from the side of the cliff
is also striking and interesting.
Grand Crossing
Is in Pensacola Avenue.
Here four large avenues branch off from the main one.
The rocks here are completely covered
with the names of visitors scratched on them.
Grand Crossing is about 2 miles and a 1/4 from the entrance.
Angelica's Grotto
Is also in Pensacola Avenue.
The little girl in the picture
is resting on Angelica's Couch
over the foot of which hangs the Pine Apple Bush,
a curious looking rock.
Scotchman's Trap
Is on the road to the river,
about 500 yards beyond the Bottomless Pit.
The trap is a small circular opening
through which it is necessary to descend a few steps
to go toward the river.
Over this narrow opening is
suspended a huge rock many tons in weight,
which, if it fell
would completely close up the avenue leading to the Echo River.
The guide in the picture is
standing at the head of the steps.
Dinning in Great Relief
Is entered after passing through the narrow, tortuous passage
called Fat Man's Misery.
It is indeed a relief
for the aching bones of the
visitor after threading the narrow path above mentioned
and the dinner party in the picture
seem to think so.
One of the guides is pouring out some of
Kentucky's unrivaled beverage,
Bourbon Whiskey,
for the relief of his companions.
Bacon Chamber
Is situated to the right of River Hall which is entered from Great Relief.
The curious projections from the roof
resembling flitches of bacon, are caused by the action of water at a period when
the chamber was completely filled with water.
It is one of the best views taken in the cave.
Is immediately above Bacon Chamber
and at the commencement of Spark's Avenue which leads to Mammoth Dome.
Several unexplored avenues branch off here in every direction.
The scene represents a party of bandits
at dinner and as reviewed by the magnesium light
exceeds in Romantic wildness the most extravagant conceptions of Salvator Rosa.
Pillars in Mammoth Dome
The Mammoth Dome is one of the largest in the world.
It is 250 feet in height
and of immense size.
Those pillars are of
colossal dimensions
and standing beneath them
one would imagine himself amid the ruins
of some Egyptian temple.
Corinthian Columns
Those columns are at the furthest extremity of Mammoth Dome
and resemble the broken columns of the Acropolis of Athens and Corinth.
Cliffs Over the Dead Sea
The Dead Sea is a black ominous looking body of water,
about 40 feet below the terrace
on which the three persons in the picture are standing.
Visitors pass along the terrace
and descend the ladder on their way to the river.
The sea lies below the foot of the rock
over which the parties in the view are looking.
Ole Bull?s Concert Room
Is a mile and a half beyond Echo River
and five miles from the entrance.
from the entrance. It is at the end of Silliman?s Avenue.
The black gorge to the right
is the entrance to Pass of El Ghor.
he celebrated violinist performed in this room during his visit to the cave.
Hanging Rocks
Are in the Pass of El Ghor
about a mile from Ole Bull?s concert room.
Visitors experience much uneasiness
in passing under these rocks,
as they seem to be on the point of tumbling down on their heads,
but since the discovery of the cave,
no rocks have been known to fall
in any part of it.
Martha's Vineyard
Is elevated about 20 feet above the Pass of El Ghor
and receives it name from the appearance,
shape and size of the dark stalactites formations on the side and roof
which closely resemble grapes
Martha?s Vineyard is six miles and a half from the entrance.
Grape Clusters
This view shows a section of the side of Martha?s Vineyard
and sufficiently explains the meaning of the name
which has been given it.
The entire walls of the vineyard
are covered with pendant clusters of mineral grapes.
Snowball Chamber
Is about a quarter of a mile beyond Martha?s Vineyard.
The roof seems to be one mass of snowballs
each of which is from 2 to 4 inches in diameter.
Mary's Bower
Is situated in Cleveland?s Cabinet
The flowers here represented are of a very delicate formation.
Rosa?s Bower
Is another section of the roof in Cleveland?s Cabinet
and consists of a beautiful collection of gypsum flowers
resembling roses and dahlias.
Cross and Flower Garden
Represent a section of the roof of Cleveland?s Cabinet.
Two crevices intersect each other at right angles
and are lined with beautiful flowers formed of plaster of Paris.
the last rose of summer
This is one of the most beautiful gypsum formations in the cave.
It is eight inches in diameter
and of snowy whiteness.
The distance from the entrance to this point in Cleveland Cabinet is 7 and a half miles
and from here to the end of the Long Route one and a half miles.