Even from the land up, this
area is just in a constant
state of
That woman's shirt says
Vagina Warrior.
Goma's the capitol city of the
North Kivu Province of the
Democratic Republic of Congo,
and is situation in one of the
world's worst geopolitical
neighborhoods.
To the southeast, there's the
Rwandan border, which largely
consists of mountain jungles
through which scores of Hutu
militants passed in the wake of
the 1994 Rwandan genocide,
fleeing the revenge of President
Paul Kagame's newly
elected Tutsi government for
their role in the massacre.
This armed migration directly
contributed to the escalation
of the First and Second Congo
Wars, in which an estimated 5
million people lost
their lives.
It was also through this
transportation corridor that
the Lord's Resistance Army,
led by the infamous Joseph
Kony, crossed the border from
Uganda and drove deep into the
heart of the Congo.
While "Kony 2012" drew a lot
of criticism for being less
than diligent when it came to
framing the quote unquote
"facts" the documentary cited,
what it did reveal is that the
best way to reach jungle-bound
dissidents wasn't through
social media, but through
good, old fashioned
psychological operations--
mostly in the tried and true
forms of leaflet drops and
radio broadcasts.
-We don't benefit anything
if we lie to you.
We want to make sure
you see the facts.
And I'm sure you're going to
decide to enter the DDR
process voluntarily.
THOMAS MORTON: So when the
United Nations extended an
invitation to embed with their
operation in several locations
across the country, our
team gladly accepted.
IAN ROWE: DDR is the
Desarmement, Demobilization,
Repatriation, Reinsertion, and
Reintegration Program.
The focus of the program is on
foreign commands that are
operating in the Congo.
There's national reintegration
programs which take over and
facilitate their reinsertion
into their
communities of origin.
The main approach that DDRRR
has for trying to convince
voluntary surrenders for
subsequent repatriation is by
radio sensitization.
This involves using radio
messages over FM networks.
THOMAS MORTON: FM
Uruguay 106.7.
Siempre presente
only the hits.
All rock, no talk.
-[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
IAN ROWE: There's messages
calling for them to lay down
their weapons and return home.
It lets them know that it is
still possible to go home.
THOMAS MORTON: Um-hm.
IAN ROWE: Hope is not lost.
Their families will be waiting
for them and there's programs
that will help them reinsert
into their society.
-This is one of our camps,
the transit camp.
And in this camp, we feed
them three times a day.
We provide them lodging, not
this best one that you may
think about, because we want
to keep that temporarily so
that they can go back
to their country.
We also give them access to
telephone so that they can
call their friends, relatives,
and loved ones.
-[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
-Now, I will like to invite
Mr. [INAUDIBLE]
to address the ceremony.
THOMAS MORTON: Oh,
that's cool.
I guess it's supposed to
represent peace of some sort,
but it kind of looks like one
of those evil war birds from
Pink Floyd's The Wall.
So we're out on MONUSCO Base,
the far eastern side, right on
the border with Rwanda
and Uganda.
There's a whole bunch of rebel
groups that kind of mix and
merge and cross borders and
take over this place.
It's a real mess.
The one most people know about,
the Lord's Resistance
Army, or LRA, are kind of the
most notorious for their
tactics, for using child
soldiers, for abducting
people, for setting
entire churches
full of folks on fire.
There's another group called
the M23, and are actually
officially about 20 or 40
kilometers outside the city
center, but we've heard
closer to 10.
These wars have been going on
since the '90s in different
little spurts.
It's basically a permanent
state of war for
the Congolese people.
It just varies, who they're
fighting, at any one given
time of the day.
And so we're going to go with a
little patrol, hopefully not
get shot at.
-[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
THOMAS MORTON: We got into
Goma this morning.
We just hooked up with a troop
of Uruguay and UN soldiers who
are going to give us a little
tour of the city--
see what a town that's basically
spent 20 years at
siege of rebel warfare
looks like
Besides the fragmented Lord's
Resistance Army, the
Democratic Republic of Congo
is also home to militant
groups such as the Mai-Mai, the
Raia Mutomboki, and the
Democratic Forces for the
Liberation of Rwanda.
But the greatest threat to
regional stability could very
well be a group known as M23.
Led by Bosco Ntaganda,
affectionately known by his
troops as the Terminator, M23
mostly consists of Congolese
Tutsis who defected from the
army last April after alleging
that the government in Kinshasa
had violated peace
accords signed on March 23,
2009, in which members of the
now defunct CNDP were be
absorbed into the country's
regular army, the FRDC.
The battle between M23 and
government troops has raged so
wildly that the United Nations
has been forced to divert
troops and resources sorely
needed elsewhere in the
country in order to get the
government in Kinshasa a
fighting chance.
This, in turn, has created a
security vacuum in which many
of the armed groups in the area
have rushed in to fill
while reigniting the cycle of
old tribal conflicts that were
never really stamped out
in the first place.
These ethnic and geopolitical
tensions are, in turn,
exacerbating an already raging
fight between local militias
to control the illicit mining
of cassiterite, wolframite,
and coltan, minerals essential
to the manufacturing of
everything from smartphones
to jet engines to airbags.
Complicating matters further, it
is widely believed that M23
is receiving aid from
the governments
of Rwanda and Uganda.
And it has been reported that
the FDRC has approached the
Hutu Mai-Mai for aid in fighting
the largely Tutsi
M23, background information
largely omitted when President
Obama ordered 100 US Special
Forces to support regional
powers in their search for our
favorite madman of Facebook.
BARACK OBAMA: And when the
Lord's Resistance Army, led by
Joseph Kony, continued its
atrocities in Central Africa,
I ordered a small number of
American advisers to help
Uganda and its neighbors
pursue the LRA.
THOMAS MORTON: So I'm not a big
fan of the UN, in general.
The track record has
been spotty for
all the 65, 67 years.
They're famous for bringing
the sex trade.
It's basically anywhere
they set up shop.
As our team's tank patrol
policed the streets of Goma's
poorest neighborhoods, as well
as power plants, airstrips,
and crossroads--
the kind of places a rebel army
would likely attack--
it became clear the UN troops
were not preparing for a
jungle assault, but for a
potential attack by M23 on
Goma itself.
So obviously, the UN's here,
on what they describe as a
peacekeeping mission.
They're supposed to mediate
between all the different
rebel groups and end the
factions of army.
There's different sections.
The Congolese army, the Rwandan
army, and the Ugandan
armies do come in here.
So it's supposed to be,
basically, the babysitter, the
grown-ups here.
At the time, you're in a tank
and they're soldiers.
Little boy's like it, but it
makes it feel kind of a little
weird, like you're in
an occupying army.
I can't help but notice we've
only really been in town.
And it's kind of weird just
to do a city patrol.
It's almost more like you're
policing the local population
than on the lookout
for rebel groups.
Maybe there's something to be
said for trying to convince
locals not to go take
up arms with M23.
In the weeks that followed our
initial visit to Goma,
skirmishes between M23,
Congolese troops, and the UN
increased with regularity
at strategic locations
surrounding the city, with
rebels even beginning to
attack food, fuel, and supply
convoys into town.
Later, the UN invited our team
to visit a camp in Goma set up
to house rebel combatants who
had recent surrendered to both
the UN and FDRC.
IAN ROWE: When escapees do come
out, they're typically,
at the moment, received by a
community member that they
perhaps cross in the road, or in
the jungle, on their route,
or something like that, and
brought to the FRDC or to our
military camp, where they'll
be kept in our transit camp
for maximum a week, within
in which time they'll be
processed in terms of getting
their information, details,
start doing the tracing
for their families.
We make contact with the Amnesty
Commission in Uganda.
And our counterparts in
Entebbe-Kampala will meet us
at the airport and we'll do a
hand-over, after which they'll
be reintegrated via whatever
systems Uganda has in place.
-[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
IAN ROWE: From the women that
have been abducted and kept as
bush wives, oftentimes the
reason that they're released
is because they've been slowing
down the LRA group
that they're associated with.
And so the fighters in the group
made the decision that,
for the purposes of allowing
them to be more rapid moving,
they would release these
women and children.
THOMAS MORTON: Now, when you
say bush wives, that's a
polite way of saying, like,
sex slave, basically.
IAN ROWE: Yes.
These are women that have been
abducted and used for sex as
porters, all these most negative
kind of uses that you
could enumerate.
THOMAS MORTON: Built on the
ruins of a home previously
belonging to deposed Congolese
dictator Joseph Mobutu, the
camp was split along ethnic and
administrative lines with
only a chain-link fence
separating Hutu and Tutsi
fighters, who out in the bush
had been spilling each other's
blood by the bucket
for decades.
The camp in Goma's indicative
of the DRC's confusing
geopolitical turmoil.
Combatants staying at the campus
must first surrender
and hand over their weapons to
UN or government troops, after
which they are processed
and held for 72 hours.
A portion of the residents are
from Rwanda, from which they
fled to the DRC, joined a
militia, became hired guns,
and now want to return home.
Other campers are Congolese who
fought with local Hutu and
Tutsi militias before
surrendering.
But there is also a contingent
of Rwandan farmers who pose as
ex-rebels in order to hitch a
free ride with the UN back
across the boarder.
To determine their status and
surmise their identities and
countries of origin, they're
quizzed on local facts and
subjected to fingerprinting
and retinal scans.
The camp is an element of a UN
program designed to transform
rebels into civilians,
reintegrating them back into
society, or what's left of it.
As the camp's public information
officer, Sam
Howard, gave us a walking tour
of the side of the camp where
some M23 fighters were housed,
it became apparent that no one
from the UN wanted to talk to
our team about the confusing
three-way battle raging between
the M23 mutineers, the
UN, and the FDRC.
They were, however, more than
happy to discuss other arm
groups that are now less active,
such as Joseph Kony
and his LRA fighters--
just not the real rebels
standing next to us.
The crumbling security situation
in North Kivu has
forced the hand of the UN and
sparked a massive reallocation
of UN assets to Goma
from places like
Dungu, Duru, and Bangadi.
In the Orientale Province,
places where the LRA were, and
to some degree, still
are active.
THOMAS MORTON: The village of
Dungu sits beside the quiet
Uele River.
The ruin of a Belgian Colonial
castle faces become Kabali
Hydroelectric Power Plant, which
has been defunct for
nearly three decades now.
Beginning in September, 2008,
the Lord's Resistance Army
launched a series of brutal
attacks in Dungu, kidnapping
dozens, killing hundreds,
and displacing an
estimated 87,000 people.
In an unusual display of
brutality, the LRA fighters
put aside their usual AK-47s
and RPGs in favor of the
machete and club.
This brutality is still being
felt in the damage to the
area's already fragile
infrastructure.
And with no standing power grid
or mobile phone network,
the only reliable method of mass
communication are the FM
radio transmitters
made available by
the UN's DDRRR program.
-[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
THOMAS MORTON: Our team first
saw examples of the UN PSYOPS
flyers with Sam Howard back at
the transit camp in Goma.
Each contain instructions in
several languages directing
LRA and other rebel combatants
on the correction procedure
for safely surrendering
for repatriation.
First, if you find a flyer,
look for the correction FM
radio station to tune into
for instructions of
where you can surrender.
Next, when the LRA goes to bed,
make your escape under
the cover of darkness.
Third, surrender to the UN,
FDRC, or another approved
African Union Force.
And finally, you will be
reunited with your strangely
Asian-looking family.
THOMAS MORTON: It's all
just LRA, right?
That's the dominant group.
THOMAS MORTON: Would just
leave the woods.
THOMAS MORTON: Right.
CAESAR ACELLEM:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHEIF MARC:
-[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
THOMAS MORTON: The question
just was have their
communities been affected
by the LRA before
working with DDR?
Just how have the
been affected?
-Of course they're
been affected.
-[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
IAN ROWE: The escapees that come
out, they're obviously
very tentative when
they come out.
THOMAS MORTON: M-hm.
IAN ROWE: Because in the past,
the reaction from the
community, the affected
communities, the ones that
they've attacked or terrorized
in the past, their first
reaction is to kill them.
THOMAS MORTON: The next morning,
our team awoke before
dawn to take a 30-minute
helicopter flight to Bangadi,
an area where the LRA has been
and, to some degree, are still
very active.
-So how long are you
going to stay?
THOMAS MORTON: I think we talked
about being picked up
at 13:20.
-You must know the
timing, also.
THOMAS MORTON: OK.
-So I will be arriving
here at 13:20.
THOMAS MORTON: Yeah, OK.
-Before that, I'll expect that
you finish your job and come
back here by 1:20.
-Yeah, as soon as we finish
the [INAUDIBLE].
-OK?
Because you should not be like
that, because I'm coming,
waiting, and you're not there.
OK?
-I know, of course.
-Because time is calculated
like that.
And we follow the datas.
-Thanks.
THOMAS MORTON: Our team made our
way into Bangadi Center,
where Tahir, our DDR man in
Orientale, had arranged for us
to meet with community leaders
and get a better sense of the
current situation
on the ground.
-We have to go over
there, yeah?
-[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
JEAN:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
Welcome, welcome.
THOMAS MORTON: Thank you.
JEAN:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
BARACK OBAMA: Finally,
never again
is a challenge tenacious.
It's a bitter truth.
Too often the world has failed
to prevent the killing of
innocents on a massive scale.
And we are haunted
by the atrocities
that we did not stop.
THOMAS MORTON: What was it
like before the camp?
Were there UN soldiers?
Was there any sort
of presence?
-No.
No.
THOMAS MORTON: Defensive
presence?
No.
THOMAS MORTON: Mhm.
THOMAS MORTON: Even
though it's Congo?
DANIEL: Yes.
Yes.
THOMAS MORTON: They
were over here.
THOMAS MORTON: Further evidence
of LRA movement could
be found in trail markers that
the under-equipped rebels have
been using to communicate
information between their
small groups.
JEAN:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
-[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
JEAN:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
THOMAS MORTON: Mhm.
JEAN:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
THOMAS MORTON: Mhm.
JEAN:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
JOSEPH:
JEAN:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
THOMAS MORTON: Interested in
hearing a firsthand account of
the LRA's snatch and grab
tactics in the area, our UN
handlers arranged for us to meet
Bolobo, a young man who
had been abducted by the LRA as
a teenager, at one point,
had come face to face with
the elusive Joseph Kony.
BOLOBO:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
-[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
BOLOBO:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
-[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
BOLOBO:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
IAN ROWE: The amnesty law that
used to allow those that came
out of the LRA voluntarily
a degree of amnesty
has now been removed.
And so that's another issue
which has also been
brought to the fore.
This has effectively removed the
best incentive we have in
trying to encourage LRA
combatants to come out.
-[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
JEAN:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
THOMAS MORTON: Mhm.
So just in the middle
of the road.
Did you bury them after that?
JEAN:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
THOMAS MORTON:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]?
JEAN:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
THOMAS MORTON: For the purposes
of kind of disarming
these people and getting them
to surrender, this ain't
helping, you know?
European-style colonialism first
made its way into the
Congo in 1876, after famed
explorer Henry Stanley,
employed by Leopold II of
Belgium, forced tribal chiefs
to sign treaties at gunpoint
that essentially granted all
of their land rights to
the European monarch.
Until 1908, Leopold ran the
Congo as the Congo-Free State,
a private corporation
with him as the sole
shareholder and as chairman.
It soon became clear that the
corporation's profits were
built on a brutal occupation
of the local people and
plunder of the Congo's
natural resources--
namely, rubber.
In 1965, following a series of
coups that ended the relative
stability of the newly
independent nation, Laurent
Mobutu seized control of the
state, changed the country's
name to Zaire, and for over 30
years, lead a brutal regime
built on Mobutu's own
cult of personality.
By way of example, under Mobutu
in a children's school,
Ronald Reagan would have
been referred to as
the American Mobutu.
In May, 1997, Laurent Desire
Kabila, father of the DRC's
current executive Joseph
Kabila, ascended to the
presidency of Zaire and changed
the country's name,
yet again, to the Democratic
Republic of Congo.
Kabila the elder achieved this
regime change through a
rebellion backed by Rwanda and
which included a grand march
from the Kivus across 1,000
miles of some of the world's
densest jungle--
the same feat now threatened
by the rebels of M23.
IAN ROWE: There's a very big
difference from the work that
DDR does in the Kivus
to the work
that they do in Orientale.
Whereas in the Kivus, most of
the combatants that we're
trying to reach are more
easily reachable.
There's a mobile network
system here.
There's the possibility to reach
out and discuss and try
to negotiate with people
to come in.
That doesn't exist
in Orientale.
Up there, you're in the
middle of the jungle.
There's no more mobile
network.
There's no contact with anybody
within the LRA.
There's no peace agreement.
So much of the work is based
a lot on the belief and the
faith that the message is
getting through them.
There's now a new African Union
initiative to implement
a strategy towards countering
the LRA problem.
We also use our troops
on the ground when
they do their patrols.
So we make a point of having
only armed elements doing
that, whether it's from
our side or the FRDC.
THOMAS MORTON: During the
patrol, we had persuaded the
convoy to drop our team off in
Duru, a village hit hard by
the LRA's 2008 Dungu
Offensive.
It is also where, according to
local rumors, a small band of
fighters have been recently
raiding local farms.
There goes our convoy.
There's American J-Op Special
Forces here who are being a
little bit cagey about
what they're doing.
They just took off all of their
insignia before crossing
into South Sudan, including
their little flag patch, which
seems a little intriguing.
There was a national policemen
from Burkina Faso.
He confirmed what we have kind
of been picking up on this
whole time.
The LRA's weak and dead
at this point.
I think it's kind
of hype-driven.
I think the Kony 2012 Facebook
campaign thing has sort of
swayed foreign policy towards
sending troops here instead of
somewhere like Goma, where
there's a huge buildup of M23
troops, which is basically where
we're kind of needed
down here, instead of pursuing
this dead, sort of starving
army of 400 people who
only attack, at this
point, to get food.
We'll hang out here and see
how people are doing four
years after the massacre.
CHIEF CLAUDE:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
-[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
THOMAS MORTON: Go talk to them
and see what the LRA's looking
like these days.
We've heard it isn't so hot.
OYO DIEUDONNE:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
-[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
MARTIN:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHIEF PAUL:
MARTIN:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHIEF PAUL:
MARTIN:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHIEF PAUL:
MARTIN:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHIEF PAUL:
MARTIN:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHIEF PAUL:
MARTIN:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHIEF PAUL:
THOMAS MORTON: Martin circled
the LRA encampment at a safe
distance and waited for
the moon to rise.
After his first shot rang out
across the night sky, the LRA
men, lulled into a false sense
of comfort, laid down their
weapons and promptly
went to sleep.
After the promised knock against
the tree echoed in the
darkness, Martin's son fled.
And the pair made their way
safely back to the village.
THOMAS MORTON: Right.
MARTIN:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHRISTIAN KILUNDU: They
saw a yellow paper.
And these guys, they tried
to read that then.
They got we through the paper
and they just read it.
And then they throw.
And then they said--
[LAUGHING]
THOMAS MORTON: That's
pretty definitive.
Almost everywhere we went, our
team seemed to encounter
conflicting opinions regarding
the reallocation of troops and
equipment across the country.
Regions where the LRA were
still active feared the
security vacuum the had been
left in by the UN and FDRC
movement of troops in support
of the Kivus.
Back in the Kivus, for fear of
showing of their hand to M23,
officials chose to focus on
operations in provinces like
Orientale while seemingly
ignoring the
wolf at their doorstep.
It seems that both fears
were well-founded.
I just walk back over
every piece.
It's funny.
I was expecting to see one in
the dog's mouth, and the
little kid's.
OK.
You ready?
Morning.
We're out looking for hippos
before our flight.
We're leaving town today.
No hippos so far.
I think they might still be
in the grass, which is
disappointing, but also kind
of an apt metaphor
for the LRA up here.
One thing that's sort of
becoming clear, especially
seeing all the NGOs here, all
the UN presence, all the
different agencies, Invisible
Children are a good
organization, despite the fact
that "Kony 2012" is a fucked
up piece of shit.
And there's this attitude that
you see with all sorts of
NGOs, that they have, you know,
a very narrow focus.
They're focused on one issue in
a region, which is the way
you do things.
You concentrate, and
you specialize.
But in an area as complex
as Eastern Congo, where
everything's connected, you
focus your troops up in the
north, where the LRA is.
You beat them in a manner of
speaking, but all they've
really done is, as I keep
saying, atomize the troops.
They split off into little
groups of one and three.
They hid in the bush.
And now taking them down as
a force is going to be
impossible.
It's going to take years
and years and years.
These guys are going
to stay here, and
they've reverted to banditry.
At the same time, the groups in
the South, like the Mai-Mai
and the M23, have taken
advantage of the focus of
attention on LRA to build
up their forces.
Now, they're a major threat
to the Lake Kivu area.
BOUDOUIN NGARUYE:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
-[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
BENJAMIN MBONIMPA:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
THOMAS MORTON: Day by day, we
can solve one piece at a time.
And there's no real
way to do that.
Solutions will come.
The situation will improve
eventually.
But this is 20 years of war.
That shit lingers.
People take it in.
And it becomes part
of their lives.
War and retribution and the
cycles that are continuing to
make it worse are a
part of life here.
This camp's going to be
here for a while.
These soldiers are all going
to be here for a while.
People are going to be fighting
and dying for a long
fucking time, no matter
how many people
sign a Facebook petition.
[TROOPS CHANTING]