Almost all Awa families
keep a number of monkey pets.
There are eight different species
in the village.
The Awa show extraordinary
tenderness for the little monkeys,
believing they're more human
than animal.
Emwi is a devoted mother,
both to her children and her monkeys.
For
Emwi and the other Awa,
breastfeeding monkeys is simply
a natural way to help an orphan in need.
Caring so intimately for an animal
they regularly kill
may appear contradictory,
but the Awa believe for everything
they take from the forest,
they have to give back.
When our lives are so deeply
entwined with animals and plants,
they inevitably become
a great source of inspiration.
Perhaps the most spectacular case
of culture imitating nature
is found amongst the people
of Papua New Guinea.
Deep in the forest,
a male superb bird of paradise struts
his stuff for a rather drab female
but she isn't the only one watching.
Geling is a bird of paradise hunter
and it's the highly prized feathers
he's after.
These coveted plumes are passed
down through generations
but occasionally damaged ones
need replacing.
Birds of paradise are so hard to hunt,
however, that Geling's enlisted help.
Peke is after the long tail feathers
of the Princess Astrapia,
and he's using fruit to lure them in
Tomorrow is a big day for Geling.
His clan will be performing
at a Sing Sing,
where his reputation
and the honour of his village
will be judged on the quality
of his feather collection.
Sing Sing events are all about competing
to see who's the best-dressed,
and Geling knows not a plume
can be out of place.
In both birds and humans,
it's the most eye-catching
who gets the most attention,
though Geling might be
overstating his conquests.
(CHANTING)
The Mount Hagen Sing Sing
is the world's largest jungle-themed
fancy-dress party.
Attended by hundreds of tribes,
it's one of New Guinea's
biggest national events.
Amidst the mayhem, Geling's putting
the finishing touches to his outfit.
In New Guinea, male vanity
is something to flaunt.
Though each clan has its own style...
...almost all wear bird of paradise
feathers as their crowning glory.
In their looks,
and even their courtship dances,
the parallels between man and animal
are unmistakable.
They're birds of a feather.
Both use these precious plumes
to display fitness and beauty.
Taking centre stage,
it's Geling's turn to show off.
This deep connection with birds of
paradise began 40,000 years ago...
...and it shows few signs of fading.
Geling's getting on a bit,
and his female admirers aren't quite
as plentiful as they used to be...
...but he's not going to let that
ruffle his feathers.
The diverse nature of the rainforest
influences the people who live here
in endless ways
and it often leads to
breathtaking results.
For the Bayaka tribe
of Africa's Congo basin,
it's the sounds of the jungle
that most inspire them.
(RHYTHMIC BEAT)
Whether using a river as a drum kit...
...or incorporating animal calls
into their work songs...
...the Bayaka consider music to be
their greatest gift from the forest.
(SINGING)
But there's something else found here
that the Bayaka prize just as highly.
So highly they're prepared
to risk their lives for it.
Tete and Mongonje are on the hunt,
but it's not meat they're after.
Honey is liquid gold to the Bayaka,
and they go to extraordinary lengths
to gather it.
Using a special vine,
Tete makes a harness to help him
get to grips with this 40-metre tree.
Climbing like this requires skill,
strength and stamina,
especially in the tropical heat.
While Tete climbs, Mongonje prepares
a bundle of smoking leaves
to help pacify the bees.
An hour's passed and Tete's
making impressive progress.
But he's still got a way to go.
News that honey's been found
has spread quickly,
and Tete's wife and kids
come
to watch.
Tete's finally made it
to the crown of the tree
but to go any further he'll have to
leave the security of his vine.
Tete's fully aware how dangerous
honey gathering is,
but the Bayaka believe it's bravery
that makes the man,
and sugar is so scarce in these forests
that honey is the best nutrition
Tete can provide for his family.
40 metres up, and unattached,
Tete can't put a foot wrong.
And now the bees
are beginning to attack.
He's made it to the hive,
but he's got to get at the honey
before being overcome by bees.
The
smoke helps,
but Tete's still being stung.
Finally Tete strikes gold.
The first basket goes down
to Tete's family...
...and even thousands of angry bees
can't stop
the feast.
Tete takes time to savour his success.
He's done enough to keep
his wife sweet, treat his children
and earn respect from his tribe.
For forest people, simple things
can hold extraordinary value,