here's my number so
call me maybe.
Hey, I just met you and this is
crazy, but here's my number
so call me maybe.
MALE SPEAKER: Colin Powell
knows the words.
Words.
Word, word, word, words.
FEMALE SPEAKER: We have live
pictures, and what you're
about to see may truly
shock you.
MALE SPEAKER: Are you sexually
attracted to young boys, to
underage boys?
JERRY SANDUSKY: I'm attracted to
young people-- boys, girls,
young boys.
I'm attracted to young boys.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Child abuse
trial of former Penn State
assistant football coach, Jerry
Sandusky, Jerry Sandusky.
FEMALE SPEAKER: 10 young boys.
MALE SPEAKER: Molested.
MALE SPEAKER: Raped.
MALE SPEAKER: Jerry Sandusky.
MALE SPEAKER: Molested.
FEMALE SPEAKER: 10 young boys.
MALE SPEAKER: Raped.
MALE SPEAKER: Jerry Sandusky.
MALE SPEAKER: Molested.
MALE SPEAKER: 10 young boys.
MALE SPEAKER: He started with
a backrub, he put his mouth.
He started with a backrub, he
put his mouth on my privates.
MALE SPEAKER: When he was
12-years-old, 12-years-old,
and kissing him on the forehead
to oral sex when he
was 12-years-old, 12-years-old,
From hugging and
caressing to oral sex.
MALE SPEAKER: His hands
down my shorts and
blowing on my stomach.
Skin on skin, rhythmic sort
of slapping sounds.
And then he says that led to
oral sex, sex, sex, sex.
FEMALE SPEAKER: I'm laying with
a boy, rubbing his back.
Kissing him on the forehead,
things like that.
I'm laying with a boy,
rubbing his back.
Kissing him on the forehead,
things like that.
FEMALE SPEAKER: He heard
slapping sounds, the showers
were running, he started
to [HEAVY BREATHING].
FEMALE SPEAKER: 10 young boys.
MALE SPEAKER: Molested.
MALE SPEAKER: Raped.
MALE SPEAKER: Jerry Sandusky.
MALE SPEAKER: Molested.
MALE SPEAKER: 10 young boys.
MALE SPEAKER: Bath salts, bath
salts, bath, bath, bath salts.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Laying with
a boy, rubbing his back.
Kissing him on the forehead,
things like that.
MALE SPEAKER: Are you sexually
attracted to young boys, to
underage boys?
JERRY SANDUSKY: I'm attracted to
young people-- boys, girls.
COLIN POWELL: Hey, I just met
you and this is crazy.
But here's my number,
so call me maybe.