there's disaster assistance plasmids
apocalypse is already
all away at the time
all governmental structures are
shattered all societal structures of
shadow
but his superstition for sc
there is still a plan in place
there are some who keep their heads
their fight for
and they have one of the and they
haven't
survival
this will be humanity's last hope
it's only hope
on our planet
now controlled
bike deleted
invaders
detailee an invasion is complete
the invaders controlled the skies
and the ground
with infrastructure destroyed human
survivors are going to be desperate
and without a plan in place
they will be on prepared
panicked
i can't guarantee it most people
are not wear face emergency because we
were like too much on
arty t_m_ cards to get
we rely on getting figures his store to
get food
nothing would be left on the shelves at
your stores
within three hours up any bench
as much as the water and food because
it's everything
demand desperation to stock up on
supplies mobs looted rioted and
destroyed
distribution fighters don't kill you
other humans might uh...
doesn't matter if you're in new york
city in l_a_ or appearing when i was
human nature shimla nature people are
going to fight over resources
now staying alive mainstream only from
stores
and the problem
terrified massive swarm out of the
c_d_c_ search of safety
in at the nighttime what where did you
see really determines that
all the big cities where there are
bright lights
to where to hide is the dark spots
the amazon
and the outback those are the places too
hot
broadway scoring twelve halt
getting out safely by car may be
impossible
listening bumper-to-bumper traffic
combustor freaking out they're gonna and
then in the car to a care in a broken
certainly not a character wasn't
it's happened before
in two thousand five as hurricane rita
approach texas millions fled
the highways around houston instantly
jammed
vehicles ran out of fuel
the entire city
highway system turned into a
parking lot
and it lasted
falls days
reciprocate coming here buddy gap
anyone happens her body runs out house
gives their cards on your statement is
done
because the interstate if structure is a
design for that big of an evacuation
even as the deleon invaders bear down on
humanity
society hasn't learned from past
mistakes
but there are other options
for men and women intent on survival
in general you got a lot of work the
main routes of travel
you know one of where the highways and
the roads in the bridges
cars maybe death traps
a successful getaway demand some other
form of transportation
a plague of course
a motorcycle
if you have a motorcycle you can we get
out of the traffic
maybe that's a lie to yourself having
their
danny
and you go to the water you can get up
skater get out of the city walk raha
everybody's
completely lost
for psalm
safety from alien forces and rampaging
humans
means going underground
literally
subway tunnels cable conduit and even
sewers
won't provide safe thanks
burning cds
bestseller systems great because so few
people ought to go through it
history lesson hits for the ugly but
it's going to be safe
relatively
this is going to be the road less
traveled and that's what you're looking
for
underground
before overweight
by car
by sport
urban dwellers around
planet join amassed exodus out of the
city's
itself
may never risky
the invaders have now destroyed
civilization as we know it
but according to the experts
the destruction of civilization is
predictable
and it's a concert four in the plans to
fight and alien invasion
in the face of invitation with highly
advanced technology
military testy maybe predictable
but it's not the end of the war
on likely victories have happened before
dekh ke gary for humanity get last as
long as they possibly can
and do things like the mujahadeen did in
the uh... soviet f_b_i_ more relaxed
where they used terrorist type
livers and rebellion too
vindicates a larger
more technologically superior force
among the survivors left on earth
incase
forests
and desert all over the planet
they always this season's of rebellion
alien invasion has calmed
now it's time for earth
to fight
god
unquestioned rises in the mind
why
employed
humanity survive
and uh... answering this question
i don't think they would come on some
random slumbering nation i think that
would attack us the farm
fl
bynoe means clearly
aliens haven't destroyed our planet
just our civilization
in the plan for ending
dr trappist taylor is cleaned out the
most likely markets for hostel
conquest
harvesting
or hunting
at best
there simply looking for supplies
maybe
there's something here on our planet
they will
one possibility is the most important
resource on the planet
but he is water that we're
discoveries about planets and moves
both in our solar system antigua in the
galaxy review a different story
water headquarters one of the most
common compounds any others
so they don't have anymore and
the invaders meeting the difference in
order to determine the treatment
but that's the real to has problems
fayed minerals minerals exist elsewhere
the largest you're on there
other planets like actually be more
attractive
the solar system is full of resources
in fact a single asteroid can continue
gold and silver aluminum nsync and has
been excavated in bowl of human history
but the canyons malignant become clearer
as history
chinnu vehicle begins to patrol
disguise
vessel stripped
units are harvested troop compounds on
purpose
that our astronomers involve nowhere
else in the know universe
chlorophyll
and protein
plants
and and
deletions are harvesting life
even prescriptions
long-distance migrations of often driven
by the need to find a new sources of
different these institutions have
completed the resource is something
reform with that
does talent
deflected common attack
status quo unlike anything that would
come folks up to the got the comes
someone was like in a somewhat like a
plays a blossoming ecosystem
politician
didn't survive
base of the new features with superior
technology
who may be hunted
with cbs destroyed
remnants of humanity here on the run
survivors must learn how to live
with nothing
life after
an alien attack
or any sort of global disaster
literally unimaginable
simply access to
clean water and food
will be
the happy prepare for that mentally as
much as anything
it's about having the will to survive
if you fail
there will be no wonder right rat
rubin chaos in the field evacuations to
thousands in the first day
more dot as food and water run out over
the next days and weeks
lack of preparation becomes a death
sentence
i would say seventy percent of people
probably won't survive
simply because they have taken no side
uh... supports any kind of preparation
or any kind of knowledge of what it
takes
with basic survival
instruments now have the
and he's trying to huh
destroyed them
but some will make it
a person survival depends on preparation
learning new skills and developing might
mental attitude for a new
resourcefulness is paramount
ordinary tools become lifesavers
scavenge supplies canned food and clean
water will be vital for the first two
years
flashlights with batteries and nights
are as good as currency
the real key to long-term survival
is other people you had fun groups that
you can trust
as an individual you would never suraj
you would have to gather in groups
and work together to survive
if you break a leg you break it arm that
that could be the end of it released a
ship your kind of just getting by
the lucky ones this keep the cds
servo
the first week simple one
survivors band together
they took shelter after canopies forests
they come together in the safety of case
coming coming
surviving groups to carry the last
minutes of human technology
yes we're here
bikini leaders have destroyed the
planet's best communications
infrastructure
who attend methods intact
heads of survivors begin to connect with
simple communications devices
walkie-talkies
we covered him radios
even whole telegraph lines
just because we don't use the telegraph
anymore doesn't mean the lines are still
intact
nerve ivor offically