AMY RITCHIE-CARTER: My mom would
tell me a dream that she
used to have when she
was a little kid.
She would dream that her dog
died and that they buried it.
And then, in the middle
of the night, it would
come back to life.
Except it wasn't like it
was when it was alive.
It came back in a bunch
of little pieces all
put together wrong.
That always scared the
daylights out of me.
This is my taxidermy
shop, where all
of the action happens.
This is all the animals that
I have in my freezer.
Frozen red fox skin.
I have several birds in here
I'm going to practice on,
since I don't do
many birds yet.
This is a skunk.
This is actually going to be a
kitten in a playful position.
Here's some frozen squirrels.
The mounted squirrels are a
really good seller on eBay.
If I need squirrels
fast, I'll shoot
them with a .410 shotgun.
That makes it a lot faster
to get squirrels.
But you can shoot them with
a .22 rifle as well.
Just takes more skill.
INTERVIEWER: So when did you
begin to support yourself as a
taxidermist?
AMY RITCHIE-CARTER: Well, as
soon as I started doing stuff
for customers when I was
15, I realized I could
put stuff on eBay.
And from about age 16 on up,
I was making a pretty good
living selling stuff on eBay
alone, in addition to the
customer mounts I
was getting in.
INTERVIEWER: What did people
your age think about it?
AMY RITCHIE-CARTER:
Like my friends?
They thought it was
interesting.
They thought it was gross too.
Most people, I just show
the finished mount to.
That way they could really
appreciate the beauty.
A lot of people can't handle
the skinning--
the behind the scenes.
INTERVIEWER: And you were
saying that you had some
trouble with PETA when you
were very young, right?
AMY RITCHIE-CARTER: Yeah, I've
gotten lots of hate mail from
animal rights activists and
people who just don't agree
with killing animals
in general.
It's gone so far as to where
they hacked into my website.
They replaced the photo on my
website with a photo of an
aborted fetus.
I think they were trying to
say what I was doing to
animals was as bad as doing that
to a person, I guess they
were trying to say.
INTERVIEWER: So what are
we going to do with
this little guy here?
AMY RITCHIE-CARTER: This is a
gray fox that we're going to
be skinning today.
And I'm going to show
you how I turn him
into a finished piece.
I'm going to get the tools
together that I'm going to
need for skinning--
which really, all it is is a
scalpel, pair of scissors, and
a pair of pliers.
I'm going to start right up here
between the ears, stick
in my scalpel, which
is fresh and sharp.
Usually it takes me about
20 or 30 minutes to
totally skin a fox.
The fox, it's impossible
to skin all the
way down to the toes.
So what I'm going to have to do
is break the bone and cut
it off right here.
OK, I'm going to skin
the tail now.
This is the grossest part,
considering where you're
working at, you know,
underneath the tail.
INTERVIEWER: When your husband
first met you, what did he
think about the taxidermy
business?
AMY RITCHIE-CARTER: He thought
it was really interesting.
We met on the internet.
But we started talking about
taxidermy right off.
And that's why he became
interested.
INTERVIEWER: What'd you guys
do on your first date?
AMY RITCHIE-CARTER: We actually
went to a gun show.
INTERVIEWER: Really?
AMY RITCHIE-CARTER: Yeah.
Looked at the guns.
And then he came back to my
house and I showed him my
taxidermy shop.
Robby is somewhat of a cowboy,
I guess you could say.
He likes wearing the
Western clothes and
the big belt buckle.
And he's ridden bulls
in the past too.
INTERVIEWER: Do you ever have
people bring you their pets to
preserve after they die?
AMY RITCHIE-CARTER: I've done
a poodle for a lady.
And I've also done a cat rug.
The lady wasn't local.
She was from New
York, actually.
And she sent me her poodle
in the mail.
She overnighted it with
some dry ice.
And once I got it, I mounted
it for her in a sleeping
position and then I mailed
it back to her.
INTERVIEWER: Do you think you'll
mount your own pets
when they die?
AMY RITCHIE-CARTER: Mm-hm.
I have a dog and a cat and a
snake that I would possibly
mount once they die.
But it'll just be a decision
I'll have to make at the time.
Are you at the ears now?
AMY RITCHIE-CARTER: Yes,
I'm at the ears.
This is the ear right here.
See that hole there?
That's the inner ear.
This is the most interesting
part, when I get to go around
the eyes and the ears.
It's interesting to take the
eyelid away from the eye.
You can see the nasal
cavity there.
I just removed the nose
along with the skin.
There you go.
The hide is now removed
from the carcass.
The first thing you always have
to do is prepare the form
that's going to go
inside of it.
INTERVIEWER: Do you ever watch
horror movies or slasher
flicks, like "Texas Chainsaw
Massacre" or anything?
AMY RITCHIE-CARTER:
Actually, no.
I don't have any desire to
watch movies like that.
I have mounted some squirrels
for the "Texas Chainsaw
Massacre" movie.
INTERVIEWER: How did
they find you?
AMY RITCHIE-CARTER: They found
me through my website.
They called me and said they
needed 12 squirrels mounted in
a dead position for one
of their shoots.
Yeah.
I haven't seen it because
I don't want to
see movies like that.
INTERVIEWER: So do you
have any hobbies?
Things you do on the side?
AMY RITCHIE-CARTER: My main
hobbies are hunting and
playing the piano.
INTERVIEWER: Do you really
hunt with the crossbow?
AMY RITCHIE-CARTER: Oh, yeah.
I've shot a dear with this.
INTERVIEWER: Yeah?
AMY RITCHIE-CARTER: Yeah.
INTERVIEWER: Is it harder
to hunt with a
crossbow than with a gun?
AMY RITCHIE-CARTER:
Definitely.
You've got to get the deer in
about as close as that target
is right there.
That was a bull's-eye
right there.
INTERVIEWER: What instrument
do you play?
AMY RITCHIE-CARTER:
I play the piano.
INTERVIEWER: What
kind of music?
AMY RITCHIE-CARTER:
John Tesh, mainly.
A lot of John Tesh and Yanni.
I actually met him when he
was in concert one time.
INTERVIEWER: Do you ever because
you work on a mount
for so long sort of give it a
name in your head, like I'm
going to work on "Bob"
today or something?
AMY RITCHIE-CARTER: I don't
really anymore.
I used to sometimes
give them names.
I would actually give them names
of guys that I liked.
Actually, the antelope up
there, his name is Dan.
INTERVIEWER: What
was Dan like?
AMY RITCHIE-CARTER: He was just
real friendly and nice.
But he doesn't even know
that there's an
antelope named after him.
This is pretty much the
finished product.
He's going to need to be
sewed on his back and
sewed on the tail.
And I'll put him on a habitat
base and he'll be ready to go.
Sometimes at night, I do
remember images of skinned
carcasses and just creepy
stuff like that.
It does bother me sometimes.
But I think I kind of just
put it out of my mind.
I'm very happy right now.
I'm the happiest
I've ever been.
I've got my own house and I'm
married now, so I'm pretty
much where I want to
be for right now.