The one-inch punch is actually
a method
of chinese Gung Fu of generating power.
One inch punch is a catchy term made,
made up by Bruce Lee which it is actually correct but
really there's all kinds
of short power I mean you can use a
short power palm strike, you can use you
know half-inch punch, or three-inch punch.
Some people call it a trick, could be a
trick it, could be a...
a motion but it does the damage for what
it is, its pretty powerful.
With your wrist joint is the best way to start usually and just flicking it
Giving yourself a flat target and you use bottom three knuckles here
and you just
pop forward
Take your time, no point in rushing it.  Make sure your elbow is in your center and just
slowly over time.  Just keep working on it you
know like a soft pad or a pad of beans.
Usually having a training partner someone hold something for you
is a good judgement for how much power you're putting out.
And you just...
keep doing it, keep doing it until you feel like
you've got a decent amount of control.  There's a certain amount of time that
wrist strengthening takes place in your training too,
that's a big part of it
has to do with training the form.
The traditional way mostly goes into the internal aspect
the centering of the chi
Chinese medicine
have this concept of chi circulation in the body
and by developing the internal power, the internal chi
you develop the One Inch Punch.  One is first through the practice of
breathing or chi meditation.
through breathing visualization, developing
power centers in certain parts of the
body.
That's the internal approach
The external approach is more muscular
and body alignment,
power base,
torque generation.
A lot of fights starts with finger pointing and a lot of that stuff
and from that finger pointing, which is the closes to someone's
solar plexus, maybe your face
You can generate that One Inch Punch
that will actually, be your winning card.
So let's say the person
attack and the person kind of intercepts my punch
That's where one inch punch comes in
Without pulling back that's from a combative stand point.
If you hit someone with the one inch punch
maybe on the surface you break their ribs.
Internally, you might shock their internal
system.
You can rupture someone's spleen,
you can damage their liver,
you can bruise someone's heart.
Something wrong with one of your vertebrae and someone strikes you really hard the power is going to
try and find a easy way out and it'll go through that injury point.
In extreme cases guys have been known to strike someone in the front and then
it injures their back.
You're hitting his vulnerable point that is also the key too
but obviously if you hit...
the weakest man in the strongest point you're not going to do nay damage because he's
got muscles protection.
In the Chinese movies
the One Inch Punch has always been showcased very well.
However, Kill Bill Vol. 2 the way that it was portrayed
was okay but it just visually it was not pleasing.
Kill Bill the way that the one inch punch was portrayed was...
was, you know, taking your skin off your knuckles and this is how it is
But
it's not about that, it is about the body mass
that moves it is not the callous on your
knuckles that does the damage.
I would continue to teach the one inch punch as part of my curriculum
if the student get that far.
If you learn how to
apply short...
shortest distances with the most powerful
impact you can generate there's a pleasure
because there's a huge discovery about
about one-inch movement.  If you look at
it in that context its got invaluable lessons.
But if you look at it as a one-trick pony...
that's it, that's the end of that show, you know?
I think there's been a slight dip
in martial arts in general.  If you think 150, 200 years ago
people were training this system
because that's all they had.
That was their livelihood, they trained a lot harder than they do today and people tend to be a little lazier.
Maybe that's why there's not that much
interests in martial arts because the kids
would just play video games all night long
why come and train and sweat
and be painful right?
You got to think, we've been doing basically the same stuff until about 100 years ago
until industrial revolution, that changed
everything, people are sitting in front of computers
And we haven't had time to catch up with
that yet
It's a radical change.  So I think the
importance of getting back in touch with your body
... is very high and continue to
become up more on the priority list for
a lot of people so I expect martial arts
to take actually you know
I think there are taking upswing back up.
Because there are systems out there that are
almost being lost
and people don't want her to go away.
I think they're going to get better.
The consequence of one inch punch that happened in Long Beach, for me at least..it's...
it's amazing and I think...
it keeps opening doors
and I think that would be the future of one inch movement or One Inch Punch.