Arm, it is the militia
movement.
Born out of the baby-ridden
ashes of Waco and Ruby Ridge,
groups of armed citizens, like
the Tri-States Militia of
South Dakota and Norm Olson's
Michigan Militia, coalesced to
the delight of hack TV reporters
and editorial
cartoonists worldwide.
Though their depiction in the
media typically ranged from
hey, look at these kooky
anti-government gun nuts to
anti-government racists, the
movement's numbers
grew and grew.
They were even making inroads
into mainstream politics until
Tim McVeigh pulled off the
ultimate PR coup by blowing up
149 people and 19 children
in Oklahoma City.
Plagued by its association with
the attack, the militia
movement foundered, and as one
of its most visible groups,
the Michigan Militia bore the
brunt of the shit storm.
There were allegations that
the Nichols brothers and
McVeigh were members,
brow-beatings at the hands of
congressional pantywaists like
Arlen Specter, and lively
infighting by militia members
upset over the leadership's
alternative hypothesis
for the bombing.
The militia disbanded in the
early '00s, and founders Norm
Olson and Ray Southwell left
Michigan for Alaska.
While this seemed like the sad
but likely end to their
endeavor, according to a
Homeland Security report
earlier this year, militia
activity, like ketamine and
Docs with shorts, is once
again on the hot list.
And Norm and Ray are gearing up
to hit the reunion circuit.
RAY SOUTHWELL: How're
you doing?
THOMAS MORTON: Thomas.
RAY SOUTHWELL: Thomas.
THOMAS MORTON: How
are you doing?
RAY SOUTHWELL: Fine, fine.
You're from the VBS TV, huh?
THOMAS MORTON: Yes.
RAY SOUTHWELL: Well,
come on in.
We've got a lot to
talk about here.
THOMAS MORTON: [LAUGHTER].
RAY SOUTHWELL: [INAUDIBLE].
THOMAS MORTON: Hi, I'm in
Nikiski, Alaska, on the Kenai
Peninsula with Norman Olson and
Ray Southwell, formally of
the Michigan Militia.
Currently of the
Alaska Militia.
NORMAN OLSON: Hi, I'm Norman
Olson, and a longtime
proponent of the Constitution.
20-year-plus military veteran.
Standing by the red,
white, and blue,
no matter what happens.
And telling it like it is.
Michigan Militia from
the very beginning.
This goes back to, let's see.
Dates--
oh, 1994.
Started the little
militia in--
in fact, this one goes back
even earlier than that.
"Patriots gather to rail
against the 'New World
Order.'" My, were we
young then, huh?
Year number one was what was
called Operation Visibility.
We knew that we had
to become visible.
If we didn't maintain our
visibility, we couldn't
maintain our legitimacy.
It's so important that if you
believe in what you're doing
is right, you've got to stand up
and make yourself visible.
Look at that mean look
on that man's face.
Oh, boy.
But we were just regulars,
trying to point out that we're
not the terrorists.
We're counter-terrorists.
We're going to stop
those people that
are destroying America.
RAY SOUTHWELL: What we've always
done with our militia--
and this is what people don't
understand, again--
militias command information.
So I may be a commander.
My job is not to give
you orders.
My job as a commander is to give
you information so that
you sort that out in your own
conscience and decide what
action you should take.
The army is command control.
You're my soldier, I'm going to
give you an order, and you
better carry it out.
An example, when you go back
to the Revolutionary War,
Washington had a heck
of a time when the
militia would show up.
The militia was not
command control.
If these guys got there and
they looked at that
battlefield and they decided,
this is not a battle worth
fighting, they left.
That's the way it
is today, too.
NORMAN OLSON: So we went fast
all over the country, starting
up militias in every state.
Some of our militia training
exercises brought in folks
from all over the country.
But we'd put on these training
sessions, dog-and-pony shows,
and the media loved that too.
They came in from all over the
world to see what we were
doing, because it never happened
before, since 1776,
you know, of course.
Or 1775, I should say, Lexington
and Concord.
And we were growing and getting
more national exposure.
RAY SOUTHWELL: Our goal was
to unite these militias.
And understand, there's militias
all over the country,
all over the peninsula, but
they're small groups-- five
people, ten people.
So we networked with each other
so we can be a unified
force, a protective force, so we
don't have to call upon the
federal troops or Blackwater.
THOMAS MORTON: It's important,
it would seem to me, that it'd
be as important in times of
crisis or impending crisis as
it is in times of well-being
to have what the Second
Amendment describes, which
you're talking about-- an
unorganized citizens' militia.
How do you go about that
in times when--
NORMAN OLSON: In
times of peace?
THOMAS MORTON: Bingo.
Of fatness, good--
NORMAN OLSON: Here's
the thing.
When you put a life preserver on
your child and you're going
out on a lake, do
you do it after?
Or do you do it with the
perception that something
could happen out on the lake?
Of course you do.
You don't wait for your
child to drown.
You think ahead.
You're frightened of the
possible situation.
That fear motivates you
to do something good.
So is the--
RAY SOUTHWELL: Who would
you rather trust?
Your neighbor, or a stranger?
NORMAN OLSON: Yeah.
RAY SOUTHWELL: You
know, that's--
NORMAN OLSON: And when somebody
comes rolling up your
driveway, when the lights go
out, would you be comforted if
you knew it was your neighbors
in it, bringing over a
generator or bringing over
foodstuffs, rather than a big,
black SUV coming to take
your guns away?
Again, to keep the control.
So the question is, who will
come in to aid us?
If we are well-disciplined
and well-trained and
well-equipped, then we
can take care of
ourselves, thank you.
But you see, the media won't
allow that to happen.
The media has to spin it so that
we are always demonized
with misinformation and looked
at as the bogeyman running
around the woods with our
cammies on, rather than people
who can help and organize
each other.
It looks like Mark Farner.
You know Mark Farner?
THOMAS MORTON: Um, Grand
Funk, right?
NORMAN OLSON: Yeah, yeah.
He's a personal friend
of ours.
THOMAS MORTON: Oh.
Neat.
NORMAN OLSON: Yeah,
he's a good boy.
THOMAS MORTON: Are you guys
buddies with the Nuge?
NORMAN OLSON: Oh yeah,
you betcha.
We did a program on the steps
of the Capitol with Ted.
Ray and I went out to Montana
there, we went up to the FBI
lines, and I was carrying a
teddy bear, and Ray was
carrying a Red Cross pack.
What we want to do is humanize
it, put a human face on it, so
that those people wouldn't
be bulldozed.
Western New York that I helped,
they were going to
bulldoze his house trailer
because it didn't comply with
building codes.
We went to help this old
gentleman, bless his heart.
Here's an old fellow
that was--
he was a construction worker in
Northern Michigan, 87 years
old, he and his wife.
And they had all this old
machinery on their property.
Well, the county came out and
said it was a blight and they
had to remove it all.
And so we went out there and
faced down the sheriff and
fought for him for
a long time.
The Stitt family.
And they lived down a little
island in northern Lake Huron,
and they were being pushed off
the island because they were
preparing for Y2K.
And they were raising chickens
and emus and
all sorts of stuff.
THOMAS MORTON: Were they
trying to grow hemp?
NORMAN OLSON: I think so.
Now I don't have anything bad
to say about marijuana.
To me, it's just like alcohol.
All things in moderation.
I'm a libertarian when
it comes to that.
Again, it's a human right.
If it's a measure of relaxation
and enjoyment, then
what's the difference between
smoking a joint or popping a
Quaalude, you know?
We went out there
to support them.
We're always trying to support
the little guy, you know?
THOMAS MORTON: One thing that's
marked a lot of the
coverage and, I think, has
muddied the waters is trying
to overlay many of
these issues with
kind of racial politics.
Mitch--
NORMAN OLSON: Mitch
[INAUDIBLE].
He was a Hawaiian.
THOMAS MORTON: Ah.
NORMAN OLSON: Yeah, yeah.
So from the very beginning,
we had racial diversity.
THOMAS MORTON: Now you guys
have referred to the Black
Panthers and stuff
as a militia--
not necessarily exactly the same
as you, but in the same
spirit, in its early days.
NORMAN OLSON: Whether you sit
down with the Black Panthers
or you sit down with the Native
Americans, I'm sure
that we all want the
very same thing.
RAY SOUTHWELL: So it's not the
black community that sees us
as racists.
It's the ignorant white
community, who are so quickly
misled by the media.
NORMAN OLSON: Who keeps
us divided?
Remember we were talking about
control and power and central
government?
Of course.
It's to the benefit of a central
government to keep us
divided, to set up these
little target groups,
marginalizing so that people
cannot come together, so that
the power cannot be given
back to the people.
As long as we're squabbling
among ourselves, we'll never
be able to stand up against
tyranny and oppression.
We'll be arguing with ourselves
while they march us
into a trench to
machine-gun us.
It just doesn't make
any sense.
Then it happened.
Boy, it all hit the fan.
I'll tell you what.
When Oklahoma City, that
event happened,
it surprised everyone.
I had heard rumors along the
Missouri border that there was
going to be a bombing against
the federal building, either
in Tulsa or in Oklahoma City.
It was common knowledge.
The Feds knew that.
They knew it was going
to happen.
They didn't know where.
But when it happened,
it surprised
everybody in the militia.
I remember Leslie Stahl was in
the gun shop there when it all
happened, and they made the
mention of Timothy McVeigh and
the brothers, what
are their names?
RAY SOUTHWELL: Nichols.
NORMAN OLSON: Nichols.
Terry Nichols.
And they linked it with
the Michigan Militia.
And then it all started
to unravel it.
We deactivated after seven years
and started to go home.
Some stayed.
People got frightened then,
because the media picked up on
it and ran with the militia
connection, to the extent that
the militia, a third of the
militia ran and hid.
A third of them went
underground.
Didn't want to be seen, didn't
want to be on a list, didn't
want to be photographed.
Another third just quit the
militia altogether.
They realized this wasn't
paintball in the
woods on the weekend.
This was life-and-death stuff.
And another third became more
aggressive, more adamant about
standing up against the
government, because we saw the
conspiracy against it, against
what was happening.
THOMAS MORTON: Do you think
there was ever a possibility
that what happened in Oklahoma
and as a result of it could
have been fully averted?
Or was it just--
NORMAN OLSON: Actually, I
believe it was the CIA.
It sounds crazy.
THOMAS MORTON: Well, the CIA's
done a lot of crazy things.
NORMAN OLSON: Well,
listen to me.
You know, when you talk about
neo-Nazis and skinheads and
white supremacists,
which McVeigh was
closely associated with--
who's funding all
of that hatred?
And if they could get a stooge
like Timothy McVeigh to do
that, and Terry Nichols
collaborating?
But what about the unknown?
What about this fellow that
went back to Germany?
I don't think it'll ever be
known, the extra leg they
found in the rubble with the
military boot on it, that they
couldn't match up to anybody.
Where did that come from?
You don't read about that,
but it was there.
And so did they know
beforehand?
Did somebody go in there
and set charges?
I don't know.
But I'm welcome to hear any
theory, because that's all I
have, is a theory.
There's something out
there, but I guess
Fox Mulder was right.
The truth is out there,
somewhere.
Did the federal government
stage the Oklahoma City
bombing to bust up the militia
because the militia was
growing too strong?
That could be argued.
And history may reveal it.
I don't know.
We think it did.
We think that they had to stop
the militia because we were
growing so fast across the
country that we were
threatening to take the power
away from the federal
government.
THOMAS MORTON: Did
you personally
meet Tim McVeigh before--
NORMAN OLSON: No,
not personally.
He was downstate.
I was up north.
I didn't get a chance
to meet him.
Of course, the federal
government did a fine job of
proving that Timothy McVeigh
was working out
of an act of revenge.
So when I went up to Washington
to testify before
the Senate and got into that
pissing contest with Arlen
Specter, I pointed
that out to him.
And he couldn't understand how
I could understand what was
going on in Timothy
McVeigh's mind.
Well, you don't understand the
problem that we've had in
Northern Ireland.
You don't understand the problem
that we've had in
South Africa.
You do not understand the hatred
and retaliation, the
retribution and the revenge that
has been going on around
this globe since
time immortal.
Then you don't understand
the dynamic, sir.
ARLEN SPECTER: Well, Mr. Olson,
I may not understand.
And that's why we've had these
hearings, so that you could
have a full opportunity
to express yourself.
NORMAN OLSON: I said well, it'd
be about as simple as I
slap you, you slap me
in retaliation.
OK?
What don't we understand
about that?
Of course, we tried to distance
ourself from all of that.
And we threw the meat in on the
other side of the river,
claiming the Japanese did it,
but what happened was is that
took all of the emphasis away
from us and headed it in
another direction.
Kind of dispersed that
whole feeling.
And fear is strong.
THOMAS MORTON: About the theory
that the Japanese were
retaliating for the
sarin gas thing?
NORMAN OLSON: No, we didn't have
any strong connection.
We brought that out--
actually, what it did
was it defused the
direction we were going.
Because we were going
headlong into a big
confrontation with the Feds.
They thought we were all
wacky and crazy.
But that actually freed us up to
go in a different direction
at that time, which we needed.
And what may be thought of as
bad actually worked out good.
Today, they laugh
at us and make--
but it's a matter of strategic
decisions that we made.
But things changed after
Oklahoma City, changed
drastically.
And a lot of people fell away.
And then Bush came onto the
scene and everything got to be
nice and the government was seen
to be a kind, friendly,
benevolent government,
ready to help us.
But that was just a facade.
That was just a cover.
They're not there to
help us at all.
They're there to eke out our
substance and to rob us of
everything that we have.
And take away our power.
So power to the people, huh?
Our job in Michigan was
pretty well done.
THOMAS MORTON: Why did
you leave Michigan?
And why did you pick Alaska?
NORMAN OLSON: I often ask
people that question.
Why did you come to Alaska?
I'm always interested
where they come from
and the reason why.
And many people don't
really know.
Something just drew them.
I know that sounds ethereal
and all of that,
but here's the thing.
Alaska is a place, it's
a new frontier.
I think socially, economically,
culturally there
is much that appeals to us.
We were in Michigan.
Michigan, anybody who wants to
look at the statistics knows
that Michigan is going bottom-up
economically.
There was nothing there for
us, no reason to stay.
And people had pretty well lost
their desire to stand up.
I think the spirit of
resistance, the spirit of
standing up against the
encroaching IRS and federal
government intrusion into
people's lives had pretty well
wasted away their spirit.
And so they feel like leaving.
We were on the tail-end of that,
and seeing it all come
about, some of us came up here
for new adventures, new
opportunities.
Others came up here to leave
something behind.
RAY SOUTHWELL: And it's the last
adventure state left in
the union, as far as
I'm concerned.
So I think that was probably
the big emphasis on
why we moved up.
NORMAN OLSON: This one was just
from a couple weeks ago,
September 16.
We are free from individual
income tax here.
Much of the state is free
from sales tax.
So there are many,
many benefits.
THOMAS MORTON: It seems very
personal-liberty-oriented, and
yet there's some odd
spots about it.
I think the lack of sheriffs
in the entire state--
how do you feel about Alaskan
state politics, in that sense?
RAY SOUTHWELL: We had an
excellent working relationship
in Michigan with our sheriff.
I met with him on usually a
monthly basis to let him know
when we were doing training,
where we were training.
And officially, he could never
support us, you know, the
politics involved with it.
But he publicly came out and
told the community through the
media that we were doing
nothing wrong.
So the sheriff, as an elected
servant of the people, truly
understands how to build that
relationship with the people.
So we trusted him.
NORMAN OLSON: You see, people
say, well, we can trust the
Alaskan government.
Well, I don't know how far
Alaska has sold out to the
federals for whatever payment
is due for all that the
federal government has
poured into Alaska.
There's too many strings
attached to a lot of the
bailouts and all
the rest of it.
So I'm always concerned about
what liberties and what rights
are at risk when we give the
promise of safety into the
hands of governmental
authorities.
I like to keep this liberty and
this freedom at the lowest
level possible--
among the citizens themselves.
RAY SOUTHWELL: I think the other
part of this area, and
probably throughout Alaska,
is our independence.
And I was talking to one of
the local gun dealers.
The peninsula has
50,000 people.
And this particular one gun
dealer is selling 1,000
military arms a month.
So in the last month, or last
year, he has sold 12,000
firearms to 50,000 people.
So you can start seeing
those numbers.
But what's happening--
NORMAN OLSON: They're
upgrading.
RAY SOUTHWELL: There's two
mindsets, I think, that are
out there, is Alaskans'
independence.
I can take care of myself
and my family.
I will arm myself and I will
prepare for whatever may come,
and I'll be ready.
The other mindset is I am doing
that same issue, but I
don't want anybody to know it.
It's a secret, because the feds
might come and take my
guns, or just a tremendous
amount of independence, but
there's also a tremendous
amount of fear.
What my fear is is that if and
when there's an economic
disintegration, there's
going to be anarchy
all over the country.
THOMAS MORTON: Given the rate
at which things are going,
does it concern you that militia
may not be ready?
RAY SOUTHWELL: Yes.
NORMAN OLSON: Oh, yes.
RAY SOUTHWELL: Yeah.
Yes.
NORMAN OLSON: Too little,
too late.
RAY SOUTHWELL: Yes.
I foresee more anarchy.
NORMAN OLSON: We're
very vulnerable.
RAY SOUTHWELL: Neighbor fighting
neighbor for goods.
NORMAN OLSON: There's
only two extremes--
anarchy and tyranny.
I'm concerned that we
are not networked.
We are not prepared.
We are very vulnerable
here in Alaska.
One road in, one road out.
The wise people will prepare
for what may be coming, and
what we believe will come with
economic collapse, with social
disruption, with more government
intrusion.
So all we are doing is being
prudent, long-viewed people
who are able to read the times,
prepare for the worst.
It's as simple as that.
And we still have some
pages to fill.
Isn't that optimistic?
If nothing else, you know, they
say at the end of your
life, everything that you own is
either going to be put out
by the side of the road,
auctioned off,
or end up in a landfill.
The only thing you can leave
your children is a legacy of
who you were, what
you tried to do.
If it's a life well spent doing
what you think is right,
then can't argue with that.
Just try and help the little
guy, you know?
Help the little guy survive.
There's a lot of folks out there
that are being chewed up
by the system and need help.
So we just keep on helping,
you know?
Call us crazy, call us fanatics,
call us loons, but
don't call us shortsighted.
Trying to look far
enough ahead to
prepare for what's coming.
[MUSIC - I'M IN YOU, "HERE
COMES THE WAR"]