boring.
Yeah, you!
Boring is easy, everybody can be boring. But
you're gooder than that.
Life is not a game people. Life isn't a cereal
either. Well, it is a cereal.
And if life is a game, aren't we all on the
same team?
I mean really right?
I'm on your team, be on my team.
This is life people, you've got air coming
through your nose!
You've got a heart beat!
That means it's time to do somethin'!
A poem.
"Two roads diverged in the woods...
and I took the road less traveled...
AND IT HURT MAN!
Really bad.
Rocks!
Thorns!
Glass!
My pants broke!
NOT COOL ROBERT FROST!
But what if there really were two paths?
I want to be on the one that leads to awesome.
It's like that dude Journey said, don't stop
believing, unless your dream is stupid. Then
you should get a better dream. I think that's
how it goes.
Get a better dream, then keep goin', and goin',
and keep goin'.
What if Michael Jordan had quit? Well, he
did quit. But he retired, yeah that's it,
he retired. But before that? In highschool?
What if he quit when he didn't make the team?
He would have never made Space Jam. And I
love Space Jam.
What will be your Space Jam? What will you
create when you make the world awesome?
Nothing if you keep sittin' there! This is
why I'm talking to you today!
This is your time.
This is my time.
This is our time.
We can make everyday better for each other.
If we're all on the same team, let's start
acting like it. We've got work to do.
We can cry about it, or we can dance about
it.
You were made to be awesome.
Let's get out there!
I don't know everything, I'm just a kid, but
I do know this:
It's everybodies duty to do good, and give
the world a reason to dance.
So get to it.
[driving music]
You've just been pep talked.
Create something that will make the world
awesome.
[electric guitar riff]
Play ball!
[movie reel sound]
[crashing noise]
Oh hi everybody!
We're all workin' hard to make this an awesome
year for other people, and you guys are doin'
it!
You've been super encouraging to me, so I
want to return the favor.
Who do you know that needs some encouragement?
Pass this pep talk along, and get the whole
world to dance.
I dedicate this video today to my friend Gabbi.
She's a cool kid, she likes pancakes, and
she's fighting cancer. Like a BOSS.
And to all you watching, who encourages you?
Send them this video, and let them know.
So get to it!
[music burst]
Bye!
[continue soulful music]
Harmonized Voice >>SoulPancake!
Subscribe!
Kid President>> Not cool Robert Frost!