[RADIO CHATTER]
JOEY: Let's go.
Let's go come on.
[GUNSHOTS IN THE DISTANCE]
JOEY: Holy shit.
What did you guys
get for me now?
The fuck you looking at?
What?
ZOMBIE: [SNARLING]
JOEY: [INAUDIBLE]
I think the fag likes me.
RORY: What did you say huh?
You talking to me?
Look at me, look at me!
What did you say huh,
motherfucker?
Why don't you try
[INAUDIBLE] me?
I dare you!
You got a problem?
Come on you scrawny
little shit--
JOEY (OFFSCREEN): Move.
RORY: What the fuck man?
JOEY: What?
RORY: You almost killed me
that thing went like that
close to my face!
JOEY: Fucking accuracy
I got him straight
in the fucking chest.
RORY: Yeah, but if you like
sneezed it would have hit me.
JOEY (OFFSCREEN): Did
I sneeze, did
I shit, did I fart?
Did I do anything?
No, I did a straight shot.
I didn't slip, shut the
fuck up, I hit him
straight in the chest.
TELEVISION (OFFSCREEN): The
Australian Defense Force today
began making available 10 liter
canisters of kerosene
for collection from military
service points, while five
liter canisters will be
delivered directly to
households in metropolitan areas
over the coming week.
The Federal Department of
Defense issued a joint release
earlier today, outlining
amendments to safety advisory
warnings being given to members
of the public in
heavily affected areas.
Key amendments deal principally
with proper
methods of destruction and
disposal of undead or zombie
infected individuals.
Contrary to previous
instruction, people are
advised against leaving corpses
in the street for
military collection.
Bodies, whole or part should be
incinerated immediately--
SARAH JANE: How the fuck
did you get in here?
JIMBO: Through the door.
SARAH JANE: I told Rory to keep
the fucking door locked.
TELEVISION: --official death
toll figures, but are instead
releasing what they've
described
as speculative estimates.
These figures, according to
New South Wales state
emergency services, represent
an ongoing readjustment of
official estimates based on
the obvious errors brought
about not only by the
overwhelming size of the numbers--
JIMBO: So, how's it going?
TELEVISION: --but by
discrepancies between--
SARAH JANE: How do you
reckon it's going?
TELEVISION: --official human
deaths and those in various
undead or zombie states.
Flexible estimates
released today--
JIMBO: What you been up to?
SARAH JANE: Excuse me but
who are you, exactly?
JIMBO: Jimbo.
SARAH JANE: So what
do you want?
[KNOCK ON THE DOOR]
RORY (OFFSCREEN): [INAUDIBLE]
open the fucking door!
SARAH JANE: I told you
to keep it locked.
RORY (OFFSCREEN): Just
[INAUDIBLE] and let us in!
SARAH JANE: If I let you in will
you promise me to keep
the fucking door locked?
RORY (OFFSCREEN): Just
let us in you slut!
SARAH JANE (OFFSCREEN):
Promise me!
RORY (OFFSCREEN): Fucking
whatever!
[DOOR OPENING OFFSCREEN]
SARAH JANE: Fucking lesbian!
JOEY: Fucks going on in here?
Hey Sarah, Jimbo wants
a hummer from you.
SARAH JANE: What?
JOEY: He wants a fucking
hummer from you.
SARAH JANE (OFFSCREEN):
What's a hummer?
JOEY: Fucking tell her, go!
Don't act like you don't know
you just fucking told me.
[INAUDIBLE] his fucking balls,
he puts it in your mouth, so
you hum and his balls buzz.
Jimbo wants one from you.
SARAH JANE: Can you both
just leave me alone?
TELEVISION (OFFSCREEN):
--suggests that the zombie
disease may have been
contracted by dogs and livestock.
Official confirmation--
SARAH JANE: I said fuck off!
--has yet to be recieved,
but emergency
services are advising.
RORY: [INAUDIBLE]
metholated spirits [INAUDIBLE]
Half a can of [INAUDIBLE] uh,
with a-- you put it, you put
it in a tub, mix it with some
water, let it sit for about
five minutes then in a seperate
tub you put about two
two cans of coke.
It'll get out any
stain you want.
Magic stuff.
JOEY: What the fuck is that?
[REVS LAWNMOWER]
JOEY: Zombie Juice!
Fuck!
RORY: [SCREAMING]
JOEY: Hey!
Come here.
Shit, come here, come on.
RORY: [SCREAMING]
JOEY (OFFSCREEN): Hey!
Hey!
Little shit.
RORY (OFFSCREEN): Zombie!
Zombie!
JOEY (OFFSCREEN): Come here you
little shit, you little
punk, come here!
TELEVISION (OFFSCREEN): The RTA,
Royal North Shore, and
St. Vincent's Hospital were
closed this morning as all
three struggle to contain deadly
zombie contamination in
their intensive care
and casualty units.
The RTA's administrative
director told a news
conference ealier today that
until the hospital was able to
implement radical new prodocals
the treatment of all
out patients that risks to
staff and existing--
SARAH JANE: What?
TELEVISION (OFFSCREEN): --from
zombie attacks is simply too
great for operations to
continue as usual.
Tight security measures are
expected to be introduced to
all three hospitals within
the next 72 hours.
JIMBO: Do you ever wonder what
a fish feels when it's caught
and gets thrown back
into the water?
Like, is it really angry at the
guy that just ripped his
mouth open with a hook
or is he confused?
Or does he just like, forget the
whole thing ever happened
like five seconds later?
SARAH JANE: Don't you have
somewhere else to be?
With your family or something?
JIMBO: No.
They're gone.
SARAH JANE: What?
JIMBO: They're all dead.
SARAH JANE: I'm sorry.
JIMBO: That's OK.
I get sad sometimes too when
I think about fish.
JOEY: The fuck you looking at?
ZOMBIE: [SNARLS]
JOEY: What's the matter bitch?
Don't you like petrol?
Fucking move!
Light this bitch up.
Fire in the butthole
motherfucker!
SARAH JANE: What the fuck?
Fuck!
What the hell is going on?
What the fuck are you doing?
JOEY: What the fuck
does it look like?
I'm making an example out of
this motherfucking zombie.
This motherfucking zombie
is my motherfucking dad.
What the fuck's wrong
with you?
RORY: He's not your
dad anymore he's a
fucking zombie now--
SARAH JANE: That's bullshit
what's wrong with you?
RORY: We're moving on,
we're just moving on
here you stupid bitch.
Yeah, we're putting this fucking
zombie out of its
motherfucking misery.
ZOMBIE: [SNARLS].
JOEY: Oh fuck me!
[SCREAMS]
SARAH JANE (OFFSCREEN):
Shit man, shit!
JOEY: Son of a bitch fuck!
RORY: Shit man he's changing!
SARAH JANE: You out of your
fucking misery yet?
[MUSIC PLAYS]