Excelsior, this is
the shuttlecraft Sturgeon.
Requesting docking coordinates.
Acknowledged, Sturgeon,
you are cleared for docking.
Don't look so worried.
Say that one more
time, and I swear
I'll bust you back to yeoman.
What's on today's schedule?
I've cleared it.
You'll have all the time
in the world.
Docking is complete, Excelsior.
Copy that, Sturgeon.
Welcome aboard.
All the time in the world...
Tracking hydrogen-antihydrogen
reaction signatures, Captain.
There's no doubt
they're venting antimatter.
Maximum resolution.
Range, Mr. Sulu?
29 million kilometers, Captain.
They've drifted well within
the Romulan Neutral Zone.
Another distress signal,
Captain.
They say they're losing
life support fast.
Mr. Sulu,
plot an intercept course.
I want us in and out
before anybody's the wiser.
Ever taken the
Kobayashi Maru test?
Course plotted and
laid in, Captain.
Full ahead.
Aye, sir.
Entering Romulan
Neutral Zone.
We are now in violation
of treaty.
Then let's not let any grass...
Captain, warp field
signatures approaching.
Dropping to sublight.
On screen.
Romulan birds-of-prey,
Imperator class.
Detecting a build-up of
hyperphasic energy, Captain,
in a triangulated pattern.
All decks-- Red Alert!
Space--
the final frontier.
These are the new voyages
of the Starship Enterprise,
its five-year mission
to explore strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go where
no man has gone before.
Spock!
What the hell just happened?
The merchant vessel has been...
annihilated, Captain.
There is nothing left.
Its very atoms
have been ripped apart.
Get us out of here, Sulu.
Yes, sir!
Captain, I'm getting encrypted
ship-to-ship
between the Romulan vessels.
Fortuitously, in a code
they are unaware
that we have previously broken.
As I suspected.
The merchant vessel was
destroyed by a new weapon,
most likely a prototype.
Captain...
they've spotted us.
They're building energy again.
We have only seconds before...
Chekov, target those
vessels and fire!
Targeting... firing phasers.
Damage report.
Minimal, Captain-- mostly from
shifts in our gravity field.
Analysis, Spock.
Shields are holding.
We are safe for the
moment-- but trapped.
Trapped.
How?
We appear to be caught in
a hyperdimensional field.
The field is producing
gravity waves...
...ripples in the space-time
continuum.
This is a strange definition
of "safe," Mr. Spock.
Lieutenant Uhura,
send out a subspace message
to the Romulan High Command,
in their encrypted code:
Weapons test a failure.
Our own ships destroyed.
Core breach... imminent.
Aye, sir.
We might at least dissuade them
from trying it again,
anytime soon.
Most logical.
Thank you, Mr. Spock.
You, Bones and Scotty
in conference now.
Mr. Sulu, you have the Conn.
Isn't the Kobayashi Maru
supposed to be
a "no-win" scenario?
Let's hope not.
The field apparently
creates a quantum disruption
that negates the strong and
weak forces binding atoms.
Anything caught within it
simply ceases to exist.
And this is going
to happen to us?
At the moment, our shields
are protecting us.
But the power drain
is considerable.
How much time?
No more than 20 hours.
I cannot say for sure, the
way the levels keep changing.
And we can't use full warp power
to escape?
Ineffective.
Due to the field,
we are in the grip of not four,
but considerably
more dimensions.
We would need
accurate coordinates
for all of them
in order to effectively
extricate ourselves.
And without the data on how
the field was generated,
the computer doesn't stand a
chance of plotting a course out.
Is it possible the bird-of-prey
has the data?
If the computer banks
are still intact...
but we can't access them
from here.
And with the field fluctuating
to hell and back,
I wouldn't dare trust
the transporters.
A shuttlecraft, then.
Wouldn't it be destroyed?
I believe we can
extend the shields out
far enough to protect it.
Mr. Sulu.
Aye, sir?
We're going to need
some fancy piloting
if we're going to get
out of this mess,
with a few extra-dimensional
coordinates thrown in.
Are you up for it?
When do I start?
Captain's Log,
Stardate 6283.6.
The Enterprise is caught
like a fly in amber,
in a tangle of multiple
dimensions.
Our only hope of survival lies
in obtaining data
from the remaining
Romulan bird-of-prey
that might help us chart
a course back to normal space.
I have detailed Lieutenant Sulu
to pilot a shuttlecraft
to the derelict ship,
accompanied by an expert
in Romulan computer science.
Sorry, sorry.
You know, we are kind of
on the clock here.
I couldn't get into
this damn thing.
Lisa Chandris, computer science,
xeno-cryptography.
Hikaru Sulu, helmsman.
I know; I saw you on the bridge,
when I came aboard
and presented my orders
to the captain.
I got here, like,
three days ago,
when you guys docked
at Altair IV.
Well, you're certainly starting
things off with a bang.
Keep them safe,
Mr. Scott.
What was that?
Gravity wave.
One of the first things
they ask you
when you sign on
for starship duty
is if you're prone
to space sickness.
I lied.
We'll be back with the data
before you know it.
If our shields don't fail,
and if that bird-of-prey
isn't torn to quarks
with us aboard it.
That about sums it up.
And that doesn't
bother you, huh?
It certainly motivates me.
Sorry if I parked too far
from the curb, Doctor.
You're a real
cowboy, you are.
Careful. Gravity's unstable.
Computer's on
a separate power grid,
so I should be able to...
Okay, we're on line.
Now all we have to do
is locate the specific data
on the weapons system.
Ah, here we are.
Of course!
This making sense
to you?
It's complex, but yes.
Good.
I'd hate to have gone
to all this trouble for nothing.
I mean... almost nothing...
Spock?
Gravity waves, Captain.
Increasing intensity.
They could destabilize the
bird-of-prey's reactor core.
Sulu! You and Chandris
get out of there now!
Enterprise! Can you hear us?
Enterprise!
Bird-of-prey reactor core
going critical!
Scotty! Keep the shields
extended around that ship
and beam Sulu and Chandris
back through!
I'll give it my best, Captain.
Spock! Bones!
Gravity waves are makin' it
devilish hard to lock onto them.
The core just blew!
Massive subspace interference.
I cannot hang onto them!
Wait. There's a signal.
One's caught in
the pattern buffer.
Looks to be Sulu,
but something's nee right.
You're not
gettin' away now, lad.
You will stand down now, sir.
You will stand down.
And see, I believe,
that you know us.
Captain Kirk...
Dr. McCoy...
Bones.
You're the same...
How can you be the same?
DNA and vitals
match Sulu's, but...
Jim-- he's 30 years older.
Mr. Sulu, you've been gone
less than a minute.
The Romulan ship
went critical
and we tried to beam
you both back...
Oh, my God!
She's all alone back there!
You've got to get her!
You've got to
bring her here!
We lost Dr. Chandris' signal.
Not Lisa! Lisa's dead!
She died 15 years ago.
Captain!
I'm picking up another signal,
faint as a whisper...
Dr. Chandris?
Doesn't match her signature.
Something else.
Lock in on it!
I'd do a fair bit better
if you'd stop shoutin' and
flailin' cutlasses about!
Aw, you're a right will
o' the wisp, you are...
but you won't be gettin' away.
Alana, don't be afraid.
Bring her back!
I've got her pattern
in the matrix.
She won't be gettin' away.
But she's not exactly arrivin'
here yet, either.
I'll have to rig up some sort of
stasis chamber to keep her here.
At least, for starters.
You called her Alana.
Who is she?
She's my daughter.
Status.
Shields at maximum, sir.
We've diverted power
from all but life support.
We're holding our own,
but we're not going anywhere.
Understood.
Report, Commander.
Sulu, just tell
us what you know.
Lisa and I were aboard
the bird-of-prey.
It was about to explode when
the transporter seized us.
Instead of materializing
on the Enterprise,
we found ourselves
on the surface of a planet.
Clearly one with some form
of civilization,
given your elaborate...
ornamentation.
A dead world, Mr. Spock.
Disease had wiped them out
centuries ago.
Nothing but ruined cities,
what remained of a...
canal system...
desert that stretched forever.
There was wildlife, fruits.
We were able to survive.
And in time, you and Chandris...
There comes a point where one
has to start living a life--
whatever it is-- rather than
waiting for one to begin.
But what was
30 years to you
was 30 seconds to us.
Fascinating.
It would appear
that the gravitational waves,
interacting with the
multi-dimensional field,
diverted you and Dr. Chandris
into a different,
more rapid timestream--
perhaps a wholly different
universe.
Mr. Sulu,
this ship will be torn
to subatomic particles
in a matter of hours,
We need that data
that you and Dr. Chandris
got off that ship.
The tricorder's back on Caliban.
We had to name the planet
something.
It seemed to fit.
It's from Shakespeare...
The Tempest.
Sulu, do you
remember anything
from the Romulan data?
It's been so long.
I...
No.
When the tricorder's
power started to fail,
I tried to hold
the information in my mind.
But after months...
years...
Lisa thought...
you had all died.
But I said,
"You don't know James Kirk.
"He always manages to snatch
life from the jaws of death.
He'll find a way."
You're that way, Sulu.
We need that data.
Captain...
Kirk here.
If you fine gentlemen
could tear yourselves away
from your pressin' business...
there's someone here
I'd like you to meet.
Father!
It's all right, Alana.
Why is she still insubstantial?
Best I can do
for now, Captain.
A good part of her's
still linked
to whatever godforsaken rock
you were livin' on.
She appears to exist in a state
of quantum indeterminacy;
partly here,
in our universe,
partly still in
the alternate universe.
That's impossible.
I suggest we make a datachip
record of these events.
It could prove invaluable
to science.
Welcome to the Enterprise.
They came.
They came for us.
Just like you said they would.
Captain, there are urgent
matters we need to attend to.
I understand, Mr. Spock.
As soon as we're clear of
this hyperspatial beastie,
we should be able
to divert enough power
to bring you
all the way through.
For now, unfortunately,
your movements are limited
to this chamber.
We'll see if we can arrange
some introductions later.
Miss...
Sulu?
Alana, please.
You're Captain Kirk, aren't you?
How did you know?
My father told me
you were impressive...
...and knew it.
You'll have to excuse her,
Captain...
There's no apologies necessary.
Mr. Sulu,
we'll need you in sickbay.
I'll try not
to keep him long.
A pleasure meeting you.
Bones, Spock,
you're with me.
I'll be back soon.
People move so quickly here.
Aye, that they do, lass.
You're Montgomery Scott,
aren't you?
My father told me
about you, too.
And just what did he tell you?
That he wouldn't want
to be your liver.
It's good
to have him back.
And to be meetin'
his fine fair daughter.
Although you no longer
consciously retain
the hyperspatial
coordinates,
your mind still
retains the data.
So... the famous
Vulcan mind-meld.
I won't tell you
this is without risk.
But then, what in life is?
Shouldn't you send me
candy and flowers first?
I do not understand.
No, I didn't think you would.
My thoughts to
your thoughts...
Sulu, relax.
Don't fight it.
My mind to your mind.
Yes...
Our minds are merging,
becoming one...
Yes.
The Romulan ship.
Dr. Chandris...
Alana...
A child...
ten years old...
What... What's...
sand... moving...
Rising up...
Alana!
Sand demon!
Fangs! Spurs!
It has her!
Too far! Too far!
I can't...!
Jim! Their vitals
are spiking!
Lisa! She's killing it!
She's cutting it to pieces!
But it's stabbing...
stabbing her!
LISA!
You saved her...
You saved our daughter...
She heard me...
I know she heard me...
Epinephrine level's
off the scale.
Blood pressure's
through the roof.
You have to stop it!
Stop it now-- before
we lose them both!
Spock! Break it off!
Spock!
The data?
Too deep.
It's clear we'll have to find
another way.
How is he?
Resting.
He'll need some time
to recover.
My God, Jim,
what he's been through...
Laudable as
your tendency
toward compassion may be,
Doctor,
it does not alter
the fact
that the ship
will be destroyed
if we do not get
that data soon.
How can that green blood
of yours be so cold?
Dr. McCoy...
Bones, we need an alternative.
Well, there are drugs,
hypnotics.
They might work.
Normally, I'd advise against it.
These are not normal
circumstances.
Do it.
They're not
standard issue.
It'll take me time
to formulate them.
In the meantime, I want you
to get on with Plan B.
I was unaware we had a Plan B.
I trust you will shortly.
Understood.
Tell me, Captain, what did you
do before you knew me?
I always made sure
Plan A worked.
Ah.
While we're at it,
maybe you can arrange
for a shave and haircut,
and rustle up
a uniform for him.
It's the least we can do.
I wouldn't.
As far as he's concerned,
his tour of duty ended
30 years ago.
He's not the man he was.
I understand.
Captain Kirk to the bridge!
Kirk here.
The gravitational disturbances
are increasing faster
than anticipated, Captain.
We're runnin' out of time.
Understood.
Go to Yellow Alert. Kirk out.
If we're going
to get out of this,
I have a feeling we're going
to need the man that he was.
Captain, I've been monitoring
fluctuations in the hyperfield.
And?
There is the possibility that,
were we able to generate a
matter-antimatter negation burst
of adequate force
to free us,
we might cause the field
to implode.
And risk imploding the ship
as well.
Our calculations
must be most precise.
How much time do we have?
14 hours, 32 minutes
and 24...
Then I suggest you start
exploring it aggressively.
Didn't even give you
an ocean view.
I'd complain to the management.
Oh, Father, it's wonderful.
You haven't seen much of it yet.
That doesn't matter.
We're here.
I just wish Mother
could have seen it.
She would have given everything
just for you to see it, Alana.
This is only the beginning.
Scotty will have you flesh and
blood in no time, you'll see.
And then...
Centauri III,
the Valles Marineris on Mars,
San Francisco--
all the places
I've told you about.
We'll roll them out
like a red carpet.
You can go anywhere,
do anything.
The whole universe
is ahead of you.
Forgive the intrusion.
Dr. McCoy's
ready for you.
I'll be back soon.
Captain...
I expect you
to behave yourself.
Your father always had
a distinctive sense of humor.
Your reputation precedes
you, Captain Kirk.
Call me Jim.
And just what exactly
did he tell you about me?
How alone you were.
He told you I was lonely?
Well, that is the price
of command.
It was more than that.
It was something
you carried with you...
a distance...
Always a
different girl on every world,
none mattering
beyond the moment.
There was one who was different.
Her name... Edith.
Some things
are best forgotten.
I don't talk about the past,
and your father shouldn't have,
either.
I-I hurt you.
I'm sorry.
I'm not good with people.
Lack of practice.
It's just... he thought he would
never see any of you again.
Life seldom takes us
where we want it to.
Jim...
I understand loneliness.
You shouldn't try
to banish memories.
They're how we live on.
They're all I have of my mother.
Did you know her?
She'd just come on the ship.
I'd seen her once or twice.
You'd have liked her.
She was funny...
and brave.
I know.
She died saving you.
She didn't hesitate.
I could never be that strong.
Well...
we never know what we can do...
...until we have to.
Captain, if I may...
Excuse me.
Sensor scans of the
external hyperfield
have proven inadequate to risk
a matter-antimatter implosion
to free the ship.
What do you suggest?
The field surrounding
Miss Sulu
seems a benign microcosm
of the larger field.
If I might be allowed to
take some measurements...
Mr. Spock would like
to run some tests on you.
Will it hurt?
No.
I would've said yes anyway.
I'll see you later.
How do we start?
We already have.
One pharmaceutical cocktail
coming up.
I swear, at times like this,
I feel like a bartender,
not a doc--
Sorry, I didn't
mean to, uh...
Oh, it's all right.
The only image
I had of her was...
I understand.
Just lie back.
You'll feel a bit
light-headed and drowsy...
Should I count back
from a hundred?
Just say whatever comes to mind.
To be snatched away
from everything you know,
dropped down
in a wilderness,
have to build your life up
from nothing,
with your bare hands...
...only one thing will let you
do that and survive.
Before all that,
I was on the career track
to captain.
Friends were for off-hours...
hobbies mere diversion.
Family?
Not in the equation.
But then...
through the long nights,
we'd sit in
the crystal towers...
listen to the wind wash
over the dead sea...
gaze up at the twin moons...
share stories we remembered,
adventures we'd had...
I may have been lost...
...but I was home.
It's a rare man
that finds that...
and a lucky one.
Can I ask you a question,
Mr. Spock?
I mean,
if it doesn't distract you.
I'm not easily distracted,
Miss Sulu.
What would you like to know?
Beyond that door...
there are
hundreds of people.
And so far, I've only met six
in my whole life--
four in the last two hours.
My father told me
that you were
the only one
of your kind on the ship.
Do you ever wonder what
people think about you,
or what they see?
They will see precisely
what you are--
a singularly astute and charming
young woman.
But I'm so different.
We are, each of us, unique.
You must admit, some of us are
a lot more unique than others.
It is grammatically incorrect
to place a modifier
before "unique."
But nonetheless,
you are correct.
Some of us are.
You still haven't answered
my question.
I endure the pressures my choice
of life demands,
because I prefer it
to one of solitude...
...and because I have found
that I can tolerate being judged
far better than being
of no consequence.
The scan is complete.
I must get this data
to Mr. Scott.
So, am I one of a kind,
Mr. Spock?
You are indeed, Miss Sulu.
Kirk to sickbay.
How're we doing, Bones?
Jim, I've tried
every neural meta-mnemonic
in ship's stores on Sulu.
And?
Scattered bits and pieces,
nothing you can use.
And I can't give him any more;
his system can't take it.
I'm sorry, Jim.
How goes Plan B, Mr. Spock?
The readings I took
from Miss Sulu
should allow us to
attempt the negation burst.
As soon as Mr. Scott
concludes his adjustments,
we can proceed.
Then I suggest you do so
with all dispatch.
What's wrong?
Jim... Alana Sulu's
atomic structure
is bound to
the hyperfield.
We can't be certain she'll
be coming with us.
Scotty said he'd be able
to bring her over in time.
Time is a luxury
we do not have, Captain,
and we may not have sufficient
power for such an attempt.
Are you sure about this?
There are some variables
in the readings.
The stronger possibility is that
she will remain with the ship.
Still...
Thank you, Mr. Spock.
Should we inform Miss Sulu,
or her father?
No... not yet.
But I expect you to do whatever
you can to better her odds.
Of course.
For now...
is there anything we can do
to make her more comfortable?
Are you still hanging around?
Don't you have
anything better to do
than make fun of easy targets?
Well, we had a few moments
before the implosion attempt.
I thought I'd drop by
and give you a surprise.
A surprise?
Mr. Scott had some bored
technicians he needed to occupy.
Would you care for a stroll?
What do you call this?
Deck 12-- it's not
very imaginative.
It's perfect.
This.
What?
The best moment of my life.
Few people recognize it
while it's happening.
All the better reason
to notice it.
It's just the first of many.
It's a good look for you.
Uhura...
It's been forever.
My God...
What?
You're younger
than my daughter.
Yeah, I heard about her.
She sounds wonderful.
She takes after her mother.
Uhura to the bridge.
Acknowledged.
We'll catch up
later, okay?
Uhura.
Don't let it all go by.
If you've got
your sea legs back,
you're free to go.
Thank you, Doctor.
Those aren't really necessary.
I know.
Bridge.
It's a turbolift.
It moves horizontally and
vertically throughout the ship.
You command miracles
and you don't even know it.
I'm starting to.
Alana!
We had nothing like this
on Caliban.
The name your parents
gave that planet--
do you know where it's from?
My mother was in a production
of The Tempest
when she was a girl.
She knew it by heart.
The sorcerer
and his beautiful daughter,
marooned on an island
until a ship arrives.
"A brave vessel,
who had no doubt
some noble creatures in her..."
We'd perform it over and over.
With Sulu as Prospero...
and you as Miranda?
I preferred Ariel...
who could fly.
And where would you
like to go, Ariel?
Where would you take me, Jim?
Yes?
We're ready to initiate
the implosion, Captain.
I'll be there momentarily.
Kirk out.
Another miracle required?
I'm afraid you'll have to return
to the stasis room, for safety.
This device will
beam you there.
Oh...
You'll see the bridge soon,
I promise.
I'll hold you to that.
Where were you?
Jim arranged a tour.
"Jim"?
Are you jealous, Father?
Status, Mr. Spock.
Ready when you are, Captain.
This might be one
of those rare times
when we actually get
out of a tight spot
with some breathing room.
All decks,
this is the captain speaking.
We're about to emit a
plasma-antiplasma burst,
in an attempt to free the ship.
Brace yourselves.
At your discretion, Mr. DeSalle.
Aye, sir.
Detonation in
five... four...
three... two...
one.
Alana!
Spock! What's happening?
Unknown, Captain.
Computer, analysis
of implosion result.
Working.
Analysis indicates
temporal discontinuity
caused by implosion.
My calculations predicted
this possibility,
but not at this magnitude.
Just tell us what
it means, Spock.
It means, Doctor,
that we are still trapped,
but instead of hours,
we now have only 32 minutes
before our shields collapse.
Sulu to McCoy! Emergency!
Captain's log, supplemental.
With drug therapy no longer
an option to jog Sulu's memory,
and our time
drastically reduced
by the implosion attempt,
our options are closing
about us--
just as the field is closing
about the Enterprise.
It's nothing, really.
I was just dizzy for a moment.
She's all right now,
near as I can determine.
Miss Sulu's
molecular structure
is indeed linked to the
exterior hyperfield.
If we fail to find a way
to fully extricate her
before risking another
implosion attempt...
Another implosion's
not an option.
And without the
navigational coordinates...
Gentlemen, I suggest
you come up with
something original,
because we're not going
to just count down the minutes
until this ship
is destroyed.
Captain,
if Mr. Scott can lock in
on the coordinates of Caliban,
it might be feasible to beam
the entire ship's company there.
It wouldn't help the ship, but...
It would save the crew.
We'd be marooned there.
But alive.
And all in all,
it's not that bad a life.
But if we lower the shields...
That might not
be necessary,
given the higher
dimensions involved.
Mr. Scott.
Aye, Captain.
Dr. McCoy, if I may examine
the data on your tricorder...
Be my guest.
How are you feeling?
Like a fool.
So, tell me, back home, how are
you set up for houseguests?
Kirk here.
Captain, can you get up here?
There's no way to duplicate
the energy wave
that sent Sulu to Caliban.
It was a one-in-a-million
freak accident.
None of us can
beam there?
But I happened
on something else.
Sulu's original
transporter pattern.
The temporal field shift
kept it intact.
Are you saying we might be
able to reintegrate him?
As he was,
when we beamed him off
the bird-of-prey.
It's possible--
theoretically, at least.
25 minutes to shield failure.
Get him up here.
It should be possible to
reverse the aging process
by passing your
current incarnation
through the pattern buffer.
Restoring, in effect,
your last saved state.
Yes, I see.
I don't understand.
You mean you'd be
giving him back 30 years?
No, we'd be
taking them away.
I'd revert to the man
I was
before your mother
and I were transported.
As far as I'd be concerned,
the life we spent there
would never have happened.
But the Romulan
navigational data
will be fresh
in your mind,
and you should be able to use
it to pilot us to safety.
The memories would be gone.
I wouldn't know you.
20 minutes to shield failure.
You can't get rid of me
that easily.
I'd be here to remind you
of every stubborn, mule-headed
thing you ever did.
If it's the only way to...
Captain.
I'm sorry, Jim.
Alana?
I thought the only danger
was the implosion.
I've been reviewing
Dr. McCoy's medical data,
along with both
my own scans
of Miss Sulu
and the exterior hyperfield.
They'd best be getting
a move on.
I've no mind to be trading
my uniform
for a white robe
at this late date.
I checked her
medical readings.
There's no doubt, Jim.
Do we tell her?
We tell them both.
Captain, what is it?
Your atoms,
your molecules,
everything that is you--
is still tied to Caliban
through the hyperfield.
It's why you blacked out.
And should we succeed
shortly in freeing ourselves,
the interference caused
by our warp engines
will result in the field
collapsing...
...destroying everything
still linked to it.
My God, do you know
what you're saying?!
Yes.
You've got to beam her fully
onto the Enterprise!
Now!
Not possible.
She is one with the universe
that spawned her.
Then, can you beam me back?
No.
But were the ship to fail
to extricate itself,
there is a 92.3% probability
the field would survive,
and you would be returned
to Caliban.
She could live.
But 430 others will die.
There has to be another way.
I can't tell you what to do.
But you alone know
the navigational coordinates,
and have the piloting skill
necessary to save the ship.
I don't care who dies--
she lives!
Not this time, Mr. Spock.
Father...
I can't let you do this.
Alana...
Even if Mr. Spock is right,
and I survive--
what kind of life would that be?
How can I go back
to that empty world...
How can I live,
knowing that you,
or that all of you,
died because of me?
I don't know
if there's an afterlife,
I don't know where
we go when we die...
...but if, Father...
...it's not how long we live,
it's how we live that matters...
...let my life mean something.
Do it, damn you!
Energize.
"Our revels... now are ended.
"And these our actors,
"as I foretold you,
"were all spirits...
"that are melted into air...
"into thin air...
We are such stuff..."
"As dreams are made on..."
Ten minutes to shield failure.
He's in massive shock.
We need him on the bridge.
What can you give him?
Two cc's of
cordrazine.
Any more will kill him.
Get him to his
station-- fast.
Jim.
In a minute.
My father told me
you were impressive.
Alana, I...
Your ship needs you.
Is there anything
that you'd like?
Two minutes to shield failure.
How young he is.
How handsome.
Hyperdimensional
coordinates entered.
Artificial gravity compromised.
Life support system's
on reserve power.
Acknowledged.
One minute to shield failure.
Ten seconds to shield failure.
Nine...
Eight...
Seven...
Six...
Warp drive engaged. Hold on!
We're free!
Free.
As you were.
How are you feeling?
A little rough around the edges.
Captain...
I'm told I attacked you,
tried to harm you.
There were extenuating
circumstances.
I've watched this.
It's like it's happening
to another person.
Alana...
My daughter.
The life I had...
There's nothing.
I'm sorry for your loss.
Did you get to know her?
Yes.
She was...
She was unique.
She lived her life fully
in the time she had...
and gave it up for love.
What better epitaph...
could anyone ask for?
Oh, God.
If I could only remember.
Mr. Sulu,
when I attempted to extricate
the data from your mind,
when our thoughts were joined...
I lived those years with you.
What are you saying?
They can be yours again.
But with the memories...
would come the grief.
Very well.
Alana?
Alana...
Captain?
Captain Sulu?
Yes, Ensign?
Your guests have disembarked
from the shuttle, Captain.
Escort them to my ready room.
Aye, sir.
Rand, you have the Conn.
Aye, Captain.
Captain?
Yes?
You're a very lucky man.
"We are such stuff
as dreams are made on..."
"And our little life
is rounded with a sleep..."
Talking to
yourself, Father?
I'd better keep
a closer eye on you.
Demora.
Say hello to your granddaughter.
So beautiful.
The whole universe
is ahead of you.
And I did as you asked--
with her name.
But... I don't understand.
Who's Alana?
You had a sister.
Subtitles: Tom Collins, Teri Davidson,
Kevin King and Bill Wooton.
Technical coordination by: Mike Savage
Editor: Kevin King
Timing: Peter Walker