and finally we get to put them together for
a project.
And we’re going to learn how to make granny
squares here.
And when I say granny squares, I mean these
squares like this.
In this little sample here, these are squares
that are this big, that are all seamed together
like this.
And you can do it that way, or I have this
long-term project here [laughs] excuse me.
Where I am making one giant granny square,
without seaming anything together.
And I’m using leftover yarn for this. And
so this is a really long term project because
I’m collecting more dk weight yarn. Or, this
is actually fingering weight yarn, to keep
making this project.
And I’ve used a lot of yarn so far, and now
I’m waiting for more leftovers so I can keep
working on this.
But, the granny squares work up really quickly,
it’s an easy way to make a blanket, a quick
way to make a blanket.
And so far in these crochet techniques, we’ve
been stabbing into stitches, which can be
hard to get your crochet hook in there.
This goes so much faster. Because granny squares,
we stab into these big gaps that are created
when we chain.
It will all be clear in just a minute.
Let’s go ahead and get started right away
with this.
Oh! There is a download associated with this
video. If you’d like to get your free copy
of the granny squares pattern, you can click
the link below, take you to my website, and
you can get your pattern.
Okay, let’s take a look.
Here we are, we’re going to start with a
slip knot, like we always do.
I’m going to chain four.
Okay.
We’re going to make a chain ring with this,
so I want to connect this around to itself.
Actually, for demonstration, I’m going to
go ahead and chain an extra one.
I want to slip stitch into this stitch here,
and I’m going to slip stitch into the left
leg of this stitch.
If you need a review of the slip stitch, I’ll
give you a link here.
So I’ll stab into there, pull up a loop,
and pull it through the second one as well.
Ta-da! We have a tiny ring.
Now granny squares are just a bunch of clusters
of three double crochets together.
I’m going to chain three to get myself setup
to work a double crochet.
And if you need a review of double crochet,
I’ll give you a link right here.
I’m going to yarn over, stab into the center
of the ring, grab a loop and pull it up, giving
me three loops on the hook, grab the yarn
pull through two, grab the yarn pull through
two.
Just a regular double crochet.
Yarn over, stab into the center of the ring,
grab the yarn and pull up a loop, grab the
yarn pull through two, grab the yarn pull
through two.
I’m going to smush those together, those
double crochets.
What I have here, when I start out it’s a
bit different than the rest of it.
I have a chain three here, then I have a double
crochet and a double crochet.
It looks like three double crochets, because
we are counting that chain three as the first
double crochet.
So that counts as a cluster of three.
I’m going to chain two.
And I’m going to work another cluster of
double crochets.
Okay, I actually worked three this time, smush
those around.
Chain two.
And work another cluster.
And while you’re working through this, I
am working kind of quickly, you can just pause
the video to catch up, and work your double
crochets, and then we can essentially move
on to the next step together.
So now I have one, two, three clusters of
double crochets. I need to work one more.
Chain two.
Okay. Four clusters of three double crochets,
chain two.
And I want to connect this into, umm, kind
of a circle, kind of a square, at this point.
So I’m going to slip stitch into one, two,
the third chain.
This is the chain three that we did right
at the beginning.
I’m going to slip stitch into this third
chain.
And there we are.
Take a look at this.
You should have four distinct gaps, where
you chained two, with a double crochet cluster
between each one.
And it is already looking like a square.
Go ahead and catch up with me, and what we’ve
done here, and next up we’re going to move
on to the next round, or the second round.
Hopefully you’ve caught up with me and you’ve
finished your first round, we’re going to
go into the second round of the granny square.
And when I work granny squares – you can
do all kinds of different things with colors
and the way you put them together and everything
else.
I’m kind of stuck on this thing where I change
colors every two rounds.
So we did the first round in this red color.
I’m going to continue with the second round
in this red color.
Let’s go ahead and take a look.
Here’s a granny square that I did.
And there’s my first round, and there’s
my second round, in pink.
And then I changed to this cream color for
the third and fourth round, and then I did
border colors in this green, for the fifth
and sixth round.
Okay.
Here we are with our first round finished.
And we were stabbing into the center circle
for the first round.
We’re going to be stabbing into these four
corner gaps right here, for the second round.
And our working loop is right here.
We need to travel over to get to this gap
here.
And to do that, I’m going to slip stitch,
usually I find that just two slipped stitches
will get me close enough to this gap.
I’m going to slip stitch into the back leg
the right leg, I guess of the V here, grab
the yarn, pull through both, stab, grab the
yarn, pull through both.
And then I want to slip stitch into this gap.
So I stab into the gap, grab the yarn, pull
up a loop, pull it through the loop on the
hook.
Let me show you that one more time.
Stab into the gap, grab the yarn and pull
up a loop, then pull it through the loop on
the hook.
Okay, now I’m actually in this gap and ready
to start working.
So I chain three to get started, get myself
set up for double crochet.
And I’m going to work – you guessed it.
Another cluster of three double crochets.
Just like with the first row, that first chain
that I did counts as one of the double crochets.
So one, two, three, chain two.
And I’m going to work a second cluster into
this same corner.
Okay.
So I have two clusters of three double crochets
with a chain two between them in this corner.
I’m ready to travel over and start working
in this corner.
I’m going to chain one this time. We only
chain two on the corners, we chain one when
we’re working across to the next corner.
I’m going to work my first cluster.
Chain two.
[laughs] My working yarn fell on the floor
a long time ago, and I didn’t bother picking
it up [laughs], so I’m just going to pull
a bunch of yarn on the table.
You notice I’m always squishing the stitches
over to make room for the next one.
Okay.
One, two, three, chain two, one, two, three.
I’m ready to travel over to the next gap,
so I chain one.
And work two more double crochet clusters.
Smush those over, chain two.
Chain one to move on to the next gap.
You see how much more quickly this goes when
you’re not carefully stabbing into a stitch.
I think that’s the slowest part of crochet,
is when you have to really watch where you’re
putting your hook into the work. And you just
don’t with granny squares.
Chain two.
Work my second cluster.
Okay.
I’m going to chain one here, because I’m
traveling over to this one.
And just like we did with the first round,
I need to connect this side to this side.
So I count up one, two, three, and slip stitch
into that stitch to connect them.
Now let me straighten this out so we can take
a look.
I should have four distinct corners.
With a chain one gap between each one.
Next up in round three, I’m going to show
you how to change colors.
Okay, hopefully you’ve caught up with finishing
that round.
We’re going to move on to the third round,
and change colors this time.
Let’s go ahead and take a look.
This is exactly where we left off in the last
video, I have this one loop left here.
And all I’m going to do is just break the
yarn, and pull that through, just like how
we fasten off in knitting.
Now, last time, we had to travel with slip
stitches over to get to the next gap.
When you change colors you don’t have to
do that.
Umm, I apologize for the colors here. I guess
it’s kind of christmasey looking. [laughs]
But, it should be easy to see, at least!
I am going to start in a corner. Because I
always start a new color in a corner.
You can start in a side gap if you like.
But I am going to stab into a corner, and
just like when I’m attaching new yarn when
I’m knitting, I’m going to fold the yarn
over, leaving myself about a six inch tail,
and make a loop, put that on the hook and
pull up a loop.
Now to get started we’re going to chain three.
To get started with double crochet I want
to chain three.
The one thing that I like to do to help secure
the tail end is I hold both strands together
for the chain three.
Okay. So my end is kind of…uhh, It’s probably
pretty much woven in there. I might want to
weave it in a little bit more, but it’s pretty
much woven in.
Now I’m going to work two clusters of three
double crochet in this corner.
Anyway, that’s the way to change colors.
You really just start working with it, and
chain up.
Oh, this yarn is so much smoother than the
red yarn!
So again, just like with the other corners,
the chain three that I did counts as double
crochet, I’m did two more, I’m going to
chain two – I’m sorry, I’m going to chain
one. Because I’m going to travel over to
this side gap here.
And I’m going to work one cluster of double
crochets in this side gap.
This is where it starts to get a little bit
different. Because the sides are becoming
longer.
So not everything is a corner anymore.
It will be clear here in just a minute.
So I’m going to chain one to travel over
here.
To work two double crochet clusters in this
corner.
And after I get these worked, I will go over
again how the pattern is emerging here.
Here’s one, I’m going to chain two, because
it’s a corner.
Okay, let’s talk about what we just did.
Whoops! I only worked one over here in this
corner!
I need a second one! But I can catch it on
the way over.
Okay, let’s just look at the part I did here.
[laughs]
We have two clusters of double crochets here,
because it’s a corner.
We have just one cluster here, because it’s
a side.
And I’m going to work a second one here.
If I had been thinking about it, I would have
worked the second one while I was there, but
since it’s the beginning of the row, I can
just work it in there when I get all the way
around the whole side.
So now, as I go over to this side, I have
this side gap here, where I’m going to work
one double crochet cluster.
And I have the corner, where I’m going to
work two.
When I’m traveling from one gap to the next,
I chain one between.
So I’m going to chain one, one double crochet
cluster, chain one, and then a double crochet
cluster here, chain two, a second double crochet
cluster in here.
Let’s actually do it.
Chain one.
One cluster of three double crochets.
I should have been working with this yarn
all along! It is so smooth!
It has baby alpaca in it.
Chain one.
To travel over to this gap.
Chain two after the first cluster.
And there you have it. You continue that around
for this whole round.
And then from here on out, the only thing
that really changes is that you’re going
to end up with more side gaps, that’s what
I call them.
There is always going to be four corners,
but you’ll have more side gaps like these
here, where you’ll work a cluster of one
in each one.
If you follow the pattern, it will tell you
exactly how to continue working for the other
rounds.
Next up, I’m going to show you how to seam
the granny squares together.
As I mentioned at the beginning of this lesson,
you have the option of doing a bunch of granny
squares and seaming them together like this,
or you can keep working around and around,
like I did here, where it’s just one giant
granny square with no seaming.
I will tell you that if you choose to do it
this way, you’re going to need greater and
greater and greater amounts of yarn to actually
make it all the way around the whole thing!
[laughs] in one color.
Which is one of the reasons this project is
on hold until I get a lot more of this weight
of yarn to keep working on that leftover blanket.
Okay, I’m going to show you how to seam here.
And crocheted seaming is really easy to do.
Easier than mattress stitch. Let’s go ahead
and take a look.
I have these two giant granny squares finished
here.
And crochet isn’t all that different from
the right side to the wrong side.
But the wrong side you’ll have your tail
end, hopefully sticking out on the wrong side,
and the stitches look a little flatter.
Once you look at it, crochet for a while,
it becomes easy to tell which is which.
The reason I’m mentioning this is because
we’re going to seam on the wrong side of
the work.
We’re going to have the wrong side of the
work facing out.
And I’m actually going to turn it this way.
Now, the sides of the crochet looks like a
bind off row.
With a bunch of Vs, and that’s exactly how
we’re going to be – that’s exactly what
we’re going to work into as we seam.
We’re going to find the bottom corner over
here on this first one, and I’m going to
work into the bottom V, or what I would call
the right leg of the V.
I’m going to stab into there.
And then over here, my Vs are going this way,
I’m going to work into the top leg of the
V.
So I’m leaving a leg of V on the inside of
the work.
Or on the right side of the work.
So I stab into both of those, and this is
really just slip stitch.
I’m going to attach the yarn. If you were
thinking ahead, you could have left long tails,
I suppose, at the end of your work.
I’m going to fold the yarn over, leaving
myself like a six inch tail to weave in.
Loop it around the hook, and pull it through
both loops.
Then again, I’m going to stab into the outside
leg of the top, and the outside leg of the
bottom.
Grab the yarn and pull it through all three
loops.
Outside leg, outside leg. Whoops, I grabbed
too much there.
Grab the yarn and pull it through all three
loops.
I’m slip stitching these, as I seam them.
And I want to show you what I’m talking about
here, why we’re grabbing the outside legs.
Because it gives you this border, between
the squares.
By leaving the leg of the V on the right side
of the work and just grabbing the ones on
the outside, it gives you this border, which
is really nice.
If you don’t want the border, you can stab
through both legs of the V, and have it go
like that, but I think it looks good.
Let me show you again.
Stab into the outside leg, the outside leg,
grab the yarn, and pull it through all three
loops.
You see how quickly this goes.
And it’s not just because I’m using super
bulky yarn, this really does go quickly.
Whoops.
Let’s take a quick look at how this looks
on the right side.
You’ll see that border that I was talking
about, showing up here like this.
Doesn’t it look good?
Now when you’re seaming granny squares, I
recommend that you do it just like you were
seaming blocks in knitting.
Seam blocks together all the way across to
make a long strip.
And then seam the long strips together.
So seam these boxes together this way, and
then seam the long strips together like that.
And that will do it! You’re well on your
way to making your granny square blanket!
Good luck.
[music]