GRACE HELBIG: When I was
younger, I wanted to be in the
Swim With the Dolphins
program.
I also wanted to be
a veterinarian.
I wanted to be an
Olympic gymnast.
I wanted to be a professional
horseback rider.
The idea of making money on the
internet was nowhere in my
brain ever as a possibility.
No way.
Well, it was confusing because
every time I told my parents
that I make web videos, my
mom thought it was porn.
Welcome to the internet!
Hi.
I'm Grace Helbig, but on the
internet, I go by Daily Grace.
I host My Damn Channel Live
Thursdays, and I have a daily
vlog called Daily Grace.
Byeee!
[RECORD SCRATCH]
GRACE HELBIG: I think it's
time for some ass play.
So I grew up in beautiful,
beautiful South Jersey.
But I grew up in a family
of brothers.
I have two brothers and
three stepbrothers.
And I really thought they were
the funniest people in the
entire world.
I remember one day on a car
ride, I was doing an
impersonation of Cartman
from South Park.
That's Kenny's creamed corn.
CARTMAN FROM SOUTH PARK: And
you will respect mah
authoritah.
GRACE HELBIG: Doesn't sound
anything like Cartman, but
they loved it.
And the one day that I did make
them laugh was the day I
was like, so validated and was
on such a pursuit to keep that
feeling going.
Michelle and I lived together
senior year and then moved to
Brooklyn together after
we graduated.
MICHELLE VARGAS: Hello.
GRACE HELBIG: Hi.
MICHELLE VARGAS: I'm Michelle.
GRACE HELBIG: I'm Grace.
MICHELLE VARGAS: And we're
GraceNMichelle.
GRACE HELBIG: What?
MICHELLE VARGAS: What?
GRACE HELBIG: Welcome
to the brand new--
GRACE N MICHELLE: Totally
T1tz Tuesday!
GRACE HELBIG: So when I moved
to Brooklyn, Michelle and I
were doing our GraceNMichelle.
and I was working for Viacom
at the time in project
management, all while
doing improv at the
People's Improv Theater.
And I am not good at
managing projects.
And I also wanted to really
pursue a more creative
lifestyle than sitting
behind a desk.
So I quit.
GRACENMICHELLE: That's great!
GRACE HELBIG: How do you
say it in Spanish?
Tittays?
And through the theater I got
a casting call for a web
series called Bedtime Stories.
That was the first thing in New
York that I ever booked.
GRACE HELBIG: Hansel
and Gretel.
Hansel noticed the witch
walked kind of
funny and took a shot.
Do you suffer from
vaginal dryness?
Why, yes, that's true.
Hansel removed a tube from his
pocket and said, then Lubricil
may be the answer.
Come back next time when you'll
hear the fable of the
Elf and the Glory Hole.
I didn't realize that it was
a web series going up on
MyDamnChannel.com.
And Rob Barnett, the CEO of My
Damn Channel, called me in and
said, we want someone
to host our website.
[MUSIC - MY DAMN CHANNEL
LIVE THEME SONG]
GRACE HELBIG: If you guys missed
yesterday's show with
Michael Showalter,
here's a clip.
MICHAEL SHOWALTER: What do
you think about Skittles?
BETH HOYT: I have nothing.
I just, I had some today.
MICHAEL SHOWALTER: You
had Skittles today?
BETH HOYT: Yeah.
I didn't buy them.
They were just in front of me,
and I would never refuse a
bowl of Skittles.
I like the sound of the
clink-clink of the Skittles.
What about you?
MICHAEL SHOWALTER:
Skittles make a
lovely clink-clink sound.
GRACE HELBIG: They do make a
So it's not just, here's
a bunch of content.
Watch it.
Instead it'd be me, going,
hey, what'd you
guys think of this?
What'd you think of this?
Let's have an internet dialogue
with each other.
A coworker doesn't seem to
understand the concept of
personal space.
How do I tell him
to step back?
OK.
This is my suggestion to you.
You get up real close to him,
super-duper close--
well, he's already probably
close to you.
You just say, listen, friend.
I have unpredictable
diarrhea right now.
Do your farts smell as
good as you look?
No.
No, they don't.
And then it grew.
Four years later, I'm making
a video every day.
I get to do my own comedy
pieces every day.
I write, shoot, edit all
of it myself from home.
These are business expenses.
A lot of my day is just
sitting around
playing with toys.
What is Grace at home?
Grace at home is pretty mellow,
pretty low-key.
Until this guy goes on.
And then shit goes crazy.
There's my face.
Crazy.
Total magic.
Record audio.
Record video.
Hi, guys.
And the [GARBLED]
mouth.
Get away from me, flies.
So I don't know if you guys
saw the Jim Carrey vlog
proclaiming his love
for Emma Stone.
This is a message
for Pat Sajak.
Pat.
Can I buy a your dick
in my vagina?
I'd like to solve the puzzle.
[BLEEP]
me.
The internet is great
because--
the reach.
It can just reach so many
people at one time.
I could never do that
on a stage at the
People's Improv Theater.
I can reach 100 people,
maybe, at that stage.
But I can reach 100,000 people
when I post a video every day.
They appreciate the work that
I put into it so thoroughly.
I just got a PO box a little
while ago, so people send fan
art and all kinds of stuff.
Yeah.
People are so talented,
and it's crazy.
It's so crazy.
These kids are insanely
talented.
And look.
Look at that.
That's insane.
I make web videos, and then
people make this.
What?
Crazy.
Hey, guys.
It's Friday here on Daily
Grace, and you
know what that means.
Sexy Friday.
It's a lot of teenage girls
that don't want to be the
pretty, vapid girl.
They like being awkward or
silly or weird or funny.
And I want to keep them feeling
like they should do
that, and that there is a place
for that, and it's fun
to be that way, and to just
enjoy themselves.
So I think--
it sounds cheesy, but the thing
that I want to do is
just to keep these girls feeling
good about themselves.
Bye!
[DING]
RYAN DUFFY: So Grace gets really
cute t-shirts from her
fans, and I get letters
from inmates with
weird stains on them.
Next up, we're going to teach
you how to get from point A to
point B without looking like a
complete and total dipshit in
the process.
This is Etiquette Update
with John Martin.
JOHN MARTIN: Here are some
rules for airport travel.
When you're in an airport, you
always walk fast, to the left,
on moving sidewalks
and escalators.
Know those people
on the right?
People in sweat pants.
Or velour pants.
Those are what failed
businessmen become
when they have kids.
Those are their kids.
Dropped an ice.
Spend $400 a year on a
decent credit card.
It'll get you in the
airport lounge.
And the beauty of that is
it'll get you away from
numbskull Floridians with
low-hanging pants.
No one wants to look at that as
they're boarding a 12-hour
flight to Mumbai.
RYAN DUFFY: Etiquette tips from
a guy who can't even sip
a gin and tonic without
spilling on himself.
Thanks, John.
Thanks for watching another
episode of Vice Today, and
come back for brand
new episodes
every Monday and Thursday.
As always, if you like it,
please do subscribe.