NICK PERATA: My name's
Nick Perata.
The thing I like to do
most when I'm not
riding steeps is jibbing.
You're riding on everything that
you see in your path--
logs, rocks, small children,
anything.
PIERRE WIKBERG: Jibbing, in a
freaking neon jacket he had,
and was just like, oh,
we're just jibbing.
Dreadlocks, just crazy Frogskins
or something.
It just seemed really innocent
back in the Tahoe days.
That word "jibbing" started,
Nick Perata said it.
DAVE DOWNING: The whole jibbing
thing was going on in
the late '80s.
It was just hitting little trees
or rocks or whatever
that was non-snow obstacles.
It kind of translated into kids
riding hand rails in the
street, or just doing stuff
in the street--
small things.
And then that escalated into
bigger and bigger things, like
Snow Park Technologies and Bear
Mountain and other places
started building specific
things for snowboarding.
And now look at it.
It's pretty crazy.
They're putting stair steps and
kink rails and wall rides
in the snow.
It's pretty cool seeing how
it came to be here.
CHRIS GUNNARSON: I told you we
were bringing it back on a
2011 scale.
CHAD DINENNA: You can't
really compare it to
the previous years.
It's on such a different
scale.
CHRIS GUNNARSON: The last
Jibfest was eight years ago.
And we set the bar so high
with the original Nixon
Jibfest that if we were going
to bring it back eight years
later, it needed to be on
a whole new level of
awesomeness.
CHAD DINENNA: The best part
of it is when all the
snowboarders come up for the
first time, and they see it,
and they start to process it.
That's what it's all about.
It's like going from small
town to the big city.
CHRIS GUNNARSON: Actually,
Jeremy called it Awesome Town.
CHAD DINENNA: Awesome Town.
CHRIS GUNNARSON: Welcome
to Awesome Town.
CHAD DINENNA: Welcome
JEREMY JONES: It's pretty
on point, really.
Dudes are just stoked.
They're stoked to be here, the
kids are stoked to be here.
They just saw all this
when they grew up.
They've all just gotten
bigger, and
so this is the biggest.
It's going to be super fun.
PAT BRIDGES: Throughout the
whole course of snowboarding,
a common thread has always
been skateboarding.
Taking the influence of
skateboarding, because
everybody skates.
Taking that influence and
bringing it to snowboarding.
PIERRE WIKBERG: I think if you
are skateboarding and you're
snowboarding, it's natural
to combine them.
Everyone who skateboards
then rides a snowboard.
It just translates.
PAT BRIDGES: They just started
trying to mimic skateboarding
beyond just how you grabbed
your board or
riding a half pipe.
These guy's took mimicking
skateboarding to all aspects
of snowboarding.
NATE COLE: We were trying to
find hand rails more than
anything at that time when
we first all started.
There was really nothing
else to do, so we'd
snowboard after the days.
No one had a job
hardly at all.
You couldn't skate.
There was no indoor
skateboarding at all.
So you'd find--
if it was snowing enough, you'd
just go find a hand rail
and slide on it.
But then it was limited, of
course, with what you can do
with that, so it'd
be picnic tables.
JAKE BLATTNER: We'd always get
pissed during the holiday
seasons when everyone would come
and they'd be eating on
the picnic tables.
I remember doing [INAUDIBLE]
where [INAUDIBLE] would do
tail slides across the thing
while people were
still eating and stuff.
ROAN ROGERS: We just went nuts
on the hand rail stuff for a
couple years, and then I don't
think we ever really thought
of it as we are starting
something or anything.
We were more or less copying
the skateboarders, you know
what I mean, and trying to
do what they were doing.
NATE COLE: And I was just so
much wanting to skateboard.
Most people were almost more
skateboarders than they were
snowboarders.
They were just wanting to do
that as much as anything, so
couldn't quite get that same
feeling, but you were going
for that always.
You felt like it should
be more like that.
DAVE DOWNING: There was a crew
of dudes that were jibbing
stuff, and then it kind
of faded away.
I don't remember the year, but
it faded away for about five
years, I'd say.
And then, really, the truth is
JP Walker and Jeremy Jones and
their little crew from Utah were
the first ones to really
bring that whole jibbing think
back into the limelight of
snowboarding.
JP WALKER: I always watched
those old videos of those guys
jibbing, and that just
seemed so cool.
And when I started snowboarding,
that's what I
started doing.
So it wasn't like I was
trying to make some
effort or bring it back.
It was just like, I'm just going
to do what I like doing
and have fun doing it.
JEREMY JONES: I had "Hard, the
Hungry, and the Homeless"
soundtrack in my Dotson B210 on
tape that I recorded from
the VCR through the
TV on to a tape.
That was my soundtrack so I'd
hear all the snowboard sounds
and the slides down the rail
driving to the mountain, and
that was it.
Burned the tape out because
that was our scene.
JP WALKER: None of us were never
really into contests at
all, but we'd been doing it.
There'd been all these different
contests happening.
We'd been going to X Games
and doing things.
And someone said the word
"anti-contest." We need to
come up with this
anti-contest.
And that wasn't so much like the
direct motivation behind
the thing, but it was just kind
of like, let's have an
event where only people we
like are at this event.
We'll only invite people from
the media that we like.
There won't be all these
spectators that are just
creating unwanted pressure
and stuff.
It kind of just started
from there.
And then, I think just because
we were so into jibbing at the
time, it was like, well, it's
going to be a jib contest.
CHAD DINENNA: Just a couple
things, you guys.
First of all, I want to thank
everyone for coming.
It's been eight years since we
brought everyone together for
an event like this.
The premise for me is just to
say thanks to the people who
have supported the brand since
the beginning, and to invite
some new people into the mix.
I think one of the fun things
for us is, because as a brand,
as we've grown up--
my background being
in a magazine--
we've really worked hard with
the different media groups to
make it something that you guys
can roll out of here and
get some really good
exposure out of it.
And not only have a good time,
but really reap the rewards of
your hard work and
your fun times.
We try not to have a lot
of rules to this.
This is not a contest.
It's a good time.
-There is a winner, though.
CHAD DINENNA: You're right,
[INAUDIBLE], there is a winner.
But you're the judges.
At the end of the day, on the
last day, we have a pad of
paper, and I'm going to
sit down with you.
And you're going to write down
who you think rode the best--
your top three favorites
and the best trick.
Someone that's going to leave a
lasting impression on you in
the four days, three days that
we're here together.
Part of it, just as much of it
as it is all of us riding
together on the hill, it's
the time that we spend
together like this.
At the end of the day, I just
want you guys to be stoked on
what's here for you,
and I want you all
to have a good time.
[APPLAUSE]
-Just like leg a season out.
We all deal with this and that,
and that's why this
thing is so cool is just
because we can
go up and just shred.