MALE SPEAKER 1: Hey, we're
The Black Lips.
We're in San Diego.
And we promised you guys we'd
play live in Mexico.
And we're only a few
miles from there.
So we're on our way
to Tijuana.
And this is what we're doing.
We're going to buy some
trinkets, play some music.
MALE SPEAKER 2: Check
out a couple spots.
MALE SPEAKER 1: I think I'm
totally going to get laid.
I've got $30.
[MUSIC - BLACK LIPS,
"BOOMERANG"]
[APPLAUSE]
DERRICK BECKLES: Well, here we
are in downtown Tijuana.
It's Friday night.
There's a young male
prostitute.
Looking for-- probably
got a suitcase full
of dildos or something.
This is Mariachi Row, where they
all hang out waiting to
be picked up like prostitutes to
come play at rock and roll
shows or children's parties
or something.
MALE SPEAKER 1: Now we'd
like to introduce our
very special friends.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
[APPLAUSE]
MALE SPEAKER 3: Mariachis.
MALE SPEAKER 4: Are
they still here?
Oh, yeah.
[MARIACHI MUSIC PLAYING]
MALE SPEAKER 5:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
[MUSIC CONTINUES]
[APPLAUSE]
MALE SPEAKER 6: Yeah!
[MUSIC - BLACK LIPS,
"SEA OF BLASPHEMY"]
[APPLAUSE]
MALE SPEAKER 1: We just
got shaken down.
Thank God we didn't smoke pot
tonight because they were
smelling all our fingers.
MALE SPEAKER 2:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
DERRICK BECKLES: How
much do you charge?
What's the going rate?
MALE SPEAKER 1: They took
my money but they put
it back in my pocket.
DERRICK BECKLES: What's
the going rate
for smelling fingers?
MALE SPEAKER 1: Uh, $40.
MALE SPEAKER 3: Maybe they were
shaking us down to see if
we had anything so they could
fucking [INAUDIBLE].
MALE SPEAKER 1: They saw me
peeing over there so that's
why they stopped us.
DERRICK BECKLES: Really?
MALE SPEAKER 2:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
DERRICK BECKLES: So they
saw you peeing and
they thought, hey.
Let's smell fingers.
MALE SPEAKER 1: Hey,
if this guy pisses
he's gotta smoke pot.
DERRICK BECKLES: Guys,
let's test for urine.
[SNIFFING]
Mmm.
You're good.
MALE SPEAKER 1: Let's
go surfing.
MALE SPEAKER: One, two, three.
[MUSIC - BLACK LIPS,
"STRANGER"]
DERRICK BECKLES: So, any
show highlights, lads?
MALE SPEAKER 2: Girls finger
popping on stage.
MALE SPEAKER 1: Yeah, two
people passed out finger
banging on a couch
in the office.
And they probably stole
[INAUDIBLE]
BlackBerry.
I'm not sure.
MALE SPEAKER 3: The Mariachi
in the middle at
the end of the set.
Can't beat that.
DERRICK BECKLES: How
was the crowd?
MALE SPEAKER 1: The
crowd was tough.
It was more about the crowd
than actually us.
Because everybody was
a part of the band.
I had to fight a little Mexican
boy because he kept
slapping me in the face and
giving me kissy faces.
And I'm usually not--
don't do stuff like that.
Our sometime US tour manager
Randy took a piss and got a 20
bag planted on him
that wasn't his.
And he got shaken
down for $800.
We only had a few
things stolen.
And overall, I think
we nailed it.
Kinda.
And the music was recorded
beautifully.
And it was a challenge.
But we're always up
to a challenge.
And that's how you
play in Mexico.
MALE SPEAKER 7: Keep going.