never done stuff like--
that, on the first date, so I
blame the heat of victory.
Stupid confidence.
Stupid cute gamer boy.
[SIGHS]
I gotta come clean
with the guild.
Better to be up front about
this than be discovered.
That would be so "after school
special." I mean, what if Vork
caught us emoting in-game,
or Clara spotted
us out at the movies?
We'd be at a foreign one, with
subtitles, and then we'd go
out and eat something exotic
afterwards, like, oysters, or
prosciutto.
Whatever that is.
Anyway, I'm gonna
tell the guild.
I'm gonna do it-- just
get it done.
Yes.
Mm.
[THEME MUSIC]
CLARA (SINGING): Enchant a
fish and make a wish, the
Festival of The Sea--
TINKERBALLA: Clara.
Stop singing along
with the MPC's.
CLARA: Oh come on,
Tink-- this is my
favorite in-game holiday.
All the Mermaid quests
and pirates--
I can't wait to get
my character that
epic coconut bra.
BLADEZZ: I get enough pirate
crap here at work.
Can we run a dungeon or
something that doesn't make me
want to spit in a
burger again?
VORK: Before we embark on the
adorable seasonal [INAUDIBLE]
pet quest, I have a proposal.
CODEX: You guys?
Hey?
Um, it's Codex.
I just wanted to say--
ZABOO: I'm gonna name our
sea horse Drowny.
Ironic'ed.
CODEX: But Vork--
I need to let you guys know
that, um, there's--
[POWER FAILS]
But--
Was that a sign?
[ALARM SOUND]
ZABOO: That-that's my
mom's ring tone.
Why is she calling?
Why now?
She hasn't called
in weeks, dude.
Don't call, don't call--
stop-- stop,stop--
uh-- uh--
VORK: Are you done now?
ZABOO: Ahh--
ah.
Yeah, I'm done.
CODEX: Back.
As I was saying--
VORK: I have decided that The
Knights of Good should have a
custom guild hall.
CODEX: --or you go first.
CLARA: What?
A custom guild hall?
Cool.
What's that?
ZABOO: Don't you read
the patch notes?
CLARA: Never.
VORK: The new expansion
has added clear design
housing to the game.
My hope is that a communal guild
area will help repair
the emotional scars from our
near recent breakup.
In addition, I want one.
TINKERBALLA: Vork.
Those things are expensive
and pointless.
Totally e-peen strokers.
BLADEZZ: You guys know how I
feel about e-peen stroking.
JEANETTE: Hey, idiot.
I can't serve a charcoal
briquette.
Remake it.
And get off that computer,
or I'm telling Ollie.
BLADEZZ: Who won't
do anything.
The boss loves me.
You, on the other hand--
[SMASH]
Watch the face!
ZABOO: If we're going to get a
guild hall, we need to get the
biggest and baddest one.
TINKERBALLA: The deluxe castle
model's half a million gold.
VORK: Precisely.
And we have-- ?
ZABOO: 20,000 in the bank.
CLARA: Half a million?
And we have 20,000?
That's like--
oh, yeah.
There's a difference.
CODEX: I, uh, I heard that the
Axis of Anarchy is saving for
a Deluxe one, too.
Huh, which reminds me--
TINKERBALLA: Those D-bags
are getting one?
That's it.
I'm in.
BLADEZZ: Yeah.
Screw those guys.
That dude Bruiser is still
dating my mom.
Get this.
He took her on a wine tour
through Napa, like she's fancy
or something.
TINKERBALLA: Yeah, and Fawkes
made the lewdest comments
about you, Codex.
CODEX: Really?
He did?
ZABOO: That's unacceptable.
VORK: He's reprehensible.
CLARA: I'm hungry.
CODEX: I'm dating him.
ZABOO: Ahhh!
CODEX: Zaboo?
VORK: What is with you today?
TINKERBALLA: You're
dating Fawkes?
He almost ripped apart
the guild.
BLADEZZ: Actually,
you started it.
TINKERBALLA: I will
dent your face.
CODEX: We've only
had one date.
And it was after
the LAN party.
I am not a traitor.
CLARA: Enemies become lovers?
Oh my god.
This is like the soap opera
I used to watch.
Maybe you have an evil twin,
and he's secretly a NASCAR
driver slash surgeon.
VORK: I am not putting my
mouth to your mouth.
[COUGHING]
ZABOO: What?
Codex is dating Fawkes?
What the heck happened?
Why did I disconnect those
surveillance cameras?
CLARA: On second thought?
Maybe he's a bull fighter,
and you're in the witness
protection program.
BLADEZZ: You're banging him,
and their Guild healer is
banging my mom.
That's guild incest.
CODEX: No, wait a second-- wait
wait wait wait wait--
I have never done anything like
this before, and, and and
there were some unique
circumstances.
Remember, I--
I had won something--
TINKERBALLA: Wait.
So you did bang him?
I never pegged you
for a ho-bag--
ZABOO: Wait--
you what?
CLARA: Whoa--
you boffed him after
only one date?
Achievement unlocked.
BLADEZZ: Wait-- did you
boff him or bang him?
Get the story straight here,
and with details.
CODEX: It's not--
Guys?
We are dating.
We are in a relationship.
So if stuff happened,
then it's private.
CLARA: Not anymore.
CODEX: I know he seemed like a
jerk, but, um, he's different.
We might be good together.
I just want to see
where this goes.
TINKERBALLA: It's
going nowhere.
He's an anarchist.
There's no way he's
gonna date you.
CODEX: That's not true.
He--
he left his jacket here.
CLARA: He left something?
Classic move.
It's like when a dog pees
on a fire hydrant.
He's totally into you.
VORK: Codex, we're discussing
building a guild hall.
This is seriously distracting.
CODEX: I was upfront
about everything.
Can't I get props for that?
UNISON: No.
[ELECTRICAL SIZZLE]
CODEX: Oh--
oh, oh oh--
Now who's judging me?
CODEX: I hope this
thing works.
I was in middle of arguing
with the Guild, and my
computer just-- pow!
This bedroom feels like
a crime scene now.
For more than one reason.
Telling the Guild about Fawkes
was the right thing to do.
I just wish they hadn't jumped
to all the right conclusions.
They're so mad at me.
I texted everyone.
Help-- computer broke.
Sad face.
And Bladezz was the first
one to respond.
He's coming over with some spare
pity parts he had lying
around, see if he can
fix the thing.
He needs to hurry.
I know they're talking
about me--
I can feel it.
Did I mention I can't get
online right now?
[PHONE RINGS]
FAWKES: Damn it, Venom-- why
don't you just cut off my dick
and tell me it's a popsicle?
[CELLPHONE RING]
Raiding.
CODEX: Hi.
It's Codex.
I've been having some computer
problems, so if you see me
offline, I--
I didn't want you to think I was
avoiding you or anything.
FAWKES: To think that would
be pathetically neurotic.
CODEX: Oh.
So--
I haven't talked to you since
our date the other night.
I don't normally drink, but
I had a really good time.
FAWKES: As did I. I believe my
favorite part of the evening
was after the second margarita,
when you said, come
back to my place and
take my armor off.
CODEX: Wow.
Drunk me is really forward.
FAWKES: It's nothing
to be ashamed of.
The sexual act is one of our
basic animal instincts.
CODEX: Well, I shy away from my
base instincts and try hard
to be really classy.
Like Audrey Hepburn?
FAWKES: At a certain point in
the evening, you farted on me.
In order to make me
taco-flavored.
It was cute.
CODEX: Moving on.
Tonight, I was thinking
that, uh--
I have your jacket.
FAWKES: Bring it to 521 Spring
Street at 8:00 PM.
CODEX: OK, it's a date.
Oh.
You hung up.
[KNOCKING]
BLADEZZ: I heard you let
the bad boys in.
CODEX: Thanks for coming over.
Is the Guild still
talking about me?
Fix my computer.
Hurry--
BLADEZZ: OK.
OK.
But just so you know, I told the
boss that I had a family
thing come up.
So if anyone asks, you're my
cousin who had boob surgery.
CODEX: Eh--
OK.
The computer's right there.
BLADEZZ: Oh.
On the bed and waiting for me.
Roar.
CODEX: Do you have to
make everything
into a sexual innuendo?
BLADEZZ: I'd like
to in your endo.
CODEX: Ugh.
God, you're awful.
CLARA: Who would've thought
that last holy bolt Codex
shoved up Fawkes' butt at the
LAN party would've goosed them
into a relationship?
So romantic.
TINKERBALLA: Reality check.
There will be no relationship.
Be prepared for her
depressed voice.
Also known as normal voice.
ZABOO: I don't understand
women.
Codex is dating a jerk, my one
and girlfriend Riley locked me
in a clothes dryer,
and then my ma--
and then my ma-- ther--
m-- mother--
see, I can't even say it--
TINKERBALLA: It's not your fault
you're a social retard
with girls.
ZABOO: It's not?
TINKERBALLA: My Psych 101 class,
which I went to once,
says it all starts
with the parents.
CLARA: Parents influence
their kids?
What is that, a new study?
ZABOO: But you're women.
And I'm totally normal
with you dudes.
TINKERBALLA: Normal?
CLARA: Because we're
your friends.
Just treat Codex like
you would treat us.
Because, let's face it--
you and Codex?
TINKERBALLA: Not gonna happen.
ZABOO: Yeah.
You're right.
I need to let go of that, and
focus on being her friend.
100%.
No.
110%.
Even though the math
is weird on that.
I'm gonna be her best
friend ever.
So--
how do I do that?
TINKERBALLA: When did this guild
go from playing a game
together to talking about
feelings and holding each
other's vaginas?
ZABOO: Do you guys
really do that?
BLADEZZ: There's gross lady
dander all in this thing.
CODEX: I didn't know you needed
to vacuum in there.
Who tells you that?
Did you fix it?
BLADEZZ: You're better off
buying a new computer.
CODEX: I can't buy
a new computer.
I'm poor.
My credit cards are maxed.
I survive on Ramen, that's why
my skin's so dry, and--
ew, I'm sharing so much
personal stuff today.
Where'd you get all these
parts, anyway?
BLADEZZ: Oh, the, uh, public
library computer.
CODEX: What?
BLADEZZ: You're a part
of the public.
OK.
Here we go.
[COMPUTER FIRES UP]
CODEX: I love that sound.
Move over.
[THUD]
I have to log on.
I can feel them talking
about me.
I have to defend myself.
VORK: The aesthetics
are irrelevant.
We're building a guild hall,
not a banjo factory.
CODEX: Oh.
So self-centered.
What's going on?
ZABOO: Welcome back, best friend
Codex my friendy friend
frienderson.
We're just discussing design
options for the guild hall.
TINKERBALLA: We need someone
with a vision.
And I am that person.
Check out my color pallate.
ZABOO: Whoa.
BLADEZZ: OK, that looks like a
preschooler's sock drawer.
Let me design it.
Can we buy a slave
girl on PCs?
ZABOO: I think we should
let Codex do it.
To show that we as a collective
are fine with
whatever personal decisions
she makes in her life.
CLARA: Vork--
I'm gonna fax you my design.
I used every single
crayon color.
TINKERBALLA: Hold up, chickie.
Who made you lead designer?
CLARA: But I want the
turret model--
TINKERBALLA: I want
the turret model.
CLARA: I want the formal
gardens add-on--
TINKERBALLA: So do I.
With the gazebo?
CLARA: And magenta walls?
TINKERBALLA: Yes-- with
the eggshell trim.
CLARA: Did you borrow
my crayon set?
And my mind?
VORK: A gazebo painted
in #FF33CC?
No.
The primary function should
be defensibility.
Or you use the austere.
#33333 stone.
#FF33CC would make an extremely
eye catching target
for an aerial dragon assault.
CODEX: That feature doesn't
even exist in the game.
VORK: There could be
future additional
downloadable content.
BLADEZZ: OK, look.
If it's defensible you want,
then the blood fountain is an
immediate in.
TINKERBALLA: No one wants to
hang out in a hair band video.
CODEX: Why don't we compromise
on a design that
everyone can enjoy?
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
That's not fair--
Great idea, long-time
companion.
No--
BLADEZZ: What are you, stupid?
CODEX: But the whole point of
building a guild hall was to
bring us together.
We shouldn't let this turn
into a competition.
VORK: I agree, Codex.
The only fair way to settle this
would be to give design
rights to whoever earns
the most gold.
CODEX: Vork, that's the very
definition of a competition.
VORK: Fundraising
shall commence--
now.
CLARA: Oh--
BLADEZZ: No fair.
I have to go back to work.
CODEX: I can't start
till tomorrow.
I have to get ready
for my date.
I want to find a really good
quote to open with.
ZABOO: So you're definitely
going out with Fawkes again.
I'm excited for you.
Because friends support
friends.
Oh, man, this is going
to be tough.
CODEX: "And one by one the
nights between our separated
cities are joined." One by one
the nights between our
separated--
VENOM: Jacket.
Now!
Nice dress.
Go die in it.
CODEX: Last night was a
miscommunication, that's all.
When I was on the phone with
Fawkes yesterday, I'm pretty
sure I heard rock sound effects
in the background.
Which meant he was ready to give
Venom her sentence, which
is super intense on the
leadership side.
Plus, I just dance around
things too much.
I should have just come out and
said, Do you want to get
together tonight for a date?
Sure, part of me is, like,
Is he the jerk I
thought he was before?
Or is that just a facade, hiding
the really cool dude
who made me feel pretty, and
awesome, and who I impulsively
went way too far with?
I'll just wait for
him to call me.
Or I could text him.
Email?
In-game mail?
IM?
That's a weird sound.
ZABOO: Man, you are set.
Man.
Bladezz used some chinky
parts in here.
I think some of it
was from an ATM.
CODEX: Thanks for
looking at it.
ZABOO: No problemo.
I hope that I'm not, like,
parachuting into Fawkes
territory or anything.
I know this is, like,
boyfriendville.
CODEX: Uh--
no, it's, it's early, so I
didn't want to bother him.
ZABOO: Look at how far
we've come, huh?
From star-crossed lovers
to inseparable BFFs.
Roller coastered.
CODEX: Ah, I wouldn't describe
it either of
those ways, but thanks.
ZABOO: And-- heh heh--
in support of your budding
romance, I had this painting
commissioned for you,
best friend.
Voila'd.
Yeah.
I know.
I was speechless, too.
This friend of mine who does
van art whipped it
right up for me.
The likenesses are
pretty special.
And, potentially, could end
up on the side of a van.
CODEX: Yeah, it is special.
Thank you.
ZABOO: I know the Guild's been
giving you a ton of flak for
dating this guy.
But I'm in support.
Put me on Team Codex Fawkes.
Team Cawkes.
Thinking about making
T-shirts.
CODEX: Uh, no.
We should play.
ZABOO: Oh, yeah, let's
play, for sure.
[RINGTONE SOUND]
Oo--
Voice mail.
Ah--
it's my mom again.
She's being so creepy.
Listen.
ZABOO'S MOM: Hello, Sujan.
It's my birthday soon, and for
me the best present would be
just to hear the sound
of your voice.
Goodbye.
ZABOO: She's insane.
CODEX: It sounded OK to me.
ZABOO: OK?
You met my mom.
You know that OK would never
be used to describe her.
Ever.
CODEX: Look.
Sometimes people change.
They might've been jerks, but
then something happens, and
you find out they aren't
jerks anymore.
So if something else happens
that makes you suspicious that
they really are the jerks that
you thought they were, you
should really give them the
benefit of the doubt, and--
and wait for them to call you.
ZABOO: Are we still
talking about me?
CODEX: What?
ZABOO: Huh?
CODEX: Yes.
Yes.
You should give your
mom a chance.
ZABOO: OK.
All right, you're right.
Wow.
This is really great.
I love being in a friend zone.
I never knew women could
be such great pals.
CLARA: Vork is a loser,
Vork is a loser.
CODEX: Sometimes.
Why the hateful chanting?
VORK: My iron ingots are not
selling in the trading house.
I've only made 2,000 gold so
far towards the guild hall.
CLARA: And Tink and I teamed
up to clean up.
Up to 5,000 gold already.
TINKERBALLA: With Clara's
tailoring and my enchanting,
we're making sets of uber
fishing gloves.
They're selling like hotcakes
'cause of all the Sea Festival
quests this week.
CLARA: We also have
a bit worked out.
We invite the guy to a private
chat channel called Fishy
Lips, and then Tink goes--
TINKERBALLA: --you want
these gloves--
CLARA: -- then I go, You need
these gloves, and then really
quick we say--
TINKERBALLA: Want.
CLARA: Need.
TINKERBALLA: 50 gold.
Pay up.
CLARA: We sell a pair,
every time.
ZABOO: Oo.
Lady voiced.
I'll buy three pairs.
TINKERBALLA: Later.
Clara--
customer.
CLARA: Oh--
VORK: Can I turn them in for
auditory prostitution?
ZABOO: For selling
fish gloves?
Seems kind of drastic, dude.
VORK: I can't let them win.
I need a defensible
guild hall, not a
glitter infested, puff--
puffy paint palace.
And where's Bladezz?
CODEX: He has a job.
He's at Cheesybeards.
VORK: Maybe he and
I can team up.
I do need someone with
a work ethic.
OLLIE: Oh-- that's quite a heave
ho in that left arm.
Good toss, lad.
JEANETTE: That's it?
You chewed my ass off
last week for
serving wilted lettuce.
OLLIE: Oo--
don't mutiny, Jeanette.
Or I'll make you
walk the plank.
BLADEZZ: Order up, Jeanette.
[DING]
CODEX: No, Zaboo, I don't want
to talk about what Fawkes
smells like.
ZABOO: I bet it's like
a combination
of nutmeg and rawhide.
CODEX: He's not a gingerbread
cowboy.
CLARA: We're back.
15 more sets of gloves sold.
VORK: Aneurysm.
CODEX: What--
what is going on with
my computer?
My character's leaping around
the screen like a
crack-filled ferret.
TINKERBALLA: Why don't
you get your new
boyfriend to buy you one?
I can't believe he went
out with you again.
CLARA: Oh, that's right.
Codex, how did your date
go last night?
ZABOO: Yeah, let's dish.
CODEX: Uh, it's a long story.
Heh-heh.
Um, dating is, it's-- the dating
world is complicated,
and sometimes--
[COMPUTER POWERS DOWN]
my computer crashed.
CLARA: Codex, Fawkes is riding
by right now with the whole
Axis of Anarchy.
VORK: Probably on their way to
purchase a deluxe guild hall
with a sensible color scheme.
CODEX: Don't message him.
Oh-- stupid computer.
ZABOO: I'll just log onto your
character from my laptop.
CODEX: Wait, you have
my password?
ZABOO: Oh.
Well sometimes I go into your
backpack and rearrange all the
items in your inventory.
Inventory Tetris'ed.
CLARA: Slash wave at him.
[ELEPHANT SOUNDS
FROM COMPUTER]
TINKERBALLA: You just
got blown off by a
guy riding a mastodon.
CODEX: Maybe he was
on auto-follow.
Or he didn't recognize me.
Yeah.
ZABOO: You know, a human
red-haired female priest with
an elite herald tunic
isn't uncommon.
CLARA: Well, maybe
you should--
CODEX: --call him.
You're right.
Because we're dating.
I should be able to do that.
ZABOO: Yeah, you
go, girlfriend.
CODEX: OK.
ZABOO: Friend girl.
CLARA: I was gonna say, why
don't you just get drunk and
show up at his doorstep?
But calling's good, too.
[TELEPHONE RINGS]
FAWKES: Journaling.
CODEX: Hi.
It's Codex.
Uh, did you get your jacket?
FAWKES: I did.
CODEX: I kind of thought you'd
pick it up yourself.
FAWKES: You can't
undo the past.
But you can certainly
not repeat it.
Bruce Willis.
CODEX: OK.
So do you want to
set a time now?
To go out together?
For-- for a date?
FAWKES: Yeah, I thought I made
this clear between us.
I don't date.
CODEX: What?
No.
No, that certainly was not
clear, because I don't do one
time deals.
FAWKES: Well apparently
in this case, you did.
CODEX: Wait, so--
[CLICK]
Oh my god.
I really am a ho-bag?
CODEX: I'm not a slut.
I'm not.
I am a good girl.
The worst thing I've ever done
is sniff a permanent marker.
But it was only 15 seconds,
tops, and the whole time I was
screaming inside,
Stop-- cancer--
stop.
What did I misunderstand
about that date?
We got along great.
Eh, that rhymes.
But with a little logic, and a
mild panic attack, I convinced
Fawkes to meet me
for a non date-
deductible business meeting.
I'm gonna figure out what
happened, deal with him
calmly, and then we
will go out again.
We have to.
A one-time deal?
What is the guild gonna think?
I'm their priest.
I have a virtual reputation
to uphold.
So I just wanted to understand
some of the nuances of the
other night more clearly.
Heh.
Um, why are we not going
out again, again?
FAWKES: Codex, you bested me
in one-on-one combat in the
Kinlandia Arena, and for that
you have earned my respect.
However, I have a strict
one date only policy.
CODEX: OK, that part?
Why?
FAWKES: I am an epicurean.
It is my goal in this life to
experience all that womankind
has to offer.
I sample once, and
then I move on.
CODEX: Yeah, but, but we, we
have so much in common.
FAWKES: Mm.
Such as?
CODEX: Well, the game.
And we both use the Internet
to play the
game, and we both--
you know what?
There is definitely something
here, or I would never have
let you plug into my port.
FAWKES: Well, we had
great chemistry.
That is undeniable--
CODEX: See?
That's something.
I mean, you were talking about
how we were all base and
animally and stuff,
and-- wait.
You're not a furry, are you?
FAWKES: I haven't gotten to that
part of the list yet, no.
CODEX: OK, so, let's
go out again.
I mean, look at us right now.
This is, like, so super fun.
JEANETTE: Honey, don't beg
a guy to date you.
That is just sorry business.
FAWKES: Out of the
mouths of babes.
JEANETTE: Mm--
you are yummy.
CODEX: OK.
You don't want to
see me again?
That's fine.
I can deal with that.
But the thing is, I kind of
told the guild about us.
FAWKES: You told your guild
about our one night of
passionate monkey sex?
CODEX: It kind of came
up in conversation.
So I'm just gonna tell the guild
that we're still going
out for just a little while
longer, and I would appreciate
it if you would cover for me.
Could you do that for me?
Please?
FAWKES: Wow, you've really put
a lot of thought into this.
CODEX: Yes.
All night last night.
Obsessively.
FAWKES: OK, what's
in it for me?
CODEX: I make good brownies.
BLADEZZ: Hey, our only
two customers.
I wanted to stop by to
see what's causing
all the guild turmoil.
FAWKES: We're causing turmoil
in your guild?
BLADEZZ: Oh, yeah.
Tink's having a fit, Zaboo
almost had a heart attack--
FAWKES: Really.
Mmm--
mwah.
Post that on your
guild's forum.
BLADEZZ: Yes, sir.
FAWKES: OK, Codex.
I'll cover for you.
CODEX: Thank you.
Thank you very much.
FAWKES: I don't want you to
feel ashamed about what
happened between us.
You are in elite company.
Last year, at Comic-Con?
I bedded the creator
of the comic
Circuitra, Robot Princess.
CODEX: Oh--
I loved that--
never mind.
VORK: I've notated
every single gold
vein in the game atlas.
If you camp the lower
quadrant--
ZABOO: Yeah, Vork, I
can't help you with
the guild hall, buddy.
I am neck-deep in my quest
for understanding women.
And this lady quiz is going to
tell my effectiveness as a
supportive sidekick.
VORK: No one in the world would
find that interesting.
ZABOO: Question number eight.
Your best friend's boyfriend
broke up with her.
Do you, A, pamper her with a
trip to a relaxing day spa; B,
take her out for salsa dancing;
or C, comfort her
with a tearjerker movie
and ice cream?
VORK: C.
ZABOO: Why C?
VORK: The majority of multiple
choice answers are always C.
In addition, comfort requires
emotional commitment, and
salsa dancing is performed
in poor lighting.
Now get out your pick axe
and start a-mining.
ZABOO: Fine.
[ALARM SOUNDING]
Aw, dude--
it's my mom.
What should I do?
VORK: If you're not mining,
you're dead to me.
ZABOO: All right.
I'm going to answer it.
I have you on speaker phone--
I'm not alone.
ZABOO'S MOM: Sujan?
It's so nice to hear
your voice.
Did you get the cyber-vite
for my birthday?
ZABOO: Uh, yes, but I'm
not gonna make it.
And I notice that you invited
Dad, and he's dead, so he's
probably not gonna
make it, either.
ZABOO'S MOM: That's all right.
This call is the best present
I could ever have.
ZABOO: OK.
Um, is that it?
ZABOO'S MOM: That's all.
Good bye.
ZABOO: Wha-- no guilt trips?
No screaming?
What's going on?
I mean, is she being
held hostage?
Is there a ransom?
I'm not gonna pay it.
VORK: I said nothing, corpse.
Carry on.
ZABOO: Question number nine.
If your friendship
was a food--
VORK: C.
ZABOO: C.
BLADEZZ: He stuck you
with the bill, too.
I have to take lessons
from this guy--
CODEX: Shut up.
It was a great second date.
We are so into each other.
BLADEZZ: Hm.
CODEX: And I why don't
we talk about
something that's your business?
Like my computer?
That you supposedly fixed,
that barely works?
How am I supposed to play?
BLADEZZ: Oh, OK.
Give me 50 bucks for a second
house call, I'll check it out.
CODEX: 50 bucks?
I told you, I'm really poor.
You're supposed to
be my friend.
BLADEZZ: Jesus, woman, you
need to be tranqed.
CODEX: I'm sorry.
It's just, I'm so stressed
right now.
I just have to have
a computer.
For the guild hall, for living--
it's, like, so
important--
BLADEZZ: OK.
Don't leak.
If you need quick dough,
Bladezz'll hook you up.
Go.
OLLIE: So, Sherman.
Just, um, who are you
to Simon here?
CODEX: Uh, it's complicated--
BLADEZZ: She's my cousin.
OLLIE: The one who
had boob surgery?
BLADEZZ: Yeah.
She made 'em smaller.
OLLIE: Went too far.
So, you ever work
in food service?
CODEX: I used to
be a musician.
OLLIE: Musician, eh?
Well, I used to be
semi-professional myself.
Heh heh heh--
pirate balladeer.
(SINGING) So, they whacked me
up, they whacked me down, the
first mate cracked me upon the
crown, and then they boogered
me round and round, when
I was just a shaver.
[LAUGHTER]
CODEX: That's a lovely
baritone.
OLLIE: Oh, I also sing
first tenor.
Well, I--
I'd like to throw you a life
jacket, lass, but, um, I'm not
hiring right now.
No, business is in the bilge.
BLADEZZ: Aw, come on, boss.
She's old and reliable
looking.
Can't she swab something?
CODEX: Well, look-- you
have a computer.
Drool.
OLLIE: Oh, that.
Never turn on the blasted
contraption.
CODEX: Wait, you've never
turned it on?
Poor thing.
Uh, do you need it?
OLLIE: Oh, aye, yes.
It-- it serves me well
as a paperweight.
CODEX: Can I stay
here and use it?
To help you?
With business?
OLLIE: How?
CODEX: Uh--
websites.
Yes, websites, and, and
social networking.
They can all get people
into your restaurant.
Right?
OLLIE: You can do that?
CODEX: Yes.
OLLIE: Well, slog
my jolly boat--
BLADEZZ: Whoa, whoa, whoa.
OK, I'm cool with throwing you
a bone, but if there's fun,
white-collar work to be done,
I'll be the guy paid to do it.
OLLIE: Oh, no way, lad.
Gotta have you where
I need you.
Grub master.
Below decks.
BLADEZZ: Bu,bu, but I--I--
CODEX: Then I will do it.
I am the lassie for the job.
OLLIE: Never say
old Black Ollie
didn't parlay with progress.
You see, I'll give you a split
of the booty, if you can crew
up those tables out there.
Deal?
CODEX: Aye, aye, Captain.
[LAUGHTER]
OLLIE: Arrgh--
CODEX: Arrgh--
Heh heh--
Bladezz got me a job.
That he's pissed at me for
getting, but, whatever.
A job.
It's been so long, it feels
weird coming out of my mouth.
Job.
OK.
I'll stop.
I'm not technically qualified,
or getting paid up front--
which is so like me--
but I think I can do this.
Social media can't
be that hard.
Every bozo on the internet
claims to be an expert.
And, I think I worked out the
whole Fawkes thing, so by the
end of week, I will have a brand
new computer, and be
innocuously broken up in
a face-saving manner.
Life is pretty good right now.
Why did I say that?
I just totally jinxed it.
Ohh--
CLARA: I can't believe
you got a job, Codex.
I'm so jealous.
Is it glamorous?
Are you wearing a
pencil skirt?
VORK: The important question
is, can I get a discount on
foodstuffs?
Namely, discounted to free.
CODEX: It's a little early to
be asking for free stuff.
I've gotta get paying customers
in here first.
But it is nice to have a
working computer again.
I named her Harriett.
CLARA: Do people really hate
Cheesybeards' food that much?
I thought their cosmos
were good.
ZABOO: Some of these comments
are horrible.
Leaky disaster.
Tastes like butt pirate butt.
VORK: Ahh--
CODEX: I know.
And Ollie doesn't even
own the domain name.
I had to get Cheesybeards.info.
CLARA: You get to buy
domain names?
Ah, you're such a
jet-setter now.
Wah--
MR. WIGGLY: What's wrong?
Are you guys-- ?
Oh.
I thought it was one
of the kids.
CLARA: Honey, Codex got a job.
She's working from work and
having so much fun right now.
MR. WIGGLY: You have
a job, Bunny.
It's the most important
job of all.
Being a mom.
[BLENDER SOUND]
Gabby?
CLARA: Meh.
Oo, Codex--
I saw that picture of you and
Fawkes that Bladezz posted.
Talk about a two- hander.
What?
TINKERBALLA: I don't want that
disaster porn on the forums.
Some of us have sensitive
stomachs.
ZABOO: Don't worry, Codex.
I'll create a separate forum
topic for you to post pictures
and videos for those of us,
you know, who want to
celebrate your love.
Also, I've been doing my friend
research, and have
learned how to braid hair in
eight different styles.
Mostly from Hairly
Legal magazine.
CODEX: No, no, no, no, no--
Tink is right.
From now on, I'll keep my
relationship with Fawkes on
the down low.
For the good of the guild.
No matter how it's going.
Ooh--
BLADEZZ: Move.
I have to keep up with
guild hall farming.
CODEX: Don't be mad at me.
I can't help it if Ollie
gave me a job
that's better than yours.
BLADEZZ: Hey, I'm the rogue.
I'm supposed to do the
backstabbing here.
CODEX: A lot of the bad
internet comments are
specifically about you.
Horrible food, cooked
by sleepy-looking
feather-haired kid?
BLADEZZ: They're called
layers, hater.
You guys can weep, but as I'm
up to 25K on guild hall
farming, prepare for bloody
axes and iron maidens.
TINKERBALLA: Correction.
Fairy and unicorn tapestries.
Clara, check our numbers.
CLARA: Tink and I are
up 60 K. Eat it--
VORK: 60 K?
I've been practicing classic
Keynesian economics and I'm
only up to 27.
In addition, I haven't left
this chair in two days.
ZABOO: Ah-- that's 'cause he's
been pounding energy drinks.
VORK: That's urine.
From my penis.
I can't waste valuable
mining time.
CLARA: We added sexy music to
our Fishy Lips chat channel,
and tell people our real-life
names are Darla and Pancake.
TINKERBALLA: Look forward to
filigree out your butthole.
And Cupid add-ons.
ZABOO: Ugh--
rococoed.
CLARA: Are you still here?
MR. WIGGLY: Don't
be mad, honey.
You and Tink seem to have
a great business online.
Isn't that enough?
CLARA: Yeah, but--
[BREATH]
Hey.
What if Tink and I started
a real business?
MR. WIGGLY: What kind
of business?
CLARA: Tink, Wiggly just
had a great idea.
We work so good together,
we have to
start a real business--
MR. WIGGLY: Uh, I
said nothing.
TINKERBALLA: Like,
out of game?
CLARA: Yeah.
Making real money.
TINKERBALLA: I like that word.
Money.
BLADEZZ: We know.
TINKERBALLA: What could we do?
CLARA: Oh, Wiggly will help us
with the stupid details.
He does this for a living.
MR. WIGGLY: Honey--
I'm in pharmaceuticals, on
salary, I've never--
CLARA: Tink, come over.
He's already making ideas.
Wiggly will put out
a cheese tray.
TINKERBALLA: Mm.
As long as you lock up
the babies, I'm game.
CLARA: Wiggly--
cheese tray.
CODEX: Looks like I started a
real-life leveling trend.
VORK: Good job, Codex.
Keep going so I'm the
only one unemployed.
I want that game and all
its assets to myself.
OLLIE: Hard at work
in here, aye lass?
CODEX: Uh, yeah.
We're working hard.
Right?
OLLIE: 'Cause I give no
quarter to stowaways.
[FANFARE]
ZABOO: Codex is gonna look
so slammin' with
this fishtail braid.
And then, I texted my
mom, Happy Birthday.
And then she wrote
back, Thank you.
I'm officially a woman
whisperer.
[ALARM]
Ah--
VORK: Visitors.
ZABOO: Oh--
[ZAP]
Vork-- no, no, no, don't open
the door, do not open the--
ZABOO'S MOM: Hello.
I came to celebrate my birthday
with my son--
ZABOO: Mom?
ZABOO'S MOM: Sujan?
ZABOO: Hi, mom.
ZABOO'S MOM: What--
ZABOO: Press the button
when I do that.
Press the button.
CODEX: I thought it would
be cool, being able
to log on from work.
But Ollie keeps ambushing me.
It's making me totally
paranoid.
This webcam's gonna look like
a cheap seaside horror film.
Anyway, I've been doing a lot of
web stuff for Cheesybeards,
and-- what was that noise?
Ollie is so stealthy
for a pirate.
Why can't he have a peg
leg, instead of a,
a sharp shiny hook?
And what's the deal with
that thing, anyway?
Is it real, or a costume?
How do you find out?
There is just no protocol.
What came first?
The pirate, or the hook?
BLADEZZ: Arrgh--
CODEX: Oh, oh, oh!
BLADEZZ: Avast ye, Sherman--
uh-hunh--
ZABOO: Mom, you can't just
show up to my place
uninvited--
VORK: Correction.
My place.
ZABOO'S MOM: But you make me
happy with the texting, Sujan.
I thought you'd want
to celebrate.
ZABOO: No.
Oh, god, you are strong.
Uh-- look, I'm not going
home with you, OK?
I'm here, hanging with
my homey, Vork.
VORK: Don't touch me.
ZABOO: OK.
ZABOO'S MOM: Why do you
assume such things?
I just came to invite
you to dinner.
ZABOO: Oh.
So you can drug me.
And then stuff me
into a trunk.
Just like when you kidnapped
me from science camp.
They were not gonna clone me.
ZABOO'S MOM: Let's dwell
on the positive.
Oo--
this is a pretty
fishtail braid.
ZABOO: Well.
It is a difficult technique
to master.
ZABOO'S MOM: Uh-huh.
ZABOO: Lots of ins and outs.
Stop messing with my mind.
[BACKGROUND VOICES]
CODEX: Vork?
Are you watching a
Bollywood film?
VORK: No.
It's Zaboo and his mother.
She arrived uninvited.
[SPEAKING HINDI]
ZABOO'S MOM: Oh--
ZABOO: How many languages
do you know, dude?
VORK: All of them.
CODEX: What?
But we downed that boss.
What does she want?
CLARA: It's her birthday, and
she's there to be friendly,
and celebrate.
CODEX: That's a weird respawn.
MR. WIGGLY: Honey, your, uh,
angry agent friend is here.
CLARA: Oh, Tink's here for
a business meeting.
Wiggly.
Pretend you're my put
upon assistant.
MR. WIGGLY: I've told you
not to call me Wiggly.
I don't--
I don't game anymore.
CLARA: Ah, Wiggly.
Fetch me some water, boy.
VORK: Codex, now that we're
alone, I want you to join
forces with me to earn money
for the guild hall.
CODEX: Join forces.
How?
VORK: As a healer, I can rent
you out to priestless groups.
CODEX: No.
No, I'm not letting you pimp
me out for your guild hall.
VORK: Plan B. I can transcribe
episodes of Dynasty from my
VHS collection.
And we can reenact scenes in
a common area, for tips.
CODEX: Who would pay
us for that?
VORK: The story lines are
sordid and compelling.
People could watch between
tournament bouts.
CODEX: Uh, thanks, sir, but I
don't think that's appropriate
for our organization
at this time.
BLADEZZ: Cleaned out the
rat traps, boss.
Whattya want to do with them?
Tomorrow's special?
[LAUGHTER]
Whoops-- my bad.
COMPUTER VOICE: Our communal
environment is at stake--
CODEX: Um, sir, we appreciate
your passion.
But a charity project isn't
something we can help with, at
this time--
VORK: Foreign talkers!
Please!
CODEX: Outsourcing.
We'll get back with you.
OLLIE: There's an empty galley
out there, Sherman.
Is this project ever gonna
put into port?
CODEX: No, I'm working hard.
I created a MyFace account,
and a Tweeter account--
BLADEZZ: Caught that,
by the way.
Our burgers are Pira- licious.
Out of three followers, two
unfollowed you, and the third
just left a comment
saying, Gay.
CODEX: I'm still getting
the hang of it.
BLADEZZ: And a lot of
nasty remarks on
that Yelp review site.
It is so hard to keep
people happy.
CODEX: If you'll excuse
us for a second.
Hunh-hunh.
I know you're leaving those
nasty comments.
NotBladezz69?
Bladezz Duh.
BLADEZZ: I'm just trying to keep
you on your feet while I
flip burgers in the bung hole.
CODEX: OK.
Let's deal.
What can I do for you,
besides quit?
Don't smile like that.
MR. WIGGLY: So--
ah, Tink.
Is that your real name?
CLARA: Honey-- stop
grilling her.
MR. WIGGLY: Tink, I'm sorry.
Please.
Forgive me.
I didn't mean to
be so invasive.
CLARA: Let's get down
to business.
Can we get a 1-800 number?
I've just always wanted one.
1-800 GET CLARA?
It's just so easy to remember.
MR. WIGGLY: Well, we might be
jumping the gun just a bit.
First let's figure out, like,
what is it that you two want
to do together?
CLARA: Something--
TINKERBALLA: --that makes
a ton of money--
CLARA: --with no effort.
MR. WIGGLY: OK.
Yeah, we're gonna have
to narrow it
down just a bit more.
All right, Clara, you're
a mom, and Tink, what
is it that you do?
TINKERBALLA: [SIGHS]
CLARA: Honey.
MR. WIGGLY: What--
Tink, I'm sorry, please--
Tink.
Stop.
No more grilling, OK?
I don't--
I don't have much to work on
here, but, see, you're both
women, and you game together--
CLARA: Oh my god, what
a great idea.
Women making real money
from gaming.
TINKERBALLA: I'd be into that.
MR. WIGGLY: No, that's not
really the plan, it's--
CLARA: I'm gonna go make
business cards.
This is official now.
[LAUGHTER]
[ARCADE MUSIC]
OLLIE: Arrgh.
Dogs with a laser--
Well that floods my poop deck.
CODEX: And that's only
video, Ollie.
OLLIE: A commercial
for the internet.
And you know how to do that?
Without makin' it look
like a shipwreck?
CODEX: It doesn't matter.
That video has 7,000,000
views.
Think about all those burgers.
OLLIE: Aye.
Aye, good point, lass.
I might have to franchise.
Expand the fleet.
CODEX: Well, let's not
get carried away.
BLADEZZ: And, lucky for you, you
have a professional actor
on this demo reel is a monologue
I did from Huck Finn
that gave my grandmother
a stroke.
Literally.
OLLIE: I like this idea.
I like this idea a lot.
Do it.
In the meantime, let's watch
more dog videos.
[BARKING FROM COMPUTER]
[OLLIE'S LAUGHTER]
ZABOO'S MOM: You're so good
at game running, Sujan.
ZABOO: I'm not paying
attention to you.
VORK: For someone who claimed
to have cracked the woman
code, you're entirely
incompetent right now.
ZABOO: Yeah, you're right.
Mom?
I will go to your
birthday dinner.
But, I'm bringing my friends.
Vork?
VORK: Who's paying?
ZABOO'S MOM: Well, it's
my birthday, so--
VORK: Mm.
ZABOO'S MOM: --of course
I'll be paying for it.
VORK: Let's go.
CODEX: Hey.
Finally got the computer back.
Never show an old person
a dog video.
It's like entering a recursive
loop you can never escape.
ZABOO: Hey, Codex.
I need you to come to my mom's
birthday dinner tonight.
Gotta have my back, bestie.
CODEX: Uh, I, uh, I,
I have a date.
With Fawkes.
Because, you know,
we're dating.
So that's what we're doing.
We're dating.
ZABOO: Sweet.
Bring him right along.
CODEX: Nuh-- but but but--
ZABOO: Directions texted.
CODEX: But, no, no, but--
ZABOO: See you there.
CODEX: No--
Uh--
God, I'm such a slow thinker.
Hey, everyone.
Fawkes couldn't make it.
It's really funny story, hunh,
I wrote it down on my hand--
FAWKES: What's a funny
story, kissy face?
Mwha--
VORK: More bread, please?
CODEX: I've never gotten into
real time strategy games.
It's hard enough responding to
a turn based scenario, but
adding a real time element?
How is that fun?
I have a hard enough time
coping with real
life in real time.
Like, if I'd had a pause button,
I could have come up
with an actual good excuse why
I couldn't go to dinner, or
cope better with the fact that
Zaboo sent Fawkes the
restaurant info, and he
actually showed up.
I was speechless.
I had nothing.
My resources were
totally maxed.
Let's face it--
I got zerged.
FAWKES: Mm--
mwah--
ZABOO: This does not
nauseate me at all.
FAWKES: I am so glad that
I was able to cancel my
emergency Anarchist's Club
meeting downtown.
CODEX: Thank you, muffin face.
You really didn't
have to do it.
Really.
ZABOO: Fawkes-- meet my mom.
FAWKES: Enchanted.
You know, with Bruiser dating
Bladezz' mom, the mothers of
The Knights of Good have
become epic idols.
You should all get together and
do a swimsuit calendar.
VORK: My mother's dead.
Employing her as Miss September
would simply be
inappropriate.
ZABOO'S MOM: So, Sujan.
Tell me about your new life.
Tell me all about it.
ZABOO: I game.
And then I game some more.
ZABOO'S MOM: Oh.
Wonderful.
ZABOO: And then I moved out of
Codex' place, on a quest to
become a man.
ZABOO'S MOM: Your father would
be so proud, Sujan.
ZABOO: Well then Codex threw me
over for a total anus faced
stunt guy, and then I started
dating this hardcore bisexual
FPS gamer chick.
She took my V-card, and then
she started dating this
paraplegic goth girl, and now
I'm staying at Vork's in a
toddler bed underneath
a bunch of pigeons--
VORK: Squab.
ZABOO: --squab, trying
to understand women.
FAWKES: It was worth the
trip just to hear that.
VORK: Just to clarify, you're
paying for the entire bill?
ZABOO'S MOM: Yes.
For the 50th time, yes.
VORK: Happy birthday to me.
BLADEZZ: Ladies?
Start drafting your
press releases on
how you knew me when.
Codex is filming a Cheesybeards
commercial
tomorrow, starring moi.
I'm gonna have to film a sex
tape after this, to capitalize
on my fame.
TINKERBALLA: Now I have
to go bleach my brain.
CLARA: Tell him about
our company, Tink.
TINKERBALLA: Bladezz?
Pass.
CLARA: We wanted to make money
off of gaming, and we thought
of a niche no one was serving.
Tees for pregnant gamers.
Say hello to Pregamers.
TINKERBALLA: Pre-Gamers.
CLARA: Pregamers.
CLARA: Preg-amers?
TINKERBALLA: Let's work
on that name later.
CLARA: We even have a bunch
of slogans already.
Newb On Board.
Mini Boss.
Don't Frag My Baby.
That one was Tink's.
Women of all ages
will want one.
BLADEZZ: All ages?
Give me one for Dena.
Her middle school teachers
are going to flip.
Where are you selling them?
CLARA: We haven't worked out
the worky icky parts yet.
TINKERBALLA: Oh, I can't wait
to design the logo.
Some 8-bit baby with
a machine gun.
[KNOCKING]
BLADEZZ: Oh, dudes, my
acting coach is here.
We need to run some
facial expressions
in the mirror tonight.
This time we're doing
number six--
Nick Cage, puzzled.
DENA: Terrible.
I can't believe I'm missing
my bocce ball
tournament for this.
CLARA: Tink, we need more
t-shirt models.
Oo-- text Codex and tell her to
get the unprotected nasty
on tonight.
[CELLPHONE RING]
CODEX: Tink.
What the eff?
VORK: The pork tenderloins--
do they freeze well, or do I
need to vacuum seal them?
WAITER: I don't know.
VORK: Then I'll only
have seven of them.
ZABOO'S MOM: Well, it is my
birthday, so I do have one
small request.
ZABOO: I knew there
was a catch.
ZABOO'S MOM: I've been going
to these meetings at AA.
ZABOO: Mom--
when did you start drinking?
ZABOO'S MOM: I haven't
been drinking.
But co-dependents anonymous is
full of very whiny people.
So, as a step in my process, I
have to go through each one of
the things that I did, and
apologize for them.
FAWKES: Well that's
very interesting.
ZABOO: I really appreciate
that, Mom.
Hey-- a toast.
To new beginnings.
Ha.
Starting--
ZABOO'S MOM: To begin
with, I took you to
modeling class, remember?
I forced you to go to it, though
your runway walk was
quite jaunty, I must say.
ZABOO: Ha ha ha, yeah--
ZABOO'S MOM: I apologize
for that.
FAWKES: We're learning all sorts
of exciting things about
you today, aren't we?
ZABOO'S MOM: And then,
at your bris--
FAWKES: Excuse me.
Isn't a bris a Jewish
tradition?
ZABOO: Yeah, we're Hin-Jews.
So anyway, yeah--
ZABOO'S MOM: We had it when he
was 10 years old, and invited
his entire modeling class.
I apologize for that.
ZABOO: No, you know
what, it's fine--
FAWKES: You are a market
researcher's wet dream.
Please, continue.
ZABOO: Dude.
Inappro, OK?
CODEX: Yeah.
Yeah, sweet face, that is
quite enough of you.
FAWKES: I'm sorry,
honey bunny.
Am I making everyone upset?
VORK: I'm not upset.
FAWKES: Really.
How's the construction of
your guild hall coming?
The Axis just bought ours.
Deluxe.
VORK: Sasafrass!
CODEX: Honey?
Come help me in the kitchen.
FAWKES: What?
CODEX: Whatever.
Come on.
FAWKES: Excuse us.
DENA: Mel Gibson, scared!
John Malkovich, happy!
Go!
Go--
BLADEZZ: My eyelid is
starting to twitch!
DENA: Robert Pattinson,
ecstasy!
Pathetic.
You call yourself an actor?
BLADEZZ: [WHIMPERS]
ZABOO'S MOM: And I am so sorry
I made you practice all the
opera singing at the
mall food court--
ZABOO: Apology accepted
for everything.
Please, just-- don't
cut my meat.
C'mon, I can do this--
VORK: Why would you not want
your meat cut into amenable
bite-sized portions?
Thank you.
I'm still in shock that the Axis
of Anarchy has already
purchased their guild hall.
ZABOO'S MOM: Are you purchasing
real estate, Mr. Vork?
Because that is my specialty.
VORK: I've been buying and
selling in-game products, but
the profit margins
are too thin.
ZABOO'S MOM: Why not make
your fortunes in
the commodities market?
VORK: The game doesn't have
anything like that.
ZABOO'S MOM: Can
you create one?
VORK: Well, I don't--
Wait a second.
You may be of value to me.
I'm shocked.
CODEX: What are you
doing here?
I shouldn't have to be dealing
with anyone but pretend you.
That was the deal.
FAWKES: Well, I've never had
the experience of being a
boyfriend before, so I thought
this would be a good
no-strings opportunity.
CODEX: I thought you
only did stuff with
a girl once, remember?
FAWKES: Ah, but tonight, I
am role playing myself.
CODEX: That is such BS.
Admit it.
This is a second date.
You like me.
FAWKES: I--
is there a fainting couch
in the ladies' room?
CODEX: A what?
FAWKES: Since I'm role playing
myself, if you were to role
play yourself?
Then it would be the first time
for role playing us to do
it on a fainting couch.
CODEX: OK.
Thanks for playing along, but,
as of tomorrow, I'm telling
the guild that we are officially
broken up.
FAWKES: You're breaking off the
fake relationship with the
pretend me.
Hm.
This is indeed a meta
meta moment.
CODEX: I guess.
It was barely fun while
it didn't last.
FAWKES: Ah--
It's just a little reminder
of what you're passing up.
CODEX: Is there a
breeze in here?
One of the most common types of
romance novels is about the
reformed rake--
a devilish man whore who sleeps
with anything that
moves, until he meets the one
right girl who makes him hang
up his man parts to
settle down for a
long, one-lady life.
She usually ends up pregnant
in the epilogue.
Thank God I called it off
with Fawkes before that.
Now, I just have to make up a
good story to tell the guild
about our equitable parting,
and I can close the book on
the whole thing.
Meanwhile, I'm filming that
commercial with Bladezz
tonight, so I have to
learn how to make
a film in 11 hours.
I just looked at my wrist, and
I'm not wearing a watch.
So dumb.
Yeah, pregnant gamer tees
are a great idea.
I don't know why people
wouldn't be into them.
CLARA: We went to, like, four
game stores wearing
prototypes, and people thought
we were a reality show prank.
TINKERBALLA: Except one guy, who
wanted us to pose for his
weird fetish website.
CODEX: Dare I ask?
CLARA:
MakingItWithBabymakers.com.
Nice website.
TINKERBALLA: Hey, what's
up with Vork?
He created a password-protected
channel,
and he's been in there with
strangers all day.
CODEX: Vork Torgothian
Average channel?
[STOCK EXCHANGE SOUNDS]
VORK: What do you advise
about war weed?
ZABOO'S MOM: Invest.
VORK: I need warweed--
50 gold-- need warweed
at 50 gold.
ZABOO'S MOM: But sell silver.
I believe player Gankmaster
is planning on
flooding the market.
He's a miner, correct?
VORK: Correct.
Got silver for 100 gold--
got silver for 100 gold.
I have to say, Mrs. Zaboo--
ZABOO'S MOM: Avinashi.
VORK: I'll never
remember that.
This is brilliant.
By creating a derivatives
market of the Torgothian
economy, we've added an
intriguing new level of
gameplay that'll net me a tidy
sum with each trade.
ZABOO: That sounds
complicated.
And scammy.
VORK: It's a free
market at work.
Your mother's a brilliant
woman.
ZABOO'S MOM: Oh, it's my
pleasure to help in
any way, Mr. Vork.
Gherkins?
VORK: Hold on a minute, woman.
I don't know where your
fingers have been.
Mm.
Tolerable.
ZABOO: What's up, ladies?
CODEX: Oh, nothing.
Just trying to learn filmmaking
in 24 hours.
ZABOO: Things are going
awesome here.
My mom is so focused
on Vork, that she's
totally ignoring me.
Ma--
gherkin.
Eee-eee-eee.
Man, she always feeds me
when I dolphinize.
This is great.
I really want a gherkin
now, though.
OK.
Man, life is perfect.
CLARA: Zaboo, your mom
and Vork hooked up?
What's in the water lately?
ZABOO: No, no.
Never that.
They're working together
on the guild hall.
See, Vork's got this awesome
plan laid out-- mmm--
VORK: What happens in
shed, stays in shed.
CLARA: I'm not worried.
We're up to 300 K in savings.
VORK: What?
But you've been offline
all day.
How will you keep up the pace
of your earnings potential?
CLARA: Well, Tink and I
have a secret weapon.
Blake and Gabby,
keep collecting
cotton for Auntie Tink.
Kill the monsters.
BLAKE: Kill the monsters!
TINKERBALLA: Boys are stupid.
GABBY: Boys are stupid.
TINKERBALLA: These kids
are growing on me.
CLARA: The Sea Festival's almost
over, but by that time
Tink and me will be serving tea
to the guild in a bitchin'
fairy palace.
VORK: I was visualizing custom
gargoyles with my face
superimposed.
But that dream is slipping
from my grasp.
ZABOO'S MOM: Oh, keep trading.
The plan will work.
VORK: Mrs. Zaboo, I don't--
[INDIAN MUSIC]
oooh--
ZABOO'S MOM: Do not
resist, Mr. Vork.
You are deserving
of pampering.
I cleaned out your
kitchen earlier.
I threw out many expired
large cans of food.
VORK: You what?
Keep your hands off my chow!
[DOOR SLAMS]
[RINGTONE]
TINKERBALLA: Oh my God.
Venom just sent me a picture of
Fawkes with some chick in a
giant panda suit.
"Check out Fawkes'
date last night."
CLARA: Aww, how creepy.
TINKERBALLA: That's so gross.
Wait.
Last night?
CLARA: What?
What a man skeeve.
That jerk-face is cheating
on Codex?
TINKERBALLA: She wishes.
So, Codex.
How's everything going
with Fawkes?
CODEX: Um, sad news.
Uh, we decided to
break it off.
This morning.
Over brunch.
Prosciutto omelets,
to be precise.
ZABOO: What, really?
CODEX: Yeah.
It was a mutual decision.
Let's not talk about
it any more--
TINKERBALLA: Codex-- you're
a total liar!
CODEX: What are you
talking about?
Why?
TINKERBALLA: Venom just texted
me and told me that Fawkes has
been going out with
girls all week.
You guys were never dating.
You were just a one
night stand.
ZABOO: Oh, that almost made
me poop a little.
Uh-- it's back in.
Turtle headed.
CLARA: Codex, you're so wiley.
Like that coyote, what's-his-
thingy.
CODEX: OK.
Fine, Tink, you're right.
I was lying the whole time.
I am a ho diddy ho bag.
But I only did it because I--
I cared about what you
guys think about me.
And now you've made me feel
worse than I already did
before, so thanks a lot.
I'm gonna go home and--
just eat a lot of calories.
TINKERBALLA: I hate
it when I'm right.
Wait.
No I don't.
ZABOO: Tink, schadenfreuded.
CLARA: Gesundheit.
VORK: I was able to run down the
garbage truck, but I could
salvage no green beans.
This is a disaster!
ZABOO: Vork--
Codex was lying about her and
Fawkes the whole time.
And I--
I don't feel happy about it.
I just feel bad for Codex.
I'm a good friend!
Yes!
Whoo-hoo!
VORK: Very supportive.
ZABOO: Get these shoulders
ready.
'Cause she's gonna cry on 'em.
Here I come, Codex!
VORK: Go get them.
And you.
Expiration dates are
mere suggestions.
Like late fees, and
traffic lights.
CODEX: If I think too hard about
what's going on right
now, I might be a little
creeped out.
But I actually appreciate
you coming over.
ZABOO: No problem.
God.
This mask is tightening
up all over my face.
Man, I'd never put this on
another part of my body.
Well, maybe.
CODEX: Why did I think lying to
the guild was a good idea?
Why did I hook up with
that guy at all?
ZABOO: Don't kick yourself.
He's got some great equipment.
CODEX: How do you know?
ZABOO: I inspected him
on the server.
Boot to helm.
CODEX: Oh.
Yeah, right.
His character's armor
is very sexy.
ZABOO: Totally.
CODEX: Uh--
I gotta get back to
Cheesybeards, film that stupid
commercial.
Work is the solace
of sorrow, right?
Oh, God.
That was a quote.
ZABOO: I knew it.
You're not over him.
Well, everything has happened
just as I imagined.
But don't worry, best friend.
I prepared for this.
Fawkes.
FAWKES: It takes one to forgive,
two to reconcile.
Generic greeting card.
ZABOO: He's good.
CODEX: What are you
doing here?
FAWKES: I wanted to see how
this scene played out.
ZABOO: See?
The sidekick always reunites
the heroine with the hero.
CODEX: Not if the heroine
thinks the hero is
a total tool bag.
ZABOO: But I was just trying
to get rid of the mopey
montage part of your sadness.
CODEX: Well, yet again, your
attempts are totally well
intentioned, but overboard
and inappropriate.
FAWKES: Are you sure that
you're over me?
CODEX: And you--
stop trolling me in real life.
ZABOO: Bye, Fawkes.
Oh.
[INAUDIBLE]
I got it from this guy
who does van art.
The likenesses are
pretty special.
CODEX: I am not going to talk
about the Fawkes thing.
Or how everyone in the guild
now thinks I'm a liar.
And forget about the
Zaboo thing.
I am not talking about
that, either.
I mean, how dense do you have
to be to think that--
see?
I'm talking about all the stuff
I said I wasn't gonna
talk about.
We just finished filming the
Cheesybeards commercial.
We've been up all night.
Bladezz is gonna edit it, and
add some graphics and stuff
before he uploads it.
I'm kind of excited to see it.
Maybe I'll discover a
hidden talent for
filmmaking and win an award.
Do film festivals have a
category for best local
internet commercial?
Heh.
I was daydreaming about
the acceptance speech.
Stupid.
I would definitely wear
something strapless.
[FESTIVE MUSIC]
BLADEZZ: Burgers ahoy!
Want to know why my roger
is so [BLEEP]
jolly?
Come on down to Cheesybeards
for all your
pirate burger needs!
Uh!
Enjoy.
Wow.
Cheesybeards really knows
how to serve it up.
These competitors can
walk the plank!
Man overboard!
Arrgh--
I'm a pirate!
So don't settle for
shark bait.
Walk the plank down to
Cheesybeards, and taste--
taste--
taste my pirate patty.
Cheesybeards.
OLLIE: Sherman!
I'm scuttling this project--
you're fired!
CODEX: No, no, we put a lot
of work into that video.
OLLIE: Ah, it looks like a grog-
dazed orangutan made it.
And what is "taste my pirate
patty?" Yeah, I got a dozen
crank messages on my machine,
and nothin' but
empty tables out there.
CODEX: 'Cause someone put in
some editing magic before they
uploaded it, without
telling me.
OLLIE: Don't pass the
doubloon, Sherman.
A captain always goes
down with the ship.
CODEX: OK.
Just give me one last chance.
I will get people in
here, I promise.
OLLIE: Oh, Sherman.
This place is all I got.
And a man with one hand can't
carve out a business for
himself every day.
BLADEZZ: Can't carve out
anything if it's his dominant
hand, right?
[LAUGHTER]
OLLIE: Oo, you're a hoot, lad.
Never stop talking.
Two days, Sherman.
You get birds at the
brownie buffet.
Or we're through!
Unh.
TINKERBALLA: Clara--
We agreed to print
50 t-shirts.
CLARA: I did order 50.
Then the guy said 50 gross, and
I said yeah, guys would
think they're gross.
I thought he was flirting.
TINKERBALLA: A gross is 144.
50 gross is this.
CLARA: Well, can't
we return them?
TINKERBALLA: Sweatshops
don't do refunds.
God, we're out so much money.
MR. WIGGLY: Honey, did you make
a withdrawal from our
savings account?
CLARA: I needed the seed
money for the business.
MR. WIGGLY: This is for the
kids' college fund.
CLARA: Oh, all of them
don't need to go.
Choose one.
Don't worry.
We'll sell them all.
TINKERBALLA: And how do
we plan to do that?
CLARA: Sshh, sshh--
geez, the game trading house
is out of control.
Leather's up 15 gold
per stack?
Is somebody hoarding
it or something?
TINKERBALLA: Must be
a server glitch.
VORK: Leather.
I am the Dragothian
king of leather.
The power is-- ha, ha, ha--
Where's your mother?
Did she place this wig warmer
here as a decoy?
Find her.
Find her!
ZABOO: In a minute.
I gotta auction off
this painting.
It's just a constant reminder
of my failure to become
friends with Codex.
I need a good, like,
title description.
Go!
VORK: Highland Ecstasy.
ZABOO: Oh, yeah.
VORK: Zaboo, your mother's
obsessed with me.
This morning she wanted to
go for a walk, with no
discernible destination.
Completely baffling.
ZABOO: Dude, it's your place.
Tell her to leave.
VORK: But I need her brilliant
economic mind.
One minute, she's helping
me create an empire.
The next, she's trying to
rearrange my novelty straw
collection.
It enrages me.
ZABOO: That's the way
she operates.
She's like the wobble demon
of the Iktar Plain.
She looks like a cute
and cuddly bunny.
But then, it sucks the life
force out of you, as soon as
you get within aggro distance.
Huh.
Highland sextacy.
That's catchy.
VORK: Agreed.
ZABOO'S MOM: Lunch time.
Tofu burgers, and beached
whale vitamins.
VORK: I do not eat this type
of, quote, food, unquote.
Mrs. Zaboo, this is
not working out.
I need you to leave--
ZABOO'S MOM: Oh-- you've
cornered the leather market.
But with the price so
high, the customer
base is sure to decline.
VORK: It will?
What do I do?
ZABOO'S MOM: Oh.
Start a loan company.
With that, you can get interest
and trading fees.
But--
you were about to
say something.
VORK: Nothing.
ZABOO: Wobble demoned.
[HIGH-PITCHED VOICE]
CODEX: Can you hear me?
Hi.
Guys?
ZABOO: Hey, Codex.
Great commercial.
CLARA: Yeah.
It's so bad, I linked it
to everyone I know.
CODEX: Ollie's so mad at me.
I came home after lunch 'cause
I started crying
in my Scurvy Fries.
TINKERBALLA: Codex-- your
mike is messed up.
You sound like a chipmunk.
CODEX: I know.
My computer's still
not working.
I'm thoroughly worried--
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
I want to apologize for
lying to everybody.
You guys--
don't yell at me--
SOBBING]
TINKERBALLA: You're not going
to let me boot her, are you?
CLARA: No.
It's super annoying, but
we should do something.
CODEX: Thanks for letting
me come over.
It's nice to know everyone in
the guild doesn't hate me for
being a lying whore-bag.
CLARA: We don't hate you.
We're excited for you.
[COUGHS]
CODEX: Clara--
this is pure vodka.
CLARA: I'm a mom at heart.
Drink up, honey.
TINKERBALLA: I knew the whole
Fawkes thing didn't add up.
He wanted you as a girlfriend,
but only wanted to go on one
date with me?
Achh.
Impossible.
CODEX: Wait.
You went out with him, too?
TINKERBALLA: How do you
think I got into
their guild so quick?
I don't do trial periods.
CODEX: No wonder you
were so mad at me.
Listen, I know exactly
how you feel.
When you have sex with someone,
you think it's gonna
be a long time deal, you know?
TINKERBALLA: Sex?
Let's be clear.
He only got to second
base with me.
And my second base is really
everyone else's first.
CODEX: Wow.
You know when you play in an
area that's way too high-level
for you, so you have to get
killed over and over again
before you wise up and go back
to an easier area to play?
TINKERBALLA: Is this
going somewhere?
CODEX: That's what I've been
doing in real life.
Fawkes was too high level
for me, this job is too
high level for me.
I mean, why did I think I could
ever get people to eat
at a restaurant?
I don't have that skill set.
That's it.
I give up.
I'm not going back.
CLARA: I'd have Wiggly take the
family, but it is the last
day of the Sea Festival, so--
CODEX: It's OK.
I have a backup plan to
get a new computer.
TINKERBALLA: Youre
lying again.
CODEX: You're right.
Can I take the sippy
cup with me?
CLARA: Yeah.
CODEX: Thank you.
ZABOO: Is Codex OK?
Tell her I picked all the wrong
dialogue options yesterday.
If I could reload my save
game, I totally would.
TINKERBALLA: She just left.
But, I was nice to her, and
I feel good about myself.
That's all that's interesting
right now.
CLARA: She's totally bummed
about the whole
Cheesybeards thing.
She said she's not going back.
ZABOO: We gotta help her.
And I have to participate in
an extremely moderate way.
CLARA: We do.
Now how to get people
to the restaurant?
Oh my God, my thinking cap just
gave me a great idea.
ZABOO: Yes.
An Idea.
From Clara.
CLARA: I know, right?
CODEX: Ooh--
three relationships in my life
have ended with a whimper.
A boyfriend in high school, a
boyfriend in college, and my
cousin Christine.
After a while we just stopped
calling each other.
They faded away.
It was easier that way.
No messy break-ups.
Well, Christine forged my
signature and took a bunch of
credit cards out in my name,
so, I guess that's a whole
'nother story.
Now, I'm adding one more
name to that list--
Ollie.
Pirate man.
Maybe he won't even
notice I'm gone.
I hope he doesn't track me
down and keelhaul me.
I wish I had a working
computer.
I could look up what that
word really means.
[CELLPHONE RINGS]
Oh--
It's Ollie.
So much for a whimper.
Rude.
Ohh--
[MUSIC PLAYS]
ZABOO: The fabric is
milk-resistant.
Oh, hey--
Welcome to Cheesybeards.
And the Festival Under
the Sea Festival.
TINKERBALLA: Zaboo--
I told you to stop
saying that.
It's stupid and redundant.
ZABOO: Well, welcome to
Cheesybeards, and the Festival
Under the Sea event.
That is not a festival.
CODEX: You guys, what's
going on here?
CLARA: Well, we threw
it together
after you left my house.
Thanks to my plus 20, too
intelligent squid hat.
ZABOO: Yeah, we spammed general
chat, and everyone
showed up to celebrate the last
day of the Festival Under
the Sea Fest--
uh-- thing-a- ma- bob.
CLARA: And Pregamers even has
a place to sell shirts to
pregnant gamer ladies.
CUSTOMER: Awesome.
I'll take one of those.
CLARA: Oh, but we're not--
TINKERBALLA: Give our largest
shirt to this man over here.
It'll fit fine.
ZABOO: And Bladezz actually
helped, in exchange for some
stage space.
CUSTOMER 2: My brother
did a mash-up of you
and keyboard cat.
Can I have your autograph?
BLADEZZ: Well, yeah.
Uh, which boob do I sign?
CUSTOMER 2: Oh my god-- he's
just as skeevy in real life.
BLADEZZ: Yeah.
OLLIE: A--
hoy.
Well, you've, uh, blown
a fair wind.
CODEX: Actually, I didn't--
CLARA: Lie, lie.
You're good at that
now, remember?
OLLIE: What?
Eh?
CODEX: Um, thank you.
Ollie.
It's been a lot to coordinate
from my home, but, uh, I think
everything has turned
out great.
OLLIE: Yeah, well, you filled
the galley tighter than a
booty chest.
[LAUGHTER]
Entertainment?
Eh?
CLARA: Oh--
Bladezz is gonna put on
a magic show later.
OLLIE: Oh.
CODEX: Yeah, that.
ZABOO: And the 8-bit band got
cut, 'cause we didn't want to
go overboard on anything.
OLLIE: No band?
No worries.
We can drop anchor
for that, eh?
Eh, beauty?
[SINGS]
So I pull off their balls, and
sever their heads, ran them
all through till the deck had
run red, scooped up the goop
from their skull like molasses,
pulled out their
lungs and filleted their
asses, served a--
VORK: Mrs. Zaboo, I can handle
my own drinking, thank you.
OLLIE: --my belly was full by
the time I was through.
[LAUGHTER]
Arrgh.
VORK: Will not happen, sir.
OLLIE: Oh, you cheap bastard.
ZABOO: Great lute
playing, Codex.
CODEX: I only know
three chords.
ZABOO: Three amazing chords.
Heh.
FLUFFYKINS: Sir Vork?
I need to talk to you about
my potion portfolio?
VORK: Fluffykins, of Gigglebunny
guild, I presume?
FLUFFYKINS: No one's investing
in the potion market.
It's hit bottom.
I need another week to
pay my debt back.
VORK: You should have considered
the long-term
repercussions, before you took a
game loan through my Knights
of Goloanar Corp.
FLUFFYKINS: It seems
unfair that you run
the stocks and loans.
VORK: Are you trying to
regulate me, sir?
Are you a socialist?
ZABOO'S MOM: The price
of Infinite Potion
has hit a new low.
VORK: Fluffykins, I suggest
you start grinding.
The deadline stays.
[BANG]
FLUFFYKINS: Mm!
ZABOO: Vork, you can't keep
manipulating the game.
You're bankrupting people.
VORK: Amassing a fortune will
benefit the game economy in
the long run.
ZABOO: Trickle downed.
VORK: The guild hall
is within my reach.
ZABOO'S MOM: Oopsie, Mr. Vork.
Allow me.
There.
All better.
VORK: Zaboo.
I'm going to the
men's bathroom.
Accompany me.
CODEX: Oh, no.
OLLIE: Well.
How 'bout a ballad, mateys?
FAWKES: Music is essentially
useless.
Santayana.
OLLIE: How'd you like
to scrape a
barnacle off me rudder?
Eh, shark bait?!
FAWKES: Nice hook.
CODEX: So, it's nice to--
I'm seein' ya.
Heh.
VALKYRIE: Hey, yeah, I heard
this whole "lass" look was
coming back in this season--
huh, huh-- but gratz.
You managed to make it
look really awkward.
RILEY: She looks OK.
Let me get you one of
those, my sweet.
Be my wench?
VENOM: Any day of the week.
FAWKES: I was just pointing out
the table where you begged
me to date you.
That experience inspired me to
blog about the feminine ego.
Got tons of up votes
at Reddit.
CODEX: Should I be impressed?
FAWKES: Well it made the
front page, so--
yes.
CODEX: Well, I don't have to
suck up your snark anymore, so
go blow a fair wind outta
your arggh holes.
VORK: Dry!
Dry!
I've been poisoned.
ZABOO: Dude, that's
what moms do, man.
I mean, she's been licking
my hair since I
was four years old.
In lieu of shampoo.
VORK: But this is 50% of my
wardrobe that I have to burn
when I arrive home.
What are you doing?
ZABOO: I'm going to
the bathroom,
'cause we're in a bathroom.
VORK: This is a conference.
Find a better time and place.
ZABOO: I'm in mid-stream.
VORK: Auhh--
just hurry up.
[GASP]
FAWKES: Go out with me again.
CODEX: Are you kidding?
Now?
Why?
Why, why now?
FAWKES: Contrary to my
expectations, this entire
experience has been very
interesting to me.
You're interesting, Codex.
And that has surprised me.
CODEX: Well, you have
been a total d-bag.
So, that has not surprised me.
Why would I go out
with you again?
FAWKES: I make good brownies?
JEANETTE: Look at that.
It's good to see you
again, cutie.
FAWKES: Ah, you must
be the waitress.
I will have a glass of
water, please, room
temperature, no ice.
Thank you.
JEANETTE: Oh, no.
You think you can just get all
up in Jeanette and then treat
her like hired help?
CODEX: You got all
up in Jeanette?
FAWKES: Well, I was until very
recently an epicurean--
JEANETTE: I'm gonna
give you something
there is no cure for.
FAWKES: Whoop!
VORK: 'Cause your bladder's
like the Hindenburg.
ZABOO: OK, I'm done, I'm done.
VORK: Now look, Zaboo.
We need to jettison your mom out
of our lives completely.
Tell me what repulses women.
It seems to be your specialty.
You're very, very good at it.
ZABOO: Well, I don't know, I
mean, Codex says I overdo
everything, so why don't you
just go overboard, you know,
make a giant gesture that's
really inappropriate, and then
she'll run the other way.
VORK: Go overboard.
OK.
Formulating--
ZABOO: I, I know this guy
who does van art, so--
collect fingernail clippings,
and make a necklace out of--
VORK: Stop.
I've got it.
Let's go.
ZABOO: All right.
I'm going.
Uh--
I gotta wash my hands
It's the law.
JEANETTE: I've had better
sex with a bicycle seat.
[CRASH]
TINKERBALLA: That satisfies
something in my brain.
Like, a lot.
CODEX: Jeanette must
be a boxer.
JEANETTE: Mixed martial arts.
CODEX: I am such an
idiot with men.
This is a lesson.
Paladins over Rogues.
TINKERBALLA: You should make
a men's litmus test.
It's the one thing in chemistry
I learned when I
wasn't sleeping.
CODEX: A litmus test?
What do you mean?
Like, a checklist
or something?
TINKERBALLA: I did
the negatives.
No misers, no amputees,
no cuddlers.
CODEX: That's a weird list.
OK.
I can do that.
And then the next time someone
asks me out, I will say,
excuse me, and consult my
list before responding.
TINKERBALLA: Uh, yeah.
You better stick to
online dating.
DENA: Hey, wench.
Bladezz needs you to help him
out with the magic show.
CODEX: Can't you do it?
DENA: I'm center stage,
or nothing at all.
BLADEZZ: Is that your card?
VALKYRIE: No.
BLADEZZ: Are you sure?
I believe it is.
VALKYRIE: Prove it.
VORK: I'll cut to the chase,
because I want this to end.
Mrs. Zaboo?
Will you marry me?
ZABOO'S MOM: Oh my goodness--
yes.
Yes, I will.
ZABOO: So.
What'd I miss?
BLADEZZ: Ladies and
Gentlemen--
for my next trick, that
I have never done
before, I will eat fire.
[APPLAUSE]
[FIRE EXPLODES]
[SCREAMS]
OLLIE: Fire in the hole!
CODEX: I can't believe Ollie
fired us because we set the
restaurant on fire.
[LAUGHTER]
I'm sorry.
It's just, like, so
lamely ironic.
I'm never getting a
new computer now.
Well that sobered me up.
Someone filmed the whole thing
from the audience and posted
it, so now Bladezz is even
more internet famous.
And, if possible,
more irritating.
This is a good life lesson--
never try anything new,
or you will fail.
What else is going on?
Oh, yeah--
Vork is marrying Zaboo's mom.
[LAUGHS]
I'm laughing, because that
sounds so crazy.
I think I'm hysterical.
Heh.
ZABOO: Codex.
Please, talk to him.
I can't become related
to Vork.
If that happens, I'm gonna
replace all my organs with
clockwork, and then sell myself
to a Steampunk museum.
Ah, ah--
CODEX: Hey, hey, hey, stop it.
Stop.
OK, calm down.
Vork--
you do not want to do this.
VORK: Of course I don't.
The very thought of marrying
this woman
makes my prostate throb.
[KNOCKING]
ZABOO'S MOM: Fiance Vork, the
ASPCA has come and taken all
your birds.
Their sound is quite
distracting.
VORK: I understand.
[BLOWS A KISS]
VORK: Mentally, I'm in hospice,
waiting to die.
Numb.
So numb.
CODEX: So just tell her
you changed your mind.
VORK: A verbal offer of marriage
is a contractual
obligation.
Herman Holden's word
is his honor.
His honor, by Jupiter!
CLARA: Codex, stop trying
to ruin my fun.
I'm so deep into wedding
planning now.
Horses' ovaries for everyone.
Num, num, num, num, num.
TINKERBALLA: Don't you
mean hors d'oeuvres?
CLARA: Sure, we can
have those, too.
CODEX: Wait, wait-- so
you're planning it?
Didn't you just skip your
own sister's wedding?
CLARA: Zaboo's mom is
letting me be a
bridesmaid, not a matron.
Plus, we're having it
at my house, so the
commute's super easy.
CODEX: Give it some time.
Vork will come to his senses.
CLARA: So 7:00 PM tomorrow.
I'm drafting the
cyber-vite now.
ZABOO: Tomorrow?
What?
Are you kidding me?
CLARA: Wiggly's ordained.
There's no need to delay.
ZABOO: Oh-- it sounds
realler now.
Oo.
Oh, dry heaved.
CODEX: Ew.
[DOORBELL]
ZABOO: I'll get it.
CODEX: If that's a subpoena from
Ollie, do not take it.
I'm too delicate
for jail time.
Vork, stop this insanity.
VORK: From a practical
standpoint, this situation
does have its advantages.
She's already set the precedent
for paying for meals.
I think a carefully worded
pre-nuptial agreement could
establish acceptable
living parameters.
How do you spell "saliva?"
CODEX: What is that?
CLARA: How much do you think
an ice sculpture of Vork's
game character and Avinashi
in a sari would cost?
TINKERBALLA: Clara?
We sold 12 shirts yesterday,
but we still have tons of
stock left.
So what's our next step?
CLARA: Business talk
is so fun.
Let me do one.
We must strategize,
to monetize.
How fancy do I sound?
TINKERBALLA: This
isn't a game.
We're supposed to be
making money, but
we're not doing that.
CLARA: That's OK.
I'm done now.
TINKERBALLA: What?
With what?
CLARA: I think I should focus
on being pregnant.
I have to work in game and the
kids like to hang out with me
some, so that's a lot.
TINKERBALLA: But we have
7,000 shirts left.
CLARA: Well, we can just put 'em
in the wedding gift bags.
OK--
remember to bring your mom's
garter belt to the reception.
ZABOO: And you are web cammed.
CODEX: I can't believe you
bought me a new computer.
I should make you
send it back.
ZABOO: No guilt.
It's legitimately yours.
I paid for it by eBaying that
painting of you and Fawkes.
CODEX: Wait, are you kidding?
Who'd buy that thing?
ZABOO: An author.
Yelena Caress, for her
new romance novel--
"As His Kilt Rises."
CODEX: I read all her stuff.
I'll probably buy that one
in e-book, though.
ZABOO: You know, it was really
tough just becoming, like,
just your friend, But I think
our relationship has been
successfully retconned.
What is this?
Litmus test.
Kind, funny, smells
good, gamer--
CODEX: That's nothing.
You are right.
We have come a long way.
I mean, not that a physical
object can really transform.
That's shallow.
You are a really good friend.
OK, I'm logging on, for
the first time.
I'm so excited.
ZABOO: I am too!
VORK: Guildies, I'd like to
focus your attention on
something very important.
ZABOO: More important than
you marrying my mom?
VORK: I have earned a half a
million gold, and I am about
to purchase the Knights
of Good guild hall.
ZABOO: Oot!
Thanks for waiting for
us to log back on.
CLARA: Vork, how did you
get that much money
in such little time?
Hacks.
VORK: Innovation, my friends.
I am a titan of industry.
A financial wizard.
So very rich.
Mm, mm mm.
CODEX: But you've made
everything so expensive
in-game, nobody can afford
anything anymore.
VORK: There has been a
touch of inflation.
But I expect the market to
self-adjust within six months.
CLARA: Business words aren't
fun when you say them.
VORK: Everyone--
gather to me, and behold the
glory that is the Knights of
Good deluxe guild hall.
ZABOO: Oo.
CODEX: It kinda looks
like a prison.
VORK: You're welcome.
ZABOO: OK, now that we have
it, what do we do with it?
VORK: We gather in it.
Son.
ZABOO: Did he just
call me "son?"
CODEX: This keyboard
is so responsive.
TINKERBALLA: I came back.
CLARA: You left?
TINKERBALLA: I just wanted to
say that I like doing business
with you, hanging out is
fun, and I'd like to
keep working together.
Please?
CLARA: Oh my gosh.
Did you just use the p-word?
TINKERBALLA: Yes.
You're a stupid influence.
CLARA: Aw.
CODEX: Zaboo?
OK.
This quiet calm thing you're
doing right now?
This is--
this is freaking me out.
ZABOO: Codex.
Stop the wedding.
CODEX: OK.
ZABOO: You have to
stop the wedding.
CODEX: Don't worry.
I will do this.
Nothing can get in the way of
true friendship, if you're
determined, and truth
is on your side.
[BELL CHIMES]
CODEX: I thought if I said it
with determination, something
would come to me.
ZABOO: This is the
nightmare level.
Just Control- Alt- Delete me.
VORK: Unfortunately, my new
paternal role will require us
to spend more quality time
with each other.
I am now looking forward to
enjoying this sporting object
in an outdoor setting
with you.
CODEX: Bladezz.
What the-- ?
ZABOO: Oh.
The devil's here.
That makes sense.
BLADEZZ: Sorry I'm late.
Been busy with fan maintenance,
baby.
Live chats, vlogging--
the job of being
me is 24/7 now.
MR. WIGGLY: Uh, the bride
is ready for the--
the-- yeah.
Please be seated.
[MUSIC PLAYING - THE
WEDDING MARCH]
ZABOO'S MOM: What is this?
CLARA: I made your character
just like you.
Except taller.
MR. WIGGLY: We are gathered
here today--
TINKERBALLA: We can't
hear you.
MR. WIGGLY: Sorry.
Button pushed.
We are gathered here today to
join these two video game
characters in cyber matrimony.
ZABOO'S MOM: This is
very confusing.
MR. WIGGLY: Yeah.
Yeah, it is.
CODEX: So we're all in
Clara's dining room.
I'm playing the wedding march
into my desktop, and I look
around, and we look like some
freaky reality show. "Amazing
Geeks," or "Nerdy Shore," or
"The Biggest Losers," or--
never mind.
Zaboo tried so hard to be
a good friend to me.
I really owed it to him
to try to do something
to stop this wedding.
And it's not because he gave
me a new computer, OK?
That's where I'm doing this
from-- do I look fancier?
Sorry.
We really have become friends.
Despite his complete lack of
social skills, Zaboo is a
smart, funny guy.
He's kind, and considerate--
oh, God, those are all things
on my litmus test.
I gotta make this
list way longer.
Good wardrobe, biceps,
hairless fingers--
no, that's creepy.
MR. WIGGLY: And if anyone
present objects to this union,
speak now, or forever
hold your peace.
UNISON: I object.
MR. WIGGLY: I don't
think you're
supposed to actually answer.
It's just a formality.
BLADEZZ: Well that seems
pretty unanimous.
So who wants to run a dungeon?
CLARA: I said no because
I want to move to a
prettier game area.
The screen shots in
here are terrible.
TINKERBALLA: The thought of Vork
with any woman makes me
want to toss my boba.
But Zaboo's mom?
You're bat- [BLEEP]
crazy.
CODEX: I objected.
All right, did you see that?
I objected.
If there's anything I've learned
in the last week, it's
that honesty is the
best policy.
Or, if you're going to lie, you
gotta cover your tracks
really well, and make sure there
are no furrys involved.
Heh.
Anyway, Zaboo's mom--
are you 100% sure that you
want to marry Vork?
ZABOO'S MOM: I have nothing to
go home to but an empty house.
Even though I can't abide the
idea of touching Mr. Vork in
an intimate way,
I'm desperate.
VORK: Are you referring
to my in- game
or out of game character?
TINKERBALLA: Your out
of game character?
Meaning you?
ZABOO'S MOM: And this way?
At least I can be with my son.
Even though he doesn't
want me.
CODEX: So you're gonna marry
someone you can't stand in
order to be close to
someone who doesn't
want to be near you?
Tink is right.
That's kind bat [BLEEP]
crazy.
Heh, oh.
MR. WIGGLY: Uh, Clara?
Something bad is happening.
CLARA: Don't worry, honey.
She's only a level one.
Two seconds, and we
can flatten her.
ZABOO: Mom?
CODEX: In-game.
Do it in-game.
ZABOO: Right.
Mom?
You came here to apologize
to me for your
past mistakes, but--
you're not the only one.
I made a mistake, too.
And that was believing that
you couldn't change.
And--
Dudes!
Could you not duel for one
second while I deal with this?
Look, Mom--
I'm sorry.
I was wrong to make
you feel unwanted.
But you don't have to settle for
this awful, awful future.
You deserve better.
VORK: Uh, did I imbibe an
invisibility spell?
Hello?
ZABOO'S MOM: You are so
like your father.
Kind, loyal, smart.
I wish I could make amends
with him, too.
CODEX: Whoa.
Litmus tested.
ZABOO: What?
Mom?
You don't have to marry Vork
just hang out with me.
Occasionally.
On weekends.
Or, every other weekend.
ZABOO'S MOM: I'm so relieved.
If I had to do that,
I would have just
drowned myself in a bathtub.
VORK: Then we should
call it off.
Another crime scene is
the last thing I
need in that house.
You should know, however, widows
statistically have a
higher suicide rate.
And are more vulnerable
to extortion
schemes and home invasions.
ZABOO'S MOM: How do I hug
you in this game?
UNISON: Type "slash hug."
KEVINATOR: Knights of Good?
[FANFARE]
Direct me to your leaders.
TINKERBALLA: Oh my God.
That's the Death Lion
Breast Plate.
VORK: I am Vork.
Guild leader of the
Knights of Good.
MALE VOICE: I'm Kevinator.
Official game master.
CLARA: A GM?
In person?
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
VORK: Here's my pitch.
KEVINATOR: Guys--
I'm not here to help.
I'm here to rip XP out of
someone's poop chute.
ZABOO'S MOM: Excuse me?
We are in the middle of
my called-off wedding.
[ELECTRICAL ZAP]
What just happened?
CLARA: He's one of the people
who work on the game.
Bow to your master.
KEVINATOR: Someone in this
lame-ass guild is running an
illegal operation that's pretty
much screwing with the
whole server economy.
Yeah, that would be Vork's
Torgothian stock market.
Did you get my complaint?
VORK: Tattle Tink.
You're the worst
in the country.
KEVINATOR: Dude?
I gotta shut you down.
If I see another forum post
about inflated herb prices,
I'm gonna start destroying
things.
And I can do that.
Because I am a god here.
[ZAP]
VORK: You can't shut me down.
It's the free market
in action.
KEVINATOR: Yeah?
I'm gonna perma-ban
you if you don't.
I can do that.
You wanna dance with me?
[ELECTRICAL SOUNDS]
ZABOO: Kevinator's
kind of a dick.
VORK: Fine.
But you, sir, are a tyrant.
KEVINATOR: Read your
terms of service.
This game ain't a democracy.
CODEX: Wait.
So, does that mean that half
million gold that Vork earned
is technically illegal
as well?
KEVINATOR: Heck, yeah.
I should take that back.
And I can, because I--
CODEX: Yeah.
Yeah, you told us.
VORK: Ha!
I sheltered it in
physical assets.
Eat that, Fed.
CLARA: Vork used it to
buy this guild hall.
KEVINATOR: This place cost
half a million G's?
Looks like a sodomy cell.
CODEX: Well, uh, maybe you
could help us with that?
I'm a girl-- in real life.
And I look just like this.
KEVINATOR: Yeah.
Nice character design.
Yeah, I can swing it.
[MUSIC PLAYS]
[CRASHING NOISES]
CLARA: Oh my gosh.
Tink, it's our design.
It's so beautiful.
Oh, honey, I want to paint
our bedroom like this.
VORK: Aw, gah--
MR. WIGGLY: Can I log off now?
VORK: First I get left at
the altar, now this.
I want to sob on principle.
BLADEZZ: I wanna vomit, but
it would match the decor.
KEVINATOR: Anyone ever tell you
your character looks like
that cheesy pirate dude?
BLADEZZ: Look like that dude?
Buddy, I am that dude.
KEVINATOR: No way.
Say "taste my pirate patty."
BLADEZZ: Ahem--
taste my pirate patty.
KEVINATOR: Dude!
You're the dude!
Walk with me?
CODEX: That was close.
Good job.
ZABOO: Thanks, best friend.
Being nice to my mom was
a trippy experience.
Kinda like that movie Psycho,
but with a happy ending.
Hey.
You forward slash
hand-holded me.
CODEX: Ah, I was just-- eh--
trying it out.
BLADEZZ: Man, Kevinator is all
over me about being the
Cheesybeards dude.
CODEX: We know.
You're insufferable.
BLADEZZ: But he wants me to come
to the gaming convention.
Make me a guest.
And I hooked us all
up with tickets.
You guys can be my manservant
entourage.
CLARA: A gaming convention?
CODEX: There's gonna
be a convention?
With the game?
VORK: Where did my grief go?
ZABOO: There's seriously
a convention?
CLARA: We're going
to a convention--
MR. WIGGLY: Yeah, honey,
about that--
CLARA: Wooooo--
[MUSIC PLAYING]