comes to some politicians they pretend
to be a little concerned but when it
comes to americans in general week i
don't make fun of north korea out we
don't really see that as a real threat
at least not the moment but with iran
there's always the sense of urgency all
my doctor building nuclear weapons we
have to do something called i got the
uranium we gotta do something
immediately
so why
is back in the atlantic did the job
breaking this down and i just cannot
wait to discuss this
so i just give you guys are uh... some
specific examples of
how american politicians speak out about
iran but don't care much about north
korea
in defense secretary timetables
full-day confirmation hearing before the
senate armed services committee but
working robs mention one and one hundred
seventy times
north transmission ten times
now remember iraq doesn't have nuclear
weapons yet yeah north korean dots now
of course that nuclear weapons that they
have or their nuclear capabilities and
all that impressive at the moment hubble
we know that
they have something that writing their
back to me brand but they do have them
they do not have exactly i'm part of the
problem
underwent distribuidora for it
double legacy firstly as the the
tensions between us and and uh... in
north korea also between north korea
south korean all that from the ratchet
up in the past few weeks let me know
at least of if read it is representative
but it's just it's just jokes like he
did on the main show couple days ago you
did the picture of uh...
uh... pins on uh...
your own with the the pig nose and
everything like yes it just seems so
easy to market
and it's because their culture is a
little bit more foreign obviously
they're their leaders are fit in such a
different position than that they have a
rich person it's easy to mark the lights
also before we get into like asian
stereotypes because that's actually part
of this and i knew that it would be part
of this let's discuss uh...
here's some of the real issues with the
wind
love this explanation thing it's the
best one so far with iran you'll have
religious martyrs right so when you talk
about nuclear war
a lot of countries that have nuclear
weapons will not engage in nuclear war
because they know that that will be the
demise of their own country
offer instead of someone tax the united
states of the nuclear weapon when you
think the united states is going to
bring in attacking you
which our nuclear weapons so what you're
on there more religious martyrs that
might be
willing to die in the name of the
original in the name of their country
with north korea they care much more
about their state
as opposed to anything else or or making
sure to preserve their stay
and you all know that there are three
has been threatening us for a very long
time this is not some new development
so i love that explanation but then they
also i kind of delved into on
stereotypes so when it comes to moslems
of course the stereotype is they're more
danger as al you know that there is a
and bill engaging riskier behavior
whereas with occasions there seem isn't
seen as worked in a and people don't
generally think of them as a threat
about sacred belief that by any way
shape or form but you know that's
just in general thinking behind it and i
thought was interesting headed to some
extent that's reflected in in popular
culture like you see that who's the bad
guy in the action movies changes over
time infor
herb the last fifteen years or so it's
usually been muslims of some stripper
data from one country doesn't matter
which
sometimes they're made up countries they
will typically be the villain whereas
north korea like they were one of the
bond movies like it never dipping down
that and i don't know if that causes
some of what leads to us to fear around
more than north korea or if it's simply
a reflection of it
but that's going on to the popular
culture
and also you know i keep in mind that we
have the influence of israel israel is
that you know very much willie are
n_b_c_ claim that they're willing to
that
anti-tax iran if they do see iran is a
threat and how many times as net neon
set
we're going to go in with an attack iran
so that kind of makes the situation in
iran a lot
shakir
uh... but another thing is and i i
didn't know this story to recently
north korea out that the state media
north korea had reported that they found
a unicorn lair
uncovered that look if you're probably
the first hour but if your
it's telling your people that you
discovered a unicorn layer
you know if you're threatening us with
nuclear weapons newman's contingency
ears i don't even know if that's the
craziest thing like he's only ever board
three hundred any invented oral sex like
there's a lot of crazy things that you
know they do but if you're in for you
but i think that you did touch on the
biggest one like they've been listening
this atlantic p several reasons that we
fear run more than north korea but i
think they israel's the most important
part
visiting like cuba real the average
american who does not care much about
any country in the world cares about
america and israel and in both of these
cases the country that we could
potentially fear has a hostage to some
extent iran has israel's hostage north
korea even more directly as south korea
as a hostage and that the average
american for whatever reason just does
not feel any connection to south korea
for some raised the specter in in at
incredible growth of u_n_ job
christianity in south korea recently
uh... i think that they just care more
about israel