There's gang violence, tons of
mafia, sectarian killings, and
in more recent years,
suicide bombings.
But for the political parties,
it's a massive turf war.
And while politicians and
businessmen would never admit
that they engage in
assassinating their rivals,
someone is hiring the so-called
target killers.
We wanted to interview one of
the men responsible for this
dirty work, so we arranged a
meeting with a target killer.
It was uncomfortable for
everyone involved.
We negotiated the terms
of the interview--
in a moving car and with his
motorcycle helmet on.
And not surprisingly, the guy
who kills people for money--
he wanted to get paid.
INTERVIEWER: [SPEAKING URDU]
ASSASSIN: [SPEAKING URDU]
INTERVIEWER: OK.
[SPEAKING URDU]
ASSASSIN: [SPEAKING URDU]
INTERVIEWER: [SPEAKING URDU]
It's been at my feet
the whole time.
[URDU].
ASSASSIN: [URDU].
INTERVIEWER: Thank you.
MALE SPEAKER: Well,
that was intense.
INTERVIEWER: That was--
yeah, that was really strange
sitting next to someone who's
killed 35 people.
And you could just tell from
his demeanor and from his
eyes, he was a hard dude.
And there's 600 guys like that
roaming around the city.
Anytime anyone has a beef to
settle with someone else--
they want to kill them-- just
hire one of these guys and
don't pay them that
much money, and
they'll do the work.
It's lawless, wild,
and chaotic here.
And that is some scary shit.