I'm going to take this straw,
and I'm going to jam it
through this potato, and you're
going to like it, but
not before you watch this.
I'm Steve Spangler, and I'm all
about making science fun.
For the last 20 years, I've
been teaching ways to turn
ordinary science experiments
into unforgettable learning
experiences.
I have an amazing team who will
do whatever it takes to
affect the way people
think about science.
And to do that, I live by one
motto, make it big, do it
right, give it class.
It's the first science
experiment that I ever learned.
It was actually in
kindergarten.
I had a kindergarten teacher
who had a whole thing of
potatoes sitting there, and
a whole thing of straws.
And the challenge was, she said
boys and girls, I want
you to take that-- because she
always said boys and girls--
take this straw and jam
it through the potato.
And do that a whole bunch of
times, and when you're done,
bring it to me.
It'll be a porcupine.
We'll put eyes on it,
and that's your
little take-home surprise.
And she didn't even have to
finish those words, and
there's 14 boys trying to jam
a straw through a potato.
If you can't see, it doesn't
work so well.
If you try to jam a straw
through the potato, it doesn't
work because it crumbles.
Unless, you use what's
in the straw.
And what is inside the straw?
Yes, ladies and gentlemen,
it's called air.
So if you put your thumb over
the end of the straw, you trap
the air inside.
And now, as you hold
onto it like this,
you just jam through.
And what I've learned
is that brown is the
potato, and pink is me.
So you have to practice where
you're going to jam, but it's
pretty good.
Here, watch this.
Straw through the potato.
See that air gives the straw
that rigid support, because
air takes up space.
It's perfect.
And here's the greatest thing.
Look at the little piece of
potato lodged right here.
This is perfect.
You don't throw the straw
away, you just jam
through one more time.
Watch.
And this is exactly what
you're looking for.
Look.
Piece of potato lodged here.
A piece of potato here.
If you can get your buddy to
come over to the table and jam
through one more time,
forgetting to put his thumb
over the end of the straw, this
end pushes up, squeezes
the air, and fires this
end at your head at
about 35 miles an hour.
That's awesome.
This, ladies and gentlemen,
is my first potato gun.
Now, today's day and age, you
can't say potato gun.
It's a potato launcher.
Our object, of course, is
just to make it bigger.
You just need to have
a bigger straw.
This is a good straw, this
is a better straw.
And this is the straw that you
need to be able to make the
larger potato launcher.
Now, thanks to Lee Merrick, who
was a wonderful chemistry
teacher, who's the first person
to show me this kind of
clear piece--
instead of using a
piece of PVC--
so you can actually see
what's going on
inside with the potato.
The ends are flared
here and here.
And I'll show you how to do
that here in just a second
when you make your own.
But this allows us to be able
to see the pieces of potato.
So the first step is you carve
out a piece of potato, and it
sits in this end, here.
Now, the object is, we've got to
move this piece of potato,
to this end over here.
And to do that--
I could use a dowel--
I'm using this fancier
piece of plastic.
A Lucite rod.
And I'm simply going to take
this now, and push it
to the other end.
Perfect.
So we now have a place
to receive
another piece of potato.
Back to the plunging.
You just carve out yet another
piece of potato and now this,
is perfect to launch.
Now, if I go back to my high
school days, they used this to
be able to teach Boyle's Law,
that said this out of the text
that was written when the earth
was still cooling--
Boyle's Law.
As you increase the pressure,
you decrease the volume of
air, thus breaching the
integrity of the potato.
Here's the deal, in modern times
it kind of means this,
jam hard this way, squish the
air, fire this at your friend.
And to do that, you'll need
your safety glasses.
And luckily for me, I have
a friend, and his name's
Higginsworth.
Higginsworth, you're going
to want to run.
HIGGINSWORTH: What?
STEVE SPANGLER: Run,
Higginsworth, run!
Light on me, Higginsworth,
keep the light on me.
Run!
Now I know that's fun, and
you're going to want
to make your own.
And you probably want to make
one out of this clear, kind of
Plexiglas polycarbonate.
I can tell you that these are
fairly expensive, so I would
suggest heading to the local
hardware store and making one
out of PVC.
Look at this piece
of 1/2 inch.
And take a look at
this one, here.
The thin wall is the way
that you want to go.
While this is cheap and
inexpensive, this makes a
better potato gun--
a launcher.
All right, here's the secret.
The secret is you need to bore
out the very end of the pipe.
You see it there?
That makes this narrow, so it's
a tapering kind of effect
on this end, and on
this end, here.
That way when you jam the potato
in, it really kind of
sticks it in place
and holds it.
And the secret is that drill.
The second piece that
you're going to need
is the pusher, right?
That dowel rod.
And what you're going to do is
you're going to find a piece
of dowel rod that's just a
little bit bigger than the
tube that you're using, because
you need something to
be able to hold on to.
And the second thing is, you
don't want to be jamming this
in and accidentally
hit your thumb.
That's why we simply just put a
piece of duct tape around it
and colored it this way so
that it gives my thumb
something to hold onto, and I
can jam it down in place.
This is perfect.
This is the hardest part and
the part of the video that
you're going to replay
over and over.
Because you need to remember
to carve out a piece of
potato, like you have here, and
we're going to move this
piece of potato to the
other end over here.
Like this.
When you hear that sound, you
know you're doing it right.
So the first piece of
potato is here.
This end is open to accept the
second piece of potato.
And now I'm ready to go.
You've got to remember to wear
those safety glasses.
When you take the dowel rod,
you've got to push it into
this end, and it's ready
to accept it.
So now I can hold on here,
and as I start to push--
again I'm increasing the
pressure, decreasing the
volume, and eventually that
end will pop out.
Watch.
That's a good one.
And the most useful tip of
all, is to remember that
there's still a piece of
potato lodged in here.
Because if you put this in your
little science drawer and
you forget about it, you're
going to smell the potato
launcher long before
you use it again.
So that's why you find another
piece of dowel that you can
use at the very end to be able
to push the last piece of
potato out.
And now you're ready wash it,
and it's ready to go.
You know, over the last two
decades, we as a country have
spent a tremendous amount of
time trying to make science
fun for kids and convince them
that science is fun.
And I know that you know this,
but kids already know that
science is fun.
We have to convince teachers
that teaching science is fun.
So we tried a little
experiment.
We thought, what if we
had 160 of these?
And we had 200 pounds of
potatoes, and we had 160 sets
of safety glasses.
What would it look like if you
dumped it all out, divided the
group, and let them go to war?
This is what it looked like.
Take a look.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
STEVE SPANGLER: Closer,
closer.
Run away, Higginsworth.
Run!
Oh, man.
I almost smacked him
right in the head.