Yeah, well, l think l do.
You know, living with you,
it hasn't been easy.
People see me but they think of you.
With this going on,
it's gonna be worse than ever.
- It don't have to be.
- Sure it does.
-Why? You got a lot goin' on, kid.
-What, my last name?
That's the reason l got a decent job,
why people deal with me in the first place.
Now l start to get a little ahead, to get a little
something for myself, and this happens.
Now, l'm asking you as a favour
not to go through with this, OK?
This is only gonna end up
bad for you and bad for me.
- You think l'm hurtin' you?
- Yeah. In a way you are.
- It's the last thing l ever wanted to do.
- l know that's not what you wanna do,
but that's just the way that it is.
Don't you care what people think?
Doesn't it bother you that people make you
out to be a joke and l'll be included in that?
Do you think that's right?
Do you?
You ain't gonna believe this,
but you used to fit right here.
l'd hold you up and say to your mother:
''This kid's gonna be
the best kid in the world.''
''This kid's gonna be somebody
bettter than anybody ever knew.''
And you grew up good and wonderrful.
lt was great just watching.
Evey day was like a privilege.
Then the time come for you to be your own
man and take on the world, and you did.
But somewhere along the line,
you changed. You stopped bein' you.
You let people stick a finger in your face
and tell you you're no good,
and when things got hard, you started
Iookin' for somethin' to blame.
Like a big shadow.
l'll tell you something you already know.
The world ain't all sunshine and rainbows.
lt's a vey mean and nasty place.
And l don't care how tough you are,
it will beat you to your knees
and keep you there permanently if you let it.
You, me, or nobody
is gonna hit as hard as life.
But it ain't about how hard you hit.
lt's about how hard you can get hit
and keep movin' forrward.
How much you can take
That's how winnin' is done!
lf you know what you're worth,
get what you're worth,
but you gotta be willin' to take the hits
and not pointin' fingers,
sayin' you ain't where you wanna be
because of him or her or anybody!
Cowards do that, and that ain't you!
You're better than that!
l'm always gonna love you no matter what,
no matter what happens.
You're my son and you're my blood.
You're the best thing in my life.
But until you start believin' in yourself,
you ain't gonna have a life.
Don't forget to visit your mother.