-Hi.
Um, I called earlier.
Um, I'm here to pick
up two pies.
-Hold on one second.
Eddie?
EDDIE (OFFSCREEN): What, man?
EMPLOYEE (OFFSCREEN):
Customer.
EDDIE (OFFSCREEN): Well, take
care of the customer, then.
Hey, how you doing?
CUSTOMER (OFFSCREEN): Hi.
-Ow, fuck.
CUSTOMER (OFFSCREEN): Um,
I called earlier.
I have to pick up two pizzas.
-What's your name?
CUSTOMER (OFFSCREEN): Lauren.
-All right.
I got your pizzas here.
LAUREN (OFFSCREEN): Fabulous.
-One plain, one pepperoni,
right?
LAUREN (OFFSCREEN): Yes.
-What the fuck is that?
-Green pepper.
-What do we got?
-One green pepper.
-We got another Bingo job.
-Ah.
You don't have pepperoni, is
what you're saying to me?
-Somebody shoot me in
my fucking head.
Oh, you're gonna give her the--
the green pepper pie?
LAUREN (OFFSCREEN): No,
I don't, no, I don't--
-Hold on one second,
I'm sorry.
You're gonna give her the
green pepper pie?
-She asked for a green
pepper pie.
EDDIE (OFFSCREEN):
No, she didn't.
She asked for a plain, and she
asked for a pepperoni.
Bingo.
-It's just peppers.
-What?
One's meat and one's
a vegetable.
Can you do me a favor?
BINGO (OFFSCREEN): It
looks pretty good.
EDDIE (OFFSCREEN): Can you
just sit for two seconds?
-No, no, no, no, no, no.
EDDIE (OFFSCREEN):
And, uh, just--
-No, no, no, no.
EDDIE (OFFSCREEN): Just, just--
here's free pizza.
-That's--
EDDIE (OFFSCREEN): We're
gonna give you--
- --wonderful.
EDDIE (OFFSCREEN): --the green
pepperoni pie for fucking--
-I can't use it.
EDDIE (OFFSCREEN): --free.
-I cannot-- this does not work.
No.
EDDIE (OFFSCREEN): You
can't use that?
-Um.
-Would you like a handful of
freshly cooked garlic knots?
-That's lovely.
-A meat patty?
-I need, I need a pepperoni
and a plain--
-We got some eggplant--
- --is that possible--
- --we got some--
- --or no?
-How long is it gonna
take you to--
LAUREN (OFFSCREEN): No?
- --to make the two pies as
opposed to the one freaking
pie you made?
BINGO (OFFSCREEN): 15 minutes.
LAUREN (OFFSCREEN): All
right, you know what?
-What'd you say?
BINGO (OFFSCREEN): 15 minutes.
LAUREN (OFFSCREEN): That's
OK, it's OK.
-15 minutes to make two pies.
LAUREN (OFFSCREEN):
No, it's OK.
-You can't sit?
LAUREN (OFFSCREEN):
No, I can't.
-Two seconds, eat a slice.
LAUREN (OFFSCREEN): No.
-Come on, it's delicious.
LAUREN (OFFSCREEN):
Sorry, dude.
Thanks.
-Just sit for two
fucking seconds.
Cinderella?
[EDDIE BLOWS A RASPBERRY]
-Sorry.
EDDIE (OFFSCREEN): Come
on, sweetheart.
-Sorry, sorry, sorry.
EDDIE (OFFSCREEN): How about
a handful of garlic
knots, you fat ass--
give me a fucking break.
FEMALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
You guys should have put--
-You know, one of these days
I'm gonna have to smack you
around in front of them.
You son of a--
BINGO (OFFSCREEN): Should
we eat her pizza?
EDDIE (OFFSCREEN): Yeah,
you want some pizza?
Can you tell me something?
BINGO (OFFSCREEN): Yeah.
FEMALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
What do you--
-Pepperoni, OK, ain't
green peppers.
BINGO (OFFSCREEN): Thought
she said green peppers.
-No, I know.
But we do this everyday.
He's got a, he's got a pepper,
pepper, pepperoni thing.
[LIGHTER CLICKING]
CHILD (OFFSCREEN): No, no.
FEMALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Let's go see those others.
Oh, hi, Eddie.
Guess what?
I'm happy I see you, because,
uh, I got a surprise for you.
-What?
-I'm pregnant.
I just came from the doctor's.
It's great, right?
It's gonna be a girl,
I'm sure.
-How do you know?
-Don't you know?
-I know.
I just came from the
doctor's, Eddie.
I'm sure.
-Don't torture me.
-I'm not torturing you, Eddie.
It's great.
You're not happy?
All right--
it's gonna be great, right?
I know it's gonna be a girl.
OK, I gotta go to music class.
Do you got the $200?
-You're taking music classes
now, little guy?
-You know that.
-He can't even speak yet.
-OK, that should do it.
I know, but he's gonna be a
great musician, isn't he?
OK, bye, daddy.
-Bye, honey.
Fucking--
FEMALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
You're so good this time.
-What is this?
What is this?
It's a bunny.
[KISSING]
You like it?
[DOORBELL]
[KISSING]
Who is it?
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Con Ed.
[GUNSHOTS]
[SHELL CASINGS HIT THE FLOOR]
[BOOGIE WOOGIE MUSIC]
[BOSSA NOVA MUSIC]