the educator-in-chief. And today we're at
a really interesting facility in North Carolina
to talk about what's possible; what dreamers
are doing to enable us to achieve a very important
national goal, and that is to become less
dependent on oil from overseas, thereby ensuring
that our national security interests are better
intact and our economic security interests
are better intact and that we're better stewards
of the environment. That's what we're here
to talk about.
But before I do, I do want to thank some people.
First, Laura sends her regrets. I'm a lucky
boy to have her -- (laughter) -- to have her
as my wife. We've got a lot of friends here
in Carolina, and she sends her best wishes
to our Carolina friends. I told some folks
yesterday, I'm not very objective when it
comes to my wife, but I think the country
is really lucky to have her as the First Lady.
(Applause.)
We're here at Novozymes, which is a company
that makes enzymes. We're going to talk to
Thomas, who is the President and Plant Manager,
about what they do here, and why it's relevant.
Before we get there, I do want to say something
about Steen Riisgaard. He's the President
and CEO, Steen. He flew over from Denmark.
I can't thank you enough for coming. I appreciate
you being here. It's interesting, isn't it,
when you're able to sit in North Carolina
and talk about a Danish company that is investing
to not only help us become less dependent
on oil, but equally importantly is investing
capital, which enables citizens from the United
States to find good work.
I toured around the facility, and I asked
people at the facility how long they had been
working here. And a lot of people have been
here 20-plus years. So for those people who
are worried about free trade, I want you to
remember that if this country were to wall
ourselves off from the world, we would miss
opportunities to find markets for our products,
and at the same time miss opportunities for
citizens who work at a facility like this
to find good work. It's in our interests that
we have free and fair trade.
And so I thank you very much, Steen, for investing
in the United States of America, and I appreciate
the fact that you're sensitive to the needs
of the workers here in the United States of
America. And I see you're sitting next to
your Ambassador. Mr. Ambassador, welcome.
I'm glad you're here. (Applause.)
A person who understands the vast potential
in the lands here in North Carolina to make
us less dependent on oil is Richard Burr.
He's the United States Senator. I'm proud
he's joined us today, and thank you for coming,
Senator. There you go. (Applause.) Congressman
G.K. Butterfield. Thank you for being here,
G.K. Appreciate you coming. (Applause.) He's
a United States Congressman from the neighboring
district, but he has enough interest in making
sure that we succeed in alternative sources
of energy, that he's here. He's also on an
important subcommittee in the House. I appreciate
your interest. Appreciate you joining us.
I want to thank the Agricultural Commissioner
from the great state of North Carolina, Steve
Troxler, who's joined us today. Steve, thank
you for coming. There he is, right there.
(Applause.) See, Steve needs to take an interest
in this like he is, because doesn't it make
sense to be able to say to our farmers, grow
what you can grow so we become less dependent
on oil. I like the idea of a President being
able to say, wow, the crop report is in, we're
growing more corn than ever before, which
means we're importing less oil from overseas.
It's an exciting time to think about that
our farmers not only are going to grow what
we need to eat, but it's going to grow what
we need to run our automobiles.
And that's coming. That's what we're here
to discuss today. I know it sounds like a
pipe dream to some -- you know, there goes
the optimistic President talking again. But
you're going to hear from some experts here.
I'm just a history major. (Laughter.) And
I'm with Ph.D.s. (Laughter.) Let me remind
you who the President is. (Laughter and applause.)
But the Ph.D.s are providing the brain power
necessary to help plants like this develop
technologies that will enable us to convert
wood chips into fuels that are running automobiles.
It's an interesting time, isn't it, when you're
able to say, we're on the verge of some breakthroughs
that will enable a pile of wood chips to become
the raw materials for fuels that will run
your car.
I appreciate the Mayor, Jenny Edwards, here,
Mayor of Franklinton, for joining us. Where
are you, Madam Mayor? Thanks for coming. Proud
to see you again. (Applause.) And all the
Novozymes employees, I appreciate you setting
this deal up and I appreciate you putting
up with the hundreds who travel with me. (Laughter.)
And thank you for your warm hospitality.
Look, here's -- I just told you the goal.
The goal is for the United States to be -- to
diversify away from old, old ways. And it's
possible. And I do believe it is a proper
use of your money, taxpayers' money, to spend
to encourage research on interesting ideas.
We spent about $12 billion since I've been
your President to try to stimulate technologies
that will literally change the way we live.
A lot of that money has gone into clean coal
technologies. If you're worried about dependency
on oil from overseas, then it seems to make
sense to me that we ought to be able to have
the technology so that we can better use the
resources we have here at home.
I don't know if you know this, we've got about
250 years worth of coal in America. That's
what they estimate. And it makes sense, therefore,
to spend money at the federal level to develop
technologies so we can burn that coal in environmentally
friendly ways. The idea is to have zero emission
coal-fired plants here in America. And it's
possible, and we're making progress toward
that goal.
I happen to believe that if you're concerned
about the environment and want to deal with
renewable sources of energy, that we need
to pursue nuclear power. Those power plants
emit zero greenhouse gases. It doesn't require
any hydrocarbons from overseas to run those
plants. So we're beginning to license new
plants. We're spending money on wind and solar
energies. It makes sense to be able to -- as
the price of hydrocarbons goes up, it makes
sense that there be alternative sources of
energy coming to the market as quickly as
possible.
So we're making pretty good progress. But
if you really want to reduce the amount of
oil that you consume, you got to reduce the
amount of gasoline you use. In other words,
if you say, we want to reduce our dependence
on oil, what you really got to do is change
gasoline usage in the United States. And there's
a couple of exciting things that are taking
place -- one is new battery technologies.
We're spending money at the federal level
-- and by the way, there's a lot of private
sector money going into alternative sources
of energy. And some day you're going to be
able to get in your car, particularly if you're
a big-city person, and drive 40 miles on a
battery. It's coming. And by the way, the
car doesn't have to look like a golf cart.
(Laughter.) It could be a pickup truck. (Laughter.)
And that technology is around the corner.
And if we're able to drive the first 40 miles,
or, say, 20 miles, on gasoline [sic] there's
a lot of big-city folks that will never have
to use a drop of gasoline on a daily basis.
They'll be driving via electricity. These
are lithium-ion batteries, technology -- so
when you hear that term, you just got to know
there's a lot of folks and a lot of money
aiming hard to get this to the market as quickly
as possible. Why? Because we've set a goal
for the United States to be less dependent
on oil.
Secondly -- and this is what we're here to
talk about today -- is ethanol. It says that
the new developments in ethanol -- in other
words, fuel derived from corn -- can be diversified.
Here's the problem: Right now we're consuming
about 7 billion gallons of ethanol a year
made from corn. And it's a pretty standard
process. People here at this facility have
developed the enzymes necessary to break the
corn down in an efficient way so that we can
use ethanol derived from corn.
The problem is we got a lot of hog growers
around the United States and a lot of them
here in North Carolina who are beginning to
feel the pinch as a result of high corn prices.
A lot of the cattle people around the United
States -- I have got a few of them in my home
state of Texas -- they're worried about high
corn prices affecting their making a livelihood.
In other words, the demand for corn, because
of agricultural use, and now energy use, is
causing corn prices to go up. I bet you the
Agriculture Commissioner is hearing from folks.
And so how do -- the question then is, how
do you achieve your goal of less dependence
on oil without breaking your farmers -- without
breaking your hog raisers -- corn farmers
happen to like it, but I'm talking about the
-- (laughter) -- people dependent on corn.
And here's how: You develop new technologies
that will enable you to make ethanol from
wood chips, or stalk grass, or agricultural
waste. And that's what we're here to talk
about: Is it possible, and if it is possible,
how close are we to achieving the technological
breakthroughs that I believe are possible
so that our -- so that we're changing our
habits.
And these are exciting times, they really
are. I've always said, America needs to stay
on the leading edge of technological change.
It will mean we remain a really important
economy in the world, but it will also mean
that our folks will be able to find good high-paying
jobs.
In this case, being on the leading edge of
technological change means that we'll also
be able to deal simultaneous with economic
insecurities that come when China demands
more for oil, the world produces less, the
price of oil goes up, and so does the price
of gas at the pump here in North Carolina;
national security concerns where some people
who've got oil don't like us, and therefore,
may be willing to use their energy resources
to try to cause America to take a different
view of the world; and environmental concerns.
And all these three concerns come together
with technology as the solution.
And so Thomas, tell people what you do. (Laughter
and applause.)
MR. NAGY: That was a -- that was a nice introduction.
Thank you, Mr. President. You may know, and
many of you here -- first of all, I want to
welcome you very, very deep from my heart
and from all my colleagues here in Franklinton,
welcome to North Carolina, welcome to Novozymes,
and also welcome to the guests here. (Applause.)
THE PRESIDENT: Well, thank you. Like you're
the President, right?
MR. NAGY: Well, you're the President. (Laughter.)
Okay, anyways --
THE PRESIDENT: It didn't take him long to
learn, you know. (Laughter.)
MR. NAGY: Novozymes is the world's leading
biotechnology company within the field of
industrial enzymes and microorganisms. We
market more than 600 products around the globe,
and all of these products have the same in
common, that they -- sort of like it's good
for environment, it's good for businesses,
because when using our products, you use less
resources, less energy, less water, and hence,
you make better use --
THE PRESIDENT: So you make enzymes.
MR. NAGY: We make enzymes. And enzymes is
sort of like the key component you need to
have when you convert starch or the corn to
sugar that you can then make to alcohol or
the ethanol. But also, it's got to be the
key component when you want to make your switchgrass
or your biomass to sugar and then to ethanol.
THE PRESIDENT: So the enzyme begins to break
down the raw materials in a particular raw
material that will enable us to make more
ethanol, is that what you're saying?
MR. NAGY: That is correct.
THE PRESIDENT: Now -- so, is this a -- is
this like a huge distillery?
MR. NAGY: Our plant here?
THE PRESIDENT: Yes.
MR. NAGY: Well, you could say what we do here,
we use microorganisms, and the way we make
these enzymes is by the use of these microorganisms.
And you could compare our process to if you
brew beer or wine. We take some agriculture
raw materials like starch, again, or corn,
and then we ferment the insides, basically,
like you would ferment wine. The product here
is the enzymes that we can then ship off to
ethanol plants around in the U.S. And they
use it today to break down the starch in corn
and make ethanol. So we are a key provider
of a key technology to make this happen for
you.
THE PRESIDENT: Absolutely. And I presume that
one of the bottlenecks to achieving widespread
ethanol production is the cost of enzymes.
Have you seen any appreciable decline in the
cost of enzymes since you have been --
MR. NAGY: Certainly. We have worked with enzymes
for many, many years at Novozymes. We have
a 60-year tradition of this, and so we are
very, very good at it. We are the leading
edge on all the technologies in all the markets
we are, and therefore we are a company dedicated
to innovation, because innovation, as you
talk about, being able to compete with others,
innovation is our tool to do so. And so we
reinvest more than 10 percent -- actually
13 percent of our annual sales back into R&D.
The research we do in cellulosic ethanol right
now is the biggest research of what we have
in the company, where more than a hundred
researchers around the globe work on solving
the issues ahead of us. What we have been
able to do since 2000 until we reported it
in 2005, on a grant provided to us from Department
of Energy, is to reduce the cost of conversion
by a factor of 30.
THE PRESIDENT: I want to repeat, because you
actually -- he's talking about your money.
(Laughter.) And he said that we gave a grant
-- we, the taxpayers of the United States,
gave a grant to the researchers of this company,
see if they could not reduce the cost of producing
the enzymes that would be critical to making
ethanol, and this company was able to do so
-- reduced the cost by a factor of 30, which
I think is a justifiable use of taxpayer's
money to see those kinds of results.
MR. NAGY: Thank you.
THE PRESIDENT: You got a lot of Ph.D.s and
advanced degrees here?
MR. NAGY: Yes, we do. (Laughter.) We have
a few, yes.
THE PRESIDENT: You do?
MR. NAGY: Yes, we do.
THE PRESIDENT: The reason I mention that is
that part of remaining a competitive society
is to make sure our children get a good education
early, so that it is possible to get advanced
degrees -- at least a degree beyond high school.
If you want a good job in America, you better
go on after high school. The jobs in places
like this are jobs that require brain power,
as much as anything else. And, therefore,
the educational system of this state, for
example, has been critical in attracting industries
such as the company we're talking about here.
I mean, I go walking through the halls and
shaking hands with people -- we got people
on -- doing sophisticated computer programming;
we got lab technicians who have got advanced
degrees in bioengineering. And my only point
is it reminds me of how important higher education
is for this country. And I applaud the folks
of North Carolina about being on the leading
edge of education, and that's why you got
companies like here, like this company here,
paying pretty good money for jobs, I guess.
MR. NAGY: That's correct. One of the reasons,
and what we really enjoy here is also the
-- you alluded to the education system here,
but it's an integrated system from community
colleges through all the levels at university.
And there's a number of universities in the
state that we also enjoy very close collaboration
amongst. Some of them are NC State University,
of course.
THE PRESIDENT: Good. Well, Thomas, thanks,
buddy. I appreciate it. You handled it well.
(Laughter.)
Kevin Wenger. Yes, Kevin, how are you? What
do you do?
DR. WENGER: I'm the manager of the R&D group
that we have here in North Carolina for ethanol
research.
THE PRESIDENT: For this company.
DR. WENGER: For this company, yes. We, about
five years ago, decided to invest in a dedicated
R&D group for ethanol process development,
and we decided to anchor that research group
here in North Carolina, because the U.S. is
really where the ethanol market has been very
strong.
THE PRESIDENT: And you've got a degree in
what?
DR. WENGER: I have a degree in chemical engineering,
Ph.D. from Colorado State University.
THE PRESIDENT: Good.
DR. WENGER: And I've been here in Novozymes
since I finished graduate school in 1994.
THE PRESIDENT: And so in 1994, were you thinking
switchgrass into -- (laughter.)
DR. WENGER: I've always been interested in
alternative energy and making ethanol. There
wasn't so many jobs related to switchgrass
in 1994. (Laughter.)
THE PRESIDENT: Well, cellulosic.
DR. WENGER: Yes. But I was always -- I've
always been interested in fermentation also,
and so Novozymes is a fermentation company
and that's how I ended up here.
THE PRESIDENT: Interesting. And so I'd like
to quote what he said. Kevin said, "It's going
to be a challenge," -- talking about achieving
what we're talking about here -- "but if we
look at how far we've come in the past five
years, we have so much momentum, it shouldn't
be that tough."
And the reason I quote a person who knows
what he's talking about when it comes to developments
necessary to bring the cellulosic ethanol
to market, I quote him because I presume in
that optimism there's realism.
DR. WENGER: Yes, I'm very optimistic, but
also I can see how the 20-in-10 goal is very
achievable. If you look at what's happening
now, what's been happening with corn ethanol
over the last five years and the developments
that are coming in terms of implementation
of cellulosic, it's really amazing. Things
are really starting to happen.
THE PRESIDENT: What he referred to is something
I should have talked about earlier, and that
is I set a goal of the United States reducing
our gasoline consumption by 20 percent over
the next 10 years. That's the 20-10 goal.
In other words, it is a goal. And I mandated
a fuel standard that says we'll be using 35
million gallons of ethanol or alternative
fuel over the next 10 years.
Now, the reason I did this is I think it's
possible to do it. And the reason I think
it's possible to do it is because of people
like Kevin telling me it's possible. Remember,
I'm the history major. (Laughter.) And so
the advances you've seen in five years -- if
you're able to take yourself back five years
ago to today, it is a noticeable difference,
a -- obviously reduced the cost of enzyme,
for example, which is an important development.
DR. WENGER: Yes, absolutely, it's a very noticeable
difference and in terms of the number of industry
players that are really interested in this
technology and are also willing to invest
in making this technology happen, including
Novozymes as an industry player, it's really
amazing what we're seeing over the last five
years.
THE PRESIDENT: The high price of energy has
caused private capital to say that it's going
to be impossible for a society like the United
States to sustain its use on gasoline. So
whether it be Novozymes who is investing,
or private sector funds, that money is coming
in. They're fueling new research and development.
So we've got the government helping, but also
you've just got to know that the private sector
is very much involved with trying to invent
the technologies necessary to take advantage
of a society that recognizes it has to diversify
away from energy.
And I repeat to you, we're all connected,
and so when a Chinese economy grows and their
demand for oil goes up, it affects the price
that you pay for gasoline. People got to know
that. And therefore, it's important for us
to continue to advance these kinds of research
projects.
I met Dr. Mike in Greeley, Colorado, a year
ago.
DR. PACHECO: Golden, Colorado.
THE PRESIDENT: Exactly, Golden, Colorado.
How quickly they forget. (Laughter.) I am
60. (Laughter.) Golden, Colorado. Michael,
tell them who you work for.
DR. PACHECO: Mr. President, I work for the
National Renewable Energy Laboratory. We're
the leading laboratory for the Department
of Energy in the field of renewable energy.
We have a very robust program, as you know,
in the field of biofuels, and it's focused
right now on cellulosic ethanol.
I agree with Kevin, your 20-in-10 goal is
very achievable. In fact, the growth of the
corn and the biodiesel industry, which since
you signed the Energy Policy Act two years
ago, have been growing at over 100 percent
per year. Those fuels are going to make a
major portion of that 20 percent. But we have
to, as you indicated, begin the transition
to use a broader base of fuels.
Two years ago we issued a study with USDA,
two agencies together, that showed that the
U.S. could produce enough raw biomass that's
equivalent to about 60 percent of all the
oil that we use in the United States. The
problem is that most of that biomass is not
an easy material to convert. It's not like
corn grain. And so our research --
THE PRESIDENT: Explain to people what you're
talking about.
DR. PACHECO: Things like forest residues,
things like fast-growing trees and switchgrass
-- the major constituent in that material
is a cellulose fiber, usually accounts for
more than half of --
THE PRESIDENT: Do you know what switchgrass
is? Tell them what switchgrass is.
DR. PACHECO: Switchgrass is a native grass
that grew in the Midwest; it's a grass that
grows in relatively poor conditions, it can
survive droughts very well.
THE PRESIDENT: Rocky soil and dry. Sounds
kind of like parts of Texas, doesn't it? (Laughter.)
Imagine, however, if you're able to grow a
grass where it's rocky soil and dry that you're
able to convert into energy. You're talking
about a major change in the lifestyle of your
children and my children and their kids. I
mean, this is -- anyway, go ahead. (Laughter.)
DR. PACHECO: You're doing very well. (Laughter.)
THE PRESIDENT: I am passionate on the subject.
(Laughter and applause.)
DR. PACHECO: But that's a
really big part of it, Mr. President, being
able to move to those marginal conditions
and grow crops in areas where we're not currently
growing crops, and then to have those crops
that are specifically designed to produce
feedstocks that are adapted well for the enzymes
that Novozymes is producing can really increase
the yield -- that is, how much ethanol we
can make from a ton of biomass.
One of the challenges when we started this
project between NREL and Novozymes was that
no one in the world really felt like enzymes
could be a cost-effective technology in producing
ethanol from raw material. Today all the leading
researchers in the world are working in that
area because of the partnerships and because
of the progress that Kevin has already talked
about.
But we're not there yet. And while I'm optimistic,
like Kevin, there's still a lot of hard work
left to do, Mr. President. And we have work
in the pre-treatment area, we have work still
to do in the enzymatic hydrolysis, and we
still have research in the fermentation side.
And so DOE right now is considering proposals
to work with industry in the area of developing
fermentation organisms, which is a really
important part because the yeast, the bugs
today that we use to make ethanol won't work
in the future with these new feedstocks. So
it's really important that we start this transition.
At NREL we work with all the other national
labs. We especially work with Argon National
Lab and Pacific Northwest and Idaho and Oakridge.
Those are all labs that work together within
my center, and we try to coordinate our efforts
to utilize all the skills at the national
laboratories, because each of the labs brings
a unique set of skills to this challenging
problem. We also work with a lot of other
companies, in addition to Novozymes. And those
interactions are equally as important, because
one of the things that we're trying to do,
Mr. President -- when we talked last year
we talked about this -- is to try to develop
transitions that grow from existing industries.
So instead of replacing the corn ethanol industry,
we see cellulosic as evolving from it.
Similarly, we can see how the pulp and paper
industry might be able to evolve into bio
refineries. Maybe even the massive petroleum
refineries can someday evolve to take biomass
materials, and you know we're doing some research
in that area, as well.
It's really important that we stay on this
track, because in the long run, there's no
other sustainable source of liquid transportation
fuels other than biomass. So we have to succeed
at this.
THE PRESIDENT: You know, it's interesting,
you're probably wondering whether or not automobiles
can be easily converted to use ethanol, and
the answer is, absolutely. There's a lot of
automobiles in the Midwest that are filling
up with 85 percent ethanol, called E85 pumps.
It doesn't take much. So one of the barriers
to the advent of a lot of ethanol use is not
the automobile. It's easy to convert them.
As a matter of fact, some of you out there
probably have got a car that can use ethanol
and you just don't know it -- flex-fuel automobiles,
they're called.
Secondly, the production process. Once we
figure out what needs to take place internally,
it's not that expensive, relative to huge
gasoline refineries. What will happen is,
when you get a wood chip breakthrough, for
example, where it becomes cost effective,
you're going to have ethanol production plants
all across North Carolina, where the wood
chips can be gathered.
One of the reasons we keep talking about costs,
it's just real practical. Somebody is not
going to fill up their car with ethanol if
it costs a lot more than gasoline. The consumer
is pretty wise, and they care about the environment,
no question about it. But if a person is having
to drive back and forth to work, they're going
to generally pick the most economically competitive
fuel to do that. People want to keep money
in their pocket, and therefore, if it costs
less using gasoline, they'll use it. So, therefore,
that's why we're driving these research dollars,
to get the cost of producing ethanol down
so it can compete. And it's going to happen,
because as that price of oil goes up, the
price of gasoline goes up, which makes ethanol
more competitive. And one reason -- just so
you know -- one reason why there's been such
a push, is because when the price of oil went
up from early 2001 to where it is today, about
$60 a barrel, people saying, we may not be
able to sustain this, we better get moving.
And that's what's happening.
North Carolina State. Ratna. Welcome. Thank
you. You're a doctor of?
DR. SHARMA: Biological engineering.
THE PRESIDENT: Biological engineering. Chemical
engineering. Biological engineering. (Laughter.)
People should be getting the picture that
we've got a lot of smart people working on
this project. When you've got Ph.D.s surrounding
the President talking about doing what's right,
we've got a lot of brain power working on
it. And that's where you're going to get your
breakthroughs.
So what are you working on?
DR. SHARMA: Mr. President, first of all, I'd
like to thank you for your support and interest
in the development of these technologies for
cellulosic ethanol.
I essentially represent all the research of
my colleagues at North Carolina State University
and across the country in different universities
who have been working in this area of converting
residues from the farm, forest, animal operations,
possibly even food industry waste to convert
it into ethanol and make our country self-reliant
and achieve the goal of 20-in-10.
But, as has been mentioned, there are challenges.
We have to overcome those, and it's possible
we can do that. We do need more investment
and funding support, definitely, to speed
up this process of achieving this goal in
10 years.
THE PRESIDENT: So what do you think? I mean,
how long have you been doing this for?
DR. SHARMA: I've been doing this for about
four years.
THE PRESIDENT: Really? So when you got your
Ph.D. you never dreamt you'd be thinking about
converting wood to oil for fuel. What did
you feel?
DR. SHARMA: Well, I was trained as an agricultural
engineer, and I grew up on -- on an ag university
campus with farms around me. So I always saw
residues lying around and plants and stuff.
And I got my Ph.D. in food safety engineering
where I learned about microorganisms. So then
I saw this opportunity, it was like putting
together engineering and microbiology, to
process something and get value from something
that's typically not --
THE PRESIDENT: And there are other people
at North Carolina State working with you on
this project?
DR. SHARMA: Yes, there are. There are people
working on utilizing forest residues, wood
chips for converting to ethanol. There are
people working on different ag residues -- sweet
potatoes, which is a starch, base feedstock,
people working on biodiesel, from -- again,
from agricultural resources.
So there are a lot of people working on overcoming
the challenges of pretreatment and converting
the carbohydrates into sugars and then eventually
fermenting it into ethanol. And my focus has
been more on ag residues, like cotton stalks,
hays and straws, which would typically not
be --
THE PRESIDENT: Cotton stalks, pretty interesting,
isn't it?
DR. SHARMA: They are.
THE PRESIDENT: They now get plowed up in the
ground. Your idea is to get them so they can
end up in somebody's automobile, not in the
ground.
DR. SHARMA: Exactly. So there is a lot of
potential. And like switchgrass, which grows
in marginal lands. And we have, like you mentioned,
a big swine industry in North Carolina. So
the advantage is we could possibly put the
two together, use animal waste as a nutrient
source to grow the switchgrass and then convert
it into ethanol so you're getting energy from
waste.
THE PRESIDENT: So are people pretty upbeat
about it? People --
DR. SHARMA: Well, people who are aware and
looking forward to switching from fossil fuels
to renewable energy, yes, they are.
THE PRESIDENT: Yes, pretty good.
DR. SHARMA: And they feel it's achievable.
We can do it. We just need to work a little
harder on that.
THE PRESIDENT: Yes. A little more money and
a little harder. (Laughter.) Talk to my man,
Michael. He's the guy distributing some of
the money. (Laughter.) Well, good. Thanks,
Doc. Thanks for joining us. I'm sure proud
you're here. NC State is a fine, fine institution.
I know you're proud to work there.
DR. SHARMA: Yes, I am, definitely.
THE PRESIDENT: Ryan, where are you from?
MR. ADOLPHSON: From the University of Georgia
in Athens, Georgia.
THE PRESIDENT: A bold man to come here to
North Carolina. (Laughter.) A great school,
by the way. What do you do?
MR. ADOLPHSON: I'm with the university's -- I'm
in charge of our bio -- our pilot facilities
that are looking into early transitioning
some of this technology from the bench out
to industry, looking at really the wide, or
broad spectrum of this concept of biomass
to energy that includes fuels and includes
electrical and different bio products, and
really running the gamut of this whole type
of industry. And we have a pretty large research
facility looking into this at all levels.
THE PRESIDENT: In Athens?
MR. ADOLPHSON: In Athens, yes -- bio-refining
and carbon cycling center that we've recently
started in the last two years.
THE PRESIDENT: What is a bio -- what is a
carbon recycling center?
MR. ADOLPHSON: Carbon cycling.
THE PRESIDENT: Carbon cycling.
MR. ADOLPHSON: Right. So we're looking into
the concept of a bio refinery, which Mike
mentioned, and really taking a little bit
bigger picture view, stepping back, not looking
only at ethanol, but counting ethanol as a
significant piece to the puzzle, but looking
at all the other products that can be generated
from bio mass. You know, similar to a petroleum
refinery that takes a barrel of crude and
doesn't just make diesel and gasoline, but
50, 60 other products out of that.
So we're looking at our wood chips as that
barrel of crude, taking that, and turning
it into a larger profit stream than just a
single product, and we believe that's going
to drive the economics --
THE PRESIDENT: What other products?
MR. ADOLPHSON: There's a whole host of products.
You know, the char, the stuff that's in a
thermochemical process, instead of a biological
process, or the sugar platform. The Department
of Energy really breaks up when they talk
about our production of ethanol in two pathways:
one is thermochemical and the other is our
fermentation, or our sugar platform that we've
kind of been talking about now.
The thermochemical platform allows us to take
all these different biomass streams, treat
them with heat in a certain way, release all
of the energy from those, and we can capture
that, turn that into our product.
So one product we have left is the carbon
that's left over. We're able to look at that
as a soil amendment and take that carbon without
releasing it into the atmosphere and put it
back into the ground. And then we have everything
that comes out of that biomass that we can
turn into ethanol and we can turn into specialty
chemicals for our chemical industry as precursors
to things like nutraceuticals, pharmaceuticals,
and then we have the gas that comes off that
could be maybe cleaned up and used as a pipeline-quality
gas, like natural gas, to heat homes.
THE PRESIDENT: All from one big pile of wood
chips?
MR. ADOLPHSON: All from one big pile of wood
chips, right. You know, we're at a very unique
place --
THE PRESIDENT: You've got to dream big in
order to be able to get it done. (Laughter.)
That's good.
MR. ADOLPHSON: We are at a unique place right
now, and the technology is there.
THE PRESIDENT: Pretty interesting, isn't it?
It's -- I'm not so sure if they'd believe
me in the coffee shop in Crawford if I told
him what he just told me. (Laughter.) But
it's possible.
MR. ADOLPHSON: It is, right. I like to say,
we're not there yet, but we can see it from
here.
THE PRESIDENT: You can, yes.
MR. ADOLPHSON: We've got two -- on the ground
in the next 18 months in Georgia, we've got
a biorefinery taking wood chips to ethanol,
we've got a traditional corn ethanol plant
going in, we've got two, what we call, integrated
biorefineries that are going to be pulling
mostly -- we have 24 million acres of commercial
forest in Georgia. So that's a big priority
for us. And the pulp and paper industry has
been -- has been going other places.
THE PRESIDENT: Are they investing?
MR. ADOLPHSON: The industry itself?
THE PRESIDENT: Yes.
MR. ADOLPHSON: The part of the pulp and paper
industry, that is the growers, the land owners,
are very interested in finding a market for
their wood so they can get a higher price
for it. I think the paper mills might be less
interested in paying a higher price for their
feed stock than the growers are. But yes,
they're definitely investing. The University
and Governor Purdue has sent a mandate out
for us to really invest in public/private
partnerships. So we can take the public money,
and he likes to say he wants to see industry
with skin in the game, who is able to put
money and people involved in this effort.
And so we're -- we've created a facility.
We can locate industry on campus with us,
so that when we do develop a technology, this
technology transfer from academia to industry
is seamless. We're excited about that because
guys like us who are in academia or government,
we can provide money and resources, but it's
going to be the market that will have to pick
it up and take it to get it into the consumers.
THE PRESIDENT: Absolutely, yes. That's pretty
interesting, isn't it? Thanks for coming.
I'm glad you came over.
MR. ADOLPHSON: Thank you, Mr. President. We're
excited to be here. Great opportunity.
THE PRESIDENT: And we're going to end up with
Terry. Terry Ruse.
MR. RUSE: All of the Ph.D.s around the table.
I don't have one of those, but I --
THE PRESIDENT: I'm glad to join you. (Laughter.)
MR. RUSE: I'm happy to report to you that
the ethanol industry is alive and well and
up and taking nourishment.
THE PRESIDENT: So what do you do?
MR. RUSE: I am the Chief Operating Officer
for Agri-Ethanol. That's a privately-held
ethanol company in Raleigh.
THE PRESIDENT: And what do you -- so what
--
MR. RUSE: We are developing -- our strategic
plan is to develop 10, 108-million-gallon-a-year
ethanol plants in the --
THE PRESIDENT: So you're going to be the manufacturer?
MR. RUSE: We are going to be the manufacturer.
Thanks to the vision of Dave Brady and the
guys that own Agri-Ethanol, I've been able
to develop a really flexible project in that
we have a design to start out as a corn plant
to process corn. We were building 11,000 foot
of track -- big loop track to be able to bring
corn in by rail and take ethanol back out.
In the center of that loop track, we've engineered
the ability to handle wood chips. We've got
all that in place. We have a CO2 company that
will process the CO2, anything -- any of the
CO2 that doesn't go to that direction to make
food grade liquid carbon dioxide will be directed
into hydroponic gardening or into growing
algae to support an adjacent biodiesel plant.
Now we have the real estate to put one of
those on.
THE PRESIDENT: So you intend to buy the enzymes
from this company to run in your plant --
MR. RUSE: We have this -- as a matter of fact,
we have offered them the opportunity to establish
a field research laboratory on our site so
that they don't have to go long distances
to get their people and do really ground work
--
THE PRESIDENT: Where is this thing?
MR. RUSE: It's in Aurora, North Carolina.
It's the first one. It's about 160 miles east
of Raleigh.
THE PRESIDENT: And when will you -- are you
building it now?
MR. RUSE: We are ready to break ground. One
of the interesting facts about that is that
we have the site completely controlled. We
have it totally permitted. But in trying to
talk to the financial people about putting
money, I've spent two years trying to convince
them that it makes sense to build an ethanol
plant in North Carolina as much as it does
one in Iowa. And we haven't gotten that done.
And so --
THE PRESIDENT: See, you can't build a plant
far away from the raw material. That's the
interesting thing about this industry. What
he's basically saying is, is that investors
think you have to be in the middle of a corn
field. Really. And that's why there's a lot
of plants being built in the Midwest because
there's a lot of corn in the Midwest.
MR. RUSE: But because of the fact we're closer
to the population density centers for the
ethanol, and the animals that we have in North
Carolina, we can prove that our plant is as
competitive as the plant in Iowa.
THE PRESIDENT: You can't have a centralized
plant and ship your ethanol long distances,
either. The production needs to be close to
the raw material and the users, is what you're
saying. And the economics.
MR. RUSE: That's exactly correct. And this
-- each one of these plants will produce about
400,000 tons a year of highly digestible,
high protein feed to help the hog farmers,
that you alluded to, get over their heart
pain of --
THE PRESIDENT: High corn.
MR. RUSE: Of high corn. And coming from the
farm, the thing that I understand most is
the resiliency of the American farmer. You
give him a good price for the corn, and he
will grow the corn. And I think that when
the March planning report comes out, you'll
see closer to 13 billion or 13.5 billion bushel
corn market, and 90 million acres planted
than what we've seen in the past.
And so all of the price concerns from the
animal growers and from the Wall Streeters
will be --
THE PRESIDENT: Will be eased somewhat. That's
right. He's right. It's amazing how the market
responds.
MR. RUSE: And the one last piece of our project
is that we intend to build a green truck stop
on each one of these sites that sells biodiesel,
sell E10 and E85.
THE PRESIDENT: That would be good. E10 is
ethanol -- 10 percent ethanol.
MR. RUSE: Ten percent ethanol and 85 percent
ethanol and then biodiesel.
THE PRESIDENT: The purpose was to give everybody
a sense of where a lot of smart people and
good capital are moving. Smart people are
here working on some amazing technologies
that -- you know, that I believe 10 years
from now people will say, gosh, it's interesting
that they were worried about this particular
technology coming to fruition, because it's
coming to fruition. And the role of the government
is to stimulate thought and investment and
set goals. And we set a big goal, really have
-- reduction of gasoline by 20 percent over
the next 10 years.
I wouldn't have done that if I didn't think
it was achievable. Part of it is to change
our CAFE standards on automobiles, which will
encourage conservation. The other part is
to change the fuel -- fuel mix across America.
And this is a coming time. It really is. And
I want to thank those of you who are on the
front line of changing it. It must be exciting
for you to be able to work on something so
novel and so encouraging and so important
for our country.
I thank the good folks at this important company
for letting me come by to say hello. I ask
for God's blessings on the United States of
America. Thank you. (Applause.)