RYAN DUFFY: So we're here in
Bolivar Square in the middle
of central Caracas.
As you might be able to tell
from the cathedral behind me,
Venezuela is, like most Latin
American countries,
predominantly Catholic.
Now the interesting bit here is
there's a good bit of kind
of Santeria and spiritism
in the mix as well.
And we've recently found a
particular group of Saints
that fascinates us.
They're called the Santos
Malandros, translated roughly
as the Holy Thugs.
Now, it's either kind of perfect
or really troubling
that in Caracas, widely regarded
as the world's most
violent city, the Venezuelan
people are worshipping at the
feet of tiny statues of now
dead armed criminals.
Over 14,000 people were killed
in Venezuela last year.
And Caracas has the highest
murder rate per
capita in the world.
Hugo Chavez's Bolivarian
Revolution may have reduced
poverty in this oil-rich
country, but he's yet to bring
any sense of safety or security
to the streets.
It's in the middle of all this
violence that the cult of the
Holy Thugs was born.
The Holy Thugs are part of a
very unique mix of Catholicism
and spiritism.
So we first visited with
sociologist Tulio Hernandez to
try and get our heads
around it.
TULIO HERNANDEZ:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
RYAN DUFFY: He explained that
the main goddess of Venezuela
spiritism is Maria Lionza, who
is represented, of course, as
a naked lady riding what looks
to be an anteater.
Maria Lionza, essentially the
queen of all spirits.
Below her there's a whole bunch
of other saints grouped
into courts.
There's the court of doctors,
of Indians, of Africans, of
Vikings, and even of
revolutionaries.
TULIO HERNANDEZ:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
RYAN DUFFY: Every court
has a leader.
And the leader of the Court de
Malandro or the Court of the
Thugs is Ismael Sanchez.
So it's mid-afternoon and we
just got to the cemetery here
in Caracas.
And right over here is where
Ishmael Sanchez is buried,
along with the other members
of the Holy Thugs.
And this is where everyone
comes to kind
of pay their respects.
FEMALE SPEAKER:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
MALE SPEAKER: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
RYAN DUFFY: At the cemetery,
we met Omar, the unofficial
caretaker of Ismael's shrine,
and his buddies, Johann and
Vamonde, who both seem
to be spiritism
priests of some sort.
MALE SPEAKER: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
RYAN DUFFY: We talked
a lot about Ismael.
There's, you know, another few
saints in similar fashion who
are part of this group.
Can you tell us about
some of the others?
Like, who is that right there?
MALE SPEAKER: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
RYAN DUFFY: About how many
people are coming through a
day to pay respects,
or to celebrate, or
whatever they're doing?
And how long are they staying?
MALE SPEAKER: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
RYAN DUFFY: At some point,
we saw a funeral
procession drive by.
And we were told that it was a
kid murdered in the nearby
slums that weekend.
Soon after, we heard a few
rounds of automatic weapon
fire and decided it
was time to leave.
[GUNSHOTS]
TULIO HERNANDEZ:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
RYAN DUFFY: So leaving the
cemetery just now, we drove by
this shop and noticed they have
a bunch of the Holy Thugs
displayed in front.
So we're going to pop in, and go
check them out, and see if
we can meet the folks
who run the place.
We met the shop owner, a
spiritist named Clara, who
said she could only talk to us
with Ismael's permission.
So she went back to
her alter to ask.
It's a boy Ismael.
It's the leader the pack and the
rest of the pack as well.
This is Antonio.
He's got a pretty
serious scar.
It's kind of right in
there above his eye.
That's a knife fight that
Antonio got in.
Fresh out of the Thunderbird.
It's the one Holy Thug who
came from Jersey, Johnny.
Domicito, that's
a serious dude.
He also has the Nike hat.
He's perhaps a little more
devious than the rest.
He's somewhat concealing
his weapon.
Clara eventually invited us
back, where she actually
offered to channel Ismael
himself for us.
CLARA: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
RYAN DUFFY: Yeah.
I mean, I'm very interested
by it, certainly.
CLARA: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
RYAN DUFFY: You can see that
just by looking at me?
CLARA: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
RYAN DUFFY: We said goodbye to
Clara, picked up some statues,
and got on our way.
MALE SPEAKER: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
RYAN DUFFY: For many
Venezuelans, living in poverty
and amidst all of this violence,
believing in the
pure and perfect Catholic saints
is a bit more of a
stretch than believing in the
more familiar and flawed
figureheads like Ismael.
MALE SPEAKER: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
TULIO HERNANDEZ:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
[MUSIC PLAYING]