>> Dr. Wafeek Wahby:
Well, before we start, I want to
tell you we are taping so we
can capture Marty McIntyre's
presentation for any of you or
for anybody else who missed
this class so we can have it
on DVD if anybody would like
to have it, and leave it
in the library as well.
So, now we start officially,
it's 5 o'clock, so good evening,
or good afternoon if you like.
My name is Wafeek Wahby, and
I am thankful to Dr. Mori Toosi
to give us his class,
your students.
And let me see by a show of
hands how many of you have been
to Marty McIntyre's
class last week.
Okay, very good.
>> Ms. Marty McIntyre:
Or last year.
>> Dr. Wahby:
Last year, last year, very good.
How many of you have been to
the plant in Alsip in Chicago?
Very good, okay.
Now the plan would be like this.
Today we will get the
theoretical background and
the fun here on the screen and
from Marty, and then on the
15th of October we will take
two vans or three vans and go
and visit the plant, and we
will talk about this later
and Dr. Toosi will
give you the details.
So we can see how things
are done in the plant,
and maybe we can
visit some projects.
So without much ado,
Marty McIntyre, and
she will introduce herself.
>> Ms. McIntyre:
Okay, hi.
I thought I recognized a
couple of you from last year,
but I work with PCI,
which is the Precast
Prestressed Concrete Institute.
It's kind of a combination of a
trade association, so we have
about 235 member companies who
manufacture precast products.
Anything from bridge beams,
hollowcore, double tees, any of
the large structural type pieces
of concrete that you would see
coming to a job site
on a truck.
So no small lentils and
nothing that goes underground.
We're also an institute, which
means we do a lot of work with
universities doing research,
product development, and kind of
state-of-the-industry work to
kind of keep things up to speed.
So this is going to be a review
for some of you who have seen
this already, but I just have a
little bit of information for
you that gives you kind of a
nice introduction to Precast.
We're going to talk a little
bit about what are the products
that are manufactured,
where are they used, and
how are they manufactured.
So feel free to stop me at any
point if you have any questions
and I'd be happy to answer your
questions for you.
I always think when I'm
starting to talk about precast
that in some ways it's kind
of fun to look at kind of
the biggest or the best or the
most interesting projects
that have been done.
So over the last year I kind of
put together, this is my own
personal list of what I call the
"Seven Wonders of Precast",
some of the projects that
I think are some of the
coolest precast projects
that are out there.
And that's kind of a nice way
for me to get started.
So you can see that they're all
over the world, but of course
I know more projects in the
US than anywhere else,
so a lot of them are right
here in our own back door.
Oops, oh, it didn't like getting
transferred, I apologize.
So this is supposed to show
you the Bahai Temple.
I can show you another
picture of it, it's up
here in the corner.
Sorry about that, I don't know
why it didn't transfer.
So the Bahai Temple is in
Glencoe, Illinois, up north of
Chicago, kind of near the
lakefront on Lake Michigan.
And it was actually done in
the 1920s through the 1930s,
it took quite a while to build.
And the entire skin of it is
actually architectural precast.
It was manufactured in
New York and then shipped,
piece by piece, to Glencoe.
And you can see on the dome and
in some of the other areas,
and if you could see the
pictures that I had put on my
slide you'd be able to see that,
some of the intricate detail
that you can actually get out
of architectural Precast.
Then those are all put together
and it can really withstand the
test of time, so it does
a nice job doing that.
In some ways
manufacturing--yes?
>> Dr. Wahby:
Would you please give us
your definition of precast?
>> Ms. McIntyre:
The definition of precast?
>> Dr. Wahby:
What precast means.
>> Ms. McIntyre:
You know, precast is anything
that's cast in a plant and then
brought to the site.
So it's cast out of concrete,
and usually it's manufactured
in some kind of formwork.
In the case of the Bahai Temple,
it's specially designed formwork
with all of those
intricate details.
Actually, all of these would
be specialty things.
But it can also be kind of
more mundane--double T's,
hollow core, different pieces
like that, that are cast
in steel beds where you repeat
the same pattern or the
same piece over and
over again.
So precast is really
manufactured at the plant
and then brought
to the job site.
So, in some ways, with
architectural precast and
what happened with the
Bahai Temple, precast has
not changed a whole lot.
If you had a client who was
willing to pay that much money,
put that much money into it,
you could still get that kind
of architectural precast and
that same level of detail.
I don't see a whole lot of
clients looking for that,
but that could happen.
The things that have really
changed in our industry since
that was done in the 1920s
and 1930s was really the
quality of the concrete
that's being used.
There's add mixtures
now that allow a much
higher strength
concrete to be used.
There's self-compacting
concrete, which allows the
concrete to flow and get into
a lot of nooks and crannies
a little bit better, and
just the whole idea of
repetition in the industry.
That's one of the first examples
of architectural precast.
And now, you know, 50, 75 years
later it's become an industry
and, you know, it's just a
much more common product
than it was then.
I don't know why it doesn't
like my pictures.
The second project that I like
to talk about is the Chunnel.
In a lot of ways this is
just as interesting.
It might not be as beautiful to
look at as the Bahai Temple,
but just the scope of the
project and the magnitude
of what they were able
to do with the precast
is really remarkable.
The entire tunnel, or Chunnel,
underneath the English Channel
is lined in precast.
And they actually had to use
two different designs for the
precast on the two different
sides of the Chunnel
because of the soil conditions.
And so they really had to look
at the soil conditions and
design the precast around it.
So all of the liner components,
they've augured all of the dirt
out of it and then placed the
liners in there and created the
Chunnel underneath the Channel.
So the Sunshine Skyway Bridge
is kind of interesting because
it's a five-mile-long bridge,
and it was really an
engineering feat that kind of
combines the two things that
we were looking at earlier.
It's the engineering of the
Chunnel and the magnitude of
that project, but it's got some
of the same beauty, I think,
that the Bahai Temple has.
It really was able to kind of
take the product and use it
in a very organic way to make
it beautiful and functional
at the same time.
So that was done in the 1980s,
and at that time it was the
longest bridge and the
first of its type.
The Jubilee Church is in Rome.
Richard Meier was the
architect, he is actually
a New York architect.
This is a Catholic church in
Rome, and Richard Meier loves
very bright white,
clean spaces.
And the Jubilee Church really
reflects his love of that kind
of starkness and the whiteness.
The interesting thing about it,
I think, is really where you are
able to take the precast and
use it as a curved product, a
molded product, a
very flowable look.
Unfortunately, you can't see
the picture of the inside of
the church, but the inside
of the church is also
very bright and white.
Some of the things that make
this one of my seven wonders
include that look of the church
that looks kind of like a sail
and that it has that ability
to come in different shapes,
but they've still managed to
use some repetition here.
You'll see that they've repeated
the same shapes in the
three sails or three surfaces.
And the other thing that's
really interesting about
this project is the bright
whiteness of the concrete.
They actually used an add
mixture that's available
from an Italian company that
is a self-cleaning concrete.
So now they won't have to go
back and clean this material
over and over again, it'll stay
bright and white like this.
The other thing that that
add mixture does is allow
the concrete to absorb CO2.
So it actually cleans
the air around it.
We've only seen it used in
one project so far in the US.
I think it's still kind
of expensive, but I think
it's one of the ways
that we'll see concrete
changing in the future.
It's not something that's
just used for precast,
you can use it really for
any kind of concrete.
But, you know, I think that's
just a really beautiful example
of new technology.
>> Dr. Wafeek Wahby:
I have a question.
In the back, please,
back one slide.
Any idea if these three bending
parts are hollow or kind of a
shell of some sort?
>> Ms. McIntyre:
I believe, no, they are not.
They are about, I think they
are about 8 inches thick.
>> Dr. Wahby:
Okay, just one solid thing?
>> Ms. McIntyre:
They are solid panels.
I believe they are structural
as well as being radius.
>> Dr. Wahby:
Okay, thanks.
>> Ms McIntyre:
I'm going to go back so we can
look at the
Sidney Opera House.
I always think that it's kind
of interesting to look at this,
which is a very modern example
of precast concrete.
And really, you can look back
at the Sidney Opera House
up on the top, all of the
white components that
look like sails, those are
all precast concrete,
it's on a steel frame.
Jørn Utzon was the name of the
architect on that project,
and he designed this, it
was a design competition.
He kind of snuck the design in
at the last minute and they had
picked something else, but
then when they saw this
they said, "No, we have to
have this opera house".
And that's really great, but the
technology was not there at the
time to build it, so then there
were all sorts of delays.
And what he finally figured out
was he was going to be able to
make it affordable and make it
happen by keeping that radius
exactly the same for all of
those different panels and to
create a lot of repetition even
without having one piece be
exactly the same as the others.
So he kind of played on
the radius to create
those different sails.
It was one of the first
projects to really use
building information
modeling and computers,
computer aided design.
And it was very controversial
because it kept having delay
after delay after delay, and
finally the architect got
kicked off the project and he
never saw the finished project.
It's such an interesting story,
you could make a movie out of
the creation of the
Sidney Opera House.
But again, this is one of the
Seven Wonders because it really
kind of did something completely
new with precast concrete.
The TransAmerica Tower is in San
Francisco, and it's the tallest
architecturally precast-clad
building in the US.
And some of the things that
make it really interesting
include that they had to be able
to, you know, put it up with
architectural precast and clad
the exterior in some place that,
you know, is going to have
to have high seismic,
in a high-seismic zone.
So that was kind of
interesting as well.
They wanted something that, you
know, they could keep clean and
neat and did it with
precast concrete.
Another early example of
architectural precast.
COSI is a little bit
closer to home.
It's in Columbus, and
it's the Columbus Museum
of Science and Industry.
Arata Isozaki is a Japanese
architect, he was the one
who designed it.
And again, very organic in the
way that he used concrete as a
very flowable material and
actually used that ability
to curve and shape it.
Each one of these pieces, you
can kind of see the people are
right here, so each one of
these pieces is 60 feet tall
and about 10 feet wide.
It was cast all in one piece in
specialty forms and then the
precaster who did it had to
create specialty trucks to cart
it to the job site.
They had to create specialty
forms for it and had to be
very careful with all of the
handling and erection of this
piece because, you know, you
can't pick up a piece of
precast in the middle because
it's actually more fragile than
you think it would be, it
can just break into two.
So they had to be very
careful about handling
and erecting this project.
And there's some, just some
examples of what it looked like
when they were handling it.
So that's kind of my fun part,
and I apologize that the
pictures didn't translate.
Anybody got any questions about
anything you've seen so far?
No?
Alright, well, let's get
down to the nitty gritty.
When I talk about precast
products, sometimes I like to
think about music as well.
So here I've got my George
Handel, who's one of my
favorites, and Metallica,
who I also like.
And I love thinking about
precast the same way I think
about music because you
are taking these two very
diverse types of music.
You probably, in a lot of ways,
wouldn't think of those two
groups, or a composer and that
group in the same light, but
when you think about it, they're
using all of the same notes.
They are creating the music
using the same scale, the same
12 notes, the same keys on a
piano, and that's the same thing
that's happening with
precast concrete.
So I always like to think
about it that way.
♪ [music playing--
no dialogue] ♪♪.
Really, what that shows is all
of the different pieces of
precast flying in and
coming together.
It's all cool stuff.
I wanted to kind of take you
through the notes on the scale
or the keys on the piano
in terms of what happens
in the precast industry.
And that would be what common,
what the products are
that are commonly used.
So probably the most common
product that you're going
to see is hollowcore.
Hollowcore comes in widths of
2 feet, 4 feet, and 8 feet,
but it's typically going to
be 4 feet long, and it can be
anywhere from 6 inches deep
to 16 inches deep.
But usually you're going to see
a piece of hollowcore that is
4 feet wide and 10 to 12 inches
deep, and then it's got these
cores that are cast
in the middle of it.
So who can tell me why they
think the cores are cast
in the middle of it?
Yeah?
>> male speaker:
[unclear audio].
>> Ms. McIntyre:
Absolutely, yeah.
That's it exactly.
Because you get the strength of
the concrete and you can combine
that with the strength of
steel that you are doing the
prestressing with and you don't
need all that extra weight.
Weight is going to be one of the
downfalls for precast concrete.
Yeah?
>> male speaker:
[unclear audio].
>> Ms. McIntyre:
Oh, yes.
He said to decrease the
weight of the pieces,
which was exactly right.
>> male speaker:
[unclear audio].
>> Ms. McIntyre:
It is also the saving of
materials, but for the most
part it's the weight, because
weight is going to be your
one thing that you want to
watch out for with, or
one of the things that
you're going to want to watch
out for with precast concrete.
You can manufacture it in a
couple of different ways.
One is a wet cast method,
where you have a pretty
typical wet mix of concrete.
You put hoses in the forms that
kind of look like fire hoses.
You place the concrete
on top of it.
As the concrete cures, you
pull those hoses out of it
and you end up
with those cores.
The other way is you can use an
extruded method, and with that
the concrete is very dry and it
actually comes out of a machine.
I always liken it to a tube of
toothpaste, where you're kind of
pushing the concrete out.
The concrete might be about
the same consistency
of toothpaste as well.
And you might have augurs
working in there, and
that's going to create
the openings in it.
And with that dry mix you can
almost walk on it immediately.
So that's the couple of
different areas that you
can manufacture it in.
Hollowcore, usually, is going
to be about 30 feet long.
And we see a lot of it
used for hotels, motels,
single-family condominiums,
schools, any place where you
want to get a nice long span
and any place that fire safety
is going to be an issue.
It can be a really good product
in any of those cases.
Double tees.
They're called double tees
because that's what they
look like, two T's right
next to each other.
Double tees have two parts
of the product.
The first part is your top
surface that goes across the
top of the tees, and that's
going to be called your flange.
Your flange is usually going
to be about 12 feet wide.
Sometimes we have 15 feet
wide, but usually it's going
to be about 12 feet wide.
And then you'll have the
two stems coming down,
the two stems of the tee, and
those are usually going to be
about 18 inches deep.
And then you're going to
have a piece of precast
that's generally 60 feet
long and 12 feet wide, but
you can go up to about
110 feet long with this.
So, we see this used a lot for
parking decks, that's really
the number one thing that
you see it used in.
You also see it used for, the
other building that I have down
there is a convention center,
where you might have heavier
loads on the floor, swimming
pools, some condominium
buildings will use them where
you need longer spans.
So, this is generally longer
spans and a little bit heavier
duty floor product than you
would get with the hollowcore.
Architectural precast, this
is what you're going to see
when you visit Alsip.
And architectural precast really
starts to be where you have
a lot more color, texture.
Usually it's a cladding product
on the exterior of the building.
You can have color integrated
right into it.
You're going to start to
have your curved pieces.
have more decorative
detail added to it.
And these are usually
cast in wooden forms
rather than in steel forms.
So you will have some repetition
with them, but usually you're
going to have formwork
that's built specifically
for that particular building.
Then you can also
have wall panels.
Wall panels can still have a
little bit of decorative pieces
to them, but in most
cases rather than having
the color integrated right
into it you're going to
stain over the concrete,
so both the yellow and
the blue are stained
right into there.
Sometimes we see people just
leave the concrete exposed
like you see here.
But these are usually cast
in what our industry calls
long line beds.
And so those beds can be
150 feet long, and they
cast multiple pieces all at
the same time, so usually
not as much decorative
detail added to those.
Then you can also have
structural products.
Those would be columns, beams,
inverted T-beams, any kind of
structural wall panel, things
like that, and that can be
the entire structure and
frame of a building.
Typically when you're using
precast as the structural
system, we see it usually
used anywhere from 2 stories
to about 11 or 12 stories,
would be typical.
There is a project in California
that goes 22 stories, that's
about as high as it's gone
but, you know, we see a lot of
8- to 12-story structures
done in structural precast.
We also have modular
construction,
in this case it's a prison.
That's probably the most
popular use for it where
we've got the prison cells.
And one of the reasons that this
is so popular for the prisons is
it can all be done off-site.
So they add the furniture,
the communications equipment,
the safety equipment, all
at the precaster's site.
They bring it out to the job
site, they stack them, one right
on top of the other, and in this
case they've got the two prison
cells and then they've got a
lip coming out for a walkway.
We don't see a whole lot of
prisons being built in Illinois
right now considering we
have one sitting empty,
but for awhile that
was being done.
The interesting thing about
these is the whole idea of
modularity is really being
carried into a lot of different
products as well, the wall
panels and floor systems.
I'm starting to see more
things being added
at the precast plant.
So the electrical conduit and
boxes are being cast right in,
holes for the plumbing
being cast right in.
So a lot of that is happening
at the manufacturer's site
rather than happening
at the job site.
And that's something that a lot
of insurance companies like
because they feel it's a more
controlled environment.
And then we also do a lot of
transportation products.
In Illinois, the three biggest
transportation products,
well, four really.
Bulb tees, like you see
going across.
Box beams--those are usually
for shorter bridges, they're
hollow boxes, usually they have
like a styrofoam piece in the
middle with four sides
of concrete around it.
The bulb tees are shaped
kind of like this with
a bulb on the bottom.
Sound wall--up in the
Chicago area, there's quite
a bit of sound wall.
And then also
retaining wall systems.
So those are the biggest
transportation products
that we see.
Yes?
>> male speaker:
[unclear audio].
>> Ms. McIntyre:
He was asking what
sound wall is.
Sound wall is a wall
system that you would see
on the side of a highway.
So usually it's some kind of
decorative concrete piece
about 8 inches thick.
You see it in more densely
populated urban areas where
they don't want the sound of
the highway going to the homes
on either side, or the
businesses on either side.
So we see a lot of that up
north, not so much down here.
So that's kind of the typical
products that you see
with precast concrete.
Does anybody have any
questions about any of
the products that you've seen?
>> male speaker:
I've got a quick question.
>> Ms. McInyre:
Oh, yeah.
>> male speaker:
On several of the buildings,
like when they were
talking about buildings,
I'm assuming that some of
that is hollowcore with
some kind of insulation
[unclear audio] unit?
>> Ms. McIntyre:
For the walls or for the floors?
>> male speaker:
Yes, for the exterior,
primarily for the
exterior walls.
>> Ms. McIntyre:
Yeah, some of them, not so they
don't use, in this part of the
country we don't see a whole lot
of hollowcore being used
for the wall systems.
In Wisconsin, we do
see that sometimes.
So it's really a matter of
what's available locally.
But yeah, you can put insulation
right into the wall panels.
It depends on what you're using
it for that starts to make it
a little bit more expensive.
So a lot of times you'll put up
the concrete system and then
put the insulaion and then
put the dry wall over it if
you're going to dry wall it.
But if you're not going to
dry wall over it, you can
put the insulation right
in the middle of it.
Anything else?
Well, I thought I would just
show you some projects just so
you can see what typical
projects look like with precast.
We do a lot of athletic
facilities--the risers, beams,
raker beams, the
exterior systems.
We see a lot of this thin brick
being added right to the
precast wall panels so you get
a lot of decorative finishes
that way, but we see
a lot of those.
And a lot of schools are using
precast these days, whether
they be just the gymnasium
with the steel form or the
steel structure on the interior
with precast wall panels
around it or decorative pieces.
Centralia High School just did
a really nice high school
out of precast.
A lot of healh care facilities.
In the healthcare market we see
more of the exterior skin on the
cladding products being used.
Some designers feel like
there's vibration issues that
they want to stay away from
with the structural system.
Although I have seen it used
successfully, structural systems
used successfully in
healthcare as well.
Industrial faciliies.
Industrial facilities, a lot of
warehouses, food facilities,
things like that, we see
a lot of those used.
I don't even remember what
that picture looked like.
Municipal buildings.
We see a lot of every, well
lately, half of my members seem
to be working on water systems,
water reclamation projects.
That seems to be one of
the few building types
that's still going
up these days.
But a lot of municipal
buildings, anywhere where
the tenant is going to be
there for a long time and
starts to really look at the
long-term cost-effectiveness
of using insulated wall
panels, for instance.
>> Dr. Wahby:
I have a question.
>> Ms. McIntyre:
Yes?
>> Dr. Wahby:
The previous screen, the
building to the right,
these walls are structural
or pure architectural?
>> Ms. McIntyre:
Right here?
>> Dr. Wahby:
Yes, and the shell.
>> Ms. McIntyre:
Yes, those are actually
structural wall panels.
It's what our industry likes to
call a total precast building,
which means that it's got
precast columns and beams.
You can see the double tee
floors, and then the exterior
wall panels are also structural,
so they have eliminated all the
perimeter structural framing.
Office buildings.
This is the FBI building
in Chicago.
One of the interesting things
that we've been doing a lot of
research on recently is
blast-resistant design.
We've been working with the US
Airforce on blast-resistant,
and that seems to be a
hot topic with a lot of
government buildings ever
since Oklahoma City.
That seems to be
a key element.
One of the other interesting
things, this is a building
actually in Milwaukee, where
they took all the cladding off
and they wanted to save the
office building so they re-clad
it in architectural precast,
and that's another trend that
I've seen quite a bit of.
And then a lot of residential,
multi-family housing.
Not a lot of people are building
that this year, but in
past years we've seen precast
used for that quite a bit.
And then transportation
products.
This is kind of interesting.
This bridge here is going over
the Dust Plains River on the
new leg of I-355, and the
beams going across there
were 176 feet long.
So one of the great things about
that is it really shows you
how long you can get
with precast concrete.
They really were trying to be
very careful about putting
anything into the river and
disturbing the habitat of a
dragonfly that was there,
so they had to have these
long beams and not
disturb the habitat.
And they went to a lot of
expense and trouble to
create this bridge, and then
it turns out that where the
bridge casts a shadow the
dragonflies won't fly there
anyway, so it ended
up being for naught.
But it did prove that
you can go 176 feet
with precast bridge beams.
And then probably one of the
most common types of projects
that you're going to see
with precast products are
going to be parking decks.
You know, that 60-foot-long
double tee that'll give you,
you know, a couple of bays
of parking and you can do
decorative finishes on the
exterior, you can do simple
finishes on the exterior.
I just did a seminar
yesterday on the history
of the parking deck.
And it's kind of interesting
to see, it's kind of turning,
they used to look a lot like
buildings, and then for awhile
they were very kind of simple
gray boxes and now it's kind of
turning back and now they're all
looking like buildings again,
so that's kind of interesting.
So that's really typically where
we see the products being used.
You guys have any questions
about the projects?
Okay, well, I thought
I would finish up by
showing you a plant tour.
>> narrator:
This video will explain the
entire process of producing
a prestressed concrete unit
at a prestressing plant.
In this case, a double tee.
A double tee is used primarily
in parking structures but can
be used in virtually any type
of building, including office
buildings, industrial buildings,
and schools, to name a few.
Double tees are kind of a unique
product, having a capability
of having a very long span.
And when we start talking
long spans, you're talking
60 feet plus, and sometimes
goes as high as 120 feet.
>> narrator:
The typical day of a
prestressing plant usually
starts very early
in the morning.
The product from the previous
day's casting has cured by now
and the pieces need to be
stripped from the form to
get ready for today's casting.
For any prestressing plant,
it is very important to
maintain a clean plant.
Maintaining neatness is not
only positive from an image
standpoint but also from a
safety standpoint, since any
debris that might be left over
from the day before could create
a tripping hazard or
other safety problem.
The first part of the process
is setting up of the form.
A thorough cleaning of the
entire form is done with basic
labor and appropriate
cleaning equipment.
Setting the side forms, or
in the case of a typical
double tee, the forms may
be fixed forms with an
appropriate draft to allow
for easy stripping.
Once the bed is clean,
it's ready for
setting up today's cast.
This particular bed is set
up for five double tees,
each about 60 feet long.
The bed has a total
length of 400 feet.
This is a self-stressing form,
where the form itself is
designed to take the total
prestressed force and
compression, and also to handle
the eccentricity of the strands.
Sometimes the producer may use
a form that is set between
bulkheads that are built
right into the ground.
The prestressing force is then
resisted entirely by the
bulkheads and their foundations.
Next, the strands are
placed in the form and
extended from end to end.
Crew members thread the strands
through each of the dividers
and then run them through the
stressing plates at each end.
The typical spacing
of the strands is
approximately 2 inches.
This divider is a steel device
that separates the individual
double tee units from
one another.
A gap of about a foot is
typical between the ends
of the adjacent pieces.
This gap is required so the
strands can be accessed and cut
and that each double tee can
be stripped from the forms.
The next step is the
tensioning of the strands.
In this case, we have a strand
pattern with straight strands
of six strands in each
stem, as shown here.
The strands are first tensioned
to about two to five kips,
based on the gauge
pressure reading.
In this case, a mark is
made on the strand after
the preload is applied.
The strand is then tensioned
to the specified level and
is measured using the gauge
pressure on the hydraulic pump.
The QC technician then checks
the elongation against
the theoretical elongation.
The requirement that is the
force on the gauge and the
elongation must match
within 5 percent.
If that tolerance is not
achieved, the reason must
be established and the
strand may have to be
de-tensioned and re-tensioned.
After the strands of this
double tee are all stressed,
the remaining embeds
are set in place.
These include stem reinforcing,
lifting devices that will be
used to strip and handle the
piece, forms for block outs
in the flange and forms for
blockouts in the stems,
flange reinforcing, and flange
connectors, or vectors,
along the edges.
In this case, one of the double
tees in the bed has typical
flange connectors applied along
one edge and special flat plate
connectors applied along the
other edge to accommodate
connections across an
expansion joint.
The form is now ready to have
concrete poured, but only after
a pre-pour quality control
check has been made and the
QC person signs off on it.
This QC check can also be done
by the bed superintendant and
depends on the particular
plant's practices.
Either way, the check
is critical to ensure an
end product with the
highest quality.
There's all these things you
look for, the mesh, you look for
anything that could be touching
the stems on the bottom,
wire ties that might have fell
in there, because that would
develop some type
of a rough spot.
You check the length.
You want to make sure that
the damps are correct.
Do we have the strand
stripped properly?
So, there are a lot of critical
areas that you need to verify.
>> narrator:
Concrete is mixed at the
batch plant under tightly
controlled conditions.
The cement is supplied
using tanker trucks.
Here the cement is being blown
from the tanker through piping
to the cement silos.
When needed, aggregates
are delivered to bins
in the batch plant.
The aggregates are stored
outside of the batch plant
in separate bins.
In this case, an enclosed
vertical bin system is utilized.
During winter in northern
climates, the aggregates must
be heated to get them to flow
properly through the batching
system and to maintain proper
concrete mix temperatures.
Payloaders are used to
shuffle the materials
to the conveyor belt.
Computers are used to
proportion the materials
for the desired concrete mix.
Cement, sand, stone, water, and
add-mixtures are measured
according to signals
from the computer.
After the concrete is
mixed, it is discharged
into a delivery device.
It's imperative that the
concrete mix be delivered
to the form as
soon as possible.
These vehicles are called
tuckers, and they are used
to deliver the concrete
to the bed in the yard.
A soft, consolidating
concrete is being used
to cast these particular
double tees.
With this type of concrete,
vibration is not required
to consolidate the concrete.
However, minor controlled
vibration is used in the
double tee stems to help
remove air from the sides of
the form, reducing bug
holes in the stems.
There are many advantages in
using this type of concrete.
We do use self-consolidating
concrete for our double tees.
We feel that it gives
us a better finish.
We feel that it's easier to
place, takes less labor,
less strain on the laborer
to place that concrete.
>> narrator:
The QC Department will make the
necessary tests at this time,
including a temperature check
of the concrete.
Since SCC is being used here,
a spread test is done to check
the concrete flow in
lieu of a slump test.
The spread is measured
to assure conformance
to the planned spread.
The edges of the circle of
concrete are also inspected
to check for segregation.
The appearance is translated to
a visual stability index number.
There is a check
for air content.
Cylinders are filled and
will be used later for
strength tests of
the cured concrete.
Back at the bed, the concrete
placement continues.
A vibrating screed is used
to level the surface evenly.
A bullfloat is used to
finish the surface.
An evaporation-reducing
spray is also being applied
to the surface to
minimize the potential
for plastic shrinkage cracking.
The final finish will vary
depending on the use
of the double tee.
If a cast-in-place topping is
necessary, the surface will be
made very rough so that a
good bond will be achieved.
If it is a roof, the finish
will be relatively smooth,
but not necessarily perfect.
In this case the surface is
broomed, as these double tees
are being used in a
parking structure.
Different patterns can be
applied depending on the
needs of the project.
The bed is now in
its curing stage.
Sometimes, particularly in
cold climates, the double tee
may be covered with tarps.
In other areas,
they may be open.
Accelerated curing is often done
using live steam or radiant heat
from heaters attached
to the form itself.
Double tees for parking
garages really need to be
held to a high standard.
When they're assembled
in a garage, they make
the finished surface.
There are tolerances for
putting these pieces together,
offsets in the surfaces.
All of the connections are
very sensitive as well.
To be executed properly, the
embedments in the double tee
have to be placed properly.
So there are, again, a lot
of critical issues that you
have to be concerned with
to get proper performance
out of that simple double tee.
After 12 to 16 hours of
curing, the tees are
ready to be stripped.
The QC Department first tests
the concrete to be sure it has
achieved the strength required
to de-tension the strands,
typically 3500 psi.
This is a typical test
being conducted.
The strands are de-tensioned in
a specific sequence established
by the QC Department or
the plant engineer.
Here, personnel are positioned
at each end of the bed and at
some of the intermediate
bulkhead locations.
On a signal, they burn
the strand at each end.
After all the strands are cut
and block-out formwork has been
removed, the tees are
stripped from the form.
Cables are attached to the
lifting devices and each piece
is removed and transported
to a detailing area for any
minor cosmetic touch-ups.
Also at this time, the QC
Department does a post-pour
QC check on each piece that is
brought to the detailing area.
When I first get back there,
I go and check the length
of the piece and verify that
within, oh there's a tolerance
of a quarter inch or so.
Check the width, we check
the vectors, we check the
electrical block-outs.
I do a visual for any type of
discoloration in the stems
underneath the piece, any type
of surface cracks, bug holes,
just do a complete visual.
>> narrator:
Any defects are noted so that
repairs can be done
before shipping the tee.
After all the work is completed,
the double tees are moved into
the storage area where they are
typically stacked using
appropriate dunage,
located near the ends.
When the job site requires
the tee to be shipped, it is
loaded on a trailer and
transported to the job site.
What you have just observed
is the process for making
one type of
prestressed product.
These other types are made using
essentially the same process.
Hollow-core plank, which are
used for floor and roof
components in multi-family
housing, schools, hotels,
and many other buildings.
Inverted tee beams, which
can be used in any total
precast concrete build system.
Columns, which are cast
horizontally and then rotated
in the air at the job site.
They are often designed as
prestressed components.
Architectural spandrels, used in
office buildings and parking
structures, can be made using
the prestressing process.
Deck slabs and box beams,
which are used primarily in
short-span bridge
construction.
Standard AASHTO girders,
which are used in
long-span bridge
construction.
Standard bulb tees
are also used in
long-span bridge
construction.
Prestressed piles that support
any type of building in areas
that have unfavorable
soil conditions.
As you can see, there
are many types of
prestressed products
available.
The variety of products that
can be prestressed in a
long line operation is almost
unlimited and is up to the
imagination of the
design professional.
We really do encourage our
customers and architects and
engineers to get to our
plants to really understand
how precast concrete is made.
They need an understanding of
the high quality that they can
get out of precast concrete, as
opposed to the random quality
that you might get out of
cast-in-place concrete.
Well, it's important that we do
things as efficiently as we can
and as cost-effectively as we
can, but also as well as we can.
And it's not only my
responsibility, but the
responsibility of everybody
here--management, labor,
everybody included--to do the
best job that they can to,
at the end of the day, make a
little bit of money, but also
have a customer that is very
happy and will possibly want
to have some return work
coming back our way.
[no dialogue].
>> Ms. McIntyre:
You'll see a very different
plant when you go to see
Lombard Architectual, but
that gives you an idea of the
process that you go through.
One of the things that you saw
there was the prestressing
operation, and I just
thought I'd show you some
samples of prestressing steel.
So, you know, like they
mentioned, they'll pull this
at three or four kips with
40,000, 50,000 psi, and it
does have that ability
to stretch and give.
They place the concrete
in, the concrete then
adheres to that strand.
After it cures they'll cut
either end, and then you'll
have an arch or a camber in the
beam or wall that you have, and
that's going to help counteract
any loads that are placed on it.
>> Dr. Wahby:
[unclear audio].
>> Ms. McIntyre:
Oh, okay, you've got a--
>> Dr. Wahby:
[unclear audio].
>> Ms. McIntyre:
Okay, here's a typical rebar so
you can see the difference,
you know, that doesn't have
that same ability.
>> Dr. Wahby:
[unlcear audio].
>> Ms. McIntyre:
Yeah.
[no dialogue].
>> male speaker:
Yeah, I was just curious what
you do with the piece of
concrete deemed unusable,
like after it's already made?
>> Ms. McIntyre:
Well, most of the time they
try not to have it
be unusable.
Every once in awhile a bridge
beam or something like that
will be rejected by the DOT,
and usually then it's just
crushed and used as road base
or something like that.
But by that point, they've got
$30,000 or $40,000, you know,
for some of those bridge beams
especially, invested in it.
So, they really try to
do everything right or
fix it in some manner.
>> male speaker:
I was just looking at your
prestressed wires, it's
seven cords in it,
does that ever change?
>> Ms. McIntyre:
No, the size might change.
You might go anywhere from 3/8
of an inch to 3/4 of an inch,
but you always have the
seven wires still in it.
>> male speaker:
Okay, all right.
>> Ms. McIntyre:
And I have no idea
why it's seven.
>> male speaker:
That's, I just, okay, I didn't
know if it was, they
don't add more wire,
they just change
the size?
>> Ms. McIntyre:
They just make it bigger, yeah.
>> Dr. Wahby:
Typically you have the
middle one and then the
others braid around it.
>> Ms. McIntyre:
The six wrap around it, yeah.
>> Dr. Wahby:
But tell us something about
the material, it's different
material than the rebars.
The feel itself is different,
it has higher inside strength
and higher [unclear audio].
So it's really different
material, kind of steel,
different type of steel.
You cannot take the rebar
and stretch it like this.
>> Ms. McIntyre:
Yeah.
Any other questions?
>> Dr. Wahby:
I have a question for you
regarding the magic formula for
holding one piece, big or small.
There's a formula for per piece
thing, if you use your trucks.
>> Ms. McIntyre:
Oh, how much you can
put on a truck?
>> Dr. Wahby:
No, I mean if you have a
small piece or large piece.
>> Ms. McIntyre:
Oh, yeah.
I talk about that a lot with
designers because every time
you pick up, to get precast on
a building, you have to have
one key thing and
that's a crane.
And you have to have a crane
that's going to be able to lift
the lagest piece of precast
that you have on that job.
So that's kind of going to be
the crane that you're going to
go with for the whole project.
So then every time you pick up a
piece off a truck and put it on
a building, you're going to pay
what we call the "pick price".
And the pick price is going to
be for the use of that crane.
So the crane doesn't really
care what size it is,
you're still going
to have to pay.
If you're in downtown Chicago,
it might be $1500 every time
you pick up a piece and
put it on a building.
So if you have a one-by-ten
column cover, you've now added
$150 per square foot to
put it on the building.
So, in general, larger pieces
are going to be less expensive.
You don't want to have a
building full of small pieces
of precast because you're going
to have to pay that pick price.
And it would also take longer
to erect the building as well.
>> Dr. Wahby:
So these two advices you give,
the repetition of the piece.
>> Ms. McIntyre:
Right.
>> Dr. Wahby:
You make many of it.
>> Ms. McIntyre:
Right.
>> Dr. Wahby:
And as large as possible.
>> Ms. McIntyre:
Right.
In general, larger is going
to be less expensive, and
then the repetition is
going to be important.
You saw how everything's
cast in a long line bed.
You want all of your strands
lined up the same way so
piece after piece the strand
pattern will be the same,
because every piece has to
be engineered for that
specific project
that you're doing.
Even though you're using
the same, you know, notes
on the keyboard, you still
have to engineer it or
compose it in a different way.
So absolutely, you want to
create as much repetition
and use the same pieces
over and over again.
And then, those are going to
be the two biggest factors
in the cost of the precast.
One is the size of the pieces.
The other is the amount of
repetition that you have.
>> Dr. Wahby:
Any other questions?
I have a question regarding
some tips or tricks of trade
that they would do for an
extremely long piece, the
longest piece they can have,
how do they transport it?
Or, if it is tall, how
do they manipulate it?
>> Ms. McIntyre:
Well, with the longer pieces,
like with that, I was
talking about that bridge
where it was 176 feet.
You really start using the
piece of precast as kind of
the bed of the truck.
Then you don't actually have a
truck bed, you'll have wheels
on the front and then another
column of wheels on the back
and then usually, the driver
will have a steering component
to actually steer the back
wheels from the truck or
the cab of the truck.
So, you know, then you'll get
it to the ground that way.
And then, also, as I mentioned,
when you're erecting precast
you always want to handle
it from the two ends.
You never really want to
handle it from the middle
because it can snap.
So, the precaster will do all of
the engineering for the pieces
of precast because when you
handle it, that's going to be
when the most pressure is
actually going to be applied
to a piece of precast, not when
it's in place in the building.
It's all of the handling
that goes into it.
So the precaster likes to do
all of the engineering of
his own pieces and all of
the connection details.
>> Dr. Wahby:
Thanks.
Now, you gave us your
definition for precast.
What is the definition
for prestressed?
Pre- to what?
>> Ms. McIntyre:
The prestressed is what uses
those prestressing steel
and you've got that steel
within the piece.
So precast is any kind,
prestressed concrete is
also precast concrete,
but precast concrete is
not necessarily prestressed.
Usually, prestressed concrete
are pieces that are longer,
that require more load
placed on them, or maybe
they'are structural pieces.
But the prestressing is what
allows you to actually use
less of the concrete material
without losing any strength
or by gaining strength.
>> Dr. Wahby:
And the "pre" term time-wise
reflects to the pouring of
concrete, so you are actually
stressing the steel of
the strands before.
>> Ms. McIntyre:
Before you place the concrete
in the form.
>> Dr Wahby:
So hence, the term "pre-"
for stressing.
>> Ms. McIntyre:
Well, you could also do
post-tensioning which is,
sometimes you see precast
done with that.
You don't see a whole lot
of it done in this area,
and they would create a
sleeve, the precaster would
create a sleeve within
the precast product.
Then it would go out to the
job site and be stressed
at the job site and then
grouted into place there.
You could get your
tension that way without
stressing it at the plant.
So really, it's a function of
stressing it at the plant versus
stressing it at the job site.
>> Dr. Wahby:
What would make an owner
or engineer or architect choose
prestressed or precast over
other post-tension
or other types?
>> Ms. McIntyre:
Well, one of it is what's
commonly used in your area,
but we usually can provide
something much faster than
other types of products if
you were casting
something in place.
Sometimes it's fire
prevention, fire ratings
are going to be important.
The city of Chicago loves
concrete because they're
real funny about fire.
So, you know, sometimes it's
the needs of the project.
Sometimes it's how fast is it
going to go up, sometimes it's
what does it look like.
But usually it's faster,
cheaper, better, you know,
the quality of the concrete
is going to be a little bit
better, too, because they're
using very low water-cement
ratio because they want to
turn those beds over and
start casting the beds
again the next day.
So, you know, that's going to
be, that's going to be key.
>> Dr. Wahby:
Talk about money and jobs.
>> Ms. McIntyre:
Okay.
>> Dr. Wahby:
In a normal economic situation,
not now, normal situation.
What is average salary,
what are the jobs,
what would our graduates do?
Would be working in concreting,
or managers, or what?
>> Ms. McIntyre:
Yeah, we have, our industry
does a few things where
they see graduates.
Sometimes they're project
managers, where they come in
and they'll supervise the
drawings and kind of,
after the salesman gets the
project in, you would supervise
getting the drawings done,
communicating with the client,
making sure that the product
gets to where it needs to be
when it needs to be there,
making sure that the materials
are ordered for the products
that you're going to make,
when they need to happen.
So that could be a job.
We also work with a lot of
erectors, companies that erect
both steel and pre-cast, and
you could be a certified
pre-cast erector and again,
project manager-type jobs
and, you know, supervising
work like that.
Marketing, I know a lot of
people who've gone into sales
and marketing with a good
construction background and,
you know, then work selling
the pre-cast products.
But usually you work
your way up through a
pre-stressing plant
to a sales job.
Those are usually some of the
better-paying jobs, so I think
a lot of people like to
work their way into those.
And, you know, some of our
plants are union plants and
some are not, so salaries
really vary different places.
But there's also, you saw
the quality assurance guy
doing that, and sometimes they
come up through the ranks or
sometimes they'll bring
people in to do that.
Engineering firms, there's a
lot of drafting that goes on
using, usually, some kind of
computer-aided design system.
So we have drafters that draft
all the different pieces
after the engineers
design them.
>> Dr. Wahby:
Now, if somebody is lucky to
end up working for a plant,
what is the magic number
for average salary?
>> Ms. McIntyre:
You know what, I have no idea.
>> Dr. Wahby:
Okay.
>> Ms. McIntyre:
I don't know.
>> Dr. Wahby:
I'll get you another question,
easy one.
What is relationship between the
PCI that you mentioned earlier
and whatever you said now.
PCI, what is PCI?
>> Ms. McIntyre:
PCI is the Pre-cast
Pre-stressed Concrete
Institute, and I work for
the Illinois-Wisconsin region.
So, is that what you
were asking?
>> Dr. Wahby:
They inspect the plants?
>> Ms. McIntyre:
Oh, yes.
They have, I'm sorry, the
plants that are members of PCI
have to be PCI-certified plants,
and that means that twice
a year an inspector comes to
the plant and checks all
of the quality
assurance manuals.
He makes sure that all of the
equipment's calibrated, how do
you store your materials, how
do you train your workers,
how do you deal with
your customers.
And twice a year he spends two
days at the plant ensuring that
they meet all of those
quality issues.
>> Dr. Wahby:
Unannounced, unannounced.
>> Ms. McIntyre:
Unannounced, yes, yes.
>> Dr. Wahby:
Okay, very good.
I think I'll stop asking here
questions, but I'll ask the
audience the last question, and
whoever answers this question,
I'll give him a chocolate,
how about that?
If you can guess, what is the
major of Marty McIntyre?
You saw how professional she is
in concrete and so forth.
What do you think?
Please, if you know
it from before,
you don't qualify for that.
But guess what was her major
when she was undergrad.
Any guess?
Chocolate?
>> male speaker:
Speech communication.
>> Dr. Wahby:
Speech communication,
she is good with that,
very good.
>> Ms. McIntyre:
No, it wasn't that.
>> Dr. Wahby:
She is talented.
Now, I tell Marty, I tell Marty
that she is a role model
for a successful person.
She will tell you where she
started and where she is now,
and this is a story of success
and it's inspired many students
in the past to change careers,
drastically, and be successful
wherever they are.
So bloom wherever you are.
So what is your major?
>> Ms. McIntyre:
My major was English literature
with an emphasis in
journalism.
>> Dr. Wahby:
Okay, so you speak English.
>> Ms. McIntyre:
And then I got out of school
and I was doing marketing
for architecture firms,
or for an architecture firm.
And I decided I wanted to write
more, so I went and worked for
"Roads and Bridges" magazine.
And then I worked for the
"Concrete Producer" magazine.
Portland Cement Association.
And now I work for PCI.
[no dialogue].