Actually, it's something I
did in my son's fourth
grade class last week.
Imagine 25 kids dropping
Alka-Seltzer into this,
another one of these like
this, and then just
letting them go.
Ready?
Go!
[MUSIC PLAYING]
STEVE SPANGLER: Bam!
There's one.
Yikes!
Come on.
Why can't they all
go at one time?
There's two.
Now that was a cool one.
See, what's stupid about that is
that, if you pop it in that
direction, it just throws
water everywhere.
And this is why kids
like this so much.
So here I was in my son's
fourth grade class.
And I'm showing them Newton's
law, because they're going to
do this whole unit on rockets.
And we're doing, for every
action, there's an equal and
opposite reaction.
And while I'm trying to show
them that, kids are wanting to
find out what these are, because
they don't know what
these little things are.
And I'm calling them film
canisters, because that's what
they're called.
Little did I realize that, if
you're in fourth grade now,
you've probably never
seen your parent use
35 millimeter film.
You have no idea that it's
a film canister.
This week, it's all about
flying film canisters.
I want to show you some cool
things to be able to do with
them, a way to be able to launch
a bunch of them at one
time, and what happens if you
take it to an extreme level.
While this is fun, what
if you could do this
with a trash can?
So here's everything you need,
just some Alka-Seltzer.
You can find the
generic stuff.
It's an effervescent tablet.
You're going to need to have
some film canisters and, of
course, some water.
The cool thing about this is
that you get the reaction
without using vinegar
and baking soda.
So your traditional vinegar and
baking soda would work in
here just fine, but this means
that the Alka-Seltzer tablet
reacts with water.
Inside the Alka-Seltzer tablet
is sodium bicarbonate, which
is baking soda.
But they also put some
powdered citric acid.
And those two combined
dry are just fine.
But they have to be careful of
these as they're packaging
them, making sure there's no
moisture that gets in.
You can always tell Alka-Seltzer
that has been
tampered with and the moisture
has gotten inside, because the
package will pop up.
And many times, they'll explode
like those little--
you know those packets that you
hit and the little bombs?
And they get bigger
and bigger.
And then they finally explode.
So it's very, very simple.
Of course, the water
goes inside.
What's kind of cool is to just
vary the amount of water
inside, because you want to
know what gives you the
biggest bang.
In this particular case, we
could even divide the tablet
into quarters.
There's still enough pressure
that's inside to
be able to do this.
And now we've got
the reaction.
I could either figure out how
high the top pops off, or
watch this.
I can actually take a tube.
So here's a little
plastic tube.
This can go inside and go
upside down like this.
So when it pops, ultimately,
the cap stays there.
The entire lid comes off.
And we get a nice little pop
that looks this way.
If I do it the other way--
I think we took out a light.
If we do it this way, then, of
course, then it just throws
water everywhere.
So this sits in and it--
See, that's really cool,
because it shoots off.
And so it's more like a little
rocket, which means this idea
is fantastic as well.
Look at this, just different
ways to be able to make it.
Here's the film canister here.
But you'll notice that there's
an actual pill vial here and,
I don't know, some little thing
for the cap and some
fins here on the side.
So now watch.
This will go in perfect.
Now the Alka-Seltzer
goes in like this.
Got it.
The whole thing goes
upside down.
And you're just going to
put the lid on, shake
the whole thing up.
Now you wait for that
bad boy to go.
You can actually see the
bubbling inside.
Newton was right.
For every action, there's an
equal and opposite reaction.
See, if that reaction is cool,
then it means that 10 of them
at once would be fantastic.
50 of them would be amazing.
This just means that we
need more people.
And I think I know where
to go get more people.
All right, so here's the idea.
I just want to launch a bunch
of them at one time.
And I can't put them
down fast enough.
That's why I've just asked a
few friends to stop doing
their work making science
gadgets and to come and help
me with this.
Fair enough?
All right, so everybody
around the table.
Grab the new little canisters.
Everybody grab one.
Dump it out.
Put the safety glasses on.
You need safety glasses.
And we'll fill them
up with water, OK?
We couldn't find enough of these
film canisters, so we
actually had them made.
So these are film canisters,
believe it or not, that are
made just to do what we're
talking about today.
There you go.
Here's some more.
All right, half full, half full,
let's do, I don't know,
15, 20 more?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
STEVE SPANGLER: Dump
those out.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Those are hot.
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah, some are.
Some aren't and some are--
[LAUGHTER]
STEVE SPANGLER: Now you
just halve them.
So you're going to need
half for each one.
All right, on your marks,
get set, drop them in.
Drop, drop, drop, drop, drop.
Drop them all in first.
Cap them.
Oh, somebody's bad.
And ready, set go!
[SCREAMS]
[LAUGHTER]
STEVE SPANGLER: Put
them upside down.
Go faster!
[LAUGHTER]
STEVE SPANGLER: Yeah.
[CHEERS]
STEVE SPANGLER: That's
perfect.
This is just a mess,
all right?
So I was looking for huge
popping all over the place.
This is what happens when
you can't launch them
all at the same time.
I have a friend, however.
His name is Science Bob.
And he claims to be able to do
a bunch of film canisters all
at one time.
And there's a little trick
he has with magnets.
I think you'll like it.
Take a look at this.
SCIENCE BOB: With a little
creativity, I found a way that
we actually just need
one person.
A regular film canister
with the water in it.
And then into that goes
this acrylic spacer.
That will keep the tablet
separated from the water.
The tablet goes on top.
And then the cap goes on.
And then a magnet goes on here,
which will put that on
to the bottom of a board.
And then all we've got to do
is flip the board over.
And our chemicals will mix.
But I don't think my classroom
has quite enough vertical
space for this one.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
SCIENCE BOB: I've snuck
into the auditorium
here to try this out.
Underneath this board are 200
film canisters with the little
spacer in them, the
Alka-Seltzer, and the water.
When I flip this over,
they'll mix.
And we should launch 200 of
these film canisters, more or
less, again, all at once.
Are you ready?
Here we go.
There they are.
I'll flip them over.
I'd better get out
of the way here.
All right.
Well, see?
There's a little one.
There they go.
Oh, now they're going.
That was good.
Oh, that's awesome.
Look at that.
That's crazy.
Oh my gosh.
Look at that.
See?
Just one last one.
All right.
That was awesome.
Where do you guys
keep the brooms?
Brooms?
Are they over here?
STEVE SPANGLER: All right, as
cool as Science Bob's idea is
for launching all those film
canisters at one time, I had a
television producer here
recently that wanted me to
launch the can, but this
is the can that he
wanted me to launch.
This is a trash can.
And I don't care how much
Alka-Seltzer you try to put in
there, what kind of seal you can
get across the top, I just
couldn't get a good launch
on something like this.
So we headed out to
the parking lot.
And the other thing that we
thought that we would use to
launch it, since the
Alka-Seltzer is nothing but
compressed air, actually,
compressed carbon dioxide, we
thought, could we compress air
in such a way that we could
cause this to launch
up into the air.
We knew that most of the air
is made of nitrogen, so why
not launch it with nitrogen?
It's not going to be bad
for the environment.
The only problem is you've got
to change it from a gas to a
liquid and allow it to expand.
This is the part of the program
I have to tell you,
don't try this at home.
We got this video footage,
because we videotape
everything that we do for
television and send it to the
producers and get
their approval.
So what you're about to see
was actually filmed in our
parking lot.
And we just let the
cameras roll.
And well, take a look.
Here's what happened.
OK, ready?
Let's try it out.
OK, here's what's
going to happen.
We're going to take
it over there.
We're going to cap it.
And then we're going
to drop it in.
Ready?
OK.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[BOOM]
[LAUGHTER]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[BOOM]
[LAUGHTER]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[BOOM]
FEMALE SPEAKER: Holy [BLEEP]!
[SIRENS]
[LAUGHTER]
FEMALE VOICE ON POLICE
RADIO: 91 clear.
8014 clear.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
FEMALE VOICE ON POLICE
RADIO: [INAUDIBLE]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[SOUND OF NEEDLE ACROSS
VINYL RECORD]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[BOOM]
[LAUGHTER]
STEVE SPANGLER: Whoa!
I just used up my lives.
[LAUGHTER]
STEVE SPANGLER: Well,
I guess that wasn't
really a very good idea.
Just stick with the
film canisters.
Stay in school.
Learn to read.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
STEVE SPANGLER: That's it.
All right, it's a wrap, guys.
Let's go.
[LAUGHTER]
STEVE SPANGLER: Well, if you
enjoyed this week's episode,
go ahead click the Subscribe
button here.
You'll be the first to know
when a brand new episode
appears each week.
This button right here will
show you some more cool
science experiments that we
do outside of the show.
This button right here will
take you to last week's
episode, just in case
you missed it.
And if you want to see the
subject that you shouldn't
see, that's the bloopers and the
outtakes, well, just click
this one right over here.
And if you want to hear me stop
talking through the magic
of television, just click
this button right here.
Go ahead.
Click it, and I'll stop.
[MUSIC PLAYING]