where, we bring together, in a unit of the national park system,
young people,
and scientists,
and park staff,
for a twenty-four-hour intensive
inventory of the natural resources of
the park.
Biodiversity
is one of the most important words in the English
language.
And Bioblitz is about exploring, understanding, and documenting
the diversity of life,
biodiversity.
And it's for all ages. It's to bring that joy to all ages. From the very youngest to the lifelong
learners.
Many of the kids have
not really experienced what it's like to
be in
nature that's less affected by humans. So sometimes it's
the first experience in getting close to people who care and close to the lovely
parts of nature.
They need the experience of actually gathering the materials
and being a part of
everything and they need to know that
this is where it all starts,
and we need to preserve it.
And the only way they're going to really remember that is to
actually experience it.
By being in the park. It's like, you know like,
watching a ball game on TV, and it's going to a ball game. They're two
completely different experiences.
And you can learn all the plants' names
and what
they look like in books,
and you come out here in the field
and you might be able to get a few of them but you're not going to be very good.
Because there is just so much variation in nature
that you just can't get it in a textbook.
I'd rather be out here
than in my classroom (laughter).
Well sitting in a classroom
and studying science
is important.
But we've seen time and time again that
when you get kids out into the outdoors
something happens.
Some change occurs in their psychology, that suddenly this is fun.
It's not as dry,
they're having discovery,
and...a sense of wonder.
It's amazing seeing the
different ecosystems, the biodiversity,
and seeing the tundra, which I've never been to before.
I've never even been to Colorado before.
Never really been to many forests. So this is just an amazing experience for me!
It's great for people who have no
idea of what is around them
and what is actually happening.
Because, now biodiversity and environment and climate change have been in the
limelight and have been talked about for so long.
Having a scientifically literate society,
has never been more important.
The only way to build an increasingly literate
society,
is by getting
kids turned on to science.
Here at Bioblitz you actually get to interact with the animals
and learn about stuff.
And I think for kids, they actually
become really excited
and enthusiastic about...
science.