and that gives the new generation a chance
for newer responses to the environment. By
responses, I mean reactions. All you get in
the environment is a reaction. If you've been
brought up as a baby, with bears an lions
all tame and you go into the woods you'd be
torn to pieces, if you use that reaction system.
If you're brought up with wolves and lions
and elephants all tamed and you walk into
the jungle you won't live very long, with
that attitude. But no one can know except
the reaction they get. Is that clear? I was
told that a rattle snake has rattles on it's
tail, and they move to warn you. They don't
move to warn you, they move period. A rattle
snake doesn't know to warn you he's going
to bite, that is his reaction to you and it
makes noise. All snakes tails move, did you
know that? When they see people whether the
rattle is there or not. The normal person
projects - the rattles are there to warn you,
or an animal looks hideous or has patterns
that look like eyes to scare you. There is
some animals that have circles on the back
of the head and they say the purpose of that
is so that if something approaches from the
rear, they'll think it is eyes - they don't
think about those things. Knowing the difference
between human project and human reactions.
That is why love would be impossible - the
actions that generate love 200 years ago are
not the same as they are today. So a person
says do you think there is enough love in
the world? I don't know what they're talking
about and I don't think they know. If they
say "do you feel that people are being oriented
to their environment" - I know what they're
talking about. But if they say "do you think
love will prevail?" - I don't think they know
what they're talking about. Love-do they mean
extending maximum courtesy to people regardless
of the person? Well that would be ridiculous.
You can't have a word like love without defining
what you mean by it. If by love you mean greeting
everyone fairly and then doing a survey asking
how you can relate to that person. After that
survey you say I might be able to relate to
them in 3 months if they listen - you don't
know that, so you try. You, what you do is
manipulate variables in languages and the
environment, if it works you take it on, if
it doesn't work you can easily get mad at
the person depending on your reaction, or
you can say the person doesn't have enough
to close that to understand what I'm talking
about. When a child says "I love my mommy"
- if mommy - if the child knows that mommy
feeds her, washes her, prevents her from when
she gets injuries, takes care of her, she
associates love with moms devotion to her
needs. When a guy says to a girl "I love you"
she says "what have you done to prove that?"
She doesn't say that. How do you manifest
that? When a guy says to a girl, "I love you
very much, more than anything in the world,
more than my life itself" the girl might be
flattered, but he said nothing. Now, if a
person says "how can I meet your needs?" Well,
if he is a nazi you say "go out and kill some
jews!" You'd be meeting his needs. But is
meeting another persons needs love? Not necessarily.
Love is not only meeting their needs but giving
them tools to fulfill their needs. Do you
know what that means? Like you - prepare that
drink because you feel it is nourishing, more
nourishing than other systems. Ok, now if
a person drinks that and has a very negative
attitude that will not nourish a person. Now
let me tell you again. If you're born with
a good brain, high quality tissue, all the
neurons in place, everything there, good,
it has no mechanism remember for knowing that
which is relevant. The brain doesn't know
anything until it experiences something, like
a certain bird with checkerboard pattern,
when it lands on you, then it pecks at your
skin and hurts you, then you stay away from
birds with checkerboard pattern, but you can't
inherit that knowledge, like look at the bird
and stay away from it without experience.
You can't walk a tight rope unless you get
on something and try to balance yourself,
over a long period of time. If you use a long
bamboo pole, there is a thing called inertia,
the bamboo pole doesn't flex as fast as you
do, so you can do this and maintain stability
with a long pole, and then you can shorten
the pole and that'll give you more and more
experience in balancing. There is some people
who learn to balance faster than others, that
is the structure of the semicircular canal
of the ear, and physical structure can give
you a propensity toward learning to balance
a little faster than the other guy, I don't
know if you understand that. Propensity means,
if you have 2 normal eyes, 1 has half the
quality of the vision of the other you become
asymmetric, you know what I mean? If they're
symmetric you stand a better chance. If the
brain is clean, meaning has no toxins in it,
your response to the environment will not
be based on the cleanliness of the brain but
the tribe you're brought up with. If they
say Moses is angry or Loeb did this, or that,
that is using the brain well, if it corresponds
to the environment, but you can't study anything
apart from the environment. Can you understand
that? Any problem with that? If you say "use
your head" a person - you're telling them
to use tools they don't have, is what you're
saying "use your head! Think about it!" well
that doesn't tell them anything, unless you
give them tools, they don't know what tools
are, so you have to show them what tools are.
Somebody wanted a bullet once that travels
around a corner, when you fire a gun it'd
go round the corner, so he shaved one end
of the bullet so it was asymmetric instead
of even 1 side was shaved, so the wind turned
the bullet around, if the gun - if it didn't
rotate. Do you understand? If the bullet rotates
that doesn't do that. So an inventive mind
is not an inborn process it's a person with
a hell of a lot of tools, that ask questions
that are relevant. How can I make a bullet
turn? I don't know. If you're boat is asymmetric,
not uniform, oddly shaped, point to 1 side
it'll go round in circles if you make a boat
like that. Do you understand? How big should
a rudder be on an airplane? Nobody knows
- they build an airplane and the rudder is
too small, and it doesn't work too well, so
they make it larger, sometimes they make it
too large. Just finding the right size meaning
the best size for that plane is called research
- "I don't know". A person that doesn't know
anything would be a metaphysician because
they make assumptions. It's alright to make
assumptions as long as you're - "these are
my assumptions" or "I'm speculating". Now
there are scientists that are trying to find
out - "what is the universe?" Is the universe
saying - I was reading that guy - what's his
name?
- [UNKNOWN]
- Kurz? - Kurzweil?
He gets off in the middle of the book, and
he says "does the universe - is the universe
intelligent?" Now what the hell does that
mean? - Is the universe intelligent? - He's
trying to say that the universe may have a
built in program to evolve - he may be saying
that. But if planets explode, and they're
all different distances, and they wobble,
I don't know what he means by "does evolution
have an end goal?" Even if evolution did,
say evolution makes a man more neural associations,
it has nothing to do with real value, because
it only has to do with that organism, do you
know that means? If your brain evolved and
your eyes become more efficient, in relation
to what? So how can you say the universe is
evolving or becoming intelligent, except in
relation to something. If you don't know what
that means, if the universe suddenly said
the sun is too bright we don't need that much
sunlight for the amount of trees on earth,
and the sun dimmed down, cause it doesn't
need all that burst of light. Then you can
say the conservation of energy seems to be
built in, in some areas it does exist and
other areas it does not exist. They say the
earth when it spins, wobbles a little, wobbles
meaning doing that, and some day it'll wobble
more than others, so, is there a purpose to
the wobble? No but there's a cause to the
wobble, not a purpose, always a cause to the
wobble. You know what that means? They say
that planets explode- well, if you live 1
billionth of a second no planet ever explodes,
do you know what that means? The higher you
go on an airplane, waves move, the higher
you go, the smaller they become and more still
it appears, you can't see waves 6 miles up,
all you can see is patterns in the ocean that
look frozen, the closer you get, the more
fluid. So, what is the true nature of things?
That's not the question. "What is your response
to nature?" Is the question. Do you know what
that means? What is your range of response
to nature? You can't see a bacteria wagging
it's little tail, so all your books on life
have to do with your receptors, not what's
around you. If you wrote you wrote a book
on the absolute truth, it'd be a ridiculous
book because absolute truth freezes things
- "this is the truth - waves don't move they're
stationary" - well from high altitude - yes.
If you lived 1 billionth of a second lighting
would be fixed, like a photograph, you wouldn't
see it go down, so you can see your experience
change. They say that - I don't know how true
it is but - certain types of insects see better
than we do, they can see a grain of sand fall,
we don't. We just see it impact. There -
probably a magnetometer can sense radio waves
- we can't. So, man builds instruments if
he wants to know those things. But the primitive
man just looks at the world and grins, he
doesn't look at an airplane and say "how does
that damn thing fly?" he has no curiosity
except he'll look at it - with his primitive
tools, but he can't say "they've really advanced
that, the people who made that - they have
an advanced way of thinking" - you understand?
He can't say that. Now you might see a person
brought up in this culture, going to church
on Sunday, they're just as primitive as the
head-hunters of the Amazon. Do you understand
that? Alright, I also mentioned many times
that Indians take turkey feathers or big feathers
and make a hat, and if you point it out, the
dancing around the fire with that hat does
absolutely nothing, they do not remove the
hat and say "thank you for being so extensional".
Do you understand that? Ok, are they bad?
No - are they mean? No, they're riding existing
paths. Their brain has a road right through
it as rigid as any other road and they're
riding that path. That's why when a person
says "let's be reasonable", they're trying
to superimpose experience with three words
"let's be reasonable" - you can be reasonable,
you can learn to be reasonable - more so.
Do you know what that means? Or "may I have
your attention?" you can only have the attention
they can give you, do you know what that means?
When an officer walks into an army tent they
say "attention!" meaning he's about to say
something, which you have to listen for "all
you guys ought a be at point A at 4 o'clock"
well that's behavioral manipulation with few
words - Yes?