SUROOSH ALVI: So we're
here in Baghdad.
Right down there, that's
Firdos Square.
That's where the famous scene
took place where Saddam
Hussein's statue was
pulled down.
We came here in 2006 when we
filmed "Heavy Metal in
Baghdad."
It was a very, very different
city then.
It was the height of
the insurgency.
It was a war zone,
full occupation.
And that occupation
is now over.
A year ago, America pulled
out their troops.
BARACK OBAMA: Tonight, I am
announcing that the American
combat mission in
Iraq has ended.
Operation Iraqi Freedom
is over.
Last February, I announced a
plan that would bring our
combat brigades out of Iraq,
while re-doubling our efforts
to strengthen Iraq's security
forces and support its
government and people.
That's what we've done.
SUROOSH ALVI: We found it
strange that Baghdad is not in
the news at all these days.
What happened?
It was the biggest news
story in the world
for almost a decade.
And then overnight, it's over.
So we wanted to come here and
see what the effects of this
occupation were.
When the Americans left, prime
minister Nouri Al-Malaki
intensified his efforts to
consolidate power among the
Shia majority.
This Sunni minority, a group
that enjoyed great privilege
under Saddam Hussein, have
been marginalized.
Naturally, the Sunnis are not
taking this lying down.
-[SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: Massive protests
in Sunni areas and a surge of
sectarian killings throughout
the country become the new
normal in postwar Iraq.
In 2012 alone, there were
more than 1,600 deaths.
Through making "Heavy Metal in
Baghdad," we met Waleed, the
original singer of
Acrassicauda.
At the time, they were the
only metal band in Iraq.
[METAL MUSIC PLAYING]
But shortly after that meeting,
Waleed was forced to
flee the country and seek
refugee status in the West
after receiving numerous
death threats.
With the war officially over,
Waleed decided it was time to
return to Iraq.
It would be his first visit home
since he left in 2004.
We sent a cameraman to accompany
him on this trip and
made plans to meet up with
them once we arrived.
-[SPEAKING ARABIC]
[IRAQI MUSIC PLAYING]
WALEED MOUDHAFAR: I don't even
know what I'm going to do when
I see my mother.
-[SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: We arrived in
Baghdad a few hours after
Waleed and were headed
to the guest house
where we'd be staying.
But that's when we ran
into the [INAUDIBLE].
They're a group of young
punks who are
basically totally insane.
[MOTORCYCLES REVVING]
SUROOSH ALVI: We're with
a Baghdadi biker gang.
We were wondering what do kids
in Baghdad do for fun.
Well, this is it.
A variety of different styles,
kind of this hybrid soccer
player meets Mad Max look, which
is my personal favorite.
Then there's this guy, who's
got the full on Fox Racing
gear, leather from
head to toe.
This guy is riding with
his flip flops.
It doesn't seem totally wise.
I worry about that guy.
I'm not sure he's going
to survive the day.
So you guys are the
[INAUDIBLE].
Are there other gangs in other
cities, like Sadr City?
-[SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: So do you ever get
in trouble with the cops?
-[SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: Do
they chase you?
-[SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: What happened?
[MOTORCYCLES REVVING]
-[SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: Do you guys have
more freedom now, or before?
-[SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: Now, that
sentiment, a seemingly
contradictory one of wanting
freedom but at same time,
missing the rule of Saddam
Hussein, was something we
would hear again and again.
And while these guys long for
American style liberties--
at least surface level
liberties, like, dressing
however the hell you want and
acting like a maniac--
it was clear that they would
trade it all for the stability
that they enjoyed under
Saddam Hussein's
notoriously cruel regime.
-[SPEAKING ARABIC]
-Look at this fucking
shit, man.
Have you noticed every street
has a check point.
SUROOSH ALVI: Put it down.