year looking for fun on
the Fourth of July.
I think you're going
to like this.
I'm Steve Spangler.
And I'm all about making
science fun.
For the last 20 years, I've
been teaching ways to turn
ordinary science experiments
into unforgettable learning
experiences.
I have an amazing team who will
do whatever it takes to
affect the way people
think about science.
And to do that, I live
by one motto.
Make it big.
Do it right.
Give it class.
You know, nothing says Fourth
of July more than red cups,
right here, for soft
drinks, of course.
But I was thinking, why not
for a little science
experiment?
So we're going to show you kind
of a classic Spangler
science experiment using red
Solo cups and some dry ice.
All right, for the first
step, you've got to put
a hole in the cup.
So we want a hole right here.
And probably the easiest way to
do that is to just use an
Exacto knife or some sort of
knife and just kind of start
to cut in just a little
bit if you want.
And finish this up with
a pair of scissors.
So we're just going to cut
a little hole in the cup.
It doesn't have to
look pretty.
This isn't Martha
Stewart hour.
I'm just putting a
hole in a cup.
Look at that.
Magic, right there.
Hole in a cup.
Step two, Saran Wrap.
You need a hunk of Saran Wrap.
That's OK.
Really, they make it so easy
to get it right out of this
container right here.
Just follow their directions.
It's perfectly fine.
You just need to kind of put
this in here like this and
just kind of pull it.
Pull it across like--
it's pretty easy to
get this out.
You just need a small piece.
So we're just going to
use a small little
chunk of Saran Wrap.
And we'll use that
up next time.
And you're going to stretch it
right over the top like this,
kind of like a little drum.
That's what you want.
And a rubber band to secure
the whole thing in place.
And simply cut off the small
little excess that
you have over here.
We're going to recycle
this for later.
Next comes the best part.
And that is dry ice.
So get yourself a
little dry ice.
Now, you've got to be careful,
because it's 78 degrees below
0 Fahrenheit, or 110 degrees
below 0 Celsius.
Regardless, it's really,
really cold.
So when you get dry ice, you're
going to break it up
into some small little pieces.
And that's what we're looking
for here are just a couple
small pieces that will fit right
into the little cup.
Good.
There's a little piece there.
This is pretty good.
This guy's looking good.
Perfect.
All right.
See?
There's our dry ice
in the cup.
The last part is you need
a little bit of water.
So take some water.
You're going to pour the
water into the hole.
Because the dry ice is in there,
we should get a little
of that fog that starts
to come out.
That's perfect.
Now, it may be too much.
But this is the whole idea,
is that you tap
on the bottom here.
And as you do that, it takes the
air that's inside the cup
and forces it out that hole.
And that fast-moving air creates
a little thing called
Bernoulli's principle, which is
just a little vortex ring
that you get to see.
Watch.
Oh, these are looking good.
Isn't that fantastic?
So what can you do with
these vortex rings?
Well, you could stand
around in the house
all day and do this.
Or you can invite friends
over and do this.
Or you could blow
out a candle.
That's been done.
You can decide, let's
make it bigger.
Well, if the red cup is fun,
that means this five-gallon
bucket will even be better.
And you just need to make some
slight modifications to the
five-gallon bucket
and you'll have a
perfect smoke ring launcher.
And you need some tools.
While you could try to just
cut a hole in here, it's a
little bit harder.
That's why this little keyhole
saw seems to do the trick.
Watch this.
Now you're the life
of the party.
We're going to modify the
lid so that there's
a ring that's left.
Just invite your friends
over early and
tell them to do this.
Perfect.
Who said that wasn't
going to be fun?
So now we have a bucket that has
a lid with a huge hole in
it, and a bottom that doesn't
hold anything.
This is perfect for our
science experiment.
Now you need a shower curtain.
I like to use these clear
shower curtains.
It's perfect.
They're nice and durable,
and they make
the best little membrane.
The object here is just
to secure this
piece of vinyl in place.
While you could use bungees or
something, this ring seems to
work really, really well,
especially if you have a
little tool that will help
hold it in place.
It's called a hammer.
[BANGING]
If you don't like to blow smoke
rings, just invite your
friends over and listen
to the song.
[BANGING]
Go for the smoke rings.
Time to trim.
Just cut off the excess all the
way around to make it look
nice and clean.
And you'll have yourself the
perfect smoke ring launcher.
The bucket's not empty.
It's actually filled with air.
And that air can easily
be pushed out.
Now, you could take your hand
and just push it this way.
We want a way to be able
to see the air.
That's where this little
device comes in.
See, it's a smoke machine.
Now, you can find them on sale
right after Halloween.
You just need a small little
blast inside here to help
color the air.
See, that little bit of smoke
that's inside there is exactly
what you need, because when you
tap on the bottom, watch
what happens.
There's your vortex.
But unlike the cup, these
go really, really far.
You can hit them pretty hard.
I know what you're thinking.
You want something that's
more patriotic.
You want it bigger.
You want it colored.
You want it--
I've got an idea.
See, you've got all of this
leftover shower curtain.
Now you just need
a bigger bucket.
So you just take the rest of
the shower curtain, and you
put it right over the
bucket like this.
Now we have to secure
it in place.
That's where these bungee
cords come in.
Pull it down, stretch
it tight.
Now this is not just a
smoke ring launcher.
It's a patriotic smoke
ring launcher.
It's Fourth of July!
See, this is the kind of
activity that's going to make
your neighbors proud.
Nothing says America more than
a giant trash can with a
shower curtain stretched over
the top and some bungee cords
and a couple smoke bombs.
That's right.
I said smoke bombs.
You can't just drop smoke
bombs in the trash can.
It'll shoot out molten
smoke bomb stuff.
And then all of a sudden the
trash can's on fire.
You've ruined the day.
So I came up with this
little idea.
Now, you don't have to use
this kind of paint can.
You can use just an
old coffee can.
But we are going to
make a smoker.
See, we're just putting some
holes in this little can so
the smoke bomb can live in here
and just have smoke come
out and trap everything
else inside.
So how many holes?
Just until the neighbors
tell you to stop.
All right.
So here's the idea.
See, the smoke bomb goes
down inside like this.
And now you light it.
Perfect.
And now this goes on top.
And it just keeps all of the
shards from coming out.
And it just oozes smoke.
This is the smoke ring launcher
I've used in my act
for almost 20 years.
But I never use this kind
of smoke on stage.
Of course, we're just using
a smoke machine.
So this one, you just have to
make sure that you cut the
hole just a little bit bigger
than the paint can so it
covers it perfectly.
All right.
We're ready for patriotic
rings of smoke.
Smoke bomb down inside.
Beautiful.
Lid on top like this.
Smoke starts to come out,
you simply cover it up.
See, this is the only way that
you can get this beautifully
colored smoke.
This is perfect.
Now watch.
As it lifts up, watch this.
You get these beautiful
smoke rings.
Wake the kids.
Call the neighbors.
Oh, wait.
That's David Letterman.
What if you could use science
to help you serve
food at your party?
I got it.
Watch this.
And just because you've seen
Mentos and Diet Coke does not
mean that you've got to turn
it off at this point.
This is different.
Watch.
First of all, we need
a dropper device.
And I've got to show
you this one.
This is clear plastic so you
can see what's going on.
But watch this.
There's a magnet that goes on
the side here, and a ball
bearing that comes down here.
See how it holds in
place like this?
That's perfect.
So when you pull, then
everything falls at once.
Next, the contraption goes
on the top like this.
And now we drop the Mentos.
See, we're just hoping that
that magnet and that ball
bearing holds everything
in place.
And so far, so good.
If we just pulled this right
now, it'd be bad because it
ruins the kitchen.
That's why you need to make
this simple little
contraption, called the Super
Soda Dispenser 3000.
So you see, it just goes over
the very top like this.
And the last thing you need,
six of your best friends.
So you're going to have limit
it to six, but these are my
six best friends.
Anybody else?
FEMALE SPEAKER: This is it.
MALE SPEAKER: This is it.
I'm going to pull this.
And it's going to drop down.
And hopefully, this is how we're
going to bring in this
exciting time of the year.
MALE SPEAKER: Rad.
STEVE SPANGLER: Ready?
Bam!
FEMALE SPEAKER: Nice.
STEVE SPANGLER: Look at that.
It's a soda dispenser,
and it's perfect.
But you don't want to waste
it all on one person.
That's why we only give each
person a little taste.
Here you go.
Some for you.
And some for you.
Cheers to science
Fourth of July.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Cheers!
MALE SPEAKER: Cheers.
STEVE SPANGLER: Well, now that
you've got an awesome drink,
and you've got all your friends
here, and you've got
smoke rings, you're ready for
the big finale, patriotic
geysers with all your friends.
Where'd she go?
MALE SPEAKER: She took off.
STEVE SPANGLER: Well, here we
are for the big finale.
I set this up first thing
this morning.
And I've been waiting
all day for it.
You're going to want to get
your phone out for this.
I've got three different
sodas.
And I've colored this one red
and this one white, of course.
This is clear, and
this one's blue.
And now when I pull this, the
Mentos are going to fall.
And like every great geyser,
it's going to
shoot up in the air.
It's going to be this patriotic
kind of color of
red, white, and blue.
You're going to want to go--
MALE SPEAKER: I've got to go.
STEVE SPANGLER: No.
Don't go.
This is going to be awesome.
I'm going to pull these strings,
and it's going to be
like in the sky.
MALE SPEAKER: I've
got to head out.
Thanks for the soda.
STEVE SPANGLER: You can pull
a string if you want.
Just take your camera.
Watch this.
It's going to be--
hey, watch this.
It's really cool.
Watch this.
Watch.
Three, two, one, go!
Watch this!
Ta da!
Look at that !
Happy Fourth of July,
everyone!
See, you missed it.
It was awesome.
This is the best year ever!
Thanks for coming, everyone.
Next year I'm going
to do six geysers!
Not just three, six.
I'm going to have some more
sodas and smoke rings.
I don't know why he had
to leave so early.
Honey?
Bring the kids out.
I got more geysers.
[MUSIC - JOHN PHILIP
SOUSA, "THE
STARS AND STRIPES FOREVER"]
The oldest trick in the book,
ladies and gentlemen.
Three pieces of dry ice
and three Solo cups.
One on the top.
Boop, boop.
Look at this.
Goes right through.
It's magic.
But hey, I'll do it again.
That's another piece of dry ice
here, right on the top.
Watch this.
Boop, boop.
And that thing goes
right through it.
Check that out.
It's OK.
I'm amazed myself.
Watch this one.
The third one is magic.
It's going to go through
this way.
Bam, bam.
Bam!
Booyah!