I was a teenager about the time
that the delorean came out back in 1981
and it just was so different than
anything else out there as there's
always a story to be told about Deloreans
john delorean started his career as an
engineer with General Motors
from that point he rose very quickly through
GM to be the
youngest vice president and by the early
seventies he was in charge
Chevrolet I think john delorean felt
hamstrung
a bit within the constraints General
Motors he wanted to build a car
was way he thought they should be built
and that would last beyond
the regular model cycle of cars lasting
two or three years
and then lost in a way. john knew the in
order to have his car stand out in the
marketplace
it needed to be different stainless
provided a unique solution to that
by obviously not rusting and it also
solved the problem with having to put
very expensive paint facilities in a
factory
gullwing doors had only been used on a
couple other cars prior to that. John
intended for the car to be an extremely
safe car and
after working with the car as long as we
have here about thirty years yeah, that
is the case. you know they got quite a
lot right
the first go around
the first prototypes were completed 76
while they're looking for a place to
build a factory there very quickly
discovered as soon as they mentioned
they were gonna at about 2000 to 2500
jobs
lots of governments came to them saying
we'd like you to build a factory here
so John began to shop for the best
financial deal cuz he knew that would
take a lot of money
but then the northern ireland
development agency came through in 1978
they started with a Greenfield plant of
about ninety acres. They're able to build
a factory, design a car, hire people, train
people and start production in a span of about
about twenty eight months which is a
record that probably still stands today
thirty years later
the first cars were built and they
started shipped to dealers in the summer
of 1981.
the auto industry was in a slump nobody
knew what was gonna happen and bomb
out comes this car that look like
nothing else before. Stainless body
gullwing doors that was a spaceship on
wheels. The press was abuzz.
Initial public response was fantastic.
Everybody was going nuts for it it was a
show-stopping
pull up and there would be crowds around
them. There were some reports of people
paying more than ten thousand dollars
over sticker price. Everybody would
be clamoring to see one and touch one
which is still the same now everybody
has to touch a Delorean you know
Trouble for the company first really
started in late 1981.
In order to improve the stock offering
that was planned they needed to be
building a certain number of cars and
have a certain number people employed
John to gamble and ordered production of
the car doubled.
As far as the economy was concerned
interest rates were extremely high.
And we got hit with the worst winter in
about 30 years so car sales
pretty much dropped almost to nothing. So
it was extremely difficult to sell
anything let alone
an expensive sports car. In fact we kept
going building these cars hoping that
the market would turn around
in time by early 82 it was clear
that wasn't gonna happen
John lost control in the factory in May
1982. He needed to come up with a
a certain amount of money to regain
control the factory.
About this time he was approached by one
of his neighbours
and he told John that he could help him
get any kind of money he needed.
In the summer of 82 when John realized
you know that this was some kind of a
drug deal
he tried to back out. According to his
testimony his family was threatened they
threatened to cut off his daughter's head and send it home in a shopping bag
he didn't feel he had any option except
to continue to go along with the deal.
Turns out that this was a sting
operation.
The DEA at that period wanted to the big bust
wanted to make
a name for themselves. In late October
of 82 he was arrested.
By the time John Delorean went to trial
in 1984
company was gone and filed for bankruptcy
the factory
contents have been sold or auctioned off.
The DEA actually set him up and it was
entrapment, truth be known as he never
went to jail he was completely acquitted
of all the drug charges.
When the factory closed in late
there was literally millions of parts to build
cars still in the factory
and is that inventory that which we now
have in our facility here. We have a
40,000 square-foot facility full of
literally millions
new old stock brand new 30-year-old
Delorean parts
Out of the 2800 or so different parts
it takes to make up a DeLorean we've got
better than 98 percent parts
availability.
One of the other things that we acquired
with this inventory of parts was a
complete set of engineering drawings
and all the engineering record for the
parts on the car so as we run out of
stuff
we have a network of suppliers and
manufacturers all around the world
who we work with to have some of these
parts reproduced.
You can't talk about Delorean cars without
talking about Back to the Future.
In the earliest versions of the script
they had intended to use
a refrigerator as the time machine and
quickly realized you know that they
didn't want kids climbing into
refrigerators cuz back in the day they
had doors
couldn't open from the inside and they
decided it would be easier to use some
kind of an automobile.
Since the company went out of business it's
been the
greatest thing to happen to the DeLorean
car. Guaranteed
some place in the world right now one of
those movies is on TV someplace so
someone new is being exposed to the
DeLorean car for the first time.
John left a legacy in the form of
9000 or so cars that bear his name. I think
one of the reasons the Delorean remains
sort of timeless because the delorean
never went through that
evolutionary process because that
didn't
happen Delorean is essentially frozen in
time. You know and as
decades ago there are always certain
things that stick out
and Delorean is definitely you know an
iconic part of the eighties.
Had Delorean had survived
that period in time and continued
there would be a big 4 now there
wouldn't be a big three. Delorean
himself he made Delorean
and he also took it down.
As the story goes apparently on the day
that he was actually arrested
they actually had an investment bank
lined up so they'd actually arranged for
the resurrection of the company
and all he had to do was sign the
document and they were looking for him
all day they couldn't find him and then
the next thing they had that he was on
the six o'clock news is
have been arrested in Los Angeles
Airport and and that was the end of it
the financing went away
you know they just had that one last
chance and it didn't happen