[DJ SCREW TRACK]
TRACE: Houston seemed the
perfect destination for us to
cover both a rock and roll
and a drug story.
[RAP]
TRACE: Today, the influence of
Houston is huge across the
whole rap community.
[RAP]
TRACE: This started basically
because of a
guy named DJ Screw.
He invented chopped and screwed
music, which was
essentially slowing down
existing records to a snail's
pace, like a syrupy drawl.
[DJ SCREW TRACK]
TRACE: One of the defining
characteristics of chopped and
screwed music is drinking
codeine-based cough syrup.
So we went down.
We drank some cough syrup, and
we listened to some chopped
and screwed.
[RAP]
TRACE: Now I'm from Houston.
I don't know a lot about
chopped and screwed.
I had to have somebody who
could lead me around.
Luckily, I met up with this
guy named Kyu Boi, who had
been a wrapper in the
scene, and part of
the South Park Coalition.
The South Park Coalition
has been around
since the late '80s.
They're one of the older
crews in Houston.
Kyu Boi was this real dynamic
guy, real funny guy, and
through him I was able to meet
most all the people.
[RAP]
TRACE: Kyu Boi realized
I didn't know
anything about rap music.
He told me the first thing I had
to do was go through the
two most important neighborhoods
in this story--
South Park and the Third Ward.
KYU BOI: now, you in the
slums of Third Ward.
This is where we at, Houston,
Texas, Third Ward Area.
TRACE: This doesn't
look so good.
[RAP]
KYU BOI: We're on Live Oak
Street, right in the heart of
Third Ward.
That's H-Town, Texas,
This really is a
grimy location.
As you can see, there's really
not too architecture-type
structures around here.
A lot of dope fiends,
a lot of junkies.
As you can see, my boy right
here, him, on that bike,
that's the product
of Third Ward.
Looking at him will let you know
where your life will be
if you don't get your shit
right-- riding a fucking
bicycle, looking like Bob
Marley fucking grandpa.
See those people over
there looking angry?
Those are the people that
you got to meet.
TRACE: The first guy we went to
meet in the Third Ward is
Dope E. And he's a particularly
important part of
the South Park Coalition.
DOPE E: D-O-P-E, capital E.
Stands for dope effects,
because of the dope-ass
music I do and the
effects I put to it.
That's what we about,
beats and rhymes.
(FREESTYLING) on the music
trying to make it last.
Just chilling in a [INAUDIBLE].
[SINGING]
TRACE: Dope E has a great
recording studio in this
house, where members from the
South Park Coalition can come
over there and record tracks.
EVERYONE JAMMING: It's
all about the dough.
Standing making cash flow.
Building up in escrow.
TRACE: There's also a lot of
really strange rules that he
has pinned up on
the front door.
DOPE E: I run a studio, closed
session, appointments only.
We going check out the music.
No visitors, though.
You got to get in touch with me
before you come to my pad.
Do not bring dead animals
inside of my
house and eat them--
cows, pigs, chicken,
turkeys, et cetera.
No disagreeables beyond
this point.
The most important thing is that
you decide what side you
want to be on, agreeable
or disagreeable.
Because Humpty Dumpty, he fell
the fuck off the wall, sitting
his ass up there.
Cracked his whole shell.
Pick a side.
[SPC TRACK]
KYU BOI: I got us two
invitations to a thug barbecue
in the hood, in South Park.
And all you got to do
is just act black.
Act black and be yourself.
[RAP]
TRACE: It's not a cookout.
These are not veggie patties.
These are not tofu pups.
We're not warming shit.
We're barbecuing it with
smoke, real fire.
This is the way people
roll in Texas.
J CHILL: It's just that that
South Side Texas flavor.
[EXCLAMATORY SOUND], you know?
TRACE: The barbecue is going
on, great gangbusters.
You see all these guys drinking,
getting up on weed.
They're barbecuing
all this meat.
And they have pythons
and what have you.
Pretty soon, the music
starts playing.
And before long everyone
is freestyling.
D ONE: (FREESTYLING) Hold on.
I gotta put this on camera.
I got on jewels, but my
name ain't Santana.
I ain't from [INAUDIBLE],
but I will [INAUDIBLE]
TRACE: A lot of people know
about the music scene in
Houston primarily because of
Paul Wall and Mike Jones.
But it's in places like this
backyard where it began.
DOPE E: (FREESTYLING)
[INAUDIBLE]
Coalition.
While we make amends
like better men.
We get better.
And now we chilling
[INAUDIBLE].
Ten years looking for shit.
Now we back.
[INAUDIBLE]
doing something black.
K-RINO: I can remember when
it wasn't a scene.
People laughed at us.
People thought we was country.
People said all we did
down here was ride
horses and rope cows.
Somebody got to be the person
to get the ball rolling.
In my eyes, it was Face and the
Geto Boys that did that.
WILLIE D: The Geto Boys was
actually formed in '87.
But not until '89 did we start
gaining some regional and
national notoriety.
It just kicked the door in and
ushered in a in whole new crop
of rappers in Houston.
It really gave people hope.
K-RINO: When Face dropped the
song, "Scarface," that's what
gave everybody motivation.
I can do this, too.
TRACE: In between Paul Walls and
the Geto Boys, is the rise
of this guy, DJ Screw.
DISTA: All this slow music and
chopped and screwed, purple
stuff, drank, lean that
cup, from us.
We got the whole
world onto it.
Ain't no way y'all can
acknowledge the world and not
acknowledge Houston.
[RAP]
TRACE: What's happening,
my baby?
I heard you're rolling
down the road.
I had to get up in there.
How you doing?
BALDHEAD: Alright, man.
TRACE: I love your rod, man.
I need to work on my style a
little bit, or you think maybe
I can make this happen?
BALDHEAD: Loosen your tie.
Relax a little bit.
TRACE: I'm thinking about
maybe getting Thug Lite,
L-I-T-E.
BALDHEAD: [LAUGHING]
You'll get hit up.
TRACE: Or maybe Thug White.
BALDHEAD: You crazy.
[LAUGHTER]
[KLONDIKE KAT TRACK]
DISTA: We been doing
our thing.
We been rocking big chains.
We been riding slabs,
big rims, all that.
We've been doing that.
Half of the styles that's out
right now, come from Houston.
There's a lot of people
emulating our style and using
our words, and they
running with it.
[KLONDIKE KAT TRACK]
TRACE: Can ya'll show me some of
your jewelry, and stuff, so
we can check it out.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
MAN: If you're from the
South Side, you
got you one of these.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
MAN: When you get that million
dollar check, that's where we
going stuff it.
Stuff it all in that
money bag.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
[RAP]
TRACE: One of our first stops
is to go meet the king of
bling, Johnny Dang,
a.k.a TV Johnny.
[RAP]
TRACE: Going to meet Johnny
Dang today, grill
master to the stars.
JOHNNY DANG: This is Johnny
Dang, a.k.a TV Johnny.
They call me TV Johnny
[INAUDIBLE]
TV jewelry.
TRACE: These are all
diamonds, Johnny?
JOHNNY DANG: Yeah, that's
all diamonds.
TRACE: Johnny Dang has been
making custom jewelry for rap
stars for a long time now.
But what he's most famous
for is his grills.
Which one is the most
popular, you think?
JOHNNY DANG: Actually, this
one and this one the most
popular one.
TRACE: I've seen a lot of
guys wearing those.
So I'm afraid to ask you this.
How much is the number three?
How much does that cost?
JOHNNY DANG: $7,000.
TRACE: Oh, OK. $7,000.
Do you have a layaway plan?
JOHNNY DANG: Oh, definitely.
One year layaway.
TRACE: One year layaway?
JOHNNY DANG: I mean, whenever
you can pay all, just pay all.
Take it out.
TRACE: Well let's go in there
and look at where
the real stuff is.
[BEEP]
TRACE: Hey, you hear that sound,
Johnny, that sound that
goes [BEEP]?
JOHNNY DANG: Yeah.
TRACE: You need to change
it so it goes "bling."
JOHNNY DANG: That's
a good idea.
We do a lot of custom
piece, necklace.
So, it's personalized
like this one.
This is for JD.
TRACE: It almost looks like it
could be the knocker on a door
when you come to the house.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
JOHNNY DANG: That's
good-looking.
TRACE: I've got a lot
of good ideas.
Maybe I could start
working with you.
I need some extra money.
JOHNNY DANG: This is the one I
special custom for Snoop with
his original hand.
I took the picture, he
held this one, and
I make it off him.
TRACE: Can we see your grill?
JOHNNY DANG: Yeah, definitely.
TRACE: Johnny, you didn't lose
your grill, did you?
How much is your grill worth?
JOHNNY DANG: About $20,000.
TRACE: So right now you just
put your $20,000 thing down
and you don't know
where it is?
JOHNNY DANG: I'm
going to find.
I'm not going to lose.
I have a second one
like this one.
They call it TVJ.
TRACE: TV Johnny.
JOHNNY DANG: That's how we do.
TRACE: Well thank you
very much for
meeting with us today.
Super interesting, super
fascinating.
Good luck.
JOHNNY DANG: Thank
you so much.
TRACE: I got to work
on my handshake.
I couldn't afford any of
the grills that Johnny
Dang had for sale.
But what I realized was
everybody had a t-shirt with
their face on it.
So I thought I'd see if I could
afford one of those.
This is my man, Sleek.
SLEEK: Sleek.
TRACE: He runs the
airbrush store.
Tell me what you
do here, Sleek.
SLEEK: Airbrush t-shirts
nonstop-- shoes, walls,
helmets, caps.
Whatever you can come up
with, we can produce.
[MUSIC]
MAN: Aw, come on, now.
[LAUGHTER]
FBI agent.
TRACE: Once you got the clothes,
and got the jewelry,
gotta get yourself a ride.
The kind of car to have in
Houston, if you want to roll
with the big boys, is a slab--
slow, loud, and banging.
[RAP]
TRACE: I like this car.
What years is this?
BALDHEAD: '73.
Chevy Impala.
TRACE: How long have
you had it?
BALDHEAD: About eight years.
That's how we do
it down South.
That's how we do it.
Stay customized.
Slab.
TRACE: Nice.
BALDHEAD: Custom, baby.
[RAP]
It's a slab.
We deck everything out with
the rims, the pop trunk,
Lamborghini doors, the music.
[RAP]
TRACE: Not moving very
fast, are we?
BALDHEAD: No, we just
in the traffic,
crawling through here.
Snail's pace.
Checking it out.
Everybody checking us out,
seeing what the business is.
WILLIE D: The guys get the
cars for the women.
Because that's what
it's about.
Women love cars.
[RAP]
[INAUDIBLE]
[RAP AND CHEERING]
TRACE: There's a lot of things I
learned about rap music when
I was in Houston.
One of the things that I didn't
know was how hard all
these guys work.
It's incredible.
Guys are always hustling.
So every time you walk up
somewhere, your pockets are
filled with fliers
and stickers.
And everywhere they go
it's a new promotion.
And they got a new CD.
And they're doing
all this stuff.
It's nothing like some lame
little indie rockers here in
Brooklyn who are
moping around.
They're businessmen, and
then they're rappers.
[RAP]
BALDHEAD: You got to grind
and put it down
every day, every night.
Live it.
Talk it.
Want it.
Every day.
And it's going to go
down for you, baby.
[RAP]
KILLAHOE: [INAUDIBLE] music
more than anything.
We are young black
entrepreneurs.
You know what I'm saying,
not a gang.
DOUGIE D: We were born to be
entrepreneurs down here.
BALDHEAD: Welcome to
the South Side.
This is going to be my
project right here.
KB: KB da Kidnapper,
Street Military.
CL'CHE': My name is Cl'che'.
That's spelled
C-L-apostrophe-C-H-E. I'm on
myspace.com, too.
You can check it out.
BALDHEAD: You can check me
out on myspace.com/bald
headentetainment.
LIL B: Backslash dirty,
T-H-I-R-D.
CL'CHE': Check out
all my albums, my
undergrounds, mix tapes.
I'm doing one [INAUDIBLE]
right now.
SHOWTYME: Got the Showtyme block
party DVD fixing to get
here, hit the streets.
DOUGIE D: We have this new
cologne called Pure Pizazz.
BUN B: Artists in Houston out
here, more than most other
regions are primarily
businessmen first.
They took all the fun out of
this shit for us out here.
All the making a record and
going somewhere and giving
someone your demo, hoping
you get a deal.
We did that shit.
We tried that shit for years,
got turned down.
Every door slammed
in your face.
[RAP]
BUN B: None of guys ever thought
they'd ever get a
major recording deal.
Most of them had seen people
try before them.
Some of them had tried
themselves.
These guys learned to make
what they needed to make
happen outside of the system.
We just said, fuck it.
And it's that fuck it mentality
that gets these cats
great deals.
And they will take advantage of
the game like they want to.
[RAP]
KB: I started off in the Street
Military back in the '90s.
We put out first record out
in '91, on Gerard Records.
Back then we were selling
records without getting no
radio play.
We made our mark
on the streets.
The radio ain't make us.
We made our mark
on the streets.
TRACE: These guys operate
outside the major
record label systems.
They make more money selling
it out of the back of their
car, selling it on the street,
hustling it themselves, than
they would ever make if
they signed a deal.
MAN: Better watch out for us.
We got a lot of big
things coming.
TRACE: It's rumored that DJ
Screw sold something like this
50,000 copies of a single mix.
BUN B: I think the screw sound,
and the fact that
someone like Screw was selling
these thousands of mix tapes
out of his house, and people
were getting all this big
local fame and shit off
of mix tape songs.
And then that was selling
40,000, 50,000 units based on
this type of stuff.
They weren't just new artists
looking for a deal.
They were businessmen.
And if they wanted to try to
come down here and use us to
latch onto the Southern music
by a market, it's
going to cost them.
Because we're already tied
into the market.
And we don't need them to get
our music to the people.
[RAP]
KB: All I need is
distribution.
$8 a CD at wholesale price.
Fuck another record company
trying to fuck me.
Hey, it's over with.
You heard me?
[RAP]
We made the vibration
over time.
DOPE E: And by sticking together
through trials and
showing everybody how to do
their shit fully, that has a
lot to do with it.
And that same attitude is what
other Coalition members did.
Each one teach one.
I started showing all the ones
[INAUDIBLE] growing up with.
That's one thing.
All you got to do is tell us.
And tell the next person.
We got that shit, as long
as you tell us.
J CHILL: I remember a point
in time when we used to go
retirement studio,
shit like that.
We ain't got to do
that no more.
TRACE: There's a real tradition
in Houston of
putting your money back into
your home recording studio.
So when you go to somebody like
Devin the Dude's place,
you're totally blown
away by his setup.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
DEVIN THE DUDE: This has been
happening for a while, Coughee
Brotha Tony and Boomer
Henfield, they
started back in the day.
They old man called
[INAUDIBLE].
Drink a cup of coffee,
[INAUDIBLE]
We always incorporate that with
the rhymes and what we've
been doing over the years.
TRACE: The guys are extremely
prolific.
They all rap on each
other's records.
Some of them are putting out
10, 15, 20 records a year.
WILLIE D: There are
some grinding.
There are some true grinders
in this business today.
These dudes work, work,
work, work, work.
They got killer work ethics.
BALDHEAD: You got to
get up off that ass
and put work down.
If you don't represent
you, who's going to
represent you for you?
Everybody cry about this cat,
this cat, done that.
Let me tell you something.
You gotta grind, baby.
[RAP]
DOPE E: It's really just
dedication and unity.
It's just us sticking
together.
And saying, no matter what, I'm
going to put SPC first.
And I'm going to do this
motherfucking music.
(FREESTYLING) niggers, they
shoot, rob banks.
Most of these people, they come
around in a Hummer tank.
When you got some real
motherfuckers that hook up
together, that's
the vibration.
That's what happen.
D ONE: (FREESTYLING)
She said, oh no.
I had to break her off slow.
Come through the South
Side, [INAUDIBLE].
BUN B: We watch hip hop.
We want people gaining
strength and numbers.
So that's all we did, was apply
that shit to what we
were doing.
We didn't invent nothing.
[RAP]
BUN B: Initially, we all
were selling Houston.
But now, we get to come together
as a collective and
say, we are Houston.
Some of us don't get along--
hell a lot of people don't get
along with each other.
But, when it comes to Houston,
to the bigger picture, we
going put bullshit aside and
stand up for the city.
J CHILL: They should do it like
the big white dudes in
them companies, and shit.
They might not like
each other.
But shit, they'll go to work,
and make money together.
And say, fuck it on weekend.
Don't ask me what the fuck I did
when I'm at home, nigger.
You just do your shit.
I'm going to do mine.
We going make this
money together.
It's a beautiful thing, if you
just take care of business and
do your shit, and don't make
it about that bullshit.
[RAP]
TRACE: And one of the biggest
hustlers of them all, the guy
who's had the most profound
impact to this
point, is DJ Screw.
[RAP]
TRACE: The sound that Houston is
most well known for today,
which is now known as chopped
and screwed, literally started
with one guy--
DJ Screw in Houston, Texas.
[RAP]
MAN: This the king right here.
He's DJ Screw.
DOUGIE D: H-Town, we really
have a sound of our own.
South Side swag and a sound
that can't just really be
emulated all [INAUDIBLE].
Everybody who [INAUDIBLE] all
screwed up, we is screwed up.
[RAP]
BUN B: A lot of people, they
don't know about DJ Screw.
DJ Screw is a local DJ from
Houston, Texas who invented
his own style of mixing.
What he did was he slowed the
records down a little past
half speed.
Kind of blended the songs
together, a little bit easy.
And it was something that fit
the slowed down, laid back,
chill Southern vibe
of Houston.
That started around
'92, early '93.
Got nationwide fame
around '95.
[RAP]
TRACE: The idea seems to have
come from him when he was
drinking this codeine
cough syrup.
Now what syrup does is it's
loaded with codeine.
It's a narcotic induced
kind of relaxation.
You're really kind of out
of it, and everything is
amorphous and cloudy
and very slow.
So DJ Screw is in his bedroom.
He's up on the weed.
He's up on codeine, and he
starts slowing records down in
an attempt to get them to sound
exactly the way he feels.
[MUSIC SLOWING DOWN]
KLONDIKE KAT: While they was
listening to they slowed down
music, they was drinking
they codeine.
Guys, including Screw,
that hung with Screw,
that's what they did.
[RAP]
[INAUDIBLE]
1980-motherfucking-5
[MUSIC]
BUN B: With rap, mostly just
kind of writing the same
rhymes and making most of the
same beats over and over
again, this was some new shit,
some original shit that no
other city, no other region
could lay claim to.
And it gave Houston its own
regional identity, apart from
everything else that
was going on.
TRACE: Screw started making
these tapes at house, the
Great Tapes.
They became a cultural
phenomenon.
MAC NYCE: When Screw was doing
his thing at his crib, and he
had people coming like
it was a club.
His whole street would be lined
up with cars, people
trying to buy Screw tapes.
LANCE: You never forget the
first time you heard DJ Screw.
And without fail you heard
it from a car.
And you would hear this booming
music coming out with
this really low, slowed
down voice.
And without fail, if you were
standing with a group of
people in those first few years,
one of them always had
this really puzzled
look on his face.
Somebody else would say,
oh, that's DJ Screw.
[DJ SCREW TRACK]
Screw ended up getting a real
big following on the south
side of town, to the southwest,
to the north side.
He had a lot of different emcees
together to come and
freestyle on the mix tapes
that he was making.
People like Lil KeKe, ESG, the
Botany Boys, [INAUDIBLE], a
lot of different people
represented Screwed Up
Clique, Li'l Flip.
LANCE: He would talk to
you during the tapes.
He would just emcee through
the whole thing.
[DJ SCREW TRACK]
TRAE: Screw was our
form of radio.
That's who had us going.
Even if he wasn't flowing
on the tapes, he had
the songs on tape.
If you song made it to a Screw
tape, people paid attention to
it real serious.
MAC NYCE: Everybody and they
mama was saying it's
not going to work.
Everybody, from rappers to
record execs, were saying it's
not going to work.
How are you going to screw a
record and put that worldwide?
We did it.
And it blew up.
[INAUDIBLE]
all that blew up, with
Lil KeKe and them,
and the rest is history.
TRACE: This was shot on November
14, 2000, just two
days before DJ Screw passed
away of heart failure.
So what exactly killed
DJ Screw?
A lot of people tried
to blame codeine.
But some people really
believe that he just
worked himself to death.
[DJ SCREW TRACK]
TRAE: We on a monument
right now.
This Screwed Up Records,
[INAUDIBLE].
This shop means a lot.
No matter what city you come
from, you could be coming from
Kansas, you could be coming from
Oklahoma, anywhere, they
always come down here to
get these Screw tapes.
BUN B: There's probably
really only one--
I would say probably three
landmarks as far that's
significant to the rap scene--
Screwed Up Records, Rap-a-Lot
Records, and wherever I'm at.
[DJ SCREW TRACK]
BUN B: This is kind of
like a record store.
But you can't really go
and buy somebody's
album that's out.
This shit only sells Screw
tapes and Screw CDs.
And they do damn
good business.
They don't have to sell
nobody else's shit.
They never had to.
People from all over the
country, all over the world,
people show a lot of love.
[DJ SCREW TRACK]
BUN B: Screw's been gone
for a couple years now.
But we keep the store going.
It's important for us to try
to make sure we keep this
thing going.
I done bought every tape
and every CD they
sell in here, twice.
And I'm going to keep
buying them.
[DJ SCREW TRACK]
TRAE: He took a lot of us under
his wing, and made us
who we are.
He molded us.
MAC NYCE: Most of the people
that you seeing out here right
now, MTV, and BET, DJ Screw, he
the one laid the foundation
for these cats.
From the ESGs the Flips, they
going double platinum and all
this because of the foundation
DJ Screw did.
[DJ SCREW TRACK]
BUN B: Screw could have made a
lot more money off the tapes.
He could have been a
lot more famous.
But it wasn't about him.
It was about the city.
And that's the type of shit I
be trying to stretch, every
time we get to feeling our
motherfucking self, or
thinking it's all about us, we
got to remember that it's
never about us.
It's about the city.
It's about the hood, and the
people we represent.
And that's what Screw
taught us.
And that's why we hold him
in such high regard.
Screwed Up Records, or RIP DJ
Screw, a real H-Town legend.
[RAP]
KILLAHOE: New York, [INAUDIBLE]
they drink.
West Coast known
for they weed.
Houston, we known
for our thing.
SCRIPT: This is lean oil.
It's something going put you to
sleep, on your ass, if you
drink too much.
Got many names, they call
it purple stuff, call it
[INAUDIBLE].
LANCE: It's codeine
promethazine.
It's a slow drug.
It slows everything down.
I think in order to understand
syrup you really have to
understand Houston.
Because Houston is a big
sprawling slow hot city.
We have nine months of summer.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
LANCE: When they say a two, a
four, an eight, they're talk
about the ounces.
So a lot of people sip
maybe a two each day.
Two ounces mixed into a
Styrofoam cup with any kind of
soda, like strawberry soda,
Sprite, anything just really,
really sweet.
KYU BOI: I fixing to get you
tore up on some syrup.
This H-Town lean right here.
I'mma pour some of this out.
You ain't got to be nervous
or nothing.
I know this your first time
sipping, but I'm going to show
you a good time.
LANCE: It's not a drug that is
consumed with an ugly use.
You don't have to tie a rubber
band around your arm and shoot
anything into your arm.
You sip it out of a cup.
[MUSIC]
LANCE: I don't think it occurs
to a lot of people that
there's anything really
wrong with it.
MAC NYCE: It's like, to me,
marijuana, drinking a beer,
having a sip of alcohol.
That's how I look at it.
KYU BOI: I'm going to show
you how to mix it up.
We going to start you
off with a deuce.
TRACE: How do you know
how far to go down?
By how much of this you got?
KYU BOI: Yeah, how many
pints you got.
AGONY LIFE: The syrup,
it's part our hustle.
It's not a fad.
It's just a way of life.
Syrup been around here before
y'all was born.
BIG RON: My mom and
them was on drink.
They used to take a teaspoon
and drink it, [INAUDIBLE].
FREEZE: We known for it.
It's something we do.
But it's not the only place.
But we definitely did
put the light on it.
KYU BOI: And then we going take
this, uh, uh, uh, uh, do
this like here.
And this where the
wonder starts.
Gotta have steady hands.
This is the real stuff.
TRACE: Let me give it a shot.
I'm pretty sure I can do it.
My hands are real steady.
I'm feeling good already.
It's obvious that not everyone
in Houston is up on the syrup
24/7, but there's a hell of
a lot of songs about it.
D ONE: (FREESTYLING) Don't
hate when you see me
[INAUDIBLE]
I never coming down, still
sipping on lean.
KLONDIKE KAT: See a lot of
people get flack because they
say, well you do, that's
all they talking
about, sipping syrup.
Everybody got their own way of
putting across what they do,
or what they see
in their hood.
As long as you make good music,
that's how I see it.
That's the plus.
BUN B: For the next young
rappers, if they don't just
speak on some aspect of it, it's
almost like they won't be
supporting the city.
Especially we got female
emcees nowadays.
They going to have to in some
way incorporate that kind of
shit in their shit.
And it is not sexy to see a
woman sipping on syrup,
getting all fat in the
fucking face, and
smoking Black and Milds.
It's a part of life.
But that shit ain't sexy.
KYU BOI: You gotta let
it marinade enough.
See, that's the marination
[INAUDIBLE].
That is wonderful.
TRACE: Aw, yeah.
KYU BOI: See how that feel?
Feel good?
TRACE: It's nice
in your hands?
Is it legal to drink this?
KYU BOI: Yeah, as long as the
police don't catch you,
drinking, anything's legal.
TRACE: I heard a rumor that they
have this strip that they
can dip into your soda and
see if it has any soda.
Is that true, do you think?
FREEZE: Yeah, that's
actually true.
I knew somebody they kind of
got put upon them when they
caught them with a case.
And it's like a felony now.
So it's a lot of stuff out here
they're trying to catch
people with.
But that's actually true.
It turns a color.
TRACE: Can I ask
you a question?
Is that OK?
COP: No comment.
TRACE: That was a no comment.
KILLAHOE: It's a good and
a negative thing.
Because it ain't that many
of us out here on it.
But we love it.
Same time we got a lot of
us that do love it.
And we going do it.
You see my white
cup right here.
I'm a member of the group.
TRACE: Do we use a straw,
or something?
KYU BOI: No, we don't
need no straws.
Straight to the bottom.
That's the purple stuff.
Only in H-Town can you
get this good stuff.
TRACE: It looks like Barney.
KB: And the negative thing is if
you get too leaned out, how
you going to go in the
studio and really put
down a bunch of work?
So you got to know when
enough is enough.
Don't get too leaned out to
where you can't take care of
your business.
Me, myself, and I, I drink
lean sometimes, too.
Matter of fact, I love it.
I love it.
TRACE: I don't think you can
drink it that fast anyway.
It's real--
KYU BOI: No, you can't
drink it real fast.
You got to sssip.
TRACE: Actually, you start
to like it after a while.
Don't you?
It really gets in your mouth
like glue, doesn't it?
MO LEW: It tastes good.
It tastes real good, huh?
[INAUDIBLE] tastes
real good, huh?
Tastes like Jolly Ranchers.
(EXTREMELY SLOWED DOWN)
Like Jolly Ranchers.
MO LEW: I had bronchitis,
so I used to give
prescriptions for it.
I hit that purple stuff, and,
shit, I was ready to roll for
the rest of the week.
Hit the studio, hit the
J-O-B. I was good.
TRACE: Makes you want
to drink a lot more.
MAC NYCE: [INAUDIBLE]
just basically buy syrup.
We got cats who like to do the
syrup and jam they screw.
But we got--
today we had cats like KB,
from Street Military.
His style is completely
different from the original
Screwed Up sound.
And then the Screwed Up Clique
had a different style.
So it's not all just based on
this one, everything's slow
and you've got to be syruped
out to listen.
It ain't even like that.
SCRIPT: Yeah, you roll some up,
and sip that, it's really
a killer combination.
TRACE: Well let's do it.
I haven't smoked
any pot at all.
SCRIPT: You ain't
smoked no weed?
TRACE: Let's get a little bit--
let's get on the weed.
SCRIPT: You haven't
smoked nothing?
Shit.
[RAP]
TRACE: The guys are just smoking
weed like it's going
out of style.
God almighty, they smoke
a lot of weed.
I've never been around guys
smoking much pot.
[RAP]
SCRIPT: That's what
I'm talking about.
Did you see how he paused
and came open?
He was feeling it.
TRACE: I am.
I really am feeling it.
SCRIPT: That's what
I'm talking about.
TRACE: I didn't think I
would even say that.
How does the syrup
make you feel?
Like there's a veil between you
and the rest of the world.
And all of a sudden your
whole body is warm.
[MUSIC]
TRACE: Kyu Boi asked me this
morning how I slept.
KYU BOI: Shit, like a baby?
TRACE: I told him I
slept like a baby.
I woke up every two
hours, crying.
[LAUGHTER]
KYU BOI: That's what
it do to you, man.
That's what it do to you.
[MUSIC]
[COUGHING]