mailbag - this is Genesis Week.
[Music]
And a welcome to this episode of Genesis
Week, the weekly program of creationary
commentary on news, views and events
pertaining to the origins controversy,
made possible by the supporters of CORE
Ottawa - Citizens for Origins Research
and Education, and exclusive right here
on youtube.  Pirate broadcasting from
Tracy Island, we show the glory of God in
Creation and bring you the information
the anti-creationists don't want you to see
or hear.  One of the most talked about
shows in Science and Technology on
youtube.
You can find us at wazooloo.com or
genesisweek.com, or click the
ever-so-convenient subscribe link up top,
and don't forget, you can also peruse
other episodes by following the links in
the upper corners of each episode. I'm
your host, Ian Juby
A spectacular find of a fossil forest in
China has garnered some interest.  Buried
in volcanic ash, these trees were
apparently buried in-situ, that is, buried
upright, right where they grew.  While I
have no problem with the idea of in-situ
burial, so far every time I have
investigated claims of "in-situ burial," the
claims didn't hold up.  This could be a
first, simply because of the description of
the site.  Fossil trees buried and preserved
upright in the fossil record are quite
common - I've personally studied such
finds In New Brunswick, Nova Scotia,
Alberta and British Columbia, Yellowstone
National park, Tennessee, Pennsylvania,
Colorado and New Mexico.  Such fossils
which are buried vertically in the rock are
called polystrate - poly for many, strate
for the strata of rock that the fossil cuts
through.
most of the Chinese fossil trees are not
trees at all, but rather giant, hollow reeds,
the same kind of plants as those found at
Joggins, Nova Scotia.
Rock layers are alleged to have taken at
least thousands, perhaps millions of
years to accumulate.  But then we find
polystrate fossils cutting through such
layers - well, those trunks won't remain in
place for tens of years, let alone
thousands, or millions.
Yet that is precisely what we are expected
to believe: When one reads the literature
available at the Joggins Fossil Center, or
the Museum of Nova Scotia website, they
couldn't be more clear.
On the Joggins Fossil Cliffs Visitor's
center website, we read:
We also see a story drawn in Laing
Ferguson's book from the museum of
Nova Scotia, and at the Joggins visitor's
center, painting a clear picture of gradual
burial over time.
The Chinese fossil plants are all buried in
a layer just 66 centimeters thick,
uncovered in a coal mine.  There were
some trunks that were reported
suspended in the rock on an angle - not
straight up and down - almost as if the
trunk was buried while fallling! Of course,
we also see this at Joggins and elsewhere
as well. Clearly these layers did not take
thousands or millions of years to
accumulate.
On the Museum of Nova Scotia website,
we read:
We also read on the Museum of Nova
Scotia Website:
Yet we find some stumps buried
polystrate through coal seams! And
sometimes coal seams are a mere quarter
inch thick - were they quarter inch deep
swamps?  The Chinese find was also
found in a coal mine, allegedly a peat bog.
Obviously, there are huge problems with
the conventional interpretation of time
and the origin of coal.
There's also a problem with the "in situ"
interpretation of the stumps - for
example, some stumps of polystrates
have their roots sheered off, while other
roots have had their rootlets stripped off -
clear evidence that the plants have been
uprooted, then buried elsewhere in an
upright position.  Some of the stumps are
upside down.
Now I proved just how lousy a gardener I
was when all of my plants commited
suicide, however, one thing I did NOT do
wrong, was try to grow my plants upside
down.  Last I checked, plants don't grow
well at all upside down and underground.
While studying dinosaur tracks at a coal
mine in Alberta with a young geologist, I
noted a most unusual phenomena:
dozens of upside down, polystrate
stumps from a giant, hollow reed like the
lycopods of Joggins.  The roots went into
the coal which was on top of the dinosaur
tracks.  Obviously, the coal, the dinosaur
tracks, and the layers the dinosaur tracks
are in that the trunks cut through, were all
laid down RAPIDLY. There is no
thousands or milliions of years here, the
conventional interpretations used to prop
up the ideas of an old earth collapse upon
scientific investigation.  All of these facts,
however, can fit in well within a global
catastrophe like Noah's flood.
With all of my talk both on this program
and in my CrEvo rants that evolution must
violate the scientific and natural law of
biogenesis, TheScienceFoundation has
repeatedly tried to "educate me"  by
claiming that Louis Pasteur actually
disproved a form of creationism and that
the law of biogenesis only applies to
modern life. [Pasteur: HUH?"]
It's obvious he got this idea from Mark
Isaak's page on talk.organs, which says:
Now if your brain just locked up, don't
worry - this is a common side effect from
trying to understand illogical arguments.
To be clear on the matter, let us hear the
words of Pasteur himself on the subject:
Pasteur was precisely refuting the idea
that increasingly complex molecules
could form primitive life.  Apparently Isaak
and TheScienceFoundation are hoping
the laws of physics and nature were
DIFFERENT in the past.  That's wonderful
to speculate, but the onus is upon you
folks for demonstrating that life can form
from non-life, as the science that's
repeatable, observable, testable refutes
you.
But it also blows me away that both Isaak
and theScienceFoundation both claimed
that Pasteur actually refuted a form of
creationism.  Really?
In the words of Dr. Manny Rios:
Brock Lee said essentially the same thing:
Lee documents this well in his book
"Comparative Views on Origins."
It is a ludicrous statement to claim that
Pasteur refuted creation - read Pasteur's
comments yourself, he knew full well the
ramifications of his experiment. Every
form of creation that I know of claims that
life only comes from life. Now yes, we
claim that the first life arose from outside
of nature, but in the end, that is exactly
what evolution must also contend,
because the first life has to arise in direct
violation of scientific and natural laws -
therefore if it violates natural laws, it must
be SUPERnatural, or outside of the
natural realm!
Ironically, both Isaak and
thesciencefoundation have both claimed
elsewhere that evolution does not attempt
to explain the origin of life - so doesn't it
seem odd to you that they would
suddenly turn around and try to argue
against the law of biogenesis?
The first life had to have come from
outside of the natural realm - I would
suggest that first life was Jesus Christ,
the Creator.
[scary, dramatic music]
Wahoo! Mail for me?
Theot58 wrote in for last week's show:
Eagleeye2102 was definitely appropriately
named, as they saw my subliminal
message in last weeks show:
Thanks for writing in, but apparently you
missed the fun from the week before, and
several shows back where I showed how
all of the alleged fish-tetrapod
intermediates were invalidated, both by
tetrapod footprints found in Poland, as
well as the tetrapod footprints in the
bottom of Grand Canyon, which John
Mackay publicized back in 1987 -
Footprints in rocks evolutionarily dated as
525 million years old, which I also went
and investigated several years ago.  These
clear tetrapod footprints predate the
alleged fishapods by some 130 million
years!  Those fossil footprints are only
one small part of the literally tons of
evidence FOR creation, and refuting
Evolutionism that you are apparently
unaware of.
No, you are talking about pseudoscience.
Apparently you missed the point I was
making: If a prediction is made based on
evolution, as I showed in the previous
show, it fails the predictions miserably.
Evolution would not predict tetrapod
footprints in 525 million year old rock!  But
rather than concede that evolution is
wrong, evolution is then made to FIT the
evidence, no matter what the evidence is!
Therefore, evolution is not scientific
because it is not falsifiable.
Several people commented on the
interesting report of the slowing spin of
Venus:
Your analogy breaks down horribly!  We're
not talking about a 1 degree temperature
change here. We're talking about a
rotation change of 6-1/2 minutes in 16
years! Secondly, I never said the slowing
was constant, I merely pointed out the
implications if it was. And isn't it amazing
how quickly the skeptics will abandon
uniformity when it doesn't meet their
purposes.
The science foundation also jumped on
this one, and was put in his place by T
Chapman500:
Indeed, the physics are quite simple -
such alleged impacts would destroy the
planet, and if there was a continuing
barrage of small impacts slowing it down
or spinning it retrograde, then we
SHOULD SEE EVIDENCE OF THIS, as the
slowing has persisted even in the past 16
years.
Thank you for writing in herbiepop
Very interesting you predicted that
Orenotter, and glad to see your
predictions shown true.
Well that's it for this week, I'm your host
Ian Juby, I hope you'll join me next
Thursday.  Please subscribe up above and
use the convenient "share" button down
below to post this video on twitfaceplus,
or to embed it in your blog or website!  Let
us remember the words of our Creator,
the Lord Jesus Christ, who said : I am the
Way the Truth and THE LIFE, no man
comes to the father but through me." See
you on the flip side.
[music]
Production Software was provided for
Genesis Week by the Big Valley Creation
Science Museum, located just 25 minutes
north of Drumheller, Alberta. In the heart
of the dinosaur badlands, the Big Valley
Creation Science Museum was built from
the ground up to give credit to our
Creator, portraying the scientific evidence
showing that creation is the faith that fits
the facts, and that evolution is the faith
that the facts have failed.
Visit BVCSM.com for more details.