that you know
who you love,
you can't deny it.
Or go back,
or give up,
or pretend
that you don't buy it.
When it's clear this time
you've found the one,
you'll never let him go
'cause you know
and you know
that you know.
When you feel
in your skin,
in your bones,
and the hollow
of your heart,
there's no way
you can wait
'til tomorrow.
When there isn't any doubt about it
once you come this close
'cause you know
and you know
that you know.
You can feel
love's around you
like the sky
'round the moon.
This is how
love has found you,
now you know
what to do.
When you know
that you know
who you need,
you can't deny it
or go back,
or give up,
or pretend
that you don't buy it.
When it's clear this time
you've found the one,
you'll never let him go
'cause you know
and you know
that you know.
Hmmm...
And it's time
you come in
from the cold.
Haaa...
And you know
that you know.