Let me tell you why you're here. You're here because you know something.
What you know you can't explain, but you feel it. You've felt it your entire life.
That there's something wrong with the world. You don't know what it is,
but itís there like a splinter in your mind driving you mad.
It is this feeling that has brought you to me.
This is your last chance, after this there's no turning back.
You take the blue bill, the story ends you wake up in your bed and believe
whatever you want to believe. You take the red pill, you stay in wonderland
and I show you how deep the rabbit hole goes.
Remember, all I'm offering is the truth, nothing more.
Follow me.
This isn't real.
What is real? How do you define real? If you're talking about
what you can feel what you can smell what you can taste and see then real
is simply electrical signals interpreted by your brain.
It's all about frequency compatibility, vibrational compatibility. If you are in a human
body and you're vibrating to a certain frequency um and here someone wants
to possess that body and is vibrating to a very different frequency, it's very
difficult to make that connection and therefore takeover the mental and emotional
faculties of that human body if you like. If you can create a genetic hybrid
then that vibrational compatibility becomes very much closer and therefore
very much more effective in terms of possession. So what has happened is
there has been this interbreeding which created these hybrid bloodlines and
this is the origin of the divine right to rule. The divine right to rule "what is that?"
It's the right to rule because of your bloodline because of your DNA. So these
hybrids became known  and their known in history as the demi-gods, part human part gods.
Gods were just other dimensional entities. And they became the kings the queens,
the emperors of the ancient world. Who claim this right because of their special bloodline
Royal dictatorship started to be resisted by the people and the royal dictatorship
started to fall. What happened is these bloodlines moved out of overt royal
dictatorship. They're still in there, the Winsorís in Britain and the Spanish
royal family and all these others. But they moved then into what I call the
dark suit professions as they've become. They moved into politics, they moved into
banking and business and all this stuff. They're in there anyway but they moved in much more
powerfully. So when you look at the transnational corporations and the major
and most powerful and influential politicians, and those that control the oil cartel, and the drug
cartel and all the rest of it, you're looking at this hybrid bloodlines. In effect, it's a software program
if you want to see the body as a computer as I do. And you want to know who they
are because you know if you got this bloodline itís like a computer program
or a computer in the sense that you got files in your computer but they donít affect the screen
the reality unless you open the file. So you go through life and these files don't affect you,
but there are certain ways that you can open these files and then bring that perception, that attitude
that behavior that personality of that file onto the screen. In other words, in the way
people behave in everyday life. And they do this with the secret society ritual.
This is why they'll target someone, the person won't realize why they've been targeted.
They might thing that "Oh they just think I'm good and they're supporting me
and sponsoring me." Powerful people suddenly sponsors people to progress
very quickly in law or politics, or stuff. People like Blair is a classic.
And then as they progress through this sponsorship and support, they get pulled
into the secret society network is all part of it, and then they go through
the secret society initiation rituals which often they have not a clue what they're about.
They're just rituals are they. Just tradition. But what's happening is these rituals
that are designed to tease open these files which they know they've got cause
they've got the bloodline in there. And then as these files open so they have more
and more effect on the personality, the screen of the person involved and there personality
changes. And you watch this classic example, you can see it around the world. You
watch people who for instance come into politics with a certain sometimes genuine
desire to change things and then eventually, as they progress into power, they
become absolutely everything that they entered politics to challenge. And It's
not always for this reason, but many times it is this reason that as this genetic
files have been opened, more and more and more, suddenly it's affecting their
personality and they're now becoming a behavioral perception expression of this
hybrid DNA. And they start to operate with that hybrid DNA in terms of their behavior
and attitudes. DNA databases now allow a highly sophisticated way of finding out
who's got the bloodline and who hasn't. Everybody is broadcasting, vibrating
to a certain frequency. Were in the same frequency range, otherwise we couldn't
see each other, but there's subtle differences between everybody, we always have
our unique vibrational code. If you know what that code is, and if you want
target that person with vibrational interference on a physical, emotional and
mental level, mind control I'm talking about with the latter one. Then you can target
them specifically on their unique frequency. Once you have the DNA you can
work out what that frequency is, so that's another reason why they want
DNA database. It's not for catching criminals, they arenít interested in catching
criminals. Criminals for them are just other ways, the highest level I'm
talking about, are just other ways to justify more and more control to protect
the people from criminals. They don't want a society that without crime without
violence without terrorism, is worst nightmare. How do you impose an Orwellian
State on a society of harmony? You can't do it. You can only do it on a society that
is divided and ruled and in fear of everything. That's why we have the society we do.
Watch US television fawning Fox CNN CBS all of them ìOH it's so wonderful, no one in America
can wait until next week." The way they're hyping it.
One week until the royal wedding this is an exciting stuff I mean itís hard to
I mean the energy is just palpable.
Young couples get married they're just hoping that some bank will be nice enough to
give them a mortgage. These folks have a number of palaces to pick from.
NBC news is launching a free Royal Wedding App for the I pad.
This is truly a love story that captures everybody's attention.
This goes back to Edward Bernays a hundred years ago saying look, to make politicians
and royalty popular we'll have Hollywood stars come to banquets and events with them.
We'll have music stars, we'll have other people go there to basically make these
elites be seen as celebrities themselves.
In the books of the Tibetan Contour
The contour consists of over a thousand volumes containing the holy texts of
Lamaism. The resulting translations are full of references to gods appearing in the sky. Of aluminous
pearls and transparent spheres in which they lived.
The search for humanities first possible contact with alien beings in prehistoric times leads
to an unlikely place, to the bibles earliest chapters, to the book of Genesis.
There were giants in the Earth in those days. And also after that when the sons of God
came into the daughters of men and they bore children to them. Genesis 6-4
While most English bibles use the word giants, the original Hebrew word is Nephilim.
In translation of the word Nephilim is the men who came down or those who came down meaning
those who came down from the sky. So it may not mean that they are physical giants. They
could just be something like great heroes that came down from the sky and produced a hybrid race.
If you say that Jehovah is an ET then that changes the basis of Judaism and Christianity
in a very fundamental way.
For many ancient Christians the book of Enoch was essential yet it was banned from the
Christian bible.
We don't know why this literature was ultimately excluded from the canon perhaps itís because
of its description of the fall of the rebel angels and their mating with mortals. Perhaps
it's understanding of the End of Time fell out of favor with Jews and Christians.
As with the story in Genesis, God blames this evil on the sons of God. Angels who
lusted over the daughters of man.
These angels are sometimes referred to as watchers they keep constant watch and they decide
one day, about 200 of them that theyíre going to descend to the Earth.
They would like to very much make contact with these mortal women.
The book of Enoch may have been an attempt to expand on the mysteries giants, the sons
of God and the daughters of the Earth spoken of in Genesis.
Anytime you read the book of Genesis there are all kinds of unanswered questions
Suddenly there is this quick few verses in the beginning of the flood story about giants in the
land that come from the sons of God mixing with the daughters of the Earth and you stop and
think wait a minute what's this all about. It's like it went by too fast and you want to grab it
and say wait a minute what was this.
And they began to go into them and defile themselves with them and taught them charms
and enchantments. And they became pregnant and they bore great giants who's height was
three thousand elves. And when men could no longer sustain them the giants turned against
the men devoured mankind.
That these angels had crossed this boundary that they shouldn't have when they decided
to descend upon Earth, this unleashed upon the Earth all sorts of problems. Not only
these giants who are blood-thirsty and violent but also these angel went on to teach human
kind a variety of forbidden crafts. They also taught human beings how to make weapons of war.
The Maya and Incas of South America believed a race of giants existed on Earth before the
great flood. So did many other ancient civilizations. Some took them for gods others left
likenesses of them in stone or wrote about them in their histories.
As long as six thousand years ago another remarkable civilization evolved. It's people were the
Sumerians who had an extraordinarily advanced culture.
There lists of first just almost sounds like a whole list of our whole society. They had the first
bicameral congress, they had the first writings, they had the first school systems and you know
and you just go on and on and on. So you have to ask where did all this come from and I think
that you need to turn to the ancient Sumerians themselves and listen very carefully to what they
have to say because what they have to say not just in one place but over and over and over again
is that they were taught civilization by these beings that came from the heavens to the Earth
And the pictorial evidence left behind by the Sumerians going back six thousand years speak and
depict a people who came from another planet I call Nibiru. And many of the depictions show
them much bigger at least by a third more than the average human beings so they were giants.
This Sumerian cylinder seal is astonishing for several reasons.
First it depicts our solar system with the sun at the center and planets arrayed around it.
A fact not known to European science until around 300 years ago.
And amazingly there's another planet, which the Sumerians called Nibiru and believed that it
was from where the Anunaki or celestial giants came from.
The ancient Sumerian text in a very broad overview basically tell us that more than 400 thousand
years ago that these Anunaki came from space and landed on the Earth in the Tigers Ufraties valley.
They began to set up a colony that they called E-den.
According to Genesis, E-den or Eden is where Adam was created from dust and Eve from one
of his ribs. Others however have a more hi-tech version of how human life began.
In time needing men-power needing workers jumped the gun on evolution using genetic
engineering
and they produced a hybrid.
Legend has it that when the Anunaki came back after several thousand years to see how
their genetic handiwork had turned out, they found the Earth females irresistibly attractive.
Thatís us. Basically the Anunaki said in their writings that the Sumerians left behind, we should make
the Adamove, they called their slave servant Adamove plural which comes to us now in the
bible as the Adam. We should make the Adamove in our own image after our own likeness and
they did that
Now wait a minute are you saying that we
the modern race of people were genetically engineered by a super-human race of aliens
that came from another planet
and that we look like them. In the cylinder seals
that we have the five thousand or so cylinder seals that we have out of the Sumerian culture
depicting gods and humans on the same cylinder seal at the same time they always look
the same. How did we lose 2 chromosomes all primates have 48 chromosomes we have 46
that is an awful a lot of DNA where did it.. if you read the Sumerian text the Anunaki flourished
from around 400 thousand years ago and by the way they called their where they lived in the Tigers
Ufratis valley the E-den. That was their word for where they lived
Well we've heard Adam and we've heard Eden.
Well it turns out a lot of the old testament is an attempt to rewrite the Sumerian Epics
of creation cause they were considered the guys with the word.
We have to break here.
And these ancient cultures they all have their stories of this interbreeding between a
reptilian race, and itís not all reptilian but it seems to be a predominant factor, and humans.
In fact, the ancient emperors of China used to claim the right to be emperor because of their
descendants from the serpent gods. Everywhere you find this reference in different phrases and names
to the serpent gods.
And out of here the Sumer, Egypt, Babylon area came some of the most significant bloodlines
which then moved up across the world to become the ruling controlling families of today.
In 1851 in what is now known as Iraq, archeologist and explorer Sir Austin Henry Leyard
discovered a library of 22 thousand tablets containing what know to be the earliest writings
on Earth. The writings date back to over 6 thousand years ago when the region was known as
Mesopotamia, Sumer, and Babylon. Amongst these vast writings is a story that mirrors
the book of Genesis in the bible. It tells a story of a great flood which reshaped the face of
the planet Earth and all her inhabitants. It tells a story of a tower built at the creation of
the spoken word.
In Japan emperors claim decent from dragon gods that came from the sky. Australian aborigines
teach of a reptilian race that lives underneath the Earth and governs over man. They believe they are
descendants of a race of dragon humans. China teaches the serpent queen Nukua interbred with man
India calls these reptilian gods Nagas, and claim they seeded their royal families. Throughout
the middle east it is believed a serpent race created man. The book of Genesis tells of giants
who came from the heavens to breed with the daughters of man. There called the Niphilim.
In Africa they call them Chitari, children of the serpent.
The royal kings of Africa claim decent from serpent gods who came from the sky.
In South America the Mayans teach that their ancestors were the people of the serpent.
Aztecs were said to be created by a serpent woman.
In America the Hopi Indians believe sky gods came to Earth to breed with their women and
refer to them as their snake brothers. The word Su means snakes, and iracoi means serpents
It seems the only places you will not find this historical story is where the history has been
methodically destroyed.
The descendants from king Anu in Sumeria and Babylon can be traced throughout time.
The pharaohs of Egypt were from the bloodlines of the Babylonian kings. The rulers of the
Roman Empire can be traced to Egyptian hierarchy. All throughout Europe the royal families
can be traced back to the great roman emperors. 34 of the presidents of the United
States are directly descendant from European royalty with the remaining 8 who are only closely
related to these same bloodlines. In 1934 president Franklin D Roosevelt placed the great
seal originally created in 1782 by the freemasons, on the dollar bill. Represented in the great
seal is the pyramid and the all seeing eye known to be used by the illusive society the Illuminati
Strung together in conspiratorial confusion are secret societies such as the Illuminati, the freemasons
and the bohemian club. In 1917 national geographic did a story on a place in Monte Rio California
called Bohemian Grove. The story reports a place where worldís elite members of the Bohemian
Club retreat to in late July and conduct and ancient occult ceremony called the cremation of care.
The alter is at the base of a 200 foot owl the Babylonian symbol of the god Molech, the god of
human sacrifice. In the video, a body is delivered up river where it is set on fire.
Upon being aired members of the bohemian club reported that the ceremony is a put-on
merely done for entertainment and fun. This history tells a story of our world leaders having
a deep involvement in Satanic tradition, worshiping our reptilian overloads, serpent gods.
It poses the possibility that we may be and have always been enslaved by our leaders
no different than sheep or cattle. There is an endless amount of information that supports
this. But donít take my word for it.
Members of the major religious organizations, how are they conspiring together towards a
global agenda, in your opinion
Well I donít think that 99.9% of people in the religions are conspiring
together, but if you go high enough to those that ultimately control those religions thatís when the
conspiracy comes in. And very very few understand those connections because it's essential to the
conspiracy unfolding unchallenged for even those that are making contributions to it everyday
not to realize that thatís what theyíre doing. So they structure everything and religion is exactly
the same, as pyramids compartmentalized pyramids. So if you look at the any organization today
including Christianity or Islam or any of it, theyíre structured as pyramids and pyramids within pyramids
so the vast majority are in the body of the pyramid and they have been manipulated to believe that
their religion is true and their God is the only God, and all that stuff. And their truth is the only truth
and everyone else must be wrong and then you keep going up and up and up and up and right at the top
of the pyramid you got the tiny few people who are actually orchestrating the whole deal. And they understand
that the religion the religious belief in whatever religion it is, is just a front for something else.
And that something else is the something else behind all at least all the major religion a lot of the non-
major religions, so Christianity and Islam and Judaism and all that stuff ultimately come from the same
source and are controlled by the same source. So if you go back to the ancient world and you pick up the
sun-god moon-goddess religion which was predominant around the world you will have Christians
and Muslims and stuff that would reject them, the goddess sun god religion that actually their religions
are just another version of it. There just hidden behind different names and behind different structures
but behind itís the same thing. If you look at the way they depicted for instances just a throw away thing,
the way they depicted the sun-god and the moon-goddess in the middle east thousands of years ago
itís the international symbol of Islam today, the moon and the star the sun. if you look at the background to
Christianity you see that Jesus was just another version of the sun god like mythra and tamos in Babylon, and
so many others dyonisis, Bacchus, the same story was told about them thousands of years before Christianity
that was told about Jesus, they've just put the story in another historical setting and changed the names.
And Jesus is a symbol for the sun, this is why what was said about him and the way he's depicted is a mirror
of the way they depicted Horus, the symbol of the sun in ancient Egypt. How they did for Tamus, symbol of the
sun in ancient Babylon. And wherever you go you find that these religions are different versions of the sun-god
moon-goddess religion which is the religion of those who are conspiring to bring about this Orwellian state.
Then you go a step further and you look into these rituals in freemasonry and the background to freemasonry
and other secret societies that connect into it. Like the Jesuits etc.,  just look at the Jesuits logo itís a sun.
And you find again and again in freemasonry that one of their prime symbols if not the prime symbol is the sun.
And so what you're looking at within the secret societies is another version of the ancient sun-god moon-goddess
religion which is their focus of worship, which is the same focus of worship when you look behind the cover
story of these major religions, and yet the major religions certainly Christianity on the surface condemn
freemasonry and all that stuff, and yet theyíre all different masks on the same face, and so again when you
take the pyramids up, the compartmentalized pyramid, and you reach the top you find that the same few
what they call elite families, interbreeding families, bloodlines are controlling Christianity, Judaism, Islam, freemasonry
Hinduism, you look at Hinduism again they are worshiping the same gods from the Vedic history as is
worshiped in other forms by the western religions. And so itís one religion including the secret societies
but the religions at the base of the pyramid where people see them in society are presented in different
a way but itís all the same score and its all the same gods that they are and you know you go back to
the original writings for the bible itís not talking about a singular god that came in the translation, they're
talking about gods, and so are the Hindu religions and all the rest of it. So were looking at the same structure
in belief and worship thatís packaged in different ways. And Of course once you re-package it, then you can play
the different packages off against each other, dividing and rule the general population as religions
fight and they argue and all this stuff over whoís right and i got the truth and you've not got the truth,
And up there theyíre on their kind of on their backs with their legs in the air absolutely in hysterics whatís
going on down here cause they know itís all the same thing theyíre arguing about. And of course
if you look at religion itís been used in such a massively effective way in terms of advancing this agenda.
First of all you go divide and rule which any small group trying to control a massive group has to divide and rule
a massive rule to have any chance of success. But theyíre also selling belief systems which are different
packages of the same belief system and those belief systems when you take them on they close the mind
down and they wall off they firewall off the mind because anything outside of the belief system must be
wrong so they wonít look at it so youíve turned someone into a person of tunnel vision and tunnel
belief. and what we believe we perceive, we edit reality by based on what we believe and you can see this
because you know when youíre having a conversation with someone who has a real preconceived belief
about you and youíre having a conversation and youíre saying things to them and you siting there and you
say "I never said that! I never said that"
"Oh you did you did"
Because what's happening is, you are saying things and it goes through the belief of the receiver
the 'preconceived belief about you' system and it edits what's coming in by the time they consciously
hear it. They are hearing what youíre saying in a way that confirms and underpins their preconceived
belief about you. And so once you take on a rigid belief you edit your reality  and perception
through that belief. So Christianity goes into Africa, it goes into Australia, it goes into North America
and it destroys or as much as it could the thousands of years of knowledge and understanding
that has been passed through that culture and imposes upon it the rigid beliefs of Christianity.
Therefore taking out, because anything that was not about the rigid beliefs of Christianity
"Itís the devil" you know. I mean Credo Mutwa the Zulu shaman in south Africa, great great friend
of mine wonderful wonderful man. He was beaten silly as a kid for depicting Jesus as a black man.
In a painting you know and he tells the story of how the Jesuits and all these people went into Africa
and it became a crime to talk about or certainly to believe the ancient African knowledge thatís
come through the centuries through the shamanistic screens, and destroying the ancient knowledge
of reality of history which we really to have access to to get another fix on how we can look at the world
and history in a different way, outside of the official history which has been written simple to get people to
see the world and where weíve come from in a way that suits the agenda, so religion is just a fantastic
weapon for this conspiracy we're talking about.
And there is corruption even amongst the family of prophet Mohamed because unfortunately
like it happened with Jesus, like it happened with Moses, like it happened with every single messenger
of life on this planet, the day after they're dead they already start making their own way making their
own changes to the religion to manipulate whatever the message was and adapt it to their own you know
their own situation. I mean these messengers obviously come for a specific mission.
Well the next thing on from the connections between religions and secret societies and the gods that
they worship is Satanism because that's just another arm of this. This might be controversial to the
believers in the religions and stuff youíve got the ancient gods which were translated into God
which are worshiped by the religions unknowingly most of them. Same with the secret societies and the
same "gods" demonic entities as theyíre called in this case that are worshiped by the Satanists are the same
gods that are worshiped by the secret societies and the religions unknowingly, in Satanism its knowingly
and these gods these non-human entities operate just outside the frequency range of human sight what is
known as visible light, itís so important for people to understand that when they look through their eyes their
not seeing everything that exists in the space theyíre looking at, we call space anyway, theyíre looking at
merely a tiny frequency range that our five senses can access. Itís like a television station, itís like a holographic
television station, and its sharing the same space as all the other realities what increasingly the cutting edge
of mainstream science is calling parallel universes, see each other thereís a wireless internet in this room
but were not aware of it, but you get a computer and you tune it into that wireless internet suddenly
out of the ether out where comes the internet on your computer screen, and this physical form
this body computer as i call it tunes us in to a certain frequency range which is what we perceive through the
five senses but in the same space are other frequency range other dimensions of reality which are sharing
the same space, now most of the time were not aware of them just like television stations are not aware
of each other but of course in a situation you might tune into a radio station and its very very close to another
station you get interference where the two radio stations interact with each other and thatís what can happen
with these realities where thereís another reality thatís really really close on the frequency scale, there can
actually be a crossing over between the two, and a satanic ritual one of the reasons they do it one of them
is to create an energy environment through the way a ritual is conducted which allows like a vibrational window
a doorway to open which allows these entities to enter the ritual. I've talked to endless people around
the world who've seen this, actually experienced this suddenly this seriously horrible often entity looking
entity appears in the so-called magic circle which is a vibrational field thatís what it is. You know they
donít use these pentagrams and stuff just for fun, some of them might the lower ones who don't really
understand it but the ones who are really involved that understand the way reality works and how you can
manipulate it these pentagrams and these various symbols used in Satanism, like the reversed pentagram
is the classic satanic symbol and the circle around it, they are vibrational fields thatís why they do these
rituals and the entity can enter this reality the range of visible light in other words what we can see
within that vibrational field and suddenly the gods appear. These gods as they're perceived feed off human
energy, they feed off low vibrational human energy, low vibrational emotional energy all round based
on fear, stressed, hatred, guilt, all these things these low vibrational emotions and another way they feed
off human energy is by human sacrifice. What they do in the sacrifice is they'll have the victim and they'll
go through this ritual and they build up the ritual to gain maximum terror from the victim so now there's
tremendous energy not just of fear, but of absolute terror and then the point of sacrifice that energy is
released massively and these "gods" that are operating just outside human sight, feed off of that energy
because that terror that low vibrational energy represents the energy field that they are vibrating to and
therefore they can absorb that energy, they can't absorb the higher dimensional energy they have to have low
vibrational energies. Look at society its structured to create massive fear, stress all these things from the
population and its feeding these quote gods
and that enters the bloodstream at the point of sacrifice
and then these sick people drink the blood cause itís got that adrenaline it gives them this rush
what shocked me when i started to understand this and investigate this was the scale of it the SCALE
is astonishing, and thereís people in America who've been involved their careers and things like the FBI
investigating it in America and one of them said it is on such a scale Satanism that if you have a reasonably
wide circle of friends, associates and acquaintances you will know Satanist who's involved in this stuff.
Now when you start relating this stuff to history you come across this common theme everywhere of making
sacrificial offerings to the gods of animals and of young virgins the young virgins sacrificed to the gods you
find it everywhere. Of course in places like the Aztec period in central America they were doing it bloody on
mass thousands of sacrifices and what was that? It was merely what is happening today. Is prepubescent
pre-sexual activity energy. Thatís why they want children. Thatís why you had the young virgins sacrificed,
they were kids! that's why they do it today for this very reason, and there are certain points where there are
vortexes within the Earth energy field and these vortexes as they spin theyíre basically places where the
connection between this dimension and other dimensions is much thinner much closer because of the nature
of the vortex. Itís basically spinning two dimensions together in affect and so if you do the rituals on these
vortexes then it is much easier energetically to manifest and bring out these gods into manifestation the other
thing about the vortexes is is they are points where lots of, the big vortexes anyway, where lots of lay lines,
meridian lines, energy lines, cross so what you do on those lines for a start is sourced by very powerful energies
cause basically you got electricity grids coming in from the point of several directions to where youíre doing the
ritual so youíre dealing with a powerful energy field which is what you want to achieve your outcome and also
what you do at that point in terms of the energy that you create of hatred and terror and all these things that then
goes through these lines from that point and youíre actually affecting the global grid by doing that. In terms of
places where this goes on I can only talk about people that I've spoken to and things that I've
come across. Certainly a lot of the major royal palaces are built on these prime sacrificial spots.
In the first years of the 21st century
a third world war broke out
those of us who survived knew mankind could never survive
a fourth
that our own volatile natures could simply no longer be risked.
So we have created a new arm of the law. The grammaton cleric
whose soul task it is to seek out and eradicate the true source of man's inhumanity to man
His ability
to feel
When the shadows, the whole world is controlled by the same force. Is that which is able
to understand the way the human computer works, the way the human mind works the way
the human emotions work that hidden shadow level that center of the web level they know
that this is all an illusion that this is a holographic illusion it only exists in our head and
therefore they can manipulate what we think our emotional state and how we see the world
and ourselves because they understand how the computer works. It's basically like if you get
a new personal computer you stick it on the desk you donít know anything about computers
what do you do? you know you turn it on you might find an on switch and flip it about a bit
you might find this and open this and oh whatís this... itís all very limited. And then a computer
programmer walks in who knows absolutely how that computer works and he can do anything
on it. That analogy sums up the human plight in the sense that this is a holographic biological
computer and the vast majority of people in the world have no idea it's even a computer
never mind how it really works and where theyíre thoughts and emotions are coming from and how
theyíre manifesting reality but the spider in the center of the web does and it has structured society
it has structured communication, it has constructed the information that we are receiving in the
computer which were downloading to impose upon us a completely false reality that allows us to be
computer like sheep rather than the infinite genius we really are if we could only break out of this
computerized control thatís being imposed upon us. So the spider is not operating at the same level
of knowledge as we are, not least because although this knowledge existed in the far ancient world
the spider has manipulated events so that knowledge has been sucked out of mainstream society
and held only by the few that pass it on through the highest and i mean highest levels of the secret
society networks and so making people aware of this knowledge of the nature of reality the nature
of who we are is fundamental to setting people free of the control that theyíre being subjected to
because you know we can work on the level of banking scams, political scams, manipulated wars,
manipulated 911s and we should because we need to know that but if thatís all were doing in terms
of communicating knowledge then basically were operating in a cycle of this is the problem but how
the hell do we get out of this. We will never know how to set ourselves free until we understand the nature
of who we bloody-well are. How do you set yourself free if you donít even know who you are? How do you set
yourself free when you donít even know the nature of reality that youíre living in and manifesting and making
happen without your knowledge that youíre making it happen, you cant. So alongside the information about
the five sense level of this conspiracy if you like, we have to just as powerfully i would say more powerfully
communicate the nature of reality and how we are creating our reality and how we are allowing it to be
created for us by having ourselves programmed with certain beliefs and certain perceptions all the time
the two must go together otherwise, were never going to get out of this. and uh.. so itís a big task to get this
stuff out but, because youíre not telling people anything you donít already know. If I tell you that thatís a computer
and you're infinite consciousness I'm not telling you anything you donít already know. Iím telling you what youíve
forgotten because what happens is you come into this world and with this knowledge suppressed. It's like
someone once said, can you imagine you come into the world and someone tells you that 2 and 2 equals 5
your parents tell you that from an earliest age 2 and 2 equals 5 you then go to kindergarten and nice teachers
tell you that 2 and 2 equals 5. You then go to school and teachers junior school senior school they tell you
2 and 2 equals 5. By now all your mates have been through the same system theyíre telling you 2 and 2 equals
5 and if you say it equals 4 they laugh at you. You then go to university, professors with letters after their names
mustaches, they say 2 and 2 equals 5 you know, oh no it equals 4, noooo Iíve been doing this for fifty years
I've met all the best brains in the world, it equals 5 that boy will not go far. And then you turn the tele on
"hey good evening, 2 and 2 equals 5... now the weather" right? Um.. Thereís a good chance that you'll go through the
whole of your life believing 2 and 2 equals 5 but it still equals 4. And when, and what this information of the nature of
reality is doing, basically its saying "do you remember 2 and 2 ... 4" "OHHH YEESSS" and this is why this has such an
impact on people when they are.. they hear it something goes "this is true ahh this is true" because theyíre remembering
it. We are in a world in which the vast majority of the population is in an amnesic state, they are in a hypnotic
trance because they have been implanted with false information about themselves and the world ever since they arrived.
Sat around a table and you said "right what we need to do is we need to find some way of getting young people
to see the world in the way we want them to see it so by the time they become adults they are completely following
the reality we want them to believe in" someone might say "well they might not have it like, but you know the ideal thing?
what we do is we have a system where we take children away from their parents at least five days a week all day from about
the age of four and five and we have control of their minds until theyíre about seventeen eighteen, that would be ideal"
But of course that's what happens itís called the education system and its indoctrination. We have two hemispheres
in the brain, the left brain which is about words and this world reality and you know the perception of this reality
we have the right brain which is where you get creativity, inspiration, and connection and then you got this corpus
callosum with connect the two. First of all we use the fraction of our brain why is that? And the other thing is is what
the system does is it turns out left brain prisoners they run the system and it does it by putting information through
schools and colleges and universities into the left brain which it then says at time of an exam "give me all that back
and if you tell me what Iíve told you well enough to believe then you'll pass the exam and you'll be very successful"
anyone that takes that information into the right brain and puts their spin on it or questions it or sees through it
and puts that in the exam they are perceived as a disruptive influence in the classroom and so what happens is for
you to become a doctor, overwhelmingly a politician, a journalist, someone often in industry, all these areas that
control the system the professions the
professions, lawyers I mean on and on we go
you have to of gone through your young life constantly taking information into your left brain and regurgitating it
out on exam papers. To become a teacher you have to go through that process then you go through teacher training
college where youíre taught how to do it to others, then you let loose on the children. The whole system is run by
left brain prisoners and if you look at the school system things like music and art that stimulate this side of the brain
the uniqueness they are constantly cut back in favor of left brain curriculums. And this is systematic, I have to get
this over to people, this is not systematic at the level of you know people who administer it into reality. It is
coldly calculated in the shadowy areas where these concepts first come from and they know what theyíre doing.
Yea these examinations, whatís happening is that you know to fit in to be part of the so called in crowd you have to
reconfirm the beliefs of the hierarchy.
You know when youíre watching the teli (TV) your mind goes into the same brainwave state as you do in a hypnotic
trance and what happens when youíre in a hypnotic trance with a hypnotist? He plants subliminal subconscious messages
which implant a false reality "Oh the audience is laughing but what theyíre laughing at? This is an apple I can taste it"
Itís a potato "no its a potato" the implanted belief is itís an apple so thatís what you are getting. Now symbolically thatís
whatís happened to the world. The human population is eating a potato thinking itís an apple because theyíve been told
from birth to death itís a freakin apple, it isnít.
People think that hypnosis is some mysterious esoteric thing, and itís not itís just simply a mental transaction
in which a person has focused their attention, theyíve stopped being critical and theyíre more open to suggestion
If someone is looking for people to hypnotize they know that 85 out of 100 are going to be able to go into some level of trance.
Hypnosis is a natural way of inducing a trance like state and we all have the ability to enter into trance.
At many times during every day of our lives we slip into trance-like states where we become absorbed in watching the Television.
The first order of business for a propagandist or an advertiser is to create the circumstances that will induce a state of mind
that is favorable to the reception of their message and that state of mind is the hypnotic state of mind making television
extremely important in this whole process of creating the unified mind-set amongst the entire population.
Television is a massive massive... Mass hypnotist to the global mind, and what happens is it is implanting a belief
in reality by the minute and then once we take on that belief implanted when information enters the eyes we edit
it on the basis of that belief and so what the global population is subjecting or is subjected, to suffering from, is
actually literally mass hypnosis and when people, when we talk about people who start to see things see the manipulation
they couldnít see before, what do we say about them? what do they say about themselves?
"I woke up!" exactly what theyíve done. When people start to go "hey I can see it now" itís like someone has gone
along like the hypnotist and clicked their fingers and itís like "oh i can see it now" mass hypnosis and that
is the greatest hypnotist on the planet, and thatís the basis of why it was created.
[TV] "forty nine unidentified man went berserk last night..."
Where does she get her view of
the world? Who will be her role model? What values will she have? Who's child is she?
Yours or the networks?
Take back your children
turn off the TV
And when you start to research the subliminals in advertising and television what staggers you is not
what they do and whatís there, but the scale of it... our consciousness is being hit by an explosion of this stuff
because you see this is a very interesting point. Experiments have shown that about one and a half seconds
before the conscious mind decides to take action and moves its arms or whatever, speak, one in a half seconds
before it consciously decides to do that the electrical signals have begun in the brain to do it
For me the conscious level is the experiencer and observer of reality but the subconscious is the creator of it
the generator of it and this is why the illuminati want the subconscious mind through subliminals. What does
subliminals mean it means below threshold, itís below the threshold the conscious mind picks up but the
subconscious mind picks everything up like a sponge, and therefore they are planting these thoughts into the
subconscious which then filters down into the conscious and we think weíre having our own thoughts when actually
theyíre implanted thoughts done at a subliminal level
If you think about it whenever you hear
news broadcasters speak you realize that their speak pattern is similar to the pattern-speech of the hypnotist
the news broadcaster looks directly into the camera and directly into the eyes of the viewer, another hypnotic trick
Terror experts are working around the clock to head off any new attempt to attack America and theyíre concerned that
in the not so distant future terrorists could easily blend in with the US population. Bob Wore now on Al-Qaidaís
latest tactics. US officials are increasingly worried that the next attack on America could be carried out by American
branded terror. Report will be released here in Washington tomorrow. It concludes that homegrown terrorism
is the rise in this country and one of the most significantly contributing factors remains the internet. My question for
you is this, I heard that on the 17th of this month George passed the executive order that says if you protest the
Iraqi war you could have your assets [cut] Oh sorry about that, sorry to cut you off uh.. balloon town Connecticut
Without these key elements in their history the children were being socially engineered into another direction.
So weíve got several generations now where this kind of social engineering has perpetuated through the school systems
fortunately there are a number of people who became aware of this particularly when Bill Benet was the secretary
of education and had said that every child in this country should be taught by a Jesuit. The Jesuits are the intelligence
arm of the Vatican and was very much corrupted to bring what Adolf Hitler said was a way to mass mind control of
generations. It was Adolf Hitler who said that if there were any free thinkers in society he wasnít concerned because
he had control of the minds of the children through the education system. That was something that I heard bill Benet
quote himself in the application of the global education into this system... been head of our senator associations comity
which means that he decides how money is going to be spent and how itís going to be delegated and he has made sure
that more and more statesí rights are lost in favor of federal intervention and that was how global education was brought
into the school systems as state rights were overwritten. Mark and I just returned from Europe, like he was saying
we spoke in Germany and that was quite an experience and to see so many people who had been affected by
mind control directly who have seen it in their own families who are acutely aware of what social engineering is
in society. They know whatís happening in the United States theyíve been talking about it for years that I'm aware
of particularly on the education aspect because it was exactly what Hitler had implemented and they were recognizing
it. They were also recognizing also the erosion of our medical system and how we were becoming more and more
financially dependent in this state, and losing more and more of our individual rights to information control but the
compassion of people not only in Germany but all over the world where mark and I have been speaking out is very
encouraging. To go outside this country is like a whole new world. I mean itís such a privilege to see that people are
awake and aware. They know what mind control, they know that mind control has a firm grip on America right now
that there is a criminal faction in control of our government that is seeking to control the world and its inexcusable
that we continue to follow leaders that we didnít elect. We know that these people that are in place right now
werenít elected. They keep taking the elections. Consider that the electronic voting machines were manufactured by
key corporation one of the among the very very few that are actually controlling the media. They also manufactured
our voting machines and Dick Chaney is associated with that corporation much the same way is with Halliburton.
At that time George Romney was the governor of Michigan and he was very much interested in taking a very powerful
form of mind control gleaned from the Catholics taken from the Catholics taken from the CIA and the Hitler/Himmler
research and also into the technological advancements and put it into his Mormon church. George Romney was very
active and very high up in the Mormon church and they could foresee that as a strong opportunity for being able to lead
people by in a religious way. People are easily led by a religion because they do want to do what God tells them to do
but the religion that theyíre being taught is outside themselves when in fact spirituality and relationship with God
is within and yet religion can pull people down a path outside themselves where theyíre more easily led and controlled
particularly when systematic abuses are going on and MK ultra mind control, and technological advances are being
used as strong as they were in the Mormon church.
Thatís not to say all Mormons are bad. Thereís quite a few Mormons who are standing up once theyíre
able to think for themselves to make a positive difference and stop the abuse in their churches as well.
But thatís a little bit slower the devastation wreaked on people within the Mormon church is extensive
and is very much like the abuses that go on in the Jehovah's witnesses church that is just coming to light
where their mind control is so prevalent there as well and every time where the mind control is prevalent
there is always abuse and its usually sexual abuse of the children. We need to become aware of how people are being
led this way. When we have a politics that have no separation of church and state it allows for them to dictate or to
provide the information through the churches on a political agenda as well and is a very dangerous and very powerful
combination yet nevertheless itís all moving towards the same goal of a mind control of the masses in Mackinaw Island
Michigan I also heard George Romney talk about what is now known as global education where bringing the form
of mind control into the education system and altering the history and also pumping information into the childrenís head
at a rate to where they lose their ability discern and to creatively utilize the information but nevertheless itís just being
pumped into their head especially with the onset of computerization and harmonics coming through the headphones
while theyíre sitting at some of those computers. The computers were also deliberately designed to alter the history
that they were being taught because it was believed that to control the future all they needed to do is control the
history, again alter that knowledge base so that when they do formulate any thought or action itís based on something
thatís totally false or is something thatís lacking key elements such as mind control such as what really went on in
Nazi Germany. They knew how the mind responds to significant trauma. Combining the Hitler/Himmler research with what
the Catholics had learned, and taking it into a new level with through the CIA and through the technological advancements
that were beginning to come forth in society. We had television then which was having a strong impact on people
and gave them the ability to implement mass mind-control far stronger than Adolf Hitler could do and also through the
music because music was coming on so strong then and it was learned then how harmonics affect the brain function
as well. Itís like when you hear a specific song and you can remember something that had happened the first time you
ever heard that song. I heard people say that quite often well "i remember what happened um 'member when we
were in the car and this song came on and remember how we fell in love to that song" I mean people remember certain
events with music. Because the harmonic vibrations that affects the neuron pathways of the brain and allows for the
song lyrics to go in deeper. So harmonics were coming on real strong as well. In the early 60s project paperclip was
in full swing. The Nazi fascia scientists had been imported to the United States were put in key positions and
information was gleaned from them on what Adolf Hitler was using as mind control in Nazi Germany. This project paperclip
that brought the information in was being taken in by the CIA and criminal faction of the government that was very
much interested on how to control the mind of individuals as well as control the minds of a population more-so than
had occurred in Nazi Germany because those people had actually broke free of the Hitler plan to with the war but yet
the war was so traumatizing that it still left them unable to think for themselves to the point where they became
socially engineered. So thereís a great deal of information that was being brought into this country regarding the affects
of trauma on human mind. Itís well known that when trauma occurs people become highly suggestible. When traumas
occur in our societies such as what happened 9-1-1. This many people in this country PTSD'ed. They developed post
traumatic stress disorder, this PTSD left people unable to think clearly for themselves they were very fearful they were
very emotionally distraught over what had happened. And when theyíre not able to think clearly for themselves theyíre more
easily lead so when theyíre told what to do by the television while those horrible images are played over and over and over
again they become complaint they become apathetical and they become so easily led that America began to lose
some of its strength to the point where the criminals that have been control now for numerous generations took a
significant step forward in their control.
Someone said, this is the Kennedy assassination here, something very true. When you try to understand who was behind an
assassination look at who had the power to remove the security at the crucial time because he said assassinations donít just
happen they are allowed to happen. And when you look at the footage taken on a camera video camera by a member
of the public when Rabeen the Israeli prime minister was assassinated its extraordinary. You have the line of soldiers
lined up to protect Rabeen as he came to his car and in among them was the guy who killed him. As Rabeen appears
on this video extraordinary sight, the soldiers just walk backwards leaving the assassin on his own. Rabeen walks past
him thank you very much Good night. And itís the same with the Kennedy assassination and so many others.
This is the point where Kennedy was hit. This is Kennedyís car at the front.. thereís nobody on it. And yet you look at the car
behind which doesnít carry the president of the united states, thereís four security guards and two out-riders.
If theyíd of been there of course Kennedy could not have been killed by a bullet from outside cause he was so well
protected but the whole thing was removed the security to allow it to happen. During the last war in the
concentration camps of Germany in fact way way back this has been known about but particularly during the last
war, they started to perfect the manipulation of a natural mechanism in the mind that shuts out trauma. What
they did is that to understand that if you could systematically traumatize someone their mind would shut out
the memory of it and create an amnesic barrier which would be disconnected from the rest of the mind
this is what happens when people have a major road accident and they canít remember what happened
itís because the amnesic barrier has been created to shut out trauma so we donít keep reliving the horror
Good thing, but they realized if you could do that systematically and start with children particularly before
the age of 5 and 6 you could turn their mind into a honeycomb of self-contained compartments none of which was
aware of the others existence. And so through trigger words and what have you and trigger sentences hypnotic
keys one amnesic barrier becomes the conscious level that experiences something or is programmed to do something
and then is pushed back and another one is pulled forward. Itís actually got to the point where amazing as it may
seem you can be drunk in one compartment and completely sober in the other. Once the programming is in there
and in the biggest secret i put incredible documentation and background to this and what happened and trauma
based mind control and how it creates assassins and people going crazy with guns to justify taking guns out of
circulation all this stuff. When you look at the background all that is necessary is to program the guy push that
programming back into the mind and that will stay there at the subconscious level until some trigger comes in
when that trigger word or trigger action or whatever is said or done that programming is activated. So you can be
in normal mode and be very normal and no problem "never noticed anything different about old' henry that night"
trigger word BANG programming youíre like a robot.
The drug trade is run by the intelligence agencies of every country and that's to finance the weapons business
And also to recycle money
okay recycle money
The whole thing has to make a 360 degree turn in a way that that money will always end up clean at the end
of this whole transformation you know of this. So the weapon dealers are happy the drug dealers are happy
the governments are happy because with the drugs they keep the people oppressed
How involved is the Vatican with this whole drug trade which is basically for the purpose of financing
the purchasing of weapons
Because the drug trade is supported by the CIA or any other agency involved it being the Mossad
or MI6 or whatever so they can go and finance those uh.. terrorist organizations that then create the
strategic tension that they require so they can implement their own police state and rule us by the stick.
Plus the drug itself makes the person who is using it depending on something which is supplies not
guaranteed so if for example in the future the government decides to truly close down those drug
cartels and stop immediately and once and for all the possibility of these drugs being spread through your
towns and through your cities then at that point you will see a lot of people coming out on the street
completely out of it because they are on a cold turkey situation and maybe theyíll start shooting and so
that really could be one of the ways used by the powerful elite to instigate a revolution just stop the drug
cartels and make all these people dependent of the white powder or any other drug get completely out of it.
We have a lot of manipulation with drugs for example the Mossad that is manipulating with the Psytrance
music all this big festivals of trance music this rave trance they call it and they have started this whole project
by taking control of the drug scene in Goa India which all this make up of all these people into this alternative
scene and so they can brainwash them with the fake religious ideals because after they take a few of these
acids they start obviously coming into contact with these demonic forces that can easily make themselves
present in their life and even they can sometimes bring them back from their dimension with them and never
get rid of them anymore
So how involved is the secret societies in the whole music industry
The involvement of secret society in music industry is very important. Since the time of the establishment
of certain lodges of Aleister Crowley in California to the subsequent spread of the beat and hippies generation
and musicians like the rolling stones, the Beatles, and many others who not only have been highly influenced
by this satanic creed but have sometimes openly embraced it like the rolling stones who have made even an album
called "Their Satanic Majesty's Request" and in fact Mick Jager has been awarded after many years for his
great work with the title of "Sir Mick Jager" by the queen herself, her satanic majesty ha-ha so you know you
get even an award if you have sympathy for the devil
But does uh.. does this even reach into the hip-hop music culture
Yes
In the hip-hop music culture there is a lot of hip-hopers that are connected to black prince of freemasonry
I myself somebody who followed the hip-hop scene at the beginning when it was still genuine but letís say by
1986 it had already been infiltrated by the feds, the intelligence, CIA and it was used by for propaganda reasons and for
establishing also hatred towards the whites from the blacks with the Niggas With An Attitude and all the rest and after
they started to politicize this whole gang phenomenon so they could use it for establishing this whole culture which
has spread all over the world not only in the United States which is a culture of completely and utter dementia
I mean itís all about the booty how you shake your booty about how many gold chains you have how many cars you have
what kind of Jacuzzi you have. These are all values of Satan himself. This is satanic but we have certain freemasons
or prince of freemasonry that have been very important in the in this link between the gangs and the masonic
world
Okay
So between the illegitimate and the legitimate
Right wow thatís real interesting
And also for the use of symbolism that a lot of hip-hopers have done using the illuminati symbols
for their own for promoting their own
like what symbols are you talking about can you show me with your hands
It can be the one dollar bill or it can be the classic masonic symbol square and compass or many others.
An electron is a tiny tiny bit of matter, like a tiny marble
Letís fire a stream through one slit. It behaves just like the marble. A single band.
So if we shoot these tiny bits through two slits we should get like the marbles two bands.
What an interference pattern, we fired electrons tiny bits of matter through
But we get a pattern like waves not like little marbles. Physicist are clever they thought maybe those little
balls are bouncing off each other and creating that pattern. So they decide to shoot electrons one at a time
There is no way they can interfere with each other.
But after an hour of this the same interference pattern is seen to emerge
The conclusion is in-escapable: The single electron leaves as a particle becomes a wave of potentials goes
through both slits and interferes with itself to hit the wall like a particle, but mathematically its even stranger
it goes through both and it goes through neither, and it goes through just one and it goes through just the other
all of these possibilities are in super position with each other but physicists were completely baffled by this
so they decided to peek and see which slit it actually goes through.
They put a measuring device by one slit to see which one it went through and let it fly. he he
But the quantum world is far more mysterious than they could have imagined. When they observed the electron
went back to behaving like a little marble. It produced a pattern of two bands not an interference patter of many
the very act of measuring or observing which slit it went through meant it only went through one not both.
The electron decided to act differently
As though it was aware it was being watched.
And it was here that physicist stepped into the strange never world of quantum events.
What is matter marbles? or waves? And waves of what...
and what does and observer have to do with any of this.
The observer collapsed the wave function simply by observing.
Tonightís talk is consciousness, creativity and the brain and if you have a golf-ball size consciousness when you read
a book you'll have a golf-ball size understanding, when you look out a golf-ball size awareness and when you
wake up in the morning a golf-ball size wakefulness. But if you could expand that consciousness then you read the
book, more understanding, you look out more awareness and when you wake up more wakefulness its consciousness
and thereís an ocean of pure vibrant consciousness inside each one of us and its right at the source and base of mind
right at the source of thought and itís all at the source of all matter
There is no matter as such all matter originates and exists only by virtue of a force which brings the particle of an
atom to vibration and holds this most minute solar system of the atom together, we must assume behind this force
the existence of a conscious and intelligent mind. This mind is the matrix of all matter.
Matter seems like a good place to begin. The solidity of the world seems totally indisputable. As a fixed thing that
you can see and touch your body also reassuringly solid but beginning with Einstein modern physics has assured us that
this solidity is a mirage.
All of physical matter, everything we have around us, is a result of a frequency and what that also means is that if you
amplify the frequency the structure of the matter will change
What this self-contained system is a hologram is what i call the super hologram every within it is an expression of that
hologram and this is one of the great characteristics of a hologram is that every part of a holographic picture is a
smaller version of the whole
itís as if reality is so connected  that when you look at
one small part you can see things about other parts that the entire whole is contained in the part and in a sense
you canít divide reality up because were cutting up a hologram. We canít find where one particle is because itís always
a reflection of all particles.
In a hologram the whole pattern is whole and complete onto itself
and if you were to take any little portion of this whole out and examine it closely you will see the entire pattern
repeating itself again and again and again. Anywhere in this pattern if we were to change one little aspect on any
one of these little holograms change would be reflected throughout the entire system.
Quantum physics has revealed what ancient masters knew - matter does not exist. The concept of substance
arose from the philosophy of Aristotle and from that concept came sciences conception of matter,
the fact of the matter is that the substance of the universe is consciousness belief that the substance of the universe
is matter leads to what i call a fear-grade dichotomy as people in their quite desperate attempt to accumulate
as many material possessions and riches as possible. In fact the substance of the universe is consciousness
therefore it is behavior that is important
If you get into the realms of fear
Fear is a very slow dense vibrational state, and the more you embody fear and the whole of this manipulated
society is globally is structured to make us fear to make us have stress to make us worry about tomorrow
and have guilt about yesterday, and forget about now. It brings us into a slow vibrating dense state.
We should be very careful about what we believe about the future. The more you attach to a belief system the more
if reality is holographic, youíre helping create it by believing it and you know the great clairvoyant Edgard Casey said
that our every thought that reality is built out of thought and our every thought starts to build reality and were like every
thought is like a spider were like spiders spinning web and that web starts to build and build
information is the key because this matrix this illusory reality that we think is real people say to me
what is the matrix its information
information create fractals as information flow
increases the number of fractals mathematically speaking increase. This was demonstrated by a mathematician
by the name Theodor Gordon, fractals are unpredictable functions so things are becoming more and more
unpredictable
when you start getting into fractals and chaos theory when you look at
it in terms of a society this is where it starts to cross over into the so called illuminati and the negative
elite the world leaders with their philosophy of order out of chaos.. there is some truth to that in the sense that
when the system becomes highly destabilized there will be random shifts that suddenly self-organize into
higher complexity
at the subatomic level reality behaves in accordance with the expectation of the observer or
the measurer the scientist why is that remarkable? Because everything in the universe is composed of those
subatomic particles
these atoms are particles that are whirling at lightning speeds around huge empty space
and the particles arenít material objects, they're fluctuations of energy and information in a huge void of energy
and information
and what the science now is showing is that when you can change the field in which the atom is
in you change the atom, and were made of those atoms. So when we have feelings in our heart were changing the
field that connects the stuff that everything is made of and were literally altering our physical reality
Once you establish the reality we live in and the nature of what the physical body is, itís a biological computer,
and the nature of what we are which is consciousness and then you start as I have looking at the way this world
is structured and how it works and why they do this and why they do that, it suddenly brings into crystal clarity
why the world is structured as it is because
you know people look through their eyes and they think this the world but it isnít itís a tiny tiny frequency
range within an infinite energy field of infinite frequency range and basically itís like holographic television channel
It is the act of consciousness that actually creates the building blocks the universe is made of. I can't even imagine a
universe that exists without us because itís the act of us observing the world around us that is creating allowing us to
create as we go in a participatory universe. We may never find the edge of our universe as we're looking to define
what this universe looks like, we may never find the smallest particle in the quantum world to see what the
stuff is were made out of and the reason is because everywhere we look everywhere that consciousness explores
with the expectation that something will be there that exploration that act of looking observation is the act
that creates something for us to see. That we are actually building this universe as we go
Consciousness is the programming language of the universe. We are consciousness conductors thatís what we do thatís
who we are consciousness comes through us emanates from us. We are the creators, we are the ones who are
targeted on this planet because we are the ones who transmit the reality just like everybody else does. If you switch
your brain off and you sucked in to the mainstream media illusion we must understand that we are being used
because we create reality so if we are manipulated in a certain way and if we are modulated in a certain way
then our creation becomes not ours but somebody elseís
And what happens if we all did
everyone in this room decides to take control of reality Iím talking about reality Iím talking about quantum physics
Iím talking about taking control of things from the quantum level up from the molecular level up and it works. One of the things
were actually dealing with is some kind of operating system that can be hacked using words
The world is like a ride in an amusement park and when you chose to go on it you think its real cause thatís how powerful
our minds are and the ride goes up and down and round and round it has thrills and chills and its very brightly colored
and its very loud and its fun for a while. Some people have been on the ride for a long time and they begin to question
is this real or is this just a ride and other people have remembered and they come back to us and they say "hey don't worry
don't be afraid ever because.... this is just a ride."
Look buddy I don't want no hassle today either pay for it or put it back
Sleep, sleep, sleep...
Can you believe it she didn't even go to Lamaze Class I told her for yourself and for the baby, Go!
[gossiping]
I'm so depressed I donít know what to do
Hey go for it man
Easy for you to say you got the promotion
Look it will come alright just don't worry about it
[TV] The feeling is definitely there, itís a new morning in America, fresh vital the old
cynicism is gone. We have faith in our leaders were optimistic as to what the comes to it all
It really boils down to our ability to accept. We donít need pessimism, there are no limits
It figures it would be something like this.
Well let me explain the (new) world order, let me help you ...
9-11
with a female underage in a motel by the Dallas police department on September eleventh 1960
We have before us the opportunity to forge for ourselves and for future generations
a New World Order a world where the rule of law not the law of the jungle governs the conduct of
nations. When we are successful and we will be, we have a real chance at this New World Order
I think a New World Order is emerging
then really a New World Order can be created
itís a great opportunity
a phrase that i often use myself that we need a New World Order
Those people who have been yelling oh the UN is going to take over global government
Conspiracy theorists
Theyíve been crazy but now theyíre right
Itís happening
When Geithner said he would be open to the idea
of a global currency last week those conspiracy people had said and suggested that for years
youíre not wrong.
We can all make a change. We don't need a US president to make a change. We don't need the
Dalai Lama to make a change. We don't need the pope to make a change. What we need to make a
change is our own heart. Our own hearts needs to be placed in the right place and it has to have
the right feelings.
I'm Sorry
But I donít want to be and emperor thatís not my business. I donít want to rule or conquer anyone. I should like to help
everyone if possible Jew, gentile, black man, white. We all want to help one another human beings are like that
we want to live by each otherís happiness not by each otherís misery. We don't want to hate and despise one another.
And this world has room for everyone and the good Earth is rich and can provide for everyone.
The way of life can be free and beautiful, but we have lost the way. Greed has poisoned men's souls, has
barricaded the world with hate, has goose stepped us into misery and bloodshed. We have developed speed
but we have shut ourselves in. Machinery that gives abundance has left us in want. Our knowledge has made
us cynical, our cleverness hard and unkind, we think too much and feel too little. More than machinery
we need humanity, more than cleverness we need kindness and gentleness. Without these qualities life would
be violent and all would be lost. The airplane and the radio has brought us closer together, the very nature of these
inventions cries out for the goodness in men. Cries out for universal brotherhood, for the unity of us all
Even now my voice is reaching millions throughout the world, millions of despairing men, women and children
Victim of a system that makes men torture and imprison innocent people. For those who can hear me I say
do not despair, the misery that is now upon us is but the passing of greed, the bitterness of men who fear the way
of human progress. The hate of men who will pass, and dictators die and the power they took from the people
will return to the people and so long as men die liberty will never perish. Soldiers don't give yourselves to
brutes, men who despise you, enslave you, who regiment your lives, tell you what to do what to think and what
to feel. Who drill you, diet you, treat you like cattle, use you as cannon fodder, donít give yourself to these
unnatural men. Machine men with machine minds and machine hearts. You are not machines. You are not
cattle.. you are men. You have the love of humanity in your hearts. You don't hate, only the unloved hate, the
unloved and the unnatural. Soldiers don't fight for slavery, fight for liberty in the 17th chapter of Saint Luke it is
written the kingdom of god is within man not one man nor a group of men but in all men, in you, YOU the people
have the power, the power to create machines, the power to create happiness, you the people have the power
to make this life free and beautiful, to make this life a wonderful adventure. Then in the name of democracy
let us use that power, let us all unite. Let us all fight for a new world, a decent world that will give man a chance
to work, that will give youth a future and old agers security. By the promise of these things brutes have risen to power
but they lie, they do not fulfill that promise, they never will. Dictators free themselves but they enslave the people
Now let us fight to fulfill that promise, let us fight to free the world, to do away with national barriers. To do
away with greed, with hate and intolerance, let us fight for a world of reason, a world where science and progress
will lead to all menís happiness. Soldiers in the name of democracy
Let us all UNITE
I know you're out there. I can feel you now. I know that you're afraid.
You're afraid of us. You're afraid of change. I don't know the future.
I didn't come here to tell you how this is going to end. I came here to tell you how itís going to begin.
I'm going to hang up this phone, and then I'm going to show these people what you don't want them to see.
I'm going to show them a world without you,
A world without rules and controls without borders or boundaries
A world where anything is possible
Where we go from there is a choice I leave to you.