white primal
that sounds like a mile and must have it
in nineteen sixty nine or
or maybe there are other than that
nineteen forty nine
now it's happening today inside a
biracial student trying to show of last
year
i was kicked out escorted away by the
police and the police and forces now
it's not suddenly run by this as
students is run by a parent organization
but the cops in force it
four students came together so that we
should do and integrated prom it's
twenty thirteen
can we set out of the time machine for a
second
and get real here
uh... it turns out a lot of people are
resisting this including the governor of
georgia i'll get to in a second but for
c_b_s_ us to the school
akamai university journalists went there
as reported back wall
white students in the back during class
wake
uh... while black kids in the front
lots of interesting
change of pace
mistakes which positions
black kids have lunch outside while the
white kids have there is in the yard
white students particularly girls who
deep black students recipient ostracized
emboli
now look
either way since the blacks in sometime
soon apart a lot of different schools
but there seems to be something that is
enforced throughout all these decades
and we know
if you're black or even biracial each
other show up to that problem
it take you out
so there's no question about that's the
case here
is a people fighting bag yes and now
whose small credit by the way position
be fairly obvious
or trying to fix the situation
and there are seven uh... people some of
the georgia state representatives formed
president truman republicans who are
saying
misfortune places
amman but what of the president was not
among them
is governor mason deal of george
is a man you see pictured here
when asked about this
he said the groups trying to integrate
the races in that high school are quote
a leftist font group
for the state democratic board
okay you know what nathan
fine you would
democrats are for integration
republicans
segregation in the year twenty thirty
began to be fair not all republicans
even george arsenal state reps are
against us
apparently have some sense that nathan
deal doesn't but look at this time warp
is stuck in that time
this guy some things like our budget
leftist more than that it is coming in
here china integrators
the racist to your magic
and the same for all
he's not done yet he says quote
we're not going to lend a hand to this
silly publicity stuff
this silly publicity stunt
trying to integrate the races in georgia
however here
every time we knew the story would be
another twice
first original story now the hopi with
nathan deal
can't believe it's the year twenty
thirteen and these guys still think this
way
has probably cuz i'm way to ninety
fighting grew up in a situation like
that
so when i see this a government united
states state this day and age saying how
you and your publicity stunts
with your left this don't strive
integrate the races
unacceptable
i'm shocked by it
i hope to it
voters in georgia rashad by and they
never make the mistake of reelected
nathan deal again