quail fight.
But now we needed to find our
way to the Ka Faroshi Bird
Market, home to all of Kabul's
rival bird trainers.
Today was the first day of Eid
[ARABIC], Eid al-Adha, the
celebration of sacrifice.
And Dardar invited us to join
in on the festivities.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
GELAREH KIAZAND: So everyone
basically comes together
before Eid [ARABIC]
And they all do the prayer
before the sacrifice.
So this is one of the main
community mosques, where,
apparently, thousands
of people come.
And they pray.
It's pretty high
security today.
Everyone's worried about
the bomb in the turban.
ABDUL SAMAD DARDAR:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
GELAREH KIAZAND: They
asked me to leave.
They say it's not good for a
woman to be inside the mosque.
So I didn't want to
cause any trouble.
So I decided to leave.
Now everyone's going to their
homes to do the sacrifice.
I think they're going to
sacrifice that cow right now.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
GELAREH KIAZAND: That's
disgusting.
So what happens is that when a
cow is sacrificed, or a sheep,
they take a little bit
for themselves.
And then they basically
cut up the meat.
And they pass it to the poor or
the rest of the community.
So we're at someone's house.
It smells so good here.
It smells like mother's
cooking.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
GELAREH KIAZAND: With
festivities for Eid finished,
animal fights were back on.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
GELAREH KIAZAND: We're on our
way to a street called Ka
Faroshi, which is where they
sell the different types of
birds that they bring
out into the fights.
For example, partridges,
roosters, canaries, pigeons,
and quails.
The shopkeepers train and fight
their animals as a team,
because the buying and
upkeep of birds is
actually pretty expensive.
If you walk around the market
for long enough, you start to
recognize some of
the rival teams.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
GELAREH KIAZAND: He's got 48
kids and 12 grandchildren.
And then they basically are
working across the street,
different shops, so he can
pay off his debts.
So these are where
all his sons are.
He owns all of these birds.
And they're going to try to put
together a fight for us.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
GELAREH KIAZAND: The next
morning, after prayers, all
the rival teams showed up for
the match with their best
fighting birds.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
GELAREH KIAZAND: The aim of
partridge fights is for one
bird to tie the other bird up.
Apparently, they're really
strong partridges.
And they keep French kissing the
birds to keep them cool.
The owners hold water in their
mouths and spit it onto their
birds to make sure they
don't overheat.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
GELAREH KIAZAND: One hour
and 30 minutes.
The bets have been raised.
Apparently it's at
100,000 now.
It started at 30,000.
So see what animal is going
to win, I guess.
After two hours of fighting, one
partridge finally stumbles
out of the circle,
ending the match.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
GELAREH KIAZAND: The bird
was bought $2,000 a
few months ago from--
he bought it from
the young guy.
An then they bought it
from the old man.
And now it won the fight.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
GELAREH KIAZAND:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[MUSIC PLAYING]