5... 4... 3..
2... 1... Hup!
Come on...
Here you go...
come on... come on...
When I was down the pit
and I got my children
She said, get a hobby.
So I got the pigeons.
I think then, pitmen were slaves.
It was very rare they saw the daylight.
you could be on the first shift...
4 o'clock in the morning
until dinner time, then you went to bed,
got up and it was dark.
It was very rare you saw the sunlight.
when you were down the pit.
They gave you something to...
fresh air and plenty of exercise and that.
Looking after them
and you always got the sun
It's a good hobby
Still is!
but... it's dying out now.
It's a dying sport.
- Another one for stan!...
- Stan's getting one...
What's that stan?
- Ordinary?
- Ordinary.
No money on it.
All the pigeons that go away
this week, cost £1.80
Just to go, with no money on
But you win the prize money out of that side
So if you fancy it to win
You can put 50p on it,
you can put a pound on!
There might be about forty or fifty 50pences
and there might be 20 or 30
pool to the pound
well, the first on of them, gets that money.
Wow!
Maurice... he's a good lad.
He's a good mate
And you always get a good laugh
He says things that make you laugh
things like that.
We've been close friends for years.
But say we try and..
competition wise...
beat each other.
If he beats you, you just try again.
and if I beat him, he trys again
I mean...
There's opposition every bloody week
isn't there, jack.
I mean, if jack wins
i'm over the bloody moon.
why i say that but
I don't really believe it.
come on get out, settle down.
You can win as many of these short races
as you like
I mean, i've won the short race Selby
oh, I couldn't tell you how many times.
but if you win the big race
and you top the combine
your name's made.
The classic race is Bourges
560 miles
now they're pigeons.
It's the one race i'd like to win again.
My first race was 1949
I came out of the army in 1955
and we started to build this
old pigeon cree.
the wood was only old wood
from colliery houses
that they were pulling down
from the pit.
But 10 years back
when this local developer
wanted the land
they decided that they would get
the pigeon cree listed.
Made a listed building.
Then he started again,
he wanted the gardens back
for a development.
(The Sound of ITV News)
The culture secretary has
pledged his support
his support to save the world's
only listed pigeon cree
and the allotments it stand on.
It's hoped the minister's visit today
will ruffle a few feathers
and help the allotment holders win
their long running battle
to save the gardens of Ryhope.
A Newcastle based development company
owns the land and wants to
build houses there.
Maurice, who's 75 and recently
suffered a heart attack
says he won't give up his
campaign to save his cree
and the allotments.
Give up and walk away? No, Never.
No, i'd rather drop dead in the
garden than do that!
Lesley McNeish ITV Tyne Tees, Sunderland.
(Maurice): It's been well publicised on the
television and all over.
It'll always be here
as long as it's in good condition
they cannot pull it down.
The developer cannot knock it down.
He might... if the worst comes to the worst
which we hope never happens mind,
this'll be left standing
and maybe the other gardens
will be taken off the lads.
It'll be a sad day
a very, very, very sad day
I'll tell the truth for that
I cannot race my pigeons if
i'm on here by myself.
and they're building round us.
see, you cannot race pigeons that way.
Now, I've brought it up and put it inside,
and I've given it a sesqui tablet
and it's had a bite... and i've
given it a drink of water
and I'll leave it there and I'll contact you
and let you know if it's coming on alright.
Ok?
This is the one i've just been
on to the chap about
it's the worst i've ever seen a pigeon
If you feel there
- oh.. dear me.
- So, what's your opinion?
- This old lady brought it to my house.
- poor little bugger.
Has it been shot like? oh here, Jack.
No, the cat's had it.
- But if you look at it's eye...
- it's a lovely eye on it mind.
- There's a bit of life in it.
- oh aye, definitely.. lovely eye on it.
...a little sparkle of life.
Put him in intensive care!
Well it was a disaster last week.
We lost all our best pigeons.
Two combines was at Clermont
and they clashed
She was my main bird
I had her pooled up to win the race.
But she was reported in Surrey.
This is the one I was going
to send to Bourges...
the big classic race.
But I can't send her now.
Because, she's too tired.
But, I'm going to send one
in it's place.
now this one has already scored this year.
So I'm going to send that in it's place.
You wanna go this week?
all shaking their heads...
don't want to go.
But they're going!
He's big and bonnie
Beautiful.
This bad bugger's fat and all.
But she always comes home.
Oh, she's bonnie though.
As I say, I cannot get them any better.
It's up to them now.
You've got to build them up for this race.
I mean, if it's a fast day it won't
take so much out of them
not so much weight.
But they've still got to fly 565 miles.
see... I'm happy with them though.
I wouldn't be sending them
if I didn't fancy them.
I wouldn't be sending them.
That's the hand book we get every year.
As they come back to my loft,
the positions are there.
I write the remarks on the bottom...
"Came Canny"
So I was pleased.
Now what i've got bottom there...
"Came Crap"
No swearing.
I got the wooden spoon, I was last.
That's for this week.
All I want's a bit of luck.
- You only got one?
- You only got three?
All the pigeons you've got and
you're only sending one?
Aye.
(in the distance)
Jackie! It only takes one to win.
He's right, it only takes one to win.
Checked Cock.
Come on bonnie lass... get in.
(Singing)
There's a place...
...for us...
That's it then.
Over the water, they all tuck into it.
That's Scotland, Yorkshire..
and it's all worked out
that the best bird wins.
They'll probably be all liberated
on the Friday morning.
They'll circle
then they'll all go away.
And as they're on the road home,
they start to think
and the good ones
splits away.
That's how you get your winners.
My opinion
it's a highly developed instinct.
But they're a marvelous animal, them.
Truly wonderful.
(Maurice) I think Jack, why we've been
mates all our lives.
It must have been 1952 when
Jackie came here.
As I say, me and Jackie,
we've been here the longest
and I think we'll be the last to leave too.
that's a certainty.
(Jackie) Oh! she's out!
I'd be lost without him
and he'd be lost without me.
So he says like.
Jackie's in poor health and all.
He got his lung taken out,
he worked in the pit and he
contracted cancer in the lung.
we were all worried over him.
I said, how long have I got?
you know? I said, tell us!
he says: Well, 3 to 6 months.
I thought, good god.
I come out with the lads and
I said, it'll not beat me.
I was doing my exercises and that.
Over there they're some steps,
have you seen them?
About sixty odd steps.
Off the football field.
I used to run up there as fast as I could
and I was fifty, you know what I mean?
Please yourself whether you believe
it or not, I don't care,
that's what happened.
So, I had to go back to the doctors
and he got the x-rays and they looked
up and they looked at me
and the doctor said, are you sure
you're John Surtees born...
I said, aye I'm sure.
he said, well your lung has not collapsed,
it's working alright.
And it's moved away from your heart,
the growth.
And I was in and operated on
two days after.
And that's what happened there.
And I've been alive since!
He's pulled round and I think coming
round the garden every day
and having his pigeons, his good hobby...
that's what's pulled him round.
They kept us alive, the pigeons.
Kept us alive that.
Something to look forward to all the time.
So you can image if it happens
where we get it taken off us.
What would we do?
That's a third prize..
that's a second..
that's a sixth..
ah, I've got a first.
That's a first prize card
I'm getting there...
It's ringing now...
(telephone) It's Saturday the
21st of June the time's 12:00
right, the convoy has been on
to me from Bourges
and he is going to liverate the
Bourges pigeons at 1:00
There's not many young lads coming
into the sport now...
ah, there's no young lads in Ryhope.
To get the bairns interested,
I wish we could!
We've got the school interested
in the gardens
we've got the headteacher, she going
to fetch a few bairns up.
Over the moon aren't they.
Over the moon!
- Which one to get out to show you?
- That one!
- Which one?
- The white one! The white one!
Just stroke it, there we are,
touch it's head.
It won't hurt you.
I think I'd like to get them coming
round the garden regular.
Get them to pick a few pigeons they like
and come round every day
to feed them and fly them
and maybe we can entice them to say,
I fancy them to go for a race this week.
Aye, then they might get into it.
But, as far as the pigeons are concerned,
I wish we had a few more youngsters in.
Today, I think they might fly about,
what? 8 hours Jack?
Aye.
If it's good weather, which it is.
The first 8 hours will be good weather.
then there'll be 4 hours tomorrow
in England.
- The good ones will be in 11:30.
- Aye, about that tomorrow.
That's the good ones.
The one's that are carrying the luck.
See his, will land on a milk man's house,
where they get up early!
Mine will land in the fields,
miles from anywhere!
Get ready!
Alright!
Pull!
We had word that the bulldozers,
the bailifs were coming in.
But nobody turned up.
If they want us off here, well they'll have
to carry us off bodily.
And I've got a big family.
It'll be like declaring war.
And we're not being awkward,
this is our way of life...
and this is the way we want
to end our lives.
and that's all there is to it.
Oh look out, it's mine!
So that's him.. I'm over the moon!
Over the moon!
First time across the channel.
Maurice!
- We're still waiting.
- I'm getting one!
- Have you?
- Aye!
I could be third.
They always turn up.
- Who's this?
- Jackie Surtees.
Waiting, wait, wait, wait...
Well, I've done very well.
I'm getting third position
and I'll get some money and that.
So I'm really... happy!
Ah, you've got to take the
good with the bad.
I think, you've got more bad luck
than good luck.
I'm not carrying the luck, that's all.
But, they'll come back.. I think..
they'll come back.
That's all there is to it.