many of the number-one uh... intended
obviously so i'm not impair your butt
if you're in a room with me and a bet
you do you know what's the news from
his mother fought more secure senators
there are
his from mississippi doesn't get him on
the lotto legislation
so why in the world with somebody send
headquarters
well it's interesting well an especially
right after the bombings in boston so
first off of course everyone is if
there's a connection
obviously we don't know yet
i've actually honestly surprised at how
low-key restless and as i do have been
briefed on it
apparently think that they're confident
that everything's gonna be okay that's
what they are all saying
uh... and they think it might be someone
did
has sent men
we ordered threatening letters in the
past
previous senators so could just be alone
wall they could be somebody
they're just took advantage of the
balmy situation did
scare more people could be headed got
absolutely nothing to do it
yeah they did have something to it well
and those two things are connected that
makes it law much less likely that is a
four attack
just because they don't believe there's
a single foreigner who knows who roger
workers
uh... any foreign country that men to do
was formerly forum group allocate or
otherwise
media pay pal roger wicker in the senate
directory
hi would have been surprise what why of
all people send him rice in
isn't in my by set up in the way there
if there is ample art
he was one of the senators republican
senators
that voted to get past the filibuster on
gun control legislation
there's a big crazy enough
percent somebody poison
because they just wooden block a debate
on an issue he's likely to vote against
the bill
among
is that enough for some crazy brazil is
an important
who knows so superior out there right
now but
coming right after the bombings
it reminds of course of
nine eleven then right after another
anthrax attacks again senators against
members of the media so obviously never
was rightfully very concerned who's even
reports earlier
but today the white house had been
cleared
while the government facials all the
press et-cetera to make sure that there
was that uh... that an unattended
package was saying carava make sure that
was not a bomb
so everybody's on edge here but it is
very curious
the united states and around the worker
bees sent this obviously terrible thank
god they caught it before heard anybody
there was caught in the screening
facility outside of congress
so uh... thank god that nobody got hurt
but it is awfully strange in we hope
that it doesn't happen again
and it's all this mystery