THOMAS MORTON: Yugoslavia is
best known as that big, goofy
country from the '70s that
turned into six little
countries in the '90s
amid an orgy of rape
and nightmare war.
The breakup of Yugoslavia led
to a period of such heinous
interethnic violence, including
acts of outright
genocide, it seemed amazing that
they had ever been able
to live together
in first place.
At the end of World War II,
Josip Marshal Tito Broz united
the six Balkan republics into
a massive socialist
federation, despite the fact
that, historically, they all
wanted to kill each other.
When Tito died, the old ethnic
tensions reawoke and the
republic started
to break away--
first Slovenia, then Macedonia,
then Croatia, then
Bosnia, and eventually
Montenegro, leaving Serbia the
last republic to carry the torch
for the old Yugoslavia.
Oh yeah, Kosovo broke
away too, if you
consider that a country.
It's been 10 years since the end
of the wars, and since the
man widely considered their
architect, Serbian president
Slobodan Milosevic, was
bulldozed out of office.
All the former Yugoslav
republics have now applied for
membership in the
European Union.
At the same time, the Balkans is
still a byword for barbaric
acts of violence, and the entire
region occupies a sort
of threshold state between
Europe and, well, not-Europe.
So we went to the Balkans to
find out once and for all if
Yugoslavians are just like
you-and-me-goslavians.
[CAR HONKING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
THOMAS MORTON: Hey,
it's Thomas.
We're in Yugoslavia-- or former
Yugoslavia, I'm sorry.
We're in Serbia right now.
We rented an old Yugo
for this trip.
I don't think we realize quite
how old it would be.
We're going about 100 K right
now-- so maybe 60-- and the
car's rattling.
It's almost like being in
a moving massage chair.
It's holding up pretty well
except that the fuel gauge is
literally doing this, so
we have to guess when
we're out of gas.
And me and the passenger
seatbelts are tied together.
I forgot about that.
So we're going to Yugoland, and
that's a kind of a farm
mixed with an amusement park.
But it's supposed to capture the
memory of Marshal Tito's
Yugoslavia.
Tell you one thing about
Yugoland, they don't
advertise very well.
There were no signs on
the highway for it.
And it is in the middle of a
very, very, very tiny village.
Yugoland's website advertises it
as a full service amusement
park in northern Serbia, based
on the former Yugoslavia.
It has different sections for
each of the old constituent
republics, except for Kosovo, so
we couldn't think of a more
perfect place to get oriented
for a road trip through the
scattered remnants of
old Yugoslavia.
So this is Yugoland.
It looks like it's kind
of in the backyard
of someone's house.
I think we might have missed
most of the action.
This might be the [INAUDIBLE]
committee.
Sounds like stuff's still going
on in the background.
Yugoland seemed pleasant
enough, if
a bit old and rustic.
Not a lot of teenagers so far,
nor a lot of ladies.
Blasko Gabric is Yugoland's
founder, a Serbian printmaker
turned Canadian turned eventual
Yugoslavian superfan,
and is generally what people
of the region refer to as
quite a character.
THOMAS MORTON: Nine years
and counting.
THOMAS MORTON: Pretty
good, yeah.
THOMAS MORTON: Yugoland turned
out to be less of an amusement
park than a park park, and
really less of that than a
yard with some picnic tables and
a lot of tipsy Serbians.
Nevertheless, its amenities
include a bandstand, soccer
fields, a reflecting pool in
the shape of the Croatian
coastline, and a scale model of
Slovenia's Mount Triglav.
THOMAS MORTON: The most
important amenity, however, is
a fervent and unconditional
love for Yugoslavia's late
partisan leader, Marshal Tito.
THOMAS MORTON: Marshal Tito's
extremely beloved for a dead
Communist dictator.
Even coming from an American
perspective, I always had a
pretty vaunted impression
of him.
He was like the dictator
who cares--
minimal human rights violations,
genuine popular
support, and he was one of the
only Communists with the balls
to tell Stalin where to smoke
it-- or where to stuff it,
however that saying goes--
and on top of that, he fucked
Elizabeth Taylor, probably.
So all in all, not a terrible
guy to worship.
The guest of honor at Yugoland
was here as Tito's grandson,
though we get the feeling the
family charm may have skipped
a couple generations.
THOMAS MORTON: It's outside.
THOMAS MORTON: Hey.
THOMAS MORTON: The
crown prince.
THOMAS MORTON: A
real who's who.
US president anywhere here?
BLASKO GABRIC: No.
THOMAS MORTON: Carter?
Or was it Reagan
by that point?
BLASKO GABRIC: No.
THOMAS MORTON: Oh,
there's Thatcher.
THOMAS MORTON: She's
somewhere.
THOMAS MORTON: A few Elvis
had a pretty big funeral.
THOMAS MORTON: Oh
yeah, a bunch.
THOMAS MORTON: Yugoland's
a pretty
harmless exercise in nostalgia.
What's creepy, though, is the
part where it's mostly Serbs
getting together in Serbia to
celebrate their Yugoslav
history, all while neatly
stepping over the decade their
country spent committing war
crimes on Bosnia and Croatia
and Kosovo.
You also have to remember that
during the '90s, when the wars
were going on and Blasko was
just getting into his
Yugoslavian heritage, Serbia
was still Yugoslavia--
Milosevic's Yugoslavia.
Go, Yugoslavia.
While the Yugolanders sort of
represent the feelgood version
of the Balkans' past,
basically retreading
decades-old national propaganda
ad nauseum, another
group of Serbs have been
barreling into the future with
a trunk full of smuggled
drugs, the
soundtrack pumping Turbofolk.