and new.
No, I know the deal.
You blew up off that first
video 5 years ago.
And it's been nothing but Rice
Krispies squares and like in
Call of Duty.
Do you play Xbox
or PS3 or what?
MO: PS3.
MALE SPEAKER: PS3.
So Carroll, PS3's
a video game.
A video game is a thing.
It's a little--
You wouldn't know that shit.
Take us back to 1995, Carroll.
Or as we call it,
your good years.
CARROLL: I can't remember
those years.
MALE SPEAKER: They were sweet.
You were skater of
the year, right?
CARROLL: '94.
MALE SPEAKER: '94.
Don't mention '94 around him.
CARROLL: What year
were you born?
MO: '90.
[LAUGHTER]
MALE SPEAKER: He was 4, dude.
MALE SPEAKER: Holy shit.
It's been downhill
since he was 4.
[LAUGHTER]
MALE SPEAKER: Mo, I don't know
what the fuck you're laughing
about, Jesus Christ.
You got to hit the gym and
start skating, man.
The fucking street league is
like, going to kick you out.
What's up with that?
How we looking this year?
MO: It's my last year.
MALE SPEAKER: Is it?
MO: Yeah.
I got kicked out.
MALE SPEAKER: You did
get kicked out?
[LAUGHTER]
MALE SPEAKER: Look at me.
I'm being real for the first
time in my life.
Get your shit together.
You're a good kid.
MO: Thanks, man.
MALE SPEAKER: You're
a lost cause.
[LAUGHTER]