Food Busker, fried chicken. We love fried
chicken.
Hi, I'm John Quilter and my two great passions in life are music and food. And Im with my
boys RDGLDGRN and we're gonna rack up some
fried chicken.
You all loving fried chicken?
Yes. We loving it.
What we're gonna do is we're gonna give it
a bit of a remix with some beautiful honey
and some lemon. It's gonna make it sweet,
it's gonna make it tasty, it's gonna be absolutely
gorgeous.
Then a funky little garnish and then you're
gonna be in chicken heaven, I'm gonna be happy,
you're gonna have a new recipe and you're
gonna be able to get that recipe here in the
description box.
What I want you to do is do the rub because
the rubs really important because we're gonna
get the seasoning onto the chicken first.
So I want a teaspoon of each of those bad
boys in there and then Lee wait to put the
flour in, we're gonna put it in there.
Then, can we get the lemon sliced up. Squeeze
it all into there and then all the honey into there.
Got you.
Crack on boys, looking good.
Now what we're gonna do is we're gonna do
the chicken. So we've got these chicken legs
and what I'm gonna do is I'm just gonna cut
through. So all you do is you just cut down
and then just where the ligament is, here,
you just wanna cut through there so we're
just gonna cut through and then just take
off the spare bits of fat and we're just breaking
them into those nice pieces of chicken.
So just get there.
Ok, so we're just getting that in there now
and that needs to marinade in there for 8
hours.
But John I'm hungry!
8 hours?!
What?!
We have a gig!
Easy boys!
Good things come to those that wait, you know
that! I talked you through this.
So it's been 8 hours later and we're ready
and fresh to take it to the next stage. And
so, what we're gonna do is, it's marinated
in its honey and lemon loving and now we're
gonna put the rest of the ingredients in.
So, corn starch, you want about a tsp of that.
Then, we want some more Cayenne pepper, another
tsp. We want some smoked paprika. Oh that
stuff just takes it to the next level. Then
the onion powder really, really takes it up.
And then the garlic powder is amazing.
And we just wanna scrunch that in. Ok. And
then flour. Now you want it to be, the majority
of it needs to be flour. Ok, and then we're
just gonna move that around and get all that
beautifully mixed in. So we'll just mix all
those ingredients in and then we take the
chicken and just get it in, drain off the
excess and get that into the flour. And then
just get that all mixed around. You wanna
make sure that it's fully coated, like this
bad boy here, and make sure that, this is
the important bit now, this is how you're
gonna get a really good coating on your chicken
because you gotta make sure you leave it for
half an hour just so it kinda is not totally
dry, it's getting a bit damp, then it's perfect.
It looks good to me John!
Oh yes!
Ok, chicken is ready to go in. So, drop them
in. and you see how they're getting a sizzle
straight away.
Can you hear that boys?! Oh yeah!
That's the sound of love!
Yes it is!
That's the sound of chicken!
Look at this! Look at this! Ok so then there
you've got your chicken. What's your tune
that's out at the moment?
The song out right now is Million Fans.
And that's the one that you shot in D.C. right,
in your hometown? It's cool. It's kinda like
you were saying earlier, it's kinda Beastie
Boys influenced. Who are your other influences
for you guys?
Like you said, Beastie Boys, Rage Against
the Machine, anything we've ever heard.
Tribe Called Quest!
Yeah.
All types of Hip-hop, all types of Rock, Bad
Brains, a lot of stuff.
So that's my honey and lemon fried chicken. Absolutely lovely! Are you loving it boys?
Loving it!
They're loving it!
So check out Jamie's Food Tube for any more chicken recipes and all the other chefs that
are on there and make sure you subscribe people!
Come on, let's be having ya!
Eat your chicken!
People of Food Tube, the Food Busker is in
da house! Check out my new channel at Youtube.com/foodbusker.
Right now people!