now this could be rather on controversy
already had a very good trade relations
with europe
uh... but in
said they decide to put something in
there called investors state
dispute resolution
now that sounds terrific legoland not
clear what it is right well let's
explain
and that's just a dispute resolution
would allow company to kill a regulatory
winnie world war
to international core
so that's why this in this field between
investors and the state
and what this is saying is waiting it
will also see
what was also small system is
wasn't just a johnson has the dispute
with param
and we've got a trade agreement with
panama for example if we did
and were about to
well they just uh... does it was a on a
u_s_ company to go to the u_s_
government seeking u
hope resolve this dispute
under this new way of doing it and it
hasn't been siding yet but
president bomb isn't there i'm sure all
the republicans are going to be in favor
because they do
it's a corporation the corporation what
other problems that yes or how how are
you sir
bob will jump to smother stuffed
so both sides are agreed to this and
so we're not world the trouble but now
that all of this new regime
well then johnson does does in the
united states air worthiness is directly
soup and
which would allow them the ability to
intimidate so many different states all
you really one of the cost of fighting
answer hundreds of lawyers will come in
for you
or you deal with that
regulation you have an awesome pollute
you're ever
now you think that's all no no no
it also puts the united states
the international body would be given
authority to impose economic sanctions
against
any country
they're violating this verdict
including the united states
you know this is
this is uh... clearer infringement
on arts summer aunty
on the conservatism poster that's
well then they don't know what
conservative is they have no idea what
their ideology stands for
this is exactly what you say don't tread
on me for you're gonna get away
you know what this would allow that
would allow foreign corporations by the
way also u_s_ corporations the coming
years a
walls to the unique in the united states
del piney and i think you know to
international court and get you
to get ready road salt you don't want
your
river an alabama polluted sad day for
you i actual court who say that
i can pollute those risks who's gonna
turn corporations and the simon indies
bind themselves
now of course everytime giving summer
ninety
you can't help but think of poor old
george w_ bush
now this was the rest of tribal
sovereignty in accordance already
at that point every hadn't even thought
of that yet right
reminds you of this
jam from the former president
what do you think
tribal sovereignty means in the truck in
the twenty-first century
and how do we resolve conflicts between
tribes confederacy contact
travel sovereignty sets up
you ready
hearing
even get a sovereignty and your
duties as sovereign
therefore the relationship between the
federal government and
tribes is one between ps
sovereign entity
uh...
dot blotting is all
laughter
along with
nitrite having bush explained every
street we
corporate sovereignty and national
sovereignty but i wish you good luck
uh... we're not done here though says
all salinas's tree represent says
framework will be subject to the
progress a presentation within the
government
brokerage firms
don't worry
uh... we got your back that they'll be
safeguards
was surprised uh... maybe they want to
his work
okay
ga-ga i'd put
noble receptors
uh... a la assault on from the sierra
club
males and she says
these provisions all big corporations
the level of nation states
and allow them to send arms over nearly
any law or policy which reduces their
future profits
and it does by the way talks about their
profits
they got a right to their profits if
your friends on the right to the
apartments all those other sovereign
entities
melting into an international court
and invalidate your national law
all conservative hence you'd be
exploring other cargonoff dogs
these are the black helicopters my
friends
any action willing to warn you
say you'll be dead studies i don't think
there actually are bringing black
welcomes them out of just be clear
but they will
get
signifi only infringe on our sovereignty
by doing this
u_s_ chamber of commerce turns it around
i love these guys
slash i can send quote
the they push for an increased
regulatory compatibility an updated
comprehensive investment terms
through caught
prevent discrimination
against investors in the trade pact
all right
the problem we had was we're
discriminating as corporations too much
now they explain this because they said
they
reporter asked miss women
you seem to have gotten everything you
want in the street agreements already
with the european what do you want here
this thing we're trying to do this
permission against us
and have a space offer
and get rid of the country's
and this is the campaign attention is
incredibly scary
this is where corporations
start to rule over the nation's
these member on broadway shows
soon nations will be under the umbrella
of corporations
uh... ivy lori wallach who's the
director of public citizen's globaltrade
watch
understood their intent perfectly says
quote
the dirty little secret about the
negotiation
is that it is not merely a bad trade but
rather what we're target
for elimination
strongest consumer health safety privacy
environmental an other public interest
policies
on either side of that way
so you'll have european companies and
banks in the u_s_ to get rid of our
regulations to get rid of
pollution standards our health and
safety standards
annual u_s_ companies
suing european companies uh... european
countries
near p and given their statements
it's a disaster in the making
and is very likely to pass