HIME HERBERT: Ky's super
awesome, obviously, because he
let us stay at his house.
HARVEY FOSTER: You've blown
it with that answer!
HIME HERBERT: What are
you talking about?
HARVEY FOSTER: Ky's
sick because we
can stay at his place?
HIME HERBERT: Well,
if you guys rolled
into my parents' town--
HARVEY FOSTER: That's
the worst answer
I've ever heard, ever.
HIME HERBERT: My parents
would never let you
stay at their house.
HARVEY FOSTER: That was bad.
Cut.
MALE SPEAKER: Ky's
sick because we
can stay at his house?
HIME HERBERT: Ky, you know
what I mean, right?
KYNAN TAIT: What if I didn't
let you stay at the house?
HIME HERBERT: I would still be
grateful for your company,
because I think you're
an awesome guy.
KYNAN TAIT: OK.
MALE SPEAKER: Little
twist, eh, Patrick?
HIME HERBERT: Ky, you
could stay at my
house anytime you want--
the whole kit.
KYNAN TAIT: My parents and my
little brother moved to Lareto
a few years ago.
I think for me it's the
perfect mix of Mexico.
It's just touristy enough for me
where most of the people in
the shops speak enough English
where you can get by not
speaking any Spanish.
And it's a well-kept city,
it's very quaint.
I love the landscape down there
and I love the culture.
I like how laid back it is and
their common disregard for
time and the whole way that
Westerners live their life.
So Lareto's kind of
the perfect mix,
like Southern Baja--
still Mexican, but still enough
tourist amenities to
keep a Westerner happy.
BRUCE WILLIAMS: Ready?
KEEGAN SAUDER: Yep.
BRUCE WILLIAMS: OK, this way.
I'm Bruce.
KEEGAN SAUDER: Bruce, Keegan.
BRUCE WILLIAMS: How you doing?
MALE SPEAKER: What does
your brother do?
KYNAN TAIT: He's now a scuba
dive instructor, so he's
traveling a lot, too.
He was living in Singapore,
now he's living in Mexico.
HEATH KIRCHART: Look
at that bird.
Spread out.
Hey Keegan, we need a hero
shot for the video.
BRUCE WILLIAMS: So they're about
600 pounds or so and
they get a little bit noisy.
We'll be pretty close to
them in the water.
You shouldn't be afraid though,
they're curious.
They're kind of used to people
being around them now.
KYNAN TAIT: One of those
spiny things?
You can touch them?
Like, they're not--
I have no interest in what's
going on under the water.
And just the feeling of
breathing underwater freaks
the hell out of me.
And I don't care to look
at the fish down there.
HEATH KIRCHART: Toys.
KYNAN TAIT: And see these weird
alien-looking fish.
Nothing about that excites
me too much.
HEATH KIRCHART: Ew, it's
got worms crawling
out of it over here.
BRUCE WILLIAMS: That's called
a brittle star.
KYNAN TAIT: Touch the middle
part of him, he's all soft.
HEATH KIRCHART: Oh, is he?
KEEGAN SAUDER: See?
You can feel it sucking on your
hand, the middle part.
BRUCE WILLIAMS: Well, I can tell
already after seeing all
of you in the water that none
of you are going to sink.
Because you have a positive
attitude and a buoyant
personality.
BRUCE WILLIAMS: That's
what you want.
The ideal situation.
KEEGAN SAUDER: Now
we're coming.
That one hurt a bit.
HEATH KIRCHART: I want in!
I can't do it.
Good luck getting in.
BRUCE WILLIAMS: Come on,
have another cigarette.
HEATH KIRCHART: Kick!
Kick!
BRUCE WILLIAMS: And your
impression at this time?
HIME HERBERT: I'm sweating
like a baked ham.
MALE SPEAKER: Was it you
that was asking for
a temperature increase?
HIME HERBERT: Yeah,
I was asking for
a temperature increases.
Now I would like a temperature
decrease.
Just maybe five or
six degrees.
BILL BRYANT: Blowing a fuse.
ARTO SAARI: I have a brake
light, but I don't have
running lights or a headlight.
It would kind of suck driving at
night with no headlight and
sunglasses on.
And couldn't be bothered putting
the goggles on because
they don't fit without
a helmet.
So I have to just follow these
guys just to try to stay as
close as possible to make sure
that I see where the road is.
BILL BRYANT: Here's that.
HIME HERBERT: Oh God,
my hands are dirty!
[BURPS]
Banana, V-8, coffee.
That's delicious.