Hey, dude, what's up?
DAVID KRINTZMAN: Hey,
how are you?
JAMES FREY: Dude, I have 10
process servers standing
outside of my apartment building
saying they're suing
me for intellectual property
theft and defamation to God
and slander to Jesus.
Should I call the cops?
Should I call the
Hell's Angels?
What should I do?
DAVID KRINTZMAN: Hang
on just one second.
JAMES FREY: Can they even
sue me for that?
Can you be sued for
slandering God?
DAVID KRINTZMAN: No--
God is not a person.
If somebody could try to file a
lawsuit, it would get tossed
out immediately.
JAMES FREY: Hey, dude,
you know what?
I'm just fucking
with you guys.
I'm with "Vice" magazine
and they had heard
I make crank calls.
So we decided to crank you.
DAVID KRINTZMAN: [LAUGHING]
JAMES FREY: [CHUCKLING]
DAVID KRINTZMAN: Motherfucker.
DAVID KRINTZMAN: See, this is
what I have to fucking deal
with when I represent
James Frey.
ROCCO CASTORO: [LAUGHING]
JAMES FREY: Later, dude.
I'll call you later.
DAVID KRINTZMAN: Bye.
JAMES FREY: Bye.
ROCCO CASTORO: So, hi, James.
How are you?
JAMES FREY: I'm good.
ROCCO CASTORO: You're
doing good today?
JAMES FREY: I'm doing
well today, man.
ROCCO CASTORO: So, there's been
a lot of press about your
book over the last few days.
And it's about a modern day
Messiah who advocates orgies
and drugs and lives for a short
time in the subways
underneath New York City.
Now, do you think people are
going to try to kill you or
anything like that because
of this book?
JAMES FREY: Are people going
to try to kill me?
I hope not, man.
I don't want to die, you know.
I don't know what's
going to happen.
I mean, some people read the
book and don't find it
offensive at all.
And some people read it
and say, how long
till you leave America?
I mean, that's part of the fun
of releasing a book is seeing
what happens, see if people read
it, see if people care,
see how they react.
The book wasn't designed to want
to make people kill me.
I tried to write a valid
religious document, write a
book about what I really think
it might be like if the
Messiah came back to Earth.
People think about the real
Christ and about the Bible.
And one of the things that's
forgotten, which is one of the
most important things, is that
when Christ was on Earth, he
was a radical.
He wasn't part of acceptable
society.
He didn't believe in anything
that acceptable
society held dear.
He was a radical preacher with
a radical message who was
dangerous enough so that he
was killed, so that he was
strung up on a cross
and killed.
I think if the Messiah were to
arrive or Christ to return, he
would be that same
type of radical.
ROCCO CASTORO: You said
it's your stab
at a religious document.
So what kind of research
went into it?
JAMES FREY: I had a number of
consultants on the book.
I had an orthodox rabbi here
in New York who was a
consultant.
I had a Pentecostal preacher,
a Catholic priest, a trauma
surgeon, a criminal defense
attorney, a
mental health advocate.
I wanted the book to be right.
I know how I feel about God and
how I feel about faith and
how I feel about religion.
But I didn't know the
mechanics of it.
There are very specific theories
about Messiah.
There are very specific
requirements within Judaism to
be considered Messiah.
And I needed to know
all that stuff.
ROCCO CASTORO: The book is
structured just like the New
Testament, Old Testament.
It's told through different
books, through different
narrators who interact with Ben
Zion, who's the Messiah.
And some of the books
are actually named--
Ruth or Esther.
How much do they have in common
with the original?
JAMES FREY: Obviously, I looked
a lot at the first two
books of the Bible.
I looked at how the
stories were told.
I looked at weird stuff
like numbers.
There's a lot of numbers
in the Bible.
And they're very specific.
I looked at the Gospels
of Christ.
I love that we don't know the
story of Christ from his own
perspective.
We just know it from people
who knew him.
And I love that the Gospels
of Christ are, in and of
themselves, unreliable.
They don't actually match
up perfectly.
They tell different stories.
I just tried to think what would
a contemporary version
of this be?
So yeah, the book is written
entirely from the perspective
of the friends, family, and
followers of Ben Zion Avrohom,
also known as the Messiah, also
known as the Lord God.
Every chapter of the book is
written in a radically
different voice.
The first chapter is a
18-year-old Puerto Rican girl
living in a housing project
in the Bronx.
The second chapter is
45-year-old foreman at a
construction site.
The third chapter is a
38-year-old trauma surgeon at
a hospital.
And it was cool to have to
literally reinvent how I wrote
with every chapter.
ROCCO CASTORO: When you were
compiling research for the
book, did you have any new
thoughts about faith?
JAMES FREY: Oh, I have a
profound respect for faith.
I mean, if anything, writing the
book gave me more respect
for religion and made me
think about it more.
But what the book really is is
me trying to work out my own
feelings about it.
I've struggled with the idea of
God and religion and faith
almost my whole life.
And it's something I've written
about every time I've
written a book.
You know, most of "A Million
Little Pieces" is about it.
I walk around New York.
And I see things that are
incredibly beautiful every day
and incredibly horrific
every day.
And you think about, well,
why are we even here?
How does my brain work?
Is my brain different from
my spirit or my soul?
Do I believe, do I not?
What do I believe in?
How do I reconcile living in the
21st century, living in an
era of nuclear weapons and
genetic engineering and living
in an era where we know being
gay is not a decision somebody
makes but the way
someone's born?
How do we reconcile
these ideas--
the physics of Stephen Hawking
with, you know, stories of a
man with a big white beard who
sits on a chair with a bunch
of dudes judging everybody?
It's really hard for me to
reconcile those ideas.
But I think it must be a
beautiful thing to believe in
God without a shred of doubt
and to have faith.
ROCCO CASTORO: Were
you brought up
with any sort of religion?
JAMES FREY: I was baptized
Catholic.
And I was confirmed Episcopal.
And my parents took us to
church every Sunday
when I was a kid.
I grew up in Cleveland.
But I've never been able
to really believe in
that kind of God.
And in a lot of ways, the book
is me writing about a God I
could believe in.
If I were to believe in
something, it would be
someone like this.
ROCCO CASTORO: I've had a lot
of the same struggles.
At the same time, when I find
myself in really crappy
situations, I might
do something that
could be called praying.
Have you done that any time
recently or in the last 10
years or anything like that?
JAMES FREY: Yeah, many times.
I mean, whenever you go through
a bad time in your
life, you want some
reassurance, or
you want some help.
And when your life's completely
out of control, you
want to try to find some way
to control it or find some
thing that can control it.
I don't really talk
about this.
I've never really
talked about it.
But my wife and I had a son who
died a couple years ago.
I sat in the hospital.
And I watched him die.
And when that was happening, I
would get on my knees every
day and beg God for help,
literally beg and plead and
cry and say, help me.
I would say, take me and
let my son have a life.
I don't need a life.
Take my life, give it to him.
And while that was happening,
I went to churches of
different denominations
around New York.
I went to a mosque.
I went to a synagogue.
I went to all these places.
And everywhere I went, I
got down on my knees.
And I begged for help.
I begged for something--
for relief, for a sign,
for whatever.
And I didn't get anything.
I didn't feel anything.
I don't know if that's because
I'm a bad guy in God's eyes.
there isn't a God.
I don't know if I did it the
wrong way or if I needed to do
it before that to be able
to get the help then.
I don't know.
I don't have the answers
to any of it.
But I've never gotten a sign.
ROCCO CASTORO: A large part of
the book has to do with the
world is ending in some way.
And whether that means flat-out
apocalypse, and
everything blows up, or just a
complete change of how humans
live, that's what Ben Zion
preaches in the book.
And that's the word of
God through him.
Do you think we could be close
to the end-- like, this could
really be happening right now?
JAMES FREY: I mean, I think we
live in a world where a lot of
people have a lot of bombs.
There are bombs that take
out tens of millions
of people at a time.
And there's a lot of hatred
between all the people who
have these weapons.
And if you look at the conflicts
around the world,
most of them are religious
conflicts--
the Middle East, Israel,
Palestine, the United States.
And Islam as a global religion
is, in large
part, a religious conflict.
9/11 was a strike in the
name of religion.
And if you look back over the
course of history for the last
couple thousand years, most of
the big wars have sort of been
land grabs done in the
name of religion.
And unless there's some other
system that comes in to
replace the ones we have--
which I don't see happening--
nothing's going to change.
There'll be some sort of major
conflict tied into religion
that will kill a
lot of people.
ROCCO CASTORO: And let's talk
about something else that's a
big deal with this book--
how you're publishing it.
So why don't you tell us exactly
what your plans are
for releasing this
to the world.
JAMES FREY: I tried to write a
radical book that wasn't like
anything anybody had
done before.
And I'm trying to release
it in a radical way.
I've had problems in my career
before when I write
controversial material, problems
dealing with sort of
corporate entities behind it
and how they disavow it or
step away from it once
the controversy
reaches a certain point.
So I decided I wasn't
even going to
contemplate doing that.
So I thought an art gallery
would be a more appropriate
place to publish books.
I got in touch with five
of my artist friends--
Richard Prince, Ed Ruscha, Terry
Richardson, Dan Colen,
and Richard Phillips.
And I'm collaborating with
them on making these
illuminated manuscripts, like
old medieval Bibles, where
they sort of make art that
is their reaction to
what they've read.
And then we publish it as
sort of a book with a
lot of art in it.
And they're going to be
beautiful, astounding,
one-of-a-kind objects.
And I think the future of
publishing is that.
We're seeing publishing change
very radically right now.
We have the internet.
We have digital devices like
the Kindle and the
Nook and the iPad.
And I don't need a publisher
to release my
books on those things.
So I sort of arrived that I
was going to publish these
beautiful books and limit the
number of them and then, at
the same time, let anybody who
wants to read the book read it
on a digital device.
I wanted to become a writer to
break rules and to get in
trouble and to do things
that pushed boundaries.
And I think at some point,
literature has become this
precious thing that doesn't
value that anymore, even
though most of the historical
figures in it only did that.
Something's a book.
And everything else
is irrelevant.
What's relevant is when somebody
picks up that book
and reads it, how it makes them
feel or if it makes them
think or, if at the end
of it, they think it
was worth their time.
All the other stuff
is just bullshit.