Yo, you already know
what it is, man.
This is B-I-G Sean.
Big Sean, man.
And this is my wildest,
craziest, ape shit party ever,
man, that I went through.
So I remember my homey
hitting me up.
He was like, yo, I'm about
to throw a party
at my uncle's house.
And I pull up on the block, and
everybody knows about it.
There's traffic on the block.
I'm like, I don't know how all
these motherfuckers is going
to fit in this house.
He's like, yo man, come
to the basement.
I'm like, basement?
Man, he told me this shit
was about to be
a banging ass party.
What you mean basement?
He opens the door, and man this
dude had a motherfucking
club in his basement, mann
Two stripper poles,
drinks all day.
Titties were flying
everywhere, man.
Titties almost hit me in
the head, in the eye.
People getting lifted,
doing what they do.
I'm looking at this one
girl I went to high
school with, right?
I always looked at her over the
years and was like, damn,
I wonder how them
titties look.
She was wearing all
black, all tight.
I'm looking at her, and
she's looking at me.
I look around, and she's still
looking at me, giving me that
"I want to fuck" eye.
I was, like, damn.
And then finally, her girl came
up to me and was like, oh
my god, she would totally
fuck you right now.
She just told me.
Oh shit!
So I'm running around
the party like,
yo, who got a rubber?
And they like, man, we ain't
got no condoms, which they
probably but they just ain't
wanna give me one.
So I go back to my
car, running like
it was a track meet.
And I'm searching through my
car, passenger side, backseat.
I looked in between the seats,
and there you have it--
the golden ticket.
I run back in the party.
I went over there and started
talking to her.
We went into our own little
private section.
So I took the titties out, and
they just flopped out like a
avalanche down a goddamn
mountain.
We started fucking in
the party, right?
In a private room.
One homey walks in.
He's trying to take pictures
and shit .
I told him to get
the fuck out.
I walked out, party
still going on.
This girl comes up to me and
was, like, did you just have
sex in the party?
I was, like, no.
Hell yeah, I did.
And she was like, aw man, that's
so fucked up man, ew.
And a year later, the same exact
girl who said that ended
up being my girlfriend for
years, like, up until now.
So that's one of the
craziest, most fun
parties I've ever had.
Funny as shit.
It's B-I-G. Man, you already
know what it is.