The explanation`s coming up. I`m Carl Azuz.
Welcome to CNN STUDENT NEWS.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
AZUZ: First up: coughing, sneezing, fever,
running nose. There`s nothing unusual about
that stuff this time of year. But if it feels
like you can`t go anywhere without seeing
these symptoms of sickness, you might be right.
Flu season is here and from what we`re seeing,
it`s a bad one.
Check out this map. All those states in red,
that`s where officials are reporting widespread
outbreaks of the flu. There are more than
40 states with that. Normally, flu season
hits its peak around late January, early February.
By the end of December, more than 22,000 had
checked into the hospital with flu-like symptoms.
Doctors say it`s hard to predict just how
bad the flu season might get but some are
concerned there are so many cases this early
in the season.
A couple weeks ago, I sat down with CNN`s
Dr. Sanjay Gupta -- he`s our chief medical
correspondent -- to talk about the flu. One
of the things I asked him is, "How do you
know when you`re too sick to go to school?"
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: With what symptoms should a student
stay home? Like, you wake up, you`re not feeling
well. At what point should you say, "I`m not
going to school"?
DR. SANJAY GUPTA, CNN CHIEF MEDICAL CORRESPONDENT:
Fever`s going to be one of the things that`s
going to be a hallmark. Usually when you talk
about a fever that`s above 101.3, 101.4, that
area. That`s a true fever.
If you have some of the classic symptoms including
sore throat but also specifically muscle aches
are something that distinguish flu from a
regular cold. You should probably stay home
with both. That`s one way you can tell the
difference.
AZUZ: How effective is a flu shot?
GUPTA: Flu shots can be very effective. You
know, there`s numbers that vary every year,
but it`s in the 70 to 80 percent range. It`s
not 100 percent but it is pretty good and
really the best thing that we have.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: All right, now, Dr. Gupta and I talked
about a lot more regarding the flu. We discussed
how the flu spreads, how to keep it from spreading.
There`s something you can do and it`s pretty
easy. Check out the interview. It`s in the
Spotlight section of our homepage, that`s
cnnstudentnews.com.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today`s shoutout goes
out to Ms. Bzdawka and the students at Achieve
Language Academy in St. Paul, Minnesota.
Jeannette Rankin wa the first woman elected
to what U.S. government body?
Here we go: was it the Supreme Court? Senate?
House of Representatives? Or Joint Chiefs
of Staff?
You`ve got three seconds. Go.
Rankin was elected to the U.S. House of Representatives
in 1916 and then again in 1940.
That`s your answer and that`s your shoutout.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: When Jeanette Rankin first walked into
the Capitol as a U.S. representative, she
certainly stood out. She was the only woman
there. If she were a member of the 113th Congress,
the one that just started this year, she`d
have a lot more company.
Ninety-eight women: 78 in the House, 20 in
the Senate. In fact, the Senators from California,
New Hampshire, and Washington are all women.
That`s just part of the diversity that this
Congress represents. With nearly 100 female
members, there are more women serving together
in Congress now than there ever have been
before.
The 113th Congress also includes 43 African-Americans,
31 Latinos, 12 Asian-Americans and Pacific
Islanders. The House and Senate have 7 gay
or bisexual members. The Senate has its first
Buddhist member. And the House has its first
member who is a Hindu.
Some interesting former jobs among the members
of Congress as well. Five had former careers
in professional sports. Two were physicists.
And one worked as a Santa impersonator before
running for Congress. That might explain why
he owns six reindeer.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: See if you can ID me.
I was established in 1800. I`m part of the
legislative branch of the U.S. government.
I`m home to more than 150 million items, which
makes me the largest library in the world.
I`m the Library of Congress and my collections
include a lot more than just books.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: The Library of Congress does hold more
than 34 million books, but it also collects
recordings, photographs, maps, sheet music,
and for the past two years, tweets.
Back in April of 2010, the Library signed
a deal with Twitter to get access to all public
tweets since the site was founded. That means
if you tweet something and it`s public, meaning
it`s not a direct message, the Library of
Congress is going to get it. This includes
everything ever publicly tweeted.
So far the Library has collected more than
170 billion tweets; millions more, as you
might expect, roll in every day. But collecting
all these tweets is only part of the Library`s
challenge. What it`s working on now is figuring
out a way to make all of that data available
to the public.
Researchers all over the world use the Library
of Congress to their work. Library officials
say they started collecting tweets because
society was communicating more over social
media than it was through letters or journals.
So the Library of Congress is starting to
focus more on the digital world. Consumer
Electronics Show has always been about technology.
This thing is the largest gadget conference
in the world. It`s going on right now in Las
Vegas, Nevada.
Dan Simon hit the convention early for a look
at what could be some of this year`s trends
in technology.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
DAN SIMON, CNN CORRESPONDENT: It`s a January
tradition here in Las Vegas as crews work
furiously to get the booths and exhibits ready
for the start of the Consumer Electronics
Show. More than 150,000 people are expected
to roam these vast halls the next couple of
days to get a glimpse of the technologies
that might hit the store shelves in the coming
year.
TVs are always the biggest crowd-draw at CES.
Last year, the companies were pushing 3D TVs.
They didn`t really take off with consumers.
This year, they`re hoping that a technology
called Ultra HD will win over consumers. These
are screens that have over four times the
resolution as a typical HD TV. But they`re
expensive. Some of these sets cost almost
as much as a car.
And speaking of cars, they`re becoming a bigger
deal every year at CES. This year you`ll hear
the term "connected car" a lot. That means
using your smartphone for a lot of different
things, including using the phone to start
the car on those especially cold winter days.
Another big theme, home automation. Run your
home from wherever you are. This category
used to be for people who were really wealthy.
Now these products are a lot more affordable,
and it`s about being able to control your
lights, your thermostat, your appliances while
on the go.
And of course look for the latest innovations
in PCs, tablets, and cameras. More than 3000
companies are on display here, all of them
really vying for one thing: attention.
Dan Simon, CNN. Las Vegas.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Well at the end of yesterday`s show,
we told you about a blog. We posted a question
asking whether your New Year`s resolutions
were holding up.
Marie resolved to stay in shape and not to
eat as much. She`s happy to say she`s partly
kept it by eating right and going to the gym.
Alex wanted to tackle procrastination. But
with homework to read a novel, that resolution
hasn`t been holding up so well.
Addison wants to spend more time with the
family, friends, and dog instead of video
games. Says it`s so hard!
Elizabeth resolves not to complain at all.
"Life is wonderful and I should be grateful
for it," she writes.
Bardock is committed to winning the spelling
bee. "I know I will one- hundred percent"
and of course spelled everything right in
that post.
Ethan didn`t make any resolutions so he has
a 100 percent success rate. OK, Ethan.
Keisuke resolves to help people in Fukushima,
Japan, and study English to let people know
more about Fukushima.
Justin was working on getting another job
so he could be more independent.
Greta wants to learn more about gymnastics
to be come a gymnastics teacher.
And Somil and Aaron resolve to watch CNN Student
News every day and they`ve been doing it.
I`m thinking extra credit on that.
Before we go, we`re going to stir up the waters
a little bit. Actually, we`re going to let
these guys do it.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ (voice-over): People on a boat in this
YouTube video were just planning on doing
some whale watching. Instead, look at this.
They were witnesses to a stampeding pod of
dolphins. I guess the marine animals are actually
attention hogs. We`re not sure exactly what
caused the stampede; these dolphins aren`t
just out for a leisurely swim. It`s pretty
obvious they`re moving with a porpoise.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
There`s a probably some crazy idea for why
this kind of thing happens and maybe you could
blow holes in the theory, but there`s no reason
to make waves. After all, this kind of story
is just fin and games.
Remember, we`re looking for your iReports
describing Dr. Martin Luther King Jr in just
one word. You have less than one week to get
those in. All the details in the spotlight
at cnnstudentnews.com.
I`m Carl Azuz. We`ll see you tomorrow.