All of us at Echo Base
They'll never capture us
Make the jump to hyperspace
We've got to make it
The transport's out
The rebels, safe
The walker's down
We've made our escape
It's a dark time for the rebellion
It's a dark time for the light side
We've gotta save our friends
So I jump in the X-Wing
Say to R2
We're going to Dagobah
To find Master Yoda
There's an astroid field
They'd be crazy to follow us
The deflector shield
Holding strong but not enough
We gotta make it
Head right for
The Star Destroyer
This is war
Now, punch it, Chewie!
It's a dark time for the rebellion
It's a dark time for the light side
Never tell me the odds
Can't catch the Falcon
We're not being followed
This isn't over yet
Got caught by Boba Fett
[Guitar music plays]
Lando's not a system, he's a man
He's a man
- He's a man
They're not gonna get me
Without a fight
Vader arrives before them with a plan
With a plan
- With a plan
And Han ends up frozen in carbonite
Mind what you've learned, save you it can
Darth Vader, I'll never join you
I'll never turn to the dark side
Obi-Wan never told you
That I am your father
You know it to be true
No, that's impossible
The Empire must fall