first she thinks is a scam
mo cav a scam it's a stamp for straight
guys to pretend that they're married and
a with one of them
so still ever art says fault
you may be a straight as an arrow
they you may have a friend that is a
straight is an hour
uh... so you had a great job with
government we had this one of the whole
clan
i mean what would you prohibit you from
saving your day
in your get married and soul of a
separate
baggett all benefits
i'll just see so much abuse in this it's
unreal
welch who is on real because that's not
usually
i know if you've seen in the movies was
that adam sandler movie with chopra
myers oven
but in the real world people are like
hey do you have a great idea man
let's pretend we're gay
so that everyone we know things were
having sex with one another
and awaiting get married maybe even do a
ceremony
uh... so we can get some sort of
benefits
i guess i would make it friends with
boom boom shoe
we should continue to announce esp i
believe a husband and wife should be a
man or woman
of the benefits should be for a man and
a woman
there is no way that this is about
equality to meet it's all about a free
ride views the president know what you
mean by a free ride
yeah this is not a giant scam on the
part of the people to help straight
people
did some insurance benefits
know they're actually gain that would
actually like to get married
and that is overwhelming
number of cases is not an epidemic
of people you know there's gay marriage
is legalized all of the states
uh... there's another damage in
massachusetts a straight guys getting
married to one another
pretending they're gay so then get some
benefits
that's not really the issue at hand but
of course sue ever heart not only caught
up on that she says squall lord i don't
get in trouble over this
well you're right
but is not natural for two women two men
to be married
there was naturally would have equipment
to have a sexual relationship
now of course homosexuality is rampant
in animal kingdom
i don't know
that that uh...
payments to argue
or bisexual siskel ourselves as an but i
feel the need to educate the good uh...
chair of the g_-eight george's g_o_p_
diamante shook march percentages
may also have equipment where the male
matches the female and if you were to
get created by the way ml could match a
male
probability and as soon
and then uh... mission which is not done
yet
ukraine with this child that is a
lifestyle bill cohen marisol also the
difference is this is not true
but a next-door neighbor who was a media
relations
i could be just as from one to them as i
could be to you
and your wife or anybody else who are
you not less simple so
infectious is quote announcing the week
our society sam
or anything like that i'm missing out
against gay marriage because once you
begin marriage
you get everything else
didn't realize that they're gay marriage
came along with everything else
pushed his maybe actually did
voices here married to another guy who
they come by with or by the way
here's everything else
this is fast food now says what i love
about it is
she really is a she's merciful
i'm not even driving out of town with a
pitchfork
thank you
here so what's it like that so we're all
important and i feel like you
on on on and again i would have been
everything straight guys good training
day
be america
she doesn't miss a living there having
sex one other there's not an epidemic of
them getting married
and pretending they're having sex will
allow the reader
jr yeah
at this couple things
little
men than women can be friends
and if they're really what i have a
standard cannot
in bob
as chris government loving them up for
instance where the sender id
let's get married and i would be married
into the benefits into business for the
watermelon funeral is that none of those
this is one thing is that the cross into
the american
hits the streets in so far if we get the
first one look easy access to what are
you
the biggest and the system
you scan the system is a national it
doesn't make any sense
there were two ccc losing
on the site and people are stressing
over and it gets off about it because it
is not actually big deal
sekhar tonight to everyone
to come back on
this big inside of system of money
we don't care about money right the
status on the day
your money removal crazy now come back
to us that the ones that work absent but
strategic
no necklaces nana
jessa brilliant point
and i would like to be the first
petition
all marriages
including trade marriages 'cause what
there was fraught
generates a great point
what people want really married one of
married to that
like for example like for abuse or
somebody or green card
yeah you know what we should end all
straight marriages
good point here nailed it
gave your endeavours whoever heart
mission idea but i got the right
equipment