My life is in stages, you know what I
mean?
We the jury of in the above-entitled action, find the defendent
Calvin Broadus
not guilty of the crime of murder in
the first degree.
Whether it's me performing live on
stage...
Let me hear you say "Snoop Dogg!"
-Snoop Dogg!
Or me going through stages in life.
That's what my life has always been
based on.
And that's what forced me to find
a new path.
Snoop Dogg is still in Jamaica,
observing and participating in
authentic Jamaican culture.
The prodigal son returns.
I've been on the top ever since I've
been in it.
I've got rap songs that will never
die.
I think with no disrespect, but,
I'm tired of rapping.
I wanna do a record, a whole record,
with no rapping.
Fuck Snoop Dogg. Don't think about
none of the shit he rapped about,
hustling and making money and drug
dealing and shooting.
All that shit be out of here.
I didn't just wanna come here, say I
made a record in Jamaica
and grew some dreadlocks.
Rastafari called me.
I finally made it to paradise.
Bless up - Snoop Lion!
Jah said to love thee one to another
for him that loveth is of Jah!
Come hit some of this Californian [weed] one
time. Calm your nerves!