AUXINS AND THE GIBBERELLINS. AND WHAT I WOULD
LIKE TO
DO TODAY IS TO CONTINUE TO TALK TO YOU ABOUT
SOME OF
THE GROWTH REGULATORS AND TO SHOW YOU HOW
MANY OF
THESE GROWTH REGULATORS, IN FACT, ALL OF THEM
IN ONE
WAY OR ANOTHER IMPACT ON MANY OF THE ACTIVITIES
OF
YOUR LIFE HAVE A LOT TO DO WITH THE FOODS
THAT YOU
EAT. AFTER THE DISCOVERY OF THE AUXINS AND
GIBBERELLINS IN THE EARLY 1950'S AND A LITTLE
BIT
EARLIER, PEOPLE BELIEVED THAT THERE MUST BE
OTHER
PLANT GROWTH REGULATORS THAT WERE OUT THERE.
AND SO
THERE WAS A LARGE AMOUNT OF RESEARCH THAT
WAS PUT
FORWARD INTO TRYING TO FIND OTHER GROWTH REGULATORS.
OTHER COMPOUNDS WHICH IN VERY LOW CONCENTRATIONS
WOULD
EFFECT PROFOUNDLY GROWTH AND DEVELOPMENT IN
PLANTS.
THE QUESTION WAS, HOW WOULD YOU FIND THESE.
DON'T
FORGET THAT AT THOSE TIMES WE DIDN'T HAVE,
THESE WERE
IN THE 1950'S, WE DIDN'T HAVE THE SENSE THAT
CHEMICAL
ANALYSIS THAT WE HAVE TODAY. SO, PEOPLE HAD
TO RESORT
TO OTHER SYSTEMS IN ORDER TO BE ABLE TO FIND
OR TO BE
ABLE TO DETECT THESE OTHER COMPOUNDS THAT
WERE
PROBABLY PRESENT IN VERY, VERY LOW AMOUNTS.
AND, ONE
OF THE WAYS THEY DID IT, WILL BE ILLUSTRATED
IN THIS
FIRST SORT OF PORTION OF THE LECTURE. I WANT
TO TALK
TO YOU ABOUT THE SYSTEM THAT WAS DEVELOPED
TO HELP
PEOPLE DETECTOR TO FIND NEW GROWTH REGULATORS.
AND
THIS SYSTEM DEPENDS UPON THE FACT THAT IF
WE MAKE A
CROSS SECTION OF THE STEM, IN THE CENTER OF
THE STEM
IS THE PITH. THESE PITH ARE UNDIFFERENTIATED
PARENCHYMA CELLS WHICH YOU HAVE ALREADY SEEN
BEFORE
WHEN WE TALKED THE STEM. NOT ONLY ARE THESE
CELLS
UNDIFFERENTIATED PARENCHYMA CELLS, BUT BECAUSE
THEY
ARE LOCATED IN THE CENTER, THEY ARE ESSENTIALLY
FREE
OF ANY MICROBIAL CONTAMINATION AND THEY ARE
SAID TO BE
ASEPTIC. THEY ARE FREE OF ANY MICROBIAL
CONTAMINATION. AND SO WHAT WAS DONE WAS TO
USE THESE
CELLS IN A TECHNIQUE WHICH WAS KNOWN AS TISSUE
CULTURE. SOME OF YOU HAVE SOME EXPERIENCE
OR HAVE
READ SOMETHING ABOUT THIS. LET'S TALK ABOUT
HOW THEY
DID THIS. WE HAD AN ERLENMEYER FLASK, ERLENMEYER
FLASK. SO HERE WE HAVE A FLASK. AND WE HAVE
A MEDIUM
HERE WHATEVER IT COULD BE, SOME KIND OF CULTURE
MEDIUM. AND, INTO THIS ERLENMEYER FLASK WE
PUT THE
PITH. THE PITH TISSUE. AND THEN WHAT THESE
WORKERS
DID WAS THEY BEGAN TO TAKE PLANTS AND TO EXTRACT
THEM,
TO FRACTIONATE THEM, TO BREAK THEM DOWN IN
TO SMALLER
AND SMALLER FRACTIONS. AND THEN TO INCLUDE
THE
FRACTIONS INTO THE CULTURE MEDIUM. AND THEN
TO SEE
WHAT HAPPENED. WHAT WAS THE RESULT. WHAT KIND
OF
PHENOMENOLOGY DID THE PARENCHYMA CELLS, THE
PITH CELLS
BEGIN TO SHOW. AND COMING FROM THIS WORK WAS
THE
DISCOVERY OF THE THIRD GROUP OF PLANT GROWTH
REGULATORS WHICH STIMULATED CELL DIVISION.
A GROUP OF
GROWTH REGULATORS WHICH IN VERY LOW CONCENTRATIONS
STIMULATED CELL DIVISION. SO, IF YOU LOOKED
INSIDE OF
THIS FLASK, WHICH ORIGINALLY HAD THE PARENCHYMA
CELLS
IN IT, WE NOW HAD A LARGE UNDIFFERENTIATED
MASS OF
CELLS. AND, BIOLOGISTS HAD TO GIVE A NAME
TO THIS
LARGE UNDIFFERENTIATED MASS OF CELLS, SO THEY
CALL IT
A CALLUS, CALLUS. YOU WILL SEE IT REFERRED
TO THIS
WAY IN YOUR TEXT BOOK. A LARGE UNDIFFERENTIATED
MASS
OF CELLS. WHEN THEY THEN LOOKED TO SEE WHAT
WAS IN
THIS FRACTION THAT WAS CAUSING THESE CELLS
TO DIVIDE
VERY RAPIDLY, THEY DISCOVERED A GROUP OF COMPOUNDS
WHICH WE COLLECTIVELY CALL TODAY, CYTOKININS.
THAT
IS, THEY STIMULATE CELL DIVISION, CYTOKINESES
WHICH IS
WHERE THE TERM CYTOKININS COMES FROM. CYTOKINESES.
THEY STIMULATE CELL DIVISION. CYTOKININS ARE
PROBABLY
OF THE GROWTH REGULATORS WE ARE GOING TO TALK
ABOUT,
THE ONES WHICH WE DON'T HAVE MUCH EVIDENCE
FOR THEIR
INVOLVEMENT IN OUR DAILY ACTIVITIES. BUT,
THEY HAVE
VERY PROFOUND EFFECTS ON GROWTH AND DEVELOPMENT.
SO,
LET'S LIST SOME OF THE GENERAL CHARACTERISTICS
OF THE
CYTOKININS. THE FIRST CHARACTERISTIC WAS THE
BASIS OF
THEIR DISCOVERY. THEY STIMULATE CELL DIVISION.
THE
SECOND CHARACTERISTIC IS A VERY INTERESTING
ONE, THEY
DELAY SENESCENCE.
SENESCENCE OR DEATH. AND THIS IS
AN INTERESTING TOPIC, ONE WHICH HAS NOT BEEN
STUDIED
TOO MUCH, BUT IS OBVIOUSLY ONE WHICH MIGHT
HAVE A LOT
OF PRACTICAL VALUE. A THIRD SORT OF THING
THAT
CYTOKININS DO IS IN, LET'S SAY, IN COMBINATION
WITH
OTHER GROWTH REGULATORS, THEY CAN AFFECT PLANT
DEVELOPMENT.
AND LET'S TALK ABOUT HOW THEY DO THIS
AND I WANT TO FOCUS ON ONE OF THE GROWTH REGULATORS
THAT THEY WORK IN COMBINATION WITH. ONE THAT
YOU HAVE
SEEN BEFORE, ALTHOUGH, THIS IS NOT THE ONLY
ONE IN
WHICH THEY HAVE EFFECTS. AND THIS COMBINATION
HAS TO
DO WITH AUXIN AND CYTOKININS. IF IN THIS TISSUE
CULTURE FLASK THAT WE HAVE DRAWN BEFORE,
IF IN THIS
TISSUE CULTURE FLASK THAT WE DREW BEFORE,
WE INCLUDE
BOTH AUXINS AND CYTOKININS. IN THE MEDIUM
WE CAN
PROFOUNDLY EFFECT THE CALLUS TISSUE AND IN
ORDER TO
SUMMARIZE A LARGE NUMBER OF EXPERIMENTS I
AM GOING TO
MAKE THIS GRAPH FOR YOU OVER HERE. ON THIS
GRAPH WE
ARE GOING TO HAVE AUXIN ON THE Y AXIS AND
THIS WOULD
BE INCREASING CONCENTRATIONS OF AUXIN WITH
ZERO DOWN
AT THE BOTTOM. EVERYBODY CLEAR ABOUT THAT?
AND ON
THE X AXIS WE ARE GOING TO PUT CYTOKININ WITH
INCREASING CONCENTRATIONS IN THIS DIRECTION.
SO, IF
THE FLASK CONTAINED NO AUXIN OR NO CYTOKININ
IT WOULD
BE ZERO. AND IF IT HAD A LOT OF AUXIN BUT
A LOW LEVEL
OF CYTOKININ IT WOULD HAVE A HIGH RATIO OF
AUXIN TO
CYTOKININ OR IF IT HAD A LOT OF CYTOKININ
BUT LOW
LEVELS OF AUXIN, IT WOULD HAVE A HIGH RATIO
OF
CYTOKININ TO AUXIN. THE FIRST THING THAT WAS
FOUND IS
IF YOU INCLUDED IN THIS MEDIUM, AUXIN AND
CYTOKININ IN
ABOUT THE SAME RATIO. WHAT YOU FOUND SO
THAT THEY ARE
ABOUT THE SAME RATIO 1 TO 1. WHAT YOU FOUND
IS THAT
THE CALLUS REMAINED UNDIFFERENTIATED.
UNDIFFERENTIATED CALLUS. ON THE OTHER HAND,
IF THE
RATIO OF THE AUXIN AND THE CYTOKININ IN THE
FLASK, I
WILL SHOW YOU SOME PICTURES OF THESE IN A
MOMENT, WAS
FAVORING AUXIN SO THAT IS, YOU HAD A HIGH
AMOUNT OF
AUXIN RELATIVE TO A LOW AMOUNT OF CYTOKININ,
THE
CALLUS FORMED ROOTS. CALLUS FORMED ROOTS.
AND, IF
YOU HAD A HIGH LEVEL OF CYTOKININ, THAT IS
SOME PLACE
OVER HERE AND A LOW LEVEL OF AUXIN AND YOU
PUT THAT IN
TO THE CULTURE MEDIUM THE CALLUS FORMED SHOOTS.
SO
SIMPLY BY VARYING THE RATIO ON THE AMOUNTS
AS WELL,
ONE COULD EFFECT IN A VERY PROFOUND WAY THE
DEVELOPMENT OF THESE CALLUS CELLS SETTING
THEM OFF ON
A COURSE OF DEVELOPMENT WHICH WAS VERY DIFFERENT,
EITHER SHOOTS OR ROOTS OR REMAINING THE SAME.
WE
DON'T KNOW MUCH ABOUT THIS PROCESS. IT IS
A VERY
INTRIGUING PROCESS, BUT VERY DIFFICULT TO
STUDY AND WE
REALLY DON'T UNDERSTAND HOW THIS RATIO IS
EFFECTING
THE DIFFERENTIATION. FOURTH EFFECT OF CYTOKININS
IS
THAT THEY OVERCOME APICAL DOMINANCE.
WHICH AS WE SAID
WAS DUE TO AUXIN. SO, LET'S LOOK AT THAT STATEMENT
OVER HERE. IN THIS PARTICULAR CASE, WE HAVE
A SHOOT
WITH STRONG APICAL DOMINANCE.
THAT MEANS THAT, WE
WILL JUST MAKE ONE HERE, THAT THE AXILLARY
BUDS DON'T
GROW OUT.
IF ON THE OTHER HAND, YOU NOW ADD CYTOKININ
AND USUALLY YOU CAN TAKE A DROP OF LIQUID
AND JUST PUT
A DROP OF LIQUID ON TOP OF THAT AXILLARY BUD,
IF YOU
ADD CYTOKININ TO THIS AND YOU WAIT FOR SOME
TIME, WHAT
YOU FIND, HERE ARE THE LEAVES, IS THAT THE
AXILLARY
BUD GROWS OUT.
GROWS OUT. WE DON'T KNOW HOW THIS
HAPPENS, BUT WE KNOW THAT THE CYTOKININ IS
ABLE TO
OVERCOME THAT STRONG REPRESSION OF AXILLARY
BUD OUT
GROWTH BY SOME METHOD THAT WE HAVE NO IDEA
ABOUT.
HOWEVER, THIS IS INSTRUCTIVE BECAUSE THERE
ARE SOME
PLANT DISEASES. ONE OF WHICH YOU MAY BE
FAMILIAR
WITH. KNOWN AS WITCH'S BROOM, IN WHICH, IF
YOU LOOK
AT THE DISEASE THE PLANT HAS ON THE BRANCH,
ALL OF THE
AXILLARY BUDS ARE RELEASED. ALL THE AXILLARY
BUDS
GROW OUT.
AND IT LOOKS LIKE THE BROOM OF A WITCH.
SO THIS IS WHY IT IS CALLED WITCH'S BROOM.
NOW, HOW
DOES THIS DISEASE CAUSE THESE AXILLARY BUDS
TO GROW
OUT? ESSENTIALLY THIS DISEASE, WHICH IS CAUSED
BY
A BACTERIUM, EITHER THE BACTERIUM PRODUCES
CYTOKININ
OR CAUSES THE PLANT TO PRODUCE MORE CYTOKININ.
THE NET EFFECT IS THAT THERE IS A LARGE AMOUNT
OF CYTOKININ WHERE THE BACTERIUM HAS INFECTED
THE
PLANT AND THIS RESULTS IN A CHANGE IN THE
RATIO OF
CYTOKININ TO AUXIN AND THE BUDS ALL GROW OUT
MAKING
THIS STRUCTURE. AND MANY OF YOU MAY HAVE SEEN
THIS
BEFORE AND NOT REALIZED THAT IT IS CAUSED
BY
A DISEASE. NOW, WE SAID THAT CYTOKININS ALSO
STIMULATE CELL DIVISION AND THIS WAS TAKEN
UP BY THE
MEDICAL COMMUNITY BECAUSE THEY WERE INTERESTED
BECAUSE
YOU CAN ALSO BACTERIAL DISEASES WHICH INFECT
PLANTS.
CYTOKININS AGAIN ARE EITHER PRODUCED BY THE
BACTERIUM
OR THE PLANT MAKES MORE BACTERIUM, AND THIS
RESULTS IN
THE PRODUCTION OF TUMORS. TUMORS. AND THESE
TUMORS
MIMIC WHAT ONE MIGHT FIND IN A MICROBIAL SYSTEM
IN
WHICH WE HAVE CANCER GROWING AND SO MANY PEOPLE
WERE
STUDYING CYTOKININS FROM THE POINT OF VIEW
OF TRYING
TO UNDERSTAND HOW THIS MIGHT BE A MODEL SYSTEM
FOR
HELPING US TO UNDERSTAND SOMETHING ABOUT CANCER.
THESE FIRST SLIDES I WANT TO SHOW YOU NOW
ARE
GOING TO BE ONES THAT SHOW VARIOUS ASPECTS
OF
CYTOKININS. HERE IS A TISSUE CULTURE SYSTEM
IN WHICH
WE HAVE PITH CELLS WHICH HAVE BEEN PLACED
ON TO AN
AGAR MEDIUM. THIS IS ASEPTIC. AND THEN IF
WE ADD
VARIOUS THINGS TO THE AGAR MEDIUM, AND IN
THIS CASE,
IF WE ADD CYTOKININS TO THE AGAR MEDIUM WE
CAN
STIMULATE THE PITH CELLS TO START DIVIDING
TO ENLARGE
TO MAKE THIS UNDIFFERENTIATED MASS OF CELLS
WHICH IS
KNOWN AS CALLUS. IF IN THE CULTURE MEDIUM
YOU INCLUDE
A HIGH LEVEL OF CYTOKININ TO AUXIN, YOU CAN
CAUSE THE
PITH CELLS TO FORM SHOOTS, THIS IS A TOBACCO
PLANT IN
CULTURE. AND IF YOU NOW CHANGE THE RATIO SO
THAT YOU
HAVE HIGH LEVELS OF AUXINS TO CYTOKININS YOU
CAN CAUSE
THE PITH CELLS TO FORM ROOTS. A VERY PROFOUND
DIFFERENCE. AND YOU CAN MAKE KIND OF A SUMMARY
CHART
WHERE THIS ONE THEY HAVE THE AUXIN ON THE
TOP AND THE
CYTOKININ ON THE SIDE. BUT THE WHOLE POINT
IS THAT
HIGH LEVELS OF CYTOKININ, LOW LEVELS OF AUXIN
YOU GET
SHOOTS. HIGH LEVELS OF AUXIN LOW LEVELS CYTOKININ
YOU
GET ROOTS AND IN BETWEEN YOU HAVE THIS
UNDIFFERENTIATED PHASE. HERE IS A PEA PLANT
NOW, THIS
IS A CONTROL WITH THE APEX UP HERE. THE AXILLARY
BUD
WOULD BE LOCATED HERE AND WOULD BE INHIBITED
FROM
GROWING OUT. IF YOU ADD A DROP OF CYTOKININ
TO THAT
AXILLARY BUD AND YOU WAIT FOR SOME TIME, YOU
OVERCOME
OR YOU RELEASE APICAL DOMINANCE AND YOU
CAN CAUSE IT
TO GROW OUT. HERE IS WITCH'S BROOM, AGAIN,
WHICH SOME
OF YOU MAY HAVE SEEN. ALL OF THE AXILLARY
BUDS HAVE
BEEN RELEASED FROM APICAL DOMINANCE DUE TO
THIS
BACTERIUM. THERE IS A TUMOR OR A GALL. MOST
PEOPLE
CORRECTLY CALL THIS A TUMOR. TUMORS CAN GET
TO BE
QUITE LARGE. FOR THOSE OF YOU AGAIN WHO HAVE
BEEN UP
TO DAVIS LONG THE QUAD, SOME OF THE TREES
WHICH LINE
THE QUAD HAVE THESE LARGE TUMORS ON THEM.
THEY ARE
LIKELY, ALTHOUGH NOT PROVEN, TO BE A RESULT
OF AN
INFECTION FROM A BACTERIUM WHICH AGAIN IS
EITHER
ITSELF MAKES CYTOKININ OR IT IS CAUSING THE
TREES
NATURAL SYSTEM TO BEGIN TO MAKE CYTOKININ.
OKAY, SO
THESE ARE THE CYTOKININS. THEY ARE OF THE
GROWTH
REGULATORS WE HAVE TALKED ABOUT. THE ONES
WHICH ARE
MOST DIFFICULT TO STUDY. THEY ARE ONES WHICH
HAVE NOT
HAD A LOT OF WORK RECENTLY DONE ON THEM, BUT
IT IS A
FIELD WHICH IS RIPE FOR STUDY BECAUSE THERE
IS SO MANY
PROFOUND EFFECTS THAT THESE REGULATORS CONTROL.
SO
FAR WE HAVE CONSIDERED 3 GROWTH REGULATORS.
AUXINS,
GIBBERELLINS AND CYTOKININS. EACH OF THESE
GROWTH
REGULATORS ARE TRANSPORTED THROUGHOUT THE
PLANT VIA
THE VASCULAR SYSTEM. THE PLANT MAY MAKE THEM
IN
SOMEPLACE AND MAY MOVE THEM SOMEPLACE ELSE
VIA THE
VASCULAR SYSTEM. THIS FOURTH GROWTH REGULATOR
THAT WE
WANT TO TALK ABOUT NOW, UNLIKE THE PREVIOUS
3 IS NOT
TRANSPORTED IN THE VASCULAR SYSTEM. AND THE
REASON IT
IS NOT TRANSPORTED IN THE VASCULAR SYSTEM
IS BECAUSE
IT IS A GAS. AND IT IS DISTRIBUTED AROUND
THE PLANTS
IN THE AIR. NOW HOW WAS THIS PARTICULAR GROWTH
REGULATOR DISCOVERED? THE WORK WHICH BEGAN
OF THE
DISCOVERY OF THE GROWTH REGULATORS REALLY
GOES BACK TO
THE TIME THAT HOUSES AND ROOMS WERE FIRST
ILLUMINATED
WITH GAS LAMPS OR HEATED WITH GAS STOVES.
PEOPLE
NOTICED THAT IN ROOMS WHICH WERE EITHER ILLUMINATED
WITH GAS LIGHT OR GAS OR HEATED WITH GAS,
THAT THE
PLANTS IN THESE ROOMS BEGAN TO SHOW SOME
SERIOUS
EFFECTS. THE FIRST EFFECT SHOWED THAT THE
PETALS ON
THE FLOWERS THAT WERE GROWING IN THE ROOMS
DISCOLORED.
THE SECOND EFFECT WAS A NEW ONE THAT PEOPLE
HADN'T
REGULARLY SEEN. THE PLANTS DISPLAYED AN UNUSUAL
PHENOMENON, AND I WILL DRAW IT FOR YOU, BUT
I WANT TO
GIVE YOU THE NAME, CALLED EPINASTY. WHAT DOES
EPINASTY LOOK LIKE? IF THIS IS THE STEM AND
THESE
ARE THE LEAVES, THESE ARE THE LEAVES, IN THE
EPINASTY
RESPONSE WHAT WE FOUND HAPPENING WAS THAT
THE LEAVES
BEGAN TO CURL BACK ON THEMSELVES. EPINASTY.
LEAVES
BEGAN TO CURL BACK ON THEMSELVES. ANOTHER
CHARACTERISTIC OF THE PLANTS THAT WERE GROWING
IN THE
ROOMS THAT WERE HEATED OR ILLUMINATED BY GAS
WAS THAT
THE LEAVES AND THE PETALS FELL OFF OR AS BIOLOGISTS
SAY, THEY ABSCISED. THEY FELL OFF. THEY DROPPED
TO
THE GROUND. NOT GOOD IF YOU WANT TO HAVE PLANTS
IN
YOUR ROOM. FURTHER STUDY OF WHY THESE LEAVES
OR
PETALS FELL OFF GAVE THE FOLLOWING INFORMATION:
IF WE DRAW HERE A STEM. A STEM. AND HERE WE
HAVE A PETIOLE. HERE WOULD BE THE BLADE. THE
WHOLE
THING WOULD OBVIOUSLY BE THE LEAF. WHAT PEOPLE
NOTICED OR WHAT INVESTIGATORS NOTICED WAS
THAT PRIOR
TO THE LEAVES FALLING OFF, THAT A ZONE BEGAN
TO
WEAKEN. BECAME WEAK.
WHATEVER THIS GAS WAS DOING, IT
WAS PROMOTING A WEAKENING OF THIS ZONE. PROBABLY
PROMOTING SOME KIND OF ENZYMATIC ACTIVITY.
AND THE
LEAVES THEN DROPPED AND THE PETALS DROPPED
VERY
EASILY. BECAUSE THIS ZONE WAS ASSOCIATED WITH
THE
FALLING OR THE ABSCISSION OF THE LEAVES AND
THE PETALS
IT WAS CALLED THE ABSCISSION ZONE. THE ABSCISSION
ZONE. AND THIS GAS SEEMED TO AFFECT WHAT WAS
GOING ON
IN THE ABSCISSION ZONE. NOW, FURTHER ANALYSIS
OF THE
GAS THEN WAS UNDERTAKEN TO TRY TO UNDERSTAND
WHAT IT
WAS THAT WAS CAUSING ALL OF THESE EFFECTS.
AND, FROM
THIS WORK THE DISCOVERY WAS MADE OF THE FOURTH
PLANT
GROWTH REGULATOR WHICH IS KNOWN AS ETHYLENE,
WHICH IS
A GAS. PEOPLE FOUND THAT IN THE ROOMS THAT
THEY LIVED
IN IF THEY CONTAINED THE GAS THAT THEY USED,
CONTAINED
ETHYLENE, THAT WE SAW ALL OF THESE EFFECTS,
EXCEPT IN
ONE HOUSEPLANT THAT PEOPLE HAD THEY DIDN'T
SEE THE
EFFECTS. WHEREAS, ALL OF THE OTHER PLANTS
IN THE
ROOMS WERE LOSING THEIR LEAVES AND THE PETALS
WERE
FALLING OFF. THIS PLANT UP HERE IN FRONT KNOWN
AS
THE CAST IRON PLANT, SEEMED NOT TO BE EFFECTED
BY THE
ETHYLENE, BY WHAT WAS IN THE GAS. THEREFORE,
IN
PROPER VICTORIAN HOMES WHICH WERE HEATED AND
ILLUMINATED BY GASLIGHT THIS WAS THE ONLY
PLANT THAT
COULD BE FOUND. AND IF YOU PICTURES OF VICTORIANS
HOME THAT ARE ILLUMINATED BY GASLIGHT THIS
SHOULD BE
THE ONLY PLANT THAT SHOULD BE GROWING IN THOSE
HOUSES.
CALLED THE CAST IRON PLANT. AND IT APPEARS
NOT TO BE
SUSCEPTIBLE OR NOT TO BE SENSITIVE TO THE
COMPOUND
WHICH WAS ETHYLENE. ETHYLENE TURNED OUT TO
BE THEN
A CONTAMINANT IN THE GAS THAT PEOPLE USED
TO HEAT
THEIR HOUSES. AND AFTER IT WAS DISCOVERED,
IT WAS
THEN FOUND TO HAVE PROFOUND EFFECTS ON DEVELOPMENT
AND
WE NOW CONSIDER IT A FOURTH PLANT GROWTH REGULATOR.
NOT ONLY IS IT A FOURTH PLANT GROWTH REGULATOR,
BUT IT
IS THE MOST IMPORTANT COMMERCIALLY OF ALL
OF THE
GROWTH REGULATORS THAT WE WILL TALK ABOUT
HERE. AND,
IT IS THE ONE WHICH IMPACTS DAILY ON YOUR
LIVES. I
WANT TO TALK TO YOU ABOUT SOME OF THE THINGS
THAT
ETHYLENE DOES.
PROBABLY, THE MAJOR ASPECT OR THE MAJOR WAY
ETHYLENE IMPACTS ON YOUR LIFE IS THAT IT AFFECTS
OR WE
COULD EVEN SAY STIMULATES FRUIT RIPENING.
AND
THEREFORE, BECAUSE IT AFFECTS FRUIT RIPENING
BECAUSE
FRUITS ARE A MAJOR PART OF OUR DIETS THIS
PARTICULAR
SUBSTANCE GAINED A LARGE AMOUNT OF ATTENTION.
NOT
ONLY CAN ETHYLENE AFFECT FRUIT RIPENING, BUT
IT
AFFECTS IT IN A VERY UNUSUAL NUMBER OF WAYS.
AND ONE
WAY IT AFFECTS FRUIT RIPENING IS BASED ON
THE
CHARACTERISTIC THAT ETHYLENE, WHICH I WILL
ABBREVIATE
AS E, ETHYLENE STIMULATES ITS OWN FORMATION.
THAT IS,
IT IS AUTOCATALYTIC.
STIMULATES ITS OWN FORMATION.
IF YOU HAVE A FRUIT WHICH IS OVER RIPE, AND
IS
PRODUCING ETHYLENE, IF YOU HAVE A FRUIT THAT
PRODUCING ETHYLENE, IT WILL CAUSE THAT FRUIT
TO MAKE
MORE ETHYLENE. IT WILL MAKE MORE ETHYLENE.
IT THE
AUTOCATALYTIC. SO, IF YOU HAVE A DAMAGED APPLE
OR AN
OVER RIPE APPLE, IT IS IN THE VICINITY OF
OTHER FRUITS
WHICH ARE NOT RIPE OR NOT DAMAGED, THIS CAN
CAUSE THE
OTHER FRUITS TO BEGIN TO MAKE ETHYLENE AND
TO SPOIL
VERY QUICKLY. AND THIS IS THE BASIS FOR THE
SAYING,
THAT ONE ROTTEN OR ONE OVERRIPE APPLE WILL
SPOIL THE
BARREL. IT IS THAT ONE APPLE WHICH IS PRODUCING
A LARGE AMOUNT OF ETHYLENE, IF IT IS IN THE
VICINITY
OF OTHER FRUITS THAT ARE OTHERWISE HEALTHY
AND NOT YET
RIPE WILL CAUSE THOSE OTHER FRUITS TO START
MAKING
ETHYLENE AND THAT ETHYLENE THEN WILL CAUSE
THE FRUITS
TO OVERRIPEN. ETHYLENE HAS WIDE APPLICATIONS.
WE
KNOW THAT IT IS INVOLVED IN THE RIPENING OF
A LARGE
NUMBER OF FRUITS. AND JUST TO GIVE YOU AN
EXAMPLE OF
A COUPLE OF THE FRUITS THAT MANY OF YOU ARE
FAMILIAR
WITH. MANY CITRUS; ORANGE, GRAPEFRUIT, LEMONS,
A LOT
OF SQUASH FRUITS AND APPLES. ALL OF THESE
FRUITS HAVE
THEIR RIPENING AFFECTED BY ETHYLENE. THE RIPENING
PROCESS CAN BE GREATLY SPEEDED UP IF THERE
IS ETHYLENE
PRESENT. AND MANY OF YOU KNOW WHEN YOU GO
TO THE
STORE, ESPECIALLY IF YOU GET TO THE PRODUCE
MARKET
EARLY IN THE MORNING, AND YOU ARE ONE OF THE
FIRST
SHOPPERS THERE. TO GO OVER TO THE BANANA'S
AND YOU
KIND OF SURREPTITIOUSLY TOUCH THE BANANAS,
YOU WILL
FIND THAT THEY'RE WARM. NOT ONLY ARE THEY
WARM, BUT
MOST OF THE BANANA'S ARE GREEN WHEN YOU GET
THEM NOW
IN THE STORES IN BERKELEY AND THAT IS BECAUSE
BANANA'S, WHICH ARE ANOTHER FRUIT THAT IS
AFFECTED BY
ETHYLENE, ARE PICKED GREEN BEFORE THEY ARE
RIPE. AND
THEN THE PRODUCE LADY OR MAN PRIOR TO PUTTING
THE
BANANA'S OUT FOR YOU TO EAT TAKES THE BANANA'S
AND
PUTS THEM IN A ROOM AND GASSES THEM WITH ETHYLENE.
AND WHEN THIS IS DONE, THIS TRIGGERS THE RIPENING
PROCESS AND CAUSES THE BANANA'S TO BEGIN TO
RIPEN.
THE STARCH THEN IN THE BANANA IS CONVERTED
TO THE
SUGARS. AND THIS IS WHY IF YOU HAVE A BANANA
AND IT
IS NOT RIPE, IF YOU TAKE AN APPLE, AN OVERRIPE
APPLE,
OR IN THIS CASE TAKE A DAMAGED APPLE BECAUSE
THIS ALSO
AS YOU WILL SEE STIMULATES ETHYLENE. YOU TAKE
THE
APPLE AND YOU PUT IT IN A BAG AND THEN TAKE
THE GREEN
BANANA AND PUT IT IN THE BAG AND THEN CLOSE
THE BAG SO
THAT THE ETHYLENE GAS CAN ACCUMULATE, YOU
CAN ACTUALLY
CAUSE THE BANANA TO RIPEN AND VERY QUICKLY
GET
SOMETHING LIKE THIS, WHICH IS VERY BROWN AND
IN WHICH
THE SUGARS HAVE BEEN FORMED AS A RESULT OF
THE STARCH
DISAPPEARING. SO THIS IS A VERY PRACTICAL
EXAMPLE.
BANANA'S ARE TYPICALLY TREATED WITH ETHYLENE.
ANOTHER
EXAMPLE OF ETHYLENE'S RESULTS ARE FOUND IN
SOME OF
THESE FRUITS; YOU GUYS KNOW THESE AS KIWI'S
AND
AVOCADO'S. THESE ARE TWO FRUITS WHICH MOST
OF YOU, AT
LEAST WE CAN GROW KIWI'S PRETTY WELL IN THE
BAY AREA,
AND IN SOME PLACES WE CAN GROW AVOCADO'S.
IF YOU
LEAVE THEM ON THE PLANT THEY GENERAL DON'T
RIPEN OR
THEY DON'T RIPEN UNTIL THE FRUIT'S BEGIN TO
DRY AND
ARE NO LONG ERE GOOD TO EAT. THE REASON THEY
DON'T
RIPEN IS BECAUSE THERE IS NO ETHYLENE PRODUCTION
OR
VERY LITTLE ETHYLENE PRODUCTION CARRYING ON
IN THE
FRUIT. BUT, BY PICKING THESE FRUITS YOU ARE
DAMAGING
THEIR ENDS BY BREAKING THEM OFF OF THE PLANT,
AND THAT
DAMAGE ACTUALLY STARTS ETHYLENE PRODUCTION
AND CAUSES
THE RIPENING OF THE FRUITS. THIS IS AN IMPORTANT
EFFECT OF ETHYLENE IN CONTROLLING RIPENING
YOUR
FRUITS.
NOW, BECAUSE ETHYLENE IS SO IMPORTANT IN THE
FARMING AND IN OUR PRODUCE INDUSTRY, A LOT
OF PEOPLE
HAVE PUT A LOT OF TIME INTO TRYING TO UNDERSTAND
HOW
WE CAN PROLONG THE SHELF LIFE THE FRUITS BY
TREATING
FRUITS WITH ETHYLENE OR BY PREVENTING ETHYLENE
ACCUMULATING. YOU SHOULD REALIZE THAT ETHYLENE
IS
A NATURALLY OCCURRING COMPOUND. WE HAVE BEEN
EXPOSED
TO IT ALL OF OUR EVOLUTION AS HUMANS. SO IT
IS NOT
SOMETHING THAT HAS TO BE REGULATED BY THE
GOVERNMENT.
WHAT WAS FOUND, WAS THAT IN TRYING TO UNDERSTAND
HOW
ETHYLENE CAUSES RIPENING, AND HOW WE MIGHT
BE ABLE TO
SLOW DOWN RIPENING, SURE YOU COULD STORE THESE
BANANA'S IN A ROOM AND CONSTANTLY CHANGE THE
AIR IN
THE ROOM TO PREVENT THE ACCUMULATION OF ETHYLENE
AND
THERE BY PREVENT THE AUTOCATALYTIC RESPONSE.
OR
PERHAPS THERE WAS ANOTHER WAY, A MORE ECONOMICAL
WAY.
AND SO WHAT WORKERS WERE ABLE TO FIND IS THAT
IF YOU
STORED BANANA'S AND MANY FRUITS IN ROOMS WHICH
CONTAIN
5 TO 10 PERCENT CO2 THAT YOU COULD INHIBIT
RIPENING.
INHIBIT RIPENING. NOW, MOST OF YOU KNOW
AT LEAST IN
OUR GLOBE TODAY, BUT IT WILL CHANGE TOMORROW,
SURELY
THAT THE NORMAL CO2 LEVELS ARE 0.03 TO 0.04
PERCENT.
SO, WE ARE GREATLY INCREASING THE ATMOSPHERE
WITH CO2
AROUND THESE FRUITS THAT ARE IN STORAGE. AND
WHEN YOU
STORE FRUITS IN AN ATMOSPHERE THAT HAS 5 TO
10 PERCENT
CO2, WHAT APPEARS TO HAPPEN IS THAT THE PROCESSES
AFFECTED BY ETHYLENE ARE SLOWED DOWN OR INHIBITED.
MAY BE THAT THE RECEPTOR FOR THE ETHYLENE
ALSO BINDS
CO2 SO THAT THE TWO GASSES COMPETE FOR THE
SAME
RECEPTOR. THIS IS THE BASIS THEN FOR BEING
ABLE TO
PROLONG THE SHELF LIFE OF MANY FRUITS BY MANIPULATING
THE ATMOSPHERE. THERE ARE ALSO PROBLEMS HOWEVER,
AND
SOME OF YOU MAY HAVE ENCOUNTERED THIS. IF
FRUITS ARE
STORED FOR TOO LONG IN A CO2 ATMOSPHERE OR
IN TOO HIGH
CO2, AND I WILL SHOW YOU A PICTURE OF THIS,
THEY CAN
BE DAMAGED. AND SO SOME OF YOU I KNOW I HAVE,
HAVE
CUT OPEN APPLES AND FOUND THEM LOOKING GOOD
ON THE
OUTSIDE BUT BROWN ON THE INSIDE. AND THAT
BROWNNESS
ON THE INSIDE IS AN INDICATION THAT THEY WERE
STORED
EITHER FOR TOO LONG OR TOO MUCH OF A TIME
IN AN
ETHYLENE ATMOSPHERE. VERY IMPORTANT GROWTH
REGULATOR.
THE OTHER POINT I WANTED TO MENTION WITH REGARD
TO
ETHYLENE AND MANY OF YOU ARE AWARE OF THIS,
IS THAT
WHEN YOU RECEIVE FLOWERS, FOR EXAMPLE, VALENTINE'S
DAY
IS COMING UP. YOU FREQUENTLY RECEIVE A LITTLE
PACKET
OF POWDER WITH THE FLOWERS WHICH YOU ARE SUPPOSED
TO
PUT INTO THE LIQUID AND TO PROLONG THE SHELF
LIFE OF
THE FLOWERS. THESE PACKETS CONTAIN RELATIVELY
INNOCUOUS COMPOUNDS WHICH AS THE CO2 DOES
COMPETE WITH
OR SOMEHOW RETARDED THE EFFECT OF ETHYLENE
AND
THEREBY, PROLONG THE LIFE OF THE FLOWERS.
YOU CAN
ALSO, BY THE WAY, TAKE AN ASPIRIN AND PUT
AN ASPIRIN
IN THE WATER BECAUSE ASPIRIN ITSELF, THE COMPOUND
SALICYLIC ACID ALSO COMPETES OR IN SOME WAY
INHIBITS
THE ETHYLENE RIPENING OR THE ETHYLENE MATURING
PROCESS
AND THEREBY, ARE ABLE TO PROLONG THE SHELF
LIFE OF
THESE FLOWERS. NOW, ANOTHER ASPECT OF ETHYLENE,
WHICH
WE WANT TO CONSIDER, IS THAT IN SOME CROPS
WHICH ALSO
MAKES ETHYLENE COMMERCIALLY IMPORTANT, AND
THE ONES
THAT I WANT TO MENTION TO YOU ARE PINEAPPLE
AND MANGOS. THESE CROPS YOU CAN STIMULATE
THEM TO
FLOWER
WITH ETHYLENE. AND SO, FOR A FARMER THIS CAN
COMMERCIALLY BE A VERY IMPORTANT ADDED BONUS
TO HIS OR
HER CROPS BECAUSE YOU CAN CAUSE ALL OF THE
PLANTS TO
FLOWER AT ONE TIME. ALL OF THEM TO SET FRUIT
AT ONE
TIME AND THEN YOU CAN HARVEST THEM ALL AT
ONE TIME.
SO, FOR SOME PLANTS YOU CAN STIMULATE FLOWERING
WITH
ETHYLENE. IN CALIFORNIA, WE DON'T NORMALLY
GROW MANGO AND PINEAPPLES BUT ETHYLENE STILL
SERVES
BESIDES CONTROLLING FRUIT RIPENING, ANOTHER
VERY
IMPORTANT, EXTREMELY IMPORTANT PROCESS. IN
THE
CENTRAL VALLEY, IF YOU GUYS GO THROUGH THE
CENTRAL
VALLEY IN THE FALL AND YOU HAPPEN TO PASS
A CHERRY
ORCHARD OR WALNUT ORCHARD THESE ARE CROPS
WHICH ARE
VERY LABOR INTENSIVE AS FAR AS HARVESTING
THE FRUIT.
IF YOU TREAT THOSE TREES WITH A COMPOUND WHICH
STIMULATES NATURAL ETHYLENE PRODUCTION IN
THESE
PLANTS, IN THE WALNUT PLANT OR IN THE CHERRY
PLANTS,
WHAT THIS DOES IS IT ACTIVATES THE ABSCISSION
ZONE.
ACTIVATES THE ABSCISSION ZONE. SO THESE CHERRY
FRUITS
AND WALNUTS ARE ALREADY JUST SORT OF WEAKLY
ATTACHED
TO THE PLANT. THEY ARE VERY TENUOUS AS FAR
AS THEIR
ATTACHMENT. AND THEN WHAT HAPPENS IS, THE
FARMER WILL
SPREAD A TARP BENEATH THE TREES THAT HAVE
BEEN TREATED
WITH THE ETHYLENE INDUCING COMPOUND AND TAKE
A MACHINE, WHICH LOOKS LIKE SOMETHING FROM
THE SCIENCE
FICTION MOVIE, WHICH HAS TWO BIG CLAWS ON
IT. AND THE
MACHINE COVERS THE CIRCUMFERENCE OF THE TREE
AND
SHAKES THE TREE AND IN THE PROCESS THE FRUITS
ARE
PICKED, SO TO SPEAK, AND THEY FALL DOWN ON
THE GROUND.
AND THIS SAVES A LOT OF LABOR AND A LOT OF
TIME AND
MAKES FRUITS, AT LEAST NOT AS EXPENSIVE
AS THEY MAY BE
IF YOU HAD TO PICK THEM INDIVIDUALLY. LET
ME SHOW YOU
NOW SOME PICTURES OF ETHYLENE. AND LET'S GET
THIS
BACK HERE AGAIN. WE SEEM TO BE --
OKAY. SO, THIS
FIRST SLIDE IS MEANT TO SHOW YOU EPINASTY
WHICH OCCURS
IN PLANTS TREATED WITH ETHYLENE. HERE IS THE
NORMAL
PLANT. THAT WOULD BE THE KIND OF SITUATION
YOU WOULD
SEE IN PLANTS IN WHICH THE GAS IN THE ROOM
WAS
CONTAMINATED WITH ETHYLENE. HERE IS THE CAST
IRON
PLANT. AGAIN, IF A MOVIE IS SUPPOSED TO BE
AS REAL AS
IT IS AS FAR AS THE SETTING FOR VICTORIAN
HOME, THIS
IS THE ONLY PLANT THAT YOU SHOULD FIND GROWING
IN THAT
PARTICULAR SITUATION. HERE ARE BANANA'S, AGAIN
BANANA'S ARE PICKED AS MOST OF YOU KNOW, GREEN.
AND
THEN THEY ARE HELD IN CO2 ATMOSPHERE, CO2
ENRICHED
ATMOSPHERE, REMOVED FROM THAT ATMOSPHERE BEFORE
THEY
ARE TO BE PUT OUT AND THEN TREATED WITH ETHYLENE.
AND
THE LAST SLIDE I WANT TO SHOW YOU ARE APPLES
WHICH
HAVE BEEN STORED IN ENVIRONMENTS OR IN ATMOSPHERES
IN
WHICH THE CO2 CONCENTRATION WAS EITHER NOT
WELL
REGULATED OR THE APPLES WERE LEFT TOO LONG
IN THIS
ATMOSPHERE AND THIS IS THE TYPE OF DAMAGE
THAT YOU
WOULD SEE IN THOSE SORTS OF FRUITS. SO, IF
ANY OF YOU
HAVE EVER ENCOUNTERED ANYTHING LIKE THIS,
THESE ARE
A RESULT MOST LIKELY OF HIGH LEVELS OF CO2
IN THE
ATMOSPHERE. OKAY. SO, THAT IS THE FOURTH GROUP
OF
GROWTH REGULATORS, A VERY IMPORTANT GROUP.
THE MOST
IMPORTANT COMMERCIALLY OF ALL OF THE REGULATORS
THAT
WE WILL CONTINUE WITH. FINALLY, IN THE LAST
15 OR 20
MINUTES I WANT TO TALK TO YOU ABOUT THE LAST
GROUP OF
GROWTH REGULATORS. IT HAS A VERY INTERESTING
HISTORY
OF DISCOVERY. AND THIS GROWTH REGULATED GROUP
WAS
DISCOVERED TWICE INDEPENDENTLY AT THE SAME
TIME. AND
LET ME TELL YOU ABOUT THE TWO DIFFERENT GROUPS
THAT
DISCOVERED IT AT THE SAME TIME. THE FIRST
GROUP THAT
DISCOVERED IT WAS IN WALES, IN THE UNITED
KINGDOM.
THESE INDIVIDUALS WERE INTERESTED IN THE
FACT THAT
DORMANT BUDS, WHICH YOU CAN JUST SEE NOW BEGINNING
TO
BURST ON THE OUTSIDE, DORMANT BUDS COULD BE
CAUSE TO
BURST PREMATURELY, THAT IS, THE LEAVES COULD
BE CAUSE
TO COME OUT PREMATURELY IF YOU REMOVE THE
SCALES THAT
WERE COVERING OVER THE END OF THE BUD. SO,
THESE
SCALES THEY HYPOTHESIZE CONTAIN SOME COMPOUNDS,
SOME
SOLUTION, SOME MATERIAL WHICH KEPT THE BUDS
DORMANT.
AND, WHEN THEY EXTRACTED, AND HERE IS ONE
IN WHICH THE
BUD SCALES HAVE BEEN REMOVED AND THINGS ARE
BEGINNING
TO COME OUT, WHEN THESE INDIVIDUALS IN WALES
EXTRACTED, THEY COLLECTED A LOT OF SCALES
FROM THESE
BUDS, AND EXTRACTED THEM, THEY FOUND A COMPOUND
WHICH
WHEN APPLIED BACK TO THE PLANT COULD KEEP
IT DORMANT.
AND THEY CALLED THIS COMPOUND DORMIN BECAUSE
IT KEPT
OR MAINTAINED DORMANCY.
NOW WHILE THEY WERE CARRYING
OUT THIS WORK IN WALES, FARMERS IN DAVIS FOR
THE
CENTRAL VALLEY OF CALIFORNIA BECAME INCREASINGLY
CONCERNED BECAUSE OF THE PHENOMENON THAT
WAS
ASSOCIATED WITH THE INCREASE PLANTING OF COTTON.
WHAT
FARMERS FOUND WAS THAT IN JUNE OF EVERY YEAR
THE
COTTON BOWLS, THAT IS, THE THINGS WHICH KEPT
ALL THE
COTTON HAIRS TOGETHER INSIDE. COTTON BOWLS
WOULD FALL
OFF OF THE PLANT. THEY WOULD LOSE 10 TO 30
PERCENT OF
THESE COTTON BOWLS IN JUNE. SO CALLED JUNE
DROP. AND
THEY WERE CONCERNED OBVIOUSLY BECAUSE IT DECREASED
THE
AMOUNT OF COTTON, WHICH THEY HARVESTED AND
THEREFORE,
DECREASED HOW MUCH MONEY THEY GOT. AND SO,
THEY
BROUGHT THIS PROBLEM TO PEOPLE AT DAVIS, U
C DAVIS,
AND THEY ASKED THEM, COULD THEY HELP TO DETERMINE
WHAT
IT WAS THAT WAS CAUSING THESE COTTON BOWLS
TO DROP TO
THE GROUND, THIS SO CALLED JUNE DROP. AND
THE PEOPLE
AT DAVIS DISCOVERED THAT PRIOR, JUST PRIOR
TO THE
FALLING OF THE COTTON FROM THE PLANTS, THAT
A COMPOUND
WAS INCREASING IN THE PLANT AND THAT THIS
COMPOUND
WHEN APPLIED BACK TO THE PLANT AFTER IT WAS
EXTRACTED
COULD SURE ENOUGH CAUSE THESE COTTON BOWLS
TO FALL
OFF. AND BECAUSE THESE FALLING OFF IS THE
SAME AS
ABSCISING, THIS COMPOUND WHICH THEY ISOLATED
IT AND
IDENTIFIED WAS KNOWN AS ABSCISING. THIS COMPOUND
WHICH THEY ISOLATED AND IDENTIFIED WAS KNOWN
AS
ABSCISIC ACID. THIS COMPOUND WHICH CAUSED
THE COTTON
BOWLS TO FALL OFF. AND WE NOW KNOW THAT ABSCISIC
ACID
AND DORMIN ARE THE SAME COMPOUND. THEY ARE
COMPOUNDS
WHICH IN THIS CASE CAUSE THE COTTON'S TO ABSCISE
AND
IN THE CASE OF THE DORMANT TO MAINTAIN DORMANCY.
ABSCISIC ACID IS A 5TH GROWTH REGULATOR. AND
PROBABLY
IF WE HAD TO SUMMARIZE WHERE IT WORKS MOST
OR WHAT ITS
EFFECTS ARE, WE COULD SAY THAT ABSCISIC ACID,
WHICH I
WILL ABBREVIATE AS ABA ABSCISIC ACID, IS A
GROWTH
REGULATOR INVOLVED WITH RESPONSES TO PLANTS
TO STRESS.
AND LET ME GIVE YOU SOME EXAMPLES NOW OF THE
RESPONSES
OF PLANTS TO STRESS. LET'S LOOK AT A PLANT
WHICH IS
GROWING IN SOIL IN WHICH THE WATER IS GRADUALLY
BEING
DEPLETED FROM THE SOIL. SO HERE WE HAVE
A PLANT WHICH
IS GROWING IN SOIL AND WE NOW HAVE, FIRST
OF ALL, THE
DEPLETION OF WATER. DEPLETION OF WATER IN
THE SOIL.
NOW, IN THIS PARTICULAR SITUATION WE KNOW
THAT WATER
IS GOING LIKE THIS, AND WE WILL TALK ABOUT
THIS MORE,
AND IS EXITING THE PLANT THROUGH THE LEAVES,
THROUGH
THE STOMATA.
WATER LEAVES. NOW, IF THE PLANT DID NOT
HAVE ANY WAY OF CONTROLLING WATER THAT IT
WAS LOSING,
BECAUSE IT IS NOT BEING ABLE TO REPLACE IT
FROM THE
SOIL, THAT PLANT WOULD DRY, WOULD DRY OUT.
SO, WHEN
THERE IS A DEPLETION OF WATER IN THE SOIL,
THIS IS
SENSED BY THE ROOTS, WHICH MAKE ABA. MAKE
ABA.
THIS ABA MOVES TO THIS STOMATA AND CAUSES
THEM TO
CLOSE.
AND THEREBY, PREVENT THE PLANT FROM DRYING
OUT. THERE ARE A LOT OF MUTANT PLANTS AND
ONE OF THE
MUTANT PLANTS IS CALLED DROOPY. IN DROOPY,
THIS PLANT
CANNOT MAKE ABA. CAN'T MAKE ABA. SO IF YOU
PUT A
PLANT LIKE THAT IN SOIL WHICH IS DEPLETED
IN ITS
WATER, DROOPY CAN'T SEND A SIGNAL TO THE
STOMATA.
CAN'T TELL THEM TO CLOSE BECAUSE IT DOESN'T
HAVE THAT
SIGNAL TO MAKE. AND THOSE PLANTS THEN LOOK
WILTED.
HOWEVER, IF YOU TAKE DROOPY AND YOU SPRAY
IT
WITH ABA YOU CAN GET THAT PLANT THEN TO ILLUSTRATE
OR
TO SHOW A NORMAL RESPONSE TO THE ENVIRONMENT.
ANOTHER
WAY IN WHICH ABA SEEMS TO BE INVOLVED IN STRESS
IS IN
PLANTS THAT ARE GROWING IN SOILS THAT ARE
VERY SALTY.
IN CALIFORNIA, AND IN MANY PORTIONS OF THE
WORLD A
LARGE AMOUNT OF AGRICULTURAL LAND IS BEING
LOST TO THE
FACT THAT SALT WATER IS COMING IN OR SALTS
ARE
ACCUMULATING IN THE SOILS AND THIS IS PREVENTING
THE
PLANTS TO GROW. WE ARE LOSING A LARGE AMOUNT
OF
AGRICULTURAL LAND THAT WAY. ABA IN PLANTS
THAT ARE
EXPOSED TO THE SALTY ENVIRONMENT, ABA SEEMS
TO
TRIGGER, SO IN A SALTY ENVIRONMENT
TRIGGERS THE
PRODUCTION OF PROTEINS
ALLOWING PLANTS TO RESIST THIS
ENVIRONMENT OR AT LEAST TO TOLERATE IT. PERHAPS
THE
MOST INTERESTING ASPECT OF THE ABA THAT
I FIND MOST
INTERESTING HAS TO DO WITH SEED GERMINATION.
MOST OF
YOU KNOW THAT THE SEED IS FORMED AT THE END
OF THE
GROWING SEASON AND THEN USUALLY THE CLIMATE
CHANGES
SOMEHOW. IF YOU COME FROM THE EAST, THE CLIMATE
GETS
REALLY COLD. HERE IT GETS COLD BUT NOT AS
COLD AS THE
EAST. AND SO, WE VIEW THE SEED AS A WAY OF
ALLOWING
THE PLANT TO PASS THROUGH THIS BAD PERIOD
OF TIME WHEN
GROWTH WOULD NOT NORMALLY OCCUR. THE PLANT
REMAINS
DORMANT. BUT THERE HAS TO BE SOME WAY FOR
THAT SEED
TO KNOW THAT THE COLD PERIOD HAS NOW GONE
PAST AND
THAT THE CLIMATE OUTSIDE CAN ALLOW THE SEED
TO
GERMINATE AND TO GROW. AND THIS IS WHERE ABA
HAS
A VERY STRONG EFFECT. WHAT WE FIND IS THAT
IN SEED
COATS FOLLOWING ABA AND OTHER RELATED COMPOUNDS
ARE AT
HIGH LEVELS.
HIGH LEVELS. AND THIS INHIBITS
GERMINATION. AND WHAT HAPPENS, APPARENTLY,
IS THAT
COLD OR PERIODS OF COLD YIELD A BREAKDOWN
IN ABA. AND
AFTER A PLANT HAS HAD A LONG ENOUGH PERIOD
OF COLD
THE ABA LEVELS AND THE OTHER INHIBITOR LEVELS
HAVE
DROPPED TO SUCH A CONCENTRATION THAT GERMINATION
CAN
NOW GO ON. SOME OF US HERE IN CALIFORNIA RECEIVE
SEEDS WHICH NORMALLY WOULD GROW IN A COLD
CLIMATE AND
WE ARE TOLD THAT IF WE WANT TO GET THOSE SEEDS
TO
GERMINATE WE HAVE TO ALSO GIVE THEM ALONG
PERIOD OF
COLD. WE ARE TOLD TO PUT THEM IN A REFRIGERATOR
OR
FREEZER. THIS PROCESS OF COLD TREATMENT IS
CALLED
STRATEGY STRATIFICATION AND BASICALLY, YOU
ARE DOING
THE SAME THING THAT THE COLD NORMALLY WOULD
DO BY
KEEPING YOUR SEEDS IN THE REFRIGERATOR YOU
ARE CAUSING
THESE INHIBITORY COMPOUNDS INCLUDING ABA TO
GRADUALLY
BE REDUCED. I WANT TO MENTION TO YOU THAT
THIS SAME
KIND OF SYSTEM OPERATES IN PLANTS WHICH GROW
IN
ENVIRONMENTS THAT ARE NOT NECESSARILY COLD.
LIKE FOR
EXAMPLE, THE DESERT. IN THE DESERT THE BIG
ISSUE OF
A SEED GETTING STARTED IS HAVING ENOUGH WATER.
HOW IS
A SEED GOING TO KNOW THAT THERE IS ENOUGH
RAIN TO
ALLOW IT TO ESTABLISH ITS ROOT SYSTEM? IN
THIS
PARTICULAR SITUATION WHAT HAPPENS IS THAT,
HERE IS THE
SEED AND THE SEED COAT, THE INHIBITOR IS IN
THE
COAT, INHIBITOR IS IN THE COAT, AND THEN WHAT
HAPPENS
IS THAT IF THE RAIN IS A SIGNIFICANT ENOUGH
RAIN TO
ALLOW THE SEED TO ESTABLISH ITSELF, IT IS
ALSO
A SIGNIFICANT AMOUNT OF RAIN TO HAVE WASHED
OUT THE
INHIBITOR. SO, IF WE CAN WASH OUT THE INHIBITOR,
THAT
IS TELLING THE SEED THERE IS ENOUGH WATER
TO
GERMINATE, ENOUGH WATER TO ESTABLISH YOURSELF.
NOW,
THERE ARE WAYS OF TRICKING THE SYSTEM IN THE
DESERT
AND THIS SOMETIMES HAPPENS. IF YOU HAVE A
LOT OF
SHORT RAINS, TINY RAINS, AND EACH ONE OF THEM
WASHES
OUT A BIT OF THE INHIBITOR BUT NOT ALL OF
IT,
EVENTUALLY YOU WILL HAVE WASHED OUT MOST OR
A LARGE
AMOUNT OF THE INHIBITOR AND THE SEED THINKS
THAT IT IS
TIME TO GERMINATE. AND UNDER THOSE CIRCUMSTANCES
THE
SEEDLING WOULD DIE BECAUSE THERE IS INADEQUATE
WATER
FOR IT TO ESTABLISH ITSELF. BUT IN GENERAL,
THIS
SYSTEM WORKS WELL IN TELLING THE SEED TO GERMINATE
WHEN THERE IS AN ADEQUATE AMOUNT OF WATER.
FINALLY, I
WANT TO MENTION ONE OTHER ASPECT OF SEED GERMINATION
CONTROLLED BY ABA AND OTHER INHIBITORS. SOME
OF YOU
MAY HAVE PURCHASED CORN BEFORE IN THE STORE
AND AFTER
YOU OPEN THE HUSK UP AND YOU FIND THE EAR,
WHEN YOU
LOOK INSIDE ON THE COB YOU WOULD SEE SOMETIMES
THERE
IS SEEDS THAT ARE ACTUALLY GERMINATING. THEY
ARE
REALLY FRUITS IN WHICH THE SEEDS GERMINATE
DIRECTLY ON
THE COB OR THE EAR. IN THESE PARTICULAR PLANTS
FOR
WHATEVER REASON, THEY HAVE ESCAPED DORMANCY
ON
INHIBITION TO GERMINATION BY ABA OR OTHER
GROWTH
REGULATORS AND WE CALL THIS PRECOCIOUS GERMINATION
VIVIPARY. WE CALL THIS PRECOCIOUS
GERMINATION VIVIPARY. IT IS A FAIRLY COMMON
CURRENCY
ON MANY PLANTS AND IT USUALLY, IF YOU SEE
IT, IS
A CONSEQUENCE OF HAVING HAD A DAMAGE SOMEHOW
TO THE
INHIBITION SYSTEM FOR GERMINATION. LET ME
SHOW YOU
SOME PICTURES NOW. THE FIRST ONE IS GOING
TO JUST
REMIND YOU OF THE COTTON BOWL AND THESE WERE
THE
THINGS THAT FELL OFF IN JUNE THAT THE FARMER'S
THEN
BROUGHT TO THE PEOPLE AT DAVIS TO ALLOW THEM
TO TRY
AND FIGURE OUT WHAT WAS GOING ON. HERE ARE
THE
DORMANT BUDS. THESE ARE WHERE THE DORMIN WAS
EXTRACTED FROM. THESE PARTICULAR BUDS SCALES
FROM THE
OUTSIDE. AND AGAIN DORMIN AND ABA TURN OUT
TO BE THE
SAME. HERE IS A SEEDLING GERMINATING. PRESUMABLY
THE
SEED COAT WOULD HAVE IN IT INHIBITORS WHICH
HAVE TO BE
REDUCED BY COLD AND THAT REDUCTION IN THE
INHIBITOR
LEVEL TELLS THE SEED THAT IT IS TIME TO GERMINATE.
HERE IS VIVIPARY. FOR THOSE OF YOU WHO HAVE
EVER BEEN
TO A MANGROVE SWAMP AND LOOKED AT SOME OF
THE
MANGROVES, THESE THINGS HANGING FROM THE MANGROVES,
I
WILL SHOW YOU A PICTURE OF THIS NOW, THIS
IS THE FRUIT
OF THE MANGROVE OVER HERE. HERE ARE THE
FLOWERS AND
AS THE FRUIT, AFTER POLLINATION, WHILE IT
IS STILL
ATTACHED TO THE TREE THE SEEDLING GERMINATES.
THERE
IS NO PERIOD OF DORMANCY AND THIS IS KNOWN
AS VIVIPARY. OKAY. I WILL SEE YOU GUYS ALL
ON
MONDAY. HAVE A NICE WEEKEND.