RICHARD GARRIOTT: I'm
Richard Garriott.
I'm probably best known
for my work in the
computer game field.
If you go back to the
beginnings, the roots, high
school in the 1970s, which was
right about the same time as
personal computers came into
existence, I was inspired by
the books like The Lord of the
Rings and games like Dungeons
and Dragons to take this new
item, this personal computer,
and started creating fantasy
role playing computer games.
My first character that I began
to play in role playing
games was known as British
because I happened to be born
in Cambridge, England, and some
of my first friends, who
I was playing with, thought for
some reason that I had a
British accent, which
I never did.
I grew up in Houston, so I've
never had a British accent.
It was the owner of a computer
store that saw this game that
I was working on in the
evenings, and said, you know,
Richard, that game is really
much better than the few games
that existed in the day, you
know, here on the store wall.
Why don't we sell it?
And so I went out and spent
what I thought was a huge
amount of money, $200 on ziplock
bags and Xerox cover
sheets, and began to sell
them on the peg board.
One of those found its way
to California, and I was
contacted by one of the first
national distributors.
They distributed about
30,000 copies.
My royalties were $5 a unit.
If you do that math, that's
about $150,000 for a high
school senior.
And they were the ones
who looked at it.
They said, well, you know,
Richard Garriott's a fine
name, it's your name.
But Lord British is much
more memorable.
Why don't we just drop Richard
Garriott, and we'll leave Lord
British on as the author?
I've been Lord British for more
than half my life now, so
I actually feel strangely
comfortable adopting the
persona of Lord British in the
real world, as much as in the
virtual world.
My first published game was
called Akalabeth, which was
really the prequel, effectively,
to the series
that I wrote for 25 years
or more called Ultima.
And published the first Ultima
in about 1981, and in total,
produced nine of the solo
player Ultimas,
plus a few spin offs.
I also produced Ultima Online,
the first of what is now
called a massively multiplayer
online game.
Instead of playing by yourself
on a computer, which is
traditionally the way most
computer games are played, in
this case your computer is
really just a terminal, a
graphics terminal connected
through the internet to a big
central server where everyone
in the world who is playing
the game can see each other,
can play together, either
cooperatively or against each
other, in the same gigantic
virtual world.
So Tabula Rasa is the first
non-Ultima game
I've done in decades.
Instead of fighting medieval
monsters, players use
wormholes to travel through a
variety of planets in space
and fight against the evil alien
hoard that has invaded
the Earth and wiped
out our homeland.
As part of the, what I call
promotional event for the
launch of Tabula Rasa, we tried
to create what you might
call a reality bridge, and try
to prove the truth of some of
what you might call the magical,
or superpower aspects
of Tabula Rasa.
So I hired a whole slew of
magicians who could come in
and do things like spoon
bending, or other kind of--
had mental powers to
physically affect,
telekinetically, the world in
which we lived, to showcase
how here in Austin, here at
my home we actually were
discovering and uncovering
some of these powers that
ultimately would be similar to
what showed up in the game.
We then bussed everybody over
to the property where I'm
building my new home where,
as we were digging the
foundations of the new
home, some of these
artifacts were uncovered.
And then we set up a
big event there.
We had a huge pyrotechnics show
that included not only
lights and sound but also
explosions and gunfire.
But my brother happens to be
a helicopter pilot, so we
actually had him come in and
swoop in with helicopters with
lights and had police cars and
the whole Men in Black kind of
confrontation between the aliens
and the human defenses.
So I'm a big believer in the
quote that I believe Arthur C.
Clarke coined, that any
technology, sufficiently
advanced, is indistinguishable
from magic.
And as you may know, right
beside us, actually, is one of
these devices.
So this is a very
special material
known as ferrous fluid.
And it basically is oil
impregnated with iron filings,
or rust, really.
Iron oxide.
So it's not sharp in a sense of
you can't injure yourself
on it, but it is sharp in the
sense of it is you're coming
up to a perfect point.
In this table, I've built a
collection of electromagnets,
that if you power on these
electromagnets, will create
magnetic fields that will come
up through this oil.
And then this ferrous fluid will
try to form along those
magnetic field lines and create
three-dimensional
shapes rising up out
of a liquid.
I enjoy, you know, exploring the
real world just as much as
I enjoy exploring the
virtual world.
And creatively, I enjoy creating
virtual worlds just
as much as I enjoy creating
physical, practical things,
like unusual homes or other big,
interactive themed events
that are physical.
Virtual exploration is really
only one piece of the puzzle
of the richness of the
tapestry of life.
And so I think it will remain a
very popular portion, but I
don't think there's any chance,
really, of people
tuning out of the real world
and locking in permanently
into their virtual existence.
Welcome to my home.
I actually call this Britannia
Manor, and right as you come
into the interior of my house,
you'll begin to see there's
already some unusual features.
Swords and crossbows here.
We then built this steel
structure, upon which is
mounted the telescope that's
in my observatory.
This is actually the highest
point in the
entire city of Austin.
I actually got a topographical
map out, and that's how I
selected this property.
That's how I selected this
property, was actually to
identify the best place to put a
telescope to get a nice, 360
degree view of the horizon,
which we get up here in the
observatory dome.
The homes I build are very much
manifestations of the
same creative drive that you see
that goes into the games
and other events
that I produce.
They function as a normal house,
but they're also big,
what you might call personal
playscapes.
So they're filled with secret
passageways throughout, and an
observatory, and dungeons,
indoor, outdoor pools, and
artificial rain.
And then of course all my
collections of collections.
It's a habit I picked up my
mother, actually, I think, is
to be this level of pack
rat, you might say.
This is my home office, where
I keep a lot of my recent
artifacts from my space trip,
including, these are some of
the items I took with me
to space and back.
So now we'll go down to what I
happen to call the medieval
portion of the house.
And I've got some nice astronomy
prints, and you'll
also begin to see some of
the more unusual bits
of art in the house.
These are actually preserved
octopus tentacles that are
here in these containers.
And then in here, in the upper
floor of what you might call
the study, a collection from
my childhood, so to speak.
I'm obviously a big fan of
The Lord of the Rings.
I've got not only first
editions but--
those are first editions--
these are pre-first-editions.
Pre-publication editions.
Proof copies.
So here on the upper floor of
the study, one of the common
questions is, how do
we get downstairs?
Because of course, there is no
obvious route between the two.
There's no staircases
or doorways.
And the solution to that
involves this surface.
And in this surface, I've
inserted 18 magnetic sensors.
In fact, there's a drop panel
on this side with nine, and
there's actually nine
more that I don't
generally use on this side.
And in this kind of eyeballs and
teeth thing that my mother
made for me, I've inserted
magnets up inside of it.
And so now if you move this
device in the right pattern
over those magnetic sensors,
that little click has
unlatched a magnetic latch that
lets us into this secret
passageway.
We can go down this spiral
staircase here to the lower
floor of the study
to the dungeon.
And the dungeon, of course, is
the room full of dead things.
Some recently, some long
dead, as well as a
few pieces of art.
This is a velociraptor skeleton
that's actually a cast.
And this is also
a piece of art.
But most of the other things in
here are real, including my
dead friend that I call Pedro.
This is the skull of an
African elephant.
Across here on the side of the
room, these are authentic
South American shrunken heads.
I have a number of vampire
hunting kits.
Everything from, like, a human
fetus that I have here in this
jar to a human heart.
These are Borneo headhunter
human trophy skulls and the
skills of everything from
African lions and prehistoric
cave bears, creatures
and critters
from around the globe.
In the living room, of course,
we have the normal things--
couches, chairs, stereos
and TVs--
but we also have something
unusual in my house, which, of
course, is the continuation of
the secret passageway network.
And so if I reach in this drawer
and reach up into the
ceiling, I'm actually pulling
a little latch.
And then if you come over here,
and you look at this
innocent looking mirror,
this is really a
secret passageway entrance.
This is actually one of two
Sputniks that I own.
So this is the first
one that I own.
And the other one's up in the
automaton room that I'll take
you to momentarily.
I'm sure that this is the
largest collection of
contemporary automatons.
But physically assembled to
create something really
masterful, artistically.
And so I find these to be a
good, what I call, physical
analogy to what we do.
Naturalist catching butterflies,
with an alien
catching him.
This one actually requires
looking in this little hole.
So this one is the American
execution.
We electrocute our victims.
And so here is this guy
being prepared for
the electric chair.
The doctors are checking
him out.
They're checking the voltages
of the machine.
They lower it down, the
thing on his head.
Turning, glowing red while
he's being electrocuted.
And he's killed.
He's playing music only the dead
can hear, so that's why
you can't hear it.
And even outside, there's fun
things, like I've got a pond
with a bridge and little cabanas
and things out on it.
I've got a three-horse carousel
that operates out in
the front yard.
Literally, throughout my entire
professional career,
I've been investing in the
privatization of space,
helping to unlock the gates
of private space travel.
I fancy myself a gentleman
explorer, you might say.
On October 12, I
launched to the
International Space Station.
And I went there on board a
Russian Soyuz rocket, actually
called a Soyuz TMA 13.
You know, that's a pretty
spectacular
day, you might say.
I'd already spent about nine
months in Russia, training.
In the long-term future of the
Earth, there's no question
that something apocalyptic
will occur.
We someday will probably be
struck by an asteroid that
will destroy most of life on
the Earth, it's only a
question of when.
We may unleash nuclear
holocaust.
Maybe.
That seems unlikely today, but
we've been through cycles
where it seems more likely,
so it might happen again.
You know, biological problems
that are pandemics that could
come up, I think are also
a practical risk.
And so if you add all that up,
one of the best ways for
humanity to ensure that we
survive into the future is to
make sure we have isolated
settlements around the
universe, in which case an
apocalypse on one won't wipe
out the whole species.
I very much agree with that,
that that's one very
compelling reason that humanity
really does need to
spread beyond the surface
of the Earth.
The only debate in my mind is
how urgently should you feel
that that's necessary.
And I personally believe there's
no time like the
present, so let's get to work.
Walking up to a fully fueled
rocket, which has kerosene and
liquid oxygen, so it's frozen
to well below freezing.
So the whole vehicle is covered
with frost, and any
air coming near it is turning
into fog, and streaming down
the sides of this rocket.
You know, you squeeze yourself
in, and on a Soyuz, you
literally squeeze yourself in
through the hatches and get
down into your seat.
And one of my jobs is to push
the button that starts up the
operation of the vehicle.
Then when the countdown reaches
zero, the thing lights
up, and it's funny--
it's a relatively gentle
ride into space.
The g-forces start very
minimal but slowly and
steadily increase to about
4 and 1/2 g's.
And after about eight minutes at
4 and 1/2 g's, the engines
cut off, and you're in space.
Before I flew--
you know, you always hear about
things that people have
said, like once you go to space
and you see the Earth
from such a distance, and you
see the world without the
boundaries between countries
and things, how it changes
your perception of life and
humanity's place on Earth.
It's pretty amazing to look out
at the edge of the Earth
and see the thin veil of the
atmosphere clinging to the
very round Earth you
can see from space.
And so you feel, still, very
intimate with the surface of
the Earth in ways that
I found unexpected.
The next thing you begin to
notice is how every fertile
place on the Earth that you
travel over is now fully
occupied by people.
There is no place that you
might describe as easy to
occupy that isn't already
occupied.
While there was no one moment
where I'd say a-ha, I've had
an epiphany, I now have a
changed perception of humanity
and Earth, it really
is something that
builds on you over time.
It really is truly there.
So upon my return, I can
definitely now reflect on it
and say that absolutely, I
believe that my perception of
what I call the fragility of
the Earth and the human
footprint on the Earth is
absolutely changed.
My father is an astronaut, so I
grew up in a household where
space felt very normal.
And in fact, not only was my
father an astronaut, but my
right-hand next door neighbor
was a guy named Joe Engle,
another astronaut.
My left-hand next door neighbor
was Hoot Gibson,
another astronaut.
Everyone in my neighborhood was
involved in some way in
putting people into space.
And so I kind of grew
up believing
everybody would go to space.
And when I was a young teenager,
I was actually at
NASA one time, and one of the
NASA flight physicians was
giving me an eye test.
And my eyesight was fairly
poor when I was young.
And they said, oh, you know, I'm
so sorry, Richard, but you
know, your poor eyesight's gonna
prevent you from ever
being selected as a
NASA astronaut.
And for me, that was like being
told, hey, by the way,
you are no longer eligible for
the club that everyone you
know is a member of.
Prior to that moment, I don't
think I was particularly
devoted to getting my way
into space until I was
told, you can't go.
I spent two days living onboard
the Soyuz while we
were catching up to and
matching orbits to
dock with the ISS.
I then spent 10 days onboard
the space station, doing a
wide variety of experiments.
Uh, yeah, I would definitely say
that this has met and, in
many ways, exceeded
my expectations.
There's no question that I've
already begun to think about
the next trip up.
MALE SPEAKER: How have your
found your zero-g
artwork to be going?
RICHARD GARRIOTT: Well, I did
create the zero-g artwork.
I came up with a glove box in
which I could release my paint
without risking painting the
walls of the station, and
created some art that I'll be
bringing back, so you can
judge for yourself.
With this trip, I was trying
to study and analyze how
private citizens might be able
to contribute to the success
here in space.
And I'll have a lot more
thoughts for that
when I come back down.
Thanks.
Station this is KSC PAO.
That's the final question
here from Florida.
We're now going to toss you
briefly back to Houston.