bodyguards.
It was like, next elevator.
It's like, what the fuck?
Is it direct-to-video,
motherfucker?
I can't take the same
elevator as this
jowly fucking hairball?
What the fuck?
Yeah, but I've talked a lot of
shit about Steven Seagal
lately, so if you see
him tonight, that's
what those are for.
He's got a reach.
HELEN CHO: Next elevator.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: Get
under his reach.
Get under his reach.
DIANE SCHUTZ: --On the street.
Just on the street.
HELEN CHO: Next elevator,
motherfucker.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: My name's
Anthony Bourdain, and I work
with Zero Point Zero Production
making a television
show called No Reservations.
I travel around the world eating
and drinking and making
self-indulgent television.
We have a core road crew.
Diane Schutz, segment
producer.
Helen Cho, the director
of social media.
Zach Zamboni is a
cinematographer and a shooter--
camera person.
Then, of course, Tom Vitale,
my go-to producer.
Basically, these are my partners
in telling stories
all over the world.
These are the people who
I spend most of my
waking hours with.
They're my closest associates
and friends.
I have something to present
to you tonight.
HELEN CHO: Oh, no.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN:
This is for you.
You might need this later.
HELEN CHO: Oh, I will.
That's sick.
DIANE SCHUTZ: That's
pretty awesome.
ZACH ZAMBONI: Let's go eat.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: I had
no life outside of
the restaurant business.
I was at work all day, and at
night, I would go out with
other chefs and talk
about business.
So the transition to television,
in that regard,
isn't that much of a leap.
What do I do?
I work all day.
I'm friends with the
people I work with.
And when we're not working, when
the cameras are off, we
continue to eat and drink
and talk about work.
So--
there it is.
ZACH ZAMBONI: We're going
to Salumeria Rosi.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: Every once in
a while, like special treat
at the Bourdain household, I'll
run over there and buy a
big pile of meat.
We're going to see the wizard.
The wonderful wizard of meat.
Thank you for hosting us.
ZACH ZAMBONI: Hey, Cesare.
CESARE CASELLA: Hey,
how are you?
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: Cesare's
an old friend.
He's made a bunch of
shows with us.
Cesare, like a lot of the chefs
I've come to know and
who I've come to be close
friends with--
as is so often the case in my
fucked-up, dysfunctional, but
wonderful life--
we started out as TV friends
and became real friends.
SERVER: Are you--
you order, or--
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: I think what
we'd like is a selection of
cured meat.
CESARE CASELLA: OK.
ZACH ZAMBONI: A little
bit of cheese.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: Just split.
CESARE CASELLA: Fantastic.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: Beautiful.
Good cured meat is something
that's always good.
It won't be too punishing
early on.
We're going for the
long haul, here.
Experience has taught me that it
would have been a bad idea
to start off with a pasta
tasting earlier in the meal,
followed by meat
and more drink.
I couldn't do that
to my friends.
ZACH ZAMBONI: Whoa!
DIANE SCHUTZ: OK, that's
tweetworthy.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN:
Look at that.
It's a low-impact place to grab
really good food, and one
of those places that I think,
just by existing, are
good for the world.
I mean, he makes and sells
products there that other
people either don't
do, wouldn't do,
or can't do as well.
And I think it's just a person
and a place that I feel really
connected to.
It's a happy day for me when
I can go there [INAUDIBLE].
Delicious.
HELEN CHO: Amazing.
CESARE CASELLA: So this is
the fagioli [INAUDIBLE].
DIANE SCHUTZ: Nice.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN:
I love that man.
See, this is something that's
just irresistible to me.
I'm happy now.
This is exactly how
I like to eat.
Part of the process of making
the show is tweeting about it
and engaging the fans.
We're all serial tweeters.
It's at the pathetic point.
We are some sad motherfuckers
here.
Look at us.
ZACH ZAMBONI: Like a
bunch of tweens.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: Right.
So, the question I had in my
mind tonight was, if any of
you got like some big hunk of
sauce or mashed bean hanging
off your cheek, would
I tell you?
HELEN CHO: Yeah, would you?
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: You know,
revenge for season 2.
There was one episode where I
had a nostril hair like this
long hanging out--
a crusty one.
DIANE SCHUTZ: Oh, you
mean New Zealand?
ZACH ZAMBONI: That
was Uzbekistan.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: Excellent.
I mean, everybody on TV has to
live with the likelihood that
if they hit their head, shit
their pants, get arrested--
that they will themselves
end up on camera.
But for a sustained night
out with a camera
relentlessly on them--
were they uncomfortable?
Who cares.
I wallowed in their
discomfort.
ZACH ZAMBONI: We usually drink
when we shoot, so feel free.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: Everybody we
got with is like, such an old
whore, productionwise.
CAMERAMAN: Zach, you can't be
shooting this show, either.
ZACH ZAMBONI: OK, here.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: Zach's
thinking about the lighting.
Diane's bussing the table.
And I'm thinking, well,
did you pay?
Because there is really now
lower person in this world
than somebody who ends
up stiffing waiters.
There is a 10th circle of
hell just for them.
So that guy's paying?
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: OK, good.
Tack on--
DIANE SCHUTZ: Thank you.
SERVER: You're very welcome.
Have fun tonight.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN:
Did he tip well?
ZACH ZAMBONI: 30%.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: 30%.
OK.
Damn.
HELEN CHO: Damn.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: We don't
tip that well.
Let's pretend you were producing
this segment.
How would we deal with
this transition here?
Did you risk [INAUDIBLE]?
Did you say, ask them where
we're going now?
HELEN CHO: Damn, he's onto us.
DIANE SCHUTZ: Shit.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: Apparently
we'll be moving on to The
Distinguished Wakamba Lounge.
Do you like a little
Latin flavor?
Do you like 8th Avenue
in the '30s?
DIANE SCHUTZ: That's my
[INTERPOSING VOICES].
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: I've never
puked in front of
witnesses in my life.
DIANE SCHUTZ: Ever?
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: And I'm
not going to start now.
DIANE SCHUTZ: Really?
Ever?
Come on.
HELEN CHO: Tonight is
the night, Tony.
Tonight is the night.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: When I was a
junkie, I would throw up in
the great outdoors.
But outside of the heroin
experience, no.
I still remember the girl who
threw up next to me in second
grade, so that was an important
experience.
Terry Jones--
lifted up her desk and blew
chunks into her desk.
OK?
And that made a big
impression on me.
And I was like, that's
not going to be me.
So I'm pretty good at holding
onto my shit.
Thank you.
I know a bar with a pool.
It's right behind the bar,
the swimming pool is.
Last time I was there, I
got fucking buck naked.
That was quite some
time ago, but--
yeah.
Pre-fatherhood.
I'm a distinguished
motherfucker now.
ZACH ZAMBONI: Yeah, it's true.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: Hence The
Distinguished Wakamba Lounge.
ZACH ZAMBONI: Yes.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: We're all
thinking the same thing when
we go into a restaurant
or a bar.
First thing we're thinking
is music.
You can't afford that music.
ZACH ZAMBONI: Uh-oh.
Unplug the jukebox.
DIANE SCHUTZ: Stop producing
the show.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: The
Distinguished Wakamba Lounge--
one of the last dive
bars of its kind.
There are plenty of Irish dive
bars around, but this is
really something unique
to Manhattan.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: Presidente?
Definitely you want to be
drinking the Presidente--
good stuff there.
They keep it properly cold,
as any proud Dominican
[INAUDIBLE] should be.
All right, so who's
been here before?
ZACH ZAMBONI: No one?
DIANE SCHUTZ: No, never.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: Why?
It's enchanting?
ZACH ZAMBONI: How come
we haven't shot here?
HELEN CHO: No, we were going
to shoot for the holiday.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: This one's
my special place.
ZACH ZAMBONI: Aw, you didn't
want to fuck it up.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: The Wakamba
Lounge has remained unchanged,
unapologetically and
unironically.
That's important.
There's nothing hipster about
the Wakamba Lounge.
It is what it is.
Anyone who's just compelled to
go there after having seen
this-- please don't
fuck it up.
So what are we drinking
shots of?
Because we're drinking
shots of something.
Definitely not tequila.
HELEN CHO: No, let's
do whiskey.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: Whiskey.
I think Jameson.
HELEN CHO: Jame-o?
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: A good
Catholic whiskey.
HELEN CHO: Let's just
drink Jame-o.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: Jame-o.
DIANE SCHUTZ: You sound
so Williamsburg.
HELEN CHO: What?
I am not from Williamsburg,
Diane.
DIANE SCHUTZ: I'm just
saying it sounded--
HELEN CHO: I'm from Brooklyn.
Oh, sorry.
ZACH ZAMBONI: Come
here, buddy.
Come on, pal.
Yeah.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: In order to
be on this show, if you want
the shot, you take the shot.
ZACH ZAMBONI: Yeah.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: That's
the way it works.
Yeah, there's no getting in and
out of there without doing
a few shots.
I just love that place.
It's politically incorrect.
So, Helen.
I pledge to you now.
HELEN CHO: And this
is not drunk talk.
This is real talk.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: I will sing
Mark Lanegan's "Wedding Dress"
at your wedding.
HELEN CHO: You fucking
pinky-swear me, dude!
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: Nice
Korean boy, though.
HELEN CHO: He has
to be Korean?
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: I've been
talking to your mom, yo.
HELEN CHO: And a Christian--
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: Mazel tov.
HELEN CHO: Mazel tov.
DIANE SCHUTZ: Mazel tov!
HELEN CHO: Oh my God.
I'm going to get
so fired, man.
What do you think
of [INAUDIBLE]?
ANTHONY BOURDAIN:
What the fuck?
I entrusted you with
this terrible--
HELEN CHO: I won't care.
I'll put it away.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: --Power.
You keep it in the
fucking silo.
Get in there, yo.
Jesus.
I mean, late night, you want
to keep it simple.
You're going to be beyond your
powers to evaluate a fine
dining experience.
Your ability to be a good
customer is certainly
diminishing.
Some of us get a little
rowdy late at night.
So I figured it would
be a good idea to
keep it close to home.
So that means my old base of
operations, Les Halles, where
it all started for me.
We'll be having a classic
French meal.
HELEN CHO: What are
you making for us?
ANTHONY BOURDAIN:
It's a surprise.
HELEN CHO: It's a surprise?
ZACH ZAMBONI: Let me guess--
does it involve beef?
Beef surprise.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: No, no.
HELEN CHO: That sounds boring.
What kind of surprise?
ANTHONY BOURDAIN:
It's a vegetable
medley of locally sourced--
HELEN CHO: Vegetables?
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: Artisanally
produced--
HELEN CHO: Vegetable,
fuck that, man!
You going to break my heart?
ZACH ZAMBONI: Anthony.
HELEN CHO: You going
to make us tofu?
ZACH ZAMBONI: People
will see this.
HELEN CHO: Anthony, right.
Because we always call
him Anthony.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: It's
a whole new me.
HELEN CHO: Um, hello,
Mr. Anthony.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: He's back, and
this time, it's for real.
RESTAURANT PATRON
1: Oh my god!
Oh my god!
RESTAURANT PATRON 2: We're
huge fans of your show.
That's why we came here.
RESTAURANT PATRON 3:
You're the best.
I love you.
RESTAURANT PATRON
4: Can we take a
picture with you, please?
RESTAURANT PATRON
5: Hey, man--
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: I've
got to go to work!
RESTAURANT PATRON 5: But I got
engaged to my first wife here,
in this restaurant.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: Oh, yeah?
RESTAURANT PATRON 5: This is
my soon to be second wife.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: Well,
I'm sorry about
the first time around.
RESTAURANT PATRON 5:
But it worked out.
RESTAURANT PATRON 6: You
brought me luck.
Thank you.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN:
That was weird.
I was a chef there when Kitchen
Confidential hit, and
Carlos, who worked with
me then, is now
the executive chef.
Carlos!
CARLOS: Chef.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: How
you doing, brother?
OK, I'd like to throw a couple
of cote du boeuf on the grill.
CARLOS: OK.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: Cook up some
cote du boeuf for my friends.
Can you trust me with that?
Think I'm good enough?
What's great about Les Halles
is they were completely
unimpressed with me in the
kitchen from the get-go.
Carlos is a good friend,
of course.
Also, he's been on the
show many times.
But I think what they
see first when I
walk into the kitchen--
I think they're all privately
hoping, oh, God, please don't
let him cook.
I'm seen as a liability to the
smooth operations of the
kitchen, not as famoso.
If anything, they bust my balls
somewhat worse than they
did when I was working
on the line.
CARLOS: Don't fuck it up, OK?
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: I don't
get to cook much.
People ask me a lot--
do you miss cooking?
Well, I don't miss standing in
the kitchen for 16 hours a
day, and I'm at an age where
I wouldn't be good at that
anymore, anyway.
You'll get an opportunity
to cook at home.
On the road, I'm eating
most of the time.
So when I get to cook for
my crew, that's a deeply
satisfying thing.
An all too rare thing.
There's a Martha Stewart
side of me, honestly.
Throwing together a little
meal for a few friends--
I like doing it.
What?
HELEN CHO: Are you making
food for us, or what?
ANTHONY BOURDAIN:
I'm making food.
It's going to take some-- look
at that piece of meat.
It's a big fucking piece
of meat, OK?
HELEN CHO: Let me see.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: It's going
to take some time.
All right.
Could you watch that for
me for a little bit?
CARLOS: Don't worry.
[INAUDIBLE].
ANTHONY BOURDAIN:
As always, yeah.
HELEN CHO: We need to do shots.
Carlos--
shot.
We want a shot.
CARLOS: I'm still working.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: I'm lame.
I can't even maintain the
illusion that I cook anymore.
I don't even have the energy
for that shit.
CARLOS: We worked for almost
a year and a half.
He's fun, man.
That guy is fucking fun.
He likes hardcore, like
Slipknot, Deftones, Pantera--
all that.
He was a fun guy to work with.
All the other guys like when
they come here, because they
want to be part of the
show, obviously.
He's a big fucking star now.
When he comes around,
people freak out.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: Here we go.
The difference between him and
me is that he gets pussy off
this fucking show.
I don't.
CARLOS: You know what, I really
thank you for that,
because I've been getting
laid so much.
HELEN CHO: Yeah, Carlos!
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: Me?
No.
CARLOS: Seriously, it's
like Captain Morgan.
I can't even count them.
DIANE SCHUTZ: Aw,
I'm so proud.
HELEN CHO: I know.
We are so proud.
We're so happy for
you, Carlos.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN: Yeah, I'm
flying to Burgundy tomorrow to
make love to Mr. [INAUDIBLE],
and he's getting fucking laid.
Oh, I'm so happy for you.
DIANE SCHUTZ: Wow.
ANTHONY BOURDAIN:
This is amazing.
So happy.
Very good.
You'll notice it's a constant.
Everybody in my life will
get on my show.
Where does reality end
and television begin?
Where does work end
and fun begin?
It's such a permeable line.
I can't tell.
I'm in this very weird place
where I get paid to be myself.
Is this a reality show?
I don't even [INAUDIBLE]
I don't even know
what reality is.
I just know what we do, and it's
a lot of fun, and it's
interesting.
And I work with them.
[THEME MUSIC]