Good night.
Good night, mommy.
Ow!
Lindsey, what are you doing?
It's an app for my phone;
It's an ultrasonic ringtone.
A what?
It works like a hearing test.
The younger you are,
the higher pitched sounds
you can hear.
I got one on my phone too.
And why do you need it?
I use it when I go
to people's houses.
It helps find
where the dogs are.
It looks like it works,
'cause there's a dog standing--
ow!
Lindsey, stop it.
I didn't do anything.
Uh, that was me.
Oh.
Let me see.
Wow, that's amazing.
I didn't hear a thing.
Well, Lindsey, just because
I can't hear your phone ring
doesn't mean
I can't hear you talking.
Good night.
Night.
Guys, can I stay up another
half hour on my computer?
You okay?
Yeah.
I've just been having
some weird dreams.
No--
okay, you can stay up...
Another half--
a half hour.
That's it.
Thanks.
Good night.
Night.
Sweetheart, close the door.
Good night.
Thank you.
Finally.
[Yawns] I can't believe
how tired I am.
Are you sleepy,
or are you tired?
'Cause I can work with tired.
Actually, I'm pretty sleepy.
What?
Are you serious?
Look, baby, I know
what you're offering,
and I would love to have it.
But if I don't get some sleep,
one of us might end up feeling
pretty embarrassed.
Really?
You could fall asleep
right in the middle?
I don't want to risk it.
Fine.
Take your tired butt to sleep.
Make sure you get well rested.
Whoa, whoa.
Let me get this straight.
When you don't feel like it,
we don't do it.
But when I don't feel like it--
we should do it anyway.
I'm a man, not a machine.
Oh, trust me;
I know the difference.
What's that supposed to mean?
It means go to sleep.
♪ Are we there yet? ♪
The No Nah Nah
S01x09 Original Air Date on June 30, 2010
♪ tell me, tell me, tell me ♪
♪ tell me,
are we there yet? ♪
-- Sync, corrected by elderman --
-- For www.addic7ed.com --
I know.
You know I want to.
Really?
Can you describe that for me?
No, no, I think
we need to wait.
Seriously.
Okay, I'll talk to you soon.
Bye-bye.
Who are you lying to now?
Her name is Scorpio.
You do realize
there's no future
with a woman named
after a Zodiac sign.
It's not her future
I'm worried about;
it's her past.
Take a look at this.
Can you give me a ruling
on that?
Is that her daughter?
No, that's her.
That's the problem.
I think she's 18,
'cause I met her at jury duty,
but you know how I love
a younger lady.
You and R. Kelly.
Ha, ha, ha.
Right.
I draw the line at teenagers.
You and R. Kelly.
Speaking of kids,
I have a situation.
And this stays here.
You say a word of this
to anybody--
yeah, yeah, yeah,
"I'll punch you so hard
that your grandkids
will get knocked out."
I got it.
I don't like to do it when
the kids are in the house.
I'm afraid they'll hear.
It makes me nervous.
Nick, I've dated women
with kids before.
There's an easy solution here.
You just get 'em
good and tired.
You have to treat children
like they're dogs.
What do you want me to do,
put them to sleep?
I was going to suggest
maybe taking them to the park
and throwing a frisbee around.
Now, what you got for me?
Because I'm not touching
this girl
until I'm sure I'm not going
to end up on Dateline.
Did you check
her driver's license?
She's from New York;
She doesn't drive.
When did she graduate
High School?
She was homeschooled.
What's her favorite song?
Aaliyah, Age Ain't Nothing But a Number.
Produced by R. Kelly.
Damn.
Why don't you just ask
this girl how old she is?
Oh, man,
she could say anything.
Did you look her up
on the Internet?
Mm-hmm, there are 48 Scorpios
in a 200-mile radius,
ages 14 to 69.
A 69-year-old named Scorpio?
Mm-hmm.
That can't be good.
Maybe you should just
cut her loose.
Uh, did you miss the part
where I showed you
how hot she is?
Yup, as hot as a night
in Roman Polanski's jacuzzi.
Okay, a little sexier
this time.
You know, I'm beginning
to worry about you two.
This isn't the first time.
It's not like that.
Yes, it is.
No, it's not.
Did you offer?
Yes.
He said?
"No."
Question.
It doesn't matter
what I was wearing, Gigi.
The man said he was tired.
Well, there's
one or two things.
Either he has diabetes...
Or he has a girlfriend.
Nick is not sick,
and he is not cheating on me.
It has to be something else.
Well, this is a long shot,
but maybe you should just
ask him what's wrong.
I don't like to talk
about my love life like that,
all clinical.
It takes the magic out of it.
Any other suggestions?
Well, if he's too tired
at night,
maybe you should just try him
in the morning.
He can't be tired then;
he just woke up.
Every now and again,
you make sense.
All right, now, pucker up
and say, "Burma's a war zone."
Burma's a war zone!
Nice.
Then we'll come out here.
And why are you making us
go hiking, again?
Your mother needs some time
to herself.
Are you guys fighting?
No, sometimes
if you love someone,
you leave them alone.
You hear that, Lindsey?
If you love me,
you leave me al--ow!
Hey, stop it.
[Doorbell rings]
Look, this is a surprise.
Do not tell your mother.
Kids: Okay.
Hey, man.
What are you doing here?
Oh, nothing.
I just wanted to introduce you
to my friend Scorpio.
It's really nice to meet you.
Martin told me so much
about you.
Mm-hmm.
Hey.
Scorpio.
Such an interesting name.
When's your birthday?
It's June.
Everybody thinks I'm named
after the Zodiac sign,
but really I'm named after
some guy in a group:
The Grandmaster Five
and The Furious Flash.
Grandmaster Flash
and The Furious Five.
Right.
My dad was, like,
their biggest fan.
Oh, boy.
He must be
a little older than me...
Like 40-something?
Actually, I don't know.
My mother refuses to talk
about him now.
He left her for a younger woman
ten years ago.
He's dead to her.
Me too.
Wow.
That must be tough on a kid.
How old were you
when they broke up?
Old enough to know
I will never take
another woman's man.
Well, I don't want
to hold you guys up.
Where you going?
We are going to the movies.
There's a special screening
of Night at the Museum 1 and 2.
It is, like,
my favorite movie ever.
And Robin Williams is so sexy.
The things I would do to him.
Come on, Martin.
I don't want to be late.
Hey, babe, why don't you
go wait out in the car, okay?
I'll meet you out there
in a minute?
Is that good?
Bye, Scorpio.
Nice to meet you, Nick.
[Both giggle]
Okay.
I can't help you, man.
Night at the Museum?
Robin Williams?
[Snoring lightly]
Sweetheart?
Good morning.
Kids: Morning.
Ow!
Lindsey, stop it.
Man, you heard that one?
Yeah, I have great hearing.
If mom and dad dropped a pin
in their room,
I'd be able to hear it.
Awesome.
Not really.
When they sleep,
they make too much noise.
Honey, I missed you
this morning.
Why didn't you wake me up?
Well, I know what it's like
to be sleepy,
so I figured I'd let you
get some rest too.
Oh, so what's going on?
Well, we got a big day
planned.
I'm taking the kids
for a walk.
Then we're going to go
to the park,
throw the frisbee around.
And then we're going to go
for a hike.
He's making us go.
Yeah, I really want to go
to the movies.
Well, I wish
you would have told me,
'cause I was hoping to spend
a little time with you
this morning.
How about I make it up to you
and we spend a little time
together tonight?
How about you guys spend
some time together right now
and me and Kevin can go
to the movies by ourselves?
Because I don't want you
to get kidnapped and molested
and have to raise your kids
in some man's backyard.
Yeah.
Bet you guys
don't hear anything tonight.
Come on, Lindsey.
There we go.
Yeah, there you go,
nice and tired.
Come on, kev.
Come on up, man.
All righty.
Oh, look at you.
There we go.
Ha!
[Sultry music plays]
♪ ♪
Ah, yes.
[Snoring]
Nick?
Baby?
He's not in the kitchen.
Nick.
What?
What is this?
What's what?
That!
That?
It's wine.
I know what it is!
So you'd rather drink
and sleep on the couch
than be with me.
I tell you what:
You better pray to God
you got diabetes.
Mom?
[Crossly]
What?
Are you okay?
I'm fine. What would
make you think I'm not fine?
'Cause you're beating eggs
with a knife.
I'm sorry.
I don't really feel
like cooking today.
Do you guys mind having cereal?
Okay.
Can we eat the cereal
with spoons instead of knives?
Sure.
Did Nick do something?
It's not what he did,
sweetheart.
It's what he didn't do.
I'm confused.
If guys get in trouble
for stuff they do
but then get in trouble
for stuff they don't do,
how are they supposed to know
what to do?
Just don't be stupid.
That's how.
[Tearfully]
My little girl is growing up.
You're so smart.
[Sighs]
I don't know, man.
How am I supposed to
explain this to a kid?
"What?
That noise?
"Oh, last night.
"Mommy and daddy
was watching a movie,
"and mommy got scared.
"What?
"Oh, you heard me scream?
I got a little scared too."
Who are you talking to?
Nobody. I was just thinking
out loud.
Well, I hope you're thinking
about how to make what you did
make sense to me,
because I don't understand.
Do you have diabetes?
No.
Why do you keep saying that?
Because I'm hoping
for the best.
Nick, I understand
your being tired.
But you're too tired
to lie down next to me,
and you're drinking?
You got it all wrong.
Are you having man problems?
No, I am not having
man problems.
Would you tell me if you were?
Yes.
[Sighs]
Okay.
Well, that's it.
I don't know
what your problem is,
and you don't seem
to want to tell me,
and that's okay.
But I'll tell you what.
Tonight it's on.
Like Donkey Kong.
Got it?
Got it.
What's up?
Whoa!
What happened to you?
Oh, nothing.
I had to tell Scorpio
I got into a fender bender.
I think that girl
is part octopus.
Anyway, I told her my neck would
be healed in a couple days,
and she's like, "as soon as
that thing comes off, it's on."
There's a lot of that
going around.
Women do not like
to be turned down.
Yeah, even if your neck
is broke.
They just won't hear it.
She won't hear it.
That's it!
I know exactly what you need.
This is the answer
to your problems.
The phone.
Ow.
Ow!
What is that?
It's an ultrasonic ringtone.
The younger you are,
the better your hearing.
Kevin is ten, so he can hear
up to 20 kilohertz.
Lindsey can hear up to 19.1,
and she's 14.
I'm guessing if Scorpio
can't hear anything
over 17 kilohertz,
she'll be in the clear.
That's insane.
I love it!
Take that stupid thing off.
Good; I think I'm starting
to get a rash.
Man, if this works,
I definitely owe you one.
Can you pay me back now?
So you've been ducking Suzanne
all this time
because you were afraid
the kids would hear?
It just started last week.
Kevin was having bad dreams.
I didn't tell Suzanne,
'cause I didn't want her
to think
I was having problems
with the kids.
That's just regular stuff.
Says the man who hates kids.
I don't hate kids.
I simply respect children enough
to know
I shouldn't be in their lives
on a regular basis.
Anyway, you know what to do.
Yeah, yeah, I'm the kids.
You're you and Suzanne.
You walk around.
You play the sound.
I tell you
when I can't hear it anymore.
Exactly.
We'll start downstairs
and work our way
around the house.
Although you are newlyweds.
I mean, what are using
for a demo here?
I mean, you don't have
a tape of--
that's my wife, man.
Hey, buddy,
it's your experiment.
It's women's tennis.
Sorry?
You ever see
a women's tennis match?
It sounds like--
ah.
For real.
Just keep listening.
You ready?
Yes, eagle one.
We are go.
[Ball thwacking
and women shrieking]
Can you hear it now?
Why, yes, I can.
Are you sure
that's women's tennis?
Yes, I'm sure
it's women's tennis.
I'm turning it down.
[Sounds continue]
Can you hear it now?
Uh-huh.
Who's the high-pitched one?
Maria Sharapova.
I just never knew
tennis was this...Compelling.
Can you hear it now?
[Silence]
Okay, right there.
Nothing.
Dude, when did you unlock
the secret of women's tennis?
The Williams sisters.
They started me watching.
Let's go upstairs.
I want to see what you hear
from the kids' rooms.
I tell you, man,
this is a great find.
It is a lot less embarrassing
to walk into blockbuster
and rent a tennis match.
What?
What was wrong
with that guy?
I don't know,
but I could bet you
that's the last time
he'll ever throw a rock
at a police car.
[Laughter]
[Women shrieking]
What's that?
That sounds like...
Oh, my God.
Okay, on three,
we make covering noises,
you take the kids to the car
and go get them
something to eat.
Do not bring them back
until I call you.
Okay.
One--
Suzanne.
What?
I'm sorry.
I was really hoping
he had diabetes.
Thank you.
One...
Both: Two, three.
♪ La la la la la la la
la la la la la... ♪
Okay.
I will not kill my man.
I will not kill...
My man.
Ootsteps]
I got to tell you, man,
I didn't think
that was going to work.
I hate to be on the down low
in my own home,
but you got to do
what you got to do.
At least now the kids
won't know, right?
Nick Kingston-Persons,
how could you?
Suzanne, no!
Do you love him?
Baby, you got it all wrong.
Don't touch me.
Um, what the hell
was that about?
Suzanne, no!
Gigi,
it's a big misunderstanding.
I know she's there.
'Cause I can hear her tell you
to tell me that she's not there.
Just tell her to come home,
please.
Gigi running interference.
Yup.
After you talk to Suzanne,
I need to talk to her.
We need to make sure
things are perfectly clear.
This is how rumors get started.
And I should know,
because I've hooked up
with plenty of women
by starting them.
Did the ringtones work out?
Turns out Scorpio can't hear
anything above 15 kilohertz.
That's good.
I mean, she's over 18.
Yeah, way over.
She's 37 and "too old
"to be messing around
with some guy
"who tries to figure out
a woman's age
by fooling with ringtones."
She said if I wanted to know
how old she was,
I should have just asked.
Like that's going to work.
I guess you guys didn't--
no.
Can I borrow this?
Excuse me.
[Doorbell rings]
Hey, baby.
Why you ringing the doorbell?
Forgot your key?
No.
But I can only take
so many surprises in one day.
Nick, please make this
make sense to me.
I mean, I can't believe
what was going on in here.
We have kids.
I know.
That's my problem.
Why are my kids your problem?
Look...
The reason I wasn't,
you know,
was because I was afraid
the kids could hear us.
The sounds you heard earlier
weren't me and Martin.
It was women's tennis.
It was the closest sound
I could think of
to what we weren't doing.
I wanted to see
how loud things could get
without the kids hearing us.
Women's tennis.
Who was playing?
Maria Sharapova.
A white woman?
Can we have one argument
at a time?
Are you telling me the truth?
Yes.
Prove it.
What?
The kids aren't here.
I told Gigi to keep them
with her until I called.
Well, then it's on.
Hey.
What?
You better not be thinking
about any white women.
It's on.
[laughs]
-- Sync, corrected by elderman --
-- for www.Addic7ed.Com --