expanding debris behind a powerful shockwave.
As the supernova remnant grows, it sweeps
up interstellar gas and gradually decelerates.
Yet even thousands of years later, its imprint
on the galaxy remains impressive.
Exploding stars and their remnants have long
been suspected of producing cosmic rays, some
of the fastest matter in the universe. Where
and how these protons, electrons and atomic
nuclei are boosted to such high speeds has
been an enduring mystery. Now, observations
of two supernova remnants by NASA's Fermi
Gamma-ray Space Telescope provide new insights.
Because cosmic rays carry electric charge,
their direction changes as they travel through
magnetic fields.
By the time the particles reach us, their
paths are completely scrambled. We can't trace
them back to their sources. So scientists
must locate their origins by indirect means,
which is where Fermi comes in. The interaction
of high-energy particles with light and ordinary
matter can produce gamma rays, the most powerful
form of light. Unlike cosmic rays, gamma rays
travel to us straight from their sources.
In 1949, physicist Enrico Fermi worked out
what he called "magnetized clouds" could accelerate
cosmic rays. Later studies showed that a variant
of his method, called Fermi acceleration worked
especially well in supernova remnants.
Confined by a magnetic field, high-energy
particles move around randomly. Sometimes
they cross the shock wave. With each round
trip, they gain about 1 percent of their original
energy. After dozens to hundreds of crossings,
the particle is moving near the speed of light
and is finally able to escape. If the supernova
remnant resides near a dense molecular cloud,
some of those escaping cosmic rays may strike
the gas, and produce gamma rays.
But electrons and protons make gamma rays
in different ways. Cosmic ray electrons do
so when they're deflected by passing near
the nucleus of an atom. Accelerated protons
may collide with an ordinary proton and produce
a short-lived particle called a neutral pion.
These pions quickly decay into a pair of gamma
rays. At their brightest, both types of emission
look very similar. Only with sensitive measurements
at lower gamma-ray energies can scientists
determine which process is responsible.
Now, Fermi observations have done just that.
They conclusively show these supernova remnants
are accelerating protons. When they strike
protons in nearby molecular clouds, they produce
pions... and ultimately the gamma-ray emission
Fermi sees. NASA's Fermi has detected gamma
rays from many more supernova remnants, but
the jury is still out on whether accelerated
protons are always responsible and what their
maximum energies may be. Nevertheless, the
Fermi team has taken a major step--a century
after the discovery of cosmic rays-- in establishing
just where they arise. Something that would
satisfy, but certainly not surprise, the original
Fermi.