SHANE SMITH: So is the
fight over now?
BEN ANDERSON: We think it might
be, but that happened
many, many times throughout
the day.
You think you can rest and it's
over, and then they pop
up and attack again.
Now the ANA are sitting down
inside the little sort of
courtyard next to the compound
here, and getting stoned.
SHANE SMITH: The first thing
they do in the break in the
fighting is the ANA
go get stoned.
BEN ANDERSON: Yeah.
SHANE SMITH: Are they getting
stoned on opium, or are they
getting stoned on hash,
or pot, or?
BEN ANDERSON: They smoke
a lot of hash.
We don't know if it was
hash or opium, but it
was one or the other.
SHANE SMITH: That guy
looks pinned.
That's opium for sure.
MALE SPEAKER: I don't understand
how they could
smoke it in the middle
of a battle.
They make you worse,
but they love it.
As soon as they get two minutes,
they fucking have
their-- start smoking it, and
passing it around, all
laughing and joking.
And then a minute
later, they're
running out towards bullets.
[AUTOMATIC GUNFIRE NEARBY]
[LAUGHTER]
BEN ANDERSON: He was so stoned
that he went outside, stood up
in full view of the Taliban,
aimed just into the sky.
A bullet fired the magazine
off his gun.
And he just picked it up off
the ground, laughed, and
walked back inside.
[AUTOMATIC GUNFIRE]
MALE SPEAKER: He's
fucking mad.
MALE SPEAKER: Why?
MALE SPEAKER: Tajimad.
We haven't got enough
ammunition to
fire bursts like that.
Short bursts.
MALE SPEAKER: Same question
from the captain.
Are they firing at anything?
MALE SPEAKER: No.
BEN ANDERSON: That happened
all the time.
You'd hear this massive burst
of gunfire, and hear one of
the Brits go, are they
shooting at anything?
And you'd hear someone
shout back, no.
We saw that time
and time again.
MALE SPEAKER: If you can't
clearly identify the enemy,
you shouldn't be
firing, really.
But trying to tell the ANA that
is a different matter.
BEN ANDERSON: Is that all the
ammo you've got left?
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah, it's
all we've got left.
We've got about 150
rounds left.
But I think we've got to go out
there about another K for
our resupply route.
SHANE SMITH: So you're running
low on ammunition now.
BEN ANDERSON: Yeah, he's
got 150 rounds left.
MALE SPEAKER: We need to start
bringing in resupplies of
water, food, and especially
ammunition.
Because we're running
low, yeah.
MALE SPEAKER: Boys are
low on water now.
But we knew it was
going to happen.
We only carry 3 liters
per man.
It isn't going to last long.
We've been on the go since half
through this morning, so
11 o'clock.
So yeah, 3 liters isn't a lot,
especially when you're
sweating as much as this.
SHANE SMITH: How hot is
it right now here?
BEN ANDERSON: Over 50 degrees.
SHANE SMITH: It's
over 50 degrees.
Which is like, I don't know,
120 degrees or 115 degrees
Fahrenheit.
But you're wearing flak
jackets and helmets.
So your balls are sweating
pretty bad right now.
BEN ANDERSON: Dripping.
SHANE SMITH: Dripping.
And you don't have any water.
BEN ANDERSON: No, the
water runs out.
Because you know, how much water
can you carry on top of
all that kit?
SHANE SMITH: So you're fucked.
BEN ANDERSON: Yeah, all of us.
[AUTOMATIC GUNFIRE NEARBY]
MALE SPEAKER: Hey
Six-Three-Alpha, ICOM chatter
suggests Taliban are pulling
back in front of our advance,
trying to conserve their own
ammunition, cause us to expend
all of ours, and then plan to
counterattack us as we withdraw.
Over.
SHANE SMITH: So what the Taliban
are doing now is
they'll shoot a couple shots,
get the ANA guys to go crazy,
stoned, shoot all
their guns off.
And then when you have to
retreat to get more bullets,
they're going to kill you.
BEN ANDERSON: Yeah.
Yeah, that could be the
Taliban's tactic for the
entire country.
You know, they know it doesn't
cost much for them to stay
there and stay fighting.
They know it costs Britain and
America and everybody else a
lot to be there.
So they think they can outpace
us, no problem at all.
They'll say, we'll fight for
10 years, like me and you
would say, let's go for
a drink, let's go
for a game of tennis.
It's nothing.
MALE SPEAKER: But be
aware of that.
Don't come down below 5,000.
[DISTANT GUNFIRE]
[LAUGHTER]
MALE SPEAKER: Fucking
spread out!
MALE SPEAKER: Right,
gentlemen.
MALE SPEAKER: Just keep
coming forward!
[BULLETS SNAPPING]
BEN ANDERSON: Hear that
popping sound?
That's not guns being fired.
That's bullets breaking
the sound barrier.
And if you hear that sound,
you're too close.
You're like 3, 4 meters
away from the bullet.
And there's hundreds of
those popping noises.
MALE SPEAKER: You coming in?
[LOUD SNAP]
MALE SPEAKER: Jesus.
BEN ANDERSON: So that's a bullet
that just came through
the door, and hit the wall
somewhere inside and then
covered us with dust.
MALE SPEAKER: Get
behind the wall.
MALE SPEAKER: Now, once that
target's destroyed, I'm hoping
that this fire will stop.
The air's coming in now.
Wait out.
BEN ANDERSON: They've called
in some planes
with 500-pound bombs.
[JET ENGINE OVERHEAD]
BEN ANDERSON: Exactly what
I was just thinking.
SHANE SMITH: So you just
said, please don't land
on me, to the bomb.
BEN ANDERSON: Yeah.
Yeah.
[HUGE EXPLOSION]
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah, I think
he needs to go south.
Yeah, he doesn't want to
come any closer to us.
BEN ANDERSON: So they
called in a
500-pound bomb, which missed.
And it wasn't that far in
front of this compound.
And they'll try again--
[BULLETS SNAPPING]
BEN ANDERSON: --try again
in about a minute.
[HEAVY GUNFIRE NEARBY]
SHANE SMITH: So the bomb didn't
seem to hit them.
They're still shooting at you.
BEN ANDERSON: What happened
there happened again and again
and again throughout my
two months there.
Bombs get dropped, missiles,
everything.
It goes quiet for a minute, you
think, that's it, that's
got to be it.
And then you hear them pop
up and fire back again.
I think they're just
firing for--
the British or ANA are trying to
keep the Taliban in place.
That way when the bomb lands,
if they're still there, that
should be the end in there.
MALE SPEAKER: Six-One-Alpha,
heads down.
20 seconds.
Out.
[JET ENGINE OVERHEAD]
[HUGE EXPLOSION]
MALE SPEAKER: Probably
has hit further east.
BEN ANDERSON: That fell even
closer than the last one.
SHANE SMITH: So that's another
bomb that they
nearly hit you with.
And then they nearly
hit you again.
BEN ANDERSON: Yeah, a bit closer
than the last one.
SHANE SMITH: That was closer
BEN ANDERSON: Yeah, yeah.
MALE SPEAKER: We'll just stay
firm here, away from all the
casualties to be dealt
with and got out.
Tell them to bring the water
forward, and give everyone a
chance to have some water.
And then we'll re-cock and go in
for those final compounds,
Whiskey and X-ray.
[HEAVY GUNFIRE NEARBY]
MALE SPEAKER: That's getting
the water out there.
BEN ANDERSON: So some guys went
out to get some water.
Came under heavy fire again.
I think this time we've come
under fire from that side and
that side at the same time.
We haven't come under
fire from that side.
So far it's total there.
Normally when you hear fire like
that, it's just because
someone's stuck their
head out, someone's
shot, whatever it was.
In this instance, guys had gone
out to pick up water that
had been dropped
via helicopter.
So it was all quiet as they went
out to pick up the water.
And then suddenly all hell
breaks loose from 360 degrees.
And we know there are guys out
there, picking up this water.
MALE SPEAKER: So we're
short of water.
Short of batteries.
Plenty of ammunition.
And plenty of Taliban.
So yeah.
All in all, good going,
apart from the water.
BEN ANDERSON: Seven guys
collapsed by the end of this
day, and some of them were in
life-threatening conditions.
I saw one guy actually collapse,
and I thought it was
trauma or shell shock or
something, because I've never
seen a guy--
I mean, he took his top off.
He tried to fight his friends,
who were going to
pour water on him.
He collapsed like a boxer who
has been knocked out.
I didn't realize that heat
exhaustion can be that bad.
And plus, these guys are
soldiers, so they're going to
deny it to the last minute.
They're going to pretend they're
OK, and struggle on
through until the very
last minute, when
it's almost too late.
Despite what's happened, the
day is far from over.
MALE SPEAKER: Oh,
far from over.
This is just the beginning.
This is just the beginning
of a very busy day.
Probably a couple of days,
if not a week.
BEN ANDERSON: Eventually the
Taliban withdrew, and we just
walked away.
I don't know if they ran out
of ammunition or something.
They packed up and left,
and it stayed quiet.
And within a very short time of
leaving that compound, we
heard over the radios that the
Taliban had retaken all of
those buildings that had
been fought for.
MALE SPEAKER: I believe we're
going to go north, go firm,
put a defensive position in.
And then we'll have a nice
quiet night in the valley
tonight, by the look of it.
Not.
BEN ANDERSON: If this small area
of the valley takes this
much of a fight to clear, how
much is the whole province
going to take?
MALE SPEAKER: Well, the country
being like it is-- and
it's classic hit-and-run
country.
It's like Normandy, hedgerows,
ditches,
plowed fields, compounds.
And these guys, they've got all
the time in the world to
set up what they want to set up,
and where they want to be.
Whereas we've got to advance
into them to flush them out.
So the whole province?
Oh, I don't get paid enough
to tell you that one.
I don't know.
I'm not going to guess.
BEN ANDERSON: How old are you?
MALE SPEAKER: 41 years old.
And I was supposed to leave
the army this year.
And I was graciously offered two
more years, and I took it.
BEN ANDERSON: Is this
your last tour?
MALE SPEAKER: Probably
yes, he says.
But I did say that last year in
Iraq, that that was going
to be my last tour.
And obviously it's not,
so we'll see.
We'll see what happens.
MALE SPEAKER: Probably the
biggest I've had in my career
since I've been in, mate,
in terms of contacts.
I've been going since
0300 this morning.
It's now 10 past 4:00 in the
afternoon, 1610 hours.
So it's been quite a long day.
It's not over yet.
We've still got to move off
to our next location, and
meet up with WFR.
And then we'll see how
we get from there.
But the boys have worked their
nuts off, as usual.
So have the ANA.
Everyone's worked really hard.
BEN ANDERSON: So when he says,
that's the most intense day
I've ever had as a soldier,
he's done tours of Iraq,
Bosnia, Kosovo, Northern
Ireland, Afghanistan.
That's not said lightly
when he says that.
SHANE SMITH: Right.
So Afghanistan has the
fiercest fighting in
the world right now.
BEN ANDERSON: Yeah.
I mean, the historians and
these guys, they're all
saying, the most ferocious
fighting since the Korean War.
MALE SPEAKER: Lucky today.
We seemed to be near cover every
time it come, didn't we?
We're lucky.
I'm surprised no one's
a casualty today.
BEN ANDERSON: Is it manpower?
The reason you can't--
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah,
it's manpower.
We haven't got the manpower.
There's not enough
people out here.
Now, they're out to fight.
And it's very rare that
you see them.
But most people here ain't
even seen a Taliban yet.
SHANE SMITH: So they can fight
the Taliban all day for 12
hours, and they'll have
never have seen them.
BEN ANDERSON: You might
see a bit of movement.
You might see a flash
of light from where
they're firing from.
That's it.
And they probably have seen lots
of Taliban when they're
not fighting.
SHANE SMITH: They just
don't know it.
BEN ANDERSON: They're in the
villages and the towns.
But how do you know?
MALE SPEAKER: As soon as it
starts getting a bit rough,
and it looks they're going to
get it, they'll fucking pick a
pitchfork up, and they're
Farmer Joe for the day.
If someone's coming towards
me on the same path,
I'll cross the path.
I don't want them to get
nowhere near me.
I want to go home.
They're the kind of people that
believe when they die,
they're going to wake
up with 27 virgins.
So how can you fight against
someone like that, who doesn't
give a shit?
It's like as soon as
I die, I'll be
going back to Tottenham.
I'll fucking run
at the bullets.
BEN ANDERSON: And you regularly
see guys that are
just dumbfounded.
Like, how can you fight
against someone
who wants to die?
Who thinks that dying is an end,
dying is a route to some
kind of paradise?
SHANE SMITH: So who is going
to win that fight?
BEN ANDERSON: People regularly
talk about how the Americans
and British always beat
the Taliban when they
meet them in a fight.
That doesn't mean the Taliban
are ever going to give up.
That's the follow-up point that
most people seem to miss.
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah, we'll
come straight
back today or tomorrow.
But the thing is, because we've
left it, we'll have to
fucking start again.
So that is just pointless,
isn't it?
I mean, we don't know what
we're doing now.
That's the hardest
bit, not knowing.
SHANE SMITH: You
went in there.
You fought all day.
You got surrounded.
People are dropping like flies
from heat exhaustion.
You nearly got bombed by your
own guys three times.
And then you had to leave, so
the Taliban just went in.
BEN ANDERSON: Yeah.
He said we haven't got the
manpower to hold on to land.
And it's the same thing with
the border with Pakistan.
They just haven't got the
manpower to either hold on to
land or patrol borders
properly.
SHANE SMITH: So it's
all for nothing.
BEN ANDERSON: With existing
levels of troops, yeah.
MALE SPEAKER: I'd say yesterday
was probably the
hardest day I've had in
17 years' service.
And I think all of the others
who fought in it yesterday
would probably agree.
It was eight hours of
unrelenting combat against a
canny, wily, determined enemy,
who was prepared to
fight to the death.
It's extremely difficult in
the Green Zone to maneuver
your forces.
BEN ANDERSON: Is there a danger
that by flattening
compounds--
and obviously civilians are
going to get caught up in the
compounds from time to time--
that you could lose
the support of the
population here entirely?
That they could either become
indifferent to you being here,
or worse, supporters and
helpers of the Taliban?
MALE SPEAKER: It's
a fine line.
I think if we were completely
indiscriminate in our fires,
then yes, we could lose
support quite quickly.
As it happens, yesterday there
was an attack aviation strike
on a compound which had
civilians and my men in it.
I was fortunate that none
of them were injured.
It was me.
I directed that attack.
I gave clearance
for it to fire.
And the responsibility for
it lies on my shoulders.
In this instance, I'm extremely
lucky that there
were no casualties, either
friendly or civilian.
SHANE SMITH: What do you think
is happening in Afghanistan?
BEN ANDERSON: I think
that is happening on
a much wider scale.
There's no evidence that the
Taliban are even thinking
about giving up.
There's no evidence that a
military solution is possible.
And there's no evidence that the
Brits or the Americans or
anyone can control anything
apart from these isolated
bases and towns.
So the Taliban have complete
free rein, especially over the
south of Afghanistan.
SHANE SMITH: So we went in
to kick the Taliban out.
The Taliban are getting
stronger and stronger.
There's more drugs coming
out than ever before.
Why are we there?
BEN ANDERSON: The most
discouraging thing I've seen
or heard from Afghanistan
recently is when I was there,
one town was left that was under
control of the Taliban.
That was taken just
after I left.
They put in charge a
guy who's Taliban.
He soon described himself
as good Taliban.
Yeah, that makes you think, why
have we been fighting and
losing people for six years,
when we could have done
exactly the same deal
that we've done
today, six years ago?
[BIRDS TWITTERING]