JAN KWIECINSKI: I wanted to
create a clash of two
margins-- the people from the
city and the people from
outside the city.
I was thinking that showing
these fancy guys from the town
who get lost somewhere and
people in the village who are
also lost can be a nice idea.
[SPEAKING POLISH]
JAN KWIECINSKI: One thing was
the margins, and the other
thing was the unknown place,
which the audience had never
seen before.
And I was thinking that maybe
that a cool idea would be if I
would go to place where I
have never been before.
So that's what I did.
[SPEAKING POLISH]
PAWEL TOMASZEWSKI:
PAWEL SMAGALA: [SPEAKING POLISH]
[SPEAKING POLISH]
PAWEL TOMASZEWSKI:
PAWEL SMAGALA: [SPEAKING POLISH]
[CHURCH BELL CHIMES]
JAN KWIECINSKI: What is great
about Parysewo is that when I
first came here, it
was totally empty.
Basically, there was nobody
on the street.
It was very mysterious.
Because you look at this amazing
big church, but it's
untouched in a way.
There are 100-year-old houses,
and you feel that you don't
have this life outside.
It feels like it's the
middle of nowhere.
I felt a quite strange
atmosphere here.
I don't know what it is.
Logistically, like from my point
of view, it's quite easy
to close the town and to
shoot the empty town.
And I was thinking that maybe
it wouldn't be such a stupid
idea to put some characters
there.
MALE SPEAKER: [SPEAKING POLISH]
CAMERAMAN: [SPEAKING POLISH]
[PRODUCTION ASSISTANT:
[SPEAKING POLISH]
JAN KWIECINSKI: My script was
based basically on very
logical structure.
I tried to write as few details
as possible because of
the fact that I want my actors
to feel creative and to be a
part of the storytelling.
And in my opinion, it's always
good to open these kind of
doors to the actors because they
straightaway feel like a
participant of the project.
And they are becoming very
creative straightaway.
MALE SPEAKER: [SPEAKING POLISH]
JUSTYNA WASILEWSKA:
[SPEAKING POLISH]
JAN KWIECINSKI: It's the first
time when I'm working with
four actors.
I was really lucky because they
knew each other before
they met in my project.
I felt there was an energy which
is coming straight from
nothing in a way.
I felt from the beginning of the
project that these are the
kind of actors which will make
these characters feel alive.
PAWEL TOMASZEWSKI:
[SPEAKING POLISH]
JAN KWIECINSKI: I got a
good group in here.
And sometimes the director who
really wants to direct can
kill the project.
A very, very important
part of the
process is keeping distance.
And what's helps you in keeping
distance is constantly
sharing this idea
with the others.
Don't think that only your way
is the good way because that
can make the project look really
like without life.
And this way of thinking about
the script, I think it's not
only connected with thinking how
should you work with the
actors, but also how should you
work with other people who
are participating in
movie projects.
And I try to not make
it my script but
their script as well.
RADOSLAWA BARDES: Say hello.
Hello, little puppy.
She's terrified.
She peed on me, like,
twice already.
We want to show that the town
got abandoned by locals, and
these dogs are homeless, and
they just hang around.
We make sure that we have bag of
kielbasa, polish sausages.
And we just bribe them.
If they come with us, they
start their career.
JAN KWIECINSKI: I really feel
so overwhelmed that I'm the
participant of this project.
And I really feel like this so
great opportunity to me.
And it's really hard
to talk about it.
Everything was so fast.
And the whole process is
like I didn't even
notice where it started.
It wasn't clear at all.
You gave us this super
opportunity to talk about
something so metaphysical that
you can't even talk about it.
So this is the four dimension of
my movie, trying to capture
something beyond our perception,
something more
than we can imagine.
So from the beginning, I was
thinking, create the story
between this magical
and real world.
But the magic has to be created
from the realism which
you are making.
And maybe we'll find four
dimensions in the end.
I hope so.
[MUSIC PLAYING]