I just started my professorial
duty in Frankfurt on Monday
night, actually.
I'm the film class professor.
It's very serious.
And one of the things I said
to one of the students was
that I was a very diligent
student, and I did my life
drawing class.
And I did my stained
glass window class.
I did my mural painting class.
The only class that I really
got deliberately ill enough
not to be able to attend
was the video class.
I always hated it.
I knew what I liked, and
what I liked was film.
And there was something very
primal for me, in that I don't
really like information to be
shot straight into my eye.
I always preferred the idea
that you are getting it in
some kind of a third-hand way.
You have the celluloid.
A light passes through.
It hits the screen.
And then your eye gets it.
And there's something softer,
even if you're watching a very
hard series of images,
with difficult ideas.
I think there's a
softer landing.
It's very telling that
technocrats and technicians
have been pushing video to be as
close to film as possible.
Therefore, film is still
on that pedestal.
When I started looking at films
in a certain way, and
doing almost nothing to them
except re-presenting the way
that they would be seen, or
could be seen, that definitely
is coming from the kind of
intellectual rigor that I had
through my studies in London.
But I think the choices of the
films that I worked on were
probably coming from
this much more
autobiographical exercise.
Let's take, for example,
Hitchcock's "Psycho" and "Taxi
Driver," for instance.
I didn't see "Psycho," I think,
until I was about 21.
And I didn't see "Taxi Driver"
until I was about 26 or 27.
I mean, there was a lot to do
with the old experience of
cinema, as well.
And the fact that there was
something happening, I think,
in the 1980s, in Britain at
least, that cinema was going
down, and TV and VCR
was coming up.
And my experience of film was
definitely much more in the
domestic situation, rather than
the communal cinematic,
or cathedral, of cinema,
which I like
to think about sometimes.
And then when I got into it, and
hit the French New Wave--
and one of the most important
books, which I think is one of
the best books on cinema ever,
is the interviews between
Hitchcock and Truffaut.
And that was kind of a turning
point, I think, for me, when I
realized that there were
different types of cinema.
They could be deconstructed,
and you could openly seduce
people at the same time as being
slightly intellectual.
One of my students, actually, in
Frankfurt, said to me, when
was the last time you
went to the cinema?
I had to kind of lie and say,
I never go to the cinema for
moral reasons.
But the last time I was in the
cinema was to see my work.
Last time I was in the
cinema before that
was to see my work.
The last time I was in the
cinema before that
was to see my work.
And that just sounds like
such a load of wank.
To a student, sometimes it's
better not to tell the truth.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
When I started to work with the
material, and I mean when
the material will be a
videotape, and like an
innocent person, I did take a
videotape and held it up-- and
there's nothing to see.
And that's magical, as well.
It appears to be nothing,
but it contains all this
information of a different--
I suppose it's the early idea of
the avatar, in a way, that
the cinema screen has all
these characters behind.
And I think with "24 Hour
Psycho," when I installed that
in Glasgow for the first time
in 1993, I wanted to put the
screen in the middle of the
space, so when you went behind
it, you just saw the same thing
from the other side, but
from the other side.
So that's when I started
to get interested
in the mirror image.
I went from there into hospital
archives, and started
to dig around and for images
which looked magical, because
they were shot by
cinematographers, even though
they were done, apparently,
for medical purposes.
It became obvious that I was
going to have to get behind
the camera one day, rather
than stand in
front of the mirror.
I had to take another step back
and be behind the camera,
and behind the lens, also
in front of a mirror.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
I knew I had to start
making films.
And actually, the first film
that I made was called
"Feature Film." Maybe I wasn't
confident enough to think that
I would make anything other than
that, so I had this kind
of very teenage, vain idea
that in my life I always
wanted to write a short novel,
make a record, and make a
feature film.
So at least I got the
feature film done.
And having done that, which
was a study of a conductor
with an orchestra--
the orchestra are never seen, so
how would you know that he
would be a conductor?
And the orchestra are playing
the score to Hitchcock's
"Vertigo."
[MUSIC PLAYING]
And when we showed that, some
people who saw it had asked me
questions like, how many little
images did you slip in
from "Vertigo?" Because they
really think that they saw
James Stewart or Kim
Novak in my film.
And it never happened.
But cinematic experience and
the music obviously was
powerful enough that images
were coming from inside of
their head, and they were
projecting their
images onto my film.
And I thought that that's an
incredibly sophisticated and
perverse thing to happen.
After making "Feature Film," and
I was quite confident by
that time then about working
in the industry.
So the premise for "Zidane" was
what if we make a feature
film which is a portrait, and
why not make it around a
football player?
And of course when we went to
see Zidane it became three
questions--
what if, why not, and
Zidane said, why me?
And we said to him, no
one really knows what
aftershave you wear.
We don't know if you go
out to nightclubs.
You exist from the first
kick of the ball
until the final whistle.
And that's what's incredibly
special about you as a player.
He represents something
which is exclusively
him, completely chimeric.
So he becomes everyone else.
The day before the match,
that's when our
crew started to arrive.
And you can imagine 17 or 18
cameras, each camera having an
operator, a focus puller,
a loader, and a runner.
I think the crew was about 150
or something like that.
The pressure was on.
And still the producers were
saying to us, you have to make
a storyboard.
And we said, we can't.
It's a live event.
And they said, but you have to
be able to say something to
the operators about what
it is that you want.
So Philippe and I had
a little chat.
The collection of portraits in
the Prado is probably one of
the best in the world.
So we took our camera
guys there on the
morning of the game.
And they opened up the doors to
the Prado, and we walked in
through the Goya entrance.
And you have this vast corridor
of portrait after
portrait after portrait.
And we said to the film guys, to
the operators, this is our
storyboard.
Look down the corridor, and
imagine that every painting is
a film still.
And as we're walking past,
please look carefully at every
still that you're seeing.
Now, we're shooting at 24 frames
a second, but we want
all of the information that
you're seeing from this Goya,
which probably took about
a year to paint--
we want a year's worth
in everything.
So we obviously set the
bar pretty high.
And it was astonishing.
These guys who shoot, who look
at people, and look at events
as their daily bread,
had never seen
anything quite like that.
One of the most beautiful
memories that I have is
standing in front of these two
paintings of the Duchess of
Alba, I think it is,
both by Goya, same
woman lying on a chaise.
One she has her clothes on.
One she is not wearing
clothes.
But the angle of observation
is slightly different.
And Philippe and I were saying,
we don't really know
how to explain what's going on
here, but look at the dynamic
between the two pictures.
It's a phenomenon.
So we got the most expensive
storyboard in the history of
film done, because we
used the Prado.
I don't think that anybody that
I really respect thinks
of themselves in any world.
The best chefs I know
are always involved
in something else.
The best filmmakers are always
involved in something else.
The best singers are always
doing something else.
I think you can be a hermetic,
but within your little hermit
cave or whatever, I think it's
important that you have
something else happening
somewhere else in the world.
One of the best comments that
a teacher ever made to her
class in Glasgow was, you're
here for four years--
don't feel that you have to
leave and be an artist.
Just enjoy this four years that
you have here, because
you'll never have this amount
of freedom again.
And as a little lotus eater
that I am, I wanted to
perpetuate that four years
for as long as possible.
So that's why I don't really
have a huge engagement with
what's perceived to be the art
market, or the art world, or
the film world, or
anything else.
People will always put
you in a pigeonhole.
Why would you fly
in on your own?