ARTO: I don't care about
the mileage so far.
It's been fine.
It's been fun riding.
I mean, that's been one of the
most enjoyable parts of the
trip is just fucking hauling
ass and just going.
And you definitely feel like
a free motorcycle renegade
riding down the two-lane
highway, going however fast
the bike can handle.
And just cruising around,
not a care in the world.
HARVEY: You know what, man?
I kind of think Victoria and
Mexico are kind of alike.
Mexico is really laid back and
there's always characters
everywhere.
But approachable characters.
That one place we stopped at and
the Sporsters ran out of
gas, and there was this
lady living in
the middle of nowhere.
And she's got a cell phone.
And she's standing on the
highway waiting for a ride.
And then probably fucking seven
miles down the road,
it's the biggest city for
smaller cities in Mexico.
KEEGAN: Any motorcycle
trip I've ever
been on in the past--
usually I'd go on trips in the
summer and it's really hot.
And we're probably
not showering.
And even if I'll go on a trip
and it's freezing, it just
became a thing with
me and my friends.
It's like, have to go swimming
no matter what.
Get in the water.
It just became this thing.
It was not an option,
you know?
ARTO: That's why we came here
for, is for the golden hour.
Look at the sunset.
From the dusty dust
bowl, this is a
little different scenario.
I'd stay here any day.
La Paz es muy fantastico.
KEEGAN: Wow.
I can't believe it's
only 5:30.
ARTO: Woke up at 6:00.
Where are we?
KEEGAN: We're already
down here.
ARTO: Really?
KEEGAN: Yeah.
ARTO: We're down here.
La Paz.
How did we get from up here to
down here in, what, six days?
Five days?
KEEGAN: Pretty easy.
We just didn't stop and
look at anything.
We just rode.
ARTO: We just drove
95 miles per hour.
It's going to be a sad moment
once we start going up.
There's no more left.
No more party.
The football season's over.
No more games.
That's it.
KEEGAN: Yeah.
It's kind of lame.
ARTO: More importantly,
should we go try to
find some fish tacos?
KEEGAN: Yeah.
ARTO: Let's go.
[IMITATES ROOSTER CROWING]
[IMITATES SHEEP BLEATING]
[IMITATES DOG BARKING]
[IMITATES COW MOOING]
[IMITATES HORSE NEIGHING]
ARTO: Wow.
[IMITATES DOG BARKING]
[APPLAUSE]
ARTO: Muy bien.
Muy bien.
Muchas gracias.
That thing is not much
else other than
just straight tequila.
It's got a decent kick to it.
KEEGAN: Holy fuck.
ARTO: That ain't fucking
around here.
Not fucking any spiders,
that's for sure.
That's what I imagined
Baha to be.
Hoo hoo-whoo!
Reggie, hell.
Let's go.
For this part of the video,
you might need subtitles.
Because the slurring's
gonna start.
KEEGAN: Things are going to
get finished right here?
ARTO: Things are about to start
slurring right now.
KEEGAN: What?
ARTO: I'm saying we can take a
taxi cab around town and see
what's happening.
DISTORTED, SLURRED VOICE
(OFFSCREEN):
Dos mas, tres mas.
Pina colada?
Muchos gracias, senor.
Uno mas.
It's like a fucking Slurpee.
This is so good here.
Muy feo.
Muy feo, pussy.
Is there better pussy?
Donde esta fantastico pussy?
[GIGGLING]
No?
No hay.
No hay en La Paz.
Aqui?
Aqui.
ARTO: [INAUDIBLE] is the one
that's just chilling to the
smooth jazz, isn't it?
KEEGAN: Hey, rasta.
Rasta, mon.
ARTO: Fresh G. Just--
KEEGAN: Was that a good
restaurant, or what?
ARTO: I'm thinking Reggie
needs to be released.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
What's Reggie?
ARTO: Reggie is all shaft
and all balls.
Reggie is a human-sized boxer.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN): Oh.
ARTO: Let's find out.
Yeah, that's right.
Oh.
(SINGING) Oh Canada--
There's the cool kids!
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
Checking your Facebook, Bill?
ARTO (OFFSCREEN): You--
you guys are--
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN):
I'm Tweeting right now.
I'm pretty much Tweeting.
ARTO (OFFSCREEN): What's
[INAUDIBLE] doing?