- What were you doing
in the attic?
- Looking for stuff to find.
- Oh, check this out.
Bam!
- "A different world"?
- What's that?
- One of the tv shows
of the '90s.
Look, I can't believe
you guys never heard of it.
It was created by bill cosby.
- Who's bill cosby?
- Are you serious?
He's one of the greatest
comedians of all time.
- Better than Nick Cannon?
- A little bit.
Anyway, this was one of the
top tv shows on the networks
for, like, six years.
- Black people
used to be on network tv?
- In the '80s and '90s, yeah.
Both: Wow.
- We had sitcoms, cartoons.
I mean, there were so many
black shows on tv,
they ran out of actors
and started using puppets.
There was this show called
cousin Skeeter.
- Yeah, I think
I remember that one.
I always wondered
why his mouth was so wide.
- Hold on.
Black puppets...
On tv.
- Mm-Hmm.
- Wow.
And I thought having
a black president was huge.
These tapes are gigantic.
- It's what we watched
before DVDs.
- Why?
- Because there were no DVDs.
- Well, can we watch
some of them?
- Sure.
I just have to find a vcr.
I think my mother has one.
- What's a vcr?
- Am I that old,
or are you that young?
Both: Both.
- Hey, baby.
- Hey, sweetheart.
- Do you know you're special?
- Mm.
I am?
- Do you really know
how special you are?
- Why don't you tell me
how special I am?
- You are so special
that you have received
an exclusive invitation
to the newest,
the hottest steakhouse
in Seattle.
- Knife?
- Bam!
- [Screams]
Oh, my God.
This is supposed to be amazing.
Wow, look at this.
- Yep, and everybody's gonna
be there.
Including me and my baby.
- Oh.
I can't wait.
I'm so excited.
When is it?
- Tomorrow night
from 7:00 to 10:00.
- Tomorrow night?
- From 7:00 to 10:00.
- Why didn't you
tell me earlier?
- I didn't know about it
earlier.
- I can't go.
The bridal expo
is tomorrow night.
- What time is it over?
- 7:00.
- I'll come get you at 7:00.
- No, but I won't be finished.
I still have to
pack everything up
and break down the booth.
- Well, I'll come by at 7:30.
- Well, I need to come home
and shower
and change and get ready.
- Well, by the time
you do all that,
the party'll be over.
There won't be nothing left
to eat but gristle and grease.
- I'm sorry.
Baby, you can still go.
Just take one of your boys.
- I don't want to take
one of the boys.
I wanted to go with you.
- Well, I wish I had
more notice.
- It's cool.
- Well, sweetie.
I can make it up to you.
I promise.
We can plan a date night.
- A date night.
What are we, 50?
Look, I was looking forward
to going out
and having a fun, sexy,
spontaneous night.
- We are spontaneous.
- No, no, no, I'm spontaneous.
When you want to do something
on the spur of the moment
with me, I'm good.
But when I want to do something
on the spur of the moment
with you,
I have to schedule it.
Uh, let's see.
Spurt of the moment on the 17th.
- Nick, I'm doing the best
that I can.
- I know.
I just was really
looking forward to this.
"For their remarkable attention
to detail"
in preparation
and presentation,
knife embodies the appreciation
of the fine tradition
"of eating good meat."
- Well, let me
make it up to you.
I can come up with something
that will make you
forget about knife.
- As long as you don't call it
a date night.
- Oh, baby,
when I'm done with you,
you will call it
whatever I want you to call it.
- ♪ Are we there yet? ♪
♪ tell me, tell me, tell me ♪
- ♪ tell me,
are we there yet? ♪
Sync & correct by dr.jackson
www.addic7ed.com
- hey.
- Hey, man.
- What are you having
for dinner tonight?
- I don't know.
Suzanne didn't say.
Why?
- Lock the kids in the basement
and take your wife to knife.
- Knife?
- Yes.
It's this new steak place,
and it is amazing.
Oh, my God.
They had this
grand opening last night.
It was insane, dude.
- Oh, man,
I was supposed to be there.
- Well, frankly,
I feel sorry for you,
'cause you missed out.
How come you didn't show up?
Everybody was there.
Suzanne had to work.
Gigi had a date,
and shouldn’t cover.
- Gigi was there.
Yeah, last time I saw gigi,
she was dancing on a table
with a veal chop in one hand
and some dude's black card
in the other.
- Wait, dancing on the table?
It was supposed to be a dinner.
- Well, it started out that way,
but then dj jazzy Jeff shows up.
- Dj jazzy Jeff was there?
- Yeah.
Loves steak.
Who knew?
The guy flew all the way in
from Philly.
Let me tell you,
I love will Smith,
but now I know
why they called it
dj jazzy Jeff
and the fresh prince.
That guy deserves top billing.
Will Smith needs a whole movie
to get people to listen to him.
Jeff, he just jumps
on the ones and twos,
and he's like...
[Imitates turntable scratching]
"Eat steak."
♪ Me... me... me... me... me
medium rare ♪
♪ knife ♪
♪ boo ♪
[Imitates explosion]
- You through?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, all right,
it was amazing.
I get it.
- Take Suzanne.
She'll love it.
She will love you.
Just so long as you
keep her away from Anna.
- Who's that?
- Only the waitress who's gonna
end your marriage.
I would describe her body
to you,
but, well, your children
have already lost one father,
and I don't want them
to lose another.
- Well, Suzanne's planning
a date night.
Maybe I'll suggest we go there.
- Oh, a date night.
Um, I'll take things old people
do for $1,000, Alex.
Seriously, what are you, 60?
- Man, I haven't hooked up
a vcr in years.
Thanks for bringing it over.
- Honey, if it would keep
your kids occupied,
I'd bring over
my washing machine.
- All set.
- Honey, I'm ready.
- Man, look at you.
Suzanne, you look amazing.
- Thank you, Marilyn.
- Whoa!
I'm coming to join you, honey...
With my skinny jeans on.
[Laughter]
- So you really must have
messed something up
to be dressing like that
on a weeknight.
- Now, why would you say that?
- Oh, girl, please,
I had a husband.
I know a "I'm sorry" dress
when I see one.
- Don't listen to her, baby.
You look incredible.
- Thank you.
You know, we better get going,
or we just might not
make it out.
- Ooh.
[Laughter]
- Ugh!
I mean, see you later.
- See you later.
- Don't bring no babies
back up in here.
- All right.
I am ready.
- Me too.
- Let's get settled in.
- Oh, wait, wait, wait.
Before we leave, I made some
mood music for our date.
It keeps with the theme.
- A theme?
- Mm-Hmm.
- Oh, that's nice.
[Smooth R&B beat]
Ooh, I like that.
You think of everything.
[Laughter]
So what are we doing?
- Oh, well, at 7:00,
we'll check in
for our reservation.
By 7:15, we'll have drinks.
After some small talk
and some light banter,
we'll share an intimate kiss
and then order our appetizers.
I figure that'll take us
through about 8:00,
and then we'll put in
our entree order
and then some
restaurant-appropriate PDA.
- Personal digital assistant?
- Public displays of affection.
- Oh, okay.
- And then after that,
we can just play
the rest of the evening by ear.
- Oh, just completely
off the cuff.
- Oh, you know, see if we
want to order dessert or not.
Mm.
- Oh, you are totally
out of control, girl.
- Whoo, I'm wild!
[Laughter]
- So where we going?
- Oh, honey, you don't have to
worry about that.
- Hi, honey.
- Good morning.
- So that was good last night,
right?
- Hmm?
- I said, last night
was nice, right?
- It was cool.
- Did you just give me
the high voice?
- No.
- Are you seriously
gonna stand there
with a straight face
and lie to me about giving me
the high voice
in the high voice?
- I am not giving you
the high voice.
- Nick, if you
didn't like our date,
you can just tell me.
- Baby, the other night,
I was looking for excitement.
Knife was
a once-in-a-lifetime night,
and we missed it.
- But our evening was romantic.
- It was perfectly planned.
- You liked dinner, right?
- Planned.
- Didn't you love
the walk along the pier?
- Planned.
- What about when we got home?
That wasn't planned;
That was good.
- It was cool.
- [Gasps]
Well, you better remember
how cool it was,
because that's the last
you'll see of that.
You can plan on it.
- Date night?
What are you, 70?
- The only reason
I had to plan a date night
is because of you.
Why didn't you tell me
you were going to knife?
You didn't think
I wanted to come?
- Well, the guy called me
that afternoon.
It's not my fault your husband
don't know how to use a phone.
- You realize I can fire you.
- Suzanne, I have told you
many times,
you need to learn
to be flexible.
Be spontaneous.
Throw caution to the wind.
- The last time
I was spontaneous,
I ended up with Kevin.
- What about Lindsey?
- That's when I threw caution
to the wind.
- Listen, I can go to the moon
on a moment's notice.
You send a rocket,
some gravity boots,
and some moon luggage,
I'm good to go.
All right, zee.
- Mm.
- I'm a let you in
on a little secret.
- What?
- People like me
count on people like you
to be boring
so we can have all the fun.
If more married people
took the ticket to the game,
to the concert,
the reservation
to the restaurant,
single people wouldn't have
half the places to go.
Half the things I do are because
married people turn 'em down.
Listen, when I told you
I was going out,
you didn't even ask me
where I was going,
because you didn't think you had
anything better to do
than to go home.
- Well, as far as I knew,
I didn't.
- The point is,
you missed out on an amazing
grand opening party,
and if you keep on trying
to plan every single thing,
Suzanne, you're gonna
miss out on life.
- You've got a point.
- Where are you going?
- Out.
You can handle this stuff,
right?
- Oh, no.
No, I can't.
This is gonna take hours,
and I was planning on
going out tonight.
- Well, that's what you get
for planning.
Bye.
- [Laughs]
You funny.
Bye.
- [Laughs]
- Hey.
- Hey, dad.
- Hey, Mr. Kingston-persons.
- Hey, Troy.
You guys still watching
a different world?
- I've been hooked on this show
for years.
I've seen every episode.
- This show is amazing.
It makes me want to go
to a black university.
- Me too.
- I think that's
what Dr. cosby intended.
- What's really cool
is that this show's hilarious,
but the story lines
address serious issues
like class and race relations.
- That's thanks to Debbie Allen.
- I just care about
the hilarious part.
- And I love whitley.
I think she should marry
Dwayne Wayne.
- Well...
- Hey, let it unfold.
- They should remake this show
with Nick Cannon.
Both: Yeah.
- So what's up with the outfits?
- Well, I'm Dwayne Wayne.
- I'm Ron Johnson.
- They tried to get me to dress
up as waiter oakes.
- Sinbad.
- I told her
she should be honored.
Sinbad is a national treasure.
You can have
your Martin Lawrence
and your Steve Harvey.
I'll take Sinbad any day.
- We looked at some of his clips
on YouTube.
He's hilarious.
- You know, I think I may have
one of Sindbad’s comedy shows
in here.
- Please tell me
it's brain damaged.
- Brain damaged.
Bam!
- Nice.
His bit on weaves is a classic.
"There's nothing wrong
with a weave,
but at least try
to fool someone."
Genius.
- Don't leave that
on pause too long.
It'll break the tape.
- [Laughs]
- Hey, baby.
- Nick, I...
- Before you speak,
I just want to say I'm sorry.
I was so busy
worrying about that party,
I let it get in the way
of our night.
I shouldn't have done that,
and I want you to know
that I'll go on a date night
with you any time.
- Good.
So let's go do something.
- Now?
- Yes, now.
Baby, I'm sorry.
You know, I was so caught up
in trying to be organized
that I let it stop you from
having a great night with me,
and lord knows we need
all the great nights we can get.
- Yeah, that's right.
So you really want to go out?
- Yes.
Let's go.
- So you don't have to
take a shower?
- No, come on.
- Change clothes?
- Nah, right now.
- And we can do whatever I want?
- Yes, let's bounce.
- Wait, wait,
what about the kids?
- Lindsey!
- What?
- Make a pizza.
Your father and I are going out.
Lights out by 9:30.
- Okay.
- Done.
- Baby.
I love it when you get
all spontaneous like that.
- Ooh.
- Surprise me, girl.
- Right now.
- Oh, surprise, surprise.
Wait, wait, where we going?
Nope, I don't want to know.
Look it, I'm so surprised,
I forgot my coat.
- What are you doing?
Let's go.
- No punching in anything?
- Let's go.
- No theme music?
No itinerary?
No typing in coordinates?
- What part
didn't you understand?
We are going
wherever you want to take us.
- All right.
- [Laughs]
Thank you.
- I'm sorry, baby.
- No, no, no.
Tonight,
we're not doing I'm sorry.
We are living in the moment.
Whatever happens, happens.
- I don't know how I thought
we could just walk in
to the newest, hottest
steakhouse in the city
without a reservation.
- But, really.
A two month wait?
It's steak.
How good can it be?
- Pretty good, I guess.
- Okay, okay,
I will call tomorrow
and get a reservation.
- I don't know why that bouncer
wouldn't let us in that club.
There was hardly
anybody in there.
- I know.
But I at least thought
we would be able
to get into the movie.
- The movies are getting worse
than the club.
Reserved seats, drinks, snacks,
reclining chairs.
If I wanted to feel like
I was at home
when I'm watching a movie,
I'd stay at home.
- All right, forget about
all that, all right?
I've got you.
We're together.
We're being spontaneous,
and that is all that counts.
- Good.
Let's get something to eat.
- Okay.
- Excuse me, excuse me.
We'd like to order.
- Oh, I'm sorry,
but the kitchen's closed.
- Oh, come on.
Now, why would you guys seat us
if you knew you weren't
gonna serve us?
- Well, we thought you were here
for the club.
- What club?
- This one.
After 10:00,
we turn into a club.
[Slow dance beat]
♪ ♪
I'm sorry, but unless you
want to order bottle service,
I'm going to need to move you.
- Move us where?
- To your feet.
- Wait, wait,
how much is bottle service?
- It starts at $400.
- For drinks and a chair?
- I know.
It's crazy, right?
- What do you want to do?
- Uh, I don't know.
What do you want to do?
- Well, whatever
you're going to do,
I'm going to need you
to do it on your feet,
because I need to
sell this table.
- No, don't...
We out of here.
- Suzanne,
what are you guys doing here?
- Leaving.
What are you do...
Okay, why are you
dressed like that?
- Well, I'm gonna dance
in a cage.
One of the dancers fell out.
The owner asked me
to do him a favor, so...
Bye.
- Lindsey.
What are you doing
up this early?
- I woke up a couple hours ago
to watch season five
of a different world.
Whitley's about to marry Byron.
- All right,
well, don't be late.
- I won't.
- Oh, hey, dad.
- Hey.
Wow.
Silky.
- It's Sinbad.
- I had that exact same outfit.
- Can you get me a copy
of jingle all the way?
- Jingle all the way.
Arnold Schwarzenegger
and Sinbad.
That was a good one.
I’ll see what I can do.
- Whatever happened to
Arnold Schwarzenegger anyway?
He should make more movies.
- Oh, my God.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Now Dwayne Wayne is
proposing to whitley instead.
Oh, my God,
this show is incredible.
- A different world?
- Yep.
I'm sorry, baby.
- Oh, there's no need
to apologize.
- Last night was a disaster.
- I wouldn't call it
a disaster.
- That's 'cause you're just
trying to be nice.
- No, I'm saying that because
as long as I'm with you,
I don't care what we do.
You win some, you lose some.
- Well, at least
we salvaged the night
when we got home, right?
- It was cool.
- Are you giving me
the high voice?
- Give me the tape!
- No!
- Kevin!
- You've been watching tv
all week.
- Kevin, stop.
I want to watch
a different world.
- You've seen every season.
I want to watch
Sindbad’s brain damaged.
- Give me the tape,
or I'm gonna damage your brain.
Come on!
- No!
- Hey, hey, what's going on?
Get over there.
What is going on?
[Both talking at once]
- Give her the tape!
- Hey!
Now, what is going on here?
[Both talking at once]
Okay, enough.
Never mind.
We'll watch what I want to watch.
How about that?
- Let's see.
- Go ahead, baby.
- What?
"Nick at the Apollo"?
Nick, did you audition
for showtime at the Apollo?
- I made the tape,
but I never sent it in.
- Oh, my God.
- Look, nobody wants to
watch this right...
What's that tape?
- No, no, come on,
we're being spontaneous.
- No, this... this one's better.
- Spontaneous.
Exciting.
[Upbeat dance music]
[All screaming]
[Laughter]
Sync & correct by dr.jackson
www.addic7ed.com