-[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
LELE SAVERI: They are asking
for resistance.
They're basically asking
everybody else
to resist the police.
[CHANTING IN PROTEST]
-[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
LELE SAVERI: Yeah, I think
that they're forcing it.
They're fighting right now.
-[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
LELE SAVERI: If I had water.
-If you had water?
LELE SAVERI: I did, fuck.
They were like, OK.
The fighting started.
Then the police attacked.
And then they start
throwing tear gas.
-[INAUDIBLE]
LELE SAVERI: Tear gas.
And then I just saw, like,
police beating some kids up.
I don't know.
-[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
LELE SAVERI: They
were throwing,
like, bombs and stuff.
But the police was attacking
a bit too much.
There were two tanks.
So I don't know what you
saw from there, but
it was quite stupid.
And I was running behind
the police, and I
could just see them.
There was one policeman beating
a kid on the floor.
And this other policeman
had to stop him, and to
just take off him.
And it was kind of laughing,
they knew, because they were,
like, all the press
was behind.
And that's when the whole--
[LOUDSPEAKER ANNOUNCEMENT
IN ITALIAN]
LELE SAVERI: Tear guns--
I think they're like,
they're asking
people to stop fighting.
-[SPEAKING ITALIAN]