(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
BARACK OBAMA, PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES
OF AMERICA: Today I want to make it absolutely
clear to Assad and those under his command,
the world is watching. The use of chemical
weapons is and would be totally unacceptable.
And if you make the tragic mistake of using
these weapons, there will be consequences.
And you will be held accountable.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: That was President Obama on Monday talking
about Syrian president Bashar al-Assad. There
are concerns that al-Assad`s government forces
might use chemical weapons, like poison gas
in its fight against rebels in Syria`s ongoing
civil war. Syrian officials say the government
doesn`t have any plans to use those kinds
of weapons. The fighting in Syria, though,
is not letting up. You can see some of the
damage here in the Syrian city of Aleppo.
Reports say more than 42,000 Syrians have
been killed since the civil war started 21
months ago.
This picture was taken from the international
space station. The giant white spiral, that`s
a typhoon, it`s the same kind of storm as
a hurricane. This one is called Bopha, and
it`s huge. At one point on Monday it was a
super typhoon, the same size and speed as
a category five hurricane. Yesterday, it hit
the Philippines. This is some of what it left
behind: massive flooding, landslides, homes
destroyed, more than two dozen people were
killed and more than 50,000 have been affected
by the typhoon. A lot of the communities in
Bopha`s path weren`t prepared for it before
the typhoon hit. Government agencies tried
to get people out of the way and to get relief
supplies and emergency crews in place to help
out afterward.
Less than four weeks to go, and still, no
deal in D.C. Yes, we are talking about the
fiscal cliff, the series of automatic government
spending cuts and tax increases that will
take place on January First, if President
Obama and Congress can`t agree on ways to
cut the nation`s debt.
We don`t have a deal, we do have a proposal.
Two of them, in fact. President Obama offered
his plan last week, Republican leaders rejected
it. Republicans offered a counter plan this
week. The president rejected it. There are
some ideas that both sides agree on, but the
two big sticking points are government spending
and tax rates for Americans who make more
than $250,000 a year. So, right now we have
proposals, but no agreement.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today`s "Shoutout" goes
out to coach Christinsen`s social studies
classes at Maize South High School in Wichita,
Kansas.
"Which of these was launched into space first?
Here we go. Was it the Curiosity Rover, International
Space Station, Voyager I spacecraft of space
shuttle Discovery. You`ve got three seconds,
go!
Voyager One was first taking off on September
Fifth, 1977. That`s your answer and that`s
your "Shoutout."
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: A 35-year road trip, and it`s not going
to be over any time soon. Voyager I is getting
ready to leave the Solar System? Or maybe,
let`s go back to start. When it launched in
1977 few people could have imagined that Voyager
might tell us more about our Solar System
than any other spacecraft. The main mission
was to explore Jupiter and Saturn. It did
that. And NASA decided to just let the thing
keep on going. Past the other planets, heading
toward interstellar space. That means out
of our Solar System. NASA officials thought
it was almost at the border, but than on Monday
when it was about 11 billion miles from the
Sun, Voyager sent back some surprising news.
Sorry, all, it turns out the Solar System
is bigger than we thought. Voyager has traveled
farther in the space than any other man-made
object, but it`s going to have to keep on
going to bust out of the Solar System. NASA`s
new prediction is that it could happen in
the few months or a couple of years.
Imagine the life of a presidential nominee:
for months of campaigning, TV cameras follow
your every move. There are these giant cheering
crowds everywhere you go. And then you get
to election night, and if you end up on the
short hand of the electoral college count,
everything stops. What is it like to lose
the presidential election and what do you
do after that? Lisa Sylvester takes a look.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
LISA SYLVESTER, CBS CORRESPONDENT: They are
a hair away from the highest office of the
land.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: The next president of the
United States of America Mitt Romney!
SYLVESTER: Then suddenly, it`s over. Mitt
Romney joins the list of the almost but not
quite, along with Senator John McCain, Senator
John Kerry, former Vice President Al Gore,
former Governor Michael Dukakis, and former
Senator Bob Dole.
DOUGLAS BRINKLEY, PRESIDENTIAL HISTORIAN:
In Great Britain, if somebody like Mitt Romney,
you know, after they lost, they would be able
to go in the House of Lords, kind of a wise
men council. We don`t have it in the United
States. When you lose, you lose.
SEN. JOHN MCCAIN (R ), ARIZONA: That alone.
SYLVESTER: Reinvention can take different
forms. Senators McCain and Kerry have their
day jobs to return to on Capitol Hill. In
fact, Kerry`s name is now being floated for
secretary of state replacing Hillary Clinton.
Vice President Al Gore made global warming
his calling, winning the 2007 Nobel Peace
Prize, Gore also promoted sustainable investing
and co- founded current TV. Bob Dole has been
a special council at a top law firm.
Moving from the political life back to civilian
life can be tricky. Take Mitt Romney, he had
round the clock secret service protection,
a legion of followers.
(applause)
SYLVESTER: Crowds of thousands chanting his
name. And then, nothing.
Former congressman Mark Kennedy who now heads
up George Washington University`s Graduate
School of Political Management offers this
sage advice:
MARK KENNEDY, FORMER U.S. CONGRESSMAN: I think
what makes a difference is having a focus:
you mentioned Al Gore. He focused on environmental
issues. If you look at John Kerry who`s focuses
on foreign policy issues. If you pick some
piece of your message that did resonate with
the American people and after a pause come
back and start emphasizing that in important
ways, that I think is the path to really helping
to make a difference after you run.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: See if you can I.D. me.
I`m a geographic landmark that`s also a popular
tourist attraction. I`m home to thousands
of different species. I`m located off the
coast of Australia and I`m the world`s largest
coral reef system.
I`m the Great Barrier Reef. And I cover around
a 135,000 square miles.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: One group is trying to map out every
inch of the Great Barrier Reef, and they are
posting the pictures online. Sure, it`s a
way for people who can`t visit in person to
see the world`s largest coral reef, but the
point of this project isn`t just for people
to see the reef, is to help keep it from disappearing.
Philippe Cousteau dives into the details.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
PHILIPPE COUSTEAU: We are in the water with
the researchers of the Catlin Seaview Survey.
Their mission map the world`s coral reefs
creating a comprehensive study for scientists
while giving the rest of us a chance to see
their work in real time.
360 degree panoramic images that will soon
be used by researchers monitoring the effects
of climate change are already available on
Google maps. And a social media campaign connects
the team with more than 2 million followers
online.
Coral reefs are source of food and income
for over 500 million people in more than 50
countries. But for most of us, they remain
out of sight and out of mind. And the neglect
is taking its toll. Overfishing, pollution,
warming ocean temperatures have all contributed
to what scientists are discovering is the
reefs` rapid decline.
OVE HOEGH-GULDBERG, CHIEF SCIENTIST: We had
a paper published on it at the (inaudible)
Sciences that shows that half of the coral
in the Great Barrier Reef has disappeared
over the last 27 years. That`s a momentous
change. And if continue on that pathway, the
Great Barrier Reef will largely not have coral
on it.
COUSTEAU: The Catlin team says waiting to
share results simply is not an option. The
future health of the reefs needs to be understood
now and not just by researchers.
RICHARD VEVERS, PROJECT DIRECTOR: There is
amazing scientific work being done, but it`s
being read by up to sort of 100 people around
the world. And we wanted to bridge this gap,
well, we need to bridge this gap between scientific
awareness and public understanding.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: Before we go, dogs like to splash around
in water. But this guy might want to rethink
his choice of play pals. That is a killer
whale. The close encounter in this Youtube
video happened in New Zealand. Luckily, the
dog did get to safety in time, although turning
around and barking back at the whale might
not have been the best decision. We`d say
the whale should pick on someone its own size,
but that doesn`t leave many options. Maybe
the thing he was just lonely and just wanted
some company. When the dog swam away, the
massive mammal was just this blubbering mess.
It brings us to the finish line for today,
but we whale be back tomorrow with more CNN
STUDENT NEWS. See you then.