CARL AZUZ, CNN ANCHOR: Welcome to CNN STUDENT
NEWS. Products being pulled off shelves. Authorities
running investigations, some shoppers protesting.
All of it has to do with meat. Some packages
that were labeled as 100 percent beef were
discovered to contain horse meat. Ireland,
the U.K, France, Germany, Sweden Switzerland,
Romania. This scandal is affecting more than
a dozen European countries. The latest news
is that Nestle, a mega food company, is pulling
some of its products in Italy, Spain and France.
It`s also stopping deliveries of some products
from a German supplier, because traces of
horse DNA were found in the meat. But let`s
get the big question out of the way: will
eating horse meat make you sick? British health
officials say, no. The meat itself not a risk,
but one concern is about a drug called "bute".
It`s used on horses and it can cause some
rare, but serious health problems for humans.
There is also a religious issue here. Some
religions have dietary laws that restrict
eating horse meat. Since these packages were
labeled incorrectly, people might have eaten
eat without knowing. In some countries like
France, China and Russia eating horse meat
is common. In others, like the United Kingdom,
the idea is unthinkable. Would this kind of
thing change your eating habits? On Twitter,
Chris told me: "Yes, there are not good circumstances
I can think of where I`d willingly eat horse."
Matt disagreed: "Honestly, I wouldn`t change
my eating habits just for one small chance
that I`ll eat horse meat."
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: See if you can I.D. me.
I`m a U.S. state that borders Canada. I have
one of America`s smallest populations. My
southern neighbor shares part of my name.
And my capital city is Bismarck. I`m North
Dakota. And my name comes from a Native American
world for "friend."
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: You might expect North Dakota to get
hammered with snow all winter, but on average,
the state gets less snow than the states to
the east or west of it. Then, there is this:
a winter storm slammed part of the state last
weekend. The I-reporter who sent this video
in, said there were four to eight inches of
snow and winds blowing through it around 50
miles per hour. The snow and fog made it hard
for driver to see, so officials put out a
travel alert. They also warned drivers to
watch out for snow plows that were working
to clear the roads.
Weather is flying, and flying is weather.
A pilot named Bob Buck (ph) wrote that, showing
that the two thing are always linked. That`s
why storms like the North Dakota blizzard
or the recent nor`easter on the East coast
always affect air travel. Flying may still
be the safest way to travel, but there is
a lot that goes into making it that way. Ayesha
Durgahee shows us what.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Ladies and gentlemen, (inaudible)
from the Atlantic. This is your captain.
AYESHA DURGAHEE, CNN CORRESPONDENT: And in-flight
forecast from the front of the plane.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: (inaudible).
DURGAHEE: Once the seat belt sign is on, we
can get back to enjoying a meal or a movie,
because the planes we fly in are designed
to battle the elements that can suddenly cross
their paths.
PROFESSOR MANU HADDAD, LIGHTNING LAB, CARDIFF
UNIVERSITY: There is one lightning strike
every second around the world. Every single
aircraft is hit by lightning once a year.
DURGAHEE: Here, at Cardiff University in Wales,
lightning strikes every day, where capacities
discharge a current of 100,000 amps in a microsecond
recreating the power of a lightning bolt at
altitude. The aluminum body of an aircraft
is highly conductive, and acts as a Faraday
cage. A metallic shield that directs the electric
charge outside towards the back of the plane.
And the passengers on board won`t feel a thing.
This $2 million lightning lab in partnership
with EADS and the Welsh government, tests
different conductor strips on the nose of
a plane and new composite materials found
on modern aircraft.
Another built-in defense mechanism is using
the heat from the engines to melt ice around
them and along the edge of the wings.
And here at Cranfield University, they have
an ice tunnel. Minus ten degrees Celsius with
a wind speed of 100 miles per hour. They can
see how ice builds up and understand its aerodynamic
qualities.
DR. DAVID HAMMOND, CRANFIELD UNIVERSITY: What
we`d find is that generally the ice that forms
in this area here, it can be quite thin, but
the ice, which forms a little bit further
back can be a lot thicker, which actually
reverses the curvature of the leading edge.
DURGAHEE (on camera): It changes the shape
of the wing, essentially.
HAMMOND: Quite dramatically, in some cases,
yes. Unless you do something to prevent it.
So, in an aircraft, typically we`ll work out
which parts of the aircraft are most critical
aerodynamically, and then make sure that they
are protected.
DURGAHEE (voice over): When it comes to aircraft
design and weather, at research level, there
are men and women dedicating their lives to
specific weather conditions, to ensure planes
are built to buffer and bear the harshest
of conditions. And then it`s up to the pilots
to do the rest.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: It`s time for "The Shoutout."
Polyethylene is used to make some plastics,
but what chemical elements make up polyethylene?
If you think you know it, then shout it out!
Is it hydrogen and silicon, carbon and hydrogen,
nitrogen and carbon or lithium and aluminum?
You`ve got three seconds, go!
Polyethylene is a chain of carbon and hydrogen
atoms that can take a long time to break down.
That`s your answer and that`s your "Shoutout."
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: How long are we talking about? The honest
answer is "we don`t know for sure." Plastics
just haven`t been around long enough. But
scientists estimate it could take anywhere
from 500 to a 1000 years for some of these
things to break down. That`s part of the reason
why Sacramento, California`s capital is thinking
about banning plastic bags. The city council
says they pile up in landfills or show up
as litter on roads and in trees or rivers.
The ban would be on plastic bags in large
grocery and retail stores. Instead, people
could bring their own bags or pay around ten
cents for a paper bag from the store. Some
of the stores were on board with the idea,
but at least one shopper said he doesn`t want
the plastic bags to disappear since he reuses
them for other things.
When the stock market closed yesterday, the
Dow Jones Industrial Average was higher than
it`s been in five years. You might know that
the Dow is one way to measure how the whole
economy is doing, but do you know how the
Dow Jones Average works? What about calculating
the interest rate on the student loan for
college? When I was back in school, I didn`t
know. There`s a program, though, that tries
to teach students that kind of financial literacy
to help the students future and possibly the
country`s.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Another key thing about
investment is there`s going to be risk -- some
amount of risk involved.
SUZANNE MALVEAUX, CNN CORRESPONDENT: Auston
Kennedy is a high school senior, and although
he can`t buy a house or a car just yet, he
wants to be financially responsible at an
early age.
AUSTON KENNEDY, SENIOR, WEST LAKE HIGH SCHOOL:
It`s important for teenagers to learn to be
financially literate so that before they are
in a position to manage their own finance,
to make their decisions, they already have
a good base as far as what`s appropriate,
what`s the best way to manage their funds.
MALVEAUX: Kennedy got his advice from a program
that brings real life banking practices into
the classroom. John Bryant heads up Banking
on Our Future, also called BOOF.
JOHN HOPE BRYANT, CEO AND FOUNDER, OPERATION
HOPE: You`re going to grow up and do well,
and do good. You don`t want to just do well
for yourself, you want to do well, and then
get back to your community as well.
MALVEAUX: Bryant`s non-profit has been around
for 20 years. He says his mission is to empower
communities to reach people at a young age
so they could control their own financial
destiny.
BRYANT: Connect education with aspiration,
these kids are dropping out of high school,
because they don`t think education is relevant
to their future. It`s real simple. Give them
something to believe in. There`s nothing more
valuable than investing in their education,
investing in their self-esteem, especially
investing in their spiritual growth and then
investing in their dream.
MALVEAUX: Hip hop mogul and entrepreneur Russell
Simmons is a big supporter of the program.
RUSSELL SIMMONS, CHAIRMAN AND CEO RUSH COMMUNICATIONS:
People need to be educated, compete in any
sector of the society. We spend so much money
on a war machine, and so little money on our
children`s education. And our kids -- they
don`t have lobbyists, so, you know, we have
to lobby for them.
MALVEAUX: As Auston prepares for college,
Bryant sees his investment paying off.
KENNEDY: I`ve been asking a lot more of the
financial aid representatives about the best
ways to manage funds in college. I probably
wouldn`t have had inclination to ask those
questions, had I not been involved with the
Banking on Our Future program.
MALVEAUX: Suzanne Malveaux, CNN, Atlanta.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: So, how good are you at managing your
money? I mean whether or not you`re considering
yourself financially literate, do you tend
to save more or spend more? Our blog is open
for business at cnnstudentnews.com.
Sometimes one golfer will play nine holes.
In this Youtube video, those numbers are flipped.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
(CHEERS AND LAUGHTER)
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Unbelievable. College seniors lined
up the trick shot as part of the monthly class
competition -- yes, they won. It wasn`t a
hole in one, though, it took them 28 tries
to nail the shot. But they didn`t want to
cheat or cut any corners. When you are golfing,
you aim for the fair way. I mean that`s just
part for the course. If other competitors
were green with envy, they can try to top
this shot, they`ll have to putt up or shot
up. That`s the whole story for today. Teachers,
we want your thoughts on today`s show. Use
the feedback link on our home page. We`ll
see you all again tomorrow.