(END VIDEO CLIP)
CARL AZUZ, CNN ANCHOR: Nice. We appreciate
the intro and the pun from Mrs. Lauther`s
(ph) class. I am Carl Azuz, presenting your
commercial free news on this Monday, January
7th.
First up today, some help is on the way for
victims of what came to be known as super
storm Sandy. The critics say that help is
not enough. On Friday, one day after getting
to work, the 113th U.S. Congress passed a
bill worth $9 billion. The money from the
federal government will be put in an insurance
program that will help cover costs for this,
this incredible damage we keep seeing from
the October storm that was 1,000 miles wide.
The money won`t do much to help businesses,
though. More than 200,000 had some kind of
damage, or were otherwise impacted by Sandy.
And that`s why some of them and many lawmakers
are calling for more government aid. Congress
is scheduled to take up another bill worth
$51 billion in business relief, but not until
January 15.
Another issue Congress is looking at - guns.
The goal is to find a way to prevent more
tragic shootings in the U.S. But there are
a lot of ideas about how to do that, so many
that in the U.S. House of Representatives
alone, almost 12 bills were introduced last
week that had something to do with gun violence.
So is the answer more restrictions on guns
or the people who can buy them, or more guns
in more places? Congress, surprise, surprise,
will have to find some middle ground on this
to get something through both Houses and signed
by the president.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
ATHENA JONES, CNN CORRESPONDENT: As students
in Sandy Hook elementary returned to class,
former Congresswoman Gabrielle Giffords, nearly
killed in a mass shooting two years ago, visited
Newtown, Connecticut. And on Capitol Hill,
lawmakers arrived to begin a new session of
Congress, with members in both chambers taking
aim at guns.
SEN. DIANNE FEINSTEIN, D-CALIFORNIA: This
is a fight that the American people are going
to have to stand up and stiffen their spine.
JONES: California Democratic Senator Dianne
Feinstein plans to introduce a bill to ban
more 100 assault weapons, 8 years after the
old ban she championed expired.
Another Senate bill would ban high-capacity
magazines, and among nearly a dozen gun bills
introduced on day one in the House are efforts
to ban online sales of ammunition, and to
require background checks for all firearm
sales, including at gun shows. Two bills from
freshmen Republican congressmen would allow
more guns around schools, echoing the position
of the National Rifle Association.
WAYNE LAPIERRE, CEO, NRA: The only thing that
stops a bad guy with a gun is a good guy with
a gun.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: We are better than 32
more gun murders every day.
JONES: Pro gun control groups plan to keep
pressing for action, but what are the prospects
for their success?
JOHN GRAMLICH, CQ ROLL CALL: If you`re talking
about stuff around the edges, like maybe banning
high-capacity ammunition magazines, that might
be possible. The NRA is the big issue, but
I wouldn`t say it`s necessarily on the Republican
side only, it`s on the Democratic side also.
You have fully half of your new Senate has
an either A+, A, or an A- rating from the
NRA. So if you want anything to happen on
gun control, you`re going to have to have
at least half the Senate upsetting the NRA,
and so that`s a very difficult proposition.
FEINSTEIN: There is no more uphill fight than
this. The question is do we fight or do we
knuckle under?
JONES: President Obama says he wants action
on gun legislation this year. He`s asked Vice
President Biden to lead a task force to come
up with recommendations on gun policy. They
are expected this month.
Athena Jones, CNN, Washington.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: See if you can ID me.
I`m a U.S. Government agency. I`m part of
the Department of Health and Human Services.
I`m responsible for protecting the health
of people and animals, and I oversee everything
from medicines to food to cosmetics.
I`m the U.S. Food and Drug Administration.
AZUZ: Chances are you`ve gotten food poisoning
at some point. The Centers for Disease Control
and Prevention estimates that each year, one
of every six Americans gets sick from something
they eat. Part of the Food and Drug Administration`s
job is to try to cut down on that as much
as possible, so it proposed two new rules
Friday that it says could prevent more than
a million foodborne illnesses each year. One
would be new safety standards for farmers
and the fruits and vegetable they grow. For
example, they`d have to make sure their water
is clean and that animals are kept out of
their fields.
The other rule would require companies to
have a plan in place to make sure their foods
don`t make people sick, and for dealing with
outbreaks if they do happen. There is a downside
here, costs for farmers and businesses could
go up, and that could mean higher food prices.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today`s Shoutout goes
to Mr. Lund`s classes at Wallace Junior Senior
High School in Wallace, Idaho.
Which of these countries has the lowest literacy
rate among women? If you think you know it,
then shout it out. Is it Pakistan, Kenya,
Jamaica or Saudi Arabia? You`ve got 3 seconds,
go.
In Pakistan, an estimated 40 percent of women
know how to read and write, by far the lowest
percentage of those countries. That`s your
answer and that`s your shoutout.
AZUZ: Malala Yousafzai is a 15-year-old who
wants to change that. You heard us talk about
her last year when she was attacked for promoting
girls education rights in Pakistan. On Friday,
Malala went home, a temporary home in the
United Kingdom, where she`s been in the hospital.
She has her family there with her, and doctors
say she`s doing better, though after wounds
to her head and neck, she has a long road
ahead, and more surgery scheduled within the
next month. Malala`s work and survival have
already gotten international attention centered
on women`s education rights in Pakistan. The
country`s government says it will protect
her if she decides to go back.
Until a few years ago, you wouldn`t have found
a woman serving aboard a U.S. Navy submarine.
It just wasn`t allowed. The rule changed in
2009 and some of the first women who were
chosen to do it said it wasn`t tougher because
they were women; it was tougher because of
the training. We`re going to dive a little
deeper on what it`s like to serve the country
underwater.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
CHRIS LAWRENCE, CNN CORRESPONDENT: It`s a
new frontier for female sailors. Submerged
for months, no sun, no space, no sleep.
LT. JG MARQUETTE LEVEQUE, U.S. NAVY: (inaudible)
dive.
LAWRENCE: Lieutenant Junior Grade Marquette
Leveque is one of the first women to qualify
for submarine duty.
(on camera): Was it everything you expected?
LEVEQUE: I got a lot less sleep than I imagined
I would.
LAWRENCE (voice over): We met Leveque a few
years ago when she went by her maiden name,
Reid.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Marquette Jay Reid (ph)
LAWRENCE: She was a cadet at the naval academy
when the Pentagon opened sub duty to women.
LEVEQUE: At the time, I was flying. I was
a pilot. Selected to be a pilot after graduation.
LAWRENCE: Leveque decided her future was under
the water, not soaring above it. And she wasn`t
afraid of breaking a barrier.
LEVEQUE: I see us being just like our male
counterparts, and I think that we`ll be accepted
the same way.
LAWRENCE: Leveque earned her dolphin.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Congratulations, great
job.
LAWRENCE: A gold chest device that means she`s
mastered submarine operations.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Sign the book.
LEVEQUE: Yes, sir.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: It`s been a long time coming,
right?
LEVEQUE: Yes.
LAWRENCE: It took a year of nuclear training,
three more months at submarine officer school.
LEVEQUE: Dive (inaudible) two five zero feet.
LAWRENCE: And then her first sea tour.
LEVEQUE: It`s a huge honor to finally really
feel like I`m a part of the submarine community.
LAWRENCE: In fact, Leveque is one of only
three women to qualify as unrestricted line
officers. That`s big, because it means down
the road she would be eligible to one day
assume command of a nuclear powered sub. And
it`s pretty clear that whenever war is waged
under water, women are going to be a part
of that fight.
Chris Lawrence, CNN, the Pentagon.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: You folks in band might like this. Before
we go, if your washing machine is rocking,
it`s usually a sign that the clothes in it
are unbalanced. This one just rocks.
(MUSIC)
AZUZ: What do you say about this? He`s 10
years old, has a great sense of rhythm, and
totally rocked YouTube by making his washing
machine his drum kit. No hum-drum performance
there. I played drums in middle and high school.
He would have totally taken me to the cleaners.
It`s not that I washed out, it would just
be hard to keep up rhythm. CNN STUDENT NEWS
will tap back into the news cycle tomorrow.
Hope to see you then.