CARL AZUZ, CNN ANCHOR: It`s Thursday, February
28th. And it`s Pope Benedict XVI last day
as pope. He announced his resignation earlier
this month, and his time as pope officially
ends this evening.
The pope is the head of the Roman Catholic
Church. Christianity is the world`s largest
religion, and Catholics are the largest groups
of Christians. There are around 1.2 billion
Catholics around the world. Yesterday, Pope
Benedict made his final public speech in St.
Peter`s Square. That`s part of Vatican City,
the headquarters of the Catholic Church, and
the world`s smallest country.
In yesterday`s speech, the pope talked about
his spiritual journey during his nearly eight
years as head of the church. There have been
controversies and scandals surrounding the
Catholic Church, like accusations of some
priests abusing children and claims of corruption.
Some analysts think the pope was referring
to these issues during his speech.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
CHRISTIANE AMANPOUR, CNN CORRESPONDENT: He
spoke about how he had so much joy, he said,
in the church, in his eight years of reign,
but he also talked about how - that it`d been
difficult times, he said, it had been far
from easy on occasion. He talked about how
the church had come across "agitated waters",
and then sometimes found itself facing the
different directions of the wind.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Pope Benedict is the first pope in nearly
600 years to resign. What comes next? He`ll
still be called Benedict, the name he chose
when he became pope, and he`ll still be referred
to as "His Holiness." But his official title
will be Pope Emeritus. He`ll live in Vatican
City in a small monastery. And Benedict is
expected to devote his time to prayer and
study. As for the Roman Catholic Church, it
has to elect a new pope and here`s how that
process happens.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
JOHN ALLEN, CNN SENIOR VATICAN ANALYST: The
pope is the spiritual leader of 1.2 billion
Catholics around the world, and the most visible
religious leader of any kind on the planet.
The new pope is always chosen by the members
of the college of cardinals. They are the
highest office in the church under the pope
himself. Normally, when a papacy ends either
through death or resignation, cardinals from
around the world gather in Rome, they have
daily meetings to talk about the issues facing
the church and the qualities the new pope
needs. We are talking about slightly over
100 cardinals who file into the Sistine Chapel
cast ballots and pick a pope.
Conclave is a term that comes from two Latin
words, meaning with a key. It refers to the
fact that the cardinals are locked behind
closed doors while they go through a highly
ceremonial process of casting ballots and
then burning them. Then it goes as long as
it takes for somebody to get two thirds - the
shortest conclave in history took a couple
of hours. The longest one took three years.
In the old days, they would burn ballots largely
because they wanted to maintain the secrecy
of the conclave, that is they didn`t want
the vote totals to get out. What they realized,
is that when people saw the smoke from the
chimney atop the Sistine Chapel, they knew
a round of balloting had ended, and so they
came up with the system where they would put
chemicals into the mix to turn the smoke black
if no pope had been elected, and white, if
a pope had been elected.
In theory, according to the law of the church,
any person who was eligible for ordination
to the priesthood and therefore, an unmarried
male, could be elected as pope. But in practice,
the new pope will be elected from among the
cardinals who are voting. That is the cardinals
who are under the age of 80, who will take
part in this election. Which means that the
roughly 150 cardinals aren`t merely voters,
they are all also candidates.
When a candidate crosses that two thirds threshold,
another cardinal will approach him and say,
do you accept your canonically valid election
as Supreme Pontiff? If he answers yes, from
that moment forward, he becomes the pope.
The next questions is, by what name will you
be known? And at that stage, the new pope
tells his brother cardinals what he wants
to be called. And in a few minutes later,
when the announcement is made from a balcony
outside St. Peter`s Square, the whole world
will know the name of the new pope.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: The deadline is tomorrow for President
Obama and Congress to come up with the deal
to lower the country`s debt. Otherwise, some
forced spending cuts are automatically going
to kick in. We are talking about $85 billion
immediately, $1.2 trillion total over the
next ten years. Tomorrow, we are going to
look at where some of those cuts could happen.
Today, we are looking at how we got here.
Every year the president is required to come
up with a budget proposal. He submits that
to Congress. Then Congress comes up with the
final budget. Right now, the U.S. government
spends more than it makes. A lot more. That`s
why we have a massive debt. Back in 2011,
during a standoff over the debt, the president
and Congress came up with the plan. They set
up the possibility of automatic spending cuts,
but only if lawmakers couldn`t agree on other
ways to reduce the debt. The idea was that
the automatic cuts would be so drastic, that
there was no way anyone was going to let them
happen. Throughout 2012, political leaders
never agreed on an alternative. The cuts were
supposed to happen on January 1st of this
year. They got pushed back two months, and
that leaves us where we are now.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today`s "Shoutout" goes
out to Mrs. Mackin`s classes at Westminster
High School in Westminster, California.
Who was known as the mother of the U.S. civil
rights movement? Is it Harriet Tubman, Coretta
Scott King, Rosa Parks or Susan B. Anthony?
You`ve got three seconds, go!
Rosa Parks is referred to as the mother of
the civil rights movement. Partly because
of her actions on December 1st 1955. That`s
your answer and that`s your "Shoutout."
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: On that day, Rosa Parks was arrested
for refusing to give up her bus seat to a
white passenger. The ensuing bus boycott is
considered the official start of the civil
rights movement. Parks passed away in 2005.
She`s gotten numerous honors and tributes
for her work for equal rights. The U.S. Postal
Service released a stamp this year, honoring
Parks. And yesterday, President Obama and
congressional leaders unveiled a bronze statue
of Rosa Parks at the U.S. Capitol. She`s the
first African- American woman to be honored
in this way.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
BARACK OBAMA, PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES
OF AMERICA: We celebrate a seamstress slight
in stature, but mighty in courage.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: As we wrap up Black History Month, you
can go to our home page and check out a gallery,
a past and present African-American pioneers.
Next story today comes from Emily Longnecker,
a reporter with affiliate WTHR. It reminds
me of this great quote from Thomas Edison:
opportunity is missed by most people, because
it`s dressed in overalls and looks like work.
For a young man in Indiana, finding work was
all that mattered. While he was on the way
to interview for one job, he landed another
almost by accident.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
JHAQUIEL REAGAN, HIRED AT RESTAURANT: I`m
out there, you know, every day, trying to
make a dollar.
EMILY LONGNECKER: Friday morning, though,
18-year old Jhaqiel Reagan was unemployed
and broke.
REAGAN: I`m staying anywhere I can.
LONGNECKER: But a walk through this restaurant`s
parking lot turned out to be the proverbial
fork in what`s been a long road for this young
man.
ART BOUVIER, OWNER, PAPA ROUX: He just says
excuse me, can you tell me how far it is to
the hotel (ph) Sherman.
LONGNECKER: The owner of Papa Roux, Art Bouvier,
was out clearing ice and snow from the parking
lot.
BOUVIER: I said, buddy, that`s about six or
seven miles to Sherman, and I fully expected
the next question was, can you give some money
for the bus? And it wasn`t. He just kept walking.
LONGNECKER: 20 minutes later, Art was driving
down 10th street, Jhaqiel and offered him
a ride.
REAGAN: I was really appreciative.
LONGNECKER: What Art heard next, though, convinced
him. This meeting was no accident.
BOUVIER: It was destiny. He said, I have an
interview at a thrift store. I said - interview
at a thrift store. You`re walking ten miles
in the ice and snow to an interview at a thrift
store.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Shrimp!
BOUVIER: And I just got the thinking, that`s
- that`s a good work ethic.
LONGNECKER: So, Art took Jhaqiel`s number
just in case. Just in case came hours later.
BOUVIER: I want to show you the ropes tonight,
if you want, we`re a little busy in there.
REAGAN: OK, that`s fun. That`s real (ph).
LONGNECKER: Art was so impressed by Jhaqiel,
he posted the story of their chance meeting
on Facebook. Now, he has regular customers
offering to buy Jhaqiel a bus pass so he can
get here, to his new job.
REAGAN: I don`t know. I get my work ethics
from my dad. You know, he`s worked his fingers
to the bone all his life.
LONGNECKER: Like father, like son. Jhaqiel
is willing to do the same. And now has the
chance to do it.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Know anyone like Jhaqiel? Tell us about
him or her in our blog. Well, today`s post
is all about work ethic. You`ll find it at
cnnstudentnews.com. The same site where we
are hoping teachers will also chime in with
their opinions about today`s show.
Well, sometimes our "Before We Go " segment
requires a little setup. But sometimes, all
you have to say is monkeys riding dogs.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Here! Here!
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Awesome.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: The racers down the hallway
are back at a local news station, the one
in pink didn`t quite make it all the way down,
but it gave her a head start to the finish.
Who knew a simian could be such a cheater?
The point of all this, was to promote a professional
bull riding event that features these guys.
I guess the monkeys just wanted to horn in
on the event and to steer all the attention
back to themselves. Or maybe they were just
monkeying around. Other way, I`m sure, people
went bananas over that performance. Sad, isn`t
it? It`s time for us to split. We`ll see you
tomorrow.