CHRIS HASLAM: We're not sure if
this place has asbestos in
it or whatever.
But if it does, then I think me
and Daewon and [INAUDIBLE]
are probably going to die in
the next couple years.
PATRICK O'DELL: So you're
going to try to film one
continuous line through
this place?
CHRIS HASLAM: Yeah.
But I'm starting up here.
Like [INAUDIBLE] right here,
which, like I said, is
ridiculously steep now.
I didn't think it was going to
be this steep but whatever.
We're coming up this wall right
there, which is another
thing that's retardedly steep.
And we're going to come through
here, this little hole
in the wall, that we probably
won't fit through.
PATRICK O'DELL: How would you
get through there , and then
what happens?
CHRIS HASLAM: We get [INAUDIBLE]
on this thing
right here.
And then I'm coming
through here.
Got to duck under this thing.
PATRICK O'DELL: How
tall are you?
CHRIS HASLAM: Tall enough,
like 6'1".
And then you duck under
this thing.
This is going to be
like the hardest.
This is where I'm going
to probably smoke
my head a few times.
I'm going over this thing.
Under this thing.
PATRICK O'DELL: [LAUGHING]
I can't even walk it.
CHRIS HASLAM: [INAUDIBLE]
yeah, go under it.
And then, front side come
around this corner
[INAUDIBLE].
Over this little wave thing.
Over the wall ride.
And the try to make it from
the wall ride back over up
that bank and that's
a full shot.
[SKATEBOARDING SOUNDS]
PATRICK O'DELL: Welcome back
to the Epicly Later'd show.
This week we have Chris
Haslam on the show.
You know when you see his name
come up and you see him about
to trick, you know it's going to
be just something new that
you've never seen before.
But he can do anything on a
mini ramp or on street.
Everything's just taken to
a whole other level.
Over and over his tricks
kind of blow your mind.
So anyway, this is just a little
bit of an intro into
the mind of Chris Haslam.
CHRIS HASLAM: Amazing
crib, man.
PATRICK O'DELL: This
is your place?
CHRIS HASLAM: This is
my friend Brandon's.
This is where he sleeps.
There's some sort of stain
on the bed there.
This my set-up.
I usually go here.
[INAUDIBLE]
It doesn't even get over
my whole body.
PATRICK O'DELL: Who's
this guy?
CHRIS HASLAM: This is Danny
Gonzales's dog, Ginger.
She's one of the most stunning
poms you'll ever see.
Danny.
PATRICK O'DELL: Which skate
videos do you have. ?
Lookit, he even has a-- damn--
401, 402.
Obviously, this one is the
finest one he has.
PATRICK O'DELL: Oh, you're
in there right?
CHRIS HASLAM: I'm
in there, yeah.
PATRICK O'DELL: Whoa,
that 's you?
CHRIS HASLAM: Yeah.
Look at this, shorts even.
PATRICK O'DELL: How
long ago is this?
CHRIS HASLAM: Gee,
I have no idea.
What is this 2000
and something?
PATRICK O'DELL: So you
just haven't cut
your hair since then?
CHRIS HASLAM: 2002, yeah.
PATRICK O'DELL: What made you
want to grow your beard and
your hair real long?
CHRIS HASLAM: I started the hair
because my buddy Steve in
Canada bet--
I told him I was going to grow
it-- and I guess he didn't
believe me.
So he bet me I couldn't grow it
as long as his or whatever.
Like $50 or something.
Something lame.
And I was like to here.
I think it was in the digital
video where I had--
That's mid transformation.
That's probably the video that
has clips of me in that one
that have the shaved head.
And the next clip is me with
long hair, with some lame-ass
bandana out of my pocket.
And then a real tight-ass
shirt.
So I will put this in.
No BMX, no blades ever.
[SKATEBOARDING SOUNDS]
CHRIS HASLAM: Oh,
first complete
round in about a year.
I got to bleach my hair.
All blond hair, surf kid.
How come all these
kids are ripping?
Oh.
Just got to pretend like I know
what I'm doing at this
place, when really I don't.
PATRICK O'DELL: Should we
watch [INAUDIBLE] video?
CHRIS HASLAM: Yeah, yeah,
I had first part.
And this is where all
that Sasquatch, me
being in the woods.
I'm getting sick of it, so I'm
sure everybody else is getting
sick of it too.
They should probably
stop putting me in
the woods and stuff.
PATRICK O'DELL: What's the trick
called that you did in
Barcelona over the bump
[INAUDIBLE] bar?
CHRIS HASLAM: I call it
a run [INAUDIBLE].
People that know skate histories
generally know what
I'm talking about
when I say that.
Most of the stuff I've done has
been done before already.
Kick foot, one footed,
nose manual, I seen
Danny Gonzales do that.
Front board, kick flipout.
I saw Chris Cole do that in,
I think, or something
[INAUDIBLE] or whatever.
That one you see when I'm
skating up to that kick-foot,
my shirt is tied around
my pants.
That's because my pants ripped
and my balls were hanging out,
so I had to tie my shirt around
my pants so that I
wouldn't be caught hanging.
PATRICK O'DELL: Do you consider
a lot of these tricks
dork tricks?
Or it's like--
CHRIS HASLAM: I've heard people
call them circus tricks.
Like just whenever like, oh
this is kind of weird.
Kind of unusual tricks
or whatever.
Surprisingly, a the three tricks
that people were the
most psyched on was the
kick-foot Smith at the end,
the one- footed board
slide, and the front
blunt on the board.
I think the reason why kids
were psyched on the front
blunt of the board was
because you could do
that any day you want.
You could do it on the front
yard, you can do it on the
driveway, or you could do
it wherever you want.
It's in the reach of any
level of skating.
I'm sure I got hated on a few
times, but I'm surprised that
I haven't just gotten completely
shunned from any
kind of sponsored skating event
from all the lame tricks
that I usually pull off.
There's been a couple, like
the crook lip slide that I
wish never really came
out anywhere, ever.
Oh what's this?
And, oh, there was one dude.
There was a career-ending
photo.
It was the World War Three.
The best trick World
War Three video.
Dude, on the back cover I
had a shaved head, these
baggy ass jeans on--
I don't know what kind of
shirt-- but blazing Benihana.
Like dude!
Just so big.
And just on the back
cover is so devo.
So bad man.
I wouldn't mind doing
another video--
well I don't want to say like
cheese and crackers--
but I want to do that
kind of video.
But not of mini ramp skating,
of doing something else.
I like those kind cheaper, free,
kind of short, and just
fun to watch videos.
You know?
Because I think people want
to see fun stuff now.
I've been skating with
Daewon for a bit.
And there'd be the demo or
there'd be like a mini ramp at
the park that we'd
go to and stuff.
So we'd be skating mini ramps.
So we knew the skill level
of each other.
And we just, one day, thought
that we might as well, maybe,
make something.
You know?
Like make a ramp video.
We wanted it to be as homemade
as possible.
There was all kinds of
stuff that we built
and tried to get.
But there was no way.
There was one part of the
extension that I built.
Kind of like a bridge to the
wall with coping on it.
I don't know what the hell I was
thinking because it's not
going to happen.
So there was all kinds of stuff
that we built that we
didn't even skate.
We spent hours building it.
MALE SPEAKER: [INAUDIBLE]
PATRICK O'DELL: Yeah?
PATRICK O'DELL: So, I mean if
you could take a look, and
then if you really think
that we need to.
MALE SPEAKER: Oh really?
PATRICK O'DELL: Yeah.