back
said
sarah
citing alleged
article
scored in bringing this far down the
road this looks like worksheets
source
assaulted
fetuses
for shit
with a little bit
if there are certainly
repertory resume soon
and seeing all the rest
you want to look at the ranch
this early in the week
looked at
attempt this over the slope
uh...
when it comes down to
is that for the past two years
de la mot has had the piss poorest
record of any united states border
patrol sector in the south and state of
texas cast
it's likely to get on that
the attitude of this division
sucks
it is so bad that i have been required
to take steps
to ameliorate the situation
mister lacey has come all the way from
washington d_c_
to demonstrate a system which he himself
has devised his invention will prove a
great whom to all of us in the
accomplishment of our goals
so we get those plans
pakistanis
this map like matrix you're looking at
represents an area forty square miles
the import
generated
ideal sensors
small electronic modules of one of the
earth covenants
and so sensitive
will pick up the quantum and park
every guy declines in their private a
search on across the border
it it
that's enough
any activity in the neighborhood you'll
sensors will generate a signal on screen
like this
there for example you can observe an
imaginary illegal aliens heading from
quadrant c_-five quadrant c six
well how do you regulate the underwear
oh question it
or the army leader i mean how do you
uh... keep it from malfunction since to
fix it asshole fast enough
why it
as i say dislike most artificial so to
speak
the actual geol sensors will be buried
throughout her sectors muriel gluck
bertelsmann
that's right
then transmit signal
to this console whenever an illegal
alien enters the area with a very
but shortly so stay sensitivity two feet
and that
brittany
p_g_ or sensors
or we detect objects appalled
butterfly sting
arm sorry are seated jack rev it up
there sector seven is bigger stamp
flat-footed and truck shipment bonuses
dan
yes
i'm just curious arrested hobbies
do you assess
effect us it'll be a need for so many
agents on patrol
means consumable savings for tax payer
what what you're trying to say here's
once we go on but stars planning state
about two thirds is didn't drop
detroit's ruins bridges and all
and work then
flag down it's working in other sectors
elommal is next
picked those plans are
what can i just get something straight
night here for you can't live
i'd just like to ask the man one
question sir please let me just that i
get it straight if that was the one
third of its left that you don't fire
why i got to be sitting in some room
watching some
some machine its wants an some other
machine added person so i i throw he
collapsed television show me what i mean
guesses about this shopaholic porter
sabotage any of this error
whatever distresses me we should have
been asked
we didn't sign on to the border patrol
here to mess with computers and radar
screens
a lot of us in a room here turned out
promotions
because we didn't want bestjobs
i think it's important to know what we
walk because uh...
which sounds is
we don't know recharged do you think i'm
gonna ask you for a vote
this is a pure decision
you're right
you don't have anti-choice
you know it's also a definite reports
watch
dated
of the village hampshire cheers
so hurt
produced by the internet
gunnison there we espouse a pack tax of
hopes they'll turn up the religion
clause that they should get from that
point just to be out there
ups dot that's already
i told you to drop it who've gone
completely full
you've got what you are correct i did
urged to appoint judges backed off you
know i will be stable a bit off the top
of time to time just like everybody else
here we carried in your big birthday
listed on the central office
somebody permitted houses but we can
being the exactly like a stream of bob
or by one night
all of laying around all of a long time
is soaring
main paramilitary dr jays birthday
figure out what the
but what about after all
basic plan
walkway
jackie i can't believe you have a
compass of god and computer
what what what do you play at the end
result that out
difficult period prepared for tomorrow
hello
when you got on the job when i got i got
like that you are today meanwhile lose
my job almost at my to highlighted can
take a look at it
leptin sometimes keeping is
dot cap
yes it is believed
got a call sheriff's office promptly
contacts
came out for a minute to there
so check out those to address on the
sales tax
dollar voter
sometimes i get the feeling that this
should really doesn't bother you
all i get a better in your view
there were a lot of hearings
surely take it out here and i'll take it
like that that is dedicated already into
it
but you get a certificate
incidentally
beats the shit out of me
through star trek's
your grade school
where stewards or
what you will
yumiko onto a seasonal
project right now at cigarette
way
kathleen it you've got your weekend
happy like that smith rekindle or you
could look at their word
now well
now you're here now we didn't do self
take it simply is no fall report
chromium we're only about
out
we all do it
what somewhat like a god damn car trap
that out
you mind if i A
take a look at your ideas
we'll be looking harder time away rap
reform level on its coming out
we like the way to press nine three from
africa is a bit telephone company and
san antonio and return ticket district
etc in durban
i grew up in their benefit
we got lost
man they got damn car crapped out yet so
you just said
and exit
surrendered
switching from him
a
keep let him go where you can
withdrawals
samples
tamils gone
horticulture
and water pump shot
felicia moon instructors
harshly unifier institutional getting
encourage and help
which one you want
anymore
your sixth grade you met
uniqueness constraint
you can contribute to the storms clear
people would call a tow truck come take
this and get a statement of probable be
ready to put more
swell broken we built a good material
anything he can do the preacher carafe
are
got that they may need
wide
excused
renegade
kebab darts
extra time cockpit
reveal
dad
kits
reassures actress yes
what
but
quiet here
more rocks
the
soda seven certificate so watch
status etc
may give up
yet upto rally on the search i got that
blanket supported by the sheriff's
department
de la toriente gerald
character
capitalize are
countryside
captain our guests are right
dot blotting out at the prob
hijacked
at the tab partner
culture
yes you're absolutely
work is a very stops
at the airport for a time
happy
there's no doubt
privilege
about it
driver of the water clickers should play
in our group stops right
cities all coming from a prepared
figured he'd stop management
just heading towards eyeball them
vibrato
prior or five years in the hospital
banglore there
coming to an end
twenty-one aldo
eight dead bob other than women first
amendment
hurting for centuries
community belonged to
hello robotic
died
kit
die
can
one stands there as well that my client
is under no obligation whatsoever dance
your questions at this time that fact mr
ancho form a greater sorrows of the
state of texas absences airfare and as
your crimes property im go question
about that way
the ban is mine
but he would take the records
it was a very poor divers or former
renters several richard about the man
behind the wheel it also
it is the mutual respect
record whatever he damn well almost but
also the driver that families bear
how unfortunate for justice
the old right around your or your
acquitted irrelevant your php
but be careful not intimidating to care
for all
this proposes respected man in his
community mist of atrocities are stupid
roseanne is strong
remark is noted officers
white
blackburn a slight w_ i_ a_t_t_
the crushes my friend
to have a calming frayed
houston here lying to our faces with
that white piece of shit lawyer in your
pocket
what i call your people your plastic
bags on
alabama's no more stolen at school bus
assault last month
you pick up what that situation
you pack 'em in anything on wheels
you promised them freedom and you saw
that day
you work for kicks ass
you are fucking watch
don't people directory mouth kit
cma you got to do the job
you okay
marathon
i have
since coming to jerusalem
brookings sd
reader marxist
because right
we don't have any choice in
still have a new
we've got a choice
than that to get outta here we were
talking about this morning
looks like a gross rate of the worst
produce land of the wall over here in
the bank yeah
portrayed warm-blooded
corrupt world
less which is not travel night
so wiper switch a
dish of some sort
thirty-some
he was making good time because of
driving
at night and rape
eight hundred thousand dollars
it straight
but what if it did so well
at this guy pulled off some heist
scott abhi
longford out now
announced steps committee from watch
would keep the was connection
the actual
but they really don't
unfunded scandalous haze of bag ma'am
but mom who decide to go independent
herb be he's a pusher reduce get paid or
for other dope shipment
no respectable civilians who drive
around as well that sketch
peace prayer risk for numbers
texas driver's license
micro
j courtesy eleven thirteen black st
burgundy san antonio texas court case in
brown hair brown eyes issues sixty two
expressed sixty six
he just place
yet texas them as a star six four seven
four nineteen sixty three
electrical
god's views
hunting fishing ships
but what do you think
it's just not going to take it
was not right
as far as a reso rose concern is money's
gone
twenty years
ship turning in our grill you were so
hot i was approached bruises you raised
walk
now we got a ticket to ride out here
first-class here worry about what was
right or not
it's all in one email
tell you what we do cover this sample
camouflage it cheap
cover for traction status these cases to
court
which echo of the money
and it's okay
and we'll split in half to get the hell
out of here
i don't know
i got a compact
you're the only men are notes group
zoned wet dream
about these things in common
and it didn't
do
word
frankly i think it will not wait wait
don't
trillion dollars
the bought a gun
belfast the patterning panties that
altieri did
patriot and pizza going about it
dad died
pieces driving on alternate
couples or
processes
redoing
mckesson i wouldn't know it was a sports
event back in our hemisphere
but there's no doubt that are still
there is anything with the
physicochemical actually donors that
would be
pieces it can happen it is a warning to
was directly to the civil right now
because that's what now
b_c_c_i_'s absolute zero
it alright
legs up
we still have a good rabbit you know in
the car pulls up missus edelman again
in most of the
anything your martin cooper
it's cracked
investments talk about basis talking
about your catholic saints this that
massive haha protect thank you
places like the reported in the big shot
in the knowledge
like work
well i mean
panning out a lot
you know that i have the best part of
your life
justice against
sometimes very cute
down
here in it
fifty years younger
still believe
and god and country charm
raiders
okay
you're going to do everything
jenifer
you'll make money
this man here
it
sridharan for prettier than incorrectly
i think that we need to
and your ticket
which is a great you know she's
student
and if you don't believe it
money still looking for the future
right
freedom
i like to think itself are critically
important no decisions
sector return it works and want to start
restaurants there
attempts to keep a copy
cases peanut
here
liked through chase
tool to use a d_c_ area
has proceeded to it with both disconnect
cars
social security nothing
here proof if it is warranty issues this
fall
when we usually still seek way trees
you which
yes lists centimeters ok road san
antonio mark
you check out the aircraft
couples with little conceive
unusual student
black church built
the mainland
yeah
she's
anybody touch it
shit
this issue he's connie
it steers
doing now
it yourself that this bill
one of the forwarded of stitched sourced
properties that states that was a
politician all day
his back yard of this come from pt
uh... there's nothing funny about a
silver certificate
slows its printed by the u_s_ today
and c_n_n_ ignores all
government studies to adam and uh...
sixty two
the background nicely sometimes numbers
paper smith doing signature
truthful about this
federal reserve mode
sixty-three green seal series
doesn't grant and signature
k
exited dallas bill
because they make a
sure
i didn't know the difference between a
good build circular probably with a list
of hearings on in this business elat
i can't come together shift
what i tell you
satisfied
such scandals
energy coming october dollars bank
escorted out anti caldwell
might not be right
well it might not be right
stephanie
i didn't ask you to bring the eldest
residents
or get bookbag
it up all the money turned into broke
he might not even
accompli meeting
itself very
polytechnic salon
re-used
dinosaur
they stopped making them substitute
nineteen sixty two
the federal reserve now sixty-two
seniors place in g
what we went to the library we just
sector see it that there was any camera
robbery or a high school within a year
interesting article
sitting on the plane tells dropped it
off
yet
senate
spilt
houses the existing
to arrange an illegal immigrant from
parking lot
tonight scheck for the accords their
records on the back for ten years
uh... today
we think montana
usa twenty four hours sort of knowing it
it's infectious has to food
crack
applying
the air stripper i was checking out my
layout against madness a slot machines
to perk ninety was taken out tomorrow
who founded
between phuket found
because i got to tell must take the
girls to hotel
i told my family
tomorrow morning school one hundred sand
beaches
yesterday love
uh...
korean
squirrels yahoo
the alpha q those go
so you can really
it again
metal
today
saupe
commercial use or care
top road
third from around dismayed
who's at standing next to him
stars right here for
weird and all the rest
it was a bus that was
they call it department of public safety
now
well you say it's a josette dash
uh... we gotta
report about a place that down over a
mile yet mister
about thirty miles east of here
a little trouble earlier
anonymous territory better and
everybody's at god's tomo wonder about
it
repair reports about a plane landing on
all the answers
comes in pretty regular sold deseret
over amarillo record
piecing it
culture to complain says its troops is
meal
here's to your dad
blestsol
better days
grow up
seriously wire i'm a slogan
board drawer
just come up from share wells place
he says you're porter playing sudden
down on our end of may so there
you put that all sharks
spokesman plane registered
have you actually seeing the plane sat
down on me so sad
electorate
disinvited
how do you know it lands on tuesdays
insanity let me see it's expensive
indecisive what
twenty west by northwest
came to
worst-covered besides flagship upto
employed by the arts
but allot
tuesday nights
kishore stalled eat
throttle kaback flaps down letter
working hard in the week
how does one chevy got chased him
out at all yet
artist weight forty years my life you're
not going to your picnic welcome dinner
give your condition
when spokesman your
bulbous prestige offered more afternoon
show forest stick it out
our guess is that so i need to itself
much blasted
before the step on it
get up to date
on blacked out
lorraine
israel for it
florida
about that
louisa body
bureaucratic about it
youthful bust
okay i want to make the bust
waters
substantial
parts are
wide are also at stake out a m logan
at like at a meeting spectacle isn't
spectacle of struck
of these gentlemen will be handling the
plane
it'll be their color
you and why it will take a listen
spectacles
elaborating on this trip of it
would you call them
bizarre bust snot a matter of who gets
the credit okay
tonight or first issues
we do our best work will lead to face
with a sister agencies
besides washington likes to get involved
in these matters
miss department always washington all
the figures it can turn explains
doctrine
it's been devastating ice here
spect carson was very impressed by the
transmitters that you install that
section seven
restate that i want to have a hotel room
one oh three
immediate nine-thirty stripped
that add up
what everything
ways women at the uniform
you know we do
admitted
simply
brooks mentally disintegrating
one group from the west establish a
parameter along this portion of the
mason
second committees to secure this quite
here
heating wire we destroyed
agent luna myself wanting the group from
the west
you're always wild
each of you will be issued walkie-talkie
operate on the number to ban are three
vehicles
your jeeps
well-being concealment at the bottom of
the mason
dheere dheere dheere
regan had ferris wheel coach
find a circus wife
what he's saying is out there in the
desert and this man made or as a regular
outlines acoustic historical
specially the area
five vehicles that they stand a good
chance of political list
so what's your and all of them
when you really just need to have no
cinnamon stick out their knowingly
split them up at the plane from both
sides of the same time assumes that
touches down i don't care about black
i want to pick up vehicle
elitist or asla drags that's just one
warehouse
nailed play near step closer to the
source
or you could let the transaction take
place at the vehicle gateway
mail the plaintiff of the vehicle in the
warehouse unit of your warehouse for
drugs and the sources lucky
okay longer
treachery
them
there were no but
there
and robert d
four and sixty eight forty one
graduate of west point
nineteen sixty three
now i'm green beret hero
three silver stars
recommendation for the maalox
at the world by the tail the twenty four
and all of a sudden
yepsen quits
no record and two seventy two
and what's he doing now
sweat ms nets out in the desert
strategy
saying yes sir assalam like broken five
years earlier would've and polishing
machine
as lady logan
bail you with your life unit to leave
to collect peace and quiet bullshit you
copped out
nicely blvd somewhere while you're doing
ellen nixon was president
if i don't like that working for the
same
welcome president of the grease ball a
computer
made all the papers
and body care
you know
system job comes no he ran away
you were afraid you might become a big
issue
no i was afraid of my good just like you
you're hiding out here to get away in
the pressure
howard
outcome
politics
it's all fuckin nation is politics
you work for the border patrol
division of the immigration bureau which
answers the department of justice which
is directly responsible for the congress
of these united states that you don't
think that's political
you think you've beaten the political
system because you're right now the
bottom
i work the system it works little law
christ
you work for the same oddities our
salaries
a lot of supply and demand
single battle with kidney
your fuckin jab depends on those wet
backs
and if we didn't have 'em
weekend benton
analyze how would you prefer testified a
million tickets from congress each year
it's the american way panel
supply and demand
and suppliers like and created
ship
morning i get up by thank god for drugs
and murder and subversion
because without them
we'd all be adamant job
who are you
you know some kid dinner for drug bust
you're in the coming year
for external auditor fix things
what kind of thing
whenever needs fixing
copier all set
ghana's
going in your
you and your name on
the whole wide what users and ballerina
and you know mean
you
we should be in the mean well being
these are my witnesses
where your witnesses asshole
it's the vest
dot fixture was soon or we don't hear
washes cargo it
senator to protect source
somebody backer technica m_i_a_
screw
well get get split from mexico
what is this
t
the
it that way where stepping out of the
year hospital
he is
hope it's ok estes dropping by like this
story it's what you call us
we're more
they told us we go
ticker becuase no never
radio
actual
prayers definitely
negatively about it
o_j_ simpson is again alan and like to
know where you work
and jammers went racing along the lines
to a guy named back from washington d_c_
and other one
used to be the dow's pleased that we're
still
u_s_ that information someone
headquarters
yet everyday cemented by denying
with name
or hand macedo yeah that's the one
we gave them and that means that you did
your mom
what about my here we really didn't have
to be home
and tidy connie can get an answer
worried
we we can increase
you must send you grant
some kind of nation
carolina folks cramming or you work
lunberg it was really happy for you
since in federal guys
homes found its farmhouse structural
copains
mullen beginning even body body with
gallagher is only one
yeah never stops made people up so
nichols aguirre fame easing
anytime
instructors
deep shit
nobody knows what the which came
which explains
school
with him
use computer
victory
nonexistent
groups speakers instincts
this man like you
made you do you mean
usually
we what what it took the cake
that cheap annemarie don't watch
your report it to you
or are they
i didn't take anything
was intended
pan
fatally force
what will the court
sports a store that scalp
through your star system their recent
i'm leaving the unit sft
three powers that the transfers made
alot ministration i'll be working in
washington
graduations
whose lucille databases
a washington promises a decision on that
within the month
the meantime inspector carson here will
be acting is energy
at this issue american way in the past
learn fasulo
seahawks they are ok
both artistic genius
well the rewards what formal
what's going on everyone
shake it up
it's like
was allowed to ask for it
world's inside
why it's important conceit for the job
still connected to stopped
some kind of criticism
buddies
european standards dot
built by the kind of guys i wanna bs
much quest
justices cars
that this
ordeal
but we did this
solicited
fourteen realism
manned
street use
this year
returns marine
standard reading in bed for you
you're sitting
lindsay
on-scene
city vehicle too interested
vernon's ann emerg
one down
check the entire state of texas verdict
he's got a job
them seriously two months after
without reporting this
wrote all the way you when i read you
one
mode is about the emotional cars don
michaela dot it was driving didn't have
anything on him by the white sands
we'll get a lemon
he on this usually causes
my
wages in england
wahi
laser incoming
the
and
with
lindon
two from the tracks everywhere
correct
siddique
leninism
ticket uh little doesn't rest with stuff
two miles
was killed this place
blockbuster would than cell static
we pick the bosses cracks skier
registering them
remi story
you had no idea what they were up to my
writing
dude
what was up to logan
drama this especially of our current
players
hattori recovery
time at the scene
and there are no problems
yeah copy
we've got informants work here that i
missed a process nowak x
spots because
but
ever get these to surrender
you heard the extract
tips your ass in gear
setup that car
throws a spot
concerts all that
static
kolkata split
tax-cuts
atwood
color card kevin card
goat help
colorful
business leaders
dolan lord
would be
and
gahlot ordered to happy
chaotic
yes for an diac pair
while they held you know where the hell
i a m
can't get your act back you know
or is there any
mind's been back home an hour
kit wouldn't do that
said he'd be here
sc
foresters excited wonderful style
cannot
transplants ko
the last time
without god
what has happened
for c
pooled
were you
brought warrant out
salir was
what you've always go big in where you
have don't call us today
well toward look there
regain their lost former senator
discouraged show up
afternoon not at the point is i could
get out are ready all white form
altogether less money
fission ride case we're growing oracle
directly to the border
about what i was told
alga bloom he's bowlers
laid at license number or not that good
enough uh... first ordered all overseas
you might as well do it you take the
back
like like it back
i want you got my state
gottschalk
trader died
tried a lot
oblivious chance because your exploring
argued that she by mothers
bob actor or about happy what did you
ever heard
your met doctor or side unite dylan
partner for that box wanted
analyst analyst radio for over an hour
volcanoes rather you won't get shot on
sight they give 'em a medal for it
they're saying
there's a accurate
catching that for
site some others
the what
what about you
all they'll be coming you can bet on
that
always here for
are you surprised
whatever admission happened years co
outright
it
we've already got an awful
pipe
i'll be back
on
b_g_h_ england
model
uh...
in
and uh...
repair
reunion
for her
from
ghar
resigned
there
more
cameras
star
band
ground
pond
car
drew you
and one
at
there
ad
out
inland
the
your
paired
or
marathon