PEOPLE, WE HAVE TO DO IT THIS WEEK BECAUSE
UNFORTUNATELY NEXT
WEEK THE ROOM'S NOT AVAILABLE. AND SO HOW
MANY PEOPLE WOULD
LIKE TO DO IT ON WEDNESDAY AT THIS TIME?
STUDENT: WE CAN'T HEAR YOU BACK HERE.
PROFESSOR: OH, OKAY. SO WE NEED TO HOLD A
REVIEW SESSION OR I'D
LIKE TO, IT'S NOT OBLIGATORY, BUT IT WOULD
BE NICE TO HOLD A
REVIEW SESSION. AND IF WE DID IT ON, WE HAVE
TO DO IT EITHER
WEDNESDAY OR FRIDAY OF THIS WEEK. SO HOW MANY
FOR WEDNESDAY
AGAIN? OKAY, HOW ABOUT FRIDAY? IT LOOKS LIKE
IT'S WEDNESDAY
THEN. SO WE'LL MEET HERE ON WEDNESDAY. AND
I'LL CONTINUE TO
HOLD OFFICE HOURS UP TO THE DAY OF THE FINAL.
BUT NEXT WEEK
I'LL PROBABLY BE IN, I'LL ARRIVE AT THE OFFICE
AND IF NOBODY
SHOWS UP WITHIN ABOUT, BY ABOUT 20 AFTER,
I'M PROBABLY GOING TO
LEAVE BECAUSE I DON'T KNOW HOW MANY PEOPLE
WILL EVEN BE ON CAMPUS
NEXT WEEK. BUT, SO BE SURE IF YOU COME TO
OFFICE HOUR NEXT WEEK
THAT YOU SHOW UP WITHIN THE FIRST 10 MINUTES,
LIKE BETWEEN 10
AFTER AND 20 AFTER. AND THE SAME GOES FOR
THE DAY OF THE FINAL.
ALL RIGHT, SO LAST TIME I GAVE YOU A BIT OF
AN INTRODUCTION TO
THE WHOLE TOPIC OF SIGNALING IN PLANTS, HOW
PLANTS CAN ACTUALLY
PERCEIVE STIMULI. WE TALKED ABOUT THE STIMULUS
OF LIGHT AND
PHOTOPERIODISM IN PARTICULAR, THAT IS PHYSIOLOGICAL
RESPONSES OF
PLANTS TO THE RELATIVE LENGTH OF LIGHT AND
DARKNESS WHICH IS
IMPORTANT WITH REGARD TO FLOWERING IN PARTICULAR
IS ONE OF THE,
THE THING WE MAINLY FOCUSED ON. I JUST WANT
TO FINISH UP ON
THAT BY POINTING OUT THAT IT'S ACTUALLY NOT
THE, THE LENGTH OF
THE DAY THAT'S IMPORTANT BUT IT'S THE UNINTERRUPTED
LENGTH OF THE
NIGHT THAT PLANTS ARE ACTUALLY PERCEIVING.
AND THIS WAS
ESTABLISHED AFTER THE NAME SHORT-DAY PLANT
AND LONG-DAY PLANT
WERE ALREADY INGRAINED IN THE LITERATURE.
SO THOSE NAMES
PERSIST FOR PLANTS THAT FLOWER DURING SHORT
DAYS AND PLANTS THAT
FLOWER DURING LONG DAYS. AND AS I MENTIONED,
THERE'S SOME
PLANTS THAT ARE DAY, DAY NEUTRAL. THEY JUST
FLOWER WHENEVER
THEY'RE AT THE PHYSIOLOGICAL STATE TO FLOWER.
BUT THE
EXPERIMENTS THAT WERE DONE TO DEMONSTRATE
THAT THIS IS A, A
NIGHT-LENGTH RESPONSE RATHER THAN A DAY-LENGTH
RESPONSE WERE
PRETTY ELEGANT. JUST BASICALLY GROWING PLANTS
IN A GREENHOUSE
SITUATION UNDER CONTROLLED LIGHT. AND WITH
A SHORT-DAY PLANT
WHICH WOULD NORMALLY FLOWER AFTER THE NIGHT
OR AFTER THE DAY
LENGTH WENT BELOW A CERTAIN LEVEL IN THE FALL
OR THE LATE SUMMER,
A BRIEF FLASH OF LIGHT WAS INTRODUCED ABOUT
MIDWAY THROUGH THE
DARK PERIOD AND THOSE PLANTS THEN WOULD, WOULD
FLOWER. SO AND
THE SAME SORT OF THING WAS OBSERVED WITH THE
LONG-DAY PLANTS
WHICH TYPICALLY WOULD FLOWER WHEN DAY LENGTH
REACHES A CERTAIN
PERIOD OF TIME, THAT FLOWER IN THE LATE SPRING
OR EARLY SUMMER.
AND IT TURNED OUT THAT A BRIEF FLASH OF INTENSE
LIGHT, JUST THE
BRIEFEST FLASH IN BOTH CASES, WOULD INITIATE
FLOWERING EVEN
THOUGH THE DARK PERIOD WAS TOO LONG STILL
FOR FLOWERING TO OCCUR
IN THIS CASE. SO IT APPEARS THAT BASED ON
OTHER WORK THAT
PHYTOCHROME ACTUALLY IS INVOLVED HERE, AT
LEAST IN PART. IT'S
ONE OF THE PHOTORECEPTORS SENSING THE OVERALL
LENGTH OF THE NIGHT
PERIOD. AND WITH THE FLASH OF LIGHT PHYTOCHROME
SIGNALS THE END
OF THAT NIGHT PERIOD. SO WITH THE LONG-DAY
PLANT, WHICH IS
BASICALLY A SHORT NIGHT PLANT, THAT FLASH
OF LIGHT BREAKS UP THAT
LONG DARK PERIOD INTO TWO SHORT PERIODS, AND
THE PLANT SENSES IT
AS A SHORT NIGHT AND FLOWERING IS INITIATED.
AND HERE WHERE THE
FLASH OF LIGHT IS ALSO INTRODUCED IN THE MIDDLE
OF THAT DARK
PERIOD, I ACTUALLY MISSTATED THIS THAT THE,
THE SHORT-DAY PLANT
WILL NOT FLOWER BECAUSE THE LONG NIGHT IS
NOT PERCEIVED.
INSTEAD IT'S PERCEIVED AS A SHORT NIGHT. SO
THESE PLANTS FLOWER
WHEN THE NIGHT LENGTH CROSSES A CRITICAL THRESHOLD,
BUT THE FLASH
OF LIGHT CAUSES THE PLANT NOT TO PERCEIVE
THAT AS A LONG NIGHT.
WHEREAS HERE THE FLASH OF LIGHT SUGGESTS THIS
IS A SHORT NIGHT
WHICH IS WHAT IS REQUIRED FOR LONG-DAY PLANT
TO FLOWER. ARE
THERE ANY QUESTIONS ABOUT THAT THEN? SO THIS
IS A, THIS IS ALL I
REALLY HAD TO SAY ABOUT, WELL, THERE'S ONE
MORE THING TO SAY
ABOUT PHOTOPERIODISM, AND IT'S PRETTY INTERESTING.
AND THIS
SEGUES INTO THE NEXT TOPIC ABOUT GROWTH REGULATION.
AND THAT IS
THAT EXPERIMENTS WERE ALSO DONE WHERE A PLANT
THAT WAS IN, WHERE
A FLOWERING HAD BEEN INITIATED, IN THIS CASE
A SHORT-DAY PLANT,
HAD A LONG-DAY PLANT SHOOT GRAFTED ON TO IT,
SO PHYSICALLY
GRAFTED ONTO THE TISSUES OF THIS SHORT-DAY
PLANT. THIS IS A
LONG-DAY PLANT THAT HADN'T FLOWERED AT THE
TIME. AND THIS PLANT
THEN FLOWERED EVEN THOUGH THE DAY LENGTH WASN'T,
WASN'T
APPROPRIATE FOR A LONG-DAY PLANT TO FLOWER
UNDER THOSE
CONDITIONS. SO THIS KIND OF EXPERIMENT CAN
BE DONE THE OTHER
WAY AROUND TOO WITH DRAFTING A SHORT-DAY SHOOT
ONTO A LONG-DAY
PLANT THAT HAD ALREADY INITIATED AND IT WOULD
FLOWER AT A TIME
WHEN IT NORMALLY WOULDN'T. SO CLEARLY SOMETHING
IS BEING
TRANSMITTED THROUGH THE TISSUES OF THIS PLANT
THAT'S UNDERGONE
FLOWERING TO THE TISSUES OF ANOTHER, OF THIS
OTHER PLANT THAT'S
RESULTING IN INITIATION OF FLOWERING. AND
THIS IS, THIS SORT OF
EXPERIMENT DATES LONG AGO, I MEAN FOR NEARLY
THREE QUART-, THREE
QUARTERS OF A CENTURY, PEOPLE HAVE POSTULATED
ON THE BASIS OF
SUCH DATA THAT THERE'S A FLOWERING HORMONE
THAT'S TRANSMITTED
WITHIN PLANTS. THEY'VE EVEN GIVEN IT THE NAME
FLORIGEN BUT NO
ONE HAS EVER SUCCESSFULLY ISOLATED THIS HORMONE,
SO IT'S STILL A
COMPLETE HYPOTHETICAL IF IT REALLY EXISTS.
BUT IT'S STILL CALLED
BY THIS NAME IN THE LITERATURE AND PEOPLE
DISCUSS IT AS IF IT
EXISTS. IT'S ONE OF THE MOST, IT'S ONE OF
THE STRANGER ASPECTS
OF PLANT PHYSIOLOGY. AND IT'S POSSIBLE BASED
ON SOME RECENT
EXPERIMENTS IN ARABIDOPSIS WHICH IS A MODEL
SYSTEM FOR STUDYING
PLANT BIOLOGY THAT THE STIMULUS MIGHT NOT
BE A HORMONE BUT MIGHT
BE A MACROMOLECULE, DN, A PROTEIN OR A NUCLEIC
ACID RATHER THAN
A MICROMOLECULE WHICH HORMONES TYPICALLY ARE.
SO THAT GETS TO
THE POINT OF PLANT CHEMISTRY. AND I WANT TO
TALK ABOUT PLANT
CHEMISTRY ONLY IN RELATION TO HOW PLANTS RESPOND
TO ENVIRONMENTAL
STIMULI. AND THIS IS A REALLY FASCINATING
AREA ABOUT WHICH
WE'RE LEARNING MORE ALL THE TIME. HUGE AMOUNTS
HAVE BEEN
LEARNED SINCE I ACTUALLY TOOK BOTANY AND TAUGHT
IT AS A GRADUATE
STUDENT. BUT PLANTS, LIKE ANIMALS, HAVE A
LOT OF DIFFERENT WAYS
FOR COPING WITH THE, WITH ENVIRONMENTAL CHANGE.
AND,
OF COURSE, MOST ANIMALS CAN MOVE IN RESPONSE
TO EITHER A
FAVORABLE STIMULUS OR AN UNFAVORABLE STIMULUS.
THEY CAN EITHER
APPROACH IT OR RETREAT FROM IT. WHEREAS PLANTS
THROUGH MOST OF
THEIR LIFE CYCLE ARE IMMOBILE AND ARE LOCKED
IN PLACE
ESSENTIALLY, SO THEIR, THEIR RESPONSES REALLY
ARE TYPICALLY IN
THE AREA OF GROWTH OR METABOLIC CHANGES. AND
PLANT HORMONES ARE
ONE OF THE WAYS THAT THE PLANT CAN SIGNAL
THESE, THIS NECESSITY
TO CHANGE, TO UNDERGO SOME KIND OF RESPONSE.
AND THESE ARE
OFTEN CALLED PLANT GROWTH REGULATORS BECAUSE
THEY DIFFER FROM
ANIMAL HORMONES IN SOME WAYS. THEY SOMETIMES
ACT CLOSE TO THE
SOURCE OF PRODUCTION. BUT THEY'RE TYPICALLY
TRANSLOCATED WITHIN
THE PLANT OR MOVE WITHIN THE PLANT LIKE AN
ANIMAL HORMONE. AND
LIKE ANIMAL HORMONES THEY'RE ORGANIC COMPOUNDS
THAT MODIFY OR
CONTROL ONE OR MORE PHYSIOLOGICAL RESPONSES.
AND THOSE
PHYSIOLOGICAL RESPONSES OFTEN HAVE TO DO WITH
PROMOTING OR
INHIBITING GROWTH. THOUGH THESE ARE RESPONSES
LIKE CELL
DIVISION, CELL ELONGATION, OR CELLULAR DIFFERENTIATION
OR
MATURATION, THE THREE MAJOR ASPECTS OF GROWTH.
AND I JUST
MENTIONED THIS, THEY'RE OFTEN TRANSPORTED
FROM THE SITE OF
STIMULUS RECEPTION TO THE SITE OF RESPONSE.
AND ONE OF THE
INTERESTING THINGS ABOUT HORMONES IN GENERAL
IS THAT THEY, THEY
CAN BE, THEY CAN HAVE A VERY STRONG EFFECT
WITH VERY LOW
CONCENTRATIONS. AND THE AMOUNT OF THE HORMONE
PRESENT CAN HAVE
A HUGE EFFECT ON ITS, ON ITS ACTION ON, ON
THE SIGNAL THAT IT
PROVIDES TO THE PLANT. AND ALSO THAT ACTION
CAN BE AFFECTED BY
THE TYPE OF TISSUE IN WHICH THE HORMONE IS
IN CONTACT OR, OR THE
AGE OF THAT TISSUE, ITS STATE OF MATURATION.
AND THESE ARE
INVOLVED IN JUST ABOUT EVERY ASPECT OF PLANT
GROWTH AND
DEVELOPMENT. AND ONE OF THE INTERESTING THINGS
ABOUT PLANT
HORMONES THAT MAKES THEM SO DIFFICULT TO STUDY
BUT ALSO
FASCINATING IS THAT THERE, AN INDIVIDUAL HORMONE
CAN BE INVOLVED
IN MANY DIFFERENT RESPONSES IN PLANTS. AS
I JUST MENTIONED, THE
SITE OF ACTION, THE AGE OF THE TISSUE, THE
AMOUNT OF HORMONE
PRESENT CAN HAVE A BIG EFFECT ON THE RESPONSE.
AND ALSO AN
INDIVIDUAL RESPONSE CAN INVOLVE MULTIPLE HORMONES,
DIFFERENT
HORMONES. AND IT'S THE RELATIVE CONCENTRATION
OF THESE
DIFFERENT HORMONES THAT'S MOST IMPORTANT GENERALLY,
WHAT WE CAN
THINK OF AS HORMONAL BALANCE WHICH IS SOMETHING
WE ALSO THINK
ABOUT IN ANIMALS. THOUGH THE HORMONAL BALANCE,
WE'LL TALK ABOUT
THAT A COUPLE OF TIMES HERE TODAY, IS REALLY
IMPORTANT. SO JUST
LIKE SO MANY THINGS IN BIOLOGY, SOME OF THE
EARLIEST INSIGHTFUL
WORK ON THESE, ON PLANT HORMONES WAS DONE
BY CHARLES DARWIN IN
ASSOCIATION WITH HIS SON FRANCIS BACK NEAR
THE END OF HIS LIFE IN
THE 1880S. AND WHAT THEY DID IS THEY, THEY
GREW UP GRASS
SEEDLINGS. AND REMEMBER GRASSES GERMINATE
DIRECTLY THROUGH THE
SOIL, THE TIP OF THE SHOOT EMERGES SHEATHED
IN A, WHAT'S CALLED A
COLEOPTILE, THE SHEATH THAT EMERGES DIRECTLY
FROM THE, FROM THE
SOIL. AND IT WAS THE BENDING OF THESE COLEOPTILES
IN RESPONSE
TO LIGHT THAT, THAT THE DARWINS STUDIED. AND
SO THEY FOUND
THAT, THAT THESE COLEOPTILES WOULD BEND TOWARD
THE LIGHT WHICH IS
A PRETTY ADAPTIVE RESPONSE IT SEEMED TO IN
TERMS OF MAXIMIZING
PHOTOSYNTHESIS. AND SO THEY WANTED TO UNDERSTAND
HOW THAT
OCCURRED AND WHAT THAT INVOLVED. SO THEY DID
VARIOUS THINGS,
BUT ONE OF THE THINGS THEY DID THAT WAS INTERESTING
IS THEY CUT
OFF THE TIP OF THAT COLEOPTILE, AND THEY SAW
THAT NO BENDING,
THIS GROWTH RESPONSE THAT RESULTED IN BENDING
DIDN'T OCCUR. AND
SO MAYBE THAT WAS JUST SOME SORT OF WOUND
RES, A PROBLEM WITH
WOUNDING THE PLANTS. SO THEY COVERED UP THE
TIP WITH A, A LIGHT
IMPENETRABLE COVER. AND THEY ALSO SAW NO BENDING.
SO THE NEXT
THING THEY TRIED IS THEY COVERED UP THE AREA
WHERE THE BENDING
ACTUALLY OCCURS, AND THE THING STILL BENT.
SO THEY CONCLUDED
THAT LIGHT IS SENSED BY THE TOP OF THE SHOOT
AND THAT, THAT SOME
SORT OF HORMONAL SIGNAL IS SENT DOWN THE,
THROUGH THE PLANT TO A,
A POINT OF RESPONSE WHERE THERE'S A GROWTH
RESPONSE THAT RESULTS
IN BENDING TOWARD LIGHT. SO THIS WAS THE FIRST
EVIDENCE FOR
PLANT HORMONES. AND THIS ELICITED A LOT OF
INTEREST BY OTHERS.
AND THERE WERE OTHER EXPERIMENTS DONE WITH
THE SAME SYSTEM AFTER
DARWIN. AND ONE OF THEM WAS THIS ONE WHICH
ESTABLISHED THAT
THIS PHOTOPTROPIC SIGNAL IS ACTUALLY A CHEMICAL
AS DARWIN
SUSPECTED. AND WHAT WAS DONE HERE WAS THAT
THE SLICED OFF TIP
OF THE COLEOPTILE IS PLACED ON A LITTLE BLOCK
OF AGAR. WE TALKED
ABOUT AGAR, OF COURSE, IS THE, THIS CARBOHYDRATE
EXTRACTED FROM
RED ALGAE. AND IT'S PERMEABLE. THIS WAS PLACED
IN BETWEEN THE
REST OF THE COLEOPTILE AND ITS TIP. AND WHAT
WAS SEEN IS THIS
GROWTH RESPONSE STILL OCCURRED, WHEREAS IF
YOU PUT A PLACE,
WHEREAS IF AN IMPENETRABLE OBJECT WAS PLACED
BETWEEN THE TIP AND
THE REST OF THE COLEOPTILE, IN THIS CASE A
LITTLE SHEET OF MICA,
THERE WAS NO BENDING. SO THE CONCLUSION FROM
THIS EXPERIMENT
WAS THAT INDEED SOME CHEMICAL WAS TRANSMITTED
DOWN THROUGH THE,
THROUGH THE COLEOPTILE AS DARWIN SUSPECTED.
OKAY, THEN IT
WASN'T UNTIL THE 1920S THAT FRITZ WENT AT
CAL TECH PERFORMED A
KIND OF DECISIVE EXPERIMENT HERE WHERE BASICALLY
USING THE SAME
SYSTEM, THIS TIP OF THE COLEOPTILE THAT HAD
BEEN INITIATED OR HAD
BEEN EXPOSED TO LIGHT AND HAD UNDERGONE SOME
EXPOSURE TO LIGHT
WAS CUTOFF AND PLACED AGAIN ON A LITTLE BLOCK
OF AGAR WITH A
SUFFICIENT TIME FOR ANY DIFFUSION TO OCCUR
INTO THIS AGAR WHICH
WAS SHOWN HERE BY THE RED, THE ACTIVE SUBSTANCE
HERE. AND THEN
THIS WAS PLACED ON DIFFERENT COLEOPTILES THAT
HAD ALSO HAD THEIR
TOPS, THEIR TIPS EXCISED THAT HADN'T BEEN
EXPOSED TO LIGHT. AND
IT WAS PLACED OFFSET TO ONE SIDE, EITHER ONE
SIDE OR THE OTHER ON
DIFFERENT COLEOPTILES. AND A GROWTH RESPONSE
WAS SEEN WITH
BENDING AWAY FROM THE, THE EDGE THAT THE AGAR
WAS PLACED ON.
AND WHEN THE TISSUES OF THOSE COLEOPTILES
WAS LOOKED AT IN MORE
DETAIL DOWN NEAR THE AREA OF BENDING, IT WAS,
WENT SAW THAT THE
CELLS HAD ELONGATED ALONG THE SIDE THAT THE
AGAR WAS PLACED ON.
SO THE IDEA HERE WAS THAT THEN NOT ONLY WAS
A CHEMICAL
TRANSMITTED DOWN HERE, THE CHEMICAL WAS RESULTING
IN AN
ELONGATION OF CELLS ALONG THE SIDE OR IN RESPONSE
TO THIS
CHEMICAL. AND SO APPARENTLY ON THE DARK SIDE
OF THE COLEOPTILE
AWAY FROM LIGHT, THERE WAS, THERE WAS A GROWTH
RESPONSE BY THIS
TRANSMITTED CHEMICAL WHICH HE CALLED AUXIN
WHICH JUST MEANS TO
INCREASE. IT WASN'T KNOWN WHAT IT WAS AT THE
TIME. IT WAS
LATER DISCOVERED TO BE INDOLEACETIC ACID.
AND THERE'S SOME
OTHER RELATED SUBSTANCES CALLED AUXINS AS
WELL THAT HAVE A NUMBER
OF DIFFERENT RESPONSES. AND SO THIS WAS THE
FIRST PLANT HORMONE
THAT WAS REALLY STUDIED, AND IT TURNS OUT
TO BE A REALLY
IMPORTANT PLANT HORMONE. AND LIKE OTHER PLANT
HORMONES, IT'S
INVOLVED IN A NUMBER OF DIFFERENT EFFECTS.
AND ONE OF THE ONES
WE'VE ALREADY TALKED ABOUT IS APICAL DOMINANCE,
THAT IS HOW A
SHOOT WILL HAVE A, A PRIMARY APICAL MERISTEM
THAT'S ACTIVE
WHEREAS AXILLARY MERISTEMS WILL BE SUPPRESSED,
THEY'LL BE
INHIBITED OR WON'T BE ACTIVE. AND IT TURNS
OUT AS WE ALREADY
MENTIONED, IF YOU CUT OFF THE TIP, THE ACTIVE
TIP OF A SHOOT,
THESE AXILLARY BUDS THAT ARE FOUND IN THE
UPPER AXLES OF LEAVES
HERE WILL SUDDENLY BE INITIATED. AND HERE
YOU CAN SEE A LITTLE,
SOME EVIDENCE OF THIS. THIS TIP WAS JUT CUT
OFF. AND HERE GO
THE AXILLARY BUDS BECOMING NEW SHOOTS THAT
ARE GROWING UPWARD
LIKE THE ORIGINAL TIP. AND ONE TYPICALLY BECOMES
DOMINANT. SO
THAT'S A PRETTY STRONG AND, AND CLEAR RESPONSE
TO, TO THE REMOVAL
OF THE APICAL MERISTEM. AND IT TURNS OUT THAT
STUDIES OF THE
PRESENCE OF AUXIN WITHIN SHOOTS SHOWS THAT
THE ACTIVE APICAL
MERISTEM IS WHERE AUXIN IS PRODUCED AT HIGH,
RELATIVELY HIGH
CONCENTRATIONS. AND WITH ITS REMOVAL THEN
WE HAVE REMOVAL OF
WHAT'S ASSUMED TO BE AN, WHAT APPEARS TO BE
AN INHIBITOR OF
THESE, OF THESE SIDE SHOOTS OF THESE AXILLARY
BUDS. AND WE'LL
GET MORE TO THAT IN A MINUTE. SO AS I MENTIONED
ALSO AROUND
THESE PLANT HORMONES HAVE DIFFERENT EFFECTS
ON DIFFERENT TISSUES.
AND ANOTHER COMPLETELY DIFFERENT EFFECT OCCURS
WITH AUXIN IN THE
PRESENCE OF OVARY TISSUE. AND SO ONE OF THE
THINGS THAT'S BEEN
SEEN IS THAT AUXIN IS PRODUCED IN PROXIMITY
TO OR PERHAPS BY THE
SEEDS OF A DEVELOPING OVARY, A DEVELOPING
FRUIT. AND HERE WE
CAN SEE A NORMAL TOMATO WHERE THERE WAS NORMAL
POLLINATION AND
FERTILIZATION WITH THE AUXIN PRODUCED IN THE
VICINITY OF THE
SEEDS BEING IMPORTANT FOR NORMAL FRUIT DEVELOPMENT.
AND IN THE
ABSENCE OF FERTILIZATION OF THOSE SEEDS, IF
THERE'S NO
POLLINATION, THE TOMATO FRUIT WON'T DEVELOP.
BUT IF YOU APPLY
AUXIN, IF YOU SPRAY AUXIN ON THAT OVARY, EVEN
IF THERE'S NO
POLLINATION, THE OVARY CAN DEVELOP, AND THIS
IS DONE TO ENSURE
FRUIT DEVELOPMENT IN TOMATOES AND SOME OTHER
FRUITS IN THE
ABSENCE OF ANY POLLINATORS. SO AUXIN DOES
HAVE THIS ABILITY,
THIS, THIS SIGNALING FOR FRUIT DEVELOPMENT.
THOUGH AGAIN, AUXIN
IS INVOLVED IN CELL ELONGATION, NOT DIVISION,
BUT ELONGATION IN
COLEOPTILES ON THE DARK SIDE OF THE SHOOT,
ON STEMS ON THE LIGHT
SIDE IT TURNS OUT. SO THOSE EXPERIMENTS BY
DARWIN AND OTHERS
WERE A LITTLE BIT MISLEADING. AUXIN OPERATES
IN SLIGHTLY
DIFFERENT WAYS IN STEMS BUT ALSO IN REGARD
TO ELONGATION OF
CELLS. IT ALSO OPERATES IN APICAL DOMINANCE,
FRUIT DEVELOPMENT,
AND IN LATERAL ROOT FORMATION, FORMATION OF
BRANCHING FROM THE
ROOTS AS I'LL TALK ABOUT IN A MOMENT. ALL
RIGHT, SO ANOTHER
POINT THAT I MADE EARLIER JUST BRIEFLY WAS
THAT DIFFERENT
CONCENTRATIONS OF HORMONES CAN HAVE REALLY
DIFFERENT EFFECTS ON
THE TISSUES THAT THEY'RE IN CONTACT WITH.
AND THIS IS THE CASE
WITH AUXIN, AS YOU CAN SEE HERE'S A GRADIENT
OF AUXIN FROM LOW TO
HIGH CONCENTRATION, HIGHER IN THIS DIRECTION.
AND HERE WE CAN
SEE A POSITIVE EFFECT OF GROWTH EFFECT AND
AN INHIBITORY EFFECT
OF AUXIN WITH NO EFFECT HERE. SO WHAT YOU
SEE HERE IS THAT
DIFFERENT PARTS OF THE PLANT ARE SENSITIVE
TO DIFFERENT
CONCENTRATIONS. BUT IN EACH CASE THERE'S A,
A RESPONSE THAT'S
QUITE SIMILAR AS AUXIN IS INCREASED BUT AT
DIFFERENT LEVELS. SO
WE INITIALLY GET AN INCREASE IN GROWTH BUT
THEN AN INHIBITION OF
GROWTH. AND IF WE LOOK AT THIS IN STEMS, YOU
CAN SEE THE
CONCENTRATION OF AUXIN THAT'S MAXIMALLY STIMULATIVE
OF STEM
GROWTH IS STRONGLY INHIBITING OF BUD GROWTH,
OF THOSE AXILLARY
BUDS AS THAT EXPERIMENT WITH CUTTING OFF THE
TIP SHOWED. AND,
OF COURSE, THE STEM TIP IS PRODUCING A LOT
OF AUXIN, SO YOU CUT
OFF THAT TIP, THE AMOUNT OF AUXIN IS REDUCED
IN THE STEM. AND
WE END UP WITH MAXIMAL INITIATION OF BUDS
AND SUPPRESSION OF
ROOTS AT THAT LEVEL. STEMS AREN'T EVEN EFFECTED
AT THE LEVEL
THAT INITIATES BUD GROWTH IN TERMS OF THE
MAIN STEM. SO,
QUESTION? YEAH, BRAD?
STUDENT: IS AUXIN JUST KIND OF A GENERIC TERM
FOR THE FAMILY OF
HORMONES.
PROFESSOR: THAT'S RIGHT. YEAH, IT'S JUST A
GENERIC TERM. IT'S
NOT SPECIFIC AS TO CHEMISTRY IN PARTICULAR,
THAT'S RIGHT.
CYTOKININS ARE, WERE DISCOVERED MUCH LATER
IN THE 1940S, BUT
THEY'RE ALSO REALLY IMPORTANT. AND IT TURNS
OUT THAT THE
BALANCE OF CYTOKININ TO AUXIN IS, IS REALLY
IMPORTANT FOR A PLANT
TO, FOR THE PLANT GROWTH RESPONSE. AND SO
CYTOKININS ARE NAMED
BECAUSE THEY PROMOTE CELL DIVISION. AND CYTOKININ
COMES FROM
CYTOKINESIS OR CELL DIVISION. OKAY, SO THAT'S
AN EASY WAY TO
REMEMBER THE TERM. REMEMBER THAT AUXINS PROMOTE
ELONGATION OF
CELLS, NOT DIVISION OF CELLS, SO CYTOKININS
OPERATING WITH AUXINS
ARE IMPORTANT FOR THE OVERALL GROWTH RESPONSE
SINCE BOTH DIVISION
AND ELONGATION ARE IMPORTANT IN GROWTH. AND
SO A HIGH
CYTOKININ:AUXIN RATIO PROMOTES ACTIVATION
OF, OF SHOOT BRANCHING,
THIS AXILLARY BUD BRANCHING THAT WE TALKED
ABOUT. AND THE, A
LOW CYTOKININ:AUXIN RATIO PROMOTES ACTIVATION
OF LATERAL ROOTS,
SO BRANCHING OF THE ROOTS. AND I MENTIONED
THAT AUXIN CAN
STIMULATE LATERAL ROOT PRODUCTION. AND IT'S
REALLY THE LOW
CYTOKININ:AUXIN RATIO THAT PROMOTES THAT RELATIVELY
HIGH AUXIN
COMPARED TO CYTOKININ HERE. SO I ALREADY MENTIONED
THIS THAT
CYTOKININ PROMOTES DEVELOPMENT OF BRANCHES
FOR, ACTUALLY I DIDN'T
MENTION THAT. I MENTIONED THAT THE REDUCTION
IN THE AMOUNT OF
AUXIN RESULTS IN THE BRANCHING OF THE SIDE
SHOOTS. BUT WHAT IT
REALLY IS IS THAT THE CYTOKININ RATIO, THERE'S
A HIGH
CYTOKININ:AUXIN RATIO WHEN, AFTER THE TIP
IS REMOVED. AND
THAT'S, THAT'S WHAT'S IMPORTANT WITH REGARD
TO THE OVERALL
BRANCHING OF THE SHOOT. AND INTERESTINGLY,
THE, THE CYTOKININS
AND AUXINS ARE PRODUCED IN DIFFERENT PARTS
OF THE PLANT BODY,
AND THEY'RE, THEY'RE MOBILIZED. THEY MOVE
IN OPPOSITE
DIRECTIONS IN THE PLANT. SO THE AUXIN IS MOVING
AS I MENTIONED
FROM THE SHOOT TIPS DOWNWARD, AND IT STILL
MOVES TOWARD THE ROOTS
EVEN IF YOU TURN THE PLANT UPSIDE-DOWN. THIS
IS NOT A GRAVITY
RESPONSE. AND CYTOKININS ARE TYPICALLY PRODUCED
IN THE ROOTS
AND TRANSPORTED UPWARD TOWARD THE SHOOT. AND
SO THIS CREATES A
GRADIENT OF CYTOKININ AND AUXIN WITHIN THE
PLANT BODY THAT'S
IMPORTANT IN MAINTAINING THIS HORMONAL BALANCE
ACROSS THE PLANT.
OKAY, SO THAT'S, THAT'S ONE OF THE INTERESTING
THINGS THAT WAS
DISCOVERED ABOUT, ABOUT THIS INTERPLAY BETWEEN
CYTOKININS AND
AUXINS IS THEIR DIRECTION OF MOVEMENT IS DIFFERENT,
THEIR PLACE
OF PRODUCTION IS DIFFERENT, AND THAT HELPS
TO SET UP THIS
GRADIENT THAT'S REALLY IMPORTANT IN GROWTH.
ALL RIGHT, SO
CYTOKININS THEN IMPORTANT IN CELL DIVISION
AND DIFFERENTIATION
IN CONCERT WITH, WITH AUXINS INVOLVED IN CELL
ELONGATION FOR THE
OVERALL GROWTH RESPONSE, AND ALSO AXILLARY
BUD GROWTH,
PARTICULARLY WHEN APICAL DOMINANCE IS REMOVED
BY DAMAGE TO THE
SHOOT TIP. BUT ALSO, FOR EXAMPLE, AT LOWER
POINTS ON THE STEM
WHERE YOU HAVE A HIGHER CYTOKININ:AUXIN RATIO,
AS YOU, AS YOU GET
FURTHER AND FURTHER AWAY FROM THE SHOOT TIP,
THERE'S LESS
INHIBITION OF BUDS TYPICALLY. ALL RIGHT, ANOTHER
CLASS OF,
THIRD CLASS OF PLANT HORMONES ARE CALLED GIBBERELLINS.
AND
THESE ARE CALLED GIBBERELLINS BECAUSE THEY
WERE ORIGINALLY
DISCOVERED IN A PLANT THAT WAS INFECTED BY
A FUNGUS CALLED
GIBBERELLA. IT'S JUST AN ASIDE, BUT THAT'S
WHERE THE NAME COMES
FROM. AND THIS FUNGUS PRODUCED A COMPOUND
THAT WE CALLED
GIBBERELLIN THAT RESULTED IN RICE SEEDLINGS
BEING STRONGLY, BEING
VERY SPINDLY, HAVING AN UNCONTROLLED GROWTH
RESPONSE. AND SO,
SO GIBBERELLINS HAVE A STRONG EFFECT IN STEM
ELONGATION AND
OVERALL HAVE A STRONG GROWTH STIMULATING EFFECT.
SO THESE ARE
SUBSTANCES WHICH TEND TO HAVE A STRONG GROWTH
STIMULATING EFFECT.
THEY'RE ALSO IMPORTANT IN PROMOTING SEED GERMINATION,
SO THE
BREAKING OF DORMANCY IN SEEDS, IN, ESPECIALLY
PLANTS THAT HAVE A
LIGHT REQUIREMENT FOR GERMINATION. AND WE
USE GIBBERELLINS ALL
THE TIME AT LOW REALLY CONCENTRATIONS TO GERMINATE
SEEDS OF
CERTAIN PLANT SPECIES IN MY LAB. AND YOU CAN
GO FROM A PLANT
THAT YOU CAN BARELY GET TO GERMINATE, YOU
HAVE TO DISSECT THE
EMBRYOS OUT TO GET THEM TO GERMINATE, TO HAVING
THEM ALMOST JUMP
OUT OF THE SEEDS. I MEAN JUST WITHIN LESS
THAN 12 HOURS THEY'LL
BE FULLY GERMINATED. SO THESE HAVE A PRETTY
STRONG EFFECT WHEN,
IN PLANTS THAT RECOGNIZE THEM FOR, AS A STIMULUS
FOR GERMINATION.
AND THEY'RE ALSO USED COMMERCIALLY TO PROMOTE
FRUIT ENLARGEMENT
AND BUNCH LENGTH IN SEEDLESS GRAPES. WE ALREADY
TALKED ABOUT HOW
AUXIN CAN STIMULATE THE INITIATION OF GROWTH
OF FRUIT
DEVELOPMENT. AND GIBBERELLINS CAN ACTUALLY
RESULT IN LARGER
FRUITS. HERE'S A, A BUNCH OF GRAPES THAT WEREN'T
TREATED WITH A
GIBBERELLIN SPRAY. AND HERE ARE SOME THAT
WERE TREATED WITH A
GIBBERELLIN SPRAY. SO GIBBERELLINS HAVE A
LOT OF USES. AND
THEY ALSO CAN BE PRODUCED BY PLANTS IN, AS
A WOUND RESPONSE AND
CAN PROMOTE HEALING IN RESPONSE TO WOUNDING.
THEY HAVE A NUMBER
OF RESPONSES. WE'RE JUST SORT OF SCRATCHING
THE SURFACE HERE IN
TERMS OF SOME OF THE MORE OUTSTANDING FUNCTIONS.
AND YOU'VE
PROBABLY SEEN BOLTING OCCUR BEFORE IN HERBS
THAT, HERBS THAT JUST
HAVE BASAL LEAVES UNTIL THEY START TO PRODUCE
A FLOWERING SHOOT.
AND THE PRODUCTION OF A FLOWERING SHOOT CAN
HAPPEN REALLY
QUICKLY, SO QUICKLY THAT IT'S CALLED BOLTING.
AND THIS IS
SOMETHING THAT'S STIMULATED BY GIBBERELLIC
ACID AS WELL.
AND
WHEN I ACTUALLY WAS A GSI IN A CLASS LIKE
THIS MANY YEARS AGO, WE
DIDN'T EVEN KNOW ABOUT THESE COMPOUNDS, THESE
BRASSINOSTEROIDS.
THESE HAVE JUST BEEN RECENTLY DISCOVERED TO
BE PLANT HORMONES.
AND THEY'RE ACTUALLY STEROIDS SIMILAR TO,
TO ANIMAL SEX HORMONES
IN TERMS OF THEIR OVERALL CHEMISTRY. BUT THEY'RE
SO SIMILAR IN
FUNCTION TO AUXIN IN TERMS OF PROMOTING ELONGATION
OF STEMS THAT
THEY WEREN'T RECOGNIZED AS DISTINCT FROM AUXIN.
AND IT'S PLANTS
LIKE THESE THAT ALLOW THEM TO BE RECOGNIZED.
THESE ARE, THESE
PLANTS ARE ONES, THESE LITTLE DWARF ONES HERE
ARE ONES THAT HAVE
MINIMAL INTERNODAL ELONGATION AND HAPPEN TO
BE MUTANTS THAT DON'T
PRODUCE BRASSINOSTEROIDS. AND THIS NAME BRASSINOSTEROIDS
COMES
FROM THE FACT THAT THESE WERE DISCOVERED IN
ARABIDOPSIS WHICH IS
THE MODEL SYSTEM FOR PLANT BIOLOGY AND IT'S
IN THE BRASSICACEAE
FAMILY OR THE MUSTARD FAMILY. JUST AN ASIDE.
BUT THAT'S WHAT
THE NAME COMES FROM. SO JUST TO LET YOU KNOW
THAT THESE ARE
STILL BEING DISCOVERED. THIS WAS A FAIRLY
RECENT DISCOVERY,
SIMILAR TO AUXIN. AND THIS IS A REALLY IMPORTANT
PLANT HORMONE,
ABSCISSIC ACID. WE JUST CALL IT ABA. THIS
ACTUALLY WORKS
ANTAGONISTICALLY TO GIBBERELLINS. AND THE
RELATIVE BALANCE OF
GIBBERELLINS AND ABA CAN BE IMPORTANT IN THE
GROWTH RESPONSE.
SO I MENTIONED GIBBERELLINS HAVE A REALLY
STRONGLY STIMULATIVE
EFFECT TO GROWTH AND SEED GERMINATION WHEREAS,
ABSCISSIC
ACID IS JUST THE OPPOSITE. IT'S IMPORTANT,
IT HAS AN INHIBITING
EFFECT ON STEM GROWTH. AND IT'S IMPORTANT
IN INDUCING SEED
DORMANCY AND PREPARING THE SEED FOR DESICCATION
AS THE SEED
MATURES. SO DORMANCY IN SEEDS IS USUALLY OFTEN
RESPONSIBLE,
ABSCISIC ACID'S OFTEN RESPONSIBLE FOR THAT.
AND IT REQUIRES
LONG PERIODS OF COLD OR SOME OTHER STIMULUS
TO BREAK DOWN ABA AND
RELEASE THE PLANT FROM THAT DORMANCY CONDITION.
INTERESTINGLY,
THERE ARE SOME PLANTS THAT DON'T PRODUCE MUCH
ABA IN THEIR SEEDS
AND DON'T HAVE DORMANCY. MANGROVES ARE REALLY
NOTABLE IN THIS
SENSE. THEY GERMINATE WHILE THEY'RE STILL
ON THE PARENT PLANT.
HERE YOU CAN SEE THE RADICLES, EMBRYONIC ROOTS
EMERGING FROM
SEEDS STILL IN THE FRUITS OF A MANGROVE THAT
HAVEN'T BEEN DROPPED
YET FROM THE PARENT PLANT. AND THIS KIND OF
PRECOCIOUS
GERMINATION IS IMPORTANT FOR THE SURVIVAL
OF MANGROVES. AND IT
JUST SO HAPPENS THAT THOSE SEEDS ARE REALLY
LACKING IN ABSCISIC
ACID.
ANOTHER THING THAT ABA DOES THAT HAS A GROWTH
INHIBITING
EFFECT BUT IT'S SUPER IMPORTANT FOR THE SURVIVAL
OF A PLANT IS
THAT ABA WILL SIGNAL THE CLOSURE OF THE GUARD
CELLS AND THE
CLOSURE OF THE STOMATES, STOMATA IN, IN RESPONSE
TO WILTING OR
ANY KIND OF DROUGHT STRESS THAT MIGHT BE PERCEIVED
IN THE ROOTS.
ABA WILL BE TRANSMITTED, FOR EXAMPLE, TO THE
ROOTS, TO THE SHOOT
BEFORE IT STARTS TO WILT. AND THIS SETS IN
MOTION THE RELEASE
OF, OF POTASSIUM IONS FROM THE GUARD CELLS.
SO THE SOLUTE
CONCENTRATION IS REDUCED IN THE GUARD CELLS,
AND WATER MOVES OUT
OF THE GUARD CELLS THROUGHOUT, BASED ON OSMOTIC
RESPONSE. SO
THAT'S, THAT'S CRUCIAL FOR PLANTS TO, TO KEEP
THEIR WATER BALANCE
INTACT. AND ABA IS THE IMPORTANT CHEMICAL
SIGNAL IN THIS
REGARD. SO AGAIN, ABSCISSIC ACID'S IMPORTANT
FOR DORMANCY,
CLOSING A STOMATA, AND IN GENERAL IT'S A GROWTH
INHIBITOR. AND
IT'S THIS BALANCE OF ABA AND GIBBERELLINS
THAT'S REALLY IMPORTANT
IN MANY CASES. ALL RIGHT, SO ETHYLENE IS A
SUBSTANCE THAT WAS
ONLY RECOGNIZED TO BE A PLANT GROWTH REGULATOR
RELATIVELY LATE.
AND THAT'S BECAUSE IT FUNCTIONS IN THE GAS
PHASE, WHICH IS A
BIZARRE THING FOR A HORMONE TO DO. BUT THIS
IS A VERY IMPORTANT
MOLECULE FOR SIGNALING THE ONSET OF, FOR EXAMPLE,
LEAF SENESCENCE
AND ABSCISSION IN DECIDUOUS PLANTS LIKE A
DECIDUOUS HARDWOOD
TREES. AND DECIDUOUS PLANTS HAVE WHAT'S CALLED
AN ABSCISSION
LAYER. IT'S A LITTLE LAYER OF PARENCHYMA AT
THE BASE OF THE
LEAF. THERE ARE NO FIBERS, SCLERIFIED CELLS
THAT CROSS THROUGH
THAT ZONE, SO THESE ARE JUST LIVING CELLS
THAT HAVE RELATIVELY
THIN CELL WALLS. AND ETHYLENE WHEN IT'S PRODUCED,
WHAT HAPPENS
FIRST IS THAT IT ACTUALLY RESULTS IN A PROGRAMMED
DEATH OF CELLS
INSIDE THE LEAF. SO THE LEAF WILL UNDERGO
THIS PROCESS WHERE
THE NUTRIENTS THAT ARE ENCLOSED OR CONTAINED
WITHIN THAT LEAF ARE
MOBILIZED BY THE BREAKDOWN OF SUBSTANCES IN
THE LEAF. AND THEN
THOSE ARE MOVED BACK INTO THE MAIN BODY OF
THE PLANT. AND THEN
THE ABSCISSION LAYER CHANGES START TO OCCUR
THERE WHERE ETHYLENE
WILL STIMULATE THE PRODUCTION OF ENZYMES THAT
BREAK DOWN THE CELL
WALLS OF THOSE PARENCHYMA CELLS IN THAT ABSCISSION
LAYER SUCH
THAT EVENTUALLY THE LEAF WILL JUST FALL OFF
BASED ON ITS OWN
WEIGHT OR BASED ON WIND. AND THEN CORK WILL
FORM OVER THAT
WOUND, SO THAT PREVENTS INFECTION OF THE PLANT.
SO ETHYLENE HAS
A REALLY IMPORTANT EFFECT IN, IN PROGRAMMED
CELL DEATH THAT CAN
BE IMPORTANT IN CAPTURING BACK THE NUTRIENTS
THAT A PLANT NEEDS
FROM TISSUES THAT ARE GOING TO BE DISCARDED.
AND IT ALSO HAS A
REALLY IMPORTANT EFFECT IN FRUIT RIPENING.
SO ETHYLENE IS
CRUCIAL IN FRUIT RIPENING RESPONSE. SO IT'S
INVOLVED IN BOTH
THE ENZYMATIC BREAKDOWN OF THE CELL WALLS.
I MEAN IT SIGNALS
THE ENZYMATIC, PRODUCTION OF ENZYMES THAT
BREAKDOWN THE CELL
WALLS OF, IN THE FRUIT WHICH MAKES THE FRUIT
SOFT, INEDIBLE IN
THAT SENSE. AND IT ALSO SIGNALS THE ENZYMES
OR IT, IT
RESULTS IN THE PRODUCTION OF ENZYMES THAT
CONVERT STARCH TO
SUGAR, SO MAKES THE FRUIT SWEET AS WELL SO
THE FRUIT BECOMES
ATTRACTIVE TO ANIMALS AND, THAT DISPERSE THE
SEEDS AS A RESULT.
AND THIS IS ONE OF THE FEW CASES IN BIOLOGY
OF A POSITIVE
FEEDBACK MECHANISM WHERE THE PRODUCTION OF
ETHYLENE LEADS TO
RIPENING. RIPENING THEN TRIGGERS MORE ETHYLENE
PRODUCTION. SO
THIS ETHYLENE PRODUCTION IS INCREASED. AND
AS A GAS, ETHYLENE
PRODUCED BY ONE FRUIT CAN TRIGGER THE RIPENING
OF OTHER FRUIT IN
CLOSE PROXIMITY, ESPECIALLY IF THEY'RE IN
CLOSED CONTAINERS LIKE
A PAPER BAG, FOR EXAMPLE. SO YOU'VE KNOW DOUBT
HAD THAT
EXPERIENCE WHERE ONE FRUIT CAN CAUSE THE,
ONE RIPE FRUIT CAN, CAN
BE IMPORTANT WITH REGARD TO THE RIPENING OF
OTHERS. AND SO
ETHYLENE SINCE IT WAS DISCOVERED AS BEING
IMPORTANT IN THIS
REGARD, IT'S USED COMMERCIALLY TO ALLOW FOR
THE PICKING OF FRUIT
WHEN IT'S STILL UNRIPE AND TRANSPORTING IT
WHILE IT'S UNRIPE SO
IT'S NOT DAMAGED DURING TRANSPORT AND THAT
IT LASTS. AND THEN
ETHYLENE GAS IS APPLIED AFTER TRANSPORTATION
OR AFTER THE FRUIT'S
READY TO BE MARKETED AND THE FRUIT WILL START
RIPENING AT THAT
POINT. AND YOU CAN STORE FRUIT FOR LONG PERIODS
OF TIME, FOR
MANY MONTHS IN AN UNRIPE STATE AS LONG AS
YOU CAN CONTROL THE
ETHYLENE PRODUCTION BY THE FRUIT. AND SO THERE
ARE VARIOUS
FILTRATION SYSTEMS THAT COMMERCIAL, THAT ARE
COMMERCIALLY
AVAILABLE TO REMOVE ETHYLENE. CARBON DIOXIDE'S
ALSO APPLIED TO
REMOVE ETHYLENE, SO THAT'S, THIS IS AN IMPORTANT
COMMERCIAL
SUBSTANCE AS WELL. OKAY. SO ETHYLENE THEN
IS REALLY IMPORTANT
IN BOTH LEAF ABSCISSION AND FRUIT RIPENING
AMONG OTHER THINGS.
SO THAT'S REALLY ALL I WANT TO SAY ABOUT PLANT
HORMONES PER SE.
WE CAN JUST SUMMARIZE THEM HERE. OF COURSE
THEY CAN HAVE A
VARIETY OF EFFECTS DEPENDING ON THE SITE OF
ACTION, CONCENTRATION
OF THE HORMONE, FOR EXAMPLE. AND THIS IS BASICALLY
WHAT I'M
SAYING HERE. DIFFERENT PLANT PARTS HAVE DIFFERENT
SENSITIVITIES
AND DIFFERENT CONCENTRATIONS. SO THIS WHOLE
NOTION OF
DIFFERENTIAL SENSITIVITY IS REALLY IMPORTANT.
AND FINALLY THE,
THEY OFTEN ACT TOGETHER. AND THIS, I'VE ALREADY
MENTIONED THIS
WITH REGARD TO AUXIN AND CYTOKININS WORKING
TOGETHER, THIS
HORMONE BALANCE IN REGARD TO THOSE TWO AND
THEN THE BALANCE IN
REGARD TO GIBBERELLINS AND ABA. SO THIS MAKES
THEM REALLY
DIFFICULT TO STUDY, OF COURSE. IT'S, IT'S
A MORE, IN MANY WAYS
MORE DIFFICULT THAN STUDYING ANIMAL HORMONE
ACTION. AND THERE'S
A LOT OF ACTIVITY STILL GOING ON IN TERMS
OF TRYING TO UNDERSTAND
HOW PLANT HORMONES OPERATE. BUT IT'S PRETTY
CLEAR THAT HORMONAL
BALANCE IS SUPER IMPORTANT IN PLANTS. OKAY,
SO IN THE LAST FEW
MINUTES I JUST WANT TO MENTION THAT PLANT
CHEMISTRY CAN ALSO BE
REALLY IMPORTANT IN TERMS OF PLANT DEFENSE.
AND, OF COURSE,
PLANTS ARE IN A, A REAL BIND WHEN IT COMES
TO DEFENDING
THEMSELVES WHEN THEY CAN'T GET UP AND MOVE.
THEY CAN'T WARD OFF
AN ENEMY OR AN ATTACKER BY GETTING AWAY FROM
IT. SO THEY HAVE
EVOLVED A NUMBER OF REALLY AMAZING STRATEGIES.
AND I'VE JUST
BROKEN THESE INTO MICROBIAL ATTACK VERSUS
ATTACK OF A
MACRO HERBIVORE. BUT IN TERMS OF SAY A BACTERIUM
OR A FUNGUS THAT
SAY MIGHT INVADE THE TISSUE THROUGH THE STOMATA
WHICH IS AN
OPENING, A NATURAL OPENING THAT PLANTS HAVE
TO KEEP OPEN BUT IT
DOES MAKE THEM VULNERABLE, THE CUTICLE CAN
WARD OFF A LOT OF
MICROBES, BUT THE STOMATES ARE ONE PLACE WHERE
THEY CAN BE
ATTACKED. A PARTICULAR MICROBE ENTERING THROUGH
THE STOMATES
CAN BE RECOGNIZED BY PLANTS. AND THERE ARE
PROTEINS THAT ARE
PRODUCED BY PLANT PATHOGENS, DISEASE-CAUSING
AGENTS THAT, WHERE
WE HAVE ESSENTIALLY AN ARMS RACE GOING ON
BETWEEN THE ATTACKER
AND THE PLANT IN TERMS OF THE PLANT'S ABILITY
TO RECOGNIZE THAT
ATTACKER, SO MUCH LIKE WE DO IN TERMS OF DISEASE
RESPONSE. AND
PLANTS, IF THEY RECOGNIZE THE ATTACKER, THEY
OFTEN HAVE A VERY
LOCAL AND SPECIFIC RESPONSE TO THAT PARTICULAR
AGENT. AND THEY
CAN PRODUCE A NATURAL PESTICIDE THAT WILL
BE DEADLY TO THAT
PARTICULAR AGENT. AND AT THE SAME TIME THEY
CAN UNDERGO
PROGRAMMED CELL DEATH IN THE REGION OF THAT
ATTACK. SO THEY CAN
WALL OFF THAT PART OF THEIR, THEIR BODY THAT'S
BEING ATTACKED BY
A MICROBE AND AT THE SAME TIME THAT THEY'RE
ATTACKING IT WITH A
NATURAL PESTICIDE. SO THIS IS WHAT WE CALL
A HYPERSENSITIVE
RESPONSE ON THE PART OF THE PLANT. OKAY, SO
THAT'S ONE WAY IN
WHICH THEY CAN PROTECT THEMSELVES FROM MICROBES.
AND WHEN
THEY'RE UNDERGOING AN ATTACK LIKE THAT, THIS
IS ALSO GOING TO
RESULT IN GENERAL STIMULATION OF PLANT DEFENSE
GENES IN GENERAL,
NOT JUST THE SPECIFIC ONES, BUT OTHER PLANT
DEFENSE GENES. AND
THIS CAN RESULT IN PROTECTION AGAINST THE
DIVERSITY OF PATHOGENS
THAT CAN LAST FOR A NUMBER OF DAYS. THIS IS
WHAT WE CALL
SYSTEMIC ACQUIRED RESISTANCE BY THE PLANT.
SO WE HAVE BOTH OF
THESE THINGS GOING ON IN THE CASE OF A MICROBIAL
ATTACK. OKAY,
AS FAR AS HERBIVORES GO, SO BIG CHOMPING ANIMALS
FOR EXAMPLE,
ARTHROPODS LIKE INSECTS OR MITES OR LARGER
VERTEBRATE HERBIVORES,
THESE CAN BE WARDED OFF BY PHYSICAL DEFENSES
OF COURSE LIKE THE
CUTICLES, SPINES, THINGS LIKE THAT, HAIRS
ON THE LEAF THAT ARE
DIFFICULT TO, FOR AN INSECT TO PENETRATE OR
GLANDULAR EXUDATES,
THEY PRODUCE. BUT THOSE GLANDULAR EXUDATES
AND CHEMISTRY THAT'S
INSIDE THE, THE LEAF OF THE PLANT CAN ALSO
BE IMPORTANT IN
WARDING OFF HERBIVORES BY PRODUCE, THESE SUBSTANCES
WHICH ARE
CALLED SECONDARY METABOLITES WHICH ARE JUST
BASICALLY ANY
CHEMICAL THAT'S PRODUCED BY A PLANT THAT'S
NOT INVOLVED, THAT'S
NOT NECESSARY FOR SURVIVAL IN REPRODUCTION
OF THE PLANT PER SE.
THESE, THERE'S A VAST DIVERSITY OF CHEMICALS
THAT PLANTS PRODUCE
THAT ARE NOT INVOLVED IN PRIMARY METABOLISM.
AND WHEN I WAS A
GRAD, AN UNDERGRADUATE, THE TYPICAL PLANT
ECOLOGIST WAS
UNWILLING TO ACCEPT THAT THESE CHEMICALS WEREN'T
JUST WASTE
PRODUCTS. YOU KNOW PLANTS CAN'T EASILY EXCRETE
THEIR WASTE, SO
THESE ARE JUST ACCUMULATED WASTE PRODUCTS.
BUT IT TURNS OUT
THAT, THAT THESE CHEMICALS OFTEN HAVE A REALLY,
REALLY ARE
IMPORTANT IN, IN WARDING OFF ATTACK BY PARTICULAR
HERBIVORES.
THEY'RE EITHER TOXIC, DIRECTLY TOXIC TO THE
HERBIVORE OR THEY'RE
DISTASTEFUL. AND IN GENERAL THEY'RE HARMFUL
TO THEIR ENEMIES.
ALSO IN SOME CASES THE ACTUAL ATTACK, THE
SALIVA, FOR EXAMPLE, OF
THE ATTACKER IS RECOGNIZED BY THE PLANT AND
THE PLANT CAN PRODUCE
VOLATILE AIRBORNE CHEMICALS THAT WILL SIGNAL
THAT THIS ATTACKER
IS PRESENT. AND HERE WE CAN SEE, FOR EXAMPLE,
SOME MITES THAT
ARE ATTACKING SOME TOMATOES. VOLATILE CHEMICAL'S
PRODUCED. FOR
EXAMPLE, HERE IS A PREDATORY MITE, PICKS UP
ON THIS VOLATILE
CHEMICAL THAT'S CARRIED IN THE AIR AND THAT
INITIATES A RESPONSE
ON THE PART OF THE MITE TO GO TO THE TOMATO
PLANT BECAUSE THAT'S,
THAT'S LIKE RINGING THE FOOD BELL. MEANS THAT
THERE ARE, THERE'S
A TASTY ITEM ON THOSE TOMATO PLANTS, AND THE
PREDATORY MITES THEN
COME TO THE RESCUE. SO THIS IS ESSENTIALLY
LIKE A CHEMICAL CALL
FOR HELP BY THE PLANT. OF COURSE, THE PREDATORY
MITE DOESN'T
REALLY HAVE ALTRUISTIC INTENTIONS TO GO TO
RESCUE THE PLANT, BUT
IT RESCUES THE PLANT ANYWAYS BY COMING AND
EATING ITS ATTACKER.
SO PLANTS HAVE ALL KINDS OF PHYSICAL DEFENSES,
CHEMICAL DEFENSES
LIKE ALKALOIDS, TERPENES, AND OTHER SECONDARY
CHEMICALS THAT
WE'RE FAMILIAR WITH THAT ARE, CAN BE HIGHLY
TOXIC TO US OR, OR
CAN BE USEFUL IN VARIOUS WAYS. AND THEY EVEN
CAN BASICALLY
BRING ON AN ATTACKER. THEY CAN WARN NEIGHBORING
PLANTS ABOUT
THE PRESENCE OF AN ATTACKER THAT CAN ALSO
HELP WITH REGARD TO,
WITH, FOR EXAMPLE, SIGNALING CLOSE RELATIVES
OF THE PRESENCE OF
AN ATTACKER. SO PLANTS DO A LOT OF AMAZING
THINGS. AND I HOPE
THAT THIS PART OF THE COURSE HAS BEEN INTERESTING
TO YOU. AND
IF DO YOU HAVE MORE INTEREST IN LEARNING MORE
ABOUT PLANT AND
FUNGAL DIVERSITY OR ECOLOGY AND EVOLUTION,
THERE'S A LOT OF
COURSES OFFERED HERE AT CAL BECAUSE WE HAVE
THE NATURAL HISTORY
MUSEUMS. THERE ARE A LOT OF FACULTY HERE THAT
STUDY ORGANISMS
OF GREAT DIVERSITY. AND THESE ARE JUST A FEW
OF THE COURSES
THAT, ON BEHALF OF MYSELF AND THE OTHER INSTRUCTORS,
I WANT TO
STRONGLY ENCOURAGE YOU TO CONSIDER TAKING
AFTER YOU PASS THIS
COURSE WHICH WILL, IS THE MAJOR PREREQUISITE
FOR, FOR MOST OF
THESE COURSES. SO IT'S BEEN A PLEASURE HAVING
YOU IN THE COURSE
AND GOOD LUCK WITH STUDYING. HOPE TO SEE YOU
WEDNESDAY.
[APPLAUSE]. THANKS.