and the psychedelic return
of an internet legend.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
JACOB SOBOROFF: This
is YouTube Nation.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
JACOB SOBOROFF:
Competitive gaming is huge.
Over 30 million people
watched the League of Legends
season three
championship-- 30 million.
Season four starts today.
But old school gaming, it
is alive and well, too.
Motherboard from VICE
made this short doc
about one of the greatest
rivalries in gaming history,
ironically, between a plastic
surgeon and a bodybuilder.
VINCENT: Now, I don't want
to see Hank win again.
But I think that if I
win, people will never
be mad to see me win, because,
I mean, come on, look at me.
HANK: I don't feel like
Vincent is nipping at my heels.
I'm not too worried about him.
No matter what score he puts
up, I could probably top it.
JACOB SOBOROFF:
Competitive "Donkey Kong"
went mainstream in 2007 with
the cult hit "King of Kong."
And this picks up
where that left off.
HANK: My mind is just
cluttered with barrels.
VINCENT: Who's going to win,
the muscle or the brain?
And of course, the
muscle will win.
JACOB SOBOROFF: Watch to
see these titans clash
and find out who wins.
BEN: I've seen a
million skate videos,
but I've never seen
anything like this.
I shared it as soon as I saw it.
They call this foot
twerking in the description,
but it's pretty much just
doing unbelievable tricks
on long boards
that are so heavy,
they're usually only
used for cruising.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
The music, the locations,
the skating-- pretty much
everything about this
captures the LA vibe
I want everyone to see.
JACOB SOBOROFF: Last weekend,
the Dallas Safari Club
auctioned off a permit to hunt
the endangered African black
rhino.
Really?
Thankfully, this next video
is the opposite of that.
A British wildlife photographer
built this tiny helicopter
that's flying the camera.
He controls it remotely while
he's watching a live feed.
He's got a range of
over half a mile.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
JACOB SOBOROFF: It kind
of feels like "The Lion
King" in real life.
You've got to love
a guy who says
his goal is to inspire people
to celebrate and conserve
the natural wonders
of our planet.
CARLY: You know
that inner scream
that you get when
someone tries to show you
952 photos from a
trip they just took?
Well, this guy is completely
changing the game.
To remember his 100-day
study abroad program in China
last fall, Dartmouth
sophomore Jake Gaba
filmed himself
dancing in over 60
locations across the country.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CARLY: Love the moves,
love but shorts.
Jake, you have
officially inspired
me to start saving
for my own adventure.
JACOB SOBOROFF: The friend
zone-- you've been there.
I've been there-- not a fan.
The most recent video from
sketch comedy gurus Extremely
Decent speaks to all the
dudes trapped in limbo.
[MUSIC - UNSUNG
HEROES, "NICE GUYS"]
JACOB SOBOROFF: They've only
been around for one year,
but I went to their
channel to watch one video,
and it is easy to get
sucked in for an hour.
This poke at Facebook racked
up four million views.
MALE SPEAKER: Now it's way
easier for your friends
to keep you in the know.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Nick, hi.
Can you come to
my birthday party?
Nick, would you vote for
my brother in his contest?
Nick, will you come to
my improv show tonight?
NICK: No, I'm not
going to any of those.
JACOB SOBOROFF: "Nice
Guys" is just the first
in a series of
Unsung Hero videos.
You've got a suggestion for
the next one, go over there.
Give them a comment.
I vote for my wife,
because you have no idea.
There is absolutely no way
we can watch every video,
so we rely on you
guys to send us
the stuff that you
find or create.
ALEX: Hi, I'm Alex, and
I'm a curator on the show.
And I come across
all kinds of videos
while looking for
stuff to feature.
But this part of
the show will be
where you can have
a chance to tell us
about your finds--
maybe something
crazy, like this video, from
the guy who did Nyan Cat.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
JACOB SOBOROFF: Thank you, Alex.
The original Nyan Cat video
has over 100 million views.
You want your face right here,
make a video like Alex did,
upload it to your
channel, post a link
with the hashtag #youtubenation.
You want some more?
Links are below.
Playlists are about
to pop up, including
one with all of today's videos.
If you like what you see, be
kind, of subscribe-- scribe--
subscribe.
Now, play out-- controller
hacker Robert Delong.
[MUSIC - ROBERT DELONG, "HAPPY"]