People say, where do you think
your project fits within this
greater discussion about
gun control?
[MUSIC PLAYING]
If we could print a gun, other
people could do this.
Like what if we gave it away,
open source style?
What would that mean?
Gun control, for us,
is a fantasy.
In a way that like people say,
you're being unrealistic about
printing a gun.
I think it's more unrealistic
now, especially going forward,
to think you could ever control
this technology.
The only things recognized and
promulgated in this culture
are irreversible.
To have a symbolic gift like the
printable gun does so much
ideological damage and violence
to these ideas.
Simply that, like, it
can't be ignored.
[GUN SHOT]