For thusands of years Iceland's volcanoes were locked in a titanic battle with ice
But then, 12.000 years ago, the giant ice sheets finally retreated
This would open a new chapter in Iceland's volcanic history,
as they were now free to wreak havoc
But, what effect would this have on Iceland and its surroundings?
One of the most dramatic effects can be found in the south-central region of the island
This alien landscape is known as Laki
A road of strange craters and solidified lava flows
that have bubbled up from a huge tear in the earth
A massive fissure eruption, it stretches for an astounding 16 miles (25 Km) across the landscape
Volcanologist Dr. Thor Thordarson is investigating Laki,
the site of one of the greatest eruptions in recent history,
one which would have devastating effects worldwide
The Laki fissures, which extend from here in the southwest,
continue here through the landscape as roll cones, up in through Mount Laki
which was split into 2 during the eruption
and continue futher to the northeast all the way to the margins of the glaciers here
Eyewitness accounts accurately date the eruption to 1783
This was one of the most disastrous years in Icelandic history
Fallout from the eruption caused harvests all over the island to fail
75% of the livestock died, plunging Iceland into a great famine which killed 10.000 people
But mysteriously, at the same time the rest of the northern hemisphere
reported freakishly cold weather
Averaging 2,3 ºF (1,28ºC) below normal, the northern hemisphere froze over
The North Sea along the coast of Holland froze,
so people skated between villages along the coast
There was on Mississippi down by New Orleans in that winter
For many years it was thought the Laki eruption and this climatic events were unrelated,
but advances in geology found it wasn't just a bizarre coincidence
Comparing eyewitness accounts with the geological remains
Dr. Thordarson has reconstructed what happened
He discovered that the eruption started with a bang on the morning of June 8, 1783
It sent rocks flying high into the air
and ripped the earth open along a 1 mile (1,6 Km) tear
But this was just the beginning
3 days later, a second eruption ripped open, then a 3rd, 4th, 5th...
In total, the earth unzipped along 10 vast tears in the crust
erupting lava continuously for over 8 months
The mammoth amounts of lava that poured out of the ground here
would have buried Manhattah to a depth of 830 feet (250 m)
But how an eruption on this small, remote island could cause climatic chaos
thousands of miles away, remained a mystery
The evidence that would link Laki with this worldwide catastrophe
was locked inside these boulders
The story is in the rocks. This rock here is part of
the material, the magma that came out during the eruption
These holes are cold bubbles,
and they form as the magma raises from deep within the ground and approaches the surface
and it really starts to boil!
The gas, which is dissolved in the magma at depth, goes into the bubbles
then it escapes into the atmosphere
When this bubble rock erupted onto the surface
it would have poured gas out into the Icelandic atmosphere
Could this gas have caused climatic chaos across the globe?
The identity of this gas can be found in the microscopic structure of the rock
If you look closely at this rock, you can see a lot of white specks
these little white specks are the crystals who grow in the magma at depth
Sometimes this crystals, as they're growing, they would encapsulate
pristine magma and bring it up to the surface
Like time capsules, the white crystals contained untouched magma from deep in the earth
locked away since 1783
Dr. Thordarson has analysed this magma and found it to contain poisonous Sulphur Dioxide
And because there was so much lava here, it would have released enormous amounts
A staggering 100 million tons of Sulphur Dioxide gas was pumped into the atmosphere
But how could gases released from Laki cause bitterly cold weather across the globe?
The answer laid in accounts of a thick, red fog reported over Iceland in June 1783
Within a few weeks it had been blown over London and Paris
By July, it had dispersed across the entire northern hemisphere
Scientists now know that the red fog was caused by the Sulphur Dioxide which rose high into the air
Mixing with water, it created a Sulphuric Acid haze
The haze blocked out the sun, and it sent temperatures plummeting
As a result, the northern hemisphere endured 3 bitterly cold winters
which brought spring floods, famine and widespread poverty to Europe
Some historians have long believed that these climatic conditions
triggered social and political unrest, which led to the French Revolution in 1789
But scientists now suspect Laki had ramifications even further afield
The cold temperatures in the north changed air currents in the south
causing dramatic climate changes
India was hit by a terrible drought
People say that more than half a million people died from the drought in India
Also, this change in atmospheric circulation caused a very cold summer in Japan
It was cold and wet
The rice harvest failed,
and the result was the greatest famine in japanese history
It is estimated that Laki killed over 2 million people worldwide,
and was one of the most devastating volcanic eruptions in the history of mankind
The evidence has proven that Iceland's recent volcanic history
has had a devastating effect on the island and the rest of the world
Enormous lava fields reveal that Laki was a gigantic eruption
Bubbles in the rock indicate that huge volumes of gas were released from Laki
The white crystals reveal that this gas was poisonous Sulphur Dioxide,
evidence that Iceland's volcanoes caused climatic mayhem across the globe
But eruptions like Laki may not be confined to the past
Some believe that the balance between fire and ice is shifting,
and has the potential to propel Iceland into another hell on earth
The evidence is mounting, that Iceland has the potential to be the most lethal island on the planet
A fearsome volcanic force lies beneath it, creating powerful volcanoes
capable of generating gigantic lava flows and altering global climates
Yet many of Iceland's volcanoes are covered in glaciers,
fire and ice are held in a delicate balance
Scientists fear if this balance were tipped the volcanoes favour,
Iceland could become even deadlier
If the remaining ice were to melt,
what effect would it have on the activity of Iceland's volcanoes?
The first clue in the investigation lies in these innocuous-looking piles of rock and rubble
They're found all over Iceland,
and yet this rocks don't come from a volcano
They're Morraines:
The geological term for rock piles deposited at the mouth of a glacier
These deposits are evidence that the glaciers are shrinking
Year by year, the glacier has melted and retreated back up the valley,
leaving a Morraine like this behind
Dr. Roberts has studied the Vatnajökull glacier for the last ten years
and has noticed this dramatic trend
The glacier is retreating at a remarkable rate since I've been visiting the area
I've seen tremendous changes. The ice has retreated annually at a rate of about
200 feet (61 m) per year. This lake over here used to be filled with ice
I've seen the ice progressively melt, this morraine has formed,
this whole valley has become almost bare
Maybe in the next 20 years this whole glacier will disappear and a lake will form in that valley
Iceland's glaciers are melting at an unprecedented rate
With 5% of Iceland's ice caps melting in the last 40 years,
the question that scientists are keen to understand
is: What effect this rapid melting will have on the volcanoes that lie beneath?
The only other time that glaciers have melted this quickly
is when Iceland came out of the last Ice Age
But what can past events tell us about the future?
Geologist professor Bill McGuire is investigating how volcanic activity changed
at the end of the last Ice Age
And he's unearthed some surprising results
Around about 11 or 12 thousand years ago you started to see quite rapid melting of glaciers
in Iceland and elsewhere
And that triggered a recognisable increase of volcanic activity,
because you were removing this large mass of ice very, very quickly
The rapid melting of ice kick-starts volcanic eruptions beneath
Volcanic eruptions are triggered by the gas in the magma,
which expands to form bubbles and the bubbles drive the eruption
It's rather like taking the cork out of a bottle of champagne
Now, if you have a very heavy weight on top of a volcano,
if it's a heavy mass of water or ice,
that can help supress eruptive activity
But when ice melts quickly, this downward pressure is suddenly released
and that's when the trouble starts
As the ice melts, so the pressure on the magma underneath is reduced,
the gas in the magma can form bubbles, they can coalesce and they can eventually
drive the magma upwards towards the surface and trigger
other explosive eruptions or effusions of lava that are spared out at a huge distances
Iceland's glaciers are melting rapidly
This has led scientists to believe that a devastating eruption on the scale of Laki
could happen again
The question is WHEN? These are things that we have to think about
and try to prepare ourselves to deal with if they happen in our lifetime
Is it possible that we can get another eruption like this in Iceland?
Definetely
The investigation has revealed how the vast and voilent island of Iceland was formed
Cracks in the Thingvellir plane and traces of chemicals in the rocks
revealed how the Mid-Atlantic Ridge and Hot Spot joined forces to create a collossal volcanic force
Massive fissure eruptions ripped the land open
Hemorrhaging millions of tons of lava, Iceland rapidly formed
Deep northern fjords were evidence that a giant ice sheet eroded the land
and entombed the volcanoes, locking fire and ice in a titanic battle
Boulders strewn in an ancient valley reveal how fire emerged victorious
unleashing cataclysmic floods
And specks of Sulphur in the rocks showed how Iceland's volcanoes
have the potential to cause global destruction
Now, glaciers melting above some of the world's most deadly volcanoes
are increasing the threat of future eruptions
Over the last 20 million years, Iceland's almighty volcanic force
has created a vast, alien landscape
Volatile and unpredictable, it may one day unleash a massive eruption
which could devastate both Iceland and a wider world beyond
English captions and subtitles by Marc Gelizo     --for a non-profit use--