single loss of life when five
soldiers from two rifles were
killed in one IED blast.
AMERICAN SOLDIER: With
IEDs, it's all luck.
I've been really I haven't
stepped on one, and a couple
of people have just stepped
in the wrong spot
at the wrong time.
MALE SPEAKER: Are we good?
[EXPLOSION]
AMERICAN SOLDIER:
Is anybody hit?
Is anyone hit?
AMERICAN SOLDIER: Can
you stand up?
MALE SPEAKER: Huh?
AMERICAN SOLDIER: Can you see?
AMERICAN SOLDIER: Can
you stand up?
MALE SPEAKER:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
MALE SPEAKER: What?
AMERICAN SOLDIER:
Hold on to me.
Let's go.
MICHAEL HASTINGS: Well, first
off, I just want to thank
Powerhouse for having us here.
This is one of my favorite spots
in all of the greater
Tri-State Area.
They have a bunch
of great events.
And it's really an
honor to be here.
So Ben is someone whose work
I've respected and admired for
its bravery, its courage, and
also his willingness to get
shot at in many places
around the globe.
So Ben's book, "No Worse
Enemy." you're
a documentary filmmaker.
Why did you decide to
write the book?
BEN ANDERSON: Originally I had
no intention to write a book.
It was just one documentary at
a time, mostly for the BBC,
then HBO, then BBC again.
But about 18 months ago, the
statements were coming out of
Kabul, London, and Washington
about how progress was being
made, our goals were being met,
the Afghans were almost
ready to take over so
we could leave with
our heads held high.
And I feel that's the exact
opposite of what I'd been
seeing for the last
five years.
I never believed it when
an author said, I
had to write a book.
But suddenly, I thought, I
have to write this book.
I have to get everything I've
seen and filmed down on paper
in one place.
And apart from literally a
handful of quotes in here from
my notebooks, it's all
from my own footage.
So it's not my opinion.
I'm not exaggerating.
it's a really simple portrait of
what the war actually looks
like, because that's so
different to the war that
we're being told is
going on now.
MICHAEL HASTINGS: Now the
strategy that we have is the
reason we could pull out, in
theory, because there's the
Afghan national security
forces, the
police, and the army.
You have a clip, I think, that
demonstrates the equality of--
I feel like it's easy to bash
the Afghans, and especially in
the US, we often do that.
You'll read the "New York Times
well, everything would
be going well in the Afghanistan
War if the Afghans
weren't such fuck-ups.
At the same time, you have
this great clip.
Why don't you introduce the
clip, and we'll start with
that to give us a flavor
of the real war that
you don't often see.
BEN ANDERSON: OK.
This clip is from my first trip
to Afghanistan in 2007,
and it's not an exceptional
clip at all.
We'd been under attack
for about six hours.
A Hellfire missile had struck
a building-- the wrong
building by mistake,
where British and
Afghan soldiers were.
We thought they'd been killed.
So we ran across a field under
Taliban fire into this
building to check
on these guys.
Found out they were all
OK, miraculously.
The British responded by saying,
this is the most
intense day of fighting
they'd ever had.
The Afghans responded by
skinning up a huge joint.
And you'll see what
happens next.
BRITISH SOLDIER: I don't
understand how they could
smoke it in the middle
of a battle.
It'd make you worse.
But they love it.
As soon as they get two minutes,
then they'll start
smoking and passing it around.
All laughing and joking.
And then a minute
later, they're
running out towards bullets.
BEN ANDERSON: But I thought it
might make them more cautious.
BRITISH SOLDIER: Yeah.
It would make me
more cautious.
BEN ANDERSON: But apparently
it has the opposite effect.
BRITISH SOLDIER: Yeah.
They love it.
BEN ANDERSON: So the Afghan--
they got stoned for
about an hour.
They were completely
out of control.
One of them had eyes pointing
different directions.
And he actually ran out and he
was so stoned that he was just
aiming at something
in the sky.
And I don't know if you saw it,
but a bullet came and shot
the top cover off his rifle,
which was pretty funny, when
you look at that footage.
But afterwards, we thought,
actually, a few inches up and
we'd have seen a guy getting
his head blown off
right next to us.
And it is difficult to bash
the Afghan National Army.
The Afghan National Police, I'm
actually happy to bash.
They're hate and feared by
the local population.
I spoke to one of the Northern
Irish guys training the Afghan
National Police, and he said 90%
of the crime in Helmand is
committed by the police.
And bear in mind that the
counterinsurgency policy is,
we're trying to persuade the
Afghans to choose us and the
Afghan security forces
over the Taliban.
It's no surprise that lots of
people in the south are going
to choose the Taliban, and see
the Taliban as the good guys.
MICHAEL HASTINGS: One of the
incredible moments in your
book, when you're sort of
explaining your reporting
techniques, you said you went
through and had what the
Afghans said translated versus
what people thought they said
at the time, and there were
big discrepancies.
Can you talk about this sort of
lost in translation aspect
of the conflict?
BEN ANDERSON: First of I was
always shocked by how few
American and British forces
learned Pashto or Dari.
And most of that is because
they do six-month tours.
And you can't learn about a
local culture and establish
relations in six months.
But for some reason, the
interpreters they employ would
often mistranslate things.
So there was a meeting with a
mullah in Sangin where he came
out of his mosque.
And he lived about 100 meters
away from a US base.
So if anyone's benefiting
from our presence there,
it should be him.
And he came out, and he said,
yesterday you shot my daughter.
A stray bullet hit her
in the shoulder.
And you wouldn't let us through
the checkpoint.
We had to take her
to hospital.
It took seven hours.
How do you expect us to embrace
you when this is how
you treat us?
The translation was, we're
very glad you're here,
security's improved, and my
kids can play outside.
And I had no idea of this until
I got back to London and
sat down with a really good
translator and went through
all of my tapes, one by one.
MICHAEL HASTINGS: That's
incredible.
Now, you mentioned just briefly
the old man who
brought his daughter
who'd been shot.
Can you talk a little bit about
the solatia payments, or
the payments we actually make
to Afghan civilians, the
families of Afghan civilians
who die?
BEN ANDERSON: Every time there
are civilian casualties,
there's a condolence payment
meeting the next day.
And the British actually pay
less than the Americans, but
the Americans pay $2,500
per life lost.
AMERICAN SOLDIER: There's
nothing we can do to bring
back your loss.
What we can do is try to help
you out by giving you the very
least that we can with a payment
for your losses.
AMERICAN SOLDIER: And again,
I'm, I'm deeply, deeply sorry.
AMERICAN SOLDIER: Gentlemen,
this is for you.
For your losses.
MICHAEL HASTINGS: What do you
think's going through that
guy's mind, when he's hearing
this from foreigners?
And what do you think
he did afterwards?
You think he joined the
Taliban or just
went on with his life?
BEN ANDERSON: I spent a lot of
time in Marja after the that
incident, and surprisingly,
he forgave the Marines.
I think he realized it was a
mistake, and he had a very
good relationship with
the Marines.
And the thing he was most angry
about at that meeting,
initially, was that McChrystal
and everybody had made a big--
Marja was announced months in
advance, so the Taliban had
months to prepare.
They built incredible networks
of bunkers and trenches and
set booby traps everywhere.
But they said to the civilians,
we're not going to
use any rockets that can pierce
the thick walls of your
house, so stay indoors.
Don't flee.
We're here to protect you.
And he said, I did what
you told me to do.
I waited inside my house
for four days.
All you had to do was shout,
and I would have walked
towards you.
And then there was nothing
but you and the Taliban.
And that's what he was most
mad about, was he'd done
exactly what he was told to
do, and he still lost four
family members as a result.
MICHAEL HASTINGS: The IED, the
Improvised Explosive Device,
it's what terrorizes both, I
think, NATO troops and also
local civilians.
Can you set up this
next clip for us?
Feel free to talk about your
own experience, obviously,
with the improvised
explosive device.
BEN ANDERSON: The last clip is
from Sangin, which is probably
the town in the whole of
Afghanistan, outside of Kabul,
which has had more manpower and
resources devoted to it
for longer than anywhere else.
And this was my last
trip to Afghanistan
with Three Five Marines.
And the IED threat was so bad
that it took four hours to
walk two kilometers
on a patrol.
You had to walk in single file,
and you literally had to
walk in the bootprints of the
minesweeper in front of you.
The man at the end of the
command wire has let us walk
over the daisy chain.
He knows there are more
Marines coming behind.
AMERICAN SOLDIER: Hey, we're
going to have to get
on the other one.
AMERICAN SOLDIER: [INAUDIBLE]
good?
[EXPLOSION]
AMERICAN SOLDIER:
Is anybody hit?
Is anyone hit?
BEN ANDERSON: Five of the
seven bombs went off.
AMERICAN SOLDIER: See
where it's at?
It was right there.
BEN ANDERSON: Just seconds after
we had walked over them.
AMERICAN SOLDIER: Can
you stand up?
MALE SPEAKER: Huh?
AMERICAN SOLDIER: Can you see?
AMERICAN SOLDIER: Can
you stand up?
MALE SPEAKER: He
can't hear you.
MICHAEL HASTINGS: Again,
incredible footage.
This is the first time I've
watched an IED go off in a
while because I can't even
watch this shit.
What keeps bringing
you back there?
Are they noble reasons?
Are they selfish reasons?
Are they adrenaline reasons?
BEN ANDERSON: It's certainly
not adrenaline.
I mean, people who say that that
is a thrill I don't think
have really experienced it or
been close to real ambushes or
firefights.
It's hard, because once you've
covered this stuff for a
while, other stories--
I mean, I try and cover the
Republican nomination, I try
and follow British politics,
and it just feels boring.
This, to me, feels like one
of the most important
stories in the world.
And now, when you ask
me a question
like that, it's scary.
But when you're out there, you
compare yourself to everyone
around you.
And the people around me
have to kill people.
They maybe have to save
their friends lives.
I don't have to do either
of those things.
And the civilians around me, the
ones who are too poor to
leave, they're really
suffering.
I mean, compared to all
of those people,
I'm kind of a VIP.
I've got a cushy job,
compared to them.
So that makes me think
I can keep on going
back and doing more.
And I really want to know
what happens out there.
I'm not at all optimistic about
the future, but I really
want to know how it turns out.
And sadly, there aren't
that many people
covering this anymore.
MICHAEL HASTINGS: Can you
describe the process of you
with the camera?
BEN ANDERSON: Everything I'd
need, I carry on my back.
And that means that I can join
an infantry group like these
guys and stay with them
for five or six weeks.
And if I sleep where they sleep
and run the same risks
they run and eat what they
eat, they open up to me.
And the goal is to film exactly
what the war really
looks like.
And I'm sure it's impossible
with me being there.
I'm sure they temper their
behavior slightly because I'm
there, but I think I've got
quite close to seeing how they
would have behaved if
I wasn't there.
MICHAEL HASTINGS: Great.
Well, I want to again thank
Powerhouse for having us in,
and also you all for
coming out and for
being engaged in this--
obviously, we spend $120
billion on it a year.
I think over a thousand
Americans have died there
since President Obama's been
elected, not to mention the
thousands of Afghan civilians.
So on that cheerful note, I want
to recommend Ben's book
very highly.
As a fellow author who does
these things, if you come,
please buy the book.
Come on.
Just shell out for the
fucking thing.
We're here, he'll
sign it for you.
It'll be good.
I'll buy your book when
it comes out too.
Just email me.
And just thanks again.
This has been a really, I think,
hopefully a thoughtful,
fruitful discussion.
And Ben's one of the best
journalists, documentary
filmmakers, who's out
there working today.
So I'd like to give Ben
a round of applause
and call it a night.
[APPLAUSE]
AMERICAN SOLDIER: This is life
in Afghanistan, see.