Social norms completely
out the window.
You are about to enter
into the twin zone.
[HUMMING]
[MUSIC]
CHRIS NIERATKO: Allow me to
introduce you to Sydney and
Thurman Sewell, AKA
the ATL twins.
About a year and a half ago, I
was in Atlanta for a Red Bull
skate tour for "Skateboarder
Magazine." My roommate and
photographer, Jonathan Mehring,
said he had just met
these gangster-ass twins who
sleep in the same bed, and
only fuck the same girl.
I pulled up my pants.
And I told my roommate,
take me to them.
The short of it is, they live
together in Atlanta in a high
rise and share everything--
clothes, women.
They were both engaged to the
same Penthouse pet, and are
both looking forward to marrying
the same woman and
fathering the same child.
The long of it is that they're
the most unique twins I've
ever come across, and are a
psychologist's wet dream.
I interviewed them for vice.com
in a twin story so
amazing, so unique, that it got
millions of page views in
the first two days.
Over the last year and change,
the twins have blown up.
They modeled in a fashion shoot
for "Purple Magazine,"
shot by Terry Richardson, made
the "Rolling Stones'" 2012 hot
list, and now starring in
Harmony Korine's new movie,
"Spring Breakers," where they
play drug dealers alongside
James Franco.
Judging from internet comment
boards, people love
to hate on the twins.
And some people doubt
they're even real.
But I assure you, they are.
And no one knows the full
story, until now.
-Yeah.
I'm walking to the courthouse
right now.
CHRIS NIERATKO: They live
double lives, working as
paralegals by day, and
gangster-ass Don Juans to
Atlanta's singles scene
on a nightly basis.
We've never seen the likes of
Sydney and Thurman Sewell.
And I doubt the world
is ready.
We are in Hotlanta.
And we are going to visit my
buddies, Sydney and Thurman
Sewell, better known to America
as the ATL twins.
SIDNEY SEWELL: You could
braid my hair.
That would be pretty amazing.
THURMAN SEWELL: Yeah.
I'm not sure it's long enough.
SIDNEY SEWELL: It's
long enough.
Trust me.
CHRIS NIERATKO: So when I first
met yous guys, you were
big fish, small pond.
Now yous guys have blown
up since then.
What's changed since
I met you?
THURMAN SEWELL: Shit, man.
We've got some good
opportunities, man.
A lot of people reached
out to us after that--
like, big names.
SIDNEY SEWELL: In that thing,
it said our dream was to
become reality stars, which
I don't know if we
ever even said that.
Maybe we did, wasted.
THURMAN SEWELL: And then
Harmony hit us up, and
Harmony's like, don't fucking
do any reality shows.
We went and met with Harmony.
SIDNEY SEWELL: It was
just magical.
We just clicked, man.
I mean, seriously, we
was in Nashville.
THURMAN SEWELL: And he was
talking about I'm doing this
movie, "Spring Breakers."
SIDNEY SEWELL: Told us all
about "Spring Breakers."
THURMAN SEWELL: The script's
already done.
But I'm gonna fucking find
a part for you guys.
SIDNEY SEWELL: Filming "Spring
Breakers" was like one of the
best times of our lives.
And we look at things
differently
now because of that.
THURMAN SEWELL: To
be in a movie, a
Harmony Korine movie--
we're huge fans of Harmony
Korine, before we ever met the
motherfucker.
SIDNEY SEWELL: He's
not mainstream.
But if you know what's up, you
would know who Harmony is.
CHRIS NIERATKO: He wrote yous
guys in, didn't he?
THURMAN SEWELL: There was a
part for a drug dealer on
Franco's clique.
He was like, I'm just
gonna make it two.
CHRIS NIERATKO: Why do
you think you guys
get hated on so much?
SIDNEY SEWELL: Why do we?
THURMAN SEWELL: I think
people just hate, yo.
SIDNEY SEWELL: People
think we're wiggers.
CHRIS NIERATKO: You think that's
what it comes down to?
THURMAN SEWELL: A
lot of haters.
SIDNEY SEWELL: A lot of
people talking shit.
Meth-head, fucking crack head,
inbred, white trash, twincest.
We've heard it all.
THURMAN SEWELL: I guess,
what was it?
If you're not getting hated on,
then you're not doing it?
I guess we're doing it.
SIDNEY SEWELL: They have
this vision of us--
THURMAN SEWELL: They
think we're real
thugged out or something.
SIDNEY SEWELL: And wiggery.
You know what I mean?
Who cares.
We have fucking grills.
So what?
It's accessories.
It's like wearing a
chain, you know?
We like to get fresh.
Sorry.
I think a lot of people we meet
in person are, like, kind
of shocked.
Like, wow.
Not to mention we're
cool as shit.
Like, I don't care who you are
and what status you are--
THURMAN SEWELL: I'm good friends
with Jamie Thomas.
I'm good friends with Guy
Mariano, Brandon Biebel.
I mean, if we're such wiggery
pieces of shit meth heads, I
mean, why would somebody
like that fuck with us?
There's a reason people
fuck with us.
You know what I'm saying?
LIL WYTE: Anytime I'm downtown,
man, I try to look
up the twins.
They're just humble
dudes, man.
I'm one of them humble
guys, too.
I don't like kicking it with
people who think they're too
Hollywood to hang out.
I don't like people that just
ain't real motherfuckers, man.
And the twins are two of the
realest motherfuckers I've
ever met in my fucking life.
Their story is some fucking
VH1 shit, too.
CHRIS NIERATKO: Do twin
friends act like this?
DORIAN GRAY: No.
Actually, they don't.
Actually, the twin friends
I knew hated each other.
But these two actually figured
out how to shine together and
make it brilliant.
SIDNEY SEWELL: We feel very
blessed to be a twin.
Like, to be twins, you know
what I mean, and just have
each other.
Because at the end of the day,
everybody can go fuck
themselves.
We have each other.
We understand that we're
born, we're different.
You know what I mean?
We understand that nobody ever
will understand what it's
really like to be how we are,
just like we'll never
understand what it's like
for you to be alone.
CHRIS NIERATKO: What's
the longest you
guys have been apart?
SIDNEY SEWELL: Six hours.
People ask the question, what
if one of you died?
Well, I would die too,
because I would go
jump off the balcony.
You know?
THURMAN SEWELL: Seriously.
It would have to be like that.
SIDNEY SEWELL: It's not
an option, man.
There's no way we could live
without each other.
Really, when it comes down to
it, we're the same person.
We play roles.
We play different roles.
But we're a team.
Like, he drives.
THURMAN SEWELL: He
manages money.
SIDNEY SEWELL: I deal
with bills and shit.
Trust me.
It's all fair, you know?
THURMAN SEWELL: But
we couldn't live
without each other.
SIDNEY SEWELL: We're just
a packaged deal.
That's how we're born.
THURMAN SEWELL: It
is what it is.
CHRIS NIERATKO: What I think
it comes down to is that
people are jealous
that yous two are
banging a bunch of chicks.
-How much do you
love me, baby?
THURMAN SEWELL: I love
you so much.
CHRIS NIERATKO: What's
going on back there?
MS. WYTE: Personally,
I couldn't see
myself dating two brothers.
But you know, I guess if I were
going to do that, I'd
want them to be as cool as
the fucking ATL twins.
SIDNEY SEWELL: I don't know.
It was just natural that we
shared girls, you know?
Honestly, we get two girls in
the mix, it fucks things up,
to be honest with you.
So we prefer girls
to be one girl.
THURMAN SEWELL: I know what
you want to hear.
-That's so wrong.
CHRIS NIERATKO: What's the
attraction for women?
It takes a special kind of
woman to want to fuck two
dudes at the same time.
SIDNEY SEWELL: They all say
they would never do it.
THURMAN SEWELL: I would
never do that.
SIDNEY SEWELL: They
do it, trust me.
THURMAN SEWELL: Because we do
have big-ass dicks, bro.
SIDNEY SEWELL: We peak
at 9, 18 combined.
Like the best thing, to me,
about fucking bitches is like
the hunt of the whole thing.
THURMAN SEWELL: It's like
an addiction, man.
SIDNEY SEWELL: It's like
drugs, you know?
-Yeah, I'm coming.
I gotta go.
THURMAN SEWELL: We
are good guys.
We're just jaded on girls.
SIDNEY SEWELL: You understand,
we've been so jaded on girls
because every girl, every
serious relationship-- we've
had quite a few relationships,
and been really in love, and
they always break our hearts.
We're to the point now,
we're like, fuck it.
You know what I'm saying?
THURMAN SEWELL: That's it.
SIDNEY SEWELL: All right,
this is the girl.
THURMAN SEWELL: Have
you met her before?
Her stage name's Michelle.
We met her at a strip clubs.
CHRIS NIERATKO: Oh,
she's a stripper.
THURMAN SEWELL: Yeah but she
only worked there for a week.
And we met her at the last 15
minutes of a Saturday night
shift and got her back to our
crib, blah blah blah, fell in
love with her.
She moved in with us the
next day, quit her job.
We ended up getting really
serious with her, and getting
her back with her parents.
She'd run away from
her parents.
Her parents are super
conservative,
and blah blah blah.
But like I said, they thought
that she was with him.
They thought I was some weirdo
who couldn't get a girl, and
they were like--
SIDNEY SEWELL: So we
never split up.
So he'd always be around.
THURMAN SEWELL: I'd always be
around, but I'd be, like,
standoffish.
I wouldn't be all up on her.
And we'd stay the
night and shit.
It was crazy.
They knew we were really about
her, their daughter.
And we looked out for
her, you understand?
SIDNEY SEWELL: After that, she
started bugging us to go back
to school, and this and that.
And all we wanted to do was
skate, and she didn't
understand that.
CHRIS NIERATKO: You guys were
engaged for five years.
What happened?
THURMAN SEWELL: Eventually one
day, she just fucking left.
And we were heartbroken,
but whatever.
The curse is, a beautiful girl
that's super into us, how she
didn't go to her rich parents
and say, hey, I'm marrying
these guys.
Or I'm with these guys.
No.
SIDNEY SEWELL: We want kids,
you know what I mean?
Of course.
We hold our last name.
It's up to us to keep
our legacy going.
THURMAN SEWELL: But it's
gotta be the right
chick, and you know--
CHRIS NIERATKO: You
don't think that
would fuck a kid up?
SIDNEY SEWELL: If their dad
comes to pick them up, we're
not going to both go show up
there and be like, hey, we're
both the dads.
I mean, there's certain things
you just don't tell people.
And it's always been like that
when we're in relationships.
Like, girls--
THURMAN SEWELL: Society
doesn't work.
I tell the girl, don't tell
them you're with twins.
No.
SIDNEY SEWELL: They're
going to look at you
like you're a nut.
You can say whatever
you want to.
Fuck society.
THURMAN SEWELL: Fuck society.
Who gives a shit?
SIDNEY SEWELL: Why play
by their rules?
THURMAN SEWELL: Who cares?
Why?
SIDNEY SEWELL: We
don't have to.
THURMAN SEWELL: Because of
what somebody thinks?
Fuck them.
When we were kids, we would
fuck with hookers.
It was so sketchy.
You'd be outside, and these
fucking creepos would come up,
you need a ride?
CHRIS NIERATKO: Really?
THURMAN SEWELL: People have
tried to kidnap us before.