The tailor's name was
Miguel Caballero.
He prefers his nickname, which
is the Armored Armani, which
is pretty good.
I mean, I don't blame the guy.
He took us on this big tour and
he showed us a facility in
the warehouse where he
did the shooting,
and he did the testing.
And it's a proper place with
soundproofed thing and the
whole thing.
I figured we'd be going
down there.
All of a sudden, we're just
halfway through the interview,
and we're sitting in his office,
and he goes, OK.
You want to get shot?
I was like, yeah, we might
as well do it.
And I went to go get up,
and he's like, no, no.
I got it right here.
Pulls it out of his desk drawer
and stands up and
shoots me in his office
from six feet away.
So here it is, my mom's least
favorite piece of all time.
Vice presents "The Bulletproof
Tailor."
So we're here in Bogota,
Colombia, and we're about to
go see Miguel Caballero,
who's been
called the Armored Armani.
He makes bulletproof gear, but
he makes fashion-forward
lightweight bulletproof gear.
So a nice blazer or an
overcoat, and even a
bulletproof tie.
The basic deal is for bodyguards
and for kind of
VIPs, people who want to look
good and somewhat sharp and be
comfortable while they're
being shot at.
You would think that with the
direction of world events,
Miguel will probably be very
busy for a very long time.
So we're going to go talk to
Miguel, see how everything is
made, and see if he won't
let us take some of
it for a test drive.
So this is the tailoring
area of Miguel's shop.
All these women are working on
bulletproof vests and shirts
and jackets for United
Nations, for various
presidents, for local
police outfits--
pretty much anyone who thinks
it's a reasonable possibility
that they'll get shot.
Where did the idea of
incorporating elements of
actual fashion and design,
rather than just
your standard bulky--
RYAN DUFFY: Do you think this
will be everyday street wear
at some point in the
not-so-distant future?
That everyone will want to feel
protected, just in case?
RYAN DUFFY: Jesus Christ.
[KNOCKING]
RYAN DUFFY: And so does
this one have plates
in there, or no?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
RYAN DUFFY: Yeah.
FEMALE SPEAKER: The plates do.
RYAN DUFFY: Oh, wow.
FEMALE SPEAKER: How
do you think that?
RYAN DUFFY: It's bulletproof.
It's about as heavy
as a wool sweater.
Almost frighteningly so.
RYAN DUFFY: And we've heard that
all employees get shot.
Is that-- is that part
of the deal?
Everyone tests it out?
RYAN DUFFY: Now we're in the
ballistics area here, and
we're seeing where they kind
of test out all the vests.
So apparently the deal is they
drop the material here, and
then this plaster background
here serves as kind of a
fill-in for the body so they
can see how much impact,
whether the bullet's puncturing
in too far or
whatnot, based on the marks
on the plaster.
Did you get shot?
Do all employees get shot?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yes.
RYAN DUFFY: Really?
That's part of the rule?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
This is the [INAUDIBLE].
RYAN DUFFY: We gotta take
it for a test ride.
Let's fucking shoot
me, Miguel.
And how do you do that?
How can the weight be so
markedly decreased?
So-- so much smaller?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Kimono.
This is for a special design
for Steven Seagal.
RYAN DUFFY: So this, Steven
Seagal came and said, I--
what's his-- who's shooting
at Steven Seagal?
Do you know?
Wow.
He's a big motherfucker,
isn't he?
God damn.
So this is, Steven
Seagal said, I'm
really into this design.
Can you guys make this?
And this was custom-made
for Steven Seagal.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
We can mail your design
wherever you want.
RYAN DUFFY: Yeah.
Super light.
But this has the padding
in it, right?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
RYAN DUFFY: So
FEMALE SPEAKER: And look at--
this is very flexible.
RYAN DUFFY: Yeah,
it really is.
You sure that stops bullets?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
Of course.
RYAN DUFFY: Steven Seagal.
Who are some of the other names
that we would know?
RYAN DUFFY: Where else
are your big markets?
RYAN DUFFY: If I was going
to go into the boutique
in Mexico and just--
I needed something.
What does an average
jacket go for now?
RYAN DUFFY: So where am I
getting shot, exactly?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Here.
RYAN DUFFY: Here?
Really?
That's OK?
It ends right there.
RYAN DUFFY: This is
not heavy-duty.
MIGUEL CABALLERO: One.
One.
RYAN DUFFY: One
MIGUEL CABALLERO: One,
two, three, boom.
One, two, three, boom.
RYAN DUFFY: [EXHALES]
MIGUEL CABALLERO: Yeah, OK.
That's all.
RYAN DUFFY: OK.
RYAN DUFFY: Oh, that's
just muscle?
MIGUEL CABALLERO: Yeah.
RYAN DUFFY: But if it goes
through there, we have a bit
of a problem, right?
There's a bunch of organs
and shit in there.
[LAUGHTER]
MIGUEL CABALLERO: Be
cool, my friend.
Be cool.
RYAN DUFFY: Man, I look cool.
I can't not be cool
in this jacket.
It is suede.
I wonder if it's waterproof.
Oh, you like that with the
collar up a little more, huh?
RYAN DUFFY: We've been told
that Miguel here is the
world's premiere bulletproof
tailor.
But you know, there's a lot of
bullshit in advertising, so
we're gonna take it
for a test ride.
MIGUEL CABALLERO: OK.
Uno, dos--
[GUNSHOT]
MIGUEL CABALLERO: Tres.
Come out here to--
RYAN DUFFY: A little sneak
attack there, huh?
Very clever.
MIGUEL CABALLERO: Check
the bullets.
That's only--
nothing?
RYAN DUFFY: Nothing.
MIGUEL CABALLERO: You felt
something like this, yes?
RYAN DUFFY: Yeah.
Wasn't bad, man.
Oh.
My knee is shaking.
MIGUEL CABALLERO:
That's for you.
It's a souvenir.
RYAN DUFFY: Oh, my souvenir.
Look at that.
MIGUEL CABALLERO: It's
there, you know?
RYAN DUFFY: That's what
he just shot me with.
[GUNSHOT]
MIGUEL CABALLERO: No,
no, don't worry.
RYAN DUFFY: That didn't
hurt nearly as much as
I thought it would.
So that's the bullet and
that's how it ends up.
That's fucking crazy.
He did the pediatrician trick,
like when you go to get a shot
when you're little, and he's
like, on three, I'm
going to stick you.
And you go, one, two, and
then he sticks you?
He did that to me.
Just now.
And it worked.