Erin, Anthony
Hi
This... is your girlfriend?
But she's hot
What, you are saying I can't get a hot girlfriend?
Euuh, yah!
Look at you.
Well, obviously I can.
Anyway, what do you want for Christmas?
Nothing
You don't want anything for Christmas?
Nope
Dear diary
I know anthony wants something for Christmas this year.
Last year he said he didn't care...
and then he got super pissed at me when I didn't get him anything.
Looks like I have to do some old school investigating to find out
what he really wants!
Yo Anthony
So I got this friend who is a lot like you
And he wants me to get him something for Christmas
So, what do you think I should get him?
Well, what's his name?
Anthon...lee, Anthonlee.
He's chinese
I don't want anything for Christmas, Ok?
HOW THE HELL DID HE KNOW MY MOTIVE?!
He's smarter then I thaught.
Looks like I need more, coverts methods.
Tell me what you want for Christmas, or I'll blow your F******
brains out!
I couldn't get an answer out of Anthony before he suffered a
minor heart attack.
I should probably pay him a visit in the hospital...
Heey
Heey!
Your the first person to come see me!
Here's some flowers.
Hah!
Anthony totally took the bait, he doesn't even know I put a
camera in the flower pot!
He's stupider then I thaught!
HAHAHA!
What?!
What's Erin doing there?
NO,NO, WHAT ARE YOU DOING WHAT ARE YOU DOING?!
NOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOO!
THIS SUCKS!
Anthony is so gay for making out with Erin, Im gonna, whooaht?
Are you writing in a diary?
It's called the captains log, you dick!
What do you want?
I just came to apologise, for you know...
making out with your girlfriend.
Well, we might have done a little more then making out...
Ah, whatever.
We weren't actually dating.
I was just paying him so he could pose as my girlfriend.
Wait, what?
Well, how else am I supposed to impress people?
No, no, you said.. you said him?
Euh, yah.
Erin's a dude.
I can't afford a real woman!
But... I did things with her.
Him.
AAAAAAAAAAH!
Merry Christmas!
Sorry about those STD's, but I brought you a little present to cheer
you up!
I didn't know what is was supposed to get you, so I just went with
something save.
A furbie?
What is this, 1998?
GET OUT OF HERE!
Fine!
Captain's log, startdate 20/10
Ian got me a furbie
Best, Christmas, EVER!
Love Anthony.
Nice diary, PUSSY!
Dear diary, I'm sorry for making fun of you. I just, WHOO!
Dodli-a-doodle-doo
BITCH!