We are starting with the U.S. presidential
election. The election night audience wasn`t
limited to the United States. From South America
to Europe, Africa to the Middle East and Asia,
the world was watching as results came in
on Tuesday night.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: It`s a day to celebrate
for Barack Obama supporters. Let`s get to
the big headlines at this moment. Barack Obama
is reelected U.S. president. The first picture
of the first couple`s victory as Obama tweets
a thank you to his voters for a second term.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: So people were watching the election
in the real world, and many of them were talking
about the election in the digital one. Karin
Caifa look at the role that social media took
on during election day and some of the trends
that defined the day.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
KARIN CAIFA, CNN CORRESPONDENT: As election
day turned into election night, millions of
votes and how they added up generated million
of tweets, leading up to this one: a thank
you from a newly reelected president of the
United States.
BARACK OBAMA, PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES
OF AMERICA: For the United States of America,
the best is yet to come.
(APPLAUSE)
CAIFA: Election day 2012 took its place as
Twitter`s biggest political event ever. And
as TV networks called the race, second screens
lit up at a rate of more than 327,000 tweets
per minute. Google searches pointed to an
anxious electorate. Top search terms during
the day included "election results", "exit
polls", "election news" and "Who`s winning
the election?" On Facebook, the number one
term Tuesday morning and afternoon, variations
of "vote", "voted", and "go vote." After projections,
"Obama wins" jumped to the top spots on both
Facebook and Google.
Meanwhile, among Instagram photos, a bevy
of proud ballot shots raised legal questions
in states with restrictions on photography
in polling places. In November 2008, about
37 percent of Americans said they used a social
networking site. Fast forward to 2012, two
thirds are socially engaged.
MITT ROMNEY, REPUBLICAN PRESIDENTIAL CANDIDATE:
You guys are the best.
CAIFA: And while Republicans made social strides,
they are still catching up to do -- Mitt Romney
amassed a respectable 1.7 million Twitter
follows during his campaign; still, just a
fraction of President Obama`s over 22 million.
In Chicago, I`m Karin Caifa.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: Well, President Obama has been elected
to a second term in the White House, but the
next four years could present some big challenges
for the president and the country. The fiscal
cliff has to do with the U.S. debt, some spending
cuts and tax increases are said to kick in
unless President Obama and Congress can come
up with other ways to get the country`s debt
under control. Most American voters said the
economy was the number one issue in this election.
One thing the financial experts look at in
order to figure out how the economy is doing
is the U.S. stock markets, specifically, the
Dow Jones Industrial Average. Yesterday, it
dropped more than 300 points, the worst one
day drop in a year. So, things are still pretty
rough on Wall Street, and that`s why economic
issues like the fiscal cliff are going to
get a lot of attention.
What else lies ahead for the president`s second
term? There is a possibility he could nominate
more justices to the U.S. Supreme Court. He
nominated two during his first term, plus
some members of the president`s cabinet have
said they`ll step down, so he`ll need to fill
those positions as well.
Before we leave election night behind, we
want to point out some firsts that happened
on Tuesday. Same-sex marriage became legal
in Maryland and Maine. A similar vote in Washington
was still pending. Judges and legislators
have approved it in other states, but this
was the first time that voters approved same-sex
marriage.
In Wisconsin, Tammy Baldwin became the first
openly gay politician elected to the U.S.
Senate. She`s also the first woman elected
to the Senate from Wisconsin.
Voters in two states, Colorado and Washington,
approved legalizing marijuana. That`s a first,
but it`s also not a done deal. The federal
government says marijuana is illegal, and
that overrules states rights in this case.
And for the first time, a majority of voters
in Puerto Rico said they would like the U.S.
territory to change its status and become
a U.S. state.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Just the facts: in 1949,
China officially changed its name to the People`s
Republic of China. The country had existed
for centuries, but 1949 was when China became
a communist nation. In a communist country,
the government controls the economy and one
political party holds all the power.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: That government and country are set
to get a new leader. Now, there won`t be a
new party in charge of China. The Communist
Party will still lead the country`s government,
but there will be a different person heading
up that party. Every five years, more than
2,200 delegates from the Communist Party Congress
get together. They evaluate the country`s
progress and set new directions for China.
Every ten years, they pick new leadership.
That process started today. Most, maybe all
of the decisions are determined in advance.
And that`s why we can tell you that this man,
Xi Jingping, is expected to be China`s next
president. He`s been the vice president for
nearly 5 years, but some experts describe
Xi as a mystery. They say they are not sure
what type of leader he would be.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: What`s the word? It`s
a type of winter storm that commonly hits
this part of the United States.
Nor`easter. That`s the word.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: There is one of those bearing down on
the Northeastern U.S. right now. Yes, this
is the same part of the country that was hit
less than two weeks ago by Sandy. A lot of
people still recovering from that storm. Hundreds
of thousands still don`t have power. And now
they are going to have to deal with this two.
You are looking at more rain, more wind, now
add snow to the mix. The Nor`easter could
drive temperatures down into the `20s, and
that could be a serious problem for the thousands
of people whose homes don`t have heat or power.
Rob Marciano has more on these winter storms.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
ROB MARCIANO, CNN CORRESPONDENT: A Nor`easter
is the storm that typically happens in the
Northeast. That`s not why it`s called a Nor`easter,
though. The name comes from the wind or the
prevailing wind that you typically get from
that sort of storm, which is out of the Northeast,
and the bigger, stronger the storm, the stronger
the Nor`east wind is.
Nor`easters are typically a weak storm that
make their way across the U.S. and will get
a little bit of energy from the jet stream,
and then when they heat the coast, that difference
in temperature between the land and the ocean,
that gives them a little bit more in the way
of instability and more fuel for the fire.
Common characteristics of a Nor`easter are
wind, rain, sometimes snow, definitely waves
battering the coastline, and because of that
you can get some beach erosion, you can get
some coastal flooding. A storm surge is possible
as well. So, a lot of damage can be done not
only along the shoreline, but also inland
in form of winds and heavy snow. Sometimes
Nor`easters can dump several feet of snow,
especially at the higher terrain.
Nor`easters typically happen anywhere really
from September all the way to May. The more
intense ones happen really in the fall and
winter time, but spring time, you can get
some Nor`easters that have some devastating
winds.
Nor`easters and hurricanes are completely
different, because they derive their energy
from two completely different sources. Your
hurricanes get your energy from the warm waters
of the Atlantic Ocean, and that latent heat
relays is what drives the engine. Once a hurricane
goes on land, it loses its energy.
A Nor`easter gets its energy from the differences
between hot and cold. Often, a blizzard will
come from a strong Nor`easter. And some cases,
they can be one and the same. Blinding snow
and wind, winds blowing 35-40 miles an hour.
And obviously, devastating cold. And that`s
why the strongest Nor`easters typically happen
in fall and winter, when you have that dynamic
contrast in temperatures.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: Well, finally today, we are going to
talk about a ping-pong player that is a machine.
Well, at least we warned you. This robotic
returner is a ping-pong prodigy. It`s on display
at an event in China. The robot`s eyes have
cameras that collect images of the ball, and
then it takes it 50 to 100 milliseconds to
respond and hit the ball back. Actually it
seems kind of like the ball is coming right
to it. So, if you were to really challenge
this thing, it might be in for some trouble.
If it couldn`t keep up, it could be up the
creek without a pedal. But for the engineers
building it, they could still get some valuable
information. And besides, it seems like they
are doing pretty well, considering the net
results so far.
Coming up with puns like that is always a
ball, and we really gave them our best shot,
and now it`s time for us to go so, we will
serve up more headlines tomorrow on CNN STUDENT
NEWS.