episode of Vice Today.
On today's installment, we hear
from Brett Ratner in a
segment called StoryTime, where
he tells us about the
best party he's ever thrown.
Then we put Justin, a weird,
little, child man who we like
a lot, in some really new and
uncomfortable situations.
But first up, we have another
episode of What's Up With
Drake, where you learn about
your favorite rapper from a
nerd with a monotone
[MUSIC PLAYING]
HANSON O'HAVER: Hey,
I'm Hanson O'Haver.
So Drake premiered two videos
this week, one for "HYFR" and
one for "Take Care." I think
that we should talk about
"Take Care" first, just
because it's the least
interesting of the two.
The video was directed by the
guy who directed the video
where Lana Del Rey dies
in a car crash.
But for this one, in lieu of
a shirtless, kind of like
face-tatted alt-bro,
there's Rihanna.
Both videos feature
wild animals.
I think in Drake's, there's like
some sort of eagle, and
then what looks like
a water buffalo.
So the video is mostly Rihanna
and Drake hugging with kind of
like an English look
on their face.
There's also some slow-mo
nature shots.
But for the most part, it's
all just in a gray room.
The director described the video
as humble, but I think
really it's just generic.
It's sort of like when you go to
a art gallery, between the
really great pieces, like the
masterworks, there's just kind
of filler stuff so that
there's enough
to make an art show.
Like it's really, instead of
being a meaningful rap video,
it's like a simulacrum of
a meaningful rap video.
So the "HYFR" video, it starts
with footage from Drake's
actual Bar Mitzvah with a
13-year-old Drake dancing, and
it's [BLEEP]
adorable.
And then the rest of the video
claims to be real footage of
Drake's re-Bar Mitzvah.
It basically shows Drake and
like his crew and some really
pretty girls and like
some dorky, old,
white men wilding out.
At one point, Drake gets like
hoisted on a chair.
A cake gets smashed.
Also Lil' Wayne has a panda mask
and a skateboard, kind of
solidifying his ascension to
cautionary tale status.
The video is funny, it's
exciting, it's
easily made into GIFs.
It's really everything that a
rap video should be in 2012.
I don't think the video is going
to do much to help solve
the Israel-Palestine conflict.
Like I don't think that Bibi
Netanyahu and the members of
Fatah are going to watch it,
but it could only help.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
RYAN DUFFY: Every once in a
while, I wonder when I watch
those if through the magic of
the internet, Drake somehow
sees them and watches it, and
just goes, what the [BLEEP]?
Our next segment is
called StoryTime.
And we're going to be making
a bunch of them.
Basically, we just visit with
people and ask about the best
story they can possibly
tell us.
In the first episode, Brett
Ratner tells us how he played
matchmaker for Charlie Sheen.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
BRETT RATNER: I think the best
party I've ever been to is a
party that I had that was--
happened just by chance.
And it was probably the luckiest
day in my life.
I get a call from the head
of Victoria's Secret.
And he says, we've never had a
party in Los Angeles, and we'd
like you to host a party
for Victoria's
Secret at your home.
And I said, well, what
do you mean by that?
And he goes, we will bring 25
supermodels to your home,
Victoria Secret models.
I said, are you joking?
He said, no, we're serious.
I go, who can I invite?
He goes, whoever you want.
I said, well I'm not inviting
many people.
And I, literally, I think
invited 10 guys.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
BRETT RATNER: I have a disco
in my house that was
built in the '70s.
25 supermodels and 10
guys in my house.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
BRETT RATNER: Three of the 10
guys ended up marrying three
of the girls.
Adriana Lima married a
basketball player.
Charlie Sheen happened to marry
the one girl that wasn't
a Victoria Secret model.
Happened to come with
my ex-girlfriend.
And the third girl, Orlando
Bloom married.
Three people at one party, and
there was only 10 guys there
and 25 girls.
That has never happened.
It was the best party
I've ever been to.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
RYAN DUFFY: Finally, we have
Adventures in BabyMan.
Justin's an editor
who works for us.
We found him swaddled
in blankets on
our front stoop crying.
He's basically an overgrown
fetus, but we like him a lot.
So we want to teach him
about the world.
In this first episode, he learns
about yoga from our
friend Clara in a romantic
setting at the waterfront.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CLARA: Hi, I'm Clara.
And today I'm going to teach
BabyMan bird of paradise.
BABYMAN: Hi.
I'm BabyMan.
[CHANTING]
[SITAR MUSIC]
CLARA: The audience really
wants to see you get it
together today.
BABYMAN: I'm BabyMan.
[SITAR MUSIC]
BABYMAN: So painful.
RYAN DUFFY: Hope you enjoyed
the third episode of Vice
Today, and stay tuned for many
more, including episode four
this Thursday.
Thanks for watching.
And if you like the channel,
please subscribe.
[MUSIC PLAYING]