(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED MALES AND FEMALES: Hi. This is
Ms. Colvin`s sixth grade advanced study class
at East Hamilton Middle School. Take it away,
Carl!
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: First up, a new economic record in Greece
and not a good one. In August, the country`s
unemployment rate hit 25.4 percent. That means,
a quarter of the entire country is out of
work, and if you are 24 or younger, that unemployment
rate jumps 260 percent.
Greece has been struggling through a recession
for five years. The country has massive debt.
It`s getting a bailout, money to help out
with this debt. But in order to get that money,
the Greek government has to find ways to get
its debt under control. What it`s been trying
so far is austerity, spending cuts to things
like workers` salaries and pensions. Many
Greeks obviously not happy about this. While
the country`s parliament was getting ready
to approve a new round of cuts this week,
thousands of protesters were fighting with
police outside the parliament building.
From Greece, we are going to move across the
Atlantic Ocean to Guatemala. Parts of that
Central American nation are recovering after
it was hit by a powerful earthquake earlier
this week. The quake had a magnitude of 7.4.
That made it the strongest quake to hit Guatemala
in more than 35 years. According to the country`s
president, at least 52 people were killed
in the quake, hundreds of others were treated
for injuries, thousands of homes were damaged,
and roads collapsed with rubble crushing cars
all over Guatemala. The president said the
damage of devastation could have been worse.
Finally, we are heading over to Japan. In
March of 2011, you might remember, the country`s
suffered its worst earthquake ever: triggered
a tsunami and giant ocean wave, and that led
to a meltdown at the Japanese nuclear facility.
We`ve reported on debris from that disaster
washing ashore in Hawaii and in Alaska. But
Japanese officials still have tons of it to
deal with there, in Japan, and as Alex Zolbert
explains, you can`t just throw it away.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
ALEX ZOLBERT, CNN CORRESPONDENT: It`s been
more than a year and a half since the devastating
tsunami in Japan`s Tohoko region. And while
substantial progress has been made, the country
is still grappling with more than 13 million
tons of debris.
About 20 percent of what remains is said to
be destroyed in other parts of the country.
Today, trucks arrive at this incineration
plan in Shizuoka, several hours drive south
of Tokyo. Officials say, these debris is the
shredded remnants of people`s homes, about
250 kilometers or 150 miles from the crippled
Fukushima nuclear plant. But with concerns
over possible fallouts still running high,
officials here measure radiation levels, before
a small crowd of onlookers. It`s a well choreographed,
very deliberate routine. According to officials,
this debris fails to trigger any elevated
readings. The shipment is cleared. The truck
pulls in and dumps its load, which is then
hoisted into the incinerator.
Once concerned citizens are pleased with what
they`ve seen today.
There are the critics here in Shizuoka, some
who question the logic in transporting these
debris more than 700 kilometers, or about
430 miles across the country. Than there are
those who said a government should have been
more transparent.
Masahiro Kasyua (ph) says the affected area
is using all of its incineration resources,
they need our help, but we will continue to
make our case as we`ve been doing. Carefully
and tenaciously.
A long and tedious project that is not short
on controversy.
Alex Zolbert, CNN, Shizuoka, Japan.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today`s "Shoutout" goes
out to Ms. Flax`s social studies classes at
Ness City Junior Senior High School in Ness
City, Kansas.
Armistice Day celebrate the end of what conflict?
Here we go, was it American Revolution, World
War I, Crimean War or World War II? You`ve
got three seconds, go!
Armistice Day marked the end of World War
I. That`s your answer and that`s your "Shoutout",
but that`s not what the holiday is called
anymore in the U.S.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: No, it`s not. Armistice Day originally
marked the 11th hour of the 11th day of the
11th month in 1918. That`s when the armistice
went into effect ending the fighting in World
War I. But in 1954, President Eisenhower changed
the name to Veterans Day in honor of everyone
who`s ever served in the U.S. armed forces.
So, whether that was during the Iraq war,
for instance, in a humvee like this one beside
me, or during a time of peace, Veterans Day
occurs every year on November 11th. There
are services like the traditional reed playing
at the Tomb of the Unknowns at Arlington National
Cemetery, and for Americans nationwide, it`s
a chance to honor one of the country`s 21.5
million veterans, even if that`s simply by
saying, thank you for your service.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Is this legit? A document
that`s faked or designed to be misleading
is a forgery. This is true. Forged document
are ones that have been made or altered falsely.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Well, you might think that as students
would forge a document in order to get out
of school. There is a 21-year old in Michigan
who recently forged a transcript and birth
certificate in order to go to school. He went
to class, played on a high school football
team. James Felton of affiliate WNEM tells
us what happened after the truth came out.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
JIM CONWAY, MOUNT PLEASURE H.S. ATHLETIC DIR.:
Any time you are duped to -- or, you know,
lied to, if you will, there is some frustration
that comes with that.
JAMES FELTON, WNEM CORRESPONDENT: Mount Pleasant
High School athletic director, Jim Conway,
is in shock. He is still trying to figure
out why a 21-year old would lie his way back
to high school and play for the football team.
That`s exactly what happened to his Oiler
ball club this season.
CONWAY: When it comes to something like this,
and integrity issue becomes difficult to swallow.
FELTON: 21-year old used false documents to
attend a school under the alias Javier Jones
(ph). He played five games for the football
team. Here you see him, he`s wearing number
one. After the school received the tip from
a concerned parent, Nash`s (ph) true identity
was discovered. He was immediately removed
from the district.
Now, two Oiler victories may be forfeited.
CONWAY: He just fit in with all the other
high school kids, with the 16-17-18 year old
kids who belong there, there were really no
red flags.
FELTON: Meanwhile, Conway says the students
athletes are angry their hard work may be
tarnished by one individual.
CONWAY: They are frustrated, or if not more
frustrated than the adults in this situation,
which was good to see. I think the kids have
learned a valuable lesson, they are asking
the questions why and now just like we are
as adults.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: Right now for a positive story from
the football field. From a football faker
to one that certainly looks like the real
thing. Watch this. The pee wee player tearing
up the field in this Youtube video, definitely
deserves a highlight reel. 35 touchdowns,
65 tackles, nearly 2000 rushing yards. It`s
amazing. She is dominating the league.
Yeah, I said, she. Samantha Gordon, she prefers
the name "Sam," nine years old, she plays
offence and defense in a mostly boys league
in Utah. And she is amazing. During tryouts
before the season started, Sam was tops in
almost every drill. What`s crazy is that she
just started playing football this year, it`s
not even her favorite sport. She likes soccer
better.
The nearly 2 million people -- yeah, 2 million
people have seen her play football, they might
disagree with that.
Rosalie Reimer is a little bit older than
Sam Gordon, she is 15. That means she doesn`t
have her driver`s license yet. But if you
think that`s kept her from getting behind
the wheel -- it hasn`t. Of course, Rosalie
doesn`t drive regular cars, she drives this.
Monster truck. She showed off her skills at
the Arizona State Fair last weekend. When
she is not in school, Rosalie is part of a
monster truck competition circuit. She actually
worked with her dad to build this behemoth,
which is named detour. She is planning to
go to college, get a degree in engineering,
go to work designing racers, but she`ll probably
still be connected to monster trucks. Rosalie
says this is kind of thing you just never
get tired of.
Finally, getting a caravan together might
be kind of a tall order. But that`s what you
are dealing with when you are transporting
a giraffe. You see its head? There it is.
Two-year old giraffe in Australia is moving
from one zoo to another, keeper said she was
old enough to start mixing with other giraffes.
Besides, she was about to outgrow her old
home. It might sound like a risky proposition
to move an exotic animal, but I`m sure they
are used to this kind of thing, they probably
didn`t have to stick their necks out. And
how do you decide which drivers get to be
in the convoy? They probably used a giraffal
(ph) system. And afterwards, they could tell
their friends, a tall tale. Yeah, that`s right.
Giraffe puns. Head and shoulders above the
rest. It`s time for us to hit the road, have
a great weekend, we`ll see you again on Monday,
by now.