is an epic
from many people's childhoods.
It's a wonderful story,
found in the Bible,
The Koran and the Torah.
But is it in fact, real history?
Now the technology exists
to examine this well known epic
with the eyes of science.
We will weigh out the evidence
from archaeological finds in Iraq...
We will examine the proof
that a global flood
did cover the whole planet...
We'll also create
a historically accurate picture
of the real Noah:
who he was, where he lived
and what he might have looked like.
The story of Noah is told
in the Book of Genesis
in the Bible and the Torah.
It's set somewhere
in the middle-east
about 5000 years ago.
Noah's family includes his wife,
his three sons -
Shem, Ham and Japheth,
and their brides.
Noah stands out as a good person -
the only virtuous man left
in a world
that had become filled
with corruption and violence.
He is described as a wine-grower,
a claim that has
an authentic ring to it
as wine was grown
in the middle east
as far back as 3000BC.
And this reference also provides
a rare insight
into Noah's character.
After the flood, the Bible says
Noah planted the first vineyard.
But it also tells us
that Noah had a weakness
Having made the first wine,
the story goes that Noah
drank too much of it.
In fact, one night this Holy Man
collapses naked and drunk.
Horrified his sons
Ham and Shem cover their father.
In the morning,
Noah is embarrassed -
and perhaps suffering
the first ever hangover -
he curses the sons
who saw him naked.
He sound like a flawed
and complex man
but perhaps that is true
of all great men.
But Noah was probably
a very reliable man,
because God gives him
a very big mission.
The story goes that God
warned Noah in a dream
that he was going to
punish humanity for its sins
with a flood that would cover
the whole earth.
To save Noah and his family
God told him to build
a boat of wood
and to line it
with pitch inside and out.
He also ordered Noah
to give the ark three decks,
a roof and a door.
But the most surprising
of God's instructions
was the sheer size of the Ark.
The Bible spells it out- in cubits.
Traditionally a cubit was the length
of a man's forearm -
about one and a half feet.
The Bible says Noah built
an Ark 300 cubits long
and 50 cubits wide by 30 high.
That's almost as big as
modern super tankers
and cruise liners like Titanic.
Nearly 450 feet long,
it would have been
a magnificent sight -
certainly the biggest boat
in the ancient world.
quite an achievement
for an ordinary man
Now the Bible assumes
it was possible to build
this monster vessel
out of wood alone.
It's a pretty big assumption.
The familiar image
from the story books
and cartoons of our childhood
is of a huge wooden ark
with the animals marching
inside two by two.
But that is a 19TH Century image.
It is completely at odds
with what could be built
in Biblical times.
According to Tom Vosmer,
an expert on ancient boats,
not even 19TH century engineers
could have built a 450 ft Ark
out of wood alone.
They had to use steel frames
inside much smaller wooden boats
just to keep them afloat.
The problem with a 450 foot boat
made of wood
is that the wood as a material
cannot maintain
the shape of the boat
and the boat
would start to distort at sea,
and the seams would open up
and it would sink.
It's a safe bet that the huge Ark
would spring hundreds
of leaks along the length
of its huge hull and sink
like a stone.
That's not to say Noah
didn't build an ark.
It's just that it would have
been much smaller.
Then there's another problem.
How could he cram two
of every different kind of animal
into the ark?
At the latest estimate,
there are 30 million species
on earth.
Even with a fleet of Arks,
Noah would have struggled
to fit them all in.
And how would he have gotten
the animals on board.
Did he personally go
and fetch them?
Or did they come to him?
It is something Noah
would have had to consider
especially since
he had a pressing deadline.
Noah had just seven days to find
all the animals
and get them on board.
30 million species in a week.
Noah would have needed
to load them
at the rate of 50 pairs a second.
But if one assumes
a more realistic loading rate then
it would have taken Noah
at least 30 years.
It may seem like
there's a stark choice:
dismiss the story as myth,
or appeal to the hand of God.
But there may in fact
be another explanation.
The instruction to load
'all the animals'
could have referred only to
all the animals
in Noah's part of the world.
In fact,
the Book of Genesis specifies
which animals Noah was to load.
The same book
has a second set of instructions
which are much less well known
but present an even more
realistic scenario.
Noah is told to take
'take seven pairs
of clean animals'.
Clean animals were
those considered suitable
for ceremonial sacrifices to God.
The Books of
Leviticus and Deuteronomy
specify 10 such species
including several types of sheep,
antelopes plus cattle,
goats and deer.
Seven pairs of 10 species
That's 140 animals.
Then Noah is directed
to take a pair
of each impure animal and bird.
Again, The books of Leviticus
and Deuteronomy list 30 or more.
They include the pig, the hare,
the lizard, the snail and so on.
That's a further 60 animals.
Then finally, Noah is told
to load 'seven pairs
of the clean birds -
like doves, ducks and cockerels.
Adding all that up,
Noah had 260 animals.
That's child's play compared
to 30 million -
especially if you discount
the elephants,
kangaroos and reluctant camels!
A smaller Ark and fewer animals -
suddenly the Noah story
looks more plausible.
But the next part of the story
may be most far fetched of all.
Noah, the Ark, and the animals
It's all meaningless
without the worst cataclysm
in human history - the flood.
According to the Bible
it rained until the whole world
was covered in water.
Such a catastrophe
should have left evidence
all over the planet
in the form of uniform
marine sediments
spread across the earth
and the ocean floor.
But have geologists
found any proof
of a devastating global flood?
The scientific quest
for traces of the Biblical
global flood
that Noah, his family
and the animals in the ark
survived actually began
more than 150 years ago.
But geologist Ian Plimer,
after searching across continents
sometimes in the most
extreme weather conditions
has found very little evidence.
A great flood
would leave a signature.
It would be
a very very large signature
apparent all over the world.
There is no such signature.
There's no evidence,
in fact there is only
overwhelming evidence
to the contrary.
The absence of direct evidence
is only one of the problems
with the story
The whole idea
of a global flood flies
in the face of what is known
about planet earth.
To flood the entire planet
to the top of the Himalayas
would take three times
the volume of water in the oceans.
It's hard to imagine
where such a deluge
could come from.
The Bible provides some clues.
It says it rained for forty days
and forty nights -
but even non-stop that's not enough.
We know how much water
we've got in the oceans,
we know how much water's
in the polar ice caps.
We know how much water
is in the atmosphere
and we know how much water
is in the rocks.
If we put all of that together,
which has happened many times
in the geological past,
we still do not
flood the continents.
If rainfall couldn't deliver
enough water,
what could?
The Bible offers
one more possibility -
'deep springs'.
The Book of Genesis says ''
All the springs of the great
deep broke through''
Could the great flood
have gushed out
of the centre of the earth?
It's an impossibility to have that
much amount of water
coming out of springs,
fountains or geysers.
If all of that water was
in the earth and in the crust
then well before it had been
released as geysers
the crust would have
been quicksand,
you couldn't have walked.
Even if the flood had been caused
by a miracle
Noah, his family and the animals
would have faced
further problems...
The amount of water flooding
the surface of the planet
would have changed
the earth's atmosphere.
The atmosphere would have
had a huge amount
of water vapour dissolved in it,
so much so that you
would have drowned by breathing.
And so much so
that atmospheric pressure
would have crushed your lungs.
Geysers present another
potentially fatal problem.
They release poisonous gases
from deep within the earth's core
which probably
would have killed everybody,
whether or not they were
in the Ark.
Geysers pump out huge amounts
of noxious sulphur rich gasses.
Even before the flood
you could not have breathed.
If nothing on Earth
could cause the flood -
how about something from space.
Like a comet.
They contain vast amounts
of frozen water.
But to flood the entire planet
the comet would have
to be 1000 miles wide,
or as big as Brazil.
And if a comet that size
hit the earth,
not many people would live
to worry about a flood.
The friction caused
by the comet's forced entry
into the earth's outer atmosphere
and its impact as it struck earth
would be equivalent
to 12 trillion megatons of TNT -
the biggest explosion of all time
Comets carry water,
they are dirty ice.
As they come into the atmosphere,
they explode,
there are massive shock waves.
Massive areas of forest wiped out,
huge extinctions of life
from a comet
The comet's devastating impact
would force the temperature
of the atmosphere
to rise
to 12000 degrees Fahrenheit -
hotter than the surface of the sun.
We would have had no life
to go onto an Ark.
Noah, his family
and all the animals two by two
would have been fried to charcoal
before the whole flood started
End of story?
Not quite.
According to the Bible,
Noah's Ark landed
in the mountains of Ararat,
today in Eastern Turkey.
The earth was revealed at last
and the animals disembarked
after months below decks
to repopulate the world.
So are there any remains of the ark?
The problem is that the evidence -
wood, rots in a matter of centuries.
Countless expeditions have been
drawn to Mount Ararat
seeking to discover
the ark's resting place.
There are no obvious
remains of the ark
on the slopes of Mount Ararat
This hasn't stopped
a thriving tourist industry -
pilgrims, ark hunters and locals -
convinced that
they will find the remains
of the Ark somewhere
on the mountain.
One French expedition in the 50s
did in fact find an ancient
looking piece of wood
12000 ft up in a glacier.
As a geologist,
Ian Plimer wanted to find out more.
He knew that for the timber
to be part of Noah's Ark,
it would need to be dated
to around 3000BC.
When this piece of wood was found
it was thought to be the clue,
this is what we need to show
we have Noah's Ark
and so they took the wood to date it
and you can date wood
by measuring tree rings
or by carbon dating.
It wasn't old enough.
The wood
was from the eighth century,
4000 years after Noah's time.
But what was the wood
doing on the slopes of Ararat?
The wood would have
been transported there
to build a structure -
something like a church.
There is a booming ark
business there now,
there was in the past.
It certainly didn't come from Noah
But just as Ararat
was looking like a false trail
for ark hunters,
this ancient mountain came up
with a new twist.
In 1949, US Air Force planes
photographed the summit
of Mt Ararat.
Rumours began to spread
that they'd spotted a boat structure
in the ice.
For decades the CIA
withheld the pictures.
But then through
the Freedom of Information
Act the CIA finally released
the photos in 1995.
At first there's nothing
in the CIA picture
to suggest a boat.
But look closely,
you can see a huge dark shape
sticking out of the ice-cap.
It's about 450 feet long -
the right length for the Ark.
The anomaly
has tantalised ark hunters
since the pictures were released.
But geologists remain unconvinced.
It's such a poor
quality grainy image
that it's very hard to tell whether
it's an Ark or chicken entrails.
You can see dark shapes
anywhere from the air,
be they in ice or on the ground.
Some of them are ark shaped,
others are not.
It's not at all convincing
from one single
poor quality photograph.
But hopes were raised again
in the year 2000
with new pin-sharp satellite
images of the strange shape.
This one shows a snow ledge
believed by ark hunters
to conceal a boat-shaped outline.
But for Ian Plimer
this is just another
of nature's random shapes.
Well this is a fabulous photograph
Far better resolution
than the CIA photograph.
However we see nothing
spectacular here.
All we see is evidence of retreating
and advancing ice
In fact, all the geological
evidence indicates
that an ark
could not have remained frozen
in a glacier for long.
The ice is constantly
pushing material
I down the slopes of Mount Ararat
and ultimately taken any ark
that might have been
there to the bottom.
It would have spat it out
as all glaciers do,
as they move down slope
anything they pick up they spit out.
Be it rocks, be it Arks.
In addition to fragments of wood
and photos
there are dozens of
alleged sightings of the ark.
Biblical scholar Lloyd Bailey
has made
an exhaustive analysis
of all the claims
and found them to be false.
An amazing amount of evidence
has been produced by ark searchers
in support of the ark
having landed there.
But photographs are alleged to exist
but you can't find them.
Newspaper articles of sightings
are alleged to exist
but they are lost.
They want desperately to be
able to support the Bible
in an age of doubt,
in a modern rational age.
And that desire is so strong
they can rationalise away
the overwhelming evidence that
there is no boat there
and no evidence whatsoever
that there ever has been.
The traditional Noah story
may not pass
a rational historical test.
But maybe it was never meant to.
Biblical scholars -
using clues in the language
used by the Bible -
are agreed that the story of Noah
was physically written down
in the 6th century BC.
The scribes who wrote it
were Jewish priests
who were in exile in Babylon -
today modern Iraq.
Maybe they sat down one day
to make up
a cautionary tale about what happens
when people disobey God.
But it's said
that all stories
have some seeds of truth.
Maybe the Noah story
is an exaggeration,
an embellishment of something
that really happened.
150 years ago,
archaeologists made some
extraordinary finds
in Iraq.
Evidence that would re-write
the famous story about Noah
and his ark full of animals.
In 1851,
British archaeologist
Sir Henry Layard
explored the ruins
of the Babylonian library
of Ninevah.
His finds were a breakthrough -
hundreds of clay tablets -
of all sizes and shapes.
They may have held vital clues
about the Noah story.
The trouble was,
Sir Henry couldn't decipher
the ancient Babylonian script.
So he packed the tablets
and sent them off to London -
to the British Museum -
to be deciphered by experts.
The museum staff
had no idea about
the sensational information
encrypted in the tablets.
So they languished
in their vaults for years
until 1872
when they came to the attention
of museum assistant George Smith.
Dr Irving Finkel today
runs the department
in the British Museum
where George Smith worked.
Smith had a peculiar quality
tantamount to genius
which meant he could look
at a cuneiform tablet
and know what it was about,
more than anybody else
before him and probably
anybody else since.
And he wasn't
a trained phrenologist,
he know a bit of Hebrew,
he knew a bit of Arabic,
he could look things up
in the dictionary
but he just had
this amazing quality that
he could look at a bit of clay
which to everybody else
looks like a dog biscuit
and know what the words meant.
And he was the person
in our Department
who read about the flood
for the first time.
What George Smith discovered
among the tablets
was an ancient story
about a great flood -
the Epic of Gilgamesh.
It was a breakthrough
Smith himself
could barely comprehend.
The impact on him was something
that he could hardly control.
He dropped the tablet back
into the tray like this,
and started to run holding his head
and making funny noises
and according to the narrative
that is recorded
he started even to take
his clothes off in his agitation
because he was the first person
after all that time,
to read this funny writing
and see that
there was to all intents
and purposes the text
that everybody knew from the Bible
and it was just too much
for him to tolerate,
he just nearly went crazy.
What seemed to upset him so much
were the similarities
between the stories
of Gilgamesh and Noah
''The great gods decided
to make a deluge ''
''Build a boat...''
''Take into the boat the seed
of all living things...''
Irving Finkel has a theory
why George Smith behaved
so oddly that fateful day.
The sheer excitement
might have triggered
some sort of brain seizure.
I was reading something
about the history of epilepsy where
this phenomenon was described
as a particular kind of epilepsy,
making this funny noise
and trying to disrobe yourself
in the agitation
of having an epileptic
fit of some kind,
And it did occur to me
to wonder whether
shock that hit him,
the real shock
might not have triggered
something of that kind.
Since then yet more accounts
of the flood story
were unearthed in Iraq -
confirming that
the story first emerged
in ancient Mesopotamia -
the place where the great Sumerian,
Assyrian and Babylonian
civilisations were born.
The ancient flood stories
had different names
and were written at different times
but they all pointed to
a common ancestor
composed some 5000 years ago -
one original story
about a disastrous flood.
It is very likely
that the biblical story
has a Mesopotamian prototype
because they are so similar,
in both cases the gods have decided
to destroy the human race
they do so by a great flood,
one family survives in a boat,
they take on board animals,
they disembark and then
they repopulate the earth.
One of the oldest flood narratives -
The epic of Atra-hasis
written before the more famous
epic of Gilgamesh -
was discovered only recently.
Alan Millard found it
while sifting through
the British Museum's
backlog of clay tablets.
It made him wonder -
perhaps the Bible
never meant a global deluge.
The ancient Hebrew language
has one word for land
and country and earth
and it's easy to suppose
that means the whole earth
but it certainly need not.
And I think that
it was a local flood
that is described there.
The discovery
of these older versions
of Noah's story
raised a tantalising possibility.
What if they had been inspired
by an actual flood?
Not a global deluge,
but a regional flood
in Mesopotamia?
In the 1930s
archaeologists returned to Iraq
to find out.
In 1931,
a team of archaeologists
led by Leonard Woolley
and his wife Katherine
were excavating the ruins
of the ancient Mesopotamian
city of Ur.
The Woolleys were a colourful
husband and wife team -
friends of Lawrence of Arabia -
and of Agatha Christie the novelist.
They left a detailed record
of their finds
revealing that they dug
five to six thousand years
into the past -
the right time frame
for the Noah story.
One day his workmen struck
an unusual layer of soil -
one that could only have
been deposited
by water.
When the soil was analysed
it showed that the silt
had been deposited by river water.
Now, Mesopotamia suffered
regular seasonal floods.
But this was a massive layer -
something out of the ordinary.
In fact,
later archaeological excavations
of ancient city streets
show that five thousand years ago
at least three Mesopotamian towns
were hit by large river floods.
So Leonard Woolley and his wife
had hit the jackpot.
There had been a massive flood
in ancient Mesopotamia after all.
It was - conclusive proof -
a real story
lay behind the Biblical
and Babylonian epics
In committing the story to writing,
the Sumerian scribes
may have embellished it
with myths and supernatural events.
But there are plenty
of practical details too,
and they are priceless
in reconstructing a story
that's historically plausible.
However,
it does mean starting afresh
It means setting aside
the storybook image
of the huge Ark,
the global deluge,
the number of animals
and the landing on Mt Ararat.
Above all it means abandoning
the familiar Biblical
image of Noah,
and introducing
a very different image
of what he might have
actually looked like
and how he might have lived.
Archaeological finds
have established
that the Noah story may actually
have happened in Sumeria -
an ancient civilisation
in what is now Iraq.
The Babylonian accounts say
that the story begins
in the city of Shuruppak.
This was the cradle of civilisation.
The Sumerians invented writing,
the wheel and accounting.
And what is known
of Sumerian culture
offers the first glimpse
of the historical figure
behind the flood stories.
The most obvious difference
is how Noah looked.
Forget the man in Biblical robes
and imagine instead a Sumerian
from head to toe -
wearing eye make-up,
with a bald head and even a kilt!
Then there's what he did
for a living.
The Epic of Gilgamesh says
the Sumerian Noah
owned silver and gold.
Five thousand years ago,
these were the currency
of wealthy merchants,
suggesting that the Sumerian Noah
was not a farmer or a wine grower
but a businessman.
Instead of an Ark
to survive the flood,
the Sumerian Noah is more likely
to have built a boat
to make money -
hauling grain, beer and animals.
All the big trading centres -
like the great city of Ur -
lay on the Euphrates.
It was cheaper to take cargo
on river barges
than by overland caravans.
The question is how big a barge
did this Noah have?
The Sumerians used a variety
of boats on the Euphrates,
from small reed canoes,
to wooden ones 20 feet long.
But the Babylonian sources agree
the flood boat
was much bigger than those.
There was an obvious incentive
for merchants
to build the biggest commercial
river barge possible.
But they would have been limited
by the technology available.
No remains or inscriptions
of large Sumerian boats
have been found yet.
So instead marine archaeologists
have asked how big a boat
could the Sumerians have built
with the available know how?
One simple solution
would have been to tie
smaller boats together.
Marine archaeologist
Tom Vosmer believes
there are clues to this effect
in the Epic of Gilgamesh.
It says that the boat
was divided in sections.
Probably one
of the best ways to do
it would be to build it in units
such as the size of this,
and use it as a pontoon
in a river barge actually
held together,
lash them together, with some rope
and heavy timbers
and then they could build the ark
on top of that.
And it was probably a system
that could have been used
on the rivers quite easily.
Since the historical Ark
was a cargo vessel,
it's easy to say
what the Sumerian Noah
loaded on to his barge.
Forget the animals marching
two by two
and think instead
of Noah loading animals,
grain and beer for sale.
Even for a rich merchant,
it's quite an undertaking
to mastermind
such a big construction.
But according
to the Babylonian sources,
Noah had more than
just wealth on his side.
They say Noah was the king
of the city of Shuruppak,
but he wasn't above the law.
Failure to deliver his cargo
would have meant social
and financial ruin for Noah,
whether he was king or not.
In Sumeria anyone who failed
to pay their debts -
including kings -
was liable to end up as a slave.
But how did the flood come into it?
The most likely answer
is that Noah was caught out
by a freak combination
of natural events.
Parts of the Euphrates
were only navigable
when river levels
were at their peak.
That meant Noah would have
had to time his departure carefully.
That meant waiting
for the melt waters.
Melting snow
from the Armenian mountains
increased the flow
of the Euphrates in July.
Records indicate that only then
were the river channels
deep enough for large vessels.
But there was a risk.
If Shuruppak was hit
by a freak storm
just at the moment that river levels
were at their highest,
then the peaceful waters
of the Euphrates
could turn into a raging flood.
But the average rainfall
in dry years in July was zero.
The odds
on a catastrophic river flood
in Mesopotamia
would have been remote
about one in every 1000 years.
So if it happened
it should have been worth
writing about
The Babylonian tablets say that
on the day of the flood,
Noah and his family
were having a banquet on the barge.
Then the weather suddenly
began to change for the worse -
a freak storm was beginning
and a catastrophic flood
was on its way.
A storm that would threaten
Noah's very survival.
If a flash flood was big enough
to sweep away Noah's ark
and put his life in danger
it would have began
with rainfall of tropical intensity
in the mountains
where the rivers rise.
Mesopotamia isn't in the tropics,
but there's evidence that hurricanes
and tropical storms
could get that far.
Some 6000 years ago
it was much warmer and wetter
and it would be
no surprise whatsoever
to get a tropical storm.
we could have had ten times
the rainfall Some
of these metereological events
are absolutely catastrophic,
and these are the sort of events
that we record in history -
we don't record the normal
day to day humdrum
If a freak storm
coincided with the seasonal
snow melt,
then the Euphrates could easily
have flooded
the Mesopotamian plain.
The Bible says the storm lasted
for an incredible 40 days.
The Babylonian tablets say
it was 7.
But even a single day
would have been terrible,
life threatening.
With much of his cargo
left behind or swept away,
Noah's barge would have been
at the mercy of
the raging Euphrates.
The following day
say the Babylonian tablets,
Noah and his family
couldn't see land.
The flood extended for miles.
After the storm,
Noah and his family
must have longed
for the waters to subside,
and ground them on the banks
of the Euphrates.
In fact, their problems
had only just begun.
All versions of the story agree
that they couldn't see land
for at least seven days.
The Bible concludes
that Noah's flood
covered the whole world.
But there is
in fact another explanation.
Noah's family would have believed
that they were drifting
on the flooded Euphrates.
They would have been relieved
that at the very least
the river water meant
they wouldn't die of thirst.
But the Babylonian versions suggest
that the water was salty.
Noah's ark, was no longer drifting
on the flooded Euphrates
If you plot Noah's course
from Shuruppak -
now in the flooded plain -
the currents
would have swept his barge
downstream into the Persian Gulf!
This tallies
with the epic of Gilgamesh
which says that
the he ''looked upon the sea''.
There's no telling how long
Noah and his family
would have stayed marooned
in the Persian Gulf.
The Bible records more than a year,
the Babylonian tablets suggest
just a week.
Either way - Noah and his family
had a big problem: salty water.
What would they drink?
Without freshwater
from rain or river,
their only alternative
would have been the beer
they were carrying
for their traders.
Beer is actually a good alternative.
And we know we had it three
and half thousand years ago.
They were brewing beer,
it's full of nutrients,
most important it's sterile
and wouldn't suffer
from contamination
like water might.
One of the hallmarks
of the Noah story
is that the Ark
is said to have landed
in the mountains of Ararat.
But if there was no global flood
then it's far more likely
that it landed
somewhere else altogether.
The mountains of Ararat
lie to the north of Shuruppak.
Swept downriver,
the barge would have grounded
500 miles away
on the shores of the Persian Gulf.
In the Bible once the ark
has grounded the story
is almost over.
But the Babylonian tablets
hint that Noah's adventure
was far from over
There are several
puzzling references -
one talks of 'the overthrowing
of his kingship',
another says the flood hero
was 'expelled'.
All of these references
clearly suggest
that for some reason,
Noah couldn't return to Shuruppak -
that even when the flood was over,
he was still in mortal danger
The most likely explanation
is that many of Noah's creditors
had survived the deluge,
had tracked him down
and were now demanding
their money back.
Under Sumerian law
Noah could be forced into slavery
to repay his debts.
He would have had to flee
the country to avoid prosecution.
Precisely where the fugitive
Noah went is something
of a mystery.
One of the Babylonian tablets says
that Noah went to live
in a land called Dilmun.
Now that's the Sumerian name
for the modern island of Bahrain.
Maybe this is where he came to rest.
That is where,
after the flood was over,
the Babylonian Noah
was settled by the gods.
Apparently it was a pleasant
place to be
where he could exist
without much work
and pass the time away
as he pleased.
If he did end up in Dilmun,
then the modern island of Bahrain
may have a remarkable secret.
Its landscape is dotted
with hundreds of thousands
of burial mounds.
And only a handful of these tombs
have been excavated.
But many date back
to Sumerian times.
They are the sort of place
a great king
would be laid to rest in.
In time the memory of a king
who survived a flood
could have been turned
into a great Sumerian legend.
It would have been embellished
with miraculous
and mythological elements.
Eventually it would have been
written down,
copied and recopied
by generations of scribes,
giving rise to new versions.
Two thousand years later,
one of those versions,
languishing in a library in Babylon
could also have come
to the attention
of the Jewish priests
who wrote the Bible.
When they first read the story,
how could they fail to recognise
the lessons it offers.
If humankind falls
short of God's laws
there's a dreadful price to pay.
Behind that moral message
lies one of
the world's great stories.
And behind that story
we can just glimpse a real man,
a real boat, and a real adventure.