ARTO SAARI: Mama's Tacos and
Quesadillas is going to have a
competitor pretty soon.
After a couple more of these.
MALE SPEAKER: There.
The thing that's not supposed
to be there but is there?
MALE SPEAKER: Yep.
MALE SPEAKER: I feel
like I got hung up.
MALE SPEAKER: That's what I do
when I get fucking wasted.
It's how I get home.
ARTO SAARI: Are you guys
going to town?
BILL BRYANT: Yeah,
such as it is.
Want in?
ARTO SAARI: Yeah, you
got room there?
BILL BRYANT: You're going to
have either squeeze or hop in
the far back.
ARTO SAARI: I don't see a
DVD player back here.
MALE SPEAKER: We got bub, we
got pillows, we got smokes.
Whoa!
MALE SPEAKER: Baja Ride, 2009.
HIME HERBERT: Oh!
ARTO SAARI: OK.
HIME HERBERT: Oh, God.
ARTO SAARI: OK, OK, OK.
I'm walking, I'm walking.
Oh, fuck.
Fuck that.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
ARTO SAARI: Oh, look at
the barbecue machine.
Broil-Mate, dude.
MALE SPEAKER: Where's
Harvey at?
Here's the dentist.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
ARTO SAARI: I think that's going
to become the currency
for the next four days.
HEATH KIRCHART: Food?
ARTO SAARI: Food and cigarettes
is going to be the
most valid currency.
HEATH KIRCHART: So buy
cigarettes, even though I
don't smoke?
ARTO SAARI: Yeah.
BILL BRYANT: Sounds
like prison.
ARTO SAARI: Huh?
BILL BRYANT: That sounds
like prison.
ARTO SAARI: They're not
vegetarian, are they?
HEATH KIRCHART: He eats fish,
but Patrick's a vegetarian.
Harvey's whatever.
ARTO SAARI: How'd he
lose his tooth?
HEATH KIRCHART: Got punched.
ARTO SAARI: Really?
HEATH KIRCHART: Yeah.
ARTO SAARI: Wow, that's
pretty gnarly.
HEATH KIRCHART: They met up
on one of the wild rides.
They just traveled
across country,
met us in South Carolina.
Kept their distance for a couple
days and then slowly
came into the fold.
Now they want everything.
We don't even do the wild
ride anymore and
they still come out.
KYNAN TAIT: I think it seems
like we come as a package.
Because we're both Canadians,
we're both friends, we both
have Harleys.
PATRICK O'DELL: Not to say that
pro skaters are going to
be wimpy or something,
because they're not.
But it's good to have people
that don't even have that kind
of agenda or anything.
They just want to motorcycle
and skate and hang out.
And Harvey, he works on
oil rigs and stuff.
He works all winter on a oil
rig, saving enough money to
get to come on these trips.
It's easy to kind of take
this stuff for granted.
But for Harvey, this is the
highlight of his year.
HARVEY FOSTER: These trips
aren't expensive to do.
It's like all right, I can work
for like three or four
weeks, if that, and I
have enough money
to go on this trip.
I like to do whatever I
want whenever I want.
I guess going where the
road takes you.
That's so cliche though.
HIME HERBERT: It's going to be
nice to get back on some
smooth pavement, actually.
Just trying to get back
on the open highway.
BILL BRYANT: We are here,
basically, Camelon.
Arizarios where we were planning
on trying to get some
lunch or dinner.
That's where Mama
Espinoza's is.
And then where we're trying to
stop is Catavina, which is
kind of the dead spot.
Middle of this no-man's land
as we switch over from the
Pacific side to the Sea
of Cortez side.
There's not much out there,
and if we end up riding El
Rosario to Catavina in the
dark, it's going to suck.
I mean, it's just a recipe
for disaster.
KYNAN TAIT: I knew he
was going to come.
I just half expected him to be
there at dawn waiting for us
when we got there.
ARTO SAARI: Where the fuck
is the Canadian?
MALE SPEAKER: You didn't hear
from Keegan at all?
MALE SPEAKER: No.
HARVEY FOSTER: That's the
question of the day.
MALE SPEAKER: I mean, we knew
that he'd be here between
12:30 and 1:00.
HARVEY FOSTER: I think
that's him.
MALE SPEAKER: That's been
said for a while.
ARTO SAARI: That's probably
going to be the name of the
trip, have you heard
of Keegan yet?
HEATH KIRCHART: Canadian God.
HARVEY FOSTER: The
Canadian God.
PATRICK O'DELL: Can you
explain Keegan Sauder?
What he means to a Canadian?
HARVEY FOSTER: Should I give
them what I actually think, or
should I hold back?
KYNAN TAIT: [INAUDIBLE].
Can't hold back.
HARVEY FOSTER: I think he's the
fucking raddest Canadian
skateboarder ever.
And I had to listen to like the
guys who didn't know him.
Like, oh fuck, this guy's just
going to show up and make us
wait around like
well, whatever.
And sure enough, he comes
blasting through the desert.
I'm like, come on, man, that's
how Canadians roll.
MALE SPEAKER: Oh, it is.
MALE SPEAKER: He's making
an entrance.
HARVEY FOSTER: I don't think I
was fanning out, but in my
head I was fanning out.
Because he knows that
I've always been
fucking stoked on that.
Like I was down from
a young age.
I think I probably even asked
him when I lived here, like
when I moved, where's Keegan?
Do you guys hang out
with that guy?
I want to see that guy
skate in person.
KEEGAN SAUDER: Harvey!
KEEGAN SAUDER: Hey, man.
Harvey is El Diablo, and Ky is
calm, cool, collected and
really pale and sensitive
to mosquito bites.
They're from the same town
that I lived in.
But I moved away and then met
them later on going back to
visit Victoria.
HARVEY FOSTER: And now that I
know him as a good person, I'm
so 100% behind everything
that he does.
Like, I'll buy his board to
throw on my wall probably.
And I hope every other fucking
Canadian kid does.
KEEGAN SAUDER: I hung up
my crown as man am,
and became man pro--
major turning point.
The premiere was the
29th, and everyone
else left on the 27th.
But it became pretty obvious
that the zero video had to
take priority over anything
happening--
which is good and
now it's done.
And this trip happened,
so this is like a
vacation after that.
The first day of riding entailed
a lot of riding.
We started in Encinitas, rode to
Cuatro Casas, met you guys
on the highway.
And I think rode the same
distance again, like another
200 and something miles
again with you guys.
Which was fine, because
it was really fun.
PATRICK O'DELL: You
know, a 350 mile
ride pretty much sucks.
And so it was cool to look
over and see Arto and see
Keegan and everyone
still psyched.
KEEGAN SAUDER: I'm a motorcycle
racing fan, so I
like to pretend that I'm one.
So I do like corners a lot.
BILL BRYANT: The long stretches
have tons of turns,
and you can just wipe out in
any one of those turns.
Some of them are just like
racetracks, and if you can see
two or three turns deep it's
fun because you know what's
coming or what's not coming, and
you just lay down and go
as fast as you can
possibly go.
But the ones that are blind,
which is the majority of them,
there's just always the
potential that somebody's
going to be coming over that
line and coming after you.
KEEGAN SAUDER: Probably the most
mentally difficult would
just be the insanely long
straight stretches and stuff
like that where it doesn't
actually seem like you're
moving anywhere.
You could just be sitting on
your bike staring ahead in a
parking lot.
ARTO SAARI: There's our posse
of rebels right over there.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
KEEGAN SAUDER: Fuck,
man, Baja's big.
You kind of forget about it.
But then you're like what,
it's 1,000 miles long.
ARTO SAARI: I thought it was
like 500 miles there and 500
miles back.
And then we got to the hotel and
they're like no, the round
trip's 2,500.
HIME HERBERT: You guys
from Victoria?
KYNAN TAIT: Yeah.
HIME HERBERT: The island?
HIME HERBERT: That place
is awesome, man.
It's like going back
in time, kind of.
PATRICK O'DELL: You
work construction?
KYNAN TAIT: No, we work around
this boat that we live on.
KYNAN TAIT: A security
guard by trade.
We live on a boat on a
construction site.
And we get paid to do security
patrols of the construction
site at night.
KYNAN TAIT: And skim
the ponds.
HIME HERBERT: Who watches the
construction site when you
guys aren't there?
KYNAN TAIT: Well, it's like
a pretty big place, so--
KYNAN TAIT: He got wasted
and went to spray it.
And he had the thing backwards
and it sprayed and it went all
down his hand.
And then we went back in the
house and he comes running out
of his room naked,
like running.
He ran to the bathroom, then ran
to the shower, ran to the
bathroom, ran to the shower.
And I guess he had gone to his
room and tried to beat off and
hadn't cleaned his hand.
So he had bear spray
all over his hand.
HIME HERBERT: Oh my God,
that is amazing.
I'll get to that washing
off part later.
KEEGAN SAUDER: Got
to go wash off.
Oh no, boner!
KYNAN TAIT: Basically.
KEEGAN SAUDER: Only one way I
know to get rid of those.
HIME HERBERT: Put pepper
spray on my cock.
KYNAN TAIT: We're so
close [INAUDIBLE].
KEEGAN SAUDER: So you guys are
living the dream over there?
That's so rad.
ARTO SAARI: And Ky's
the captain.
HARVEY FOSTER: Yeah.
ARTO SAARI: What are you?
Cabin boy?