CARL AZUZ, CNN ANCHOR: It`s a new month, but
millions of Americans are starting November
in the same situation as how they ended October.
In the aftermath of the so called Super storm
Sandy. It leads off today`s program.
One meteorologist called Sandy a storm that
will be talked about for generations. The
numbers tell part of the story. At least 50
deaths in the U.S., millions of people still
without power on Wednesday, 10 to $20 billion
in estimated property damage and lost business.
But the images, the snapshots of the devastation,
that`s what really make it hit home. Head
up to the Jersey shore to Seaside Heights,
the boardwalk, the amusement pier. This is
what it looks like now, the park still there.
Some of the pier was washed out to sea, the
rollercoaster is still standing, but now it`s
out in the ocean. Getting around parts of
New York and New Jersey means riding in a
yellow cab, but these won`t be stopping to
pick up passengers any time soon: Flooding
caused damage to rail lines all across New
Jersey as well.
Two airports in the New York area were planning
to start limited service yesterday, but not
LaGuardia Airport. It`s runways and concourses
remained empty because of significant storm
damage although it is scheduled to reopen
today.
Getting around underground was limited, too.
Most New York Subway tunnels were still flooded
yesterday with no estimate for when they might
reopen.
Of course, those aren`t the only images from
the past few days, this was a massive storm,
it brought scenes of disaster and it brought
scenes of heroism, too.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
VOICE OF MAYOR BILL AKERS, SEASIDE HEIGHTS,
NEW JERSEY: We`re riding around, it`s two
o`clock in the morning, and we are pulling
people out of the water. You see these people
and these cars load down the street, and these
guys do this -- they do this with no regards
to anything other than they want to do the
right thing and help. And you get inspired
by things like that, and I just don`t know
where it comes from in individuals like this.
VOICE OF SEN. ROBERT MENENDEZ, NEW JERSEY:
You have National Guard now, thank God, helping
rescue people out of their homes, but there
is nowhere to go. There is a very thick stench
of gasoline in the water as well. So you have
a real challenge to the (inaudible) here.
VOICE OF GOV. ANDREW CUOMO, NEW YORK: First,
once again, I want to congratulate all the
first responders who were still out there,
and still doing a magnificent job under difficult
circumstances. We should all be very proud.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: There are many ways you can help the
victims of Super storm Sandy. Go to cnnstudentnews.com
and click on the impact your world link in
the spotlight section to find out how you
can get involved in relief efforts.
That`s something the presidential candidates
did as Governor Romney and President Obama
stopped campaigning for a few days. Romney
turned his campaign rallies in the storm relief
events. And people were encouraged to bring
canned goods to help victims.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
MITT ROMNEY, REPUBLICAN PRESIDENTIAL CANDIDATE:
We have heavy hearts, as you know, with all
the suffering going on in a major part of
our country, a lot of people hurt in this
morning, they were hurting last night, and
the storm goes on.
I appreciate the fact that people right here
in Dayton got up this morning, some went to
the grocery store, I see and purchased some
things that these families will need. And
I appreciate you generosity.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: President Obama and Governor Romney
have been encouraging donations to the Red
Cross, and yesterday, the president went to
New Jersey to see some of the damage caused
by Sandy and to extend his thoughts to the
families affected by the storm.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
BARACK OBAMA, PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES
OF AMERICA: Our hearts go out to the families
who have lost loved ones. It`s true that because
of some good preparation, the loss of life
was kept lower than it might have been, but
for those individual families, obviously,
their world has been torn apart. The sooner
we can get our kids back into school, the
sooner they are back in the routine, that
obviously helps the families and helps the
kids as well.
GOV. CHRIS CHRISTIE, (R ), NEW JERSEY: Right
now, I`m much more concerned about preventing
any other loss of life, getting people to
safe places, and then we`ll worry about the
election. The election will take care of itself.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: OK, Governor Christie understandably
says he`s focused on people over politics
now. But some folks are thinking about next
Tuesday`s election, and one thing they`ve
been wondering is whether Sandy will have
an effect. Remember, power is out in parts
of several states, places where people vote
may had been flooded or damaged, but officials
in most of these states still expect things
to go smoothly on election day.
As for the candidates, they took a break for
the campaign trail for a few days, but things
started to pick up again on Wednesday.
Governor Romney was attending a campaign event
in Florida, President Obama is scheduled to
be out on the campaign trail again today.
One difference, thought: the tone of the campaigns,
which have gotten kind of harsh at times,
is more positive.
We`ve been looking this week where President
Obama and Governor Romney stand on some of
the issues. Today, we are focusing on healthcare.
For both candidates, a lot of the focus on
this issue involves the Affordable Care Act,
also known as Obamacare. A lot of political
experts consider it President Obama`s biggest
accomplishment. It says that insurance companies
cannot deny someone coverage, if they have
a preexisting condition. And it requires most
Americans to have some kind of health insurance
by 2014, or face a fine. There were some law
suits about whether that requirement was constitutional.
The U.S. Supreme Court eventually said" "Yes."
Governor Romney says, if he`s elected, he`ll
work to get the health care law overturned.
When he was governor of Massachusetts, Romney
helped create a health care plan that was
similar to President Obama`s. One difference,
he says, is that it was limited to one state.
Governor Romney says health care solutions
should come from individual states rather
than from the federal government.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today`s "Shoutout" goes
out to Mrs. Bowyer`s world history class at
J.P. Knapp Early College High School in Currituck,
North Carolina.
Which country has the largest population in
the European Union? Here we go, is it Germany,
France, United Kingdom or Spain? You`ve got
three seconds, go!
With more than 80 million residents, Germany
has the European Union`s largest population.
That`s your answer and that`s your "Shoutout."
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Germany is also where you find the largest
American military community outside of the
United States. And part of the reason for
that is what happened after World War II,
Germany was divided into two countries, you
had East Germany and West Germany. The West
was established in part by the United States,
the East was controlled by the Soviet Union,
a rival of the U.S. And Germany reunified
in 1990, near the end of the cold war. But
George Howell shows us how history has a hold
on those raised between different nations.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
RONALD REAGAN: Mr. Gorbachev, tear down this
wall!
(END VIDEO CLIP)
GEORGE HOWELL, CNN CORRESPONDENT: This year
marched the 25th anniversary of that famous
phrase, but the impact of the U.S. military
build-up in Germany during the Cold War is
still being felt today, in an unlikely place:
the soccer field. A half dozen sons of American
soldiers, stationed in Germany, born to German
mothers, have elected to play for the U.S.
national soccer team rather than Germany`s
in the last few years.
For some, this decision relates to their racial
identity: Danny Williams and the other five
players all have African American fathers.
(on camera): What does it mean to be biracial
in Germany versus being biracial here in the
United States.
DANNY WILLIAMS, UNITED STATES MIDFIELDER:
When people are looking at me in Germany,
they know that I`m not 100 percent German.
I told my parents that it isn`t -- I feel
more American than German.
HOWELL (voice over): Jermaine Jones was the
first of this recent wave from Germany to
join the American soccer team.
JERMAINE JONES, UNITED STATES SOLDIER: I`m
different, when you see me, to German people.
I`m a different guy. I`m mixed.
HOWELL: Unlike Williams, whose American father
raised him in Germany, Jones grew up in a
single parent household.
JONES: My mom and him goes when I was young,
separate ways, and for me it was hard, too,
to grow up with no dad.
HOWELL: But since electing to play for the
U.S., Jones had rekindled his relationship
with his father. After scoring his first goal
for the Starts and Stripes, Jones performed
a simple, but poignant tribute to his soldier
father.
(on camera): You gave a salute to your dad.
JONES: Yeah, he called me after game, he`s
like -- God, thank you all, my mom, my brother,
everybody sees it, and everybody`s proud of
you.
HOWELL: A simple gesture of pride, but one
rooted in history.
George Howell, CNN, Miami.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Before we go, it`s all about some school
spirit. HLN asked college marching bands to
send an I-Report to their best work, and X
marks the spot for Bethune Cookman (ph). Marching,
playing and not running into each other -- truly
extraordinarily.
Now, for the University of Iowa. They are
paying tribute to an old school Michael Jackson
hit, giving the hawk-eye audience a "Thriller."
And while the term "horseplay: indicates you
are not taking something seriously, look at
this -- Ohio State`s band, seriously awesome.
Some would say these buckeyes are nuts.
It`s amazing what can happen when people band
together. They get so attuned to what`s playing
out around them, that after getting their
marching orders, the result is band to the
trombone. All right. Saying a lot of puns
a little bit at a time can leave me kind of
winded. But take note -- we`ll be fielding
more headlines tomorrow, on CNN STUDENT NEWS.