Watch.
I'm going cause it to float
in the air, watch.
I'll put a spell it, float.
[SINGING]
do, do, do, do.
Isn't that amazing?
And then they can
break the spell.
Break the spell.
And then in ancient Hindu
Faquirs would be in the
streets of India and they can
cause it float in the air like
this, float.
[SINGING]
do, do, do, do.
And they would climb
to the top of it.
[SINGING]
do, do, do, do, do.
Today, the science of
things of-- hey.
Higgensworth, why didn't
you tell him to--
fired.
The things that float.
I'm Steve Spangler and I'm all
about making science fun.
For the last 20 years, I've
been teaching ways to turn
ordinary science experiments
into unforgettable learning
experiences.
I have an amazing team who will
do whatever it takes to
affect the way people
think about science.
And to do that I only
have one motto.
Make it big, do it right,
give it class.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Hey Higgens, I'll show
you a trick.
Here, watch this.
Pick a card, pick a
card, pick a card.
Perfect.
Look at it?
Got it?
Now, I want you to put it back
in the deck wherever you want,
that's perfect.
All right, so it's lost
in the deck, ready?
A lot of mixing around,
OK, I mixed it around.
OK, now I'm going to find your
card and I'm going to cause it
to come right out of the
deck, it's going to
float out of the deck.
Watch this, magic hand.
[SINGING]
do, do, do, do.
Whoop.
Got it, that is your card?
BRYAN HIGGENS: No.
STEVE SPANGLER: I know
it is, it's for sure.
BRYAN HIGGENS: Not at all.
Weren't You raised
by magicians?
STEVE SPANGLER: Shut
up, I don't have my
magic wand with me.
God, I knew I got it.
I'm going to give a little
cut like this, [WHISTLE].
Bam, and is this your card,
the eight of hearts?
BRYAN HIGGENS: No.
And I didn't sign it
and it says Deb.
STEVE SPANGLER: It's from
another show I did.
Any of these three
cards yours?
BRYAN HIGGENS: No,
no they aren't.
STEVE SPANGLER: Look at these
cards and tell me
if you yours anywhere.
You see them?
BRYAN HIGGENS: Yes.
STEVE SPANGLER: You seem them?
BRYAN HIGGENS: Yep.
STEVE SPANGLER: Are we good?
BRYAN HIGGENS: Yes.
STEVE SPANGLER: Now I'm going
to it a little shuffle.
You see them at all?
BRYAN HIGGENS: Yep.
STEVE SPANGLER: You
see it in there?
BRYAN HIGGENS: Um, hmm.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK, good.
Do you see your card
right here?
BRYAN HIGGENS: Yes.
STEVE SPANGLER: Ah, perfect.
Do you see it in here?
BRYAN HIGGENS: Yes I do.
STEVE SPANGLER: Yes.
Do you see it in here?
BRYAN HIGGENS: No.
STEVE SPANGLER: [BEEP]
[BEEP], [BEEP].
OK, is this your card right
here, this queen?
BRYAN HIGGENS: No.
STEVE SPANGLER: Three
and [INAUDIBLE].
BRYAN HIGGENS: That's it.
STEVE SPANGLER: See.
Can you cut that?
[BEEP]
STEVE SPANGLER: Stand
by in three, two.
And out of all the cards that
you picked and I shuffled them
and threw them all on the floor,
I'll pick up one card.
Is this your card?
BRYAN HIGGENS: That's it.
STEVE SPANGLER: Thank
you very much.
BRYAN HIGGENS: Impressive.
STEVE SPANGLER: Thanks.
You ever see Criss Angel
in Las Vegas like
float up in the air?
Easy.
But another object like a
Styrofoam cup, very tough.
Ready, watch this.
Do, ah.
And you'll see that it's
defying gravity.
I got my finger in the
the back of the cup.
That's awesome.
Don't tell you Higgensworth.
Higgensworth, I'm going
to do a cup trick.
Well here, every man
has one of these.
All right, so you take a regular
handkerchief like this
and you take your hair
out, [WHOOSH]
and you tie it onto
this thing here.
And then you tie it here like
this, and then you pull it
down, and it floats.
And then you take your scissors
and you cut it.
Magic.
This will keep Higgensworth
busy for hours.
Higgensworth, get your scissors,
come over here.
[DOOR SHUTTING]
For this you're going to need
some uncooked rice and some
recycled plastic
water bottles.
All right, so the rice goes
down inside like this.
You simply fill the container
up like this.
And you're going to do two of
them so you want them to be
exactly the same.
And so you can see they'll the
same, I filled that one
previously.
[HAND CLAP]
So now we're ready to go.
And you're going to need
two chop sticks.
All right, so here's
what you do.
You take your hand and you
plunge it in like this.
And now, only using your
fingertips you pick this up
like this and you realize
it comes out.
But this one here, watch.
Ah, like magic, it floats.
Now I know what you're
thinking.
You're thinking maybe it's the
chopsticks and there's a
secret with that.
I switched chopsticks.
I'm going to do the same thing
again, watch this.
It goes in there like this and
it goes in here like and now
you pick it up.
Watch.
The secret is look.
This is light rice, gravity
defying rice and
this is heavy rice.
I know what you're thinking,
there's something
wrong with the rice.
There's not, watch this.
We dump them out like this and
the rice flows out like this.
There is absolutely nothing
wrong with it.
If you look, there's nothing
hiding in the bottles.
Two empty bottles, the
same amount of rice.
Well of course it's not
magic, it's science.
And it actually is about the
science of friction.
And the guy who discovered
friction, right here.
Leonardo DiCaprio.
BRYAN HIGGENS: Wait,
wait, wait.
STEVE SPANGLER: I actually
got to meet him.
He signed this to
me back-- what?
BRYAN HIGGENS: I said, see here,
it was Leonardo da Vinci
in the 16th century.
STEVE SPANGLER: Di--
BRYAN HIGGENS: Not DiCaprio,
da Vinci.
STEVE SPANGLER: Could you hang
that back up on my wall?
BRYAN HIGGENS: Yep.
STEVE SPANGLER: Could
you maybe work on
your script as well?
da Vinci.
What you see is what you get.
You're going to need
the materials that
I showed you before.
Two empty water bottles, some
rice, some chopsticks.
That's it.
It's how the rice goes into the
bottle that's the secret.
Let's do the light rice first.
This is the gimmick-ed
bottle so to speak.
So we're going to fill
it up with rice.
Keep on putting rice in
here until it's full.
Have you ever seen that old
puzzle where they fill a
bottle with something, like
pebbles and they say, is the
bottle full?
It's filled to the top with
pebbles and somebody says yes.
And you go no, no, no.
And then they start pouring in
sand and now the sand fills up
the little crevices.
And they say is it full?
And everybody says yes.
And you go no.
And finally they fill
it with water.
And only at that point
is it full.
Well that's a long way of being
able to tell you that
this bottle is not full even
though it looks like it's
filled to the top with
rice, like this.
All right, see, it's full.
But it's not really full.
Here, watch this.
All you have to do is tap it.
And watch how the rice
begins to compact.
Look at how far down
it will go.
These plastic water
bottles are great.
The original-- this is an old,
old magic trick and so the
original one were these kind
of fancy glass bottles, but
these work so well.
See how much more rice
I can get in.
All right, back to this.
Some more will go in, I'll even
push it in with my thumb
a little bit.
A little bit here.
Tap it down.
It'll even take a
little bit more.
All right, we don't want to
make it look too obvious.
All right, so this here is hard
to squeeze, there's a lot
rice that's in here.
This bottle here, we're going to
fill up, no tapping at all.
We really want it to be
very, very fluffy.
I'm trying not to tap
this down at all.
I want this to be nice and
fluffy, for there to be a lot
of space in between all
those pieces of rice.
All right, I think it's really
good at the very end to put it
in there when you're actually
doing the trick so it makes it
seem like they're exactly
the same.
All right, so here's what's
going to happen.
I'll spin these around.
This will be light one
of course, and this
is the heavy one.
See, this one already started
to go down a little bit, so
you can fill it up.
All right, with the chopstick,
this one extremely easy to be
able to push in because that
chopstick is going in between
those kernels of rice with
no problem at all.
But this one here is pretty
amazing because when you push
it down here like this, it's so
full but you can actually
hear it, listen.
[RICE CRUNCHING].
Hear it going in?
What's happening are all those
pieces of rice are realigning
themselves this way.
They are actually digging
into the piece of wood.
So no wonder when you try to
pick up this one here, of
course it doesn't work at all.
And this one here, absolutely
no problem at all.
It's fun to do with a friend,
you're the magician and your
friend can't do it and
you can do it.
And the secret of course,
is friction
with Leonardo da Vinci.
Now here's the problem.
When you go to pull this one out
here, it's a little harder
to pull out.
You will want to put your
fingers here and pull a little
bit so it looks natural.
There's more rice in this
one than this one.
So when you go to dump it, as
you're talking, begin to pour
this one first.
So you can say, all I used
was regular rice, watch.
And now it begins to pour
because I had that little bit
a head start.
When they flow, they should
both kind of fall out, you
hope, as you are shaking them
out exactly the same.
Bingo, and you've got it.
Not a bad way to do it.
The other secret, believe
it or not is the
shape of the bottle.
You need to have a bottle
where the neck
comes up like this.
In doing so when you push this
down, it actually allows the
rice to push up against that
neck and create the friction
that you need to pick
up the bottle.
If you use another container
like this, even though there's
a lot of rice packed in there.
No matter what you do, it won't
pick up the container.
[DOOR CLOSING]
Well for this trick you're using
unpopped popcorn and a
steel ball bearing.
All right, watch this.
The ball bearing goes into the
corn and most people don't
realize that corn and the ball
bearing have this chemical
reaction here.
Watch this, I'll spin
it around, watch.
And you'll see that magically,
it turns
into a ping pong ball.
It doesn't take a rocket
scientist to figure this out.
Look at the secret,
it's there.
Here's the ball bearing.
This is a density
demonstration.
So watch, the little ball
hides under the
surface, like this.
Now nobody knows that it's
there, it's perfect.
So now if you take the ball
bearing, and you drop the ball
bearing in, this eventually, as
you start moving it around
will sink down.
And believe it or not, the corn
will help push the ping
pong ball up so as you are
holding it here like this,
here watch.
Ta da.
So if you're teaching science,
what does this teach?
Basically nothing.
I don't know, you can tie it
into density if you wanted to.
I think it's a cool trick.
Ah.
Well for this little gem you are
going to need to have some
table salt.
And where to you get
the table salt?
From your friend's
mom's house.
While you are there, get
yourself her credit card
because you're going
to need to also
get a baby soda bottle.
Where do you baby soda bottle?
A website called
stevespanglerscience.com [BEEP]
I've been asked to remove
that one offensive part.
Forget the friends get the
salt from your own house.
So this is more of a puzzle
than a magic trick
but it is very cool.
So you fill this little
test tube.
You can use anything that's like
this, but this test tube
works really, really well.
You fill it up with
salt, like this.
Then you take an ordinary
marble and drop it in.
And now you put the cap
on top like this.
That's why we like to use these
little baby soda bottles.
And now the object is this, is
to ask a friend, again a
puzzle, to move that little
marble from one end to the
other end as fast as they can.
And they're going to try
to shake it like this.
And they are going to try to
move it down here like this.
It really is tough to move it
down, especially if there's
some time involved with it.
It'll take them forever.
If you're a baby sitter,
this is perfect.
It'll keep the kid
busy for hours.
And if you're ever babysitting
for Higgensworth,
it'll take him days.
Ta da.
That only took me about
10 minutes.
There's an easier way to move
that little marble from one
end to the other.
And the secret is this.
If you turn the whole thing
upside down, so see it's at
the bottom.
If you want to move into
the top, here's
what you have to do.
You have to send everything up
into the air and when you do
that, the salt will work its way
underneath the marble and
literally begin to push the
marble to the very top.
So you have this motion of up
and down and let it fall down.
And there it is.
So in a matter of seconds,
it's at the top.
This is a perfect technique for
getting the toy surprise
out of your cereal.
You know how they put the
toy surprise in there?
It's never at the top
where you want it.
And you have to get your
hand in here and
you have to dig around.
And you've got dirty hands,
[SNOT BLOW], then all of a
sudden nobody wants
your cereal.
So here's how you get the
toy surprise to the top.
You go like this, and you
shake it up like this.
So if you give it a shake, now
that toy surprise will slowly
work its way to the top.
Ta da.
It's at the top.
Who put this in here?
That's not funny.
[DOOR CLOSING]
All right, now let's do
a real magic trick.
This is very, very cool.
It uses two glass bottles.
These were, I don't know, water
bottles or something.
And two pieces of rope.
So examine them, make
sure they're OK.
They should be absolutely
the same.
OK?
So here's what we're
going to do.
I want you to pick one of the
bottles, left or right?
Bingo.
Pick one of the pieces of
rope, it doesn't matter.
Got it, all right.
This is called do as I do.
So what you're going to do is
you're going to ask him to put
the rope inside the bottle.
Higgins, put the rope
inside the bottle.
Do as I do, like this.
BRYAN HIGGENS: OK.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK, put it in.
Hold it in your hand
like this.
And now turn it upside-- hold it
like this-- turn it upside
down and cause the rope to
float in the bottle.
Ha, ha, ha, ha.
No it's because I have a magic
spell on mine, so watch.
You take the rope like this.
BRYAN HIGGENS: OK.
STEVE SPANGLER: And put it in
here like this, got it?
Good and now turn
it upside down.
And it floats.
And then you take it
like this and the
bottle floats like this.
So when you put yours
inside like this,
it'll float like that.
And when you want to release
the spell, then it's gone.
See how that works?
So I could put this in
here like this, you
turn it upside down.
You go wiggle, wiggle, wiggle.
There's actually a genie inside
the bottle and then the
genie holds onto the rope.
It hangs onto it like this.
And you can release the little
genie down inside by pushing
the rope down in here
and wiggling.
Wiggle, wiggle, wiggle.
And the genie comes out.
See how it works?
You probably think it's--
BRYAN HIGGENS: There's
no genie in mine.
STEVE SPANGLER: See, maybe you
need a different bottle.
So here, take my bottle.
Take my rope.
I'll take your robe.
I'll take your bottle.
Watch this.
Take the piece of rope, put it
down inside, turn the whole
thing upside down.
Let go, wiggle, wiggle,
wiggle.
See it stays here like this.
Turn it upside down.
And it floats like magic.
And that's how you do a special
little trick called
the prayer vase.
Did you get it Higgens?
BRYAN HIGGENS: No, not yet.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK, go and let
it go, it'll be perfect.
This is actually an IQ test so
if you can do it on the first
try, you're pretty smart.
And if you do this,
really smart.
So here's, believe it
or not the secret.
A little bit of aluminum foil.
All right, you're not going to
need much, you are going to
tear off a little square of
aluminum foil like this.
And what we need is we need
something that will hook onto
the rope inside.
So what I want you to do
is fold it up like
this and make a ball.
So you're going to want to
squeeze this down so that it
very easily falls right
into the bottle.
The original ones from the magic
shop would use a little
piece of cork that somebody
had worked on.
I think the aluminum foil
works perfectly.
And you can keep on working it
and it will fall into the
bottle with no problem at all.
Here's what's great
about this bottle.
I happened to find it.
It's this blue which
I thought was cool.
I took some black spray paint
and actually shot it inside
the bottle here so that
you can't see
through the neck here.
You can see a little bit through
here which is great,
but you can't see through
the neck.
So when you drop this down
inside you can't-- nobody
really sees, it's on the bottom
and when it's trapped
there in the little neck, nobody
can see it at all.
But so you can see what's going
on, let's trade out for
a clear bottle.
At the very beginning I had the
little piece of aluminum
foil in my finger like this.
So it's called a finger
palm, or a clip.
So it's being held
here in my hand.
And you turn your hand over and
it looks fairly natural.
Now if you sit here and you're
worried about, then everybody
going to know that it's
in your hand.
But you're not.
Here's a piece of rope and
here are the bottles.
And pretend like we had these
two bottles, that's fine, OK?
But I'm going to show you
how it works with it.
So the little ball goes
down inside and now
we're ready to go.
I'll show you about how to load
it in here in a second,
but I want to show
you how it works.
First of all you take the piece
of rope and the rope
goes down inside.
When you turn it upside down,
look at what happens.
The little ball gets lodged
between the rope and the side
of the bottle.
So now we've set up some
fraction that's here.
Pull and you can see.
So when you let go nobody can
see this because again, that
neck is black.
So you can't see it.
And now when you turn it upside
down, the rope hangs
which is beautiful.
Now to release it, all you have
to do is put your hand
here like this.
And when you put your hand on
it, it the rope down enough to
be able to release the ball.
I can easily release
this and I can do
the whole thing again.
And if they ever it to say
there's something in the
bottle you simply turn it upside
down and draw attention
to something on the bottom.
All that's really doing is
loading that ball back into
your fingers like this.
You pull it back out and you
hand them the bottle.
You take this bottle here and
you say see, mine's the same.
I loaded it back in and now I'm
ready to go once again.
It's tricky.
All right, so let's see if
my student can do it.
Ready, hold it in your finger
like that, you got it?
Turn it upside down, load
it in, perfect.
Turn it back over, perfect.
Nobody hears.
Now this goes in here like this,
turn it upside down.
Wiggle, there's a little genie
inside, do you have it?
Ah.
Bingo.
And now take and swing it.
[SWOOSH]
You, see you are amazing.
All right, so now put
it back down again.
Push it down a little bit
because that will release it,
so you're going to have
to do it here close.
So release it, good job.
Pull it back out again
and you've done it.
BRYAN HIGGENS: Awesome.
STEVE SPANGLER: That's
awesome.
And now you know the science
of things that float.
You did a good job.
Now if you get this and
the rope thing in the
handkerchief or--
you could do kid's
birthday parties.
You could put it all
in a little tub.
BRYAN HIGGENS: That's true.
STEVE SPANGLER: My
boys are having a
birthday party next Saturday.
BRYAN HIGGENS: Why didn't
I see this coming?
STEVE SPANGLER: And you should
put it all there because the
kids would love to
see you there.
You could maybe make a
little extra money.
Not from me of course, but if
you did a good job on mine,
there might be some neighbors
that would want you to come.
BRYAN HIGGENS: All right.
STEVE SPANGLER: Maybe some
YouTube viewers would like you
to come their house too.
BRYAN HIGGENS: I'll let
you know Steve.
STEVE SPANGLER: I think
you should do that.
And then you're not going to let
me know, I need you there
at the house.
So it's next-- if you take out
your phone, all right, write
this date down, OK?
BRYAN HIGGENS: All right.
STEVE SPANGLER: It's next week,
it's next Saturday.
If you come a half an hour
early, we got to get the
backyard set up so.
So that would be perfect.
Press Save, save.
Good.
So if I were, I'd
get practicing.
You are going to
do a good job.
My kids are going to love you.
And if they're bad, we're going
to shut this circus down
like they were bad at the last
magician, but they've learned.
OK?
You'll going to do great.
My kids are going to love you
[MUSIC PLAYING]
STEVE SPANGLER: If I were to
ask this what this is, you
would probably say a pitcher
full of milk.
But what it really is
is evaporated milk.
Let me show you what I mean.
I'll pour the milk into the cone
and all it takes for the
milk to evaporate is
my magic wand.
[LAUGHTER]
Evaporation is complete.
MALE SPEAKER: For
heaven's sake.
How did you do that?
STEVE SPANGLER: Very well.
[LAUGHTER]
MALE SPEAKER: Just like his
father is what he is.