CHARLET DUBOC: I realize that
there are fashion weeks going
on all over the world all the
time that aren't Paris, New
York, London, Milan.
The episode you're about to
watch is one of our favorites,
Colombia Fashion Week.
It's got everything in there,
stroppy models, urban pole
dancing, Pablo Escobar's
brother's even in there, and a
rather grisly bum implant
operation.
So, yeah.
Here it is, Fashion Week
International, Colombia.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHARLET DUBOC: Welcome to
Fashion Week International, a
new show that reports on the
most fabulous fashion weeks in
the world and the culture and
politics behind them.
We were here for Colombia
Fashion Week, a celebration of
Colombia's second most famous
export, beautiful girls.
[MUSIC PLAYING IN FOREIGN
LANGUAGE]
MALE SPEAKER 1:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[MUSIC PLAYING IN FOREIGN
LANGUAGE]
FEMALE SPEAKER 1:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
MALE SPEAKER 2:
MALE SPEAKER 3:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
MALE SPEAKER 2:
CHARLET DUBOC: Do you
know there's a
fashion week going on?
MALE SPEAKER 4:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: Shh.
Most fashion weeks are
synonymous for cocaine.
This fashion week is having an
extra hard time totally trying
to dispel that because Medellin
is the old stomping
ground of Pablo Escobar.
And yeah, we're just going to
have a big fashionable time
and not take any cocaine.
We started in the trade show.
This wasn't so much high fashion
as it was high street.
I couldn't help but notice the
women perusing and working the
stores all flaunting
their Latin curves.
The girls all stuck to fairly
mainstream, high
street honey look.
But there was some who were
at least making an effort.
Do you really think you're
going to find the latest
trends here?
MALE SPEAKER 3:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
MALE SPEAKER 2:
CHARLET DUBOC: Wow.
FEMALE SPEAKER 2:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: Well, it's
really weird that she
obviously forgot that she had
bum implants and a boob job.
But maybe there's a collective
amnesia going on here.
That night we attended the first
fashion show of the week
held in a disused factory
across town.
It didn't take us long
to make friends.
I was pounced on by the
inimitable Diego who insisted
on taking me under his wing.
CHARLET DUBOC: Yeah!
Great walk!
CHARLET DUBOC: No?
CHARLET DUBOC: I have to be
a little bit careful, OK.
MODEL 1:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: Diego, what
are we doing here?
DIEGO: OK.
Give me one second.
OK.
Hello, everyone.
We are in Colombia Moda.
OK.
Which is a very important
event about money.
I mean, about, you know,
this kind of stuff.
You know, this is very
important for us.
OK.
CHARLET DUBOC: No.
I had no idea what he was
talking about, but I knew it
was all very important.
DIEGO:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
JOHN:
CHARLET DUBOC: Lost
in translation
again, thanks to Diego.
It was an odd show and
surprising first impression of
Colombian fashion.
Cocaine had gone from being the
elephant in the corner of
the room, to just a giant pile
of prop drugs in the
middle of the room.
The vibe was very European, a
long way from what we'd seen
at the trade show.
We skipped across town
to the next show in
search of some answers.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHARLET DUBOC: We're backstage
at Colombia Moda.
And the models are practicing.
And they're really hot.
But they don't look like
Colombian girls.
MALE SPEAKER 4:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CARLOS:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
MODEL 2:
CHARLET DUBOC: Narco beauty?
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: Would you say
that this fashion week and
models like you represent
the rest of Colombia?
MODEL 2:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: She didn't
like that question then.
The term narco beauty seemed to
be as much to do with class
as fashion.
After the show, someone tipped
us off about a separate
fashion event going on
across town called
Moda para el Mundo.
I wanted to find out the buzz
from some of the girls at
Colombia Moda.
Have you heard of this other
fashion week, Para el Mundo?
FEMALE SPEAKER 3:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
FEMALE SPEAKER 4:
FEMALE SPEAKER 5: Moda
para el Mundo is more
like for people that--
I don't want to say it.
CHARLET DUBOC: The following day
we resolved to check out
this other fashion week
to see for ourselves.
So we've just arrived
in, like, a
really fun area of town.
I guess you'd call
it downtown.
It's literally a stone's throw
from the actual, fashion week
but it's worlds apart.
It's called Moda para el Mundo,
Fashion for the World.
And it's supposedly going
to represent more
of Colombian fashion.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHARLET DUBOC: Wow.
MODEL 3:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: How do you feel
about the fact that the other
fashion week, Colombia Moda,
they're slowly phasing out
Colombian girls and
girls with curves?
MODEL 3:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: Although some
girls were natural, most
definitely had some help to
achieve those curves.
The plastic surgery was
ubiquitous on the cat walk.
MARIA:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: Hi.
MALE SPEAKER 1:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[SINGING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: It was unusual
for me to hear women's body
parts referred to as bits,
comparable to accessories such
as sunglasses.
MALE SPEAKER 1:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: What was that?
FEMALE SPEAKER 5: He just
said [INAUDIBLE].
CHARLET DUBOC: Did he say that
I need boobs or bum?
[MUSIC PLAYING IN FOREIGN
LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: After
one of the shows,
I made a new friend.
One of Medellin's most popular
commercial fashion
photographers, Felipe.
He offered to give me the
Colombian model experience to
gain some insight into Colombian
girls' motives and
feelings about the way they
present themselves.
FELIPE RESTREPO: Here's is
one of my makeup artists.
FELIPE RESTREPO:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
FEMALE SPEAKER 6:
FELIPE RESTREPO:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: I don't
think that's good.
What do you think?
CHARLET DUBOC: Wow.
How long is your pick?
We're trying on various really
traumatic things.
And I don't think I'm ever
coming out of this bathroom.
I'm going to try
another one on.
Bye.
[MUSIC PLAYING IN FOREIGN
LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: So we've arrived
at the shoot location.
It looks amazing.
There's these cool old kind of
carriages and stray dogs.
And it's a bit cold.
No.
LIZ: Please!
CHARLET DUBOC: No.
It's not happening.
Felipe's wife, ex-model, Liz,
was determined to star me in
nothing but a bikini.
I wasn't giving in
without a fight.
LIZ: Please!
You can.
You look--
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
CHARLET DUBOC: No.
I just don't want to be
in my bikini top.
Yeah, but I'm not.
I'm just not.
I don't want this
filmed either.
I did my best diva impression,
and we argued 'til nightfall.
FELIPE RESTREPO:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: I felt
so at odds with
myself in those clothes.
I think I have the beginnings
of an identity crisis.
CHARLET DUBOC: We then moved
location for the final shot
where, I have to say, things
only deteriorated.
MALE SPEAKER 5:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: Oh.
CHARLET DUBOC: Let's face it.
No amount of retouching
was going to make a
Shakira out of me.
For me, it would be off to
the operating table.
We'd arranged to meet with one
of Medellin's most revered
plastic surgeons to talk about
the city's prolific cosmetic
surgery culture.
DR. JUAN MEJIA:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: Dr. Juan is
finding himself performing
more gluteoplasties
than ever before.
And it's no wonder, as the cost
in Colombia is about a
third of what we might
pay in the West.
He gave us a tour of his
spotless office.
And to my combined horror and
delight, invited us to shoot a
live gluteoplasty procedure
later in the week.
DR. JUAN MEJIA:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: If I lived here,
I'd probably want to
look like that.
DR. JUAN MEJIA:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: What changes
have you seen since you
started practice?
DR. JUAN MEJIA:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: Oh.
What's that?
DR. JUAN MEJIA:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: Oh, my God.
What was that?
Go back.
What is that?
Is she dead?
DR. JUAN MEJIA:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: Do you think that
a lot of young Colombian
girls think that if they have
plastic surgery, it's going to
help them get a better quality
of life and a richer
boyfriend, for example?
DR. JUAN MEJIA:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: Girls
objectifying themselves to
climb social ladders
is nothing new.
However, there was one group of
girls in Colombia who were
taking their femininity
into their own hands.
I think they're up there.
Pin-Up Girls Pole Dancing School
teaches that there are
other ways of getting a great
figure and boosting your
self-esteem than going
under the knife.
[MUSIC PLAYING IN FOREIGN
LANGUAGE]
ZULLI:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
FEMALE SPEAKER 6: But more than
that, the goal of this
place is to change girls in
the way they feel about
themselves.
CHARLET DUBOC: You're lean, or
you're curvy, or strong.
FEMALE SPEAKER 6: Like,
we looked amazing
because we feel amazing.
Like, you're real chunky and you
carry yourself up proud,
you're going to look amazing.
FEMALE SPEAKER 7:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
FEMALE SPEAKER 6: When
she first came
here she had anorexia.
FEMALE SPEAKER 7:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[MUSIC PLAYING IN FOREIGN
LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: I'm about to
learn how to pole dance.
ZULLI:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: This
is really awkward.
What do you do if you fall?
FEMALE SPEAKER 6: Some
girls do fall.
And if you start to fall it's
not, like, a big deal.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
FEMALE SPEAKER 6: Run with
your feet first.
Really good for your
first lesson.
CHARLET DUBOC: Really?
FEMALE SPEAKER 6: Yeah.
CHARLET DUBOC: I don't know
how we can go back to the
fashion week now.
It's going to be [INAUDIBLE].
Yes.
Let's go outside.
ZULLI: OK.
CHARLET DUBOC: The girls were
preparing to compete in the
national pole dancing
championships in Bogota the
following day.
But before they left, they
treated us to a taster of a
unique sport, urban
pole dancing.
I guess it's like a sexy
version of that most
tragically uncool pursuit,
parkour.
[MUSIC PLAYING IN FOREIGN
LANGUAGE]
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
MALE SPEAKER 6:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: But, what if all
the pole dancing in the
world isn't enough to
plump your buns?
We headed across town to meet
44-year-old single mother,
Maria, the patient who we would
witness go under Dr.
Juan's knife the
following day.
We've arrived at the house of
the patient who's having the
gluteoplasty tomorrow,
AKA bum implants.
She lives up here somewhere.
MARIA:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: You're
so beautiful.
She's so beautiful,
MARIA:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: Are you dating
anyone at the moment?
MARIA:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: And what
does he think?
MARIA:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: How are you
hiding it from him?
How are you getting
away with it?
MARIA:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHARLET DUBOC: Whilst the
fashion continued minute by
minute, amazingly, I managed
to wangle a meeting with
Roberto Escobar, the late
Pablo's brother, accountant,
and general right-hand man.
I felt that if anyone could
shed some light on narco
beauty, he might be the one.
ROBERTO ESCOBAR:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: Can we
please come into
your beautiful house?
ROBERTO ESCOBAR:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: Your brother
obviously was attracted to
beautiful things.
Did that extend to the way
he presented himself?
ROBERTO ESCOBAR:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: What
do you think about
this term, narco beauty?
ROBERTO ESCOBAR:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: We abandoned that
line of questioning and
let this sweet, old, blind man
continue to touch me up as he
gave me the tour.
ROBERTO ESCOBAR:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: How do I look?
ROBERTO ESCOBAR:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: Ciao, Roberto.
[MUSIC PLAYING IN FOREIGN
LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: Later on we
battled against the traffic to
make it in time for
Maria's surgery.
MARIA:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
SISTER ALMA:
MARIA:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
SISTER ALMA:
DR. JUAN MEJIA:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
MARIA:
CHARLET DUBOC: She's
obviously nervous.
She's holding it together quite
well, unlike some of us.
DR. JUAN MEJIA: We are going
to begin the surgical
procedure at this moment.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: When I see her
lying there, it almost makes
me feel as if she's about 44.
She's pretty gorgeous.
It almost does seem
a bit unnecessary.
DR. JUAN MEJIA:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: I just have
to try and stay calm.
As soon as we feel a bit sick,
we have to leave immediately,
otherwise we will faint.
DR. MEJIA'S ASSISTANT:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
DR. JUAN MEJIA: This is a
regular kind of liposuction.
CHARLET DUBOC: I'm just
pretending I'm watching TV.
And if I feel like changing the
channel, I just look out
the window.
DR. JUAN MEJIA:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
Look at the skin without fat.
This is the side that
we have finished.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: I think It's like
trying to get a square
peg in a round hole.
One implant's in, and
one's halfway in.
Yay!
That's the second implant in.
DR. JUAN MEJIA:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: Yes.
What's this?
DR. MEJIA'S ASSISTANT:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: I've just
witnessed my first
gluteoplasty.
And it looks amazing.
It looks really natural.
It looks so much better.
I'm a bit jealous
to be honest.
We left Maria in recovery
and moved on to the
final fashion show.
ANNOUNCER:
[YELLING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: The Leonisa
Lingerie Show is a combination
of all the different beauty
and style ideas we'd come
across during our time
in Medellin.
Backstage was packed full of
world class models, and yet
the energy and atmosphere was
still uniquely Colombian.
MODELS:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: Narco beauty is
clearly a dying aesthetic, a
hangover from a time that was,
in all seriousness, a fiercely
unhealthy chapter in
Colombia's history.
It's no surprise that the new
fashion trends are looking
towards a more sleek,
European ideal.
Hopefully the Latin spirit
doesn't become completely
diluted in the name
of high fashion.
[MUSIC PLAYING IN FOREIGN
LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: Someone said to
me when we were backstage,
fashion in Medellin's
always a fiesta.
And I think that kind
of summed it up.
So now we're going to go
and have a fiesta.
[MUSIC PLAYING IN FOREIGN
LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: The afterparty
was a bit of an anticlimax.
Inert models stood half-naked in
cold, shallow water, gawked
at by gross men with bad hair
and shirts, a depressing
example of how quickly
the male gaze can
turn sexy into seedy.
It was getting late.
And before my cameraman was lost
forever to an elevator
full of lingerie models, I felt
we'd probably come to the
end of our Colombian jaunt.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHARLET DUBOC: We still had one
last person to catch up
with before we left.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
MARIA:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: Maria.
MARIA:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: How did you
feel when you woke up?
What was the first thing that
came into your head?
MARIA:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: You look
like a model.
Your figure looks incredible.
MARIA:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CHARLET DUBOC: Where
does it hurt?
MARIA:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[MUSIC PLAYING IN FOREIGN
LANGUAGE]