ERIK ELLINGTON: This is where
I'm going to put the tire
swing, and eventually I'll
build Julius's tree fort.
That's going to be sick.
I'm going to refinish that, get
it all cleaned up, maybe
put some white Christmas tree
lights around here, make it
all enchanted.
This is the grand finale
right here.
There's downtown Hollywood.
MALE SPEAKER: In life, like--
I mean, you seem like you've
come a long way in life to get
a place like this.
ERIK ELLINGTON: Yeah,
I feel like that.
I'm definitely pretty
thankful, man.
I try not to take
it for granted.
MALE SPEAKER: You didn't grow
up wealthy or anything?
ERIK ELLINGTON: No, no.
We moved around a lot.
When we lived in Alaska,
my step-dad--
he had money.
He made a decent living.
He had a body shop for
cars and stuff.
But then like, move back and
forth, shit goes wrong up
there, move into a janky
little apartment.
Or, you know, whatever.
We've been up and down.
I think it's a good way.
It's a good experience.
To know both sides
of the tracks.
Hey, how you doing?
Oh, I just bought the
house right here.
Yeah.
I'm Erik Ellington.
PATRICK O'DELL: Hi.
Welcome back to the show.
This episode is about
one of my favorite
skaters, Erik Ellington.
Erik's style is always
really cool, and the
way he lands tricks.
He's got something that he has
that not very many other
skaters have.
It's kind of sketchy, but
it just looks so cool.
And he's still of my
favorite dudes.
He's the kind of guy, you see
him do a flat ground kickflip,
and you go, oh, that's
why that guy's pro.
MALE SPEAKER: Wait, what's
on that tape you were
going to give me?
ERIK ELLINGTON: Old footage
from Alaska.
Like, sponsor me tape
footage, when I
was like 15 or something.
We had a launch ramp.
We put the launch ramp up to
a high ledge or something.
Just all kinds of stuff.
Like, little rails and
curbs and shit.
MALE SPEAKER: What kind of
gear are you wearing?
ERIK ELLINGTON: Let me see.
Oh actually, 101 had just
started, maybe.
Yeah.
It's just maybe like shorts
and a beanie and--
I don't know--
a purple t-shirt or something.
I don't know.
I did a 360 flip board lipslide
on a curb, just a
regular curb where you're
sliding and your wheel's over,
so it's like--
What else was there?
Nollie nose manual.
Just some stuff at the time, it
seemed like it was like--
at the time of that,
it was kind of--
I was pretty psyched.
Maybe it was a little bit before
that, I sent the tape
to H-Street.
And they sent me the
Mike Carroll
Calvin and Hobbes board.
Yeah, I was freaking out, man.
I was shaking when
I got the box.
That was pretty cool.
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah!
Fuck, that was bad.
[PHONE RINGING]
JAMIE THOMAS: Hello?
PATRICK O'DELL: Jamie.
This is Patrick.
JAMIE THOMAS: Patrick,
this is Jamie.
PATRICK O'DELL: What's
up, man?
JAMIE THOMAS: Not much.
PATRICK O'DELL: How would you
describe Erik's skating?
JAMIE THOMAS: This is
kind of a hard one.
It's kind of like, that's
not really a good--
I know you probably will only
use the things that make sense
in this interview.
But what am I supposed to say?
He looks sick.
And doing stuff good.
Like, that's a hard
thing to answer.
MALE SPEAKER: What tricks have
you done that you were the
most psyched on?
That you look back and you go,
that was my pinnacle trick?
ERIK ELLINGTON: I don't know.
I hope I really haven't
had a pinnacle trick.
I don't even know.
I mean, I'd say like an
era or something.
Like, just times--
times in your life different
things are happening, and you
feel differently about--
you know, I don't know.
First video that I
was in that was--
I guess it would have
had to have been
the first Zero video.
Thrill of it All was the first
video I was in that was kind
of major, where everybody
saw it.
But before that was the Welcome
to Hell video in the
fringe section.
Because Jamie Thomas came
out to Arizona.
Me and Scott Copalman talked
to Jamie quite a bit.
And it was like we were on
Balance at the time, and he
was starting Zero clothing.
So he wanted us to ride
for the clothing.
Actually, he wanted Scott to
ride for the clothing.
And Scott said he wouldn't do
it unless I was on too.
Well, he just said, I won't
leave Balance unless Erik
comes with me.
So by default, I got on Zero.
JUSTIN REGAN: But he did
have some slams.
There's this one where--
and I'm not even sure if
it's the same video.
But it's like this
kinked rail.
And like, I don't know.
He just decided he wanted to
go off and do this rail.
And he got wrecked on it.
ERIK ELLINGTON: Oh, yeah.
I tried to boardslide
that thing.
I don't know what
I was thinking.
I can't really even boardslide
kinked rails.
I just thought, maybe
I could do it.
MALE SPEAKER: (SLOW MOTION)
Fucking shit.
ERIK ELLINGTON: Dude, that
thing was like--
I think it was like three
or four kinks.
No, I tried it about maybe
20 times or something.
No, I slid through a couple
of the kinks.
You got to, like--
I don't know.
I just don't really
know how to do it.
I was just amped, you know?
MALE SPEAKER: You
just thought--
ERIK ELLINGTON: I thought
I could do it.
JUSTIN REGAN: Erik's one
of those skaters that--
he puts in the work
to get his part.
When he does a trick, it
just looks so cool.
And there's like sweat flying,
and his shirt's dirty because
you know he was battling
for it.
But somehow the one that he
makes, it's effortless.
ERIK ELLINGTON: Zero time
was cool because
I was kind of like--
I was on the verge of being
kicked off Zero, and I was on
the verge of not knowing
what I was going
to do with my life.
And then it was like--
I was just like, fuck,
I'm in California.
Tripping out, ready to be
chop, chop, chopped.
I don't know.
Adrian Lopez told me.
One time he was like, man--
because we were on a tour, and
it was just sort of towards
the ending.
Like, it was after that Thrill
of it All video came out.
And it was like, I think Jamie
had a little bit higher
expectations for what I was
supposed to be doing.
And then I didn't really
come through.
I kind of was just piled out.
I was thinking like, oh, I
was just smooth sailing.
And then he kind of let me know
I wasn't, but in a way
that it was like--
I think it taught me quite a
bit about things that have
worn off on me-- to where to
this day-- that I look back on
and think like, those are some
fucking pretty important tips
or pointers or whatever.
JAMIE THOMAS: We're trying to
film for Misled Youth, and
Scotty and Erik went through
a spell of several months
without doing absolutely
anything.
And everybody on the team was
trying to film, and everyone
was trying to do things and get
stuff going for the video.
And those guys were starting
to drink a little more and
starting to do their
own thing.
It kind of really didn't have
anything to do with what we
were doing.
And Eric had this sketchbook,
and he just-- it was basically
a sketchbook and a journal, and
he just wrote everything
about every day and
all this stuff.
We're riding in a van on this
tour, and Lopez like leaned
over and borrowed Erik's
pencil and drew a boot.
Like, when we were filming for
Misled Youth, he probably had
10 or 15 tricks right up until
the last month of the video.
He seriously probably
filmed a trick a
month up to that point.
And then all of a sudden
he filmed like 25
tricks in one month.
And it was all the gnarliest
stuff in Misled Youth.
It was all done in one month.
And so it goes to show what
he's capable of and his
potential, but he just always
put it off until
he had to do it.
And then when he had to do it,
he would always get it done.
So that's pretty much the
story of Misled Youth.
His part came together in the
last month and helped launch
his pro career.
It's pretty rad.
ERIK ELLINGTON: They take a look
from outside of being in
his circle, and they just
hear what he's doing.
And a lot of the things I
disagree with, a lot of things
he probably disagrees
with what I'm doing.
And then a lot of
people fucking--
I don't know--
talk shit or something.
But it's like, he's
down to work.
And if somebody's not putting
in the work, then he's going
to let them know.
He's not going to pussy
foot around the fact
to that, you know?
MALE SPEAKER: Fuck him up!
ERIK ELLINGTON: Julius,
come here.
Come here.
GREG: My name's Greg,
by the way.
ERIK ELLINGTON: Erik.
GREG: How do you do?
ERIK ELLINGTON: Nice
to meet you.
Yeah, pro skater.
What is it?
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
But I wouldn't be able to
tell you without knowing
what it was, but--
GREG: You understand why--
ERIK ELLINGTON: I understand
that, though.
I understand that.
But I pretty much--
I can give you some--
you could probably talk to the
people that are running this
thing, and then maybe they can
give you some advice on what
to do and kind of handle
things that way.
And I was like, I'm
a little confused.
You know, I can't really
give you much advice.
I don't know what it is.
I pointed him to Erica.
I pawned him off on Erica.
NECK FACE: Oh, Ellington is--
Ellington's my favorite.
I mean, he was my favorite
growing up.
Like, seeing his skating
and shit.
Like, damn, this fool's straight
white trash fucking
skating and shit.
And then when I met the
dude, it was like
even more of my favorite.
I was like, damn, this
fool doesn't give
a shit about anything.
He's fucking crazy.
Ellington is nuts.
MALE SPEAKER: Oh, shit!
ERIK ELLINGTON: Let's get
fucked up tonight!
ANDREW REYNOLDS: To me,
when I look at him,
he's like Eric Koston.
But just with this like--
take away all the perfection
and everything and add this
lazy attitude problem
or something.
He's that good, but it's just
like, well whatever.
He's really that good.
And it's just like, everything
he does has this special
Ellington style about it, like
every move he makes.
It's in his skating, in his
walk, when he bowls, when he
carries his kid.
It's just this certain
way of doing it.
ERIK ELLINGTON: It's not too
bad except that the top
doesn't really match
the pants.
All right.
Ooh, let me get a little--
MALE SPEAKER: Te-qui-lia.
ERIK ELLINGTON: Have
a bit of that.
MALE SPEAKER: Little standby.
ERIK ELLINGTON: Little tequila
right in there, huh?
You look beautiful.
Look at you.
[KISSING]
[THUD]
FEMALE SPEAKER: Oh!
ERIK ELLINGTON: Jujube!
FEMALE SPEAKER: All right!
MALE SPEAKER: How'd
you meet her?
ERIK ELLINGTON: She
was out here.
I wanted to take her out for
dinner, and then she took off
the next morning
and ditched me.
So then I took a train down
to San Diego, and I
shacked up with her.
Ever since then, I moved into
her apartment with like three
of her friends.
They bought a Suzuki Swift, this
fucking piece of shit.
And we were driving that thing
back and forth all the time.
It's like, damn, got
a car, rolling.
Yeah, we got married three
months after that.
MALE SPEAKER: Really?
Three months?
ERIK ELLINGTON: Mm-hmm.
And we've been married for
seven years in October.
MALE SPEAKER: Whoa, so you just
knew at three months?
ERIK ELLINGTON: How
do you like that?
MALE SPEAKER: You
got actually--
did you plan it out?
ERIK ELLINGTON: No, no.
We were like, well let's
just get married.
Fuck it.
BRAYDON SZAFRANSKI: Check.
One, two, one, two.
What it is.
Please get the stages of Erik.
The drunken stages are by far
the best thing of him.
Like, his skating, amazing.
His life, amazing.
Drunken stages, golden.
First, OK.
Like, I've seen him tonight.
He has a button up shirt on.
Great.
So this is where you can
fully catch his stages.
What'd he start with?
Probably like five or
six buttons down it.
You know what I mean?
The more he drinks-- because
this is an open bar in here.
The more he drinks, every
half an hour, a
button will be popped.
Bam.
Easily.
Was that a fourth button?
ERIK ELLINGTON: That's
a fourth button.
BRAYDON SZAFRANSKI: Did
I just see a fourth--
I seen it.
I actually witnessed it
with my own eyes.
DUSTIN DOLLIN: Look, it fits
perfectly in there.
Look, look, look.
Look.
BRAYDON SZAFRANSKI: Whoa, it
does fit perfectly in there.
Whoa!
MALE SPEAKER: Don't do that.
DUSTIN DOLLIN: Anyway, he's
basically my father.
I don't have one.
So he's pretty much the tough
guy I got to look up to.
You know what you should do?
You should do an episode
on all of our mothers.
That would be a fucking--
our mother--
his father.
Like, whoever we think's
weirdest in our family.
BRAYDON SZAFRANSKI: Yeah,
everyone in the family that's
just jacked.
ERIK ELLINGTON: Well, I'll
call you in a little bit.
All right?
All right.
MALE SPEAKER: Luciana?
ERIK ELLINGTON: Yeah.
MALE SPEAKER: You had to get
permission for another night?
ERIK ELLINGTON: Well, I didn't
really get permission.
MALE SPEAKER: What'd she say?
ERIK ELLINGTON: She's
just over it.
Yeah, it's been like a lot
of nights in a row.
I normally don't even
go out anymore.
Me and her, we just chill
at the house, watch
movies or do whatever.
Damn.
It's like, all this.
This makes me so happy.
My son makes me happy-- my wife,
my mom, my family, my
friends, all that.
But then it's just like, you
land something that you didn't
think you could do
or something.
And it's just like--
I mean it's like the best--
gives you chills, you know?
It's the best thing ever.
Give the camera a kiss.
Where'd you guys park?
Down here?
One, two, three.
Woo!