DAVID CHOE: China's
a huge place.
The landscape keeps changing.
It goes from vast canyons to
sand dunes to, like, these
desolate zombie towns, where
there's huge complexes where
there's just no people
living there.
Things like that, they
make you think about
your position in life.
We go into these towns and
these worker bees, these
people are working for pennies
doing these huge
construction projects.
I mean, it makes me
think about shit.
It's like, I spill paint on
these expensive rugs and then
sell it for shitloads
of money.
And if I was born in this
shithole town and I had to
paint that whole thing and I
spilled a drop of paint, then
I'd get fired.
It's fucking crazy.
It's life circumstance.
But I don't know.
Hopefully life on the road, us
expressing ourselves through
dance and music and hitchhiking,
maybe we'll start
some kind of a revolution.
But probably not.
Let's go.
So we're outside of a
town called Xi'an.
It's our next biggest city.
There's a bus.
We're just going to get on.
I guess we're just
going to get on.
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID CHOE: Let Homegirl know
we don't have any money.
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID CHOE: We're drifters.
DAVID CHOE: We inherently
don't pay for rides.
It's against the religion
of the road.
No money.
I got a jizz tissue
and some dust.
We got to get off?
So mean.
OK, OK.
Shit.
Moving.
You're very cute, you
know, in this life.
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID CHOE: All right.
So they were kind enough.
That was a 10-cent ride.
I guess we could have fucking
faked it and paid for it.
But sort of goes against
my religion.
It goes against everything we
believe in at Thumbs Up.
And then--
Look at this.
Jump-- let's go.
Get in.
Jump in.
Squeeze in.
Yeah!
Hi.
Hello.
[CHINESE].
What are your names?
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID CHOE: Jiang Ho.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Jiang Ho.
DAVID CHOE: What up, Jiang Ho?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Jiang Ho,
what's up, what's up?
DAVID CHOE: What's up?
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID CHOE: Hey, ask him if he
knows Street Fighter, the
video game.
Street Fighter.
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID CHOE: Chun Li.
DAVID CHOE: Does he know Chun
Li from Street Fighter?
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID CHOE: All right.
All right.
Thank you.
[CHINESE].
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID CHOE: I've often wondered
why Chun Li from
Street Fighter had
huge thighs.
Every time I got to take a
dump, I got to squat like
this, because all the toilets
are squatter-style.
But the chicks, they got to
squat every time they got to
pee or shit.
They get the hugest hamstrings
and calves.
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID CHOE: Yeah, yeah,
yeah, all right.
HARRY KIM: All right.
DAVID CHOE: Party.
HARRY KIM: Yay.
DAVID CHOE: Party, party,
party, party.
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID CHOE: Give us
a ride, dude.
Be cool.
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID CHOE: Whether you give us
a ride or you don't give us
a ride, it'll never
change the fact--
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID CHOE: --what a handsome
devil you are.
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
FEMALE SPEAKER: Ah, come on.
Come on.
DAVID CHOE: Yeah, yeah?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Come on.
Come on.
Get in.
DAVID CHOE: Yeah, yeah.
You, sir, are a handsome
devil.
I like you.
Yeah!
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID CHOE: Look
at that smile.
I want to fucking kiss
you right now, man.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Kiss him.
Kiss him.
DAVID CHOE: No, you kiss him.
I'm not going to kiss him.
[LAUGHTER]
You're the best.
One, two, three.
Go!
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID CHOE: Yeah.
[EXCITING ROCK MUSIC PLAYING]
DAVID CHOE: We're in Xi'an.
It's our first big city
after Beijing.
I got the shits.
Had to take a dump, and I had
a accident on my shirt.
We came out.
These guys looked pretty
cool and hip.
The dude with the orange hair,
he looks like a freak, so we
just sat down and
ate with them.
We had a delicious meal.
It turns out they're
punk rockers.
They're in a rock band
called Echo Rush.
We're giving them massages
right now.
They're going to go out
and party tonight.
So you guys ready to rock?
Yeah?
All right, let's do it.
Echo Rush.
[PUNK MUSIC PLAYING]
DAVID CHOE: I love this guy.
DAVID CHOE: Yeah.
[PUNK MUSIC PLAYING]
DAVID CHOE: Echo Rush.
We fucking rock China so hard.
China!
Fucking love China.
I come to China,
and the fucking
girls have little mustaches.
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID CHOE: I like it.
I fucking like it.
I saw it, and I was
fucking scared.
I was scared when I saw the
mustache, and now I
fucking love it.
Do you know how to love?
Do you love, or do you fuck?
MALE SPEAKER: Yes, I love.
DAVID CHOE: Who do you love?
What's the last name?
HARRY KIM: Do you fuck?
DAVID CHOE: Do you know
what love is?
Do you know what love is?
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID CHOE: You're
the lead singer.
You should fuck everybody.
Fuck everybody.
MALE SPEAKER: OK.
DAVID CHOE: There's
no time for love.
There's no time for love.
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID CHOE: Don't be a bitch.
Fuck everybody.
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID CHOE: Fuck from China
all the way to Russia.
MALE SPEAKER: You can help me?
DAVID CHOE: I'll help you.
HARRY KIM: Oh god,
you can do it.
DAVID CHOE: I'm not that shit,
but I'll do it for this guy.
All the fucking Chinese bitches
with mustaches, I'll
fuck them all.
I love this guy.
[COUGHING]
DAVID CHOE: That's not water.
FEMALE SPEAKER: I'll
be right back, OK?
DAVID CHOE: So we're
still in Xi'an.
It's a city that's known for
the Terracotta Warriors.
And this guy, I can't travel
with this guy if he looks like
shit all the time.
So we're going to get him
a haircut right now.
I don't know.
There's not much we
can do with it.
But let's go check it out.
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID CHOE: Sausage party,
all you can eat.
That's what last night was.
With the good-looking dudes
in a rock band.
And once again, it took Harry
to show rockers how to rock.
My band, KGB, Koreans Gone Bad,
with my brother Harry, we
formed this shit years ago.
We get on stage.
The guy writes a song.
It goes, ching chong China,
ripping a vagina.
I mean, I know I get pissed
at Harry sometimes.
I know I yell at him.
But you know what's worse
in life than being mad
and pissed at Harry?
It's not having Harry
in your life.
So today I'm going to treat
Harry to a day at the spa.
Get a haircut.
This is what you call
traditional-style
Chinese bowl cut.
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID CHOE: All right.
HARRY KIM: Hey.
DAVID CHOE: Look good, man.
DAVID CHOE: Remember that baby
we saw in that little village?
We want this haircut
on this guy.
All right, we're going
to do Harry up one up
better than this one.
Yeah, finish it off.
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID CHOE: So in the entire
hair salon, Harry's getting
his hair cut by the one girl
that is not certified, and has
never done a haircut before.
We think she's the
receptionist.
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
FEMALE SPEAKER: She's a little
nervous right now.
DAVID CHOE: Oh, don't
be nervous.
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID CHOE: If you guys are
bored watching this, how about
we read this girl's shirt
while Harry's
getting his hair cut?
It says--
HARRY KIM: OK.
Here, man.
DAVID CHOE: I know Harry hasn't
been picking up too
much road pussy on this trip.
That's all about to change
after this haircut.
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
HARRY KIM: Oh.
Hey.
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID CHOE: Oh, excuse me.
DAVID CHOE: Would you
ever date a guy
that his this style?
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID CHOE: You like
this kind of look?
No?
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID CHOE: The irony being,
she's not into guys that have
this kind of style.
But the fact is, Harry would
fuck her better than any
fucking guy she's ever been
into, better than any of them.
And she'll never know that
pleasure, because she's
judging him.
HARRY KIM: Yeah.
DAVID CHOE: So I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
You will never know.
You will never, ever,
ever know.
You will never know.
You will never, ever know.
Sorry, Harry.
I tried.
HARRY KIM: It's all right.
[HONKING]
[SHRIEKING]
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID CHOE: How-how for Echo
Rush, whose favorite drummer
is Usher's drummer.
Total sweetheart.
Total cutie.
He let us stay, the whole band
and crew, at his grandmother's
house last night.
And then even better,
their fucking tour
driver, Jacob, aka Hong--
hi.
JACOB: OK, hi.
DAVID CHOE: Echo Rush just
finished their tour, so he's
heading-- what's that city?
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID CHOE: I can't
pronounce it.
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID CHOE: And it seems to be
south, so he's nice enough to
give us a ride.
Jacob?
JACOB: OK.
DAVID CHOE: You're on the road
a lot with these punk bands.
So is it lonely on the road?
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID CHOE: I mean,
those guys in that
band were pretty young.
When you're giving a ride to
all these young bands, are
they annoying?
Do they get on your nerves?
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID CHOE: So since he's all
over China, does he have like
a girlfriend in every city?
There's a lot of girls
on the road?
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID CHOE: Road pussy.
Road pussy.
Jacob, you know what I
said, come on, man.
The girls everywhere,
all over China.
Road pussy.
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
FEMALE SPEAKER: Called Mimis.
Called Mimis.
DAVID CHOE: Yeah, Mimis.
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID CHOE: Do you have
a girlfriend?
Are you married?
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
FEMALE SPEAKER: See, they're--
he's separated right now.
DAVID CHOE: Oh.
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID CHOE: Oh, wait.
So that's very interesting.
Jacob, I've been in a very long
relationship myself also.
But the road kills all.
In the end, you can
only choose one--
love or the road.
If you love the road, that
will destroy any
relationship you have.
And if you choose love, you get
love, but you have to stay
at home and be boring.
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
FEMALE SPEAKER: Because
that's why after five
years they did separate.
He chose the road.
DAVID CHOE: Jacob, the
road destroyed me.
The road destroyed Harry.
Or not us, but our love lives.
But in the end, after the
dust settles, we're
totally gay for the road.
So it doesn't matter.
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
FEMALE SPEAKER: He says he
chooses the road as well.
DAVID CHOE: Oh, yeah!
JACOB: Yeah.
DAVID CHOE: Yeah, dude.
JACOB: Fuck you.
Fuck you.
[LAUGHTER]
DAVID CHOE: The road is long
and hard, like Harry's shit
this morning.
But we just got the
longest ride on
Thumbs Up China so far.
In my experience of all my years
of traveling, when you
get rides like this, people
either pick you up because
they want you to keep telling
them stories to keep them
awake while they're driving,
or they want to spill all
their shit on you, like you're
a roadside psychiatrist, and
they confess all their sins.
Jacob, my main man, did
what few drivers
usually let you do.
And that is sleep.
And I mean, we've done
everything to offer this guy--
cigarettes, Red Bull, coffee.
He is a fucking driving
machine.
And I just wanted to ask,
because we're almost to the
town he's going to drop us off
in, does he have any words of
wisdom or advice that he would
like to give to us?
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
FEMALE SPEAKER: He says, my
good words to you are that
there are beautiful bitches
waiting ahead for you.
DAVID CHOE: Yeah!
Yeah.
All right.
JACOB: Fuck you.
[LAUGHTER]
DAVID CHOE: It's another
beautiful day in China.
Thumbs up, China.
Thumbs up, everybody.
There's more rides to be had.
There's more fun to be had.
Let's get the fuck
out of here.
Dude, we got one of the
best rides we've
ever got in our life.
True road warrior, down for the
road, ride or die shit.
Fucking Jacob.
JACOB: Fuck you.
[LAUGHTER]
DAVID CHOE: Longest ride.
Drove us out.
Think we're along the Yellow
River right now.
It's pretty dirty.
I think some rare dolphin
went extinct in it.
We're also spending more
time out in the sun.
And I was thinking we're
getting darker, and the
Chinese girls out here like pale
skin, so that might be a
problem too.
We're going to cross this
river right now,
head in that direction.
Thumbs up, China.
Let's keep rolling it.
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID CHOE: Hi.
More, more.
Oh!
Hit that fool.
Hit him.
Oh.
Ooh, hit that bitch.
Oh!
Oh.
I like the dude on the left.
Yo Harry, I got $100-- oh!
Fuck yeah, dude.
Oh!
Oh.
My money's on Harry.
Go.
Oh, come on, you pussy.
Bash that shit, dude.
Oh.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Come
on, honey.
Let me touch you.
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID CHOE: Are you guys
in a bike gang?
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID CHOE: Yeah?
What's the name of their gang?
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
FEMALE SPEAKER: They
don't have a name.
They just fucking roll.
They spin around.
DAVID CHOE: That's cool, man.
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
FEMALE SPEAKER: He
wants to know if
we want to go somewhere.
DAVID CHOE: Yeah,
of course, dude.
As far as he'll take us.
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID CHOE: Ride or die.
DAVID CHOE: Yeah,
come on, man.
Come on, man.
Let's ride.
[HORN HONKING]
DAVID CHOE: Thumbs up, China.
Harry's balls are touching
his back.
My balls are touching
Life doesn't get better
than this.
Thumbs up, China.
[HORN HONKING]
DAVID CHOE: Yeah.
This is my makeshift
cooking show.
I'm going to show you how to
eat really healthy and
nutritious on the road.
What is that?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Baby chick.
DAVID CHOE: OK, one.
One.
Just one.
Some baby birds.
Little baby canaries,
like Tweety Bird.
Eat that shit, dude.
How is that?
HARRY KIM: Mmm, it's good.
DAVID CHOE: It's good?
HARRY KIM: Mm-hmm.
DAVID CHOE: How's the flavor?
HARRY KIM: A little spicy.
DAVID CHOE: It needs
a little something?
HARRY KIM: It needs a little
something, though.
Mm-hmm?
DAVID CHOE: You want to
put something on it?
HARRY KIM: Yeah, let's put
something on this thing.
DAVID CHOE: All right.
This is the candy man.
He takes whatever you want, and
he makes it into candy.
Like that Iggy Pop song.
B-52s.
(SINGING) Candy, candy, candy.
So we got these chickens.
They taste like shit.
But there's like this thing that
they have in LA, like the
Roscoe's Chicken and Waffles.
It's, you got some chicken, and
you got some sweetness,
some sugar.
It's that same concept.
So we got a baby little pigeons,
and we're going to
caramelize them with some sugar,
and have chicken bird.
This guy thinks we're a fucking
moron, but we're going
to have tasty treat.
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID CHOE: And lettuce.
Yes, yes, yes.
Lettuce.
Oh.
Yeah.
It's crunchy on the inside, and
crunchy on the outside.
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID CHOE: Crunchy crunch.
Oh!
[SPEAKING CHINESE]
DAVID CHOE: This is Chinese
style, ancient Chinese style.
Fucking delicious.
Oh my god.
All right.
Mmm.
That shit is good.
Cabbage, cabbage pops.
This is fucking real eating.
This is some gangsta
shit right here.
You want one?
Want one?
Yeah.
Some gangsta shit.
This is healthy for you.
HARRY KIM: Healthy for you.
DAVID CHOE: It's delicious.
Yeah!
Dude, that's the best spinach
you're ever going to eat in
your whole life.
Your dad's never going to give
you spinach like that, never.
Eat that shit, dude.
Mmm.
That's some good shit.
[CHINESE].
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYING]