Delivering the Monday edition of CNN STUDENT
NEWS to you and classrooms all over the world,
I`m Carl Azuz.
New York City subway, closed. The New Jersey
bus and rail service, shut down. We just got
word that almost 2 million public school students
are out today, and it`s all because of this
massive storm system named Sandy. On Sunday,
it was a Category 1 hurricane. A lot of times
with these storms, forecasters focus on the
center and where and when it might land. With
Sandy, one expert said it might not matter
where the center is, because the entire thing
is so large. And things could get worse. There`s
a cold front coming from the western part
of the U.S. If that meets up with Sandy and
the two weather systems merge together, it
could have a severe impact on the East Coast.
Sandy is already being blamed for at least
60 deaths from when it moved through the Caribbean.
Yesterday it was off the coast of North Carolina
and moving north. Predictions estimated that
Delaware, Maryland and Virginia could get
up to a foot of rain.
Governors all over the northeast declared
states of emergency to help make resources
and money available to prepare for this storm.
Our next headline takes us all the way across
North America to Canada`s British Colombia.
An earthquake, and a pretty big one, hit there
on Saturday. And no major damage was reported,
but the quake`s potential impact, where the
quake had threatened reached across the Pacific
Ocean out to the Hawaiian islands.
The sirens in this Youtube video are letting
people know about a tsunami warning. The concern
was that the quake in Canada would trigger
a large ocean wave that would wash up in Hawaii.
Now, that didn`t happen, and the tsunami warning
was canceled after a few hours.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Is this legit? In order
to be U.S. president, you have to be at least
45 years old. Not true. There is an age requirement,
but it`s not 45. Presidents have to be at
least 35.
AZUZ: Well, of course this year`s presidential
candidates meet that constitutional requirement.
Barack Obama is 51, Mitt Romney is 65. With
the election just eight days away, we wanted
to share a little more about the men running
for the Oval Office. Both of them are family
men. Romney and his wife Ann have five sons.
Obama and his wife Michelle have two daughters.
If you look back at where they went to school,
they started at almost opposite sides of the
country. Obama went to college at Columbia
University; Romney graduated from Brigham
Young. One thing they have in common: both
men have degrees from Harvard Law School.
Romney also has a degree from Harvard Business
School.
How about prior work experience? Mitt Romney
helped found an investment company called
Bain Capital. He also helped organize and
run the 2002 Winter Olympics, and he served
as governor of Massachusetts.
Barack Obama worked as a community organizer
in Chicago. He served two terms in the Illinois
State Senate, and he was elected to the U.S.
Senate in 2004.
This is the second time that both men have
run for president. They were candidates in
2008 as well, and they both made some history
along the way. In 2008, Barack Obama became
the first African-American presidential nominee
for a major political party, and this year,
Mitt Romney became the first Mormon to be
a major political party`s presidential nominee.
President Obama and Governor Romney are both
aiming for the same number -- 270. If you
want to win the presidency, that`s at least
how many votes you need to get in the electoral
college. Jonathan Mann explains how that works
and what it could take for the candidates
to reach that magic number.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
JONATHAN MANN, CNN CORRESPONDENT: It`s nice
to be popular, but it does not win the White
House. The national poll numbers show that
more people prefer Mitt Romney lately, but
winning the presidency is not a popularity
contest. You have to win states, not just
votes. And for Romney, that`s a problem. Even
though the poll numbers are moving his way,
the color-coded CNN electoral map has barely
budged in months, and it speaks volumes. It
still projects that Obama is leading in the
electoral vote with the blue states, comfortably
in his corner. Romney`s safe states are in
red. Each state has a different number of
electoral votes, though, based on its population.
And the thing is that whoever wins 270 electoral
votes will win the election.
That`s why the yellow states, the tossup states
are crucial. Polls in those states show the
race is still too close to call. Romney`s
problem is that he needs to win most of them.
Just this week, North Carolina turned light
red, showing that the state is now in the
leaning Romney category. Romney has a slight
edge in Florida, so we`ll be turning that
state red as well. He has high hopes for Virginia
and for Colorado. If they turn red too, he
is still, though, 13 electoral votes short
of the 270 he needs to win. He`d have to win
two more of the smaller states, or the big
prize, Ohio, to win the election.
Now, resetting the map, there is more wiggle
room in Obama`s path to the presidency. His
campaign is setting its sights on Iowa, Wisconsin
and all- important Ohio. Those three states
alone could put him over the top. Any other
wins would just be extra insurance. But say
Obama wins Ohio and Wisconsin, and loses Iowa.
Well, he wins New Hampshire, Romney wins the
rest. Each candidate ends up with 269 electoral
votes, a tie. That hasn`t happened in more
than 200 years, but it could, and if it did,
the newly elected House of Representatives
would actually be the ones to vote to break
the tie.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: A tie for president. That might sound
unbelievable, but it has happened before,
and it`s something we`re going to look into
more later on this week, so please keep watching.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: See if you can ID me.
I was established in 1789. I lead one branch
of the U.S. government. I have one chief and
eight associates, who can serve as members
for the rest of their lives.
I`m the U.S. Supreme Court, to which thousands
of cases are filed each year.
AZUZ: So let`s say you`re a college student,
you`re looking for ways to help pay for tuition,
and you come up with a plan to buy some stuff
and then sell it to make some money. Sounds
simple, but it might not turn out that way.
It`s the starting point for a case that the
Supreme Court is about to hear, and as Joe
Johns explains, the decision could go a lot
further than just college campuses.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
JOE JOHNS, CNN CORRESPONDENT: It`s a case
that could cause trouble for anyone who ever
thought about selling an old iPhone or iPad,
donating clothes to charity, or even unloading
junk at a yard sale. The issue about to be
argued before the Supreme Court is whether
the original copyright holder on U.S. products
manufactured or purchased in other countries
can control your ability to resell the product
once you buy it.
Davis Klyonaga resells old products at this
eBay consignment store.
(on camera): How much of this stuff is foreign
manufactured?
DAVIS KLYONAGA, OWNER, DROP & SHIP: I`d probably
say 85, 95 percent.
JOHNS: He fears the case could put him out
of business.
KLYONAGA: I think it`s ridiculous. I mean,
I have known about it because it could affect
my business so horribly, but I kind of pushed
it back, because I`m like, how could this
possibly happen? The repercussions would be
ridiculous.
JOHNS: Even libraries are worried that a legal
defeat could require them to seek the copyright
owner`s permission before lending books printed
overseas.
Andrew Shore represents a coalition of interests,
including libraries.
ANDREW SHORE, ATTORNEY: The rule we`d like
to see is very simple. You bought it, you
own it, and you could do with it as you please.
JOHNS: Otherwise, Shore says, copyright owners
could demand a fee every time you try to resell
almost anything not made in America.
(on camera): Anything I`m wearing, would that
apply?
SHORE: It`s got a copyright.
JOHNS: Right. DVDs?
SHORE: Yes.
JOHNS: What else? Iphones?
SHORE: Iphones.
JOHNS: Computers.
SHORE: Yes.
JOHNS: Televisions?
JOHNS: Cars?
SHORE: Yes.
JOHNS: Jewelry?
SHORE: Everything with copyright.
JOHNS (VOICE-OVER): The copyright`s holders
and their lawyers say the rhetoric has gotten
a little overheated.
THEODORE OLSON, LAWYER FOR PLAINTIFF: You
know that you`re on the right side of the
case when the other side, the best answer
that they can come up with is that the sky
is going to fall. Garage sales, museums, and
that sort of thing, none of that is going
to happen.
JOHNS: Powerhouse attorney Ted Olson says
this is mostly about books and movies and
other so-called intellectual properties, and
making sure producers of such works have exclusive
rights to distribute them in the U.S.
OLSON: It is protecting the integrity of the
copyright system in the United States, which
was created by the Constitution in order to
create an incentive for people to create works
that make us all laugh or cry or educate us.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: Finally today, there are times I`m very
glad I do most of my reporting from a studio,
because the field presents perils, like when
this fish flaps and the field correspondent
freaks. Only problem, her backup`s balance.
But it is more or less embarrassing than what`s
about to happen to this reporter. The problem
with being out in the air is the birds, and
one of them just dropped a present on the
reporter`s shoulder. That`s just a sign of
disrespect. You word hard, toil at your job,
and then a bird does something to foul it
up. If we keep this up, this show is going
down the tubes, so we`ll see you tomorrow
on CNN STUDENT NEWS.