too much stuff, and way too little of
what we really want.
Now we're going to start looking at the
stories behind the story of stuff.
That's where we'll find ways to turn
this situation around.
Welcome to Season Two.
Ever since I learned where our stuff
really comes from - and how this system
is trashing people and the planet - I've
been trying to figure out how we can
change it. I've read a lot of these: 100
Ways to Save the Planet Without Leaving
Your House,
50 Simple Things You Can do
to Save the Earth,
The Little Green Book of Shopping.
I thought they might have the
answers, but their tips all start here
with buying better stuff
and they all end here - with recycling
all that stuff when I'm done with it.
But when it comes to making change, this
story of "going green" - even though we
see it everywhere -
has some serious shortcomings.
It says that if I become a smarter
shopper,
and tell my friends to do the same,
I've done my part.
And if I don't buy all this green stuff,
then it's my fault that the planet's
being destroyed.
Wait a minute. My fault?
I didn't choose to put toxic products on
the shelves or to allow slave labor in
factories around the world.
I didn't choose to fill stores with
electronics that can't be repaired
and have to be thrown away. I didn't
choose a world in which some people can
afford to live green, leaving the rest
of us to be irresponsible planet
wreckers! Of course when we do shop we
should buy the least toxic and most fair
products we can,
but it's not bad shoppers here
who are the source of the problem, it's
bad policies and bad business practices
here.
And that's why the solutions we really
need aren't for sale at the supermarket.
If we actually want to change the world,
we can't talk only about consumers
voting with our dollars.
Real change happens when citizens come
together to demand rules that work.
Look, it is important to try to live
green.
As Gandhi said, “be the change.”
Living our values in small ways shows
ourselves and others we care.
So it is a great place to start.
But it's a terrible place to stop.
After all, would we even know who Gandhi
was if he just sewed his own clothes and
then sat back waiting for the British to
leave India?
So how do we make big change?
To answer that question,
I went back and looked at Gandhi,
the anti-apartheid movement in South
Africa, the U.S. Civil Rights Movement,
and the environmental victories here in
the 1970s.
They didn't just nag people to
perfect their day-to-day choices.
They changed the rules of the game.
It turns out, there are three things you
find whenever people get together
and actually change the world.
First, they share a big idea for how
things could be better.
Not just a little better for a few
people,
a whole lot better for everyone.
And they don't just tinker around the
edges;
they go right to the heart of the
problem, even when it means changing
systems that don't want to be changed.
And that can be scary!
Hey, millions of us already share a big
idea for how things can be better.
Instead of this dinosaur economy that
focuses onlyon corporate profits -
we want a new economy that puts safe
products,
happy people, and a healthy planet first.
Duh, isn't that what an economy
should be  for?
Trying to live eco-perfectly in today's system
is like trying to swim upstream,
when the current is pushing us all the
other way.
But by changing what our economy
prioritizes,
we can change the current so that the
right thing becomes the
easiest thing to do.
Second, the millions of ordinary people
who made these extraordinary changes
didn't try to do it alone.
They didn't just say, “I will be more
responsible.” They said, “We will work
together until the problem is solved.”
Today it's easier than ever to work
together.
Can you imagine how hard it was to get a
message across India in 1930?
We can do it now in less than a second.
And finally, these movements succeeded
in creating change because they took
their big idea,
and their commitment to work together,
and then they took action!
Did you know that when Martin Luther
King junior organized his march on
Washington,
less than a quarter of
Americans supported him?
But that was enough to make change -
because those supporters took action -
they did stuff.
Today 74% of Americans support
tougher laws on toxic chemicals.
83% want clean energy laws. 85% think
corporations should have
less influence in government.
We've got the big idea and the
commitment. We just haven't
turned it all into massive action yet.
And this is our only missing piece.
So let's do it.
Making real change takes all kinds of
citizens -
not just protestors.
When you realize what you're good at and
what you like to do,
plugging in doesn't seem so hard.
Whatever you have to offer, a better
future needs it.
So ask yourself,
“What kind of change maker am I?”
We need investigators,
communicators,
builders,
resisters,
nurturers,
and networkers.
At StoryofStuff.org,
you can explore these types of change
makers and find your first,
or your next, step to take action.
Being an engaged citizen starts with
voting.
That's one of those basic things that
everyone's just gotta do.
But it gets way more exciting - and fun
- when we put our unique skills
and interests to work alongside
thousands of others.
I know that changing a whole economic
system is a huge challenge.
It's not easy to see a clear path from
where we are today to where we need to
go.
And there's no ten simple things we
can do without leaving our couches!
But the path didn't start out clear to
all these guys either.
Doctor King said, “Faith
is taking the first step even though
you don't see the whole staircase.”
So, they worked hard to get organized,
practiced the small acts that
built their citizen muscles
and kept their focus on their big idea -
and when the time was right, they were
ready.
It's time for us to get ready too -
ready to make change and write the next
chapter
in the story of stuff.