dismount before the trip.
Hopefully they're done
before it gets dark.
Just busted him.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
BRAD GERLACH: He calls me and
says, hey man, let's go do
some motorcycle riding.
Bring it on, dude.
I'm ready to go.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
How do you-- hey, how do you
[INAUDIBLE] gas [INAUDIBLE]?
CHRIS CHRISTENSON: Lefty
loosey, righty tighty.
BRAD GERLACH: Yeah, I know that,
but I mean did you press
it down or something?
Great, got to get
it on footage.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, Chris.
How do you get the gas
tank open, man?
CHRIS CHRISTENSON:
You just do.
BRAD GERLACH: Spin it?
I looked at a couple
of his boards.
I was like, oh man, this
guy looks like he
knows how to shape.
I just called him up to--
hey, I want to get a board.
CHRIS CHRISTENSON: The
conversation was probably like
five minutes on the phone before
I even knew who he was.
BRAD GERLACH: When he really
knew it was me after a while,
I was like, oh shit.
Sorry, dude.
CHRIS CHRISTENSON: What was
your last name again?
He's all, Gerlach.
I'm like, oh OK, OK.
BRAD GERLACH: He's kind of
a grump, you know, so--
He's [GROWLING], you know?
CHRIS CHRISTENSON: It's a big
commitment to sponsor
someone like Brad.
These guys are like
50 boards a year.
And I don't have those cards
in my deck right now.
BRAD GERLACH: Oh, we just ended
up becoming friends.
CHRIS CHRISTENSON: Friends are
first to me anyway, so--
Brad seems like a
complete nut.
And he is a complete nut.
And he's always a good
time, and you never
know what to expect.
BRAD GERLACH: Those are called
"foors," fake doors.
Do you ever do that
with words?
You put two words together
like sweaty
balls, "swalls." Woo!
"Swalls!"
The exciting part was that we're
going to meet in New
York, pick the bikes up in New
York City, and then head up
north to New England.
And I'm always looking
for waves.
And I'm always in some car,
boat, or airplane.
And the most comfortable way to
go looking for waves is on
motorcycle, for sure.
It's really fun to cruise with
one of your best buds.
CHRIS CHRISTENSON: Obviously
we have surfing in common.
But when we get together, it's
kind of like the last thing we
usually talk about.
BRAD GERLACH: Think about when
we first got going in New
York, couple times driving
along, and then all of a
sudden going like--
I had a couple of visions of
eating it and I was like, OK
just let it go.
Let it go.
Because it's just
like [SIGHING].
Think about it.
You can just eat it so easily.
You're just like, splatter.
Hey, cheers.
Here's to not eating
shit, huh?
That guy just threw a cigarette
butt at you.
[INAUDIBLE]
Welcome to the Hamptons.
CHRIS CHRISTENSON: This
guy needs to ride
a motorcycle backwards.
Look at that hair.
BRAD GERLACH: Which guy?
CHRIS CHRISTENSON: Right here.
BRAD GERLACH: What?
That's who you're
talking about.
That's who he's talking about.
CHRIS CHRISTENSON: No,
there's another one.
BRAD GERLACH: There's
another one?
The guy with the--
oh.
What?
The guy with the blonde hair?
Now he stopped talking and
looked over and said--
CHRIS CHRISTENSON: Yeah,
we're talking to you.
What the fuck you want?
BRAD GERLACH: We're just
wondering where we
could get the same--
is that a beanie?
Because that's cool shit, man.
I need that.
CHRIS CHRISTENSON: There she
is, the mighty Atlantic.
BRAD GERLACH: Oh, shit.
Pumping.
CHRIS CHRISTENSON: Think we're
going to surf this whole trip?
BRAD GERLACH: Oh, look
at that little--
maybe low tide.
CHRIS CHRISTENSON: There's
definitely a swell.
Those tides are so high.
BRAD GERLACH: Yeah.
Settle down, would you?
CHRIS CHRISTENSON: If we can
find it where the beach maybe
like goes in and then hooks
around that way, it'll
probably pick up swell.
BRAD GERLACH: We don't have any
surf connection up here.
Like there's enough swell right
now where people are
like, oh god, you could've
come around the corner.
It was was like four feet
and pitching out.
Oh you guys are playing
around a shore break.
Stingy and Doobag are over here
doing four foot aerial
reverse and varials and
shuvits and what not.
Because the waves offer that
kind of playfulness, you know?
CHRIS CHRISTENSON: See
that right there?
BRAD GERLACH: Maybe.
CHRIS CHRISTENSON: Let's go up
another 20 more mansions.
BRAD GERLACH: Chicken!
Honey, I shrunk the kids.
Look at that thing
right there.
Paddling into it, you're
seven inches tall.
You and me are hooting because
that thing feels like it's
about 30 feet.
Look at that right.
Look at it.
Off the bottom, boof into the
lip, around that, we're in
France by supper.
You're on that next one.
Whoa, big cut back, float that
section, come around there.
[MAKING SOUNDS]
Bam.
Bang.
[MAKING SOUNDS]
Air reverse.
Oh god, see.
I told you.
Just around the corner.
I neglected to mention that
Stinger or Doobag are only two
inches tall.
Let's get out of the leathers.
This board here was
a gift from Skip.
This thing's 26 years old.
Chris was [INAUDIBLE].
CHRIS CHRISTENSON: We brought
Harleys, then we got some Skip
Fryes, and we got
an 11-footer.
You know, it's just such a
different trip by bringing all
the standard boards, you know.
It's just fun to mix it up,
ride something that you
normally wouldn't bring
on a surf trip.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
BRAD GERLACH: Of course we're
hoping to catch some surf.
But yeah, we didn't get it.
But we're kind of surfing on
those motorcycles anyway.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHRIS CHRISTENSON: And if the
waves were insane out here all
the time, this would be
the best place in the
world to live, huh?
BRAD GERLACH: This would be a
great place to have a surf
trip, when there's just waves.
And just come out, go around.
You come here in the
fall time, get all
the colors, you know?
It looks like Hansel and
Gretel live here.
CHRIS CHRISTENSON: These bikes
are perfect for this type of
riding, too.
Riding through the coastal
towns, it's
almost like an instinct.
Like the other guy can just make
a facial expression, and
you what he's going to do,
or you know which way
he's going to turn.
Instincts take over with
every [INAUDIBLE]
and different communications.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
BRAD GERLACH: Going through the
beauty of New England with
the lakes and the rivers and the
trees hanging over and the
cherry blossoms and the
beautiful, perfect little
gingerbread houses-- it's like,
is there a better place
in the world to ride
a motorcycle?
[MUSIC PLAYING]
BRAD GERLACH: That's it.
I just wanted to pull over and
look down one of these streets
just to check it out.
CHRIS CHRISTENSON: I thought you
had to make a phone call.
[LAUGHING]
CHRIS CHRISTENSON: I got
to take a leak, man.
BRAD GERLACH: I might be Chief
Two Beers, but this guy's got
to piss every fucking
five minutes.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHRIS CHRISTENSON: It's just the
diversity of the way the
land is here.
You just don't know what to
expect because you can't see
what's coming, where down south
it's just a straight
line, where up here--
it's almost fun getting lost.
We don't know where we're
going to end up.
None of the roads
are straight.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
MALE SPEAKER: How
far you going?
BRAD GERLACH: The cool thing
is we don't know.
MALE SPEAKER: How far
you going today?
CHRIS CHRISTENSON: We're going
to end up in Rhode Island,
Narragansett.
MALE SPEAKER: I'm going
up to Maine.
CHRIS CHRISTENSON:
Up to Maine.
How long is that going
to take you?
MALE SPEAKER: I don't know.
CHRIS CHRISTENSON: Yeah.
So you're like us, huh?
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHRIS CHRISTENSON: It
should be like--
It's going to be just one of
those trips where you like,
talk about years and years and
years-- you know what I mean?
BRAD GERLACH: Oh, this one time
I did this bike trip with
this asshole.
[LAUGHING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
MALE SPEAKER: Here comes
the thunderhead.
Look at that real stuff.
CHRIS CHRISTENSON:
Chris, damn it.
Chris.
BRAD GERLACH: It's definitely
raining now.
CHRIS CHRISTENSON: A little
wet out there.
Time for some cold ones
and some crab legs.
Some real New England food,
that's what I want right now.
BRAD GERLACH: So what are
you going to have?
CHRIS CHRISTENSON:
I want crab legs.
What else do they
eat out here?
Crab legs, lobsters.
BRAD GERLACH: Scallops.
CHRIS CHRISTENSON: Scallops.
Lots of scallops.
BRAD GERLACH: Fish.
CHRIS CHRISTENSON: Beer.
BRAD GERLACH: Clams.
CHRIS CHRISTENSON: Clams,
yeah I want some clams.
BRAD GERLACH: Steamers.
Steamers.
I'm going to have just
a garden salad.
MALE SPEAKER: Yup.
You want the red wine
vinaigrette?
Put it on the side?
BRAD GERLACH: No, I don't
even need any dressing.
MALE SPEAKER: Nothing?
Just dry?
BRAD GERLACH: Maybe--
MALE SPEAKER: Blue cheese?
BRAD GERLACH: Maybe a lemon.
MALE SPEAKER: All right, I'll
put a lemon for you.
Just remind me if I
forget about it.
BRAD GERLACH: OK.
MALE SPEAKER: Just go ahead
and rip you out
the big one, right?
BRAD GERLACH: No, the small.
MALE SPEAKER: Just a regular
small salad?
BRAD GERLACH: Even just smaller
than the small.
If they could just
put a little bit.
If you could make a note just
to make it really small.
CHRIS CHRISTENSON: You
need to put some meat
on your bones, man.
You just getting a salad?
All right.
I'm going to get--
I want to get some
fish and chips.
Are they pretty small or big?
MALE SPEAKER: It's
a good size.
CHRIS CHRISTENSON: Good size?
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah, it comes
in two pieces usually.
CHRIS CHRISTENSON: All right.
And then I want to get
a couple appetizers.
I want to get the seared ahi.
MALE SPEAKER: That's awesome.
CHRIS CHRISTENSON: I'm going
to get some clam cakes.
MALE SPEAKER: Is that for you?
CHRIS CHRISTENSON: Yeah.
And then--
which one do you recommend,
the jerk wings
or the buffalo wings?
MALE SPEAKER: I think
the jerk, man.
They got the little sticky--
CHRIS CHRISTENSON: All right.
We'll get--
I want to get some jerk wings.
MALE SPEAKER: Jerk wings.
CHRIS CHRISTENSON: He'll help me
with a little bit of these.
BRAD GERLACH: Jerk wings?
CHRIS CHRISTENSON: And then I'll
get some kind of lobster
because we're in New
England right now.
BRAD GERLACH: Jesus.
CHRIS CHRISTENSON: What are
these different ones?
BRAD GERLACH: Yeah, the
blueberry one's pretty good.
Even number four.
CHRIS CHRISTENSON: Hold on let
me try my beer right now.
BRAD GERLACH: This one's
fucking tasty.
[INAUDIBLE]
that?
That was his food intake.
[MAKING SOUNDS]
MALE SPEAKER: I come out here.
I spit raps and rhymes, guys.
I'm the best dressed homeless
man in all of Newport.
Singing's my game.
Bricks is the name.
Slick Rick [INAUDIBLE]
taking the blame.
And the money I make, I
make it all by myself.
And then I have to share
it with everyone else.
So [INAUDIBLE] took his rhyme
to the very next level.
I don't carry a brick, but
I will ring your bell.
A Roxbury crackhead
don't sound cool.
Sing it.
You're a trip and a
motherfucking fool.
And if you really don't mind,
I got a show to put out.
Or do I really have to get
to the very next shell.
Tick, tock, tick.
I see the clock on the wall.
The rhymes are still ripping.
Woo!
All right, fellas.
Thanks, my brother.
CHRIS CHRISTENSON: It's
been one of our better
pit stops, for sure.
The rain came and I
guess it couldn't
have been better timing.
Hey, Bradley.
Hey, how you doing, buddy?
How'd those two beers
treat you?
BRAD GERLACH: I think
I had more than two.
BRAD GERLACH: Old Chief
Two Beers has got his
shoes off right now.
We're always waiting on Brad.
It's either he had two beers or
he's talking to his chick.
I'm ready to go to
the next spot.
But maybe I will just--
I think I might go check
out some [INAUDIBLE].
I'll be back.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
BRAD GERLACH: There's
no communication.
You're driving and just moving
and passing things.
And it's almost like--
thoughts, too.
You know, like, here's
a house.
Here's a lake.
You know, that's a thought.
[WOOSH]
Now you're past it.
And you're coming up.
Here's a gas station.
Here's an old monument,
a statue.
Oh, wow.
[WOOSH]
And you're passing that.
And then you come around
this corner--
The coolest thing is just like,
I've never been to this
place ever before in my life,
right where we're at.
And the motorcycle's what
brought us here.
You almost want to get lost
because getting lost is part
of the fun.
[MUSIC PLAYING]