everybody loves it, it's fantastic. You
can have it with butter, ice cream, or just
on its own as a little cake. Beautiful. It
is such a great little dessert and its all
the way from the Caribbean to rainy old England
so let's brighten up our day, shall we?!
So, we've got some Golden Syrup. Now 125g
is what you need. Beautiful. Now I'm gonna
put it all in first then I'm gonna put it
on a heat ok? So it's probably 3 of these
big old spoons. I mean it is very, very naughty,
which is not a bad thing because it's a dessert
and you deserve it.
Treacle! This stuff is lethal. Look at that!
Wow! I wouldn't lick the spoon because you'll
probably pass out. Ha ha it's really sweet!
A bit of Rum. 60ml of dark Rum. Now we've
got some sugar! Dark brown sugar. You can
use a bit of Demerara if you like. So pop
that in. It just makes it really sort of a caramelly
sort of flavour going on, rather than just
using normal caster sugar, ok.
50ml of water in there. Unsalted butter, 125g,
get that in there. And I'm just gonna turn
that on now.
Now, while that's melting you've got enough
time to chop up your stemmed ginger. It's
in a lovely syrup so it's really sweet, so
we're doing a dessert so it really does work.
You can buy it in the supermarket like this
already. Roughly chop it because you want
those little bits of ginger in there. You
don't want it to disappear completely.
In with the old stemmed ginger. Now that's
ticking away nicely, you don't wanna boil
it. We only want this to tick away until the
butter has melted and all the ingredients
have come together. Have a little taste. Aww
that's marvellous! Honestly, it' so good!
Our cake or our bread needs to rise to the
occasion so we need a bit of bicarbonate of
soda, 3/4 of a tsp there. I'll just pour that
in there now. Alright, lovely. Flour, I've
sieved out 250g of the lovely plain flour.
Now we're gonna add our spices. We've got
a tsp of ginger in there, half a tsp of all
spices. That is the actual spice of Jamaica.
I've got half a tsp of nutmeg and 1 and a
half of cinnamon. Alright, so in you go. Obviously
try and distribute it around. Mix it together.
If you can find a smaller spoon, do so. What
am I doing?! Get a big one, why not!
Beautiful! Now I'm just gonna crack 2 eggs
and whisk them up ok because the yolks are
gonna add that nice richness and the whites
gonna help it rise up.
Give it a whisky whisky, ok. We're gonna add
this lovely, naughty mixture into our eggs
ok. But you gotta do a little bit at a time
because you don't want to scramble the eggs,
do you know what I'm saying?! Once a little
bit's gone in there it sort of brings the
temperature down. I'm just gonna whisk it
up a little bit, make sure it all comes together.
Now we mix this into our flour. Make sure
you really do give it a good old whisk because
you don't want any lumps in there. You can
see bubbles moving there. That's the bicarb.
Can you see it working?!
Delicious! That is it.
All we have to do now is bake it. So I've
got this nice little loaf tin over here. A
little bit of butter inside and some greaseproof
paper, that's it. Now make sure your oven
is preheated to 170°C. Let's introduce this
into the tin now. Here we go. Wow!
Give it a little knock like that, make sure
the bubbles have gone out and it's distributed
nicely in the tin. So there we go. That goes
into an oven at 170°C for about an hour and
fifteen minutes.
An hour and fifteen minutes has passed! What
Jamaicing? Ginger cake. Ooooh.
Let's see if it's ready. Boom, straight in
the middle. Now this, should, in theory come
out nice and clear. Spot on every time. Look
at that. Beautiful. If it's got a bit of goo
on it whack it back in for another 5-10 minutes.
Yummy! I've had this on a cooling rack for
half an hour now. Beautiful! Look at that
little baby there. You can see lovely, sticky
treacle in there. What better accompany than
a nice bit of vanilla ice-cream. Look at that!
Praline, oooh yeah!
What's that? He prefers it with butter, I
like it with ice-cream. Guys, go for it. Mmm
really works with that ice-cream. Wooo, that's
lovely! Yep alright, in a minute.
Guys give it a go, you have to! If you haven't
tried it before, please do it. Comment down
below. Share the recipe with your friends
on social networks. Subscribe right now. Like
it guys, it's gotta be done.