-In Aleppo, as the battle for
Syria intensifies, ordinary
Syrians struggle to survive.
In 2010, Syrian farmers exported
nearly 2.2 million
tons of food.
But today due to shortages of
basic commodities like flour
and diesel fuel, the average
resident of Aleppo has seen
the price of bread increase
by over 100%.
Every day, the men, women, and
children of Aleppo must risk
their lives to stand in line and
hope that they can buy a
kilo of bread.
MUHAMMAD:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
-According to bakery owners and
Aleppo residents, at least
10 bakeries and bread factories
in the province have
been attacked by Assad's fighter
jets, gun ships, and
artillery batteries over
the last few months.
-Do you think you will
find bread today?
-[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
-With the country's violent
upheaval, crippling exports,
and disrupting trade routes,
there is no guarantee of food
security even for those who
risk their lives every day
just to feed their families
in this besieged city.