been up to lately.
So there are really
two big pieces of
Drake news this week.
The first is that he announced
a tour that's sort of like
monsters of blog rap tour.
It's with 2 Chainz, formerly
Tity Boi, J Cole, Waka Flocka,
and the geographically
confoundingly
named French Montana.
Personally, I'm not really a big
fan of concerts, because I
think all the best Drake songs
are kind of sad, like about
being lonely.
I think it's sort of weird to be
with 2,000 people in a room
feeling alienated.
The other piece of news, he
was in Miami alongside of
Birdman, Lil' Wayne, and DJ
Khaled filming a video for
"HYFR." Personally, I think that
"HYFR" is probably one of
the worst songs on Take Care,
just because the chorus of
"Hell yeah, fucking right"
is really dumb.
Like, to just repeat that over
and over doesn't really do
much for me.
And also because in the song,
Drake and Lil' Wayne talk
about fucking the same girls,
and it's kind of weird.
Like, I just think Lil'
Wayne's sort of gross.
But to be fair to Wayne, I knew
this girl in high school
that moved to LA, and I heard
that she sucked his dick, and
nothing bad happened to her.
Like, she's fine
and everything.
So if Drake's cool with that,
more power to Drake.
But anyways, the video's
supposed to
be Bar Mitzvah themed.
I never got a chance to go to a
Bar Mitzvah, so I hope that
the video will kind of show
me what that's all about.
Take care.