ROB DYRDEK: What we didn't know
at the time is how crazy
rapped-out ghetto he really
was, 'cause Jamie kind of
cleaned him up.
Like no jewelry, just kept him
like, you know how Jamie does,
is like finds you and
like turns you
into a street soldier.
And he had just sort of cleaned
him up, to where when
he finally quit to ride for
Alien, his inner hard-core
Dallas/Michigan ghetto side like
exploded the moment he
got on Alien.
We're like, what the hell?
JOSH KALIS: I mean, I
was just coming out
of that Dallas shit.
Tech N9ne earrings and Tech
N9ne pinkie rings.
And I mean, we thought we
were kinda doing it.
JAMIE THOMAS: Well, Alien,
at that time,
though, was that way.
I mean, it was basically
all those guys, like
corn rows and cargoes.
And it was basically a full
product of the '90s.
So all those dudes
were into it.
Kalis went back to Texas and
filmed a lot of footage for
his Timecode part, and
he had cargoes
throughout the whole thing.
ROB DYRDEK: Despite Alien having
that Memory Screen sort
of crazy, artistic--
that set this new precedent in
what video production even
could be, us as a team, we were
united in this sort of
like more broad scope.
Like we weren't all flowing
around and artsy.
We were all listening to hip-hop
and it was sort of
like a nice blend of the artists
and the creation of
what the brand was.
But we all still sort of
maintained the same sort of
style in unity.
And it wasn't overly hip-hop,
but it wasn't like rock or
anything else.
And he fit into that really,
really well at the time.
He was part of the beginning of
that new guard for Alien at
that particular time.
ANNOUNCER: Prepare
to timecode.
Josh Kalis.
JOSH KALIS: To tell you the
truth, it had nothing to do
with the image and
art direction.
It had to do with Rob Dyrdek,
John Drake, and Duane Pitre.
And in Bo Turner was like
one of the best dudes.
He was such a ball breaker.
I just wanted to be a
part of all that.
We never talked about videos.
Ever.
I don't even know how
Timecode came out.
Like I think Dyrdek and maybe
Mike Hill or somebody, I mean
they just took whatever
footage people
had and made a video.
We weren't filming
for a video.
We weren't doing any
of that stuff.
They were just, like, man, we
gotta put something out.
ROB DYRDEK: And at that
time, he was so raw.
Nobody was putting it
down in the streets
harder than he was.
STEVIE WILLIAMS: That's right
when he had the cover of
TransWorld, doing a backside
180 with the Golden Gate
Bridge in the back
with the Adidas.
It was hot, yo.
It was really, really hot.
You know, me being out in
California in San Francisco,
and Josh being Josh, and I was
still hanging with little hood
motherfuckers.
So he couldn't really hang with
me like that, like he
could in Philly.
But when Josh came through-- it
was still all love, but you
know, as far as being
competitive and having a good
sponsor and having a wack
sponsor, and shooting with the
right photographer and shooting
with the wrong
photographer, and not having
whatever to get to the next
level, Josh had it all.
It was something that you could
model yourself after.
Like, damn, I want
to be like Josh.
I want--
I want to get the cover
of TransWorld.
I want the DC this.
I want-- you know, but you
gotta work for that shit.
I was staying at Josh's house.
And I was wildin' out.
I was only 15, so I was wildin',
like throwing up,
just spilling shit, getting
caught stealing and running
back in the crib.
Like just--
just blowing the spot up.
And then here comes
Lennie Kirk.
I'd go into the crib and
like this new dude's
sitting on a couch.
And he's like, yo,
you gotta leave.
I'm like, shit, I don't
gotta go nowhere.
My man live here.
And Josh was like, yeah,
you gotta leave.
And I was like, wow.
So it was a real big fuck
you to Lennie Kirk.
But the powerful era that they
had wasn't about me.
That's how I look at it now.
It was like, he ran hard with
Lennie Kirk for a while.
JOSH KALIS: Well, when the
Timecode came out, I didn't
hang out with anybody but,
actually, Lennie.
Like me and Lennie were
roommates in San Francisco.
And like, I love Lennie.
Because Lennie is
crazy as shit.
Before his Jesus stuff,
he was like so
ghetto gangster, just--
like we were two
peas in a pod.
You know what I mean?
He had his corn rows and his
camos, and I had my camos, and
I mean, we just-- we
thought we were the
hardest dudes ever.
But Lennie would take it a
little bit further than me.
ROB DYRDEK: You know, when
I think of Lennie, how he
skates, I think of that one
photo where's he's grinding
this ledge in between a pool,
where his arm is just so
rocketed out.
JOSH KALIS: Every time, his arm
would be looking like he
was fucking punching the air.
And I mean, he was just,
like, so dope.
I loved how he skated.
Like, I was jealous
a lot of times.
Because I can't really
jump off shit like
he could, you know?
He could do the most tech shit,
or he could grind the
most gnarliest shit.
MIKE BLABAC: With Lennie, he's
just such a rad dude to watch
on a skateboard.
That works out bad, that
grind-out drop thing.
Like he had to literally pinned
himself against the
door and like ran and fucking
threw his board down, and it
was pretty raw.
It was sick.
I just remember thinking,
like, holy
shit, this guy's insane.
JAMIE THOMAS: I was always
a Lennie Kirk--
I was always a fan
of his skating.
His Timecode part, seriously
hands-down my
favorite video part.
It's definitely in
the top five.
The song, the vibe, his whole
kit and that time was like
untouchable.
His skating was so
sick and so raw.
It was like, I don't even know
if anybody's ever even come
out that raw.
Like maybe Train Wreck?
Like maybe?
It was that, like, uncut
and unfiltered.
JOSH KALIS: Lennie's skating,
it was identical to his
personality.
RB UMALI: Oh, back in the day,
gangsta Lennie days?
He would roll up with
like corn rows,
blasting gangsta rap.
And he had like--
I know he had this bat in the
backseat of his car with like
screws drilled into it.
I think he really have had
like a spiked bat.
Because I think he was listening
to Wu Tang, and he
wanted to have a spiked bat.
And yeah.
Just driving around drunk,
going to house parties,
starting fights.
I remember this one fight broke
out in Houston, and they
ended up going back with, like,
empty Snapple bottles
they got from my
room and like--
I think they torched the house
in the middle of the night.
JOSH KALIS: We were at Denny's
one time in San Diego.
Some Marines were in there.
So what's Lennie do?
Like blah, blah, starts talking
all this shit to them.
Marine starts talking shit.
About ready to fight.
Lennie reaches under his fucking
seat and pulls out a
BB gun and cocks this BB
gun to this Marine.
Like what's up now?
Cocks a fucking BB gun.
Well, here comes the Marine,
grabs a hammer, like a real
hammer, not like a fucking gun
hammer, and fucking bashes
Lennie's car, punches
him in the face.
And here come all eight
Marines out the thing.
Lennie!
Let's fucking go, dude.
But he was just like that.
Always drawing attention.
And then he hit his head.
And like, smoked weed,
and tripped out, and
fucking found God.
LENNIE KIRK: Ask Jesus to
forgive your sins always.
Pray always.
Get to know the Lord.
Study and obey the Bible.
Quit sinning.
Escape hell.
JAMIE THOMAS: I've told that
story so many times.
It's always a good one
to tell in vans, the
story of Lennie Kirk.
Basically what happened
to Lennie, you know?
JOSH KALIS: Well, I wasn't there
when you grinded the
dumpster and fell back
and smacked his head.
But that's not what made
him turn to religion.
Either a few days before or a
few days after that, he got
ran over by a Pacific
Bell truck.
Like full-on from his ankle
all the way up.
And he didn't break a bone.
And it was in front
of mad skaters.
Then a couple days after that,
he was skating across Haight
Street, and this Jeep like,
beep, honked the horn at him.
And he must've ran the
light or something.
The guy in the Jeep was
like, hey, boy,
don't you see the light?
And he was like, don't I
fucking see the light?
Like, whatever.
Skate around.
And then that night, he was
hanging out with some chick
and he was smoking weed.
And I guess, he was telling me
that he was thinking about the
dude in the Jeep.
Don't you see the light?
And fucking bam.
Like, he said he went sober,
kicked the chick out, and then
all that psychoness that he
had went into religion.
And next thing you know, before
every time he tried a
trick, he'd open up the Bible,
read a verse, and that was
going to be the outcome
of the trick.
In Timecode he 50-50 grinds this
long ledge, it's on the
top of a parking ramp and it
goes flat, and then he pops
off onto the sidewalk.
And while we were skating that
thing, he fucking grinds, his
front truck comes off and he
falls backwards and rolls and
[CLAP]
whap!
I mean, he smacks his
head so hard.
So I run over there to see if
he's all right and he's
praying and he's asking for
forgiveness and he's
apologizing.
And when he was done praying,
I'm like, yo, dude.
Like what are you praying?
What are you apologizing for?
He was like, man, I jerked off
this morning and that's my
punishment.
So we'd start watching the
footage on the camera, and
he's like, you see that?
You see that?
Like he swore that he could see
God's hand come down and
boom, mush his head
into the ground.
And I was like, get the fuck
out of here, right?
And I had to deal with that
every day until I just had to
like completely separate
myself.
If you are wearing-- like
for me, I would
be wearing a necklace.
And he'd be like,
yo, Kalis, dude.
You're going to hell.
You gon' burn in hell for
wearing that necklace.
You representin' a female.
ROB DYRDEK: It was the most
cockamamie jibber-jabbish.
Like he spoke in tongues.
It was so all over
the crazy map.
I had this argument with them
about Hubba Hideout and how he
was going to switch back
tail it, even though
Kalis already did.
And I'm like, you
can't do that.
He's like, it don't matter.
It doesn't matter.
I'm like, you can't.
So he was doing a sermon
for this church.
There was probably
300 people there.
He's just, you know, like, and I
walk, I was in the gutter, I
was a [INAUDIBLE]
days.
He's going, he's like--
And I don't, I don't care
who did what on what
ledge or who did--
I'm like, it turned into where
he was focusing in on me.
Like in the middle of the
sermon, he just somehow
twitched into the memory of
having the argument of a trick
already being done.
He got fixated on like a young
girl, like in a tight top,
like, and you're dressing around
like a whore, coming
around, acting like a whore.
And you think you can come
around putting your body--
I had to get up, be
like, yo, dude.
Yo.
And he's just, like, uh!
And people were saying to
me, I can't believe
that didn't move you.
And I'm like, what?
None of it even made sense.
Like the guy was just like, it's
like it was so crazy, in
they were just like, aaahhh.
JAMIE THOMAS: He has some pretty
heavy mental stability
issues that far outweigh
anything he wants to do.
You know what I mean?
He could want to be someone, but
he's mentally not capable
of being the person
he wants to be.
And I think that that--
I mean, it's like, how
do you avoid that?
Basically, I don't know if
Carter was the dude who was
helping Lennie, or
who was the dude.
But somebody was giving Lennie
a temporary platform to be--
like have a normal
life for a while.
And then once that kind of
crumbled or fell apart, or he
burned the bridge, then he was
out there on his own again,
left to his own devices.
And we all saw where
that went.
ROB DYRDEK: It just became one
of those things, that like he
really never skated after
Timecode, really ever again.
Not only was he just being so
focused on all things God and
preaching and being in the
streets preaching, that
eventually they just,
they had no choice.
JOSH KALIS: I mean, in his
brain, he is 100% right.
You know what I mean?
I heard he was robbing
old ladies in Frisco.
So I'll call him up, Lennie,
what are you doing, dude?
Robbing old ladies?
And he was like, man,
it's tough times.
The Lord said it
was all right.
I was like, wow.
And it was shortly after that is
when he got busted robbing
that taxi cab driver, and
off to prison he went.
I mean, I don't know
the whole story.
I just heard all the rumors
about him walking around Pier
7 with a shotgun in his
pants, you know?
No, he got out after
a few years.
And I actually went to
Frisco and skated
with him for a week.
Every day.
And he was killing it.
Like, there's sick footage
right now of Lennie board
sliding this flat rail.
It was awesome skating
with him.
And next thing I know, I
got a phone call from
San Francisco jail.
Like, hey, man.
And I need $20 grand
for this lawyer.
I'm like, what are you
doing in there?
He's like, I got seven
charges, man.
Allegedly it was like kidnapping
and some other
crazy shit.
I don't know.
It was pretty wild.
ROB DYRDEK: After he first
went to jail, it was on
September 10.
So he kept calling me
over and over from
jail, like, see, Rob?
I told you God just
put me in jail.
The end times are here, the
end times are here.
And this would have been
September 10, 2001.
The next day, 9/11 happened.
So he was like, for sure, the
end of the world, God put him
in jail because of that.
And it was like, it was
pretty ridiculous.
But the crazy thing, too, is
he went-- now he's like a
vato, you know what
I'm saying?
Now he's like a Mexican
gangster.
Like, have you ever
seen his MySpace?
PATRICK O'DELL: No.
ROB DYRDEK: Wow.
Where it's like, La Vida Loco,
and it's like, (IN VATO
ACCENT) Fuck all, fuck all the
bitches and my vida, my
bitches and my loco--
like, whatever.
It looks like a Spanish
gangbanger's MySpace page.
It's incredible.