THURMAN SEWELL: Never
get down.
SIDNEY SEWELL: [INAUDIBLE]
to get where we're at.
[MAAL THE PIMP, "CHATTANOOGA"]
-Let's start at the
beginning, I mean.
Chattanooga, Tennessee.
Have you guys ever been
to Chattanooga?
SIDNEY SEWELL: Well,
Chattanooga's actually a big
touristy because they have the
aquarium, they have like this
Rock City bullshit.
I don't know how other people
might perceive it, but the way
we grew up there, and where we
grew up at was fucking gnarly.
THURMAN SEWELL: It's
really a ghetto-ass
little fucking town.
CHRIS SCOGGINS: The first thing
you're going to see is
the East Lake courts.
Look at those beautiful
buildings there.
This is the most dangerous
projects in Chattanooga.
Any one of these streets right
here you turn down the wrong
time of day will get
you killed, or it
might get you laid.
SIDNEY SEWELL: When we were kids
we would like, you know,
fuck with hookers.
THURMAN SEWELL: It
was so sketchy.
You'd be outside, and these
fucking creepos would come up,
"You need a ride?"
CHRIS NIERATKO: Really?
THURMAN SEWELL: People have
tried to kidnap us before.
SIDNEY SEWELL: Like why
would they be wanting
to give us a ride?
You're fucking creeps trying
to butt-fuck us.
You know what I mean?
CHRIS SCOGGINS: Look
at this one.
They got more junk
in the front yard
than 10 houses combined.
There's a cop right there, just
hanging out, talking to
the dope dealers.
Smell the stuff cooking.
SIDNEY SEWELL: We grew up
super in like poverty.
You know what I mean?
Like on food stamps, our dad was
disabled, so we got like
these checks every month.
It was just super ghetto.
Our parents, the way they
raised was they told us
everything, like how it was.
You know what I mean?
THURMAN SEWELL: We watched
R-rated movies when we were
five years old.
CHRIS NIERATKO: So you look
at that as a good thing?
THURMAN SEWELL: Yeah.
SIDNEY SEWELL: Yeah, 'cause we
got brought up to see life how
it really is.
CHRIS NIERATKO: How many
sisters you got?
SEWELL BROTHERS: Two.
SIDNEY SEWELL: Nah, man.
You know what's crazy
is one of our
sisters went to Harvard.
THURMAN SEWELL: Studied
her whole life.
Got this like financial aid into
the private schools, and
we were kind of like counting
on her to be like the family
fortune, like fuck this shit.
We're just gonna skate, and
she'll be rich one day, and
we're not gonna have
to do fucking shit.
You know what I mean?
Like we really had
that mentality.
SIDNEY SEWELL: We never even
went to high school.
CHRIS NIERATKO: Really?
SIDNEY SEWELL: We went to
fucking half of eighth grade,
and like school?
Fuck school.
We always hated school.
All right?
We always got fucked
with at school.
Like I'm sure now like in
school, skate boarders are
popular kids.
It was not like that.
CHRIS NIERATKO: So eighth
grade is as
far as you guys got?
SIDNEY SEWELL: Yeah.
Still to this day, I hate it.
THURMAN SEWELL: I don't
regret quitting.
SIDNEY SEWELL: I don't want
to go to any school.
People try to get us to
go back to school.
No.
We were bad kids, yo.
We were just fucking punks.
We didn't go to school.
We didn't do shit
except skate.
CHRIS NIERATKO: How about
when your mom left?
She left your old man.
Why did she leave?
What was the reason?
SIDNEY SEWELL: She
was unhappy.
THURMAN SEWELL: He was disabled,
and she wanted to
live her life.
SIDNEY SEWELL: She had four
fucking kids her whole
god-damned life.
THURMAN SEWELL: She got married
when she was 16.
She was just over it.
She wanted to go live life.
SIDNEY SEWELL: So she did.
Mom left dad when
we were like 12.
We were really close to our
dad, you know what I mean?
Our dad--
THURMAN SEWELL: He had
gotten a pacemaker.
SIDNEY SEWELL: It was just
sketchy, kind of, and he'd
take insulin, take all
this shit, diabetes.
THURMAN SEWELL: He would
take about 50
different pills a day.
Like it was just crazy,
I mean it was crazy.
CHRIS NIERATKO: And were you
guys responsible for taking
care of him?
THURMAN SEWELL: Somewhat.
We watched our dad die.
CHRIS NIERATKO: What happened?
SIDNEY SEWELL: What happened
was, man, I won't get too deep
into it 'cause it's pretty
emotional, but--
THURMAN SEWELL: So he just
woke us up one morning.
It's a Saturday, wakes us up
like, "I don't feel good."
SIDNEY SEWELL: He got up--
THURMAN SEWELL: He starts going
like that, he starts
blacking out, and we're
like, fuck.
What the fuck, you know?
SIDNEY SEWELL: So I called 911,
and they were like uh,
telling us how to do mouth
to mouth and all
that type of shit.
THURMAN SEWELL: We
tried all that.
SIDNEY SEWELL: We tried,
and it wasn't working.
THURMAN SEWELL: Then the
ambulance showed up, and they
were like doing the electric
shocks, and we
just kind of left.
SIDNEY SEWELL: We were
freaked out.
THURMAN SEWELL: We didn't
want to believe it.
SIDNEY SEWELL: We were
really hysterical.
THURMAN SEWELL: We thought, like
all right, he'll be all
right, because they
took him away.
SIDNEY SEWELL: But deep
down we knew.
THURMAN SEWELL: We knew, but
then we get a call like an
hour later, our aunts called,
like yeah, your dad's dead.
It was just crazy.
CHRIS NIERATKO: What's the
relationship with your mom?
SIDNEY SEWELL: We were all
bitter about it, because we
thought it was fucked
up that she left.
THURMAN SEWELL: So anyway,
so we're in
Chattanooga, whatever.
My mom was in Knoxville, so
after our dad died, we were
forced to move to Knoxville,
Tennessee,
SIDNEY SEWELL: There's a guy--
THURMAN SEWELL: Another
shit hole.
SIDNEY SEWELL: All right, but
there's a guy we met named
Chris Scoggins, who was five
years older than us, and he
lived right around the
corner from us.
CHRIS SCOGGINS: That was like
early '90s, pulled up into
this hood-ass neighborhood and
saw these two cats sitting on
the front porch, and these two
kids like finishing each
other's sentences.
I can't tell them apart, like
fucking long-ass black hair
with like Misfits skateboards.
And we just start kicking it
every day, just skating out in
front of the house and fucking
with the neighborhood kids and
getting into fights and shit,
and fucking with the
prostitutes.
They walk by, we
holler at 'em.
And I guess in turn, yeah,
we taught each
other how to skate.
SIDNEY SEWELL: He really showed
us the way as far as
like everything, what's cool.
So we started skating in the
hood, and we waxed this curb
up at a Dollar General store,
and we really got into
skateboarding for real and
really started skating.
CHRIS SCOGGINS: I was skating
a lot, but when I met those
dudes, they taught me the
difference between cake flip,
Nollie flip, switchfoot,
fakie flip.
Taught me fucking who Pepe
Martinez was, who Mike Carroll
was, who Stevie Williams was.
I didn't know all that.
I just skated.
Sidney and Thurman were
my favorite skaters.
THURMAN SEWELL: It
was amazing.
We had the time of our life.
We just skated.
SIDNEY SEWELL: All
we did was skate.
THURMAN SEWELL: Every day, all
day, and then just party.
JON NEWPORT: At the time, we
were all catching rides to get
to downtown Atlanta to go skate,
and we would go skate
with all the older heads, 'cause
we were kind of on the
same shit, and there was this
graffiti yard called 40 Yard
in midtown Atlanta.
Man, we all used to
skate 40 Yard.
We all helped build it, and the
twins used to come down,
and they wouldn't talk much, but
they were ripping always.
Man, it was just a time.
CHRIS NIERATKO: I
saw old footage.
These guys were good.
Why didn't you pursue
skateboarding?
THURMAN SEWELL: Well, we did
it in the way we thought we
were, but deep down that shit's
like making NBA, you
know what I'm saying?
That was a dream.
That was everybody's
fucking dream.
SIDNEY SEWELL: Really, our dream
was just to get free
shit, like--
THURMAN SEWELL: A box.
SIDNEY SEWELL: Like get a box.
THURMAN SEWELL: That
was amazing.
CHRIS NIERATKO: You never
thought to go to California?
THURMAN SEWELL: We did,
but I think we were
just scared back then.
I think if we would've been
around people like
Pearson and all that.
SIDNEY SEWELL: Now we're
homeless brothers.
THURMAN SEWELL: It was like
we fit right in with them.
You know what I'm saying?
If he would have just been
around back then, we could
have made it, I think.
JOSH KALIS: The first time I
met the ATL twins, I think
they were called like the Kalis
twins in Atlanta for
awhile or something like that,
we just clicked, man.
Dudes were cool.
They got kind of the same
history as me when it comes to
like the way we grew up and the
way our families were and
all that type of shit.
Not to mention, they're
full street skaters.
They rip.
They know pretty much everything
that's has to do
with any type of
skateboarding.
I'm psyched every
time I see 'em.
CHRIS NIERATKO: So this
is the playground.
THURMAN SEWELL: Yeah, man,
this is fucking crazy.
SIDNEY SEWELL: Yeah, this place
is amazing, like this is
a bougie-ass mall.
This is a bougie mall.
THURMAN SEWELL: This is like
Stevie Williams' park.
SIDNEY SEWELL: You never know
who you'll bump into here.
Anthony Williams.
ANTHONY WILLIAMS: What's up?
SIDNEY SEWELL: It's just fucking
private and it's dope.
THURMAN SEWELL: Tupac
piece up there.
SIDNEY SEWELL: Like a lot of
fucking people came in here
and really tag it up.
Manual pad, fucking ledge.
Little ledges.
Damn, Dorian.
Slow down, man.
THURMAN SEWELL: Slow down.
Yeah.
Hell, yeah.
By the [INAUDIBLE].
We're gonna skate and see what
we can come up with.
For us, we don't get to skate
every day, but we're gonna see
what we can do.
We're not those dudes.
We still love it, but the act
of doing it, I just wanna
drink and fuck bitches.
I don't wanna skate.
I'm not 13 years old anymore.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
-Nobody wants to see Marv Albert
in a slam dunk contest.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
SIDNEY SEWELL: I wanna see it.
THURMAN SEWELL: Yes,
we do wanna see it.
SIDNEY SEWELL: [INAUDIBLE]
THURMAN SEWELL: And
we'll hype it up.
And we'll be like, aaah.
For real.
SIDNEY SEWELL: NJ all day.
NJ all day.
THURMAN SEWELL: NJ all day.
SIDNEY SEWELL: NJ
all day, baby.
Gonna get back and skate,
motherfuckers.
THURMAN SEWELL: That was sick.
SIDNEY SEWELL: That was dope.
THURMAN SEWELL: Hard
ass trick.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
THURMAN SEWELL: That
shit was hard, yo.
SIDNEY SEWELL: You got it now.
You got it now.
[HIP HOP MUSIC]
THURMAN SEWELL: We told Selena,
like, yo, your fans
are fucking attacking us.
She's like yeah, don't
fuck with my fans.
They're loyal.
THURMAN SEWELL: It's an army of,
I would say, anywhere from
five to ten million people.
SIDNEY SEWELL: You wanna try
to call her right now on
speaker phone.
See what happens.