You waiting for the book?
-Yeah.
NIMROD KAMER: You know it's 20
quid and it's just pictures of
people in the streets.
Are you a big fan of
the Sartorialist?
-Yes.
NIMROD KAMER: I love him.
I think he's like redic
and unconvent hashtag.
#fab, #marv, #immense,
#incred, OMG, WTF.
Those girls were HAStags--
hashtag for has-beens.
Are you single?
-Sorry?
NIMROD KAMER: Are you single?
-Single or singer?
-Yeah, he's available.
NIMROD KAMER: Single.
I mean, emotionally available.
-Emotionally?
I'm not sure I'm emotionally
stable to
be emotionally available.
NIMROD KAMER: I'm into guys now,
because I want to be in
the Sartorialist.
Do you have any friends
on the book?
I'm on it.
-OK.
NIMROD KAMER: Yeah, on page 16
if there wasn't a mistake.
-You would need to pay for this
scarf in this department.
NIMROD KAMER: Oh, I'm still
staying in the floor though.
-That's all right, but you would
need to pay the scarf in
this department.
NIMROD KAMER: So I'll keep it
here for a sec, and I'll come
back to pay.
-I can hold it for you.
That's fine.
NIMROD KAMER: It goes
well with the book.
I just want to have the look
for the book signing.
-No problem.
NIMROD KAMER: Because I just
want the blogger to like me.
-Yeah.
NIMROD KAMER: That's
his thing.
Fashion street art.
-I know.
NIMROD KAMER: Hey, hello.
My name is Nimrod.
SCOTT SCHUMAN: Hi,
how are you?
NIMROD KAMER: Like the
Green Day album.
SCOTT SCHUMAN: Ah.
NIMROD KAMER: Nimrod.
Actually, instead of signing the
book, can you mention me
on Twitter?
SCOTT SCHUMAN: I don't know.
I don't usually do that but
I can sign the book.
NIMROD KAMER: But can you--
SCOTT SCHUMAN: Is that fair?
NIMROD KAMER: --put my name
on Twitter, like on
your Twitter feed?
SCOTT SCHUMAN: I don't know.
I'll think about it.
NIMROD KAMER: OK.
And basically I have this
photo if you want to
use it in your blog.
Just go and consider it.
It's me on a snowball.
SCOTT SCHUMAN: I see that.
NIMROD KAMER: Yeah.
SCOTT SCHUMAN: Huh.
NIMROD KAMER: Think about it.
Yeah, you can leave it.
SCOTT SCHUMAN: I'll put
it right there.
NIMROD KAMER: And can
I follow you?
SCOTT SCHUMAN: You what?
NIMROD KAMER: Can
I follow you?
SCOTT SCHUMAN: Sure.
NIMROD KAMER: I mean follow--
SCOTT SCHUMAN: You're welcome.
NIMROD KAMER: Follow
you home, whatever?
SCOTT SCHUMAN: Probably not
home, but we'll figure
something out.
NIMROD KAMER: OK.
I love the tie.
SCOTT SCHUMAN: Thank you.
-Thank you very much.
-So you bought it?
NIMROD KAMER: I didn't buy it.
I just took it from the
shelf, had it signed.
And then actually I also tried
to sell it to someone else.
Do you want to buy a book
from me with my
signature for 25 quid?
-So now you're waiting in
line to do it again?
NIMROD KAMER: Yeah, to
sell it to another
person for more money.
Because you need to
make some money.
I mean, all the money goes
to Sartorialist.
You want to make some money.
-But it's 5 quid!
NIMROD KAMER: It's
profit for me.
-I know, but that's
like $7 US.
NIMROD KAMER: But I
do it 10 times.
If you want to buy my book
signed for just 5 more quid.
-Oh, OK.
NIMROD KAMER: Because he takes
advantage of the street, he
should give back money to
the streets, basically.
Can I just leave the book here
because I'm not sure I want it
now?
-But it's been signed?
NIMROD KAMER: Yeah,
it's been signed.
But I forgot to buy before, and
now I think I'm just going
to leave it here if it's OK.
-OK, yeah.
I'm sure that's fine.
Have a good day.
NIMROD KAMER: But you can
use the signature.
NIMROD KAMER: No.
I mean, I don't have the book.
I had it signed, and
then I left it.
NIMROD KAMER: Yeah, because I
just had it signed, and then I
just regretted it.
NIMROD KAMER: I can't resell?
OK, OK.