different problems they have a white
prague event so-called into racially
integrated probable suites where you
know the black students have their prom
right in the cool like it to go
drown me at some something clan
and now what's happening right now is
our forces that are fighting there
they're trying to raising money
to have a racially integrated trial
because what the high school does is
they don't have their own probably have
private parties
provide for a prom okay
so hot
parents add maybe some members of staff
knows they provide funding for you know
white prom and then the other prom on it
since they're privately funded the
school really doesn't have much say in
terms of what happened switched back i
think is the as if it's a prom that's
tied to your students you should not
allow any any type of segregation it of
course and so
the other problem obvious is not really
racially integrated because they're
having to raise money for a whole
different
racially integrated products another
headed have three props
if your wife there you go to all three
of us kind of cool
kid dependent now seriously getting him
and
i'm and literally have trouble reading
the story okay so there's a lot of news
of our i want to show that see you guys
to and because it'll give you some more
detail than
how it works and what happened to one
o'clock sitemap dot that's the issue
left to the white from looks at their
world full-color wilcox county has
caused those people who says black and
white
there the white prominent had a
annotated prompted n erased other than
cartesian tries to and the white brown
they would probably have a policeman and
well-prepared
that was the case just last year as a
biracial student was turned away by
police it's been away for as long as
anyone can remember it doesn't stop it
from
homecoming is almost everyday
and the homecoming king queen
one the one was more than one this year
for the first time in and out of black
and a black man away what
it was a black and white and black
and they were uh... they were allowed to
pictures two for the year but
harmonica
so that when people say race in this guy
now look have we made progress
of course we have this is an would have
described entire herself
you know forty fifty years ago
that goes to show it wasn't that long
ago that
because we still have remnants of it
in twenty thirteen this storm playing
this
the fact of the activities in that town
have put up with it
you know is amazing i mean obviously not
want to know that we could escorted out
of the dalai
but cars
but if ever there was a time to call and
then double a_c_p_ et cetera this is a
that they have a little story keep the
black kids from goldman were probably
just go to the white promptly ended this
year
but you did you get the police com the
political complicated story allow what
charge
and by the way of thinking about whether
black people in that time to get a fair
shake
on other matters act let alone when it
comes to the police those police are
escorting a black is for the prompt even
imagine they turn around and say
although no i'm not gonna pull the plug
of respondents
or do you think they make certain
assumptions about coordinated since
as a candidate the regular fare sort of
it's formats of the school this is a
well into the while the school is no
official stance on that
does the have travis and definitely do
have an official stance have to have one
uh... but another point that i wanted to
make
the fact that you don't we talk about
institutional racism and we talk about
certain uh... obstacles that a black
people have to go through just to become
successful and one thing that we
unfortunately get the chance to talk
about earlier this week was a study that
was done on uh... networking and how lot
of times
people who are c_e_o_'s are managers are
owners of companies
uh... art typically white and when we do
they do favors for their boyfriends and
those are the people that usually get
hired into their companies so bill
redeker position with
uh... robert johnson who said who was
that had it bt
than i thought was a really
interesting
but rogers amends process from a
conservative
but i thought his answer served or other
words replicating said any mentioned
just that point it it's not
even malicious nine if you are exactly
you know if you're a regular guy your
carpenter were you when i'm here
and for that one of the job opens up the
you know
carpenter position
your son your nephew jesus you know
that would help okay although he kinda
left i know
say i'm not sure is a great carbon
may be happy to know
and so that's just the way it works here
in a union
and so one of the reasons you need
affirmative action was to break through
that national barrier
that was a demon s early malicious
okay now this in georgia is malicious
prepared by the way law that either
watched
yet over the course of course pack a day
but even now i'm just saying that right
here is that you know i'll give you know
the we work with your friends yet and if
you have no exposed anybody else's gonna
keep perpetuating the situation
and it's amazing to in another
blaming the victim he don't get me wrong
but
summation among people problems
i know that it was incredible part of
the story and this has been going on for
decades
there'll they're like uh... talent
frozen in time
innocent civilians are spread this story
and it has a proposal earlier this week
when i first read i think this is an
april fool's joke sorry there's no
question about it
but now it's a real this is the kind of
suffered some having a country
suffolk ip alike
ignored it lacked and then just pretend
like we don't have any problems of
racism