JASON MCAFEE: His spiritual side
is all over the place, in
a good way.
I think Freddy believes and
dabbles in a little
bit of all of it.
JOHN ODA: My teacher, he's
a Tibetan Buddhist.
This is called Gongfucha.
It's like Kung Fu tea.
And then if all the elements
are in the right proportion
with care and good timing, then
it's like liquid gold.
JASON MCAFEE: I really
enjoyed it.
And it took me a few times
to realize what it was.
I mean, there's a lot
of love behind it.
What's really great about it,
too, is you actually sit
together and talk.
JOHN ODA: Apocalypto really
fucked me up.
JASON MCAFEE: Yeah, dude,
that shit was crazy.
When you saw the Royal Family
and how all the kids are all
fat with all this jewelry.
JOHN ODA: Yeah.
JASON MCAFEE: There are times
we'll just like keep drinking
and keep drinking, and we're
just like la, la, la, la.
We're just so caught up in our
chores, and day-to-day life,
and television, and what's
going on on the news or
whatever, that it's something
that's been going on for
centuries that we can still
participate in, and I think
that's really a magical
part of it, too.
JOHN ODA: Did you guys
get it good?
JASON MCAFEE: Yeah, I'm so glad
that we had to do this.
JOHN ODA: Do you guys
feel different?
I mean, it does something
to your awareness.
You feel up but relaxed
and almost a
little euphoric sometimes.
JASON MCAFEE: Mm-hm.