- I’m not normal. What does that - what
is logic? 'Use your head, use your natural
inclinations.' He’s saying, 'look at it
my way.' Yes, that's what he's saying. Let
us sit and reason together means, see if you
can see things my way. That's impossible conversation.
Or, 'you shouldn't have done that' if a person
honestly doesn't know what to do about something
you say 'you shouldn't have done that', it's
better to say what you can do to make it work.
Rather than you shouldn't have done that.
Give them something to do that'll make it
work. If your cat rubs its body against you
and you kick the cat, that doesn't change
the pattern, he may move away then. But what
you're really interested in is - I'm getting
right to the point now - is manipulating the
environment, that's what you really want.
The purpose of language is not to communicate,
it's to control the behavior of other people.
When you tell another person 'mow the lawn,
I'll give you 5 bucks' he says 'no' - '10
bucks?' - 'yes I’ll mow the lawn', y'know.
Money is a control device to a limited extent.
If you offer a girl 5 dollars to have sex
with her, she’d feel terribly insulted,
but if you give her 1 million dollars , she
might have to think about it, even though
she's a moralist. She might have to sit a
moral society for that deal, otherwise I have
to work for 40 years and never get that opportunity.
Is it an opportunity? It could be an insult
to some people. So, 'use your head' is no
language at all, or 'you’re dumb, you’re
dumb' there's no language no communication,
or 'you shouldn't have done that’ is no
communication, or 'I hate you!' is no communication.
Unless you say, 'the sink run and overflowed
everything and I had to work 4 hours cleaning
it up, try not to do that again, otherwise
I won’t let you near the sink' ok? Whatever
it is that you have to do. So you've got a
long way to go - most language is noise. When
people sit and talk to each other and check
with them 3 days later what did you talk about,
they usually don’t know cause it was not
significant. When normal people get together
and talk, they usually say nothing, they can't
say anything. So when you have a Zeitgeist
meeting, they can only talk within the realm
of what they think that means. Are you with
me? Do you understand if the brain is perfectly
organised, all the tissue is good quality,
it has no mechanism for knowing how to react
under varying conditions, that's learned.
They say 'you can't pass on what you learn'
- it seems to me - that’s a semantic term
'it seems to me' it's always good to use 'it
seems to me that this is so' meaning 'that's
so' - 'it seems to me' - now if I look at
person that's tri-sexual, tries anything,
I would say that they’ve been off into some
odd direction, but I don't look down at them.
I know that I could've been brought up that
way, I could've been brought up by the headhunters
- if you take a baby from a civilised world,
2 years old and bring him up as a head-hunter
he'd be a head-hunter, and if you say 'that’s
a terrible thing' I don’t know that it's
much more terrible than the world you live
in. When a guy's a plumber and another guy's
an electrician, I think that's unfair use
of the brain to make a person an electrician
or a plumber - generalist, you're giving them
more tools, not all the tools but more tools,
that's what a person craves at a meeting,
they don't know why they go there, they say
they go there because 'I like the Zeitgeist
Movement' or 'I like the Venus Project' and
if you pin them down - what do you think the
Venus Project is? 'It's a different interpretation
of lifestyle' - 'how different?' pin them
down, see if you can get information. They
usually don't provide the information, because
they don't know that much about it. I'll open
this up to questions. If you have any? I had
some requests from people if you could talk
more a little bit about anthropology? Anthropology?
As a scientific discipline. In anthropology
they're ok, when they step out of the field
they usually conform, or they can get a job
as a teacher of anthropology but the anthropologist
studies different cultures, mainly primitive,
but he doesn't think his own culture is primitive.
See, unfortunately, there's no field you can
study today that isn't entrapped in
a culture somewhere. Do you know what that
means? It's hard to escape, and if you really
succeeded in escaping from your culture, you'd
have difficulty talking to people, alls you'd
be doing is informing them. And they say,
'what are your qualifications for informing
me?' say 'what do you get out of it?' that's
the qualifications, if you get nothing out
of it there's no qualifications. Qualification
is, how well does the system work? If you
don't water your plants they don't grow, so
you water them. If the water's contaminated
with chemicals and poisons, the plants die,
the only way to know that is to do what they
call 'the wrong thing' it’s never the wrong
thing. In science like on the Larry King show
last when they were talking about brain and
mind and trying to distinguish one from another.
yes, what's the difference? Yeah I don't see
any. The brain is like a battery, the charge
is the mind. Do you know what that means?
If I put up a sign 'batteries free of charge'
that would mean no electrical charge in them,
it doesn't mean you can take it home for nothing.
If I give you a battery free of charge, a
mind free of charge sometimes it's a brain
hit by lightening, it so saturates everything
so the guy doesn't know he's even there. The
brain's been shocked into nonassociative systems.
That can happen, or the brain can be partially
shocked, into no association systems. Then
there's such a thing as neurotoxins - poisons
in the brain, that make it unable to operate,
and there's conditioning that makes the brain
unable to operate, it's hard to tell the difference,
because neurotoxins can stop the brain from
operating and a guy brought up in a thalamic
country - you know what that means? emotional
only, and he only gets angry when people don't
do what he asked them to do - 'I told you
to cook the chicken' you know and they get
angry, that means you didn't affect their
behavior the way you wanted to, you know you
can't say to kids 'I want you to listen to
every word I say' he can't even hear the words
you say, unless you tell him what the words
mean. So you've got a much bigger job than
you think, it isn't just saying 'now you listen
to me, I'll tell you the truth' you can't
walk over to a judge and say 'everything you
do is based on ignorance' he says 'how do
you see that? How do you mean that?' - I say,
if you ever run into a judge that talks that
way, you're half way there. I've never met
a person who says 'how do you mean that?'
you know. So if you say to a judge 'everything
you do is erroneous, unreal, you might as
well be a head-hunter. You're putting people
in jail, you're judging people, you know nothing
about their background' he says 'I know plenty
about their background! He's a criminal, he's
been in jail before' that's his yard stake
- associative memory. So all our actions
are based on associative memory, do you understand
what that means? Your experience. Not the
truth. When a person says 'I'd like to know
the truth about something. Does the universe
change?' and another person might say 'at
what rate does it change?' you know, you can
take a camera and a telescope and photograph
the universe every 2 hours and the stars will
move to different positions, but normally
looking at it, all the stars appear to be
fixed. So even that time frame camera, if
set to photograph every month, the planets
will move a great deal, so you can record
and say - when you're scientific, you can
say 'within 12 minutes, this is what we get.
Within 40 minutes, this is what we get' -
'which is the right one?' - that doesn't
make sense. If you photograph an automobile
with an ordinary camera, the wheels appear
to be turning backwards, have you ever noticed
that on cars? On a motion picture? Well if
you can sync your camera, with real events
in real time, you can get the wheels to appear
to turn in the right direction. So, all knowledge
is based upon time, when a chemist looks at
something, he looks at it as a chemist. When
a writer listens to a person he listens for
story, what he feels would be commercially
saleable. When a sales man looks at person,
he's looking at something entirely different
- 'Can I sell you a lawn mower?' Now, it
seems to me that if you were to tell the average
person, if you had a city of 10,000 people,
and they all chipped in 10 bucks a piece and
built a community bank, and all the profit
went to that city, he should lap onto that
cause that makes sense. You know what I mean?
If it was a community owned bank and all the
profit went to everybody, if the community
of 10,000 people chipped in 10 bucks a piece,
and bought a farm, food would be much less
for everybody. So, when they say 'that sounds
like communism' that doesn't deal with anything,
the person's not addressing the subject. What's
wrong with a community bank? He says 'it'll
kill incentive' - have you ever tried it?
'No' - then how do you know it'll kill incentive?
You know, you're always wrestling with people.
So, if you got 4,000 houses or say 300 houses
and each 1 buys a lawnmower, if you bought
6 gigantic lawnmowers and mow the whole area,
it'd be better than selling a lawnmower to
every house, but it's better for business,
but collectivism is obviously better than
any other system. So people say to me - or
I’ve been reading anti utopian books, it
says 'man doesn't stay fixed, he's changing'
well it depends on the rate of change, man
they say can’t be controlled because he’s
not a fixed entity, when you see all these
Chinese marching together in North Korea,
they march like 1 unit, and we did 2,000 plane
raids over Germany, how'd you get 2,000 planes
off the ground without making them very uniform?
You know what I mean? Now, what degree of
uniformity can you attain with people? It
depends on how sophisticated your equipment
is. Now, when they say 'is there a place for
individuality?' when you say to me 'if a guy
likes to fuck frogs, would there be a place
for him?' What do you mean by individuality?
I don’t know what they're talking about,
I know what they think they're talking about,
'will they be free?' they’re never free,
you can't be free of your background, you
speak in some language always, Japanese, Chinese,
but you can't be free. If a guy comes up and
he says '[UNKNOWN] - I'm an individualist'
that's what that means, it means he doesn't
respond as you do, well you can’t deal with
him if he doesn't. You can’t make any deals,
you can’t get any behavioral cooperation.
So, the Zeitgeist Movement should be a system
that indoctrinates people to a working system,
that's beneficial to most people.