You could also wait until maybe
Virgin Galactic finishes
their project.
That's going to take
a long time.
But wouldn't it be much more fun
if you just created your
own spacecraft yourself, your
own space rocket, fly into
space doing that?
-Go.
KRISTIAN VON BENGTSON: Working
metal doesn't sound very sexy,
but it's actually one of the
best skills that I've obtained
through life, except sketching
and drawing.
I mean, creating anything
in metal is just--
there's no limits to what
you can actually do
if you have an idea.
And of course, wood is nice, but
you're not going to go far
in a space rocket
made of wood.
Yeah, my name is Kristian
von Bengtson.
I'm a co-founder of Copenhagen
Suborbitals, a non-profit and
open-source DIY space program.
We're not doing open-source
space flights at the moment.
We're not aiming for
it right now.
We're doing suborbital
space flight.
That's a parabolic flight where
you go up and down, a
short trip.
Copenhagen Suborbitals was
founded in 2008 by myself and
my partner, Peter Madsen.
I was back in Denmark after
I've been working at NASA
Johnson Space Center.
And at that time, I read in
an article that Peter was
launching his first and last
submarine nautilus.
And in that article, I read that
Peter had a prior history
doing rocket engines, and he
wanted to work again with
rocket engines.
So I thought to myself,
let me talk to Peter.
And I contacted him, and we
met in his submarine.
And basically, within
a few hours, we
decided to join forces.
He would be creating the
launch vehicles.
I would be creating the
space capsules.
And from that moment,
actually, Copenhagen
Suborbitals was founded.
PETER MADSEN: My name
is Peter Madsen.
I'm with Copenhagen
Suborbitals.
My part of it is the rocket
engines that propel the
spacecraft.
And it's also the construction
of launch pads and all the
systems, essentially, that
takes the spacecraft from
planet Earth and into Space.
Well, I'm not obsessed.
Not at all.
It's all the other people who
are obsessed with footballs
and that sort of thing.
I'm just doing what I've
always been doing.
I'm playing.
-[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
PETER MADSEN: This is the
TM65 rocket engine.
It uses two components
for its propellants.
The one is liquid oxygen.
And the other is alcohol,
the same type of
alcohol that we drink.
But this is just slightly
more concentrated.
So it's a schnapps
locks engine.
This engine really works the
same way as the engines that
originally propelled the Saturn
V Rocket to the moon.
It's the same type
of technology.
The difference from the Space
Shuttle main engines to this
one is that while a shuttle
engine consists of literally
tens of thousands of components,
this one is a
couple of hundred components.
All the parts that this engine
is consisting of--
primarily the valves, the
actuator, the nuts and bolts,
the tubes and pipes
and everything--
are all the products of modern
industry, and they're all off
the shelf things.
If it wasn't used in this rocket
engine, very likely
this component would have found
its way into an ordinary
house for heating purposes
or the water
mains used in a kitchen.
It's the sort of things that are
completely normal that we
put together and turn into
a rocket engine.
KRISTIAN VON BENGTSON: Using
off the shelf products that
you can buy in vast numbers
are actually
very reliable systems.
Instead of trying to invent our
own valve, for instance,
why not buy one that's
been produced
maybe a million times?
When you're working a DIY
project, the natural premise
is that you don't have much.
You don't have much
money, funding.
You don't have, maybe, all the
technology like the pro guys,
or the materials.
And then you have to come
up with solutions.
And that sparks a lot of new
technology, new ideas.
And sometimes it also takes the
solution that you would
normally do--
very expensive, very complex
in the professional world--
and bring it down to a level
and show people that it's
actually possible
to do the same--
come up with same solution
for less money.
The first rocket we tried to
launch, it contained a hair
dryer to keep one of the
valves heated up so it
wouldn't freeze up.
It was actually a
great solution.
PETER MADSEN: We have left the
workshop now, and we have
walked about 100 meters to one
of the two test stands.
And what we have is
a steel gantry.
And up there, a room for the the
four 16 millimeter bolts
that keep the engine in place.
And we have a crane that we
use to hoist it up there.
And on top of this steel
structure, we have the
propellant tanks of, totally,
700 kilos of propellant that
the engine consumes in
about 15 seconds.
[APPLAUSE]
KRISTIAN VON BENGTSON: Launching
rockets is actually
like anything else
we're doing here.
It's tests of different
systems.
We have to prove to ourselves
that we are capable of
handling different
technologies.
-[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
KRISTIAN VON BENGTSON: There's
always certain things we are
testing on.
So it's all a part of the big
puzzle ending up for a big
rocket with a capsule on top.
And of course, we're going
to do more launches.
PETER MADSEN: We are aiming
for a manned mission.
But of course, we are only
flying the big rockets with a
crash test dummy inside.
We're not going to be flying
any persons, any live human
being, until we believe
that it's fairly safe.
KRISTIAN VON BENGTSON: This
is is our space capsule,
Beautiful Betty.
And it's the first prototype of
this kind of capsule-type
space vehicle for one person.
Most of this--
the capsule--
I welded myself.
But I did the sign--
and some of the interior
welding--
I did with a guy called Klaus.
He's my partner in doing
these capsules here.
And we're also together
developing the new capsule.
It was tested about
two months ago.
It got pretty roughed up.
But it's still here.
And we can still do
a lot of tests.
And it's a foundation of all the
new capsules we're going
to do in the future.
Well, Randy, the crash
test dummy,
was inside this capsule.
And, well, he lost a leg.
It's possible, actually, that
he would have survived, only
because of the direction
that it hit water.
But he might be in a wheelchair
forever if it was a
live person.
Randy has been a good
friend of ours.
He's been flying for
the last two years.
So every time we have a capsule
or a spaceship, he's
going to be in the
seat, and he's
going to take the beating.
That's why you have a
crash test dummy.
Keeping one person alive, even
only for a 15 minute ride, is
a big challenge.
You need to create a reliable
piece of confined room,
confined space for one person,
where you have a small seat,
where you're comfortable but
also work with all the
acceleration from launching
the rocket but also when
landing on sea.
This is where you're going to
be, and this is where you're
actually going to experience
this incredible ride, where
you're going to feel
the rocket lifting
you away from Earth.
And it's going to be so fast.
And eventually, you're
going to see Earth
turning around out here.
And it's just an amazing
feeling, actually, just to
have those thoughts.
When the US, they launched the
first astronaut, Alan Shepard,
the whole countdown actually
stopped because the engineers
suddenly became scared.
They realized they had
a person inside.
And they weren't really prepared
mentally for that.
So the countdown stopped
until Alan Shepard--
he told them "light
the candle"--
his famous words.
-Lift off.
ALAN SHEPARD: All
right, there.
Lift off, and the clock
has started.
KRISTIAN VON BENGTSON: An
organization like this--
I don't know what's going to
happen when everybody had a
part in it, and they suddenly
understand that this--
what they did--
if it doesn't work, it will
have a fatal outcome.
Or maybe it's not going
to be a problem.
Maybe everybody's just going
to find it exhilarating.
PETER MADSEN: It doesn't take
much courage to climb on board
a rocket and have the hatch
sealed and somebody light it,
because it either works
or it doesn't work.
And if it doesn't work, the
period of time you'd have to
realize that is usually
very short.
But it takes a lot
of courage--
it takes an unimaginable
amount of courage--
to be the ground crew, to be the
commanders on the ground,
to make the decision, let's
launch this thing
and see if it works.
And Kristian is one of the few
people that I've ever met who
is courageous enough
to do such a thing.
-T-minus 10, 9, 8, 7,
6, 5, 4, 3, 2, 1.
KRISTIAN VON BENGTSON: Human
space flight has always had
this holy grail kind of
sphere around it.
It's supposed to be expensive.
It's supposed to be
very complex.
So you just completely just
forget the notion or the idea
let's try and build our
own space rocket.
People just don't want
to touch it.
But I hope we can inspire people
that space rocket, you
can actually build
it yourself.
If there should be some kind
of legacy from what we are
doing here on this DIY project,
that should be
showing the world that human
space flight can actually be
done on a completely different
scale, on a completely
different level, with very
simple technology.
You're welcome to come
and join us.
You're also welcome to come here
with a measuring tape and
your camera.
Take all the pictures or
download all of the images and
sketches from our blog and just,
you know, copy the work
or go from there from
what we're doing.
Basically, everybody can do this
if they want to do it.
[MUSIC PLAYING]