the largest amphitheater in the
classical world
stands as a monument to roman
engineering team
but it was much more
a powerful tool
the masses
passionate kiss
perpetrating rooms domination
the brainchild of an upstart
the story of the coliseum secretion
missus bloody and violent as the event
staged with it
beating heart of the roman empire
through stretch from britain in the west
to sit here in the east
making it the most powerful empire in
the kitchen
capital was home to more than a million
people
restless
all the time all
one improvement of the greatest agreeing
that the world
coliseum
interesting stuff blockbuster
entertainment of the day
the coliseum is about more
the activities that the states in the
music
stance
all of this would have guessed literally
blown away
it was the largest freestanding
amphitheater in the world
engineering required to build it was
revolutionary
it took the genius of the roman punch
accused on a colossal scale
trying to build an interesting aspects
of the pyramids renzo nhtsa
the most wonderful building in the
entire world
if timing of the use of building
materials still with us today
would prove the ultimate test of roman
ingenuity
there was no telling whether this
building at that would work as a
building but this is just the supreme
confidence romance
the story of the coliseum is
construction
dates back to two thousand isn't
didi sixty eight
the confirms imprimir
accrual dictator rules romantics empire
against the advice of his innocence
he levies huge tax increases on two nd
citizens
the money goes to build interest in the
heart of room
competes with the forty six in the
hospital or bronze statue
nero himself
heroes cost tax regime
dispute throughout the empire
having today
xbox involved
he calls on the general who was long
becomes a favor
a man who made his name in the
conquistadors
agenda-setting
is the species
miri brings back
displays in
put down the jewish revolt the simple
reason that the spacing isn't arrival
dr ray lawrence from the university of
birmingham in the u_k_
believes the two species was calculated
choice
visa humble person fused
alpha phi effect
therefore he's not seniors potentially
dangerous
disputed marches into tuesday
and built a huge wall around the city of
jerusalem
but one year later
nero has lost his grip on power
knowing the groom's population will back
declares nero and enemy of the state
and face execution
he commits suicide
is in crisis
tree and please come
in a motel blood
the empire desperately needs a strong
and credible lead
powerful engines in peace and decide
that this crazy interest amount for the
job
nicole spreads through rooms provinces
from the danube
ancient syria
and finally reaches this p_c_r_ intraday
p_l_o_ ambition to be emperor
mcnally answers the call
squeezing until smooth
the senate's declares him and
but he was concerned with the hearts and
minds of rooms why it's a small
and live on the handouts across
he decides on the ground crowd-pleasing
gesture
when you're in schools and palace wants
to
he will build a greater powers of the
people
amassing sporting arena football of rome
the symbolism wonder lost on anyone
corey brandon of rutgers university
is convinced that this peace instruments
is known accident
knocked down
team parked out your bill from
self-control is already over golden
house and built this magnificent
amphitheatre
which was meant to be visible from all
across from
none more so than territorial gains
but they played a much more fundamental
and occupy
circuses
has the boom in the city
for keeping the peace
room was one of the largest cities in
the world
more than a million people
filled the streets in ten minutes
from the moment went into sports
efforts to require a stadium out fifty
thousand people
service pays you needed to build the
grandest laboratory we now have a
concealed
warmest disappoint in the very moment it
was designed to appease
will be set out filbert's
certainly he told his builders this has
got to be the biggest the most
magnificent
darius arya a few american institute for
roman culture systems at scale was
foremost in this pc and smiled
contemporary with the construction of
this
effort the air there were all there
ever theaters almost as large certainly
this beijing told his builders
this had to be the biggest
because he wasn't just to the people
it would also help this pcms family the
philippines
launch indeed in the city
decimation abt convinced one of the
family dynastic monument
that was going to uh... really
proclaimed that his family the flavin
dynasty
was here to stay
dampers agenda riskier romaine the
coliseum
disobedient
displease you needed just under two and
a half hectares of middle ground for the
foundations
eastern we live near his golden palace
was no good because it was on the slow
into the south
needs to be great templeton encryption
keys
the only suitable area
the schools have been ornamental link
it looked as if this basins plans were
thwarted
before he had even begun
his solutions characteristically
ambitious
innocent human feelings
i think of the entire
building project on designing it
implement do you have to their race a
structure that was your kids you've got
to drain out the lake directly after
welcome to one side of such a monumental
times
before the season ends engineers can
start building the coliseum
they had to be
limits the size of more than five foot
archaeologists have discovered that the
builders dot the boss trench nearly
fifty meters wide around the lake
sinking into six meters below the next
day
highlighted the trench with stone walls
three meters thick
and fill the space between them
with a waterproof cement
they'd regulate through an existing
channels funneled water into the river
tied
warnaco momentarily
it even once the lake wasn t potential
sentence
they have to find a way to stop
rainwater floating the arena
the solution
likud dreams that would constantly
channel water out of the structure as it
was being built
to ensure inefficient float
the species engineers had to sleep the
trains gradient of two-and-a-half
percent
at the end of the plan is to challenge
wouldn't it doesn't rain away
if it is too great
it backs up
underwater simply put
johnson wasn't genius
the engineers poured water into a groove
wooden boards to make the rudimentary
spirit left
complete correct
perfect horizontal line above ground
peacekeeping mission down
to work at the close of the trains the
loan
drain pipes
swooped at just about ten
species engineers created a system of
drainage channels and the three
kilometers long
which ones water from people
into four massive storm drains the flak
from the center
conduits to collect water arranged all
around the coliseum
water flushed out so quickly
it was pretty eight gallons a second
which is sixty bathtubs full uh... n all
this would have been cially end up
rates or from the clock amok sum up
but the foundations set species could
start building the stadium
he needed to things on a scale never
seen before
and money
extravagance new
bankrupted the and
this pc unspeakable through
dreamed his finances
later peter
consulate in sleeper people
and bring attempt
crashing down
stacie n
is at a crossroads
he desperately needs money to build his
coliseum degrees in texas could turn
altman romance against him
lately for him
is some titles is still besieging
jerusalem
famous
fritz temple treasures
in september eighty seventy
titus assaults the city
after a bitter resistance
much of it is burned to the ground
legendary treasures of the temple on the
amount
carted back to world
inherited money which comes from the
second reason using them
squeeze we care about infestations
triumphant there's course off the coast
of then see if there is wondrous things
like candlesticks enable treasure
the taxes which the jason taking
template now infestation strengths
soldiers marched tens of thousands of
genes back to rumors slayings
there is a popular myth but they were
forced to work on the coliseum
but the truth
is more complex
does not mean likely you just bring over
huge workforce thirty thousand jews to
build the coliseum
that was taking too long or the taking
too long
trained and this is not about on-the-job
training
in the policy is all about being
efficient and fast in getting it done
real values the slaves to the cities you
know
was money
thirty thousand jewish prisoners and to
the world in chains
total public parade
and
they were sold
there was a ready mark
slaves were an integral part of her life
a rich from a montana several hundred
but even the average citizen could
afford a housewife
the race card to nation
what without slates slaves a part of
their lives and it's part of this
five-c_
it's their expectations
if you sell thirty thousand slaves you
get past huge amounts of money would go
away
the labor of the third of the population
of writing for a whole year it is
something which then he can catchy
aunt espy's ian would need has returned
to painting for his coliseum
williams were
constantly will organized
professor michael davis isn't
architectural historian from mount
holyoke college in the united states
he's in and out about the manpower quiet
it's been estimated that
uh... perhaps as many except quarter of
the population of loan
was involved in some ways or other
homes interviews were accomplished
buildings
this would be the greatest challenge
they needed a nafta theater beacon
strong enough to hold over fifty
thousand people
without collapsing under its own weight
the solution late in three ke
architectural innovations that formed
the secrets of rooms great monuments
the most important
is the bachche
he launches an almost perfect designs
daring halos
and that designed so simple
a series of when she blocks is assembled
together in a semi circular forum
and supported on top of tubular spot the
side
the weight of the building is absorbed
by the keystone the center of the march
and distributed evenly over the entire
span of the margin went down into this
tubes side pillars
this allows the pillars to bear enormous
loads
and because displease in between the
killers instantly
this reduces the weight of the building
even further
starts would become hooked
greenstein throughout the building with
the coliseum
eighty gigantic auctions seven meters
high
former judge removed on the perimeter
on top of the secession other eighty
patches on top of the uses of food
making two hundred
forty arches in or
the coliseum really
is nothing
but arches it's symphony
of arches
uh...
the organization required to achieve his
feet of engineering was phenomenal
even here brooms engineers had a trickle
to a determines
building was a business of mass
production
standardization uski efficient building
of the cards
for example the romans used the arch and
artistic p_d_ again to begin weekend by
countless teams
of builders and that kind of
standardization
is very keen to what we have been in
industrialized world today
breaking down of the building allows
them to have lots of workdays
you skills to just disagree with it
in this way
thousands of labor is working on the
policy that could be left to build a
section with minimal supervision
confident in the knowledge that made
this would be repeated pulled over the
structure
it and have a lot of unskilled
levers you could have a lot of prickly
you can have a lot of people
that's have some sort of skill
all but they're not going to be
replied no more than a whole lot
they didn't have a lot but still leaves
people they're going to be carvings
columns people they're going to be
carving the statues that are going to go
and it is in the upper floors
steven have a lot of skill classmate
if they have a lot of unskilled people
participating in this very massive
important instructions
the concept of repetition was at the
heart of the coliseum is design
the architects put to theaters
back-to-back to create one john and
theater in the round war
and if the actual since the greeks
contact
is trying to remember to acquire
encountering
eighteen options
this estee seems engineers planned for
the six concentric rings of options
written into the center of the coliseum
the space between the central beans was
bound together with rough looks a bulk
annexed to fire
versatile building style
peaceful in the case
of the superstructure
but even building with options would
require an enormous amount of stone
more than two hundred thousand tons of
limestone would be used to
policies
subtly
liberty schools particularly brooms
doorstep
macquarie citizens
thirty-five column inches away iliad
natural instincts nervous travertine
which could be cut institute karti
two-room
the material has to be coming in
to the cd cards day in india
rosen rosa parks heart travertine still
many carved by b
hundreds and hundreds of still in part
in fact his estimate of the two hundred
carts making dietrich specific six who
used to transport systems of the site
stone arches made a building with the
coliseum possible
but it was so she chick the building
still face the unthinkable
if it was made entirely understand
mystery seems grand arena could simply
crumbled
under its too late
it
eighty seventy five
the coliseum has been under construction
for five years now the scale of the
project is becoming clear
the buildings and he's convinced me to
finds it together
beaches more tourism tourism controlled
the part of intelligence
grumman continue to solve the problem
mixes
folk access
but the more times down
they called it cooper's sick leave
request
concrete
use completely revolutionized
roman architecture
so what you have to ease this material
that he she feeds you
at parts
or faults
so it's very fluid and contains on
uh... for idea of shapes and this is
what i think again white battle in such
a distinctive quality to roman
architecture
it's main advantage
his versatility
concrete was much stronger than
traditional molter
responses
and waterproof
much liked instead
throughout the rooms to create a
lightweight version of the college
ideal for spamming largest pieces
like those between the crucial
structural beams
concrete was also used to create the
superstructure on which the city was
late
and it allows the seating to be raised
two key optimum angle for the spectators
so minorities sleepers in angola thirty
degrees rising to fifty five degrees
thirteen
that's great
spectators at the back quickly review of
the people
vinod verma
but the seating plan at another time
seating
because see unlike the seeking a
different standard building
inbred world
has a hierarchy of weight you've got it
at the very firm to the stadiums the
podium
web room senators have reserved seats
behind them
on nine terraces of model seats puts it
the equestrian is rooms business class
these aristocrats chose not to into
politics so they could concentrate on
the business of making money
must belong to the families of the
senators in front of him
into tears about sethi ordinary citizens
of road packed together along twenty
miles thirty terrorists
this is that
limits of the space isn't subregional
amphitheater but it sounds out of the
fifteen years working terraces to which
the poorest members of roman society
will relegated
so the coliseum would be much more than
just a sporting arena
it'll be a microcosm
society
as you go up to say
will lie in all of these where do i fit
in
spelled out to a precise position in the
higher
received
right around that into see uh... the
whole populace of rome
city where they were supposed to
but with a build still in its infancy
species as engineers would bristling
with more fundamental boxes
concrete wasn't suitable for every
structural job
they still needed like sweet alternative
that would be a strong stone
what we turn to
so monday
so common to lot everyday lives
renewed on the even notice it
it's a good revolutionize the way the
buildings were made
the romans
invented to read to bring
the romans traditionally used terra
cotta
the red clay found throughout the
mediterranean today
roofing tiles
they started experimenting
ray mysteriously take
details of the bridges
in houston as facing material or
involves in architecture
and this leads the news review
possibilities and ways of building the
haven't existed before
nowhere uses more obvious that the
coliseum
these everywhere
and when combined with concrete
he gave the ever-present uh... chin
which is so important to the coliseum a
whole new lease of life
the romans skillfully combined different
materials
to build structures that were very large
and high
off the ground for at least built
but he's still not arches to support the
weight of the structure above
using the language reveals a brick and
concrete
they've built a second
level of arches about that
and then the third level of arches about
that
they could plant your point era arches
to build structures that were higher n
lighter than any that have been built
before
but building a types of up to fifty
meters had created yet another child
new cream existed that could lift
building materials so high
the whole she go to the construction the
coliseum
uh... resides in the fact that we have
before main stories we can see right
over here that we have the first story
with a series of arches
than we have the people standing robert
second-story and it didn't work out for
and that's where you put it you're
praying to get more building material
and working on that level
building up the next week
to move all this material groomsmen
peter cantik cranes operated by large
trade
he seems to clean genius block and
tackle system
depicted in accounting for the time
too pleased to have you got
onto the platform
and summed up by forwarding the same
thing you're pushing at the cranes are
putting up a building materials and
working on that very clear
finally you're able to work on the top
floor
at that point they getting
quite high yes
there are more than a million breaks in
the coliseum
to keep the project on the track
the romans needed to produce bricks and
a terrific right
the solution is something we can will
recognize today
governments purchased at bricks in
factories all over the city
he's recalled fabricate
two thousand years before henry ford
improvements they devised the production
the building of the coliseum round like
of well loyalty mission
so you can imagine that
as this goes up units stories you've got
things are still going on in the lower
floors like decoration on the vaults the
painting in the stock going into self
this is going on for you here's in years
and years
given
coliseum project would consume the whole
of room for more than a decade
and ultimately outlived its creator
in eighty seventy nine improve the
spacing
the man whose vision that made between
the reality
dies
as room mourns the loss of its popular
and
is some titus takes the throne
he decrees that his father's great
amphitheater will
the new emperor
has just said his workers
the builders of the coliseum and they
seem to compute the stadium in time for
its king local games
they have only partially succeeded
as the students to learn from the time
shes
it's still missing sometimes for
true to role in tradition
this building probably wasn't even told
we can't just so you have many
inaugurations many dates in which the
people show up and you still have a
staffing up by the staffing behind
exp teaching team
first still
now brooms coliseum opens for business
must have been locked spectator
really got everyone's attention
was the scale
gleaming white
no one's been here before your
inaugurates place
all of this would an incredible
spectacle
every sports fan in room is clamoring to
see the including sc
tens of thousands of people
crowd outside the stadium
newspeople safely and quickly to the
seeds
will be a mammoth task
the coliseum still does
of cracks the proper
on the northwestern corner
there five bwz embedded into the
pavement
all that remains of distinctions crowd
control system
this is to keep people back
prior to entry this is where you could
check the people going aight
it what people think so they can't be
directed
towards the right numbered gateway
didn't feel coliseum itself
just like a modern spectator today
every room in the coming to the games
was issued a ticket
deficit to them
that's about one of the total which of
the seventy-six stadium entrances to use
you can still see many of the intrigued
and discarded into the stand above the
entrances today
they have used a crafty trick
up the excitement
i think that the seating was
deliberately restricted it was a tough
ticket to get
and opt for a specially for the big
games
these tensions
is dedicated to a certain sectors of the
society
the more important to her
these here it was to get a seat
entered through a richly decorated came
to the south side
which was later replaced by an
underground passageway direct to his
house
the grand entrance opposite allowed
rooms official magistrates to walk
straight to bed bugs
right next to the arena
this entrance was shared by the senators
over the next step down in the pecking
people sit in georgia ringside
in each culture of the stadium three
gates who is a
further questions
and in a corridor commercial flight of
stairs bullpen out into their seats
ordinary citizens of rome had to let
them pass before it using the remaining
fourteen gates to spiral up several
flights of stairs onto the terraces
just stoked up
thirteen eight steps to get to the
wooden benches
so if your plan
and upload without money keeping or even
a slave on the day off you're going up
to the newest but since there are no
elevators you could have the pulpit all
the way up there
in your view that can be a good deal
this extremely efficient system
maintained a constant flow of people
eliminated choke points as much as
possible
it's been estimated that
the fifteen fifty five thousand people
that would feel the coliseum uh... could
exit within half an hour that kind opt
for active called efficient planning
hasn't been surpassed today and in many
ways still provides a kind of model
uh... four uh... modern steel design
listen sign consent
but when it was first okay
onto the computer
court economists
besides and hans the since the practice
constraints
and the stadium corridors winter storm
in the spring
everywhere he went to pick a random
approves this whole thing selling every
kind of merchandise civilians fast food
sex you name it
they've got it because several for
was the gladiators
justice with boldness for stocks
there is merchandising all of packet we
find gladiators appearing on raymond
land speed fine
gladiators born strom speak freind
literally soldier like traci exits for
aids
and these are extremely popular that's a
great souvenirs
and you think that when these people
were the superstars update date
they're being in recognized
fourteen so many ways including
emergence
now for the first time
the spectators steps out
into the stadium
i was hit
by a wall of sound
the super dome
dominates the romans skyline
encompassed resumes vision has become
the most spectacular amphitheater vote
world has
upwards of fifty thousand
crowded constancy
according to one side
appt eighty seven thousand might
compacting
that's more than most super jones today
modern sports stadium or allot less
claustrophobic
contributing
roman coliseum
very little seed space for forty two
percent
they work past
quite literally cheek by job
and it could get unbearably hot on the
terraces during summer months
up to forty degrees celsius
top malval's uh... unhappy mob
and unhappy malts are prone to buy a
house
into the stadium writing
practitioner
in presenting his would have to come up
with the way if she didn't produce from
the side
the top corner of the pump a picture
shoes the ingenious solutions to clients
kansas could
colder than a week
coliseum
selenium suspended for two hundred and
fourteen miles set in brackets all
around the top of the stadium
no one knows quite how it goes
but if the campaign finance typical
it was suspended from kl
openssl groups
held together by broke in the center
which wonderful through which the son
sean on the arena
the whole system was operated by a
thousand sailors trusted in from the
roman feats of missing
no one would see it
intractable conflict this again for two
thousand
but nobody had come here tomography
which is the first day of the local
gains of the coliseum is packed with
excited spectators
waiting for one thing
spacings amphitheater is about to be
kristin
time of the gladiators
has arrived
eighteen peter
one-year after titus has become
since the coliseum
profibus pays him
texas is simply inherited
decreases sectors
some spectacular
i think this was a sweet marshall
captures the excitement of the occasion
priestesses cirrus clouds
from london pops tune
both for tonight composer like gave
strife uske quantified
inauguration
of the policy in ways
unbelievable without parents
because you had one hundred
the straits
in one single boats etc
five thousand animals were slaughtered
hundreds of defenseless criminals put to
death
this was just because that's what i said
to the main feature
fights for the death between hundreds of
gladiators armed two teeth
to modernize its a bloodthirsty
spectacle
to the goldmans
it was top quality entertainment
the inaugural games reached new heights
of extravagance
some salsa suggested the tightest even
have the coliseum flooded
distinction even talking
evidence for it
is i witness accounts
they're written down in the book missus
marshall
he's describing these things and for a
long time people didn't believe the
actually happens
but we know they did and there's also
the events but the train system in
hydraulic system
the coliseum street each network
designed to add to the old lake
could have been refers to flow into the
arena
but the theory remains controversial
to achieve water deepened
that meant waterproofing a huge area
the skeptics point out the clue evidence
waterproofing
what is uh...
is that once the coliseum was an
established venue
dermatitis at the grand spectacles grew
but grew
the task of keeping rooms crimes happen
and easy to government required constant
innovation
five years after the coliseum
was completely remodeled by this pc in
seconds and the mission
to create an underground complex on a
scale never seen before
was that the g_m_
the subterranean mavericks worked as a
backstage area
allowing the kids to be mounted a good
even grander scale
as the crown st front lines
hundreds of gladiators hurry to take
that position
palmer's prepared weapon
prop masters moved scenery
derina slaves went about the thousands
of times since the campus of moving
got sick sensabaugh
peace and so-called arena in latin which
is where we get the name arena from
and it's not just gladiators who inhabit
is twenty twenty one
it's also home to thousands of exotic
animals imported from went into the
empire
to be killed for sport
these fights for intents and you do have
these animals are killed at lot but you
have that
these massive the base the addy people
trained to fight and kill white adults
they show up in here they have to fight
they're expected to fights they could
just go on in gates the end
but the beast rights
said to function beyond sheer
entertainment
denied traction seems to have been
animals from far-flung locales brought
into wrong and it really was an
expression of imperial greatness that
you could see nubian hippopotamus
african elephants and austrians and
characters from the rahman east
brought together
roman arena
most of the animals will captains to
depends in the basement
and were transported up to the arena
using an ingenious political system
beast hunts hooded animals intelligence
posted along this week or two
reprinted in conan
between the two nd public anger drew
trying to work
and into the arena
but that wasn't me
in the remains of liberty and you can
still see dozens of elevator shafts
separated by options
peace between wooden platforms operated
by winches
because if both animals and gladiators
the system held more than sixty truck
tools
thirteen elevators
now man and animals could emerge
you know when they're going to come
how many reddit com how frequently going
to come out that's part of the
experience that you don't have a hit
with jane and you don't really have a
policy
it wasn't designed to spice up the main
event
dr utah real combat
it's not hard to understand the appeal
of the gladiators
termed editorial resident
aerobic confrontation
but for the romans
these fights to the death went deeper
the new competition
remains strategist for instance and
that's the friction the
all names by their friends and amaze or
mistletoe characters
system gladiators were dressed and arms
interest and it means to be here
epic battles
others
accident with the logical stories
puzzle designed to make the romans feel
good about their appearance status
as a heavily-armed sweets
an option
it's helmets represents the sea
creatures
was breaking pitted against the retail
areas was arms like a fisherman the
trident
protesting the spot every morning asking
for transmittal
as another old enemy as well
uniform in the side of the report
across the sea
the symbolism of others like the fear
it's acutally
has been lost at the time
seems the most heavily armed at the mall
to compensate his helmet a
specially-designed to limit his vision
each of these types of static in
specific opponents this guaranty
discipline
dot peterson at fishing stuff
contends criminal
were granted that freedom
after a successful career
despite this latest status
they were the superstar celebrities
affecting
ingratiating found a campaign
fans recorded that he was victories just
like a football fan mike today
behind it doesn't know it
he says he simply
dental removal to put it into the same
way too
many people are personal to perform
movies today it's something brain julie
what chain that clearly
keep going uh... coliseum tuzi mail to
diffuse the hundreds of years
and this is this is what they do
became squirm integral part of the
society
dispense justice
cemented the social structure
reaffirmed rooms mastery of the world
it was just a great day now
knowingly and when you go to a sporting
event today you're you know you go to a
movie theater you want to be entertained
any new ultimatum seem to be policy
for the several hundred years which was
in use
but you truly were in it
the coliseum remains one of the grandest
in the spectacular engineering
achievements have been inching toward
would become the group reads the stadium
not just throughout the roman empire
throughout history
in fact many would argue it's basic
design has never been better
it's a surprise to more than two
thousand years to stand as a magnificent
testaments to the end
and ingenuity