It was an incredible thing to see.
We are going to tell you how it all turned out.
I`m Carl Azuz.
Welcome to a new week of CNN STUDENT NEWS.
Last week we reported on Malala Yousafzai.
She`s a blogger and an activist for education
and women`s rights. She`s 14 years old. Last
Tuesday, Malala was targeted and shot by the
Taliban. That`s a militant group that has
a strong presence in the part of Pakistan
where Malala lives. Lot of her country has
rallied behind her. Thousands of people turning
out to be part of a demonstration in the city
of Karachi this weekend. They were showing
their support for Malala and speaking out
against the Taliban and its strict policies.
Those include denying girls the chance to
get an education, and that`s something that
Malala spoke out against. Pakistani officials
say doctors are keeping a close watch on Malala.
As of yesterday afternoon, she was unconscious
and using a breathing machine, but authorities
said she is making slow and steady progress.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
See if you can I.D. me.
I am an organization that was established
after World War II. I currently have 27 member
countries. A continent is a part of my name,
and my currency is the Euro.
I`m the European Union. And I`m responsible
for my members` economic, social and security policies
(END VIDEO CLIP)
The Nobel Committee says the European
Union`s efforts to advance peace, democracy
and human rights are why that organization,
the European Union is this year`s winner of
the Nobel Peace Prize. The award was announced
last Friday. It`s not the first time that
an organization has won the Peace Prize instead
of an individual person. The committee says
the E.U.`s win is a message to the whole world
about finding ways to solve conflicts.
For more, we turn to Jonathan Mann.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
Look past all the protests
in the streets of Spain and Greece.
Look past all the high level talks
and tangled finances. Look back to the centuries
of war in Europe, a place where nowadays dozens
of countries are so completely at peace that
virtually no one notices. The Norwegian Nobel
Committee awarded the Peace Prize for 2012
to the European Union. Because born out of
the ashes of World War II as a way to unify
the continent and keep it from fighting again,
the Nobel Committee says the European Union has worked.
THORBJORN JAGLAND, CHAIR OF THE NORWEGIAN
NOBEL COMMITTEE: Over a 70 year period, Germany
and France had fought three wars. Today, war
between Germany and France had -- is unthinkable.
This shows of true well aimed efforts and
while building mutual confidence,
historic enemies can become close parties.
The partnership now includes 27 nations,
with more waiting to join. 500 million people
grappling with their own national politics
evolving European institutions, and its still
experimental common currency mired in crisis.
Everything from interest rates to austerity
measures and unemployment eventually leads
back to the E.U. In the streets of Spain,
where the economy went from boom to bust,
the E.U. is both credited and criticized,
and its Nobel Prize got a mixed reaction.
All right. We are wrapping up out Hispanic
heritage month coverage today with a tasty
segment for you. Here is some food for thought:
did you know the names of some of the things
we eat and drink have Spanish ties. Like the
chocolate in my hot chocolate. It`s pronounced
chocolate, the word comes from Nahuatl,, which
is a group of languages from parts of Mexico
and Central America. Another tasty word with
Spanish routs is tomato, the name of this fruit
yes, this is technically a fruit, comes
from Nahuatl, too. In Spanish, it`s tomate.
We can`t give you fruit and dessert without
a main course. Tuna, like the fish, comes
from the Spanish word, atun.
I think it`s a pretty amazing event,
that`s why I`m here with my daughter,
to make sure that she sees it
and is a part of it.
Also, once in a lifetime thing to see a special,
all going down the street,
especially at the streets of L.A.,
so I had to see it.
You heard it right, and it was a sight
to see. A space shuttle rolling down the streets
of Los Angeles, not part of a movie, it`s
the final act for NASA`s shuttle program.
That is Endeavour. It flew 123 million miles
in space cruising along at supersonic speed.
This weekend, it was crawling, just crawling
along the roads of California. It`s not because
of traffic. Endeavour had the streets to itself,
as it`s slowly made its way to the California
Science Center where it`s going on display.
It turns out, this last journey had some holdups.
Streets, no surprise aren`t designed for shuttles
that are nearly 80 feet wide and more than
120 feet long. So some road signs had to be
taken down, some trees, some of them very
old, had to be cut down. But officials said
aside from that, there were no reports of
damage to or by the shuttle.
This was more like a space dive than a sky
dive. Yesterday afternoon, Felix Baumgartner
was trying to set the record for the highest
jump, from 120,000 feet above the Earth. Not
exactly, how it went down. He stepped out
from his capsule at 128,000 feet. That is
more than 24 miles up. Scientists say, he
broke the speed of sound as he hurdled toward
earth. You can imagine what that must have
felt like. It took ten minutes for the 43-year
old Austrian daredevil known as Fearless Felix
to be back on solid ground. Max Foster spoke
to him before his record shattering skydive.
What no man has ever done before: jump from a capsule
attached to a giant balloon from 120,000 feet
where the view looks like this.
I`m going to slide the door open, bail out
and then going to be the first human person
in freefall, who`s breaking the speed of sound.
FOSTER: He makes it sound simple enough, but
Felix Baumgartner`s attempt to jump from the
edge of space comes after five years of exhaustive
testing, development and even a legal hatch.
What`s the biggest challenge here,
why have - has no one tried it before
and what`s the challenge that you`ve managed
to overcome to make it possible?
It needs a lot of research,
it`s not just you lock yourself in a pressure capsule
and you go up, you need a lot of research.
You need to find the right people to work with.
Explain a bit more about the suit, how it works,
and what sort of technology is in there.
So the suit is protecting you.
It provides you with oxygen, it keeps temperature,
the cold temperature out. It also -- you also
need the pressure suit, because if you reach
65,000 feet, which is called the Armstrong
Line, your blood starts boiling. And that
suit keeps you alive.
It`s beautiful, beautiful, beautiful.
Baumgartner is no stranger to death-defying
stunts. He has based- jumped from the world`s tallest buildings,
set a record for the lowest such jump of
Rio`s Christ the Redeemer statue
and completed the first crossing of the English
Channel with a specially made fiber wing.
But freefalling from the edge of space is
a whole new ball game.
The big problem that we faced
here, is at 120,000 feet you have no supportive air.
So the first 30 seconds, you cannot use
the air, and that requires a really stable
exit, that`s the reason why we
practiced a lot of bungee jumps.
Perfect.
You had a chance to meet Neil Armstrong.
I just wanted to ask you about
it, in 2010, didn`t you?
So, what advice did he give you?
Well, he said, go for it, you`ve
got the right team behind you, you are prepared,
you have the skills, so he definitely thinks
it`s possible.
Halloween still a couple of weeks away,
but we are giving you a spooky showcase for
your creative pumpkin projects right now.
We are talking about Halloween I-reports.
You`ve got to be at least 13, send us your
best by October, 26th, and your pumpkin, which
doesn`t have to have my face on it, could
pop up on cnn/studentnews. Boo-ya!
Before we go, maybe you don`t agree with one
contestant in this cook-off, who said it`s
what nature intended for people to eat. But
if you are looking to make your taste buds
really jump, you might go nuts for squirrel,
and not just run off the fence grilled squirrel.
We are talking about jalapeno squirrel poppers.
Squirrel burgers and sliders, bacon wraps
squirrel wings, not sure how they pulled off
that last recipe, since squirrels don`t have
wings, but there is no way we are going to
squirrel out of having a little pun with this.
Of course, it might sound a little nutty,
some of you think all of our pans are acorny,
but we always hop at the chance to put them
to the nest, and frankly, I see nutting wrong
with that. Thanks to our Facebook and Twitter
followers for helping out with those,
CNN STUDENT NEWS, we`ll tree you tomorrow.