You've got to smuggle
it wherever you go.
I'd be shaving and looking
at myself in the mirror.
Then, I could see who's
coming or who's going.
When they come and search
your cell, they
hit yourself so hard.
And they like to break things
and take things.
So this mirror has made it with
me most of the time--
more than half of
my way in there.
STEVEN CALES: Skating is
Peter Smolik said--
there's no coaches.
You're your own boss.
So there's really no structure
is the right word-- to be
like, hey, you've
got to get up.
You've got to do this.
And we do what we want.
So you've got to live
and learn, you
know what I'm saying?
FABIAN ALOMAR: How we even got
into skating was crazy.
I stole my first board.
I didn't even know
about skating.
I see two oriental kids on the
block when we were on bikes.
And we went and told them that
we could borrow their
skateboards, because they seen
them hopping on the board.
I hit them up, like
how much are they?
How much are these boards?
And they told us this price, and
it was $49.50 at the time.
$49.50 is a lot of money
for my mom and dad.
So where do we go?
We went out towards Beverly
Hills, Eagle Rock, Glendale
looking around.
And I hate to say it, but we
were looking around for little
white boys to rob them.
JOEY SURIEL: I had seen him
skate a few times when he
would come riding around with
our other friend, Juan.
And I knew these guys were
on top of their game.
They were the best I had seen,
so I said, OK, there are the
guys I need to be around.
I wanted to be around
the best.
And I knew that being around
Fabian was going to help me.
FABIAN ALOMAR: Back in the day,
back in '87, '88, we used
to go to this ramp on 23rd
and Vermont near USC.
And to get there, you've got to
pass through at least three
or four different gang
neighborhoods.
-At least, at least.
FABIAN ALOMAR: So to get
there and to come
back home was a mission.
-I lived in a gang
neighborhood.
FABIAN ALOMAR: Rockwood.
-And I guess a rival gang had
come looking to shoot up, and
they actually caught us
right when Fabian
was about to leave.
And I was like, all right,
man, I'll see you later.
FABIAN ALOMAR: It was a burgundy
Regal with a sun
roof.
-And then soon as I look, I was
like, yo, these guys are
cruising by real slow.
FABIAN ALOMAR: It
was like this.
-All of a sudden, bro, all I
remember was some dude coming
out of the roof-- yo,
the first time
I've see a real Uzi.
I remember when you are in here,
it was like you in a
different world.
You forget that you
were in the hood.
You forget.
There'd be I don't even know
how many shootouts
we've see back then.
-You think it's a
nicer area now?
FABIAN ALOMAR: Now,
it's way nicer.
Echo Park all the way up to
here at Silver Lake, as of
2002 or 2003, it
really changed.
You see a lot more artsy people
living in Echo Park
running around now.
Back then--
I grew up, born and
raised there--
and you would never seen that.
Yeah, all right in this area
right here there's Crazies,
Echo Park, Headhunters
and Diamond.
We're on Douglas Street.
If you go two blocks
up and to the left,
that's Diamond's street.
This is Headhunters.
-So why is that?
Why don't--
FABIAN ALOMAR: It's
just who it is.
A group of kids that grew up on
this block didn't get along
with the group of kids that
are on that block.
And that's how it started.
Back in the '80s.
And there's always been 18th
Street lurking around.
Our whole family was
raised right here.
We lived here.
My mom, she was raised
right here, too.
-In this house.
FABIAN ALOMAR: In this
house, yeah.
If you're talking about gang
area, this is Headhunters.
-This is where you
started skating?
FABIAN ALOMAR: No,
I was too small.
Right here was just me
growing up, learning
how to ride a bike.
-Those are bullet holes.
FABIAN ALOMAR: Yeah.
Look, you can see.
Those are bullet holes
right there.
If these streets could talk,
they'd have a better story to
tell you than what I could--
a way better story.
Like I said, a lot of my friends
in skateboarding used
to really trip out on how they
would see my dad or my uncles,
my sisters, everybody
in my family, were
considered gang members.
And you're guilty by
association, regardless.
A lot of the times, they
wouldn't even want to drop me
off at home.
Like I said, they would--
two blocks away and let
me walk the rest.
GINO IANNUCCI: Well, I remember
meeting Fabian.
And the first impression was
that he was a nice guy.
He was really cool.
He was just down to
introduce himself.
And he was just a good guy.
But I knew that he was real.
I knew that if a time came when
he had to throw down or
anything like that, I wouldn't
want to fuck with him.
And I knew that his family was
all up in it and skateboarding
kept him away from that.
-Were you in a gang or
anything like that?
Or just joined what
they were doing?
FABIAN ALOMAR: Yeah, I did.
But I never got too
deep into it.
I knew it was always there,
because I was
born into it, man.
There's no oh, I want to go
hang out with these guys.
I'd go home and I'd
be with them guys,
you know what I mean?
It's a difference when you've
got to go somewhere and be
with your home boys
or your gang.
But when you go home and
you live with it,
it's nothing to you.
It's just how you are.
-Who would you say, out of the
Menace guys was the most
motivated to get tricks?
SOCRATES LEAL: Probably
Joey and Fabian.
Those guys were always
motivated.
Fabian would call me.
You want to go film?
Like, yeah.
-Were there, though, a lot of
other crazy stories, filming
with Fabian?
SOCRATES LEAL: I wouldn't say
just crazy, just maybe not
normal for regular skaters.
But Fabian wasn't like
your regular skater.
He just didn't take bullshit.
JOEY SURIEL: Since we were
kids, Fabian always had a
short fuse.
Not to mention everything was
put on a platter for us, from
women to drugs to fame.
So you add that to the formula,
and it's a recipe for
destruction.
FABIAN ALOMAR: Skateboarding
saved me from getting into
trouble, but at the same time,
I think I had a lot of time
and money in my hands.
From not having nothing to have
a little something, it
felt pretty good.
And sometimes you think
you're invincible.
Oh, man, you know what?
I've got to take you
to this house.
It was a drug house.
Instead of having
a big pitbull, I
was their guard dog.
They know that I used to
skateboard and everything.
They trusted me.
When my money was good,
they loved me.
You know what I mean?
When the money was good, I had
all kinds of money to buy dope
from them and to give them
skateboards when they need it
for their kids or whatever.
And then when my money
ran out, guess what?
They didn't like me no more.
FABIAN ALOMAR: I was selling
and doing, mostly doing.
But one thing I did and I'm
thankful for is I separated
the gang life and my drug use
and my skateboarding--
for a lot of reasons, mainly
because I was embarrassed and
I didn't want to show my face.
And I was looked at as Fabian
Alomar, pro skater.
He's a good skater.
A real ghetto kid,
real coming up.
And I didn't want
to ruin that.
That image I had was good,
because I kept skating and I
produced and I did everything
I was supposed to do.
But I felt this weird
feeling inside.
I couldn't come around.
I didn't want to burn
no bridges.
I couldn't burn my bridges
with skateboarding.
I wanted to keep it separate.
So I stood in the hood.
I stood around in the spots
where no one will come.
JAVIER NUNEZ: He grew up in the
streets, so it was tough
to make a transition to being
a full on skate and shit.
You skate and then you go back
to the hood, and then you're
dealing with all these
obstacles.
It's not like we're going back
to the suburbs and it's all
good and we can skate
every day.
It wasn't like.
And it caught up to them.
Fabian got locked up.
That's when [INAUDIBLE]
was like, you know?
I got to think about making it
a real skate company, not
about an image thing.
FABIAN ALOMAR: There were so
many things going on in my
life at the time that it
was bound to happen.
I showed up to Karim's house to
pick up my check one day.
And he's telling me, you know
this is probably one of your
last checks right here.
This is it.
I've cut you so low that I can't
be-- and now, I don't
see you doing anything.
And I'm telling them--
and it's true-- my ankle
was swollen, but
from skating on dope.
Once I got kicked off, things
took a whole other turn.
See where that bungalow is?
-Yeah.
FABIAN ALOMAR: That fence where
the diamond is, the
baseball diamond?
There's bathrooms right there.
You see?
There they are.
The white bathrooms?
Those were my offices,
my [SPANISH].
Anybody who when in there
got fucked up while
I was smoking crack.
These dudes playing tennis,
these little Filipino dudes
and shit-- they all all go in
there in the morning and
they're like, (ACCENT) hey, it's
7 o'clock in the morning.
Let's go play some tennis.
And they go in there and they
want to play tennis and they
want-- (ACCENT) hey, why is the
bathroom locked and shit?
I could hear them talking.
And they would try to force it
open, because I'd locked it on
purpose because I'm in there
smoking dope looking at nudie
magazines and shit.
And that's what I did.
I'd do me and do me.
So I'm in there fucking
doing my thing.
Wait, that's my church.
So I'm getting loaded in there,
and they're fucking up
my high by trying to get
into my offices.
And I'd be like, man,
what the fuck?
So when they come in, all
they did was get robbed.
I'd fuck them up and then
I'd end up leaving.
I would say a prayer before
I go rob you.
God, please don't let
me get caught.
Don't let me get hurt.
I'm sorry for what
I'm about to do.
I know it's wrong, but I feel
like I have no choice.
And so I would go and rob this
person and jack them.
And I'd let them know, hey,
straight up, I'm on dope.
I'm smoking crack.
You'd better give me all
your money or you're
going to get hurt.
And if you don't give it up,
believe me, I'm going to cut
you or I'm going to shoot you.
So you're bound to give it up
either way, whether you want
to walk away or me drive away
with you laying there.
So most of the time, they
would cooperate.
And I was driving people
right outside my door.
When you're on cocaine, that
stuff really plays a number on
your head, you know
what I mean?
So I would do it
at all times--
in the evening.
If I catch you slipping,
I would get you
and rob you, whatever.
That was my mentality.
Come here, puppy.
Look at these dogs, man.
They've probably been so abused
that they don't trust
nobody, dude.
Look, there he comes.
Get it.
I'm not proud of it, man.
I'm not boasting about it.
I'm not trying to put any light
on it in a positive way.
It's a negative thing
I was doing.
It was bad.
But at that point my life,
I didn't care.
I didn't care about nothing.
I didn't even care about myself,
so why would I care
about somebody else?
BILLY VALDES: I think with
Fabian, too, that might have
been a consequence of adjusting
after skateboarding.
The last time I seen Fabian,
I was hungover living in
Hollywood, and he came over
the next morning.
And I hadn't seen him
in a long time.
And he wanted to sell me a
pitbull puppy, because he
knows I'm into dogs,
or some sodas--
cases of sodas.
And he with some dude
in a random band.
So it was a trip for me.
FABIAN ALOMAR: You want to ride
down the alley where I
got arrested for my crime?
This is where I got arrested.
They cornered me in here.
There was five cop cars
here and a helicopter.
And they caught me right in
this alley right here.
They surrounded me.
I was busted right here.
They told me, get out the car.
They were behind me, in front
of me, and I was just trying
to make it to my--
my mom lived two houses away
from the dope spot where we
were just that.
And I was trying to make it to
my mom's, because I knew these
cops were probably going
to beat my ass.
That was it right there.
I got locked up.
I was done.
I went to prison for
eight years.
I got arrested for carjacking,
kidnapping, robbery, with an
11 inch ice pick.
The ice pick had someone's DNA,
and it had crack residue,
because I was using that same
weapon that I used to
whatever, stab, and I was
using it to smoke.
And that's why I had it.
They sent me to Salinas
Valley, level four.
I was in the 270 yard there.
And it's nothing but
solid lifers.
People got life.
People were just straight
killers and drug dealers and
nothing bad at all.
You notice nobody smiles
in prison.
So you don't get those smiles.
-You show up the
first day and--
FABIAN ALOMAR: You show
up, you're new fish.
You're in prison.
You're sketchy on everything.
FABIAN ALOMAR: That's
a good question.
If you were raised here and
brought up here and you've got
that the southern Hispanic ways,
then you're considered
South sider.
You're a homie automatically,
and don't try to get out of it
and don't try to fight it,
because a lot of dudes try to
deny just to get away
and try to hide.
But if you're actually a Puerto
Rican native and come
over here and you don't know
what the hell's going on, then
they'll give you a pass and
you could be an other.
You could be an other.
Other is--
you could be Samoan, Chinese,
you could be whatever.
Others is anything.
It's a mix.
All the southern Mexicans-- we
all stick together, man.
I got sent to this other
person called
California Men's Colony.
It's no good, meaning no good as
far as they hold snitches,
rapists, child molesters.
All of my friends told me,
hey, man, you know where
you're going.
You're going to have to get off
there and do your thing.
You've got 72 hours to
handle your business.
That means I have 72 hours to
crack someone, stab them, beat
them up, or whatever
I'm going to do.
FABIAN ALOMAR: I was mingling
and chopping it up and eating
and hanging out with
a bunch of rapists.
And I didn't do nothing.
Nobody likes their kids
being touched by
another human being--
man or woman.
So all these people deserved
to get cut, and I
cut a couple of them.
FABIAN ALOMAR: Yeah,
a child molester.
I hit him with a razor.
They brought me the paperwork,
and I seen it.
I knew the next day what
I had to do, which
was Christmas Eve.
I got added more time to me.
FABIAN ALOMAR: Yeah, he
survived, unfortunately.
He survived.
-Well, but if he had died, you
would have been still in here.
FABIAN ALOMAR: Oh, I would still
be-- there wouldn't be a
story right now.
There wouldn't be a good happy
ending to this story.
FABIAN ALOMAR: Oh, yeah.
Yeah, I only told a few.
I only told a couple.
I would get pictures sent to
me from the internet--
pictures of me skating
and stuff.
And I told a couple
of my cellies.
And they were like,
wow, that's you?
Inside there, I used to make a
little full on skate park.
I would get sent cards, or I'd
use old cards that my friends
were trashing.
They were going to discard
and get rid of stuff.
So I'd set up and tape and use
Koolaid for glue, and I'd get
pieces of tape that come in
letters, and I'd make a skate
park-- like a ramp to
wall, pyramid ramp.
I put together a little
mini ramp.
The boards were hard to make.
I used to pretend just
with my hands,
just with my two fingers.
It was always when I
go to sleep and lay
down and knock out.
I had so many crazy thoughts
of different things-- like
man, what if I would
have done this?
Where would I be if I just
continued skating and not got
caught up in all this drugs and
all this crazy violence
that I did?
And I should've just stood
hanging out with this person,
or I should have just continued
to skate and not--
why did I-- you know?
All the whys and what ifs.
You've just got to keep
going forward, dog.
All those questions--
if you could drive yourself
mad with that.
The very same night I
got out, I went to
Skatelab in Simi Valley.
FABIAN ALOMAR: I went there just
to go, because when it
first opened, I had
a board up there.
I wanted to see if it was still
there or if they kicked
it out or what.
And it was there.
I called up Jeron Wilson
and we talked.
He was like, damn, good
to hear from you.
I'm here.
I'm here skating with
Guy and Costin.
And I was like, what?
Let me talk to Guy.
Guy was like, dude, I'm going
to go get you and
pick you up, man.
Where you at?
So he came.
He picked me up.
And we hung out.
We used to always hang out.
That's my best friend
right there.
That's my boy.
Once he scooped me up, I
embedded the idea of me
skating again.
And so he started taking
me around with him.
And yeah, if anybody got
me back into it, I
could say Guy did--
back into the scene period And
I'm going to be honest with
you, I didn't think
skateboarding was going to
accept back again or have love
for me because of what I did.
I got this board out SK8MAFIA.
I'm about to put this shit
together tomorrow.
STEVEN CALES: You've got to take
advantage of the things
that skateboarding gives you.
If you're getting paid and it's
paying your bills and you
ain't got to work, then, man,
give skateboarding 115%.
Just stick to skating, you
know what I'm saying?
And stay out of jail.
Stay free.
Stay off of drugs.
I did 32 months that one time,
and then I got out.
20 days later, I
did 24 months.
And then I had done 20 months.
And then I had done a year.
And then I had done six months,
which got broken down,
so I did four months out
of that six months.
Altogether, I say I did
about probably a cool
nine years in jail.
STEVEN CALES: Oh, yeah.
Yeah.
The freedom is so much better,
breathing fresh air.
Fresh air to me is the city
buses, dirt, you know?
Not in the mountains
somewhere.
That's fresh air, but still, out
here, it's so much better.
It's better.
-This is your fresh air.
STEVEN CALES: Yeah,
it's my fresh air.
No matter how much money you
ain't got or how much money
you got, freedom is
the best, man.
Nothing is more better.
It's priceless.
Fabian is doing good, man.
I'm proud of him.
He's doing good.
I'm not going to say he picked
up where he left off, but he's
doing better than when he
left off, even when
he was doing good.
He's doing good.
He's doing really good right
now, and I'm proud of him.
FABIAN ALOMAR: I like
the struggle.
It makes you want
to go for more.
This acting--
it's making me some money.
FABIAN ALOMAR: I'm working
with a few, man,
like Mos Def on Dexter.
-You were on Dexter?
FABIAN ALOMAR: Yeah.
It's not something that I
can say I'm getting rich
right now from it.
But I can see the yellow
brick road.
I'm following it, you
know what I mean?
And as long as I say on
this road, I'll be OK.
FABIAN ALOMAR: You know
what I do miss?
I miss the good people that
I left behind in there.
I left a lot of good people--
good, solid people that should
have had another chance.
They deserve one more chance.
But no, I don't miss
the place at all.
Hell no.