it's what keeps us from falling off the earth,
it's what keeps the earth in orbit around
the sun, and it's what caused the sun itself
to form four and a half billion years ago!
It's amazing to think that every massive object
attracts every other in the universe –
that means that your dog, the earth,
and a black hole in the Andromeda galaxy 2.5
million light years away
are all gravitationally attracted to you,
and you to them.
In the 17th century, Isaac Newton discovered
that the strength of the gravitational force
decreases by the square of the distance between
two objects – so if you're twice as far
away, gravity is only one fourth as strong!
He also discovered that the strength of gravity
is proportional to the mass of the objects
in question: the more massive an object, the
stronger the gravitational force. That's why
we can all feel the Earth pulling on us, but
don't really notice the pull of the moon – it's
smaller, and farther away! (the moon's gravity
is strong enough to cause the tides, though!)
And when I said earlier that gravity is an
attraction between objects with mass, I lied.
I meant objects with Energy. Because in addition
to massive objects, gravity also attracts
light and other massless (but energetic) particles,
so that a photon of light can be bent slightly
passing the sun, or trapped completely by
a black hole.
Now do you understand the Gravity of the situation?