voted the worst company in america had
no part of the reason why this happened
is because i'd be screwed up the release
of uh... sim city
and a lot of people are upset because i
uh... servers are crashing and play it
players weren't able to even access the
gamecube orchard get to the microphone
because i'm asking her questions back in
march of course is our high you donor
dillard host issue knows a lot about
electronics and about video games soak
and why were people so upset about sim
city what was the dramas behind that
location where
uh... and hasn't always on the air and
mandatory which means you have to be
online connected online to play the game
about even if you're playing
single-player with no
connected it to anyone at all and the
palette that was everyone to play for
the service dot clock
a lot of people couldn't play that they
put it off and eat didn't really came
with well they said
people want always iberian people like
you and the truth is everyone fuckin
hates that shit
it's ironic that a bunch of video game
people
complain with themselves and
by and
all right
so obvious and i just updated understand
but if i was a video game player or a
gamer as as they like to refer to
themselves
it's high time and i i they couldn't sit
on their computer and internet if you
had to be on my daughter and i don't
like people were crashing the self if
you want to pay sixty dollars for a gay
you can't possibly hope to play
uh... florida function that's completely
unnecessary
yes no i doubt it would i would really
irritating and i'm not saying that
sarcastically so i totally understand
their frustration i mean he said to me
because i keep there's a video game
player in like the ladies
with sega genesis n_b_a_ made all the
best sports games and not be a
so this does kinda make it said but i
thought that the letter
that the c_e_o_'s and average was kind
of thing
so he says and in the past year we have
received thousands of emails and
postcards protesting against eighty
eight for allowing players to create
elegy bt characters in our day
this week we cinco some conservative
websites urging people to protest are
algae bt policy by voting eating a the
worst company in america that's an
interesting accusation i don't know i am
if
kid that's what's putting email over the
edge right uh... but if that's really
happening that's disgusting behavior
how much will work in the anti date
people get break how much lower comming
diego this date you know it's not only
in the real world not like the people in
this world that we all live in
we actually don't like them too
like sixteen-bit anymore you know we
really like the number two what what we
believe that's the case
that they had
you know campaigns and mailing lists
then that you know again this is where
you got it back in the area of the boys
so they're getting ahead of for it