THAT MEANS LATER ON.
AND NORFOLK UPGRADES ITS ENERGY
PLANT AND IT MEANS THE LIGHTS
STAY ON AND IT'S NICE AND COOL
IN THE SUMMER.
OCEAN VIEW, BE READY.
ST. PATRICK'S DAY IS COMING IN A
VERY SPECIAL WAY, RIGHT HERE ON
NORFOLK PERSPECTIVES.
CAPTIONING PROVIDED BY
CAPTION ASSOCIATES, LLC
www.captionassociates.com
>>> WELCOME TO NORFOLK
PERSPECTIVES.
I'M BOB BATCHER.
I GOT TO BE HONEST, IT'S
GORGEOUS OUT TODAY WHEN WE'RE
TAPING THIS SHOW AND WHAT BETTER
TIME TO TALK ABOUT BASEBALL THAN
RIGHT NOW, AND PETE ALLEN, EVEN
THOUGH IT'S GOING TO BE 30
DEGREES TOMORROW, YOU'RE TALKING
BASEBALL.
>> YES, TIME FOR BASEBALL.
PLAY BALL!
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
OKAY, RBI AND SOFTBALL, WHAT'S
THE DIFFERENCE BETWEEN THE TWO?
>> WELL, IT'S THE SAME.
RBI HAS A BASEBALL PROGRAM AS
WELL AS A SOFTBALL PROGRAM, AND
THE SOFTBALL, OF COURSE, IS FOR
THE YOUNG LADIES AND BASEBALL IS
FOR -- WE HAVE A CO-ED PROGRAM
AS THE YOUNGER AGES AND AS THEY
GET OLDER, IT'S JUST BASEBALL
FOR THE GUYS.
>> OKAY.
AND WITH THE GALS, AS THEY GROW
OLDER, THEY STICK WITH THE --
>> SOFTBALL, YES, SIR.
>> OKAY.
NOW, I GOT TO TELL YOU, I'M KIND
OF LEARNING SOME NEW INSIDES
WITH THE FITNESS CENTER AND WITH
RPOS.
>> YES, SIR.
>> REALLY, I THINK OUR
BACKGROUND IS REALLY OUT IN THE
FIELD, ISN'T IT?
>> IT IS ON THE FIELD AND
SPEAKING OF THE FITNESS CENTER,
I HEARD YOU'VE BEEN SPENDING
SOME TIME OVER AT NORFOLK
FITNESS AND WELLNESS CENTER.
>> THE WORD IS GETTING OUT?
>> YEAH, I HEARD YOU OVER THERE
BREAKING RECORDS AND ALL KINDS
OF STUFF.
>> THAT'S RIGHT, I MADE A
COMMITMENT BECAUSE YOU GUYS KEEP
COMING ON THE SOFA AND
HARANGUING ME ABOUT NOT GETTING
OUT THERE AND PLAYING SOFTBALL,
BUT I'M NOT READY.
>> YOU ARE READY.
>> MY WIFE TAKES ME BALLROOM
DANCING, I GET WINDED, SO I WENT
AHEAD AND WENT WITH IT AS PART
OF OUR HEALTHY NORFOLK
INITIATIVES A I'M GOING TO START
WORKING OUT AND I'M GOING TO LET
THE VIEWERS SEE IT AND IT'S ON
THIS WEEK AND IF I CAN DO IT,
ANYBODY CAN DO IT.
TALKING ABOUT IT, LOOK AT YOU,
MR. SELF.
>> NO, I'M TRYING TO STAY IN
SHAPE AND EAT RIGHT AND EXERCISE
REGULARLY.
>> I'M ON MY SECOND PROTEIN BAR
FOR THE DAY AND I'M GOING TO
SUCK MY BELLY BUTTON INTO MY
SPINE.
>> I'M SURE YOU'LL BE FINE.
>> IS THAT WHAT WE DO, SUPERMAN?
>> NO.
POKE YOUR CHEST OUT, THERE YOU
GO.
>> CONTINUE TALKING WHILE I DO
THAT.
RBI.
>> IT'S THE INITIATIVE IF MAJOR
LEAGUE BASEBALL.
>> THAT'S THE BIG-LEAGUE GUYS.
>> YES, SIR, REVITALIZING
BASEBALL IN THE CITY AND THE KEY
IS TO GET INNER CITY KIDS BACK
INTO BASEBALL.
IT'S GREAT.
THEY HAVE A BUNCH OF RESOURCES
FOR US TO BE SUCCESSFUL AND NOT
JUST BASEBALL AS WE SPOKE ABOUT
EARLIER, IT'S SOFTBALL AS WELL
AND FOR AGES 5 TO 17.
AND IT'S A GREAT TIME.
AND THE KIDS WHO ARE SUCCESSFUL
WITH THE TEAMS, THEY HAVE AN
OPPORTUNITY TO MOVE ON TO
NATIONAL TOURNAMENTS, SO, YEAH.
>> THIS IS SERIOUS STUFF.
>> YES, SIR.
THEY HAVE AN OPPORTUNITY TO PLAY
IN NATIONAL TOURNAMENTS SO IT
GIVES OUR KIDS THE TYPE OF
EXPOSURE TO GET THEM TO THE NEXT
LEVEL.
>> BECAUSE I REMEMBER GOING TO
THE, YOU KNOW, BASICALLY FIELD
AND THE LOCAL NEIGHBORHOOD AND
WE DID THE WHOLE THING ABOUT
FOLLOWING THE BAT.
AND I WAS ALWAYS LAST ONE OUT
BECAUSE I WAS BAT BOY.
WE'RE NOT TALKING ABOUT THAT
KIND OF INFORMAL PICK-UP GAME.
>> NO, SIR, THIS IS LIKE ANY
OTHER REGULAR LITTLE LEAGUE
BASEBALL, BUT THIS IS SPONSORED
BY MAJOR LEAGUE BASEBALL SO
WE'VE RESOURCES AVAILABLE TO US
THAT OTHER LEAGUES DON'T HAVE.
FOR INSTANCE, WE MAY HAVE
OPPORTUNITY TO TRAVEL AND PLAY
AGAINST DIFFERENT RBI TEAMS IN
NORTH CAROLINA OR IN FLORIDA,
YOU KNOW, SO IT'S GREAT.
AND PLUS WE ALSO HAVE, YOU KNOW,
MAJOR LEAGUE BASEBALL PLAYERS
WHO WILL COME BACK AND SPEAK TO
OUR KIDS, SO WE HAVE TRAINING
AND STUFF LIKE THAT.
>> COOL.
WHEN YOU START TALKING ABOUT
TRAVELING TO NORTH CAROLINA,
THAT GETS EXPENSIVE, WON'T IT?
>> IT CAN, BUT LIKE I SAID, THE
RESOURCES THAT MAJOR BASEBALL
PROVIDE, THEY ALSO GIVE US
FINANCIAL SUPPORT TO TAKE SOME
OF THESE TRIPS.
>> OKAY.
SO REALLY, IT'S OPENING IT UP TO
KIDS WHO MAY NOT THINK THEY HAVE
A CHANCE BECAUSE OF THEIR
CIRCUMSTANCES INSTEAD OF THEIR
TALENT.
>> CIRCUMSTANCES, KIDS THAT VENT
BEEN EXPOSED TO BASEBALL, YOU
KNOW.
RIGHT NOW, BEING COMPLETELY
HONEST WITH YOU, FOOTBALL AND
BASKETBALL IS KIND OF LIKE
RULING IN SPORTS RIGHT NOW.
>> I KNOW.
>> AND THERE ARE OTHER
OPPORTUNITIES, BASEBALL, TENNIS,
LACROSSE, SOCCER, ALL THOSE
SPORTS THAT I THINK THEY NEED TO
BE EXPOSED TO AND THIS IS JUST
ONE WAY WE CAN GET GOING IN THIS
PARTICULAR SPORT, WHICH IS
BASEBALL, AND I MEAN, IT'S A
GREAT DEAL.
YOU'RE BACKED BY MAJOR LEAGUE
BASEBALL, SO --
>> SO ALL THE SPORTS YOU TALK
ABOUT, WE CAN GET PLUGGED INTO
AT THE REC CENTER.
>> YES, SIR.
>> SO IT'S REALLY SIMPLE AND A
LOT OF OUR REC CENTERS ARE
WALKING DISTANCE FROM
EVERYBODY'S HOUSE.
>> YES.
>> IN ORDER TO GET PLUGGED INTO
RBI, HOW DO THEY GO ABOUT DOING
THAT.
>> CALL LAKEWOOD, AND WE'RE
GOING TO HAVE A REGISTRATION
ENDING THE END OF MARCH, MARCH
29th.
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE A SKILLS
CLINIC MARCH THE 23rd AT
BRAMBLETON REC CENTER, SO ALL
KIDS OUT THERE INTERESTED IN
JUST LEARNING DEVELOPMENTAL
SKILLS, THEY CAN COME OVER TO
BRAMBLETON REC CENTER MARCH 23rd
AND WE ALSO HAVE -- I CAN'T GO
FURTHER WITHOUT MENTIONING
NORFOLK POLICE DEPARTMENT AND
THE PALS, HOLLY WILLIAMS, SHE'S
AWESOME.
THEY HAVE BEEN SUPPORTING US,
HELPING US OUT WITH THE BATTING
CAGE OVER THERE.
NORFOLK STATE, COACH CLARK, THE
BASEBALL COACH OVER THERE, HE'S
ACTUALLY GOING TO COME IN, BRING
HIS FLAIRS AND DO A -- PLAYERS
AND DO A LOT OF DEVELOPMENTAL
STUFF FOR THE KIDS AND HE'S
GOING TO ACTUALLY RUN THOSE
CAMPS AND CLINICS.
THEY'RE GETTING COLLEGE
COACHING.
>> COOL, SO IT'S REALLY HOOKED
UP.
WEBSITE FOR SOMEBODY TO GO TO?
>> NORFOLK.GOV.
>> AND LIKE WOOD, WHERE IS THAT
LOCATED.
>> 1612 WILLOW WOOD DRIVE,
BETWEEN TIDEWATER DRIVE AND
GRANBY STREET.
>> I GOT TO TELL YOU, MY BELLY
BUTTON MOVED AWAY FROM MY SPINE,
SO THIS IS OVER.
>> NO, JUST WORKING ON IT AND
PRETTY SOON, YOUR CHEST WILL
STICK OUT JUST BECAUSE.
>> WHEN WE COME BACK, WE'RE
TALKING ABOUT THE NEL PROGRAM
AND NO, IT'S NOT
A GAL.
\M [ SINGING ] \M
>> 60 MINUTES OF PHYSICAL
ACTIVITY A DAY AND EATING WELL
CAN HELP GET YOUR CHILD HEALTHY.
SO KEEP THEM ACTIVE AND EATING
WELL EVERY DAY.
GET IDEAS, GET INVOLVED, GET
GOING, AT LET'S MOVE.GOV.
>>>
WELCOME BACK TO NORFOLK
PERSPECTIVES.
I'M CONFUSED BECAUSE THE PERSON
SITTING ON THE SOFA I KNOW FOR A
LONG TIME, JANET WILLIAMS,
YOU'VE BEEN IN HUMAN RESOURCES,
BEEN IN PUBLIC WORKS, BEEN IN
I.T., AND NOW YOU'RE IN
RECREATION, PARKS AND OPEN
SPACE.
I CAN'T THINK OF A BROADER-BASED
PERSON HAVING EXPERIENCE.
OH, AND THE AUDITOR'S OFFICE.
WHAT ELSE DID I MISS?
>> MANAGER'S OFFICE.
>> AND GRANTS.
AND NOW YOU'VE BEEN KIND OF THE
LEADER OF NEL.
FIRST OF ALL, WHAT IS THAT.
>> IT STANDS FOR NORFOLK
EMERGING LEADERS PROGRAM.
>> YOU HAVE THE POSITION DOWN?
>> YEAH, WHICH MEANS REACHING
FORWARD WHILE PULLING SOMEONE
ALONG.
>> THERE WE GO.
>> THAT'S WHAT IT IS NOW, BUT
IT'S BEEN IN EXISTENCE ABOUT SIX
TO SEVEN YEARS.
I THINK I'VE BEEN WITH IT ABOUT
FIVE YEARS NOW AND IT'S A
PROGRAM THAT'S REALLY STARTING
TO KIND OF CHANGE LIVES, YOU
KNOW.
THESE PEOPLE THAT COME THROUGH
THESE PROGRAMS, THEY END UP
WORKING IN OUR ORGANIZATION AND
WE'RE REALLY PROUD TO BE A PART
OF NEL.
>> BECAUSE I KNOW WE'VE TALKED
ABOUT THIS IN THE WORKPLACE.
I MEAN, LET'S FACE IT, INTERNS
HAVE THIS REPUTATION -- OR
INTERN PROGRAMS HAVE THIS
REPUTATION OF YOU HAVE A HIGH
SCHOOL KID OR COLLEGE KID SHOW
UP AT THE WORKPLACE, THEY KIND
OF SURVIVE THE SUMMER AND THEY
GO BACK TO SCHOOL.
>> RIGHT.
>> THAT'S NOT WHAT NEL IS ABOUT,
IS IT?
>> I THINK ONE OF THE THINGS IS
PEOPLE NEED TO STOP THINKING
ABOUT WHAT ARE YOU GOING TO DO
WITH YOUR YOUNG PERSON EARLIER
IN THE YEAR.
NEL HAS TWO KEY COMPONENTS.
THE FIRST COMPONENT IS A 16 TO
19-YEAR-OLD PROGRAM WHICH
FOCUSES ON INDIVIDUALS IN MIDDLE
AND HIGH SCHOOL, AND EVEN THOUGH
IT'S NOT CALLED AN INTERNSHIP
PROGRAM, WE FOCUS ON MAKING SURE
THAT THEY COME INTO OUR
ORGANIZATION AND REALLY GET A
GOOD SENSE OF HOW LOCAL
GOVERNMENT WORKS.
WITH THE EXECUTIVE INTERNSHIP
PROGRAM, THAT'S FOR INDIVIDUALS
MATRICULATING THROUGH COLLEGE AT
ANY AGE, AND THIS YEAR, WE HAVE
BROADENED THAT PROGRAM TO NOT
ONLY HIT UNIVERSITIES AND
COLLEGES WITHIN THE STATE OF
VIRGINIA, BUT WE HAVE ACTUALLY
OPENED IT NATIONWIDE.
AND YOU WANT AN EXECUTIVE INTERN
AND THAT MEANS YOU REPORT TO THE
CITY MANAGER'S OFFICE AND OUT OF
THAT OFFICE, YOU MAY BE ROUTED
TO ANOTHER DEPARTMENT, BUT YOUR
KEY FOCUS IS YOU'RE GOING TO
WORK ON TWO OF OUR MAJOR
INITIATIVES IN THE CITY, WHICH
IS LIFELONG LEARNING AND
WORKFORCE DEVELOPMENT, SO THIS
IS A REAL-LIFE JOB BECAUSE
BECAUSE OF THIS EXPERIENCE AS AN
EXECUTIVE INTERN, YOU CAN BECOME
A FULL-TIME EMPLOYEE AND OUT OF
THE NORFOLK EMERGING LEADERS
PROGRAM, YOU CAN ELEVATE AND
BECOME AN EXECUTIVE INTERN WHEN
YOU GO THROUGH COLLEGE.
>> WE DO FOCUS, THOUGH, ON
LOOKING AT NORFOLK RESIDENTS
EVEN THOUGH THEY MIGHT BE GOING
TO SCHOOL THROUGHOUT THE
COUNTRY.
>> WE LOVE TO SUPPORT OUR
NORFOLK CITY AND OUR NORFOLK
RESIDENTS ARE PART OF WHAT MAKES
OUR CITY GREAT AND THAT WOULD BE
SOMETHING THAT WE FEEL GOOD
ABOUT HAVING THE INITIATIVE
FOCUS ON THAT.
>> I'M GOING TO PUT YOU ON THE
SPOT.
>> OKAY.
>> I REMEMBER WE TALKED ON THE
SOFA A COUPLE YEARS AGO WHEN
THIS WAS AN IDEA.
>> YEAH.
>> WHEN YOU MENTIONED THE IDEA
OF NEL AND THE INTERNS AND
FULL-TIME, WE HAVE SOME CASE
STUDIES FOR THAT THAT ARE FOR
REAL.
LET'S TALK ABOUT BULLY VIDEO.
WHEN I SAY BULLY VIDEO, WHAT DO
YOU THINK ABOUT?
>> I THINK ABOUT HOW MUCH
POTENTIAL CAN 20 TO 22 STUDENTS
GET DONE IN 20 WEEKS.
I THINK ABOUT GIVE THEM AN
ASSIGNMENT AND LET THEM DO IT
AND STEP BACK AND SEE THEM GET
IT DONE.
LAST YEAR THEY DEVELOPED A PSA
INITIATIVE ON AN ANTI-BULLYING
CAMPAIGN AND THAT'S WHERE THEY
COULD HAVE STOPPED.
THEY TOOK THAT CAMPAIGN TO
NORFOLK PUBLIC SCHOOLS, THE
PUBLIC SCHOOL BOARD, GOT IT
APPROVED, AND TODAY IT'S PART OF
THE CURRICULUM THAT NORFOLK
PUBLIC SCHOOLS USES AS A PART OF
THEIR ANTI-BULLYING CAMPAIGN.
I THINK SOMETIMES YOU
UNDERESTIMATE THE CAPACITY OF
WHAT AN INDIVIDUAL CAN DO AND
WHEN YOU COME TO BE A NORFOLK
EMERGING LEADER OR INTERN, WE'RE
GOING TO PUSH YOU AS FAR AS YOU
CAN GO.
A PSA DEVELOPED IN TEN WEEKS IS
PRETTY AMAZING SO THAT'S WHAT
THEY WERE ABLE TO DO.
>> AND PEOPLE SEE THAT PSA ON
THIS STATION ALL THE TIME.
>> ALL THE TIME.
>> LET'S TALK ABOUT THE GUY THAT
WAS KIND OF THE HUB OF IT,
BRYCE.
>> HE CAME THROUGH OUR PROGRAM
LAST YEAR IN 2012 AND HE
ACTUALLY WORKED IN CIVIC
FACILITIES AND I BELIEVE HE
ACTUALLY WORKS IN COMMUNICATIONS
RIGHT NOW, BUT KINETIC
TECHNOLOGY I THINK IS HIS MAJOR
AND JUST ALL KINDS OF MAJORS.
BUT THE INTEREST TO BE IN
GOVERNMENT IS WHERE BRYCE MAKES
US MOST PROUD AND HE'S SOMEONE
WE'RE PROUD TO CALL A CITY
EMPLOYEE RIGHT NOW.
>> IT'S REALLY COOL -- AND WE'LL
TALK ABOUT BRYCE EVEN THOUGH
HE'S NOT HERE, BECAUSE WHAT HE
REPRESENTS IS HE WASN'T WILLING
TO JUST STICK WITH CHECKING THE
BOX.
>> NO.
>> HE ACTUALLY TOOK ADVANTAGE OF
HAVING THE OPPORTUNITY TO SAY,
HEY, I'VE GOT A LOT OF FIRE IN
MY BELLY THAT I WANT TO GIVE TO
THE CITY AND WE'RE NOW SEEING
HIS WORK ON THE STATION A LOT.
>> IT'S NOT THAT YOU GOT TO PUSH
THEM.
YOU GOT TO MAKE SURE THAT THE
COMMUNICATION IS REALLY GOOD
WITH THEM BECAUSE SOME PEOPLE
HAVE HIDDEN TALENTS THAT COME
INTO A JOB THAT THEY DIDN'T KNOW
WHAT TO EXPECT, THAT CAN REALLY
KIND OF BRING OUT THE BEST IN
THEM, SO NEVER UNDERESTIMATE THE
QUIET PERSON OR THE INTROVERT.
>> I KNOW THERE'S A MOM OUT
THERE WHO SAYS MY DAUGHTER JANET
IS GOING TO MAKE IT, SO WHAT DO
YOU HAVE TO SAY SO THAT MOM OF
JANET?
>> THAT MOM OF JANET?
>> WHAT SHOULD JANET BE DOING IN
ORDER TO APPLY?
>> SHE SHOULD BE MAKING SURE
THAT SHE'S EITHER GONE TO HER
LOCAL LIBRARY OR THE NORFOLK.GOV
WEBSITE WHERE THE NEL
APPLICATIONS ARE, NOT ONLY THE
NORFOLK EMERGING LEADERS
APPLICATION IS OUT THERE, BUT
THE EXECUTIVE INTERN APPLICATION
IS OUT THERE ALSO.
THOSE APPLICATIONS WILL BE OUT
THERE UNTIL MARCH THE 15th, SO
THIS IS A CREDIT CAM TIME RIGHT
NOW -- CRITICAL TIME RIGHT NOW
WE'RE ASKING YOU TO THINK ABOUT
WHAT YOU WANT TO DO IN THE
SUMMER RIGHT NOW.
>> AND WHEN YOU AND YOUR TEAM
ARE MAKING THE DECISION, IT WILL
BE A TOUGH JOB.
>> IT WILL BE TOUGH.
>> THANK YOU FOR EVERYTHING YOU
BROUGHT TO THE CITY, BUT ALSO TO
OUR YOUTH IN THE COMMUNITY
INVESTING IN THE FUTURE.
>> YOU'RE WELCOME.
>> APPRECIATE IT.
>>> WHEN WE COME BACK, IT'S JUST
ABOUT ME BEING COOL IN THE
SUMMER, IT'S YOU TOO WHEN YOU
COME TO CITY HALL.
STAY TUNED.
>>> HEY, SANDRA.
>> OH, SORRY.
I'M JUST REALLY SURPRISED AT HOW
EXPENSIVE FOOD HAS GOTTEN.
WE'VE BEEN TRYING TO PUT ASIDE
SOME MONEY TO BUY A HOUSE, BUT
WE CAN BARELY MAKE IT FROM ONE
CHECK TO THE NEXT.
>> I'M IN THE SAME BOAT, BUT
WITH THE MONEY I'M GETTING FROM
THE EITC, WE'RE BETTER OFF.
IT'S THE EARNED INCOME TAX
CREDIT.
>> FOR MORE ON THE EITC AND FREE
TAX PREPARATION, CALL OR VISIT
OUR WEBSITE.
>> WELCOME BACK TO NORFOLK
PERSPECTIVES.
WE'VE GONE FROM ALL KINDS OF
THINGS AND NOW WE'RE TALKING
ABOUT MY COMFORT AT THE OFFICE.
IS THIS WHAT IT'S ABOUT, MY
COMFORT AT THE OFFICE?
DENISE THOMPSON.
>> IT'S PARTLY ABOUT YOUR
COMFORT, BOB.
ACTUALLY, IF EVERYTHING WORKS
FINE, YOU WILL BE COMPLETELY
COMFORTABLE AND YOU WON'T EVEN
KNOW WE'RE REDUCING COSTS AND
REDUCING OUR ENERGY USE AT THE
SAME TIME.
>> YOU JUST TOLD ME I HAD
NOTHING TO DO WITH IT.
>> NO, YOU DO BECAUSE YOU'RE THE
CLIENT, REALLY, OF OUR CENTRAL
ENERGY PLANT AND WE WANTED TO
COME AND TALK WITH YOU ABOUT
IMPROVEMENTS THAT WE MADE TO THE
CENTRAL ENERGY PLANT AND WHY,
AND HOW THAT TIES IN WITH THE
BIG PICTURE OF SUSTAINING
NORFOLK'S ENVIRONMENT.
>> OKAY, JERRY SPIVEY.
>> YES.
>> NOW, YOU'RE RIGHT-OF-WAY
PROGRAM MANAGER.
HOW DID YOU GET WRAPPED UP IN
THIS?
>> WELL, I WEAR MANY HAT.
>> WHICH IS A LOT OF PEOPLE IN
CITY HALL.
>> YOU HAVE TO.
I'M A CERTIFIED ENERGY MANAGER
AND I'VE WORKED WITH DENISE
SINCE SHE'S BEEN WITH THE CITY
ON ENERGY PROJECTS AND WE
RECENTLY COMPLETED PURCHASE OF A
SOFTWARE CALLED ENERGY CAP AND
WHAT WE DO WITH THAT IS WE INPUT
ALL THE UTILITY BILLS FROM ALL
OVER THE CITY, ALL THE
DEPARTMENTS.
>> YOU HAVE A BUNCH OF
FACILITIES.
>> HUNDREDS.
100 BUILDINGS, 3.5 MILLION
SQUARE FEET AND WE PUT ALL THE
INFORMATION IN, NATIONAL GAS,
ELECTRICITY, WATER, OIL, AND
WE -- MEASURE, MANAGE AND SAVE
IS WHAT WE LIKE TO SAY.
>> SO JERRY SAYS THERE'S A LOT
TO BE DONE AND SHE'S A -- YEAH,
OLIVER, ARE YOU DESIGNING IT?
>> I'M DESIGNING IT.
>> I FIGURED THAT ONE OUT?
>> YOU FIGURED THAT ONE OUT.
>> WE CAN GO OVER THAT.
>> I'M OVERSEEING THE
CONSTRUCTION AS WELL.
>> CAN I BE FRANK WITH YOU GUYS?
>> ABSOLUTELY.
>> I HAD NO IDEA THIS WAS GOING
ON.
>> THAT'S THE WAY WE LIKE IT.
IF YOU DON'T KNOW, WE'RE DOING
IT RIGHT.
WE DID OVER A $4 MILLION
IMPROVEMENT OF THE CENTRAL FLANT
AND YOU DIDN'T -- PLANT AND YOU
DIDN'T EVEN KNOW IT WAS GOING
ON.
>> CAN I ASK YOU ANOTHER
QUESTION?
>> YOU SURE CAN.
>> WHERE'S THE CENTRAL PLANT?
I MEAN TALK ABOUT BEHIND THE
SCENES.
I THINK THE GUYS -- IS IT IN THE
CENTER PART OF THE CITY?
>> IT IS NOT.
THE CENTRAL PLANT IS PROBABLY --
JERRY, YOU CAN HELP ME WITH
THIS.
I WOULD SAY A THOUSAND FEET
OUTSIDE THE CITY COMPLEX.
>> BY THE CITY GARAGE.
>> OH, THE BUILDING I WALK PAST
EVERY DAY, THAT ONE WITH STEAM
COMING OUT.
>> THAT'S IT.
>> NOW, DOES THAT -- MYTH HAS IT
THAT NOT ONLY CONTROLS MY
OFFICE, BUT THE OTHER
FACILITIES?
>> THE JAIL, CITY COURT, THE
CITY HALL.
>> I'M ASSUMING THE NEW
COURTHOUSE IS GOING UP.
>> YES.
>> THEY SAID FINALLY WE'RE GOING
TO BUILD SOMETHING INDEPENDENT
OF ALL THAT.
>> THAT'S CORRECT.
>> IT'S BEING POWERED BY THE
CENTRAL ENERGY PLANT.
>> HEATING AND COOLING COMES
FROM THE CENTRAL PLANT FOR THE
NEW COURTHOUSE.
>> AND THE NEW COURTHOUSE, AND
AGAIN, THIS TIES IN WITH THE BIG
PICTURE OF SUPPORTING
ENVIRONMENTAL QUALITY AND
SUSTAINABILITY AND REDUCING
COSTS AND THE NEW COURTHOUSE
BEEN A LEED CERTIFIED BUILDING,
WHICH MEANS LEADERSHIP IN ENERGY
AND ENVIRONMENTAL DESIGN AND IT
WILL HAVE SPECIAL ENERGY-SAVING
FEATURES, RECYCLED MATERIALS
FEATURES.
IT'S LOCATED NEAR TRANSIT, SO
THAT'S A GOOD THING.
WE HAVE LOTS OF LEED BUILDINGS
IN NORFOLK.
>> SO HOW ARE YOU ABLE TO PULL
THAT OFF WITH A PLANT -- I'M
ASSUMING PLANT WAS BUILT ABOUT
THE SAME TIME CITY HALL WAS,
WHICH WAS BEFORE DENISE WAS
BORN.
>> THANK YOU, BOB.
>> 1965, RIGHT?
YEAH, IT WAS BUILT AROUND 1965,
SO SOME WOULD SAY, TEAR IT DOWN,
REPLACE IT WITH NEW TECHNOLOGY.
IT DOESN'T WORK THAT DAY, DOES
IT?
>> WELL, WE HAD A REALLY GOOD
PLANT AND YOU MIGHT WANT TO TALK
ABOUT SOME OF THE INNOVATIVE
FEATURES.
>> LET'S TALK A LITTLE BIT ABOUT
HOW THE PLANT WORKS AND I'M
GOING TO KEEP IT SIMPLE.
>> PLEASE, BECAUSE I'M DOING
THIS TO MY THERMOSTAT.
>> WE'VE BASICALLY HAD PIPES
THAT RUN FROM THE CENTRAL PLANT.
>> I'VE BEEN IN THE TUNNEL.
>> EXACTLY.
OVER TO THE VARIOUS BUILDINGS,
CITY HALL, THE JAIL, THE COURT,
AND THEY SUPPLY COLD WATER AND
HOT WATER AND THE PIPES SEND
THAT WATER THROUGH COILS THAT
ARE IN AIR HANDLING UNITS AND
THAT DISTRIBUTES THE COLD AIR OR
HOT AIR IN THE BUILDING.
WELL, WHAT WE DID WAS WE
BASICALLY TOOK THAT EXISTING
INFRASTRUCTURE AND IMPROVED IT.
WE PUT IN MORE EFFICIENT MOTORS,
MORE EFFICIENT CHILLERS, ADDED
BOILERS, ADDED DIGITAL CONTROLS
TO THAT EQUIPMENT.
SO THAT'S THE WAY WE TOOK THAT
1965 TECHNOLOGY AND BROUGHT IT
UP TO DATE.
>> NOW, I REMEMBER SITTING IN
COMMITTEE MEETINGS WITH YOU,
DENISE, SEVERAL YEARS AGO WHEN
THE MANAGER CAME ON BOARD AND
REALLY LOOKED AT DOING THIS KIND
OF STUFF AND BIG BUCKS CAN BE
SAVED.
>> ABSOLUTELY, AS OPPOSED TO
STARTING FROM SCRATCH AND
BUILDING A WHOLE NEW PLANT.
>> BUT NEVER ONCE DID I HEAR YOU
TALK ABOUT BRINGING A SWEATER TO
WORK.
I THOUGHT CONSERVING ENERGY IN
THE WINTER MEANT GETTING COLD.
>> NO, NO, NO.
ON YOU SOMETIMES HEAR PEOPLE --
YOU SOMETIMES HEAR PEOPLE
TALKING ABOUT THE ENVIRONMENT
AND SUSTAINABILITY, THEY SAY
IT'S ABOUT PEOPLE, PLANET AND
POCKETBOOK.
SO THE GOAL IS FOR YOU TO BE
COMFORTABLE AND PRODUCTIVE AND
FOR IT NOT TO COST A LOT, FOR US
TO CONTINUE TO USE LESS ENERGY
AND THAT THEN KEEPS THE COST
DOWN, AND TO -- BY USING LESS
ENERGY, WE'RE -- WE'VE GOT LESS
OF AN IMPACT, LESS OF A CARBON
FOOTPRINT ON THE PLANET.
>> IT'S KIND OF COOL BECAUSE I
GOT TO TELL YOU, WHEN I GO IN
THE MEN'S ROOM, I DON'T HAVE TO
WORRY ABOUT TURNING THE LIGHTS
ON AND OFF.
>> IT'S MAGIC.
>> HOW DO THEY KNOW I'M THERE?
>> I LOVE AUTOMATION.
THEY DO KNOW YOU'RE THERE AND
THEY TURN OFF AFTER ABOUT 10 OR
15 MINUTES DEPENDING ON HOW
THEY'RE SET AND THAT WAS A
WONDERFUL -- THAT WAS OLIVER'S
PROJECT.
THAT WAS A WONDERFUL
APPLICATION.
>> YOUR PROJECT?
>> YOU DON'T WANT TO TALK ABOUT
THAT.
>> WONDERFUL TECHNOLOGY.
>> IS THAT THE KIND OF THING
WE'RE SEEING INCORPORATED
NATURALLY INTO THE NEW
COURTHOUSE, RIGHT?
>> ABSOLUTELY.
>> AND WE DON'T HAVE TO WAIT
UNTIL THEN.
I'VE BEEN OVER TO THE FITNESS
CENTER, AS WE ALL HEARD, AND
SOME OF THE NEW ONES --
>> YES, WE'RE PUTTING THOSE IN
FACILITIES NOW.
WHEN WE GO IN, WE'RE DOING
RENOVATIONS, ESPECIALLY IN
RESTROOMS AND CONFERENCE ROOMS
THAT ARE NOT ATTENDED OFTEN AND
THAT'S THE PRIME OPPORTUNITY TO
HAVE THOSE TYPE OF FEATURES.
>> I WAS AT LAMBERT'S POINT AND
THE WHOLE GYM, WALKED IN AND THE
SAME, WHATEVER IT IS, ELF.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
>> THE LIGHTS CAME ON.
>> IT'S A FABULOUS TECHNOLOGY
BECAUSE IF THE LIGHTS ARE LEFT
ON INADVERTENTLY ALL NIGHT LONG,
YOU'RE BURNING WHAT?
EIGHT, 10, 12, 14 HOURS OF
ENERGY FOR NOTHING.
>> BUT DENISE, LET'S BE CANDID.
WE HAVE THE MONEY IN THE BUDGET.
DOESN'T IT JUST WORK THAT WAY?
YOU BUDGET FOR ENERGY.
WHAT'S THE PUSH?
>> NO, NO, BECAUSE YOU BUDGET SO
THAT YOU CAN MEET YOUR NEEDS AS
WELL AS MEET THE NEEDS OF THE
FUTURE.
SO WE'RE IN A TIME WHEN WE'RE
ALL LOOKING AT THE BUDGET AND IF
THERE'S PLACES THAT WE COULD
SAVE MONEY AT THE SAME TIME THAT
WE CAN MEET OUR GOALS, THEN YOU
DON'T -- YOU DON'T WANT A BUDGET
THAT'S HIGHER THAN YOU NEED.
WHY WOULD YOU -- WE COULD SPEND
THAT MONEY ON SCHOOLS, SPEND
THAT MONEY ON BIKE RACKS, SPEND
THAT MONEY OR NOT SPEND THAT
MONEY AND KEEP OUR TAX RATES
DOWN.
>> YOU SOUND LIKE THE PEOPLE I
HEARD AT THE COMMUNITY
CONVERSATION.
>> I KNOW.
>> I JUST GOT THE WRAP-UP TIME,
BUT YOU SAID THIS HAD A LOT TO
DO WITH THE COURTHOUSE.
>> WE BROUGHT THIS FOR YOU.
ONE OF THE THINGS THAT THE OLD
PART OF THE PLANT DOES AND PART
OF THE REASON WE KEPT IT IS WE
CHILL WATER AT NIGHT IN THE
SUMMERTIME WHEN THE RATES ARE
LOW AND THEN WE USE THAT WATER
TO COOL OUR FACILITIES.
AND IT'S A GIANT THERMOS, SO --
>> I THINK OF THE THREE OF YOU
GUYS EVERY TIME I DRINK OUT OF
IT.
THANK YOU.
>> YOU'RE VERY WELCOME.
>> THANKS FOR KEEPING US ON THE
LEADING EDGE BY BEING LEED.
>>> WHEN WE COME BACK, WE'LL
TALK ABOUT THE PARTY EVERYBODY
KNOWS ABOUT, THE OESHVIEW PARADE
BY THE KNIGHTS OF COLUMBUS.
STAY TUNED.
>>> THE AVERAGE TEXT TAKES YOUR
EYES OFF THE ROAD FOR NEARLY
FIVE SECONDS.
[ SOUNDS OF CRASH ]
>>> WELCOME BACK TO NORFOLK
PERSPECTIVES.
OKAY, WE'RE READY TO ROLL OUT
THE BIGGEST, THE BEST PARADE IN
MARCH IN OCEAN VIEW EVER, RIGHT?
>> SATURDAY, MARCH 16th, 10:00,
NORTH SIDE MIDDLE SCHOOL AT
GRANBY AND WESTMONT.
CONGRESSMAN SCOTT RICHELLE WILL
BE CUTTING THE TAPE AND THE
PARADE STARTS NORTH ON GRANBY
STREET.
>> AND CARL, YOU ARE THE MEDIA
COMMUNITY LIAISON WITH THAT, AND
IF WE TELL PEOPLE THAT'S WHEN
THEY NEED TO BE THERE, THEY'RE
GOING TO MISS THE PARADE.
>> WE TELL PEOPLE TO GET THERE
EARLY, GET THEIR PARKING, BE
RESPECTFUL OF THE NEIGHBORHOOD
PARKING SITUATION.
THERE ARE PARKING LOTS TO THE
NORTH PART OF THE CITY ALONG THE
BEACHFRONT THERE, BUT GET THERE
EARLY BECAUSE PARKING IS VERY
LIMITED.
>> IT'S PRIME.
JIMMY ROGERS, YOU'RE THE CHAIR,
THE ONE PULLING ALL THE STRINGS
AND MAKING IT WORK.
>> I KIND OF DIRECT EVERYBODY
AND MAKES SURE IT GETS DONE.
>> IN FULL DISCLOSURE, AS HOST
OF THE SHOW, I HAVE A LOT OF
FUN, BUT MORE IMPORTANTLY
BETWEEN TAPES SHOWS, I HAVE THE
PLEASURE OF WORKING WITH GUYS
LIKE YOU AND WE'VE BEEN SPENDING
THE LAST -- YOU'VE BEEN SPENDING
THE LAST YEAR GETTING READY FOR
THIS PARADE, RIGHT?
>> YES.
JIMMY CALLED EVERYBODY TO WORK,
RIGHT BACK IN LATE JUNE AND
WE'VE BEEN MEETING WITHIN THE
PARADE COMMITTEE ITSELF, WE'VE
BEEN MEETING WITH THE CIVIC
LEAGUES IN THE COMMUNITY TO GET
THE THEME AND ISSUES THAT WE
WANTED TO ADDRESS WITH THE
PARADE, AND IT'S A LOT OF WORK.
>> YEAH, BECAUSE SOME PEOPLE --
JIMMY, HOW LONG HAVE YOU BEEN
CHAIRMAN OF THE PARADE?
>> ALMOST TEN YEARS.
>> SO YOU FORGOT WHEN THEY SOLD
YOU THE BILL OF GOODS ABOUT
CHAIRING THIS --
>> ALL YOU HAVE TO DO IS BE
THERE.
>> JUST SHOW UP AND PUNCH
TICKETS, RIGHT?
>> YEAH.
>> HOW DO YOU PULL IT OFF?
>> WE WORK CLOSELY WITH THE
CITY, THE CULTURAL EVENTS
DEPARTMENT AND THEY HELP US WITH
ALL THE OPERATIONS THE CITY
WOULD TAKE CARE OF, SO POLICE,
TRAFFIC, GETTING THE PERMITS AND
ALL THE THINGS THAT WE NEED IN
THAT AREA, BUT THEN WE WORK WITH
PEOPLE, THE SHRINERS ARE A BIG
PART OF OUR PARADE.
THEY BRING A LOT -- THEY ARE
PARADE PEOPLE AND THEN WE ALSO
HAVE OTHER GROUPS AND
ORGANIZATIONS THROUGHOUT THE
CITY AND THE ENTIRE HAMPTON
ROADS AREA THAT WANT TO BE PART
OF IT, BUT WE TRY TO BRING
SOMETHING THAT'S NOT ONLY
ENTERTAINING, BUT INFORMATIONAL
TO THE PUBLIC.
>> YEAH, I GOT TO -- I'M NOT
SURE IF I SHARED THIS, BUT I HAD
THE PLEASURE OF DRIVING IN THE
PARADE IN 2004.
MY DAUGHTER WAS MISS NORFOLK,
AND SO WE WERE IN THE PARADE.
YOU GUYS PUT US BACK BY THE FIRE
TRUCK, BUT THAT'S ANOTHER STORY.
BUT BY THE END OF THE PARADE,
SHE HAD BEEN PROPOSED TO SIX
TIMES.
>> I BELIEVE IT.
>> SHE DIDN'T ACCEPT ANY OF
THEM, BUT THE PEOPLE, THE
CROWDS, IT'S A
COMMUNITY-BUILDING EVENT.
>> WE HEAR ALL THE TIME THROUGH
THE CIVIC LEAGUES AND THE
COMMUNITY PEOPLE, IT'S A REUNION
TIME AND ALSO TIMED AROUND THE
SPRING BREAKS OF THE COLLEGES SO
A LOT OF YOUNG STUDENTS ARE BACK
IN THEIR -- WHERE THEY'RE FROM
AND THEY COME TO THE PARADE.
IT'S A BIG REUNION.
>> BUT THE COMMUNITY HAS REALLY
TAKEN OWNERSHIP OF THIS PARADE.
THEY WANT TO BE A PART OF IT,
AND MOST OF THE PEOPLE THAT
WATCH IT HAVE AT ONE TIME
ACTUALLY BEEN IN THE PARADE, SO
THAT HELPS ADD TO THE
EXCITEMENT.
>> NOW, LAST YEAR WAS A BANNER
YEAR BECAUSE IT HAPPENED TO FALL
ON THE ACTUAL DAY.
THIS YEAR, IT'S --
>> THE 16th.
>> THE DAY BEFORE.
>> BUT WHAT I'M LEARNING IS IT
DOESN'T MATTER IF IT'S THE DAY
OF, THE DAY BEFORE, THE WEEK
BEFORE, THE IRISH KNOW HOW TO
PARTY, BUT DO WE HAVE THAT MANY
IRISHMEN IN NORFOLK?
>>S A PAERGE WE DO BECAUSE --
APPARENTLY WE DO BECAUSE THEY
ALL COME OUT, BUT THE ENTHUSIASM
EVERY YEAR, SOMETIMES THE PARADE
IS THREE OR FOUR DAYS BEFORE
ST. PATRICK'S DAY AND THEY STILL
COME OUT AND ENJOY THEMSELVES
AND HAVE A GOOD TIME.
>> BECAUSE WHEN YOU LOOK AT THE
SPECIAL EVENTS CALENDAR, YOU
GUYS REALLY LAUNCH THE WHOLE
CELEBRATION TIME AND THEN
THERE'S THE GREENING OF GHENT
AND THEN THERE'S A CONCERT
DOWNTOWN THE SAME WEEKEND, SO
THERE'S A WHOLE LOT GOING ON.
>> WE ALWAYS SAY PEOPLE ARE
TIRED OF THAT CABIN FEVER AND
THEY CAN'T WAIT TO GET OUTSIDE
AND GET OUT IN THE PARADE AND
MEET THEIR COMMUNITY.
>> BECAUSE I'VE NEVER MET SO
MANY PEOPLE THAT WANTED TO PARK
IN THE MEDIAN.
I MEAN, THAT'S JUST --
>> THEY'RE THERE THE NIGHT
BEFORE.
>> WE'RE TRYING TO DO -- AND I
APPRECIATE YOUR COMMENT BECAUSE
WE'RE TRYING TO -- I MEAN, KEEP
IN MIND THAT PEOPLE LIVE IN THIS
NEIGHBORHOOD TOO.
>> WE'VE HAD GREAT WORKING
RELATIONSHIPS WITH, AS JIM
MENTIONED, WITH THE CITY AND
CITY OFFICIALS AND THERE'S A LOT
OF THINGS THAT WE'VE BEEN
WORKING AT AND PUBLIC WORKS THIS
YEAR, SOME OF THE ISSUES ABOUT
CHILDREN REACHING INTO THE
PARADE, THEY HAVE ADDED YELLOW
STRIPING ALONG THE ROADS THERE
ON THE MEDIAN, SO AGAIN, WE'RE
REALLY ASKING PARENTS TO KEEP
THEIR KIDS BEHIND THE YELL LO
LINE SO THEY'RE NOT IN -- YELLOW
LINE SO THEY'RE NOT IN DANGER,
AND JUST YESTERDAY, WE MET WITH
THE POLICE REPRESENTATIVES TO
TALK ABOUT ISSUES.
>> SO YOU'RE REALLY CONTROLLING
IT, BUT IT'S STILL GOING TO BE
ONE HECK OF A GOOD TIME.
>> WE TELL EVERYBODY TO COME AND
HAVE A GOOD TIME.
>> THEY'RE RAISING THE BAR
BECAUSE I WAS AT A MEETING THE
OTHER DAY WITH THE ANIMAL CARE
CENTER AND THEY'RE ALL EXCITED
BECAUSE THEY'RE MOVING FROM
TIEING TWO GROCERY CARTS
TOGETHER TO ACTUALLY HAVING A
FLOAT IN THE PARADE.
>> WE'RE GOING TO HAVE THE CITY
RECYCLERS HERE, THE HAMPTON
UNIVERSITY PROTON BEAM THERAPY
CENTER IS PUTTING ON A FLOAT.
IT'S A HAMPTON ROADS EVENT.
>> AND THEN YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE
A COUPLE OF IRISHMEN.
>> A COUPLE.
>> SO COME LOOK FOR THEM.
YOU HAVE AN AWESOME WEBSITE.
WE HAVE A LINK AT NORFOLK.GOV,
BUT THE LINK IS A DIRECT SITE.
>> NORFOLKPARADE.COM.
>> AND I WISH YOU GUYS TO HAVE
ONE HECK OF --
>> IT'S NOT JUST A GOOD TIME, IT
HAS A LARGE ECONOMIC IMPACT ALSO
THROUGHOUT THAT WHOLE PART OF
NORFOLK ALONG LITTLE CREEK ROAD
AND EVERYTHING.
>> SURE DOES AND ON YOUR
WEBSITE, THERE'S GOING TO BE
SOME PARTY AND A LOT OF
BUSINESSES TAKE ADVANTAGE TOO.
THANKS A LOT FOR EVERYTHING YOU
GUYS ARE DOING TO BRING THE
WORLD TO OCEAN VIEW ON MARCH
16th.
>> WE'VE ACTUALLY TALKED TO THE
PEOPLE IN IRELAND ON A VISIT WE
MADE.
>> ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU.
THANKS A LOT.
>>> HEY, WE WANT TO HEAR FROM
YOU WHAT YOU WANT TO SEE A
TV-48, BUT MORE IMPORTANTLY,
WHAT'S GOING ON IN YOUR
NEIGHBORHOOD.
GIVE US A HOLLER AT 664-6510 AND
AS USUAL, IT'S A WONDERFUL TIME
TO BE IN NORFOLK JUST BECAUSE OF
YOU AND YOU AND YOU.
THANKS A LOT.
CAPTIONING PROVIDED BY
CAPTION ASSOCIATES, LLC
www.captionassociates.com