MAN: Rockets and guns, huh?
TRAVIS: Rockets and guns.
Will it be
"Sweet Drone Alabama"?
Oh!
Or will our weaponized aircraft
fail to make the grade?
Oh, no! Oh, no! Crap!
I'm Travis Taylor.
I'm a rocket scientist in
the space and defense industry
here in my hometown
of Huntsville, Alabama,
where my daddy
helped build the rockets
that sent us to the moon.
DADDY: Have y'all been drinking
rocket fuel again?
TRAVIS: Sometimes big science
moves too slow for me,
so come the weekend,
I round up my best friend Rog,
my nephew Michael,
and my buddy Pete
to tackle important problems
with a little
down-home ingenuity.
ROG: Damn it, boy!
TRAVIS: Right on.
Hey, is there any more beers
in the cooler?
TRAVIS: The U.S. military's
been taking out
all kinds of enemy targets
with the help of combat drones.
And this weekend,
we're going to join them
in creating the next generation
of drone technology--
ones that don't cost
millions of dollars to make.
I told all the guys
to bring anything
that looks like
it's a remote control vehicle,
electronic airplanes,
helicopters, whatever,
lightweight
construction material.
PETE: We don't need this.
ROG: Why we dragging
all this crap out for?
TRAVIS: What we're gonna do is
we're gonna build a UAV drone.
The American military
is looking to make
a small unmanned
aerial vehicle, or UAV,
that can be carried by a single
soldier out in the field.
In fact, the Defense Advanced
Research Projects Agency,
or DARPA,
has issued a challenge
to citizen scientists
to build a drone
that can do three things.
One, fly a couple miles.
Two, send back video.
And three, fit into a backpack
so a single soldier
can carry it.
Let's say this soldier
gets into trouble,
so he pulls his UAV
out of his backpack,
tosses it up,
it flies up over the trees
and looks and finds
where the bad guys are.
They give him either an escape
route or an attack route.
MICHAEL:
My dad's in the military.
I'd love for him to have
something like this.
So this is
a real important build to me,
and I think I can
contribute a lot to it.
TRAVIS:
People are used to drones
that look and fly
like airplanes,
but I want ours
to take off vertically,
so we're gonna make
a helicopter drone.
We're gonna use remote-control
helicopter motors for lift,
and below them
we'll mount a video camera.
And even though DARPA
isn't calling for their
portable drones to have weapons,
we're gonna add
rockets and a gun
that can be fired remotely.
For our first test,
we've already got a gun
hooked up to a couple motors
from a remote control
helicopter.
We're gonna see if it can
get off the ground
and if we can
fire off of some rounds
using this really cool
firing system
that Michael designed.
When we push a joystick
on the RC controller,
a small motor, also known
as a servo, will rotate,
driving an armature
into the trigger
like a plastic finger...
and bang!
The enemy
won't know what hit 'em.
We're about to take it
out in the backyard
and see if we can fly this thing
with two motors
and fire
this paintball gun with it.
ROG: How cool is that?
We just made ourselves
a flying gun.
I bet we can take that thing
duck hunting.
PETE: We loaded it up
with plenty of ammo,
and Mr. Taylor made us
a nice target to shoot at.
TRAVIS: Here we go,
We're gonna bring the motors up.
We're coming on up.
Yeah, there we go.
Are we getting any lift?
You feel like it's
pulling out of your hand?
MICHAEL: It's pulling.
Just not enough.
TRAVIS: Careful with it now.
All the way, all the way.
Going full throttle.
MICHAEL: Full throttle it.
ROG: Stay with it.
Michael: Is that wide open?
TRAVIS: It's wide open.
It ain't gonna lift it. Crap!
Yeah, I thought it
would have lifted it, man.
PETE: Maybe those batteries--
TRAVIS: That gun's
just a lot heavier,
and the paintballs
added more weight.
That's a lot of weight
'cause that's all liquid
in them paintballs.
PETE: It's obvious
we're gonna need more motors
to lift all the payload
on our weaponized drone.
But before
we work on that problem,
we're gonna go ahead and see if
our remote trigger works.
MICHAEL: Gun's hot.
TRAVIS: Alright, here we go.
Gun's hot, ready to fire it
in three, two, one.
MICHAEL: When they hit
that remote trigger
on the controller,
that plastic finger should
rotate and fire the gun.
TRAVIS: Crap!
DADDY: Now, I like to see
things go off
when you pull the trigger.
MICHAEL: You ain't got nothing.
TRAVIS: Crap.
DADDY: I'm just frustrated.
The motors didn't work,
and neither did the trigger.
We got our work
cut out for us on this one.
TRAVIS: One complete motor...
One of the things
we learned from this test
is we need to know exactly how
much weight each motor can lift,
because we want our drone
to carry not just a gun,
but a camera
and a whole bunch of rockets.
MICHAEL: What you think
about that?
DADDY: Hey, that's neat.
MICHAEL: We didn't know
how to measure
how much weight
the motor could lift,
but then Papaw had an idea.
DADDY: Why not just use
my old fish scales?
TRAVIS: Everybody get
your safety glasses on.
All right, so what
we're gonna do with this
is measure the lift
of this engine, all right,
by looking at the scale
right there
and see how much thrust
we're getting out of it.
Y'all be careful
because the blades are sharp.
They'll cut your finger off
in a heartbeat.
All right, here we go.
[motor revs]
TRAVIS:
That's good. That's good.
How much was that?
MICHAEL: Five pounds.
TRAVIS: So if one motor
can lift five pounds,
then four can lift twenty.
That ought to be enough,
so that's the plan.
We're gonna build
a four-propeller
helicopter drone.
We're gonna put our propellers
on a frame,
and we'll hang the camera
and the weapons from that.
I want to get this thing
done today
or first thing in the morning
'cause a buddy of mine
that's a UAV expert
over at University of Alabama
in Huntsville
told me he'd come over here
tomorrow about 2:00
to see our solution.
Dr. Brian Landrum
has been working with the army
and on UAVs for years.
He's written dozens
of scientific papers
and analyzed UAV designs
for the military.
If we can impress him
with our drone,
I think we can
get it seen by DARPA.
ROG: He's got this guy
coming over here tomorrow,
and we've got tons of stuff
to figure out.
And I don't see how we can be
half done by then.
TRAVIS: You and Pete figure out
why that gun didn't fire
and figure out what we gotta do
to do four motors at once.
If we're gonna have
four motors on this thing,
then we're gonna need something
to attach them to.
So I sent Rog
out to the hardware store
to find us some kind
of lightweight frame.
ROG: Wait a minute now.
ROG: When I was driving by,
I saw at my buddy's house,
his wife was out in the yard,
and his little girl
was doing the hula-hoop.
And I got an idea.
We ain't gonna
have to build a frame.
A hula-hoop's already
made like that, you know.
So I did a little bartering,
and I traded my hat
for the hula-hoop.
And I think I got
a pretty fair deal.
PETE: I've got them ready.
TRAVIS: That's all right.
DADDY: Hold that thing up level.
[horn honking]
DADDY: Oh, man.
TRAVIS: We sent Rog out
to get a frame for our drone,
and here he comes back
with a hula-hoop.
What are you gonna do
with a hula-hoop?
You working on
your girly figure?
ROG: I figure
we put that as a base.
DADDY: That's not a bad idea.
TRAVIS:
The plastic is fairly rigid.
I think it's gonna work great
for our airframe structure.
ROG: Anything for
the project of the week.
TRAVIS: Now that
we've got the frame,
we've got to get back to
figuring out that trigger.
When we pushed the joystick
on the remote control,
the motor is supposed to turn
and drive a plastic finger
into the trigger,
but that motor just won't move.
MICHAEL: It ain't going.
TRAVIS: I heard something.
You don't reckon
the servo is stuck, do you?
MICHAEL: You know what?
The trim might not be set right.
Uncle Travis thinks
the servo motor is broken,
but I doubt it.
I think the remote controller
isn't set up right.
I can make a simple adjustment
to something called the trim.
That should fix the problem.
It'd be as easy
as adjusting the dial.
But sometimes Uncle Travis has
just got to do things his way.
TRAVIS: Maybe I'll just
change the servo out.
Do we have an extra one?
MICHAEL: Check the trim.
TRAVIS: I think it's something
wrong with that servo.
MICHAEL: So we did exactly
what he told us to.
We replaced the servo.
And guess what?
We put a brand-new
servo on here,
and it's doing the same thing.
It ain't the servo.
TRAVIS: Look, you got to figure
this part out
'cause this is a main part
of the dag gum UAV, right?
MICHAEL: We're trying.
TRAVIS: Don't try. Do it!
MICHAEL: Just give us some time.
TRAVIS: All right.
MICHAEL: Try that trim.
Adjust that--
whatever way it is,
throw it all the way.
TRAVIS: Oh!
What the crap was that?
DADDY: These
experiments are dangerous.
These guys are
real rocket scientists.
Don't try this at home.
TRAVIS: We're making
a portable weaponized drone
to match
Defense Department specs.
It's got to fly two miles,
send back video,
and fit in a backpack.
And there's a UAV expert who's
gonna be here in just 24 hours
who's gonna tell us
if it makes the grade.
MICHAEL: Try that trim. That's
the only thing we hadn't tried.
Adjust that--whatever way it is,
throw it all the way--
TRAVIS: Oh!
What the crap was that?
Did you all just shoot
a paintball on Daddy's floor?
MICHAEL: No. I don't think
it was a paintball.
TRAVIS: You ain't got
the paintball, but did it go?
MICHAEL: I think it just--yeah.
TRAVIS: Do it again.
Pete, are you making it do that?
PETE: Yup.
TRAVIS: Hey, hey, look at that.
TRAVIS: He was right.
Michael said it was the trim,
and I should have
listened to him.
You sure I didn't
tell you to check that?
Now, that that's fixed,
Michael and Pete are
working on the remote video
that mission control will use
to control the drone.
We're gonna make it
so that a single soldier
can control the drone
from the field,
but if he needs to,
he can hand off that control
back to home base
that's miles and miles away.
PETE: Was that about 100 feet?
MICHAEL: Yeah, that's
crystal clear, ain't it?
PETE: That's good.
TRAVIS:
Once Rog finished putting
all the motors and blades on,
we created
some unique landing gear.
Daddy, we're gonna be using
your cat fishing noodle.
DADDY: I always have
some of those noodles
you use in the pool
for kids to play with.
I use them for fishing.
Never imagined we'd be
using them for a DARPA drone.
TRAVIS: Cut me off
four of them beer-can high.
ROG: Beer-can high?
Ain't that a unit of measurement
that the Egyptians used?
TRAVIS: They can zip-tie
all the way through it.
All the way,
just set 'em right on there.
Here, Michael.
Hey, you two settle down
before I get on the both of you.
I think we're done.
All we gotta do
is hook the power up,
and we're ready to go.
There's still
a lot to figure out,
but if this thing doesn't work,
we're screwed.
We're gonna see if it flies.
DADDY: I don't think
he's a very experienced driver.
I'm thinking he's probably gonna
run the thing into us.
TRAVIS: Everybody be ready.
Here we go.
Coming up with the throttle.
[popping]
Watch out now.
DADDY: By George,
it does fly, don't it?
Look out for my truck.
TRAVIS: There it goes!
Oh!
Oh, crap!
Something happened,
it went unstable.
ROG: He started
running that thing.
I thought he had it,
and I thought, man,
'cause he just missed
this one tree over here.
And he hit
these limbs right here.
And I didn't know he
couldn't drive that thing, man.
TRAVIS: There's some things
that come loose.
I'm gonna have to go
back through all the connections
and make sure it works.
DADDY: What do you think, son?
What do you think happened?
Did it just get out of range
of the controls
where it wouldn't respond?
TRAVIS: It was pilot error.
I couldn't tell
where I was looking,
and I think I just
lost orientation
of where was the front
and where was the back,
and when I made the correction,
it wasn't the right way.
I either need more practice
or figure out
a better way to do it.
But that's after
we fix the thing
back to where we had it.
I'm getting nervous
because we still have to do
a flight test in the morning
before the expert gets here.
It's gonna be
a long night, man,
'cause we ain't even
thought about
how to put the rockets on there,
y'all ain't figured out
how to ignite 'em,
we still got to get
a gun mount on here.
We're a long way.
At least we got
a cooler full of beer.
Man, we worked
through the night,
but we got it all fixed up.
We're gonna do this test
where we see how far of a range
we can go with the helicopter
and what kind of video
we can get back.
PETE: We're good with picture.
TRAVIS: I'm gonna come in there
and fly it from the video then.
Then we got that UAV expert
gonna be here in a little while.
Gonna throttle up.
There we go.
ROG: I mean, it was just cool
to be in the garage
and watch that thing fly.
But the best was when we flew
over our buddy Sloth's house.
TRAVIS: Sloth. What's he doing?
MICHAEL:
Looks like he's working.
ROG: He's looking
for Easter eggs.
DADDY: Working my foot.
TRAVIS: You can't throw
a beer can that high, Sloth.
The whole time I was hovering
over Sloth's house,
he kept throwing beer cans up.
He knew that Rog was probably
behind it somehow or other.
Boy, that one got fairly close.
Did you see that one?
He's got a pretty good arm.
I could have messed
with Sloth all day.
Here, I'm gonna
get on outta there.
ROG: Fly that thing home.
TRAVIS:
We had to fly the drone home
so we could continue
to work on it.
We got our UAV
back in one piece.
Now that we know we can control
it better with video,
we still got to
put that gun on there,
and we've still got to put
that rocket on there.
Now, the other big requirement
of the DARPA challenge
is getting this thing
to fit in a backpack.
With all the setbacks,
I just haven't had
any time to work on that.
But Michael and Pete assure me
they've got that covered.
I guess we'll just
have to wait and see.
First, Michael has got to
get our rockets working.
Michael, you about figured out
how to fire them rockets yet?
MICHAEL:
Yeah, we're programming it.
TRAVIS: While Michael
worked on that,
Rog figured out how to
mount the gun to our drone.
ROG: We got that gunner
aimed right at you.
TRAVIS: Look at what he's done.
He's put the gun
on the bottom of it.
It looks pretty good.
It's gonna work out just fine.
Michael, I got to have
that circuit finished
to fire them rockets.
So go finish that circuit.
We're completing our arsenal
with rocket-propelled
explosives.
But to fit them below the gun,
we have to add legs
to the bottom.
Of course this all
just adds more weight,
but if we want to impress DARPA,
we have to add those rockets.
ROG: Where's that feller at?
TRAVIS: Dr. Brian Landrum
from the University of Alabama
Huntsville
will be here any minute.
He's an expert on drone design
for the Defense Department.
So he's the perfect guy
to judge what we're doing.
DADDY: When Dr. Landrum sees it,
he's got to get over
his first initial shock.
I mean, this thing's built
by the Rocket City Rednecks.
It's built out of hula-hoops
and fun noodles.
He's gonna think,
"What in the world?"
PETE: We want to do
one more test.
And the big question is,
with all this weight
and all these new weapons,
will this thing
even get off the ground?
MICHAEL: We ready?
Here we go.
TRAVIS:
Alright, bring it up Michael.
There we go.
What's going on?
MICHAEL: It won't come up.
TRAVIS:
With all this extra weight,
our drone is really
struggling to get enough lift.
ROG: Oh, oh, no!
TRAVIS: Watch out.
ROG: Don't touch that!
TRAVIS: We built a portable
weaponized drone
for the DARPA challenge
and invited a UAV expert,
Dr. Brian Landrum,
to evaluate our design
during today's field test.
TRAVIS: Oh, no, no, no!
But his arrival
wasn't exactly perfectly timed.
The dag-gum UAV crashed
right as Dr. Landrum's
driving up.
DADDY: Rockets going off,
hitting the trees...
TRAVIS: Hey!
Hey, there's Dr. Landrum.
I just played it cool,
hoping that he wouldn't notice
that something was really wrong.
ROG: I know he saw that.
TRAVIS: We've had a few
little ups and downs.
We just did
a rocket test, and...
DR. LANDRUM:
Rockets and guns, huh?
TRAVIS: Rockets and guns
and helicopters.
LANDRUM: Oh, well,
that's a mix.
TRAVIS:
We're gonna tweak some things,
so, Daddy, why don't you
take him over to the test field,
and we'll meet y'all over there
in a couple minutes.
We've set up
a field test with targets
to put the drone
through its paces.
But we're in trouble.
We've only got a few minutes
really to fix this thing,
so the next test flight is gonna
be in front of the UAV expert.
ROG: We put it back together.
We're expecting it to work.
At least that's what
we're telling the expert guy.
TRAVIS: Turns out those legs we
added to the bottom of the drone
affected the balance just enough
to keep it from flying right.
So we redistributed
some of the weight.
I think that should do it.
The key thing for this project
is that it can be carried
in a backpack
by a single soldier
in the field.
Now, I've assigned Michael
and Pete to solve that problem.
I'm kind of excited to see
what they've come up with.
Is this the backpack you made?
MICHAEL: Well, it's a backpack.
You said, "Protect the UAV."
TRAVIS: Can you even
get that thing on?
It's this huge box that
you just slide the thing in.
There's no disassembly
of the UAV at all.
I can't see a soldier
wearing that into the field.
But it is too late
to fix that now.
Hopefully we can
impress Dr. Landrum
with other aspects
of our design.
DADDY: Yeah, there's some
pressure on it
because you don't want
to mess up
in front of a guy like that.
And I figure we're about to.
LANDRUM: I finally got a good
look at their drone design,
and it's unique,
to say the least,
but I'm gonna
reserve my judgment
till I see it in action.
TRAVIS: Put it in,
be careful.
Don't tear up the rockets
or whatever.
Y'all figure that out.
Alright, so, Brian,
what we're gonna do
is I've set up a war game.
And we're gonna put Rog
out there somewhere.
He's gonna take the gun,
he's gonna go hide,
and he's gonna be a sniper.
So then I'm gonna crawl in
through the woods
somewhere here,
and I'm gonna
come out and decide
this is the right place
to deploy the UAV.
And then we're gonna launch it.
It can be controlled from the
tactical operations center here,
and you guys will be able to
watch it on the big screen.
And then, when we're done
taking out the sniper,
we've got some
larger vehicles over the hill
that we're gonna go
and take out with the rockets.
Michael, did you put targets
out there like I said to?
MICHAEL: You will be surprised
when you head out there.
TRAVIS: So you did put
some targets out there.
Rog and I
got our paintball gear on,
and he took off
to go hide and play sniper.
ROG: Yeah, I had
a real good hiding spot.
It was real snaky.
You know how snipers
like snaky spots.
TRAVIS: Then Michael
helped me get the backpack on.
I started easing out
into the grass and hiding,
trying to find a good place
that I could deploy this thing
and then go look for Rog.
TRAVIS: Hey, Michael.
MICHAEL: Yeah, go ahead.
TRAVIS: I think I found
a pretty good spot.
Rog can't be too far away,
so I'm gonna start getting ready
to deploy this thing.
MICHAEL: 10-4. We're set up,
and we're waiting on a signal.
TRAVIS: Here we go.
I took off running,
and I turned control over to
Daddy back at the command post.
Shoot him.
If you can find Rog,
start shooting him.
ROG: Yeah, I went both guns
blazing at the drone.
It wasn't doing anything.
The propellers
would just eat it up.
DADDY: I'm looking at Rog,
and I'm thinking,
"This is my chance.
I've got him in my sites,"
so I pressed the trigger.
ROG: You got me!
DADDY: I got Rog.
Now, he said
he wasn't gonna get hit,
and I agreed with him.
There's no way we'd hit him.
MICHAEL: Oh, you got him!
DADDY: And I zapped him
right in the chest.
ROG: I'm out!
LANDRUM: For this next test,
I'm not so sure they're gonna
be able to hit their targets
with these rockets.
MICHAEL: We're moving towards
the tanks and the trucks.
DADDY: Now we're gonna try
to take out the convoy
of tanks and trucks
with our rockets.
Alright, here we go.
MICHAEL: Oh, we launched
the first rocket.
Daddy: Oh, missed--
[laughing]
TRAVIS: Y'all missed it.
Y'all hit it a little better.
MICHAEL: That second shot...
Missed it on the second shot.
Rog: Oh!
TRAVIS: There we go! Yeah!
When they started
firing off those rockets,
I wasn't sure if they were
hitting anything.
And then I saw
a big fireball go up,
so it was clear they hit
one of the targets.
MICHAEL: Oh, yeah.
After I set up the targets,
I also doused them in gasoline.
Come on, hit that thing.
Come on, let me get
the nose down.
There you go.
[laughing and cheering]
DADDY: Got him!
PETE: Good job!
We're bringing this thing home.
We got all three targets.
Good shooting.
MICHAEL: That's incredible.
DADDY: I figured we'd crash
and tear it up
like we'd been doing,
but we actually got
the thing back in one piece.
TRAVIS: Did you get him?
DADDY: We shot him.
ROG: Which one of y'all
shot me, man?
TRAVIS: Look at that
right there. Who got him?
MICHAEL: That was Papaw.
TRAVIS: That's good shooting,
Daddy. Look at that!
LANDRUM: Weaponizing
a small system like this,
I really think this is something
DARPA would be interested in.
Overall, this was
just a great test.
I think it really has
a lot of promise.
TRAVIS: Our UAV drone
worked really well.
Putting rockets on there
and a gun was pretty neat.
So I think there's
some immediate
real-world applications
for our design.
Hula-hoop taters,
hula-hoop taters.
ROG: Right on, right on.
All this talk about
real-world applications
got me to thinking.
So I took my boys out, and we
did a little drone fishing.
Look at that fish!
He's too little.
We got to throw him back.
You want to touch him?
Okay.