ARTO SAARI: I first met
Dylan in Barcelona.
He was just a little kid, and
he had massive audios on,
birdhouse board, hat backwards,
long hair--
same long hair.
And he must have been
like 14 or 15.
He didn't talk much back then.
INTERVIEWER: He was
really quiet?
ARTO SAARI: Yeah, he
was pretty quiet.
I was recovering from my
first knee injury.
I wasn't able to skate,
but I was just wanted
to go out and stuff.
It was just me and him.
I ended up filming him on some
random spot, skating.
I was like, come on,
do something.
I'm pointing the
camera at you.
INTERVIEWER: You were filming?
ARTO SAARI: Yeah, I
was filming him.
And I think Anton was around.
So I just tried to shoot a
couple of photos and stuff.
But no, he didn't have
a crazy kid style.
It was like--
or maybe it was right at that
time that he started
developing it.
It was early, early stages
of his style.
No, he was already
good back then.
He was actually [INAUDIBLE]
before me, I think.
MARK OBLOW: Basically once he
started coming on all the
quick trips, he just started
coming into his own.
And then at that time, Reese
was a pretty big
influence on him.
And then Reese started
Rasa Libre.
And basically they were just
like, come to Rasa Libre.
And it was on.
DYLAN RIEDER: Reese asked me to
ride for him, Reese Forbes,
because he started
it with Matt.
He asked me to ride for him.
I was like, yeah, fuck
it, let's do it.
INTERVIEWER: It seemed like
it had really good
art direction, also.
DYLAN RIEDER: The graphics
were sick, man.
They had awesome graphics.
I think it was all like Michael
Leon and stuff.
I don't know if you ever
saw the board.
It was like, the wine
bottles, and like
the flowers and stuff.
And then there was this one with
this snake stuff on the
back of it, just blank wood.
There was a bunch
of cool ones.
I think a lot of people
were paying
attention to Rasa Libre.
It was such an awesome
company.
I think that helped me out.
ANTHONY VAN ENGELEN: I had seen
the kid around, skating,
and knew that there was some
special about him.
Because no one had seen anything
of Dylan either.
All he had was this Quicksilver
promo thing.
MARK OBLOW: I think the
TransWorld part really set him
from being a little kid to
being a good amateur.
HEATH KIRCHART: That was kind
of him coming into his own,
showcasing his style
of skating.
So the TransWorld video was
I think when probably most
people learned about him.
ANTHONY VAN ENGELEN: I feel
like he was on the--
he was working on that,
riding for Rasa Libre.
And then Rasa Libre fell apart,
I feel like, in the
middle of that video.
And he finished it out riding
Workshop boards.
I want to say that he did.
Or that transition was
happening, or something.
DYLAN RIEDER: I don't really
know, honestly.
I mean, I was pretty
young at the time.
I didn't think it was
like, oh, it's
going out of business.
I mean, whatever, cool.
MARK OBLOW: You know, at that
time, when the Rasa Libre
thing was going out, he had
numerous phone calls from
other sponsors that wanted
to hook him up.
Out of all the thing when the
Rasa Libre thing went-- he was
like, there was Omar, there was
Reese, there was all those
guys I was dealing with.
But Dylan was by far the most
that everyone was wanting.
Everyone was calling,
going, all right,
what's up with Dylan?
GREG HUNT: People were saying
that he kind of wanted to
maybe ride for Anti Hero,
but he wasn't sure.
Because he was through
Deluxe, too.
He'd been talking to
those guys, maybe.
MARK OBLOW: Yeah, obviously
he had to get
voted on to both companies.
I don't think he was voted on
completely with Anti Hero.
I knew he definitely looked
up to those dudes.
DYLAN RIEDER: They asked me
to ride for Anti Hero.
Which I was super psyched on.
Then I talked to Jim.
And he wanted me to
ride for him.
And I remember thinking, fuck,
I don't really fit the roster
for Anti Hero.
I'm not a super gnarly
pool skater.
Because at that time, there
wasn't any Vans on the team, I
don't think.
It was just Tony and Stranger
and Hewitt and stuff.
I went on an Anti Hero Vans
trip, but I didn't really get
along with one of the riders.
So I told Stranger
I was over it.
[LAUGHTER]
INTERVIEWER: Do you want
to tell me who it was?
DYLAN RIEDER: No.
Not really.
I probably shouldn't even
have brought that up.
At the same time as well,
AVE had asked
me to ride for Workshop.
So that was a big factor
in it as well.
I don't know.
I just felt that Workshop was
kind of more my steez.
And fucking AVE and
Dill and Heath
were my favorite skaters.
So I was like, fuck, I want to
ride for the company with all
the dudes I look up to.
Not too many kids get to say
they ride for their favorite
company with their
favorite skaters.
GREG HUNT: He got on right
before that TransWorld video
part came out that he was in.
And he just seemed like he
really fit, especially with
where Workshop was
at the time.
They were talking about starting
to do a video.
And at the time there weren't a
lot of young guys-- like new
ams on the team.
HEATH KIRCHART: I mean,
Greg was the main
motivation behind that.
He was really psyched
on Dylan.
It was all Greg trying to--
because Greg was working
on "Mind Field."
And at the time, he was like,
well, the video needs these
younger kids, and stuff.
And I agreed with it,
and everything.
And it did.
And so Greg was the
main motivation to
make the video better.
ANTHONY VAN ENGELEN: We were
starting the workshop video.
I was living with Greg.
It was 2000 fucking 6, or
the end of 5, I think.
And I think we were kind of
riding out that lull of when
Pappalardo had originally
quit.
It was a slow start.
And there was no real new
blood on the team.
And we knew we needed that in
the video and just for the
Workshop in general.
I remember talking to Greg.
And I was like, dude,
this kid--
Omar and Dylan being
a ideal package.
We were talking about both
of them at the same time.
We needed to kind of jump
on these kids, you know?