BRYAN IGUCHI: I guess I could
say an average person could
definitely become a
good snowboarder.
You know good enough to have a
great time in the mountains.
It's worth it, it's fun.
SPEAKER: It could take up to
a month to become a pro.
BRYAN IGUCHI: Oh at least.
BRYAN FOX: He's legendary
everywhere, but down there he
was you know, that type of thing
where like the Guch is
like from here.
There's not a lot of people
who are from Southern
California and really made any
sort of impact on snowboarding
in general.
I'd say Guch is like the most
influential Southern
California snowboarder.
That'd be my personal opinion.
PAT BRIDGES: Guch was a
sponsored skateboarder, I
think he skated for
EPIC skateboards,
something like that.
So even before he got into
snowboarding you knew he was a
skater which was cool.
BRYAN IGUCHI: I was 13 years
old and I got sponsored by
EPIC Skateboards out of
northern California.
But I actually got my first
skate shot in "TransWorld,"
Spike Jones shot it.
And I was doing a feeble grind
on like a flat bar in '89, I
think it was.
So the skateboarding
thing was always--
I was trying to go pro doing
it but then I started
snowboarding at the same time.
And just kind of shifted from
skateboarding to snowboarding.
KEVIN JONES: When I started
snowboarding, I really thought
it was gay.
I mean, in gay in the true
sense of the word.
I was like wow there is other
people out there like me, they
skateboard and they snowboard,
wow this is cool, maybe it's
not as gay as I thought
it was.
And then you saw like these
trend setters, you saw all
these guys that are--
Guch especially, just this
little short guy with these
huge jeans, and then the irony
was after a day of shredding
they would get wet, and when
the sun would go down, and
you'd be riding in them , and
they would turn into these big
bells, these frozen bells, and
your leg would just be like in
this thing.
It was like--
it was the worse like coldest
trend in snowboarding to date.
But that era was just funny.
But it was like--
it was the whole attitude
of the snowboarders and
skateboarders back then,
it was like rebellious.
And everybody made fun of you
because you wore big jeans,
but you were like yeah
that's right.
You don't understand man, you
don't understand what I'm
doing with these jeans.
TERJE HAAKONSEN: I met
Guch, just kind of
signed up with Burton.
He was riding in big baggy
jeans, he had a small bong in
his pocket, he had super long
hair, he was from SoCal, he
loves his chips and
salsa, and he
introduced me to a few things.
KEVIN JONES: Guch kind of has
this lure to him, this like
ninja, Japanese, like mystical
Guch, and there's this shot of
him with like-- it's all
back-lit and there's just a
huge pony coming off,
you know the soul--
you know I'm hardcore, I listen
to punk rock music, I
skateboard, but I'm
also very soulful.
He's just looking off into the
distance like, you don't even
know what I'm looking at right
now, what I'm looking at is
totally heavy, and
you have no idea.
It was freaking awesome.
BRYAN IGUCHI: I guess--
once I got out of junior--
Well I did that, it's mostly
junior college, and once I got
out and moved up to Big Bear,
and that was kind of the
beginning of snowboard parks.
That was the first time that a
mountain had given like full
permission to just build jumps,
and build these features.
And no one really knew how--
we didn't really know at the
time how big to build them or
what really kind of features,
so we started experimenting.
The technical aspect of it
was just accelerating.
It was like we've built this
like skate park, where it was
like kind of bowled corners and
banks long runs, and then
gaps, and then we put up
rails, and everything.
The riders around were just-- it
seemed like every day there
was some new trick going on or
there was just really intense
amount of progression happening
in that park.
DAVE DOWNING: Bear Mountain
was like the only real
snowboard park.
Like they're building jumps
and Mike Parillo was like
digging this half pipe with
a chainsaw, it was
pretty raw back then.
And Bryan was just definitely
the innovator of the whole
group there.
He started doing those like
shifty backside 180s off these
hips and stuff and I remember
just everybody trying to do
shifty backside 180s like
Bryan Iguchi did.
There's this one rainbow rail
that is pretty famous, it was
like a piece of a chair lift
tower that was just laying in
some scrap pile and Parillo like
drug it out and stuck it
in the snow.
That was like one of the first
like metal rails in a
snowboard park, Bryan used to
just kill all that stuff.
BRYAN IGUCHI: The word got out
then people from all over the
place were coming down.
There was people from the
Northwest and East coast, and
then people from Europe,
and we kind of--
the snowboard park just caught
on and pretty much changed the
way people were snowboarding.
It really blew up and it
created the X Games.
It just kind of created this
environment where snowboarding
could really progress on a
level where there is--
there was a lot of spectators,
and events, and things.
It seemed like a lot of things
were happening at that time.
TERJE HAAKONSEN: He would
always do something
amazing on the board.
He was like the guy who could
do a lot out of little.
Guch was really into spinning
and all the little jib things,
he was a really good
skateboarder, still is.
So there was a lot of
jibonks and lot of
tail and nose maneuvers.
BILLY ANDERSON: I guess like one
of his influential things
too were just like all the
nose butter stuff.
Like that was one of his deals
just like spinning around from
his tip to his tail, and
ollieing, and bouncing around
with one foot, that was
all stuff that no
one had really done.
BRYAN IGUCHI: It was probably
two months after I moved to
Big Bear, there was a big pipe
contest at Snow Summit, and I
was living in my Jeep and
whatever, and I really wanted
to do this contest.
I got started--
ride the bunch and felt like
maybe I could do--
maybe I could go pro
or whatever, that's
what I wanted to do.
It was the first pro contest I
entered and halfway down my
first run my binding
broke, and I didn't
qualify for the event.
And I was so bummed,
wasted that money.
I don't even know what I was
thinking, I was just pissed.
Next day, I went out and I was
just riding the pipe at Bear
Mountain, just doing my
thing, just sessioning
with a couple friends.
It was a nice day and
the pipe was good.
So I was having a good session,
and went to take a
break to grab some water, and
Tim Pogue was the team manager
of Burton snowboards and he
was there with some of the
team and had seen me ride during
the contest, or in the
practice for the contest in that
morning, and approached
me and gave me his business
card, and said, give me a call
in two weeks, I'll be in
the office and I'd
love to help you out.
BILLY ANDERSON: It's kind of
crazy because when I think
about it I don't think of him
as really a progressive pipe
rider for the time.
But then when you start talking
about it, he was one
of the ones that was really
pushing it at those times.
The early-- and I think it's
in A Lively Ride, he does a
cab nine in the pipe, and a
bunch of switch stuff, and a
ton of spinning.
I think he was one of the first
ones to really kind of
take that up and I think, Hard
The Hungry and The Homeless, I
think he was doing some 900s.
PAT BRIDGES: But he was also--
in A Lively Ride, he was doing
Alley-Oop McTwists and tail
grabs on this quarter pipe that
couldn't have been more
than six feet wide
and 10 feet tall.
It was really, really
impressive to see.
I mean here's a guy who was
buttering, he was trying to
hook 1080s, 9s, off
of everything.
And he was ruling on McTwists
and stuff like
that, it was sick.
DAVE DOWNING: That's when he
was filming The Hard, The
Hungry, and The Homeless.
And then after that, Burton
brought Bryan
in and helped him--
Bryan helped Burton develop
the twin, which was that
question mark Ouija twin
that was pretty famous.
BRYAN IGUCHI: I think it was
early enough in snowboarding
there was a big change
happening.
It was kind of one of those
things you go, well here go
travel with Mack dog
and go film, and
then go to these contests.
So we filmed between the
contests and kind
of just road tripped.
I just jumped in the car
with him, we drove
from event to event.
But it was more of the filming,
we would go out and
film, hook up with locals
at different
places and go film stuff.
And the project turned out to
be The Hard, The Hungry, and
The Homeless, that was
the first snowboard
film I'd worked on.
That was where my career kind
of shifted to is more the
filming stuff, it was
just kind of--
that was gaining in popularity
more than the events.
The events were kind of you know
I would say pretty well
dominated by Terje
and everyone.
And it was just more of a--
I don't know, it just seemed
like it was a better
opportunity for me.
DAVE DOWNING: Guchi
seemed like he
just came out of nowhere.
And it's interesting because
all the other riders, they
still had to do contests and
stuff, with the exception of
like Damian, and those guys.
But he was the first pure
freestyler who actually just
seemed like first he did movies,
then he did contests.
BRYAN IGUCHI: I've never
had the best
luck with the contests.
I ended up feeling frustrated
a lot at contests.
It's just one of those
things, I don't think
competition's easy.
I remember Dave Seoane came up
to me at the ASR show in San
Diego and he said he had
this concept for
this snowboard movie.
We're going to all jump in these
Cadillacs, and drive
around, and road trip around
the states, and make a
snowboard movie.
I'm like that sounds awesome,
who's going to go?
He's like well I got Terje, and
Ranquet, and John Cardiel,
I was like done,
let's do this.
We'd go shred all these spots
but then we'd go skate as
much, if not more.
It was like on that trip, I
remember skating Burnside with
him, and some mini ramps
in Colorado.
And just everywhere we went
there was like-- we would hook
up with the skaters or we
would hook up with the
snowboarders, or whatever.
It was a really cool time.
DAVE DOWNING: He basically
took off with Dave Seoane
during the Roadkill filming
sessions, he was gone for a
couple months.
I didn't even know what was
going on until that movie came
out and then I was like, whoa
Bryan was doing that, it's
pretty sick.
PAT BRIDGES: And then you saw
him in the Vulcan movies.
A Lively Ride, was the first
Vulcan film I saw him in, and
then obviously he had a lot
of clips in The Garden.
BRYAN IGUCHI: Throughout the
process of making it, we just
kind of went out, OK we're doing
Vulcan snow project, and
Wooly the owner, he'd be out
in the field with us in the
back country hiking filming the
super 8 and Troy Eckert.
It kind of all came together at
Sonora Pass in California
and that's where we came up
with the name, The Garden.
We would go up there, we'd camp,
and hike these jumps,
and we'd have these amazing
sessions where it would be
exhausting long days, hiking
around, and just having a
blast, and sitting around the
campfire at night telling
stories, laughing,
and partying just
having a good time.
That's when we were like this is
the butterfly garden, this
is The Garden.
This is the movie, this movie's
about this, this is
what snowboarding is about.
It's hanging out with your
friends, and going out and
finding these places
that are special.
It was a really kind of a
liberating experience for all
of us to be able to get out from
the ski resorts, from the
crowds, and from the
crazy park scene
that was blowing up.
I mean, making The Garden was
probably still to this day the
highlight of my snowboarding
career.
It kind of got me inspired to
continue to search, and
explore, and recreate that
kind of feeling.
And been trying to keep that
dream alive by riding.