that has ever existed in the past.
Most decisions were made by kings, politicians, statesmen
but nothing based upon resources.
To better understand the meaning of a Resource Based Economy
picture an island somewhere in the South Pacific.
And you really want to know how many people
can that island support and to what degree
can the extravagance of the island be maintained.
First, you have to know how much wood there is
how much water, how much arable land.
Once you do a survey of the resources of that island
that can best be the method for determining
how many people it will support.
If the materials do not exist, you can only design a culture
based upon the materials that do exist.
You can only grow food based upon the arable land area
and the water surrounding the island
the fish, crustaceans, all the other things.
And if you have an agronomist on your island
or a series of them, they can advise you
as what is best to grow in that tropical region.
So you really need technical competence
in order to arrive at decisions that make sense.
You cannot arrive at decisions
that make sense by consensus.
By asking people what they want.
You have to find out what the island has to offer.
And that's what you can determine the future by.
All other systems will fail.
Politicians have opinions about everything
and information about nothing in particular.
Therefore you understand
that the decisions are not made by the majority of people.
They are made by the majority of people that have technical competence
that have information in the areas you wish to excel in
and methods of scientific scales of performance.
If you have a million sincere people that have no technical competence
I can assure you, nothing can be accomplished.
So you have to ask the questions:
Can we build a society of sustainability?
If you have no information as to the availability of resources
you cannot undertake such a project.
Suppose you have a shortage of resources.
That's the function of research labs:
to make alternative materials
that will substitute for lack of materials.
Technicians do not tell you what to do or how to live.
They merely carry out the function of designing elevators
transportation units, bridges, housing systems.
They do not tell people what to do, what to think or how to live.
That's a mistake that most people make.
They think that a Resource Based Economy
has technicians that also tell you what lifestyle to use.
No they don't. The resources determine that.
All that the technicians do
is build a system that can utilize those resources
for the benefit of all the people involved.
It has to be global.
If it's not global, if you have most of the resources
and most of the building equipment and most of the automated machinery
and most of the arable land and most of the drinking water
countries that do not have that will attempt to invade your country
and take what they need.
Every nation wants a piece of the pie. Keep that in mind.
So, to the degree that you try to live a sustainable life to yourself
will not work because other nations
that lack material will invade you.
In the rebuilding of cities throughout the world
you have to consider how far those cities are from resources.
That means available materials: concrete, steel reinforcement, etc.
If the cities are near that source
then it becomes more efficient to design the cities
as systems operations, meaning that the city itself
must meet the needs of the people that live there.
We announce on television what is available
and what is not available at the time
and when it probably will be available.
So the public has information of where to go
to access whatever it is that they need.
So people will have access to more things than they've ever had
in a monetary system.
More things and more opportunities will be available.
All of the cities are designed
to utilize the minimal amount of energy for maximum service.
In that way, we conserve energy
so that we can handle more people.
There are people throughout the world that do not have access
to high energy systems.
We will be able to provide more for human need
if we use efficiency.
Naturally, if we fail to do that
you can only take care of a limited amount of people.
The Resource Based Economy has millions of slaves.
But they are machines. And machines do repetitive
boring and dangerous jobs.
That's what the machines are for. They are not to put you out of work.
If they can turn things out faster than you, we don't need you working.
In fact we don't want you working in industrial plants.
We want you to go back to school and study whatever you're interested in
whatever you think you'd like to study
whatever you feel you'd like to understand better.
Unfortunately, money doesn't represent things in existence.
If you set a value on every tree
every inch of arable land, all the water
and you printed money proportionate to the resources
so that the money represents resources
then it can have meaning, but today
that is not accomplished. Although they may tell you
that demand will really bring about these things.
No, demand doesn't bring about the things.
Available resources do.
And if money doesn't represent available resources
it has no basis for social management.
When you live in a false society
that bases its wealth upon money
then that society itself will collapse eventually.
Not because I say so. Because it's not based on physical referent.
In a Resource Based Economy, where production and automation
can turn out more goods and services
there's no need to use money anymore.
If you really wish to put an end to war, poverty
hunger, territorial disputes
you must utilize all the world's resources
as the common heritage of all the world's people.
Anything less than that will remain
with the same problems that you've had continuously for centuries.
Now you have to consider what I'm saying.
The reason nations invade other nations is because of scarcity.
When a few nations control most of the earth's resources
you've got to have territorial disputes.
No matter how many treaties you sign or laws you make
if you don't declare all the earth's resources
as the common heritage of all the world's people
and bring all the separate nations together
in one unified system -
there is no solution other than that.
And this is why we recommend the Resource Based Economy.