- What were you doing?
- Incline crunches.
Where were you, anyway?
- On the treadmill,
where you left me.
- I didn't leave you.
You say that every time
we go to the gym.
- Well, I say that,
because whenever we're there,
We're never together.
I used to work out with you.
Now I just work out
at the same gym.
- Look, we go together.
We leave together.
That's together.
We go to movies.
We watch tv.
We surf the web.
Remember that "David goes
to the dentist" video?
That was funny.
- Nick, that's not what I mean.
I want to do something
together-together,
Meaning if you're not doing
a part of it,
And I'm not doing
the other part,
It can't be done.
- Well,
we can do that upstairs.
- Nick.
- Look, the problem is,
I'm the one always
planning stuff for us to do.
- Okay, that is not true.
- Yes, it is, all right?
Look, whenever I ask you
what it is you want to do,
You say, "I don't know.
I want to do
whatever you want to do."
And then I say, "I want
to do something you want to do."
And then you say, "good.
Whatever you decide
is what I want to do."
- Well, I do,
unless I don't want to do it,
Which I don't know
until I do it.
- Fine, I'll tell you what,
you want to do something?
You decide what it is,
and I'll do it.
- Really?
- Really.
And when you come up
with something,
Just let me know.
Can I ask you one favor?
- Yes.
- After we do what you want
to do together,
Can we do what I want
to do together?
- Slow your roll, crook neck.
Let's worry about me first,
and then we'll worry about you.
- Mmm-Mmm, yes, indeed.
Ow.
sync and correct by dr.jackson
www.addic7ed.com
- Hey, good morning.
- Good morning.
- I didn't know
you were already here.
I've been calling your cell.
- Yeah, I came in early.
I'm trying to find something fun
for Nick and I to do together.
- Oh, what you looking at?
- Pottery making?
Seriously?
- Do you have a better idea?
I'm trying not to pick
the same old boring stuff.
- Well, if you're looking for
the new boring stuff,
You found it.
- Okay, Nick said that he'll do
whatever I want him to do.
It's on me.
Oooh, now, this looks fun,
and it does not look boring.
- Salsa dancing.
- Yeah, I love salsa.
It's so sexy,
the moves, the clothes.
- Yeah, well,
have fun with that.
- Okay,
what's wrong with salsa dancing?
- Nothing is wrong with it.
I used to love it,
until the accident.
- What?
Gigi, you didn't tell me
about any accident.
- It happened
about three years ago
When I met Jesus.
He would dip me,
spin me around,
Flip me over his back.
Oh, it was incredible.
And he was sexy and confident
and in control
And just amazing.
And that accent, ooooh.
- Do you need some time alone?
- No.
- Okay, so the accident?
- Right, I was hooked.
- Mm-Hmm.
- And then I made
the fatal mistake
Of moving the relationship
out of the studio
And into the street.
You dated him.
- Yes, it was a disaster.
It didn't even last a week.
I mean, in the studio,
he was the sexiest man alive,
But on the street,
he was broke.
I mean,
he lived in a studio apartment,
Wore the same pair of jeans
every day,
And when we went out to eat,
he wanted me to pay.
And he drove a car.
It was horrible.
I mean,
I can't remember the name of it.
It started with a "u."
- A "u"?
- Yeah.
- What kind of car
starts with a "u"?
- Used.
It was used.
- Okay, I love you,
but you have to be stopped.
- Well,
that will never happen again.
Do they have a word for people
Who are afraid
of poor Latin men?
- Yeah, Republicans.
- You know what?
I know one thing.
When I stare into
a Latin man's eyes, I'm done.
- Okay, I have an idea.
- What?
- You should come with us.
- And why would I do that?
- Because you have a crazy,
irrational fear,
And you have to face it.
Now, come here.
Come on.
- okay, I'll go.
But when I fall,
you better be there to catch me.
- Mom, look at these boots.
- Ohhh, those are so cute.
No.
- What?
- No.
- I'll pay you back.
- I'll tell you what,
Save the money you were
gonna use to pay me back,
Then buy the boots.
- What do you want?
- Who says I want anything?
I'm here to give you something.
- And what might that be?
- Advice.
Now, listen,
I've been watching you,
And I hate to tell you,
but you're never gonna get
What you want
if you keep asking like that.
- Really, genius?
What would you
have done differently?
- Okay,
let me put it like this.
The key to getting what you want
is making the person believe
It was their idea
to give it to you.
I call it the bait and switch.
- What?
- Bait and switch.
It's simple.
Just ask for something
The bait.
And en go for something
The switch.
Ha, watch and learn.
Hey, dad.
- What up, party people?
- Hey, dad, the mariners
are playing this weekend.
- I thought you didn't care
about baseball.
- I saw a game on tv, and it
turned out to be kind of cool.
You think we can go?
- I'll see what I can do.
- Yes.
- All right.
- So what.
You asked for tickets,
and you didn't even get them.
- That's not the point.
I didn't want them.
Okay, is there anything else
you want besides those boots?
- Well, there is this watch
I really like.
- Okay, so here's the deal.
The next time dad asks you
to be somewhere, you be late.
- What? That doesn't even make
any sense.
- Shh.
You'll find out soon enough.
- Get your finger off my face.
- Nick, baby, I found something
for us to do together.
- What is it?
- Salsa.
- Ooh, that is nice.
- So what do you think?
- About what?
- Salsa.
- The dance or the sauce?
- The dance.
Nick, I want to take
salsa lessons together.
- Dance class?
- You said you were down
for whatever.
You don't want to do this?
- No, it's cool.
It's just that I don't need
to take dance lessons.
I can dance.
- Baby,
although you do the robot
Better than any man or robot
that I've ever known,
I don't want to be doing that
with you when I'm 50, okay?
Now, salsa, on the other hand,
it's classy, it's grown-up,
And I get to look like this
when we do it.
- Ohh, okay, okay,
we'll go salsa dancing.
But can I ask you a favor?
- Yeah, what?
- When you go in there,
please don't do that.
- Mean.
- It looks like
you're stomping grapes, babe.
- Why do women
love taking classes,
Cooking classes,
painting classes,
Exercise classes?
- Look, it's salsa.
It will be fun.
- Look, all I'm saying is,
why do I have to take salsa?
I mean,
it's not like I'm going to Cuba.
- Duh.
You're not going for the dance.
You're going for the women.
- I'm married.
- Do this,
and you will stay married.
In my years of experience,
I have found there is nothing
sexier than a Latin woman.
And if you can get your woman
to bring out
Her innermost sexy latina,
you will be a very happy man,
Exhausted but happy.
- So Latin women are sexy,
but they're not the only one.
Look, they may be annoying,
But the Kardashians
are sexy...Mostly.
- No, they're Armenian.
Do you know what Armenians
are known for?
Excessive body hair.
You know what latinas
are known for?
Creative ways of ripping it out.
Trust me, you want to do this.
- You're serious.
- I am.
Can I come?
- I can't believe
you just invited yourself
To my salsa class.
- Yeah, it's weird.
It was like
I was trying to convince you,
And I ended up somehow
convincing myself.
- Lindsey, you are late.
You were supposed to be
home early to stay with Kevin.
- Yeah, I know, at 5:15.
- No, it's 6:00.
- Oh, it's my cheap watch.
It goes in and out, so it
doesn't keep the time anymore.
It's all raggedy and tired.
- Well,
you need to get a new watch.
- You think so?
- Yeah, I think so.
Look,
you need to be places on time.
You need a decent watch.
- What about this one?
I mean,
I know it's kind of expensive,
But I hear it's really good.
- $300?
What, you need a new watch so
you can be on time for your job?
You need to find
something cheaper than that.
- What about this one?
It's not as nice, but it's got
some extra bands
And some other stuff.
- That's more like it.
I'll see if I can find it.
- Thanks, dad,
and sorry about being late.
- Whoo, I am starting to like
this salsa.
Well,
you think you like it now.
Wait till I know what I'm doing.
Oooh.
- Yeah, you go, girl.
Get your fine self
on out of here.
You just go
and get yourself going.
- So, honey,
it sounds good, right?
And then at the end
of the series,
We will get to perform
an entire routine.
- Series?
As in more than one?
- Yeah.
Honey, you can't learn to salsa
in an hour.
I mean, really, come on.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
- That's okay.
Hey.
- Uh...
- What?
- Gigi, what are you doing?
What happened to you?
You look like an extra
from the color purple.
- I'm disguised
as a normal person.
- Okay, why?
- Because even if I can't resist
a salsa instructor,
Maybe if I'm dressed like this,
he can resist me.
Otherwise, I'll be shacked up
living off taquitos and beans.
- Okay, taquitos are Mexican.
- Shh, here he is.
- Hola, everyone.
Welcome to salsa 101.
My name is Diego salsa,
and this is my assistant, Elena.
- Hola, amigos.
Sorry I'm late.
Did I miss anything?
huh?
- It's my salsa shirt.
It was given to me by a woman.
She said I was muy caliente.
I'll give you details later.
- Ooh, I like your shirt.
You look like Fernando lamas.
- All right, everyone,
Elena and I have prepared
performance for you guys
So you guys could see exactly
what you're gonna look like
At the end of the series.
oooh. I like that.
Yeow!
Oooh. Whoa.
- All right, now I'd like you
to find your partners.
- See, honey, together.
- I got it.
I got it.
- Would you mind dancing
with me?
- No, I don't think so.
- Don't be shy.
The class needs to see
that even a normal-looking woman
That nobody ever wants
to dance with
Can become the woman she wants
through salsa.
- Mm.
- What's your name?
- Gigi.
- Gigi?
- Mm-Hmm.
- That is a beautiful name.
- Yep, thank you.
- It's the letter g...
- Yep.
- Twice.
- Did everyone find
their partners?
All right, this is where the man
takes the woman's right hand,
Place in his left hand,
take the right hand,
Place on her back,
and the lady takes the left hand
And puts it on her man's
right shoulder.
Then the man and his woman
look at each other in their eyes
And begin.
One, two, three.
- Okay, Nick,
you're not doing it right.
- No, I'm doing
what he told us to do.
- Okay, well,
let's just try it again.
- Okay.
- All right.
- Here we go, baby.
We got it.
- Okay, and one... ow, ow.
Nick,
you keep stepping on my feet.
- I'm trying to step
on the floor,
But every time I do,
your feet get in the way.
- Okay, okay, why don't we
have you dancing with Elena,
And why don't we take you
and your amazing
Technicolored dance shirt
over to beautiful Gigi?
- Ohh.
- Here we go. One, two, three,
five, six, seven.
One, two, three,
- Wow, you're a quick study.
You have great form.
- Oh,
you're not half bad yourself.
- Diego,
can you show me how to do that?
- I can certainly try.
- Okay.
- Here we go.
- Oh, sorry, sorry, sorry.
- Okay, let's try that again,
and...
- Oh.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, no, you know, I'm fine.
My feet hurt, so I'm just gonna
sit down for a minute.
Thank you.
- Wow, this is great.
Here we go.
- Whoo.
- Now let's try the shake.
- That's it.
- There you go.
- I'm so glad my wife took me
to this class.
- Good morning.
- A present for moi?
Did you look in it?
- No.
- Oh, my gosh.
It's so pretty.
Let's see.
"you are my flower.
"I cannot wait
to see you blossom.
"for my favorite student.
Diego."
Come on.
What is this?
Damn.
- A beautiful Latin man
sends you a sexy dress
And says he can't wait
to see you blossom,
And all you can say is "damn"?
- I mean, who knew he would go
all fat Greek wedding on me?
- Gigi.
- What?
- Maybe it's a sign.
Okay,
he wants to see you blossom.
Go ahead and blossom.
You can do this.
- Fine,
when are you going back?
- Oh, I'm not going back.
- Why?
Nick looked like he was having
a good time.
- Yeah, did you notice
it wasn't with me?
- No,
'cause I couldn't see much
Behind Martin's
technicolored dance shirt.
- I took this class
to be with Nick,
Not to watch him be
with somebody else,
And then I freaked out on him
when I got home.
- Wait, Suzanne.
You've never taken
a salsa class before?
- No,
I thought I'd learn with him.
- See,
that's where you went wrong.
I always do recon before I take
a lesson with a man.
I want to know
what I'm supposed to know,
Because even if I don't know it,
I know one thing.
I'm not gonna be out there
looking like I don't know
And not know it.
- Was that advice?
- You better ask somebody.
Did you like it?
- You know it.
Hi.
- Hola.
Suzanne, right?
- Mm-Hmm.
- You were here last night.
- Yeah, you danced
with my husband, Nick.
- Yes, I remember.
He's a little rough
around the edges,
But he's not bad.
If the two of you take
a few more classes,
You'll be out on that floor
in no time.
- Oh, well, that's actually
kind of why I'm here.
I was hoping to get a refund
on the remaining classes.
- ¿por que?
- What?
- Why?
- What why?
- The refund.
Oh, oh, okay, yeah,
I thought I would enjoy it,
But I didn't, so...
- Suzanne,
can I be honest with you?
- Si.
- Diego danced with you,
and afterwards,
He told me you could be
a decent dancer,
But he said
you're a control freak.
- What?
That is so rude.
- In salsa, the man has to lead,
and the woman has to follow.
Otherwise, it doesn't work.
- Okay, but I thought I was
letting him lead.
- Can I show you something?
- Uh, yeah, sure.
- Great, just relax.
- Okay.
- In salsa,
it's all about letting go,
Starting with this foot, back.
Good.
Let the music transfer
through your body.
You might want to look up.
- Oh, sorry.
- There you go.
- Now we're gonna go
to the side.
Good.
Now let loose.
- Okay.
- I knew you were gonna be
a natural.
And turn, side, ole.
- Wow.
Oh, goodness.
- Please come back to us.
- Okay, maybe I will.
- Can you bring your friend,
the one with the glasses?
- Here I am.
- Mi Amor.
- Yes, I Amor.
- Yes.
Yes, how you have blossomed.
My gift looks muy caliente.
- Gracias.
- I know you are a rare thing,
a delicate flower.
I would love nothing more
than to take our dance
Into the real world.
Can I please take you out?
- No, Diego.
I cannot go out with you.
I am just here
to face my demons.
- ¿por que?
- What?
- Why?
- What why?
- Demons.
Oh, yes, demons.
I can't let myself fall for you,
so this...
This will have to be
our last dance.
- Then we have to make it
a great one.
- Mm.
Ahh.
- Okay, Elena,
he just oozing sensuality.
How do you handle it?
- After a while,
you get used to it,
But why wouldn't she
want to go out with him?
He's beautiful, romantic,
and he can dance.
- And he's broke.
- Diego?
His last name is salsa.
His family owns the name salsa.
He's worth over $500 million.
- Are you serious?
- Just kidding.
He's broke.
- Okay, Gigi, stop looking.
Don't look into the light.
- What?
- Come on. Let's go.
Bye-bye, Diego.
Bye-bye. See ya.
Thank you so much.
No, no, no, this way.
Let's go.
- Can't help it.
- Hey, mommy.
- Hey, sweetheart.
- Wow, that's a nice new watch.
Where'd you get that?
- Dad bought it for me.
- Oh, well, what was wrong
with your old watch?
- It wasn't working, so
he thought I needed a new one.
- Oh, okay.
So, honey.
- Hey.
I just saw Lindsey's new watch.
- Yeah, she needed a new one.
Her old one was making her late.
- Really?
Let me guess.
So she was late because
her old watch wasn't working,
So she needed a new pink one
with rhinestones.
- Right.
- Mm-Hmm, Nick, watch this.
Lindsey.
- Yeah, mom?
- What time is it, honey?
- It's 7:38.
- Thank you.
- No problem.
- You see that?
She didn't even look
at her watch.
She uses her phone
to tell the time.
- Wow, she's good.
- She got me.
- Well,
I know now for next time.
- I hope so.
- Well, I've got a full day
ahead of me tomorrow.
I'm taking Kevin to the x games.
- Wow, that's really nice.
- Yeah, it's the least I can do
Since I couldn't get him
the mariners tickets.
- Mariners tickets?
Since when is Kevin
into baseball like that?
- It's a consolation prize.
I mean, I felt bad, so I got him
the x games tickets instead.
- Nick, hold on a second.
Kevin.
- Yeah, mom.
- So some mariners tickets
opened up this weekend,
So you can go to that
instead of the x games.
- They did?
- Mm-Hmm.
- Oh, well, you know,
maybe me and dad
Should just go to the x games,
you know,
Since dad already bought
the tickets and everything.
And, you know, somebody else
can go to the baseball game
Instead of me and you,
you know,
If they ever find out
that they can get tickets.
- You see that?
- I haven't seen a tap dance
like that
Since bring in 'da noise,
bring in 'da funk.
- Kevin, go to your room.
- Yes, ma'am.
- He was so believable too,
Like a little will Smith
with the ears and everything.
- Mm-Hmm,
it's the old bait and switch.
- Where do these kids learn
to do stuff like that?
- I don't know.
- I wish there was a class to
teach you how to deal with it.
- I think there is.
Hey,
you want to take it together?
Nick, wake up.
- Oh, this is the class
I want to take.
Bait and switch.
Sync and correct by dr.jackson
www.addic7ed.com