through a number of
degrading treatment for and kept them in
the isolation
and she said that uh... they were wrong
in
but cutting office customer one are our
exercise thereof for that month
period there were
wrong in the uh... how they dealt with
this so-called sunshine call where you
would actually be go out for twenty
minutes
they were on the stripping him down
naked
uh... et cetera in fact she says quote
at some point continuing p_o_i_
prevention of injury watch
over the recommend
insures overruled over mental health
professionals becomes excessive
absent a change in circumstances
so yes we were right all along
bradley manning worst-kept
and in circumstances
that would lead to his illegal
punishment
now what as a consequence of this
now i've said
you know even if he is convicted of the
charges of fraud of the that he should
be released now for time served you've
served a lot of time
he has been a malcolm warning to and
military george
already been illegally punished
enough is enough
that daniel ellsberg never went to jail
for the pentagon papers and
that obama administration the bush
administration report
leaked
classified information
all the time nobody ever went to jail
for it
that was suppose pro-government
now if you need information that is not
pro government all the sun
you get legally punish the victorian to
a military judge
instead though she has said
that she will
take some credit
and give it an applied to whatever has
had this might eventually be
all that is good news
how much a credit is in my estimation is
not great news it's nearly four months
of credits a hundred twelve days
that he gets for being uh...
for time served
on top
uh... because of the illegal punishment
it they will be whatever his final said
this is they will remove
on june twelve days from that sentence
when we
illegally punish people and in other
cases we tortured people in
this case we put them in isolation and
some proposed psychological torture in
fact it
united nations has already
uh... told us that we were in violation
of
of rules that led to this kind of
psychological abuse
uh... well i think
consequence of that should not be just
hey we give him another four months off
remember it's in the air facing a
possible
life sentence
so
there is a life send this to inform us
all of that doesn't help you much
time served
under free bradley manning
that's what the results should be but
today is a good day
it is the military
saying yes we were wrong and how we
punish them
and there should be consequences