senator roadblocks office now
he is uh...
republican senator and he's not be shy
in the past about
uh... pushing legislation that was in
favor of monsanto and snot any other
corporation though that might give him a
donation now mother jones reports that
he uh... was likely source
of the monsanto protection i did you
don't know what that was
as it was a little
attachment to the budget bill that had
to pass a budget though overall
but this attachment the need to be a
narrow all it wasn't saying that my
central it and other cultural companies
are protected from certain types of
lawsuits
now that's outrageous why would they
need to be protected if the did
something wrong they should go to court
like everybody else in the fatten them
selves
too for the congress to supersede the
courts and say no no
this is a company that's above the law
is absolutely outrageous course though
bombing administration did not object to
it and the democrats uh... are the ones
that uh... also
put it you know through while barbara
mikulski who runs that
committee in the senate is a democrat
allowed to go forward
as she says she's not in favor of it was
kinda funny way of showing it
'cause she allowed in the into the belt
if senator autoblog is the person who
really did put afford a smoother joe
suggests
well that makes some sense because they
also outlined where roy blount gets his
money so how much the j from monsanto
recently well back in two thousand eight
when he was in the house he to ten
thousand dollars from those the warm-up
uh... legalize pride
and twenty ten when he was running for
senate yet forty four thousand two
hundred fifty dollars and then twenty
twelve when they were getting ready for
the monsanto protection act
well that's what i had a pony up sixty
four thousand two hundred fifty dollars
well this is directly toured a lot
what about the pax was one of those
and the biz packs overall is all they
can call to companies have given
a fifty one thousand dollars in twenty
twelve to wrote a blog
and then twenty ten
who when he was running for senate
two hundred and forty three fx
the house and all that
narrower blunt
according to public citizen of the
watchdog over these matters
quote the legislative leader
who not only has surrendered his office
to the imperative monied interests but
who has also done so
with two studies you'll and efficiency
uh... he is also in the past for tobacco
companies
his wife works for craft
craft was also part of a
trying to defeat california probs this
thirty-seven
which would've label g_m_ os monsanto
also added to that effort
four borders will be married to
corporate interest in this case
uh... but you don't have to go that far
you're so that is num where yeses money
when i've done yet
coursework one is not the only one
taking mine
democrats are also taking other
republicans as well when you look at who
attire monsanto packed in its receipt
but as a small your twenty eleven twenty
twelve not a big deal but i was repair
but he had a sense of scale here on
off-year claire modesto thirty two
thousand city for nicely done
and that bronco obama number two a
twenty three thousand so my money weblog
a number three and wagner an eighteen
thousand five hundred amendments
mcconnell
we think that day and a regular little
bit more to uh...
the man who loves uh... all things
corporate
unfair but most angeles's for dr
and if that's not enough we've got more
so
contributions to candidates began that
off your twenty eleven twelve twenty
twelve
individuals related to monsanto
employees etcetera
here over a hundred twenty nine thousand
dollars
the candidates and los angeles packs on
average a three hundred an eighty five
thousand dollars
you see this is how you get
the monsanto
protection act
you just go to congress and say who
would like to legalize bright
and here's what you get
allotted takers
people go to
really neat
and what what does that their head of
that group
now you know
that's our government has bought every
single day
and that's how they got this outrageous
community put into our budget deal
have i told you before about wolfpack
back dot com
you know there and you know what we do
we fight back
i want to beat the sons of bitches