THOMAS MORTON: We're in the
goat house, basically.
It's like a farmhouse
kind of on the
other side of the mountain.
We slept here.
It's just from yesterday, this
kind of felt like a third
grade slumber party.
God, it's like the
whole fucking
yard is an alarm clock.
The day after PJAK's birthday,
we finally headed up to the
mountains to meet the female
division we'd be fighting
with, or at least hanging
out with.
The one-hour car trip across
one hill we were promised
turned out to be a nine-hour
journey that involved numerous
hills, numerous stops to get
the truck out of the mud,
possibly took us across the
Iranian border at some point,
and required a magic
[INAUDIBLE]
with the fourth and
final river.
This is it.
We just met the guys who are
going to be hanging out with
us, and they took our cell
phones so we can't sext while
we're here.
I kind of expected it to be kind
of buried in the trees
and covered with those weird
perforated leaf things they
put on helicopters and stuff.
This is pretty out in the open,
I guess, just incredibly
impossible to get to is all.
We took a short hike up the hill
to our soldiers' camp and
ran another awkward
handshake line.
This particular PJAK division
fights for women's rights in
and around the Iranian border.
Thankfully, after a grueling
morning trek, we caught them
just as they were sitting
down for tea.
FEMALE SPEAKER:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
THOMAS MORTON: How are women's
rights there--
better or worse than they are
for Kurdish women in like
Turkey, and Syria, and Iraq?
Is Iran the worst?
FEMALE SPEAKER:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
THOMAS MORTON: The leader of
the division took us on a
short tour of the camp, where
the women were all boning up
on their Apoism after lunch.
If you took away the sniper
rifles, they'd, basically,
look like college kids out
on a nice day doing their
[INAUDIBLE] reading.
We were still a little unsure if
this was really business as
usual, or if we were
being given the old
dog and pony show.
The division had a pretty
permanent looking bunker dug
into one of the hills, filled
with sleeping bags and posters
of PJAK martyrs they were
keen on showing us.
FEMALE SPEAKER:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
THOMAS MORTON: Again, a little
suspicious on the whole, is
this all just set up
for us, front.
FEMALE SPEAKER:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
THOMAS MORTON: Does everybody
have their portrait
taken when they join?
FEMALE SPEAKER:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
MALE SPEAKER 1: Finally, study
time ended, and the division
reassembled to run some drills
and show us what makes them
the most fearsome female
warriors in the Middle East.
FEMALE SPEAKER:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
THOMAS MORTON: Probably a closer
resemblance to, like, a
girl's summer camp than what I
would associate with usual
military drilling.
The Kalashnikovs are a little
different, but that could be
replaced by archery.
I don't know if I hit
the rock or not.
I feel like I'm getting all
the positive reinforcement
with everybody else though.
It's more about putting
in an effort.
FEMALE SPEAKERS:
[SINGING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
THOMAS MORTON: Just basic army
stuff, just having lunch on
the grass and then
line dancing.
FEMALE SPEAKERS:
[SINGING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
THOMAS MORTON: It's interesting,
I don't know,
every time you think of women
soldiers, I think of like Lt.
Vasquez in "Aliens," girls
butching themselves
up to meet the boys.
It's kind of refreshing to see
female soldiers who, on their
own, hold on to a modest
amount of femininity.
Shortly after the circle dance,
somebody radioed our
division leader that they'd
compromised their unit's
security by firing their guns.
And so, our time with the ladies
of PJAK came to an end,
with us completely baffled how
these very nice, but not
exactly professional, female
fighters could ever hold their
own against the Iranian
Revolutionary Guard--
that is, without a lot
of outside help.
But as confusing as it was to
watch a supposed crack squad
of PJAK guerrillas giggle and
clap their way through basic
calisthenics and introductory
riflery, it actually sums up
the whole Kurdish situation
pretty nicely.
There are sort of two competing
narratives with the
Kurds in Iraq.
In one, they're the classic
scrappy underdogs who, by dint
of their skill and sheer
commitment to their cause,
beat the greatest army in their
region and establish a
beachhead for their
future nation.
In the other, they are the
persecuted minority, who
appeals to the West to save them
from genocide, and are
now forever grateful for
America's intervention on
their behalf.
The thing is, they're
sort of both true.
And the Kurds are more than
happy to use whichever one
suits their needs at any given
time, and whichever one suits
the needs of their allies,
whoever those happen to be on
that particular day.
It's basically the old
schoolyard technique of
pitting the bigger kids
against each other.
I tell them, hey, Craig just
beat me up, and he says you're
too much of a pussy to
do anything about it.
But the Kurds have raised it
to the level of national
political philosophy, which is,
honestly, a pretty great
approach if you're a homeless
ethnic group sandwiched
between Iran, Turkey,
Syria and Iraq--
just provided the older
kids never catch on.
[MUSIC PLAYING]