type of health or seen health hazards
uh... which is completely disasters
before you comment and jump inject let
me tell you how this was done
first of all it was proposed by
and an honest member of the house we
don't know what is which is super
questionable
so
this is as usual
uh... politics as usual where they
justice
like out there must have felt what
deal would you like
oclc debate we don't know if that's the
day stating that they would only go to
judiciary committee or any other gotten
and committee
and by the way who ask for this
it's not republicans the democrats are
in charge the senate and it seems that
id originally
that idea came from the senate obviously
both the house and senate have to agree
to it by president obama has assigned it
anne got put in into a uh... budget deal
that have to pass
so this is what the intrepid
the budget deal has to pass some corrupt
politician which they're all corrupt
almost all corrupt right
says ok gut
i'm a sneak this into the bill ok
answers the bill passed the past they
have to vote for haha
and is no debate
if the president
didn't want that to be in the bill it
would have been in the bell abdullah
spare me like to go to the clintons
moods of the president as though they
did it
not about defeat of the senators and
representatives
listen if you put this in the bill i'm
not on on board board i will be toward
et cetera there's no way it's in the
bill
instead of course has always the mobile
app
and the corporates democrats alike
yaz hardly a plaza
appointed all i think you should think
about how we became worse that it is so
someone and they didn't know what
they're completely blown
one of the poison dart group unless
needed but wanted boxes so i really do
you mean
get out of jail free car and some sick
of the got a job regards the bankers get
one now these but you know companies
that are doing genetically modified
foods gets a j get out of jail free cart
you've got in trouble they had a
breakdown that
ever on you
local aberystwyth below what i have a
step in shorts
also useful for two thousand rides and
other daughter does another time within
the who served on the efforts so what
blood centers monsanto behave screw up
our entire food supply
who cares you know a lot of reading the
court
but look i daresay monsanto dead and you
have to understand these companies they
do a good as well as back right you know
they've increased
it they've got plenty of increasing the
food supply cetera now of course the
downside of mass until and other
companies in the field
is many for the we've done many stories
about that determination of the farmers
you know and then getting this involving
and other crops that might cause birla
probs
putting that aside what do you agree or
disagree opined that outrageous or the
balance of how you but look at all those
factors you can upgrade with a lot of
says know what has occurred
yes and i think that that's the
important thing to keep in mind here a
lot of times when it comes to you any
issue
uh... involving monsanto if monsanto
gets a pass at something people will be
like don't criticize anything anti
science but it didn't work this has
nothing to do with science
this has to do with consumer protections
this has to do with
you know making sure that you know that
these uh... the behavior of monsanto
isn't impacting the environment and
negative way and i love that you mention
that there are signs and downsized
monsanto of course they're creating
genetically modified crops beckett
withstand a hot climate change and the
horrible things that were already doing
to the environment but at the same time
no peer reviewed studies indicating that
g_m_ also are one hundred percent say
i know that at this point it's
conventional wisdom alex safe don't
worry about it don't worry about it
because i think i like that but support
letters will be pocket just released
and there's no question that we're not
talking about is any way shape or form
once said to have to do this religiously
key way
now if u are
i think you've got a permissive product
why would you get your bride politicians
to make sure they put the law and that
this is you can't be sooo
weicker's you worried about the that
you're gonna get sued what they know
that we don't know if i didn't question
monsanto before which i did i was just a
question of after this one
and by the way how much of the bride
politicians okay so the provision
success is viewed by many as a victory
by companies like as ingenta corporation
cargill uh... monsanto an affiliate tax
they donated seven point five million to
members of congress since two thousand
nine
and three hundred seventy two thousand
two members of stat of the senate
appropriations committee
yes seven half million dollars and they
probably do that i would go into the
hard having nothing to do with molly get
out of jail free card and again i keep
seeing job courses
civil litigation
but it's just term of art area in terms
of
being free of liability and so
i'd
if you thought you know bob was going to
bring you change you're nuts
phone safety czar
the food safety czar is the former top
lobbyist
or monsanto but was he a pot appointed
by it
president frodo block
archaic
guy loves corporations will do anything
for his lobbyist and donor friends
and he lobbied in in in in i'm sorry
argued ford two thousand eight
that he was gonna bring change into the
south dakota washington
where lobbyists and owners got special
deals
does this look like a steel this looks
like the exactly the kind of special
deal
the robot was said he would stop
instead always done instead that process
up
with bob insurance like this
he is a julliard and owner of fraud
so you think that's too strong
sat there for you these are the facts
you don't like the facts
you can't stand the fact
soon but such a nice guy voted former
couple times
this such a lovely smile but i can't dot
he has won a wonderful family has
he told me it was for change he's on my
tv side team democrat notes of fraud
is a politician just like the rest of
them
and he takes that money he doesn't
exactly as he is told