on youtube, this is Genesis Week.
[Music]
And a welcome to this episode of Genesis
Week, the weekly program of creationary
commentary on news, views and events
pertaining to the origins controversy,
exclusive right here on youtube.  Once
again in the top ten most talked about
videos in Science and Technology on
youtube, we bring you the information the
anti-creationists don't want you to see or
hear, and we show the glory of God in the
Creation.
Don't get lost in cyberspace, just punch in
wazooloo.com or genesisweek.com, and
you will find us, or click the
ever-so-convenient subscribe link up top.
I'm your host, Ian Juby
A live science article carried the bold and
revealing headline: "Belief in Evolution
Boils Down to a Gut Feeling."  Now I must
first make a disclaimer: The vast majority
of people I have met who are of
evolutionary persuasion, are good,
honest people who simply have never
heard any of the overwhelming evidence
refuting evolution and affirming creation -
after all, evolution has an army of judges,
lawyers and school policies to hide
behind and thus protect the masses from
those inconvenient facts.  Thus the reason
for this program, to educate people on
what they haven't been told.
Dealing with this subject regularly, I of
course run into many people who
religiously cling to evolution in spite of
the facts, not because of them.  And so
the live science article is an especially
interesting read.
The live Science team was reporting on
an article by Minsu Ha, et al., in the
Journal of Research in Science Teaching,
available on line for free
After waxing eloquently on how central
and important evolution is to biology, the
authors lament the fact that:
In what has to be the ultimate irony, the
authors never stop to ask questions like
"Do these people who understand
biology, perhaps have a good scientific
reason to reject evolution?"  Ohhh, no, no,
no, no, no! Instead, they go on to propose
that people who accept or reject evolution
do it based on... gut feelings.  The
researchers never stop to consider their
own psychological projection, that they
themselves are believing evolution strictly
because their gut tells them so, and not
because of any scientific fact.
I have some news for you folks:  There are
numerous lines of scientific evidence
which refute evolution, and in fact, the
evidence from biology is some of the
most powerful evidence refuting
evolution, hence the reason many
biologists reject evolution as the only
explanation for life and its diversity.  You
know, people like geneticists Dr. Kevin
Anderson, Dr. Jean Lightner and Dr.
Jonathan Sanford - co-inventor of the
gene gun.  Or Dr. Jerry Bergman who
holds nine degrees, two of them Phd's.
The good scientific reasons from biology
that refute evolution and instead point to
a Creator are too many to list, but some
examples are the origin of life,
codependency of systems within life,
genetic entropy, irreducible complexity,
the lack of biological mechanisms to
produce new, useful genetic information,
etc., etc...
Never considering even once that
evolutionary theory could possibly have
problems or - heaven forbid - be WRONG,
the authors make an interesting
comment:
Translation: Meh. We don't have the facts
to convince them, we just need to focus
on putting on a convincing show.
The National Center for Science
Eradication has decided to take on global
warming, now called "climate change"
because global warming was so
thoroughly refuted it's gotten a bad name.
Comparing global warming to creationism,
the NCSE has decided to take on this
battle in the schools.  Basically, teachers
in schools are feeling pressured to teach
the controversy (in other words, teach the
facts) of alleged "global warming,"
specifically the connection between
human activity and global warming.  This
is not difficult to discredit. We had an ice
age, we are no longer in an  ice age, and
the recession of the ice age had nothing
to do with human activity.  One good
volcano emits more "greenhouse gasses"
than the entire industrial world does in a
year. The correlation between sunspot
activity and global temperatures is
staggering, and let us not forget the huge
methane beds buried in the continental
shelves around the world, which contain
waaaay more methane than all of the cow
flatulations that McDonald's can produce.
So it's to be expected that the NCSE
would stand up for bankrupt "science"
and help defend teachers against those
who would like to see our children
educated with actual facts instead of
propaganda.
It's interesting to note that the NCSE is a
private organization, funded by private
individuals with unknown motives and
intentions. The NCSE has publically
supported open, flagrant bigotry in
academia towards anyone who dares
question evolution, and has spearheaded
most of the legal wranglings in a
desperate attempt to protect evolution
from scientific scrutiny in our education
system.  This group has always targeted
schools, and specifically aimed their guns
at propagandizing your children.  Although
they have "science" and "education" in
their name, it's akin to the so-named
"Planned parenthood" - an organization
which has nothing to do with planning, or
parenthood!
It is clear that the NCSE's actions are
anti-science, and anti-education.  Real
scientists don't seek court protection and
mandate for their theories to be taught in
our schools, and real science welcomes
scrutiny.  I welcome scrutiny in everything
I say, because I'm not afraid of the truth
and the facts.  Why does the NCSE so
venomously fight scrutiny? Hmmmm?
It's finally here, and the wait has been
worth it.  For those of you who caught my
good friend Spike Psarris's volume 1 of
"What you aren't being told about
astronomy", he has just released volume
2.  It was more of the fantastic
drinking-from-the-firehose information,
revealing God's astounding handiwork,
showing why there has to be a Creator,
and that the Creator of the Bible is the
most likely culprit.  Many of those in the
anti-creation community went into major
"damage control mode" when Spike's first
video came out - criticizing Spike
personally on blogs and on youtube, while
never addressing the scientific points he
made, or worse - trying to respond to his
points and making a bigger mess for the
evolution of the solar system.  In his latest
video, he takes on the origin of stars and
galaxies. One of the many points he
makes is showing how every secular
theory on the origin of stars and
galaxies....requires pre-existing stars.
This video is only a few more nails in the
coffin of the evolution of the astronomical
bodies, and you can get your own copy
from creationastronomy.com, for a
measely fifteen bucks. I highly
recommend the video, and am so looking
forward to volume III.
Homeschoolers: Carey Jane Clark has a
homeschool blog and is now holding a
"Think about it Thursday", starting   today,
where she has a segment devoted to
creation and homeschooling.  I'll be the
guest writer on the blog, and we'll attempt
to address common questions home
schoolers may have.  Here's the link to her
website.
[scary, dramatic music]
Wahoo! Mail for me?
I was again impressed with the comments
of CircusOfPrecision on youtube, who
posted dozens of very enlightening
comments - which were met by a barrage
of willfully blind individuals.  Too many
comments to repeat here, I'll simply
encourage viewers to take a look, and I
commend CircusOfPrecision - who
apparently is not a young earth
creationist.  I can only commend you for
your diligence in educating those who do
not want to be educated, and will simply
remind you that you are being read by
many others who are not commenting,
but are paying close attention to how you
have thoroughly and fearlessly decimated
those who propone falsehoods.  Precision,
for your valiant efforts in the intellectual
battle - particularly against those who
seem to have come to an intellectual
battle unarmed, I salute you!  I'd buy you a
Tim Horton's coffee, cause I'm sure your
head must hurt after the barrage of
non-sequitors and bad science that's
been hurled at you.
That was just such an excellent question
Johnbgroovy - thank you for writing in.
You are quite correct - an intelligent
designer is a vague concept - we need to
ask the question, if there is an intelligent
designer, then who is that designer?  and
how would you know?  Jesus claimed to
be the Creator, but hey - I've had people
tell me they were God.  Just because
someone claims they're God doesn't
mean they're God.  So when someone
comes up to you and claims they're God -
what's the first thing that comes out of
your mouth?  I don't know about you, the
first thing I said was "Oh ya? Prove it!"
Let's prove Christ is God.  He proved it
with so many miracles that even his
enemies didn't deny them - including the
miracle of rising from the dead.  Stalin
didn't do this, nor did Buddha,
nor did the flying spaghetti monster.
Islamics even specifically state that
Mohammed did not do any miracles, and I
actually agree with them when they say
they does not mean he was not a genuine
prophet. After all, the Bible referred to
John the Baptist as the greatest prophet
ever, and yet he did no miracle.  Rather,
the question here is, will the real and true
Creator God please stand up? Jesus did
countless miracles -but hey - Chris Angel
does "miracles" all the time, perhaps
Jesus was just a really good magician?  As
a further sign that He was who He said He
was, we have books written thousands of
years before His arrival that made over
400 specific prophecies about Christ -
that were all fufilled in Christ.  God told
the people of earth He was going to come
to earth as a human, to redeem us.
Basically He said "You will know it's me
because I will do this, this, this, this,
........"
He fulfilled those prophecies, including
where he would be born, where He would
die, HOW He would die, that none of His
bones would be broken, that He would be
betrayed by a friend, and for how many
pieces of silver He would be betrayed.
Finally, that He would rise again from the
dead.  No one else has ever done this.
That is how you know who the Creator is,
and this Creator rose from the dead to
show us He is the way, the TRUTH, and
the LIFE.
The Science Foundation said this:
Oh yes - you're right, the coelacanth has
changed in one way: its name.....which
was assigned by evolutionists who want
to make them out to be as different as
possible.  We have more variation in dogs
than we do in the fossil and living
coelacanths.  So the only change that has
happened, is in the name.  We see this in
multiple cases, such as the herring. The
fossil form is called Knightia, the modern,
living version which is identical in every
respect, is called Clupea.  The only
evolutionary change evident, is in the
name.
Orge121 had a couple of interesting
comments:
Well, I didn't think NephilimFree was a
ranting idiot, but thank you for writing,
and you know what? I don't mind
someone disagreeing with me, or saying
I'm wrong.  After all, I am only human, I
can make mistakes too, and I would like to
be corrected if I am in error. You'll
understand I typically ignore most replies
as they aren't even worth paying attention
to. They are simply assertions,
accusations, insults and red herrings
having nothing to do with whether or not
I'm right.  So I appreciate your demeanor,
thank you.  You also made a further,
interesting comment worthy of a
response:
I agree with your fossilization statement -
in fact, that was exactly my point: The
absence of a fossil in a rock layer does
not mean it was not present when the
layer was formed.  In other words, not
finding a fossil fish in, say, the Cambrian
does not necessarily mean that fish was
not there during the Cambrian.
Consequently, you cannot build an
evolutionary sequence based on any
supposed order of fossils appearing in
the rock record.  As for whales not
hanging out in coastal areas, well, the
entire whale watching industry is built
upon coastal whale watching. When I
went whale watching in Cape Breton, we
were never more than about a mile and a
half from the coast! In fact, I don't think it
was even that far!  But thank you for
writing in.
Yes, I did say that.  Look at the gene pool:
You had more variation in the bacterial
gene pool before the exposure to the
antibiotics, which wiped out a huge
portion of the population, leaving behind
bacteria - which already existed -
but now with less variation in their
genome. In other words, less information
in their genomes - genetic information
was wiped out - lost. This is reverse
evolution.
Yes, that would be the famous "Lucy"
skeleton.  If the evidence doesn't fit, make
it fit.  I covered this in Complete Creation,
part 16.
Indeed!  If you haven't figured it out
already, Teno is one of those people who
knows Joe Taylor personally.
And yes, even though I have shown
numerous lines of scientific evidence that
supports the paluxy tracks, lawilsom still
chooses to assert - with no evidence
whatsoever - that they are all fakes.  Ya,
somebody carved human footprints
underneath 18 inches of undisturbed
limestone. I'm one of the guys who has
helped break up that rock to expose
tracks, in front of multiple eye witnesses,
on more than one occassion - it's hard
work!  In fact, public excavations are held
ever year in the Paluxy riverbed by the
Creation Evidence Museum - it's been
going on for years.  There has literally
been hundreds of eye witnesses who will
attest to the human footprints uncovered
there.
SwordOfTheSpiritUK immediately
recognized the issue of human and
dinosaur footprints found together, and
its relation to the age of the earth. While
he is an old-earth creationist, his
comments and analysis has been very
interesting, and he's been documenting
his intellectual journey on his blog.  He
certainly has not let me get away with
anything, and has been a faithful skeptic.
I look forward to following his journey.
Well that's enough for this week - thanks
to everyone who wrote in, agreeing or
disagreeing, and thanks for watching.
Remember how easy it is to share this
program with your friends by clicking the
convenient "share" button, down below.
I'm your host Ian Juby, signing off for
now and reminding you that Jesus said I
am the way, the truth and the life - no
man comes to the father but through me.
We'll see you next Thursday.
Production Software was provided for
Genesis Week by the Big Valley Creation
Science Museum, located just 25 minutes
north of Drumheller, Alberta. In the heart
of the dinosaur badlands, the Big Valley
Creation Science Museum was built from
the ground up to give credit to our
Creator, portraying the scientific evidence
showing that creation is the faith that fits
the facts, and that evolution is the faith
that the facts have failed.
Visit BVCSM.com for more details.