PATRICK BROWN: My photographs
are different from me.
The photograph's a record
of what's been
happening in front of me.
It's not something
I've constructed.
If I'm able to give a voice for
that situation, then I've
achieved my objective.
And that's really important to
me as an individual, but also
as a photographer.
I love Bangkok for exactly the
same reasons I hate it.
I love it for its noise.
I love it for its intensity,
sweatiness.
And there's always some treasure
troves in Bangkok.
And for all those reasons,
it just drives me bonkers
sometimes, and I
have to leave.
But every place in the world
must drive people crazy and
happy at the same time.
My name is Patrick Brown.
I'm a photographer.
I've been based in Thailand
for the last 12 years.
And this is home for
me for the while.
[SPEAKING THAI]
PATRICK BROWN: I've traveled
all my live,
since I was about five.
Originally from England,
from Sheffield.
Grew up in the Middle East.
I spent some time
in South Africa.
And I spent some
time in Canada.
And finally, the family
settled in
Australia when I was 13.
I'm still doing what I did
when I was a young boy.
I'm still travelling, still
meeting interesting people.
I think photography for me was
the best visa I've never had
in my life.
I've been with racing
car drivers
I've been with homeless.
I've been with drug addicts.
I've been with politicians.
I've been with royalty.
It's one of the best vehicles
to move in and out of
societies that normally you
wouldn't be able to navigate
your way through.
That's my car that I rebuilt
when I was 18, modeled on an
old English car.
Took me about three months to
rebuild it, maybe even a bit
longer, actually.
I'm trained as a tool-maker,
which is somebody that makes
machines and stuff.
I really enjoy working
with my hands.
And I like the craft of
photography, not just taking
the photograph or the equipment,
but actually I like
to produce a photograph.
I like to go in the darkroom.
I find the darkroom very
therapeutic, just dodging
between the light and
making a photograph
darker or lighter here.
And it's hand-printed.
You can never make another
print exactly the same.
And I find that really
adorable.
I was incredibly naive about
what documentary
photography could do.
I was working in a multi-story
carpark.
And I saw a little snippet
about this guy
in the local rag.
And he was in Africa, where he
was the only surgeon for 2 and
1/2 million people.
So I sold my car and my
surfboard and went over there
and documented him.
And I was there for six weeks.
Six weeks was all I could
get off for work.
And I came back to Australia,
had an exhibition.
It raised a lot of money for--
his name is Robert Weeden.
We made awareness for
him in Australia.
And then it was published
in Australia.
And it won a couple of awards.
It was one of the pivotal points
when I realized you
could actually make a difference
with a photograph.
And it wasn't until about '96,
'98 that I made a decision I
could actually make
money from this.
And then started to do more and
more work with magazines
in Australia.
This is all animal trade, by the
way, full of animal stuff.
As you can see, everything's
under alphabetical order.
Only I know where to find it.
A colleague convinced
me, just get out of
Australia and come to Asia.
Have a look around.
If you don't like it,
you can move on.
And then I ended up in
Chiang Mai and met
some Burmese refugees.
They gave me access to places
I would never be able to get
to, and opened up a whole world
to me that I really
didn't know existed to the
extent that it did, and that
was the Burmese border.
This is on the Thai-Burma
border near [INAUDIBLE].
And then you've got actually
real tiger
teeth, and tiger claws.
And these are different
tiger teeth.
And they have different value
where they come from.
These are used as potency, or
protective elements regarding
the person that wears them.
They have amulets on them,
or into key chains
and things like that.
"Trading to Extinction," I
started working on it in 2002.
This is my first solo book.
And I had no idea what the
animal trade was about.
For me, the animal trade was
little trinkets selling in
shops at that stage.
And most of the world, I think
in some way, thought the same.
Four years ago, the statistic
was $52 billion annually.
That's what the animal trade is
worth, which rivals some of
the biggest electronic
industries.
One of my favorite statistics
from this whole project is
that there's more Bengali tigers
in Texas than there is
in the Bay of Bengal.
It's a huge industry.
And I would be still working
on this until
probably the day I die.
So there had to be
some physicality
of boundaries placed.
Southeast Asia was the spot.
And plus, I live here.
It made it quite logical.
This is patrolling in southern
Cambodian in a
place called Bokor.
That was really quite an
amazing trip, that one.
The first story I did was
anti-poaching team in Bokor.
And this anti-poaching team,
we'd go in on a night
insurgence.
And we would hunt down or trace
down the poaching team.
And most of the guys in the
actual anti-poaching team are
actually ex-poachers, because
there's nothing better than a
poacher to catch a poacher.
He knows his routine and
he knows his habits.
They're about to plan to do a
night insurgence, which I have
to say is one of the scariest
things to do, because you're
in total darkness.
And you can only just see the
person in front of you.
And the way your eyes work, the
center of your retina is
actually damaged from the
amount of sun it's had.
So you have to look out of
the corner of your eye.
That's the most sensitive
part of your eye.
That was a pretty intense
trip, that one.
This is a poacher that's
been caught.
And that's his name, his age,
and the crime, and where it
was, and the date, obviously.
And they did it to all the
poachers that they captured.
I have quite a lot of empathy
for the poachers.
A majority of the poachers
are just doing what their
ancestors have done,
which is hunt.
The Cambodian poachers that I
went with, I think they got
$10 or $15 for each monkey--
very, very little money.
They have very, very little
knowledge of where that
product's going to go.
This is pretty much all
I'll be taking.
So take my four cameras, my
Polaroid, the Rolleiflex and
my two Nikons, and three lenses,
and my film bag.
Welcome to Guangzhou
from Bangkok.
Guangzhou is close to the
Hong Kong border.
It's southwest China.
And it's the economic powerhouse
for this region.
It's very close to Tianjin,
which is the manufacturing
powerhouse of China.
Due to the wealth of the
manufacturing of Tianjin and
the money that's come in to
this area, this has always
been a fruitful place for
animal trafficking.
What I'm hoping to achieve is to
see where we are five years
down the track.
It's a 10-year project.
So where was I halfway through
this project I was
here the last time.
It's good to come back
and relive it and
see where we are.
And what I'm hoping to
find is that things
maybe have moved on.
I don't think the trade is
in any way dwingled.
I think they've just got smarter
about hiding it.
They're not as confident
as the used to be.
They know these things
do get out into the
world outside China.
So they're a bit more paranoid
about people with cameras.
-[SPEAKING CHINESE]
PATRICK BROWN: I never
ask permission.
I just get in there.
And I know I've got a very short
window of opportunity to
get the pictures.
As soon as you start to ask for
permission, people are not
going to be themselves.
And a few times, I push
it, and I push it.
If somebody's stopping me from
taking pictures, or tries to
stop me from taking pictures,
I push it even further,
because there's a reason
why this person is
trying to stop me.
Because he knows they're
doing something wrong.
So the hardest thing
in a photograph is
capturing an emotion.
So if I'm able to capture this
angry person trying to stop me
from taking pictures, it also
adds another little dimension
to the body of work.
We go into one pet shop which
specializes in selling fish.
One fish in this particular
shop, I think,
was worth about $10,000.
The people-- the owner of the
shop openly talks about how he
smuggled the fish in from
Australia, and smuggled them
in from the Philippines.
-[SPEAKING CHINESE]
-This is from the US.
PATRICK BROWN: US?
So that's an American
fish in China.
-Yeah.
They can make sure that--
-[SPEAKING CHINESE]
-Yeah, they don't really have
a legal channel to help you
ship it back to Australia.
He just confessed to me that a
lot of fish are smuggled in.
PATRICK BROWN: He did?
-Yeah.
PATRICK BROWN: These guys
are untouchable.
It's just not on the radar of
the law enforcement offices.
It's not important
enough for them.
Everything in the market
isn't endangered, no.
That's where that gray zone
of the wildlife trade
comfortably sits in.
And I'll use the crocodile
as an example.
2 and 1/2 thousand tons of
live animals go through
Heathrow a day.
You have a shipment of, say,
25, 30 crocodiles.
So the custom guys at Heathrow,
he's looking for
contraband, he's looking
for drugs.
But he's not a reptile expert.
So he counts 30 crocodiles,
ticks that off, yeah, move on.
In that 30, there could be
10 very, very endangered
crocodiles.
Guangzhou's also very famous for
its wild game restaurants.
But one of the most common
things is you can go choose
your alligator, choose
your crocodile.
And in this particular
restaurant, it's just out
there in the open.
And it's got its snout bound.
And guests, that's the first
thing the see when they walk
into the restaurant
is a crocodile.
I want that crocodile
to be chopped up.
And I want it for my dinner.
That's all you have to say,
and it will be done.
With the animal trade, the
consumption of animals, it's
more to do with you
are what you eat.
So you consume a piece of the
tiger, you'll inherit a part
of that tiger.
And you become more virile and
stronger and you'll fight off
a cold, or you'll beat
the arthritis.
Most of the animal is consumed
in some form or manner, or
used to develop a cream
or a soup or a tea, or
something like that.
We went to Safari World, which
is about 40 minutes outside
the central Guangzhou.
And it's just a huge
entertainment complex for families.
It revolves around animals.
There is a circus.
And there is a zoo.
And I do agree with them.
They're very educational.
And you need those
institutions.
But realistically, an
elephant in a zoo
is actually a prisoner.
They've got X amount of space.
And they know that X amount
of space like the
back of their hand.
Zoos make a lot of money.
They're a great money earner.
And the rarer the animal you
have, or the rarer collection
of animals you have,
the more people are
going to go see them.
Some zoos are legitimate,
and some zoos aren't.
The majority of zoos and in this
part of the world are not
so legitimate.
When we went to Safari World,
they have flamingos in
restaurants.
So people can have a nice
steak and watch a pink
flamingo, which is obviously
not native to Asia.
Then in another restaurant,
you have the White Tiger
Restaurant, where you can sit
down and have your meal and
watch probably one of most
endangered tigers in the world
walk around while you
have your meal.
And supposedly in this
particular institution, it has
50% of the world's population
of white tigers.
That's something wrong there.
I'm not an animal activist.
It's more about exposing those
subcultures in society.
The animal is not really
the story.
What's happening to the
animals is the story.
And that cause is actually the
subcultures of smugglers and
poachers and customers.
That's what I'm interested in.
My career as a photographer in
the last 10 years has been
focused around the
animal trade.
Every little penny I've
earned has gone
back into this project.
And one of the biggest
discussions that I had with
publishers was that it was
in black and white.
If I had shot this in
color, I think it
would have no problems.
It would have been printed
straight away.
But for some reason, because
it's in black and white, it
scares people away,
financially.
The reason I shot it in
black and white was a
really simple reason.
I really understand black
and white film.
I dream in black and white.
I don't dream in color.
So on a subconscious level, I
think black and white is more
of a powerful tool to let people
delve more into their
subconsciousness to actually
get a bit more
of a sense of placement.
They let their imagination go a
little bit further than they
would do if they were looking
at a color photograph.
For me, it really tells
a story in a much
more clearer sense.
We visited the Guangzhou
Medicine Market, which is a
very famous institution.
It's pretty wacky.
You see a lot of crazy things
there, from seahorses, geckos
drying on the street, turtles,
a multitude of different
creatures for sale, and parts
of different creatures.
What drives the industry
is naivety and greed.
Naivety in the sense of lack
of education regarding what
the health benefits from some
of these products do.
Rhino horn is one
of the classics.
If you consume a rhino horn,
mythology believes that you'll
be able to mate for two
or three hours.
It doesn't work.
But it's very porous.
So one of the tricks of the
trade is to soak the rhino
horn actually in the Viagra.
So that drives the
trade as well.
It's all this naivety.
And it works, because it's
soaked in Viagra.
A bag of [INAUDIBLE].
A few hundred years ago,
people would be
invited to a wedding.
And just the immediate family
would have shark fin soup.
And guests would stand around in
awe that they were able to
eat shark fin soup.
It was a very sought
after delicacy.
Now the wedding parties have
grown to 300 or 400 people.
And they all have
shark fin soup.
When you look at the shark fins,
you see the bags and
hundreds of bags
of this stuff.
And three fins basically
means one shark.
It's just a staggering amount
of sharks that have died for
something that's basically
cartilage and
doesn't taste of anything.
While we were in the medicine
market in Guangzhou, this guy
in a blue track suit comes up
to me while taking pictures.
And he's trying to sell me
some bear bile products.
He was a little bit
uncomfortable with the Chinese
watching him, and watching
the deal go down.
So we get him aside, and
we go talk about it.
-[SPEAKING CHINESE]
PATRICK BROWN: He said he bought
it off some guy who was
either from Tibet
or from Nepal.
And he got a customs official
on the border to
get it in to China.
And he's going to Guangzhou,
which traveling thousands of
kilometers to sell two items
shows you how much of a hub
Guangzhou is.
After 9/11, there was a big push
to find out who are the
people who are generating income
for the terrorists and
the smuggling routes.
And it wasn't until Congress
decided to put a lot of
funding into that, once it was
researched, it pretty much
took everybody by surprise how
big the animal trade was.
-[SPEAKING CHINESE]
PATRICK BROWN: What
about just there?
-[INAUDIBLE].
PATRICK BROWN: He wants to
keep the camera out?
-Yeah.
It attracts a crowd.
PATRICK BROWN: It attracts
a crowd.
I understand.
Well, he's doing something
that's legal.
We'll just stand in there.
And the camera will
stay out here.
We'll just stand in there, so
the camera doesn't come.
10 years in the project, I've
never had somebody literally
come up to me and want to do the
deal there and then, and
totally blase about it all.
He saw me as an opportunity to
try and make a quick dollar.
He wanted $1,000 basically
for a very small
amount of bear bile.
OK, thank you.
This is the last trip for
the animal trade.
This is it.
I'm 43 years old.
I've been doing this for just
under a quarter of my life.
A few months from now, people
will be holding a book in
their hands.
And it will no longer
be my book.
It'll be their book.
I always knew I would
get to this stage.
But now I'm here.
Actually, it's just kind of
weird that it doesn't actually
feel like it's really
happening.
It's 10 years in the making.
And it's going to where
I initially thought it
would always go.
It's quite a nice feeling,
actually, I have to say.
[MUSIC PLAYING]