200 TO 300 MILLION AT A TIME
OR THEY WILL EVENTUALLY DIE
AND BE REABSORBED.
THESE SPERM CARRY
THE MAN'S GENETIC MATERIAL
AND THEY ARE FULLY MATURE.
BUT THEY ARE NOT YET ABLE
TO FERTILIZE A WOMAN'S EGG.
THEY DO NOT ATTAIN THAT ABILITY
UNTIL THEY ARE ACTUALLY FAR UP
INSIDE THE WOMAN'S BODY.
THEY MAY STAY IN THE EPIDIDYMIS
THE BAG-LIKE STRUCTURE
ON THE LEFT
FOR SEVERAL WEEKS.
WHILE HERE, THEY DEVELOP
THE ABILITY TO SWIM.
A SPERM PROPELS ITSELF
BY MEANS OF A LONG TAIL,
A FLAGELLUM
WHICH LASHES VIGOROUSLY
FROM SIDE TO SIDE.
THIS EXTRAORDINARY ACTIVITY
HAS BUT A SINGLE PURPOSE:
TO DELIVER THE GENETIC MATERIAL
IN THE SPERM'S HEAD
QUICKLY AND PRECISELY
TO THE WOMAN'S EGG.
ON THE TIP OF THE SPERM'S HEAD
IS A LAYER OF ENZYMES
AND ENZYME INHIBITORS.
THE INHIBITORS
PRESERVE THE ENZYMES
WHICH WILL BE NEEDED LATER
TO PENETRATE
THE SURFACE OF THE EGG.
THIS IS HOW THE SPERM'S HEAD
LOOKS WITHOUT ITS ENZYME CAP.
THE MATERIAL OF THE HEAD
ITSELF IS LOADED
WITH THE ACTUAL
GENETIC INFORMATION
WHICH WILL BE TRANSMITTED
TO THE EGG.
THESE ARE THE STRANDS OF DNA
WHICH WILL BE TRANSFORMED
INTO CHROMOSOMES.
THIS IS ONE OF
THE MANY FUEL PACKETS
ARRANGED ALONG
THE MIDPIECE OF THE SPERM.
THE FUEL CONSISTS OF SUGARS
WHICH IS CONVERTED INTO ENERGY
FOR THE SPERM'S LOCOMOTION.
THE PROPULSION SYSTEM
OF THE SPERM'S TAIL
IS MADE UP OF A BUNDLE
OF CORDS, OR FILAMENTS.
THE FILAMENTS ARE COVERED
WITH THOUSANDS OF TINY HOOKS.
AS THE HOOKS INTERMESH,
THE WHOLE BUNDLE BEGINS TO BEND
AND THE TAILS OF THE SPERM
BEGIN TO WHIP AROUND LIKE THIS.
IT IS A PRIMITIVE, BUT HIGHLY
EFFICIENT, SYSTEM OF PROPULSION.
THE SYSTEM DOES NOT
FUNCTION PERFECTLY EVERY TIME.
ON THE AVERAGE, UP TO 20%
OF A NORMAL MAN'S SPERM
ARE DEFORMED
OR IMPERFECT IN SOME WAY.
PERHAPS ONE REASON WHY A MAN
PRODUCES SO VERY MANY SPERM
IS THAT SO VERY MANY THINGS
CAN GO WRONG
WITH THE SPERM THEMSELVES.
THEY MAY HAVE TWO TAILS,
LIKE THIS ONE.
SOME EVEN HAVE THREE TAILS.
IN ANOTHER COMMON DEFORMITY,
THE HEADS OF THESE SPERM
APPEAR TO BE NEARLY SEVERED
FROM THEIR TAILS.
THIS SPERM HAS BEEN ATTACKED
BY BACTERIA.
AND THIS ONE MAY HAVE
BEEN PRODUCED TOO RAPIDLY.
IT WILL NEVER COMPLETE
ITS DEVELOPMENT.
WHITE BLOOD CORPUSCLES,
THE LARGE, ROUND CELLS
ARE OFTEN FOUND TOGETHER
WITH DEFECTIVE SPERM.
THEIR PRESENCE INDICATES
THE LIKELIHOOD
OF INFECTION, FEVER
OR EVEN A COMMON COLD.
MOST OF THESE SPERM DEFORMITIES
COULD HAVE BEEN CAUSED
BY JUST A SLIGHT ELEVATION
IN THE TEMPERATURE
OF THE TESTICLES.
ENVIRONMENTAL CONDITIONS, TOO,
OFTEN DAMAGE SPERM PRODUCTION.
OVERCROWDING...
STRESS...
SMOKING...
CHEMICAL POLLUTION
OF AIR AND WATER...
OCCUPATIONAL HAZARDS...
RADIATION...
POOR NUTRITION...
ALL PART OF MODERN LIFE.
EVEN OUR MODERN CLOTHING
MAY AFFECT SPERM PRODUCTION.
TIGHT BLUE JEANS, FOR EXAMPLE
HOLD THE TESTICLES
UP CLOSE TO THE BODY
PERHAPS RAISING
THEIR TEMPERATURE
THOSE FEW CRITICAL DEGREES.
BUT IN SPITE OF SUCH OBSTACLES
HUMAN BEINGS HAVE BEEN
SUCCESSFULLY REPRODUCING
FOR MILLIONS OF YEARS.
SINCE THE FIRST ORGANISMS
SWAM IN THE SEA
THE CYCLE OF LIFE
HAS BEEN CONTINUOUS
FUELED BY THE NEED
AND THE DRIVE TO REPRODUCE.
AMONG HUMAN BEINGS
THAT DRIVE IS INTIMATELY LINKED
WITH ATTRACTION AND DESIRE.
AFFECTION AND ROMANTIC LOVE MAY
INITIATE THE DANCE OF COURTSHIP
WHICH MAY LEAD TO CONCEPTION.
SEXUALITY, AFFECTION
AND TENDERNESS
CAN ALL BE PART OF
THE COMPLEX RITUALS OF MATING.
BUT DESIRE AND PHYSICAL LOVE
POSSESS A SILENT LANGUAGE
ALL THEIR OWN
THAT SIGNAL PARTNERS'
READINESS TO EACH OTHER.
THE EYES ARE PART
OF THAT SILENT LANGUAGE.
VISUAL IMPRESSIONS STIMULATE
AND EXCITE SPECIAL NERVE CELLS
IN THE SEXUAL AREAS
THROUGHOUT THE BODY.
THE SKIN, TOO, IS PART
OF THE SILENT LANGUAGE.
IT IS AMAZINGLY SENSITIVE
AND RESPONSIVE TO THE TOUCH.
IT CONTAINS MILLIONS
OF THESE SENSORY RECEPTORS
WHICH WHEN STIMULATED
DIRECT MESSAGES
OF SEXUAL AROUSAL TO THE BRAIN.
MANY OF THESE ARE CONCENTRATED
IN THE BODY'S MOST RESPONSIVE
AREAS: THE EROGENOUS ZONES.
ONE OF THESE, THE MAN'S PENIS
IS DENSELY PACKED
WITH SENSORY RECEPTORS--
HERE SEEN AT
ENORMOUS MAGNIFICATION.
THEY RELAY MESSAGES OF
SEXUAL STIMULATION TO THE BRAIN
WHICH TRIGGERS THE COMPLEX
SEQUENCE OF EVENTS
LEADING UP TO EJACULATION.
THE LENGTH OF THE PENIS IS
MADE UP OF MANY SMALL CAVITIES
CALLED ERECTILE TISSUE.
WHEN A MAN IS SEXUALLY AROUSED,
THE SIGNALS FROM THE BRAIN
CAUSE THESE ERECTILE TISSUES
TO BECOME ENGORGED WITH BLOOD.
AS WE CAN SEE IN THESE IMAGES
FROM THE THERMAL CAMERA
THE SUDDEN FLOW OF BLOOD TO THE
PENIS RAISES ITS TEMPERATURE.
THE MAN'S BLOOD PRESSURE,
HEARTBEAT
AND RESPIRATION INCREASE.
AND THE BLOOD CAUSES THE PENIS
TO BECOME ERECT AND ELONGATED
SO THAT SPERM CAN BE MOST EASILY
DELIVERED TO THE WOMAN'S EGG.
IN THE EPIDIDYMIS, THE HUNDREDS
OF MILLIONS OF WAITING SPERM
WHICH WILL SOON BE EXPELLED
FROM THE MAN'S BODY
ACCUMULATE IN A MASS.
AS SEXUAL AROUSAL
REACHES ITS PEAK
THE ENTIRE MALE SEXUAL SYSTEM
MUST FUNCTION PERFECTLY
FOR EJACULATION TO TAKE PLACE.
COWPER'S GLAND...
PROSTATE...
SEMINAL VESICLES...
AND EPIDIDYMIS.
THIS IS THE ACTUAL JOURNEY
MADE BY THE SPERM.
AT THE CLIMAX OF SEXUAL AROUSAL
THE MAN'S NERVOUS
SYSTEM TRIGGERS
RAPID INVOLUNTARY CONTRACTIONS
OF THE MUSCLES
IN THE WALLS OF THE EPIDIDYMIS.
THESE PROPEL THE SPERM
UP INTO THE MAN'S BODY
ALONG THIS TUNNEL-LIKE TUBE,
THE VAS DEFERENS.
THE SPERM THEMSELVES
TRAVEL THE DISTANCE--
A LITTLE OVER 12 INCHES--
IN ONLY A FEW SECONDS.
THE SEMINAL VESICLES
RELEASE NOURISHING FRUCTOSE
WHICH BLENDS WITH THE SPERM
AS THEY PASS BY.
THEY MIX WITH
THE PROSTATE FLUID.
THE BLENDED SEMEN
APPROACHES THE URETHRA.
ITS TOTAL VOLUME IS ACTUALLY
ABOUT ONE HALF A TEASPOON.
THIS IS THE LAST LEG
OF THE JOURNEY.
THE SEMEN CONTAINING THE SPERM
IS FORCED OUT THROUGH THE PENIS
BY THE MAN'S
MUSCLE CONTRACTIONS.
AND AT LAST, IT IS EJACULATED
INTO THE WOMAN'S VAGINA.
AS THE SEMEN ENTERS
THE WOMAN'S BODY
IT IMMEDIATELY SLOWS DOWN
AND COAGULATES.
PERHAPS IT BECOMES THICKER
TO ENSURE THAT MOST OF THE SPERM
STAY WITHIN THE VAGINA
OR PERHAPS THE COAGULATION
IS A KIND OF DEFENSE
FOR THE ENVIRONMENT IN
THE VAGINA IS EXTREMELY ACID.
THE ACIDITY PROTECTS THE WOMAN
AGAINST BACTERIA AND INFECTIONS
BUT IT IS ALSO DANGEROUSLY
INHOSPITABLE TO THE SPERM.
NEARLY ONE-QUARTER OF THEM
WILL DIE ALMOST IMMEDIATELY.
ABOUT 20 MINUTES
AFTER EJACULATION
THE SEMEN BECOMES FLUID AGAIN.
THE SURVIVING SPERM
BECOME VIGOROUSLY ACTIVE
SWIMMING RAPIDLY AGAINST
THE DOWNWARD CURRENTS
IN THE WOMAN'S BODY.
THERE IS GREAT URGENCY
FOR THE SPERM WILL REMAIN
VIABLE-- ABLE TO FERTILIZE--
FOR ONLY 28 TO 48 HOURS.
THIS IS THE SOUND MADE
BY THOUSANDS OF ACTIVE SPERM.
( rumbling )
THE SPERM'S GREAT ACTIVITY
HAS BUT ONE GOAL:
TO FIND AND FERTILIZE THE EGG.
THERE ARE SO MANY OF THEM
THAT SUCCESS MIGHT SEEM ASSURED
BUT THE BARRIERS, TOO,
ARE NUMEROUS.
THE HIGH PERCENTAGE
OF DEFECTIVE SPERM
HAS ALREADY LOWERED THE ODDS.
SO HAS THE VAGINA'S
HOSTILE, ACID ENVIRONMENT.
AND THE WOMAN'S OWN DEFENSE
SYSTEM ATTACKS THE SPERM.
THEY ARE UNWELCOME CELLS
FROM ANOTHER ORGANISM
AND THEY ARE POTENTIAL ENEMIES.
HER DEFENSE CELLS AGGRESSIVELY
PROTECT HER FROM THE INVADERS
BY DESTROYING THEM.
THE SPERM ARE PROGRAMMED
TO SEEK THE EGG
BUT SOME OF THEM
TRY TO FERTILIZE
THE FIRST ROUND OBJECT
THEY FIND--
IN THIS CASE,
AN ORDINARY BODY CELL.
STILL, IN SPITE OF THE OBSTACLES
HUNDREDS OF THOUSANDS OF SPERM
MAKE THEIR WAY
UP THROUGH THE VAGINA
TO THE CERVIX--
THE MOUTH OF THE UTERUS--
WHICH WILL LEAD TO
THE FALLOPIAN TUBES AND THE EGG.
THE CERVIX SECRETES STRANDS
OF A SPECIAL FLUID PROTEIN
CALLED MUCIN.
DURING OVULATION,
IT IS VERY LIQUID
AND EASY FOR THE SPERM
TO SWIM IN.
THE STRANDS OF MUCIN
PROVIDE TINY CHANNELS
LESS THAN 1/100th
OF A MILLIMETER WIDE
DIRECTING THE SPERM
CLOSER TO THEIR OBJECTIVE.
BUT MANY OF THEM NEVER FIND
THE STRANDS OF MUCIN
AND THEY WILL DIE
IN THE VAGINA.
THOSE THAT SURVIVE
WILL SWIM UP THE MUCIN CHANNELS
TOWARD THE UTERUS.
THEY SWIM IN DENSE BUNCHES.
THE OUTER ONES
MAY PROTECT THE INNER ONES
FROM THE WOMAN'S ACIDITY
AND DEFENSE SYSTEMS.
ONCE INSIDE THE CERVIX
THE SPERM CONTINUE
ON THEIR JOURNEY.
SOME REMAIN HERE
PERHAPS TO PROVIDE A BACKUP
FOR THOSE THAT CONTINUE ON.
THE REST PROCEED UP
THROUGH THE CAVITY OF THE UTERUS
IN SEARCH OF THE EGG.
THEIR NUMBER IS
NOTICEABLY REDUCED.
HERE, FROM INSIDE THE UTERUS
WE SEE THE OPENINGS
TO THE TWO FALLOPIAN TUBES.
THE SPERM SWIM TOWARD THEM.
ONE LEADS TO THE WAITING EGG...
THE OTHER TO AN EMPTY TUBE.
ONLY HALF OF THE FEW
REMAINING SPERM
WILL SWIM UP THE TUBE
WHICH HOLDS THE EGG.
THE TUBES ARE LINED
WITH MILLIONS OF TINY CILIA--
THE SAME CILIA WHICH
HELPED DRAW THE EGG
FROM THE OVARY TOWARD THE UTERUS
AT OVULATION.
THESE CILIA SWAY CONSTANTLY
CREATING A GENTLE
DOWNWARD CURRENT
THAT THE SPERM
MUST SWIM AGAINST.
SOME SPERM GET STUCK
IN AMONG THE CELLS
LINING THE WALLS OF THE TUBE.
OTHERS LOSE THEIR
SENSE OF DIRECTION.
DURING THIS PART OF
THE SPERM'S JOURNEY
THE LAYER OF ENZYME INHIBITORS
AT THE TIPS OF THEIR HEADS
IS SLOWLY BEING WORN AWAY.
THE SPERM ARE FULLY CAPACITATED
AND ABLE TO FERTILIZE THE EGG
IF THEY EVER ENCOUNTER IT.
OF THE 200 MILLION SPERM
THAT BEGIN THIS LONG JOURNEY
ONLY ABOUT 50
EVER REACH THE EGG.
THE EGG IS SURROUNDED BY TWO
LAYERS OF THE NUTRITIVE CELLS
WHICH HAVE NOURISHED IT ON ITS
JOURNEY IN THE FALLOPIAN TUBE.
THE SPERM IMMEDIATELY RELEASE
THEIR DIGESTIVE ENZYMES
TO BREAK THROUGH THESE
PROTECTIVE NUTRITIVE LAYERS
IN ORDER TO REACH
THE EGG ITSELF.
AT BEST, ONLY ONE
WILL EVENTUALLY ENTER
AND FERTILIZE THE EGG.
THE JOINT FORCE
OF THEIR EXERTIONS
STARTS THE EGG ROLLING AROUND
LIKE A MYSTERIOUS
CELESTIAL BODY.