[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHARLOT DUBOC: Have you heard of
Full Figured Fashion Week?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Well,
not really.
FEMALE SPEAKER: No.
FEMALE SPEAKER: What's that?
FEMALE SPEAKER: No, I haven't.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Full Figured
Fashion Week,
what does that mean?
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHARLOT DUBOC: I was in New
York for fashion week.
No, not that one.
The First Annual Full Figured
Fashion Week.
The dress size in the US
is 14 and growing.
Sick of fad diets and stretchy
muumuu dresses designed to
disguise their lady lumps, these
women want to celebrate
their shape with couture
adaptations and sequins.
I came here to investigate the
extent to which the plus size
industry is really empowering
the fuller figured woman or if
it's simply a case of cashing
in on the fat dollar.
So we're going to the runway
competition to see a load of
models from all over America.
And they're going to just battle
it out on the catwalk.
Where are we going?
Five.
Here we go.
Hey.
How are you doing?
FEMALE SPEAKER: So
good to see you.
MALE SPEAKER: Likewise.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Thank you
so much for coming.
Put your hands together for
these beautiful ladies who are
going to rock the stage.
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE]
FEMALE SPEAKER: Ladies,
are you ready?
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE]
FEMALE SPEAKER: Let
me get some music.
DJ, please.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE]
MALE SPEAKER: Somebody that
wasn't full figured might do
that and they probably would
have broke down and cried.
But her being so confident and
her, she made it work.
And it took a lot of guts
and it took some
fortitude to do that.
And that's what it is.
CHARLOT DUBOC: When you see that
full figure on the cat
walk, what happens?
MALE SPEAKER: I just like
their attitude.
And it surprises me how
confident they are in them
self when society wants them
to be something else.
You know what I mean?
And I'm glad that they
embrace that.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHARLOT DUBOC: What are
you looking for?
What makes a winner?
BRANDON: If you feel sexy, if
you feel confident, if you
feel curvy, then you can
work the runway.
With no matter whether you're a
size 2 or a size 22, you can
still do it.
My name is Brandon Coats.
And I'm here today.
And I'm actually judging the
full figured and fabulous
competition.
CHARLOT DUBOC: What do you think
of this whole event?
What do you think of full
figured fashion week?
BRANDON: Plus sized women
for too long have been
marginalized and
not catered to.
So here's actually a market
where we celebrate plus sized
women in all their fabulosity.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHARLOT DUBOC: So, hi.
Your wife just won
the competition.
How do you feel?
MALE SPEAKER: I'm a lucky man.
I mean, not a lot of people can
say that they're married
to a model.
Bigger is better.
What can I say?
[APPLAUSE AND CHEERING]
FEMALE SPEAKER: I am ecstatic.
I mean, words can't really
express exactly how I feel.
I've worked so hard for this.
You know, you can be full
figured and healthy.
CHARLOT DUBOC: One of the
hilarious things that somebody
said to me was, it's hard to be
a full figured runway model
because your thighs rub together
and people don't
realize that.
[LAUGHTER]
FEMALE SPEAKER: That
is a problem.
CHARLOT DUBOC: And did
you feel emotional?
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah, I did.
I did.
I'll cry later.
CHARLOT DUBOC: But what--
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
MALE SPEAKER: Wait until it just
becomes fashion, not full
figured, not, you know, regular
figured, just fashion.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHARLOT DUBOC: After a raucous
start to the week, I went to
find out a bit about
the shopping
options for these women.
So we headed to a sample sale
organized by the fashion week.
What's this?
Curves in the City
Sample Sale.
Oh. my god.
So it's like "Sex in the City,"
but not at all like
"Sex in the City."
I don't know if I'm going to
be the only empty figured
person there.
Hi.
MALE SPEAKER: Good morning.
CHARLOT DUBOC: This way is
for the sample sale?
MALE SPEAKER: Yes, it is.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yes.
CHARLOT DUBOC: Thank you.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
CHARLOT DUBOC: Over there's
Brenda [INAUDIBLE]
She's the organizer for
the whole thing.
We've heard she's a bit of a
force to be reckoned with.
Hi.
I'm Charlot.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Charlot,
finally I got a
chance to meet you.
CHARLOT DUBOC: I wanted you to
show us your favorite store.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Oh.
It's going to be hard to narrow
that down, but I think
I know just the person.
CHARLOT DUBOC: Come on, then.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Come on.
Let's go shopping.
This is the layer patch leather
dress, which she has.
This is the royal fishtail
This is the stormy mesh dress,
which is fabulous.
It could be worn in the
summertime and wintertime,
which she has.
FEMALE SPEAKER: You just can't
get this type of fashion in
those sizes so readily
available.
With her, you just go online
and it's there.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Oh, anything
with ruffles, flowers, that's
all me right there.
Oh, this is beautiful!
FEMALE SPEAKER: Wear
your curves.
Love your curves.
Show your curves.
FEMALE SPEAKER: I wrote this
book, "Stop Dieting Now." It
really becomes the focus of your
life when you're trying
to lose weight all the time.
Diets create anorexic
thinking.
And if you talk to someone who's
had anorexia and you
talk to someone who is dieting,
the way they talk
about food is very similar.
The diet industry needs
you to fail.
But I also get a lot
of backlash.
CHARLOT DUBOC: What are the
sort of negative things do
people say?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Everything from
just repeating the same
diet paradigm of like, well,
it's just calories in,
calories out.
About you don't--
You know, all that.
To, you know, you should
go die, you know.
So, yeah.
It's pretty crazy.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Right now what
you're looking at is our True
Sheroes, plus size,
curvy comic book.
CHARLOT DUBOC: Are you here?
FEMALE SPEAKER: And I'm here.
CHARLOT DUBOC: That's you?
What are your super powers?
FEMALE SPEAKER: My super
power is I get my
powers from the sun.
She gets hers from the
gamma-ray bursts.
Then you have one with the
strength of 1,000 men.
That's pretty much
what we are.
We're not a fat girl movement.
We're all about the
woman with curves.
That's just who we are.
CHARLOT DUBOC: Tell us
what you've got on.
It's really cute.
FEMALE SPEAKER: OK.
This is body jewelry.
I don't know exactly
what it is.
CHARLOT DUBOC: So you're not
supposed to wear it with
nothing else?
[LAUGHTER]
FEMALE SPEAKER: Oh, my God.
We're feeling fabulous.
No, you always have an outfit
under there, especially if
you're under 21.
But if you're over 21 and
married like me and do it,
it'll be just fine.
Rock it!
I say, rock it!
[LAUGHTER]
FEMALE SPEAKER: OK.
I could tell you how
you grow your tits.
You and I can go together
because I need to lift mine
up, suck it out there.
They're going to suck
it out of me.
Put it in you.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Don't hate
'cause I just ate.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHARLOT DUBOC: We're going
to the world's
largest fitness class.
It's called Walking Curves.
I kind of didn't
dress properly.
But I'm going to do my best.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHARLOT DUBOC: What
is your aim here?
You don't want to lose
your curves.
FEMALE SPEAKER: People
have a misconception
about what health is.
You know, just because you're
a person of a certain size,
they equate that to
being unhealthy.
But that's a misnomer.
Because a person that's
a smaller
size could be unhealthy.
But because of the way
they look, you think
that they're healthy.
We got to help each other
along the journey.
FEMALE SPEAKER: So
let's do it!
FEMALE SPEAKER: Woo hoo!
Walking Curves!
[APPLAUSE AND CHEERING]
MALE SPEAKER: So what
we're going to do
is called the wobble.
Have y'all heard
of the wobble?
[SCREAMING AND CHEERING]
MALE SPEAKER: Oh, OK.
The wobble.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
FEMALE SPEAKER: I just want to
thank you all for coming to
Walking Curves national debut.
We might be a small group,
baby, but we
pack a mighty punch.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHARLOT DUBOC: Considering 78%
of Americans don't meet the
basic recommended activity
level, it was encouraging to
see that such an event
was part of the
fashion week schedule.
But just a stone throw across
town, nothing tastes as good
as being thin feels.
We headed to New York's high-end
shopping district to
try and get an idea of how size
is perceived among the
city's most discerning
fashion consumers.
Do you think stores like
Chanel or any high-end
boutique should be stocking
above a size 12?
FEMALE SPEAKER: I can't believe
I'm saying this, but I
don't think so.
FEMALE SPEAKER: I think that
people who are into high
fashion are very conscious
of the way they look.
And part of the way they look
dictates how much they weigh.
FEMALE SPEAKER: I don't know.
It's harder to make something
fashionable
if it's really large.
FEMALE SPEAKER: There are enough
secluded stores who
only exclusively sell
over size 14.
FEMALE SPEAKER: It just
depends on the person.
If you see a size 22 woman, you
know, slumping around in a
big, you know, potato sack, she
might not be attractive.
But if you see her in a
beautiful dress with lots of
confidence, I think that's just
as beautiful and fabulous
as a skinny girl.
CHARLOT DUBOC: If you went to
bed tonight, woke up tomorrow,
and you're a size 22,
what would you do?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Ooh.
I think I'd go to the gym.
FEMALE SPEAKER: I would probably
go on an immediate
diet because I would
feel awful.
I wouldn't leave my house
until I lost 100 pounds.
FEMALE SPEAKER: I would probably
start balling.
That sounds terrible.
But I'm actually on my
way to go shopping.
And I do know that if I go
shopping and I've just eaten,
I don't feel as good when I'm
trying on the clothes.
Just because everyone gets,
like, a little natural pooch
after they eat.
You know, it's totally
natural.
FEMALE SPEAKER: So I think
they'd be wasting their time.
I think they should do
petite departments.
That's where it's at
for high fashion.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHARLOT DUBOC: Dispute the
general feeling that plus
sized fashion should be kept in
the back of the high street
department stores, there are
numerous independent boutiques
popping up around the city such
as Redress, a plus sized
vintage store in Brooklyn
where I met Glen.
Glen, where are we?
What is this place?
GLEN: Well, you're at Redress
New York City.
It's a vintage and resale
clothing shop
for plus size folks.
The teggings are
really popular.
People come specifically
for it.
People will follow us on
Facebook or Twitter, come in
town from, like,
North Carolina.
And be like, where
are the teggings?
Because it's like a tight
and legging hybrid.
They're one size fits all, which
we do not say lightly.
We're not the kind of shop
that's going to be like, one
size fits all.
Because that would make someone
feel really crappy if
we're like, one size fits all
and it didn't fit me.
I'd be, like, man,
that's not right.
That says one size fits all
and it doesn't fit me.
Your store sucks.
But these--
I don't know what this
is made out of.
It's some magic material.
It's super comfortable.
It doesn't dig into you.
These little pins are $1 here.
And people buy them.
And they say things like,
there's no wrong way to have a
body, back fat is the
new cleavage.
My background is in queer,
radical, sex positivity.
And so that's my answer to how I
learned to know that it's OK
to have any kind of
body and feel hot.
But it's definitely a journey.
You got to work a little
bit to get the party.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHARLOT DUBOC: It seemed
appropriate that the finale
fashion show would be held in
the outsized, overstimulating
phenomenon that is
Times Square.
I got the feeling that what the
event lacked in subtlety
would be made up for in pure
entertainment value.
So we're going to go and see
what's going on backstage
because that's probably where
all the action is.
Hi.
FEMALE SPEAKER: We're backstage
at Full Figured
Fashion Week and we're
getting ready to go.
I got my iPod so I can
get my music going.
And we're ready to
hit the runway.
We're ready to go.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yes.
Yes.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Could
you do me a favor?
You could do your hair back like
that when you're walking
down the runway.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Sure.
FEMALE SPEAKER: It takes a lot
for a woman to be able to hold
this and be confident with it.
And I love it.
I just love my curves.
I love how they move.
I wouldn't wish to
be any other way.
FEMALE SPEAKER: This group of
people, all these designers,
were shunned by Mercedes
Benz Fashion Week.
And they don't think we're
real designers.
And I think they don't think
we're real women.
And we are real women who are
deserving of fashion.
We are deserving of couture.
And it's a mission of mine to
keep pushing the envelope
until we can get into
one of those shows.
Because we need to
be represented.
FEMALE SPEAKER: We're
going to be doing
pirouettes and turning.
And doing all sorts of things.
FEMALE SPEAKER: We have
about eight minutes
until the show starts.
Everyone's going
a little crazy.
I'm sure that most of
the models have
butterflies just like I do.
FEMALE SPEAKER: So, are
you ready for fashion?
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE]
FEMALE SPEAKER: I said, are
you ready for fashion?
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHARLOT DUBOC: I've never seen
full figured women presented
in this way or move
in that way.
FEMALE SPEAKER: It's
ovehwhelming.
What it is is that we're not
used to seeing that.
Like, women being so confident
about their size and embracing
it, and loving it, and out there
with clothing that you
would never think
to see them in.
It is emotional.
CHARLOT DUBOC: It
is, isn't it?
FEMALE SPEAKER: And I
cry at everything.
I have to tell you my
mom was a big woman.
And her two favorite words
was poly and ester.
[CHEERING AND LAUGHTER]
FEMALE SPEAKER: Y'all
know about that.
And to see the fashion today,
it's ridiculous.
I mean, one sleeved dresses,
sequins, it's just so much
beautiful fashion
to choose from.
And we're blessed to
have it today.
You guys looks beautiful.
Please give a big hand and
applause for yourselves for
being here.
FEMALE SPEAKER: They get excited
when you're excited.
I'm not excited.
Why are you in my face?
[LAUGHTER]
FEMALE SPEAKER: Sergeant
Runway, here.
CHARLOT DUBOC: I'm no stranger
to the bi-annual fashion week
rip tour of the big
four, London, New
York, Paris, and Milan.
There can be nothing so dull
as watching cadaverous,
androgynous-looking models walk
past you in clothes and
only just make it back
up the runway alive.
The atmosphere at Full Figured
Fashion Week was brimming with
a sense of triumph and unity--
nothing short of
life affirming.
It was very much a case of the
girls wearing the clothes
rather than the clothes
wearing them.
As a result, I nearly forgot to
look at the clothes, some
of which were outlandish, others
frankly quite ugly.
But the girls rocked
every last piece.
What are you doing
here tonight?
MALE SPEAKER: I'm here to see
beautiful full figured women.
CHARLOT DUBOC: That's
so great.
So you're a fan of the
fuller figured lady?
MALE SPEAKER: I am.
I am.
Yes.
It's all, like, shape and
proportion really.
And I like curves and voluptuous
women, really.
And I'm here to hopefully get
some phone numbers and meet
some new chicks.
FEMALE SPEAKER: We're showing
women that are classy.
Woman that love their bodies.
Women that are confident.
And we're showing women
that are fashionable.
And they will strut
their stuff.
They show what they got to show
and they have attitude.
And they respect themselves.
And absolutely, we need to
showcase that in the US and
around the world.
Men need to understand that we
are a whole lot of women
looking for a whole
lot of man.
MALE SPEAKER: There were some
that shouldn't have been in
high heels.
And there were some that I would
have rather seen in just
high heels, just by their
self, high heels
and birthday suits.
But, you know, 12 and
up, light skin,
long hair, don't care.
That's how we getting it.
CHARLOT DUBOC: It's
all finished.
And I have been honestly
overwhelmed.
Because I've never seen women,
full figured women, presented
in that way, celebrated in that
way, moving in that way
to the extent that I feel like
if I woke up tomorrow and I
was a size 16, 20, or 22,
I'd be like, let's go.
And that is amazing.
And I just think if the rest
of the world were affected
like I was, then things
would improve.
And I just think everyone's
got it wrong.
Everyone's had it so
wrong for so long.
And, I mean, hell.
These women are hot.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHARLOT DUBOC: To top it all
off, we were invited on a
celebratory cruise around
Manhattan Island
called Curves at Sea.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Good evening.
[LAUGHTER]
FEMALE SPEAKER: OK.
Would you guys stop rocking
in the boat, please.
Full Figured Fashion Week
started sort of like a little
dream of mine.
I went to my first fashion
event and I sat there.
And I said, something's
not right about this.
There had to be other curvy
girls in the world such as
myself who want to go to Fashion
Week and be able to
see the fashions come alive
via curvy models.
And they want to buy.
Because you want to
know something?
We have an incredible amount
of power through
our spending dollars.
What do you say?
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE]
FEMALE SPEAKER: OK.
So I'm sitting there.
And I'm like, you know what?
I need to do something
about this.
I am going to create my own
full figured fashion week.
And guess what?
The rest is freaking history.
So put your hands together
for Ms. Shonda Freeman.
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE]
SHONDA: Thank you.
Thank you all so much.
I just wanted to say that for
me, Gwen came to me at a time
in my life--
GLEN: Oh, Lord Jesus.
SHONDA: I'm sorry.
I just lost my mom.
And [INAUDIBLE]
understand, it's not
about fashion.
It is about respect,
inspiration, and all of us
empowering each other.
I feel like Full Figured Fashion
Week is a sisterhood.
And just God bless all of you.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yes, he is.
SHONDA: And keep you safe.
And always a lady first.
Thank you.
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE]
FEMALE SPEAKER: Repeat
after me.
Size!
ALL: Size!
FEMALE SPEAKER: Doesn't
bury our!
ALL: Doesn't bury our!
FEMALE SPEAKER: Our beauty!
[APPLAUSE AND CHEERING]
ALL: Our beauty!
FEMALE SPEAKER: Oh, my God.
Give yourselves a thundering,
thunder,
thunderous round of applause.
[APPLAUSE AND CHEERING]
FEMALE SPEAKER: Love and
kisses to you all.
Enjoy yourself.
And have a blessed, blessed
Full Figured Fashion Week.
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHARLOT DUBOC: As Shonda said,
Full Figured Fashion Week was
about much more than
just fashion.
I've been welcomed into the
bosom of what felt more like a
sisterhood than a
fashion crowd.
First, no one's denying that
it's everybody's right to feel
and look good, the question of
size and health remains a
massively divisive topic
in western society.
But at that moment, on that
boat, at one of the best
fashion parties I've ever been
to, I felt pretty convinced
that bigger is definitely
better.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
FEMALE SPEAKER: A big
cake for a big girl.
Fab, full figured is in.
[MUSIC PLAYING]