And that's definitely me.
I love that dish.
It's absolutely a big part of
the Hoof's identity, that
young, really talented cooks
come in here and find their
voice and become chefs.
BRANDON OLSEN: I came
up with this dish.
I wanted to do foie gras
and banana bread.
And then I realized
that I like eating
bananas with Nutella.
I also really enjoy
pain perdu.
So I made banana bread
into a pain perdu.
And then I combined it all.
JEN AGG: That's the genesis
and the story of the
restaurant---
really, I think , though,
is the cooks get to--
there's so much experimentation.
They're working with so many
interesting things.
They have to have a really
strong voice to begin with.
But I think every single person
who's come through this
kitchen has only gotten better
from working here.
[IMPACT SOUND EFFECTS]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
JEN AGG: Hi, my name's Jen.
I'm owner of the Black Hoof
restaurant in Toronto, raw-bar
and cocktail bar.
What would you like know?
One of the things that we are
most known for and almost
every diner has --unless
they're coming in
here all the time.
They might skip it
occasionally-- is the
charcuterie, the cured meets.
We make everything in house.
It's been something right from
the beginning, where--
it says it, actually, on the
awning-- charcuterie.
And that's the starting point
for what the Black Hoof is, is
that we cure our own meats.
BRANDON OLSEN: Small [INAUDIBLE]
char, pickles.
Bar, one, two, three.
JEN AGG: Brandon is the chef.
And he's really on top
of all of that stuff.
And he knows how to read the
molds and how to understand
when things are ready.
Because you have to be
very careful with it.
Is a very scientific approach.
BRANDON OLSEN: One of my
favorite passions in life is
to make cured meat.
Here's our charcuterie board
It's a combination of whole
mussels and salumis plus two
cooked products--
the mortadella and the
summer sausage.
And it varies from day to day,
depending on what I have and
what I want to use.
Spicy horse heart salami.
Summer sausage.
Pork mortadella.
Capicollo.
All my pork is whey-fed
Berkshire.
I have two farmers
that I deal with.
I have another farmer.
That's beef.
And then I also have a horse
farmer out in Quebec that I
get my horse hearts.
This is my favorite one.
This is beef and spruce.
It's like eating a
Christmas tree.
In the spring time, we go
out into the forest.
And we harvest the young spruce
tips, chop them up, and
put them in a salumi farce
and dry it out.
That's a charcuterie
board right there.
It's a labor of love.
[LAUGHS]
Vance!
Table 11.
JEN AGG: People are in awe of
what the chefs and cooks are
able to do on an
electric stove.
It's the way that we started
in the beginning.
I really love that this
is how we do it.
The smoked sweetbreads are
something we've had on the
menu, again, for a
really long time.
There are one of the
anchor dishes.
Sweetbreads are the
thymus gland.
So it's here.
And it's around the heart
in baby cows.
Smoked sweetbreads and tuna is
probably one of my favorite
Hoof dishes, my favorite
Brandon dish.
And you think about tuna crudo
and smoked sweetbreads.
Most people are like, I don't
know if I want have that.
It's so wacky.
It's so quirky.
It's so crazy.
But then it just works.
MALE SPEAKER: Know what I
can picture you doing?
Pull out that John Travolta
strut, listening to the Bee
Gees "Staying Alive."
BRANDON OLSEN: I could
probably do that.
JEN AGG: Being friends with
your staff, it happens no
matter what.
You can't avoid it.
So my extra super best friend
Ian is here because everyone
else that I know is working.
And Ian used to work here.
So it kind of counts.
The bond that we have
is so easy.
It's so--
we just pick up where
we left off.
IAN MCGRENAGHAN: I consider
myself a feminist, apart from
my previous womanizing
tendencies.
Insofar as you definitely
inspired me to stay in the
restaurant industry, despite the
fact that I thought it was
a chauvinistic douche-bag
industry.
And I mean that generally.
JEN AGG: It is a chauvinistic,
douche-bag industry.
IAN MCGRENAGHAN: No, exactly.
But you showed me that it could
be something different
than that, insofar as--
on a individual level.
JEN AGG: And you've hired
so many female managers.
IAN MCGRENAGHAN: Well, you
know-- oh, Colin's calling me.
JEN AGG: [LAUGHS]
Ian met us at the Hoof.
And then Ian, Brandon, and I
all went to Grand Electric.
It's this, like, taco
restaurant.
You may have heard of it.
IAN MCGRENAGHAN: Just tacos.
JEN AGG: Tacos and stuff.
Bourbon and tacos.
IAN MCGRENAGHAN: Yeah, dicks.
JEN AGG: Even though Grand
Electric and the Hoof don't
feel like the same restaurant, I
feel like they're connected.
IAN MCGRENAGHAN: Colin's
my business partner.
And he likes knife fights.
We use to live with each other
and also worked with each
other at Jen's restaurant.
JEN AGG: You almost
said great!
They took a lot of things that
they learned here and applied
them to a slightly different
model of doing things.
And they've just--
It's exploded.
It's so amazing.
COLIN TOOKE: We specialize
in fine Mexican cuisine.
We're going make something
for you tonight.
Albacore tuna ceviche.
Marinated albacore tuna there,
avocado mayo, tostada shell.
Now today, he's going to put a
little herb salad on top, a
little bit of crispy shallots,
tweaked Mexicano.
That looks pretty.
That's squid from Goo.
We stole it from Goo.
It's the best thing
ever in the city.
So we just replicate it
in a Mexican style.
He's going to make so it
doesn't fall over.
We marinate it, deep
fry it, sauce it.
Pretty grimy.
Squid sauce that we make, it's
peppers and sweetness.
We make our own mayo.
Come on, bro.
Yeah, we make our own mayo.
Oh, this guy's building
a mountain over here.
Put the serranos on there.
MALE SPEAKER 2: That's
about it.
There you go.
COLIN TOOKE: Squid, man.
JEN AGG: With Ian and Colin,
there was a bond
formed a long time ago.
And when they left,
it was so hard.
But I was so happy for
them and so proud of
what they were doing.
Ah, this is really good.
COLIN TOOKE: Brandon we--
I remember when you cried
the last day at work.
When I left.
You were.
Remember on my last
when you cried?
You remember when I left
and you cried?
IAN MCGRENAGHAN: Brendan
do you remember that?
How did--
Show me on the doll where
he touched you.
BRANDON: I'm in touch
with my feelings.
JEN AGG: Oh yeah, good idea.
Shots of bourbon.
IAN MCGRENAGHAN: This a reality
show about being real.
[DRUM ROLLS]
COLIN TOOKE: Come
let's be real.
IAN MCGRENAGHAN: 7 things
of the Pappy 20 year.
JEN AGG: Oh, wow.
BRANDON: That's good, eh?
JEN AGG: It's like a gentle
velvet strangulation.
Why are you wrecking
my fucking comedy?
I think we're going, Colin.
Let's get ready to go.
OK.
COLIN TOOKE: There we go.
JEN AGG: Now I'm kind of drunk
I see them a lot, but we
don't necessarily get
to hang-out a lot.
Oh Colin.
COLIN TOOKE: Bank walk.
JEN AGG: Ah, God.
Jesus, Colin.
Ah, shit.
That was really fun just to
be squished up in a car.
IAN MCGRENAGHAN: There's
something poking into
something else.
JEN AGG: [LAUGHS]
IAN MCGRENAGHAN: Oh, boy.
COLIN TOOKE:
[MAKES GAGING NOISES]
IAN MCGRENAGHAN: Oh, god.
Oh, god.
Oh, fuck!
JEN AGG: There's spittle.
IAN MCGRENAGHAN: He's getting
red and shit.
Ugh.
[JAZZ MUSIC]
JEN AGG: Ah!
Oh fuck, Colin!
Yeah seriously, puke.
It's all oozing.
Disgusting.
Cold Tea is the bar that we seem
to be going to the most.
We're overrun with
hipster bars.
And there are a couple
of cocktail bars.
Matt and his partners, of
course, totally nailed the
concept of doing
a hipster bar.
But also, hey, there might be
some people that want to have
a delicious cocktail.
That concept meeting each other,
it's the first time
I've seen that done.
And they do it so well.
And the design of the place
is just awesome.
The have a cocktail there.
Green Dragon, I think,
is what it's called.
It's tequila, muddled pineapple,
and cucumber, and
lime juice.
And it's so simple
and is so good.
Would you say this is my
favorite drink in the city?
SARAH PARNIAK: I don't know.
Would you say it?
JEN AGG: Normally,
I drink wine.
But for Sarah, I drink this.
[WHISPERS]
We should probably
have some shots.
Um, yeah.
Bourbon and Bronco, sure.
Is that a thing?
Taste it.
Really good.
I was actually going to
feed it to you, so
you'd look extra gay.
Get out of there.
No, no.
It's really good, right?
IAN MCGRENAGHAN: My ass pussy
was sweating last night.
JEN AGG: Guys, you're giving
me a headache.
IAN MCGRENAGHAN: Pussy?
JEN AGG: Yeah, I am getting
a headache in my pussy.
Oh, well!
Oh!
That's a good idea.
GROUP: Cheers.
JEN AGG: Pretty good.
IAN MCGRENAGHAN: What?
It's bourbon and Bronco?
Woo!
I could drink that
for breakfast.
MALE SPEAKER 2: Yeah,
you should.
JEN AGG: OK, we got to
go do nachos now.
I'm fucking going to die.
How do people have the stamina
for this shit?
It's fucking old, man.
IAN MCGRENAGHAN: Where are we
going for the munchies?
JEN AGG: Ah, Black Hoof?
IAN MCGRENAGHAN: Sick.
JEN AGG: I think it's
pretty much--
hey.
It's a spoon.
This is all a spoon.
It's one giant spoon, except
for Colin, who doesn't get
spooned at all.
COLIN TOOKE: I don't
fucking care.
I ain't fucking [INAUDIBLE]
JEN AGG: Oh, bullshit!
You love spooning,
no question.
COLIN TOOKE: Fuck that.
JEN AGG: Colin, don't
be a dick.
[LAUGHTER]
IAN MCGRENAGHAN: Oh!
JEN AGG: I think this where
we're going to eat--
BRANDON: It's like you're
breaking and entering.
JEN AGG: To eat nachos
or something.
I really don't understand how
I was physically able to put
that nacho platter together.
That was something.
[LAUGHS]
I'm too old for all
that drinking.
And I'm actually still
recovering from that.
So thank you very much
for all of that fun.
We're going to have some fairly
ghetto nachos, even
though we've already had
Mexican food tonight.
But this is more like
whitey Mexican food.
We did sort of a Mexican-Tex--
Tex-Mex kind of influence,
with lots of cheese.
Because that's not really
super Mexican.
Grated three pounds of cheese.
Brandon made this--
This is a chili tongue, right?
BRANDON: Yeah.
JEN AGG: It's like chili
but made with tongue.
Brandon, this smells awesome.
BRANDON: It smells awesome.
Looks like cat food, though.
JEN AGG: Doesn't matter.
It's nachos.
Mm, la!
All right.
It's pretty basic salsa.
I don't even want to brag
about what's in it.
It's whatever.
But it is agave syrup.
It's really good.
OK, into the oven with
you, Nessie!
One thing that I think is really
important is a real
sense of family.
And I know that's something that
everyone in the industry
says and pays lip service to.
But they're saying it.
And then there's actually
doing it.
There's actually caring about
the people who work for you.
And there's-- you know, you
want to come, when you're
spending this much time in
a place, you want to come
somewhere where you
can be happy and
comfortable and feel good.
That was the worst.
That was just a mess.
[LAUGHS]
MALE SPEAKER 3: No it wasn't.
JEN AGG: No it wasn't.
Brandon is--
may be--
may be an undiagnosed
narcoleptic.
And that's been the been
the joke around
here for a long time.
There's people everywhere.
There's nachos everywhere.
But that's his special
skill is that he can
sleep anywhere, anytime.
It doesn't matter.
Yeah, and I don't think
that'll ever go away.
I think that's his trademark.