CARL AZUZ, CNN ANCHOR: We`re a week and a
half away from Halloween, the presidential
election is two weeks off and you are right
on time for a new week of CNN STUDENT NEWS.
My name is Carl Azuz, let`s go ahead and get
started.
First up, protesters in Lebanon, including
one former prime minister, are speaking out
against Lebanon`s current prime minister.
They want him out of office. Lebanon is home
to around 4 million people. It`s located in
the Middle East, on the Mediterranean Sea,
right next door to Syria. Some observers are
concerned that the violence that`s been going
in Syria could spread to Lebanon where it
has already. Last Friday a car bomb went off
in the Lebanese capital of Beirut. Three people
were killed including the country`s intelligence
chief. Syria spoke out against the attack,
but some Lebanese officials blame Syria for
it. Yesterday, after the intelligence leaders
funeral protesters fought with security forces
in Beirut. The crowd threw rocks, police used
tear gas to break up the protests. Several
people were reportedly injured.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Is this legit? Someone
is officially recognized as a saint when he
or she is canonized.
This is true. In the Roman Catholic Church,
canonization is the act of recognizing a saint.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: The Roman Catholic Church recognized
seven people as new saints over the weekend.
The canonization ceremony included some history
as well. For the first time, a Native American
was named a saint. During a special mass in
Saint Peter`s Square on Sunday, Pope Benedict
XVI and other worshippers celebrated the new
saints. The pope praised Kateri Tekawitha
for living a life of service. Tekawitha was
a member of the Mohawk Tribe, sometimes known
as Lily of the Mohawks. She converted to Catholicism
and served as a nun.
This week is a special time for another world
religion. It`s Hajj, one of the five main
observances of Islam. Millions of Muslims
participate in Hajj every year, traveling
to the city of Mecca in Saudi Arabia. Fionnuala
Sweeney has more on this annual tradition.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
FIONNUALA SWEENEY, CNN CORRESPONDENT: Its
name means "to set out for a place," and for
Muslims around the world, that place is the
holy city of Mecca. The Hajj has begun for
millions of Muslims, with pilgrims making
their way toward Islam`s most sacred site.
A cube shaped building called the Kaabaa located
in the Grand Mosque. For daily prayers, Muslims
face this structure from any given point in
the world. They are also required, if able,
to make this pilgrimage at least once in their
lives. And then walk seven times around the
Kaabaa, counter clockwise in a ritual called
the Tawaf.
IBTISAM SAYED HASSAN, EGYPTIAN PILGRIM (through
translator): Islam is beautiful, and we are
beautiful. We love all people, we love all
countries.
SWEENEY: The Grand Mosque`s gleaming minarets
soar skyward, pilgrims here cry as perform
the daily prayers from these towers, calling
the faithful five times a day. Fionnuala Sweeney,
CNN.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: To our viewers who are already on Facebook,
at Facebook.com/cnnstudentnews, we asked if
the release of a popular videogame could distract
some people from voting.
Awnna says "Maybe. Some people are so obsessed
with video games that they put aside the thought
of who`s running our nation."
Nicolo assumes that most people who are interested
in games aren`t as interested in the presidential
election."
Janie writes, "I play games, but I`m voting
this year. If someone lets a game to take
their right to vote away, then they are ungrateful.
Tyler doesn`t think video games will be distracting.
He says most people interested in Halo aren`t
old enough to vote.
Jamie says, "Games are better than politics
when the country is in dire financial crisis.
You need something to lift people`s spirits
and lighten the mood.
From Bridgette, "As a gamer, I get excited
for releases and caught up in the game. But
taking a few minutes to vote is not a difficult
thing to do.
From Andrew, if a person puts a videogame
before their future, then our country is in
trouble. And Cambria says, "As time goes on,
game releases could impact things if politics
doesn`t move into a region that everyone cares
deeply about.
But before we get to election day, President
Obama and Republican presidential nominee
Romney go head to head in person one more
time. It`s debate number three, it`s in Boca
Raton, Florida, it`s happening tonight at
9 p.m. Eastern. Before you watch the debate
either on CNN or at cnn.com/debates, Athena
Jones gives us a preview of what to look for.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
ATHENA JONES, CNN CORRESPONDENT: The third
and final face-off between President Obama
and Governor Romney will focus entirely on
foreign policy.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: No! Get out! Get out! Get
out!
JONES: From Afghanistan and Pakistan to Israel,
Iran and the changing Middle East.
(CROSSTALK)
JONES: The candidates will spar over America`s
role in the world, the new face of terrorism
and how to deal with the rising China. With
polls showing the president`s advantage over
Romney on foreign policy has narrowed since
the summer, Mr. Obama tried to highlight one
of his biggest foreign policy accomplishments
at a light-hearted charity dinner in New York.
OBAMA: And Monday`s debate is a little bit
different because the topic is foreign policy.
Spoiler alert -- we got bin Laden.
(laughter)
JONES: For his part, Romney could try again
to bash the president for his administration`s
messy response to the attack in Libya last
month and link it to what he says a failed
approach to the region.
MITT ROMNEY, REPUBLICAN PRESIDENTIAL CANDIDATE:
This calls into question the president`s whole
policy in the Middle East. Look what`s happening
in Syria, in Egypt, now in Libya.
JON ALTERMAN, CSIS, DIR., MIDDLE EAST PROGRAM:
The challenge for President Obama is going
to be defining the Middle East strategy going
forward. I mean, he`s had some successes,
he`s had some things that are still pretty
murky.
JONES: Romney`s task could be bigger.
ALTERMAN: I think for Romney, there is a broad
challenge, and that is how do you drill down
into specific policies? The Republican Party
hasn`t really figured out what a Republican
foreign policy looks like after the Bush administration.
I think Romney has been uneager to really
delve into that.
JONES: Still, while important to many voters,
foreign policy ranks far below the economy.
RYAN LIZZA, "THE NEW YORKER": If you are Mitt
Romney, every second you are talking about
foreign policy is wasted, which might mean
that Romney tries to break out of that and
tries to bring home some of the foreign policy
issues to domestic economic issues.
JONES: With time running out, this is their
last chance to make their case to millions
of voters in a single night. Athena Jones,
CNN, Washington.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today`s "Shoutout" goes
out to Mrs. Scarborough`s "Studizens" at Independence
Middle School in Virginia Beach, Virginia.
The Rangers, Kings, Bruins and Jets all play
in what professional sports league? Here we
go, is it the NBA, MLB, NFL or NHL? You`ve
got three seconds, go!
The only place you`ll find all four of those
teams is the National Hockey League. That`s
your answer and that`s your "Shoutout."
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: The thing is, you won`t see any of those
teams on the ice any time soon. The National
Hockey League season was supposed to start
in October, 11th. The league already canceled
its schedule through October 24th, and on
Friday it extended that through November 1st.
The issue is that the NHL has locked out its
players. The two sides are trying to negotiate
a new contract for how they split up the money
that the league makes. So far, though, they
haven`t been able to make a deal. 135 games
were scheduled between October 11th and November,
1st. The last time the NHL had a lockout was
in 2004, and that year it was the entire season
that ended up being canceled.
We think you are going to get a kick out of
this next video, but we`ve got to set the
scene for you. High school football game in
Spokane, Washington, two seconds left, team
was down by three, coach sends in a kicker
to try a field goal. No pressure, right? Now,
try this: it`s a 67 yard attempt. The kick
is up, but it`s got a long way to go. Watch
this.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Wow!
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: He mega kicked.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Yes, he did. It`s good. 67 yards by
a high school senior. The NFL record is 63
yards. The kick sent the game in overtime,
and the team would go on to win by a touchdown.
And before we go, we are heading to a mountain
top in China, but that`s just a jumping off
point for this story. It`s an international
wing suit flying competition. What`s a wing
suit? That thing. It uses extra material between
the arms and legs to help with flight. The
competitors had to fly a certain path through
a valley before popping open their parachutes.
Fastest time to complete the course wins.
Though flying without an airplane might seem
kind of crazy, those guys probably don`t spend
time nervously winging their hands about it.
It suits them just fine. It`s time for us
to fly away on a wing and a prayer, but CNN
STUDENT NEWS will be back tomorrow with your
debate coverage. I`m Carl Azuz. See you soon.