WADE DAVIS: I did what one would
do, is you take all this
stuff back for taxonomic
identification.
You look in the literature to
see if there's any reports on
what it might have.
It was a mix, a plethora
of ingredients--
everything from snakes, dried
toads, and various plants, and
then these curious fish.
HAMILTON MORRIS: While Alex
arranges a meeting with a new
bokor, I decide to see if I can
find the ingredients Davis
described on my own.
WADE DAVIS: I identified the
plants and the amphibians.
And I finally went around
to the fish guys.
And I found this ichthyologist,
literally with
his head sort of inside this big
jaw of some massive fish
he was counting the teeth
of or something.
And he literally reached up
and pulled from his shelf,
between these dusty volumes of
the journal of ichthyology, a
copy of Ian Fleming's James Bond
book, "From Russia With
Love, one of those early books
in the James Bond saga.
007 gets kicked in the
shin, and he dies.
And then he turns back alive
in the next book.
That's how the guy in the lab
introduced me to the fact that
I had really landed
on something.
HAMILTON MORRIS: The pufferfish
is a marvel of
evolution and biomechanics.
Its internal organs contain
one of the most potent
neurotoxins ever discovered.
It is the TTX in the pufferfish
which induces the
total body flaccid
paralysis, almost
indistinguishable from death.
WADE DAVIS: The simple
identification of the fish
suddenly took the whole zombie
investigation from the realm
of the phantasmagoric into the
realm of the conceivable.
The fish that were used in the
poisons had a very interesting
molecule in their viscera, in
their liver, in their ovaries,
and on the surface
of the skin.
And this was a neurotoxin called
tetrodotoxin, which is
a complex molecule.
It's about 160,000 times more
potent than cocaine as an
anesthetic.
It's about 1,000 times more
toxic than potassium cyanide.
A lethal dose of the pure
molecule would balance on the
head of a pin.
But more interesting than the
sheer toxicity was the way
that it killed.
And we knew the poison could
do just what was necessary.
It mechanically blocks cilium
channels in the nerves, which
brought on peripheral paralysis,
dramatically low
metabolic rates, and yet
consciousness was retained
until the moment of death.
-[SPEAKING CREOLE]
HAMILTON MORRIS: He got it.
It's all puffed up.
Oh my god.
The fish is shot with
a spear gun and
pulled out of the water.
The entry wound is close to the
brain, with an exit wound
in the stomach.
-[SPEAKING CREOLE]
HAMILTON MORRIS: Oh, wow.
Look, he's puffing up.
Much to my astonishment, when
it's pulled out of the water,
it begins to inflate itself,
despite the two gaping holes
in its body.
How is this possible?
I tentatively identified the
fish as Diodon hystrix, a
species so poisonous that people
have been hospitalized
for merely touching
the spines.
WADE DAVIS: The fish that I
found in Haiti being used in
these preparations were members
of a pantropical order
of fish called the
Tetraodonitiformes, which also
include the famous fugu
fish of Japan,
the culinary delicacy.
For centuries, or certainly
for generations, specially
trained chefs have been
preparing these toxic fish.
They carefully eliminate the
toxin so that the person can
enjoy the nontoxic fillets
of the fish.
The real role of the fugu chef
is not to eliminate the toxin
altogether but to reduce it
to the extent that the
connoisseur still enjoys
the effects of a mild
intoxication, which
include waves of
euphoria, tingling sensation.
It's one of the few substances
that walks a fine line between
food and drug.
HAMILTON MORRIS: It sounds like
there's a biphasic thing,
where it starts out with
the TTX poisoning.
And then after, then they're
given scopolamine or atropine.
WADE DAVIS: So we've talked,
for example, about the
tetrodotoxin.
But then what's fascinating is
that, by all accounts, as the
zombie comes back around, he is
fed the paste of (CREOLE),
the zombie's cucumber.
Now this is based on datura,
and it includes, of course,
these tropane alkaloids,
scopolamine and atropine.
-[SPEAKING CREOLE]
HAMILTON MORRIS: Davis
hypothesized that the
chemicals in the zombie cucumber
were used to keep the
zombie in a state of submissive
confusion.
There's one right there.
But I'm not so sure that this
is Datura stramonium.
Oh, it has to be older?
-Yeah.
WADE DAVIS: This would be the
perfect drug to kind of
socialize the individual
into a new state of
psychosis, if you will.
These are powerfully
active drugs.
They bring on a state of induced
psychotic delirium,
visions of hellfire, a burning
thirst, a sensation of flight.
These are the drugs of choice
of every black magician and
sorcerer throughout the world.
And they create kind of a
psychic dislocation that is
described invariably by anyone
who takes the drug as being
incredibly terrifying.
HAMILTON MORRIS: After the
preparation, which consists of
a de-spining and crude
hepatectomy, the remaining
organ meat it scrambled,
salted, and
served on a silver dish.
WADE DAVIS: There was this
enormous literature on just
what these fish could
do to you.
It turns out by folk custom in
Japan, if you succumb to fugu
fish, you're laid on the ground
for several days to
make sure you're really dead.
And there are case after case
after case in the literature
and in the newspapers of Japan
of people nailed into their
coffins by mistake.
On this dish is a species of
puffer, which is known to be
poisonous, in October, a season
where the fish is known
to contain deadly quantities
of TTX.
Yet nobody around me seems
concerned in the slightest.
The meat is chewy, and I'm
delighted to say, tastes
almost indistinguishable
from chicken.
WADE DAVIS: At the time, no
one really understood the
biogenesis of the toxin
within the fish.
There was a tremendous amount
of variability.
And we knew that 50% of the
time, these fish were not
toxic at all.
But what was fascinating is that
this meant that at least
50% of the time, these toxins
would be ineffective,
pharmacologically.
So what's going on here?
Well, that really turned out to
be the key to the puzzle.
Every drug, in a sense,
particularly hallucinogenic
drugs, they have absolutely
neutral potential for good or
evil, an ambivalent potential.
And everything depends on the
cultural matrix in which the
drug is used.