I want to clarify once and for
all, there's been no other
kind of love.
EMMA HEARST: Heterosexual
life mates.
SARAH KRATHEN: That's going
to be our corporate name.
EMMA HEARST: People used to
think we were homosexual life
mates, but we're not.
SARAH KRATHEN: Yeah, which Emma
thought was hilarious
when we were building Sorella,
because she had a boyfriend.
And I was just like this
single lesbian
in love with her.
EMMA HEARST: My name
is Emma Hearst.
And I'm the co-owner
of Sorella in
the Lower East Side.
My business partner
and co-owner of
Sorella is Sarah Krathen.
And she does the entire beverage
program and all the
front of the house.
Sarah and I met in
culinary school.
We signed a lease here
when I was 21.
And it's been almost
four years.
Age has been a factor since
we've opened here.
Everybody told us, don't
open up in New York.
You're not ready to go play
with the big boys.
We were like, fuck it.
We focus here on a region of
Italy known as Piedmont.
Lots of good stuff
comes from there.
Most people relate it with
truffles and Barolo wine.
These are little pastas called
Agnolotti del Plin.
And they're only found
in Piedmont.
It means little pinched
pillows.
They're filled with a red wine
braised short rib that's mixed
with a little bit of cabbage
and shallots and lemon zest
and a hint of nutmeg.
We definitely like to deviate
from Piedmont as well.
Our dish that is definitely not
Piedmontese in any sense
of the form would be our
broccoli fritto.
So we're taking this broccoli
and putting it
in rice flour batter.
It goes into our fryer.
And then when we pull it out, it
gets tossed in a little bit
of salt and then topped with
a pickled hot pepper aioli,
basil, and Grana
Padano cheese.
It came on as a special,
originally, and then it just
never came off.
It's always fun to watch people
eat this dish for the
first time, because their faces
are, like, blown away.
My pastry chef is
Yarisis Jacobo.
The reason why Yarisis and my
food work so well together is
because she's such a fan of
contrasting textures and sweet
and salty, as am I. And it
should be like an explosion
every time something
hits your mouth.
Yarisis's desserts are
absolutely exquisite.
And people come here just
for dessert, too.
Our mentality in here is to
make things like little
Italian grandmothers.
The most awesome thing about
Sorella, in my opinion, is
that I get to work with my
best friends every day.
And I couldn't ask for anything
more than that.
YARISIS JACOBO: Yeah, everyone
knows each other, hangs out
together all the time.
It's a very friendly
environment.
EMMA HEARST: When we're
not working,
we're drinking together.
Family that plays together
stays together.
And we not only drink
when we leave work.
We also drink during work,
especially Sarah and I,
especially on stressful days.
But everything in moderation.
SARAH KRATHEN: Shall we?
EMMA HEARST: Let's blow
this popsicle stand.
Margarita time.
So we're headed to
Mesa Coyoacan in
Williamsburg, Brooklyn.
And we are going to go get
sauced on some margaritas.
SARAH KRATHEN: I am so specific
about a margarita.
Want the fresh ice, always.
Shaken and then strained
into fresh ice
is the biggest thing.
Fresh juice.
EMMA HEARST: Good tequila.
SARAH KRATHEN: Never
taste sweet.
Good tequila is key.
I don't want all salt.
I want half salt.
I want the option.
I love margaritas.
EMMA HEARST: I wonder what Ivan
and Gerardo are going to
be cooking up tonight.
All right.
Here we are.
Let's go get our drink on.
How are you, chef?
IVAN GARCIA: How are you?
EMMA HEARST: Good.
Hi!
GERARDO ZABALETAVE:
How are you?
EMMA HEARST: My friends,
Gerardo and Ivan, they
actually found Sorella, the
space that we're in.
We met them about
six years ago.
And we've remained
close friends.
We're going to get
some margaritas.
Half salt.
SARAH KRATHEN: Not too sweet.
EMMA HEARST: Cheers.
Bottoms up.
SARAH KRATHEN: Cheers.
Cheers.
EMMA HEARST: I wish yellow
Gatorade tasted like this.
I would drink it all the time.
I would just drink it while
I was working out.
But it had all the same benefits
as Gatorade, like
margaritas with electrolytes.
-Cazadores Blanco.
EMMA HEARST: Oh, hey now!
-Are you ladies set to order?
Do you know what you want?
EMMA HEARST: Yeah.
Some guacamole, the shrimp
ceviche, the cochinita tacos,
and the pescado tacos.
-The shrimp tacos?
EMMA HEARST: The fish tacos.
-The fish tacos?
EMMA HEARST: Yeah, and then
the special, and the
cochinita.
-And the cochinita.
EMMA HEARST: Yeah.
And ceviche-- shrimp ceviche.
SARAH KRATHEN: After we do this,
we won't even remember
what we ordered anyway.
You're winning.
Here's to the last thing
we remember tonight.
EMMA HEARST: Yum!
We can always rely on them for
really tasty, homemade,
delicious Mexican food.
IVAN GARCIA: This
is mole poblano.
It's one of my favorite
dishes here.
This is a secret recipe
from my grandmom.
It's a little hard to make mole,
because we need only
five ingredients to make a
real and delicious mole.
One of the important ingredients
is the chiles.
We use four different
kinds of chiles.
Mexican chocolate--
this is very important for the
recipe, Chocolate Abuelita.
EMMA HEARST: Wow, this
stuff looks great.
It smells fantastic.
SARAH KRATHEN: It's
so flavorful.
EMMA HEARST: Yeah.
That's my favorite mole
in the city, for sure.
It's so good.
-Cheers.
EMMA HEARST: Cheers.
Thank you so much
for having us.
SARAH KRATHEN: Thank
you for having us.
-Thanks for coming.
SARAH KRATHEN: It's so
nice to be here.
-Anytime.
EMMA HEARST: It's always
good to be here.
-Anytime.
EMMA HEARST: Well, that
was an excellent meal.
Well, after Mesa Coyoacan, we
were open here at Sorella
until 2:00 AM.
So of course, we all came
back here for dessert.
What else?
YARISIS JACOBO: We
should have--
SARAH KRATHEN: Bomboloni.
YARISIS JACOBO: Little
bomboloni, a little bit of
coconut stracciatella,
some biscotti gelati.
EMMA HEARST: Sure. chunky.
YARISIS JACOBO: Chunky.
EMMA HEARST: We should just
have all the gelato.
YARISIS JACOBO: Maybe we should
just have a little bit
of everything.
EMMA HEARST: Probably.
Did anyone bring a joint?
I think the desserts here are
definitely a great late-night
snack, because they do encompass
all the savory and
sweet components into one that
you would get eating chocolate
and potato chips.
Our bomboloni are definitely
a crowd pleaser.
They are little Italian fried
donuts with a filling that
changes seasonally.
What's the filling right now?
YARISIS JACOBO: Peanut
butter caramel.
EMMA HEARST: And then we also
serve just traditional glazed
ones that are like Krispy
Kreme donuts on crack.
Hi, Isaac.
YARISIS JACOBO: Hi, Isaac.
EMMA HEARST: Isaac's going to
go steal our bomboloni.
-He's a little monster.
YARISIS JACOBO: This is challah
bread with a pistachio
black pepper toffee that's
swirled into it and then
seared in brown butter.
And then it's filled with
vanilla pastry cream and
served with lemon curd.
And then I think we just need
some gelato to finish this up.
EMMA HEARST: Our gelatos
are very popular here.
Our gelatos are traditional
Italian flavors that have
collided with American
stoner influence.
It's like Ben & Jerry's
but better.
YARISIS JACOBO: This is
our Chunky Sorella.
But we are kind of known for
salted caramel gelato with a
chocolate ganache swirl
and chocolate covered.
EMMA HEARST: Some good stuff.
See this right here?
This is quality.
This is the reason that
my thighs hate me.
YARISIS JACOBO: Beautiful
gelato--
EMMA HEARST: Oh yeah.
YARISIS JACOBO: And sorbets.
EMMA HEARST: Oh my
god, I forgot how
fucking good that is.
-Emma, this mango is dope.
EMMA HEARST: Isn't it?
-Good job.
EMMA HEARST: I think working
in restaurants, it's
definitely a high stress
environment.
And you are constantly serving
other people and at other
people's beck and call.
So yes, everybody needs
their time to blow off
steam and have fun.
We are very good friends,
all of us here.
They are some of my
best friends.
It's been a lot of fun.
And it's like our home.
It's our house.