But, will our wearable
transforming ATV
stand up to the
ultimate redneck test?
I've transformed
and I can't get up.
Rog: [laughing].
Travis Taylor:
I'm Travis Taylor.
I'm a rocket scientist
in the space and defense
industry here in
my hometown of
Huntsville, Alabama,
where my daddy
helped build the rockets
that sent us to the moon.
Daddy: Have y'all
been drinking
the rocket fuel again?
Travis Taylor:
Sometimes, big science
moves too slow for me.
So come the weekend,
I round up my
best friend Rog.
Rog: Hey!
Travis Taylor: My nephew
Michael and my buddy Pete,
to tackle
important problems with
a little down-home ingenuity.
Rog: Damn it, boy!
Travis Taylor: Right on.
Hey, is there any more
beers in the cooler?
Sometimes we get the
inspiration for our
projects in
unexpected places.
Me and Rog and Michael
went down to this
racecourse and man we've
been having a blast.
All of a sudden every
time I give it throttle,
it would just bog down and
stop and I got stuck right
out there in the middle
of the mud and the water.
Michael: You stuck
or something?
Travis Taylor: Yeah, look.
Michael: Look on
that other side and
check your linkage.
Travis Taylor: What
the hell is a linkage?
Michael: The throttle
linkage I mean.
You got a multi tool.
Travis Taylor: Multi tool.
Michael: Tighten them
thing up with them pliers.
Travis Taylor: Well I
got it pulled loose,
but now I need
a screwdriver.
How do I get the
screwdriver out of this?
Michael: I don't
know, I bet that
multi tool has got one.
Travis Taylor: Oh
look a transformer.
Just like it's a
transformer, man,
how do get in
there to it though?
The multi tool, it was
a transforming tool
and man that gave me
the idea right then.
If I was a
multi tool, man,
if I was stuck in
the mud, I just,
I just change forms
whatever it is just
get up and walk out.
Rog: You are a multi tool.
Travis Taylor:
Shut up, Rog.
That's what we are going
to do this weekend;
we can call daddy and
Pete and build us a
transforming ATV
that would be bad.
Michael: Yeah it would.
Travis Taylor: What
are you doing?
You better not.
Watch out!
Hey, crap!
God, dang!
Well I was at the house
and I took a shower and
got a change of clothes, I
got to thinking about it
and I saw my son's toys.
Look at this thing;
it might give us
some ideas about
how the joints might work.
We're gonna do something
like that with the ATV,
so you can pretty much
wear the ATV and then when
you're ready to go, you
can just fold it out and
get down on it then it,
then it, then it goes.
Our transforming ATV is
gonna need a lightweight
metal frame that conforms
perfectly to my body.
We'll attach 4 wheels,
and a lightweight
engine to it.
The rib cage has to be
especially strong because
it'll protect my internal
organs and support all my
weight when the frame
pulls down into a
full-fledged ATV.
This is gonna be a very
complicated project,
so we're gonna
need to build
a wooden prototype first.
We are gonna use lawn
mower wheels on the front.
Pete and Michael are
heading out to find two
bicycle wheels
for the back.
Michael: Road trip in
Uncle Mule's truck.
Travis Taylor:
Don't wreck my truck!
They are going
over to Rog's to
see what he might have.
Michael: There
is a bike, black.
Pete: There it is.
That would give him
some ground clearance
on his knees.
Let's get it and go.
Michael: On our way
back from Rog's,
I decided to have
a little fun.
Somebody keeps
driving through my
momma's yard
tearing it up.
I know she's home
today and I was in
uncle Travis's truck, so
I thought I'd drive his
truck through our
yard and make it look
like it was him driving
through the yard.
And she'd get
mad at him and
he wouldn't even know
what was going on.
I thought it would be fun.
Momma will think
its Uncle Travis
driving through the yard.
Travis Taylor: Well
this could pop up.
There could be a pin
that goes in place.
Daddy, Rog and I are
figuring out the rib cage.
It's the single
most critical part
of this build.
Let's make me a
box like this,
so cut me
whatever you said,
Rog those pieces were
and we'll go from there.
Daddy: I'm real
concerned about
getting this
rib cage right.
If it's not
designed correctly,
Travis could be crushed.
Travis Taylor: Needs
to be no more than,
certainly 2 feet's enough.
You got them two 2-foot
pieces done yet?
Rog: I don't know
quit telling me
to do 7 things, man.
Travis Taylor: [laughing].
Rog: I can only
think in two things.
Travis Taylor:
That's pretty quick.
Michael: Yeah what
else you all need,
let's go on
another road trip.
Pete: Yeah, it's
cool in there.
Travis Taylor: That tire
is flat as a flute, man.
Is that all y'all
could come up with?
Michael: Put air in
it and it won't be.
Pete: It's all
you ask for.
Travis Taylor: Y'all all
went over to Rog's house
and came back with
2 bicycles and
I said to come back
with 2 wheels, the same,
that aren't flat.
Michael: How are
they different?
Travis Taylor: Well
that's a back wheel,
it's got a different
kind of hub,
that's a front wheel and
it's got a different
kind of hub.
What do they
come back with?
Two tires that
are different and
one of them is flat.
Crap we might not
have measured right.
I wasn't thinking
about it just right.
Pete: Open these up.
Travis Taylor:
Take these off.
Pete: We should
only have to open
one of them up though.
Travis Taylor: All right,
so here's the deal.
I'm thinking we
might cut it here,
put piano hinge
here, so the front,
the front is gonna
do like this.
Ah thank you Rog,
there you go my brother
that's beautiful.
Yeah aww!
Pete: We either have
another spring here
that's holding it to
that, against it.
Travis Taylor: Pete
and Daddy are working
on the front end.
When I'm in ATV mode my
hands will be holding
onto the front axle
and I'll steer by
turning the front wheels.
The big problem is where
to put the back wheels so
they can be deployed
when I want,
but don't get in
the way of walking.
First up, I'm
gonna assign Pete
to work on the front wheels.
Pete: My job is to
figure out how to roll
and steer the transformer.
We're gonna start by using
the lawn mower wheels.
Two forks that are
coming off the
outside of his arms.
Just have to
figure out which
way you want the
forks to pivot.
Daddy: How much
does he need to turn?
I can lop that corner off
right there pretty quick.
There's no room for
the wheels to turn,
so I had to cut off the
corners of the frame.
Now it should
turn on a dime.
Travis Taylor: I've been
wrestling with the idea
about where these rear
wheels are gonna go when
I'm standing up and
suddenly, it hit me.
I got an idea about this.
This piece pins to that
piece and the wheel is
gonna be right
here at this pin.
So I got knee joints and
I got everything
else, right.
Then when I get
ready to go,
then I just lean
over on the wheel.
Michael: Just as Uncle
Travis was figuring out
how to attach the
wheels, my phone rings.
There she is, she's
calling me now.
And it's my momma.
This is gonna be good.
Hello.
Momma: Why the hell did
you drive through my yard?
Michael: Well it
wasn't me drivin'.
Well you saw what
truck it was.
Travis Taylor: He's trying
to blame me for it PK.
Momma: Yeah it was a red
truck with you driving
and Pete in the
passenger's seat.
Michael: All right Momma.
Rog: You got busted!
Michael: We'll talk later.
Rog: He is gonna
get a whoopin' as
soon as he gets home.
[laughing].
I love it!
Momma: I don't want
my yard destroyed
like Grandma Mary's.
Rog: Oh she's low rated.
Michael: Yeah.
Travis Taylor: Michael
was trying to get me in
trouble by driving
my truck through his
momma's backyard,
but it completely
backfired on him.
He's so nervous, he's
upset he's not gonna go
home for 2 or 3 days.
'Cause he don't want his
momma to yell at him.
'Cause it's the funniest
thing I've ever seen.
We're having a blast;
he's not gonna
live this down as
long as we can make it.
I recommend you go
spend the night down
at ACE tonight Michael.
Michael: Yeah.
Travis Taylor: I
don't believe I would
go home for a day
or two if I was you.
Pete: Yeah.
Travis Taylor:
Since Michael and
Pete brought me back
two different wheels,
one of which was flat,
we're gonna call an
audible and make the rear
wheels out of plywood.
We're going to have
some bungees that helped.
Put it on.
We're getting
really close to doing a
prototype test with
the suit, the ATV,
except we won't
have any motors on it,
kinda like a wagon.
Hopefully the guys
will push me around.
We'll see if the
steering works,
we'll see if the
wheels works,
we'll see if it can
transform from standing up
and walking around
and going down in
the ATV position.
If this prototype works,
we're gonna move on and
make the real
one out of metal.
If it doesn't, I might be
spending a lot of time
with the chiropractor.
This is heavy, man.
Michael: If you can't
handle it, let it go.
Travis Taylor: Watch
out, can I let it go?
Michael: Yes, yes.
Travis Taylor:
That's all right.
Pete: His wheels are
almost straight.
Travis Taylor: All right
now let's see if I can
transform and get
down and make it roll.
All right there.
Michael: There's one leg.
Oh you're hung
on your own leg.
Travis Taylor:
Something broke loose.
Michael: All right.
Travis Taylor:
Something broke loose.
Pete: Probably
just the Velcro.
Travis Taylor: Oh crap
something's loose,
it broke loose.
What broke loose?
Michael: You got to
drag your knees up.
Travis Taylor:
Why am I stuck?
Rog: [laughing].
Travis Taylor:
I can't get up.
Pete: Is that bungee?
Travis Taylor: No
ain't the bungee.
I can't get up.
Rog: Seeing Travis
in this prototype was
the funniest
thing I ever saw.
He looked like
he was stuck in a
fold out couch
or something.
Travis Taylor: Ough!
Rog: Stay with it, Mule.
Travis Taylor: I
can't get up, man.
[laughing].
Listen, listen,
oh watch out, Rog.
Hey, look.
Rog: Let me push, push ya.
Travis Taylor: Stop.
Oh crap.
Daddy: That ain't
gonna get it.
Travis Taylor: No,
this ain't right,
something ain't
right here boys.
I've transformed
and I can't get up.
Oh crap.
Ow!
Daddy: These experiments
are dangerous.
Don't try them at home.
In fact, I wish these
guys wouldn't try em
at my home!
Travis Taylor:
Why am I stuck?
Rog: Stay with it, Mule.
Travis Taylor: We're
building a wearable ATV
that can drive
over any terrain,
then transform into a
suit for walking around.
But our prototype
has a huge problem.
In ATV mode the frame
collapsed putting
all the weight
directly on my spine.
I can't, it won't undo,
it's stuck wherever it is.
Daddy: It's a good thing
we made this out of wood
first because if it was
made out of metal we could
have broken his back.
Travis Taylor: Something's
loose, it broke loose.
I could feel the pressure,
but I couldn't stop it.
Michael: C'mon up.
Daddy: Can you
come out of there?
Travis Taylor: Yeah,
I can get out of this.
See look in order for it
to roll right, now look,
if you did this,
look, it will roll,
look that right
there will roll.
Michael: Yeah.
Travis Taylor: That's
what we gotta to have
it locked together,
right there.
The front worked fine.
Rog: Yup.
Travis Taylor: This
part's fine, worked good.
I can even lean out
and it will fall out
in front of me
that's a good idea.
This right here concerns
me 'cause that puts all
the weight of the vehicle
right in my back.
To get my body in the
right position in ATV mode
we need to keep the
frame from falling flat,
so we're gonna need to
add a locking mechanism
in my hips to keep
the frame stable and
prevent it from
breaking my back.
Pete: We have a plan for
the frame but we also need
to figure out how we're
gonna power this thing.
Travis Taylor: 200cc
gas powered engine.
Daddy: No, no.
Travis Taylor: Or an
electrical motor or
whatever.
Daddy: Forget gas engine.
Now you, I'm not gonna
put up with you putting
a gas engine on the back.
Travis Taylor: Well
I don't even where
we'd put it Daddy.
If we put it here a
gas engine weighs
what a 150 pounds?
How much does a
5-horse engine weigh?
Daddy: There's no way
I am letting him drive
around the road with a
tank of highly flammable
liquid strapped
to his behind.
I don't want gas
on your back.
Travis Taylor: I don't
want gas on my back
either, Daddy.
Daddy: Take that
out of the loop.
Travis Taylor: Well then
if we are gonna do that,
then it means that
it's electrical,
that means we got to
find electrical motors
that will do it.
Michael: We got to go
get some materials.
Travis Taylor: Let's
see what we're doing.
We need
parts of ATV's.
Michael: Right.
Travis Taylor: That we
can start working on.
Why don't you and Rog
go find us some parts,
me and Daddy will start
digging into this and
figure out what we
did wrong so by the
time you get back.
Rog: Road trip.
Michael: Road trip.
Pete: Oh c'mon guys.
Travis Taylor: Hey, y'all
don't stay gone long.
Michael: You say
that every time we
go on a road trip.
Rog: We ain't
never gone long.
Travis Taylor: Yeah,
because you always
stay gone too long.
Rog: Whatever.
Pete: He means it
every time too.
Rog: Shot gun.
Travis Taylor: So
I sent Michael and
Rog out to look for some
small electrical motors.
Rog: We got motor
city right there.
Right there.
Michael: Where, what?
Rog: That little blue
motor city thing.
Michael: You're right.
Rog: Pull in there.
We headed over to this
street that has all these
little junk shops
and antique stores.
I figured that's where
we'd find a good used
electric motor.
Michael: Let's see
if you was right.
It may not be
worth a damn, Rog.
Rog: So number 2.
Michael: What?
Turn it on,
see if it works.
Michael: Things
got a lot of power;
it will carry you
around won't it?
We found this
nifty motorcycle,
so we're gonna take the
motor from that but I
think we're gonna need
a little more power.
We checked out
that motorcycle.
Clerk: That's a
good one there.
Michael: It runs
pretty good,
you got anymore
like that thing.
Clerk: Yeah.
I got a 4 wheeler
right there.
Rog: Where?
Michael: Check that
4 wheeler out Rog.
This toy ATV has a
working electrical motor
that we could tear out.
And if we put together
with that little
motorcycle engine,
we'll actually have the
equivalent of
a gas engine.
Man, that looks good.
Travis Taylor: I'm done.
While Rog and
Michael were gone,
we built a new locking
metal hinge and
installed it on
the prototype.
This is to just
make sure that this
is the right idea.
Ok well, y'all push me.
Well, it's rolling fine.
It does all right,
this is the right plan.
Daddy: Get out and
let's start making on
a good one.
Travis Taylor: Yeah
we need to figure out
how to make this
out of aluminum
or somethin' now.
[Car horn].
Travis Taylor:
There they are.
About time they got back.
We got the idea this
works just fine.
Look at that,
those are nice,
we use all that
for something.
Michael: We had
to make two stops.
Pete: There's
some good shocks.
Travis Taylor: That's
it, look that has got
electrical motors in
it, we can use them.
Michael: Right there
is the batteries
for it under there.
Travis Taylor: Let's
start getting it out,
let's find us some
aluminum pieces,
turn that prototype
into a real transformer.
Rog and Daddy can start
measuring the pieces
and figuring out
how to convert this
over to the aluminum.
Pete, why don't
you tear into them
motorcycles that
they just bought?
Pete: Ok.
Travis Taylor: And
find the motors and
electronics and all that.
Michael: Here's
the instructions.
If you feel like reading
instructions.
Daddy: I don't know
what you need to read the
instructions, we're
gonna tear the thing
apart not put it together.
Rog: Does it have
instructions to tear it apart?
Travis Taylor: We're
gonna build the frame
out of aluminum,
skin it with armor and
when we get it done,
we're gonna put this
transforming ATV to the
ultimate redneck test.
A beer run.
Rog, you help Daddy
figure out how to
reproduce this
with aluminum.
Cut the pieces and
get them to Michael
as fast as you can.
Michael, you weld them
Daddy: All right,
there's one of them.
Michael: Here is your
leg part finished.
Travis Taylor: Oh
man, look at that.
Michael: Oughtta
wait with the.
Travis Taylor:
Is it still hot?
Michael: No, it
ain't hot no more.
Travis Taylor: So that's
that piece right there.
Michael: Yeah, drilled
all the way up to
mount to the
hip somewhere.
Travis Taylor: All right,
go make the other one.
Daddy: All we need
you to do is line
the washers up
with that hole.
While those boys were
mounting the new set of
bike wheels, Pete and I
were attaching the motors
and the batteries from
those toy vehicles.
Pete: I think it's
pretty well lined up.
Daddy: Uh-oh.
Pete: Pull that
out and we'll see.
Travis Taylor: It
ain't going nowhere.
All right.
It took us a while to
finally attach the motors
to the frame, but I think
we got that working.
Hey, hey, hey!
Hold on just a minute.
I told Michael to get
working on the chest plate.
When I turn around, I see
a disaster in the making.
What in the crap
are y'all doing?
Michael's doing
one of the worst
welding jobs I
have ever seen him do.
This is the rib cage
that's gonna protect
my chest and he has
got angels going
every which way.
Look how cock
eyed that is, now.
Rog: Who did that?
Who did that?
Travis Taylor:
What in the world?
Michael: First
Uncle Travis says,
"Do it as fast
as you can."
Then, when I do
it fast, he says,
"That's not good
enough, do it over."
There's no
pleasing this guy.
Travis Taylor: You
got, that means you
are gonna have to
completely redo it,
you got to grind
them off and
put them up here
and re-weld it.
Michael's welding
job actually puts
my life in danger.
I already nearly got
my back broke and
now I could get
my chest crushed too.
And Michael and Rog think
it's all fun and games.
Rog: I'm glad I ain't
the one who done that.
Travis Taylor: Man.
Michael: Who
designed that thing?
Travis Taylor:
I designed it,
but you didn't weld
it for nothing.
Michael: Who
designed that thing?
Daddy: That beats
anything I've ever seen.
Those boys fight so much;
sometimes I think
Michael intentionally
messes things up.
Travis Taylor: You're
gonna break that.
Michael: No I ain't.
I didn't do nothing.
Daddy: Travis
gets really mad,
but that just seems
to tickle Michael.
The madder Travis gets,
the more Michael
seems to enjoy it.
Travis Taylor: I can't
believe you did that.
I just, God that
aggravates me.
Pete: All right, let me
mark these real quick.
Travis Taylor: We're
building a wearable
transforming ATV
that will fold into a
full size all
terrain vehicle.
But Michael's lazy
welding makes my
chest plate vulnerable
and dangerous.
Hey, hey, hey!
Look how cock
eyed that is, now.
Michael: Who
designed that thing?
Travis Taylor:
I designed it,
but you didn't weld
it for nothin'.
Michael: Who
designed that thing?
Travis Taylor: With
a little persuasion
Michael did finally
get it right.
And we're back on track.
Michael: There it is.
Travis Taylor: All
right, look here,
we got the chest
plate about done.
So the skin is gonna have
to cover the inside.
All right, I got this
piece up here we're missing.
Next we had
to work on the brakes.
Yeah get in there.
Michael: Put the
round thing in first.
Travis Taylor: Yeah, yeah
I've done this before on
my bicycle before I know
what's happening here.
Michael: All right
now hit the brake,
hit the brake.
There it is.
Travis Taylor: Did
it let off though?
Michael: Yup.
Travis Taylor: Now
it's the last step,
skinning the
ATV suit with an
exoskeleton and mudguards.
Rog: We took a bunch of
plastic pieces from the
toy ATV and cut them up
so the transformer really
looks cool as it's
rolling down the road.
Travis Taylor: What do
you think about that?
Now it's time to do
our first road test.
I'm nervous because I
might get stuck in it
again or, it could just
collapse at high speed or,
who knows, I might
just run over myself.
Here we go,
you ready?
Michael: Yeah hit it, go.
Daddy: Look at him go!
He left here like
Lindburg didn't he?
Travis Taylor: It
was pretty amazing.
I started out slow, but I
soon started picking up
speed and it was
smooth as silk,
this transforming
ATV really is more
than meets the eye.
Michael: You best stay
out of the monkey grass,
before you get
grandma all fired up.
[laughing].
Michael: It works.
Daddy: Watch out.
Michael: Can you get up?
Travis Taylor: Well,
I should be able to.
Rog: I don't know
about all that.
Travis Taylor: This is
the moment of truth,
this has proven we can
make a wearable ATV,
but have we really built
a transforming ATV?
Right there is locked,
it won't come in.
Can I even stand
up in this thing?
Michael: There you go,
there is one foot.
Rog: Look at
him, look at him.
Travis Taylor: Boom,
transforming taters
right there.
Now I can
walk around in it.
Whoo, how about that?
Michael: That's
impressive.
Travis Taylor: Now
it's time to put our
transforming ATV
to the ultimate
redneck challenge,
a beer run!
Ho-yah!
Rog: Settle down, Mule.
Travis Taylor: Michael
go get the wagon.
Hook it up
to this thing,
we gonna
celebrate tonight.
Rog get on here.
Rog: Let's go son,
I got my billfold.
Travis Taylor: Well
let's go get some beer,
come on.
Rog: Let's go.
Travis Taylor: Here we go.
Daddy: Hey Rog,
put this on.
Grab that and stick it on.
Travis Taylor: Put that
on your melon head, Rog.
Rog: It's on.
Michael: This is the
best invention yet,
you can drive that
to the beer store.
Daddy: Look at that
pulling a little wagon,
just like he did
with a tricycle
when he was a kid.
Michael: Yeah.
Rog: Turn right here,
right out front.
There we go.
This is where
we need to be.
Travis Taylor: You done?
Rog: Transform.
Travis Taylor:
I heard that.
Rog: Look at you, son.
Travis Taylor: Ah, son!
Rog: Ain't
nothing like it.
Travis Taylor: We
need to get us some
beer up in here.
We need a keg of beer.
Clerk: We can do it.
Travis Taylor: We've
been working hard
building this
thing all weekend.
Let me hold
the right door.
Rog: All right come on.
Travis Taylor: Here we go.
I got it, I got it.
What are we gonna,
go right here?
Rog: Look at it.
Travis Taylor:
This is one of my
favorite things
we've ever done.
Rog: Yeah I am glad
we built it to bubba.
Look at there, let's go.
Travis Taylor: This
is one of the most
amazing things
we ever built.
We took a couple of
electric motors,
ATV parts and some
aluminum framing and
built a real life
transforming ATV,
just like I
use to watch on
Saturday morning cartoons.
Rednecks roll out!
Wahoo!