that so far about
4 million people
have taken advantage
of across the country.
You've got about 800,000--
ANNOYING BANANAS: Ahhh!
ANNOYING ORANGE: Yaaaaa!
ANNOYING LEMON: Ahhhhh!
ANNOYING APPLE: You
guys wait for me!
ANNOYING ORANGE: Whoa, hold on!
ANNOYING APPLE: Wassup!
ANNOYING BANANAS: Heh heh!
Yeah!
ANNOYING ORANGE: Yeahhh!
[MUSIC PLAYING]
PAUL VASQUEZ: Ahh!
Oh, my God, look at that!
It's starting to look
like a triple rainbow!
Oh, my God, it's full on--
[MUSIC PLAYING]
MALE SPEAKER: --the spirits
of all those in Iran who have
striven for freedom, and
the Persian word "neda"--
[MUSIC PLAYING]
MALE SPEAKER: This
behavior's a dead end,
and P Diddy is not your friend.
You'll end up like Lindsay
Lohan, La-la-la-la Lo-han.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
MALE SPEAKER: --to
your Facebook account.
Here's how.
Just go to youtube.com, click
on Account, Activity Sharing,
Connect--
MALE SPEAKER: [SINGING]
Sitting there late
at night on Chat Roulette.
Girl in the dark, how
you doing tonight?
Where you living in the world?
Are you doing all right?
MALE SPEAKER: --I've ever
written, ever, in life.
All right, I know
I'm not a poet,
but I think it's pretty decent,
so just don't laugh, OK?
[CLEARING THROAT]
EDWARD CULLEN: I
know the consequences
of this choice you're making.
After a few decades, everyone
you know will be dead.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[MUSIC_-_"PAPARAZZI"]
MALE SPEAKER: --is on
target again, is Malinga.
[INAUDIBLE], we talked
about the other night,
but 17 of Malinga's 33 wickets
in IPL history have been
bowled--
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[MUSIC - "I WILL
ALWAYS LOVE YOU"]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
MALE SPEAKER: --are
literally risking their lives
to do what they're doing, and
YouTube gives them a venue.
FEMALE SPEAKER: If all MAC nail
polishes were this quality,
I would buy all MAC
polishes over OPI.
This is amazing.
So if you like this
color, I definitely
recommend the quality
of this polish.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
MALE SPEAKER: --a lot of people
who just came to the site
to bolster certain questions
that they wanted to be sure
would be asked, and selecting--
MALE SPEAKER: You should
end up with a video that
is shorter than the original.
If it ends up longer
than the original,
then we can only assume
that you found a fault
in the space-time continuum.
FEMALE SPEAKER: [SPEAKING
FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[BIRDS TWEETING]
KATY PERRY: Yeah, it's
funny, I kind of really
went through that when
I was in Los Angeles
because I moved to Los
Angeles when was 17--
MALE SPEAKER: If
it is, I'd love you
to film it and send
the footage to me.
But I'd also like to think about
it a couple of other things.
Three questions I'd
like you to answer.
First of all--
MALE SPEAKER:
--shirtless Old Spice guy
replies on Twitter via
hilarious personalized videos.
Thanks, Alyssa, but you want
to know what's really genius?
[MUSIC PLAYING]
MALE SPEAKER: So here we are
at the Teen Choice Awards,
and Shane is nominated, of
course, for Choice Web Star.
Shane, say something nice about
iJustine, your competition.
SHANE: I think her hair--
[MUSIC PLAYING]
MALE SPEAKER: --bacteria
and residue on the tongue.
On your tongue!
Now your mom doesn't
sound so stupid
for telling you to brush
your tongue, now, does she?
Tongues are like sponges,
soaking up all that bacteria--
[MUSIC PLAYING]
MALE SPEAKER: If you want
to make a difference,
one message with now
over 50,000 stories.
It gets better.
They touched hearts--
FEMALE SPEAKER: --show
you how to as it happens.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Best of all,
you can add real time comments
as we're live streaming so we
can respond to your questions
and comments instantly.
FEMALE SPEAKER:
First up today, we'll
show you some tips
on how you can--
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[CROWD SHOUTING]
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
[MUSIC_-_"MIND_GAMES"]
[MUSIC - JOHN LENNON, "IMAGINE"]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
COOKIE MONSTER: That why
me made audition tape.
Yeah, me show you that me be
great host of "Saturday Night
Live."
So here it is,
whole show in just--
JON BON JOVI: Hi,
this is Jon Bon Jovi.
On November 10, me and
the guys in the band
will be performing live
on the YouTube stage,
but I'm going to need your help.
I need a set list.
Why don't you submit
your favorite Bon Jovi--
FEMALE SPEAKER: --without
any of your help,
without any of your support
and your encouragements.
And I couldn't think
of creating a better
video than this video
right here, and I want to--
[MUSIC PLAYING]