Kevin and Lindsey,
the children
of the woman I married.
Suzanne.
Kevin and Lindsey.
Lindsey's the girl.
Look, that's why you need
to spend more time with them.
Besides, Suzanne is working;
I'm working.
This way,
they'll be with family.
You heard me.
I said family.
We'll see you tomorrow.
Why do we
have to hang out with her?
She hates us.
She hardly even knows you guys.
She can't wait to see you.
You didn't say
she doesn't hate us.
She just needs a chance to g.
She hasn't spent
a lot of time around kids.
Didn't she raise you?
Like I said,
she hasn't spent a lot of time
around kids.
Look, just do me a favor.
Don't call her grandma
or granny
or mammy, Nana,
nothing like that.
I'm just gonna call her
Mrs. Persons.
Call her Marilyn.
Once she gets to know you,
she's gonna love you.
That's what they said
to Britney Spears' kids.
♪ Are we there yet? ♪
The Day Off Episode
S01x03 Original Air Date on June 9, 2010
♪ tell me, tell me, tell me ♪
♪ tell me,
are we there yet? ♪
-- sync, corrected by elderman --
-- for www.addic7ed.Com --
Hey, baby.
You okay?
No.
I've got a problem.
What's up?
How is this a problem?
I'm a professional
event planner.
I don't do unplanned well.
Why don't you just plan
on doing nothing?
Why don't you
just file that under
you don't know
what you're talking about?
Come here.
Sit down right here.
You could just do this
for three days:
Espn, Espn2, Espn Classic,
Espn Extreme.
I'll just go in to work.
Why?
Look, you're the one
always complaining
about how tired
and overworked you are.
That was just last night.
Okay, well, I suppose
it could be fun.
You and me, we could go
down to Pike's Place,
grab some breakfast,
do some shopping.
Oh, that sounds great, baby.
Good.
We'll do it.
I can't.
You're the one
with the three days.
I got to work.
Use this as your "me" time.
[Sighs]
Okay, well, maybe I can spend
some time with the kids:
Go down to Pike's Place,
grab some breakfast,
do some shopping.
Oh, that sounds
nice, baby.
Good.
Not good.
They're spending the day
with my mother.
Why?
She hates them.
Kids: Told you!
[Sighs]
Okay, kids, remember,
no touching anything
at grandma's house.
Oh, they won't be going
anywhere near my house.
I just laid white carpet.
We are going to the mall.
Go stand by the car.
Bye, mom.
Bye, sweethearts.
Sounds like a lot of fun.
Mm.
Uh, Marilyn, these are
just a few important numbers
we think you should have:
My cell, Nick's cell,
home phone, pediatrician--
did you not hear me say
we are going to the mall?
I did, Marilyn, but bad things
can happen there too.
Um, for the kids,
no sugars before 12:00 noon
or after 3:00.
Look, little bitty woman,
if your kids do not know
how to eat by now,
I am not teaching them.
Please make sure
that they wash their hands
for a full 15 seconds--
you do realize I managed
to raise your husband, right?
Barely.
Nick told me that
when he was five,
you put him up for collateral
in a poker game.
I had a full house,
kings high.
Where was the risk
in that?
[Car horn honks]
No, they did not
touch my horn.
I got a number for you.
911?
Yup, because
if your kids go missing,
I am not looking for them.
[Door closes]
Mm, that was good.
I can't wait till you have
another day off.
Want anything else?
Mm, I'm good.
I got to go to work.
Have a good day, baby.
[Sighs]
Crap!
Heh-heh!
Ha ha ha!
Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah, boy.
Hah. Hah.
[Mysterious music]
♪ ♪
[sighs]
Tennis.
Ping-pong.
Skateboarding.
[Electronic zapping]
I thought you were working.
I am working.
No, you're not.
You're fighting Count Dooku.
No, I'm calibrating the motion
sensors on the Wii mod
by fighting Count Dooku.
So...
Uh, enjoying
your vacation, baby?
No.
I can't just sit around
the house and do nothing.
Why don't you call Gigi?
She's at work.
You just killed Count Dooku.
Sorry.
It's okay.
At least I know
the motion sensor's working.
So you're finished?
No, I've got
three more of these.
Why don't you go
see a movie?
Nick, the only thing
more depressing
than sitting at home by myself
is going to a matinee
by myself.
Look, baby, I don't know
what to tell you,
but I've got to go to work.
I promised my client
I'd have this fixed by tonight.
What kind of client
can't wait a day for their Wii?
A mother with two kids.
[Sighs] Fine.
Play with Count Dooku.
Okay, people,
here's how it's gonna work.
I'm gonna be at that bar
over there,
catching up with my friends
Jack and coke.
These are for you.
They're prepaid cards.
Really?
How much is on them?
That's for me to know
and you to find out.
And when they're maxed out,
so are you.
Thanks, grandma.
Say it again and see
what happens to you.
What am I gonna do?
Well, you are going to be
in that arcade right over there.
So I can just play
in the arcade the whole time?
And I can go
wherever I want to in the mall?
Yes, just be back here
by 3:00,
and be smart.
Watch out for pickpockets.
What about
"no talking to strangers"?
Yeah, that too.
What if I meet a overly
friendly guy with a puppy?
Are you gonna be
a problem?
No, I just don't want
to end up
on that show
with Chris Hansen.
He spends a lot of time
on the Internet.
Here.
Thanks, grandma.
I told you,
I am not your grandmother.
If anything, I'm your...
step-grandmother.
Nobody has
a step-grandmother.
Exactly.
Good-bye.
Well, if I sound bitchy,
it's because
I need the massage.
Next month
doesn't work for me.
Thank you.
Bye.
How come
you're not at work?
Because when I got there,
you weren't there.
I assist you, nobody else.
Well, since
you're not doing anything,
let's hang out.
Who said
I wasn't doing anything?
My plane for Cabo
leaves in two hours.
I just came
to borrow your espadrilles.
Hold on; You found out
this morning
that you have
three days off,
and you've already booked
a trip to Mexico?
Booked it, comped it,
and my name is on the V.I.P.
list for the P. Diddy party.
Holla!
I couldn't even get
an appointment at Aqua Spa.
Oh, girl, you've got
to plan ahead for Aqua Spa.
I couldn't plan ahead,
because I didn't know I was
gonna have the time off.
Why don't you go
to Mexico with me?
I have kids.
Do does Mexico.
My kids have plans.
I don't know
what the problem is.
You have time off,
and you have a man.
Why don't you spend time
with your man?
I tried to.
He blew me off.
Blew you off?
You wanted to?
Yes.
And he said...
No.
Question.
What?
What were you wearing?
This.
[Chokes]
That's your problem.
And I think
you know the solution.
[Laughs]
Vamanos.
One, two,
one, two, three.
♪ ♪
♪ when the funk
between my toes ♪
♪ hits your nose ♪
♪ makes you go ♪
♪ ow, ow, ow, ow ♪
♪ ♪
Dude, come on.
I'm not paying you guys
10 bucks apiece
just because I don't need
30 bucks.
We got work to do.
Nick.
Oh!
Whoo, honey, slow down.
I didn't think
it was gonna work that fast.
Baby?
Huh?
You don't understand.
Understand what?
[Screaming]
Hey, guys.
Hey, Nick.
How was it?
It was a little scary
at first,
but then she gave us money
and let us wander around
the mall by ourselves.
Yep, turns out,
she doesn't hate us after all.
Okay.
Go wash up.
Mom fixed dinner.
Cool.
All right.
Looks like you had a good time
with the kids, ma.
Don't tell me
what kind of time I had.
I need a glass of water,
and by "water,"
I mean vodka.
What's wrong with you?
Suzanne's been mad at me
all day.
Well, if she worked anywhere
near as hard as I did,
I'd be mad too.
That's just it.
She didn't go to work.
She had the day off.
I don't know what kind
of sick game you're playing,
but the next time
these kids are at home
and their mother is at home,
you let them stay home.
She's their family too.
I didn't want to change
your plans.
What is wrong
with you, man?
I had plenty of things
I could've been doing
besides babysitting
those kids at the mall.
Now, if they were
my grandkids,
it'd be a different story.
They are your grandkids.
You know what I mean.
Boy, where is my vodka?
I...
I'm sorry
about what happened earlier.
No, you're not.
I'm sorry.
They saw me naked.
You act like it's my fault.
I would never come down
to your job in my drawers
and pose in the doorway
and then get mad
when everybody stared at me.
It is not the same thing.
I don't work in the garage.
Just because
my office is at home
doesn't mean
I'm not at work.
You don't see Michele Obama
waltzing around the oval office
in her panties.
So now you're the President
of the United States?
You just have to pretend
I'm not here.
Now my workday is over.
Get off of me.
I'm still pretending
you're not here.
Kevin, Lindsey,
dinner is ready!
How come you're not eating?
I'm not hungry.
Me neither.
We ate.
I specifically asked
your grandmother
not to feed you past 3:00.
She didn't.
But we ate everything
we wanted from 2:30 to 2:59.
Well, that's just great.
I sat around this house
all day long
and couldn't figure out
a thing to do,
and the one thing
I came up with
was cooking a nice dinner
for my family.
And what does your mama do?
She takes the kids to the mall
and lobs a corn dog right
in the middle of my plan.
Nick, if this is
how you're going to treat me
when I'm at home,
why didn't you just let me
go to work?
'Cause I love
your mashed potatoes?
I'm telling you, Chuck,
sometimes you can't win
for losing.
If anybody knows that,
it's you.
If I knew she wanted to do that,
I would've come in late.
[Beeping]
Hey, ma.
It's Nick.
I need you to keep
the kids tomorrow.
Kevin and Lindsey.
[Sighs]
Both: Hey, Marilyn!
So what are we
doing today?
I don't know,
but you're coming home hungry,
I can tell you that.
Can we please
go back to the mall?
Sure, as long as you promise
not to talk to me until...
As long as you promise
not to talk to me.
Hey, ma, you want
a cup of coffee?
You got six hours to fix
whatever's going on
with you and your wife.
Come on, people.
Thanks, ma.
[Smooth music]
♪ ♪
Hey, baby.
What?
Brush your teeth
and come downstairs.
I made breakfast.
I'm not hungry.
I know you're upset, baby.
Just please, just come
downstairs, please?
Fine.
It's 9:00.
Don't you have to be at work,
Mr. President?
[Hums Hail to the Chief]
♪ ♪
[music stops]
mm.
My compliments
to the chef.
You sure
you don't want any?
No.
Problem solved.
Why can't I do that
with Suzanne?
You can; You just got to treat
your woman like a hard drive.
Do you want
to explain that?
See, women possess
all the information a man needs.
You just have to
access the data.
Access the data.
Dude, it's almost 10:00 A.M.
Why didn't you
say something?
Because you have
a watch on.
Dude, I got a date
with this really hot chick.
A date?
It's 10:00 A.M.
Yeah, see, she works
the night shift,
so we hit up this coffeehouse.
But I'm telling you, man,
you get a couple mimosas
in her,
she's good to go.
It's like happy hour.
Never underestimate
what a woman will do
when she is brunch drunk.
Brunch drunk.
Oh, yeah.
This woman plainly stated
that she can't sleep with a guy
who can't be on time.
See, when women
tell me things,
I believe them.
Behhhh!
See, Suzanne told you she
doesn't do unplanned well.
She said she'd rather
just go to work.
Now, was she lying?
No.
She told you
the truth about herself,
and you convinced her
to do something different.
Sorry, buddy.
This one's on you.
But if it's any consolation,
those were
some kick-ass waffles.
It's noon.
How come you're not at work?
Lunch.
I give myself 50 minutes.
I'm sorry.
What are you sorry for?
Whatever made you mad.
You know,
I do work hard,
even though
it may not seem like it to you.
No, no.
Honey, I understand.
Count Dooku is
a menace to society
and needs to be dealt with.
The Empire is not gonna
defeat itself.
Honey...
I'm glad that you have
a job that you love.
I guess I just wanted to feel
more important.
Of course you are.
You know that.
You never said
what you were sorry for.
I tried to make you do
what I would do
if I had a few days off
instead of listening to you.
I want you to respect
the way I operate,
so I should respect
the way you operate.
I like that.
And I love you.
I love you too, baby.
Anybody home?
Because these kids are.
Damn.
What happened?
Why are you home so early?
Because these are
your kids, not mine.
But you said
you'd give me till 3:00.
Well, my nerves
only gave me till now.
Ma, I never asked you
for anything, right?
Wrong; You asked me
to take care of your kids
two days in a row.
I meant before that.
Wait, don't try
to guilt-trip me.
Just tell me
what you want.
I need you to stay here
with the kids.
What?
I want to spend some time
with Suzanne.
I thought
you had to work.
Not today.
Where are you going?
To spend some time
with the kids.
I don't want to sit around
for another day and a half,
and I don't want to bother you
while you're working.
I'm not working today.
I'm taking the day off.
Mom's gonna stay home
with the kids.
Both: For real?
Look,
I don't mind
bonding with you,
but you have got to stop
trying to touch me.
Okay, so...
What are we gonna do?
Well, I figure we could go
to Pike's Place,
grab a little something
to eat,
go shopping,
and go somewhere
and finish
what we were talking about
upstairs.
For the record,
we know
what you're talking about.
-- sync, corrected by elderman --
-- for www.addic7ed.Com --