way to you lose it
the u_s_ senate
average winning race cost ten million
four hundred seventy six thousand
four hundred and fifty one
so yet and a half million dollars well
you know what a satirist
if you don't have ten million dollars
good luck to you about it
do we really have a marketing careful
armor
you know are metaphor
the t_b_ then become a senator
of course that it is a local farmer kato
global poverty ocap even dentist do it
no the only way you can do is you're
you're incredibly rich
or
you will in the sucked up to people
or corporations were incredibly rich
of course
well out of the house i mean that's
probably a portable right
winning race one million six hundred
eighty nine thousand five hundred and
eighty dollars
who's up on average the candidates who
won
raise that much money
now where they got to get that money of
course they're gonna get it for
multinational corporations
who become then
the master of the house
and by the way
every if you work your atw he might be
able to raise a from small donors
but what do you think i a sinner centers
in india
made a hundred calls
try to get a hundred dollars at a time
really gonna make one call to a giant
corporation is a
help a brother out
and you'll get it in return
that's exactly what they're gonna do
about already had that system citizen
and have a report on steroids
but back in two thousand eight
leverage joining as senate seat was nine
million to within one thousand
my house was one million ford in seventy
one thousand so yes is doubly getting
worse right
but those are joint numbers to begin
with now to give you a sense again going
back to twenty twelve numbers
how much money they would have to raise
every single day in two years
to get to be able to get reelected if
they were ready congress for example
in the senate they would have to raise
fourteen thousand three hundred and
fifty one dollars
every single day for two years
now the congressional seats
there are only four two years they lasts
only two years
and every day of those two years yet
there is two thousand three hundred and
fifteen dollars
to be able to win
so it's no wonder that they spend
literally a majority of their time fifty
to seventy percent of their time
raising money
not legislating not giving again about
their constituents not meeting with
their constituents
not writing bills not doing research
but raising money because that's the
only thing that gives them elected
this system is literally sick
this corrupted to which cor
it's not a democracy
is by the rates for the rich
and certainly all of the rich
now we got to change the system entirely
obviously you know but i think wolf bags
the way to do that walt bash pack dot
com
and we do is to push for a
constitutional amendment
that takes away corporate person heard
so they can spend unlimited money
buying our politicians to legalized
bribery
that's exactly what this is
and you actually
do funding of elections publicly so
there are the go begging for cash so we
write their checks and they work for ops
not for the big donors
one more thing that's really important
ralph nader uh... was
gore and uh... different
democrats and ask him hey listen
why aren't you guys running tougher
campaigns
the republican party is an historic
popularity
lolz they were before the twenty twelve
election
you gotta run
halfway populist campaigns in you wanted
reich step
why did you do that why did you win the
house now of course a robot mo one they
won the senate
then biggest plan was to win twelve
house-senate
the answer twelve house seats back
what that would know when the house back
for them so they didn't even planning
with the house back
senator asked them
and of course a lot of them he says
given answers like well we had
gerrymandered districts
and uh...
you know there was big money support for
public as that's true decision are
gerrymandered
panorama is you have a ton of money
but one high ranking democrat
even the answer
that is the most roofing and i have ever
seen in politics
he told him quote
because we graze less money
the reason the democrats
run tough campaigns
even more progressive campaigns against
republicans
is because they would then anger their
corporate bosses
indeed results money
so if they were to tell the american
people look at these corrupt republicans
let me know they're taken money from
mother who'd been doing favors from the
they're working for the lobbyist in the
special emphasis at our
than those same one is a special
interests and say how beer you know
we're taking away your money
and then you have no chance of winning
you see that right there
it's not democrats versus republicans as
democrats and republicans verses us
they can really go out for the
republicans
why
because then they'd raise less money
from the donors their all be holding two
wall that packed up from
become a member
contribute volunteer do whatever you
gotta do but we got it is a system
position result was not a democracy