the screen that says
"try this at home."
If you do try it at home, just
let me say you probably need
some safety equipment.
So I always recommend these
super thermonuclear warfare
gloves, because this
will protect your
hands at all times.
And you'll notice that the
aliens of the future only have
four fingers.
And you should always have
good safety glasses.
So always wear your
safety glasses.
And just in case a bomb was to
go off, you should have ear
protection as well.
It also lets you stop
hearing people say,
don't try this at home.
And then, if all else fails,
have a safety mask.
If you do all those things, you
can try most anything that
we say it is OK for you
to try at home.
But please know that the lawyers
say that you can only
try the things that involve
carnations, food coloring,
milk, Elmer's glue,
and paper clips.
Everything else, off-limits.
Was that good?
Knock yourself out.
CARLY REED: Like so many things
around here it all
starts with a phone call.
Anywhere from a Boy Scout troop
to "The Ellen Show"
could call.
And in this case, the Colorado
Rockies called.
They wanted Steve to come do an
event that teachers could
bring their students to that
would be somewhat educational,
and then stick around and
watch the baseball game
afterwards.
STEVE SPANGLER: So they want
me to team up with Kathy
Sabine, who's our meteorologist
at 9NEWS.
And together, we're going to
take some of the demos that
we've done on TV and somehow
play them at a big field like
Coors Field.
The original proposal was that
they're going to take some
kids and get them down close to
the dugout and Kathy and I
would stand on the Colorado
Rockies dugout and just
address these 200 kids.
Within a week that went to,
well, maybe that's 2,000.
And now ticket sales are
at almost 5,000.
The kicker is they want some
interactive activity that can
happen in the stands, that the
people there watching can do
at the same time that we're
doing it down on the field.
So in essence, I have to do a
hands-on science experiment
with however many people-- let's
just say 5,000 people.
I don't know exactly what that's
going to be just yet.
CARLY REED: Steve said that I
needed to talk to Jeff to pull
the whole team together to get
a bunch of experiments
together and go outside and try
them out, kind of like a
big play day for us.
BRIAN FIROOZ: All right.
So this is a solar bag.
We're going to have to--
so solar bags are really
tightly wound.
And as you open them up,
it's kind of how--
just kind of like
a garbage bag.
Nothing real special or anything
like that about that.
But we're going to want to make
sure when we're on the
field that they're going to be
opened ahead of time, since
they are kind of folded upon
themselves, we're going to
want to pump a little air
through them so that they get
open and the plastic isn't
folded on top of itself and
stuff like that.
So it's a really simple--
really simple.
You just get a little bit of air
and then go ahead and push
it through.
And that'll have it just kind of
start to open up on itself.
And that's it.
STEVE SPANGLER: So we've been
manufacturing these giant bags.
It's nothing more than just
a giant trash bag.
It's 50 feet long.
It's about three feet in
diameter, holds a tremendous
amount of air.
The secret is it's made out
of a very thin plastic.
And of course the color of the
bag is black, so that black
bag absorbs the heat
from the sun.
So as you run with it, you scoop
up the air and then you
tie it off.
And within seconds, you can
already start to feel that air
start to heat up.
And literally, two to three
minutes later, you start to
see the buoyancy factor
of that bag.
It becomes almost like
a solar sausage that
floats up into the sky.
It's a really, really cool
way to be able to teach
that hot air rises.
We're doing good.
We have a slight tear.
But everything's all right.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
FEMALE SPEAKER: No!
No!
STEVE SPANGLER: I do best when
I get to rally the troops, go
grab a whole bunch of demos,
and take them and start
playing with them.
Because it's only when we start
playing with them that
we know this is going to work
or stumble over this one.
And we'll actually create
something new out of it.
So this play is really,
really important.
So here's what's happening.
The liquid nitrogen's going
inside the bottle.
It's a pretty slow process,
because the liquid nitrogen
wants to come out.
So it's 320 degrees
below zero.
And the trick is just a nice
slow pour to fill it up.
So a slow pour.
BRIAN FIROOZ: Good job, Carly.
CARLY REED: I can't see
the bottom of it.
STEVE SPANGLER: That's OK.
BRIAN FIROOZ: You're
doing all right.
STEVE SPANGLER: Keep going.
Keep going.
You're doing fine.
So here's that slow pour.
So right now, the liquid
nitrogen is trying to turn
into a gas.
So it's 320 degrees.
And what is it, about
70 degrees out here?
So there's a difference.
The water in there
is just basically
room temperature water.
So I think you're good.
OK?
All right.
So that's out of the way.
That can go down.
MALE SPEAKER: So Steve, your
goal is a third full.
STEVE SPANGLER: Yes.
A third full.
MALE SPEAKER: I'll put
a line on there.
STEVE SPANGLER: All right.
So now everybody's
going to show it.
OK.
Got it?
Good.
Twist it on.
MALE SPEAKER: Soon as
it's sealed, Brian,
just drop it in.
STEVE SPANGLER: Twist it hard.
Good.
So here's what we're trying
to demonstrate.
Liquid nitrogen, when it goes
from a liquid into a gas,
expands 700 times.
And because it's in that
plastic, you can actually see
the energy that's released.
And of course, it's important
to point out, you don't try
this at home.
We're in a testing facility with
emergency personnel right
around the corner.
So the company I work
with is 9NEWS.
And being a big media company,
they've got cool toys.
And they said that we have use
of the helicopter that day.
So totally cool.
Helicopter comes over, gets this
aerial shot of all these
kids doing science.
Hard part is, I've got to figure
out something for all
the kids to do that the
helicopter can see.
So this little thing's
not going to work.
So that's why I'm thinking
these big wind
bags will play well.
They're colorful, and hopefully
from the air you can
see just this sea of
science going on.
It could be cool.
So I think this is the solution
for the interactive
activity with everybody
in the stands.
They're wind bags.
I've been doing this for years
and years and years.
So it's a great big long bag.
It's like a plastic
sandwich bag.
If you're at home, it's like
a Diaper Genie refill.
And the object is, how many
breaths would it take to blow
up this eight-foot-long bag.
So you can see how kind
of colorful they are.
Here, you tie up one
end like this.
Hang on there.
And then you're supposed to
guess how many breaths it
would take.
And everybody does
it like this.
And they slide it down and say
it would take you like 15, 20
breaths to blow up the bag.
So since it's weather and
science day, if you use
Bernoulli's principle that says
fast-moving air creates
this area of lower pressure, you
can actually blow up the
bag in one breath.
So watch.
You empty it out like this.
Here, hang on to the end here.
All right.
No go back a little ways.
So now watch.
If you stretch it out like this,
the secret is you've got
to keep your mouth
off the bag.
If you open it up like this,
see, and then you blow into
the bag, this fast-moving stream
of air actually creates
this area of lower pressure
and the air around it goes
into the bag.
So watch.
See that?
Ta da!
It's good, huh?
Oh.
If you want to do this at home
and you don't have a colored
bag like this, sandwich bag,
here's what you use is a
Diaper Genie refill.
So these things that
you put diapers in.
So if you pull out a section of
Diaper Genie, just make it
as long as you want
and cut it off.
You can do the same
exact thing.
Now it smells baby
fresh, right?
Just remembering that you've
got to keep your mouth away
from the bag.
And if you blow from far away,
this fast-moving air creates
this area of lower pressure,
blow up the
bag in a single breath.
It's pretty cool.
Now the hard part is meeting
with the executives of the
Colorado Rockies and to get them
to sign off, because they
now have to see everything
that we're going to
do down on the field.
So I somehow have to sell them
on the idea that all these
things are good.
So 19th and Wazee for
the Chophouse.
Yes.
We're going to go around
the Chophouse.
We're going to work in there.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
MALE SPEAKER: If there was
ever a day to be on time,
today should have been it.
STEVE SPANGLER: So kids, who
wants to learn about the
properties of air?
AUDIENCE: We do!
We do!
STEVE SPANGLER: Bring some
of your friends.
MALE SPEAKER: I have
none, have none!
MALE SPEAKER: I think
this is going to be
quite a wonderful event.
Most of the Rockies anticipate
[INAUDIBLE].
[MUSIC PLAYING]
STEVE SPANGLER: I didn't expect
any pushback at all
with this one.
And this is the one I got the
most notes on, the solar
sausage, that solar bag.
So you run across the field.
So before any of our team was
allowed on the field, we had
to go over the rules
and regulations of
being on the field.
And as long as we were on the
outfield kind of running
around, everything was OK.
So after everybody got trained,
they loved that idea
of the solar bags.
And I think it's probably the
best educational point that we
have in the show, because
teachers can really show their
kids and use it as an
illustration that those
balloons fill with air, the sun
heats the air, and all of
a sudden, the kids should be
able to see them rise, like
they're doing the program.
So pretty cool science lesson
at the same time.
MALE SPEAKER: How much will you
give me if I huck this at
that solar bag and nail
it in the air?
If you agree, don't
say anything.
[LAUGHTER]
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
FEMALE SPEAKER: Oh!
STEVE SPANGLER: What
did you do?
You tried just to step
on it, didn't you?
FEMALE SPEAKER: No!
STEVE SPANGLER: Yes.
FEMALE SPEAKER: No.
Video will show--
MALE SPEAKER: OK.
New plan.
I casually walk by Jeff's
strings, solar bag string, and
just snip it.
What do you think?
If you agree, don't
say anything.
Silence is the same
as complicity.
OK.
STEVE SPANGLER: What we're going
to do is let Kathy talk
and let some of this happen
behind us at the same time, so
that we can [INAUDIBLE].
All right.
Let's go.
We'll talk about this outside.
We'll get out of the sun.
CARLY REED: So I'm working on
the event, and details are
finally starting to
come together.
And then I look over at Steve's
office and he's on the
phone with someone.
And as soon he hangs up, he
lets us know that he's now
going for a Guinness world
record on this event.
So just one more thing.
STEVE SPANGLER: Of all the
things we can control, the one
thing I can't control,
the weather.
So they're saying a possibility
of rain or snow.
So it could be one
of these freak
snowstorms in the spring.
So can't control it.
Just have to kind of
work around it.
And our team will work hard
to pull it off it anyway.
I just don't want kids cold
out there in the morning
watching this.
And snow would be a disaster.
So crossing my fingers
for sun.
I want you to know the
number that gives
us the highest geysers.
That's over 7,000 bags
in under 2 minutes.
This is going to be awesome.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Can we
do that again, Steve?