Logging is one of the greatest threats
facing the world's rainforests.
Yet there are a few places where
its effects are far less destructive.
The jungles bordering India and Burma
are harvested
using one of the most forest-friendly
methods of all.
And it involves harnessing the raw power
of the mightiest creature in the jungle.
This is Ramprasad - five-and-a-half tonnes
of bull Asian elephant.
And this is Sumir, his mahout.
Before nightfall, they have to drag
a two-tonne log
three kilometres out of the forest.
Ramprasad is the mightiest elephant
in the camp,
but it's still a mammoth test of
brute strength and communication.
Sumir steers Ramprasad
with over 1 00 different commands.
He can be operated in Hindi,
Assamese
and he even understands
a little English.
And Sumir's pretty fluent
in elephant too.
Unbelievably strong
and surprisingly nimble,
elephants are far superior to
logging machines in this tangled terrain.
And most importantly, the forest
doesn't have to be completely cleared
just to access a few selected trees.
There's no need for expensive spare parts,
and elephants run on 1 00% green fuel.
But, unlike a machine,
Ramprasad has a mind of his own
and must be treated with respect.
It's essential to break elephants in
before they're put to work,
but they're still wild at heart,
and keeping control of such raw might
is a fine balancing act
of command and compassion.
Sumir and Ramprasad make it
to the collection site in good time
and help load the trucks.
Transporting logs to the sawmill
is the only mechanised part
of the entire process.
But they're not out of the woods yet.
Once again, underjungle conditions,
elephants out-perform engines.
Job done, time for a well-earned wash.
The jungles of East India and Burma
form the largest area of rainforest
left in Asia
and provide sanctuary for the last
healthy population of Asian elephants.
Ramprasad and these other elephants
have lost their freedom,
but this way of logging helps secure
the future of their species
and their home.
It's through partnerships with nature
that people manage to live within
the jungle without destroying it.
But in most areas of tropical rainforest,
the picture is not so harmonious.
In just 50 years, half the planet's
tropical forest has been cleared.
As many as 1 00 rainforest species
go extinct every day...
...often before
they've even been discovered.
And it's not just animals and plants.
We're also losing human cultures
that we know almost nothing about.
Even in the 2 1st century,
there are still people who exist
in isolation from the rest of humanity,
and virtually all live in jungles.
These vast, unexplored forests
are the only places left on Earth
where entire communities
can live undetected.
Brazil is thought to be home
to around 70 isolated tribes,
around two-thirds of the world total.
Jose Carlos Meirelles works for FUNAI,
a government agency that protects
Brazil's indigenous people.
Today he's hoping to encounter
one of these uncontacted tribes.
He needs to get to them
before others do.
Logging and mining
are encroaching on these forests
and there are some who want to deny
that uncontacted tribes
live here at all.
Meirelles needs evidence.
The fight to protect these people
depends upon proving
and publicising their existence.
This is the very first aerial footage
of an uncontacted community.
Very little is known about their
way of life or even their language,
and Meirelles would rather
it stays that way.
He's dedicated 40 years to protecting
isolated tribes from the outside world,
but this isn't as simple
as just leaving them alone.
Using a stabilised zoom lens,
it was possible to film
from a kilometre away,
minimising disturbance.
Meirelles believes the more people
are aware these tribes are here,
the more effective the fight
to preserve their way of life.
Humans have survived here
by becoming part of the forest,
but it's this specialisation
that leaves them so vulnerable
in these changing times.
These people are the guardians of
a wealth of knowledge and skill
that enable humans to forge a life
within the natural world.
And there are very few
whose existence remains
as intimately connected
with the rainforest
as the remote tribes of West Papua.
The Korowai are so adapted to life in
the jungle, they've taken to the trees.
(SHOUTING)
This clan is building a new house...
...but it will be no ordinary one.
All materials must be sourced on site,
and much of the cutting is still done
using stone-age tools.
It's an ambitious project.
The plan is to build their new home
in a tree 35 metres up.
Just as well they've chosen an ironwood,
the strongest tree in the forest.
The first step is to build
a ladder to its crown.
These are the only tribes in the world
who live in tree houses...
...and they do so for a number of reasons.
It's an escape from the floods and
the biting insects on the forest floor.
It offers protection
from enemy attack,
but most of all, it's a display
of theirjungle prowess.
For the Korowai, the higher the house,
the greater the prestige.
The Korowai's skills may be exceptional,
but builders are the same the world over.
As one of the clan's
strongest climbers,
Wayo is the foreman overseeing
the most dangerous jobs.
Thinning the branches keeps the house
from shaking apart in the wind.
A fall would mean certain death,
but teetering in tree-tops
is second nature to the Korowai.
(WHOOPING)
As the house goes up,
more trees come down.
But they have to fall
in the right direction.