gooey material--
can be used to learn something
about the science of glaciers.
I'm Steve Spangler, and I'm all
about making science fun.
For the last 20 years, I've
been teaching ways to turn
ordinary science experiments
into unforgettable
experiences.
I have an amazing team who will
do whatever it takes to
affect the way people
think about science.
And to do that, I live
by one motto--
make it big, do it right,
give it class.
So how do you make the stuff?
It's very, very simple, but
there's a change the normal
recipe that you may
have found online.
And so these are the materials
you're going to need-- a
little bit of glue--
OK, a lot of glue--
some water, and some
Mule Team Borax.
A box of this will last you a
life, but this is the secret
to making all the slimes and
gaks and ooze and all those
other things.
It's the cross linker.
We'll talk about the chemistry
here in just a second.
First, the glue.
I would suggest using
Elmer's Glue.
Don't use school glue
or anything else.
Elmer's Glue is actually
polyvinyl acetate, and
polyvinyl acetate has the same
behavior as polyvinyl alcohol,
which is the main ingredient
for slime.
So that's why it
works so well.
You think of this-- it's
just like spaghetti.
You cook spaghetti, and
in the pot, those
noodles move around.
The pasta moves back
and forth.
Even when you drain the water,
it still slips and slides all
over each other.
That's exactly what
glue is like.
Once glue dehydrates, though,
and all the water's gone,
those molecules now stick into
place wherever they were.
And so that's how glue works.
What we want to do is to
keep all the moisture.
In fact, we want to add some
moisture and hook the
molecules together
at the same time.
All right, I'm adding water.
It's hard to tell you
exactly how much.
You just want this really,
really soupy mess in here.
And there's no substitute to
getting your fingers in there
and feeling it.
It is going to feel
very, very runny.
And you know that that's the
perfect consistency.
It's still thick and viscous,
but not nearly
as thick as it was.
This is pretty good.
There's no going back and adding
more water later on, so
you're going to want to
experiment with a small batch
before you make a large
one to know exactly
how it should feel.
Technically speaking, Borax
is sodium tetraborate.
It's the perfect cross linker
that we need to hook those
molecules together.
It's very simple to make
a solution with water.
You just need to make a
saturated solution.
So a saturated solution is a
solution when you stir it up
and let it sit for a second
that there's still a small
amount remaining on
the very bottom.
It's when that last teaspoon
doesn't dissolve.
That's a saturated solution.
That's a perfect Borax
solution to hook
our molecules together.
It's when I pour in the Borax
solution like this that you
start to see the stringiness.
Again, there's no substitute
for getting in there and
really mixing it around.
You may have to make up some
more Borax solution.
Again, it's totally by feel.
Every batch is a little
bit different.
While you can use a standard
recipe, it's best to just use
your hand and make
it by touch.
I can tell that it's starting
to work out, but we need
definitely a little bit more
water, a little bit more Borax
to hook this last little
piece together.
We want this gooey, slimy
consistency, but we don't want
to sticking to the sides.
All
Right.
This is just about the
perfect consistency.
This is what you want, for
one piece of it, anyway.
So you can see the movement
of this, because it
is this great material.
Make the same batch again, but
this time add some food
coloring to it.
I like to make it blue.
This is a non-Newtonian fluid,
meaning that it doesn't obey
the laws that Newton--
Isaac Newton-- set
out to describe--
something that goes from a
liquid to a solid or from a
solid to a liquid.
You can see that this flowing
liquid here actually has
solid-like properties when
you add pressure to it.
Watch.
See how it breaks off?
It literally shears off an edge,
very similar to what a
glacier does when that
pressure is there.
You have literally a liquid--
the constant movement shearing
off into a solid.
Yet if you allow it to work its
way back together again,
it becomes and flows
just like a liquid.
It's perfect to explain the
properties of a glacier.
Now you can see why we want
a different color.
Blue and the white is
perfect, because now
we can see the movement.
If you were actually in Alaska
and you could see the ice, you
would see blue ice.
It's just this water that has
this tremendous amount of
pressure on it.
And as those molecules get
packed together, it's
literally more dense than
regular water, and the light
refracts through there
differently than it normally
would through just regular water
that we would normally
see in a glass.
So let me fold this in.
Ah, this is great.
Good.
And now, as we break this-- the
shear factor-- you start
to see these layers that are
inside that look fantastic.
Let's allow it to flow
like a real glacier.
Perfect.
Notice how it's already
starting to flow.
The weight of this is now
causing it to move down.
And it moves ever so slowly.
That's why this is so good
when we're teaching
kids about a glacier.
You can actually talk about the
glacier receding or the
glacier advancing.
And in this particular case, you
can see how the weight of
the gak here is pushing
this part of it down.
Take a look here
along the edge.
If you were in Alaska, the
naturalists would tell you
that that shoreline, over the
years, actually was picked up
by the glacier.
And you get this glacial silt
that's moving its way in.
And you can see it actually
come into the glacier.
Well, as cool as this is,
nothing compares to standing
in front of a glacier and
actually seeing a piece of the
ice calve off and to hear that
crunching sound of the ice.
Well, we created an experience
called Science at Sea.
We partnered with our friends
at Holland America, and the
whole goal was to take a hundred
science enthusiasts--
people like you-- on a week
long expedition and to go
places that other normal people
couldn't go with some
of the best naturalists
in the world.
Well, that's what we did with
Science at Sea in Glacier Bay.
Take a look at this.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
FEMALE SPEAKER: We saw a
breaching humpback whale right
out there, that shore.
JOHN SCHEERENS: We're looking
at one of the most exciting
things here in Glacier Bay
National Park, which is a
humpback whale breaching
completely out of the water--
a 40 ton animal throwing most of
its body is completely out
of the water.
We've had a group of probably
35 to 50 people up here all
morning since 8:30-- it's
now about 11:30--
in the rain watching whales.
It's been a pretty exciting
morning out here on our way
into Glacier Bay.
We're just getting started.
[MUSIC PLAYING]