GELAREH KIAZAND: So here,
we're at the dog fights.
-[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
GELAREH KIAZAND: He's saying,
it's wrong, it is bad.
Whatever people may think, I
love it, and I'm going to do
it until the day I die.
Because that's my addiction.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
GELAREH KIAZAND: When you think
of gambling, you think
of Las Vegas and tacky
slot machines.
And when you think of
Afghanistan, you think of its
reputation for corruption,
its never-ending
wars, and the Taliban.
But in spite of all this, the
men of Kabul have found refuge
in a world of quail fighting
parlors and dusty
dog fighting circles.
We're going to explore this
culture of illicit gambling
and see how the men of Kabul
thrive in a realm of sport
that defies Islam.
We're going to Marshal
Fahim's gardens.
This is really exciting.
We just got a phone call saying
that there might be a
buzkashi game on today.
So we're on our way there now,
and hopefully we can see the
game and maybe talk to
his spokesperson.
Buzkashi is the national
sport of Afghanistan.
It's a lot like polo, but
instead of a ball, they play
with a headless goat carcass.
The sport is legal, but all
the side betting that the
crowds take part in is not.
And since Afghanistan's vice
president, Marshal Mohammed
Fahim, was hosting the game at
his estate, it was a bit
tricky for us to get in.
-[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
GELAREH KIAZAND:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
-[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
GELAREH KIAZAND:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
-[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
GELAREH KIAZAND: All right, so
we got in, and then we got
sent out again.
Because today, Mr.
Fahim decided to
show up to the game.
And with Fahim, they're not
going to be allowing just
anyone-- especially
a foreigner, a
woman, with a camera.
Kabul is the center of
this gambling world.
But since betting is illegal,
reputation is very important.
It was unlikely that they were
going to allow an Iranian
woman into the bettor's circle,
especially with a camera.
So we had to find some one
people trusted, an old-timer--
Dardar.
We're in West Kabul right now.
We're to meet Mr.
Samad Dardar.
He's an 80-year-old man who,
back in the days, they called
him The Gangster, because
of all the fights
he used to get into.
He's a very, very hard
man to get a hold of.
ABDUL SAMAD DARDAR:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
GELAREH KIAZAND:
ABDUL SAMAD DARDAR:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
GELAREH KIAZAND: So he was just
angry that I didn't know
him that well.
ABDUL SAMAD DARDAR:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
GELAREH KIAZAND:
ABDUL SAMAD DARDAR:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
GELAREH KIAZAND:
ABDUL SAMAD DARDAR:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
-[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
ABDUL SAMAD DARDAR:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
GELAREH KIAZAND: Thursday
morning--
our first in.
We get a phone call
from Dardar.
8:00 AM, there will be
a quail fight 20
minutes outside of Kabul.
We're at Saleh Dezama's cafe.
It's away from all the
craze of the city.
They're very strict on the
people they let in.
They don't just let anyone in.
During the Talib times,
obviously this place was
closed down, and no one
would come here.
-[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
GELAREH KIAZAND: The Taliban
banned the sport, largely
because the fights were
community-driven and brought a
wide spectrum of influential men
together that could form
alliances dangerous
to the regime.
So head of the circle is sitting
there with the white
bag in front of him.
I'm trying to get people to put
more birds out or fight a
bit, because they're
a bit reluctant in
front of the camera.
Everyone here pretty much
has a bird with them.
They usually fight for
a couple hours.
They sell them behind here in
case you don't have one.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
GELAREH KIAZAND: So what they're
doing right now is,
they go around and they start
comparing the different quails
to each other.
So what they have to
do is, they have to
get the same weight.
And then, once they pick, then
they come out in the middle.
So how does a bird win?
One quail has to push the other
out of the ring, or in
this case, close to the
edge of the carpet.
When a quail is pushed out of
the ring, or simply flees,
it's game over.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
GELAREH KIAZAND: After the
first couple rounds, the
betting slowed down.
The Taliban were known for
targeting animal fights and
gambling rings when they
were in power.
And even now, the bettors were
nervous about being caught
gambling on camera.
The owner noticed, and told us
to turn off our cameras.
Yeah, they want us to leave.
-[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
GELAREH KIAZAND:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
-[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
GELAREH KIAZAND: I was just
asking why they're not
bringing their women
to the fights.
He's like, no, she has
to stay at home.
-[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[MUSIC PLAYING]