or assumptions, like am I
predicating this on the way
things were 30 or 50
or more years ago?
It becomes overwhelming.
I go to the conventions and it's
insane, the quality level
and the intelligence of
a lot of the people.
And it's just so phenomenal--
it just took off.
NICK BUBASH: Thom deVita, what
set him apart was that he was
doing tattoos, because nobody
else was doing tattoos.
ED HARDY: Of course it was
completely underground.
And if anybody said anything,
you said we're going to see
The Tattoo Man.
He was so thoroughly integrated
in being a denizen
in Manhattan.
NICK BUBASH: Thom was reflecting
his environment
through his tattoos.
MALE SPEAKER (OFFSCREEN): Were
you known for your designs?
THOM DEVITA: No, I was known
for $30 tattoos.
VALERIE VARGAS: I was heavily
into comic books and stuff
when I was younger, so
there was a lot of
that kind of influence.
If somebody asked me for a woman
or a figure, I'd just go
crazy with it.
STEWART ROBSON: Valerie can
characterize a mood and a
feeling in a tattoo.
She understands that stuff.
I think she understood
that stuff before
she understood tattooing.
DANTE DIMASSA: I hadn't
planned on
giving Valerie a job.
It was almost by mistake,
to be quite honest.
STEWART ROBSON: She can tattoo
circles around most of the
tattooers that work
around her.
Now everyone knows
Valerie Vargas.
MUTSUO: [SPEAKING JAPANESE]
MASA: [SPEAKING JAPANESE]
ED HARDY: We never dreamed that
it would get like this.
In terms of just art, like the
imagery and tattooers working
on stuff that doesn't
necessarily have to be tattooed.
And I don't know anything
else in the world that
happened like that.