You know, before you got all swollen up,
I actually thought you were trying
to keep me out of the apartment
so you could throw me a surprise party.
Right, it's your birthday.
I had no idea it was your birthday.
I completely forgot.
What a lousy way to spend a birthday.
It's all over now.
There is a party, isn't there?
Maybe.
- Are you mad?
- How could I be mad?
You actually risked your life
because you care about me.
Yeah, that's why I did it.
All right.
Here we go.
My first birthday party.
Dude,
everybody left an hour ago.
Surprise!
Okay, Leonard.
I am at your birthday party.
I don't know where you are,
dude, but it's really kick-ass!
Everyone is very, very drunk and...
And look,
there's a girl taking her shirt off!
That's my friend Carol.
Remind me,
I gotta introduce her to Howard.
Oh, sweet Krishna,
shake that rupee maker!
I'm so sorry you didn't get your party.
It's okay.
Happy birthday, anyways.
When's your birthday?