Out near the orbit of Jupiter, a faint speck
of light is moving through the black of space.
At first glance it doesn't look like much,
no brighter than a thousand distant stars
speckling the velvet sky behind it; indeed,
it takes a big telescope make out that it
is a comet.
But what a comet it could turn out to be…
Later this year, “Comet ISON” could blossom
into a striking naked eye object visible even
in broad daylight.
“Comet ISON is a sun grazer,” explains
Karl Battams of the Naval Research Lab. “The
orbit of the comet will bring it very close
to the sun, which we know can be a spectacular
thing.”
Russian astronomers Vitali Nevski and Artyom
Novichonok found the comet in Sept. 2012.
It bears the name of their night-sky survey
program, the International Scientific Optical
Network, or ISON.
As 2013 unfolds, the comet is still very far
away, near the orbit of Jupiter.   That’s
why it looks like a speck.   “But for
an object at such extreme distance, it is
actually very bright," says Battams.
The comet’s glow suggests that is spewing
gas and dust from a fairly large nucleus,
“in the 1 to 10 km range,” estimates Matthew
Knight of the Lowell Observatory.
On Nov. 28, 2013, this “dirty snowball”
will fly through the sun's atmosphere little
more than a million km from the stellar surface.
If the comet survives, a big IF, it could
emerge glowing as brightly as the Moon, briefly
visible near the sun in broad daylight. The
comet's dusty tail stretching into the night
sky could create a worldwide sensation.
Some reporters have started calling ISON the
"Comet of the Century," but Don Yeomans of
NASA Near-Earth Object Program thinks that's
premature.
"I'm old enough to remember the last 'Comet
of the Century'," he says.  In 1973, a distant
comet named Kohoutek looked like it would
put on a great show, much like ISON.  The
actual apparition was such a letdown that
Johnny Carson made jokes about it on the Tonight
Show. “It fizzled,” says Yeomans. “Comets
are notoriously unpredictable.”
"Comet ISON has the potential to live up to
the hype, but it also has the potential to
do nothing," agrees Battams.
One hazard is the sun. Solar radiation can
affect the comet’s trajectory and gravitational
effects have been known to destroy comets.
A recent example is Comet Elenin, which broke
apart and dissipated in 2011 as it approached
the sun.  Elenin, however, was a much smaller
comet.
A better comparison, perhaps, is Comet Lovejoy,
which flew through the sun's atmosphere in
2011.  Lovejoy emerged intact and wowed observers
with a garish tail for weeks.
"Comet ISON is probably at least twice as
big as Comet Lovejoy,” notes Knight. “This
would seem to favor Comet ISON surviving and
ultimately putting on a good show.
One of the most exciting possibilities would
be a partial break-up.  "If Comet ISON splits,
it might appear as a 'string of pearls' when
viewed through a telescope," speculates Battams.
“It might even resemble the famous Comet
Shoemaker-Levy 9 that hit Jupiter in 1994.”
A break-up would pose no threat to Earth,
assures Yeomans.  "Comet ISON is not on a
collision course. If it breaks up, the fragments
would continue along the same safe trajectory
as the original comet."
Whatever happens, northern sky watchers will
get a good view. For months after it swings
by the sun, Comet ISON will be well placed
for observers in the northern hemisphere.
It will pass almost directly over the North
Pole, making it a circumpolar object visible
all night long.
Will comet ISON fizzle or sizzle? The answer
will be plain to see.