bill o'reilly in his guest doctor keep
ab allow
but gonna try to explain
dot norm style
yes
this is gonna be or so
validly say that i south korean guy a
call themself cylia
has put out a video that has been viewed
more than eight hundred million times on
the net that's a record
hill road blood infrastructure abruptly
still lifestyle e
but or jasmine decide
what's wrong with you
but it was best for
apparently they have trouble
understanding within the video
i think with this fellow's tapping into
uh... is in fact this side p_s_ why is
tapping into the fact that people don't
want any meaning right now music the
most popular music apparently is that
intelligible words to some extent that's
simply conveys year to uh... distant
place be twice doesn't try to convince
you to anything i doesn't try to raise
your emotions it just is sort of like a
drug and that seems to be what most
people seem to want right now in the
ality not feeling not mean alright so it
means nothing
but it's uh... it's got a nice up
to it and you can uh... do the pony
and right around
that that i can not
reacting to meaning is that it has no
meaning
uh... it is the son of face book if you
will the false face that so many people
now put on their lives uh... the lack of
insight if you will
or to start
so i think i've already does leave that
up
that well
is without intelligible words
or a but
instead different language
its inquiry
la jolla you up and said i want to say
that i can say i guess i don't know
maybe
alfonse nearest body key on the man
god how unbelievably stearate are you
the entire another excited excited trial
goes on and self and interest
but it never has a meeting by the way
that she does have a meeting
he is satirizing begun num district in
south korea which is where a lot of rich
folks apparently lived answers you no
doubt that forces the stables et cetera
that lifestyle they're close this out
now that's a mess of course fighters
would like
but they didn't even bother to check
that out of the interview or does that
make up for our directory
but it continues to get better and
better
listen to bill o'reilly perot-like
where's the sky
animate
sick not like anybody i don't
elvis presley's didn't invent sexuality
but he tapped into the growing sexuality
outlook well better why why why why why
way elvis presley can sit
nearly good boys his son who has worked
stone from the s ok products
well he put on a sharjah show
this is a little fact i've from yang
yang research places see all wearing
sunglasses whatever
andy's jumping up and down
is no comparison between side
and i you know they're like sixteen guys
name sai long island i can tell you
about the don't look like him
alva suicides
had worked
this also rose words it's in correa
is awfully well read this is exactly how
they think if we click if you're not
exactly like maybe don't look like me
besides i don't know what i had no one
would look like at all
immuno speak like i speak in u wide-eyed
a different language it
well then you look in those words don't
actually exists
and of course you can hear as good as
gold this year about what her anger
side alright hotlanta planet just on the
pony okay
and by the way
he's not permit yang yang
young gang is in north korea
now twice keep ab allow all bent up
about this family he's more mad the no
riley's
pillow talk
better more
highlight a little kids book i wrote i
sent a note if you probably should send
a
bemoan the fact is teaching it seems
like it has a message
isn't law yet about empowerment well
books about messages right now itself
take along with the cable if you want
that kind of stuff to secure a student
at kibbutz in it
filled with the elephant that you take
the little pig likes red shoes
to try to talk about courage that's not
going to be purchased by the great
masses who now want not to be tapped on
the heartstrings if you will but simply
to be pushed toward a good beat
patents workbooks well
is going on
people and you know it
is
if they had great not like their part
is this possibly
exile cm long with this uh... israel on
it
well look uh... is there anything wrong
with it uh... i guess i'd say this
to the extent that you're evelyn things
that don't speak to you that you use
something to transport you away from
real fought and deep feeling now there's
something wrong with their eyes only
decision a dozen times a day that might
not be good
do you like your attitude
fetuses get in hyd
and now i have been miniature paralegals
and i have brought up
yeti hai
fifty separate ever doubted it was like
a drug
anti-islamic doesn't speak to you really
doesn't speak to you because you're
crabby old white guy stain glass apple
cider adult
but that's not what i don't like that
what in there but my book what like cell
on support what the better than me
i was still there is staying with
interpolation and i love how the final
day working tues can explain it
here might have been or at least removal
but i
tigers in toddlers i'd never
miscommunication
you can explain that
uh...
don imus outcomes and depend on him
sebab goes out
you can't explain
mirabella