Bryan May: For the New
Madrid earthquake.
Wilma Bryant: For a
series of F-5 tornados.
Narrator: And
protect themselves.
Aton Edwards:
Watch it Tim,
push him away,
push him away.
Cameron Moore:
Stop right there!
Narrator: From what they
perceive is the fast
approaching end of the
world as we know it.
Jayden Southwick: Dad!
Braxton Southwick:
Leave her alone!
Narrator: Next, we go
inside the lives of two
committed preppers,
who have devised an
extensive plan,
gone to great lengths.
Tom: Come right here!
Narrator: And made huge
personal sacrifices,
to ensure their
very survival.
And take on the
apocalypse, together.
Steve: This is
not the plan!
Let us the
hell in!
Narrator: The experts
will assess their preps,
to see if they
have what it takes.
Steven: Target
acquired Tom.
Narrator:
To survive.
Tom: Bring on
the terrorists.
Narrator: This is
Doomsday Preppers.
Dr. Tom Perez is a
retired chiropractor,
who lives in
Houston, Texas
with his wife Monica
and their three kids.
Tom: I have a daughter
by the name of Kat.
Our son Thomas
is 12 years old
and we have Matthew,
the youngest.
Narrator: The Perez's
built their 6800 square
foot home in an upscale
neighborhood near good
schools and
high-end shopping.
But Tom's trained his
family to give up their
life of luxury in
a moment's notice.
Tom: We do not plan
to stay in Houston;
we plan to bug
out as quickly
and efficiently
as we can.
I'm preparing for a
terroristic attack.
On your knees!
Man: Please.
Narrator: Tom fears
the dirty bomb.
An everyday explosive,
like dynamite or TNT,
packed with
radioactive material.
Once detonated, its blast
can spread radiation
anywhere from a city block
to several square miles.
But that radioactive
debris could lodge in
buildings, and chemically
bind with concrete and
asphalt, making
decontaminating a city
difficult, and possibly
forcing affected
neighborhoods
to be abandoned.
Tom: If a dirty bomb
exploded in the Houston
metroplex area there
would be disarray.
There would be
people yelling,
screaming,
shooting.
There could be looting,
home invasions.
People would do things
they normally wouldn't do.
I do not want to
be around that and
I do not want to put
my family at risk.
Narrator: Because Tom
fears Houston could be
uninhabitable after a
dirty bomb explosion,
his entire prepping plan
begins with bugging out.
Tom: If the (bleep)
hit the fan I
would definitely
get out of there.
We practice how quickly
we can get out of our
homestead and
load up our goods,
so we can get
out of Houston.
Narrator: The fastest
Tom and his family have
bugged out of their
home is 10 minutes,
a drill they usually
practice twice a month.
Matthew:
Hurry, hurry.
Tom: Get strapped
in, okay buddy?
Narrator: Today
is the start of
their 3rd drill
this year.
Tom: You got
everything?
You got your gun?
That's bugging out.
Narrator: Tom's bug out
route bypasses over
3,000 miles of
Houston's highways and
once on the open road,
they travel due west
to their safe house.
300 miles away in
Brackettville, Texas.
Tom: We have prepped
for many years
to go to a compound.
Narrator: It's normally a
six-hour drive to Tom's
compound, but he
believes it could take
as many as 21 hours, if
the other two million
Houstonians are also
attempting to flee.
As a result, Tom
has three back-up,
bug-out routes.
Tom: You cannot over
prepare for a disaster.
Narrator: The Perez's
bug out compound is
700 acres bigger
than 100 square
New York City blocks.
Tom's nicknamed
his compound and
its two limestone
homes "the Alamo."
Tom: This is what we
consider our last stand.
Narrator: The original
Alamo in San Antonio is
synonymous with
a last stand
against
impossible odds.
If the Perez's ever
come under siege,
Tom wants to
ensure they don't
suffer the same fate.
So he's spent 10 years
and more than two million
dollars turning his Alamo
into a veritable fortress.
Tom: I designed it, set
up the security for it.
We have layers
of security,
such as solid steel
bars on the windows,
we have alarms.
Narrator: Tom's Alamo
is fortified with
seven-inch thick,
bulletproof walls.
Surrounding it is four
miles of seven-foot tall
barbed wire fencing.
And beyond that is the
Chihuahuan desert;
the largest desert
in North America.
Tom: It is a
harsh terrain.
It would be hard
for individuals
to come across
this barren area.
That's why we
decided to have this
as our safe
bug out area.
For me prepping is
not an obsession,
it's therapeutic.
When I pass
our gates here,
my blood pressure
drops 8 to 10 points.
Narrator: But
not before Tom
performs a
security check.
The rest of the family
must wait in the vehicle
until Tom determines
it's safe to enter.
Tom modeled his security
check strategy after a
SWAT team technique called
"deliberate entry."
Anyone in here?
Narrator: Which
is typically used
in narcotic raids
when the exact
location of a
threat is unknown.
Tom: Anyone
in here?
Okay, cabin
one secure.
Narrator: Once the
cabins are secure,
Tom makes sure
every other part of
his plan is in
working order.
Tom: I spend
approximately five hours,
six hours a day
determining what
I have prepped.
We investigate, modify,
exchange, sell,
to have the most current
available MRE meals,
rifles, ammunition.
Prepping is infinite.
Narrator: Tom
maintains about
46,000 rounds
of ammunition;
enough bullets to
shoot every person
in the county
12 times.
But all of Tom's preps
play a defensive role,
even his food and water.
The Perez's have a
nine-month supply of food
at the ranch, but not all
of it is safe to eat.
Tom: I also have
taken the liberty of
contaminating 10% of my
food and water supply.
If it is ever compromised,
I'm the only one that
knows which supplies
are affected.
Narrator: Tom wants his
toxic supplies to be an
unwelcome surprise
to anyone foolish
enough to storm
the Alamo.
But while most preppers
might consider
contaminating water
counter intuitive,
Tom isn't worried
because he has an
almost endless
supply.
Tom: This is my
lifeline for water.
Narrator: Tom
strategically built his
ranch above the
Edwards aquifer,
an underground water
source roughly 10 times
larger than the
city of Los Angeles.
The aquifer provides
water to close to
two million Texans
everyday and
Tom has his own
personal access.
His 45-foot tall windmill
draws water directly up
from 1,000 feet
below ground and
can pump 11,000
gallons a day.
Tom: As long as
the aquifers are
energized by rainfall
we should have
adequate water for
many years to come.
Narrator: If the Alamo
ever comes under attack,
and the windmill
is damaged,
Tom's main water supply
could be cut off,
so he has a reserve
supply of more than
2,000 gallons in
concrete tanks.
Tom: I coulda gone
with plastic tanks,
woulda been a lot
easier, a lot cheaper.
Narrator: Unlike plastic,
concrete is fire resistant
and Tom believes it
will keep his water
protected against
incendiary bombs,
such as Molotov
cocktails.
To test his theory, he's
making his own brand of
Molotov cocktail from a
secret recipe of ordinary
household items,
like high proof alcohol
and detergent.
Tom: Torch fuel, don't
leave home without it.
Narrator: Tom's goal
is to make his custom
recipe produce a longer
lasting flame that can
stick to a target,
similar to the
effects of napalm.
Tom: Now that's a good
Molotov cocktail.
Narrator: With the help
of local law enforcement,
he's ready to test it
for the first time,
to prove his tank is
in fact fireproof.
Tom: Bring on
the terrorists.
From what I've seen
after numerous examples
of these explosives,
it's built to last.
It can take a
licking and
will keep on
storing water.
Narrator: If survivors of
a dirty bomb attack do
penetrate every layer
of Tom's security,
he has a last line of
defense, his family.
Tom: How would you
defend the door?
What would
you do,
since we've been
talking about it?
Matthew: Shoot
through the window.
Narrator: Tom
knows he can't
defend the
Alamo alone.
So he's been training
17-year-old Kat,
12-year-old Tommy, and
six-year-old Matthew
how to use
various firearms.
Tom: If you're going to
talk to your children
about drugs, talk to
them about prepping.
It's no different.
Narrator: Matthew,
who has been shooting
since the age of four,
can hit a target from
100 yards
away with his
child-sized
sniping rifle.
Matthew: Really
prepared for,
like invasion
or something.
Tommy: He's not
like other dads.
He teaches us many
tactical ways to survive.
Tom: Wow,
that is good.
Katarina: He's very
smart, very smart.
You know we're always,
like, on our toes.
Monica: He
orchestrates pretty
much everything as far
as keeping us safe.
Narrator: Because
Tom wants his family
ready at all times,
he drills their defense
skills weekly.
Tom: Alright
hold my spot.
Narrator: So, today he's
asked off-duty officers
from the local
sheriff's department
to ambush
their home.
Without telling
his three kids.
Katarina: Don't give
him the gun Thomas!
Officer Villarreal:
I'll shoot her!
Put your
gun down!
Katarina: No,
get away!
Narrator: Fearing a
dirty bomb attack in
his home city of
Houston, Texas,
Tom Perez has
built himself a
700-acre compound
300 miles away
called "the Alamo."
He routinely drills his
family's defensive skills,
and today he's having
off-duty officers from the
local sheriff's department
attack the compound.
But his wife and three
kids don't know it yet.
Tom: Grandpa's here,
Grandpa's here.
Narrator: Tom's trained
his family to quickly
respond to specific
code phrases,
each of which indicates
a particular threat.
Monica: "Grandpa's here"
means get ready.
There's an
intruder, get armed.
Narrator: In the
"grandpa's here"
counter attack strategy;
Tom's given each family
member a designated post.
Monica patrols the east
side of the property,
while the children take
a defensive position
closer to the home,
armed with AR-15's.
Officer Spence: We
need water please.
Please help
my friend.
He's over here.
Officer Spence:
Please, please.
Monica: Get down.
Narrator: Tom thinks
that bands of marauders
will stop at nothing
to gain access to the
Alamo and its
supplies.
Monica: Get
down, get down.
Officer Spence:
Please help.
Please, I'm
not armed.
Monica:
Get down.
Narrator: Today, he
wants to see how
his two youngest
would react if their
father, mother, and
older sister have
men holding guns
to their heads.
Officer Villarreal:
Put y'alls guns down.
Put the gun down,
I'll shoot her.
Katarina: Thomas, don't
give him the gun!
Officer Villarreal:
I'll shoot her!
Katarina: Don't
give him the gun!
Officer Villarreal:
I'll shoot her!
Katarina:
Matthew, no!
Get away!
Officer Villarreal:
Put your gun down.
Put your hands
behind your head.
Sheriff Pena: Ok,
everyone quit.
We're done,
c'mon in.
Katarina: It's scary
to see my mom getting
held up by one of the
gunman and seeing
my two little brothers
just surrendering.
Thomas: Me and my
little brother we were
kind of not sure
what to do.
Officer Gutierrez:
Criticize right
off the bat;
everybody comes
out of the house.
Everybody should
be in the house.
For your
protection.
Narrator: Officer
Gutierrez believes coming
outside the safety of
the house makes each of
them more vulnerable
to assault.
Officer Gutierrez:
Carlos came up behind
the house, picked
your daughter off.
Officer Spence: I
was getting close.
It's okay to
be aggressive.
Don't be afraid to,
to be aggressive.
You know you were
going away from the
threat instead
of coming to it.
Tom: I like that
recommendation of being
aggressive and you
know get in there
and putting
them down.
Katarina: I think my
family needs more time
and more planning on
strategies because
like a situation
today, you know,
everything just
fell apart.
Tom: I will tell
you one thing,
I will heed to
those criticisms,
and I will implement
what's necessary.
Thank you so much
for your time.
This is the Alamo and we
will be here to defend it.
Narrator: Tom believes
defending the Alamo's
expansive land and
provisions is a greater
task than his family of
five can take on alone.
So to strengthen their
forces against what
could be millions of
displaced Houstonians,
Tom recruited another
prepping family.
When the time
comes, Victoria,
Gobriela and Steve
Vanasse will unite with
Tom at "the Alamo."
Steve: Prepping is
probably in the back
of my mind
more than sex.
Tom: Steven, he's
rather unusual.
However, he is no
different than what I am.
Steve: I'm preparing
for a dirty bomb blast
in the city
of Houston.
The time of reckoning is
just around the corner
and that's why
I'm prepping and
that's why the rest
of you are prepping.
A dirty bomb is
particularly dangerous
because of the readily
available nature of any
radionuclide that would
be used in a dirty bomb.
Elements such as
cesium, strontium;
those radionuclides
are available in
medicine in the
medical field.
Narrator: Radioactive
substances can be
found in hospitals,
research facilities
and construction
sites.
These materials are
required to be secured
from unauthorized
access,
but Steve fears a
theft could occur.
Steve: It's so easy
to manufacture.
The unpredictability
of a dirty bomb
is the terrorists'
best weapon.
We've been
lucky so far.
I don't think our
fortune will hold out.
Some might call
preparing for
a disaster an
obsession.
I am obsessed with
my family's safety.
Narrator: A single dirty
bomb could contaminate an
area thirty times the size
of the initial blast site,
which could cover up
to twenty city blocks.
The radiation would not be
detected by human senses,
and the effects of
exposure can be immediate.
Steve checks radiation
levels in his home once a
week using a calibrated
Geiger Mueller probe.
Victoria: Can you use
it on someone else?
Steve: Sure.
Narrator: Many preppers
purchase radiation meters,
but unless one has
been trained in how to
interpret readings,
like Steve,
nuclear experts consider
Geiger counters
worthless.
Steve: Your counts
per minute are
reading very well,
looking very low.
Gobriela: Good.
Tom: I have chosen
Steven because he
has expertise in
areas that I am weak.
Steve: I've been
certified as a
radiation
specialist.
The filed I am in,
I'm constantly reminded
of the necessity to
prepare and be safe.
Narrator: Steve
is a radiation
safety officer for
a company that
assesses contaminated
sites throughout Texas.
An area of expertise Tom
values highly in preparing
for radioactive dispersal
from a dirty bomb.
Steve: Graham, I
have the water sample
from the bayou.
Graham: Oh good,
excellent thank you.
Let's just see
what we got here.
Narrator: But radiation
exposure is not Steves main
concern in prepping for
a dirty bomb explosion.
Steve: The dirty bomb
would be the tipping
point that pushes mild
Houstonians into chaos.
Narrator: Steve thinks
anarchy following an
attack could
be more deadly,
so amassing firearms
is his top priority.
Steve: I want to
be able to defend
against a
large-scale assault,
should such an
assault occur.
Narrator: In fact, when
Steve became a prepper,
the first thing he did
was purchase a rifle.
And his collection
has grown since.
Steve: I have more
than one weapon
because I consider
my family backup
as well too.
I wanna train Victoria
in the proper
and responsible
use of firearms.
For goodness
sakes, who knows?
Someday she might
have my back.
Victoria: I don't
want to shoot guns.
Gobriela: I think about
Victoria firing a gun.
It freak me out.
It's very
dangerous.
I don't like the idea,
but she need to do it.
Victoria: Yes, I
really have to learn
cause I "need" to.
Where are we going?
Steve: Victoria, we are
going to Shiloh shooting
range, introduce you to
the proper handling of
firearms and respect
for firearms.
Just want you
to be safe.
We take all these
opportunities
to do things
as a family.
It's our
prepping.
Tracy: Uh, so we're
gonna learn to
shoot some guns
today right?
Victoria: Right.
Tracy: Have you
every shot before?
Steve: Yes.
Tracy: And
have you?
Victoria: No.
Tracy: And uh
what caliber are
you experienced with?
Steve: 40 cal, I have a
40 caliber I'm carrying now.
Tracy: All right well
let's head back to the range.
Steve: Thanks.
Narrator: The 40 caliber
pistol is considered
one of the most
effective hand guns in
stopping a threat
with a single shot.
And is used by many
law enforcement
agencies across
the country.
But Victoria will be
learning how to use a
.22, which is
considered a top choice
for beginners, because
there is less recoil.
Tracy: Rack it back
and just let it go.
That will
load the gun.
Alright so we're
gonna push out,
slowly gonna work
your finger back on
the trigger
nice and easy,
and the gun
goes off
and you make
your shot.
Okay?
That's gonna be
about how loud it is.
Alright, you ready
to give it a try?
Victoria: No,
but yes.
Tracy: There
you go, lovely.
Stuff that in
there, good.
It's ok.
You see that front
sight right there?
You see that dot?
Now try and keep that
front sight on the x as
you bring that
trigger back nice and
smooth and slow
for me okay?
Great job,
very nice;
that was a
good shot.
Victoria: Really?
Tracy: Yeah, look,
very good job.
How'd that feel?
Victoria: Weird.
Tracy: Weird.
A little bit
exciting?
nervous?
Victoria: Yea a
little bit exciting.
Tracy: Yeah, you want
to try another round?
Ok, let it go.
Okay slowly
work it back.
Good job!
Right next
to my shot.
Very good,
you're a natural.
Dad's so proud.
Usually the younger
girls are a little bit
more timid and scared
but she dived right in
and did her thing, she
did a really good job.
Victoria: I was
scared because I was
scared of
hurting someone.
Steven: I feel so
proud right now.
Victoria: I don't think
I will shoot again.
Steven: And I feel like
I'm better prepared now,
because I can
count on Victoria.
Narrator: While Steve
is just starting to
train his daughter how
to protect herself,
his prepping
partner, Tom Perez,
has been conditioning his
children since birth.
But, he thinks there are
still some skills they
need to master, in order
to prove to him they
have what it takes to
survive at the Alamo.
Tom: Ok give
me your hand.
You ready?
Tommy: Yeah.
Tom: Hold it
tight, real hard.
Narrator: For
the last 4 years,
Tom Perez has been
collaborating
with his prepping
prepper, Steve Vanasse.
Together they've created
a plan to escape a dirty
bomb attack in Houston,
and unite at Tom's
700-acre ranch in
Brackettville Texas,
which is equipped
with two homes,
stored food stuffs,
and unlimited water.
But Tom believes their
stocked supplies will
eventually run out,
and they will have to
live off their land's
natural resources.
Tom: Here at the
compound we use various
methods to capture
animals by using
snares and traps.
Narrator: Tom uses
restraining traps,
which are designed
to keep an animal
alive until the
hunter returns.
Tom: By knowing how to
trap various critters
provides the nourishment
that we will need
to help us through
those hard times.
Narrator: Today he
wants his sons to finish
the job he started.
Tom: Today's
the big day.
You ready?
Tommy: Ya.
Tom: You looking
forward to it?
Tommy: Kind of.
Narrator: Tom is teaching
12-year-old Tommy and
6- year-old Matthew,
how to kill a goat.
A prepping rite of passage
in the Perez family.
Tom: If I'm not around
during doomsday or
terrorist attack,
hopefully I
will be here,
but if I am not that's
why you are here today.
And you are going
to learn today too.
Today we are going
to use your knife.
Did you sharpen
it today?
Matthew: What's a
terrorist attack?
Tom: You know
when they blew up.
They, they just do a
lot of bad stuff so.
So this is the backup
right here, ok?
Narrator: Tom is teaching
his sons how to kill a
goat with a knife,
rather than a gun,
because he believes that
ammunition will be in
finite supply after
a dirty bomb attack,
and knowing how to
use other weapons
will be essential.
Tom: Ok whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa.
Tommy and Matthew:
Whoa, it's a goat.
Tom: Well, I'll tell
you what, Thomas,
Uh I'm to climb
in there and
then hand
me my bag.
Okay?
If something happens
get your knife out.
Hold him down.
Hold him with your
fist like that.
Alright now
get up.
It's a quick,
painless death.
And you want to
be swift about it
because this animal
will provide
food for many days.
Okay?
Tommy: Uh-huh.
Tom: And we have
respect for animals.
Alright give
me your hand.
You ready?
Tommy: Yeah.
Tom: Hold it
tight, real hard.
Come right here.
Ok, ready?
Hold him down,
hold him down.
You did very good,
you did very good.
Matthew: Ugh.
Tom: Matthew
come over here.
I want you to come
over here this way
and face us
this way.
Why did we kill
this goat today?
Matthew: For extra
back up plan.
Tom: Good back up
plan, way to go.
He's gone to a
better place now.
Do you like
it out here?
Is it safer for us?
We'll be moving
here soon, okay?
Permanently.
Alright, Thomas here,
this was your first goat.
Narrator: As a symbol
of completing their
rite of passage,
Tommy and Matthew
will wear the blood
of their first kill.
Tom: Was this
your first goat?
Matthew: Yes.
Tom: Okay let me put
a little bit here.
And this shows
your manhood.
Now you guys
someday will do
this with your
children, ok?
I am very proud of you,
very proud of you.
1,2,3.
Tommy: The killing the
goat part was really,
really challenging
part for me.
I felt sad for
it, in a way.
Matthew: I felt
sad for the animal;
like you feel sad
when you kill a goat
or something.
To cut it's
neck off.
Tom: 2, 3.
All right there?
Okay there we go.
Narrator: Tom is
training himself,
and his kids
to survive a
world without
stored goods.
But their hunted game
is not just for them.
In following their
plan for doomsday,
the Perez and
Vanasse families
will soon
combine forces.
But Tom has decided
to make a change in
Steve's regular
arrival routine.
Tom: Get on
your knees.
Steve: This is
not the plan.
Tom: What plan?
Narrator: Steve
Vanasse and Tom Perez
have been prepping
together to survive a
dirty bomb attack in
the city of Houston.
They plan to team
up at Tom's ranch,
300 miles away in
Brackettville, Texas
where they will live
off their preps
and protect
what's theirs.
But their first step
towards survival is
getting out.
Steve: I don't plan
to know what Houston
will look like a week
or a month after
a dirty bomb
descends on Houston.
I'm leaving;
I'm heading
to the ranch.
Narrator: Steve believes
downtown Houston
will be ground zero in
a dirty bomb attack.
Because it is just four
miles from where his
family lives, he
thinks they could be
at risk for
radiation exposure.
So he puts Gobriela
and Victoria
to the ultimate
test, bugging out.
But before they can
leave their house,
Steve thinks they must
be protected from
the bomb's
radioactive debris.
Steve, Gobriela,
and Victoria
are wearing
Tyvek suits.
Steve: Put your
hood on first.
Narrator: Which protect
against hazardous
materials as small
as one micron and
make certain
radioactive particles
unable to penetrate
their skin.
Steve: Can you
grab the two bags?
I'll grab weapons.
Steve: Let me run
you off some strips.
Gobriela: Okay.
Steve: Get the big vents
up at the top too.
Narrator: Steve is
taping the vents
inside their car
because he's worried
about radioactive
dust from outside,
being pulled
into the vehicle.
In addition, they have
self-contained-breathing
apparatuses secured,
because inhaling bomb
particles,
could be fatal,
both immediately
and long-term.
Even though Houston
temperatures can reach
over 100 degrees,
they will not run the
air conditioner
during their bug out.
Victoria: Turn on
the air conditioner.
Steve: Unfortunately
I can't right now.
Victoria: Ayyye.
Steve: I know.
Great dry run
everyone.
Victoria: Are
we there yet?
Steve: We're trying
to move as far as
we can from an
anticipated blast zone.
Narrator: The distance
radioactive material could
travel in a dirty
bomb attack is
dependent on wind and
weather patterns.
Steve: Once we're
outside any anticipated
blast radius, we
can pull over,
take some readings.
If those readings look
good, we can relax.
Narrator: So
when bugging out,
Steve plans to stop
at various points to
determine if they've
outrun the radiation.
Steve: Victoria,
could you put
out your
hands please?
Narrator: But if Steve
determines they are
unsafe, they will
have to keep driving.
Steven: Let me
check your feet.
Readings are
all clear.
I think that we're
all clear here.
We'll be able
to take off our
personal protective
equipment.
Gobriela: Our bug out
today was wonderful,
quick and positive.
Victoria: No.
I didn't because it was
too hot in the suit.
Steve: My family really
came together on this.
From here, we're on to
our bug out location.
Narrator: Bugging
out to "the Alamo"
is central to
Steve's plan.
But even after prepping
together for four years,
Tom views Steve
as his protg.
Tom: Steve has
become an integral part
of our prepping.
However, I try to
give him advice,
but in my opinion,
I would say I'm a
better prepper.
Narrator:
Experience aside,
Tom thinks that
trust is what will
hold their survival
team together.
So today, for
the first time,
he is testing Steve's
commitment to their plan.
Steve: Hallelujah.
That is the best
site I could imagine.
Narrator: Tom has
trained his kids to
challenge the Vanasses
when they arrive,
to make sure they
do not bring
anyone but
themselves;
because Tom
perceives additional
people as a threat
to their survival.
Tom: Boy, let me
see your hands.
I'm not gonna let anyone
come on this property,
because each
person takes
away months
of supplies.
Who are you?
Slowly.
Steve: Be cool,
be cool.
Tom: Get on
your knees.
Steve: This is
not the plan.
This is not the plan!
Katarina: What
about the girls?
Do they have
weapons?
Steve: They're
both unarmed.
We drove all the
way from Houston,
let us the hell in.
Katarina: Dad,
its Steven!
They're friendlies.
Tom: Damn!
Steve: You scared
the hell out of me.
That's some serious
operational security Katarina.
Tom: Come on in.
Alright.
Steve: That
was alarming.
I had every course
of adrenaline
just pushing
through me.
He did exactly what
he should have done.
Narrator: Tom and
Steve will test their
most destructive
defense tactic yet.
And discover its
power is even more
dangerous than
they imagined.
Producer: We have an
ambulance on the way.
Narrator: Houston
prepper, Steve Vanasse,
has trained his wife,
and their 11 year old
daughter, to escape
the city after a
dirty bomb attack, and
drive 300 miles away
from the explosion's
radioactive dispersal.
Victoria: Are
we there yet?
Narrator: Their
final destination is
Brackettville, Texas,
where they plan to
live on a
700-acre compound
with Steve's
prepping partner,
Tom Perez and
his family of 5;
because Tom and Steve
believe strength,
is in numbers.
Steve: I really need
to thank Tom Perez
and his family for
including our family
in their bug
out plan.
Based on the
plans we've made,
our families can
form the basis of a
whole new society and
maybe a better society.
Narrator: Tom and
Steve believe their
post-apocalyptic
society will be built
on teamwork.
Steve: Katarina
and Victoria have
been working
on some basil,
and some garlic
and some oregano.
And so it is just
a combination on
the herbs the girls
have cultivated.
Narrator: When Tom and
Steve's family convene on
the ranch they live off
what they have prepped.
Tonight's dinner,
is an 80 pound goat,
which can yield 40
pounds of meat and
provide them with more
than 200 servings.
Steve: The
brains inside?
Tom: Oh yeah.
Steve: Yum.
Tom: Would you suck
the eyeballs out?
Steve: I would eat
every bit of it,
every bit of
the goat.
Tom: I forgot to
tell you this
was Thomas'
first kill.
Steve: You got to be proud
man, that's awesome.
Narrator: But the
main focus of Steve's
visit is to
assess and improve
their security maneuvers.
It could take more
than one hour to patrol
the perimeter of the
700 acre ranch on foot.
And even with 8
preppers on site,
not every inch of land
can be guarded at all times.
Tom: We always try to seek
other methods to improve
and refine the
areas of weakness.
Narrator: So today, they
are testing their most
deadly defense plan
to date, IED's.
Steve: This would
be a great place
to practice
IED placement.
Tom: Okay.
Steve: See how
effective these would
be under real life
circumstances?
Narrator: IED's
are homemade bombs
and they are the
most frequently
used terrorist
weapons.
Tom: The ball bearings
and all the nails
and stuff, we'll get
at least 30 yards.
Narrator: Tom and
Steve plan to hide
them every
30 yards.
This strategic placement
creates what is known
as a kill-zone: a
regularly used
ambush tactic
in the military.
The high concentration
of explosives,
combined with
coordinated gun fire,
ensures a target is
not just injured,
but destroyed.
Tom: You know
the rule.
Trespassers
will be shot,
survivors will
be shot again.
Narrator: Tom and Steve
will detonate an IED
from inside a hunting
blind, 20 feet high,
which eliminates
face-to-face threats and
provides a panoptic view
of the Alamo's land.
This allows them to detect
enemies from miles away
and direct their fire
towards the kill zone.
Steve: Sighted in.
Tom: 3, 2, 1.
Get back, Steve.
One thing I find
irritating about
Steven is safety.
Steven has not grown up
with weapons like I did.
Steve: I am a
big believer in
large capacity
magazines.
My attitude is, the
bigger the better.
Narrator: Steve's rifle
has a 100 round capacity
magazine, which is
recommended for ambush
situations because
it can sustain a
high volume of fire.
Because the firing
power is so great,
it is outfitted
with a muzzle brake,
to reduce recoil and
increase accuracy.
Steve: Target
acquired Tom.
Fire, in the hole.
Medic: No you're
not bleeding and
you don't have
any discharge.
Does it hurt
at all?
Tom: I can't
hear you.
God damn
it Steve.
Medic: Sit down,
come on.
Tom: I don't want to stand
things are spinning.
Medic: Do you
feel better now
that you're
laying down?
Tom: Things
are spinning.
Narrator: Muzzle
brakes reduce recoil,
but they can increase
sound volume to
more than 140 decibels
and cause serious injury.
When Steve fired his
shot from inside
the hunting blind.
The high volume noise
inside the confined
space might have caused
Tom to lose his hearing,
even with his ear
protection on.
Medic: Can you
hear me at all?
I need you to
answer my question.
We're going to get
your blood pressure,
let you lay
down, cool off,
calm down a
little bit.
Steve: I saw the
shell eject toward
the windows.
It wasn't near his
face or anything.
I'm not coming up
with excuses or
explanations or
anything.
I don't know
what happened.
Medic: Your blood
pressure's a
little bit high.
Producer: We have an
ambulance on the way.
Narrator: After four
years of planning for a
dirty bomb
attack together,
Steve's mistake
might be the end
of their prepping
partnership.
Tom: Man, you
(bleep) up man.
I can't hear.
This is (bleep).
Narrator: Tom Perez
and Steve Vanasse are
prepping to protect
their families from a
dirty bomb attack in
Houston and assemble
at Tom's ranch
300 miles away.
They have combined
their families,
Steve's radiation
knowledge,
and Tom's weapons
experience,
to create a prepping
partnership that they
believe will increase
their chances of
protecting the
ranch's 700 acres.
But after testing their
most deadly security
weapon to date, Tom
may have sustained a
serious injury and
severed his ties
with Steve.
Medic: We checked him out,
his vitals were a little
bit elevated just
from the adrenaline,
the shock, the fear,
but, he was fine.
Tom: Man, you
(bleep) up man.
You fired inside the
freaking blind dude.
I have to let
you go, dude.
I'm serious.
I'm sorry, I'm gonna
have to let you go.
I'm sorry;
I just don't know what
else to tell you.
Steve: No matter
what happens, man,
I'm still
here for you.
I am.
I'm heartbroken.
He's in pain.
Narrator: But
after realizing he
did not suffer any
permanent damage,
Tom reassessed
whether or not,
to end his four-year
partnership with Steve.
Tom: We're gonna have to
work on a lot of rules.
Safety needs to
be put first.
I mean, I'm just
worried that's all man.
Ya know?
It's cool, I
trust you man.
But, we're just
gonna have
to work on
safety man.
Okay?
Steve: Your
ranch, your rules.
I respect that.
Tom: Alright,
right, ok man;
we can eat and
just move on.
Now notice the
legs are much
more well done
than the ribs?
Steve: Being prepared
is not a straight line.
Tom: This is
in my opinion,
the best survival team
that could come together.
Steve: I certainly have
room for improvement.
Alright, let's
eat, feast!
And I recognize
that.
Katarina: Just swallow
it, just swallow it.
Narrator: Tom and
Steve, the experts,
Practical Preppers
have reviewed and
assessed your plan
to survive a
dirty bomb attack.
Steve, your chance at
surviving a major disaster
depends on your
successful ability to
bug out to
Tom's ranch.
Steve: Yes.
Narrator: Tom, your
water preps are highly
impressive because you own
the water rights beneath
your property, and your
food re-supply plan is
enough to sustain
both families.
However, the 300-mile
trip to your compound
could be difficult
if a flood of
people is also
leaving Houston.
You may have to
travel by foot.
The experts recommend you
store hidden caches of
supplies along
your bug out route.
Tom: I haven't gone
all in just yet,
so I'm holding back
on a few cards.
Narrator: To determine how
long you could initially
survive a catastrophe,
Practical Preppers has
scored your preps in five
categories of 20 points
each, for a total
possible score of 100.
Water: 20 out
of 20 points.
Food: because
Steve isn't
bringing his
own supplies,
there will be
fewer resources.
10 out of
20 points.
Shelter: you should
build a bunker under
the Alamo, in case you
come under attack.
16 out of 20 points.
Security: take a
combat related class
to improve your
existing strategies.
15 out of 20 points.
Joining forces
helps give you
16 out of 20
x-factor points.
Your total survival
score is 77;
this gives you 15
months initial
survival time
together.
Tom: I agree with
a majority of the
assessments, however
as a prepper,
I don't disclose
all my resources.
I hope others
will learn and
I am learning from others
that are preppers.
Steve: Prepper brother
and sisters and
welcome back
National Geographic.
National Geographic's
experts brutally
nailed me on
their assessment.
Victoria's been training
in high caliber weapons,
archery, and she's
deadly accurate.
And she's also trained
in defensive driving
maneuvers and she loves to
drive and does it well.
Gobriela and I took
fencing classes and
we're also studying for
our HAM radio license.
Tom: Hello, this is
Tom uh reporting
back on a
follow-up.
Just thought I'd
let you all know,
we've decided to home
school our kids.
If something
were to happen,
we continue to
educate our child.
We have a well-written
curriculum here at
"Doomsday Academy,"
something handy just
for a little
fire drill.
And I'm also trying to
procure a uh armor car
vehicle used, and
uh that will be our
new bug-out vehicle.
And also we're working
on our bunker now,
uh on undisclosed
areas.
Here at Doomsday
Academy, signing off.
God bless our troops,
God bless America.
Narrator: Since 9/11,
anti-terror governmental
agencies have been on
the look out for
potential dirty
bomb attacks.
However, dirty bombs are
not considered weapons of
mass destruction and
both the explosion and
radiation dispersion
would be limited.
To date, no
dirty bomb has
successfully
been detonated.