ANOTHER RECESSION. >> >>PEGGY: AND A SAN DIEGO
STATE PROFESSOR EXPLAINS HOW HIS NEW COMPUTER
SOFTWARE PROGRAM HELPS KEEP HIGH RISK KIDS
FROM DROPPING OUT OF SCHOOL. PLUS A FORMER
EMPLOYEE AT THE SAN ONOFRE POWER GENERATING
STATION TALKS ABOUT THE REASONS BEHIND THE
LOOMING LAYOFFS OF MORE THAN 700 WORKERS AT
THE NUCLEAR PLANT. >> >>DWANE: BALBOA PARK
LILY POND IS LOOKING A LITTLE MORE LIKE ITS
OLD SELF AGAIN TONIGHT. AND HUNDREDS OF LOCAL
MARINES ARE BACK FROM AFGHANISTAN, BUT ARE
CIVILIANS NOTICING THE ONE WHOSE DON'T MAKE
IT BACK SAFELY? EBBING >> >>: KPBS EVENING
EDITION IS MADE POSSIBLE BY JOAN AND IRWIN
JACOBS AND BY: >> >>DWANE: A DRAMATIC TURN
TODAY AT THE ARRAIGNMENT OF A MAN ACCUSED
OF MURDERING HIS ESTRANGED WIFE. KATIE ORR
WAS AT THE COURT HOUSE AND JOINS US WITH THIS
UPDATE. KATIE, WHAT HAPPENED DURING THE ARRAIGNMENT?
>> >>KATIE: DWANE, ARMANDO PEREZ WAS BEING
ARRAIGNED ON CHARGES HE MURDERED HIS ESTRANGED
WIFE DIANA GONZALEZ IN 2010. UNDER STATE LAW,
ANYONE FACING A FELONY CHARGE CANNOT PLEAD
GUILTY AT AN ARRAIGNMENT. HE ENTER AD PLEA
OF NOT GUILTY WHICH PEREZ WAS NOT HAPPY WITH.
>> >>: I'M GUILTY. >> >>DWANE: NOW, KATIE,
IS PEREZ ACTUALLY FACING THE DEATH PENALTY
IN THIS CASE? >> >>KATIE: NO, HE'S NOT. AFTER
GONZALEZ'S MURDER, PEREZ IMMEDIATELY FLED
TO MEXICO. HE WAS TRACKED DOWN EARLIER THIS
YEAR, BUT MEXICO WOULD NOT ALLOW HIM TO THE
TO THE PEREZ IS INSTEAD FACING LIFE WITHOUT
THE POSSIBILITY OF PAROLE. DIANA GONZALEZ'S
HUSBAND HOPES PEREZ NEVER SEES THE LIGHT OF
DAY AGAIN. >> >>: WE WOULD NEVER WISH DEATH
TO ANYONE, SO WHAT DOES THE PERSON WHO LEAVES
A TEN MONTH OLD BABY WITHOUT HER MOTHER DESERVE?
WHAT DOES THE PURSE WHOON SNATCHES A DAUGHTER
FROM HER PARENTS DESERVE? >> >>DWANE: KATIE,
DIDN'T THE DISTRICT ATTORNEY KNOW ABOUT PEREZ
BEFORE THE MURDER? >> >>KATIE: DIANA GONZALEZ
HAD FILE AD POLICE REPORT ABOUT TWO WEEKS
BEFORE HER DEATH ACCUSING PEREZ OF KIDNAPPING,
RAPING AND CHOKING HER. THE D. A.'S OFFICE
DECLINED TO PRESS CHARGES THAT CASE. TODAY
BONNIE DUMANIS DEFENDED THAT CASE. >> >>: I
AM VERY, VERY DEEPLY SORRY FOR THIS LOSS,
AND I THINK THE COMMUNITY IS SORRY FOR THIS
LOSS. WE DID WHAT WE ARE LEGALLY REQUIRED
TO DO. THE ONE THAT'S RESPONSIBLE FOR THIS
IS ARMANDO PEREZ. >> >>KATIE: SINCE GONZALEZ'S
DEATH THE D. A. HAS SET UP A TASK FORCE TO
BETTER IDENTIFY AND PREVENT OTHER CASES LIKE
HER. DOMES SAYS SHE DOESN'T KNOW IF SUCH A
TASK FORCE WOULD HAVE PREVENTED THE MURDER
OF DIANA GONZALEZ. >> >>DWANE: A NEW REPORT
SAYS THE FEDERAL STALEMATE OVER TAXES AND
SPENDING CUTS COULD LEAVE SAN DIEGO AND THE
NATION INTO ANOTHER RECESSION. DEMOCRATS AND
REPUBLICANS DISAGREE ON HOW TO EXTEND BUSH
ERA TAX CUTS AND HOW TO REDUCE FEDERAL SPENDING.
THE CUTS ARE EXPECTED TO EXPIRE IN JANUARY
AND SPENDING WILL BE SLASHED ACROSS THE BOARD
AT THE SAME TIME F.THAT 457 NS, RESEARCHERS
AT NATIONAL UNIVERSITY SAY THE IMPACT TO SAN
DIEGO COULD BE CLOSE TO SIX BILLION DOLLARS.
LAST YEAR, THE REGION'S ECONOMY GREW BY NEARLY
SEVEN BILLION. THE CONGRESSIONAL BUDGET OFFICE
HAS ISSUE AD SIMILAR BARNING TODAY. THERE
WILL BE MORE ON THIS STORY IN THE PBS NEWS
HOUR AT 7 PM. SAN DIEGO CONGRESSMAN DARRELL
ISSA HAS JOINED REPUBLICAN LEADERS TELLING
MISSOURI CONGRESSMAN TO TODD AKIN TO DROP
HIS CAMPAIGN. HE IS ON FIRE FOR SAYING VICTIMS
OF LEGITIMATE RAPE CAN'T GET PREGNANT. ISSA
SAYS AKIN'S STATEMENT WAS TOTALLY INAPPROPRIATE
AND HE CONTINUES TO MAKE ATTEMPTS TO DEFEND
ISSA SAYS TOM AKIN'S COMMENTS DON'T REPRESENT
THE VIEWS OF ANY OTHER REPUBLICAN HE KNOWS
AND AKIN SHOULD RESIGN THE CAMPAIGN. AKIN
SAYS HE'S STAYING IN THE RACE. HUNDREDS OF
MARINES ARE BACK AT LOCAL BASES TONIGHT. 300
MEMBERS OF THE THIRD MARINE AIR CRAFT WING
RETURN TO MCAS MIRAMAR TODAY. THEY HAD BEEN
DEPLOYED TO AFGHANISTAN. ALSO RETURNING HOME
130 MEMBER OF CAMP PENDLETON'S FIRST MARINE
DIVISION. PRESIDENT OBAMA PLANS TO PULL 23,000
TROOPS OUT OF AFGHANISTAN BY THE END OF THE
SUMMER. KPBS HOME POST BLOGGER BETH FORD ROTH
HAS THE STORY. >> >>: TODAY MARKED THE 2,000TH
AMERICAN DEATH. CNN REPORTED THE DEATH TOLL
AT 2000 BACK IN JUNE, WITH THE 2,000TH DEATH
A TWENTY NINE PALMS MARINE KILLED ON JUNE
THE NUMBER OF U.S. TROOPS DEAD AT 1, 972,
THE POINT IS ARE CIVILIANS EVEN NOTICING?
AND MOST POLLS SAY NO. THE ASSOCIATED PRESS
TOOK A POLL THAT SHOWED 66% OF AMERICANS WEREN'T
IN FAVOR OF THE YEUN BEING IN AFGHANISTAN,
WITH 27% IN FAVOR. ANOTHER POLL DONE 67% OF
REGISTERED VOTERS IN THE UNITED STATES SAY
WE SHOULD NOT BE FIGHTING THE WAR IN AFGHANISTAN,
WITH 31% SUPPORTING U.S. INVOLVEMENT. >> >>DWANE:
BETH FORD ROTH REPORTING. YOU CAN FIND MORE
ON HER BLOG, HOME POST.KPBS.ORG. A SAN DIEGO
NAVY SHIP IS BACK HOME TONIGHT FROM AROUND
THE TRIP. THE U.S. KATE ST. GEORGE HAS BEEN
AWAY SINCE DECEMBER. INCLUDED A TRIP DURING
THE STRAIT OF HORMUZ DURING TENSIONS WITH
IRAN. WE ARE LEARNING MORE ABOUT A FRESNO
SLAUGHTER HOUSE, UNDER INVESTIGATION. IT SOLD
21 MILLION POUNDS OF BEEF TO THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT
LAST YEAR TO SCHOOLS AND OTHER NUTRITIONAL
PROGRAMS. THIS VIDEO CONTAINS SOME GRAPHIC
IMAGES. IT COMES FROM THE ANIMAL RIGHTS GROUP
COMPASSION OVER KILLING, SHOWING COWS AT THE
CENTRAL VALLEY MEAT COMPANY BEING DRAGGED
ON THEIR WAY TO BE SLAUGHTERED AS WELL AS
BEING PRODDED AND ELECTRICALLY SHOT IN THE
HEAD. SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA EDISON PLANS TO
LAY OFF MORE THAN 700 EMPLOYEES AT ITS SAN
ONOFRE POWER PLANT IN OCTOBER. PEGGY PICO
SHOWS HOW THE DOWN SIZING IS LINKED TO THE
DAMAGED REACTORS. >> >>PEGGY: DAMAGED TUBES
THAT CARRY RADIOACTIVE WATER THROUGH THE STEAM
GENERATORS AT THE SAN ONOFRE NUCLEAR POWER
PLANT, SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA EDISON SAYS LAYOFFS
ARE COMING BECAUSE THE REDUCTION OF EMPLOYEES
TO 1500 WILL REDUCE OPERATING COSTS WHILE
REGULATORS CONSIDER THE VIABILITY OF THE PLANT.
HERE TO TALK ABOUT STAFFING AT NUCLEAR FACILITYSIS
NUCLEAR CONTAINMENT EXPERT AND SDSU PROFESSOR
MURRAY JENNEX. YOU WORKED AT THE SAN ONOFRE
GENERATING STATION FOR 20 YEARS, YOU ALSO
WROTE A PAPER ON WHO TO HIRE AND WHO TO LAYOFF
AT NUCLEAR FACILITIES. SHOULD WE ALL BE SURPRISED
BY THESE LAYOFFS? >> >>MURRAY JENNEX: NOT
AT ALL. REMEMBER THEY JUST GOT DONE ADDING
THE GENERATORS A COUPLE OF YEARS AGO. THEY
KEPT THAT STAFFED BECAUSE OF THE PROBLEM OF
THIS OUTAGE. THEY PROBABLY WOULD HAVE BEEN
GONE HAD THIS ISSUE NOT COME UP. >> >>PEGGY:
SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA EDISON TOLD US THEY WERE
NOT DOING ON AIR INTERVIEWS AT THIS TIME,
BUT THEY HAVE AN UPDATE ON THE PROGRESS SAYING
THEY ARE DEFUELING UNIT THREE AND DO NOT EXPECT
TO SUBMIT AN ACTION LETTER ON THOSE REPAIRS
BEFORE THE END OF THE YEAR. MURRAY, DOES DEFUELING
UNIT THREE MEAN THEY HAVEN'T FIGURED OUT WHAT
TO DO TWHIS REACTOR OR SOMETHING ELSE? >> >>MURRAY
JENNEX: ACTUALLY T MEANS THAT THEY'RE PUT
TG INTO A LOW COST MAINTENANCE SITUATION.
THE DEFUELING REDUCES THE STAFFING REQUIREMENT
TO OPERATE OR MAINTAIN THE PLANT. THIS IS
A VERY NORMAL ACTIVITY THAT THEY DO EVERY
REFUELING ANYWAY. >> >>PEGGY: AND THEY NEED
TO DEFUEL IN ORDER TO MAKE THE REPAIRS AS
WELL. >> >>MURRAY JENNEX: THEY WOULDN'T NECESSARILY
HAVE TO, BUT BY DEFUELING, IT MAKES IT A LOT
EASIER TO DO THE MAINTENANCE. >> >>PEGGY:
THERE'S RADIOACTIVE WASTE, OR FUEL AS IT'S
CALLED, AT THE PLANT. WHERE WILL THAT BE STORED
DURING THIS DEFUELING OR WHERE WILL IT BE
KEPT? >> >>MURRAY JENNEX: THEY HAVE A FUEL
BUILDING THAT'S DESIGNED TO HOLD THE FUEL
WHEN THEY TAKE IT OUT, AND IT ALSO HOLDS THE
HOTTEST WASTE. >> >>PEGGY: IS THERE ENOUGH
ROOM THERE TO STORE >> >>MURRAY JENNEX: ABSOLUTELY,
FOR NOW THERE IS. >> >>PEGGY: OKAY, SO SOUTHERN
CALIFORNIA EDISON SAYS THEY HAVEN'T DETERMINED
WHICH DEPARTMENTS WILL BE AFFECTED BY THE
LAYOFFS. IN CASES LIKE THIS, WHAT DO YOU SUSPECT?
ARE THERE CERTAIN PEOPLE WHO TYPICALLY GET
LAID OFF FROM NUCLEAR POWER PLANTS? >> >>MURRAY
JENNEX: THERE ARE PEOPLE WHO ARE BROUGHT IN
FOR OUTAGES OR SPECIAL PROJECTS. IF THEY'RE
GOING TO CUT INTO PERMANENT STAFF, THEY WU
WOULD LOOK AT WHAT THE KNOWLEDGE NEEDS CAPABILITIES
ARE TO OPERATE THE PLANT AS THEY EXPECT TO
SEE IT. THEY WILL DO AN ANALYSIS TO SEE WHICH
EXPERTISE THEY CAN USE. >> >>PEGGY: SOUTHERN
CALIFORNIA EDISON SAYS THE DOWN SIZING EFFORT
STARTED ABOUT TWO YEARS AGO BECAUSE THEIR
STAFFING COSTS WERE HIGHER THAN SIMILAR PLANTS.
IS THAT SOMETHING THEY DO ROUTINELY, A FINANCIAL
EVALUATIONS FOR THE SHAREHOLDERS OR FOR WHOMEVER?
>> >>MURRAY JENNEX: ACTUALLY, IT IS. THEY
STARTED DOING A BENCH MARKING EXERCISE IN
ABOUT THE YEAR 2000. SINCE THEN THEY'VE BEEN
ON GOING. ALL THE PLANTS COMPARE THEMSELVES.
NUCLEAR INDUSTRY LOOKS AT THEMSELVES AS COMPETITORS
WITH OTHER POWER PRODUCING INDUSTRIES. >> >>PEGGY:
TYPICALLY YOU SAID A PLANT THIS SIZE WOULD
HAVE ABOUT 1300 EMPLOYES AND WE HAVE 1500.
>> >>MURRAY JENNEX: THEY COULD PROBABLY GO
WITH 1300. WHAT I EXPECT THEY'RE DOING IS
ALLOWING NATURAL ATTRITION TO LOWER IT MORE.
>> >>PEGGY: DO YOU THINK THE LAYOFFS COMBINED
WITH THE TUBE ISSUES IS POINTING TO A PERMANENT
SHUT DOWN OF THE PLANT? >> >>MURRAY JENNEX:
I DON'T THINK YOU CAN READ THAT AT ALL. I
THEY DON'T THINK THEY'RE LOWERING THE COSTS
TO BE PRUDENT, WHICH IS WHAT THE RATE PAYERS
WOULD EXPECT. I THINK THEY UNDERSTAND POLITICALLY
THEY'RE NOT GOING TO GET UNITED THREE RUNNING
RIGHT AWAY, AND I THINK THEY'RE GOING TO BE
DOING AN ON GOING ECONOMIC ANALYSIS TO SEE
WHAT IS THE MOST PRUDENT ACTIVITY TO DO WITH
THE UNIT. >> >>PEGGY: WE'RE OFTEN TOLD THERE'S
A STRAIN ON OUR POWER GRID, NO ROLLING BLACKOUTS,
BROWN OUTS, WE HAVE THE SUN RISE POUR LINK,
THE TURBINES IN MEXICO. DO WE NEED SAN ONOFRE
ANYMORE? >> >>MURRAY JENNEX: WELL, THE NEED
IS MORE ECONOMIC THAN IT IS, I GUESS, FROM
A PURE POWER REQUIREMENT. THE POWER LINK HAS
DEFINITELY IMPROVED POWER RELIABILITY IN SAN
DIEGO. BUT SAN ONOFRE HAS BEEN A LOW COST
PROVIDER FOR MANY YEARS. PLUS THE CONCERN
I STILL HAVE IS I DON'T THINK YOU CAN HAVE
A LARGE AREA WITH A LARGE POPULATION AND NOT
HAVE SOME POWER PRODUCTION LOCAL. RIGHT NOW,
WE'RE RELYING ON EXTERNAL SOURCES. THAT WON'T
ALWAYS BE AVAILABLE. >> >>PEGGY: ALL RIGHT.
WELL, WE'VE RUN OUT OF TIME. THERE'S MORE
INFORMATION ABOUT THIS AND WHAT IT COULD MEAN
AS FAR AS FOR TAX PAYERS AND RATE PAYERS ON
OUR WEBSITE. MURRAY JENNEX, THANKS SO MUCH
FOR BEING HERE. >> >>DWANE: IT WAS INSPECTION
DAY FOR DIESEL TRUCKS HEADED SOUTH OF THE
BORDER, HIGHWAY PATROL WORKED WITH AGENTS
FROM THE STATE AIR RESOURCES BOARD TESTING
TRUCKS FOR FUEL EFFICIENCY AND AIR POLLUTION.
MOST TRUCKS WERE IN COMPLIANCE. CITY WORKERS
HAVE FINISHED TEMPORARY REPAIRS TO THE LILY
POND AT BAL BOY A PARK, THEY PATCHED UP SOME
OF THE PLUMBING AND PLANTED NEW FLOWER. THE
POND WAS DAMAGED TWO WEEKS AGO WHEN HUNDREDS
OF FOLKS STAGE AD LATE NIGHT WATER GUN FIGHT.
REPAIRS ARE SCHEDULED AT A COST OF ABOUT 19,000
DOLLARS. >> >>DWANE: THE PASS RATE FOR CALIFORNIA'S
HIGH SCHOOL EXIT EXAM INCREASED SLIGHTLY FOR
SAN DIEGO TENTH GRADERS THIS YEAR. THE SCORES
FOR SAN DIEGO UNIFIED WERE AN IMPROVEMENT
OVER THE PREVIOUS YEAR'S CLASS. EIGHTY SIX%
OF STUDENTS PASSED THE MATH PORTION WHILE
83% PASSED THE ENGLISH SECTION OF THE TEST.
THE STATE WIDE AVERAGE WAS SLIGHTLY LOWER
FOR MATH AND ENGLISH, 84 AND 83% RESPECTIVELY.
THE SCORES WERE SLOIT SLIGHTLY HIGHER AT OTHER
SCHOOL UZ CROSS SAN DIEGO COUNTY. CALIFORNIA'S
DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION SAYS 95% OF THE CLASS
OF 2012 STATE WIDE HAVE PASSED THE EXIT EXAM.
KEEPING KIDS FROM DROPPING OUT OF SCHOOL HAS
GONE HIGH TECH THANKS TO A NEW SOFTWARE PROGRAM
DEVELOPED BY A PROFESSOR AT SAN DIEGO STATE.
PEGGY PICO HAS MORE. >> >>PEGGY: THE NEW SCHOOL
YEAR IS NEARLY UPON US, AND THAT'S A PROBLEM
FOR MANY HIGH RISK LEARNERS IN SAN DIEGO COUNTY
ABOUT 10% OF STUDENTS DROP OUT OF SCHOOL EACH
YEAR. BUT THAT MAY CHANGE FOR THE BETTER THANKS
TO A NEW COMPUTER PROGRAM CREATED BY MY GUEST,
DR. ROBERT BRIGGS, A PROFESSOR AT SDSU'S COLLEGE
OF BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION. DR. BRIGGS, HOW
DO YOU GET A STUDENT TO BE ENGAGED IN AND
STAY IN SCHOOL? >> >>ROBERT BRIGGS: BOTTOM
LINE IS YOU HAVE TO FIND SOMETHING THEY CARE
ABOUT AND USE THAT AGAINST THEM. >> >>PEGGY:
SOMETHING LIKE THAT IS RELEVANT TO THEM. >> >>ROBERT
BRIGGS: INDEED. >> >>PEGGY: HOW DO YOU DISCOVER
WHAT IS IMPORTANT TO THEM AND WHAT'S RELEVANT?
>> >>ROBERT BRIGGS: YOU HAVE TO ASK THEM.
WHEN WE STARTED THE PROJECT IN THE D. C. PUBLIC
SCHOOLS WE WERE ASKING THE STUDENTS WHY THEY
WERE DROPPING OUT. ONE CHILD SAID I GOT ON
THE WRONG SIDE OF A GANG, I MAY NOT GET HOME
TONIGHT IF. IF I DO GET HOME, I DON'T KNOW
IF MY MOM'S GOING TO BE STRUNG OUT ON HEROIN,
AND IF SHE IS STRUNG OUT, I DON'T KNOW IF
I'LL GET ANYTHING TO EAT UNTIL MONDAY. WHAT
DO I CARE WHAT 7 TIMES 5 IS. >> >>PEGGY: YOU
TOOK THAT INFORMATION AND WHAT'D YOU DO WITH
THAT? >> >>ROBERT BRIGGS: WE DECIDED INSTEAD
OF PRI PREPARING STUDENTS FOR A FUTURE THEY
DIDN'T BELIEVE IN, WE SHOULD PUT THEM TO WORK
ON PROBLEMS THEY HAVE A STAKE IN RIGHT NOW.
WE REASONED THAT IF WE DID THAT THAT WOULD
MOTIVATE TO LEARN, WE WOULD HAVE TO CHOOSE
THOSE PROBLEMS SO THAT THEY WOULD HAVE TO
LEARN WHAT WE WANTED THEM TO KNOW TO GET WHAT
THEY WANT. >> >>PEGGY: A STUDENT SITS DOWN,
AND WHAT DOES THIS PROGRAM OFFER THEM? >> >>ROBERT
BRIGGS: IT WAS ORIGINALLY DESIGNED TO BE USED
IN BUSINESS AND IT WAS VERY EFFECTIVE THERE.
AND WE USED IT TO MAKE PROBLEM SOLVING TIME
MUCH SORT SHORTER. >> >>PEGGY: WALK US THROUGH
IT. >> >>ROBERT BRIGGS: AN EXAMPLE, THE CHILDREN
DIDN'T WANT TO STUDY HISTORY, SO I SUGGESTED
TO THEM HISTORY MIGHT BE A SHORT CUT FOR ACHIEVING
GREATNESS. WE PUT THEM INTO A BRAIN STORMING
SESSION, WHO ARE YOUR FAVORITE HEROS FROM
HISTORY, THEY GENERATE AD LIST, WE SAID VOTE
ON IT, WHO DO YOU WANT TO LOOK AT RIGHT NOW,
THEY CHOSE MARTIN LUTHER KING, I SAID GREAT,
LET'S BRAIN STORM, WHAT MAKES HIM GREAT, THEY
GENERATED A LIST OF 13 ATTRIBUTES OF GREATNESS,
THEN WE'RE GOING TO WRITE A POEM PO EM, SPEED
POETRY, WE MADE A RACE,. >> >>PEGGY: SO THEY
FOUND THIS TO BE RELEVANT, THE SUCCESS RATE
>> >>ROBERT BRIGGS: IT WAS THEIR HERO AND
THEIR INCITES AND THEIR WORK, WHICH THEN,
YOU KNOW, THERE WAS A POEM THAT DIDN'T EXIST
WHEN THEY CAME IN THAT MORNING. SO THAT WORKED.
WE RAN PROJECTS LIKE THAT OVER A COURSE OF
TWO YEARS AND AT THE END OF TWO YEARS, THEY
WERE TWO YEARS AHEAD OF THEIR PEER ON READING
AND WRITING SCORES AND THEY WERE OFF THE CHARTS
ON CREATIVE PROBLEM SOLVING SCORES. >> >>PEGGY:
HOW IS THE CLASSROOM TEACHER IN THIS? >> >>ROBERT
BRIGGS: THE CLASSROOM TEACHER CAN LEAD THE
EXERCISES, AND THE CLASSROOM TEACHER HAS TO
GET TO KNOW WHAT THEY CARE ABOUT SO SHE CAN
PICK THE PROBLEMS U.YOU ACTUALLY HAD TO DO
SOME TRAINING FOR TEACHERS? >> >>ROBERT BRIGGS:
WE DID, WE HAD A SUCCESS ACADEMICALLY AND
A FAILURE TRANSFERRING TO THE TEACHERS. >> >>PEGGY:
HOW COME? >> >>ROBERT BRIGGS: IT TOOK US 20
YEARS OF RESEARCH LEADING UP UNTIL JUST ABOUT
A MONTH AGO BEFORE WE FELT WE WERE READY TO
GO BACK INTO THE CLASSROOMS. >> >>PEGGY: DOES
THE SOFTWARE COME WITH A TEACHER COMPONENT,
SO A TRAINING COMPONENT? >> >>ROBERT BRIGGS:
THE GOAL WAS TO DESIGN THE SOFTWARE SO IT
COULD BE RUN BY PEOPLE WITH NO TRAINING. >> >>PEGGY:
DO YOU INCORPORATE STANDARD CURRICULUM? >> >>ROBERT
BRIGGS: WE DON'T INCORPORATE A CURRICULUM,
BUT WE COVER THE SAME MATERIAL WITH A VERY
DIFFERENT KIND OF TEACHING APPROACH. >> >>PEGGY:
HOW CAN A SCHOOL DISTRICT IF THEY WANT IT,
GET THE PROGRAM, AND HOW MUCH DOES IT COST?
>> >>ROBERT BRIGGS: RIGHT NOW, THE SOFTWARE
IS FREE, BUT IT'S NOT SO MUCH THE SOFTWARE,
IT'S WHAT WE'RE DOING WITH IT. WE'RE RUNNING
A PILOTED PROGRAM IN CHICAGO, WE'RE GOING
TO START THAT UP THIS COMING YEAR. IF THAT
PILOT PROKING PROGRAM IS SUCCESSFUL Y HAVE
A TEACHER IN SAN DIEGO AND ONE IN TUCSON,
TO TEST IT. IF THAT GOES WELL, WE DO SOME
PROOF OF VALUE RESEARCH IN A NUMBER OF CLASSROOMS
IN A NUMBER OF CITIES. >> >>PEGGY: HOW DOES
IT FEEL TO BE SOMEBODY WHO DEVELOPED SOMETHING
THAT CAN ACTUALLY CHANGE SO MANY STUDENTS
LIVES? >> >>ROBERT BRIGGS: IT'S SO EXCITING,
FEELING WE'RE RIGHT ON THE BRING TO MAKE THIS
HAPPEN. WE FIEMY HAVE A WAY TO MAKE IF ACCESSIBLE
TO TEACHER WHICH MAKES IT ACCESSIBLE TO STUDENTS
SO VERY EXCITING. >> >>PEGGY: THANK YOU DR.
BRIGS. >> >>DWANE: NOW STANDARDIZED TESTING
HAS ITS CRITICS. THEY SAY ITS FOCUS ON BASIC
READING AND MATH SKILLS HAS CROWDED SUBJECTS
LIKE ART AND SCIENCE OUT OF MANY SCHOOLS.
KYLA CALVERT TELLS US CALIFORNIA'S STARTING
TO ROLL OUT NEW CURRICULUM STANDARDS THIS
YEAR, AND SOME FOLKS HOPE IT WILL BRING ART
BACK TO THE CLASSROOM. >> >>: THERE ARE ABOUT
20 TEACHERS AT THIS REHEARSAL STUDENT. THE
HALF FACING THE BACK OF THE ROOM ARE DRAWING
AND THE REST CAN SEE A PICTURE PROJECTED ON
TO A SCREEN. TERRY MILLER IS DOING HER BEST
TO DESCRIBE WHAT SHE SEES SO HER PARTNER CAN
SKETCH A REPLICA OF WHAT LOOKS LIKE THE REMNANTS
OF A MINING OPERATION. AFTER A FEW MINUTES
OF DRAWING, MARVA CAPPELLO A SAN DIEGO STATE
PROFESSOR LEADING THE CLASS TELLS THOSE DRAWING
TO TURN AROUND AND SEE THE IMAGE THEY'VE BEEN
TRYING TO O REPRODUCE. VOLUNTARY NATIONAL
STANDARDS FOR PUBLIC SCHOOLS. CALIFORNIA IS
JOINING 44 OF THEM IN WASHINGTON D.C. AND
ADOPTING THE MATH ASK LANG LANGUAGE ARTS STANDARD.
THE SKILLS INCLUDE HIGHER ORDER SKILLS TOO.
>> >>: THESE ARE DIFFERENT IN THAT THERE'S
A FOCUS ON CRITICAL THINKING AND PROBLEM SOLVING,
THAT REALLY WASN'T IN THE CONTENT STANDARD
BEFORE. THERE ARE A FEW INSTRUCTIONAL SHIFTS
WE HELP TEACHERS COME TO TERMS WITH. >> >>: BEFORE
IT'S TIME TO GO BACK TO CLASS, EDUCATORS FROM
ACROSS SAN DIEGO COUNTY SPEND A WEEK AT LOCAL
CULTURAL INSTITUTIONS LIKE THE LA JOLLA PLAY
HOUSE LEARNING HOW THEY CAN INCORPORATE THE
ARTS INTO THEIR NORMAL CURRICULUM. THIS DRAWING
EXERCISE IS ONE PART OF THE EXERCISE. THE
TEACHERS VISITED THE TIMKEN, MINGEI, AND PHOTOGRAPHIC
ARTS MUSEUMS IN BALBOA PARK. IN ANOTHER WORK
SHOP, THE TEACHERS ARE ROLE PLAYING WHERE
THEY DI D SCRIBE DIFFERENT ARTIFACTS. LAURA
SLOAN IS TRYING TO USE MESSAGES LIKE THIS
TO GET KIDS TO THINK ABOUT WHAT KIND OF LANGUAGE
TO USE WITH DIFFERENT PEOPLE AND IN DIFFERENT
SITUATIONS. >> >>: IT HAS BEEN A WONDERFUL
EXPERIENCE. FROM THE STANDPOINT OF ALL MY
KIDS CAN BE SUCCESSFUL USING THE STRATEGIES,
EVERY LAST ONE OF THEM REGARDLESS OF THEIR
LABELS, REGARDLESS OF THEIR READING LEVELS
OR THEIR ENGLISH LANGUAGE FOR PROFICIENCY.
>> >>: COLLEEN TEACHES FOURTH GRADE AT CRAVER.
>> >>: A LOT OF THINGS I THINK I CAN USE WITH
FOURTH GRADE HI OIR, IS THE CALIFORNIA HISTORY,
WITH OUR SCIENCE STANDARDS, THAT I THINK WE'LL
BE REALLY ENGAGING FOR THE KIDS AND ALSO TO
HELP THEM UNDERSTAND THE CONTENT. >> >>: CAPPELLO
SAYS THERE AREN'T THE SAME OPPORTUNITIES TO
BE WRONG WITH THE KIND OF ARTS FOK OWS LESSONS
SHE'S INTRODUCING TEACHERS TO. EACH STOONT
CAN PARTICIPATE IN SOME WAY. >> >>: I THINK
THEY'RE MUCH MORE ENGAGED, MUCH MORE ACCOUNTABLE,
BECAUSE EACH STUDENT IS BEING ASKED TO DO
SOMETHING THAT THEY'RE ABLE DO DO. WE HAVE
TAKEN SO MUCH ART OUT OF THE SCHOOL THAT AT
LEAST WE GET A LITTLE CHANCE TO DO SOMETHING
ARTISTIC AND HANDS ON AND I THINK EACH KID
IS ABLE TO DO UP TO THEIR LEVEL WHAT THEY
CAN DO. >> >>: CAPPELLO SAYS ITSELF JUST ABOUT
BUSY WORK OR HAVING FUN IN CLASSES. >> >>: HELPING
STUDENTS USE ORAL AND WRITTEN LANGUAGE ALONG
WITH PRINT
HELPS THEM GET TO A DEEPER LEVEL OF UNDERSTANDING.
IT REALLY ENHANCES COMPREHENSION. >> >>: GETTING
ARTS BACK INTO MORE SCHOOLS HAS ALWAYS BEEN
THE FOLK OS F CARE, WHICH IS A PARTNERSHIP
OF THE INSTITUTES HOSTING THIS SEMINAR. THEY
TRY ESPECIALLY TO REACH TEACHERS IN LOW INCOME
COMMUNITIES WHERE ARTS PROGRAMS ARE LEAST
LIKELY TO HAVE SURVIVED. >> >>: NOT ONLY IS
THERE A PROBLEM OF DECLINING RESOURCES IN
PUBLIC EDUCATION, WE UNDERSTAND THAT THERE
ARE SEVERAL OUTCOMES THAT HAPPEN AS A RESULT
OF HAVING EXPOSURE TO THE ARTS. MANY OF THOSE
ARE IMPORTANT TO A 20TH CENTURY WORK FORCE
N CLUING CRITICAL THINKING. >> >>: TERRY MILLER
IS AN ARTS TEACHER. SHE'S HOPING THE COMMON
CORE STANDARDS WILL OFFER A WAY TO PROTECT
PROGRAMS LIKE HERS. >> >>: I THINK I GAINED
AMMUNITION SO THAT WHEN THE BUDGET NEEDS TO
BE CUT, I CAN SAY HEY, MY STUDENTS ARE WRITING,
NIE STUDENTS ARE SPEAKING, MY STUDENTS ARE
LISTENING, MY STUDENTS ARE READING, MY STUDENTS
DEAL WITH SUBTEXT AND INFERENCE, AND SO IT
MAKES IT DIFFICULT TO CUT IT OUT. >> >>: THIS
FALL CAPPELLO WILL TAKE TIME AWAY FROM TEACHING
TO DISCOVER HOW VISUALIZING THINGS IN THE
CLASSROOM HELPS STUDENTS WITH LITERACY SKILLS.
>> >>PEGGY: IN TONIGHT'S PUBLIC SQUARE FUNDING
CUTS WILL FORCE THE CLOSURE OF THREE CAMP
PENDLETON COMMUNITY CENTERS. THE CENTERS PROVIDE
FOOD, CLASSES AND SUPPORT TO MILITARY FAMILIES.
MARINE OFFICIALS SAY ONE CENTER WILL CLOSE
ON SEPTEMBER 7, THE OTHER TWO ON SEPTEMBER
>> >>PEGGY: ANOTHER MILITARY NEWS, NEARLY
68 YEARS AFTER HE WENT MISSING OVER THE SKIES
OF GERMANY, THE REMAINS OF ARMY AIR FORCE
STAFF SERGEANT JOHN E.H OGAN HAVE BEEN IDENTIFIED
AND RETURNED TO HIS FAMILY. THE DEPARTMENT
OF DEFENSE SAYS HE WAS PART OF A 19 MAN CREW
WHEN HE WAS SHOT DOWN. HOGAN'S METAL DOG TAGS
WERE FOUND IN A GERMAN CEMETERY. HOGAN WILL
BE BURIED AT THE ARLINGTON NATIONAL CEMETERY,
WITH FULL MILITARY HOPPERS ON FRIDAY. YOU
CAN FIND OUT MORE ABOUT THESE STORIES ON OUR
KPBS MILITARY BLOG, OR YOU CAN FOLLOW US ON
TWITTER, LIKE US ON TWITTER, OR E MAIL US
AT PUBLIC SQUARE @ KPBS.ORG. >> >>DWANE: AND
YOU CAN FIND TONIGHT'S STORIES ON OUR WEBSITE,
KPBS.ORG/EVENINGEDITION. THANK YOU FOR JOINING
US. YOU HAVE A GREAT NIGHT. hV7E hV7E hV7E
hV7E hV7E hV7E [Content_Types].xml Iw}, $yi}
_rels/.rels theme/theme/themeManager.xml sQ}#
theme/theme/theme1.xml w toc'v )I`n 3Vq%'#q
:\TZaG L+M2 e\O* $*c? )6-r IqbJ#x ,AGm T[XF64
E)`# R>QD =(K& =al- 4vfa 0%M0 theme/theme/_rels/themeManager.xml.rels
6?$Q K(M&$R(.1 [Content_Types].xmlPK _rels/.relsPK
theme/theme/themeManager.xmlPK theme/theme/theme1.xmlPK
theme/theme/_rels/themeManager.xml.relsPK
<a:clrMap xmlns:a="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/drawingml/2006/main"
bg1="lt1" tx1="dk1" bg2="lt2" tx2="dk2" accent1="accent1"
accent2="accent2" accent3="accent3" accent4="accent4"
accent5="accent5" accent6="accent6" hlink="hlink"
folHlink="folHlink"/> marge Normal.dotm marge
Microsoft Office Word Title Microsoft Office
Word 97-2003 Document MSWordDoc Word.Document.8