so that's a real problem because the
regulators have done nothing
to go after the big banks
beshi question the regulators before
news is great moment we should ask them
he when's the last time you brought to
the top banking service to trial
we should all the regulators lined up
and not one of them could answer because
it was so far back know what we're
member of the last time they brought
and big bang executive to trial right so
this time around to pass them
but we've just
video
where you protected the bankers again
and but you know
all that what they were doing in for
closing outhouses was wrong
ish in a bid for closing on those houses
and your job is to protect consumers so
she's got a question amman that town and
it's going to be a loss
regarding the basic data and
processes of the independent foreclosure
review
we may fourteen specific request to you
in january
and despite multiple letters back and
forth and multiple meetings
you have provided only one full response
three partial or a minimal responses and
no response to nine of our requests
cashiers they haven't asked for
that you know you're supposed to be
accountable palace you're supposed to
call the government you're holding the
bank's account of what we're past the
are you doing your job we have nothing
from you as she cited daniels the
powerful loss of the control of the
currency in which a dash in or the
federal reserve board of governors and
these are supposed to be really good
banks now let's watch what happens
you know have evidence
in your files
all of the illegal activity i'd take it
for some of these banks
it's affair really wants to bring a
lawsuit
you're both lawyers would it be helpful
if you're going against one of these
people banks would it be helpful for
these families
to have the information about their case
that's in your finals
possession
it would uh...
you would be helpful obviously there
have been for mation related to be
entering that should work
so
do you plan to give the families
this information
i think that's a decision that we're
still considering we haven't made a
final decision yet
so you have made a decision to protect
the banks but not a decision to tell the
families who were illegally foreclosed
against
we have made a decision about when
information we will provide the
individuals
mistress to pune
receptionist
the embarrassment that he had in that
like split-second
at the end at the end yet latrines gonna
crimea like uh...
that was officer was under which
shane that's what was that's exactly
right
and he had the same insecure
you're right now we have protected the
banks
we have not given the information that
they needed to
to protect the consumers
who were the victims yes you're right
that's exactly what we've done
the exact opposite of what we were
trying to appeal it's great to see it
was before doing this you know we talked
about this uh... leaving before the show
because back in february she went out
the regulators as you
as you mentioned the plot all the court
that the other course grade
also is there was a e described as a top
executive atop for banking executive
emailed
to pull it off
uh... well and said well senator warner
never write cast pointed questions of
today's the senate banking committee
hearing
proclaim that nobody believes that bank
books
are honest is just plain wrong
perhaps someone on a reminder senator
that the campaign is over
and she should act accordingly
if she wants to be taken to
venue of civil right for bring that
quote back
right there and not shows the
expectation in washington
you run progressive during the campaign
ofcourse we understand your trick people
into getting their votes
almost elections over if you want to be
taken seriously
you come back into the fold and you do
with the corporations the banks wanted
yet because what is being taken
seriously
has to be taken seriously meanest
you want us to support
you are still close some of our money to
you you want us to you want to be in the
crowd that were or
and or worst or we have a target
natalie attorneys try to get you out
three days a civilization she definitely
being taken seriously by
that's right
yet that's that's why people lover right
and and what he's also saying
anticipating plus a part of washington
is
that you're in that committee
would you like to be the head of
activity
now understand that you go along being
unserious like this you have no chance
of being evacuated
now the house is it
the greatest example this was the house
ways and means committee at that
one point the democrat intro to the
steps down
uh... was charlie rangel exceed the
september's revelations an excellent
seniority was pete stark possibly the
most progressive member of the house
carefully right
and that was you know the couple years
ago
and i said others know where they're
going to make peace smart the head of
the most powerful committee in the house
be stars a relevent
he lasted
one day
literally one day
and he was made to step down
give uh... it's a i'm not right for this
role
and it'd this place was put someone
friendly the corporate interests so
that's what they mean by you want to be
taken seriously are you wanna be like he
starts on a serious very soon
but what is the level last even if it is
absolutely his job
under seniority rules under every rule
lonely less one day
and now for most senators on friday that
the committee on
cut back the powerful and by the way
also more donations cuz
well doesn't have a committee is more
donations
more likely to get reelected as a but
they don't know what it dealing with
here are the rules of the bargains that
damages ahead of activity
if she's got a sellout
to be the head of the committee what
obama was elected in the senate two
thousand four eight two thousand two
thousand lives are in
als with warren was
uh... was elections just elected board
so twenty two thousand four two thousand
eight obama rent two thousand eight moon
an experienced senator fourier sir and
point sixty
chiller for your sister
well i'll tell you what every progress
in the country would be
just beside themselves in in excitement
if that happens right
and hillary clinton wouldn't talk about
the liquid
made wing blurry gasoline clinton
happened five years ago six years ago
because she was to establish
so that when she got less establishment
since then
so well this is a possibility that we
were wrong
no no no no we don't act look i think
him we were never on retroactive
resentful about about that offers a
resume or or the other although it won't
be there but we will win by the wrong
about who was more staff yeah jack
genessee last right
but that's it while lighthouses damning
with faint
free praised what one more from was with
one of your christian identity massive
has restricted the street freely skit
pennies on the dollar
in the settlement
for having been the victims illegal
activities or mistakes in the banks
activities
do you like the banks and inhuman el
nino individual cases where the banks
violated the law and you're not going to
tell the homeland's or at least it's not
clear yet whether not you're going to do
that
we have in their decision will bring
some homeowners
people want to know
that they're regulators are watching l
for the american public not the banks
and the only way that we can evaluate
whether or not you're doing your job
is if you make some of this information
publicly available
so far you're not doing that
and without transparency we can't have
any confidence
either in new york oversight
or at the markets are functioning
properly handle
water looked like a pilot lecture i said
what are we talking about why not
it's interesting the use of the
conference because she is the opposite
of all bombing how she's handled the
first time
present no model went with the hillary
clinton uh...
it keep your head down
don't ever do anything don't challenge a
bush say things that i was like out can
you believe that bush is so bad let's
get changed but don't introduce any
legislation don't you know don't speak
out in committee hearings shot up bright
and it didn't work for you know right or
wrong to work for
he say
issues now wild sheep i mean it's a
pretty good i mean she's so let me know
if you don't know threat over the world
right itself but on it
in terms of what she serious or not
place she says because
she does not go wade into territory
but she's not
totally well person so she's not going
into other committees like guns blazing
its acrobat botswana for back pain
scene no was this
and nobody knows a better than her and
she if she knows it she's missing of
course and stick my head up
that's why i got elected the whole point
was to represent people
and about let him get away with it
so she's gone with that strategy and and
i think that it's obviously having serai
strategy
and obviously as you point out
four years is not too short a period of
time
so up it out