Jan need to brush his teeth.
Jan, your breath stink.
Oh, Escalades with the scooters
attached on the
sides, like some on Batman
and Robin shit.
No, I'm just fucking around,
because we don't even need
this footage, in case I say
something funny, dude.
I mean, it could happen
sometime, fucking dickhead.
DAVID: I would like to hear,
though, like, we came here and
we have to--
EDDIE HUANG: Why don't you
just host the show?
Like, instead of telling
me to say what you
would like to hear--
DAVID: Let's go.
Right so we came all the way
to Taiwan, and I just think
that you can't come here without
eating stinky tofu.
It's something I grew up
with when I was a kid.
It's something you don't
have in the States.
You probably don't really
know anything about it.
It's something that is very,
very specific and
official for me.
So I think right now we're
going to go try that.
EDDIE HUANG: Official!
[MUSIC PLAYING]
EDDIE HUANG:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
Shen Keng is originally not
known just for its stank tofu,
but it's known for
tofu in general.
Because the water has
a flavor of coal.
It has the essence of coal.
So it gives it a little kind of
smokey charcoal flavor in
the food, especially
the tofu that they
make with this water.
So it's called stinky tofu.
I call it stank tofu.
But proper is stinky
tofu, chou doufu.
So watch what happens when
I press down on this.
Look how tender this tofu is.
Look at that.
That tofu is silky, dude,
it just falls out.
For anyone that's like, I don't
like tofu, I don't eat
tofu, I beg you, look at this.
Taste this.
When you have good tofu, it can
take on the flavor of coal
through the water.
It has leather.
It has tannins.
It has umami that you can't even
get in animal proteins.
Right?
And tofu, you can do dishes that
let the essence of the
tofu speak for itself,
like this one.
And it's just a touch of lard
and some shallot soup, right.
You could have this one, where
you get the very stinky tofu,
and you combat it with sesame
oil, sugar, rice wine, soy,
basil, and garlic.
Give it the aromatics, and
ginger, and they come together
for a very deep,
powerful dish.
You could do a coal.
And this is regular flavored
silken tofu.
This took on the flavor
of the tea.
What this dish is showcasing
is the tea.
And the funkiness is
coming from the
thousand year old egg.
So this is just cooking
science, right?
I love this.
Because every dish has to
have these elements.
But they're choosing which
vehicle to bring those
elements out.
They're choosing which ones
to showcase in every dish.
And it's fucking amazing how
this entire restaurant is
specializing in tofu.
And they're just firing on all
cylinders and showing you the
versatility.
It's really fucking cool.
It's like the Randall Cunningham
tofu restaurant.
There's not one way to
play quarterback.
There's not one way to cook.
There's not one way
to eat tofu.
And this is living proof, man.
This is fucking on fire.
-How did that happen?
EDDIE HUANG: So this
is called gua sha.
And he's scraping me.
Gua sha is kind of a
diagnostic step.
When you gua sha, it will show
you where the injuries are in
your body, and where there's
issues with your muscles or
nerves or pressure points.
Like this one hurts a lot.
And then he will target
those areas.
Doing the ba guan is very, very
good for relieving the
pressure in your pressure
points, circulation.
And also, that's how your body
has healing, is blood brings
the nutrients.
And blood circulation health
with all sorts
of healing and immunity.
So if you have a cold, if you
have the flu, headache, this
is a very good thing
to come do.
EDDIE HUANG: Shorty at home, you
know who you are, the kids
going to be sleeping
like this.
I've had MRIs.
I've had x-rays and
things like that.
This guy, just by using this
instrument and gua sha, he was
able to see things that
cost thousands of
dollars on the MRI x-ray.
And he also gave me the added
bonus telling me that's what's
affecting my stomach
and intestines.
Now, I want viewers to know
this is not voodoo.
This is not some cult.
This is thousands, 5,000 years
of Eastern medicine.
And it's not better than
Western medicine.
They are very good used
in conjunction.
EDDIE HUANG: So the first step
in a tea ceremony, pour hot
water over your teapot.
The reason he's getting it hot
is because the clay will react
to the heat.
So that's the amount of tea that
you would put into a pot
like, about one fifth.
He poured in 100 degrees
Celsius boiling
water into the pot.
Then he let it sit like
maybe two seconds, and
then dumped it off.
So a lot of the things we do,
whether it's cooking, whether
it's drinking tea, you
throw out the first.
And you see how he is constantly
seasoning his pots
with the first that
he's throwing out?
He's pouring the tea
over the pots.
He's seasoning them.
And it's that overflow with the
100 degrees Celsius water,
push it down, and then
let it hang out.
And you see the color of it,
it's like light golden color.
EDDIE HUANG: Just like you'd
smell the nose on a wine.
Before we left Taiwan,
I had to take you to
[FOREIGN LANGUAGE],
Old Street.
And not to be nostalgic about
the past, or not to be like,
it was better back then, or
be really somber about it.
But just to show you this is
a 5,000 year old culture.
The medicine is different.
We have a different
way of life.
And it's not better.
It's not worse.
It's just what it is.
And then lastly I wanted to show
you how tea, in a lot of
ways, is similar to wine,
and how stinky tofu
is similar to cheese.
If there's one thing to learn
from "Fresh Off the Boat" it's
no culture is better or
worse than another.
It just is, all right?
"Fresh Off the Boat,"
with Eddie Huang.
Taipei, we love you.
We out.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
-[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]