Okay.
You guys know thunder Clark
from the station, right?
- The weatherman?
- No, thunder Clark the plumber.
- Okay, what about him?
- Well, as one of the top
personalities at the station,
He was invited to play
in a celebrity golf tournament.
- Good for him.
- Well, not exactly.
It turns out thunder came down
With a really bad case
of pinkeye,
And it's highly contagious,
So they don't want him to play.
So since thunder is sick,
The station manager asked me
to step up and take his place.
- Babe...
You can't play golf.
- That is a surprise.
- No, that's not the surprise.
- Well, honey, can you hurry up
And tell us
what the surprise is?
- Fine,
I've been picked to play
In a celebrity golf tournament,
And we've all been invited.
- To see you play something
you don't know how to play?
- It's a lot like
my third grade band concert.
- Oh, yeah.
- Ow, now, see, Kevin,
Your trumpet solo
for all about the Benjamins,
That was...Amazing.
- Then where's the tape, mom?
- I lost it.
- I'm proud of you, dad,
Even if you can't play golf.
So where's the tournament?
- At Walt Disney world.
We're going to Disney world!
- We're going to Disney world?
- Yes!
- In Orlando?
- Walt Disney world?
- Yes, we're going
to Walt Disney world
In Orlando, Florida!
Oh, my God!
- We're going to Disney world!
- Whoo!
- I don't know what you guys
are gonna do,
But I'm gonna see
the hall of presidents.
I heard they added Obama.
I voted for you, man!
- Oh, honey, that is amazing.
So unbelievable.
This'll be, like, our first
official family vacation.
- Oh, this is going to be great.
- So when do we get to go?
- This weekend!
- As in this weekend?
- Yes!
- No.
- You might not want
to film this part.
- Okay, well,
remember when I told you
That my firm asked me
to plan this corporate retreat?
- Yeah, big account, huge.
- I'm supposed to give
the perfect presentation
At a big breakfast
this Saturday.
- Which means what?
- I can't go.
- Oh, that's... that's bad.
Hey, dad, can we still go?
- Yeah, please?
Can we?
sync and correct by dr.jackson
www.addic7ed.com
- Oh, baby.
Can't you let somebody else
take this one?
Look, it's not
your first big client,
And it won't be your last.
- I know, but Gigi and I
brought them on.
If I bail now,
it'll just look bad.
- Look at that.
I was just planning on doing
something really special for us,
You know, riding some rides,
Catching the fireworks,
A little romance,
Family stuff.
See, you can't miss that.
- Nick, honey, I don't want to,
but I have to.
- Fine.
I'll tell the kids we can't go.
- No, no, no, no.
Don't do that.
You know, maybe Kevin
had the right idea.
Just because I can't go
Doesn't mean
that you guys can't.
This is too important.
It's a once-in-a-lifetime
opportunity.
- Thank you, baby.
- You better go now,
Because once they see you
play golf,
You'll never be invited
to another tournament again.
- I love you too, baby.
Are you sure?
- Yes.
- Okay, then.
We're going to Disney world.
Yes!
- Going to Disney!
Going to Disney!
- Ooh, ooh, let me get that.
Let me get that.
Kevin, did you pack
extra underwear?
- Define "extra."
- Boy, you are not gonna be
in Orlando
Flipping your drawers.
Now, four pairs, go.
- We're going to Disney world!
- Okay, please tell me
you just bought that.
- No, no, no, no.
I am very proud of my ears.
Disney reminds me
of what being good is all about.
- He's coming to caddy for me.
- Yeah, and to get some items
signed for the store.
If I can get my 9-iron signed
by Anthony Anderson,
My trip will be complete.
- Well, my trip will be complete
when we get back.
- You're gonna have
a good time.
It's the happiest place
on earth.
- Dah-ah-ah-ah.
Disneyland
is the happiest place on earth.
Disney world
is the most magical.
- See, ma?
It's magical!
- Yippee.
- I'm just happy
you're coming along
To help out with the kids.
- I almost forgot,
I have something for you guys.
- Ooh.
- Video cameras,
to capture the memories.
- Oh, thanks.
- There you go.
- Four pairs of underwear.
- Are they clean?
- All I know,
As soon as Kevin comes back
with clean underwear...
We're going to Disney world!
- Yeah!
- Oh, my God, Gigi.
- Hey!
I'm having a bad day.
I'm get all of this
fixed later.
But for now,
Let's just say I look fine,
Unless you want to spend
the next two hours
Talking about it.
- Okay.
So here are the bullet points
Of what the client wants
for the retreat.
They want to get out
of the pacific northwest,
Someplace sunny.
They want a location that has
enough meeting amenities
But also numerous
fun activities
To enjoy
after business is over.
- That sounds more
like a vacation.
- Don't remind me.
I'm supposed to be
in Disney world right now.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
Too bad you can't
have the retreat there.
- Wait a minute.
That's it.
The client wants someplace
That combines meeting space
and resort activities,
Someplace sunny.
Don't you get it?
- You want to have the retreat
in Dubai?
- No, Disney world!
It's perfect!
- It is?
- Yes.
I'm gonna call Nick and tell him
we are on our way.
- Can I say it?
- Go ahead.
- We're going to Disney world!
Oh, my God!
- Hey, babe, we made it.
Mom and the kids
are going to the parks,
And I'm going to check in
for the golf tournament.
We miss you.
- Can we go now?
I want to ride space Mountain.
- Yeah, and I want
to go swimming
At the typhoon lagoon.
- All right.
I'll meet up with you guys
after the golf tournament.
- I'm coming.
Look, I know this place
is magical,
But walking too fast will cast
an evil spell on my feet.
Come on.
Where we gonna go first?
- We should go swimming.
- Do you have the map?
- Yeah, here's the map.
- Okay, which way are we going?
- Oh, Nick Kingston-persons.
KAWT sports in the house.
- Wow, Anthony Anderson,
you know me?
- Uh, no.
I know you're gonna lose,
though.
Unfortunately for you, brother,
I'm playing.
And although you will love
your time down here at Disney,
Your time on the links
will be dismal.
- Oh.
Okay, well, we'll see.
Who am I playing with?
- Toby.
Al Roker.
- You're teaming with Al Roker.
- Yeah.
- So what are you gonna call
your team?
Team chrome dome?
- Okay, okay.
Get your jokes in now.
Get 'em in.
- Oh, I will.
I will.
- There you go.
- What's that for?
- Oh, I'm gonna send you
this picture after you lose
So you can remember
what it looked like
When you were happy.
Little black smiley face!
- Oh, snap.
Okay.
Nick Kingston-persons
got jokes.
- Nick Kingston-persons.
- What's happening,
my white friend?
Have you been teaching him
how the game is played?
Because I believe
you're gonna need
All the help that you can get.
- Yo mama.
- What'd you just say to me,
my man?
- Martin.
He didn't mean that.
- I don't really do trash talk.
It just kind of popped
into my head.
My apologies, sir.
- Yeah, all right, brother.
I'll see you out there.
Bring your "a" game.
- Brought.
- Loved you in trippin'.
- Voice mail again.
Hi, honey.
It's me.
Guess what.
I'm at Disney world!
- Whoo!
- Can't wait to see you guys.
Love you.
- Okay, first, the spa
And then poolside cocktails.
- No, we have to find Nick,
and then we have a meeting
With the convention director
for the tour.
- Question.
- What?
- Do you really need me
to assist you on the tour?
I mean, it's not like I'm gonna
see something with my own eyes
That you can't see
with your eyes.
- Fine.
- Thank you.
- Go to the spa,
but book something for me.
- Okay, what?
Pedicure.
Saw your toes.
They look a mess. Come on.
- Wait!
That's why I'm wearing boots!
- Wow, big thunder Mountain
was awesome.
- Then why were you crying?
- Those were tears of Joy.
Oh, Marilyn, you missed out
on a great ride.
- No, I didn't.
You missed out
on a great frozen lemonade.
- Oh, look, it's Pluto!
Marilyn, can you take a picture?
- Sure, get together.
Got it.
Nice.
Nah, I'm good.
- That lady made Pluto cry.
- Really?
- Bam!
What do you think?
- Nice,
but you need to figure out
What you're gonna say
to Al Roker
When he finds out
you don't know how to play.
- Here, take a picture.
I want to send it to Suzanne
and ask her what she thinks.
Dick Wolf?
- What?
- I don't know.
- Hello?
Who is this?
Yeah, man.
Whatever you say, man.
No, I do not want to be
on a new law & order.
I really do, huh?
No, I don't.
Who am I?
You want to know
who I am, Dick Wolf?
Well, I'm Rick Fox.
Yeah.
Uh-huh.
Wha... yeah?
Well, your mama.
- Let me.
Let me.
Hello?
Uh, no, this is not
Anthony Anderson.
Who is this?
Dick Wolf from law & order?
No, no, no.
You probably had
the wrong number.
No, Mr. Wolf.
I don't find that funny at all.
I will absolutely tell Anthony
you called.
Law & order.
Absolutely.
Yeah, bye-bye.
- Please don't tell me
that was really Dick Wolf.
- Okay.
- I have Anthony's phone,
don't I?
- I think so.
- I guess we better
go find him.
- Yeah.
- Please, Marilyn?
It'll be fun.
- What don't you all understand
About the phrase
"I don't like rides"?
- Are you scared?
- If I was, I wouldn't be scared
of this one.
It's called dumbo.
Nothing scary about that.
- That's the lady
that made Pluto cry!
- Make you cry next.
- Okay, if there's nothing scary
about the ride,
Then why don't you just
get on it?
- Yeah.
- If I do,
will you leave me alone?
- Deal.
- Come on.
- Yes.
- Back of the line.
Go.
- Um, Marilyn,
are you all right?
- Man, that was incredible!
- Really?
- Yes!
You know, I never got
to come here when I was younger.
And whenever
I would see somebody
In those football games,
I would always say,
"why would a grown man want
to come to Disney world?"
Well, now I see why.
Can we do another one?
- Sure.
- Then let's go!
- You know, I left a message
for Anthony Anderson
On his phone and at his room.
- Well, you can tell him
in person, 'cause there he is.
- Oh, hey,
what's up, Bagger Vance?
- Don't say it.
- For the record,
Bagger Vance was black.
- Remix.
Uh, ving rhames,
I think I have your phone.
- Yeah, and I think
I have yours.
- Oh, okay.
- Did I get any calls?
- Yeah, some girl named Susan
or Suzy called.
- Suzanne, my wife.
- Yeah, something like that.
did I get any calls?
- No, no.
I didn't even hear it ring.
Did you, Martin?
- Did not hear a thing.
- Oh, okay, cool.
Oh, I also beat your high score
in brick breaker.
Just a little prelim
before the main event.
- Oh, Anthony, um...
You know,
now that I think of it,
You did get a call.
- Oh, from who?
- Your mama!
- Oh, yeah.
Good.
- Cute.
Just like your outfits.
- Mr. Kingston-persons?
- Yes?
- I am sorry to tell you,
But Al Roker's flight
was canceled.
He won't be able to play.
I'm afraid we have to take you
out of the competition.
- No, whoa, whoa.
- So who's playing
against Anthony Anderson now?
- Ha!
Your mama!
Bam!
- Hey!
- Hi.
This place is amazing.
- Ahh.
- This location is perfect.
The client is going to love it.
- Oh, girl, I know I love it.
Have you heard from Nick?
- No, and it's weird,
Because I tried him earlier,
And I got the wrong number.
- With speed dial?
How is that even possible?
- I don't know.
I'm gonna try Lindsey now.
Oh, no.
- What now?
- My phone is dead.
Can I use yours?
- Of course you can,
but it's in my room charging.
- Oh.
- Coconut punch?
- Ooh, yes.
- Look at Mickey on the cup.
That's my drink.
- Mm-Hmm.
- Why are you drinking it?
- Oh, Nick.
Man, I'm sorry you got scratched
from the tournament.
You know,
I was gonna really enjoy
Beating you like a bongo.
- Why are you still
talking trash, man?
We are not playing each other.
It's over.
You ought to be happy.
At least this way,
you can keep on dreaming.
- You really think
you could beat me?
- Like eggs on Sunday morning.
- Well, tomorrow
let's arrange something
To settle this, then.
- Arrange it, then.
- It's done.
- Oh, and bring
your big fat mama.
- Bring yours.
I'll bring her gravy bowl.
- Wait.
So were you just
insulting each other,
Or are you actually
bringing your mothers?
- Both.
- So what do you guys
want to do now?
- Can we take a break?
- A break?
I'm having the time of my life,
And you want to take a break?
- Our feet hurt.
- Oh, who's the grandma now?
Oh, fine, we'll stand here.
We'll watch the party
and catch our breath.
Ooh, look! Look!
Aha!
- I don't even know
where to look.
- Me neither.
- Said the parade, right?
- Yeah.
- Gigi, I'm never
gonna find them out here.
- Don't worry.
They'll show up.
Enjoy the parade.
Look!
Oh, look!
- That was great, everybody.
But now it's time
to take it to the street
And get ready
to move it to the beat,
To our move-it, shake-it,
celebrate-it street party.
So everybody get out
in the street
And get ready to move!
- Ah!
Nick!
- Uh, buddy...
Do you know that woman?
- Who?
- Right there.
- Nick!
- I told you!
- Suzanne!
Suzanne!
Oh-ho-ho!
Baby!
What are you doing here?
- Honey, I've been trying
to find you guys all day.
Where are the kids?
Mom! Dad!
- Ah!
Oh, my God!
- Excuse me.
- Excuse us!
- Excuse me!
Excuse me!
Ohh, yeah!
- Hi!
- Come here.
Come here.
Come on up.
There you go.
There we go.
- I'm in love.
- Hi, there!
- Go, Mickey!
Go, Mickey!
- So, Nick, you ready for this?
- I was born ready.
- You can take him, honey.
- Yeah, dad, you can do this.
- I see you brought your mama
And your little cheering squad.
Let me tell you something.
This is my course.
- Yeah, just keep talking,
little man.
I just hope you can play golf
better than you can act.
- Ooh.
- And I hope your son
can play golf
Better than whatever it is
that he does,
Which I know nothing about,
because he's not famous.
- It's okay, mama.
I got this.
You ready?
- I'm ready.
- Drop your ball.
Ooh.
Yes!
- Wait. Hold up.
- Ergh!
- Ha-ha!
- Yes!
- Go in. Go in.
Go in. Go in.
Go in. Go in... oh!
- Yes!
- Okay, Nick,
You land a hole-in-one here,
the game is yours.
If you don't, Anthony wins,
You let everyone down,
And you ruin
your first family vacation.
No pressure.
- Your mama.
- Is that how that works?
- That's how it works.
- All right.
- You can do it, Nick!
Whoo!
- That's right,
'cause I raised a winner.
- And he's about
to become a loser.
- Yes!
Yes!
Ha-ha-ha-ha!
- Yeah!
Ahhh!
Whoo!
Wow!
Uh! Uh!
Uh!
- Good game, man.
- Oh, good game?
wait.
After all that trash
you was talking,
You just... all you can say
is, "good game"?
Whoa, whoa, you're an actor,
man, look.
Act like you got beat!
- ooh. Ouch.
- Hey, you need
some motivation, huh?
Ask your mama!
- That's all right.
That's all right.
I'll see what you're all about
after my bocce ball tournament.
- You tell him, baby.
- Be quiet, mama.
- Ooh.
- Loser.
- How you gonna talk
to your mama like that?
- Buh-bye.
Hey guys.
- Hey, dad.
- Quit playing for a sec.
I've got a surprise for you.
- Quick, stop playing.
His last surprise was the best.
- I have to interrupt.
Okay, so I gave my Disney world
proposal to the client,
And guess what.
- What?
- They said
it was the perfect site.
Landed it!
- Congratulations, baby.
- Thank you.
Thank you.
- But now it's time
for my surprise.
- What?
- I just edited
the Disney trip.
- I cannot wait to see this.
- Congratulations, baby.
- Thank you, honey.
- I can't hold it much longer!
We're in Disney world, player!
- Whoo!
- Hey, Lindsey.
- Hi.
- We saw Mr. Obama.
- Oh, come on, no.
- You know what?
Can you move over?
- One, two, three...
Animal kingdom!
- I love it.
I'm having so much fun.
I've had a great time.
We watched the fireworks
last night,
Just Nick and I.
- Can I go get a funnel cake?
- I can't wait
to get in another ride.
- I'm just gonna lick it.
- Oh, gross.
- This is awesome.
- We should try to make this
a yearly thing, huh?
- I love it so much.
- You enjoyed it
more than we did,
And that's saying something.
- And if you tell anybody,
I will snatch the tongue
right out of your mouth.
Sync and correct by dr.jackson
www.addic7ed.com