I am always interested in
other people, and in how
people think about
other people.
So what I try to do in
photography is to play with
these prejudices.
I don't want to say to people,
you are wrong or your idea
about other people is wrong.
I also don't want to
say, you're right.
But I just want people
to think about it.
My name is Rob Hornstra.
I'm a photographer, but
I consider myself as a
storyteller, a documentary
maker, slow journalism.
It's not so much about
photography, but I use this
medium to tell stories.
I graduated in 2004, from the
Art Academy, and I'm working
now, for seven years,
independent, on mostly long
term projects.
I'm from Holland, so here
we are in Utrecht.
And from here, I'm going out to
other countries sometimes,
Russia, Iceland, I hope
some more in the
future, but not too many.
I just don't feel that I'm the
type of person who will travel
anywhere for one month just to
see a country, to meet the
people over there, and get
a few shots or something.
I want to go deeper and it has
its disadvantages because now
many people call me the
Russia photographer.
I'm convinced that I'm not
a Russia photographer.
But I'm just focusing
for, maybe 10 or
15 years, on Russia.
So at the end of my life, people
will see that I also
did other things.
At least, I hope that I have
time left for that.
This is, maybe, nice
to see because it's
like the older series.
This is my graduation project.
I graduated in 2004
with a book,
"Communism and Cowgirls".
For one month, I went to
Russia and I focuses,
particularly , on the younger
m the first generation who
grew up after the fall
of Communism.
The West became extremely
popular, like, Coca-Cola and
Ramstein was extremely
popular.
I didn't only photograph them,
but I also made photos of the
places they're living in.
But also, for example, of
their grandparents.
This contrast was especially
fascinating to me.
When I finished the art academy,
I was quite sure
that, with the work I
made in Russia, I
wanted to make a book.
And of course, I couldn't
find a publisher.
And then I started to
investigate how much it would
cost to print this book, an
offset print, a real book.
And it was seven and a half
thousand euro for 250 copies.
And I was completely shocked.
But on the other hand, I was
working as a bartender, and I
explained this to
my colleagues.
And then this colleague
immediately said, I want to
buy a copy in advance, so here
you have 30 euro and maybe you
could sell some more
copies in advance.
And maybe it's possible.
And it worked.
The book sold out within
three, four months.
So that's good.
Got the money back and I
printed my first book.
And as a result of this, at a
certain point, I was asked for
a commission in Iceland.
And I did a project over
there, also interested,
especially, by the young
generation doing nothing in
these villages.
Then this Iceland book, I
started a new pre-sale, and it
sold out within three days,
instead of three
weeks or four weeks.
So I did it again in 2008.
My third book "101 Billionaires"
and what
happened was that it
sold out within a
few hours, this pre-sale.
At that moment, Russia had 101
billionaires, and what I
showed actually was the 99% of
the rest of the country.
Well, every morning I have to
do shift some books, the
orders which come in.
And it's not that difficult.
That's it, actually.
This is for today, so we'll
bring it to the post office.
The difficulty is, of course,
when you are self-published,
is that you have to organize
everything by yourself.
So you start with finding
a designer.
You have to work with writers,
with a translator.
You have to find a budget, you
have to find money, organize
the payments, of course.
And when you finish it, the
book is finally there.
Then you also have to
ship all the books.
So it's a lot of work.
On the other hand, I believe
that if you publish the books
yourself, you are completely
free in whatever you want to
do with the book.
The only thing I care about is
that I want to tell my story.
I'll have to sell this book,
but it's really secondary.
I want to make this book and I
believe that, if I tell the
story in a perfect way, that
people will be interested.
That's actually my only
idea behind it.
In 2008, right at the moment
that I published "101
Billionaires", I was approached
by a writer, Arnold
van Bruggen.
I was already working with
him, also for "101
Billionaires".
And he told me about Olympic
Winter Games in Sochi.
It was announced in 2007.
And Arnold tried to convince me
to do a long term project
about the region around Sochi.
The goal of this project is to
document it for five years and
to make an atlas of the region
in words and images.
Sochi is over here, quite
far to the west and to
the south, of course.
And actually, what you see over
here is the whole Soviet
Union, but partly, the lighter
brown is Russia.
And Sochi is near the Black Sea,
so it's a holiday resort.
And from Sochi, you go
straight up into the
mountains, the Caucasus
Mountains, into the more or
less troubled republics,
Chechnya, Dagestan,
Ingushetia.
It borders Georgia, borders
Abkhazia, also a conflict zone
where a lot of things
go on right now.
So I just arrived last night
in Sochi, from Utrecht,
Amsterdam, Moscow, Sochi.
We're now on the 15th floor of
the Hotel Zhemchuzhina, which
means the pearl.
It's a hotel built in the
end the '90s, end
of the Soviet times.
And I think, actually, that the
view you have over here
from Zhemchuzhina, is
one of the most
brilliant views in Sochi.
I took already many photos.
What we, for example, want to
do is to show what kind of
place Sochi is.
And Sochi is really a tourist
resort, but maybe things are
little bit different
than you expect.
And this is also kind of an
aim or goal for me, within
photography, to tell stories
which make people think and
maybe they start to reconsider
their prejudice.
What we tried to do is to
document this region to give a
good view also because you can
be sure that, around these
Olympic Games, there will be a
big facade from Russia to show
how great and fantastic
everything is.
We are, right now, at
the area where they
built the Olympic stadiums.
What we see over here is really
a journalistic picture,
I think, because it's the new
stadiums and the old houses,
all in one shot.
I don't like this kind of
picture, by the way.
That's really what the
journalists like.
It explains, actually,
the situation.
But I do not really like
it for my work.
It tells you too much.
It's like exactly what it is.
It doesn't leave anything
to your imagination.
Slow of journalism is a little
bit strange description of
what we are doing.
Actually, this term was
invented, I think, by someone
in the Netherlands.
And I believe slow journalism
is similar to documentary.
And I believe, actually, that
the big difference is that
journalism is focusing on what
is happening, and slow
journalism is more why these
things are happening.
Now what's this?
This food is really amazing.
What you see over here is what
will be the main stadium.
On the first of April, this
year, 2011, we started the
third year of the
Sochi project.
So at a certain point, I
came up with the idea--
We were sitting in a restaurant
and there was a
singer starting his show
again, which in the
restaurant, in Sochi, always
means that you cannot talk
with each other any more.
And this is actually a really
typical Russian cultural
thing, but even more
typical for Sochi.
So what I will do, in the
upcoming days in Sochi, is
investigate if it can be a
good subject for a new
publication.
Last night we went to a cafe
restaurant, [INAUDIBLE] which
means South.
And it looked like a very
interesting place, beautiful
background, some interesting
details like a [INAUDIBLE]
standing on the right, and there
was a nice toilet sign
near the stage.
So there must be a good
picture in it.
I was happy with it.
So when we started
this project we
decided we need money.
And we cannot rely on magazines
and newspapers, just
the story everybody's telling.
So we wanted to do something
different.
And we looked to the U.S., and
what we saw over there was
kickstarter.com and spot.us,
both crowd funding sites.
And they were very interesting
to us because we didn't notice
in the Netherlands and we were
almost sure that we didn't see
it in Europe yet.
So we tried to copy this model
from the U.S. Many people were
interested in it and started
donating, not enough to do
what we want to do, but it's a
really big amount of money.
And we hope we can make
it for five years.
In 2009, we started by making
our first trip and we came to
the idea to make a publication
about sanatoriums in Sochi.
Sanatoriums are extremely
important and
Russians like it a lot.
We decided to stay there for
almost two weeks and to do
exactly what Russians also do.
You have to go in the mineral
bath, massage, and you get
like an electric loaded clay
treatment and those kind of
things, very interesting
to see for us.
And then we heard that, because
of the Olympic games,
they want to change them into
four or five star hotels.
And that's the reason why we
decided to make the first
publication about sanatoriums
because that's the only way we
can preserve this history.
There are only a few boxes left
with the last really big
book, Empty Land
or [INAUDIBLE].
We were already working, at that
time, for four years in
the neighboring country of
Abkhazia which is really
neighboring the Olympic
stadiums within five
kilometers, so it's
walking distance.
So the second year, we made
a book completely about
Abkhazia, and it's a very
complicated story over there.
Actually, this country is
isolated because it's not
recognized by any country
in the world until 2008.
Russia decided to recognize
Abkhazia as
an independent country.
it's an extremely complicated
story, so in the end, it also
became an extremely book.
It's a big historical,
political
document about this region.
We are in a hurry tonight,
because I actually want to do
five restaurants.
That's quite a lot, but
they are very close.
We're now in the center of Sochi
and hope to do five.
So we have to hurry.
What we realized immediately is
that we cannot make such a
big document as we did in
Abkhazia, within a few months.
We worked on this
for four years.
So our idea came to do a
more simple subject.
We cannot do such a big book,
but we can do these Sochi
singers, the lounge singers.
That will be, probably, our
new publication in 2011.
I'm making a series about
musicians in restaurants.
And the most beautiful is, if I
have a big interior, well, I
will have it over here, and if
you sing like you do, what you
also normally do, so don't pay
too much attention to me.
Sometimes look at the camera,
and then, finally, it will be
a brilliant picture.
And in 2013, we will probably
make our end book a really big
book and what he call
the atlas about
the region of Sochi.
This will be combined with a
really big exhibition in, we
hope, many places in Europe,
around the Olympic Games.
Well, I think I will be here
earlier before the Olympics.
But actually what we do, we also
try to present projects
in different ways.
We don't have to think about
these newspapers and
magazines any more.
We don't have to think about all
traditional ways to tell a
story, especially, because
I'm self published.
And there are many
self publishers.
You don't have to think in a
way that documentary makers
did it 20 years ago.
We can do, actually, anything,
because nobody tells us,
nobody tells us what
to do, actually,
so we can do anything.
And that's really good
about these times.