We're giving you guys a chance to travel from
anywhere in the world. Wherever you are, we
will fly you here for our next live show!
Tickets, boom.
Spending money. How do you like them apples?
Ohh, that's five hundred quid. We should be
arrested! We've got hotels, two plane tickets,
cold hard cash.
How rad is that?
Say you're from Papa New Guinea, I've got
to go there, or Kenya, or India, or American,
well fly you from Milton Keynes, we'll fly
you from Canada. Well maybe not Milton Keynes.
We can get you like a train or something,
We'll put you up in a hotel, in London and
five hundred squid. Cold, hard cash, to spend
when you're here.
And we're going to wine you and dine you at
Jamie Oliver's restaurants. But to be in with
a chance to win this competition you have
got to watch the live show.
You have to tune in this Tuesday the 21st
January, from 8pm on man. We're Holding an
anniversary party, we've been on Youtube for
a whole year.
So we've got the whole family here celebrating.
Jamie Oliver, Gennaro doing rad party food,
myself and Michael from V Sauce will be here.
Ow!
So make sure you watch the live show, 21st
of Jnauary, 8pm. That's a Tuesday y'all.
So watch it.