powerful spiritual hub.
I think the plan is he's going
to show us this stone, which
is part of a old stone circle.
This is the main one where,
apparently, Satanic rituals
happen on a regular basis.
So this is a place here, then,
where you think these
rituals-- or you know
these rituals--
DAVID ICKE: These rituals
definitely go on at
this place up here.
KEVIN MORPURGO: Is this--
DAVID ICKE: It's called
the Longstone.
And in fact, it's two stones.
One's on its side and
one's standing up.
And it's a beautiful walk,
this direction.
KEVIN MORPURGO: Let's go.
After you.
DAVID ICKE: Cheers, mate.
It opens out, eventually, and
you get a fantastic view.
It's interesting.
When you look at the traits--
this is mainstream science.
When you look at the traits of
what we call the "reptilian
brain," reptilian genetics,
which we all have, one of the
traits is an obsession
with ritual.
So when you look at all the pomp
and ceremony of the royal
family, you know?
With Buckingham Palace and all
this stuff, and all the
ceremonies and the guards and
the horses and the colors,
you're looking at ritual.
KEVIN MORPURGO: But you say that
the people that actually
live on the island
are part of this.
There are people--
there's a network on the
island that are--
DAVID ICKE: Oh, big time.
I mean, the Isle of Wight's
a beautiful place.
And if you pick up the higher
levels, the vibrational levels
of it, it's a very pleasant
place to be.
But my goodness me, if there
is a network of Freemasons,
Satanists, and pedophiles
that run this island.
KEVIN MORPURGO: And
this is police--
DAVID ICKE: They run
its government.
KEVIN MORPURGO: --the
government, everything.
We're almost here at the
top to see the Long--
DAVID ICKE: Oh, dilly.
KEVIN MORPURGO: There it is.
The Longstone.
DAVID ICKE: There we go.
It's funny though, you come on
a day like this, it's a nice
day, there's families around,
and you see these stones.
If you could see these on May
1, Halloween, these ritual
periods of the year--
KEVIN MORPURGO: Then you'd be
a totally different story.
DAVID ICKE: You would
see something
very different, yeah.
KEVIN MORPURGO: So this is the
center point of this energy,
then, that they're trying
to tap into?
DAVID ICKE: What they would do,
among many other things,
you'd have them in their robes
and hoods all around here, and
you'd probably have, or you
would have the sacrifice on
the slab here.
KEVIN MORPURGO: This
is the altar?
DAVID ICKE: This is
their altar, yeah.
And what they're doing--
it's horrible, but let's
get the truth out.
What they're doing is
manipulating the sacrifice.
The sacrifice knows the
sacrifice is coming, and who's
going to help them?
Look.
KEVIN MORPURGO: Right.
DAVID ICKE: At midnight
or something.
No one.
And what they then do is they
sacrifice the victim and they
drink the blood immediately,
which has this chemical
substance in it.
And they go crazy.
I mean, I've talked to people
who've been at these rituals,
and how once the sacrifice
happens and the blood runs,
these people go crazy
with blood.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
DAVID ICKE: There was a man
called Stanley Kubrick, the
great filmmaker.
KEVIN MORPURGO: I think
I've heard of him.
DAVID ICKE: Stanley Kubrick was
an insider, and he wanted
to expose it.
And his last movie was called
Eyes Wide Shut.
KEVIN MORPURGO: I've seen it.
Yes.
DAVID ICKE: Now, Eyes Wide Shut,
he died very, very soon
after it was presented to
executives at the film company.
And was given no fanfare
whatsoever when it came out--
KEVIN MORPURGO: They maybe
edited the hell
out of it as well.
DAVID ICKE: Yes, they did.
They took 25 minutes out of it,
which he refused to do.
Now, he filmed a ritual with Tom
Cruise in it, in which I
only know more recently was
a Rothschild mansion.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
DAVID ICKE: And what he filmed
is a mild, mild version of
what goes on.
Because he knew.
And you had the colors.
You have most people in the
ritual in Eyes Wide
Shut were in black.
The main guy was in red.
Here we go again.
You had the orgies going on, and
you had the people being
killed, the lady being killed.
But that was such
a mild version.
I don't know what was
in the 25 minutes
they took out, mind.
Because the real version
is that there's blood
every-bloody-where.
We see a hierarchy in the public
arena of presidents,
secretaries of state, of prime
ministers, secretaries of
state, down, down, down, down.
That's the public hierarchy.
The real hierarchy,
in the shadows,
is the occult hierarchy.
And if you're higher in the
occult hierarchy, the satanic
hierarchy-- which is incredibly
hierarchical, it's
all hierarchical--
then you have more power over
someone higher than you in the
public hierarchy.
KEVIN MORPURGO: You know, people
familiar with your work
would know that you've made
some predictions over the
years, and they've
come to pass.
I mean, I think this may be part
of the reason why people
are really starting to
pick up on your work.
Something like the internet.
What do you see--
because at the moment, this
is how people are getting
information spread
to each other.
It seems, at least at the
moment, to be relatively free
in most countries.
What do you see happening
there?
DAVID ICKE: The big thing that
they're going to say is
because of the danger of
terrorism and terrorists
communicating on the
internet, these
things have to be stopped.
I mean, what did Cameron say
after the London riots?
We may have to talk about
censoring Twitter and Facebook.
And Bill Clinton--
and when Bill Clinton, like Tony
Blair or George Bush or
anybody, when they open
their mouths, it's
the Rothschilds speaking.
And just a few months ago,
Bill Clinton came out and
said, we need, basically,
a censor organization, a
Ministry of Truth, to police
the internet and to stop
people-- he specifically talked
about people who were
spreading rumors on the internet
that are not true.
They are true, Bill, OK?
They're in my books.
There's documentaries
about it.
They're true.
Go away.
Drink your milk.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
KEVIN MORPURGO: Do people just
turn up at your door, though?
I'm sure you have fans that--
DAVID ICKE: Well, they do.
I hope they're not fans.
I hope they're not followers,
or they're not listening.
But yeah, I have people come
quite a lot from time to time.
I'm a very private
person, you see.
It's one of the strange things
about my life, really.
I'd guess you'd call it a
paradox, but I don't suppose
it is, really.
And that's that almost
everything I've done in my
life has been a public
profession.
I was a footballer.
Then I became a journalist
and television presenter.
Then I was a national spokesman
for the Green Party.
Then I did this, of course.
And yet I'm an incredibly
private person.
And I talk to thousands at
an event, and I love it.
I just love being there.
It's like being in
another reality.
There's a massive interaction
going on energetically between
the audience and me.
You feel what humanity is behind
the programming and
behind the false sense
of limitation, and I
Can't and Little Me.
You feel the true magnitude
of what we are
coming off the audience.
What we need is not
compliance.
We need a non-comply dance,
where we beat to a different
drum and we dance to
a different drum.
Where we refuse to acquiesce
to this control system that
seeks to enslave us even more
than it already has.
Non-comply dance.
Do this.
Comply.
No.
Enough.
It's time to fly.
Thank you very much.
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE]
DAVID ICKE: Thank you.
It's funny, Kev, you know.
You brought me here, and it's
kind of a real strange,
spooky, surreal feeling, because
I used to stand here.
I was a little boy.
I could just about see over the
top of this bloody fence.
Same fence.
Think it is, anyway,
repainted.
And I used to watch the
steam trains come up.
And I wanted to be a footballer
and I wanted--
I love steam trains and
all the rest of it.
And nearly 60 years later, I'm
standing in the same spot and
I've been talking to you about
a moon bloody matrix,
shape-shifting reptilians,
a few families
run the bloody world.
I mean, whatever happened
to you?
Just keep watching
the steam trains.
Look at the trouble you've
got me into.
And it's just as strange,
where life goes.
You never know where it goes,
so all you can do
is enjoy the moment.
And I love this moment, this
moment when I was watching
those steam trains, I
was in my heaven.
And standing here, I'm in
another kind of heaven,
because given what happened
20 years ago and
many years after that--
I was ridiculed in the street,
called a nutter, and I
couldn't fill a phone box.
And now, suddenly, it's
so different.
It just shows that if you keep
walking, and keep walking,
believing what you're doing,
then something comes
out the other end.
And it's just beginning to.
KEVIN MORPURGO: Even within
conspiracy circles, David Icke
is a controversial figure.
Many view him as a harmless
eccentric, while others claim
he must be an agent provocateur,
discrediting
conspiracies by mixing
documented fact with wild
allegations of rapist
reptilians and their
artificial moon base.
Maybe they're just jealous.
Icke has sold over 20 million
books worldwide, while his
website is an iconic forum for
the global esoteric community,
with over four million
views a month.
So this is David Icke--
visionary, multimillion-selling
author,
global icon, one-time messiah,
former goalkeeper, and the
single greatest threat to
the lizard apocalypse.
Good luck, my friend.
[MUSIC PLAYING]