SEEN EARLIER THAT MIGHT AT LEAST IN PART BE
RESPONSIBLE FOR THEIR
SUCCESS LIKE THE OVARY THAT PROTECTS THE OVULES
AND MECHANISMS
PROMOTING OUTCROSSING. AND THEN I STARTED
TALKING ABOUT SOME OF
THESE POLLINATION SYNDROMES THAT REFLECT ADAPTATION
WITH
PARTICULAR GROUPS OF POLLINATORS. WE TALKED
ABOUT BEE
POLLINATION, THE MOST IMPORTANT BIOTIC POLLINATION,
MOTHS,
BUTTERFLIES, BIRDS AND BATS. AND I JUST WANT
TO WRAP THAT UP
BEFORE GETTING INTO SOME OF THE INNOVATIONS
OF THE ANGIOSPERM
LIFE CYCLE THAT ARE REALLY IMPORTANT TO CONSIDER
IN TERMS OF THE
SUCCESS OF ANGIOSPERMS. AND THEN WE'LL TALK
ABOUT FRUITS AND
SEED GERMINATION TO WRAP UP THIS OVERVIEW
OF DIVERSITY IN THE
COURSE. AND THEN STARTING NEXT TIME WE'LL
BE GETTING MORE INTO
THE ANATOMY AND STRUCTURE OF PLANTS AND HOW
THAT AFFECTS THEIR
ABILITY TO GROW AND TRANSPORT NUTRIENTS AND
WATER ET CETERA. SO
SOME REALLY DIFFERENT TYPES OF ADAPTATIONS
IN THINGS YOU'VE SEEN
IN ANIMALS. ALL RIGHT, SO I JUST BRIEFLY TALKED
ABOUT FLY
POLLINATION AT THE END OF LAST LECTURE AS
ANOTHER EXAMPLE OF
DECEIT POLLINATION. REMEMBER IN POLLINATION,
IT'S OFTEN A
MUTUALISM WHERE THE PLANT OFFERS A REWARD
TO THE POLLINATOR THAT
BENEFITS IN SOME TANGIBLE WAY, OFTEN GENERALLY
FOOD. THE PLANT,
OF COURSE, BENEFITS BY BEING POLLINATED. BUT
IN FLY POLLINATION
LIKE IN THOSE BEE ORCHIDS, THE POLLINATOR
LOSES, BUT IT'S STILL
EFFECTIVE. THE FLY POLLINATION SYNDROME IS
ASSOCIATED WITH
REDDISH OR MAROON-COLORED INFLORESCENCES OR
FLOWERS THAT AS I
MENTIONED ARE LIGHT-SPOTTED WHICH SORT OF
RESEMBLES MAGGOTS
GROWING ON ROTTING MEAT. AND THEY OFTEN HAVE
A FLESHY TEXTURE,
I MEAN A DEFINITE FLESHY TEXTURE COMPARED
TO MOST FLOWERS THAT
CAN FOOL FLIES INTO THINKING THEY'RE WALKING
AROUND ON ROTTING
MEAT AND IN THE PROCESS POLLINATE THE PLANTS.
AND THE FLOWER,
THE FLORAL SCENTS ARE INCREDIBLY SIMILAR TO
CADAVERS, WHICH HAS
LEAD TO A LOT OF THESE PLANTS, FLOWERS BEING
CALLED CORPSE
FLOWERS WHICH BOTH OF THESE ARE, EVEN THOUGH
THIS IS AN
INFLORESCENCE, NOT A, NOT AN INDIVIDUAL FLOWER.
AND SO THE
FLIES, THE FEMALE FLIES VISIT THESE, THESE
FLOWERS AND LAY THEIR
EGGS. AND THEN THE EGGS HATCH AND THE MAGGOTS
DIE. THEY STARVE
TO DEATH BECAUSE THERE'S NO FOOD HERE FOR
THEM. SO THIS IS REAL
DECEIT POLLINATION. BUT FORTUNATELY FOR THE
PLANTS AND THE
FLIES, THERE ARE A LOT OF FLIES TO GO AROUND,
SO THERE'S NO LOSS
OF THE POLLINATOR THROUGH TIME. AND ONE OF
THE NEAT THINGS
ABOUT FLY POLLINATION IS IT'S ASSOCIATED WITH
SOME OF THESE
ABSOLUTELY HUGE INFLORESCENCES AND FLOWERS.
AND I MENTIONED
LAST TIME THE TITAN ARUM WHICH IS ACTUALLY
IN CULTIVATION UP AT
THE U.C. BOTANICAL GARDEN. AND WHEN IT FLOWERS,
IT'S ADVERTISED
ON THE BERKELEY HOME PAGE AND DEFINITELY WORTH
CHECKING OUT. IT
GETS UP TO 10 FEET TALL, THE INFLORESCENCE,
AN IMMENSE THING.
IT'S NATIVE TO THE FORESTS, RAIN FORESTS OF
INDONESIA, WHICH
HAPPENS TO BE WHERE YOU ALSO FIND THIS PLANT
WHICH IS DISTANTLY
RELATED. IT'S A CASE OF CONVERGENT EVOLUTION
ON FLY
POLLINATION. IT'S CALLED, THE NAME IS RAFFLESIA
ARNOLDII. THE
NAME'S NOT THAT IMPORTANT AT ALL. BUT IT'S
A INDIVIDUAL FLOWER,
AND IT'S THE LARGEST FLOWER KNOWN ON EARTH.
IT GETS UP TO ABOUT
A METER IN DIAMETER. AND IT, IT WEIGHS, IT
WEIGHS IN AT OVER
20 POUNDS, SO IT'S A HUGE FLOWER. AND IT'S
NOT ONLY A, IT'S NOT
ONLY CHEATING FLIES IN THE PROCESS OF GETTING
POLLINATED BUT IT'S
ALSO PARASITIZING ANOTHER FLOWERING PLANT
FOR ALL OF ITS
NUTRIENTS. THIS THING IS A HOLOPARASITE. IT
HAS NO STEMS,
LEAVES, TRUE ROOTS. IT'S JUST GROWING INSIDE
THE TISSUES OF A
MEMBER OF THE GRAPE FAMILY. SO YOU CAN'T EVEN
TELL IT'S THERE
UNTIL IT FLOWERS AND THIS GIGANTIC FLOWER
EMERGES. IT'S PRETTY
BIZARRE. OKAY, SO WIND POLLINATION ALSO OCCURS
IN ANGIOSPERMS,
AND REMEMBER THIS IS THE DOMINANT TYPE OF
POLLINATION IN
GYMNOSPERMS EXCEPT FOR CYCADS. AND IT'S SECONDARILY
EVOLVED WE
KNOW NOW FROM INSECT POLLINATION OR ANIMAL
POLLINATION. IT
OCCURS IN ABOUT 20 PERCENT OF ALL FLOWERING
PLANTS, SO NOT AN
INSIGNIFICANT NUMBER, GIVEN THAT THERE ARE
LIKE 300,000 FLOWERING
PLANTS. AND IT USED TO BE THOUGHT THAT THESE
WIND-POLLINATED
FLOWERING PLANTS MOSTLY CONSTITUTED A SINGLE
GROUP, A NATURAL
GROUP. BUT IT TURNS OUT THAT'S NOT TRUE. THINGS
LIKE OAKS,
BIRCHES, BEECHES, HAZELNUTS SHOWN HERE ARE
NOT CLOSELY RELATED TO
THINGS LIKE MULBERRIES AND STINGING NETTLES
AND MARIJUANA WHICH
ARE A SEPARATE ORIGIN OF WIND POLLINATION.
AND THERE ARE SOME
OTHER EXAMPLES TOO. BUT THEY'VE ALL EVOLVED,
OR NOT ALL, NOT
EVERY CASE, BUT THERE'S A SUITE OF FEATURES
THAT THEY'VE
CONVERGED ON EVOLUTIONARILY THAT MAKE THEM
APPEAR VERY SIMILAR.
SO IT'S A REALLY GREAT CASE WHERE WE HAVE
MULTIPLE ORIGINS OF A
TYPE OF POLLINATION WHERE A WHOLE SUITE OF
FEATURES COMES ALONG
WITH THAT THAT PRETTY CLEARLY ARE IMPORTANT
ADAPTATIONS TO THAT
TYPE OF POLLINATION. SO ONE THING IS THAT
THE FLOWERS ARE
EITHER PISTILLATE OR STAMINATE BUT NOT BOTH.
SO THAT HAS SOME
OBVIOUS ADVANTAGES IN TERMS OF PREVENTING
SELF-POLLINATION. AND
OFTEN THE PISTILLATE AND STAMINATE FLOWERS
ARE BORNE IN SEPARATE
INFLORESCENCES, SOMETIMES ON SEPARATE PLANTS,
ALSO PROMOTING
OUTCROSSING. AND THE PETALS NOT SURPRISINGLY
ARE REALLY SMALL
OR ALL TOGETHER ABSENT. AND THAT MAKES SENSE
BOTH IN TERMS OF
INVESTMENT, WHY INVEST IN A BIG ATTRACTIVE
SET OF DISPLAY
FEATURES WHEN YOU'RE NOT TRYING TO ATTRACT
AN ANIMAL POLLINATOR
ANYMORE, BUT ALSO IT'S A REAL DISADVANTAGE
TO HAVE BIG SHOWY
PETALS IF YOU'RE WIND-POLLINATED BECAUSE THEY'RE
JUST GOING TO
GET IN THE WAY OF THE POLLEN BEING DISPERSED
AND RECEIVED. SO
IT'S TO THE ADVANTAGE OF THE PLANT TO NOT
HAVE THESE INERT
SURFACES AROUND THAT CAN BLOCK POLLEN. AND
THAT ALSO THE CASE
ABOUT THEIR FLOWERING TIME. SO IN MANY CASES,
NOT ALL CASES BUT
IN MANY CASES, ESPECIALLY, WELL, WHEN WE HAVE
DECIDUOUS TAXA
INVOLVED, WHICH MANY OF THESE ARE, A LOT OF
OUR HARDWOODS FALL
INTO THIS CATEGORY, WIND POLLINATION THAT
ARE WINTER DECIDUOUS,
THEY'LL FLOWER BEFORE THE, THE LEAVES EXPAND
IN THE SPRINGTIME.
AND THAT'S AN ADVANTAGE IN TERMS OF MINIMIZING
BLOCKAGE OF POLLEN
BY THESE INERT SURFACES. AND ALSO THE ANTHERS
LIKE IN A LOT OF
CASES WHERE WE HAVE DISPERSAL FROM SPORANGIA
AS WELL AS
MICROSPORANGIA AND GYNOSPERMS, THE ANTHERS
OPEN IN DRY WEATHER
WHICH PROMOTES DISPERSAL OF POLLEN. AND THEY
TEND TO HAVE
ENLARGED STIGMATIC SURFACES. THIS IS REALLY
COMMON LIKE IN
GRASSES AND OTHER GROUPS WHERE YOU GET THESE
FEATHERY LOOKING
STIGMAS THAT MAXIMIZE SURFACE AREA TO CAPTURE
POLLEN. SO THAT'S
A, A COMMON FEATURE. AND ALSO WHEN YOU LOOK
AT THE POLLEN
ITSELF, IT'S REALLY DIFFERENT FROM THE INSECT
POLLINAT- OR
ANIMAL-POLLINATED FLOWERS WHERE THE POLLEN
IS IN CLUMPS AND IT'S
STICKY OR OILY AND ORNAMENTED. HERE YOU CAN
SEE IT'S DRY AND
IT'S SMOOTH-WALLED. IT'S DISPERSED IN SINGLE
GRAINS, WHICH
MAXIMIZES BOUNCY IN THE AIR. SO THERE'S A
LOT OF THESE GREAT
FEATURES THAT WIND-POLLINATED PLANTS HAVE
EVOLVED. AND, AND
THEY, THEY'RE REALLY, THEY CAN GET THEIR POLLEN
AROUND REALLY
WELL. SOME WIND-POLLINATED PLANTS CAN DISPERSE
POLLEN OVER
LARGE DISTANCES AND TO THE MISFORTUNE TO A
LOT OF US THAT HAVE
HAYFEVER, POLLEN ALLERGIES. AND THERE'S ALSO
EVEN WATER
POLLINATION. THIS IS REALLY RARE, BUT THERE
ARE SOME
ANGIOSPERMS THAT HAVE GONE BACK TO AN AQUATIC
ENVIRONMENT.
ANCESTRALLY THESE WERE LAND PLANTS. BUT SOME
ANGIOSPERMS HAVE
BECOME AQUATIC, BOTH IN FRESH WATER AND IN
MARINE SITUATIONS.
AND THIS IS ONE OF THEM, VALLISNERIA WHICH
IS THE RIBBON WEED.
AND THESE, SOME OF THESE HAVE, THEY HAVE A
WHOLE, THERE'S A BUNCH
OF DIFFERENT ADAPTATIONS TO POLLINATION IN
THESE DIFFERENT GROUPS
OF PLANTS THAT HAVE GONE BACK TO WATER. BUT
IN VALLISNERIA YOU
HAVE THE RELEASE OF THE MALE FLOWERS. IT ACTUALLY
JUST POPS THE
MALE FLOWERS OFF OF THE PEDESTAL AND THEY
FLOAT UP TO THE TOP.
AND THEY FLOAT AROUND ON THE SURFACE. THE
FEMALE FLOWERS ARE
HELD WITH SOME TENSION SO THAT THERE'S, THERE'S
ACTUALLY A
DEPRESSION IN THE WATER SURFACE, AND THE MALE
FLOWERS FLOATING
AROUND WILL BE DRAWN INTO THE DEPRESSION IN
THE WATER SURFACE AND
POLLINATE THE FEMALE FLOWER OR THE, I SHOULD
SAY THE PISTILLATE
FLOWERS. SO IN THE EELGRASSES WHICH, I SHOULD
SAY RIBBON
GRASSES ARE NOT REALLY GRASSES. THEY ARE MONOCOTS
JUST IN CASE
YOU'RE INTERESTED. EELGRASSES, WHICH YOU CAN
SEE OUT IN
ESTUARIES ALONG THE COAST HERE AND EVEN OUT
IN THE OPEN OCEAN,
ARE OUR ONLY LOCAL GROUP OF MARINE ANGIOSPERMS.
AND THEY'RE
ALSO NOT REALLY GRASSES, BUT THEY ARE MONOCOTS.
AND THEY
ACTUALLY RELEASE THEIR POLLEN UNDER WATER.
POLLEN IS USUALLY
REALLY VULNERABLE TO WETTING. IF POLLEN GETS
WET, IT'S USUALLY
CURTAINS. BUT IN THE CASE OF RIBBON, I SHOULD,
EELGRASSES THEY
CAN WITHSTAND EMERGING IN SALTWATER. AND THIS
THREAD-LIKE POLLEN
THAT IS CARRIED AROUND IN THE CURRENTS WILL
WRAP AROUND THE
STIGMA WHEN IT COMES INTO CONTACT AND GERMINATE
IT. SO THERE'S
A BUNCH OF REALLY AMAZING ADAPTATIONS OF FLOWERING
PLANTS TO
POLLINATION, SPECIALIZATIONS INVOLVING BOTH
ABIOTIC AND BIOTIC
AGENTS. OKAY, SO ANY QUESTIONS ABOUT POLLINATION?
BEFORE WE
MOVE ON? ALL RIGHT, SO I JUST WANT TO TALK
BRIEFLY ABOUT SOME,
SOME EVOLUTIONARY TRENDS THAT WE SEE IN FLOWERING
PLANT FLOWER
EVOLUTION. THERE IS A NUMBER OF THINGS THAT
COME UP REPEATEDLY
ACROSS FLOWERING PLANTS. ONE OF THEM IS THE
LOSS OR REDUCTION
IN NUMBER OF FLORAL PARTS. SO WE LOOK AT SOME
OF THESE
FLOWERING PLANTS THAT RECONSTRUCT AS HAVING
FAIRLY ANCESTRAL
FLOWERS, THEY USUALLY HAVE A LARGE AND INDEFINITE
NUMBER OF PARTS
OF THE DIFFERENT FLORALS OR DIFFERENT GROUPS
OF PERIANTHER,
SEPALS, PETALS, STAMENS, AND CARPELS. AND
WE TEND TO SEE A
GENERAL REDUCTION THROUGH TIME. THIS IS A
RED MAPLE WHERE IT'S
LOST THE PISTILS, FUNCTIONAL PISTILS IN THESE
PARTICULAR FLOWERS.
THERE ARE SOME PLANT, FLOWERS ON THESE PLANTS
THAT CAN BE
BISEXUAL. AND THEY READILY SELF. BUT WE SEE,
THIS IS A
PARTICULAR SPECIES WHERE WE SEE A TREND TOWARD
DIOECY OCCURRING
DURING THIS SNAPSHOT IN TIME. SO IT'S KIND
OF AN INTERESTING
SPECIES IN THAT REGARD. ALSO I MENTIONED IN
WIND-POLLINATED
PLANTS YOU CAN HAVE LOSS OF THE PETALS ALL
TOGETHER. THERE ARE
VARIOUS SPECIALIZATIONS THAT HAVE RESULTED
IN LOSS OF FLORAL
PARTS. AND IT'S RARE THAT WE SEE AN AMPLIFICATION
IN NUMBER OF
FLORAL PARTS ALTHOUGH IT CAN HAPPEN. ANOTHER
THING THAT WE SEE
IS FUSION OF PARTS OF BOTH THE SAME TYPE,
LIKE PETALS TO PETALS
IN THE CASE OF THIS FOXGLOVE HERE WHERE ALL
THE PETALS ARE FUSED
TOGETHER INTO THIS TUBULAR COROLLA. THAT'S
A COMMON THING. WE
CAN ALSO GET FUSION OF UNLIKE PARTS. FOR EXAMPLE,
STAMENS FUSE
TO THE INSIDE OF PETALS. AND THAT'S WHAT'S
GOING ON INSIDE THE
FLOWER HERE. YOU CAN'T SEE IT. BUT THAT SORT
OF FUSION OF LIKE
PARTS AND UNLIKE PARTS CAN HELP TO INTEGRATE
THE FLOWER IN A WAY
THAT IT FUNCTIONS AS A WHOLE VERY EFFECTIVELY
DURING POLLINATION
AND CAN ALLOW FOR MORE PRECISE, ACCURATE PLACEMENT
OF POLLEN ON A
POLLINATOR. SO, FOR EXAMPLE, A POLLINATOR
LANDS ON THE THROAT OF
THIS FLOWER AND DEPRESSES THAT LOWER LIP AND
THAT'S GOING TO
CAUSE THE STAMENS ABOVE TO COME DOWN ON TOP
OF THE BACK OF THE
POLLINATOR AND DEPOSIT POLLEN OR THE STIGMA
TO COME DOWN AND PICK
UP POLLEN. THOUGH THAT CAN GO HAND-IN-HAND
WITH REDUCTION IN
NUMBER OF PARTS BECAUSE IF YOU HAVE MORE ACCURACY
AND PRECISION
IN YOUR POLLEN PLACEMENT AND POLLEN REMOVAL,
YOU DON'T NEED
NECESSARILY, FOR EXAMPLE, AS MANY STAMENS.
THAT'S SO THESE
KINDS, THESE TRAITS, THESE TRENDS CAN GO TOGETHER
IN SOME CASES.
ANOTHER TREND THAT WE SEE IS A SHIFT FROM
RADIAL SYMMETRY WHERE
WE HAVE BASICALLY LIKE A PIE WHERE YOU CAN
CUT IT IN ANY, IN ANY
DIRECTION AND GET TWO EQUAL HALVES, RADIAL
SYMMETRY, AS OPPOSED
TO BILATERAL SYMMETRY LIKE US WHERE YOU CAN
ONLY CUT US IN HALF
IN ONE PLANE AND GET TWO EQUAL HALVES. AND
THAT'S WHAT WE SEE
IN THIS FOXGLOVE AS WELL AS IN THIS ORCHID
WHERE THAT'S THE ONLY
PLANE IN WHICH WE COULD CUT THIS FLOWER AND
GET TWO EQUAL HALVES.
AND WE GET THIS BILATERAL SYMMETRY EVOLVING
IN A LOT OF DIFFERENT
GROUPS, THE FLOWERING PLANTS, AND IT OFTEN
GOES ALONG REALLY WELL
WITH SPECIALIZATION IN POLLINATOR, IN POLLINATION
WITH PARTICULAR
POLLINATORS. SO IT ALSO PROMOTES PRECISION
AND ACCURACY OF
POLLEN PLACEMENT. IN THE CASE OF ORCHIDS,
MOST ORCHIDS ONLY
HAVE A SINGLE STAMEN. SO THEY'VE GONE DOWN
TO A SINGLE STAMEN,
AND THEY TRANSFER ALL THEIR POLLEN AT ONCE
WITH THAT SINGLE
STAMEN. THOUGH THERE'S, THAT'S A REPEATED
TREND AND THESE
GROUPS THAT SHOW BILATERAL SYMMETRY OF FLOWERS
HAVE SIGNIFICANTLY
HIGHER DIVERSITY THAN GROUPS THAT DON'T. THAT'S
BEEN SHOWN IN A
NUMBER, THERE'S ENOUGH DIFFERENT PLANT FAMILIES
WHERE THAT'S
EVOLVED THAT IT'S BEEN, WE CAN DO COMPARATIVE
STUDIES AND MAKE A
RIGOROUS CASE FOR AN INCREASED DIVERSITY WHEN
YOU EVOLVE THIS
KIND OF SPECIALIZATION. AND ANOTHER TREND
THAT WE SEE HAPPENING
OVER AND OVER AGAIN IS ADDITIONAL PROTECTION
OF THE OVARY, OF THE
OVULES. AND REMEMBER THE OVULES ARE ALREADY
CONTAINED WITHIN AN
OVARY IN FLOWERING PLANTS UNLIKE IN GYMNOSPERMS
WHICH PROVIDE
SOME PROTECTION FROM HERBIVORES, FROM DRYING
OUT IN THE, WITH
REGARD TO ABIOTIC FACTORS, ET CETERA. AND
IN SOME FLOWERING
PLANTS, OTHER FLORAL WHORLS LIKE THE PERIANTH,
THE, THE PETALS
AND SEPALS, THE BASES OF THE STAMENS CAN FORM
A FLORAL TUBE THAT
FUSES AROUND THE OVARY OR THE OVARY CAN ACTUALLY
BECOME EMBEDDED
IN THE TIP OF THE STEM LIKE IN A CACTUS HERE.
AND WE CAN HAVE
TISSUE IN ADDITION TO THE OVARY FUSED AROUND
AND PROTECTING THE
OVULES. SO THE OVARY IS WHAT WE CALL INFERIOR
IN THIS CASE
BECAUSE IT'S LOOKS LIKE IT'S ACTUALLY DEPRESSED
DOWN INTO THE
STEM WHICH IT ACTUALLY IS IN CACTI, BUT IN
MOST PLANTS THAT HAVE
AN INFERIOR OVARY, IT'S THE OTHER OUTSIDE
PARTS OF THE FLOWER
THAT FUSE AROUND THE OVARY. BUT THOSE ARE
JUST DETAILS. BUT
THE MAIN POINT IS THAT THERE'S OTHER TISSUE
IN ADDITION TO OVARY
TISSUE THAT SURROUNDS THE, THE OVULES THAT'S
FUSED TO THE
OVARIES, TO THE OVARY. AND YOU ONLY GET A
SINGLE OVARY IN CASES
LIKE THAT. OKAY, SO NOW THE LIFE CYCLE OF
ANGIOSPERMS IS PRETTY
SIMILAR TO THE GYMNSPERMS, THE OTHER SEED
PLANTS, BUT THERE'S
SOME REALLY IMPORTANT DIFFERENCES THAT MAKE
A LOT OF SENSE IN
TERMS OF HOW THESE MIGHT HAVE BEEN BENEFICIAL
TO SUCCESS OF
ANGIOSPERMS. SO LET'S LOOK AT THE POLLEN DEVELOPMENT
FIRST.
AND THIS IS A DIAGRAM FROM YOUR TEXTBOOK.
AND JUST LIKE IN THE
GYMNOSPERMS WE HAVE THE MICROSPOROGENESIS.
WE HAVE MICROSPORES
FORMED IN MICROSPORANGIA WHICH, THROUGH MEIOSIS.
THIS IS, THESE
ARE POLLEN SACS AS WE CALL THEM, BUT THEY'RE
MICROSPORANGIA.
AND HERE YOU CAN SEE THE FOUR PRODUCTS OF
MEIOSIS. AND THE MALE
GAMETOPHYTE THEN, OF COURSE THE MICROSPORE
GERMINATES, UNDERGOES
MITOTIC DIVISIONS, ALREADY HAPLOID LIKE ANY
OTHER SPORE. AND
THE GAMETOPHYTE'S HAPLOID. BUT AT THE TIME
OF DISPERSAL THE MALE
GAMETOPHYTE USUALLY CONSISTS OF ONLY TWO CELLS,
A TUBE CELL THAT
WILL DIRECT THE GROWTH OF THE POLLEN TUBE
AND A GENERATIVE CELL
THAT WILL UNDERGO ANOTHER MITOTIC DIVISION
TO PRODUCE TWO SPERM
CELLS. THOUGH THIS IS THE BEAR MINIMUM NUMBER
OF CELLS THAT
THIS MALE GAMETOPHYTE NEEDS TO FUNCTION PROPERLY.
IT HAS TO HAVE
A TUBE CELL IN ORDER TO PRODUCE THE POLLEN
TUBE TO GROW DOWN
THROUGH THE STYLE AND REACH THE OVULES IN
THE OVARY. AND IT
NEEDS BOTH OF THOSE SPERM CELLS, OKAY, UNLIKE
IN THE GYMNOSPERMS
THAT ONLY NEED ONE OF THEIR SPERM CELLS, ANGIOSPERMS
NEED BOTH OF
THE SPERM CELLS OF THE MALE GAMETOPHYTE. WE'LL
GET INTO THAT IN
A MINUTE. THAT'S ANOTHER IMPORTANT INNOVATION
WE'LL GET TO.
OKAY, BUT FIRST LET'S TALK ABOUT THE FEMALE
GAMETOPHYTE.
REMEMBER IN THE GYMNOSPERMS THE FEMALE GAMETOPHYTE
IS A FAIRLY,
IT'S TAKES UP THE MAJORITY OF THE SEED AND
IS THE MAIN NUTRITIVE
TISSUE FOR THE DEVELOPING EMBRYO AFTER IT
DEVELOP, AFTER
FERTILIZATION OF THE EGG. SO IN THE CASE OF
THE FLOWERING
PLANTS, THE FEMALE GAMETOPHYTE, IT'S NOT THIS
LARGE MULTICELLULAR
GAMETOPHYTE OR I SAID LARGE, YOU KNOW, FAIR-,
RELATIVELY
SPEAKING, BUT MORE CELLS THAN YOU'D CARE TO
COUNT THAT'S FOR SURE
IN THE CASE OF THE GYMNOSPERM FEMALE GAMETOPHYTE.
AND THE
PRESENCE USUALLY OF MULTIPLE ARCHEGONIA IN
THE GYMNOSPERM FEMALE
GAMETOPHYTE REMEMBER WHERE THE EGGS ARE FOUND.
BUT IN THE
FEMALE GAMETOPHYTE OF ANGIOSPERMS, THE MATURE
FEMALE GAMETOPHYTE
ONLY CONSISTS USUALLY OF ABOUT SEVEN CELLS
AND EIGHT NUCLEI.
ONE OF THE CELLS, THE CENTRAL CELL, THE LARGEST
HAS TWO NUCLEI,
WHAT ARE CALLED THE POLAR NUCLEI. BUT HERE
YOU CAN SEE THE
OPENING IN THE OVULE HERE WHERE THE POLLEN
TUBE WILL ENTER. AND
THERE'S VERY LITTLE TO THIS FEMALE GAMETOPHYTE.
THERE ARE THREE
CELLS UP AT THE BACK END OF THE OVULE, THE
ANTIPODAL SO-CALLED,
THESE TWO POLAR NUCLEI IN THE BIG CENTRAL
CELL. AND HERE'S THE
EGG AGAIN CLOSE TO THE OPENING IN THE OVULE,
THE MICROPYLAR END.
AND IT'S FLANKED BY TWO INDIVIDUAL CELLS,
ONE ON EITHER SIDE,
THAT ARE CALLED SYNERGIDS. NOT IMPORTANT BUT
THESE MAY BE THE
VESTIGES OF AN ARCHEGONIUM. BUT THERE'S REALLY
NO CLEAR
ARCHEGONIUM PRESENT, NO GAMETANGIUM, YOU KNOW
SAC THAT CONTAINS
THE GAMETES. JUST LIKE IN THE POLLEN, THEY'VE
LOST THE
GAMETANGIUM. SO THE ANGIOSPERMS DON'T HAVE
EITHER FEMALE OR
MALE GAMETANGIA IN THEIR GAMETOPHYTES. THOSE
ARE THE REALLY
STRIPPED DOWN FEMALE GAMETOPHYTE AND THE SUPER
STRIPPED DOWN MALE
GAMETOPHYTE AS WELL AS IN THE ANGIOSPERMS.
SO A PRETTY MINOR
INVESTMENT HERE COMPARED TO THE WHAT THE GYMNOSPERMS
MAKE IN
THEIR GAMETOPHYTES. ALL RIGHT, SO FERTILIZATION,
WE TALKED
ABOUT POLLINATION LAST TIME OF ANGIOSPERMS
WHERE THE POLLEN'S
DEPOSITED NOT ON THE OVULE ITSELF LIKE IN
GYMNOSPERMS, BUT AT THE
STIGMATIC AREA, ON THE STIGMA. AND WE TALKED
ABOUT HOW THE
POLLEN TUBES HAVE TO GROW DOWN THROUGH THE
STYLE TO REACH THE
OVULES. AND ONCE THAT OCCURS, THE POLLEN TUBES
GROW IN THROUGH
THE MICROPYLAR END, AS THEY DO IN GYMNOSPERMS.
AND WE HAVE
FERTILIZATION OF THE EGG BY ONE OF THE SPERM
CELLS. AND THERE'S
NEVER ANY FLAGELLAE ON THE, I THINK I ALREADY
MENTIONED THERE'S
NO FLAGELLUM ON THE SPERM AND ANGIOSPERMS.
THEY'RE DELIVERED
RIGHT TO THE, TO THE FEMALE GAMETOPHYTE BY
THE POLLEN TUBE. SO
THAT'S NOTHING NEW IN TERMS OF A ZYGOTE BEING
FORMED. BUT THE
OTHER SPERM, THE SECOND SPERM PRODUCED BY
THE POLLEN TUBE, ALSO
UNDERGOES FUSION NOT WITH THE EGG BUT WITH
THOSE TWO POLAR NUCLEI
IN THE CENTRAL CELL. AND SO YOU END UP WITH
THIS TRIPLOID
NUCLEUS. AND THIS WILL NOW UNDERGO A LOT OF
FREE NUCLEAR
DIVISIONS WITHOUT THE FORMATION OF CELL MEMBRANES
AND CELL WALLS
SEPARATING THEM FROM ONE ANOTHER INITIALLY.
AND THEN IT'LL START
WALLING OFF THOSE NUCLEI. SO WE GO FROM THIS
MILKY ENDOSPERM TO
A CELLULAR ENDOSPERM. NOW THE SIGNIFICANCE
OF THIS, SO WHAT
HAPPENS IS AFTER THE ZYGOTE FORMS AND THIS
ENDOSPERM FORMS, WE
START GETTING A LOT OF ACTIVITY OF THIS ENDOSPERM
TISSUE. IT
STARTS RAPIDLY DEVELOPING REALLY BEFORE THE
ZYGOTE'S DOING
ANYTHING. SO WE'RE INVESTING IN WHAT BECOMES
THE NUTRITIVE
TISSUE. THE ENDOSPERM BECOMES THE NUTRITIVE
TISSUE FOR THE
EMBRYO, THE DEVELOPING EMBRYO. THOUGH THE
IMPORTANT THING TO
CONSIDER HERE IS THAT IN THE GYMNOSPERMS,
THERE'S THIS HUGE
INVESTMENT IN THE FEMALE GAMETOPHYTE, THIS
VERY LARGE ORGANISM
INSIDE THE SEED RELATIVE TO THE SIZE OF THE
FEMALE GAMETOPHYTE IN
ANGIOSPERMS. BUT IN THE CASE OF, BUT IF IT
DOESN'T GET, IF THE
EGG DOESN'T GET FERTILIZED IN A GYMNOSPERM,
ALL THAT INVESTMENT
IS A BIG WASTE OF RESOURCES FOR THE PARENT
SPOROPHYTE THAT
PRODUCED THOSE OVULES BECAUSE THAT FEMALE
GAMETOPHYTE AND THE
GYMNOSPERM IS PARASITIC ON THE, ON THE SPOROPHYTE
THAT GAVE BIRTH
TO IT. SO THAT'S A REAL PROB-, OR THAT'S A
POTENTIAL PROBLEM IN
TERMS OF WASTAGE THAT ANGIOSPERMS GET AROUND
BY WAITING TO INVEST
IN THE NUTRITIVE TISSUE FOR THEIR DEVELOPING
EMBRYOS UNTIL AFTER
FERTILIZATION HAPPENS. SO ANGIOSPERMS WAIT
AND THEN START
DEVELOPING THE NUTRITIVE TISSUE, THIS ENDOSPERM.
AND IF YOU'VE
EVER BROKEN OPEN A COCONUT, WHICH COCONUTS
HAVE THE WORLD'S
LARGEST SEED SO THIS IS EASY TO SEE, THE MILK
INSIDE THE COCONUT
IS THE ACELLULAR ENDOSPERM, SO THAT'S THE
FREE NUCLEI FLOATING IN
CYTOPLASM WHERE WE HAVEN'T YET HAD CELL WALLS
FORM. WHEREAS THE
MEAT OF THE COCONUT THAT LINES THE INSIDE
OF THE SEED, THAT'S THE
CELLULAR ENDOSPERM THAT, WHERE WE HAVE HAD
CELL MEMBRANES AND
CELL WALLS PARTITION OFF THE NUCLEI. AND THE
EMBRYO'S REALLY
JUST A TINY LITTLE THING THAT YOU HAVE TO
BREAK OPEN THE, YOU
HAVE TO DIG AROUND IN THE CELLULAR ENDOSPERM
TO LOCATE. SO
THAT'S, GIVE YOU A LITTLE BIT OF CONTEXT FOR
ENDOSPERM. SO ARE
THERE ANY QUESTIONS ABOUT DOUBLE FERTILIZATION
THEN? OKAY, SO IN
THE END THEN AN ANGIOSPERM SEED -- YEAH?
STUDENT: [INAUDIBLE]
PROFESSOR: THAT'S A GOOD QUESTION. YEAH, WELL,
THAT'S, THAT'S
EXACTLY WHAT WE'RE GOING TO GET TO RIGHT NOW.
IT'S REALLY
UNCLEAR TO BE FRANK ABOUT IT IN TERMS OF WHETHER
THE TRIPLOIDY OF
THOSE NUCLEI, YOU KNOW, HAS ANY NUTRITIVE
BENEFIT TO THE EMBRYO
OR NOT. BUT IT IS STILL A CLEAR DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN WHAT YOU SEE
IN AN ANGIOSPERM SEED VERSUS A GYNOPSPERM
SEED. HERE'S A CARTOON
OF AN ANGIOSPERM SEED. AGAIN WE HAVE THIS
DIPLOID EMBRYO, THE
YOUNG SPOROPHYTE. WE HAVE THE TRIPLOID ENDOSPERM
THAT FORMS THE
NUTRITIVE TISSUE FROM, DEVELOPED AFTER FERTILIZATION
WITH THAT
SECOND SPERM FUSING TO THE POLAR NUCLEI. AND
THEN WE HAVE
DIPLOID SEED COAT TISSUE FROM THE INTEGUMENT
THAT WAS PRODUCED
AROUND THE OVULE BY THE PARENT SPOROPHYTE
THAT MADE THE OVULE.
AND IN CONTRAST IN THE GYMNOSPERM WE HAVE
BASICALLY THE SAME
ARRANGEMENT EXCEPT FOR THE NUTRITIVE TISSUE
HERE IS HAPLOID, IT'S
FEMALE GAMETOPHYTE TISSUE. WHEREAS THE FEMALE
GAMETOPHYTE, IT'S
RELATIVELY INSIGNIFICANT IN TERMS OF ITS NUTRITIVE
VALUE TO THE
EMBRYO COMPARED TO THE ENDOSPERM. OKAY? THOUGH
THIS INVESTMENT
WAS MADE BEFORE FERTILIZATION. THIS INVESTMENT
WAS MADE AFTER
FERTILIZATION IN THAT NUTRITIVE TISSUE. ALL
RIGHT, SO ANOTHER
INNOVATION THAT MAY HELP TO EXPLAIN SUCCESS
OF ANGIOSPERMS IN
PART IS THE EVOLUTION OF FRUIT. AND WE'VE
TALKED ABOUT FRUITING
BODIES IN MUSHROOMS. BUT THAT'S SHORTHAND.
STRICTLY
BOTANICALLY SPEAKING, THE ONLY REAL FRUIT
IS PRODUCED BY
ANGIOSPERMS. AND FRUIT HAS REAL VALUE TO ANGIOSPERMS
IN TERMS OF
PROMOTING DISPERSAL OF SEEDS. SO WE TALKED
ABOUT DIFFERENT
POLLINATION SPECIALIZATIONS, THESE DIFFERENT
POLLINATION
SYNDROMES, FOR EXAMPLE, THAT PROMOTE DISPERSAL
OF POLLEN WHICH IS
ONE WAY IN WHICH ANGIOSPERMS CAN GET THEIR
GENES AROUND IS BY
MOVING AROUND THE MALE GAMETOPHYTES WHICH
ARE MOBILE RELATIVE TO
THE REST OF THE LIFE CYCLE. THE OTHER STAGE
OF THE LIFE CYCLE
THAT'S MOBILE ARE THE SEEDS. AND SO FRUIT
IS AN INNOVATION OF
ANGIOSPERMS THAT PROMOTES DISPERSAL OF SEEDS.
AND BASICALLY
SPEAKING A FRUIT IN ITS STRICTEST SENSE IS
JUST A RIPENED OVARY.
SO REMEMBER THE OVARY IS THE BASE OF THE PISTAL,
THE CHAMBER IN
WHICH THE SEED OR, THE OVULE OR OVULES ARE
LOCATED. AND AT
MATURITY THE RIPENED OVARY BECOMES ALL OR
PART OF THE FRUIT.
SOMETIMES THERE ARE ADDITIONAL TISSUES THAT
MAKE UP THE DISPERSAL
UNIT OF THE FRUIT. SOMETIMES THE FRUIT ISN'T
THE DISPERSAL UNIT
BUT IT IS STILL THE RIPENED OVARY, AND WE'LL
GET TO THAT IN A
SECOND, THAT IS, ANGIOSPERMS CAN DIRECTLY
RELEASE THEIR SEEDS AND
THE SEEDS CAN BE DISPERSAL UNITS, BUT OFTEN
THE FRUIT IS THE
DISPERSAL UNIT CONTAINING THE SEEDS. SO THERE'S
A LOT OF
CLASSIFICATION THAT HAS REVOLVED AROUND DESCRIBING
DIFFERENT
TYPES OF FRUITS. AND THE IMPORTANT THING TO
REALIZE HERE IS
THAT THE CLASSIFICATION OF FRUITS IS NOT A
NATURAL
CLASSIFICATION, THAT IS IT DOESN'T REFLECT
PHYLOGENY. THESE
DIFFERENT SO-CALLED TYPES OF FRUITS ARE CONVENIENT
WAYS OF
CLASSIFYING FRUITS THAT HELP TO UNDERSTAND
THE MORPHOLOGY OF THE
FRUITS, AND THE ANATOMY OF FRUITS AND CAN
ALSO BE BENEFICIAL IN
UNDERSTANDING DISPERSAL. BUT THEY'RE NOT,
THESE DIFFERENT TYPES
OF FRUITS HAVE EVOLVED MULTIPLE TIMES IN DIFFERENT
GROUPS OF
FLOWERING PLANTS. AND THE MOST WIDESPREAD
TYPE OF FRUIT IN THIS
THREE, THREE-TYPE CLASSIFICATION I'M GOING
TO TALK ABOUT HERE
BRIEFLY IS IN YOUR TEXTBOOK IS CALLED A SIMPLE
FRUIT. AND A
SIMPLE FRUIT'S A GOOD NAME FOR IT BECAUSE
IT SIMPLY IS A FRUIT
DERIVED FROM ONE IS OVARY. THOUGH IT'S BASICALLY
DERIVED FROM
ONE OVARY OF ONE FLOWER. THAT OVARY MIGHT
BE FROM ONE CARPEL OR
FROM MULTIPLE CARPELS THAT WERE FUSED TOGETHER
INTO A COMPOUND
PISTIL, BUT IT'S FROM ONE PISTIL REGARDLESS
OF WHETHER THAT
PISTIL IS FROM ONE OR MORE CARPELS FUSED TOGETHER.
AND A
CHERRY, APRICOT, THESE ARE GREAT EXAMPLES
OF SIMPLE FRUITS THAT
ARE FLESHY FRUITS OBVIOUSLY, ALTHOUGH THE
PIT OF THE CHERRY, THE
PIT OF THE APRICOT IS ALSO A FRUIT WALL THAT
PROTECTS THE SEED
INSIDE. THERE ARE DIFFERENT WALLS OF, DIFFERENT
LAYERS OF FRUIT
THAT CAN BE REALLY DIFFERENT FROM ONE ANOTHER.
AND FRUITS CAN
BE DEHISCENT OR INDEHISCENT, THAT IS FRUITS
CAN OPEN UP AT
MATURITY AND RELEASE THE SEEDS DIRECTLY IN
WHICH CASE THE SEED IS
GENERALLY THE DISPERSAL UNIT, OR THE FRUIT
CAN REMAIN FUSED
AROUND THE, OR IT CAN REMAIN, IT DOESN'T ACTUALLY
OPEN BY SOME
SORT OF SUTURE AND SURROUNDS THE SEEDS IN
WHICH CASE THE WHOLE
FRUIT IS TYPICALLY THE DISPERSAL UNIT ALONG
WITH THE SEEDS. SO
ANOTHER TYPE OF FRUIT THEN IS AN AGGREGATE
FRUIT, THE SECOND OF
THESE THREE MAJOR TYPES THAT YOUR BOOK DESCRIBES.
AND AN
AGGREGATE FRUIT IS SOMETHING LIKE A RASPBERRY
OR A BLACKBERRY
THAT IS A FRUIT DERIVED FROM MORE THAN ONE
SEPARATE CARPEL OF ONE
FLOWER. SO SEPARATE PISTILS, EACH FROM ONE
CARPEL YOU CAN SEE
ARE THESE LITTLE, EACH ONE OF THESE LITTLE
FRUITLETS THAT MAKES
UP A RASPBERRY OR BLACKBERRY IS AN INDIVIDUAL
PISTIL FROM ONE
CARPEL THAT ARE, THEY'RE SEPARATE BUT THEY'RE
STILL BASICALLY
PART OF A COMMON DISPERSAL UNIT HERE. THE
WHOLE, THE WHOLE
AGGREGATE FRUIT IS REMOVED AS A UNIT TYPICALLY,
BY AN ANIMAL AND
DISPERSED. SO THAT'S ONE, ANOTHER TYPE OF,
OF FRUIT THAT'S
STILL IS FROM A SINGLE FLOWER BUT FROM MULTIPLE
PISTILS. AND
ANOTHER TYPE OF FRUIT IS A MULTIPLE FRUIT.
AND A MULTIPLE FRUIT
IS A FRUIT DERIVED FROM MULTIPLE FLOWERS.
AND THIS IS A CASE IN
THE PINEAPPLE WHERE YOU HAVE CLEARLY DISTINCT
FLOWERS INITIALLY.
I MEAN THEY'RE OBVIOUSLY DISTINCT AT THIS
POINT IN THEIR, IN
THEIR DEVELOPMENT. AND THEN AFTER, AFTER WE'VE
HAD
FERTILIZATION AND SEED DEVELOPMENT, THE FRUIT'S
DEVELOPING HERE.
AND EVENTUALLY ALL OF THESE FLOWERS COALESCE
TOGETHER INTO ONE
BIG DISPERSAL UNIT, ONE LARGE PINEAPPLE WHERE
EACH OF THE LITTLE
SEGMENTS THAT YOU SEE, THOSE LITTLE WALLED-OFF
UNITS IN THE
PINEAPPLE REPRESENT INDIVIDUAL FLOWERS OF
A COMMON INFLORESCENCE
OF AN ENTIRE ARRAY, A COMPACT ARRAY OF FLOWERS.
ANOTHER GREAT
EXAMPLE OF THIS KIND OF FLOWER OR THIS KIND
OF FRUIT IS A
MULBERRY WHICH LOOKS A LOT SUPERFICIALLY LIKE
SOMETHING LIKE A
RASPBERRY BUT IT'S ACTUALLY MULTIPLE FLOWERS
THAT MAKE UP THAT,
THAT STRUCTURE. AND HERE AGAIN, THE SIMPLE
FRUIT, THE AGGREGATE
FRUIT, THE MULTIPLE FRUIT. FRUITS CAN BE EITHER
DRY, THEY DON'T
HAVE TO BE FLESHY. FRUITS CAN BE DRY ALTOGETHER.
LIKE A PEAPOD
AT MATURITY, IT DRIES OUT, SPLITS OPEN, AND
RELEASES THE SEEDS.
THOUGH FRUIT IS JUST A MATURE OVARY. IT DOESN'T
NECESSARILY HAVE
TO BE THE DISPERSAL UNIT BUT IT OFTEN IS.
AND EVEN IF IT IS, IF
IT IS THE DISPERSAL UNIT, IT CAN BE DRY OR
FLESHY, AS WE'LL LOOK
AT HERE IN A MINUTE. ONE LAST TYPE OF FRUIT
TO MENTION IS THIS
ACCESSORY FRUIT. AND THIS IS KIND OF A COOL
THING TO THINK ABOUT
BECAUSE IN ACCESSORY FRUITS, THE RIPENED OVARY
IS PART OF THE
FRUIT BUT IT'S NOT THE FLESHY PART. THERE'S
ANOTHER FLESHY PART
THAT'S DERIVED FROM OTHER PARTS OF EITHER
THE FLOWER OR THE
INFLORESCENCE. AND THERE ARE ACCESSORY FRUITS
THAT FALL IN THE
CATEGORY OF SIMPLE, AGGREGATE, AND MULTIPLE.
SO THIS IS A, SO
SIMPLE AGG-, SIMPLE, AGGREGATE, AND MULTIPLE
FRUITS CAN ALSO BE
ACCESSORY FRUITS WHEREAS I MENTIONED THE FRUIT
HAS FLESHY PARTS
THAT ARE DERIVED FROM, LARGELY FROM TISSUES
OTHER THAN THE OVARY.
AND AN APPLE'S A GREAT EXAMPLE OF THIS. SO
HERE'S THE STALK OF
THE APPLE FLOWER, WHERE THE FLOWER WAS ATTACHED.
AND HERE'S
WHAT'S LEFT OF THE, OF THE SEPALS, THE STAMENS,
AND THE, THE
STYLES OF AN APPLE. AND YOU'VE KNOW DOUBT
SEEN THOSE AT THE
SUMMIT OF AN APPLE. SO THE OVARY IS RIGHT
HERE. THE OVARY IS
THE CORE OF THE APPLE, THE PAPERY PART THAT
YOU GENERALLY DON'T
EAT BUT THROW ASIDE. AND THE, THE REALLY JUICY
CHOICE PART OF
THE APPLE, THIS OUTER PART IS ACCESSORY TISSUE.
IT'S ACTUALLY
THE FLORAL TUBE FORMED FROM THE BASIS OF THE
SEPALS, PETALS, AND
STAMENS THAT HAVE FUSED TOGETHER AND FUSED
AROUND THE OVARY. SO
THE OVARY IS INFERIOR LIKE WE MENTIONED BEFORE.
IT'S PROTECTED
BY THIS TISSUE. AND DISPERSAL AGENT COMING
AND GRABBING AN
APPLE OR EATING AN APPLE IS PROBABLY GOING
TO BE CONSUMING MOSTLY
THIS EXTERNAL PART AND LEAVING THE CORE AND
THE SEEDS. THOUGH
THE ACCESSORY TISSUE'S IMPORTANT IN DISPERSAL
AND IT'S NOT PART
OF THE OVARY. THE OVARY CAN BE SPARED FROM
BEING EATEN AND THE
SEEDS AS WELL, BUT IT CAN GET MOVED AWAY FROM
THE PARENT PLANT.
THE STRAWBERRY'S ANOTHER TYPE OF ACCESSORY
FRUIT THAT'S AN
AGGREGATE. AND THE LITTLE GRAINY INCLUSIONS
ON THE OUTSIDE OF A
STRAWBERRY, THOSE ARE THE OVARIES. SO THE
OVARIES ARE LITTLE DRY
INDEHISCENT FRUITS THAT WE CALL ACHENES. THE
TERM'S NOT
IMPORTANT, BUT THEY'RE NOT ACTUALLY, THEY
DON'T OPEN AT MATURITY.
THEY CONTAIN A SINGLE SEED EACH. AND THE ACTUAL
FLESHY PART OF
A STRAWBERRY IS THE RECEPTACLE OF THE FLOWER,
WHICH IS BASICALLY
THE PODIUM ON WHICH THE OTHER PARTS OF THE
FLOWER ARE BORNE.
AND IT'S USUALLY NOT AN ENLARGED STRUCTURE.
IT'S PRETTY
INSIGNIFICANT. WE DIDN'T EVEN TALK ABOUT IT
BEFORE. IT'S JUST
THE TIP OF THE STEM THAT THE FLOWER'S BORNE
ON, BUT IT BECOMES
THE FLESHY PART OF THE FRUIT THAT'S THE ATTRACTANT
FOR ANIMAL
DISPERSAL HERE. AND HERE YOU CAN SEE THE SEPALS.
AND IN A FIG,
THE FLESHY PART OF THE FRUIT IS BASICALLY
THE WHOLE
INFLORESCENCE. THE FIG INFLORESCENCE IS LIKE
AN INFLORESCENCE
TURNED INSIDE OUT. AND THE, ALL THE FLESHY
JUICY PART IS MOSTLY
NON-FLORAL TISSUE. SO IT'S THE WHOLE INFLORESCENCE.
THOUGH
THERE'S A LOT OF INNOVATION AND DIVERSITY
IN FRUIT MORPHOLOGY.
AND IN DIFFERENT GROUP OF PLANTS THEY'VE GONE
IN FOR VERY
DIFFERENT KINDS OF WAYS OF ATTRACTING POLLINATORS
AND DISPERSING
THEIR, THEIR SEEDS VIA DIFFERENT FRUIT INNOVATIONS.
AND SOME OF
THESE ARE SHOWN HERE. NOW THIS IS DISPERSAL
BY WIND AND WATER.
SO NON-ANIMAL DISPERSAL. AND THERE'S A REALLY
WIDE RANGE OF
ADAPTATIONS TO NON-ANIMAL DISPERSAL, TO WIND
AND WATER DISPERSAL,
OR ABIOTIC DISPERSAL IN ANGIOSPERMS. AND SOME
OF THESE ARE LIKE
IN GYMNOSPERMS WHERE THE FRUIT OPENS UP AT
MATURITY AND RELEASES
THE SEEDS, AND THE SEEDS MIGHT BE WINGED OR
HAVE A TUFT OF HAIR
ON THEM THAT MAKES THEM DISPERSABLE BY WIND
FOR EXAMPLE, LIKE
THIS WINGED GOURD SEED HERE. SO SIMILAR TO
SAY A PINE SEED.
WHERE THE SEED'S THE DISPERSAL UNIT. BUT IN
OTHER CASES THE
FRUIT IS DISPERSED IN THE WIND. FOR EXAMPLE,
IN A MAPLE, THERE
ARE WINGS ON THE FRUIT, THIS KIND OF FRUIT
WE CALL SAMARA THAT
BLOWS IN THE WIND. AND IN SOMETHING LIKE A
DANDELION, YOU'VE NO
DOUBT SEEN THE FRUITS. THE FRUITS ARE ACTUALLY
DRY, INDEHISCENT
STRUCTURES THAT ARE ATTACHED TO THE SEPALS
WHICH ARE PERSISTENT,
AND THE SEPALS BECOME PARACHUTE-LIKE AND CARRY
THE FRUIT ALONG IN
THE WIND, VERY BUOYANT. AND IN SOME PLANTS
THE ENTIRE PLANT IS
THE, IS A WIND DISPERSAL UNIT LIKE THE TUMBLEWEED
WHERE IT BREAKS
OFF AT THE BASE AT MATURITY AFTER IT DRIES
OUT. THE OUTLINE OF
THE WHOLE PLANT IS SPHERICAL, AND IT JUST
BLOWS IN THE WIND
CARRYING ALL THE FRUITS WITH IT. SO THERE
ARE DIFFERENT UNITS
OF DISPERSAL FROM THE SMALLEST UNIT, THE SEED,
TO THE ENTIRE
PLANT. CACTI ARE ANOTHER EXAMPLE WHERE ENTIRE
STEMS CAN BE
DISPERSED BY IMPALING AN ANIMAL'S LEG WITH
THE SPINES OF THE
CACTUS AND CARRYING THE FRUIT ALONG WITH IT
LIKE IN THE SO-CALLED
JUMPING CHOLLA DOWN IN OUR DESERTS HERE WHICH
ARE PRETTY
DANGEROUS TO WALK AROUND FOR THAT REASON.
AND ALSO YOU CAN GET
DISPERSAL BY WATER. A LOT OF DIFFERENT TROPICAL,
ESPECIALLY
PLANTS, A LOT OF OUR ISLAND PLANTS IF YOU
GO TO THE HAWAIIAN
ISLANDS OR TAHITI, SOME OF THE TROPICAL ISLANDS,
RIGHT ALONG THE
EDGE OF THE WATER YOU'LL FIND A LOT OF PLANTS
THAT HAVE DISPERSAL
ADAPTATIONS TO WATER, WHICH HAVE BUOYANT FRUITS
LIKE THE COCONUT.
AND THESE FRUITS HAVE HARD SEED LAYERS OR
FRUIT LAYERS THAT
PREVENT THE, THE SEED FROM BEING PENETRATED
BY SALT WATER UNTIL
AFTER DISPERSAL. SO THIS IS ANOTHER WAY IN
WHICH PLANTS CAN GET
AROUND. THOUGH AS I MENTIONED HERE, YOU KNOW
JUST AS FLOWERS
HAVE EVOLVED IN RESPONSE TO POLLINATORS, FRUITS
HAVE EVOLVED IN
RESPONSE TO DISPERSAL AGENTS. AND SO WE HAVE
THESE, ALL OF
THESE DISPERSAL, ALL OF THESE MECHANISMS FOR
DISPERSING POLLEN IN
POLLINATION, WE HAVE ALL THESE MECHANISMS
FOR DISPERSING SEEDS
WITH, THAT INVOLVE, OFTEN INVOLVE FRUIT. SO
THESE ARE VARIOUS
IMPORTANT INNOVATIONS OF ANGIOSPERMS. AND
AS FAR AS ANIMAL
DISPERSAL GOES, THERE'S A REALLY WIDE DIVERSITY
HERE AS WELL.
SOME DRY FRUITS ARE ANIMAL DISPERSED EITHER
INTENTIONALLY LIKE
ACORNS WHICH CAN BEING PICKED UP BY SQUIRRELS
OR BLUEJAYS AND
CARRIED SOME DISTANCE AND CACHED. AND THEN
SOME PROPORTION OF
THOSE ARE FORGOTTEN ABOUT AND THEY END UP
GERMINATING. SOME ARE
CARRIED LONG DISTANCES. JAYS CAN FLY BETWEEN
MOUNTAIN RANGES
WITH ACORNS IN THEIR, DOWN, CARRIED INSIDE
AND REGURGITATED WHEN
THEY GET TO A NEW AREA. SOME ARE INADVERTENT
LIKE BARBED FRUITS.
AND SOME OF THESE ARE RELATIVELY PAINLESS
IN TERMS OF JUST HAVING
SAY HOOK PRICKLES OR SOMETHING THAT ATTACHES
OR STICKY EXUDATES
THAT ATTACHED TO THE OUTSIDE OF FUR OR FEATHERS
AND ARE CARRIED
FROM ONE PLACE TO ANOTHER INADVERTENTLY. BUT
OTHERS ARE MORE
INSIDIOUS. THE PUNCTURE VINE HAS FRUITS THAT
ACTUALLY WILL
PUNTURE THE FEET OF ANIMALS, INCLUDING PEOPLE
IF YOU'RE WALKING
AROUND BAREFOOT IN THE DESERT, AND REALLY
NASTY THINGS THAT YOU
HAVE TO TAKE SOME EFFORT TO GET OUT AND PRESUMABLY
CARRIED SOME
DISTANCE SOMETIMES BEFORE THEY'RE REMOVED.
SOMETIMES AGAIN THE
SEED IS THE DISPERSAL UNIT. AND LIKE IN THE
GOURD I SHOWED YOU
THAT ARE, THAT'S WIND DISPERSED, SOMETIMES
THE SEED HAS SOME
INTERESTING INNOVATIONS TO PROMOTE DISPERSAL
THAT WE DON'T SEE IN
GYMNOSPERMS, FOR EXAMPLE, LIKE THIS LITTLE
FLESHY ATTACHMENT TO
THE SEED HERE. THE TERM'S AN ELAIOSOME. YOU
DON'T HAVE TO
KNOW THAT, BUT IT'S A LITTLE EDIBLE BODY,
HIGH IN OIL OR PROTEIN
THAT'S ATTACHED TO THE SEED AND MAKES THEM
ATTRACTIVE TO ANTS
WHICH'LL CARRY THEM ACTIVELY TO THEIR NEST
SOME DISTANCE AWAY
FROM THE PARENT PLANT. THEY'LL CACHE THESE
SEEDS DOWN IN THEIR
NEST. THEY'LL EAT THE, THE FOOD BODY. AND
THEN THEY'LL DISCARD
THE, THE SEED OR THE SEED WILL REMAIN IN THE
NEST AND EVENTUALLY
GERMINATE. SO THERE ARE SOME, THIS HAS EVOLVED
MULTIPLE TIMES IN
DIFFERENT GROUPS OF PLANTS. AND THEN, OF COURSE,
THERE ARE
FLESHY FRUITS THAT ARE, OR OTHER, OR EVEN
DRIED FRUITS THAT ARE
EATEN DIRECTLY. AND THE FRUIT MAY BE DIGESTED,
BUT THE SEED
ISN'T. IN FACT, THE SEED CAN BE STIMULATED
TO GERMINATE BY THE
CHEMISTRY OF THE GUT AND THEN ENDS UP IN SOME
FERTILIZER AT THE
END OF THE PROCESS AND GERMINATES FROM THAT.
SO LOTS OF GREAT
DISPERSAL ADAPTATIONS. AND JUST ONE FINAL
NOTE ABOUT FRUIT IS
THAT, YOU KNOW WE PROBABLY ALL THINK WE KNOW
WHAT FRUIT IS AND
WHAT VEGETABLES ARE, BUT THESE ARE ALL CLASSIFIED
BY U.S. LAW AS
VEGETABLES. AND YOU CAN SEE SOME THINGS IN
HERE THAT ARE
CLEARLY FRUITS, TOMATOES, FOR EXAMPLE, PEPPERS.
THESE ARE
RIPENED OVARIES THAT CONTAIN SEEDS AS YOU'RE
ALL AWARE. BUT
THEY'RE OFFICIALLY CONSIDERED VEGETABLES BECAUSE
THEY HAVE
SAVOURY RATHER THAN SWEET FLAVOR. AND ACTUALLY
THERE WAS A CASE
THAT WAS TAKEN TO THE SUPREME COURT YEARS
AGO BY AN IMPORTER WHO
WAS BRINGING IN TOMATOES FROM OUTSIDE THE
COUNTRY. AND THERE WAS
A TARIFF ON VEGETABLES AT THE TIME BUT NOT
ON FRUIT. AND SO HE
ARGUED THAT, YOU KNOW, I'M JUST BRINGING FRUIT
IN. I'M NOT
BRINGING IN VEGETABLES. I DON'T HAVE TO PAY
THIS TARIFF. AND
IT WENT ALL THE WAY TO THE SUPREME COURT.
AND THE SUPREME COURT
RULED THAT YES, WE AGREE THAT BOTANICALLY
THE TOMATO IS A FRUIT,
BUT WE RULE IT OFFICIALLY BY U.S. LAW TO BE
A VEGETABLE.
[LAUGHTER] SO, SO THE SUPREME COURT HAD THE
LAST WORD ON IT EVEN
THOUGH, YOU KNOW, THE BOTANISTS HAD TO TAKE
SECOND PLACE THERE.
BUT BOTANICALLY SPEAKING FROM THIS COURSE'S
PERSPECTIVE AT LEAST,
WE'RE GOING TO CONSIDER IT A FRUIT. ALL RIGHT,
SO ANGIOSPERM
DIVERSITY AS I MENTIONED, HUGE ALL OVER THE
WORLD. WE'RE STILL
TRYING TO UNDERSTAND HOW MUCH DIVERSITY'S
OUT THERE AND HOW IT'S
RELATED, HOW THESE DIFFERENT ANGIOSPERMS ARE
RELATED TO ONE
ANOTHER. AND AS I MENTIONED, HOW ANGIOSPERMS
ARE RELATED TO
OTHER SEED PLANTS, GYMNOSPERMS, IS SOMETHING
THAT WE HAVEN'T
FIGURED OUT. FOR AWHILE WE THOUGHT WE HAD.
IN FACT, LIKE TEN
YEARS AGO WHEN I WAS TEACHING MY UPPER DIVERSION
SYSTEMATICS
COURSE, IT WAS DOGMA THAT THE ANGIOSPERMS
WERE THE CLOSEST
RELATIVES OF THE GNETOPHYTES, THOSE THINGS
LIKE THE PLATYPUS OF
THE PLANT KINGDOM THAT I SHOWED YOU. THE WELWITSCHIA,
OR THE
EPHEDRA THAT PRODUCES THAT STIMULANT EPHEDRIN.
BUT NOW IT'S
CLEAR THAT THOSE ARE ACTUALLY MORE CLOSELY
RELATED TO CONIFERS
THAN ANYTHING ELSE. THE GNETOPHYTES AND THE
CONIFERS ARE
CLOSELY RELATED. AND WE'RE NOT SURE WHAT THE
CLOSEST RELATIVES
OF THE ANGIOSPERMS ARE, BUT WE DO HAVE A BETTER
IDEA ABOUT
RELATIONSHIPS AMONG THE MAJOR GROUPS OF ANGIOSPERMS.
AND FROM
HIGH SCHOOL BIOLOGY IF YOU HAD ANY MENTION
OF FLOWERING PLANTS
THERE, YOU PROBABLY HEARD ABOUT DICOTS VERSUS
MONOCOTS, THESE TWO
MAJOR GROUPS OF FLOWERING PLANTS. WELL, IT
TURNS OUT THAT'S
SORT OF AN ARTIFICIAL DISTINCTION. ITS TRADITIONAL
DISTINCTION'S SIMPLISTIC. AND THE MONOCOTS
ARE A GOOD
MONOPHYLETIC GROUP. AND WE'LL GET TO THEIR
FEATURES IN A
MOMENT. BUT THAT INCLUDES ABOUT A QUARTER
OF ALL FLOWERING
PLANTS. SO THAT'S A HUGE DIVERSITY OF FLOWERING
PLANTS THERE.
IT INCLUDES THE GRASSES AND GRAINS. THE DICOTS
THOUGH ARE ALL
THESE YELLOW LINEAGES, AND SO THEY'RE NOT
A MONOPHYLETIC GROUP.
THEY'RE A PARAPHYLETIC GRADE. AND IT LOOKS
LIKE THE PRESENCE OF
TWO COTYLEDONOUS OR EMBRYONIC LEAVES IS ANCESTRAL
FOR FLOWERING
PLANTS. AND IT'S NOT A DERIVED FEATURE THAT
DIAGNOSES A
MONOPHYLETIC GROUP. BUT THERE IS ONE GROUP
CALLED THE EUDICOTS
THAT CONTAINS ABOUT TWO-THIRDS OF ALL ANGIOSPERM
DIVERSITY,
TWO-THIRDS OF THE RECOGNIZED SPECIES. AND
REMEMBER EU MEANS
TRUE, THESE ARE THE TRUE DICOTS AS THEY'RE
SO-CALLED NOW EVEN
THOUGH THESE OTHER LINEAGES DO HAVE TWO COTYLEDONS.
AND THEY'RE
A NICE MONOPHYLETIC GROUP. TOGETHER WITH THE
MONOCOTS THEY MAKE
UP THE VAST MAJORITY OF ALL THE FLOWERING
PLANTS. THESE OLDEST
LIVING LINEAGES HERE, WHICH YOU NO DOUBT,
WELL, YOU MAY HAVE SEEN
WATER LILIES WHICH ARE AMONG SOME OF THE EARLY
DIVERGING
LINEAGES, BUT THE OTHERS ARE OBSCURE, MOSTLY
SOUTHERN TEMPERATE,
SOUTHERN TEMPERATE GROUPS IN THE SOUTHERN
HEMISPHERE. THAT'S
ONLY ABOUT A HUNDRED SPECIES TOTAL THERE.
AND THE MAGNOLIAS AND
RELATIVES, THAT'S ABOUT 8,000 SPECIES. BUT
THE BULK OF THE
300,000 OR SO SPECIES ARE OVER HERE. AND WE'RE
GOING TO FOCUS ON
THESE FOR THE REST OF THE COURSE. ANY QUESTIONS
ABOUT THAT?
THAT'S JUST SORT OF A GENERAL OVERVIEW. JUST
WANT TO MAKE IT
CLEAR THAT THE, WHY WE'RE CALLING THEM EUDICOTS
RATHER THAN
DICOTS AS A WHOLE BECAUSE THIS IS THE NATURAL
GROUP OF DICOTS
THAT MAKES UP MOST OF THEM. SO THESE ARE SOME
OF THE FEATURES
SHARED BY MOST MONOCOTS AND SHARED BY MOST
DICOTS. AND IN SOME
CASES THE FEATURE IS DERIVED IN THE MONOCOTS
AND SOME CASES, OR
SOME CASES THE FEATURES THAT DISTINGUISH THEM,
IN ONE, ONE OF
THEM'S DERIVED AND ONE OF THEM IS ANCESTRAL
BASICALLY HERE IN
MOST OF THESE COMPARISONS. THOUGH MONOCOTS
HAVE ONE
COTYLEDONOUS LEAF, AND WE'LL TALK ABOUT THAT
MORE WHEN WE TALK
ABOUT GERMINATION. AND THAT'S A GOOD FEATURE
THAT WE FIND ACROSS
THE GROUP. ONE EMBRYONIC LEAF IS PRODUCED
IN MONOCOTS WHEREAS
IN EUDICOTS LIKE IN OTHER DICOTS THERE ARE
TWO COTYLEDONOUS
LEAVES THAT WE'LL LOOK AT HERE AGAIN IN MORE
DETAIL IN A MINUTE.
AS FAR, THIS ISN'T VERY HELPFUL THOUGH BECAUSE
THE COTYLEDONS ARE
LOST EARLY IN DEVELOPMENT. THEY'RE JUST EMBRYONIC
LEAVES THAT
DON'T PERSIST VERY LONG. IN TERMS OF IDENTIFICATION
IT'S NOT A
VERY HELPFUL FEATURE EVEN THOUGH IT'S CONSISTENT.
LEAF
VENATION'S A GOOD FEATURE. MONOCOTS HAVE THIS
DERIVED FEATURE OF
HAVING THEIR, THEIR VEINS, THE VASCULATURE
OF THEIR LEAVES IN A
PARALLEL ORIENTATION OR SEMI-PARALLEL, AS
YOU CAN SEE, FOR
EXAMPLE, IN A GRASS LEAF. WHEREAS THE VEINS
OF A EUDICOT ARE
OFTEN NET-LIKE, SORT OF A RETICULUM OR WEB
OF VENATION DIVERGING
IN DIFFERENT ANGLES WHICH IS NOT, IS ACTUALLY
AN ANCESTRAL
FEATURE SHARED WITH EARLIER ANGIOSPERMS. IF
YOU CUT OPEN THE
STEM, IF YOU DO A CROSS-SECTION OF THE STEM
-- AND WE'RE GOING TO
GET INTO THIS A LOT MORE, SO I'M JUST GOING
TO BRUSH OVER IT NOW
-THE VASCULAR OR CONDUCTING TISSUE IN A MONOCOT
STEM, VASCULAR
TISSUE IN GENERAL IS IN LITTLE BUNDLES. THESE
LITTLE BUNDLES
HERE INSIDE THE STEMS OF FLOWERING PLANTS
DURING PRIMARY GROWTH.
WE'LL TALK MORE ABOUT THAT LATER. BUT IT'S
SCATTERED AROUND
INSIDE THE STEMS OF MONOCOTS WHEREAS IN EUDICOTS,
THE BUNDLES ARE
ARRANGED IN A RING LIKE THAT GENERALLY SPEAKING.
AND WE'LL TALK
MORE ABOUT THAT LATER. BUT THAT'S SOMETHING
THAT YOU CAN USE TO
DISTINGUISH MONOCOTS AND DICOTS, EUDICOTS.
AND AS FAR AS ROOTS
GO, THEY'RE VERY DIFFERENT. AND THIS IS IMPORTANT.
IN
EUDICOTS, THE EMBRYONIC ROOT ACTUALLY CONTINUES
TO DEVELOP AS A
TAPROOT, THE MAIN ROOT, AND THAN LATERAL ROOTS
ARE PRODUCED FROM
THAT. WHEREAS IN MONOCOTS, THE TAPROOT DOESN'T
PERSIST VERY
LONG. THE EMBRYONIC ROOT GROWS FOR AWHILE.
AND THEN YOU START
GETTING ADVENTITIOUS ROOTS. AN ADVENTITIOUS
ANYTHING IS JUST
SOMETHING THAT ORIGINATES FROM A POINT OTHER
THAN ITS USUAL
ORIGIN. SO ADVENTITIOUS ROOTS FORM FROM THE
BASE OF STEMS. SO
THE BASE OF THE STEM STARTS PRODUCING ROOTS.
AND THE TAPROOT
DOESN'T CONTINUE TO DEVELOP. AND WE END UP
WITH A FIBROUS ROOT
SYSTEM THAT'S OFTEN QUITE SHALLOW LIKE IN
GRASSES, A TURF ROOT
SYSTEM, WHEREAS IN THE CASE OF EUDICOTS YOU
OFTEN GET, OFTEN GET
A DEEP TAPROOT. OKAY, AND WE'LL HAVE TO COMPLETE
THE REST OF
THIS NEXT TIME. AND WE'LL GET INTO GERMINATION
AND DEVELOPMENT
RIGHT AWAY.