at least a deacon. (Laughter.) I was hearing
-- "Welll" -- (Laughter.) He was starting
to get the spirit up here. I'm going to take
Juan on the road to introduce me everywhere.
(Laughter.) Can I hear an "amen"?
AUDIENCE: Amen!
THE PRESIDENT: Amen.
I want to thank Mark Hernandez, Ricky McDowell
-- (applause) -- and Martin Daum for hosting
us and being such great tour guides. Thank
you so much, everybody. Give them a big round
of applause. (Applause.)
We've got a few outstanding North Carolinians
in the house. You've got your Governor, Bev
Perdue, is here. (Applause.) Your mayors,
Bryan Hough and Anthony Foxx are here. (Applause.)
Two outstanding Congressmen, Mel Watt and
Heath Shuler are here. (Applause.) Thank you
all for being here.
It is good to be in North Carolina. Anthony
Foxx pointed out that I decided to wear a
tie that could be a Tar Heel -- (applause)
-- but it's got a little Duke color in there,
too.
AUDIENCE: Booo --
THE PRESIDENT: I didn’t want to get in trouble
with anybody, so I was hedging my bets. (Laughter.)
I always tell people I am one of the best
advertisers for North Carolina. I love this
state. (Applause.) Love this state. Everybody
here is so nice, so welcoming. Even the folks
who don't vote for me, they're nice to me.
They usually wave five fingers. (Laughter.)
So it's just a great pleasure.
And I just had a chance to see some of the
folks who are doing the work here today. I
couldn't be more impressed. Some people have
been here -- like Juan -- 32 years, 25 years.
Some folks have been here for four months,
or six months, have just gotten hired. But
everybody had such pride in their work.
And the Freighterline trucks that you’re
making here at this plant run on natural gas,
and that makes them quieter, it makes them
better for the environment, it makes them
cheaper to fill up than they would be with
diesel. I hear you sold your 1,000th natural
gas truck last November -– (applause) -- the
first company to reach that milestone. And
it was made right here in Mount Holly. (Applause.)
And last year, this plant added more than
1,000 workers, hiring back a lot of folks
who were laid off during the recession. (Applause.)
That is something to be proud of.
Now, here at Daimler, you're not just building
trucks. You're building better trucks.
AUDIENCE: That’s right.
THE PRESIDENT: You're building trucks that
use less oil. And you know that’s especially
important right now because most of you have
probably filled up your gas tank a time or
two in the last week, and you've seen how
quickly the price of gas is going up. A lot
of you may have to drive a distance to work.
Higher gas prices are like a tax straight
out of your paycheck.
And for companies that operate a whole fleet
of trucks, the higher costs can make a big
difference in terms of the profitability of
the company.
Now, here's the thing, though -- this is not
the first time we've seen gas prices spike.
It's been happening for years. Every year,
about this time, gas starts spiking up, and
everybody starts wondering, how high is it
going to go? And every year, politicians start
talking when gas prices go up. They get out
on the campaign trail -- and you and I both
know there are no quick fixes to this problem
-- but listening to them, you'd think there
were.
As a country that has 2 percent of the world's
oil reserves, but uses 20 percent of the world's
oil -- I'm going to repeat that -- we've got
2 percent of the world oil reserves; we use
20 percent. What that means is, as much as
we're doing to increase oil production, we're
not going to be able to just drill our way
out of the problem of high gas prices. Anybody
who tells you otherwise either doesn’t know
what they’re talking about or they aren’t
telling you the truth.
Here is the truth. If we are going to control
our energy future, then we’ve got to have
an all-of-the-above strategy. We’ve got
to develop every source of American energy
-- not just oil and gas, but wind power and
solar power, nuclear power, biofuels. We need
to invest in the technology that will help
us use less oil in our cars and our trucks,
in our buildings, in our factories. That’s
the only solution to the challenge. Because
as we start using less, that lowers the demand,
prices come down. It's pretty straightforward.
That’s the only solution to this challenge.
And that’s the strategy that we’ve now
been pursuing for the last three years. And
I’m proud to say we’ve made progress.
Since I took office, America’s dependence
on foreign oil has gone down every single
year. In fact, in 2010, it went under 50 percent
for the first time in 13 years.
You wouldn’t know it from listening to some
of these folks out here -- (laughter) -- some
of these folks -- (laughter) -- but a key
part of our energy strategy has been to increase
safe, responsible oil production here at home.
Under my administration, America is producing
more oil today than any time in the last eight
years. Under my administration, we’ve quadrupled
the number of operating oilrigs to a record
high. We’ve got more oilrigs operating now
than we’ve ever seen. We’ve opened up
millions of new acres for oil and gas exploration.
We’ve approved more than 400 drilling permits
that follow new safety standards after we
had that mess down in the Gulf.
We’re approving dozens of new pipelines.
We just announced that we’ll do whatever
we can to speed up construction of a pipeline
in Oklahoma that’s going to relieve a bottleneck
and get more oil to the Gulf -- to the refineries
down there -- and that’s going to help create
jobs, encourage more production.
So these are the facts on oil production.
If somebody tells you we’re not producing
enough oil, they just don’t know the facts.
But how much oil we produce here at home,
because we only have 2 percent and we use
20, that’s not going to set the price of
gas worldwide, or here in the United States.
Oil is bought and sold on the world market.
And the biggest thing that’s causing the
price of oil to rise right now is instability
in the Middle East. You guys have been hearing
about what’s happening with Iran; there
are other oil producers that are having problems.
And so people have gotten uncertain. And when
uncertainty increases, then sometimes you
see speculation on Wall Street that drives
up gas prices even more.
But here's the thing. Over the long term,
the biggest reason oil prices will go up is
there's just growing demand in countries like
China and India and Brazil. There are a lot
of people there. In 2010 alone, China added
nearly 10 million cars on its roads. Think
about that -- 2010, 10 million new cars. People
in China, folks in India, folks in Brazil
-- they're going to want cars, too, as their
standard of living goes up, and that means
more demand for oil, and that's going to kick
up the price of oil worldwide. Those numbers
are only going to get bigger over time.
So what does that mean for us? It means we
can't just keep on relying on the old ways
of doing business. We can't just rely on fossil
fuels from the last century. We've got to
continually develop new sources of energy.
And that’s why we've made investments that
have nearly doubled the use of clean, renewable
energies in this country. And thousands of
Americans have jobs because of it. It also
means we’ve got to develop the resources
that we have that are untapped, like natural
gas. We're developing a near hundred-year
supply of natural gas -– and that's something
that we expect could support more than 600,000
jobs by the end of the decade.
And that’s why we've worked with the private
sector to develop a high-tech car battery
that costs half as much as other batteries
and can go up to 300 miles on a single charge.
Think about that. That will save you some
money at the pump. And that is why we are
helping companies like this one right here
and plants like this one right here to make
more cars and trucks that use less oil.
When I ran for office, I went to Detroit and
I gave a speech to automakers where I promised
that I was going to raise fuel standards on
our cars, so that they’d go further on a
gallon of gas. I said we should do the same
thing on trucks. I have to tell you, when
I said it, I didn't get a lot of applause
in the room, because there was a time when
automakers were resisting higher fuel standards
-- because change isn't easy. But you know
what, after three decades of not doing anything,
we got together with the oil companies, we
got together with the unions, we got together
with folks who usually do not see eye to eye,
and we negotiated new fuel economy standards
that are going to make sure our cars average
nearly 55 miles per gallon by the middle of
the next decade. That's nearly double what
they get today -- nearly double. (Applause.)
Now, because of these new standards for cars
and trucks, they're going to -- all going
to be able to go further and use less fuel
every year. And that means pretty soon you’ll
be able to fill up your car every two weeks
instead of every week -– and, over time,
that saves you, a typical family, about $8,000
a year.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: We like that.
THE PRESIDENT: You like that, don't you?
AUDIENCE: Yes! (Applause.)
THE PRESIDENT: Eight thousand dollars -- that's
no joke. We can reduce our oil consumption
by more than 12 billion barrels. And thanks
to the SuperTruck program that we’ve started
with companies like this one, trucks will
be able to save more than $15,000 in fuel
costs every year. Think about that, $15,000.
It looks like somebody might have fainted
up here. Have we got some of the EMS, somebody.
Don’t worry about -- folks do this all the
time in my meetings. (Laughter.) You’ve
always got to eat before you stand for a long
time. That’s a little tip. But they'll be
okay. Just make sure that -- give them a little
room. All right, everybody all right? Okay.
So these trucks can save $15,000 every year.
I want people to think about what that means
for businesses, what it means for consumers.
It is real progress. And it's happening because
of American workers and American know-how.
It's happening because of you. It's happening
because of you.
We’re also making it easier for big companies
-- some of your customers, like UPS and FedEx
-- to make the shift to fuel-efficient cars
and trucks. We call it the National Clean
Fleets Partnership. And since we announced
it last year, the number of companies that
are taking part in it has tripled. And that
means more customers for your trucks. (Applause.)
We're creating more customers for your trucks.
And I am proud to say that the federal government
is leading by example. One thing the federal
government has a lot of is cars and trucks.
We got a lot of cars and we got a lot of trucks.
And so what I did was I directed every department,
every agency in the federal government, to
make sure that by 2015, 100 percent of the
vehicles we buy run on alternative fuels -- 100
percent. (Applause.)
So we’re one of the biggest customers in
the world for cars and trucks and we want
to set that bar high. We want to set a standard
that says by 2015, 100 percent of cars, alternative
fuels.
So we’re making progress, Mount Holly. But
at the end of the day, it doesn’t matter
how much natural gas, or flex-fuel or electric
vehicles you have if there’s no place to
charge them up or fill them up. So that’s
why I’m announcing today a program that
will put our communities on the cutting edge
of what clean energy can do.
To cities and towns all across the country,
what we’re going to say is, if you make
a commitment to buy more advanced vehicles
for your community -- whether they run on
electricity or biofuels or natural gas -- we’ll
help you cut through the red tape and build
fueling stations nearby. (Applause.) And we’ll
offer tax breaks to families that buy these
cars, companies that buy alternative fuel
trucks like the ones that are made right here
at Mount Holly. (Applause.) So we’re going
to give communities across the country more
of an incentive to make the shift to more
energy-efficient cars.
In fact, when I was up in New Hampshire, in
Nashua, they had already converted all their
dump trucks -- they were in a process because
of this program -- they were converting it
to natural gas-driven trucks.
This is something that we did in education
-- we called it Race to the Top. We said we’ll
put in more money but we want you to reform.
We’re going to give you an incentive to
do things in a different way. And if we do
the same thing with clean energy, we can save
consumers money and we can make sure the economy
is more secure. So we’ve got to keep investing
in American-made energy and we’ve got to
keep investing in the vehicles that run on
it. That’s where our future is.
And in order to continue this progress, we’re
going to have to make a choice. We’ve got
to decide where our priorities are as a country.
And that’s up to all of you. And I’ll
give you an example. Right now, $4 billion
of your tax dollars goes straight to the oil
industry every year -- $4 billion in subsidies
that other companies don’t get. Now, keep
in mind, these are some of the same companies
that are making record profits every time
you fill up your gas tank. We’re giving
them extra billions of dollars on top of near-record
profits that they’re already making. Anybody
think that’s a good idea?
AUDIENCE No!
THE PRESIDENT: Me, neither. (Laughter.) It
doesn’t make any sense. The American people
have subsidized the oil industry long enough
-- they don’t need the subsidies. It’s
time to end that taxpayer giveaway to an industry
that's never been more profitable, invest
in clean energy that's never been more promising.
(Applause.)
So I called on Congress, eliminate these subsidies
right away. There’s no excuse to wait any
longer.
AUDIENCE: That's right!
THE PRESIDENT: And we should put every member
of Congress on record: They can stand up for
the oil companies or they can stand up for
the American people and this new energy future.
(Applause.) We can place our bets on the fuel
of the past, or we can place our bets on American
know-how and American ingenuity and American
workers like the ones here at Daimler. (Applause.)
That’s the choice we face. That’s what’s
at stake right now.
So, in between shifts, get on the phone or
email or send a letter or tweet -- (laughter)
-- your member of Congress; ask them where
they stand on this -- because it will make
a difference. And you’ll know where I stand
on this. Let’s make sure our voices are
heard. The next time you hear some politician
trotting out some 3-point plan for $2 gas
-- (laughter) -- you let them know, we know
better.
AUDIENCE: Yes!
THE PRESIDENT: Tell them we’re tired of
hearing phony election-year promises that
never come about. What we need is a serious,
sustained, all-of-the-above strategy for American-made
energy, American-made efficiency, American
innovation, American fuel-efficient trucks,
American fuel-efficient cars. We may not get
there in one term --
AUDIENCE: Four more years! (Applause.)
THE PRESIDENT: It's going to take us a while
to wean ourselves off of the old and grab
the new. But we're going to meet this challenge
because we are Americans. Our destiny is not
written for us; it is written by us. We decide
what that next chapter is going to be.
AUDIENCE: Yes!
THE PRESIDENT: And I'm confident, working
with folks like you, the outstanding working
people of Mount Holly, of this plant, of North
Carolina, of states all across the country,
we can pull together, and remind everybody
around the world just why it is that the United
States of America is the greatest nation on
Earth.
Thank you very much, everybody. God bless
you. God bless the United States of America.
(Applause.)