Sing me some harmonies!
It's a small picture in a shop somewhere
And I know who it is!
It's Mormon Judy
And cow people.
A little pitchy
But mmm
Good stuff!
Governor Romney's black
I mean, uh, I think "black" can be judged—
How do I do this?
Dude, I don't have a Jet-Ski…
Not the kind you're talking about.
Plus everyone can see that I'm not black.
I mean, this isn't scientific stuff!
I heard there's not going to be a test!
But I mean, I do want you to support me and be my man…
That's beautiful!
I know he's black…
Ahmed, how did you know about whodunnit in the lounge?
I didn't know.
Oh, you didn't! Oh, oh, well they started clapping
for the mad cow!
Until someone sold him
And then, and then when he died, they had him stuffed!
Like that water buffalo…
Stuffed.
That dude's the sickest.
We hate him.
Because he had eggs for a bath.
Gonna throw up tonight.
Ahhh, but if you throw up
Then it's as a jealous woman.
In horrible weather, I sneeze and I just lose the puppets.
I'm thinking, Governor Romney won't do that, ok?
And this has got me thinking…
I see a purple
idiot
Who speaks German
With a big, spunky, Irish Labradoodle puppy.
Ohh, he got me
And I want you to feel bad
'Cause I've got funny radiation coming up on my desk and it's too much
Ah come on, I'm not a robot, okay.
I wish.
Then I could go higher, and you could rotate my arm
and send me whooshing into space
Can you hear me?
Now Matt, shush, because the sofa bears don't know.
Go ride off, and I'll defeat 17 bears while you're gone
But first I want you two to turn and look at each other.
Yeah.
Oh, now that's nice.
Just stare deeply into each other's eyes.
Yeah.
Good, now say the first thing that pops into your brain!
I don't want to touch sandpaper.
I like "The Wiz"!
Okay, all right
Now I want to try something
Why don't we go, "mmmm"
Just go, "mmmmmmmmm"
"Mmmmmmmmmmmm…."
"Mmmmmmm…"
"Mmmmmmmmmmmmmmmm…"
Yeah, ok, good, that's what I want you to do.
Now follow my lead.
I'm jumping in a pimento shower.
I wanted the music first.
In the tragic square of the Fresh Prince
There went a perfect brown baby.
The guards can see we're all out of weapons, no machetes
Lotion raw bruises
Lotion raw bruises.
Drink
Or sip
A wench
At our hotel
Wolf government
Anchovies
When they laugh at you, you'll drown
Eye of the Sparrow
This girl slipped on my arrow.
I love you two, okay?
Now I want you to turn and look at me.
[snoring sounds]
Ahmed?
Yeah
Uhhh, he's asleep…
Ah! Oh!
It's party time, chumps!
Drink! [Drink!]
Or sip! [Sip!]
A wench at our hotel!
Wolf government!
Anchovies!
If they laugh at you, you'll drown!
Eye of the Sparrow!
That girl slipped on my arrow!
Drink!
Or sip!
Anchovies!
GO!