I HAVE   OFFICE HOURS TODAY AFTER LECTURE.
VERY HAPPY TO TALK   TO YOU OR TAKE QUESTIONS
DURING LECTURE. SO, PLEASE   TAKE ADVANTAGE
OF THAT. ONE OF THE PEOPLE WHO SIGNED
UP FOR THE BOOK CLUB, I SEEM TO HAVE THE
EMAIL WRONG,   FOR TIM MCCAULLY, IF YOU
COULD SEE ME AFTER, I HAVE   YOUR EMAIL
WRONG OR SOMETHING. THANK YOU. A REMINDER
FOR THOSE WHO ARE DOING THE READING THAT
THERE IS   A COPY OF THE CHAPTERS WE ARE
READING FOR THIS WEEK   IN THE BIO 1B GSI
ROOM. THAT A WAY, I THINK. THAT YOU   CAN
PHOTOCOPY IF YOU HAVE NOT BEEN ABLE TO GET
THE   BOOK. IF OTHERS WANT TO JOIN, IT IS
NOT TOO LATE. I   WILL EVEN THROWN IN THE
2 OF THE MBZ (SIC) FOR THOSE   WHO STICK
AT IT. VERY COOL STUFF.   OKAY, I HAVE TO
START WITH A MEA CULPA TODAY.   ONE OF THE
GSI'S POINTED OUT ME THAT I MADE A  HUGE
BOTANICAL BLUNDER. BECAUSE I AM A ZOOLOGIST.
I   EAT PLANTS AND THEN I (INAUDIBLE). SO,
TURNS OUT THAT   POLLEN CONTAINS SPERM SO
THAT FIGURE WAS RIGHT. THE   MALE GAMETE
IN PLANT IS THE SPERM. THEY ARE RIGHT I
AM WRONG. THERE YOU GO THE OTHER MESSAGE
IS, YOUR   GSI'S ARE ALWAYS RIGHT. OKAY,
SO IN THE LAST LECTURE   WE TALKED ABOUT
THE NEODARWINIAN SYNTHESIS, WHICH IS
THE BRINGING TOGETHER THE PRINCIPLES OF EVOLUTION
FOR   DARWIN AND WALLACE WITH THE MECHANICS
OF INHERITANCE,   ALA, MENDEL, AND THEN
SUBSEQUENTLY BRING IN KNOWLEDGE   OF DNA'S
AND GENETIC MATERIALS, GENOMES AND SO ON.
SO, INVIGORATING THE WHOLE FIELD OF EVOLUTION.
AND   ONE OF THE POINTS THAT I WANT YOU
TAKE FROM THAT AS   TECHNOLOGY LABELS, NEW
DISCOVERIES LIKE GENOME   ARCHITECTURE,
THE VARIATIONS IN GENES, AND SO FORTH.
WE ARE REFINING THE THEORY OF EVOLUTION
IN TERMS OF   MECHANISMS BUT THE FUNDAMENTALS
HAVEN'T CHANGED. SO   DARWIN GOT IT RIGHT
AND WAS ABLE TO MAKE PREDICTIONS  TO HELP
US UNDERSTAND DETAILS OF THE NATURAL WORLD.
ANYONE LEAVE THIS BEHIND, A LITTLE GOLD
THINGY. ALL   RIGHT. SO, WE ARE LOOKING
AT THE FIELD OF POPULATION   GENETICS. THAT
IS, THE DYNAMICS OF GENETIC VARIATION
WITHIN POPULATIONS. AND LOOKED AT THE HARDY-WEINBERG
EQUILIBRIUM, WHICH IS A VERY SIMPLE WAY
OF PREDICTING   WHAT THE GENOTYPE FREQUENCIES
IN THE POPULATION SHOULD   BE GIVEN THE
FREQUENCIES OF THE ALLELES IN THAT   POPULATION.
SO YOUR FAVORITE THING, P SQUARED 2PQ AND
Q SQUARED. WE ENDED UP WITH APPLICATION
OF THAT.   WHICH IS TO PREDICT
THE FREQUENCY OF HETEROZYGOTES FOR   RECESSIVE
TRAITS OR RECESSIVE ALLELES.   I JUST WANT
TO TOUCH ON THAT BECAUSE I THINK I   CONFUSED
PEOPLE AS I WENT THROUGH IT AND THEN WE WILL
GO ON TODAY TO ASSUMPTIONS OF HARDY-WEINBERG
AND BRING   IN THINGS LIKE GENETIC DRIFT
AND MUTATION AND SEE WHAT   THAT DOES TO
POPULATIONS. SO AGAIN TO REMIND YOU, IF
WE HAVE TWO ALLELES IN A DIPLOID POPULATION
WE HAVE 3  GENOTYPES. IF A IS RECESSIVE
OVER B, THESE ARE   A SINGLE PHENOTYPE.
THIS IS THE DOMINANT PHENOTYPE   THAT IS
THE RECESSIVE PHENOTYPE. THINK ABOUT THE
PURPLE AND WHITE FLOWERS AND THE EXPECTED
FREQUENCY ON   THE HARDY-WEINBERG OF THIS
PHENOTYPE IS PÓ PLUS 2PQ.   EXPECTED FREQUENCY
OF THIS HOMOZYGOTE, WE EXPECT   THE FREQUENCY
OF THE HETEROZYGOTE. THE EXPECTED   FREQUENCY
OF THIS PHENOTYPE IS QÓ. SO THAT GIVES US
A   WAY TO ESTIMATE THE FREQUENCY OF THIS
ALLELE GIVEN THE   OBSERVED FREQUENCY OF
THAT PHENOTYPE. IF THE   FREQUENCY OF THE
B PHENOTYPE IS QÓ, THEN THE FREQUENCY
OF THE B ALLELE IS THE SQUARE ROOT OF THE
FREQUENCY OF   THE B PHENOTYPE, THE RECESSIVE
PHENOTYPE,
WHICH IS Q.   WE KNOW THE P IS ONE MINUS
Q. JUST TWO ALLELES. THIS   CAN BE GENERALIZED
TO ANY NUMBER OF ALLELES, BY THE   WAY.
BUT I AM JUST DOING THE TWO ALLELE SITUATIONS.
WE HAVE Q AND AN ESTIMATE OF Q AND AN
ESTIMATE OF P.   SO 2PQ IS OUR ESTIMATE
OF THE FREQUENCY OF THE  HETEROZYGOTE, ASSUMING
GENOTYPES ARE IN THE   HARDY-WEINBERG PROPORTIONS.
WE HAVE TO ASSUME   HARDY-WEINBERG TO DO
THIS. OKAY? SO THEN, ARE YOU   ALL WITH
ME ON THAT? IT IS A USEFUL THING TO BE
WHETHER IN DIAGNOSTICS OR WHATEVER. LET'S
LOOK AT   THAT CASE OF THE DIAGNOSTICS FOR
CYSTIC FIBROSIS.
THE FREQUENCY OF INDIVIDUALS WHO DISPLAY THAT
TRAIT IS 0.0004. 4 IN TEN THOUSAND. ASSUMING
HARDY-WEINBERG, THAT IS QÓ. SO, Q IS
THE SQUARE   ROOT OF THAT. 0.02. 2PQ IS
AN ESTIMATE OF THE   INDIVIDUALS WHO CARRY
THE ALLELE BUT DO NOT EXPRESS   IT, BECAUSE
IT IS RECESSIVE. 0.02 TIMES .98 TIMES
2. THE P IS ONE MINUS THIS.
WHICH IS APPROXIMATELY   0.04 IN THE CAUCASIAN
POPULATION. 1 IN 25 OR 1 IN   21 ROUGHLY,
INDIVIDUALS CARRY THIS ALLELE IN   HETEROZYGOUS
STATE BUT DON'T EXPRESS IT BECAUSE IT
IS RECESSIVE. OKAY? I MESSED UP THE NUMBERS
A BIT   ON MONDAY, SO ARE YOU WITH ME ON
THAT? SO, LET'S  GO ON. ONE THING TO NOTICE
HERE THIS FOLLOWS   DIRECTLY FROM THE MATH
THAT THE CYSTIC FIBROSIS   ALLELE IS MUCH
MORE COMMON IN HETEROZYGOTES THAN IT
IS IN THE HOMOZYGOUS FORM. RARE ALLELES ARE
MOSTLY   FOUND IN THE HETEROZYGOUS CONDITION
RATHER THAT THE   HOMOZYGOUS CONDITION.
THIS BECOMES IMPORTANT IN   A NUMBER OF
ASPECTS OF EVOLUTIONARY DYNAMICS THAT
WE WILL COME BACK TO.
SO FOR RARE ALLELES, THAT IS, Q, THE FREQUENCY
OF THE B ALLELE, LESS THAN 0.1, ROUGHLY.
QÓ IS MUCH   LESS THAN 2 PQ. THAT ALLELE
OCCURS MOST OFTEN IN THE   HETEROZYGOUS
STATE. THE FACT THAT WE CAN DO A LITTLE
GRAPH OF THAT JUST BY LOOKING AT THE EXPECTED
FREQUENCIES OF THESE GENOTYPES GIVEN
ALLELE FREQUENCY.   AND THIS IS THE FREQUENCY
OF THE A ALLELE, FROM   LOW TO HIGH. AND
THE FREQUENCY OF THE GENOTYPES, SO   THE
HOMOZYGOTE IS QÓ. LOOKS LIKE THIS IN TERMS
OF   PROPORTION IN POPULATION GIVEN CHANGE
IN THE ALLELE  FREQUENCY.   BUT, HETEROZYGOTES
LOOK LIKE THIS. SO LET'S   TAKE OUR EXAMPLE
OF A RARE ALLELE AT 0.1. SOMEWHERE   HERE.
SO, IF WE LOOK AT THE FREQUENCY OF THE
HOMOZYGOUS STATE THAT IS QÓ, 0.01. LOOK
AT HOW OFTEN   THAT ALLELE TURNS UP IN HETEROZYGOTES.
0.18. THIS IS   GENERALLY TRUE IN A RANDOM
MATING POPULATION, ASSUMING   HARDY-WEINBERG,
IN PARTICULAR THE POPULATION IS RANDOM
MATING. SO, RARE ALLELES ARE MOST COMMON
IN THE   HETEROZGOUS STATE. AND WE WILL
COME BACK TO THAT   A COUPLE TIMES AS WE
GO ON. ARE YOU WITH ME?   YES? P'S AND Q'S.
I CAN'T EVEN READ THIS. YOU   CAN DO IT
THE OTHER WAY AROUND. SO, IT IS THE SAME
PRINCIPLE. LET'S CALL THIS P AND LET'S
CALL THIS PÓ.   SAME THING. BRING INTO
LINE WITH THE DIAGRAM. IT IS   THE SAME
THING, ONE JUST RECIPROCAL OF THE OTHER.
THANK YOU FOR POINTING THAT OUT. OKAY,
SO IN THINKING   BACK TO HARDY WEINBERG
WE MADE A NUMBER OF  ASSUMPTIONS. ONE OF
WHICH WAS LARGE POPULATION SIZE.   THAT
IS, YOU ARE TAKING A SUFFICIENT SAMPLE FROM
THE   POPULATION IN EACH GENERATION SO THAT
YOU DON'T HAVE   CHANCE FLUCTUATIONS IN
THE ALLELE FREQUENCY. SO, NOW   WE WILL
LOOK AT (INAUDIBLE) ASSUMPTION AND LOOK AT
SMALL POPULATIONS.   THIS IS THE PHENOMENON
CALLED GENETIC DRIFT.   LET'S FORGET GENETICS
FOR A MOMENT AND THINK   ABOUT A SURVEY.
IF YOU ARE BEING SURVEYED ON YOUR   ATTITUDE
TOWARDS A REALLY BIG HIKE IN TUITION FEES.
IF I JUST PICK 3 OR 4 PEOPLE OUT OF THIS
CLASS AND ASK   THEM WHAT THEY THINK ABOUT
THAT I MAY BY CHANCE PICK   A NON-REPRESENTATIVE
EXAMPLE. MAYBE I WILL PICK SOME   REALLY
RICH PEOPLE OR PEOPLE WHO THINK INCREASED
TUITION IS GREAT BECAUSE IT WILL HELP
PAY MY SALARY.   IT IS WONDERFUL. IF I ASK
THE ENTIRE 1B CLASS I WILL   PROBABLY GET
A MORE ACCURATE REPRESENTATION OF THE
OPINION OF THAT SUBJECT. SAME WITH VOTING.
DO YOU  VOTE NOT AT ALL, DEMOCRATIC, REPUBLICAN.
YOU HAVE   MORE FAITH OR MORE, ACCEPT MORE
READILY THE RESULT IF   10,000 PEOPLE WERE
SURVEYED THAN IF 100 PEOPLE WERE   SURVEYED.
10 THOUSAND IS A BETTER SAMPLE OF THE
POPULATION AND OF THE OVERALL VOTING INTENT.
SO, THE   SAME IS TRUE BIOLOGICALLY IN TAKING
GAMETES TO FORM   ZYGOTES. SO, WE HAVE A
BUCKET AND A SPOON. A BUCKET   OF EGGS.
WE ARE GOING TO SAMPLE OUT OF EACH OF THESE
BUCKETS ONE OF EACH TO FORM THE EMBRYO,
THE ZYGOTE.   SO, BASICALLY THAT IS FERTILIZATION
GOING ON TO FORM   THE NEXT GENERATION.
WE WILL GET A MORE ACCURATE   REPRESENTATION
OF THE TRUE GENETIC STRUCTURE OF THAT
POPULATION OF THE VARIATION IF WE TAKE A
BIG EXAMPLE   THAN IF WE TAKE A SMALL SAMPLE.
IF YOU TAKE A SMALL   SAMPLE OUT OF A POPULATION,
THAT IS, IF YOU FORM VERY   FEW ZYGOTES
GOING ON TO ADULTS IN THE NEXT GENERATION
YOU WILL GET A CHANCE ERROR IN THE FREQUENCY
OF THE   ALLELES. SO, SMALL POPULATIONS,
THIS GIVES RISE TO  RANDOM CHANGE IN ALLELE
FREQUENCIES FROM ONE   GENERATION TO THE
NEXT. IT MIGHT GO UP, IT MIGHT GO   DOWN.
AND THE SMALLER THE POPULATION THE BIGGER
THE   SAMPLING ERROR, THE BIGGER THESE RANDOM
FLUCTUATIONS   IN THE ALLELE FREQUENCY.
SLIDE 3 IS A PRETTY PICTURE   THAT SHOWS
WHAT THIS MIGHT DO IN A POPULATION OF
FLOWERS OF SOME SORT. WHERE YOU HAVE RED
ONES AND   WHITE ONES AND PINK ONES, PROBABLY
SNAPDRAGONS. GOING   FROM ONE GENERATION
TO THE NEXT TAKING A VERY SMALL   SAMPLE,
A SMALL POPULATION SIZE. AND YOU CAN SEE THAT
THE ALLELE FREQUENCY IS CHANGING FROM
ONE GENERATION   TO THE NEXT. REMEMBER,
HARDY WEINBERG PREDICTS NO   CHANGE IN INHERITANCE
ALONE AND PREDICTS NO CHANGE IN   ALLELE
FREQUENCIES. BUT, IN A VERY SMALL POPULATION
YOU VIOLATED ONE OF THE ASSUMPTIONS.
SO YOU GET THESE   RANDOM REPEATED CHANGES
IN THE FREQUENCY.   YES?
THE POPULATION ITSELF IS SMALL. SO THE
NUMBER OF BREEDING ADULTS IN THE POPULATION
IS SMALL.  A BIG POPULATION TAKING A SMALL
SAMPLE. YEAH. MY   CONTRIVED EXAMPLE IS
ILLUSTRATING SAMPLING ERROR. IN   THIS CASE
IT IS THE POPULATION ITSELF THAT IS SMALL.
FROM ONE GENERATION TO THE NEXT YOU GET
RANDOM CHANGES   IN ALLELE FREQUENCY.
SO, IF WE LOOK AT THE CHANGE IN ALLELE
FREQUENCY   OVER GENERATIONS, YOU MIGHT
EXPECT SOME, FORGET THE   HASH MARKS, YOU
GET SOME FLUCTUATION. MAYBE EVEN TO   THE
POINT WHERE ONE ALLELE BECOMES THE ONLY ONE
IN THE   POPULATION AND YOU LOST THE OTHER
ONE, YOU LOST   GENETIC VARIATION. YOU FAILED
TO SAMPLE THE OTHER   ALLELE TYPE IN THE
POPULATION, IN THAT PARTICULAR   GENERATION
OF FORMING THE DIPLOIDS OR THE ZYGOTES.
IN A SMALL POPULATION, THIS WOULD BE A
VERY   SMALL POPULATION. IN A LARGER POPULATION,
I CAN'T   DRAW TODAY, THIS IS GOING ON BUT
THE AMPLITUDE IS MUCH   SMALLER FROM ONE
GENERATION TO THE NEXT.
THAT IS THE SAMPLING ERROR IS LESS.  SO,
WHY DOES THIS MATTER? IT MATTERS IN   A
VARIETY OF CONTEXT. BASICALLY WHERE THE POPULATION
SIZE IS SMALL. THAT CAN ARISE FROM SEVERAL
DIFFERENT   SITUATIONS. SO, IMAGINE POPULATION
SIZE, WHICH I WILL   CALL N OVER TIME, YOU
MIGHT HAVE A SITUATION WHERE   POPULATION
SIZE IS ALWAYS SMALL.   AND THIS PROCESS
WILL JUST GO ON AND ON AND ON   OR YOU MIGHT
HAVE A SITUATION WHERE YOU START WITH
A BIG POPULATION WHICH BECOMES SMALL, FOR
SOME REASON.   THINGS THAT MIGHT RELATE
TO THIS, FOR EXAMPLE, IN   CONSERVATION
BIOLOGY, LOSS OF HABITAT OR   OVER-HARVESTING.
PRODUCING LARGE POPULATIONS TO VERY   SMALL
POPULATIONS. SO, ONE EXAMPLE IS FROM HABITAT
LOSS. AN EXAMPLE SHOWN THERE IS FOR PRAIRIE
CHICKENS   ON THE RIGHT-HAND SLIDE OF SLIDE
4. WHICH FORMERLY   OCCUPIED IN VERY LARGE
POPULATIONS, VAST AREAS OF   NATIVE PRAIRIE.
THAT PRAIRIE NOW IS LARGELY LOST DUE
TO EXPANSION OF INTENSIVE AGRICULTURE. THERE
IS VERY  SMALL PATCHES OF THIS HABITAT LEFT
AND THE PRAIRIE   CHICKEN POPULATIONS HAVE
BECOME VERY, VERY SMALL. AS   A CONSEQUENCE
THEY HAVE LOST GENETIC VARIATIONS. WE
CAN MEASURE THE GENETIC VARIATION IN HISTORICAL
SAMPLES, SPECIMENS TAKEN 100 OR MORE
YEARS AGO BEFORE   THE HABITAT LOSS. YOU
MEASURE GENETIC VARIATION NOW   AND WE SEE
REDUCTION IN GENETIC VARIATION OF   POPULATION
BECAUSE OF THIS SAMPLING EFFECT, LOSING
ALLELES, ALTERNATIVE ALLELES AT LOCI. THAT
CAN ONLY   COME BACK IN BY MUTATION, WHICH
WE WILL SEE LATER IN   A PARTICULAR GENE
IS A VERY RARE EVENT. AS   A CONSEQUENCE
OF THAT, THAT LOSS OF GENETIC VARIATION,
THE HATCHING RIGHTS OF THOSE PRAIRIE CHICKENS
HAVE   DECLINED FROM 93 PERCENT TO, I HAVE
FORGOTTEN WHAT THE   EXACT NUMBER IS, TO
LESS THAN 50 PERCENT. THAT IS   IMPACTING
THE REPRODUCTION AND SURVIVAL OF THE PRAIRIE
CHICKENS. IN THIS PARTICULAR CASE, WHEN
THEY MIX   POPULATIONS THEY CAN RESTORE
THAT GENETIC VARIATION  AND RESTORE THE
HATCH RIGHT OF THE POPULATION. WHICH
BRINGS UP ANOTHER IMPORTANT POINT, THIS GENETIC
DRIFT   IS CAUSING ALLELE FREQUENCIES TO
BOUNCE AROUND FROM   ONE GENERATION TO THE
NEXT. THAT IS A RANDOM PROCESS.   IN CALIFORNIA,
LIKE TOTALLY RANDOM, I PRACTICED   THAT
FOR TEN YEARS. DO I STILL NOT HAVE IT? LIKE
TOTALLY RANDOM. NO. I WOULD NEVER MAKE
A VALLEY   GIRL, WOULD I. IMAGINE WE HAVE
POPULATION 1, I REALLY   DO TRY, POPULATION
2. IN POPULATION 1, IF THIS IS THE   ALLELE
FREQUENCY FOR A PARTICULAR GENE, IT'S BOUNCING
AROUND. POPULATION 2, MAYBE IT DOES THAT.
AGAIN,   BECAUSE THERE IS NO PARTICULAR
DIRECTION TO THE   CHANGE.   SO NOW WE
CAN SEE HERE YOU HAVE LOST VARIATION,
HERE YOU LOST VARIATION. BUT YOU HAVE GOT
DIFFERENT   ALLELES. THESE ARE NOW ALL B.
THESE ARE ALL A.   SO IF YOU MIX THEM YOU
GET BACK THE GENETIC   VARIATION.  WE
WILL COME BACK TO THIS WHEN WE TALK ABOUT
MIGRATION, WHICH I BELIEVE IS WHAT WE
ARE COMING UP   TO.   OKAY, SO JUST TO
REVIEW GENETIC DRIFT, IT   ISPHENOMENON
IN SMALL POPULATIONS. IT CAUSES RANDOM
CHANGES IN ALLELE FREQUENCY FROM ONE GENERATION
TO THE   NEXT. IF THE POPULATION IS SMALL
ENOUGH OR THE   PROCESS GOES ON FOR LONG
ENOUGH, IT WILL LEAD TO THE   LOSS OF GENETIC
VARIATION WITHIN POPULATIONS, BUT   MIGHT
INCREASE DIFFERENCES BETWEEN POPULATIONS,
IF THE   POPULATIONS ARE ISOLATED.
ANOTHER EXAMPLE WHERE THIS IS IMPORTANT, THAT
IS   SORT OF CONSERVATION BIOLOGY THING.
ANOTHER EXAMPLE   IS COLONIZATION. SO, AS
WE WILL SEE LATER IN THE   COURSE, THE MODERN
HUMAN SPECIES, HOMOSAPIANS, AROSE   IN AFRICA.
IT APPEARS ABOUT 100, 150 THOUSAND YEARS
AGO A RELATIVELY SMALL SAMPLE OF AFRICANS
COLONIZED   INTO EUROPE, AND SOME ACROSS
SOUTH ASIA INTO AUSTRALIA  AND BEYOND. SO
WE TOOK A SMALL SAMPLE OUT OF THAT BIG
AFRICAN POPULATION AND WHAT WE SEE TODAY
THERE IS FAR   MORE GENETIC DIVERSITY AMONGST
AFRICANS THAN THERE IS   AMONG CAUCASIANS
AND EUROPEANS. THERE WAS A LOSS OF   GENETIC
DIVERSITY WITH THAT NATURAL COLONIZATION.
THE   SAME IS TRUE OF ISLANDS. SO, HUMANS
COMING OUT OF   AFRICA FROM ISLANDS, REMEMBER
THE DARWIN FEATURES FROM   THE GALAPAGOS.
THEY STEM FROM A SINGLE ANCESTOR OR   A
SMALL NUMBER OF ANCESTORS THAT COLONIZED THE
GALAPAGOS SUCCESSFULLY FROM MAINLAND
SOUTH AFRICA. IN   NATURE, WHAT WE SEE IN
ISLANDS IS THAT THERE IS A LOT   OF SHIFT,
VERY RAPID CHANGES IN MORPHOLOGY AND
PHENOTYPES AND IN GENETIC VARIATION. PERHAPS
ASSOCIATED WITH THIS COLONIZATION PROCESS.
THIS IS SOMETIMES REFERRED TO AS A FOUNDER
EVENT.   AND FIGURES OF THIS CAN CONTRIBUTE
TO THIS   INITIAL SAMPLING, PERHAPS WITH
LATER POPULATION  GROWTH, CAN CAUSE VERY
RAPID CHANGES IN THE GENETIC   MAKE-UP OF
POPULATIONS. PERHAPS EVEN GENERATE NOVEL
PHENOTYPES OR NOVEL COMBINATIONS OF GENES
THAT MIGHT   BE FAVORED IN THE NEW ENVIRONMENT
OR NOT.   OKAY. SO WE WILL TALK NOW ABOUT
MUTATION. ARE   YOU ALL OKAY WITH GENETIC
DRIFT? THE SAMPLING   PROCESS? OKAY. ANY
QUESTIONS? SO, ANOTHER   ASSUMPTION OF HARDY-WEINBERG,
ONE THAT TURNS OUT NOT   TO MATTER VERY
MUCH IN THE CONTEXT OF HARDY-WEINBERG
IS A MUTATION. SO, LET'S LOOK AT THE PROCESS
OF   MUTATION. HERE WE GET TO SEE HOW GENTLE
I CAN BE. SO   IF I TAKE THIS SMALL SAMPLE
OF THE TOTAL CLASS HOW   MANY PEOPLE HAVE
NOT TAKEN ANY MOLECULAR BIOLOGY AT   ANY
STAGE? OKAY. I WILL BE GENTLE. I AM SURE YOU
HAVE THAT PLEASURE AHEAD OF YOU.
SO I WANT TO TALK NOW ABOUT MUTATION. ARE
YOU ALL OKAY WITH
GENETIC DRIFT? THE SAMPLING THE PROCESS? OKAY.
ANY QUESTIONS?
SO, ANOTHER ASSUMPTION OF HOW THEY, ONE THAT
TURNS OUT NOT TO
MATTER VERY MUCH IN THE CONTEXT OF HARDY-WEINBURG
IS MUTATION.
SO LET'S LOOK AT THE PROCESS OF MUTATION.
HERE AGAIN I'LL NEED TO FIGURE OUT HOW GENTLE
I CAN BE. IF
I TAKE THIS SMALLISH SAMPLE OF THE TOTAL CLASS,
HOW MANY PEOPLE
HAVE TAKEN ANY MOLECULAR -- HOW MANY PEOPLE
HAVE NOT TAKEN ANY
MOLECULAR BIOLOGY AT ANY STAGE? OKAY. I'LL
BE GENTLE.
I'M SURE YOU HAVE THAT PLEASURE AHEAD OF YOU.
SO LET'S LOOK
AT MUTATION.
MUTATION, THAT IS, CHANGES IN THE GENOME OR
THE
NUCLEOTIDE SEQUENCE. IT IS SORT OF THE ULTIMATE
SOURCE OF
VARIATION. WITH THAT MUTATION ALL GENES IN
THE POPULATION WOULD
JUST HAVE THE SAME SET OF ALLELES. YOU ARE
GOING TO GENERATE NEW
VARIANCES OF ALLELES. AND THAT PROCESS THAT
GENERATES THAT IS
MUTATION.
SO, IF YOU TAKE A LOOK AT SLIDE FIVE AND SUMMARIZE
SOME OF
THE DIFFERENT FORMS OF MUTATION THAT CAN OCCUR
AT THE LEVEL OF
GENES OR THEIR CONTROLLING ELEMENTS.
SO ONE TYPE OF MUTATION THAT CAN OCCUR IS
A CHANGE IN THE
CODING SEQUENCE.
WHAT DO I MEAN BY CODING SEQUENCE?
SO EUKARYOTES IN GENERAL, A SORT OF CARTOON
FORM. A GENE
MIGHT BE STRUCTURED SOMETHING LIKE THIS. WE
HAVE EXONS AND THE
INTRONS. IT'S THE EXONS, THE WHOLE THING IS
TRANSCRIBED IN THE
MESSENGER RNA AND THEN THE INTRONS ARE CUT
OUT. WHAT YOU
EVENTUALLY END UP WITH IS THE MESSENGER
RNA THAT IS TRANSCRIBED.
THE INTRONS ARE CUT OUT. SO THE MESSENGER
RNA REPRESENTS WHAT'S
IN THE EXONS. THIS THEN GOES THROUGH TRANSLATION
TO FORM THE
PROTEIN.
ELSEWHERE, YOU MIGHT HAVE AND THAT COULD BE
QUITE DISTANT
FROM THIS GENE, YOU'LL HAVE SEQUENCES THAT
CONTROL GENE
REGULATION.
PLAYS WITH THE ENZYMES THAT TRANSCRIBE THE
DNA AND
THOSE COMPLEXES WILL BIND TO DETERMINE HOW
MUCH, WHERE AND WHEN
THIS PARTICULAR GENE IS EXPRESSED. THAT IS,
TRANSCRIBED AND
TRANSLATED TO MESSENGER RNA. THERE IS A LOT
OF STUFF GOING ON AS
WELL, BUT THIS IS WHAT YOU NEED TO KNOW FOR
NOW.
SO WITHIN THESE EXONS, YOU BLOW THIS UP. YOU
GET A SEQUENCE
OF NUCLEOTIDES WHICH COME IN THREE'S, WHICH
ARE CALLED CODONS.
AND THESE FORM THE PARTICULAR CODE. PARTICULAR
CODONS SPECIFY
PARTICULAR AMINO ACIDS IN THE PROTEIN. OKAY.
YOU ALL WITH ME ON
THAT? A LOT OF REALLY COOL STUFF GOING ON
BESIDE THIS BUT THAT
WILL DO FOR NOW.
WHEN I REFER TO A CHANGE IN THE CODING SEQUENCE,
I'M
REFERRING TO A CHANGE IN THE EXONS AND ONE
IN WHICH PERHAPS
CHANGES WHICH AMINO ACID IS ENCODED IN THAT
PROTEIN THAT'S
PRODUCED. AN EXAMPLE SHOWN THERE IS FOR THE
HEMOGLOBIN OR THE
BETA-GLOBIN GENE IN HEMOGLOBIN. IN THAT SLIDE
REMEMBER WE TALKED
ABOUT HEMOGLOBIN A AND B? HBBA, HBBS, IN THE
LAST LECTURE THE
SICKLE CELL MUTATION. THAT'S DUE TO A CHANGE
IN THE CODING
SEQUENCE FROM, IN A PARTICULAR CODON FROM
CCT TO CAT. YOU'VE
CHANGED FROM A "T" TO AN "A" THERE. WHICH
CHANGES THE PARTICULAR
AMINO ACID CODE IN THAT PROTEIN WHICH GIVES
RISE TO THE DISTINCT
PHENOTYPE. THAT IS A CHANGE IN A CODING SEQUENCE.
YOU CAN ALSO CHANGE REGULATORY SEQUENCES.
SO THIS STUFF.
IT IS A MUTATION THAT'S GOING TO OCCUR IN
THE DNA THERE THAT WILL
CHANGE THE EXTENT, THE TIMING OR THE PLACE
OF GENE EXPRESSION,
WHICH CAN MATTER A WHOLE LOT.
OKAY? SO IN HEMOGLOBIN, FOR EXAMPLE, DIFFERENT
GLOBIN GENES
ARE EXPRESSED AT DIFFERENT STAGES OF DEVELOPMENT.
THEY ARE
EXPRESSED IN PARTICULAR TISSUES TO FORM THE
HEMOGLOBIN, ET
CETERA, ET CETERA.
WE CAN ALSO CHANGE THE NUMBER OF COPIES OF
GENES IN THE
GENOME. WE ARE JUST NOW STARTING TO SEE HOW
VERY COMMON THIS IS.
SO THESE ARE SO-CALLED COPY NUMBER VARIANCE.
SO GENES CAN
BE -- EXTRA COPIES CAN BE MADE OF GENES THROUGH
ERRORS IN
REPLICATION OR ERRORS IN RECOMBINATION OR
BY MOBILE ELEMENTS
TRANSPOSABLE ELEMENTS. A WHOLE VARIETY OF
MECHANISMS. YOU CAN
CHANGE THE NUMBER OF COPIES OF GENES. THAT
AGAIN CAN EFFECT THE
PHENOTYPE. THE FACT THAT IT'S TURNING OUT
TO BE QUITE A COMMON
CAUSE OF DIFFERENCES IN A WHOLE NUMBER OF
HUMAN TRAITS, DISEASES
AND SO FORTH. CHANGES IN THE COPY NUMBER OF
GENES, NOT THEIR
INTERNAL STRUCTURE. AND PARTICULAR PARTS OF
GENOME DO THIS A
WHOLE LOT AND OTHER PARTS ARE ALL STABLE.
IT IS SOMETHING THAT
ONLY NOW THEY ARE ABLE TO ASSESS ACCURATELY
IN HUMAN POPULATIONS.
AND FINALLY YOU CAN CHANGE GENOME ORGANIZATION.
MAYBE EVEN
DUPLICATE THE WHOLE GENOME. QUITE COMMON
IN PLANTS.
THAT IS,
YOU CAN CREATE POLYPLOIDS. SO DIPLOID TO TETRAPLOID.
COPY THE
WHOLE GENOME. AND THIS HAS HAPPENED MULTIPLE
TIMES IN CERTAINLY
THE EVOLUTION OF VERTEBRATES AND OTHER ORGANISMS.
IN FACT, IN
INDIVIDUAL SALMONA CELLS YOU GET DIFFERENT
PLOIDY LEVELS. FOR
THE WHOLE SALMON FAMILY IN GENERAL THEY HAVE
COPIED THEIR WHOLE
GENOME AND THEN GENES HAVE DIVERSIFIED AMONG
THOSE COPIES.
OKAY. SO THESE -- OR YOU CAN CHANGE THE ORGANIZATION
OF
CHROMOSOMES, YOU CAN FUSE CHROMOSOMES TOGETHER
OR BITS CAN BREAK
OFF AND JOIN ANOTHER CHROMOSOME. SO ALL THESE
ARE FORMS OF
MUTATION THAT ARISE MOSTLY THROUGH ERRORS
IN REPLICATION,
RECOMBINATION OR THE ACTION OF TRANSPOSABLE
ELEMENTS OR MOBILE
ELEMENTS IN THE GENOME.
HOW COMMON IS THIS? WELL, PEOPLE HAVE TRIED
TO FIGURE THIS
OUT FOR A LONG TIME. WHAT'S THE FREQUENCY
OF MUTATION? SO JUST
RECENTLY A FEW WEEKS AGO THERE WAS A REPORT
OF COMPLETE GENOME
SEQUENCING OF MULTIPLE FAMILIES. BOTH PARENTS,
BIOLOGICAL
PARENTS, OF COURSE, AND THEIR OFFSPRING, AND
I DID THIS FOR THE
WHOLE FAMILIES. SO I COMPARED THE WHOLE GENOME
BETWEEN PARENTS
AND OFFSPRING TO IDENTIFY CHANGES, ALLELES
IN THE OFFSPRING BUT
NOT THE PARENTS. THE CONCLUSION FROM THAT
IS THAT THE MUTATION
RATE IS ROUGHLY 10 TO THE MINUS 8 PER NUCLEOTIDE
PER GENERATION.
10 TO THE MINUS 8 IS A TINY LITTLE NUMBER.
ONE IN 100 MILLION.
BUT THINK ABOUT HOW MANY NUCLEOTIDES YOU HAVE
IN YOUR GENOME.
THE GENOME IS APPROXIMATELY 3 BY 10 TO THE
9 BASE PAIRS IN
HUMANS. SO MULTIPLY IT OUT. HERE IS THE
RATE PER NUCLEOTIDE PER
GENERATION. HERE'S THE NUMBER OF NUCLEOTIDES.
SO THE NUMBER OF
NEW MUTATIONS ACROSS THE WHOLE GENOME IN A
PARTICULAR INDIVIDUAL
CAN BE ROUGHLY 30. EACH OF US IS A MUTANT.
AND WE SHOULD
CELEBRATE THAT. IT IS THE ULTIMATE CAUSE OF
HUMAN DIVERSITY.
SO, ON AVERAGE THERE IS A LOT OF VARIATION
IN THIS NUMBER.
YOU ARE GOING TO CARRY SOME TENS OF CHANGES
IN YOUR DNA SEQUENCE
COMPARED TO YOUR PARENTS. I THINK THAT'S COOL.
NOW, DO THESE
MATTER? MOST OF THE GENOME ISN'T IN THESE
BITS. MOST OF IT'S IN
THE CHUNKS OF DNA BETWEEN GENES. NOW, SOME
OF THIS MATTERS IN
WAYS WE DON'T YET UNDERSTAND. PERHAPS IN GENE
REGULATION, SO AND
SO FORTH. SO MOST OF THESE CHANGES PROBABLY
AREN'T LANDING IN
EXON OR IN ARTIFACT GENE REGULATION BUT SOME
DO. SOME SMALL
PROPORTION OF THOSE WILL. SO, WHY DO WE ALL
HAVE TEN
FINGERS -- SORRY. 11 FINGERS? SO ON AND SO
FORTH. THESE ARE
MOSTLY HETEROZYGOTES. WE'RE NEARLY ALL HETEROZYGOTES.
BECAUSE
IT'S A UNIQUE MUTATION. IT IS LANDING RANDOM
SOMEWHERE IN THIS
WHOPPING BIG GENOME. SO THE CHANCE OF THAT
SAME MUTATION
OCCURRING WHEN YOUR MOM MADE THE EGGS AND
YOUR DAD MADE THE SPERM
HITTING THE SAME PLACE IS VANISHINGLY SMALL.
SO THESE ARE
ESSENTIALLY ORGAN B HETEROZYGOTES AND MOSTLY
RECESSIVE. THAT IS,
PARTICULARLY IF IT'S A MUTATION THAT KNOCKS
OUT A FUNCTION. OR A
LOT OF TIMES WHEN YOU HAVE ONE OR THE OTHER
COPIED AND IT IS
FUNCTIONAL, YOU'RE OKAY.
SO, ALTHOUGH WE ALL CARRY MUTATIONS, WE STILL
FUNCTION
PRETTY WELL AS ORGANISMS. NOW, THERE IS
ONE LITTLE DANGER HERE.
WHAT HAPPENS IF YOU MATE WITH A CLOSE RELATIVE?
INBREEDING.
RIGHT? MATING WITH CLOSE RELATIVES WITHIN
FAMILIES CAN BRING
THESE OTHERWISE RARE MUTATIONS TOGETHER. IF
THE SAME MUTATION
HAPPENS TO BE SHARED ACROSS GENERATIONS BECAUSE
THESE WILL
ACCUMULATE ACROSS GENERATIONS, AND YOU'RE
MATING WITH A BROTHER,
SISTER OR FATHER OR WHATEVER, THEN YOU MIGHT
BRING THESE,
OTHERWISE, VERY RARE MUTATIONS TOGETHER IN
THE SAME OFFSPRING,
WHICH IS BAD.
BECAUSE THEN THEY'RE EXPRESSED. THEIR HOMOZYGOUS
AND IF IT
IS A KNOCKOUT MUTATION OR SOMETHING THAT CAUSES
DAMAGE TO THE
PHENOTYPE, IT WON'T BE REAL GOOD. SO, JUST
DON'T INBREED IS MY
ADVISE. TURNS OUT DARWIN MARRIED HIS COUSIN,
WHICH IS REALLY
COMMON IN VICTORIAN ENGLAND. AND SOME SOCIETIES
DO PRACTICE IN
BREEDING. BUT THERE IT IS. THAT IS WHY IN
PART INBREEDING IS
SUCH A BAD THING.
OKAY. SO, IN SLIDE 6 I SHOW YOU AN EXAMPLE
OF THESE
DIFFERENT FORMS OF MUTATION THAT ACTUALLY
RELATES TO CODE COLOR
IN MICE, WHICH YOU WILL BE STUDYING IN THE
LAB. SO ON THE LEFT
IS A NORMAL SORT OF MOUSE. ON THE RIGHT IS
A DARK MOUSE, IN
SLIDE 6.
SO TURNS OUT THESE MUTATIONS CAN ARISE THIS
PARTICULAR
PHENOTYPE WHICH TURNS UP AGAIN AND AGAIN ON
LAVA FLOWS. THE NEXT
LECTURE I WILL BRING YOU SOME EXAMPLES OF
THESE ANIMALS. YES?
YES. EXACTLY. SO WE'LL TALK ABOUT THIS. SO
IF THE
MUTATION CAUSE AN INCREASE IN SURVIVAL OR
INCREASE IN
REPRODUCTION, THEN IT WILL BE FAVORED BY SELECTION
AND IT WILL
INCREASE IN THE POPULATION. OKAY? THAT'S ABSOLUTELY
CORRECT.
YES, BUT IT TAKES MUCH LONGER. WE ARE GOING
TO TALK ABOUT
THAT IN THE LECTURE ON FRIDAY. NEW MUTATIONS
COME IN. THEY MAY
HAVE NO EFFECT ON THE PHENOTYPE BECAUSE THERE
IS SOME IN THE DNA
THAT LITERALLY HAS NO EFFECT. BUT MIGHT HAVE
AN EFFECT BUT BE
RECESSIVE AND MIGHT HAVE AN EFFECT AND BE
DOMINANT. AND THAT
REALLY CHANGES HOW THE WHOLE DYNAMIC GOES
FROM THERE IN TERMS OF
WHETHER IT'S FAVORED BY SELECTION. MAYBE LOST
BY GENETIC DRIFT.
REMEMBER IT WAS A DRIFT THING. IF YOU START
DOWN HERE AT A VERY
LOW ALLELE FREQUENCY, A NEW MUTATION, THERE
IS A GOOD CHANCE THAT
WILL ACTUALLY BE LOST. UNDER GENETIC DRIFT
GOING INTO THE NEXT
GENERATION YOU WILL FAIL TO PICK UP THAT EXCEPTIONALLY
RARE
MUTATION IN AN OFFSPRING IN THE NEXT GENERATION
IN SORT OF MODEL
SIZE POPULATIONS. SO IT IS REALLY INTERESTING
TO THINK ABOUT
WHAT IS GOING TO BE THE FATE OF THIS MUTATION.
A LOT OF TIMES
THEY WILL JUST BE LOST. WE'LL FAIL TO GET
THEM IN THE NEXT
GENERATION. IF THEY ARE FAVORED BY SELECTION
THEN HOW QUICKLY
THEY INCREASE WILL DEPEND ON WHETHER THEY
ARE RECESSIVE OR NOT.
AND WE'LL TALK ABOUT THAT. THAT IS A GOOD
QUESTION. ANY OTHER
QUESTIONS?
OKAY. WHERE WAS I? MICE. OKAY. SO THIS PARTICULAR
EXAMPLE, AND AGAIN THE DETAILS OF THIS DON'T
MATTER. IT IS JUST
ILLUSTRATING THESE DIFFERENT FORMS OF MUTATION.
IN THE MELANIN
PRODUCTION PATHWAY THE MELANIN IS WHAT MAKES
THESE MICE DARK.
AND IS FAVORED BY SELECTION IF THEY'RE LIVING
ON LAVA FLOWS, FOR
EXAMPLE. IT MAKES THEM LESS CONSPICUOUS TO
A PREDATOR.
AND THAT PATHWAY, A LOT OF WHICH IS NOW KNOWN
FROM STUDIES
OF MICE, YOU'VE GOT A CELL, YOU'VE GOT A RECEPTOR,
ON THE EDGE OF
THAT CELL THAT WILL INTERACT WITH A HORMONE.
COMING AT THIS
PARTICULAR RECEPTOR THE PROTEIN IS CALLED
MC1R, MELANOCORTIN
RECEPTOR. OR WAS IT MC1R? YEAH, MC1R. SO A
CHANGE IN THE CODING
SEQUENCE FOR THIS PROTEIN, IN THE DNA IN THE
EXONS, CAN CHANGE
THE EFFICIENCY WITH WHICH IT RECOGNIZES THE
HORMONE AND THEN
INITIATES EVENTS INSIDE THE CELL TO PRODUCE
MELANIN. DON'T WORRY
ABOUT WHAT'S GOING ON IN HERE.
BUT IT ALSO INTERACTS. SO MSH HERE IS THE
HORMONE,
MELANOCYTE STIMULATING HORMONE. SO THAT'S
AN EXAMPLE OF A CODING
MUTATION. WE'VE CHANGED MC1R TO INTERACT WITH
THAT HORMONE. BUT
ANOTHER POSSIBILITY IS FROM A DIFFERENT PROTEIN
CALLED A GUTI,
WHICH SUPPRESSES THE ACTION OF MC1R. SO THIS
PROTEIN INTERACTS
WITH THAT PROTEIN TO DETERMINE ITS FUNCTION.
AND THERE ARE NO
MUTATIONS IN MELANISTIC MICE WHERE THE CODING
SEQUENCE OF THE
GUTI IS NOT CHANGED, THE GENE REGULATION IS
CHANGED. THERE IS
MORE OF IT. SORRY. THERE IS LESS OF IT. SO
WE'RE DECREASING A
GUTI, WHICH IS REDUCING SUPPRESSION OF MC1R,
PRODUCING MORE
MELANIN. SO THE CASE OF A GUTI, THIS IS A
REGULATORY MUTATION.
THIS ONE IS A CODING SEQUENCE MUTATION. NOW,
THOSE TWO THINGS
INTERACT, AND ONE OR THE OTHER CAN LEAD TO
THE CHANGE IN
PHENOTYPE. WE HAVE A SPECIFIC PHENOTYPE
CAUSED BY INDEPENDENT
MUTATIONS. ONE BEING A REGULATORY MUTATION
IN A PARTICULAR
PROTEIN AND OTHER BEING A CODING SEQUENCE
CHANGE IN A DIFFERENT
PROTEIN WITH WHICH IT INTERACTS. EITHER ONE
CAN CAUSE THE CHANGE
IN PHENOTYPE. ANY QUESTIONS? YES.
NO, GUTI IS JUST A DIFFERENT GENE. IT IS A
GENE JUST LIKE
THIS. BUT IN THAT PARTICULAR CASE THE MUTATION
IS ONE THAT
EFFECTS ITS EXPRESSION, A CHANGE IN THE GENE
REGULATION. THE
CODING SEQUENCE OF A GUTI IS THE DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN A PALE MOUSE
AND A DARK MOUSE. THE CHANGE OCCURRED IN THE
REGULATORY
SEQUENCES. OKAY. ANY OTHER QUESTIONS?
OKAY. SO, AGAIN DON'T GET HUNG UP ON THE DETAILS
AND WHAT
WAS THE NAME OF THAT HORMONE AND WHAT WAS
THE NAME OF THAT GENE.
THE IDEAS OF DIFFERENT TYPES OF MUTATIONS
EFFECTING PHENOTYPE.
SOMETIMES GENERATING THE SAME TYPE OF PHENOTYPE
THROUGH A
MECHANISM. OKAY.
SO LET'S COME BACK TO THIS QUESTION. GENETIC
DRIFT. SO IN
THE PRAIRIE CHICKEN I POINTED OUT THAT DIFFERENT
POPULATIONS ARE
UNDERGOING GENETIC DRIFTING GENETICALLY. SOME
ARE FIXING, THAT
IS, GOING TO ALL "A" AND SOME ARE GOING TO
ALL "B" AND SOME ARE
STILL BOUNCING AROUND IN BETWEEN. SO EXPECT
GENETIC DRIFT TO
INCREASE DIFFERENCES BETWEEN POPULATIONS.
SO ONE THING THAT IS OPPOSING IS MIGRATION,
WHICH YOU CAN
ALSO THINK OF AS GENE FLOW. SO IF WE HAVE
A COUPLE OF
POPULATIONS LIKE THIS, THIS 1P IS POINT "A"
AND THIS 1P IS POINT
TWO. THEY DIFFER IN THIS CASE BECAUSE OF
GENETIC DRIFT OPERATING
IN THOSE TWO POPULATIONS. IF INDIVIDUALS ARE
BORN HERE AND MOVE
OVER HERE TO REPRODUCE, IT IS ESSENTIAL THEY
REPRODUCE FOR
MIGRATION TO GIVE RISE TO GENE FLOW. IF THEY
ARE BORN IN ONE
POPULATION AND REPRODUCE IN ANOTHER, THEY
CARRY THEIR GENES FROM
HERE TO HERE.
THINK OF VIKINGS, SAILING FROM SCANDINAVIA
TO SCOTLAND AND
ENGLAND AND SO FORTH AND GENEROUSLY SHARING
THEIR GENES AS THEY
WENT.
THAT'S GENE FLOW. OKAY. SO THE EFFECT OF THAT
IS TO REDUCE
DIFFERENCES BETWEEN POPULATIONS. IT OPPOSES
GENETIC DRIFT. IT
CAN EVEN OPPOSE LOCAL ADAPTATION. WE'LL TALK
MORE ABOUT THAT
LATER.
THAT IS, IF ONE ALLELE IS FAVORED BY A SELECTION
HERE AND
ANOTHER ALLELE IS FAVORED BY SELECTION HERE,
THEN THESE MIGRANTS
COME ACROSS CARRYING THE WRONG ALLELE WILL
SLOW DOWN THAT
RESPONSE TO SELECTION.
FINALLY, IT SPREADS MUTATIONS THROUGH THE
SPECIES RANGE.
SO, SHOWING YOU AN EXAMPLE THERE ON THE SLIDE,
SLIDE 7. AND
THESE ARE MEASUREMENTS OF PARTICULAR ALLELES
BETWEEN TWO VERY
DIFFERENT ENVIRONMENTS.
HEAVILY POLLUTED SITE WITH HEAVY METALS, A
MINING SITE WHERE
A PARTICULAR PHENOTYPE AND GENE IS FAVORED.
IN AN ADJACENT
NONCONTAMINATED PASTURE WE SEE SOME OF THE
ALLELES THAT ARE
ADVANTAGEOUS HERE YET THEY NOT ADVANTAGEOUS
HERE YET THEY OCCUR
THERE.
AND THE REASON FOR THAT IS MIGRATION. BORN
IN ONE PLACE OR
GAMETTES PRODUCE IN ONE PLACE, ENDING UP FORMING
ZYGOTES OR
REPRODUCING IN THE OTHER POPULATION.
SO MIGRATION IS VERY IMPORTANT IN TERMS OF
REDUCING THIS
EFFECT, SPREADING THE MUTATIONS THAT CAN OPPOSE
LOCAL ADAPTATION.
WE'LL COME TO THAT WHEN WE TALK ABOUT SELECTION
IN THE NEXT
LECTURE. THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
REMINDER OFFICE HOURS NOW IN WHATEVER...