JOHNNY: Hey, Rocco.
ROCCO: Hey Johnny.
JOHNNY: How are ya?
ROCCO: Wonderful day.
JOHNNY: Who's your
friend, Rocco?
ROCCO: This is my friend
from Sicily.
JOHNNY: Oh.
So it's a Sicilian, eh?
[INAUDIBLE]
MALE SPEAKER: [SPEAKING ITALIAN]
JOHNNY: [SPEAKING ITALIAN]
What brings you to
Little Italy?
ROCCO: I'm not ask a favor.
I've never had a problem.
My son the one with
the problem.
JOHNNY: Everybody's
got problems.
You know that, right?
ROCCO: How much do you ask
eh, [SPEAKING ITALIAN]
This every week you come
for box, your place.
One box marked blue money.
This box--
my dealer $5--
JOHNNY: Get the fuck
outta here.
Get outta here.
You too, get the fuck
outta here.
Don't come back here no more.
ROCCO: I'm your friend.
JOHNNY: You my friend,
you talk like this?
Get out.
ROCCO: I'm sorry.
JOHNNY: Don't come back here.
[BABY CRYING]
FEMALE SPEAKER: But did
you put the sauce--
you put the sauce on?
EDDIE: Come here.
You want some pasta?
You want pasta?
Come on.
Come on, baby.
It's delicious.
I love it, I mean--
FEMALE SPEAKER: No,
I didn't say that.
Did you warm the sauce up?
EDDIE: Yeah, it's warming up.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Dad is waiting
for some warm sauce.
EDDIE: Don't worry.
It'll be there in a minute.
Give you a little
bit more there.
I gotta go on a diet.
I'm eating all these--
FEMALE SPEAKER: Sit down!
You know, we got to
solve this problem
with you and our daughter.
You're so lucky to have
her for a wife.
She's a good wife.
She's a good mother.
She's a good daughter.
Come on, you're going to have
to work a little harder.
I don't understand, there's
still this problem with these
tables and chairs outside
the restaurant.
EDDIE: You gotta have a permit.
You know?
You just can't have, you just
can't have tables outside.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yeah, but
the Sopranos do it.
They sit outside
their pizzeria.
EDDIE: That's in New Jersey.
How many times I got
to tell you?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Did you ever
try to go and get it?
EDDIE: No.
They said you gotta
build a step.
If I don't build the step, it
takes-- if I don't build the
step first, then I can't
get the permit.
[BABY CONTINUES TO CRY]
FEMALE SPEAKER: So talk
to Dad and we'll try
to resolve the problem.
EDDIE: Shut the kid up!
ROCCO: You're giving
them a pass.
This city, too tough now.
EDDIE: What?
ROCCO: Too tough.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Look how
upset you made him now!
ROCCO: No give permits.
FEMALE SPEAKER: So what
do we do, Rocco?
In a situation like this,
what are we going to do?
ROCCO: You play--
[INAUDIBLE].
FEMALE SPEAKER: Look how upset
you made him Eddie.
EDDIE: I made him upset?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yeah!
EDDIE: She can't talk below
a screaming level.
This is how she normally
talks.
ROCCO: Hey, hey.
[INAUDIBLE]
EDDIE: That's how she
normally talks.
ROCCO: Take it easy!
Take it easy.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Don't you
talk to me like that.
ROCCO: You have to respect
your mother-in-law.
FEMALE SPEAKER: That's right.
I'm good to you.
EDDIE: Oh, OK.
Hey.
Oh, shit.
You guys are early.
Hey, I'm sorry.
You guys got here early.
Yeah, I got it.
Don't worry.
ROCCO: [INAUDIBLE]
EDDIE: I'm just setting
up for you right here.
Hi, how are you?
Good to meet you.
Come on in and sit down.
Trying to get everything
ready here.
Sorry.
We got the best mozzarella
you've ever seen.
ROCCO: [SPEAKING ITALIAN]
He speak just Sicilian,
no speak English.
EDDIE: Yeah.
ROCCO: Take the box
mozzarella?
EDDIE: Yeah.
ROCCO: They are one mark,
you know what to do?
MALE SPEAKER: Capisce?
[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
ROCCO: [SPEAKING ITALIAN]
MALE SPEAKER: [SPEAKING ITALIAN]
You understand?
[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
No speak English.
Guy with the box with
the mozzarella.
EDDIE: Mozzarella.
ROCCO: One mark--
the box marked, you know
what you need to do.
EDDIE: It's $5,000.
ROCCO: $5,000 in the mozz.
MALE SPEAKER: In the mozz?
ROCCO: In the mozz.
[INAUDIBLE] not make
a mistake, the
box will have a mark.
MALE SPEAKER: I won't
make a mistake.
X marks the spot.
$5,000?
ROCCO: In the mozz.
EDDIE: Aye aye, Skippy.
No worries.
ROCCO: All right?
All right.
[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah?
OK.
Ciao.
EDDIE: Hey.
Thank you.
MALE SPEAKER: Grazie.
EDDIE: Grazie.