After three months at sea
the Santa Maria, the Pinta and the Niña anchor off the Bahamas.
Europe has found the Americas.
Next comes conquest and colonization by settlers who remake America in their image.
They advance and destroy.
But there is another story about the animals and plants they bring here.
And the natural treasures they find here.
And how the Americas are completely transformed.
It all began five hundred years ago.
It's 1491.
A year from now Christopher Columbus will set foot on this quiet beach.
What's here before he arrives is a world of unbelievable natural wealth.
Two vast continents teeming with life.
More than six hundred thousand miles of coastline are surrounded by pristine waters.
Shoals so dense they're said to slow the passage of ships.
Countless species numbered in their tens of millions.
Inland from the atlantic shores
great forests stretch in every direction.
This new world is a land of stark contrasts.
From the lush jungles of South-America
to the glaciers of the Arctic north.
and the great plains of the midwest where gigantic herds
thunder across North-America
There is room for caribou, antilope, bison and the giant grizzly.
In the sky above flocks of birds nearly block out the sun.
as millions of pigeons, ducks and geese cover the horizon.
No one in Europe has dared imagine the magnificent bounty that exists
on the other side of the Atlantic Ocean.
In 1491
Christopher Columbus stands on the coast of Spain, looking west.
He dreams of leading an expedition to find a new trade route to Asia.
Success will mean glory and riches for himself and the Spanish monarchy.
In Europe the nobles have grown wealthy by trading with the east.
Spices and gold, gemstones and silk,
are the most lucrative goods.
But Europeans have lost the silk road to the Turks and foreign trade is in decline.
The wealth of kings is in danger.
Isabella, queen of Spain,
is desperate to find new routes to India.
And she has a plan.
Isabella is the most powerful woman in Europe,
a continent of expanding horizons filled with competitive and inventive souls.
For five hundred years they have been building castles, palaces and centres of trade.
Kings and popes have raised armies to fight each other and their enemies on Europe's borders.
Nowhere else are rivalries so intense.
Gold fever is so widespread,
religious fervour and business expertise
as tightly wound as in Europe in 1491.
Ideas are moving forward,
curiosity and the thirst for power
pushes Europe's limits.
Europe is a busy and crowded continent,
trying to feed a growing population
of one hundred million people.
Natural resources are already exploited as land becomes scarce and overworked.
Most of the peasants are farmers working land that belongs to someone else,
owned by the nobles or the Church.
Their main diet is bread and porridge,
both made from harvesting grains.
They plant rye or wheat in winter,
oats or barley in the spring.
And every third year the field lies fallow to regenerate.
They've learned to harness water and wind for power.
It is hard work
but good for producing higher yields in smaller spaces.
This agricultural revolution allows the European population to grow.
With the help of one more important element:
domesticated animals.
Horses  pull ploughs,
cattle provide meat, fur and hides.
The pig is a main source of meat and leather.
And so too are sheep.
And the mules can pull a cart.
Cows also give them milk, butter and cheese.
It is not only people that domesticate animals.
The big five: horses, cattle, goats, pigs and sheep domesticate the European landscape.
They contribute to Europe's overcrowded conditions.
In 1491 the Americas too are a crowded and prosperous place.
But in a very different way.
The Andes cradled a vast empire ruled by powerful god kings.
Messoamerica is densely populated and home to the most impressive civilizations on the continent.
The atlantic coast is filled with smaller villages and fields.
And along the great rivers great cities are built around monumental plazas.
It is an ancient world
inhabited by one hundred million people,
hunters and gatherers,
fishermen and farmers,
kings, slaves and soldiers.
Down among the trees,
where the Missouri, Illinois and Mississippi rivers merge,
lies one of the largest civilizations on the continent.
The native Mississippians are mound builders occupying a vast region
from the great lakes in the north
to Florida in the south.
The first explorers thought these great mounds were natural, carved by retreating glaciers.
Now we know that they are the centerpieces of cities.
Cities like Cahokia, busy trading posts of earth and wood,
with populations of up to thousands of people.
No one knows what they called themselves or what language they spoke.
But we know why were they successful.
These Mississippians are farmers.
Their staple crop is fuel
for the ever growing population.
It is a plant native to the Americas unknown to the rest of the world.
But corn is not a blessing from nature or a gift of the gods.
This crop is the outcome of man's first feat of genetic engineering.
Once they learned how to grow it, they could stay in one place.
This simple diet
translated straight into the energy to build a civilization.
The cultivation of corn
is the key to flourishing cultures in the Americas before Columbus.
The staple crop in North-America was corn.
Six thousand years ago ears of corn were only about as long as a person's thumb.
and they were barely edible. It took thousands of years to develop a more
nourishing and larger hybrid and also a hybrid that can grow in cooler climates,
outside Messoamerica.
It wasn't until about eleven hundred years ago that corn reached the Mississippi river valley.
Corn is the result of the domestication of the wild teosinte grass.
Early Americans started with this spindly stock.
And over the centuries they developed it into today's giant corn.
Archaeologists and biologists are still debating how corn was achieved
out of a tiny grass.
Corn is one of the keys to understanding American civilization.
Wherever it flourishes
so do great cultures.
Yet the greatest American empire of them all is found where corn cannot grow.
High in the Andes.
The Inca empire stretches nearly two thousand five hundred miles down the west coast of South-America.
Inca built palaces, storehouses and castles in the tall mountains.