The land they seize seems to be the right place to exploit.
Forests and rivers, coasts and lakes owned by no one.
But not all native Americans succumbed to European diseases.
And this land is neither empty
nor uninhabited.
It is the land of the Powhatan, more than fourteen thousand people living in
small communities,
around two hundred villages on the coast and along rivers,
in large houses surrounded by cleared forests and mixed fields of squash, beans
and corn.
These are farmers and hunters.
There is no gold,
no silver, that settlers dreamed of.
Just the land and its people.
For a while
the settlers and the natives managed to co-exist.
This land is rich with resources that Europe lacks.
In the long run
resources that are far more valuable than gold and silver.
And there's more than enough for everyone.
Europeans wanted to travel west to the great empires of Asia.
Instead the new world they find amazes them
with its natural abundance.
They discovered almost miraculous unbelievable quantities of fish in these estuaries and rivers.
One particular kind of fish which
very much impressed settlers
was the river herring or alewife as it's otherwise called,
and seasonally these would ascend the rivers to spawn from the sea
in their millions.
For example in the Potomac river,
near Washington DC,
during the eighteenth century, something like seven hundred and fifty
million alewife were caught, just from that one river in one year.
It was a remarkable abundance and people
described the rivers as having more fish than water.
Whole shoals are caught in the settlers' nets.
In the eighteenth century
hundreds of thousands of tons are caught
and shipped in one single year and sent from North America to England,
Portugal and Spain.
Fishing boats sink under the weight of their captures,
and the colonies thrive.
It takes only two hundred years to achieve what had taken a thousand years
in Europe.
Overfishing.
Fishing tends to remove the biggest oldest individuals from the population,
and by doing this,
it changes the selected pressures on the population
so that fish begin to
grow more slowly
they reach reproductive maturity at a smaller size and earlier in life.
And these things all reduce the productivity of a population.
Fish are salted, hacked and sent home for money.
Along with them the settlers send another resource that the old world is desperate for.
It is said that there are trees as far as the eye can see.
Such that a squirrel starting off at the Atlantic coast
need never touch the ground
to ** to Georgia.
This is so different from the Europe they left behind.
They have finally found a replacement for something that is disappearing at home.
An infinite accessible source of the raw material of the age.
The forests must fall if the settlers are to succeed.
From now on
the trees are doomed.
When the first settlers arrived in the new world
they found forests that they had never seen in Europe.
Endless forests with huge trees penetrating into the heart of the land
was also a woe against the forest. The ax became the yankee emblem.
At the same time forests would degrade resources that the land had to offer.
You could make plenty of money exporting timber in Europe would have become expensive
and so the greatest forest destruction in history now took place.
The clearing of forests that seemed to belong to no one and cost nothing
goes so far that by the late seventeenth century many areas of the Caribbean and
the Atlantic islands are completely bald.
An incredible amount of wood
is really squandered in this country for fuel.
"Day and night, all winter for nearly half a year in all rooms a fire is kept going"
observes a European traveller.
Wood consumption in the forests of New England
just like in Europe,
is out of control.
For fuel, for building and to clear agricultural land.
The resources in this vast continent
seem to be inexhaustible,
but in time
fish stocks will dwindle in the Americas too.
They create this new world
in the image of the one they left.
Europeans change America by what they take away
but they change this continent even more
by what they bring with them.
They come in search of their own land,
something almost impossible to find in Europe.
They come in search of religious freedom,
in search of a better life.
They believe they are responsible for their own success
and happiness.
For the first time women settlers come too, and they bring the whole way of life with them.
They bring animals and plants
that are all new to the American continent.
Livestock and grains from Europe will transform the new world and make it a true New England.
With the newly imported plough
they will leave little land untilled.
This domesticated livestock and little tools have never been seen on this continent.
An environmental revolution takes place.
In no time
their European wheat is growing
in this foreign soil.
Wheat, barley, oats and rye are brought to America.
But in the process some less welcome guests **
Europeans introduced
crops such as wheat to the Americas, but in the bags of seed they brought with them
them to the Americas they also brought along seeds for weeds
dandelions,
other kinds of weeds and these are everywhere in the Americas now.
From the most insignificant weed
to the continent's greatest mammal, the bison,
nothing is untouched.
America's native flora and fauna
is forever changed.
Where the bison once reined,
cattle soon roam.
To the settlers' delight
their livestock multiplies more quickly here than it did in Europe.
In a few hundred years
European cows eat away the American grass
and trample the soil,
deposit their excrement and distribute the seeds of the weeds.
The invasion of European insects
and animals changes the American landscape for ever.
Horses, pigs, sheep,
goats, chickens
and huge herds of cattle take over North and South America.
The cattle alone doubles in numbers every fifteen months
and feed the settlers.
The new world settlers defend themselves inside sturdy forts
but there are no shortages of any kind.
Meat has become one of the cheapest food in the Americas.
They are the best-fed people in the world.
Hides are in great demand in America as well as in Europe.
And fur from the wild animals they shoot brings them a steady export income.
Some like the beaver are hunted almost to extinction.
Settlers are not forced to adapt to the landscape.
They domesticate and dominate it.
Most trees are cut down and turned into pasture,
in gardens where all kinds of vegetables
and root crops that we know in England
grow in profusion.
They replace the trees they have cut down with their own trees.
Europeans bring peaches, pears and plums.
They bring figs
olives and bananas.
And their trees flourish.
They never know