my name is martin
and i have a deep passions are
travelling
traveling gives me the unique experience
of widening my horizons
by seeing the world
and or which it has to offer
i travel in earnest yanning to find an
answer
to fill the emptiness i have inside me
an emptiness that only grows with each
day
and each travel
i have a man
searching for that which can fill the
sentence
before it is too late
i have searched far and wide for
assigned that will direct and guide me
only to discover
the time actually living in close
proximity to it
expectancy
calling me from within myself
it easy indeed the closest took the
truth
quarter is the secret of life
not life itself
wealth is an element of happiness in
life
however
surely not everything
i take a glance around me and
concentrate on the facts
introduced everything around
redistribute
i would remain all by myself
void of the essence that makes life
and my repeated attempts at ignoring
this feeling of emptiness through
indulging myself in life and its affairs
instantly the celtics in this most
feeling
bubbling up again
resurfacing more intensely
questions upon questions
day after day
i am still searching for the significant
thing that i sense
do not know
i feel like i am narrowing down my
search and i'm closer than ever defined
jingle water i wont
often
i feel that his ought to talk to someone
converse with another human being
one to one
i have many
many questions
i feel like i'm close to finding the
link
for the moment i'm still seeing much of
the world's via the internet
talked
window
bundle
type
and still online so much for knowledge
and i hope that one day
i will find that which i am so charles
he does all this
your inquiries are the point of our
interest
let's discuss