issue
that uh... eric holder of said we can do
drawn strikes on u_s_ citizens on u_s_
soil
without a trial
if you are an actual progressive or a
liberal
you would find that
agents and clearly
obviously unconstitutional
as some of you have
if u
well i don't care about principles and
you're not actually a progressive or
liberal
you just uh... democrat and you like
being a team democrat you like wearing
the blue outfits
and with the big olin hope in changi
like you can see slogans
well then you would be opposed iran paul
because you're not a principled person
you're just go along with
inside asia have some pompoms
'cause your job is really a cheerleader
what does my dear leader robots eight
april u_s_ electron
also
i don't buy them to be awesome i fight
it'd be despicable
i'll go as far as say i'm really glad
that ran paul who i disagree with ninety
percent of the time
has one that seat in kentucky now the
democrat had one that see do you think
it will lead a filibuster against
president bombers unconstitutional
actions
you know they have said that
and as much as i disagree a grand paul
ons so many different issues
what he's doing here is monumentally
important
without further ado let's hear from
rental
the fact
the deal bomb administration has told
the u_s_ senator that there is a
circumstance where the government could
target and kill an american citizen
on american soil without charge and
without trial
is a stark example of an imperial
presidency
if there were an counts of courage in
this body
i would be joined by many other senators
saying that they will not tolerate this
that we will come together today in
bipartisan fashion and tell the
president tell any president
that no president will ever have the
authority to kill americans without a
trial
damn straight
he's a hundred percent right about that
as we are live on there right now he's
missed half hour that this filibuster
and how many senators have joined him
seven others
putting only one democrat ron white
once again missing-in-action are all
those soap operas of democrats played
bernie sanders was with warren et cetera
so now rantoul explains
whereas
president i'll bomb of all people but of
two thousand seven great point here
i'm a republican i didn't vote or
support the president
by the time
but i've marin
vertically in two thousand seven many
men
i admired his uh... ability to stand up
and say we want to work for people
that's not what america does how does
the president's mind work the uh... the
presidency and so on the wall
seem so concerned with all rights seem
so concerned with the right not to have
your phone with that
now says he's not concerned with whether
you can be killed without a trial
where is the brocco bomb of two thousand
seven
great question
well that bravo obama no longer exists
if it ever existed
one possible theory is that he was lying
all long an entire by the wire tapping
in fact
we know that he gave a pass to the big
telecom companies
during the primaries e_s_l_ ur clinton
he's an old filibuster doughnut
and then after the primaries are over no
i don't get away with it
of course he led the bush administration
there were all there was like any of
that president obama does what was
wiretapping himself right now
cid ministration revels in it
the indefinite detention is willing to
sign and the national defense
authorization act
which allows for the indefinite
detention of u_s_ citizens by the
military
let alone on u_s_ citizens and now
he is out cheney cheney
and he says i get back security
residences
on u_s_ soil
due process be damned what happened all
bomb of two thousand seven what c l_
lion
or did he somehow change
i doubt we'll get an answer from the
president on that in either
doesn't seem very open
although of course he is running the
most transparent administration in
history
laugh along with me
one more break or from rempel
now when the president says he doesn't
intend to do so
you really have to think that the route
he wants us to remember in thing could
have him because he says i don't intend
to do so
well it's not enough
i mean would you tolerate a republican
who stood up and said
well i'd like the first amendment on
um... quite fond of the first amendment
and i don't intend to break the first
amendment but i might what conservatives
tolerate someone is that i like the
second amendment
i think it's important and i'm poor guy
membership and i don't intend about the
second amendment
but i might
when we tolerate
but he doesn't intend to do so as a
standard
i've been fighting online all day on
this issue
and so
democrats china go well you have a
single case a bit
president expiry u_s_ citizen on u_s_
soil yet
he just has the authority to do so
apparently you fundamentally miss
understand our process an art form of
government
you know just give the president the
right to do that and then hope he
doesn't use it well why don't we just
have a king instead and get them all
those words in fact
the magna carta was designed to make
sure it became didn't have love specific
rights
we're going back now in history
past the magna carta
this is one of foundations of western
democracy
and nobody administration is apparently
gleefully
tearing it down and any progressive or
liberal that supports them doesn't
understand what it means to be a
progressive or liberal
at all
so this is something i should be crossed
partisan
libertarians lybrand paul conservatives
who care about the constitution and
liberals we should all agree on this
buses bush did it l baba dead out
fortunately
mostly country agrees uh... the
constitution bidet
has already team leaders
told otis it was ok i'd love that ran
paul says it is not ok