Hello?
[phone beeps]
[door slams]
[heavy music in car]
[banjo music plays]
[music fades]
Jess: Oh Cass, do you have a sec?
Cass: If I said no would it matter?
Jess: Um, well something really big has come up and I need more hours.
Cass: Same as you and everybody else.
[noisy chatter]
Cass: Sorry about the wait.
Jess: What about an advanced pay or something?
Cass: No.
Jess: Or I could take day shifts because the tips are a heaps better?
Cass: Jess, if you don't like the arrangements quit.
Jess: Why do you need to be such a...
Cass: Such a what? You think you get special treatment because you're pregnant?
Jess: Please?
Cass: [sighs]
Cass: Don't make this my problem. If you can't look after your baby now I can't help you.
[rousing guitar music plays]
[tires splash]
[bell rings]
[door closes]
Jess: Wow it's really coming down!
Woman: Thank you.
Jess: No worries. Do you want to sit?
Woman: Oh look at you!
Jess: Yeah can't miss me.
Woman: Is it a boy or girl?
Jess: We are praying for a girl but the way it's kicking is telling me it's otherwise.
Woman: Is this your first?
Jess: Yes, it's kind of scary.
Woman: When's it due?
Jessica: Next month.
Woman: Next month? Oh my goodness, you should be at home resting.
Jessica: Yeah, um well with the baby and everything I have to work.
Woman: I'm so sorry I didn't - I didn't mean to...
Jessica: No, um let me know when you're ready.
[phone beeps]
Woman: Oh!
[knock, knock, knock]
Man: Your tire's flat.
Woman; Well I'm so glad you came along to tell me that.
[phone clatters]
Man: Nice car.
Woman: Yes they said there will be people coming along soon.
Man: Look why don't you just pop the boot. Let me get at the tire.
Man: Have a look around. How long you been waiting already?
[boot latch clicks]
[guitar music plays]
[spoon scraping plate]
Woman; Are you from around here?
Man: A few towns over. Out this way looking for work.
Woman: How's that going?
[tire lever clatters]
Man: Arrgh!
Man: Arrgh [exhales]
Jess: Here we go. Oh thanks I'll just grab your change.
[boot slams]
Man: Well you're all set.
Woman: Go on, you need it. Go on.
Man: Thanks but no thanks. We've all been there hey.
Woman: You're a good man.
Man: [chuckles] I'm quite the catch.
[till slams]
[customers chatter]
[soft piano plays]
[uplifting music plays]
[door slams]
[engine stutters]
[uplifting music continues]
Jess: You'll never guess what happened to me today.