is actually the set
for seasons "all"
of Boardwalk Empire.
We're going to meet the show's
creator, and a main director,
main writer--
Terence Winter.
He came up writing spec
scripts in early '90s
Hollywood for such classy fare
as Sister, Sister and Xena:
Warrior Princess.
Then he became one of the main
staff writers on The Sopranos
and created this thing
with Martin Scorsese.
THOMAS MORTON: Hi.
TERENCE WINTER: Hi.
THOMAS MORTON: Thank you
for taking us out here.
What's going on today?--
some sort of glue?
TERENCE WINTER: This
is, I guess, just
touch up on the boardwalk.
These boards are actually
weathered.
I mean, Atlantic City is
actually right on the ocean,
so the whole place
is weathered.
Actually, when we built this,
even when it was brand-new, we
had to weather down the
boardwalk to make it look like
it wasn't new, because it's
supposed to be the real thing.
THOMAS MORTON: I wanted to ask
you because it's something
that's always kind of both
inspired and terrified me
about your history, is the
switching to screenwriting
when you were almost 30, which
is where I'm almost at.
Because you were in law, and you
did a bunch of other stuff
before that.
And you're from Brooklyn.
Was the writing thing something
you did on the side
and slowly simmered until you
couldn't take it, or was there
some sort of snap moment where
you kind of realized your--
TERENCE WINTER: It simmered.
I didn't do it on the side.
I hadn't written a script until
I already decided to
quit everything and just go
and fully commit to that.
My ambition as a kid was really
relegated to, I wanted
to make money, and by the time
I grew up a little bit, the
only two jobs that I was really
focused on that I knew
made a lot of money, or at least
I thought, were doctor
and lawyer.
So lawyer seemed feasible
because I was a pretty good
bullshit artist.
And I thought, all right,
well let me do that.
I didn't even consider whether
or not I would like it.
It just seemed like an important
job, and I wanted to
be important.
And have a diploma
written in Latin.
So I did that, and I was
really miserable.
But all the while, I was still
a big fan of movies and TV.
And that ambition was
sort of growing.
THOMAS MORTON: Now, did you
ever actually learn
screenwriting, or was it
in-built from years of
watching television and kind
of picking up the rhythms?
TERENCE WINTER: Yeah.
It was mostly that--
mostly osmosis.
And I started out
writing sitcoms.
I watched a gazillion hours
of TV sitcoms as a kid.
There's a station--
WPIX--
in New York-- channel 11 that in
the '60s and '70s just ran
Gilligan's Island, The Munsters,
The Abbott and
Costello Show--
just over and over again.
So I just soaked all that in.
And I felt like I understood the
rhythms of a sitcom, and
also the idea that a sitcom
sitcom script is 30 minutes
long, 22 minutes long.
And I thought, OK,
I can do this.
I got to L.A. I went to
the Writers' Guild.
I got actual physical scripts.
I looked at how they
were formatted--
I think, maybe read Syd Field's
screenplay book and
just got the basics, and
then I just plunged in.
I wrote a Doogie Howser
spec script.
That was the first thing I
ever wrote, because I had
heard about a guy back
in Brooklyn.
His uncle knew a guy who was an
electrician on Doogie Howser.
I thought, oh, this is great.
I'll just write a
Doogie Howser.
I'll get it to him, and I'll
get a job on the show.
THOMAS MORTON: Slide it under
the bathroom stall.
TERENCE WINTER: Yeah.
That, unfortunately, did not
happen, but that was it.
And then I just kept doing
it from there.
And I used to actually tape
sitcoms and dissect them.
I'd stop and watch a scene.
I'd write down what happened
in a scene.
I'd watch the next scene,
and write down
what happened in it.
It's almost like when people say
they want to grow up to be
an engineer, and they used to
take a radio apart and put it
back together.
I used to do that
with stories.
THOMAS MORTON: When you were
writing for sitcoms, like
Sister, Sister, and Xena, and
stuff, what were the other
writers like there?
I think a lot of people tend to
kind of look down on that
stuff as pretty lowbrow,
but it takes a level of
workmanship just to make
things that good.
TERENCE WINTER: Early on in my
career, I wasn't planning out
a career path.
If you offered me a job writing,
I would say yes.
I mean, that was my standard.
I just was thrilled to be making
a living at this, so I
was proud to have those jobs.
And, look, I mean, you take a
show like Sister, Sister.
It's a show generally written
for kids between the
ages of 9 and 13.
So, yeah, it's not going
to be Seinfeld.
It's a different animal.
And there are a lot of people
who worked on those types of
shows for a long time--
Full House, Family Matters.
That's a skill set.
And there's an audience for
that, and there's a generation
of kids who will look back at
that and go, ah, that was my
favorite show growing up.
I've actually gotten more
attention from friends' kids
for that than I have
for The Sopranos.
They go, oh, I used
to love that show.
THOMAS MORTON: How did you catch
David Chase's attention?
How did you start working
on The Sopranos?
TERENCE WINTER: I got
pilot the episode--
actually, the videotape.
I'm dating myself.
My agent sent me the tape of
the pilot of The Sopranos.
And he said, I want you
to watch this thing.
And I thought it was the
greatest thing I'd ever seen.
And I'd grown up in Brooklyn--
sort of knew people like
that in that world.
I actually worked in a butcher's
shop that was owned,
basically, by Paul Castellano,
who was the head of the
Gambino family at one point.
And I just sort of was familiar
with that terrain.
So I called my agent and
said, you've got to
get me on this show.
The second call was to a guy
named Frank Renzulli, who
co-created the first show I
ever worked on, called The
Great Defender.
Frank grew up in Boston in
a similar environment.
I said, have you seen
this thing?
He said, yeah, I'm actually
meeting with this guy David
Chase on Friday.
I said, you've got to get
me in there with you.
He said, I'll do my best.
As it turned out, Frank was the
last guy David hired for
his season one staff, so
the door got shut down.
So, basically, what happened
is most of the first year
staff didn't survive.
Frank was one of the
few people who did.
And when it came time for Season
2, finally, David said,
all right, who's this guy you've
been telling me about?
And he says, it's my friend,
Terry Winter.
I'm telling you, he can
write the show.
Just give him a shot.
And David did, and he gave me
an episode to write, and it
was basically an audition.
And the idea is if I did good,
I would get hired,
and I guess I did.
THOMAS MORTON: So it was yet
another spec script?
TERENCE WINTER: Yeah,
basically.
THOMAS MORTON: So you've got a
show you're making with Martin
Scorsese and Mick Jagger.
Can you tell us about that
or is it hush-hush?
TERENCE WINTER: Yeah.
We're developing a show that
we set in New York City in
1973, which was the year that
disco, hip-hop, and punk rock
sort of all were born--
centers around the music
business, if you haven't
guessed already.
Basically, an A and R guy sort
of the middle of his career.
And it was a really interesting
period, musically.
The city was at a low
point, in terms of
economics and crime.
And, as is often the case,
great art is born
of times like that.
And it was just an amazingly
fertile time for music.
And I'm lucky enough to be
working with Martin Scorsese
and Mick Jagger on this,
which is just--
these are the days when I wake
up and go, OK, I'm dreaming--
the first time you find yourself
in a room with those
two guys, and think,
how did I get here?
THOMAS MORTON: How was it going
from being a writer for
like 20 years into making
your own writing room.
And the whole show--
I'm sorry.
There's a lot more
to it that that.
But how hard of a transition
was that?
TERENCE WINTER: It wasn't
really hard.
I had the great good
fortune to learn at
the feet of the master.
David was just an incredible
manager of the entire show,
not just the writers' room,
but the whole thing--
and really great at putting a
crew together, and really
mixing and matching people who
really wanted to work together
and hang together, and we had
a really fun, happy set.
THOMAS MORTON: Well, could we
take a look around this set?
TERENCE WINTER: Yeah, sure.
Absolutely.
This is our Boardwalk set.
This is, I think, the size
of a football field.
It took months and
months to build.
It was designed by our
original production
designer, Bob Shaw.
It's essentially a replica of
the Atlantic City boardwalk,
circa 1920.
Most of the stories you see are
based on the research of
stores that were very similar
or actually existed in
Atlantic City.
The Fralinger's taffy store
is actually still there.
And the incubator baby exhibit
was actually something that
was in Atlantic City
and Coney Island.
THOMAS MORTON: Worth paying
$0.25 to see,
some underweight babies.
TERENCE WINTER: Yeah.
Really, Atlantic City was
so cool because it means
everything from highbrow
entertainment, like the best
of Broadway, to lowbrow stuff,
like carnival stuff.
THOMAS MORTON: How much
research did--
I know you're fastidious about
it for the creation of the
show, but in its initial
inception, how much background
had you done when you were
bringing it to the table?
TERENCE WINTER: Oh, months
and months of research.
There are so many different
components to the show.
There's the World War I
component with Jimmy Darmody.
-I've been kissing your
ass since I was 12.
-And what about the
last three years?
-I wanted to serve my country.
-And nearly get yourself
killed.
TERENCE WINTER: There was the
prohibition component, the
political component.
-This establishment is being
shuttered for violation of the
Volstead Act.
-It's loaded, sir.
There is over 200 cases of
brandy wine and champagne.
TERENCE WINTER: Pop culture--
there were so many different
aspects of the show--
what was going on in the
gangster world, what was going
on in Chicago.
-You guys gonna get into the
liquor business, too?
THOMAS MORTON: Now, was there
something before the book that
led you into it, or was that
the primary source?
TERENCE WINTER: No.
The book--
I started there, and the book
was given to me by HBO.
This wasn't something that was
necessarily on my radar.
I didn't know what I was going
to do next after The Sopranos.
HBO called me up in 2007 during
the last season, and
they said we have a book called
Boardwalk Empire.
It's basically the history
of Atlantic City.
Why don't you read it and see
if you think there's a TV
series in there.
And oh, by the way, Martin
Scorcese's attached to this.
The signage has changed from
season to season, too, because
they advertise different things
on the boardwalk.
This set over here we're
coming to is called the
Swiss-Knit Shop.
And we couldn't figure
out what that was.
And what it is is that people
would rent bathing suits, and
they were knit wool
bathing suits.
So you wear a wool bathing suit,
and then give it back,
and it was actually rented
to somebody else.
THOMAS MORTON: I think
I'd rather spend my
quarter on the preemies.
TERENCE WINTER: Actually, the
boards on this are actually--
this is the level of detail--
I don't know if you noticed,
like, some of them, like, form
an arrow facing that way,
and some form an
arrow facing that way.
If you're moving either north
or south on the boardwalk,
they basically tell you
which way to walk.
THOMAS MORTON: Oh, so they're
kind of like lanes.
TERENCE WINTER: Yeah, sort of.
If you're heading this
way, stay this side.
And that way, the other side.
THOMAS MORTON: You mean that's
how it is on the
Atlantic City boardwalk?
I've never heard of that.
TERENCE WINTER: Yeah, these are
absolutely the same pattern.
THOMAS MORTON: Psychological
pressure to keep moving.
TERENCE WINTER: Yeah,
exactly, and head
in the right direction.
One of the few things that we
purposely changed was the fact
that our benches face
toward the ocean.
In Atlantic City, they actually
face toward the
boardwalk, so people would
actually watch each other
promenade in their Easter
bonnets and stuff.
But we figured, in modern day
you'd want to look at the
ocean, even though we don't
have an actual ocean.
We put it in later digitally.
This is the Ritz Carlton
set where Nucky
lives and has his offices.
He actually lived in the real
Ritz Carlton in Atlantic City,
but the real Ritz Carlton was
one of the few really kind of
boring looking structures.
It didn't really have anything
special about it, so we
cheated a little.
We took another hotel whose
name I can't remember, and
said, well, we'll call that
the Ritz Carlton because
nobody really knows, because
it just looked more fancy--
so built it out, and, yeah, a
little more, like, befitting a
guy like Nucky.
And the great thing about this
set is you can come right in
and go all the way
to the elevators.
And the elevators don't go up,
but the doors open and close.
So you can take him right off
the elevator, open it up, and
have people in here talking,
drinking tea, playing the
piano, and right all the way
straight out into the
boardwalk in one shot,
and it just really
makes it come alive.
It's also, you remember this
factored in pretty
heavily in Season 1--
the Belle Femme dress shop--
and this-- same thing--
you can walk right in there, and
have people interacting,
and looking through
the window.
And it just gives life
that goes far
beyond your normal set.
And, just again, the level of
detail from our production
design, it's just--
everything just looks so--
see, this chandelier is like--
yeah, it's amazing.
THOMAS MORTON: It's
incredible.
Well, thank you, man.
This has been a real
good time.
TERENCE WINTER: My
pleasure, man.
Really nice meeting you
and talking to you.