and uh... then they want to add more
loopholes
now normal isn't having that passes
actually
bless your heart snow a lot of you out
there were saying oh aging sebi adrian b
he got this right he said that
uh... gun control laws in the past
well to be fair that's only half true
uh... i fought the assault-weapons ban
was going to pass of course is that he
got crotch
on a forty votes
freer tho busted even have a filibuster
and then uh...
uh... high-capacity magzine that i said
that was in the past
net income goes either
i got about forty six votes that also
didn't get a majority soda all i was
sure right about that stuff
but i actually thought and i was i even
of at some point i guess i think the
background checks
would be a fig leaf
that they would say all right here you
go get some background checks nine new
much anyway
well you know we kill the relevant
portions the spell
and that it would be you know obama
moment it with a mission accomplished up
their and that's a historic gun control
legislation
and particularly i fought back
because bloomberg came to a twelve
million dollars
now twelve million dollars makes a lot
of nevers and politics is pressuring you
run ads against
certain politicians apparently they
haven't gotten that memo yet
they definitely got that are a mammal
because then or is this thing out money
for decades
now things might turn around a couple
years i'll tell you i am i turn around
in my body and a couple years two things
that happen
those bloomberg ads are gonna run and
then the politicians are gonna start to
feel the pain of that
and it's already become immediate to
them
animator dot all man all i didn't know
you have that much money
whether there are a had more money okay
my battles which my book
the same thing that's going to happen is
base root out today
so uh... the main
background check by board of drums up
compromise obviously didn't pass right
why is that a screw-up
because you're supposed to put a fig
leaf on a this is how washington
normally works
and say we solve it and move on
but you didn't do that so what happened
was anger
live so they're trying to cut the same
time anything into it
hang on this
it's the n_r_a_ overplaying their hand
the bill was already incredibly weak
you should have just take it
instead you jump the shark
there's signifi enter in the country now
look
it stretches out
across everyone but it started at this
moment when buying city and of course as
the head of the senate businesses role
but he does time to time as the vice
president
uh... ceremony only
uh... window votes were announcers what
up
yours and
the world
on his vote the yeas are fifty four
the nature of forty-six under the
previous order requiring sixty votes
reduction in this amendment
the amendment
is not agreed to
it not been reading but i got your name
who cares majority doesn't rule anymore
the minority rules because harried in
his infinite stupidity didn't fix a
filibuster
hindu reform on that not meeting for for
what he did it at that link report
which have not former all so little
problem is you know i don't give a damn
at ninety one percent the country grease
with this
i don't care you don't who you've got
shot and you brought the family members
are
out your own
where i get paid by the n_r_a_ i'd vote
no and i feel about straight
so even though they have plenty of all
it's a passenger or any
it got killed anyway that's when
uh... two women in vertigo started
uh... sings share
aim shez
who are they want a lead researcher may
show shea
which is a person
who's stopping jhrlaw funner
from grabbing his third clap
she's a hero tucson arizona
they always say like our differences and
they have any both are in a magazine
or guns don't kill people well patricia
may says that that's not true
i saw on my own eyes the war does he
have a more bullets he had killed more
people he killed she knows she's the one
at the concert magazine away
in fact i wanted or course right now
she said
looked you don't have established
starters hussein issue should be ashamed
from the rafters right
there of course escort her out of the
chamber
and in the capital poisonous for out of
the building when reporters definite
and what what the police do and they
talked her here's what she says
when i was told
it was done
i decided that i could not stay
still any longer
that they needed to be ashamed of
themselves
they have no souls
they have no compassion
for the experiences that people have
lived through
having a child or loved one murdered by
a gun
issue and i must say
there are nim barris man to our country
as giving that's harsh way to get a
lotta gabby giffords
she's of course a congresswoman was shot
mad
and she did not pull back either she put
out a statement say moments ago the u_s_
senate decided to do the unthinkable
about gun violence
nothing
at all
he went on to say
over two years ago
when i was shot point-blank in their
head
the u_s_ senate shows and do nothing
four months ago twenty first graders
lost their lives
and a brutal attack on their school
and the u_s_ senate shows to do nothing
it's clear to me that members of the
u_s_ senate
refused to change the laws
to reduce gun violence then we need to
change
the members of the u_s_ senate
damn straight
but that's my khana language
you either
get a lot of ninety one percent of the
country
when you get the hell out of the this
place
that this is what we need to spend money
time energy resources
to make sure but the people who voted
against this bill that they'd leave
politically
we go to get them
well that pitchfork
and if it takes bloomberg's miami you
grab bloomberg's money
everything's getting different safe
shame on you i got shot on the head
out your fellow congresswoman
i got shot padding you didn't know
anything about it
well then that's what we know s
this isn't coming for your guns
this is the simplest
piece of legislation
hate week you can just buy a gun without
doing a background check
we need to know what your credibility or
terrorist
but there are a so strong it doesn't
matter you can buy a gun even if you're
on the terrorist watchlist did you know
that
that's why it because it ad already has
this
congress lock stock and barrel they got
locked up
and they shot it today
ashamed
at the very least they should be ashamed
so now were nowhere
nowhere we've gotten awfully
but that andrew will rise and now let me
tell you the third reason
why they will eventually lose on this
because unfortunately there will be
another tragedy
solely a matter of time
the mass shootings keep on coming in
i wish that hell they didn't
but they do
you think there won't be another
horrible tragic nationally
and you think it won't happen relatively
soon
you they would have to wait a couple of
years i wish we waited forever and never
happen again
but it's gonna happen again and again
that and again
and then the next time
you wanna cnr
is going to be real anger
because you know why
you didn't do the one thing you're
supposed to do most of all
you're supposed to protect the citizens
protecting the citizens isn't
going in and being a country like iraq
had been the packers
starting senseless war so defense
contractors
an auto companies gain get paid in get
rich
protecting our sentences
is making sure that what young kids
don't get shot and killed in a
classes they went to
it's pretty it
something you're not only for becca
gotten stable from getting shot of the
head
you know as all these people are saying
uganda has had you know she
but the answer is obvious
of course they don't
of course they don't all they care about
is
who signs my checks
and if there are a signing my checks i
don't give a damn who gets murdered
that's what the boat was about today