But they're not even a household
name in the United States--
yet.
K-pop sensation 2NE1
just dropped two videos
and practically
broke the internet.
[MUSIC - 2NE1]
Last week, they released their
first album in four years,
and it's about the crack the
top 10 in the iTunes charts.
2NE1 kicked off a huge
tour last weekend,
but if you're not going to have
the chance to see them live,
head over to their
channel for almost 300
more servings of
K-pop awesomessness.
Hey, it's Amy Pham.
Amy, episode two of "Ask
Amy!" is online right now.
AMY PHAM: Indeed it is!
JACOB SOBOROFF: What
is going on with that?
AMY PHAM: People
can ask questions,
whether it's a style
dilemma, fashion problem,
or any other question
they want to ask me.
And we feature their
questions on the show.
AUDIENCE: How can I wear
a full leather jumpsuit
without looking
like a dominatrix?
AMY PHAM: You are
ballsy, and I love it.
The key to this
outfit is to pair
the super tough,
badass leather fabric
with softer, casual
details to keep
it less superhero
and more street wear.
JACOB SOBOROFF: Do people
ask about, like, underpants?
AMY PHAM: No, actually.
I haven't gotten one yet.
I want them to.
I would love to address
underpants situations.
JACOB SOBOROFF: If you
have a fashion dilemma,
or if you think I have a
fashion dilemma that Amy
could help me deal with--
AMY PHAM: You send
them to the platform
using the hashtag #AskAmy.
JACOB SOBOROFF: When you dial
9-11 in this neighborhood,
the fire department may
not be the first to arrive.
Rocky Robinson co-founded
the Bed-Stuy Ambulance Core
when his niece died due to lack
immediate medical attention.
And he realized he needed
do something about it.
ROCKY ROBINSON: I
saw this group called
Hatzola, a Jewish
Ambulance Core.
When I was working with EMS,
and what we got on the scene,
Hatzola already had their
people to the hospital.
But then when we'd
respond to the ghetto,
the person was dead
most of the time
because the ambulance
took too long to come.
JACOB SOBOROFF: The People's
EMS is entirely funded
by donations, and even the
commander's own pension
when the money gets tight.
To learn more about
what is really
just an incredible organization,
head over to their website
and you can get involved.
CARLY: I love books,
like, love, love books.
Like,
the-floor-of-my-apartment-is-probably-going-to-collapse-due-to-the-weight-of-all-of-my-bookcases
love books.
Which is why this gorgeous
stop-m motion animation
tugs at every single one of
my bookworm heart strings.
I can't believe this is made
by an animation student.
And it only has a few hundred
views, so let's fix that.
If you know a book lover
or two, send this their way
and brighten their day.
Hey, that rhymes!
JACOB SOBOROFF: CT Fletcher
has three drug-free world
titles in bench press,
three curling titles,
and less than a decade ago,
he flat-lined three times
during open heart surgery.
But that didn't
stop the 54-year-old
from coming back and winning
the drug-free world bodybuilding
title.
In this video, with
almost 2 million views,
he introduces us to his friend,
appropriately called Da Hulk.
CT FLETCHER: We
about to break bread
and eat up in this [BLEEP].
Hulk crash!
And there's a whole bunch of
[BLEEP] on YouTube going, What?
JACOB SOBOROFF: Fair
warning-- his videos
have no shortage of f-bombs.
But if you're down
with that, they
will get you pumped up for
anything-- Job interviews,
tennis matches, calling your
bank-- whatever your thing is.
Sometimes people here are
so passionate about getting
a video on this show,
they'll submit it
outside of working hours.
You know who you are.
EARNEST: Hey, Jacob.
It's Earnest, of course.
And I want to share with you
this thing called "Big Head,"
and it's the funniest thing
that you will see today.
BIG HEAD: Has anyone
seem my gloves?
Really need to know
where my gloves are.
Of course I looked
in my coat pocket!
That's the first place I looked!
Now I can't go into work
early, use the bathroom
like I normally do.
I know they're not in my car so
I'm not even going to go check.
Yeah, they weren't in my car.
JACOB SOBOROFF: Thanks, Earnest.
We want to know what
you guys are watching.
Film yourself talking about
a video that you love,
and then post it with the
hashtag #youtubenation.
Now play us out, Liam Lynch.
[MUSIC - LIAM LYNCH, "COOKIES
FOR LATER"]