-Whoa.
It's been a couple of torturous
days of riding the
dirtiest, sandiest, windiest
conditions.
It's nice to be somewhere
moist and warm.
How is it?
-This is paradise.
You can't open your beer.
-Home spa.
-Oh!
-Save it.
Save it.
[MUSIC IN SPANISH]
[FILM REEL SOUNDS]
[PROPELLER]
ARTO SAARI: I think Patrick sent
me either a text message,
or he might have called
me, actually.
And said, you want to go to Baja
with a bunch of people,
and go ride motorcycles
and skateboard?
And I was like, fuck, that
sounds amazing and dangerous.
Yeah, let's go.
I went on a trip with Heath
before, an Alien trip.
I've seen Patrick around, but
I'd never traveled with him.
Right as Patrick called me,
I was reading a newspaper.
I think it was like three
newspapers that I saw in the
next three days that all had
front page news about drug
cartels in Mexico.
And of course I read them all
and I was just so freaked out.
I was like, oh, this is what
it's going to be like.
It's going to be all about
just craziness.
I felt like whoever's going to
come on the trip, they're
going to be fucking badass.
And they're going to fucking
stick through it.
And that's it, whoever
shows up.
HEATH KIRCHART: This is my main
mode of transportation.
I ride a motorcycle like it's
A to B at this point.
I don't really care
where I go.
I care who I go with, and as
long as I'll be comfortable.
Arto had been like on
a four day trip.
He was on a tour with
Alien and tripped
with us for four days.
And we rode in separate cars.
Like, I didn't really know
Arto before this.
They're people I respect.
So they're people
I like to know.
And it's good for these trips
for that to force me into
that, basically, to
get to know them.
I'm old and these
trips are gone.
So I take them when
I can get them.
PATRICK O'DELL: I think I just
thought the more the better.
And anyone that's down, I feel
like anyone that you tell, OK,
we're going to ride-- how
many miles is it?
2,000 miles or something
through the desert.
Anyone that's down to do that
should get to come.
Because they're down
to do that.
[CAR HORN]
HIME HERBERT: Fuck.
My real name's actually James
David Herbert the Fourth.
But everybody calls me Hime.
Patrick sent me a text message
that said we're going to Baja
for a few days.
He said two guys from Vancouver
were coming.
Harvey and Ky showed up.
I introduced myself,
saw Harvey didn't
have a front tooth.
And I knew from that point
on this was going
to be pretty epic.
[LAUGHING].
Most people I know without front
teeth are pretty epic.
HARVEY FOSTER: And the truth
of the trip, too.
Ky told me about the Mexico
trip, and I was like, there's
like gang wars and killings
and swine flu.
What?
Why?
Why would you want to put
yourself through that.
He was like, Harvey, man,
that's just the TV.
I'm going to do it.
I was like, all right.
OK.
I'm with you on these trips.
[MOTORS RUMBLING]
HARVEY FOSTER: All it takes is
someone to plan something out.
I usually jump on board.
[MUSIC - ROLLA OLAK, "WNTYO"]
ARTO SAARI: As soon as I got
on the bike, I was antsy.
I was shit scared until
we got 20 minutes
away from the border.
HARVEY FOSTER: I loved it.
When we were riding into
Tijuana, I think I was the
only one that noticed that
big ass Mexican flag.
And I was like, we're doing
this right now.
We're entering their
fucking territory.
And then everyone's like, we're
going to blast through.
Don't worry everyone.
But the whole time, I was like,
I want to just chill.
There's all these Mexicans
standing here.
I've never been to Mexico.
I've seen Mexicans in
California, but then I just
think they're like now
Americans, right?
So I was like, whoa.
They're just sitting
on a fence.
Why are they just sitting
on-- what?
Are they going to try to make
a run for the border?
And everyone was
blasting ahead.
And I was like, well, there's
someone behind me kind of
going a bit slower.
So can I slow down a
little bit, too?
I liked that first
day, though.
I had a lot of fun.
ARTO SAARI: Just driving next
to the wall coming out of TJ
through the border and cutting
across to the beach, with a
lot of wind and a lot of sand
in your face between trucks
and cars and this and that.
It's just like [GASPING]
oh fuck.
And I didn't know anything
about Baja.
Whatever.
After we got through the first
toll booth, it was just like,
oh, it's going to be good.
[MUSIC - FERNANDO GONZALEZ,
"CIELITO LINDO"]
BILL BRYANT: I think my first
time in Baja was 1984.
Came down to help pit crew
for a local racer.
And that sort of cracked the
seal on the whole Baja thing.
I've been coming down
ever since.
This was a different group than
what I'm used to riding
with, because no one had ridden
together, as far as I know.
Well, Canadians had ridden with
Heath, and what have you.
But there wasn't a whole lot of
experience riding together.
One of the first things that
I asked, is it a bunch of
spoiled brat kids?
Because you're pretty much on
your own and just have to be
self-reliant.
And there's not a whole
lot of external help.
You can't really trust
the police.
You don't know whether
to trust the army.
And that's part of what
makes me consider it
sort of Wild West-like.
It depends.
In Ensanada, you got to wear
your helmet, or they're going
to pull you over.
I've gone everywhere else on the
peninsula without it, and
had no problem.
How are you going to prove that
there's a helmet law or
there's not a helmet law?
I don't know, you know
what I mean?
[MUSIC - ROLLA OLAK,
"SWAMP FANG"]
BILL BRYANT: We've done a bunch
of racing down here.
So we've been on a lot of the
stuff that you can't pass in a
regular car.
Or some stuff you can, but you
would just never go in a
regular car to try and discover
it, because you don't
know what you're getting into.
The road to Cuatros I think was
a surprise to the guys.
There wasn't a whole lot of
information given to everybody
before on what exactly
to expect.
We had that little informal
breakfast, and
I said a few things.
And maybe somebody listened.
I don't know.
HEATH KIRCHART: I had no
idea what he said.
BILL BRYANT: And I don't
even know if I
mentioned the dirt road.
[TIRE POPPING]
PATRICK O'DELL: [SHOUT].
Damn it.
Fuck.
We just turn off, and I'm
thinking it's like right
there, right off the highway,
the hotel was going
to be, or the spot.
But it was miles.
Like you get over a hill
thinking, OK, it's going to be
right there.
And then I remember seeing
the ocean, and
nothing in any direction.
And I remember seeing way off
in the distance some smoke,
and thinking there's no way
that's where we're going.
And it was.
HARVEY FOSTER: That was
fun, though, man.
And it was kind of like, yeah,
totally destination unknown.
[MOTORS RUMBLING]
-Fucking great ride, guys.
-Nailed it.