Who are you talking to?
No one.
Well tell no one I said nothing.
Okay.
- Hey mom.
- Hi.
Mind if I watch some futbol?
Well at least one of kids
is speaking to me today.
Of course sweetheart, go ahead.
Thank you.
Hey honey, what's up?
Nobody. Nowhere. No nothing.
Hey, Kevin.
What are you up to?
Nothin'.
Just watching football.
Football?
I didn't know
you were into football.
Are you kidding?
It's the greatest sport
in the world.
My man.
I didn't even know
the preseason had started.
The super classic continues.
It's a huge one today,
as it's the Western conference
semifinals game two, tied 2-all.
What's this?
Put it on football.
What do you mean?
This is football.
Boy, my eyes may not be
what they used to be,
but I know the difference
between soccer and football.
Now, change the channel.
This is real football,
futbol.
I don't know
what fruit bowl is,
but in America,
we play football,
the sport I played
in college,
with the pads
and the helmets
and the guys
who knock each other around,
the sport real men play.
Goal!
No fair.
He used his hands.
What kind of sport
doesn't let a man use his has?
No wonder
nobody watches this stuff.
It's the most popular sport
in the world.
That may be,
but it's the least popular
sport in my house.
Now, change the channel.
Change the channel.
You know what?
It's not fruit bowl, okay?
It's futbol.
Look it up in the dictionary.
Futbol, man.
Suzanne.
♪ Are we there yet? ♪
The Soccer Episode
S01x04 Original Air Date on June 9, 2010
♪ tell me, tell me, tell me ♪
♪ tell me,
are we there yet? ♪
-- sync, corrected by elderman --
-- for www.addic7ed.Com --
goal, goal, goal,
goal, goal!
Yes!
Hey, Kevin.
This came for you.
Cool.
What's that?
It's my autographed photo
of Hope Solo.
She is my favorite
football player.
There are no football players
named Hope.
Football players have names
like mean Joe Green,
Refrigerator Perry,
L.T., T.O., A.P., Eli.
What about Chris Hope
on the Tennessee Titans?
Can you frame that for me?
Sure.
Goal!
Yes.
Hey, baby.
Hey.
What are you doing?
Uh, taking a quiz.
Who is Tyra Cyrus?
Oh, that's me.
I created a fake profile
and friended
one of Lindsey's friends.
That way,
she would friend me.
This way,
I can see her profile.
So since your daughter
won't speak to you,
you decided the best way to get
to know her was to spy on her?
Hey, that's the way we deal
with North Korea.
And, Nick, it's not spying.
It's friending.
Do what you want,
but I think it's a bad idea.
Did you know that Lindsey
is into saving the dolphins?
And if she had $5,000,
she'd spend it on a Segway.
Why wouldn't she spend it
on saving the dolphins?
Because nobody asked you.
Who is that?
Oh, that's Hope Solo.
Did you know
Kevin was into soccer?
Yes.
I'm his mother.
He's been into soccer
since he was five.
What's the problem?
The problem is,
it's a girls' sport.
Only men I know
who play soccer
are Pele and that dude
who married Posh Spice.
You're worried
about my son's masculinity,
but you know
who Posh Spice is?
That's 'cause I like girls.
I'm not trying
to Bend it like Beckham.
Okay, well,
Kevin loves soccer.
You should give it a chance.
You might like it too.
No way.
I like using my hands too much.
He should give football
a chance.
Well, do what you want.
I know my children.
Lindsey just joined the group
"Megan Fox must be stopped."
Hmph.
Hey, buddy.
Got here
as fast as I could.
Thanks.
You got it?
Bam.
Here it is, Madden 11.
This baby is so new,
John Madden
doesn't even know about it.
Put it over there
by Barkley.
I didn't think
Kevin was into football.
He's not.
That's the problem.
He's into soccer.
And his favorite athlete's
a girl.
I don't want to have
to buy him a sports bra.
Mm, ouch.
And the final score
is girl power 1,
father figure nothing.
All that's gonna change
after we play a few games
of Madden.
Unless he plays it
and decides he wants
to be a cheerleader.
It happens.
Uh.
Who are you, strange boy
sending my daughter gifts?
I'm gonna have
to friend you too.
Suzanne,
I have an emergency.
What is it?
You know that guy
I've been dating, Jonathan?
Yeah.
What did he do?
Nothing.
That's the problem.
Every time I call him,
he doesn't answer.
And when I ask
why he didn't call me back,
he acts like
he never got the message.
So last night,
I tried one last time
to get his attention
by sending him
naked pictures of me.
No, you didn't.
Yes, I did.
And he didn't respond.
So tomorrow I'm gonna
break up with him.
Okay, what's the problem?
You've broken up
with tons of guys.
The problem is,
I want to make sure
those pictures are deleted
off his phone first,
because the last thing
you want to do
is break up with a guy
who has naked pictures of you.
I mean, you've seen
what happened to John Edwards.
Okay, what do you
need me to do?
Okay.
Tomorrow night, I'm going out
to dinner with him,
and at 9:00,
I need you to call me.
And when I answer, I'm gonna act
like my phone went dead
and ask to borrow his phone.
And then I'm gonna go
into his phone
and delete the pictures
I sent him.
Why don't you just ask him
to delete them?
Like a man would voluntarily
delete naked pictures of me.
I don't think so.
That's funny, though.
Right.
Click
click
What are you doing
with my hat?
I'm trying to take
a better picture for my profile.
Well, if you wanted
a better picture,
you might as well wear
a paper bag over your head.
- Give me my hat.
- No.
- Give me my hat!
- No!
What's wrong with you?
Hey, hey, hey, you two.
What is going on?
Nothing.
Whoa.
What's wrong with Lindsey?
I don't know,
but I am about
to find out.
Hey, Kevin,
you want to test out
a early version
of the new Madden game?
Madden?
What's that?
It's a football game,
NFL football.
Sure, I guess.
All right, cool.
See, it's working.
What's the latest
on Lindsey?
She just updated
her profile pic,
and Jenny likes it.
It's working.
"Me too."
Smiley face,
send.
All right, Kevin,
I'll be the Seahawks.
You should be the Vikings.
They have Adrian Peterson,
the fastest-rated player.
Who's got the best kicker?
Kevin, no one picks a team
based on the kicker.
The Lions' kicker looks good.
I'll be them.
No, no.
You cannot be the Lions.
Kevin, the Lions
are the only team
in the history of the NFL
to go 0 and 16.
I don't even know
why they wear uniforms.
They should just play
in jean shorts.
I don't care.
I want to be the Lions.
Fine, you can be the Lions.
But don't come crying to me
when you don't reach
the end zone.
What's an end zone?
Okay, this is gonna be
a long game.
To return this kick.
McGill still going.
Yes.
First down.
Not bad, Kev.
You made it
down to the 40-yard line.
I think you might be better
than the actual Detroit Lions.
Wait. Wait.
What are you doing?
You can't line up
for a field goal.
Why not?
Because it's first down,
and you're
on the 40-yard line.
You want to score
a touchdown.
I like field goals.
And it's good.
Yes!
Field goal.
58 yards
straight down the middle.
This kid can kick.
Pick up...
Pick up the thing.
Let's go.
I'll whup you.
He's down to the 10,
the 5, and fumble!
Oh! And the Lions take over
at the Seahawks' 1-yard line.
Ho, baby.
And in a surprise move,
the kicking team
trots back out onto the field.
Wait.
What are you doing?
You're on the 1-yard line.
You have one yard to go
for a touchdown.
I like field goals.
Yes! Field goal!
And our score:
Lions 6, Seahawks 0.
Pick it up.
Come on.
I'm hungry.
Pick it up. Let's go.
Play.
Field goal.
Field goal!
Yes!
I win.
Turn out the lights, folks.
This party is over.
I can't believe you won
on all field goals.
Hey, at least you were right
about one thing:
He never did make it
to the end zone.
Touchdowns are stupid.
Why would you let everybody
hit you
when you can just kick it
right over their heads?
He does have a point.
Plus, lots of these kickers
were former soccer players,
and everybody knows
soccer players are better
than football players.
Excuse me?
I know
a lot of soccer players
who could easily
play football.
I don't know
any football players
who could play soccer.
And you are excused.
I was a football player,
and I could beat you in soccer
any day of the week.
How about tomorrow?
We can have a shoot-out.
Fine.
What's a shoot-out?
What's a shoot-out, man?
Hi Lindsey
"If you're still
thinking about it,
I say go for it."
Go for what?
Hey, Lindsey.
Hey.
Been thinking
about anything?
Not really.
Going for something?
Huh?
No.
Hey, Gigi.
You're not gonna
believe this.
What now?
That man deleted
naked pictures of me.
Voluntarily?
Yes!
Last night worked perfectly
when you called me.
But when I borrowed
Jonathan's phone
and went outside to delete
the pictures I sent him,
they weren't even there.
That's great.
No, it's not.
I don't send those pictures
to just anybody.
How dare he delete them?
Wait.
I thought the whole point
of this scheme
was to get your pictures
off of his phone.
Yes, it's okay
if I delete them,
but he shouldn't.
He should be sending them
all over the Internet.
I should be on the front page
of Media Takeout.
I see.
Gigi, what's up
with the gear?
Oh, I just came
from boxing class.
I'm trying to work off
my aggression
before I see him
again tonight,
because this time,
I'm gonna make him beg me
to send him pictures,
and then
I'm gonna dump him.
I see.
Well, that'll teach him
to delete
inappropriate pictures of you
that you wanted
to delete anyway.
I knew you'd understand.
Did you drive like that?
Can you help me?
- Gigi.
- What?
There's no
peripheral vision.
You can't even see.
Well, I didn't have to see
all that much.
It was just a straight line,
then I had to turn,
and then
another straight line.
Then I did a u-turn.
Agh!
Bring it in.
What makes the grass grow?
Chalk makes the grass grow.
Dah.
Hut, hut, hut.
Hah!
Huh! Hah!
What are you doing?
Defensive football drills.
Soccer players wouldn't know
anything about it.
What are you doing here?
Somebody had to bring
the snacks.
Plus, I need to be here
to make sure everything is fair
and that nobody has anything
to complain about,
no matter what happens.
Orange slice?
You ready?
I was born ready.
Goal!
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
I wasn't ready.
Now I'm ready.
Oh!
Goal!
You know what?
You'd better enjoy that one,
'cause that's gonna be
the last one you get.
Oh!
Oh. Ahh!
Look, Gigi.
Lindsey has 69 friends
on here.
Wow.
Bang!
Look, she's taken a quiz:
"Who is your
biracial boyfriend?"
And she's joined
another group.
"Did you know Megan Fox
has club thumbs?"
What is up with her
and Megan Fox?
Oh, look,
she's been poked 67 times.
And Jeremy commented
on her post,
"am thinking about going
all the way this week."
What do you think that means?
I think it means
what it's always meant.
Sex? No way.
Mm-mm, not my Lindsey.
That could mean
any number of things.
What is going on
out there?
Soccer shoot-out.
Oh, soccer players.
So athletic.
What do you mean, it could mean
any number of things?
I don't know.
Well, you need to have
a talk with your daughter.
Bang!
I don't believe this.
And while
you're on the subject,
make sure you tell her
never to send a guy
naked cell phone pictures.
How'd the game go?
It was great.
I beat him 10 to 1.
He did better
than I thought, though.
Well, why don't you
go upstairs and get cleaned up?
I didn't even
break a sweat.
Go.
Fine.
Nick, I need to talk to you
about Lindsey.
Can we do it
sitting down?
Okay, so Lindsey
is thinking about having sex.
I saw it on her web page.
See? I told you spying on her
would lead to trouble.
Spying on who?
Lindsey, would you
have a seat, please?
Um, okay.
Maybe I should leave
you two alone.
No, Nick, you stay.
I need your support
on this.
Fine.
What's this about?
Your mother--
are you thinking
about having sex?
What? Why would you ask me
something like that?
I saw it on your web page
that you're thinking
about going all the way.
You saw my web page?
How?
I created a fake profile
so I could see it.
Lindsey,
why didn't you tell me
that you were thinking
about having sex?
I thought I could trust you
to come to me
with things like this.
Wait a minute.
You created a fake profile
to spy on me,
and you're talking
about trust?
I was just trying
to find out more about you,
because it seems like you never
want to talk to me anymore.
Well, that's not the way
you go about it, mom,
and I'm not thinking
about having sex.
Then why does it say
on your profile
that you're thinking
about going all the way?
I was talking
about my hair.
I hated my last haircut,
and I was thinking
about cutting it really short.
Really?
Really.
How could you spy on me
like that?
Sweetheart,
I'm sorry
for spying on you.
It was wrong and stupid.
Will you forgive me?
Yes.
Which one of my friends
are you?
Tyra Cyrus.
Tyra Cyrus?
Really?
That was nice.
No thanks to you.
You barely said anything.
Thanks for backing me up.
I never knew soccer
could be so hard, Charles.
All I wanted to do
was prove to the little guy
I still had it,
like when you played
with Scottie Pippen,
although we did make
a little connection.
I spent more time with him
in the last two days
than I did
the whole last month.
How are you feeling?
Like I just played
a double-overtime game
in the Super Bowl and lost.
Oh, my big, strong man.
Ow.
Ooh.
I'm sure you probably
let him win.
Yeah, kind of did.
Thanks, baby.
Kevin loves soccer.
That's not gonna change.
You know what else
is never gonna change?
How much I love you.
Come on,
let's go inside,
and I'll rub
your tired old legs.
Oh, let's go.
Any chance
we could stay out here?
Oh. Ow.
Ooh.
Oh, my goodness.
I know.
Okay.
Whoo, help me.
Morning.
Oh, did you break up
with Jonathan yet?
Actually, no.
Get this: Turns out
I always had his number wrong,
which explains why he never
returned my calls
and why my pictures
weren't on his phone.
He never got them.
So who's been getting
your pictures?
I don't know.
I texted the person
this morning,
but I haven't heard back yet.
Oh, the mystery person.
"Hi, my name is Carl."
Oh, no, it's a guy.
"Thanks for the pics.
"Let's get together soon.
Here's a picture of me."
Eww!
Doesn't anybody send pictures
of their faces anymore?
You didn't.
Oh, damn, now I got to get
a new phone.
All right, with seconds
left on the clock,
double-k-p sets up.
He shoots.
Goal!
And the crowd goes wild!
Hey, man.
Hey.
I got something for you.
Who's this?
Pete Gogolak,
placekicker for the Giants
and was also responsible
for bringing soccer-style
kicking to the NFL.
Whoa. Thanks, dad.
I love it.
Turns out
he was also the Giants'
all-time leading scorer.
A former soccer player.
Who'd have guessed it, huh?
Yeah.
I guess
I underestimated you.
Hey, I'm ten.
It happens.
So she's your favorite
soccer player, huh?
Yup, but that's not
why I wanted the picture.
Huh?
No, it's 'cause she's hot.
-- sync, corrected by elderman --
-- for www.addic7ed.Com --