DAVID CHOE: In the end,
only kindness matters.
That's what Jewel says.
And this is where she's going
to be playing, at the
Horseshoe Casino Hotel in
beautiful Tunica, Mississippi.
And not to be a cocktease--
I have absolutely no desire
to see Jewel.
I'm here to gamble
with some money.
Got a cash advance on
my credit card.
I need to buy a boat.
I want to go down the
Mississippi River.
Thumbs up, America.
Hate to do the obnoxious money
shot, but, 20 minutes later,
nice hand at the blackjack
tables with
Jeff, the dealer, and--
looks like I got some
boat money.
Hate to be a fucking prick,
but you know how it goes.
Ready for a nice boat
ride, Harry?
HARRY (OFFSCREEN):
Let's do it.
To win some, you lose some.
DAVID CHOE: Tunica,
Mississippi.
M-I-S-S-I-S-S-I-P-P-I.
HARRY: It's time you won.
Let's do it.
DAVID CHOE: Benny, who's wearing
a shirt that says
Benny Thompson, but it's
actually not him, just came
out here to warn us that a
lady complained about--
BENNY: And she thought
y'all were some
terrorists or something.
DAVID CHOE (OFFSCREEN): She
thought we were terrorists
because we're backpacked
and we're foreigners.
BENNY: Yeah.
DAVID CHOE: All right.
What are they saying exactly?
There's foreigners out there
that look like terrorists?
BENNY: Yeah, but you
don't though.
DAVID CHOE: Bin Laden's
cousin.
BENNY: [INAUDIBLE].
Where y'all hiking to?
HARRY: Well we want to go
to Greenville tonight.
DAVID CHOE (OFFSCREEN): Well,
the only reason why we might
want to go to Greenville is
there's a Walmart there, and
there's an inflatable
raft at the Walmart
that's waiting for us.
I want a boat.
I want to take a boat down
the Mississippi River.
A little boat.
Not a big boat.
BENNY: In the Mississippi
River?
DAVID CHOE (OFFSCREEN): Yeah,
in the Mississippi River.
BENNY: What are y'all
smoking on, man?
You're talking about-- you're
going to get crushed in that
river, man.
DAVID CHOE (OFFSCREEN):
From what?
It's of water, man.
BENNY: Man, that's the most
dangerous river in the world.
DAVID CHOE (OFFSCREEN): Why?
Why is it dangerous?
BENNY: There's holes, sinkholes,
and all kind of
stuff like that.
DAVID CHOE (OFFSCREEN):
What's a sinkhole?
BENNY: It's a sinkhole when a
barge comes up down the river,
and it wipes you on the
side of it, man.
DAVID CHOE (OFFSCREEN):
Oh, wow.
And have you gone swimming
in the Mississippi River?
BENNY: No.
Anybody's gonna be swimming
[INAUDIBLE]:?
DAVID CHOE (OFFSCREEN): Have you
known anyone that's swam
in the river?
BENNY: No.
I know a couple guys--
DAVID CHOE (OFFSCREEN): So
you're from Mississippi and
you don't know anyone
who's ever swam in
the Mississippi River?
BENNY: No.
DAVID CHOE (OFFSCREEN): All
right, I'll find a boat.
BENNY: OK, I'll tell--
DAVID CHOE (OFFSCREEN): I'm
going to sail down the
Mississippi River.
I'm going to ditch
the sinkholes.
the undercurrent.
I'm going to ditch the sewage.
BENNY: All right.
I only heard of Huckleberry
Finn.
DAVID CHOE: I'll be your
Huckleberry Finn.
How about a ride?
How bout a lift?
Come on.
BENNY: I ain't got time.
I got work to do.
DAVID CHOE (OFFSCREEN): Where's
your truck, Benny?
BENNY: My truck's right there.
DAVID CHOE: Give me
a fucking ride.
BENNY: My truck's right there.
DAVID CHOE: Let's go talk
about it in the truck.
Benny's totally fucking
with us right now.
Pointed at his truck and said it
was a white guy truck, then
told us it's really his truck.
BENNY: It's my truck.
DAVID CHOE: It's obvious Benny
has a high sex drive.
He has his own custom
Ford sticker with a
naked woman on it.
Benny.
BENNY: He's cool, man.
Hooks me up with everything,
man.
Clothes.
Shoes.
DAVID CHOE: Let's
go, let's go.
Bye, Benny.
Thank you, sir.
Yeah, let's go, let's go.
Yeah, let's do it.
Oh, my god.
You are crazy, sir.
This is the best ride ever.
We're in Tunica, Mississippi.
Just jumped in a fucking limo.
HARRY: Limo!
DAVID CHOE: And we're
going to Walmart.
Wow.
And the lights are changing.
What's your name, sir?
LENNY HILL: Lenny Hill.
DAVID CHOE: Lenny Hill?
Thank you so much
for the ride.
This is the best ride ever.
We thought we were going to
get a ride with Benny, and
next thing you know, we get a
ride with Lenny Hill, in the
fucking limo, heading over to
Walmart, Tunica, Mississippi.
HARRY: Wow.
Thumbs up, America.
Dreams do come true.
DAVID CHOE: Lenny, thank
you so much, sir.
LENNY HILL: All right, hope
you enjoyed yourselves.
DAVID CHOE: Yes.
I enjoyed it, too.
Are you from out here?
LENNY HILL: Yeah.
DAVID CHOE: Lenny, we were
standing out there for no less
than 10 minutes in front of a
gas station when Benny, the
guy you saw us talking to, his
employer came out and told us,
two women came in and complained
that they saw
foreigners wearing backpacks,
and that we were terrorists,
and that they were going to
call the police on us.
LENNY HILL: Oh, my lord.
DAVID CHOE: And then you came
in and you saved the day.
You got us out of town.
LENNY HILL: Well, you don't look
like terrorists to me.
DAVID CHOE: And at any point
during this ride, were you
scared of your life?
At any point in this ride, did
you have any weird sexual
feelings towards me or Harry?
LENNY HILL: No.
DAVID CHOE: Nothing?
OK.
You're really champion.
This was one of the
best rides ever.
Thank you so much.
If there was women in the
back, it would've been a
little bit better.
LENNY HILL: Sorry
about the women.
DAVID CHOE: I'm not complaining
at all.
Thank you so much, man.
LENNY HILL: Bye bye.
DAVID CHOE: This is
fucking amazing.
There's a golf course
right there.
So here we are at hole seven
or hole number eight,
somewhere in Mississippi golf
courses, some of the best
places to have sex, some of
the best places to light
fireworks, some of the best
places to just get some
shut-eye after the
whole shut-down.
You know, country living,
living in style.
Cornfield right next
to the golf course.
We're right next to
the golf course.
We'll catch some shut-eye here
and then, we'll be off on the
road tomorrow.
Good night, America.
HARRY: Peace.
DAVID CHOE: Day 12.
We got our limo driver yesterday
to stop at five
different Walmarts so that we
could find an inflatable raft
to take down the Mississippi
River.
And basically, everyone that we
talked to, everyone that we
met is born and raised
in Mississippi.
They know of people that have
actually swam in the
Mississippi River but
they all died.
And no Sport Mart, no sporting
goods store, no Walmart
actually sells an inflatable
raft because it's a fucking
stupid idea.
There's sinkholes, there's a
strong undercurrent, and
nobody really takes a
raft down the river.
And so the closest we could find
is the Monster Deck Tube.
And I imagine our adventure
down the Mississippi River
will resemble this
a little bit.
That's me.
That's Harry.
So, I just want to give an early
"fuck you" to everyone
who said, "Don't do it.
You're a fucking idiot." I'm
about to go down the
Mississippi River.
I'm going to have
an awesome time.
And I'm gonna get
a killer tan.
DAVID CHOE: We're trying to
get down to Louisiana.
The current seems sort of weak,
but you know, that might
be misleading.
DAVID CHOE: Here we are, going
down the Mississippi River.
Me and my buddy, Harry.
Our camera man, Jacinto--
great guy --had absolutely
no faith in going down
the river with us.
So it's just me and Harry and
our little shitty camera.
HARRY (OFFSCREEN): Yup.
DAVID CHOE: All right.
My feet are starting to
itch a little bit.
We're going by some factory
industrial-looking thing, and
there's some brownish-looking
water pouring into the river.
All right, America, I gotta
start paddling, so fuck off.
You see that shit, dude?
We're at least going like
five miles an hour now.
It's the umbrella sail.
HARRY: Wow.
We don't have to row anymore.
DAVID CHOE: This is awesome.
Dude, we're fucking
moving, man.
My credit card company called
yesterday and said I'm late on
all my payments, on all
my cash advances.
It's amazing how
the tide turns.
One day you have no money.
Next day you win a couple grand
in Tunica, Mississippi.
Next day, you're on a boat.
The credit card company can
eat my ass right now.
There's really no where else
I'd rather be right now.
I'm fucking sailing down
the Mississippi River.
I wish--
the only other thing that I
would like is if I was-- whoa!
HARRY (OFFSCREEN): If
you're on board.
DAVID CHOE: Is if I was lying
on my back like this, and my
girlfriend was sitting
on my face.
And I'm holding the umbrella
sail like this.
HARRY: That would be amazing.
DAVID CHOE: But, really there's
no where else I'd
rather be right now.
HARRY: Bon voyage.
I'm going to brave
the sinkholes.
DAVID CHOE: Can you
touch the bottom?
HARRY: No.
DAVID CHOE: Can you
see any catfish?
HARRY: I don't feel any.
DAVID CHOE: Can you see any?
HARRY: Can't see shit,
it's all brown.
DAVID CHOE: Are there any black
mermaids down there?
HARRY: I think.
DAVID CHOE: We changed
our mind.
We're having too much
of a good time.
Fuck camping out.
Let's fucking keep this
adventure going.
We're going to stay on
the river all night.
See how far we get.
We went 20 miles today.
Probably get 30, 40, maybe even
50 miles by tomorrow.
Only thing is, we're stuck in
like some kind of weird
current in the middle
of the river.
HARRY (OFFSCREEN): Guess they
don't want to stop for us.
DAVID CHOE: Let's give
them a honker.
HARRY (OFFSCREEN): Yeah, let
them know what's up.
[HONK]
DAVID CHOE: Yeah, we're OK.
How far are you guys headed?
SPEAKER 1: We're getting
ready to go fishing.
DAVID CHOE: Can you
give us a lift?
SPEAKER 1: Yeah, man.
DAVID CHOE: All right.
All right.
SPEAKER 1: OK.
DAVID CHOE: What's your name?
SPEAKER 1: [INAUDIBLE].
DAVID CHOE (OFFSCREEN):
Dave and Harry.
SPEAKER 1: Dave and who?
DAVID CHOE (OFFSCREEN): Harry.
SPEAKER 1: Harry?
HARRY (OFFSCREEN): Yeah.
SPEAKER 1: Nice to meet y'all.
DAVID CHOE (OFFSCREEN): Nice
to meet you guys, too.
What do you guys do
during the week?
SPEAKER 1: Work.
DAVID CHOE: Yeah?
Where?
SPEAKER 1: I drive a truck.
[INAUDIBLE].
DAVID CHOE: You ever pick
up hitch-hikers?
SPEAKER 1: You know, I haven't
seen no hitch-hikers no more.
DAVID CHOE (OFFSCREEN):
That's true.
Why do you think that is?
SPEAKER 1: You see?
On the interstate border?
DAVID CHOE (OFFSCREEN): Right.
SPEAKER 1: A guy picked
up girls up there.
He was killed.
DAVID CHOE (OFFSCREEN):
Oh, OK.
SPEAKER 1: Fucking heard
it on the news.
DAVID CHOE (OFFSCREEN):
That was you?
SPEAKER 1: Hell no.
They killed him.
He was killed and thrown
in the Arkansas River.
HARRY (OFFSCREEN): Damn.
DAVID CHOE: It really, really
doesn't get better than this.
Who says you can't get picked
up by truckers?
These are our friends
from Arkansas.
They just gave us--
truckers that gave us our first
lift on a boat, and
hooked us up with some beer.
Thank you, gentlemen.
Have a good time fishing.
Have a good weekend.
Take care.
Awesome ride, thank you guys.
SPEAKER 1: Thank you.
DAVID CHOE: Wow.
It really doesn't get
better than that.
All right, I'm fucking in my
boxers, lying on a raft,
drinking beers and booze with
my friend Harry, and they're
fucking cold.
HARRY: Yeah.
DAVID CHOE: Harry, can
I ask you a question?
HARRY: What?
DAVID CHOE: Why is
life so rad?
HARRY: It is.
It just is.
And we're down in the river.
DAVID CHOE: They brought us at
least 8 miles down the river.
New Orleans is at least 400
miles still away, so that'll
probably take us two weeks to
get to, but as long as we get
about 8 more miles to a town
called Eudora, Arkansas.
We can get to service road from
there and hitch on down
to New Orleans.
I don't know how the light looks
to you guys, but the
sun's going down, and it's gonna
be pitch-black in about
30 minutes.
And it is gonna be super
dangerous out here.
Pitch black.
2:00 in the morning, floating
down the Mississippi River.
I mean this is shit that
film or video will
never be able to capture.
One of these big barges come by,
and every time they go by,
it makes little wakes that makes
your boat feel like it's
going to flip over.
I mean, it's unbelievable.
It's just me and Harry drifting
down this river at
two miles an hour.
All you hear is grasshoppers,
and locusts, and
cicadas, and dogs and--
see every fucking star.
It's beautiful.
We just docked our
boat right there.
It's about 2:00 in
the morning.
We got scared when our boat
started poking into the sticks
coming out of the ground, so
we're going to camp out here
for the night.
It's good a place as any.
We got two bonfires going.
We got this old tree that fell
down, and we're lighting the
entire stump on fire.
The smell of burning
embers in the air.
We got the little baby
one started.
I cut off my shirt.
I'm starting to look like
the Incredible Hulk.
As day 13 arrives, Sunday, I
really had my heart on going
to church tomorrow, but this
might be better than church at
getting in touch with God.
I hope with my fried brain, I'm
able to remember nights
like this because this is one of
the best nights of my life.
Rise and shine, America.
We're at day 13 at Thumbs
Up, America.
The light's starting
to come up.
I'm guessing it's 4:00,
5:00 in the morning.
The sun has not yet risen
over the Mississippi.
I have swamp butt, mud butt.
My face is swollen from
the morning frost.
Spider bites, horse
flies, mosquitoes.
I can't even feel my face.
It feels worse than when we
slept at the golf course.
It got a lot colder
than we thought.
But, I'll tell you what,
I couldn't be happier.
Anyway, the sun's coming up.
We want to head a little deeper
into Louisiana before
we hit the streets.
So, wish us luck, America.
I think if my calculations are
correct, we're either at the
very tip of Arkansas, or at
least at the tip of Louisiana.
That'd be awesome if we made it
all the way to Louisiana.
Looks like we made it.
Lake Providence, Louisiana.
Of all the places we could end
up, we end up in the Private
Resort Hunting Club.
They shoot on sight.
HARRY: No trespassers.
DAVID CHOE: We got here in the
daytime instead of night.
So we're lucky.
DAVID CHOE: And they
all have guns.
DAVID CHOE: We're in Louisiana
in the south.
Catching a ride from a private
hunting club to the main road.
Just got off the river.
I see cotton fields and I see
a noose hanging by a tree.
What do you think about that?
DAVID CHOE (OFFSCREEN):
I know I've been
constipated for a few days.
If I saw that, I would've
went [POOP NOISE].
That is--
I'm scared just sitting
here right now.
DAVID CHOE (OFFSCREEN):
I'm laughing
but I'm crying inside.
DAVID CHOE (OFFSCREEN):
Oh, my god.
SPEAKER 2: Well, how
is hitch-hiking
these days and times?
DAVID CHOE (OFFSCREEN):
Well, have you
ever hitch-hiked before?
SPEAKER 2: I used to.
I've hitch-hiked very little,
but I used to pick up
hitch-hikers back in the
early '80s, but I don't
pick them up any more.
DAVID CHOE (OFFSCREEN): And
your reason for that is?
SPEAKER 2: Frickin'
nuts out there.
DAVID CHOE (OFFSCREEN): But what
happened in the '80s and
'90s until now that--
the world has just transformed
into a bunch
of nut jobs or something?
SPEAKER 2: Yeah, some of them.
DAVID CHOE (OFFSCREEN): I
mean, I don't think the
quotient of nut jobs
have changed.
I think the media has
changed, you know?
SPEAKER 2: I don't know.
As you get older and you get a
family, you get more scared
about people.
DAVID CHOE (OFFSCREEN):
That's true.
SPEAKER 2: Y'all will have
something to talk about when
you get older.
[INAUDIBLE]
I think it's pretty cool.
DAVID CHOE (OFFSCREEN): Yeah.
I appreciate the ride.
DAVID CHOE: We gotta
get a recap.
Get into it.
Get off the river.
That last family in town, they
didn't leave for hunting for
the day for whatever reason.
Get lucky, they gave us
15 miles into town.
I mean, ha-ha-ha, funny, it's
like what the fuck, dude.
Two Chinamen just rolled in on
a raft into your backyard.
And we gave them the raft.
About to get two
cheeseburgers.
Tired as fuck.
Dehydrated as fuck.
I'm gonna faint.
I'm gonna eat like six of these
fruit smoothie, cream
slush, shakes and malts.
We're in Louisiana, so gonna
hit New Orleans.
Should be there by tonight.
We're gonna hitch out
of town right now.