[MUSIC PLAYING]
OJ: Welcome to another edition
of Vice Today.
I'm OJ, filling in for Ryan
Duffy, who is either sick or
has been kidnapped by
the Legion of Doom.
On this episode, we meet another
one of our weird and
wonderful friends from the
internet, the Reply Girl, in
the third installment
of My Life Online.
Then we find out about the
future of interior design in
outer space with our premiere
episode of Spaced Out.
But first, we check in with
our favorite office house
plant, Hanson O'Haver, for
another installment of What's
Up with Drake?
[MUSIC PLAYING]
HANSON O'HAVER: Hey,
I'm Hanson O'Haver.
So Drake did a couple of
interviews recently where he
talked about some hot
button issues.
In one, he talked about his
substance use, which is
basically that he smokes pot
occasionally, drinks a little
bit of wine, and occasionally
sips lean.
And then in another interview,
he talked about how he's
single, but he's definitely
looking for the one.
I think that when you compare
these statements to like, for
example, the recent GQ Rick Ross
interview, which was like
six pages of just Mercedes and
strippers and just like sex
rooms and food and so much weed,
it sort of gets at a
larger point about Drake's
relatability.
I think that the most
interesting part of "Take
Care" is probably when the
heartfelt voicemail from his
grandma segs into the beat
from "Back That Azz Up."
But a close runner up, I think,
is when he says, I've
had sex four times this week.
I'll explain.
Because even assuming that
he's talking about four
different people, it's
not that much sex.
I mean, Drake's a very famous
guy, and presumably millions
of women want to have
sex with him.
Whereas, I feel confident that
there's probably someone in
this office that has had sex
with four people this week.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
OJ: You know what, he's
not a house plant.
He's actually a fern.
Next up, we travel to Montreal,
where we met with
Alejandra Gaitan, who makes
her living on the
footnotes of YouTube.
This is My Life Online.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
ALEJANDRA GAITAN:
So, hi everyone.
I just saw this video
about a dog
REPLY GIRL 1: --at
a vet's office?
REPLY GIRL 2: --giving his--
the person behind the
register a receipt.
ALEJANDRA GAITAN: It's
just really, really--
REPLY GIRL 1: --cute.
REPLY GIRL 3: -So anyways--
yeah.
MALE YOUTUBER 1: There's a trend
happening on YouTube
right now which is basically
just a bunch of fat-tittied
girls making stupid-ass
reply videos to
everything that comes up.
MALE YOUTUBER 2: They're
flipping everywhere, even on
this video because it's
about reply girls.
There will be about five down
here to the left of me.
You look down in related videos,
there'll probably be
some reply girls there.
THE LUCHADOR: They
do shitty videos.
They're completely terrible.
MALE YOUTUBER 1: Just these
girls yapping nonsense for
long enough to fit an ad in
so they can make money.
THE LUCHADOR: People take hours
and hours and hours to
produce a quality video
and original content.
And they just pretty much
watch it for pride.
And they get 100 times
what I would get in
views, and like this.
MALE YOUTUBER 2: The
end result is
almost painful to watch.
MALE YOUTUBER 4: Oh, hey guys.
MALE SPEAKER: Oh, they
made me so hot.
-[SPEAKING GERMAN]
ALEJANDRA GAITAN: Peace
and love, guys.
See ya.
Thank you very much
for watching.
Bye.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
ALEJANDRA GAITAN: Now, in case
you don't know me, I am The
Reply Girl, probably one
of YouTube most hated
personalities right now.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
When I started YouTubing, I was
below the poverty line,
and I really, really, really
needed a way to get out of
that situation.
Hi guys.
My first month, I made enough
to pay a cell phone bill.
It was-- and I worked so much.
Well, it's very simple.
You go on YouTube, and
you look for the
videos that are trending.
I like those that are like
random and funny.
-Good morning, Senor Luchador.
I brought you breakfast with
lots and lots of bacon.
[SHOUTING]
THE LUCHADOR: Alejandra, well,
to be honest, she is my
girlfriend's sister.
And all considered, she's
my YouTube mentor.
-Hey guys, I just--
THE LUCHADOR (OFFSCREEN): Reply
Girl, Reply Girl, I need
some advice.
Haters are trying
to get at me.
And you know what, I got to go
break their necks one by one.
THE LUCHADOR: So what happened
was that she
showed me her check.
And it was a nice check.
For what she does, it was a
very, very beautiful check.
ALEJANDRA GAITAN: I always
wanted to be an autonomous
worker or have a company
or make money on my
own, be my own boss.
And I just never knew what
exactly I wanted to
do to make it happen.
I just knew I wanted--
I want it to happen.
I started programming but that
didn't work out very well
because I'm not--
I'm not a very good
programmer.
And I also did some
babysitting, but
that's how it is.
THE LUCHADOR: I tried doing
replies myself.
And believe it or not, it's
a harder job than
you think it is.
It's long, it's boring,
tedious.
It's annoying.
I mean, it's not a fun job.
And the haters, the people out
there who are hating on reply
people and like, oh, what
they do is brainless.
You know what, do it yourself.
If you don't like it, don't
do it and don't watch it.
Simple as that.
There's times that these haters,
they're posting videos
and threats about finding her
address, her IP address, and
knowing where she lives.
I've seen posts on YouTube,
people actually posting, and
they thought that they
found her address.
And they post it everywhere.
What kind of a bad person are
you to take a hated person's
address and post it
to the public?
So someone, some crazy person
comes over and sees the
address and does something
that they're going to
regret later on.
Oh, Jesus.
If only they knew.
I'm waiting.
OJ: Geez, that was really sad,
but I was kind of distracted
by something else.
And finally, we check in with
those crazy, underfunded nerds
at NASA to find out what their
interior designers have in
store for us once Earth has
become a barren wasteland.
This is the series premier
of Spaced Out.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
EVAN TWYFORD: Three-dimensional
design, for
me, was always kind of the
greatest form of creation,
being able to take an idea from
that very tiny amount of
energy, being this idea
in your head, and then
formulating that into
a fully functional
three-dimensional product.
Take that step further, I
always kind of wanted to
design the ultimate
three-dimensional object, right?
And so, designing space
vehicles, to me, was like that
ultimate form of creation.
It's like, what's the most
bad-ass thing you can design
would be a spaceship.
And NASA really was kind of
the final frontier for me.
My name's Evan Twyford, and I'm
a habitability designer at
NASA's Johnson Space Center.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
EVAN TWYFORD: We, in our group,
do conceptual design
for NASA's Human Space Flight.
A lot of these projects are
coming down as major, kind of
campaign-level design projects
where they're saying, hey,
we're doing a mission
to the moon.
We're working on a pressurized
rover.
We've got this idea, and
we want you guys to
help us make it happen.
So starting off with sketching
and rendering, very
conceptual, take it to a
full-scale, mock-up phase out
of wood, foam core, low-fidelity
materials.
We use those to kind of sketch
out the volume of how big the
vehicle might be and how it
might feel on the inside.
Part of what we'll do when we're
designing a habitat is
we'll look at how the corners,
how the edges are treated,
what type of paint schemes
are going to go inside.
There was actually an issue with
one of the colors that
they had painted on the
International Space Station,
where one of the hatches was
like a salmon color.
And the crew really disliked
it, so we try to
avoid salmon now.
And then working out the details
in a CAD system on the
computer and developing a
fully-functional prototype.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
EVAN TWYFORD: The type of design
at NASA that we do kind
of crosses the line between
fine art and engineering.
So it's a lot more problem
solving, though, which is what
makes it really exciting.
So this is the SEV, the Space
Exploration Vehicle on the
chassis, Gen1B.
For interior design for space
vehicles, there is certainly
the problem of confinement,
which is a psychological issue
for crew members over time.
So we have to deal with ways of
designing environments and
designing products that will
reduce the effects of feelings
of confinement in space.
Yeah, so this is the interior
of the SEV Rover, Gen1B.
And most of the interior design
elements was a product
of our team, as well the
robotics team that we've been
working with on this vehicle
for some time.
And we've been charged with
making the interior of the
vehicle more comfortable and
more luxurious, if you can
call it that.
[SPACE SOUNDS]
EVAN TWYFORD: Seeing as most of
us haven't actually been to
outer space, it can make
things very difficult
sometimes because everybody has
a different opinion, or
different assumptions that
they're making about what that
experience is like.
It's a very testing and
evaluation-intensive work
environment.
So we have to do whatever we
can to ensure that these
products will work in their
intended environment.
So sometimes that means flying
products or mock ups on a zero
gravity flight in the
parabolic aircraft.
Sometimes it means going out
into the desert and testing
them in a very harsh kind of
desolate environment that
might be similar to what we
would encounter in space.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
EVAN TWYFORD: There's always
that kind of thing with
designers between, are you going
to be like a stylist or
are you going to be
a problem solver?
And you can look at a product,
and say this accomplishes
exactly what we needed to
accomplish, and that's what
makes it beautiful, and that's
what makes it successful.
It's a very pure design problem
that we're dealing
with, which is to create
products and environments that
the crew will find useful and
will make them successful and
productive in their
daily routines.
MALE SPEAKER: Go for
main engine start.
T-minus 10, 9, 8, 7, 6, 5--
all three engines
up and burning--
2, 1, 0, and lift off.
The final lift off
of Atlantis.
EVAN TWYFORD: The shuttle
program and the International
Space Station were started
in the '80s as sort of a
longer-term analog for human
space flight and establishing
a permanent, human presence in
space to start to learn more
about how humans would behave
and interact in longer-term
space flight scenarios.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
EVAN TWYFORD: I kind of felt
like a lot of people, in
general, are maybe not as
excited by the International
Space Station or by the shuttle
program, or at least
not as much as they were maybe
in the '80s when the shuttle
was brand new.
I just hope that we can really
re-engage people in the right
way, and get people excited
about space flight because
this next generation of space
vehicles is going to be the
most bad-ass that
we've ever seen.
OJ: Hope you enjoyed another
episode of Vice Today.
Check back every Monday and
Thursday for new episodes.
And as always, if you like what
you saw, please subscribe.
[MUSIC PLAYING]