Chinese New Year is just around the corner,
so we're making some delicious pot stickers.
Pan fried dumplings that look like little
nuggets of gold. Legends says that they will
bring good fortune if eaten on New Years Eve.
Our pot stickers have a juicy pork filling
and we whip up a fab dipping sauce to go with
them too!
So let's get started.
First up dumpling wrappers, now these are
so ridiculously easy that you'll never have
to buy them from the shop again.
And with 300 grams of flour, goes a good pinch
of salt and 220mls of boiling water to bring
it all together.
Now this is a neat little trick to stop them
getting too sticky. But do take your time
because the dough is scorching hot!
Try getting your chopsticks in there too,
think of them as useful tools to get you from
kitchen to dinner table.
Now to work on those arm muscles!
knead the dough for about 10 minutes until
silky smooth. Now before we let this baby
rest we're going to hcop it into two and then
form each into a bagel.
This is our little tip to get all the pot
stickers the same size.
Don't try that at home!
Now while the dough's resting we're going
to get started on our filling. So here we
have some lovely pork shoulder. We're going
to mince it up ourselves even though you can
use pork mince. Because that's the way that
Mum taught us and it's always made for a scrumptious
filling.
Give it a good bash up with your cleaver,
300 grams of pork shoulder should make 32
dumplings.
To tenderise the meat we're just going to
chuck in a little bit of baking soda and corn
flour. These two are magic ingredients in
the Chinese kitchen, Baking soda breaks down
the tough proteins in meat while the corn
four creates a velvety mouth feel.
Salt, sugar and a wee bit of white pepper.
To plump everything up we're just going to
chuck in some water, bit of salsing rice wine.
Dark soy, light soy and sesame oil.
Then just grab your chopsticks and give it
a good mix.
And to make our dumplings a complete meal
we're going to chuck in a wee bit of leafy
bok choi as well.
And just to finish it off we're going to chuck
in some garlic and ginger and of course as
always spring onion a staple in the Chinese
Kitchen.
Mix it up in one direction just to make sure
that everything binds together so we get a
lovely bite when we sink our teeth into those
dumplings.
Right, these babies are ready to go!
Through the middle, line the halves up and
keep dividing until you get 16 pieces.
There you have it a little army of identical
dough pieces. Place a piece cut side up, flat
onto your palm and we;ll get on with turning
these into dumpling wrappers.
Now I'm going to use a rolling pin, the skinnier
the better. If you're right handed that#s
where your rolling pin will be, here we go.
Roll, twist with your left hand, roll, twist
with your left hand, roll, twist, roll, twist,
roll twist, roll, twist.
And just keep going!
Time to get our wrap on. SO start by making
a cradle for your hand with the dumping wrapper
then grab some filling and pop it in the middle.
Smooth down the top, then fold it over with
your thumb In the middle. Give it a wee pinch
at the end before guiding it over and folding
it over with your thumb and index finger.
And again, and again, making sure to pinch
as you go along.
All the way until the end.
When you're left with a lovely crescent shape!
Should we do like ghost?
This is good for date night. Perfect for date
night. You mean look longingly into each others
eyes?!
Ha!
Put your thumb in there!
Get a frying pan with a tight fitting lit
over medium heat and a splash of veg oil.
Let's get these bad boys in. Nestle them in
really tight around the pan. Big spoon, little
spoon.
When the bottoms are golden like this, pour
on water and cover.
While the dumplings are cooking we're going
to make out the easiest dipping sauce of all
time.
First, sesame oil, then we've got some light
soy sauce, generous with that one.
And just to finish off, a nice blob of chilli
oil. So chuck that in. I like that quite spicy.
Done.
Ohh yum!
Right, these are done when the water's all
gone. Just remember to put those golden bottoms
on show.
And if you don't want to miss out on wicked
recipes, make sure you subscribe to Food Tube
and the Dumpling Sisters too!
We'd love to have ya!
So that's it guys, our perfect potstickers.
A must have for Chinese New Year's Eve because
they bring prosperity and good luck and we
love eating them in a huge pile like this.
And don't forget that glorious sauce!
Oh yum!
Thanks so much for watching guys and happy
new year!