OK, also, we speak English?
OK.
I remember when we shot Science
of Sleep, you were
hiding from the camera,
especially
in the first scenes.
And it's interesting.
CHARLOTTE GAINSBOURG: But I
remember, I don't know, it has
nothing to do with this, but I
remember, I must have been
used to so many years of hiding
because I was on my
mother's sets when she was
acting, and just hiding to
look at the scene.
So I was in this position of
trying to find the place where
nobody would say, go away and
just being like a mouse.
And spying on the scenes
and loving it.
And then suddenly, when I was, I
don't know, 12 when I did my
first film, I remember hearing
people say, move away.
And I always thought
it was me.
MICHEL GONDRY: [LAUGH]
CHARLOTTE GAINSBOURG: And no,
this time it wasn't me.
MICHEL GONDRY: That's great.
Actually, I had the same
feeling with Mos Def.
Mos Def, he is so oblivious of
the camera, that he would
always end up to have his back
like blocking the view.
Sometimes I just have to
ask him to go away.
At least, if you don't want to
be in the show, don't stop the
others from being in the shot.
But I have to say,
in counterparty,
he has a great presence.
Because he's not--
if you put the camera here, he's
not going to feel that
the camera. is there.
And I think you have
this quality too.
That you can be scrutinized by
the camera, or I guess, the
microphone or whatever.
And it doesn't feel you're
communicating with this equipment.
You're still communicating
with the other
person or the audience.
But a lot of peoples have--
to me I see that as, they
have a little eye
inside of their eye.
So if, for instance, if I look
at you and I'm aware that the
camera is here, I'm not
really looking at you.
In fact, I'm looking at the
camera here to make sure the
camera looks at me.
And a lot of actors
have this problem.
It's very hard because you
want to help them to be
communicating with the person,
to create the moment.
But they have little eyes in the
white of their eye that is
looking to the camera,
and it's horrible.
You coming from, probably, the
most famous couple from this
era in France?
CHARLOTTE GAINSBOURG: Yeah,
because I was young when I
started, I didn't think,
ooh, I have to be as
good as them, or--
I was just having fun
with the films.
And with the album,
I did think--
I was preoccupied, yeah.
And that's why I chose to do it
in English, was because I
didn't want myself to be able to
compare the words with what
he had written.
Because it was too
strong for me.
MICHEL GONDRY: Using the foreign
language, it's a very
good help for this kind of--
CHARLOTTE GAINSBOURG: It was
easier for me, much easier.
Because I remember, I tried
to write, and it was so
dreadful, in French.
And I read stuff.
And maybe I could've read
a masterpiece, I
wouldn't have seen it.
I was just pushing
everything away.
MICHEL GONDRY: Yeah, there's too
much things interfering.
CHARLOTTE GAINSBOURG: Yeah.
MICHEL GONDRY: But there is this
relation that's really
complex and interesting because
all those guys that
worked on this album are direct
influenced by what your
father did.
CHARLOTTE GAINSBOURG:
Yeah, yeah.
MICHEL GONDRY: And basically
their music is a tribute.
Without you, way before they
met you, the music is a
tribute to what your
father was doing.
CHARLOTTE GAINSBOURG: But each
time I could hear that
something was close to one of my
father's songs in the music
I was really proud.
It was in the words that I
didn't want to be like a pale
copy of something he had done.
In the music, they came
out like tributes.
MICHEL GONDRY: Yeah.
CHARLOTTE GAINSBOURG: And we
were all aware of, not my
father's presence, but it was
like, everybody knew what I
had in my head, that he was--
that I thought about
him all the time.
And Air, and Nigel, and Jarvis,
and Neil Hannon, too,
they were all very, very
discreet about him.
And I was always starting
to talk about him.
It was strange, yeah.
MICHEL GONDRY: Yeah, that's
interesting, yeah.
But I think it's a nice loop
that comes back to a sort of
healthy place.
The way inspiration and tribute
and then coming back
to where it started, and
somewhat in a different
generation.
CHARLOTTE GAINSBOURG: Mmm.
MICHEL GONDRY: So we're
talking about
being in the studio.
And I like the idea that the
studio is a place where things
are created.
CHARLOTTE GAINSBOURG:
Yeah, well for me it
was also just being--
because I wasn't composing
any music.
And I was trying to write
lyrics, but I wasn't
very good at it.
And I was very embarrassed
about myself,
and what I was writing.
So at the beginning, I was
really enjoying just being a
witness of their work.
And just being able to be
there whilst they were
creating something, and
instrument after instrument.
It was such a magical
time for me.
And with Nigel behind
the commands.
But I remember, before we
started going in the studio, I
remember just talking to Nicolas
and Jean-Benoit, for
such a long time because I was
so scared to start something
that I wanted to talk about what
it was going to be like,
and what kind of music,
and the words were so
important for me.
So what lyrics, and after a
while, they just pushed me and
said, we can't just talk
about it for years.
You have to go in the studio
and see what happens.
And it's true because maybe
nothing could've happened.
And it just did.
And with no pressure.
Until we weren't happy,
we could go on.
And that was a great luxury
to have that.
MICHEL GONDRY: So they were
really probably so pleased to
be next to you.
And I think sometimes, even
if you don't physically or
actively participate, if you're
there next to the
person, it makes all
the difference.
CHARLOTTE GAINSBOURG:
I think it did make
a difference because--
MICHEL GONDRY: Because they feel
they are doing it with
you, even though you
weren't singing.
Although where they would feel
like just record like session
musicians, and then you come
to do your vocals.
CHARLOTTE GAINSBOURG: Exactly.
I would have hated to just
receive a CD with all the
tracks and then just go in
the studio and record it.
I wanted to be there.
I wanted to be a part
of everything.
And I know that they
knew that.
I needed that time, also, for
myself, to be able to go
behind the microphone
and just try things.
MICHEL GONDRY: That's nice.
It reminds me, I did some video
with Bjork where she's
hardly not in it.
We flew over Iceland, and we
took a lot of pictures.
But I was scared to death
in the small plane.
We went to this airport, and
they have some crashed plane
on the side, and we're have
to go in the same one.
And she would go,
always, with me.
And I think the fact that she
was there, and even if she's
not in front of the camera, it's
like it goes through me,
like waves or something.
And I think I always try
to work this way.
Even if the artist is not
in front of the camera.
He has to be behind or it's a
collaborative [INAUDIBLE].
CHARLOTTE GAINSBOURG: Yeah.
And Nigel was very important,
too, because
he was a great judge.
And I felt very close
to him in his--
every judgement he had on the
lyrics, mainly, for me.
He was a great support.
Also, to be able to think about
subjects I wanted to
talk about.
And just to make it feel
personal, I had
to do it that way.
MICHEL GONDRY: How old is he?
CHARLOTTE GAINSBOURG: Nigel?
He's exactly my age.
He's 35.
MICHEL GONDRY: And so he worked
with Beck and Radiohead?
CHARLOTTE GAINSBOURG: He
worked with Beck, with
Radiohead, with Paul
McCartney.
I was very intimidated
at first.
Especially once the music was,
not finished, but there were
times when I had to try
and put my voice on.
I was so embarrassed, thinking
he's worked with such talent.
MICHEL GONDRY: He has
the same feeling,
probably, towards you.
CHARLOTTE GAINSBOURG: He
can see I'm a fake.
[LAUGHTER]
MICHEL GONDRY: So are you going
to tour with the band?
CHARLOTTE GAINSBOURG:
I don't think I can.
I don't think I'm capable
of doing something.
But maybe later.
Maybe when I won't feel I have
to, I'll want to do it.
But for the moment, I'm just
too nervous about it.
MICHEL GONDRY: Well, don't you
think this nervousness is
going to give something
to the concert?
CHARLOTTE GAINSBOURG: No.
MICHEL GONDRY: Oh, I think so.
MICHEL GONDRY: But I think
the awkwardness is very--
he gives you a different
level of
connection with your audience.
And I find that with Bjork.
Bjork, OK she's a very
professional singer.
And she's done a ton
of concerts.
But she doesn't connect
with the audience
in a classical sense.
She's not going to talk to the
microphone and say, hey, New
York I love you.
All this bullshit.
She's on camera.
CHARLOTTE GAINSBOURG: No, of
course, but she's such a
performer that something--
MICHEL GONDRY: I know
but, I think--
CHARLOTTE GAINSBOURG:
--is happening.
MICHEL GONDRY: What I like the
most in her concert is this
non-connection she makes
with the audience.
CHARLOTTE GAINSBOURG: Yeah,
but no, the thing is, I'm
worried that--
and really, it's not fake
modesty or something.
But I'm just worried it
will be very boring.
Because I'm not a performer,
so [INTERPOSING VOICES].
MICHEL GONDRY: Well, to
me what's boring is
professionalism.
There is some quality
in not being in
control of the situation.
CHARLOTTE GAINSBOURG: Yeah, but
also, the thing is, for
this album, because we did it
all together with Air and
Jarvis, the fact that I would be
on stage on my own without
them doesn't make any sense.
MICHEL GONDRY: Well, of
course, but why don't
you tour with them?
CHARLOTTE GAINSBOURG: Well,
they have their
own album to release.
MICHEL GONDRY: All right,
well that's different.
But I think you should
tour with them, yes.
I saw them in Los Angeles.
And they were doing the songs.
The singer that was doing their
big hit at the time--
I forgot her name-- and
she was so shy.
It was a great moment.
Obviously, she was just coming
from one song, and she could
hardly sing.
And it was a great moment
because the audience just
wanted go with her,
and help her.
And it was really--
CHARLOTTE GAINSBOURG:
An American singer?
MICHEL GONDRY: Yeah,
it was in--
I don't know if she's
American or English.
It's that song that
goes [SINGING].
It's one of their big hits.
CHARLOTTE GAINSBOURG: Yeah,
and she sings on
the album, or she?
MICHEL GONDRY: Yeah, yeah, that
was the singer on the
album, but she sing few songs,
or maybe only one.
But she came for this song.
I can't sing it, but
it goes [SINGING].
Do you know it?
CHARLOTTE GAINSBOURG: [LAUGH]
MICHEL GONDRY: So anyway,
yeah, you
should tour with them.
You should not tour with the
professional [INAUDIBLE].
CHARLOTTE GAINSBOURG: Yeah.