in the bush and were busy
talking to them when things
started to get a bit hairy.
Now these guys are
coming back here.
The dude with the crowbar
is coming back.
MALE SPEAKER 1:
[SPEAKING KOREAN]
KIM YUN ZUN: [SPEAKING KOREAN]
IGOR "THE FISH" RYBAKOV:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
SHANE SMITH: He says, what
is that, your off switch?
MALE SPEAKER 1:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
SIMON OSTROVSKY: He says I use
it for fixing tractors.
SHANE SMITH: I like the
Fish more and more.
He took the crowbar from him and
said, what is that, your
off switch?
And two North Koreans
came back.
Now they're giving
Mr. Kim shit.
And they're quite angry.
So we're probably going to
have to get out of here.
MALE SPEAKER 1:
[SPEAKING KOREAN]
SHANE SMITH: And so, oh shit,
here comes another truck.
Now we're surrounded.
They're got a truck up there.
They've got a truck
behind here.
What'd he say?
SIMON OSTROVSKY: He said he
came to tell us that he
doesn't want us filming anymore,
and he's come to
block the road.
SHANE SMITH: Really?
All right.
Well, let's go find
another crew.
Let's go.
The Fish is the boss.
As the Fish took us further
into the forest on these
rutted dirt tracks, the
atmosphere in the truck got a
little bit goofy because of
the lunacy that was being
played out in the oddest game
of low-grade cat and mouse
I've ever seen.
Ask about how we get home.
We're in a high-speed car chase
at five miles an hour
through the wilds of Siberia.
They're stopping, we go to
try to pass them, and
then they speed up.
We sort of go on a side road,
and then they head
us off at the pass.
It's a game of chicken out
in the middle of nowhere.
IGOR "THE FISH" RYBAKOV:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
SIMON OSTROVSKY: He was
just telling us.
KIM YUN ZUN: [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
IGOR "THE FISH" RYBAKOV:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
SIMON OSTROVSKY: He says he's
on their blacklist.
SHANE SMITH: The Fish seemed
tired of this game and
suggested we pull over for some
lunch, which consisted of
paprika chips, bread, vodka,
and a shotgun.
IGOR "THE FISH" RYBAKOV:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN], cowboy.
SHANE SMITH: Cowboy.
SIMON OSTROVSKY: Cowboy.
SHANE SMITH: The North Koreans
are going-- what the fuck kind
of journalists are these?
Well, we found our
North Koreans.
Now let's get wasted and shoot
off guns with the mafia.
I hit it, but I didn't
break it.
[APPLAUSE]
SHANE SMITH: It turned
out there was method
in the Fish's madness.
Because our lunchtime shooting
party seemed to have cowed the
North Koreans just enough to get
us out of the wilderness,
which was very good because
the all-menacing Siberian
darkness was fast approaching.
When we finally got to town,
they, of course,
were waiting for us.
And the North Korean security
dude just showed up.
And he won't leave us alone.
And he's just standing
there trying
to look at our passports.
And trying to see all
of our stuff.
He's trying to be scary.
SIMON OSTROVSKY:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
MALE SPEAKER 2:
SHANE SMITH: And when we got
on the train and said our
teary goodbyes to the Fish, we
realized that half the one-car
train was our crew, and the
other half were North Koreans.
[SPEAKING KOREAN]
SIMON OSTROVSKY: That was
the captain of the camp.
SHANE SMITH: Great.
So we locked ourselves into our
compartment and spent the
night backing up our hard drives
and hiding all of our
footage, which turned out be
wise because we were met back
in Tynda by the FSB, the local
militia, the North Koreans,
and some plainclothes detectives
who promptly
detained us.
So they asked us a
lot of questions.
And they kept asking us
about the pipeline.
Are you here to shoot
the pipeline?
We were like, we don't know
anything about a pipeline.
We're here to shoot
North Koreans.
They knew about the Russian cop
who had taken us to the
North Korean camp.
They knew about the chief
of police in the north.
Simon refused to be intimidated,
and he said, if
you want to ask any questions,
ask me here.
I'm not going with you.
I'm not going away with you.
They finally let us go.
We freaked out a little
bit, grabbed our
stuff, and took off.
We quickly hired a car
and made a break
for the Chinese border.
When we finally got to the
border, we realized that part
of the reason for all this panic
and fear on the North
Korean and Russian side was that
Kim Jong-Il, who almost
never leaves North Korea, had
secretly come to the same
place we were, the Amur region
of Russia, coincidentally at
the exact same time we were
there to hold talks with
President Medvedev about more
trade and labor agreements
between the two countries.
So this means that, while we
were there, the Great Leader
was selling even more of his
people off, so he could make
even more money, so you could
make more weapons, so he could
extort more food and aid and
supplies from America and
Japan, who he's technically
still at war with.
And this, better than almost
anything I could think of,
sums up the lunacy of
the modern world.
Thank you and goodnight.
MALE SPEAKER 3:
[SPEAKING KOREAN]