meet face to face.
Over the years, I've read your
books and watched your videos,
perused court documents,
police records, and
affidavits, yet I still feel
confused about what happened
between you, Todd, and the LSD
laboratory so many years ago.
I hope that when we are
together, I will finally
understand what transpired,
and the truth will shine
brightly as a crystal
in the Kansas sky.
Much love, Hamilton.
Krystle Cole is one of the most
unlikely figures in the
psychedelic community.
A Goth stripper from Kansas
whose introduction to the
psychedelic underground came in
February of 2000, when she
fell deeply in love with a
mysterious man named Todd, who
was the heir to a spring
manufacturing fortune.
She quit her job as a dancer
and moved in with Todd at a
decommissioned nuclear missile
silo that served as his
private pleasure of
lysergic delights.
Exactly what happened in that
laboratory at the dawn of the
new millennium is still a
subject of heated debate.
But it is known that Todd formed
a partnership with
Leonard Pickard, an accomplished
clandestine
psychedelic chemist.
And together they began to
assemble what would have been
the world's largest LSD lab.
But before the lab could be put
into full operation, it
was destroyed by the DEA.
After verifying that my
intentions were pure, Krystle
agreed to meet with me to
discuss her involvement in the
lab and take me on a guided tour
of the subterranean LSD
palace that she once
called home.
Last night we flew into Kansas
City, and right now we're on
our way to meet Krystle Cole.
Outside of what she's written in
her book, Lysergic, and her
numerous YouTube videos,
there's very
little known about her.
I have a lot of questions.
I've wanted to meet her
for a long time.
Here we are.
Hey, what's going on?
It's Hamilton.
Nice to meet you.
KRYSTLE COLE: I was raised in a
small Kansas town, which is
comparable to being sucked into
a spiritual black hole.
I was surrounded by flat, bleak
cornfields farmed by
similarly flat, bleak people.
At a young age, my classmates
labeled me as a nerd, causing
me to never quite fit in.
The first thing that comes to
mind upon reflection is, thank
god for being an outcast.
My peers were the perfect
example of white
trash at its worst.
The majority of them had already
given birth to a
couple children and dropped
out of high
school because of it.
No aspirations existed in their
minds beyond the next
round of incestuous
sex, six-pack of
beer, and line of meth.
HAMILTON MORRIS: Krystle is
one of very few people
surrounding the bust who is not
currently incarcerated.
And in the wake of extraordinary
heartbreak,
trials, and prison sentences,
she used her life experience
to inspire a variety of
informational YouTube videos
that have garnered much
attention across the internet.
KRYSTLE COLE: So this is the
green screen that I use to
shoot all the NeuroSoup
videos.
So I came up with the name
NeuroSoup because it's
basically the combination of
neurology and then the soup,
we all have this soup of
different neurotransmitters in
our brains.
And so drugs affect these
neurotransmitters, and so
that's kind of how I came up
with the name NeuroSoup.
HAMILTON MORRIS: Mm.
You were saying that your most
popular YouTube video is the
Shamanic Colonic
anal DMT video.
-Hi.
Some people have gotten onto the
NeuroSoup forum and asked
me about the time that
I took DMT anally.
And so today I want to describe
that for you guys.
There are some benefits to it.
I've only done it anally once,
because I guess the negative
side effect to it, while I'm
talking about all the
positives, is that it burned
really bad, and it just kind
of put me in this weird
head space.
KRYSTLE COLE: That was my most
popular one until YouTube
forced me to remove it because
of its new community content
guidelines.
There's some other paintings
and more
paintings and more fractals.
I kind of have them on
the walls everywhere.
And of course, Grateful
Dead bears.
That one is the one that I put
on my first edition of
Lysergic book cover.
It's my favorite one.
And the language around the side
of it are things that I
kind of saw when I was
tripping, these
alienesque-type languages.
I don't know what you
would call it.
HAMILTON MORRIS: Can you talk
about just the things you talk
about the beginning of Lysergic,
how you initially
got involved in all of this?
KRYSTLE COLE: Yeah, well, I
met Todd at a strip club.
I worked there for about
three months.
And he came in--
well, actually, one of
his employees came
in and saw me first.
And then they went back, and
they said, oh, there's this
girl down there you should
see, kind of thing.
So then he came and met me.
And shortly thereafter, I was
driving one of his Porsches
and living at his
missile site.
HAMILTON MORRIS: I asked Krystle
to take me on a tour
of the silo, which is now
owned by a vintage tank
enthusiast.
It will be the first time
Krystle has entered the silo
since her romance with Todd.
When Todd was seducing
you, what kinds of
things would he say?
KRYSTLE COLE: Oh, boy.
I don't know.
Um, at first he was
very gentlemanly.
It wasn't like he was drugging
me and taking
advantage or anything.
At first he was being the utmost
gentleman, to try to
win my trust over.
HAMILTON MORRIS: On the way,
we passed the place Krystle
and Todd first met--
Club Orleans, one of Topeka's
premier exotic dance
establishments.
KRYSTLE COLE: This was the club
that I met Todd, although
it was a different
name back then.
They've kind of remodeled
since then.
I did kind of an interesting
act.
I did a bondage act.
And so I--
really stood out for the Kansas
crowd that's in there.
I would play death metal music,
and I had this, like,
chain that I would hold around
my neck with a dog collar.
I'd wrap it around the pole
and stuff, and I'd
whip myself on stage.
I was really into
Goth back then.
Because I really hated Kansas,
and I was just rebelling
against everything that this
whole place was about.
And so he comes in there.
He was sort of like
the mad scientist.
If you can imagine, like, a guy
walking around with this
big metal briefcase,
you know, bald--
and his hair, like, what hair
is left sticking up
everywhere.
His clothes rattered,
tattered everywhere.
He would come in there and just
sit with me and pay me
like lots and lots of money just
to hang out in the VIP
room with him.
And he would sit there
for the whole day.
And we did that for
a couple of times.
And then he's like, well, why
don't you just come out to
where I live, and stuff?
And I was like, well, OK.
I'll go out to your
place with you.
They have a policy where you're
not supposed to leave
with customers.
You're not supposed
to do that.
And I never would have done
that, but Todd was so
persuasive.
And so, I kind of gave in.
I probably shouldn't have.
If I wouldn't have met him, I
wouldn't have had all this
horrible stuff happen.
But I also wouldn't have had
all the cool stuff happen.
He drove Porsches and
had lots of money.
And, you know, he bought me
Armani clothes and gave me
money, and I didn't
have to work at
the strip club anymore.
So I was like, hey,
let's party.
I didn't care.
I'm kind of excited to see what
it looks like in there.
I think it's going to bring
back a lot of memories.
HAMILTON MORRIS: As we drew
near the legendary missile
silo, I tried to imagine Krystle
arriving here with
Todd for the very first time.
KRYSTLE COLE: You used to have
to call in using this system
right there, or you'd
have an access code.
HAMILTON MORRIS: Upon entering
this silo, Krystle left the
spiritual black hole of Kansas
behind forever and was
introduced to Todd and Leonard's
underground ring of
chemists, dealers, and drug
enforcement agents.
KRYSTLE COLE: These tunnels
are really fun when you're
tripping, because they'll start
swirling on you and
you'll be, like, hanging
on, like, ahh!
HAMILTON MORRIS: And what was
your experience with drugs
before having met Gordon
"Todd" Skinner?
KRYSTLE COLE: Virtually none.
Of course, I did the normal
drinking alcohol, smoking pot.
I tried meth twice and
I did coke once.
But other than that--
I'd never even heard of MDMA.
I didn't even know
what it was.
All I know is, he's like, it'll
make you feel good.
Just try it.
You like it.
Don't worry.
You'll like it.
And boy, did I.
Back then, I was on so many
different substances.
It was like living in an
entheogenic monastery, because
I didn't have to work.
I didn't have to worry
about paying bills.
I didn't have to do anything
other than use psychedelics
and pray to the god
that we all share.
The whole situation was centered
around tripping, so
we just wanted to
be comfortable.
This here is the missile bay.
About where the tanks are is
where we had a platform set up
with a stereo, and we would have
a couple of king-sized
beds in here and a bunch of
different couches, like
leather couches and things.
That way we could hang out and
have plenty of places to sit
down and lay down or whatever.
HAMILTON MORRIS: Todd spent
money with wild abandon,
decorating the silo with stone
statues, Persian carpets,
cedar saunas, a marble bathroom
with a tub large
enough to accommodate a
half-dozen people, and a
$120,000 stereo system, which
he used to play both Sarah
McLachlan and Deep Forest at
extremely high volumes.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
KRYSTLE COLE: Yeah, we would
all get in here and shower.
There was lots of nudity.
You can imagine, you
know, lots of cute
girls running around.
And the parties were-- could
get really wild.
One of the things they really
liked to do was have IVs set
up and have some DMT or some
5-MeO in the IV bottle.
They would sit there, and then
they would like, crank it up
so they'd start tripping more.
And then they'd roll it down
a little bit to kind of--
and so you could, like-- he
would like surf in the DMT
high, you know?
I would do a lot,
but not that.
Todd seemed like the most
spiritual person
you would ever meet.
And when we would trip
together, it was
like, I don't know.
Tripping with him is different
than tripping with anyone I've
ever tripped with, you know?
And we experienced things like
telepathy together, and you
know, we experienced
God, if you want to
label it that, together.
HAMILTON MORRIS: Krystle was
exposed to a cornucopia of
psychedelic substances, ranging
from the more common
chemicals like LSD, DMT, and
MDMA to such rarities as
ALD-52, ergot wine, a variety
of fluorinated AMT analogs,
and a mysterious substance
made by
Leonard called diazedine.
Unbeknownst to Krystle, Todd
and Leonard began to argue,
and Todd was slowly overcome by
fear of both Leonard and an
impending bust by the DEA.
KRYSTLE COLE: Todd was so
secretive about everything.
A couple weeks before the bust
happened, he gave me some MDMA
and said, go in the bedroom and
trip and leave me alone.
Don't come out here.
So I was like, pretty high,
and I came out there, and
like, what are you doing?
I'm bored.
And so then I got to
see all the stuff.
He had pictures of Leonard and
all this stuff about Leonard,
like this huge file on him.
Looking back on it, I should've
known something was
getting ready to come down when
he had all that stuff
out, because then I could
have said, Leonard,
you gotta watch out.
KSNT REPORTER: Wamego residents
say they were
shocked when DEA agents arrived
into town on November
6, looking for drug fugitives.
HAMILTON MORRIS: In October
2000, Todd formally contacted
the DEA and declared that he
would like to turn in the
world's largest LSD
manufacturing conspiracy.
Todd received total immunity for
his involvement with the
laboratory and walked away a
free man, while Leonard was
chased by the DEA, outrunning
them on foot and hiding in a
barn with his body covered
with cold leaves to evade
thermal cameras.
The following day, Leonard was
turned in by a farmer and
eventually given two concurrent
life sentences
without parole.
MALE SPEAKER: Wamego Police
Department were brought in to
assist in the manhunt, which
ended up being an 18-hour hunt
for the individual.
KSNT REPORTER: DEA agents
believe the LSD lab is one of
the largest in the world.
HAMILTON MORRIS: After the
bust, Krystle and Todd
traveled across the country for
three years with a small
group of ravers and drug
enthusiasts, selling
phosphorescent capsules of
MDMA and living like
psychedelic royalty in Seattle,
Mendocino, Tucson, and Tulsa.
KRYSTLE COLE: Here's our
California house.
We had our own private
beach down there.
We would try to get the best
we could everywhere.
HAMILTON MORRIS: There were
peacocks on the property?
KRYSTLE COLE: Yeah.
Yeah.
There were peacocks
on the property.
You would think having
peacocks would be
cool, but it wasn't.
Outside of our houses was
all these Amanitas.
And so we would go pick
Amanitas and stuff.
You can see us, we're
identifying them and
researching them.
Some of these don't have Todd in
them, because he didn't let
us take a lot of pictures.
There towards the end, I think
all the stress of the court
case, and everything, you know,
the years of running,
and the years of all the
problems, you know, just
really were piling in on him.
And I think that he was
just kind of going
a little bit crazy.
Todd was very much escalating
things.
He started abusing me,
like literally
physically abusing me.
I was willing to look over some
of the bad stuff that I
started to see the first couple
years, because, oh, I
know underneath all this,
it's just the stress.
It's just temporary.
Underneath all that, he's this
beautiful, spiritual person.
And he's doing all this
for good reasons.
And now looking back on
it, no, he was just
manipulating me.
I was--
I was just a stupid girl.
You know?
He always had a couple of
other girlfriends, and I
always had boyfriends.
And we were each other's
primary, you know, I mean, but
like we always had other
people around.
And so the boyfriend at the
time, Brad, he was the first
guy over the years that I dated
that wanted-- that said,
look, this situation's
no good.
You need to get away
from this.
And so, so I'm like, OK, well,
the only way for us to get out
of this is for us to go to the
DEA and basically do what Todd
did to Leonard to Todd.
And so we go to the DEA
together, and we basically
spill everything about Todd's
local operation that he's got
going there.
They were already familiar with
the Pickard case and all
that stuff.
And so they knew who I was, that
I was Todd's girlfriend
and all that.
They had a case.
They had me.
They had the boyfriend.
And I told them where
one of his labs was.
So they had more than enough
of a case, and more than
enough of a reason
to go after him.
You know what they said to me?
They're like, well, we'll
give you a call.
And I'm like, OK.
And so they had my
phone number.
So I go home.
And then conveniently, two days
later, Todd called me up.
Well, I know you went
into the DEA.
HAMILTON MORRIS: So you
went into the DEA.
You told them that
he was dangerous.
They took down all
the information.
Didn't do anything at
all to stop him.
But told him that you had
reported him and just
infuriated him?
KRYSTLE COLE: Yes.
And that is why he kidnapped me
and Brad and did the things
that he did to us.
HAMILTON MORRIS: On the 4th of
July, 2003, believing he was
immune to legal prosecution,
Todd lured Krystle and Brad to
the Tulsa Doubletree Inn.
Shortly after meeting, Todd
offered Brad a communion wafer
laced with an unknown
psilocin analog.
KRYSTLE COLE: The next thing I
know, he's duct-taped up, and
they were injecting
him with stuff.
And they were telling me, you
know, if you don't obey
everything we say, we're going
to give him something that's
going to kill him.
And we have to get information
out of him.
We have to know what he said.
HAMILTON MORRIS: As the drug
took effect, Todd taped Brad
up and spent one week subjecting
him to psychedelic
tortures of unfathomable
depravity.
KRYSTLE COLE: I know that he
was giving him stuff like
barbiturates and things
like Valium and stuff.
HAMILTON MORRIS: But
he was using
psychedelics as a truth serum?
KRYSTLE COLE: Yeah.
And he was using psychedelics
as well.
He was giving him IV DMT.
Any drug he had, he pretty much
was giving it to him.
You know, and after that, after
it was over, I had to
stay with Todd for
a whole month.
And I mean, he drugged me, he
raped me, he sodomized me, he
did horrible things to me.
It's hard for me to talk about,
because I have PTSD now
because of what he did.
But I mean, it's horrendous.
I mean, to think that somebody
would use psychedelics for the
kinds of things he
used them for.
HAMILTON MORRIS: Todd fled to
Burning Man, where he was
arrested for MDMA distribution
and ultimately tried for
kidnapping and assault with
a dangerous weapon.
For these acts, Todd was
sentenced to life in prison.
KRYSTLE COLE: Todd was so tall
that he had to really watch
out for those things, or he
would hit his head on them.
KRYSTLE COLE: Yeah.
He has life, so you don't have
to worry about him coming back
and haunting the place here.
Once you trip a lot, you can
make any trip a pleasant
experience.
Unless the person's literally
standing above you and
injecting you and strangling
and threatening you and
yelling at you and stuff.
You can't-- there's no way
to make that good.
The last few years have been a
difficult road for me to walk
down, yet they have made me
a much better person.
I got so far out of touch with
a normal person's reality.
For years, I never worked a job,
watched television, or
even went a week without
being around someone
who was on an entheogen.
I basically had to start
life all over.
I began watching the news to
get up to speed on current
events, got an apartment of my
own, and started a business to
support myself.
I feel like even after four
years, I'm still working on
reintegrating into society.
In the spirit of actually doing
something with what I've
learned through entheogens, I
founded a nonprofit website
called NeuroSoup.com.
My hope is that it will be a
place for people to learn,
share their beliefs about
spirituality, entheogens, and
themselves.
Namaste.
HAMILTON MORRIS: After
everything that has
transpired, Krystle still
considers Todd
the love of her life.
We are all brothers in the
family of humanity, and life
is a cosmic giggle on the
breath of the universe.
Namaste.