Or are they facing
a Hillbilly Hindenburg?
ROG: Oh, the humanity!
TRAVIS: I'm Travis Taylor.
I'm a rocket scientist in
the space and defense industry
here in my hometown of
Huntsville, Alabama,
where my daddy helped
build the rockets
that sent us to the moon.
DADDY: Have y'all been drinking
the rocket fuel again?
TRAVIS: Sometimes, big science
moves too slow for me.
So come the weekend,
I round up my best friend Rog...
ROG: Hey!
TRAVIS: ...my nephew Michael
and my buddy Pete
to tackle important problems
with a little
down-home ingenuity.
ROG: Damn it, boy!
TRAVIS: Right on.
Hey, is there any more beers
in the cooler?
Human beings have always
wanted to fly.
From Leonardo Da Vinci
to the Wright brothers.
So this weekend, I wanted us
to fulfill the dream
by creating
a one-man flying machine.
In fact, the US military
has been trying to create
a personal aerial device
since the 1950s.
Ours has got to be small,
portable,
and able to soar into the sky
without killing the pilot.
The only problem is
I've got a scheduling conflict.
The guys are gonna have to wait
until I get back this afternoon
before they get started.
DADDY: Y'all doing good
cleaning up, huh?
ROG: Where's Travis at
when we all cleaning up
his ideas and crap over here?
DADDY: Well, you're doing
a good job of cleaning up,
but he's at the science fiction
convention is where he's gone.
TRAVIS: I'm a huge fan
of science fiction
and a science fiction author.
This weekend I'm at
a science fiction convention
talking about my writing.
What I like to see, what
I usually do with my characters
is they get what's
coming to 'em,
and then we blow 'em up
some more.
[laughter]
It's a lot of fun, and you never
know what you're gonna see next.
GORDO: I was at both panels.
It was awesome.
TRAVIS: Oh, thanks, man!
Thanks a lot.
GORDO: I really like
what you said.
TRAVIS: I appreciate it.
What's your name?
GORDO: Uh, Gordo.
TRAVIS: Gordo, "To Gordo...
Stay with it."
GORDO: Yeah, if you ever have
like an assistant
you could hire or something,
'cause, like, I write a lot.
TRAVIS: This one fanboy, Gordo,
he's been following me around
pretty much in this con.
It happens sometimes.
I have no idea
what he looked like,
because he's wearing
a gray alien suit.
TRAVIS: All right, thanks, man.
Thanks, Gordo.
ROG: Travis ain't here,
but that's no reason we can't
start the project without him.
We've got enough brainpower here
to surprise him
with a flying machine
by the time he gets back.
Let's make a jetpack
like they had on
the Six Million Dollar Man.
You remember?
He wanted to be an astronaut
when he was, like,
six years old.
That's why we have rocket stuff
laying around,
because he's a rocket guy.
DADDY:
Y'all think we can build one?
ROG: Shoot, yeah,
we got some rockets.
Well, Charlie, you care if
we rage and go power around,
we get all the stuff we need?
DADDY: Would it make
any difference?
ROG: Well, you don't care.
DADDY: Go ahead.
ROG: Hey, Michael, we got
some of them mannequins.
MICHAEL: Oh, I'm sure we do.
DADDY: I think,
I think the truth...
ROG: I'm fixing to write
on the chalkboard.
Alright, Pete.
I went up to the chalkboard,
wrote Pete does the ciphering,
deciphering the math.
These people in the south,
sometimes they decipher.
That's what you do.
Charlie.
Charlie keeps everybody
straight.
MICHAEL: I like that, Rog.
ROG: Michael and I might have
to go on a road trip.
DADDY: Road trip?
ROG: Well, maybe it might
if it comes up.
We don't know.
There's nobody there to yell
and scream at everybody.
And I thought, I can be a diva.
That sounds like a good job.
I'm gonna be Travis.
You know he don't do nothing
but walk around and holler.
DADDY: You know,
I got this suspicion,
Rog has always wanted
to be the boss.
ROG: He walks around here,
I hear him all the time.
"Well, I'm gonna go
check on Rog."
check on Daddy."
[laughs]
PETE: That's right.
MICHAEL: I'm gonna go
find them dummies.
ROG: Charlie and I dug out
the rocket motors
while Michael rounded up
a couple of dummies.
Everything we needed
is right here.
Boy, he's got pretty eyes.
Is that, that's a boy, ain't it?
I'm a sucker for pretty eyes,
and them eyes were saying,
"I want to fly."
Build like a frame,
put it on his back.
All we need is a frame
and that...
Charlie, can we use that
backpack over there?
DADDY: Man, if that thing
pulls hard enough
to pick him up off the ground...
PETE: Yeah, I know.
DADDY: You're gonna have to have
more than one strap
coming through like that.
That, that thing...
PETE: Yeah, he's gonna need
a hefty jockstrap.
Actually, building a jetpack
is more complex
than just putting a rocket
in a backpack.
These are K-sized motors with
nearly 100 pounds of thrust,
so we'll need a structure
to keep it from just
tearing off the backpack.
We're also gonna need to add
some fins for flight stability
if we want to get airborne.
ROG: I'm gonna go check
on Michael and Pete.
MICHAEL: Shut up, Rog!
ROG: Oh, is it too early?
MICHAEL: It was definitely
different with Rog,
you know, running the show.
ROG: Here.
MICHAEL: Thanks, man.
I like you as the boss.
ROG: Well, thank you.
I'm gonna check on Charlie.
MICHAEL: That's the best thing
about Rog being the boss
is he keeps you in beer.
ROG: I'm gonna go check on Pete.
PETE: Now I'm not sure
what Travis is up to
at the sci-fi convention,
but I doubt he's having
as much fun as we are
watching Rog play boss.
GORDO: So what are you doing
after this?
TRAVIS: Uh, I'm not sure.
I have to look at the schedule
what they got me scheduled for.
Man, that Gordo was on me
like bees on honey.
GORDO: Do you ever, like,
think for when you're writing,
do you ever, like, have, like,
an assistant that you'd hire
or something?
TRAVIS: But, hey, I'll make time
for anybody who loves
science fiction,
because, to me,
it's very important.
Science fiction drove me
to become a scientist,
and I believe there are
all sorts of things
in science fiction that
the authors imagine
years before it ever happened.
And in a lot of cases,
the reason it happened
was because the scientist
or engineer read that story
and said, hey, maybe,
just maybe.
PETE: Careful,
that's a loaded rocket.
ROG: Lock them nuts down
tight as you can get 'em, man.
MICHAEL: Both of 'em?
ROG: Yeah, both of 'em.
See how fast stuff gets done
when I'm the boss?
We got our jetpack
on our dummy's back
and fins on his feet.
This thing's almost ready to go.
We got the thrust structure
and the rocket with
100 pounds of thrust.
He got pretty eyes still,
don't he?
PETE: He does.
DADDY: I wish you'd forget
about the eyes, Rog.
ROG: Well.
PETE: I've been trying to give
the guys some guidance
in rocket science know-how.
I'm a little concerned about
how this is gonna work.
That's a K-motor in there.
They are made for high-power
experimental rockets
that are designed to go
about a mile high.
It packs a lot of thrust in
a very short amount of time.
MICHAEL: All right,
that backpack's locked down.
PETE: But anytime we get to
strap a rocket to anything,
it's always fun,
so I figure, what the heck.
Let's see what happens
and hopefully not get killed
in the process.
ROG: Hey, look, right up there,
that's a good spot.
PETE: So we headed off to
our favorite test field
where we can stand as far away
from this thing as possible
when it goes off.
All right, we got a hot rocket!
ROG: Hurry up, Pete!
We ain't got time for
your shenanigans.
MICHAEL: You know,
this is something that
as long as it works
I want to try it out, too.
ROG: Everybody ready?
PETE: Yeah.
DADDY: I hope this truck
protects us
from what's about to happen.
Part of me wants
to close my eyes,
and the other part don't want
to miss a second.
ROG: Three, two, one.
[laughs]
DADDY: Oh, man!
You want to put my son
on that thing?
ROG: We let it go
and she does a loop-de-loop.
[laughs]
DADDY: That thing went
end over end, heel over head,
tumbling and it wrecked.
Tore it all to pieces.
MICHAEL: That thing
actually flew!
DADDY: Actually flew?
Yeah, it flipped in circles.
MICHAEL: Three circles.
ROG: He did a face-plant.
Look at here.
DADDY: A mannequin is not
a very good rocket.
What did you think
it was gonna do?
ROG: Well, if it don't work,
we'll go do something else.
Let's go back and draw pictures
on the chalkboard,
figure out something better
that we can control.
PETE: Yeah.
ROG: So much for the first
jetpack idea.
Maybe we need bigger rockets.
I figured I'd call Travis
and see what he thinks.
TRAVIS: What?
Hang on just a minute, Gordo.
Rog, Rog, you, you're...
No, you can't do that
with a rocket engine, Rog.
In fact, it'll blow up.
No, hang on just a minute.
I'll talk to you in a minute,
Gordo.
It's alright.
What?
No, you can't put
a rocket engine on that.
Rog, those motors are too big.
It'll start a fire
and it might blow up.
It'll kill somebody.
No, I--what are you--
I can't believe that.
I got to--
no, you're not doing that.
I decided I'd better get back
before Rog blows everybody up.
ROG: Travis didn't seem too keen
on bigger rockets.
Luckily, Michael came up
with a totally different
flying machine idea.
MICHAEL: We were on the way back
from this test
and I had an idea.
I got this helicopter that,
you know, it flies.
I built it out of a kit and
a bunch of radio control parts.
This radio-controlled,
six-blade chopper,
thought it would work real good
for a flying machine
if you, you know,
scale it up a whole lot.
It's something that's stable
and that we can control,
and it's a whole lot safer
to ride on.
This is a radio-controlled
helicopter.
Here you go, Rog, you think
you can fly this thing?
ROG: No, I can't fly.
DADDY: We're gonna have to
build it to pick up 200 pounds,
'cause that's what your Uncle
Travis is gonna want to do.
He's gonna want
to fly the thing.
ROG: Of course, we're gonna
have to do a test
before we strap a bunch of these
on Travis.
And since we only have
one copter right now,
I grabbed our little
two-pound light mannequin.
DADDY: What?
ROG: Lookie here.
You know it'll pick him up.
DADDY: Well, that thing
don't weigh anything.
ROG: Well, still, that's what
we gonna tow to, ain't it?
MICHAEL: Ain't tried carrying
anything with this copter yet,
so it's good to start light.
We need to make sure
we can control it
before adding too much weight.
ROG: Let's see what
this thing will do.
ROG: Wake up, mule, wake up.
MICHAEL: Wake up!
PETE: Oh, man, you got plenty
of lift right there.
TRAVIS: When I pulled up,
there was the weirdest thing
I'd ever seen
in Daddy's front yard.
MICHAEL: Hey.
TRAVIS: What in the wide, wide
world of sports
is going on here?
DADDY: These Experiments are
dangerous.
These guys are real rocket
scientists
Don't try this at home!
TRAVIS: We're building
a one-man flying machine.
Since I was at
a science fiction convention,
the guys got started without me.
ROG: Everybody ready?
PETE: Yeah.
[laughs]
DADDY: Oh, man.
TRAVIS: Looks like I couldn't
have got home a moment too soon.
[horn honks]
[laughs]
What in the wide, wide world
of sports is going on here?
DADDY: We're playing
with your new toy.
TRAVIS: Look at that!
I got home from
the science fiction convention
and I pull into Daddy's, and
there are the guys out there,
and they've got this,
this helicopter thing up there,
and there's a dummy
hanging from it.
I mean, what in the world
are they doing?
It looked cool, though.
DADDY: Now, I'm gonna tell you,
this is the second effort.
The first one was
a total bomb-out.
TRAVIS: What'd y'all do
the first go around?
ROG: Come over here and look.
We'll show you.
TRAVIS: I thought it was
pretty cool of the guys
to be working on the one-man
flying machine thing
while I was off at
the science fiction convention.
It feels heavy.
What motor did you use on it?
PETE: K-motor.
TRAVIS: A K-motor! Holy crap!
That'll do it.
Broke this one's leg off!
MICHAEL: He broke his own
leg off when he crashed.
TRAVIS: Oh, and his head!
DADDY: That's about
what you'd look like
if you'd been hooked
on to that thing.
TRAVIS: I wouldn't let y'all
hook a K-motor to my back.
DADDY: We decided
we had to do something,
then Michael had
this helicopter.
TRAVIS: It's not a bad idea.
We could probably do this
if we could find the motors
and the propellers.
We're gonna scale up Michael's
remote-control helicopter
so that it's big enough
to lift one man.
ROG: Look at these
pretty eyes, mule.
Have you seen these eyes
on this guy?
TRAVIS: So I sent the guys
to find
the biggest hobby helicopter
propellers they could find.
We're back in business.
You know where to get
that kind of stuff?
MICHAEL: Yeah, I know where
we can find some.
ROG: Let's go, road trip.
MICHAEL: Road trip, Rog,
come on!
ROG: Travis came back in
and fell right into
his diva-boss-princess mode.
TRAVIS: Buy every big motor
they got!
ROG: I didn't mind,
'cause first thing I got to do
is go on a road trip.
TRAVIS: Tell 'em to put it
on Rog's tab.
MICHAEL: All right.
PETE: And don't forget
propellers and controllers.
TRAVIS: We're gonna create
a lightweight aluminum frame
with six arms to hold six of the
biggest motors and propellers
we can find.
Then we'll have the pilot seated
underneath it all
in a lawn chair.
We are gonna add
thick Lexan shields
on all sides of the cockpit.
To protect the pilot from debris
and the chopper blades.
Once Michael and Rog got back
with a whole bunch of motors
and propellers,
I started divvying up the jobs.
Sent Daddy and Rog to start
cutting the materials,
Michael started
drilling the holes,
Pete and I were figuring out how
it was all gonna fit together.
It's gonna be a cage like that,
so now figure out those pieces,
Pete.
PETE: All right.
TRAVIS: We're real concerned
that the motors we got
were not gonna be enough
to lift me and the helicopter,
so we had to do a test.
DADDY: We set up a scale system
so we could measure
the lift weight
of the motor and the propellers.
Now, I keep telling these boys,
these blades are very sharp
and very dangerous,
they can shatter any second
and send wooden spikes
going in all directions.
TRAVIS: Stay away from
the blade, Pete.
DADDY: I made everybody get
behind a blast shield
for protection.
Come on, son,
it'll take your head off.
TRAVIS: You guys ready?
ROG: Yeah.
MICHAEL: Yeah.
TRAVIS: All right, here we go.
5, 10, 15...
20, 25, 30...
almost 35 at times.
PETE: That's all...
TRAVIS: All right,
bring her down.
It looks like we're gonna get
about 33 pounds of lift
from each motor.
That's including lifting
its own weight.
PETE: Let's unhook it.
TRAVIS:
Yeah, unhook the battery.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
What'd you do?
[whistles]
MICHAEL:
Don't turn it off, Pete.
You nev--don't ever cut that.
PETE: Yep, I remember that now.
MICHAEL: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Man, you weren't
but an inch from that.
Don't do that again.
PETE: When that motor started up
right next to me,
probably doing
a good 2,000 RPMs,
that scared the crap out of me.
TRAVIS: I'm really glad Pete
has those Aikido reflexes.
He got away from it really quick
and turned everything off.
PETE: You know, that's one
of the times luck won out.
TRAVIS: We're gonna be right on
the hairy edge
of having enough lift to do it.
PETE: Yeah, I know.
TRAVIS: Once we got the aluminum
cut and the holes drilled,
we began to put together
the frame of our flying machine.
It's got to hold
six of those motors
and the pilot will hang
beneath it in a lawn chair,
surrounded by thick, protective,
plastic shields.
DADDY: It's another long day
and another long night.
Thankfully,
Travis picked up some dinner
to help us get through.
TRAVIS: By morning, we had
most of the frame together.
Our propeller test showed us
that we needed six propellers,
but with the extra weight
of the shields,
I was afraid that wasn't
gonna give us enough lift.
So we added two more propellers.
TRAVIS:
You got these two blades.
They're opposite direction
and opposite pitch.
That end's got to be
the same as that one.
PETE: Right.
TRAVIS: Once we had it
all wired up,
we added some safety cushions
and padding,
and we were ready
to fly this puppy.
There are a lot of things
that could go wrong
with this helicopter,
but there are a lot of things
that could go right.
MICHAEL: What do y'all reckon
it weighs?
TRAVIS: I don't know,
I'm thinking with everything,
the motors and all,
about 80 pounds.
DADDY: If this thing weighs
80 or 100 pounds,
and Travis weighs 200 pounds,
that's around 300 pounds
we need to lift.
That's beyond the hairy edge,
if you ask me.
TRAVIS: Into the wind, yeah,
back toward the house.
Alright, right there.
That's a pretty strong one.
Where'd that wind come from?
Ain't been blowing all day.
We come out to test fly
the helicopter.
Alright, let's clear out.
For safety's sake, Daddy ain't
gonna let me get in that thing
until we know it'll fly
and we can control it.
But as soon as we can
fly it right,
I'm gonna hop right in it
and have the ride of my life.
Alright, guys, this is it.
I want this thing to fly.
ROG: Who don't?
TRAVIS: Yeah, I tell you what!
Come on, let's bring
the power up!
ROG: Spinning mule.
DADDY: There she goes.
TRAVIS: They're all spinning.
PETE: That's a good sign.
TRAVIS: Bring it up
nice and easy, nice and easy.
DADDY: Come on.
TRAVIS: Come on, baby, come on.
TRAVIS: Come on.
DADDY: Get up.
TRAVIS: Coming on up,
coming on up.
DADDY: Get up.
TRAVIS: Coming on up.
Well, she's kicking up
some dust a little.
Coming off the ground,
coming off the ground.
We're flying! We're flying!
We're flying!
PETE: Oh.
TRAVIS: Oh!
Crap!
ROG: Son of a...
TRAVIS:
We spent the whole weekend
building a one-man
flying machine...
Let's all grab a leg
and let's fly it.
PETE: All right.
TRAVIS: ...and we finally went
to get our homemade copter
airborne.
Coming off the ground.
We're flying! We're flying!
We're flying!
But then, disaster.
Oh!
MICHAEL: This one right here's
busted all to, hmm.
TRAVIS: We blew another,
another gusset here.
DADDY: Here's one propeller
tore all to pieces.
TRAVIS: This isn't anything
unheard of
when you're talking about
experimental aircraft.
You don't ever get it right
the first time.
Now I got to go back and see
what we broke,
what ain't broke,
what we got to do to fix it.
We made three major
modifications to the copter.
We made the frame taller
and the base wider,
so it's less likely to flip.
We got rid of the Lexan
protective shields
to lighten it up,
and most importantly,
we doubled the amount
of propellers
with top rotors and
bottom rotors on each arm.
That should give it
twice the lift.
Now we're gonna take it out
and I'm gonna ride that thing.
Let's take this thing around
the corner and hook it up.
DADDY: Wait a minute, son.
TRAVIS: What have you got there?
DADDY: I got old Sidney here.
He's gonna pilot this thing.
There's no way in the world
you're gonna get in that thing
before we try it.
This contraption is more
dangerous than ever.
They not only took off
the safety shields,
they doubled the rotors,
so it's twice as deadly.
We need a test dummy before
I let anybody get in that thing.
TRAVIS: We better tie this thing
down really good, though.
I don't want anything coming
loose and getting into a blade.
We moved the whole thing to
the test site in the backyard.
Crawl up under there
and tie it off.
And then we tethered the copter
to the ground
to keep it from flying away
out of control or flipping over.
So I think it's about
as safe as it'll get.
Y'all get back away from 'em.
Y'all get out of there.
MICHAEL: It's good.
TRAVIS: Alright, spin test.
Get over here where you're safe
in the safe zone.
Everybody in the safe zone now.
Be ready to run away
from the helicopter.
ROG: Yeah.
TRAVIS: We're gonna throttle it
up a little.
Here we go!
Everything's still spinning.
Come on, baby.
PETE: Come on.
ROG: There you go, son!
There it is!
TRAVIS: Yeah!
ROG: That's a good deal.
TRAVIS: Oh, yeah!
Now we're talking.
ROG: Alright!
PETE: There you go.
TRAVIS: Now let's bring
her down, bring her down.
PETE: Bring it down.
Easy, easy.
TRAVIS: Yeah, right there.
PETE: Good job, man,
that was awesome!
TRAVIS: Helicopter taters.
That was awesome.
The copter flew perfectly level.
It looked like it could've just
flown like that forever.
It was a perfect test flight.
Now it's my turn.
Now we got to recharge
the batteries
and let's do a man flight.
DADDY: I'm still not confident
with this.
That dummy's only
20 pounds or so.
Travis is eight or ten times
heavier.
This might not even
get off the ground,
and if it tips over again,
Travis could be
seriously injured.
ROG: Look at that boy, yeah.
TRAVIS: I've got my fireproof
race driver's suit
and my helmet,
and I'm ready to be
the test pilot.
Y'all about got it ready?
This is gonna be a lot of fun.
DADDY: Is there any way
I could talk you out of this?
TRAVIS: Probably not, Daddy.
MICHAEL: Get in there
and fire it up.
TRAVIS: I can't wait to get in
that thing and fly it.
MICHAEL: Do your little test and
then as long as they all spin,
we're out of here.
Got it, we're gone.
PETE: Alright. The field
is clear, you're good to go!
MICHAEL: It's all you!
PETE: All right.
DADDY: Oh!
It ain't gonna work.
I knew it.
ROG: Yeah!
PETE: Yeah!
ROG: All right.
ROG: Look at him, son!
PETE: Woo!
MICHAEL: That's awesome,
that's awesome! Shut him down.
TRAVIS: When I hit the ground
and I realized I wasn't dead,
I thought that was the greatest
thing I'd ever done.
Look at that.
PETE: That was awesome, buddy!
TRAVIS: How about that?
PETE: How'd that feel?
TRAVIS: Oh, that was great!
DADDY: You know,
this has got to be
what the Wright brothers
went through.
They didn't know if
they could fly or not,
but they proved that they could
and this afternoon,
Travis proved that we could
build a helicopter right here
in this garage
and make the thing fly.
TRAVIS: Man, let me tell you,
it felt like,
I couldn't really tell how high
I was off the ground,
but at one time I thought
I was up there pretty good.
PETE: Oh, you were about
like that, yeah.
TRAVIS: That was cool, man.
DADDY: I tell you,
it was a hoot. I loved it.
TRAVIS: Go watch any flight test
on a new vehicle,
they only fly it a few feet
off the ground
the first few times anyway.
That's 100% success right there.
ROG: Well, it ain't a jetpack,
but we built a flying machine
in a garage and made it fly.
It's like something out of
Travis' sci-fi books.
I bet even his biggest fan
wouldn't believe this.