EDDIE: Didn't nobody see that
I bonged it into the bowl.
EDDIE (NARRATING): What's up?
It's your boy Eddie Huang--
chef, writer, human panda,
Bang Bros connoisseur, and
I'm horny for more.
EDDIE: We tripping, man.
EDDIE (NARRATING): If I had to
explain "Fresh Off the Boat,"
I'd say that it's a cultural
show told through the lens of
food, putting on voices that
have long gone ignored.
Fuck with the human panda, this
is "Fresh Off the Boat."
EDDIE (NARRATING): Today we're
headed to the Bay Area to hang
with some barbers and the Rice
Paper Scissors crew.
But first it's off to Oakland to
shoot some rabbits with the
East Bay Rats.
EDDIE: Let's shoot some guns.
Let's kill some rabbits.
Let's do this.
TREVOR: Cool.
Done.
EDDIE: All right?
TREVOR: All right, let's
take a walk.
You guys stay up here
and practice.
EDDIE: So you--
I mean, this is not
just a hobby.
It's kind of a lifestyle
for you.
Instead of going to market, you
by shells, you drive, you
come out here and do it.
TREVOR: Yeah.
EDDIE: All the way.
TREVOR: I eat a lot of
food out of here.
I come up here every
Sunday to hunt.
I started planting
fruit trees.
And eventually I'll just
eat what's off of here.
People that eat meat and aren't
willing to kill an
animal are fucking pussies.
And fuck them.
Bang bang.
EDDIE: Got him.
How do we do this.
How do we get these--?
TREVOR: Hopefully we see
some rabbits down here.
And we'll walk down
here and sneak in,
and see what happens.
EDDIE: Should we stand somewhere
in particular?
Where is he?
[RAPID SUCCESSION OF GUNSHOTS]
Are those all your
friends up there?
TREVOR: Yeah.
EDDIE: They're all in the
bike gang and stuff?
TREVOR: No, not at all.
You'll meet the bike
club after this.
What I was saying before is I've
been teaching all these
hipster kids from the coffee
shops how to hunt and shoot.
Trying to get the next
generation coming.
And just the fact that
everybody's moving from the
country to the city, it's
a whole nother movement.
All these skills
are being lost.
Nobody younger than
us is hunting.
Nobody's applying for
hunting licenses.
And it's just the whole
thing's changing.
People don't do it.
That's the whole thing.
Teach them gun safety now
and then they'll get it.
EDDIE: I'm holding this
properly, right?
TREVOR: You're good--
EDDIE: On the back, yeah?
TREVOR: As long as you don't
point it at me or anybody
else, were happy.
EDDIE: Just so the
viewers know.
TREVOR: Kind of the
bottom line.
EDDIE: Point it up and
away, down and away.
Whoa.
TREVOR: Ooh.
EDDIE: Yo, so do you
have, like, a stunt
rabbit for this show?
You know, one we could
let loose.
TREVOR: I've got some rabbits
that I raise, and I wonder how
they'll taste.
EDDIE: Yeah?
TREVOR: We could pull
it out and kill it.
Billy, you wanna
kill a rabbit?
With your hands?
BILLY: Yeah.
Want to grab one?
TREVOR: You've got
to eat the heart.
BILLY: I will.
EDDIE: Which one are you
going to pull out?
BILLY: This guy right here.
EDDIE: OK, perfect.
BILLY: Whitey.
TREVOR: Whitey.
[LAUGHS]
We're going to kill Whitey.
EDDIE: Kill Whitey.
Kill Whitey!
I'm a man who--
I have no problem
killing shrimp.
killing a crab.
I have no problem
killing a fish.
I'll drop a live lobster in a
pot of boiling water and not
think twice about it.
But I have a moral
inconsistency.
Because watching that rabbit die
under that dude's knee--
And we knew for weeks that we
were going to come watch
Trevor either shoot a wild
rabbit or slaughter a rabbit
that he raised for slaughter.
And still, our crew was not
emotionally prepared and did
not know how they were
going to feel.
Tough, right?
MALE SPEAKER: I still want it.
EDDIE: And now you don't
feel so tough.
MALE SPEAKER: No.
EDDIE: We're so cut off from
the process of slaughter.
We're not reminded.
We don't see the image
every day.
This enables these companies
and these people, and even
places like my restaurant to
sell you more animal protein
than you would actually eat if
you were reminded and were
conscious of what
had to go down.
It'd be hard to sell as much
meat as people in America buy
if there were someone playing a
video out front of a grocery
store, like this is
what happened.
It's not a game.
MALE VOICE (OFFSCREEN): Don't
worry about the fur.
BILLY: Yeah, he just seemed
like dumbshit the
whole time I was--
MALE SPEAKER: Can I just shoot
shit still, or no?
EDDIE: What's up, Trevor?
TREVOR: Hey, hey, man.
EDDIE: How you guys going
to cook the rabbit?
TREVOR: So she decided to bread
it, buttermilk it, and
deep fry it.
EDDIE: Nice.
Is she from the South?
Because I see this cast
iron skillet.
TREVOR: No, she's
from New Jersey.
But she's been working at a
Southern restaurant, so I
think she's got her
technique down.
Hell yeah.
TREVOR'S GIRLFRIEND: Wild
rabbit is a little
bit gamier, for sure.
This is rabbit that we've been
raising and feeding in a cage,
so there's a ton more meat
and a lot more fat on it.
EDDIE: Try this.
This looks good.
A rabbit tender over here.
It's like a mix of chicken
and gator.
TREVOR: Yeah.
Thank you very much
for the rabbit.
It was delicious.
You got skills with
that skillet.
Thank you for having us.
TREVOR: All right, man.
Good stuff.
Come by any time.
EDDIE: Thank you so much
for that, man.
We'll see you soon.
EDDIE (NARRATING): Every time
I eat meat now, I have to be
conscious of the fact that I am
choosing to enable someone
to kill an animal and create a
market demand for slaughter.
And I don't think there's
anything wrong with that.
You just have to be conscious
with the choice you make.
Every time you eat meat, just
remember that bunny's head
fucking falling off.
You know?
And if you can still eat,
more power to you, man.
Do you.
But I will try as long as I can
to keep that image in my
mind, because I don't want
to be unconscious of
what's going down.
"Fresh Off the Boat"
with Eddie Huang.
We out.
FUBU.
For us, by us food show, kid.
A'ight?
EDDIE (NARRATING): Next up on
"Fresh Off the Boat," we're
headed to San Francisco's
Mission District to grow
cephalopods on the block with
the Rice Paper Scissors crew.
EDDIE: We need this
in Chinese school.
You know, man?
These Chinese kids don't use
their dicks till they're 40.
[LAUGHTER]