have competed each year for a twenty-five thousand dollar college scholarship,
and the honor of being crowned the National Geographic Bee Champion.
Winners of the state-level competitions met in Washington late last month.
Representing DoDEA this year was Gavin Moulton, a 7th Grade student from
Naples American Middle School in Naples, Italy.
While in the Nation's Capitol, the Moulton family toured DoDEA Headquarters,
and met with Deputy Director Charlie Toth.
Moulton, who placed a respectable 16th in this year's event,
had one piece of advice for future competitors.
"Study, study, study.  If you want to do well, you have to study.
Many kids there spend a lot of their time and they're very, very, very smart.
I mean if you watched any of the DVD's they had of the finals,
you can tell that all the kids are very, very smart."
National Geographic Channel will air the BEE competition over
four nights beginning Monday, June 13th.
That's all for this edition of DoDEA News in a Minute, thanks for watching.
[MUSIC]