The cloud is lifting
over the city.
We almost died in our
Yugo last night.
So we decided to give it a
rest and trade up for our
fixer's Chevy Aveo.
So you can see, the choice has
made all the difference.
We're automotively living in
a lap of luxury right now.
This is our fixer, Elvis.
He's blind in one eye, which
kind of makes him look like a
Bosnian David Bowie.
He's also wrecked three cars in
the week we've known him.
THOMAS MORTON: Yeah.
I was wondering where all
this mist came from.
[HORN HONKS]
THOMAS MORTON: Before the Serbs
turned it into Hogan's
Island in the '90s, Sarajevo
was an extremely modern
European city.
It's also the biggest Muslim
city in Europe.
Though most residents are
Muslims the same way, like,
New Yorkers are Jews
or Christians.
They go to mosque for prayers
and the holidays, but
that's about it.
All the men have shaved
faces, most people
drink, ladies wear jeans.
It's relaxed.
While the majority of Sarajevans
and really Bosnians
in general are sort of Friday
Muslims, Islam is still a
really big deal.
During the wars, the Bosniak
Muslims became a cause celebre
in the Arab world, with
countries like Saudi Arabia
and Afghanistan sending money
for humanitarian aid and even
funneling Mujahideen fighters
in to lend a hand.
All of which is basically
a push to increase Arab
influence in the region and
stoke a national religious
revival, which naturally would
play into places like Saudi
Arabia's political interests.
This mega mosque in
Sarajevo was built
entirely with Saudi money.
It's also on the grounds of
the Saudi Embassy, which
technically means it's on
Saudi Arabian soil.
And obviously the crowd here
looks a little different from
the congregation across town.
Now, our goal right now is to
see if we can meet some local
Muslims and figure out
what's going on.
And figure out why they're
more kind of into Islamic
identity and, by possible
extension, extremist Islamism
in their parent's generation,
or if that's true at all.
MALE SPEAKER 1:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
THOMAS MORTON: How hard is it to
keep up the faith, like, in
this environment?
MALE SPEAKER 1:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
THOMAS MORTON: Sarajevo and
Bosnia's other big cities
aren't exactly seed beds of
fundamentalist Islam,
at least not yet.
But there's a village in the
north of the country called
Gornja Maoca that adheres
to strict Wahabi Islam.
The men there have beards.
The women wear full niqab.
It's kind of quaint.
Well, quaint in the way that
Western newspapers describe
with things like "Afghanistan
in Europee" and "a potential
terrorist training camp."
The residents of Gornja Maoca
aren't super receptive to this
criticism or really the
media in general.
Actually, almost every camera
crew that's gone to visit them
has been driven out
of the village.
In addition to just bad press,
Gornja Maoca has also been
raided by the local
and national
police numerous times.
In 2010, the Bosnian DA's office
sent 600 officers to
the village to search for
guns and evidence
of terrorist activity.
We were nervous about swinging
by the village unannounced.
However, our fixer, Elvis,
spent the previous month
hanging out with the Gornja
Maocans at noon time prayers
and has kind of become
buds with some of the
younger guys there.
Which hopefully means we can
stop by and have a nice,
pleasant chat without having
rocks thrown at our heads.
THOMAS MORTON: To show our
goodwill, or at least what we
hoped would be perceived as good
will, we left the camera
in the back seat of the car and
got out to wait for the
villagers to finish there
afternoon prayers.
We don't want to look
around, right?
We did take a live microphone
with us though, which may have
been a slightly bad move.
MALE SPEAKER 2:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
ELVIS: He wants to
know who we are.
Listen to us.
MALE SPEAKER 2:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
THOMAS MORTON: We wanted to know
if we could talk to them.
ELVIS:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
MALE SPEAKER 2:
THOMAS MORTON: That revving,
by the way, is the village
leader, who's probably pushing
70, pulling up on his Harley.
I cannot describe how
awesome he looked.
ELVIS: No, not right now.
ELVIS: No.
MALE SPEAKER 2:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
ELVIS: OK.
ELVIS: No.
MALE SPEAKERS:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
THOMAS MORTON: No.
We have none.
MALE SPEAKER 2:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
ELVIS: Do not show
up ever again.
MALE SPEAKER 2:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
THOMAS MORTON: OK.
We are sorry we have to leave.
Please apologize.
ELVIS:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
MALE SPEAKER 2:
ELVIS: Right.
THOMAS MORTON: Then we can.
OK.
MALE SPEAKER 2: Yes.
THOMAS MORTON: Well, thank
you and we're sorry.
THOMAS MORTON: OK.
MALE SPEAKER 2:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
THOMAS MORTON: OK.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
THOMAS MORTON: And that's
somebody you had
never talked to?
THOMAS MORTON: OK.
THOMAS MORTON: Well, yeah.
Oh, this is not good.
We just got here just a little
before afternoon prayer.
This angry dude came up and told
him he had to leave and
picked up rocks, which maybe he
just picks up rocks, but I
don't know.
I saw that as kind
of provocative.
Sort of like picking up ammo.
We're trying to regroup
right now.
We're back to the Serbian
cemetery.
This will be very disappointing
if we're unable
to talk to anybody.
Especially because more and
more I learn about these
people, the less, like, you
know, I wouldn't say I'm on
their side, but the more I kind
of respect them being off
on their own and doing
this shit.
Fuck.
Since it didn't seem like we
were getting back in with the
Wahabis, we decided to hang out
with their closest Muslim
neighbors, the Bosnian Eugene
Mirman and his lovely wife.
Do you have many interactions
with the
people from that village?
AVDO:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
THOMAS MORTON: One of the
reasons we know about this
village is that the police has
come up here a couple times,
but they haven't
found anything.
Were you here?
AVDO:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
AVDO'S WIFE:
AVDO:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
THOMAS MORTON: Dispute being
walked out of the village by
bearded men with the rocks in
their hands, the more we
learned about Gornja Maoca, the
more sympathetic we became
to it's wacky Wahabist
residents.
Then two months later, one of
those guys shot up the US
Embassy with an assault rifle,
which seems a little off.
So what have we learned
in the Balkans?
My generation grew up ingrained
with the idea that
things like ethnic and racial
and religious differences were
ultimately just bullshit.
The Balkans and the wars in
the '90s is kind of a
centerpiece of this
way of thinking.
We'll acknowledge that they have
different cultures, and
they live in different
geographies.
But we think about it the same
way we think of people from
different states, sort of like
Americans versus Canadians.
We say, hey, they
look the same.
So what's the freaking
problem?
As if that's some sort
of solution.
But the ethnic differences
aren't what actually matters.
It's the way people have
internalized these differences
and the way they've been doing
so for 1,000 very messy years.
This isn't unique to
the Balkans either.
There's isn't something
intrinsic about Serbs and
Croats that makes them hate each
other, ditto Bosnians.
What's really kind of scary is
what happened here in the '90s
could happen seriously
anywhere on Earth.
We're all just simmering pots
of rage and intolerance
waiting for an excuse to
brutalize each other like
fucking ape men.
That's the real lesson in
Yugoslavia, that and none of
these clowns have any business
making cars.
[MUSIC PLAYING]