WATER.
AND WRECKING CREWS MOVE INTO HORTON PLAZA
FOR THE START OF A 14ÊMILLION DOLLAR REDEVELOPMENT
PROJECT.
AN ALARMING NUMBER OF IMMIGRANT WORKERS ARE
ABUSED ON THIS SIDE THE BORDER.
WE'LL TAKE AN IN DEPTH LOOK AT REVEALING NEW
RESEARCH.
I'M PEGGY PICO.
DWANE BROWN IS OFF TONIGHT.
KPBS EVENING EDITION STARTS NOW.
CAPTIONS PROVIDED BY ECAPTIONS LATE THIS AFTERNOON
A HISTORIC VOTE CHANGED THE FUTURE OF SAN
DIEGO'S WATER SUPPLY.
THE COUNTY'S 24 WATER AGENCIES VOTED TO APPROVE
A 30 YEAR CONTRACT TO BUY DESALINATED WATER
FROM THE PRIVATE COMPANY PO SIDE N RESOURCE
SES.
KPBS REPORT ALISON ST. JOHN JUST RETURNED
FROM THE MEETING.
TELL US WHY THIS VOTE IS SO IMPORTANT.
>> >>ALISON: SAN DIEGO CURRENTLY DEPENDS ON
IMPORTED WATER AND MAKES IT VULNERABLE TO
BEING CUT OFF IN A DPROWT SITUATION.
THIS AGREEMENT WILL GIVE SAN DIEGO AN INDEPENDENT
SOURCE OF WATER USING OCEAN WALTER THAT'S
BEEN DESALINATED BY THE BIGGEST DESALINATION
PLANT EVER BUILT IN THE UNITED STATES RIGHT
HERE IN CARLSBAD.
THE PLAN WILL BE BUILT FOR ALMOST A BILLION
DOLLARS AND THE CONTRACTOR AGREED TODAY COMMITS
SAN DIEGO FOR ALMOST 50ÊMILLION GALLONS OF
WATT AR DAY FOR 30 YEARS ONCE THE PLANT IS
BUILD BUILT, WHICH COULD BE BY 2016, BECAUSE
THE COMPANY ALREADY HAS ALL THE PERMITS.
THAT WILL BE ABOUT 10% OF ALL THE WATER SAN
DIEGO NEEDS.
ONE BOARD MEMBER SAYS YOU CAN'T RECYCLE WATER
IF YOU DON'T HAVE IT AND THIS WILL CREATE
NEW WATER.
>> >>PEGGY: WHAT DOES THIS MEAN FOR RATE PAYERS?
>> >>ALISON: THE COST IS STILL NOT KNOWN.
THE COST OF SERVICE AGREEMENT IS NOT YET HASHED
OUT AND SOME ESTIMATES ARE 5 TO 7 DOLLARS
TO THE AVERAGE WATER BILL, AND OTHER PEOPLE
SAY IT WILL ADD 10 TO 20 DOLLARS, OA EVEN
MORE FOR BIG WATER USERS.
OPPONENTS OF THE PROJECT POINTED OUT DESALINATION
TAKE AS LOT OF ENERGY AND ENERGY COSTS COULD
SKY ROCKET.
THAT COULD THROW ALL THE CALCULATIONS OUT
OF WACK.
THEY SAID IT WOULD BE BETTER TO SIGN ON TO
WATER RECYCLING FIRST.
THEY POINTED TO DESAL PLANTS IN AUSTRALIA
THAT HAVE HAD TO BE SHUT DOWN BECAUSE THE
COSTS SPIRALED OUT OF CONTROL.
SUPPORTS SAY THE CONTRACT HAS BEEN WRITTEN
TO PROTECT RATE PAYERS. THE WATER AGENCIES
AGREED TO START A COLLABORATIVE PROCESS TO
DECIDE HOW TO SHARE THE COSTS.
AS ONE MEMBER PUT IT, NOW THE REAL FIGHT BEGINS.
>> >>PEGGY: TOMORROW THE U.S. SUPREME COURT
WILL KUN SITEDDER IF IT WILL REVIEW A LEGAL
CHALLENGE TO PROPOSITION 8, CALIFORNIA'S BAN
ON SAME SEX MARRIAGE.
SUPPORTER OF THE BAN ON SAME SEX MARRIAGE
ARE APPEALING A LOWER COURT RULING.
IF THE HIGH COURT AGREES TO TAKE ON THE CASE,
ORAL ARGUMENTS COULD BE HEARD AS EARLY AS
NEXT SPRING.
IF THE JUSTICES REJECT THE APPEAL, THE LAST
RULING WILL STAND, MEANING CALIFORNIA'S BAN
ON SAME SEX MARRIAGE WILL NOT BE LEGAL.
THE COURT'S DECISION ON WHETHER TO HEAR THE
CASE IS EXPECTED ON MONDAY.
A SECOND MAN HAS BEEN RESENTENCED UNDER CALIFORNIA'S
NEWLY REFORMED THREE STRIKES LAW, BOTH CASES
WERE HEARD HEAR HERE IN SAN DIEGO.
THERE'S A TWIST IN THIS NEWEST REFORM CASE.
KPBS FRONTERAS REPORTER ERIN SIEGEL IS IN
THE NEWS ROOM WITH MORE.
LAST WEEK KEN KENNETH CORELY WAS RESENTENCED
AND RELEASED FOR CREDIT FOR TIME SERVED.
>> >>: IT'S NOT QUITE SO SIMPLE.
WHEN SERGIO
WAS CONVICTED BACK IN 1995, HE WASN'T A U.S.
CITIZEN.
HE ONLY HAD LEGAL RESIDENCY.
SO THIS MEANS NOW HE'S GOING TO BE DEPORTED
AFTER HE'S RELEASED FROM PRISON.
>> >>PEGGY: IS THERE A PLAN TO HELP HIM STAY
IN TIJUANA AND OUT OF TROUBLE ONCE HE'S DEPORTED?
>> >>ERIN: CERTAINLY, THERE IS.
HIS LAWYERS TOLD ME THIS MORNING THERE IS
AN EXTENSIVE PLAN IN PLACE FOR HIM.
ONCE HE GETS TO TIJUANA, HE HAS A JOB IN PLACE,
WORKING AS A MECHANIC, HE'S ALSO HAS A BED
RESERVED FOR HIM FOR SIX MONTHS AT A REHAB
FACILITY WHERE HE COULD BE OFFERED BENEFITS
LIKE GROUP THERAPY AND OTHER THINGS.
>> >>PEGGY: SAN DIEGO STATE UNIVERSITY CONDUCTED
THE FIRST SCIENTIFIC STUDY OF LABOR TRAFFICKING
IN THE U.S.
THE REPORT INCLUDES INTERVIEWS WITH LOCAL
MIGRANT WORKERS.
THEIR STORIES REVEAL AN ALARMING AMOUNT OF
DANGER, INJUSTICE AND ABUSE.
I SPOKE WITH ONE OF THE STUDY'S RESEARCHERS
ESTELA DE LOS RIOS, EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR OF
THE CENTER FOR SOCIAL ADVOCACY.
WHO DID THE RESEARCHERS TALK WITH AND HOW
DID YOU GET THAT INFORMATION?
>> >>ESTELA DE LOS RIOS: DUE TO OUR RELATIONSHIP
IN THE COMMUNITY, WE HAD CONVERSATIONS WITH
MIKE RNT WORKERS IN DIFFERENT AREAS OF THE
SAN DIEGO REGION.
NORTH COUNTY, SOUTH COUNTY, EAST COUNTY, IN
RURAL AND REMOTE AREAS.
THEREFORE DR.ÊJANE CONNECTED WITH US TO OUTREACH
TO THESE COMMUNITIES AND GET A RANDOM SAMPLING
OF ALL THE REGIONS.
>> >>PEGGY: YOU TALKED TO ABOUT 826 UNAUTHORIZED
WORKERS, SPANISH SPEAKING.
YOU ALSO OFFERED THEM SOME COMPENSATION FOR
THIS.
TELL US WHY.
>> >>ESTELA DE LOS RIOS: YES, WE HAD SOME
INCENTIVES FOR THIS BECAUSE QUITE HONESTLY,
THEY ARE LOSING A DAY'S WORK IN A WHOLE DAY.
SO WE HAD A FOCUS GROUP AND ASKED THEM WHAT
WOULD BE FAIR AND APPROPRIATE.
THEY CAME UP WITH 30 DOLLARS A DAY, AND THEN
HAVE THE REFERENCE IF THEY REFERRED SOMEONE
IT WOULD BE 10 DOLLARS EXTRA.
THEY HAD THE OPPORTUNITY TO HAVE 60 DOLLARS
FOR THAT DAY.
>> >>PEGGY: WE'RE GOING TO COME BACK TO THE
QUESTIONS.
FIRST, THE STUDY IDENTIFIED WHERE THESE WORKERS
WERE EMPLOYED AND 20% WORKED IN FOOD PROCESSING,
ANOTHER 17% IN CONSTRUCTION, 17% IN JANITORIAL
SERVICES, 10% IN AGRICULTURE, AND 6% IN MANUFACTURING.
I THINK PEOPLE WOULD BE SURPRISED THAT THESE
SORT OF ABUSES OR THINGS THAT HAPPENED TO
THESE IMMIGRANT WORKS DIDN'T HAPPEN OUT IN
THE FIELDS.
TWENTY% WERE IN FOOD PROCESSING.
DID THAT SURPRISE YOU?
>> >>ESTELA DE LOS RIOS: ABSOLUTELY, THAT'S
CORRECT.
THESE PERCENTAGES REFLECT THE STUDY.
THIS IS WHY IT'S THE HIDDEN POPULATION BECAUSE
YOU WOULD NOT SUSPECT IN RESTAURANTS OR FOOD
PROCESSING, THERE WOULD BE LABOR TRAFFICKING.
>> >>PEGGY: KIND OF IN PLANE SIGHT.
THE STUDY REVEALED NEARLY A THIRD IMMIGRANT
WORKERS, 38,000, I BELIEVE, EXPERIENCE LABOR
TRAFFICKING.
TELL US WHAT LABOR TRAFFICKING IS.
>> >>ESTELA DE LOS RIOS: THAT'S A VERY GOOD
QUESTION BECAUSE MANY TIMES THE CHALLENGE
IS THESE ARE JUST LABOR ABUSES OR PRACTICES
THEY'RE NOT LABOR TRAFFICKING.
THERE'S A FINE LINE.
WHEN IT BECOMES CORGZ COERCION, THREATS, FEAR
TO LEAVE YOUR WORK OR THREATEN YOUR FAMILY'S
LIFE OR HAVE SOME SEXUAL ABUSE, THEN IT BECOMES
TRAFFICKING.
>> >>PEGGY: THERE WERE REPORTS OF SEXUAL TRAFFICKING
AS WELL, RAPES, ASSAULT, THINGS LIKE THAT.
>> >>ESTELA DE LOS RIOS: YES, THERE WAS A
LOT OF CRIMES REPORTED FOR AN INSTANCE ONE
THAT RESONATES IN MY MIND CONTINUOUSLY IS
A MOTHER THAT SAW HER DAWRT BEING RAWPED,
SHE WAS 12 YEARS OLD, AND THE 12 YEAR OLD
OBSERVED THE MOTHER BEING RAPED.
WE'RE SPEAKING RAPES, KIDNAPPING, THIS IS
LABOR TRAFFICKING.
>> >>PEGGY: LABOR OR SEXUAL TRAFFICKING.
>> >>ESTELA DE LOS RIOS: EXACTLY.
>> >>PEGGY: DO THESE IMMIGRANT WORKS REPORT
THIS TO AUTHORITIES?
>> >>ESTELA DE LOS RIOS: THAT'S THE CHALLENGE.
WE HAVE TRIED TO WORK WITH AUTHORITY AUTHORITIES.
AUTHORITIES HAVE BEEN VERY POSITIVE IN OUR
COLLABORATION. THE CHALLENGE IS THIS: THEY
FEAR DEPORTATION, THEY FEAR THAT THEY'RE GOING
TO BE THE ONES THAT ARE GOING TO BE INCARCERATED.
WE CONTINUOUSLY LELT THEM KNOW THEY HAVE ROILGTS,
THEY HAVE AN OPPORTUNITY FOR VISA, OPPORTUNITIES
TO SPEAK UP.
BUT THE FEAR FACTOR REMAINS.
>> >>PEGGY: BEING DEPORTED OR WORSE.
>> >>ESTELA DE LOS RIOS: EXACTLY.
>> >>PEGGY: WHAT WERE SOME OF THE OTHER LABOR
AND SAFETY ISSUES MAYBE NOT AS LARGE AS THAT
BUT JUST AS IMPORTANT.
>> >>ESTELA DE LOS RIOS: IN CONSTRUCTION,
THEY WOULDN'T GIVE THEM THE HARD HATS, A LOT
OF THEM WORKED WITH CHEMICALS AND WOULD GET
BURNED.
THEY WOULD HAVE A LOT OF HEALTH ISSUES AFTERWARDS
WITH BREATHEING, PESTICIDES, AND ONE WOULD
SAY JUST REPORT THEM TO OCEA, BUTS IT'S HUGE.
BECAUSE YOU GO BACK AND THE EMPLOYER DISAPPEARS.
>> >>PEGGY: AND ALSO I UNDERSTAND THERE WAS
SO NO PAYMENT, IMPROPER EQUIPMENT AS YOU SAID.
>> >>ESTELA DE LOS RIOS: EXACTLY.
>> >>PEGGY: SOME PEOPLE WOULD ARGUE THAT MIGRANT
WORKS PUT THEMSELVES IN THIS VULNERABLE SITUATION,
THEY'RE HERE ILLEGALLY, SO WHAT IS YOUR RESPONSE
TO THAT CRITICISM?
>> >>ESTELA DE LOS RIOS: IN REGARDS TO THE
STATUS WHETHER THEY'RE HERE UNDOCUMENTED OR
DOCUMENTED, THESE ARE CRIMES.
THESE ARE SERIOUS CRIMES WE'RE SPEAKING ABOUT.
I BELIEVE THAT CRIME SHOULD BE PROSECUTED.
>> >>PEGGY: WHAT DID YOU DO WHEN YOU HEARD
ABOUT SOME OF THESE HORRIFIC CRIMES LIKE THE
MOTHER/DAUGHTER RAPE.
HOW DID YOU GUYS HELP THE PEOPLE ONCE YOU
FOUND OUT ABOUT THESE?
>> >>ESTELA DE LOS RIOS: WE FOLLOWED UP AND
OUR ATTEMPT WAS TO TRY TO ASSIST THIS WOMAN
TO REPORT THIS FIRST AND FOREMOST.
BECAUSE OF THE TRAUMATIC EXPERIENCE, SHE JUST
WANTED TO LET IT GOAVMENT THESE ARE THE EXPERIENCES
WE HAVE ON A CONTINUOUS BASIS.
>> >>PEGGY: BUT YOU DID REACH OUT TO MANY
OF THESE WORKERS.
>> >>ESTELA DE LOS RIOS: YES, WE ALWAYS REACH
OUT TO THEM AND GIVE THEM THE OPPORTUNITIES
TO ASSIST THEM WITH RESOURCES.
>> >>PEGGY: OKAY.
ESTELA DE LOS RIOS, THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR
TALKING WITH US.
YOU CAN READ THE ENTIRE SDSU REPORT CALLED
LOOKING FOR A HIDDEN POPULATION, TRAFFICKING
OF MIGRANT LABORERS IN SAN DIEGO COUNTY ON
OUR WEBSITE, KPBS.ORG.
>> >>ESTELA DE LOS RIOS: THANK YOU.
>> >>PEGGY: RESEARCHERS AT SAN DIEGO STATE
HAVE ALSO LAUNCHED A NEW STUDY ON AUTISM.
SCIENTISTS WILL LOOK AT THE DIFFERENCE OF
BRAIN NETWORKS AND TEENS WITH AUTISM COMPARED
TO THOSE WHO AREN'T.
RESEARCHERS HOPE THEIR WORK WILL HELP WITH
EARLY DETECTION, DIAGNOSIS AND TREATMENT.
MEAN WHILE, ANOTHER TEAM IN SAN DIEGO PLANNED
ANOTHER TEAM OF RESEARCHERS PLANED TO SEND
FRUIT FLIES INTO SPACE.
THAT'S RIGHT, THE FLIES WILL HELP SCIENTISTS
STUDY THE IMPACT OF SPACE TRAVEL ON THE HUMAN
HEART.
THE TEAM FROM SANFORD BURNHAM MEDICAL RESEARCH
INSTITUTE SAYS FRUIT FLIES ARE PERFECT FOR
THE STUDY BECAUSE THE GENETIC AND MOLECULAR
MAKE UP OF THE CRITTER'S HEARTS ARE QUITE
SIMILAR TO OUR OWN HUMAN HEARTS.
ON THE NEXT NEWS HOUR.
MELTING POW POLAR ICE SHEETS IN GREENLAND.
THURSDAY ON THE PBS NEWS HOUR.
>> >>PEGGY: IF YOU USUALLY GO TOOLT DOWNTOWN
COUNTY BUILDING TO PAY YOUR PROPERTY TAXES
YOU MAY WANT TO CHANGE YOUR ROUTINE THIS DECEMBER,
MAJOR CONSTRUCTION IS UNDER WAY IN THE AREA,
AND THE COUNTY TAX COLLECTOR IS URGING PEOPLE
TO PAY SOME OTHER WAY; ONLINE, BY PHONE, AT
BRANCH OFFICE OR BY MAIL.
NO MATTER HOW YOU DO IT, PROPERTY TAX PAYMENTS
ARE DEW ON DECEMBERÊ10.
DEMOLITION IS UNDERWAY AT HORTON PLAZA, THE
OLD ROBINSON'S MAY BUILDING IS BEING TORN
DOWN TO MAKE ROOM FOR A NEW PUBLIC PARK.
THE 14ÊMILLION DOLLAR PROJECT IS ONE OF THE
FINAL PROJECTS CREATED BY SAN DIEGO'S NOW
DEFUNCT AGENCY.
DATING BACK TO FORMER MAYOR PETE WILSON.
>> >>: WE THOUGHT THAT WITH A LITTLE PUBLIC
ASSISTANCE WE COULD SPUR A TREMENDOUS AMOUNT
OF CONFIDENCE AND THEREFORE PRIVATE INVESTMENT
AND PRIVATE RENEWAL, GAS LAMP DID NOT EXIST.
BUT I WOULD HAVE TO SAY WHAT'S HAPPENED HAS
EXCEEDED MY FONDEST EXPECTATIONS.
>> >>PEGGY: WESTFIELD OWNS THE SHOPPING CENTER
AND SOLD THE ROBINSON'S MAY STORE BACK TO
THE CITY FOR THE NEW 1 ACRE PUBLIC SQUARE.
WE CAUGHT UP WITH KEVIN FAULCONER FOR THE
ARE R Y DEVELOPMENT.
>> >>PEGGY: THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR JOINING
US.
EXPANSION OF THE OLD HORTON PLAZA PARK IS
ACTUALLY A CITY PROJECT AND SUPPOSED TO ADD
PUBLIC SPACE IN FRONT OF THE HORTON PLAZA
SHOPPING CENTER.
REMIND US OF WHAT THAT LOOKS LIKE NOW AND
HOW THAT'S GOING TO CHANGE.
>> >>KEVIN FAULCONER: THANK YOU FOR HAVING
ME, IT WAS A VERY EXCITING DAY DOWNTOWN.
WE'RE EMBARKING ON A REMARKABLE TRANSFORMATION.
WEER GROARING TO TEAR DOWN THAT OLD BUILDING
RIGHT IN THE FRONT THAT USED TO BE THE PLANET
HOLLYWOOD, AND WE'RE CREATING WORLD CLASS
PUBLIC PARK OPEN SPAIRKS 1 DISPA HALF MAKERS.
ONE AND A HALF ACRES THAT WILL BE A SPECIAL
PLACE.
>> >>PEGGY: LET'S TAKE A LOOK THAT ARCHITECT'S
PLANS.
THE FIRST ONE IS SORT OF AN OVERVIEW HERE.
TELL US WHAT WE'RE LOOKING AT.
>> >>KEVIN FAULCONER: YOU CAN SEE RIGHT THERE,
THE PHOTO OF THE NEW PARK YOU SEE TOWARDS
THE RIGHT HAND PORTION OF THE PICTURE, THE
CURRENT PARK.
BUT WE AREÊ THAT BUILDING GOES AWAY, WE CREATE
AS I SAID BEFORE AN ACRE AND A HALF OF PUBLIC
OPEN SPACE TO SEE THE NEW TREES, THE AMPHITHEATER
THERE, THE SEATING, RESTROOMS, FOOD PAVILIONS.
>> >>PEGGY: LET'S TALK ABOUT THAT AMPHITHEATER.
WHAT'S THAT GOING TO BE USED FOR.
>> >>KEVIN FAULCONER: THE WHOALD IDEA OF THE
SPACE IS TO ACTIVATE IT, MAKE SURE WE'RE ATTRACTING
PEOPLE DURING THE DAY AND DURING THE NIGHT.
SO WE HAVE ABOUT 200 DAY AS YEAR WE'RE PLANNING
ON PROGRAMS FOR ANYTHING FROM DANCES TO CONCERTS
TO MOVIES ON THE BACK OF THE WALL THERE.
THE IDEA IS LET'S BRING PEOPLE THERE, ACTIVATE
IT.
>> >>PEGGY: I WANT TO GET A SHOT OF THAT MOVIE,
THE RENDITION ARTIST'S RENDITION.
CAN WE SHOW EVERYBODY? LOOK AT THAT GIANT
SCREEN.
>> >>KEVIN FAULCONER: A GREAT SHOT A NIGHT
SHOT, IF YOU WILL, WITH EVERYBODY SITTING
AROUND THE AMPHITHEATER.
THE BUILDING THERE NOW, THAT'S DESIGNED TO
BE A DIGITAL BACKGROUND FOR MOVIES AND SPECIAL
PRESENTATIONS AND OTHERS.
I THINK AS YOU LOOK AT THE POSSIBILITIES THERE,
YOU KNOW, SEVERAL HUNDRED PEOPLE OUT THERE
ON A WARM SAN DIEGO NIGHT, THAT'S THE TYPE
OF GATHERING WE'RE TALKING ABOUT.
WORLD CLASS, OPEN PUBLIC SPACE, AND THAT'S
THE OPPORTUNITY.
>> >>PEGGY: LET'S TALK ABOUT DURING THE DAY.
WE SAW THE MOVIES THERE AT NIGHT, BUT THERE
WAS AN ARTIST RENDITION WE'LL PUT UP HERE
FOR EVERYBODY TO SEE, WHERE THERE'S ACTUALLY
TENTS IN THE CENTER OF THIS.
WHAT ARE THOSE FOR?
>> >>KEVIN FAULCONER: THIS IS A GOOD ILLUSTRATION
THAT SHOWS WHAT MIGHT BE POSSIBLE ON A SATURDAY
OR SUNDAY AS WE HAVE VENDORS FOR A FARMER'S
MARKET OR OTHER TYPES OF THINGS TO ATTRACT
PEOPLE, TEMPORARY TENTS, DO SOME SHOPPING,
BE OUT DOORS, OUT IN THE SUN SHINE, AND SO
THIS RENDERING RIGHT HERE IS I THINK WHAT
YOU'LL PROBABLY SEE A LOT DURING THE DAY ON
A SATURDAY OR SUNDAY.
>> >>PEGGY: THERE'S SOMETHING ELSE ABOUT THIS
OPEN SPACE YOU TOUCHED ON.
LET'S TAKE A LOOK AT THIS LAST ARTISTS PICTURE
HERE.
YOU CAN SEE YOU WERE TELL ME YOU CAN SEE THROUGH
NOW THE AREA ALL THE WAY BACK TO TELL US WHAT
WE'RE LOOKING AT SO WE CAN SEE.
>> >>KEVIN FAULCONER: THIS IS ONE OF MY FAVORITE
RENDERINGS.
YOU LOOK ON BROADWAY LOOKING BACK, THE BUILDING
IS GONE, AND WE CREATE AD REMARKABLE VISTA
VIEW TO THE HITS HISTORIC BALBOA THEATER YOU'RE
SEEING IN THE BACKGROUND OF THE SHOT.
LOOKING THROUGH THE COLUMNS, YOU SAW THEM
LIT UP AT NIGHT.
THIS IS GOING TO BE A WHOLE NEW FRONT PORCH
FOR DOWNTOWN SAN DIEGO, AND AS YOU CAN SEE
BY THE AMPHITHEATER SHOT THERE, AND ALL OF
THE TREES, IT'S GOING TO BE A PLACE OF GATHERING
PLACE FOR FAMILIES, FOR OTHER FOLKS, AND WE
WERE OUT THERE TALKING TODAY AT THE GROUND
PEOPLE A LOT OF PEOPLE SAID THIS WOULD BE
A GREAT PLACE TO HAVE NEW DWREER'S EVE CELEBRATIONS.
>> >>PEGGY: THE EXCITEMENT OF IT.
THE CITY ACQUIRED THIS STORE PROPERTY, I THINK
IT WAS ROBINSON MAY MAY THEN HOLLYWOOD PLANET.
>> >>KEVIN FAULCONER: PLANET HOLLYWOOD.
>> >>PEGGY: BUT THEY DID IT IN A CREATIVE
WAY.
WHAT WAS THAT ARRANGEMENT?
>> >>KEVIN FAULCONER: GRIET GREAT PRIVATE
PUBLIC PARTNERSHIP WITH THE WESTFIELD CORPORATION.
THEY WERE LOOKING TO MAKE SOME CHANGES AND
THE CITY HAS BEEN LOOKING TO PROVIDE MORE
OPEN SPARK SPACES AND PUBLIC PARK PARKS. THIS
CAME FROM FINANCING FROM WESTFIELD, REDEVELOPMENT
AGENCY, NOW CIVIC SAN DIEGO, A GREAT PARTNERSHIP
WITH THE IDEA HOW CAN WE GET THIS DONE AND
COMPLETED.
TOOK ABOUT TWO YEARS.
AND SO TODAY WAS A PRETTY BIG MILESTONE.
>> >>PEGGY: WILL THIS GENERATE ANY FUNDS FOR
THE CITY?
>> >>KEVIN FAULCONER: IT WON'T GENERATE MUCH
FUNDS.
WE'LL IS HAVE SOME SALES TAX FROM SOME OF
THE VENDORS, BUT THIS IS ABOUT PROVIDING AN
AMENITY, PROVIDING THE GATHERING SPACE.
WHEN YOU LOOK AT OTHER CITIES WHETHER IT'S
ACROSS THE COUNTRY OR ACROSS THE WORLD, ONE
OF THE HALLMARKS OF A GREAT URBAN SPACE IS
TO HAVE GAISÊ GREAT URBAN CITY IS TO HAVE
THESE GREAT PUBLIC OPEN GATHERING SPACES.
WE DON'T QUITE HAVE THAT IN DOWNTOWN SAN DIEGO,
BUT WE'RE GOING TO NOW.
>> >>PEGGY: WHAT WILL WESTFIELD GET OUT OF
IT?
>> >>KEVIN FAULCONER: THEY WANTED TO MAKE
HORTON PLAZA MORE INVITING, MORE ATTRACTIVE.
REMEMBER WHEN HORTON PLAZA WAS DEVELOPED,
DOWNTOWN WAS A VASTLY DIFFERENT PLACE.
IT WASN'T THE SAFEST PLACE TO BE, THE SHOPPING
CENTER WAS DESIGNED INWARD, NOT OUTWARD, THEY'RE
GOING TO BE LOOKING TO MAKE SOME MAJOR CHANGES
IN THE FUTURE TO HELP OPEN THAT UP.
THIS IS A BIG PART OF DOING THAT, TO MAKE
IT MORE INVITING FOR PEOPLE TO COME DOWN AND
ENJOY IT.
>> >>PEGGY: HOW MUCH IS IT EXPECTED TO COST.
>> >>KEVIN FAULCONER: $14ÊMILLION CONSTRUCTION,
GOING TO BE STARTING, AND WE TOLD FOLKS TODAY
LOOK FORWARD TO DOING THIS IN SPRING OF 2014.
>> >>PEGGY: CITY COUNCIL MEMBER KEVIN FAULCONER.
YOU CAN TAKE A CLOSER LOOK AT THE PLANS FOR
HORTON PLAZA PARK ON OUR WEBSITE KPBS.ORG.
>> >>PEGGY: NO CHARGERS WILL BE SEEN ON LOCAL
TV THIS WEEKEND FOR THE THIRD TIME THIS SEASON.
THE TEAM DID NOT SELL ENOUGH TICKETS TO AVOID
AN NFL MANDATED TV BLACKOUT.
THERE ARE STILL 11,000 TICKETS AVAILABLE FOR
SUNDAY'S GAME.
RIGHT NOW, THE CHARGERS RECORD IS FOUR WINS,
AND SEVEN LOSSES.
AND THE BENGALS ARE FAVORED TO WIN THIS WEEKEND.
TWINKIES MAY BE BACK IN LUNCH BOXES SOON.
HOST ESES, THE COMPANY THAT MAKES THE SWEET
TREATS SAY THEY'VE GOT MORE THAN 100 POTENTIAL
BUYERS FOR ITS PRODUCT LINE AS IT LIQUIDATES.
MEAN WHILE, THE COMPANY IS SEEKING COURT APPROVAL
OF NEARLY $2ÊMILLION IN BONUSES FOR ITS TOP
EXECUTIVES AS IT SHUTS DOWN.
HOST ES DECLARED BANKRUPTCY FOR THE SECOND
TIME AFTER ITS BAKERS UNION WENT ON STRIKE
EARLIER THIS MONTH. THE UNION WANTS AN INDEPENDENT
TRUSTEE TO OVER SEE THE COMPANY'S LIQUIDATION.
AND TOMORROW MARKS THE END OF THE LINE FOR
A HISTORIC OYSTER FARM ON THE COAST OF NORTHERN
CALIFORNIA.
THE DRAKE BAY OWES OYSTER COMPANY HAS BEEN
IN COMPANY FOR A HUNDRED YEARS.
IT HAS 30 EMPLOYEES, BUT TODAY THE U.S. DEPARTMENT
OF THE INTERIOR SAID IT WOULD NOT RENEW THE
COMPANY'S LEASE.
ENVIRONMENTALISTS SAY THE OYSTER FARM THREATENED
WILD LIFE.
THE LAND WILL BE RETURNED TO MOTHER NATURE
AS A WILDERNESS SITE.
A HIGH SURF ADVISORY IS IN EFFECT FOR SOUTHERN
CALIFORNIA THROUGH MONDAY AFTERNOON.
STORMS IN THE PACIFIC ARE CAUSING THE HEAVY
SURF.
WAVES REACHED ABOUT 7ÊFEET IN OCEAN BEACH
EARLIER TODAY, AND ARE EXPECTED TO GET EVEN
HIGHER WITH PREDICTIONS UP TO 14ÊFEET ACCORDING
TO SURF LINE.COM.
ALONG WITH THE HIGH SURF, THE NATIONAL WEATHER
SERVICE SAYS WE CAN EXPECT A CHANCE OF SHOWERS
OVER THE NEXT FEW DAYS.
HERE'S A LOOK AT THE FORECAST.
EARLIER IN THIS NEWS CAST WE TALKED ABOUT
THE FUTURE OF SAN DIEGO'S WATER SUPPLY WITH
THE APPROVAL OF A CONTRACT TO BUY MILLIONS
OF GALLONS OF DESALINATED WATER.
THAT'S THE FUTURE BUT KEN KRAMER TAKES US
BACK TO SAN DIEGO'S WATER PAST.
>> >>: HERE IT IS, JUST A FEW PARTS OF IT
REMAINING, ABOUT ALL THERE IS LEFT TO SEE
IN FACT OF WHAT WAS ONCE THIS.
ONE OF THE MOST AMAZING STRUCTURES EVER BUILT
IN SAN DIEGO MADE OF 9ÊMILLION BOARD FEET
OF RED WOOD IT WAS A 33 MILE LONG OPEN TRAIL
FLOWING WATER.
I THINK YOU HAD TO SEE IT TO BELIEVE IT, BUT
AT LEAST THERE ARE PICTURES.
SEE, IT USED TO BE IN SAN DIEGO THAT MOST
OF THE WATER WE DRANK AND USED FOR IRRIGATION
CAME FROM WELLS AND IT WAS SALTY, SOMETIMES
NAUSEATING, NOT GOOD WATER, REALLY.
BUT IN 1889, THIS BLOOM CHANGED EVERYTHING
AND IT WAS JUST AN ENORMOUS PROJECT TO BRING
GOOD N WATER FROM THE MOUNTAINS FROM THE EASTERN
PART OF LA MESA AND ON TO SAN DIEGO.
THERE HAD TO BE A DAM BUILT WAY UP ON THE
SAN DIEGO RIVER AT BOULDER CREAK.
THAT'S WHERE THE WATER WAS CAPTURED TO BE
PUT IN THE FLUM.
IT WAS SIX FEET WIDE, 18 INCHES DEEP, FULL
OF WATER, RUNNING ALL THOSE MILES, AND IT
HAS H TO BE ALL DOWN HILL OF COURSE SO THE
WATER WOULD KEEP FLOWING.
THERE WERE TUNNELS, HERE'S THE LOS COCHES
TUNNEL, AND MORE THAN 300TRESSELS, 1,000Ê
65ÊFEET HIGH, NOBODY HAD EVER SEEN ANYTHING
LIKE THAT IN SAN DIEGO.
SO AMAZING WAS THIS THING THAT ON OPENING
DAY, 22ND OF FEBRUARY, 1889, PUBLIC OFFICIALS
AND DIGNITARIES TOOK A RIDE ON WOODEN BOATS
DOWN A GOOD PART OF THE FLUME.
THAT'S THE GOVERNOR OF CALIFORNIA, WHOSE NAME
INTERESTINGLY WAS ROBERT W.WATERMAN.
THE FLUME WAS BUILT AND HAD TO BE MAINTAINED.
IT WAS WOOD, AND SOMETIMES LEAKED.
SO YOU HAD FLUME WALKERS WHO SAW TROUBLE SPOTS,
AND MADE REPAIRS, INSPECTORS, AND HOUSES BUILT
ALONG THE ROUTE SO THOSE WORKERS AND THEIR
FAMILIES HAD A PLACE TO LIVE.
LOOKING BACK THERE WERE LOTS OF ISSUES WITH
THE SAN DIEGO FLUME.
FOR ONE THING, IN THE HOT SUMMER MONTHS ALL
THAT WATER IN A SHALLOW CONTAINER MOVING ALONG,
TOO MUCH OF THAT WATER EVAPORATED.
IN 1919 A WIND TUNNEL BLEW OVER THE SWEET
WATER TRESSEL.
IN ITS TIME AND FOR ITS PURPOSE, IT DID ITS
JOB.
THE WATER EVENTUALLY ENDING UP IN LA MESA
RESERVOIR PIPED FROM THERE INTO SAN DIEGO.
LA MESA RESERVOIR WHICH WOULD LATER BE BUILT
UP INTO WHAT WOULD BECOME LAKE MURRAY.
AND SOME OF THE WATER TOO WENT TO A RANCHER'S
POND, SOMETIMES KNOWN AS DUCK POND.
IF YOU'VE EVER BEEN TO ANTHONY'S FISH GROTTO,
YOU KNOW THE DUCK POND IS STILL THERE, EVEN
THOUGH THE FLUME IS GONE.
IT JUST DIDN'T AGE WELL.
BY THE LATE 1920S, CUSTOMERS WERE DEMANDING
REPAIRS AND THE STATE OF THE ART WATER DELIVERY
AND STORAGE HAD CHANGED.
IN TIME DAMS WERE BUILT, THE LOWER OTAY, AND
MORENA, AND PIPES CYPHENS, AND CONCRETE TUNNELS
REPLACED THE FLUME.
BUT WHAT A THING IT WAS.
HERE'S OLD HIGHWAY 80 AND THE FLUME, NOW THE
LAKE JENNINGS PARK ROAD OFF RAMP, WHERE JUST
UP THE ROAD AT THE LEAVY WATER TREATMENT PLANT,
THE HELIX WATER DISTRICT HAS KEPT A FEW BITS
OF THE FLUME VISITORS CAN SEE, AN OLD WAGON
THAT ROLLED DOWN THE FLUME DURING THE CONSTRUCTION,
AND THEN A SECTION, JUST A SECTION OF WHAT
WAS ONCE AN ENGINEERING MARVEL THAT DELIVERED
GOOD, IT SWEET WATER FROM THE MOUNTAINS AND
BECAME A REMARKABLE PART OF HISTORY ABOUT
SAN DIEGO.
>> >>PEGGY: YOU CAN SEE MORE OF KEN KRAMER'S
STORY ABOUT SAN DIEGO TONIGHT AT 8:00ÊP.M.
RIGHT HERE ON KPBS.
RECAPPING TONIGHT'S TOP STORIES, THE SAN DIEGO
COUNTY WATER AUTHORITY APPROVED A 30 YEAR
DEAL TO BUY DESALINATED WATER FROM A PLANT
IN CARLSBAD.
THE POSEIDON PLANT WILL BE THE LARGEST OF
ITS KIND IN THE WESTERN HEMISPHERE.
CONVERTING SEA WATER WILL GIVE US A MORE RELIABLE
SUPPLY. THE COST TO RATE PAYERS STILL ISN'T
WORKED OUT.
AND DEMOLITION IS UNDERWAY AT HORTON PLAZA,
THE OLD ROBINSON MAY BUILDING IS BEING TORN
DOWN TO MAKE WAY FOR A 14ÊMILLION DOLLAR
PUBLIC PARK, ONE OF THE FINAL PROJECTS CREATED
BY SAN DIEGO'S NOW DEFUNCT REDEVELOPMENT AGENCY.
SUPPORTER OF THE
SAME SEX MARRIAGE BAN ARE APPEALING A LOWER
COURT RULING CLAIMING ITS UNCONSTITUTIONAL.
THE COURT'S DECISION ON WHETHER TO HEAR THE
CASE IS EXPECTED ON MONDAY.
IF THEY SAY NO, THE LAST RULING WILL STAND
TAKING PROP 8S OFF THE BOOKS.
YOU CAN FIND ALL OF TONIGHT'S STORIES AND
MORE ON OUR WEBSITE KPBS.ORG/EVENINGEDITION.
THANK YOU FOR JOINING US AND HAVE A GREAT
NIGHT.