But, can we create
a homemade death ray
that kills the enemy,
without killing us?
Michael: Cut it off,
cut it off!
Travis Taylor:
Turn the power off.
I'm Travis Taylor.
I'm a rocket scientist
in the space and defense
industry here
in my hometown of
Huntsville, Alabama,
where my Daddy helped
build the rockets
that sent us to the moon.
Daddy: Hey, have
y'all been drinking
rocket fuel again?
Travis Taylor:
Sometimes big science
moves to slow for me.
So come the weekend,
I round up my
best friend Rog.
Rog: Hey!
Travis Taylor: My nephew
Michael and my buddy Pete
to tackle important
problems with a
little down-home ingenuity.
Rog: Damn it, boy.
Travis Taylor: Right on.
Hey is there any more
beers in the cooler?
Rog: Anybody ready?
Travis Taylor:
Ready Rog, pull!
[shotgun fire]
Pull!
Mankind has been using
gun-powder weapons for
almost a thousand years.
Michael: We tore
that up, didn't we?
Daddy: I've got to
find some more shells.
Travis Taylor:
The problem is,
once you run out
of gunpowder and
bullets all you have left
is a fancy looking club.
All right, pull!
I want to come up with a
weapon that doesn't use
gunpowder or bullets,
a weapon of the future.
[shotgun fire]
Rog: Good shot, Charlie!
Daddy: [laughing].
Travis Taylor: Since
armies of the future might
be totally reliant on
electronics and robotics,
I want a weapon that
can help us fight off
the rise of the machines.
And I think the key to
doing that is to zap them
with a big jolt of energy,
a real life death ray.
In fact, the US military
just announced it's
trying to build an
electric lightning gun
to take out enemy vehicles.
Let's go put them back
in the room, Daddy.
Daddy: Yeah, just
put them back.
Travis Taylor: For our
weapon of the future,
I want to start with
something everybody
has in their
own kitchen and
some people have
in their garage.
Daddy's got one over here
for heating up fish bait.
We could probably
make an invisible
beam gun right here.
If we took that
screen off,
the micro waves would
come out the door.
Daddy: Let me see
if I got this right,
he wants to weaponize
my microwave oven?
If you all ain't
using my microwave
that's for fishing.
I have to thaw
out my fish bait;
you see the freezer
right there.
Travis Taylor: Ya'll
got a new one in a box.
Daddy: Right now we're
renovating the kitchen
and we just had a new
microwave delivered.
If my wife finds
out that's missing,
she is gonna flip.
Travis Taylor: Momma's
microwave has gotta
be twice as
powerful as Daddy's.
It's gonna be perfect for
our making our death ray.
Daddy: Listen, I'm
not having any part of
going into that kitchen
and getting microwaves
and stuff like that.
Rog: I don't know what
Charlie's all-nervous
about, we're just
gonna borrow it,
we'll put it right back,
she'll never know.
Charlie you blame
it on Travis,
he sent me in
here to get this.
Travis Taylor: Yeah.
Daddy: Mmm-hmm,
blame it on Travis,
you go in there and get
that new microwave and
you gonna wish you hadn't.
Rog: Dag gone it,
childproof bologna.
Look it here.
One Horno de Microondas.
Travis Taylor: All right.
Rog: Did I say that right?
Travis Taylor: I don't
even know what that means.
Rog: Microwave oven.
Travis Taylor: Open
that up, Michael.
Was Mom in there?
Rog: No, she was gone.
Michael: This
is brand new.
Travis Taylor: It's
gonna look good
in the kitchen, Daddy.
Michael: That's
a nice microwave.
Travis Taylor: Hey
look right here.
Y'all watch this.
We all know what
microwaves do to food.
So we want to see what
they do to something
electrical like
a light bulb.
Michael: Of course,
it wouldn't be fun
just to put a
light bulb inside,
so Uncle Travis
had to toss some
other stuff in there.
Daddy: Everybody
tells you not to put
metal in a microwave.
Of course Travis
has got to try it.
So right now he's got a
pile of metal shavings in
there and put a charge of
my gunpowder in with it.
Travis Taylor: Daddy
you're gonna miss it.
Rog: Look at that light.
Travis Taylor: That's
the metal shavings,
it's absorbing the energy,
acting like an antennae
and it's killing
our light.
Go ahead and stop it.
So, the microwave
lit up the light bulb
and eventually
burned it out.
Our next step in building
a microwave weapon is to
modify the microwave
so we'll shoot a beam
out of the oven and then,
light up the bulb
from a distance.
There's a reason why
your microwave oven
can cook your food
without cooking you.
Have you ever noticed
that screen you see
when you look
through the glass,
that's what's known
as a Faraday cage.
It's a metal mesh that
conducts electromagnetic
energy and keeps the
radiation inside the oven,
but if we want to turn our
microwave into a weapon,
that radiation is
gonna need to get out.
Cut it.
Cut me a 5-inch
square hole out in
the middle of it somewhere.
So I had Rog cut a
hole into that screen
on the front door.
The biggest obstacle to
building a future weapon
in our garage is that
we might get killed.
Pete: It's got a
little bit left there.
Travis Taylor: Micro waves
are invisible radiation
that can cook a chicken,
so it can cook you.
So you got to be
careful with it,
so don't try this at home.
This is good enough;
let's angle out right
through yonder.
With the Faraday cage
removed the micro waves
are gonna bounce all
around the inside of the
oven and then go
out the front.
Right now we're gonna do
a test to see how much
energy we can get from
our microwave beam.
We're gonna see
if it'll light up a
light bulb
from a distance.
Michael: Microwave
radiation can kill ya,
and if it doesn't kill ya,
it can make you sterile
and I haven't had kids yet
like the rest of these
guys, so I'm gonna
stay out of the way.
Travis Taylor:
Nobody stand any,
you know stay a cone
backwards like this.
Rog: Yeah.
Travis Taylor: All right
are we, we're ready?
Turn me on, Daddy.
Daddy: All right,
power's on.
Travis Taylor: All right
and here we go, starting.
I don't believe it's
getting enough out of it
to turn the light on.
It's too much lost inside
that cavity inside there.
This ain't even warm;
it means it's not
getting a whole bunch.
Go ahead and turn
it off Daddy.
Daddy: What was
that, that blew up?
Travis Taylor:
The door broke.
Pete: The glass
got too hot.
Travis Taylor: Clearly
we're not gonna be
able to put that thing
back together and
give it to mom.
If it's not lighting
this light bulb,
it's not a whole lot of
energy getting out here.
We need to tear
into this thing.
Daddy: Well you
might as well,
'cause now that
you have broken it,
I don't think it's
a good idea to let
your mother see it at all.
Travis Taylor: Well
it just came out of
the box this way,
didn't it Rog?
Rog: Yeah, as far
as I can tell.
Michael: Bad
shipping, wasn't it?
Travis Taylor: Bad.
[laughing].
Travis Taylor: Man you
can't trust that anymore.
Daddy: I'm telling you.
Travis Taylor: Let's roll
it on back in the shop.
We need a new plan.
A microwave uses this
thing called a magnetron
to produce micro waves.
We're gonna take the
magnetron out of the
microwave, put it in an
aluminum box and attach a
feed horn to the front.
That should focus the
micro waves and give us
enough power to
fry the enemy.
While Rog and Michael are
cutting the copper for the
feed horn, Pete and I are
tearing the microwave
apart to get the
magnetron out.
There's our magnetron.
It's got all the circuitry
to turn it on and off
and leave it on for a
certain amounts of time and
even adjust the power level,
so we're gonna save all the
circuitry and
keep it working.
If this light
right here is on,
it means the
microwave is running.
Michael: Hey,
ya'll done yet?
Do I need a washer or can
just stick it over there?
Pete: No, Charlie's
got a washer.
Travis Taylor: Once we got
all the stuff out of that
microwave that we needed,
we attached the magnetron
to the feed horn, hooked
up all the circuitry
and put it all in
an aluminum box.
All right let's see,
probably about right
here but let's turn.
Michael: Don't
point it at my junk.
Travis Taylor: Let's turn
it like right about,
like that, oh about there.
All right, let's
test this thing.
We're gonna need to keep
a real close eye on the
micro waves coming
out of that feed horn.
Pete, you gonna hold
the antenna over here?
Pete: Yeah.
Travis Taylor: Michael,
you oughta hold
the signal meter.
Michael: Yeah,
I'll hold this.
Travis Taylor: That
meter is gonna tell us
just how powerful
our new weapon is.
Michael: All
right, we ready?
Pete: Safety
glasses, Michael.
Michael: Yeah,
safety glasses.
Travis Taylor: All right,
we're ready to go.
We're just gonna do a
quick test here to make
sure everything is wired
up right and working.
Hold on;
let me turn the
microwave up.
All right Daddy,
put that in there.
Michael: Here we go.
Daddy: You need
me to turn it on?
Travis Taylor:
Turn it on.
Ow whoa.
Turn it off.
Turn the power, power,
power, turn it off.
Michael: Kill it, kill it.
Travis Taylor: Aw crap!
Daddy: Oh, man.
Travis Taylor: Holy crap.
Pete: What in the world?
Michael: Phew smell it.
Travis Taylor: Man, we
lost all that smoke.
We let the
smoke out of the
high voltage
circuit for sure.
Holy crap.
Pete: Man, I had
a spike right before
that thing blew.
Dang.
Travis Taylor: Did you?
Pete: Yeah it just.
Travis Taylor: Something
happened and we got too
much power in the
magnetron or something
and it just flooded
out with micro waves
and burnt out everything.
Michael: Gollee.
Rog: Yeah nice.
Travis Taylor: Dang it.
Rog: That thing is shot.
Daddy: I'm probably
radiated over here and
don't even know it.
Travis Taylor: I guess
some of the microwaves
must've back fed
through the feed horn
and fried the circuitry.
Man, it was
microwave suicide.
Michael: That thing
stinks close that lid.
Travis Taylor:
Here comes mom.
Michael: We're busted.
Travis Taylor: Thought she
was gonna be gone all day.
Daddy: Yeah, what a time
for her to show up.
Travis Taylor: Uh-oh.
Looks like we just
might go the way of the
microwave if Momma finds
out what we were up to.
Momma: Hey guys,
whatcha ya'll doin'?
Travis Taylor:
Uh, just working.
Rog: Nothing much.
Michael: We're just
hanging out, Grandma.
Travis Taylor: Yeah,
it ain't working
too well today;
we still got a
lot of work to do.
Momma: Y'all
just keep at it.
Michael: Well
that was easy.
Travis Taylor: Yeah, that
was all right for now.
Well maybe we will
make it out of
here alive after all.
Momma: Charles Herbert
where is my microwave?
Travis Taylor: So we're
about ready to go.
We're making a weapon
of the future that could
fry enemy electronics
or an entire robot army.
Turn it on.
Ow whoa.
Turn the power, power,
power, turn it off.
Aw crap!
We probably shouldn't
have started with
my mom's new microwave.
Momma: Charles Herbert,
where is my microwave?
Rog: Oh, Charles Herbert.
Daddy: What?
Rog: Charlie
got in trouble.
Travis Taylor: I'll let
Daddy handle that one.
Michael: Yeah I'm gonna
hang out right here.
Rog: I am going
right over here.
Daddy: We borrowed it,
to do a little experiment
with it out here.
And we had a
little accident.
Michael: Hey I'm
going with him,
at least hide
out, out back.
Daddy: We blew it up.
That's the just
all there is to it.
Momma: Just
tell them to go,
I am done with this.
Just tell them to go,
I am tired of it.
Go!
Michael: What she saying?
I think we'd
gettin' thrown out?
Rog: No.
Travis Taylor: No, we
ain't getting thrown out.
Go in there
and ask her for
an egg sandwich, Michael.
Daddy: I don't believe I
would right now, Michael.
I don't blame her
for being mad.
Right now the best
thing we can do
is make ourselves scarce.
She doesn't want to see
anymore of us today.
Travis Taylor: Making a
future weapon out of a
microwave has turned out
to be a complete bust.
I'm not sure what
we're gonna do.
Then it hit me.
I remember the US
military is working on a
lightning gun to destroy
enemy vehicles and
I think we can do
just that using stuff
we can find right
here in Alabama.
And I know just
the guy to call,
our buddy Cameron
that Rog and
I went to
high school with.
Listen to that.
Rog: What are
they playing?
Travis Taylor:
What in the world?
Daddy: What is that?
Travis Taylor:
Hey, Cameron, hey.
The first thing I see are
these two Frankenstein
like Tesla Coils shooting
electricity everywhere
and playing the
Camp Town Ladies.
Rog: The Camp Town Ladies.
Travis Taylor:
Camp town ladies,
well talk about
these mad scientists
up in here, man.
Daddy: What in the world?
Travis Taylor: That is
awesome right there.
Cameron: I'm very happy
to show them around,
it's been my
life's work and
I am always happy
to talk about it.
Travis Taylor: What you
got going on right there?
Cameron: This is a
vacuum tube Tesla coil.
Travis Taylor: Vacuum
tube Tesla coil.
So instead of a
spark you've got.
Tesla coils are named
after their inventor
Nikola Tesla;
he was doing all kinds
of crazy things with
electricity more
than a 100 years ago.
Turn that thing on man.
Daddy: Is it safe
to stand here?
Cameron: Yes, it is.
Travis Taylor: Only
if you don't touch it.
Daddy: 30,000 volts
will get my attention.
Travis Taylor:
There it is.
Oh that will wake you up.
Haha, oh baby.
The way a Tesla coil works
is electricity first moves
through a transformer
which amps up the voltage.
From there, it
passes through
two coils of copper.
They're called the primary
and secondary winders.
That boosts the
voltage even higher,
then that high voltage
electricity collects
along the surface of the
big donut at the top.
And finally, it
discharges into those
giant crazy arcs
of lightning.
That's cool.
Tesla was an amazing
mad scientist guy;
I mean he
invented AC power,
which is what's in
every house in America.
But the bad thing about
it is, he died dirt poor,
but there was a
box of his notes
that were classified
immediately;
we still don't know
what was in that.
You know, if anybody
invented a death ray it
would have been Tesla.
What do you think
about that Daddy?
Daddy: That was crazy.
Travis Taylor: That
I was holding a 100,000
volts right there
with this screwdriver,
ain't that awesome?
When I saw these two
Tesla coils by each other
and they're throwing
sparks a few feet away,
there's our beam
weapon right there.
The challenge is that
lightning likes to take a
random path through
the air to the ground.
To weaponize it,
you need to give it
a path to follow.
The military is trying to
do this with a laser beam.
I think we can do it with
a stream of argon gas.
Cameron gave us
these pieces we needed
to put together
a giant Tesla coil.
This is gonna be exciting,
but really dangerous.
At some point here
I need to be starting
on us a Faraday cage.
If we're gonna build a
big Tesla coil that is
throwing arcs and stuff we
need a safe place to hide.
Kinda like the
Faraday cage on a
microwave keeps the
dangerous radiation in,
we need something that's
gonna keep the high
voltage from the
Tesla coil out and
it's got to big enough
for us to fit into.
Luckily, I've got an
old dog kennel over
at the house that I think
is gonna be just perfect.
Daddy: Not only
metaphorically,
we're literally gonna
be in the doghouse?
Travis Taylor: Yes.
Daddy: [laughing].
I love it!
Michael: We need
to do this at
the same time Pete.
Pete: Yeah.
Travis Taylor: We need to
get that inside there,
that's the high
voltage power supply.
There you go, that
makes too much sense.
Now we're gonna go right
over there in the middle
of the open area.
We rolled out our
primary winding,
and then set the
secondary on top of that.
Rog, throw another
hand up in there.
Let me get that wire
coming down towards you.
All right, the wire
is in the hole.
Michael: Where you
gonna grab it to?
Daddy: I don't know.
Travis Taylor:
We in like Flynn.
And finally, the giant
donut goes on top.
Man, this thing is
gonna be so wicked.
Daddy: I'm looking at this
thing and this is crazy.
It's 3 or 4 times bigger
than the one we saw before
and I'm thinking, this is
mad scientist stuff and I
don't know if I like it.
Travis Taylor: I betcha
it'll throw arcs out to
here, at least, at least.
Rog: I wanted us to have
a target that was flesh
and blood, so we're
gonna test our death ray
on a frozen turkey.
Travis Taylor: Look
at this right here.
Michael: What
did you find?
Travis Taylor: To create
our stream of argon gas
that will direct all that
electricity towards the
turkey, we're gonna turn
one of Michael's old
pressure washers into
a Tesla coil gun.
To make our gun we're
gonna take the voltage
from the top of the Tesla
coil and run it into the
pressure washer barrel,
then it meets up with the
argon gas from the tank
which flows to the gun
through a non
conductive rubber hose.
The electricity will
ionize the gas and then
shoot out of the gun
and hit the target.
There we go, right there.
Michael: I gotta operate
the gas from outside the
Faraday cage, so I'm
moving clear to the other
end of the garage so those
arcs can't reach me.
I'm gonna operate
it from right here.
Travis Taylor: Oh yeah
that will be good.
Hey, Michael run the gas.
Michael: All right.
Travis Taylor:
Here we go,
coming up
with the voltage.
Daddy: Pete,
watch your head.
Travis Taylor:
I'm seeing sparks.
Yeah, I saw something.
Fire, fire!
[loud screeching sound]
Michael: Cut it
off, cut it off.
Daddy: We're performing
real science experiments,
with dangerous
chemicals and tools.
We're professionals and
we take every
safety precaution.
Don't try these
experiments at home.
Travis Taylor: We're
using a million volts of
electricity from a giant
Tesla coil to make a
weapon of the future, a
lightning bolt death ray.
Fire, fire!
[loud screeching noise]
Michael: Cut it off,
cut it off!
Something is conducting.
Travis Taylor: But
it's not working out
like we planned.
Michael: It ran
straight down here.
Travis Taylor: It ran
right down that wire,
look at that.
Michael: And it's
a rubber hose.
Travis Taylor: It turns
out that the electricity
actually travelled
backwards along the
hose to the
gas canister and
gave Michael a
bit of a jolt.
You all right, Michael?
Michael: Yeah.
Travis Taylor: Did
it kill your phone?
Michael: I don't
know, I need to look.
Daddy: I don't know if it
killed his phone or not,
but it went and
made my hearing aids
go totally crazy.
Travis Taylor: Oh
I believe that.
Daddy: They started
making some kind of
surreal scream, about
bust my brains out.
I don't think anybody
on our crew has worked
with this kind of voltage;
it's something we don't
know a lot about and
that's when you
usually get hurt.
Travis Taylor: The
mistake we made was
putting our gas hose
too close to the floor.
Since lightning likes to
take the shortest path to
ground, the electricity
followed the gas hose
instead of channeling out
the barrel of the gun.
Daddy: You look at that
and tell me how an
electrical current
followed that.
Michael: 'Cause
a million volts,
a million volts
will follow a lot
more than you think.
The thing probably weighs.
Travis Taylor: So what
we've gotta do now,
is raise the gas
canister and
the hose up off the ground.
We need to get a
ladder up in here.
And get it higher
than the gun barrel.
Move forward a
little bit more, ho,
ho that looks good.
Go get your
bucket steer and
let's put the tank up there.
Rog: Look at old Yerp!
Travis Taylor:
Yeah, I gotcha Pete.
Hey, how did I end
up on the short end
of this deal?
Rog where are you?
Rog: Oh we're gonna ride?
Travis Taylor: Yeah.
♪ Rog: I wanna ride,
I wanna ride, ♪
♪ I wanna ride. ♪
Travis Taylor:
Yo, right there.
All right, Rog,
just see if we can,
just slide it.
Michael: That's good.
Travis Taylor: The
tank is sitting on a
Lazy Susan so now we
can move it around to
point the lightning gun.
We can control it with
some fishing line that
goes all the way back
to the Faraday cage.
Give us plenty
of room Pete.
All right that's
probably good.
Pete, you done tying
that string yet?
We're switching
from a rubber hose to
copper tubing so it'll
conduct the electricity
and channel it out the
barrel like we want it to.
All we got to do now
is connect the wire
to this tank over
to the Tesla coil.
Rog is steering.
Pete: Oh you are.
Travis Taylor:
That's all right.
Pete: I was wondering
why this thing
is getting away from me.
Travis Taylor: It
works great, Rog.
I think we got
ourselves a gun now.
So, let's go get us some
targets and set up out
here and let's
test this thing.
A weapon of the
future is gonna have
to destroy an army
of the future.
So it's gonna have to
fry their electronics.
What are you doing?
It will destroy
that computer.
Michael: Good, I'm
tired of this thing.
Travis Taylor: Michael
has agreed to donate an
old laptop of his, so
that we can begin the
fight against the
rise of the machines.
Well let's see if we
can blow it up then.
Get up there and
turn that gas on.
Get out of there now.
Come on over here,
watch the strings.
Close the door.
All right coming up.
Whoa!
[laughing].
Daddy: When that arc
hit the computer,
it just exploded.
Pete: Shut the gas off.
Travis Taylor:
I love that.
[laughing]
Rog: What made it
smoke like that?
Travis Taylor: Oh
man, look at that.
Look at the keys, man.
Look at that right there.
Son that joker is hot.
Look at that.
That is too cool man.
I want to blow
something else up.
We've seen what our
Tesla coil gun can do
against an old laptop.
That sure ain't
gonna work is it?
Michael: No.
Travis Taylor: Now,
it's gonna have to take
on an army of the future.
Look here, we got
us an army here man.
Set them out there
somewhere Rog.
See if we can get 'em.
All right Pete, ya'll
get in the cage,
Michael, get the gas going.
Get in here,
sending it up.
Go Pete, go Pete.
Holy crap.
Lookie here, his
back is on fire.
[explosion]
Whoa.
[laughing]
Michael: Let's
go check it out.
Travis Taylor: Now
that's cool right there.
I'd say that gun
works awesome.
Daddy: That it does.
Travis Taylor: Hey,
that's a future weapon
for future menacing
robots, right there.
Pete: That's right.
Travis Taylor: Man,
that is just too cool.
Michael: Look at
that, you blew the
whole top of that one off.
Travis Taylor: Blew
his head right off.
Michael: Oh shoot,
it's going, get back.
Rog: Go york, get it york.
Travis Taylor:
Hit it, Michael.
Now, this weapon may not
be deployable right now,
but imagine firing
something like this from
space or the air at a
high tech facility and
destroying all
their electronics.
With 100-year-old Tesla
technology we made a
weapon of the
future today.
Michael: What's up,
let's blow them up.
Travis Taylor: An
invading army of
robots wouldn't
stand a chance.
Momma: Where
are my robots?