- Uh, let's see...
Oh, there was cousin Isaac.
We called him Izzy.
- Oh, really? What's his story?
- That was it.
His name was Isaac,
and we called him Izzy.
- He did do
something important once,
but nobody would tell me
what it was,
and he went to jail.
- Hey, you know,
I know this story about a boy
who had a sister
who was half girl, half dog.
- And I know a story
about a girl
who punched her brother
in the face
and gave him two swollen eyes.
- Okay, enough.
What is this for anyway?
- I have to write about
an interesting relative
for my English class.
- Oh. Well, your father
has a bunch
of old family photo albums.
Maybe you can find
somebody interesting
on his side of the family.
- Wow.
That's a really good idea.
Thanks.
- Hey, you know,
if that doesn't work,
I know another story
about this kid...
- Say another word,
and I will spit in your ear.
By the time mom gets over here,
it'll be too late.
Thanks, mom.
- Oh, you're welcome.
sync and correct by dr.jackson
for www.addic7ed.com
- Hey, thanks for coming over
and doing my blog for me, Ray.
- Hey, man, I just want
to get as much attention
for my charity
as I possibly can.
We got this real big event
coming up:
music, comedy,
a celebrity basketball game,
a fashion show,
and a pancake breakfast.
- Throw in Tom joyner,
and you could put all that
on a cruise.
- Yes, it's for the kids.
But I'm telling you,
I'm having the hardest time
pulling it all together, man.
Seriously.
- You know what,
you should talk to my wife.
She plans stuff like this
all the time.
- Hello.
- And there she is.
- Here I am.
- Suzanne, this is star
first baseman Ray savage.
Ray, this my wife, Suzanne.
- Hi.
- Oh, it's nice to meet you.
All right, now, is that Suzanne
with a "z" or an "s"?
- Ah, a "z."
- Mmm. I like the "z"s.
You're a lucky man, Nick.
Lucky man.
- You know, I know you.
I've seen you in those
commercials with the kids.
Yeah, that's kind of my thing.
You know, George Clooney is
for helping out Africa.
Sting is for saving
the rain forests.
And Sean penn, you know, he's
for helping out them Haitians.
Me? I'm for the kids.
- Hey, babe, are we still going
to the movie on Wednesday night?
- Oh, yeah. We're good.
- Okay, 'cause I was just
looking at the review.
Four stars.
- I can't wait.
- All right, bye.
- Oh, whoa. Wait, wait.
Ray is putting together
this huge charity event,
and, uh, it sounds like
he could use your help.
- Oh, okay.
Well, I will get
your information from Nick,
and I'll have my assistant,
Gigi, give you call
and schedule something
and discuss consultation fees.
- Fees?
- Yeah.
I do it for money,
not for the kids.
- Ha.
- Oh, and this is my mother
with granny "V"
at a negro league baseball game.
One of her boyfriends played
for the San Francisco sea lions.
- What's that in her hand?
- Oh, that's an early version
of the number one finger.
It was made entirely of wood.
- Wood?
- Yeah, styrofoam was
too expensive back then.
You know, a lot of people say
granny "V" was ahead
of her time.
- Why do they say that?
- Have you ever heard
of madam C.J. Walker?
- No. Who's she?
- Well, she was the first
woman millionaire.
- Wow, she was like
the first Oprah.
- Yeah.
- Was granny "V" her partner?
- Oh, no, no.
Granny "V" was the first woman
to borrow $20,000 from her.
She was more like
the first Gayle.
- Anyway, she had
this great idea for a shop
where people could get
eyeglasses in an hr.
Now, at the time,
nobody thought it would work.
- Did it?
- No.
She lost every dime.
And madam C.J. Walker
never spoke to her again.
Wow.
- Yeah, she was pretty special.
- Wow, this is
the weirdest-looking leg
I have ever seen.
- Yeah, that's Nick's
great Uncle Blackie.
And he wasn't white.
He was an albino.
- Then why'd they
call him Blackie?
- Because if they didn't,
everybody would have thought
he was white.
- Oh, it's kind of like
the first the rock.
Special.
- Hey, man.
Here's your package.
Man, you got
your feet up on my...
What the hell?
Martin.
Martin!
Are you okay?
- He can't hear you.
What you lookin' at here...
Is the latest in advanced
field-interrogation apparati.
- It's not just a box
on his head?
- No, it's not.
It's the all-new,
portable
sensory-deprivation chamber.
Oh, God. Free at last.
They use that thing on people?
- Not if you tell us
what we need to know.
- Hey, man.
Thanks for signing
for my package.
- Why are you having
all this stuff
sent to my house anyway?
- You think I'm crazy enough
to let people know my address?
- Or is it that the post office
doesn't deliver
to a windowless black van?
- How you know it's black?
- Okay, so what's in that one?
- Oh, that's just some socks.
Argyle.
What's that?
- What? What could it be?
- What is what?
- So lame.
So...
Suzanne is meeting up
with Ray savage, huh?
- Yeah. Why?
- Let's just say my man has
a bit of a...reputation,
and that Sandra Bullock would
do well to stay away from it.
- Yeah, well, Suzanne's
just doing business with him.
- Okay. I'm just saying,
keep your eye on that guy.
- Good morning.
- Hey, baby.
I saved you some breakfast.
The kids left
for school already.
- Thank you.
I didn't realize
it was so late.
- Hmm. What time
you'd get in last night?
- I don't know.
Around midnight.
- Oh, that was a long meeting.
Well, I guess you guys
got everything
pretty much figured out.
- Nick, I know you don't want
to admit this,
but you should just say it,
"I am jealous."
- I am not jealous.
- If it makes you feel
any better,
Ray was the perfect gentleman.
All he did all night
was talk about the kids.
- At a hotel lounge
at 1:00 in the morning.
- I was not there
- Well, you weren't here.
- Yes, I was.
- So you do know
what time you came in?
- Yes, after you were asleep
and before 1:00 A.M.
I can't believe you.
- Oh, you can't believe me?
What if I was the one coming in
at who knows what time?
- After 12:00 and before 1:00.
- In a hotel lobby
with some strange woman?
- That I introduced you to.
- Well, what difference
does it make how I met her?
- I wouldn't introduce you
to somebody
that I was worried about
you being around?
- Well, what if
you didn't get worried
until after I was around her?
- And why would I be worried?
- Because I came home
after 12:00 and before 1:00
when I said
I'd be back by 10:00.
And, yeah, I'm jealous.
- Okay, so at 6:00 P.M.,
we'll have
the celebrity basketball game.
And that should give us
enough time
to open the doors at 9:30
for the comedy show.
- Ooh, ooh, ooh.
You think we can get
Wanda Sykes?
- You think we can bet
a big, fat check?
- Bob Saget'll work.
- Suzanne,
can you come over here
and take a look at this web page?
- Just send me a link.
- You know, I don't know
how to do that.
- I'll help you
with that, baby.
- No, thank you.
Suzanne, I really need you
to come look at it.
- Flowers for
Mrs. Kingston-persons.
- Oh, thank you.
So...
What's this?
- Ah, my check.
- Oh.
Thank you.
But it's missing a zero.
- Uh, you know what, I think you
might have to earn that.
- If I work too hard,
you're not gonna be able
to afford me.
- Mmm.
- So, Gigi,
what'd you want to...
Did you see where Gigi went?
- I wasn't watching her.
I was watching you.
- Okay. Sure.
So when will you need me
to pick that up?
- Hello?
- So can you explain to me
exactly what it is
you're trying to do.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
I have no idea
what you're talking about.
- No, uh, uh, I'm sorry.
It's just... it's a little
too close for comfort.
- Yeah.
Well, I understand
your concern.
But I don't think
that's gonna be an issue.
- Yeah, well,
I just want you to know,
I've done
a full background check,
and it turns out not only
is the client
married to another firm,
but he's doing business
with several small companies
around town.
Yes.
Yeah, I just don't think
this is a relationship
we want to continue.
- Well, I've got everything
under control,
and I'm gonna wrap this up
in a couple of days,
and I'll talk to you then.
Okay? All right.
Thanks so much for calling.
Buh-bye.
- Yeah, okay.
Okay. Yeah.
Mm-Hmm.
Yeah, I just want you to know
that I'm not happy
with the situation.
Right.
Yeah, and I can't promise
to keep my mouth closed.
Right. Okay.
All right.
Bye-bye.
- Gigi, what'd you want
to show me?
- I sent you the link.
- Ladies,
as much as I've enjoyed
the pleasure of your company,
I have a stadium to fill
and bases to steal.
- Oh, that's too bad.
Let me get your jacket.
- I didn't bring one.
- Take one anyway.
- Uh, I'll text you later.
- Bye.
Bye!
- Yeah.
- B-y-e.
Bye.
- And then in 1956,
granny "V" lost her house
and moved into a retirement home
after spending
her entire savings
in an attempt to market water
sold inside of bottles.
What do you think so far?
- Boring.
What you should do
is write that report
on somebody who's
ten times more interesting,
more dynamic,
mystious, and handsome.
- Like who?
- Like me.
- Well, I guess
it's not too late.
Do you mind if I ask you
some questions to start?
- Shoot.
- When were you born?
- I was born on the 127th day
in the Chinese year
of the Yang metal dog.
- Can you give me a number?
- 4667.
Dang, are you they teaching
y'all anything in school?
- What's your middle name?
- I don't want to tell you.
- Is that top-secret too?
- No. I just don't like it.
- Is there anything
you can tell me.
- Lindsey, I told you enough,
all right?
I told you
I have a middle name.
I told you my birthday.
You know I'm your uncle.
You still can't write it?
- Look, I once had to do
a report, 300 pages,
off of a severed ear
I found in the sand,
using the severed ear.
Tell me,
could granny "V" do that?
- Mm-mm.
- Uh-uh.
Now, when you finish
your report on me,
I need to look at that
because I might
have to redact a few things,
you know what I mean?
I done told you enough.
Tell your father thanks
for the package.
- What is in that anyway?
- Oh, this is
a sonic annihilator.
- What's a sonic annihilator do?
- It delivers an incapacitating,
seemingly silent shot of sound
to any hostile target.
- Mm.
- It's the latest
in nonlethal close combat.
Watch this. Kevin!
- Oh, my God.
Is he gonna be okay?
- Uh, yeah, you know what,
just... just wrap him up
in a snuggie
and don't tell your mom
I was here.
Uh...What's that?
- Ugh!
- Yeah, I forgot my keys.
What's that?
- Two pizzas, 20 minutes. Cool.
Ooh-whee.
Look at you. You look amazing.
- Thank you, honey.
You look nice too.
Where are you going?
- I'm going out with you.
Dinner, movies.
Four stars, remember?
- Oh, Nick. I'm so sorry.
I forgot. Can we reschedule?
- You forgot we were going out?
- I forgot.
- Then, why are you dressed
like that?
- I told Ray I would meet him
and his partners again tonight
so we could finalize everything.
- Dressed like that?
Where's the meeting... Vegas?
- Nick.
It's at a restaurant.
- Does your dress know that?
- Nick, stop it.
- I don't have to stop it.
Look, when you didn't like women
I was working with,
you were ready to upside
people's heads
and put bullets
in their behinds.
- That was different.
- How?
- Okay, that wasn't different.
But, Nick, if you just
give me a chance
to finalize everything tonight,
after that, I promise,
I am all yours.
- Okay. You go ahead.
But while you at dinner,
I want you to think
of something.
- What's that?
- Me, here, hungry,
alone, and sad,
watching a one-star movie.
- Okay, now, that's low.
- Not lower than me.
- Oh, my God.
- Have fun.
- I'll take another one, please,
and one for her too.
- Uh, no, actually.
Thank you. I'm fine.
- Yes, you are.
- Thanks.
- Come on. Loosen up.
Let's have some fun.
- You know, Ray, I like having
fun as much the next person,
but I'm actually here
to discuss business.
- Okay, ivanka trump.
Let's discuss business,
all right?
- Okay, thank you.
- Business.
- So I was thinking we could get
all the local food restaurants
to sponsor food tents,
and that way, they could...
W-what... what are you doing?
- I couldn't see your face
when you were talking.
- You want to go somewhere
where there's more light?
- I was thinking someplace
with less light.
- Can we bring your wife?
- She's with the kids.
Hey, my boy's got
a table at the club.
Let's roll over there,
and we can talk on the way.
- Ray, I'm not going
to a club with you.
- Come on,
Suzanne Kingston-persons.
Look, if we're gonna
discuss business,
we gotta hit this club,
and we got to hit it right.
Let's ride.
I see ride in your eyes.
Are you rolling or not?
Come on.
- I'll take "or not" for $20.
- Girl, quit playing.
Ser...
Hey, I'll text you the address.
No, serious...
I'll see you there.
- Hey, babe.
- Hey.
What are you doing here
so early?
I didn't expect to see you
till the morning.
- Okay, okay. I'm sorry.
I was wrong.
- Well, I hope you got
all your work done.
I hate to think I was sitting
here sad and lonely for nothing.
- Okay, Nick, stop it.
Nick, Ray hit on me.
- Really?
You mean to tell me you met
a guy in a dark place
late at night in a sexy dress
and he hit on you?
Really?
I'm shocked.
In other news,
ice cream is cold.
- You're not mad, are you?
- A little bit.
How am I supposed to feel?
- Disappointed but proud of me
that as soon as I realized
what was happening,
I got out there and came home.
- Nah, I'm gonna stick
with mad.
So what now?
- Well, tomorrow I'll have Ray
come to the office.
I'll return his deposit,
and I'll tell him
I can't take the job.
- Good.
'Cause you have a lot of work
to do at home.
- When do I start?
- Right after the game goes off.
- After the game?
- Yeah, unless you want me
to be sad.
Good morning, everybody.
- Hey, dad.
- Knock knock.
- Hey, Terrence.
- Hey, Dick.
Where's baby sis?
- Here I am.
- Look, we need to talk.
- Okay.
- About what?
- First of all, I think you need
to get these kids out of here,
'cause this is
grown-folk business.
- Kevin, Lindsey, please go
finish getting ready for school.
- Okay.
- Kevin, get moving.
- Good morning.
- Boy, what is wrong
with your hearing?
- Hey, Kevin.
You gotta get ready
for school now.
- Oh, okay.
I'll catch ya later.
- Oh, calculator?
Yes, in the drawer.
- What is wrong with that boy?
- I don't know.
- It's them damn Dr. Dre
headphones you bought him.
I told ya they was too loud.
- Okay, so what is going on,
Terrence?
- You tell me.
What's this I hear about you
all up in the club,
getting close and personal
with Ray Savage?
- You know what,
is this any of your business?
- You my baby sis, right?
- Yeah.
- And you knew about this, man?
- It's not what you think.
Suzanne was there for work.
I guess he had some other ideas.
- But I came home,
and I told my husband, Nick.
Okay? Are you happy?
- No. I'm not happy. All right?
I got a reputation.
I can't have my little sister's
name drug through the streets.
- Hey, man.
Don't worry about that.
Look, you can't stop
people from talking,
especially when they don't know
what they're talking about.
- I know that's right,
'cause I don't brought down
more than a few people
with my campaigns
of misinformation.
You heard about mubarak?
- You did that?
- Did what?
- Nothing.
- I got your package.
- Oh, yeah. Thanks, man.
This should be the last one.
- What in the world?
- Oh, whoa.
- What is that?
- I can't tell you,
but it's not socks.
Man, you're a better man
than me, trick.
Look, man, if my wife was
in the club with some dude
and he was pushing all on her,
man, I don't know what I'd do.
- Let's just hope
you wouldn't have done
whatever you was gonna do
with whatever's in that package.
- Ah, man, this ain't gonna
do nothing to you.
This ain't nothing
but a blow-dryer.
See y'all later.
- Hey, good morning, ladies.
- Hi, Ray.
- We gonna get down
to some business?
You know, we could have took
care of this last night.
- I'm sorry, but we're not
going to be able
to coordinate your event.
- Oh, well, I thought
this was a done deal.
- Well, it's not.
- Well, then,
what have we been doing
for the past few days, then?
- I was about to ask you
the same question.
- Whoa.
What's that supposed to mean?
- Wow.
You aren't going to
actually stand there
and act like you don't know why
you've been inviting my wife
out to clubs and dinners
and hotels
for the past few days?
Really, Ray?
Are you gonna come at me
like that?
- Hey, man.
I was doing it for the kids.
- You know what, man,
I think you better go,
'cause what I'm about to do
ain't got nothing to do
with the kids.
- Oh?
- Yeah.
- Oh-ho.
Are you threatening me?
- He just said
what he about to do
ain't got nothing to do
with the kids.
What part of
"ain't for the kids"
don't you understand?
- It's time for you to go.
- I've been hit
by a pitch before.
Call me.
- Bye.
- Tweet me.
- Facebook.
- Bye.
- Skype.
- Hey, brother.
- BBN.
- Bye.
- Even after she moved
into a retirement home,
granny "V" remained
as active as ever.
In 1955, after eating a dinner
of barbecued ribs,
granny "V" complained that there
wasn't enough meat on the bones
and wrote a letter
to the butcher.
Afterwards, she became
a local spokesperson
for their new-and-improved
meatier ribs,
when her slogan,
"where's the pork?",
became the tag-line
on their radio and tv ads.
- Very good.
- Nice job.
- Wow.
Oh, sweetheart,
that was just beautiful.
Your granny "V" would be
so honored.
- And thanks so much, Marilyn.
I couldn't have done any of this
without your help.
- Oh, baby, you are so welcome.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
there seems to be a hole
in the bottom of my glass.
- Lindsey, that was
a very well-written essay.
- Thanks, dad.
- I'm proud of you.
- Thanks.
- Wow.
She did a great job
on that paper.
- I know.
Too bad none of it was true.
- What? You lied to Lindsey?
- Embellished.
Well, what was I gonna do?
She needed help with her paper.
What was I gonna tell her?
My granny "V" was
a big, fat liar?
Spent her last few years
in the crazy house?
- Ma, you never told me that.
- I didn't?
Well, sorry.
But, in my defense,
everything I told her was stuff
that people told me
until I got older
and other people told me
it wasn't true,
which I am now telling you,
which you can tell her one day.
Anyway, let me know
what grade she gets.
And if there's trouble
at school, don't call me.
sync and correct by dr.jackson
for www.addic7ed.com