Because the settlers also bring bees with them for their honey.
The native American bee pollinates only a few species,
but European honey bees can live almost everywhere and pollinate any plant in sight.
Gardens turn into plantations
for consumption at home and abroad.
Apples thrive
and become a major
industry in North America,
eventually yielding a harvest of five million tons a year,
all beginning
with European seedlings.
This is biological imperialism in full swing.
Europe's fruits
and vegetables conquer the new world.
But it is also an exchange.
It is of the Columbian Exchange.
European kitchens may not see native meat from America, bison or lama,
but new world vegetables make a big impact.
The plant with the greatest impact on Europe needs a couple of centuries to
take root in its culture.
"This tuber is insipid and mealy and cannot be classed among the agreeable
foodstuffs but it's furnishes abundant and rather wholesome nutrition to men
who are content to be nourished.
It is justly regarded as flatulent but what are winds to the vigorous organs of
peasants and labourers?"
wrote Diderot in his Encyclopedia in the eighteenth century.
Introduced into Spain
potatoes slowly spread to Italy and to northern and eastern Europe.
By sixteen hundred the potatoes enter Austria, Holland, France, Switzerland,
England and Germany.
Frederick the Great himself urges its cultivation in Prussia.
But it is the Irish who adopt the potato with open arms.
They have a limited food supply and grain grown here has often been
destroyed or burned as the result of war.
But the potato safely under ground
survives these hardships.
In one hundred years Irish population
more than doubles.
And towns like Berlin grow into great cities.
By 1700
there is an unprecedented population explosion in Europe,
thanks to a plant from the faraway Andes.
Only one domestic animal from the new world sets foot in Europe:
the turkey.
Turkey and a few vegetables enhance the European diet, but otherwise
their life is relatively unchanged.
So why was the Columbian Exchange so one-sided?
Why did it go primarily in one direction from Europe to America?
With the exception of things like potatoes and potato blight,
why was Europe not overtaken by American plants and animals?
It's difficult to say why something did not happen,
but you have to remember that
the ecological invasion was a cooperative enterprise,
disease and plants and
animals working together
and Europe remained densely-populated and didn't have diseases depopulate its people
and so you didn't have niches open up for livestock to graze
and then weeds to take over the areas that livestock had overgrazed and trampled,
so that that critical part it worked in one direction primarily.
The European elites want more than just turkeys and potatoes from the new world,
they want luxury products.
Sugar and tobacco,
meet the requirements
of the upper class.
The first British settlers quickly acquire a taste for American tobacco
and export large shipments to Europe.
To satisfy such high demand
settlers build immense plantations.
Growing sugar becomes a business on the same scale as tobacco.
The new model cultures cover entire landscapes.
For this sole purpose some ten million Africans are transported to America
and enslaved to cultivate luxury items for Americans and Europeans.
Because of the rapid depopulation of the Americas owing to disease,
Europeans faced a shortage of labour in their effort to exploit
the resources of the new world particularly to exploit the soil,
so the Europeans, first the Portuguese and then the Dutch and then eventually the English
imported slaves from west Africa to cultivate sugar in the Caribbean and Brazil,
tobacco in Virginia, rice in South Carolina and by the nineteenth century
in mainland North America,
it's no exaggeration to say that
these cash commodities
produced by slave labour were central to the export economies of the Americas.
By the eighteenth century the metamorphosis of much of America is complete.
New Spain and New England are fully established.
Nature has been transformed
and is in the hands of man.
Now pioneers are heading west.
There is still empty land in that direction.
They will complete what was begun
in the east.
In the creation of the new world
perhaps ninety percent of the native American people died.
The people who took their place
came from all over Europe,
as conquistadors,
settlers,
explorers,
and colonists.
And they came from Africa as slaves.
But it was the transfer of animals and plants from Europe to the Americas
that really made the creation of the new world possible.
In today's chrome and steel cities
we sometimes seem so cut off from Nature
that it may be difficult to believe the Columbian Exchange ever happened.
But in the final analysis the skyscrapers
and the melting pot of the races
owe their existence not only to humans
but also to the natural world.
People came to the Americas for many reasons. Some came to make money,
some came for religious freedom, some came involuntarily as slaves
but those populations took hold
in the Americas because of the accident of ecology,
because of the microbes, the plants, the animals that they brought with them gave them
an advantage over the people who were already here.
And the legacy
of the Columbian Exchange is also still largely biological,
and that legacy will continue into the future.
It all  began five hundred years ago,
Columbus
had a vision
and three ships set out in a quest for India
and found the new world.