looking busy.
They're all at computers though,
which means what
they're actually doing is
basically what you are doing--
screwing around on
the internet.
I work on a computer too.
I'm no stranger to YouTube
links, and so I decided to put
together a few of my favorites
from this week.
So come enjoy the cream
of the crap.
[SIGH]
Since it's our first week
together, we are forging a
little bond of intimacy with us,
I figured instead of doing
the week's round up, I would
kind of dig back into the
personal archives and share
with you five of my--
maybe not all time favorite,
but I think significant
YouTube clips from
my own life.
Our first one is completely
self-contained and
self-explanatory.
It's an Asian reporter
going down a slide.
REPORTER: [SPEAKING CHINESE]
[SCREAMING]
THOMAS MORTON: Look, I'm
not going to try to--
kind of want to make that my
ringtone, to be frank.
The next video is what qualifies
as a griefing video.
It's labeled "An epic troll,"
which is kind of like
"slander" and "libel"--
they're both more or
less the same term.
The audio is piped in, which
makes it even funnier.
And then to emphasize that, and
make sure you understand
exactly what swears they're
sputtering,
they've added text.
THOMAS MORTON: As a veteran of
many busted NES controllers
and harsh words to my mom in
other rooms, I think it's only
par for the course.
But it's kind of like a grunting
in tennis, it helps
you play better.
So the deal with this kid
is, I think it's like a
10-year-old who has a camera,
but probably also Autism.
So this is just one video from
this kid who has a whole page
that you should subscribe to
immediately, because all his
videos are of--
not at him, but of what he sees
through the camera, and
then him talking about the
camera and then kind of
getting angry about the
camera's occasional
non-functionality.
CHILD (OFFSCREEN): Dang it.
Can't zoom up on this camera.
Wonder if all these people
have ever heard of
the camera I have?
THOMAS MORTON: This is as a
little more cerebral fare.
It's a robotic birth simulator
as being demonstrated by a guy
who has clearly been inside a
countless number of vagina's.
He makes Wilt Chamberlain look
like Tiny Tim, basically.
MALE SPEAKER: Often junior
doctors can place the first
blade, but have a lot of
difficulties to place the
second blade.
THOMAS MORTON: I cannot believe
this hasn't been taken
down and moved to RedTube yet.
MALE SPEAKER: And the junior
doctor has to go through the
spheres in order to
place the forceps.
THOMAS MORTON: This last clip
was a favorite of our British
office for a while, I think
because all British people are
racist against every other
country in Europe.
It's a pool girl at--
as evidenced by the bathing
suits-- an Eastern European
party of some sort, in the
mother of all k-holes.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
THOMAS MORTON: Thanks, really
hope you enjoyed this.
And don't not come back again.
Subscribe to our channel, and
keep on YouTubing in the
YouTube world.
[MUSIC PLAYING]