It's that head-to-head
battle, in that it's
almost combat out there.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[ENGINES REVVING]
- Moments away from the first
race here in Brno.
With the championship tied
between Sturla Fagerhaug and
Jakub Kornfeil, with seven
riders still in the chance to
win this championship,
excitement is
huge here on Saturday.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[MOTORCYCLE ENGINES]
COMMENTATOR: Sturla's going to
be in about tenth place as
they go into the first corner.
You can see the red helmet.
He's pulled across to the right
hand side, but it's
[INAUDIBLE]
and--
I think that's Florian Marino--
will beat him to the
first corner, and [INAUDIBLE]
in about twelfth place.
And there is the red helmet
of Sturla Fagerhaug.
Fagerhaug still back in about
seventh place, chasing his
arch-rival for the cup,
Jakub Kornfeil, as
they come up the hill.
Gagne puts him under pressure
goes up the inside.
Gagne takes the lead.
Leads the Red Bull Rookies Cup,
the penultimate round
here at Brno.
[INAUDIBLE]
from the Californian out onto
the start and finished, to
complete lap one.
[MOTORCYCLE ENGINES]
- We're still in second
right now.
It's all good.
COMMENTATOR: Fagerhaug breaks
off, passes two guys going
into the [INAUDIBLE]
advantage.
He drifts a little bit
wide, [INAUDIBLE]
beautiful line out onto
the start and finish.
There is number 84, Kornfeil,
just hating the fact that
there are about eight guys
between him and his arch-rival
for the Cup.
They're three abreast,
they close up.
Fagerhaug [INAUDIBLE]
it's five abreast
going into the corner.
COMMENTATOR: It's Fagerhaug
there in about fifth place,
ahead of Hiura.
It's Florian Marino that leads
Danny Kent across the line.
Florian Marino wins his first
Rookies Cup race.
[MOTORCYCLE ENGINES]
COMMENTATOR: Absolutely
fantastic stuff.
Incredible fastest laps
of the race from Danny
Kent who was second.
Alejandro Pardo was third,
Fagerhaug was fifth.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
STURLA FAGERHAUG: Even though
I only finished fifth, I'm
still leaving the championship
three points ahead of Jakub.
Because he finished,
like, eighth.
I pulled away a bit again,
but it's not by much.
Lots of things can happen
in the race tomorrow.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
- MotoGP is what it's
all about right now.
So, for us to have the
opportunity to come back over
here, possibly, would
be awesome.
And I would do everything in my
powers to make sure that we
could get him back over here.
We just don't know.
It's a funny thing, we're
at the right place
in the wrong time.
The economy's tough.
Sponsorships are tough.
I don't know, no more than
anybody else here knows,
what's really going to
happen next year.
GUSTL AUINGER: So my friends,
may I have your attention a
little bit?
So we have our final briefing.
Not just for today, not just for
the weekend, for the whole
season maybe.
Anyone needs some help, or some
information later on, you
will find me anyway.
But I think, it's nothing
more to say.
Thank you from my side, thank
you for doing this job, thank
you for improving so hard.
And please once [INAUDIBLE]
today.
Thank you very much friends.
Good luck.
[APPLAUSE]
HAYDEN GILLIM: Before the year
started, everybody put this
thought in my head that I was
too big for a 125, and it's
just stayed there all year.
I'm not really sure what I'm
going to do next year,
racing-wise.
-If he gets invited back, when
to sit down, because if he's
not going to be determined and
give it his all and come over
here and actually ride like he
knows how to, then we would
definitely decline.
- Last year in the US, he was
used to winning and winning
and winning.
Now he got his butt kicked,
and I think that made him
stronger, and think
a little bit more.
BENNY SOLIS: I want to continue
racing, I mean,
everyone has their ups and
downs, and that's not gonna
make me quit.
JACOB GAGNE: Next year, if I
came back, I'd just try to
learn more and just improve my
riding, and try to be faster.
Really that's all you can try
to do, is keep going faster
and faster.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
I'd like Jakub to win
the Rookies Cup.
He's not big-headed, he just
keeps himself to himself.
And he's quiet and he's a
good rider, and I think
he deserves to win.
I would bet on Sturla winning
The Rookie Cup.
He has a lot more experience.
I think that he is
a better rider.
- Have fun.
STURLA FAGERHAUG: I will.
Thanks.
COMMENTATOR: So this is it, the
final race of the season.
It's all come down to this.
Just straight points between
the two guys, Fagerhaug and
Kornfeil, for the cup.
[MOTORCYCLE ENGINES]
COMMENTATOR: [INAUDIBLE]
And wow, looking back on another
mediocre start from
Fagerhaug, a little bit better
from Jakub Kornfeil.
Some bumping going
into the corner.
And that's all played into
Florian's hands.
And we've already
had a faller.
And Nico Thoni is
one of those.
He's walking away.
Another man lies injured.
There is number 33, with
the red helmet.
Kornfeil does have now a
half-second advantage.
Half-second advantage
over Fagerhaug
with ten laps remaining.
He goes for the inside line, and
this really is gonna slow
things down for his pursuers.
These guys are messing
each other up.
They've got to use
the slipstream.
They've got to settle their own
differences, and really
chase after Kornfeil.
It's very sad to see Hayden
Gillim pull into the pit.
He's not had the luckiest
of years, hasn't he?
COMMENTATOR: And it's Fagerhaug
that picked up the
slipstream from everybody,
and goes shooting past,
and takes the lead.
So it's all changed in just
a couple of corners.
Fagerhaug [INAUDIBLE]
and Kornfeil goes
up the inside.
This is all heating up to be the
most dramatic Rookies Cup
race of the year.
They're on the brakes.
He goes up the inside, back
through the gears.
He can't do it, Fagerhaug is too
quick around the outside.
So close, those guys, absolutely
almost sitting on
the same motorcycle.
Two guys, three guys, five
guys side by side.
[INAUDIBLE] swoops across
the nose of all of them.
Beautiful job from
Jakub Kornfeil.
Yes he does.
Jakub now fighting for every
[INAUDIBLE] corner, but
Sturla's having nothing of it.
It's all down to these--
just last lap at Brno.
For the first time Jakub
does make an
overtaking maneuver there.
He seals the lead, but
he's got two guys
looking over his shoulder.
Jakub Kornfeil at leads.
Hiura moves up into second
place, just what Fagerhaug
didn't want to see.
Perfect maneuver from
Jakub Kornfeil.
[INAUDIBLE]
- Whoops.
Whoops.
- What happened?
- This is going to get settled
between Jakub Kornfeil and
Sturla Fagerhaug in the last
two corners here at Brno.
COMMENTATOR: Jakub Kornfeil is
gonna take the Cup, the Czech,
at his home circuit.
He wins the 2009 Red Bull
MotoGP Rookies Cup.
- OK.
I think he's very upset
now, very sad.
I feel sorry for him.
- Quite right, mate.
[MOTORCYCLE RUMBLES]
[APPLAUSE]
[INAUDIBLE]
[APPLAUSE AND WHISTLING]
MATHEW SCHOLTZ: I suffer from
something called fat-ass.
When I come out of
the corners--
HAYDEN GILLIM: You weigh
as much as Jake.
MATHEW SCHOLTZ: My back just,
just like loses--
HAYDEN GILLIM: No, you weigh
as much as Jake.
MATHEW SCHOLTZ: I
dunno why, but--
HAYDEN GILLIM: I'm fat.
MATHEW SCHOLTZ: I dunno why,
on the straights my back is
just like falling behind.
HAYDEN GILLIM: Stop.
Stop whining.
MATHEW SCHOLTZ: I'm whining.
BENNY SOLIS: I did OK.
I got fifteenth.
- You got one point,
which is good.
You took the last point.
It's good.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
[CZECH NATIONAL ATHEM]
JACOB GAGNE: Those few laps were
pretty crazy, it was us--
I think five-- at the front,
and everybody was
going back and forth.
I knew them two were fighting
for the championship, so I
didn't want to mess with
them too much.
But, I just tried to find a way
through, and it worked out
really good.
So I'm happy.
- It's good.
The championship coming down to
less than 2/10 of a second
in the final round, I
think, is amazing.
Jake Gagne rode good.
Daijiro Hiura.
All the guys in that group
seem to respect that
championship battle
that was going on
between Jakub and Sturla.
To me, good clean competition.
There was a little bit of
bumping, but I don't think
anything that was real
intentional.
STURLA FAGERHAUG: Yeah, I'm
quite disappointed.
The race was great and
all, but I lost the
championship, so--
anyway, it was my fault I
crashed the last two races, I
got hit by Daijiro on the last
lap, so that's a bit
disappointing.
Anyway, great race.
I'm just looking forward
to my next race.
MATHEW SCHOLTZ: I do feel bad
for him, because he is one of
my best friends.
So yeah, I feel bad for him.
- I'm sure, as disappointed as
he is in the final result and
being second in the championship
by two points,
he's going to be that much
smarter and that much better
of a racer for the rest
of his career.
GUSTL AUINGER: I'm a bit sad
because the season ends so
[INAUDIBLE]
there's so many heart
blood in it.
And I'm not happy
to go home now.
- These guys are all such young
kids, they could still
become lawyers and bankers and
whatever else they want to be.
But, I think we have enough
talent here that we might even
have some future world
champions here.
JACOB GAGNE: I just love the
feeling of riding, of going
fast, and racing, and having
a competition, and
everything about it.
That's why we all race.
We love it.
HAYDEN GILLIM: Even after I
retire, I'll probably still be
riding at home, riding
dirt bikes.
I'm hoping to die at an old
age on a motorcycle.
- I couldn't imagine life
without it, because it's
always been there.
Racing has always been around.
So I would miss it completely.
But I'd be OK if my kids decided
not to, but I would--
I would definitely miss it.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
- When you get a two-stroke bike
right, and you rev it,
and it comes by you on the pit
wall, and you feel the
resonance of the exhaust,
and the tone.
And he's down and he comes
absolutely howling by you,
it's beautiful.
And this is what all racing
people like to see.
And the unfortunate things that
go with it, i.e, taking
all your money.
Or a child, or husband, or
boyfriend getting injured.
But the passion for this sport
overcomes all that.
If you're passionate
about it you come
back and you try again.
[MUSIC PLAYING]