MICHAEL HOLSTINE: We're standing
on top of level four
of the Green Bank Telescope,
the largest fully steerable
radio telescope in the world.
We're standing directly under
the reflector for the main
structure, which is
2.4 acres in size.
KAREN O'NEIL: Radio astronomy
started back in
the 1920s and '30s.
It really got its start when
people were surveying the
radio sky to understand noise
that they were seeing within
their own radio observations.
And they began to realize that
that radio noise was actually
coming from outer space, from
the sun, from the stars, and
from the distant galaxies
that we see out there.
And so with that became the
field of radio astronomy.
And that grew and grew until
eventually, in the 1950s--
1956--
the United States realized that
if we were going to be a
player in this new field of
science, we needed to build a
national radio astronomy
facility.
When they decided to build a
national radio astronomy
facility, they began looking
around the country to
determine where the best site
for that facility would be.
And they had a lot of different
criteria in that decision.
But one of the biggest, and
possibly most important in the
long run, was they wanted an
area where radio frequency
interference was minimal.
MICHAEL HOLSTINE: You can
imagine, in 1958 there were no
wireless communications
to speak of.
But in the last 10 to
15 years, wireless
technology has exploded.
Everyone has a cell phone.
And now simply because the
telescope is so sensitive
that, for instance, your cell
phone that you're so attached
to, if it, alone, that single
cell phone, were placed on
Mars, for instance, it would be
the brightest radio object
in the sky to us.
So we have to figure out a way
to allow communications,
particularly for emergency
medical purposes, and still
protect the data that the
observer is trying to receive.
So from this point on, beyond
this gate, we require that a
diesel engine only
travel down here.
And you can see the "no
spark plug" sign.
We design, build, and
run these extremely
technologically advanced
instruments.
But here, on site, we can't
use the technology that
everyone else is
used to using.
We don't have cellphones.
We don't have microwave ovens.
There are a few people that are
upset that they can't have
the conveniences that
maybe their aunt and
uncle in Ohio have.
But again, we try to find a way
to work with those people
to provide them what they would
like to have without
having the wireless
be part of it.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
KAREN O'NEIL: When the GBT came
along, it's not just very
sensitive, but it has a very
wide frequency range.
That is, we can look at
wavelengths from many, many
meters down to things that are
just three millimeters in
wavelength, so very,
very small.
And with that came the idea of
well, let's just use this
incredibly sensitive telescope
with its incredibly wide
frequency range and go see what
we could find out there.
So they pointed the telescope
into areas where you can
expect to find complex
molecules, like
star formation areas.
And they found very, very
complex molecules, more
complex than anybody would
have imagined, up to very
basic sugars in space.
So that tells us that the
building blocks of life are
everywhere out there.
As Douglas Adams said,
the universe is huge.
It's mind-bogglingly huge.
And we're already discovering
stars that have other
planetary systems, very much
like our own Earth, here in
our own galaxy.
There absolutely is
life out there.
I would even go as far to say as
I think there's intelligent
life out there.
KAREN O'NEIL: The bigger
question is, even if the
universe is teeming with
intelligent life, are we going
to be able to detect
it in our lifetime?
That's an incredibly difficult
feat to do.
MICHAEL HOLSTINE: We are, with a
certain suite of instruments
here right now, at least
trying to reach back to
milliseconds after the
Big Bang occurred.
And we're looking at the epic
of re-ionization, when there
started to be a coalescence
of material.
Once you have star creation, you
have a long laundry list
of things that, at least for
us, end up into human
creation, because we're all
made of the stuff that the
stars produce.
So it's a very interesting
thing to watch.
I really think there was
something before
the Big Bang, too.
I think that there may have been
many big bangs, because
the logic, for me, is there
that it occurred.
Every day, people here think
about those possibilities, not
just whether it's possible, but
how do I go about proving
that that's a possibility?
And the instruments that are
here allow a lot of that work
to be done.
[MUSIC PLAYING]