of the most evocative names in the world of
motoring. But for the last few decades the
firm hasn't had a sports car that lives up
to their illustrious sporting heritage but
now they have - this car, the Alfa Romeo 4C.
With a carbon fibre chassis, dual-clutch gearbox
and a mid-engine layout the spec sheet reads
like a super car, yet it costs less than 50K.
But how does it compare to arguably the best
mid-engined sports car in the world - Porsche's
Cayman. Well, in an Auto Express track battle,
let's find out. The stunningly beautiful 4C
is a return to Alfa Romeo's sports car past.
With its carbon fibre chassis, it weights
just 895kg while the 1.7-litre four-cylinder
turbo engine produces 270bhp and 350Nm of
torque. Now into its second generation the
Porsche Cayman is famous for its perfect handling
the 2.7-litre flat-six engine has 271bhp and
290Nm of torque. But it weights 1,310kg so
that's 400kg heavier than the carbon-fibre
Alfa Romeo. So we've got a very standard Cayman,
it's not a Cayman S just a standard Cayman.
Hasn't got an active damping system - it's
just a very standard Cayman. The Cayman's
lovely it works on so many layers it's a fantastic
road car, rides relatively nicely, quite comfortable
on the road so it's got that element. But
the big question is, can it take on the Alfa
for pure driving thrill? And, so many things
about this car just feel perfect - the second
you drive onto the circuit you just feel absolutely
at the centre of the action. Everything's
beautifully balanced - you just feel like
the car is pivoting around you so obviously
mid-engined, rear-wheel-drive, just absolutely
perfect balance in the chassis. There's a
little bit of roll in the car but nothing
bad, you know it's just such a wonderfully
well-balanced car. It's got a sports exhaust
which is really good. Traction is amazing
- it's quite long gearing in the Cayman so,
and the engine only really starts to sing
above 4,500RPM so on the road you can sometimes
feel like it's a little bit out of its comfort
zone but the track when you get it working
it really sounds amazing so that's the first
lap done, little bit of heating to the tyres.
It's come round and you start a flying lap,
so across the line, second gear, and again
because that gearing is quite short down the
second here, there's so much feel through
the steering that you just always know what
the car is doing. Change of direction is amazing
there, lots of grip as the car's loaded up
with that long long left-hander. Up to third
gear, just over 100mph and 110 hard on the
brakes down to second gear for the corner.
Loads of feel through the brakes, ABS doesn't
come in too hard. Third gear, amazing traction
on the exit of that tight corner. Again, into
these higher-speed corners the control and
the balance on the car is just - you really
feel what's going on, it's such a joy to drive
this car. It's so beautifully balanced, sounds
great and just communicates so well. Third
gear, high speed change of direction here.
You can feel the weight through here but,
still, pretty amazing through there. Right
up at the top of the revs in third, down to
second, really good brakes. Into the apex,
great traction into the last corner. Such
a lovely car and across the line. So the Porsche
was a joy to drive and lapped the circuit
in 1 minute 12.7 seconds the question is,
is the Alfa Romeo going to be faster? Starting
a practice lap the first thing you notice
about the car is that it doesn't have power
steering. Surely the reason for not having
power steering is to save weight, but also
to give you an uninterrupted purity of steering
feel - unfortunately, the steering feel isn't
very good. The steering really squirms around
and kicks back quite a lot. But you can't
really feel what the front end's doing which
is a shame because the one thing you're going
to want if you've got no power steering is
good steering feel but it's a shame. The engine's
quite coarse, it's not a nice noise like the
six-cylinder Porsche. It does make itself
known in the cabin but the dual-clutch gearbox
is pretty quick and perfectly suited to the
job. The other disappointment you notice really
is the fact that the brake pedal - it's very
strong and there's plenty of stopping power,
but there's not a lot of feel to the brake
pedal and it's quite hard to brake progressively.
The retardation is quite grabby and it gets
into the ABS very quickly, but the body control
around that high-speed corner is just amazing.
There's hardly any roll in this car it does
feel like a really planted track car. So,
let's see if that gives it the advantage against
the stopwatch. So, coming round now starting
the lap - trying to get good traction out
of it, which is pretty good. Much shorter
gearing than the Porsche, so we're a gear
up in some of these corners, so change the
gear into this first corner here - really
good through there as it changes direction
from left to right. A little bit of understeer
as you get on the power - there is a little
bit more understeer in this car than you probably
would like and because of the fact with the
Turbo power it's quite hard to dial the understeer
to oversteer because when you get back on
the throttle you have the engines not on boost
and then it suddenly comes into boost. It's
better now on the track when it's dried off,
when the track was damp that made the car
quite edgy quite tricky. Now that it's dried
off it's pretty good and through these high
speed corners turning and the really stiff
body control means that there's lots of grip
and it is really planted through here. But
again just a little bit too much understeer,
mighty through here though, little lift through
the right. Back on the throttle flat out through
the left over 100 on the exit hard on the
brakes squirms a little bit again too much
on the braking. Power through the gears, second
gear, third gear around to the last corner
coming up to the line now and across the line.
Incredibly, given how different they are to
drive this pair record an identical lap time
around our test track. That's the first time
that's every happened - so what's going to
win our track battle? Well the Alfa is beautiful,
has loads of grip and fantastic body control
but unfortunately it lacks the sublime chassis,
communication and fingertip feel of the Porsche.
The Cayman is also more practical, cheaper
and better to live with day-to-day. So, while
we love the look of the Alfa, the all-round
abilities of the Cayman make it one of the
best sports cars money can buy - and it wins
this track battle.