STEFAN RUIZ: For me, what I've
always been interested in is
this contrast between rich
and poor, between--
just the craziness
of the world.
How different people live
different ways.
People are the same.
People are different.
But just to try to photograph,
in a similar way, all these
different things, and let them
speak for themselves.
I would say people think of me
as a portrait photographer--
Well, no.
It's weird.
Because some people think of me
as a portrait photographer.
Other people think of me as a
landscape travel photographer.
So I kind of like that,
because they
don't always cross.
I think in the States,
especially, I'm considered
this third world photographer,
who photographs down and outs
or something.
I don't really know.
I do tons of celebrity portraits
for the Sunday
newspaper magazines in the UK.
I photographed James
Brown for them.
I photographed P Diddy.
Liza Minnelli.
I don't know.
All kinds of people.
I'm still pretty shy, but
I was really shy.
And for me to meet people, or
do anything, the good thing
with photography, and working
for magazines, or just
travelling and going on these
things was I was thrown into
these situations where
I just had to deal.
And I like that.
And I like the fact that I get
sent places, and from one week
to the next, I'm not really sure
who I'm going to meet,
where I'm going to go.
And I'll do advertising.
I'll do my own stuff.
I'll do portraits of
celebrities, or poor people,
or I'll do some kind of
documentary thing.
And for me, it's always
interesting.
I'm definitely a hoarder,
a collector.
It runs in the family.
My mom is a crazy hoarder.
It's so hard for me to
throw anything away.
But at the same time, I travel
all the time, and I've gotten
quite good at going places and
buying things that you can't
really find in other
places, or it's
harder to, or whatever.
I buy photographs.
I buy things that I think
are weird I buy anything
portrait-based.
Cups.
I don't know.
I bought five jockey coffee mugs
the other day, because
they're portraits of jockeys.
It's just retarded.
I like this one, because he's
kind of like Burt Reynolds.
I don't know why I collect
portraits.
I think that portraits just kind
of work, aesthetically.
Some of this is from Mexico,
South Africa.
I've got my Pablo Escobars.
We've got Robin Hood, and him as
a businessman or a Senator,
and then him casual.
They're made by a guy
in [INAUDIBLE].
This is from Mexico.
These are some of my favorite
types of photographs.
These are these carved
old photographs.
I've got a bunch of them.
They're really fragile.
A lot of them are really old.
These are photos I
bought in Egypt.
So these are Egypt
in the '70s.
Yeah, they're hand-colored
from the '70s.
They got a little wild
there in the end.
But I'm into studio
photography.
I got this in Colombia.
I think it's a photographer's
advertisement for his skills.
I like this one.
We have the butt.
We have the beer being poured.
I like that one.
Or that.
What else?
I collect records as well.
This is Gal Costa.
I also like this one, though.
This is one of my favorites
of the moment right now.
The salsa is my law, really.
This is Patrick, trusted
assistant for years now.
I'm from San Francisco.
I went to university
in Santa Cruz.
I studied drawing and painting,
and I got into
photography kind
of by accident.
I worked for a professor of mine
in Northeast Ivory Coast.
That first trip, I didn't
consider myself a
photographer.
I liked taking pictures, but
I just wanted to travel.
I think that's how I got
into photography.
The first photos I took
were actually there.
I went back to California.
I had no money.
I got a job in a bar.
And while I was working in the
restaurant, I was also
teaching drawing and painting at
San Quentin, at the prison.
And then I really wanted to take
pictures of them, so I
started taking all
these photos.
And then I put this whole little
notebook together.
And I would carry this box.
This was before laptops,
everything.
Maybe I'd changed boxes
at one point, but this
is basically it.
I used to bring this to Europe
with me all the time.
And then I would show this, and
this is how I'd get jobs.
So these are a couple of
guys from my class.
5150s, clinically insane.
So these are all from the
early '90s, I'd say.
In London, you'd always have
meetings in the pub.
And as I'd get more and more
drunk, eventually I would
start showing my photos
to people.
And one of the guys, he started
doing "Caterpillar."
And he basically hired me to do
photos like my photos from
the prison for caterpillar.
That's when I first started
really making some money, and
start figuring, maybe I could
make a living at photography.
The guy I worked with on
"Caterpillar," he started
working at "Camper." And then
he hired me for the first
campaign he did there.
And I did six campaigns with
"Camper." He wanted something
a little bit quirky, and he
gave us a lot of freedom.
Tons of freedom.
It seemed like we could
do anything we wanted.
And then, when I was probably on
the fifth or sixth campaign
for "Camper," I was asked to
be creative director at
"Colors."
"Colors" was this magazine that
took things, and each
issue had a theme.
Whether it was war,
or whatever.
And instead of doing a type of
documentary photography that
was probably seen a lot at that
time, we were trying to
do a more polished image
of this thing.
Not artificial, but just,
maybe, well-lit,
well-composed, hopefully
respect.
Quite interesting to look at.
I'd take the same equipment I
would take to photograph some
celebrity, I would take
on my ad jobs.
And I would set it up pretty
much the same way.
But you're photographing
a refugee, or
maybe a doctor or something.
Not necessarily a
stolen moment.
Something that is about
participation.
Where the sitter has
to participate in
the photo as well.
You're not just taking
something from them.
Kind of like this negotiation
or something.
You have to work with
the person.
Some of these are
my own projects,
and then other stuff.
The telenovelas series is
something that is definitely
important to me.
The telenovela project started
with "Colors." The idea of
doing a whole issue on soap
operas in Mexico City came up.
I thought they were interesting,
because so many
people watched them, because
it's kind of like there's
these unattainable dreams for
the people watching them.
But there's all these social and
political things that are
behind it and in it.
You're dealing with things like
with money, with race,
with these Cinderella stories.
Part of it was also because half
my family's from Mexico.
And my family came across
the border illegally.
They were poor, trying to better
themselves, whatever.
Trying to get this dream.
It all kind of made sense
to me in that way.
I've been shooting in Mexico a
lot of over the years, and
tomorrow I'm going back
to shoot, but
to start a new project.
I'm going to Mexico tomorrow,
so I'm packing now.
I'll probably throw my clothes
in with the tripod and stuff.
I travel with this,
the lights.
Some light stands here.
This is the camera I use.
It's a great camera.
These are film holders.
This film here goes in there.
And that's kind of it.
And all my spare
Mexican pesos.
OK.
So we just got here
in Monterrey.
I've been to a lot of places
in Mexico, but not here.
We came to Monterrey, Mexico to
do a shoot on the fashion
and hairstyle of these kids
who listen to a lot of
vallenato and cumbia
from Columbia.
They call themselves Colombians,
but they're not
Colombians.
They're from Mexico,
and particularly,
they're from Monterrey.
I don't know.
They've been called
"Cholombians."
With that like documentary-style
portrait,
you're really dependent on
the people showing up.
And a lot of times, they
don't show up.
Because they don't know you,
and they don't really--
I think you've got to bring
yourself to them.
So first, we went to the market,
where they buy music,
and they can buy videos,
shirts, hats, trinkets,
Colombian things, Colombian
pictures.
They buy this, and it's kind
of a gathering point.
They sell a lot of bootleg
films, and there seems to be a
little brothel behind where
we are shooting.
I didn't want to shoot them,
necessarily, with all the
grime and stuff, like,
say, in the market.
I wanted to keep the
image clean.
Because they're interesting
enough on their own, and I
think the background would
just distract.
I wasn't trying to make some
kind of social statement about
where they live, or about
anything like that.
It's more about them
and their style.
I still shoot mostly
with the 4x5.
Almost only.
My camera is made in Germany.
It's a Linhof.
I'm like this dinosaur.
I get hired on ad jobs to use
my 4x5, and then the art
directors are like, wow,
I haven't seen one of
those in a long time.
They're really slow, though.
Sometimes I hate my camera.
But it's great at
the same time.
I guess the thing was, I was
never really a 35 millimeter
kind of war photographer style,
like run around, shoot.
Snap, snap, snap.
Different angles and stuff.
Since I did do painting, and
since I was used to setting up
compositions, I felt more
comfortable with that.
Still trying to figure
out my framing here.
I've never really been into the
idea of trying to convince
someone to do a photo by
giving them money.
I think it creates kind
of a weird dynamic.
So my way around that, a lot
of times, has been to just
shoot Polaroids, and give
them Polaroids.
So I'm giving him the one
he likes the most.
And keep a few for myself, so I
can work out what I'm doing.
I can critique how this
shoot's going.
I will also show them
what I'm doing.
I think it builds a sense of
trust, if they look at the
Polaroid and they see
what I'm doing.
They show it to their friends.
Their friends get interested,
their friends want pictures.
We just got our first shot,
about five or six guys.
Tonight we're going to a party,
and if all goes well,
we'll be working pretty
fast, and we'll
get quite a bit done.
Obviously, people are hearing a
lot about Mexico these days
for violence and drugs.
I've been coming here fairly
often, and I've never really
had bad experiences so far.
But you can tell that there's
some tension here.
We knew of some concerts, and we
were going to try to shoot
in these clubs, but when we
asked for permission, the
owner said no, because a lot
of gangsters or narcos hang
out in these places.
They said it's quite
dangerous for us.
That at least we'd get beat
up, if not worse.
And they also said that the kids
probably stay away from
there more now.
So we went out to the suburbs.
We went to a club called
Lone Star.
And basically, that had tons
of these kids there.
They are quite young.
They seem to be all
mostly teenagers.
And basically, they dance
around in circles.
It all seems pretty
mellow, actually.
PATRICK: The way Stefan shoots
is we always do kind of a
portable photo studio.
We try to find a
wall, usually.
But this one has too
much texture to it.
So we want to keep it simple.
STEFAN RUIZ: I've shot a lot of
times outside clubs, or all
over the place.
I'm quite used to doing this.
I like doing it.
I'll often let the person
pose themselves.
I'll compose it the way I like,
but I often want them to
present themselves.
Whether it is a refugee, or
someone who's insane, or some
politician.
When I was, I think, 16, my
parents got divorced.
And my dad was a lawyer.
My mom was an art teacher.
She wanted to go to Italy,
because her family was from
Italy, and she wanted
to go there.
And we went and lived
in Florence.
At that point, I totally
didn't like Renaissance
painting or anything.
I finally got into a school,
like a high school.
An art high school.
And so I had to copy all
these famous paintings.
I had to copy famous
sculptures.
And by the end of year, I
actually started getting quite
into Renaissance art.
I especially like the older
portraits and stuff.
And I like Flemish painting
a lot, too.
I would say that's a huge
influence in my portraiture.
So we got quite a few
people that night.
Maybe 20?
I don't know.
We stayed there until about
3:00 in the morning.
Yesterday, we photographed
downtown.
There's a 7-Eleven that's
below a radio station.
All of the Cholombianos,
they hang out there.
We went there.
We just picked some of
the guys, asked them.
And if they're into it, then
we set up a little studio
around the block.
And yeah.
I think we got a lot
of good things.
At the end of the day, I think
that work should work on a lot
of different levels.
It should be interesting
to look at.
It should be technically
well-done.
The subject itself, hopefully
it's got a political thing.
Maybe the photo makes you
think about something.
Maybe it's not just eye candy.
It's not just a one
idea thing.
All right.
I think we're done.
I think I'm going to be really
happy with this shoot.
I think these guys are
pretty genius.
And just by taking time to
document their style, I think
I'll be really happy with it.