which sounds kind of normal.
Except that in this
series, all we ever
see are previews for
the upcoming episode.
Each episode begins with
a calm, collected scene,
and then it quickly escalates
into absurd hilarity.
And the show is produced
by Ben Stiller's company.
NARRATOR: Next time,
on an all-new "Lonny."
CHET: Holy [BLEEP], Lonny!
What happened?
LONNY: I think she's dead.
CHET: What did you do, Lonny?
What did you do?
LONNY: I don't
know, some [BLEEP].
CHET: This is really bad!
LONNY: What are we going to do?
CHET: We have to bury the body.
NINA TERRERO: Season two
begins in just a couple weeks,
so make sure to head
over to Nacho Punch
to catch up on
all of season one.
Felicia Day's channel Geek
& Sundry has been releasing
a ton of super
cool stuff lately.
This new series follows a
team of superhero roommates
who turn to crime after falling
on some pretty hard times.
It's got some big name
actors like Harry Shum, Jr.
from "Glee" and Abby
Miller from "Justified."
PENNY BLUE: I just--
actually, I just
walked out of a job interview,
so-- [EXPLOSION] Dad,
I've got to go.
NINA TERRERO: The show
looks great, so make sure
you check it out
every Wednesday.
The ladies of "#hotmessmoves"
are on a mission to celebrate
the super spazzy, ridiculous
lives of the average
20-something, from
overly dramatic picnics--
LYLE: You are beautiful,
and you are a great friend.
And I just sometimes have
to tell you how I feel
and get it off my chest, and I
just think I should be allowed.
NINA TERRERO: --to lying about
your emotional dysfunction.
ASHLEY: Where are
you going, girl?
LYLE: Nowhere.
ASHLEY: What, are you
going to go to the gym?
LYLE: No.
ASHLEY: Are you going on a date?
ASHLEY: You going to
go visit your mom?
LYLE: No.
NINA TERRERO: They've only
been around for five months,
but they've already developed
a huge cult following.
The best part?
You can watch two new
episodes every single week.
What web series are
you loving these days?
Let us know with the
hashtag #youtubenation.
Hope you love these.
And if you're craving even
more, check out our playlist
with other web series that
you might have missed.
CHET: You know what the dog
said to me the other day, Lonny?
LONNY: No, no, I don't--
CHET: He said it'd sure
be swell if Carolyn died,
because then I could
be your new girlfriend.
Hey, Lonny, can I
be your girlfriend?
LONNY: Oh my god.
CHET: Lonny!
Lonny, where are you--
[DOG BARKING] What's that?
DOG: You should kill him, Chet.
CHET: Sure thing, dog moon.