Hey, it's Tyler.
I'm here to tell you about my
crazy fucking story, about a
party, story.
I was with my friend [BLEEP].
We're at this fucking
party at this dude's
house in Malibu, right?
We found this party
on Facebook and
we just went there.
I didn't know the nigger, and
it was like a couple blocks
down from the beach.
Big ass mansion-- this
is Malibu, them white
motherfuckers are rich.
It was people everywhere
passed the fuck out.
It was shit on a white couch,
like actually doo-doo.
It was like drinks everywhere,
bitches passed out, panties,
nigger's crying and throwing
up and shit.
They was actually watching
a pit bull video.
We're in there, we
walk in and shit.
We're like oh man, this is kind
of cool and shit, people
are fucking drunk
and shit, right?
He's like, oh dude,
go upstairs to
the balcony and shit.
We go to the fucking
balcony, right?
There's fucking people
throwing up on
there, bugging out.
These dudes start fucking
fighting.
One of the dudes was short,
black and fat.
And the other one was this
skinny white dude, not that
tall but fucking out of
his fucking mind.
I think they were high off
speed or some shit.
The fat, black, short, musty
motherfucker says, yo, if you
don't back the fuck up I'ma
go fucking get a machete.
This dude runs downstairs,
come back with a fucking
machete and tries to
stab at the white
motherfucker, who is so drunk.
The white motherfucker falls
off of the roof onto this
balcony that's in the parent's
bedroom thing.
Falls on there, drunk as fuck,
doesn't feel nothin'.
Runs in the house, the other guy
tries to run in the house
to catch him.
We go in that motherfucker,
everybody's running after the
dude with the machete and shit
to see if he stabs this
motherfucker, right?
The fat, black, musty
motherfucker catches him and
has him in a fucking headlock
saying, I'm going to cut your
fucking head off.
Next thing you know, there's
fucking cops in that
motherfucker everywhere.
A lot of motherfuckers
are in handcuffs.
Luckily me and my
friend [BLEEP]
sneak the fuck out,
but [BLEEP]
are still in there.
Their phone is dead, so they
have to run up the fucking
block in order to find us.
Come to find out, [BLEEP]
stole the fucking laptop.
Bow.
Went to the pawnshop and cashed
that motherfucker.
Bought Fat Burger nigger.
[MUSIC PLAYING]