DISTINGUISHED THE TWO MAJOR GROUPS OF ANGIOSPERMS,
THE EUDICOTS
AND THE MONOCOTS. AND THIS IS IMPORTANT BECAUSE
IN TALKING
ABOUT SEED GERMINATION AFTERWARDS THERE ARE
SOME MAJOR
DIFFERENCES THERE. AND ALSO WITH REGARD TO
THE STRUCTURE AND
GROWTH OF, OF ANGIOSPERMS, THE EUDICOTS AND
THE MONOCOTS DIFFER
PRETTY DRAMATICALLY IN REALLY INTERESTING
WAYS. SO THIS ISN'T
JUST A COMPLETELY ESOTERIC DISCUSSION ABOUT
THE, DISTINCTION
BETWEEN THESE TWO MAJOR GROUPS OF FLOWERING
PLANTS. AND SO
TODAY WE'RE GOING TO MOVE FROM TALKING ABOUT
DIVERSITY IN GENERAL
AND START TALKING ABOUT THE STRUCTURE AND
FUNCTION OF PLANTS AND
REALLY THE ELEGANT ANATOMY AND MORPHOLOGY
OF PLANTS AND THE WAY,
WAYS IN WHICH THEY GROW WHICH ARE PRETTY STEREO-,
PRETTY
CONSERVED ACROSS THE GROUPS OF FLOWERING PLANTS
AS WELL AS IN
OTHER CASES, OTHER, OTHER VASCULAR PLANTS.
AND IT'S, IT FOLLOWS
SOME BASIC RULES WHICH ARE REALLY ELEGANT
AND, AND FAIRLY EASY TO
UNDERSTAND ALTHOUGH YOU HAVE TO KEEP SORT
OF A 3-DIMENSIONAL
PERSPECTIVE AS WE GO THROUGH THIS. OKAY, SO
LAST TIME I WENT
THROUGH THESE FEW CHARACTERS HERE THAT DISTINGUISH
MONOCOTS ON
THE LEFT FROM THE EUDICOTS ON THE RIGHT. THE
SINGLE COTYLEDON,
OF COURSE THE BASIS OF THE NAME HERE, IN MONOCOTS
WHICH IS THE
DERIVED FEATURE, THIS SINGLE EMBRYONIC LEAF,
AND I'LL TALK MORE
ABOUT THIS IN A MINUTE. AND THEN TWO COTYLEDONS
OR TWO
EMBRYONIC LEAVES IN EUDICOTS WHICH IS ANCESTRAL
IN FLOWERING
PLANTS, THE MONOCOT CONDITION BEING DERIVED.
AS FAR AS LEAF
VENATION GOES, THE LEAVES ARE, HAVE THEIR
VEINS ORIENTED IN THIS
PARALLEL PATTERN TYPICALLY AND MONOCOTS, WHICH
IS A DERIVED
FEATURE, YOU KNOW, VERSUS THE EUDICOTS WE
HAVE MORE OF A NET-LIKE
OPENLY BRANCHING SORT OF VENATION PATTERN
WHICH IS SOMETHING
ANCESTRAL IN ANGIOSPERMS. AND WE'RE GOING
TO GET INTO THE STEM
ANATOMY A LOT MORE, BUT I'LL JUST MENTION
AGAIN THE VASCULAR
TISSUE OF THE CONDUCTING TISSUE THAT TRANSPORTS
WATER AND SUGARS
THROUGH THE PLANT AND THE ANGIOSPERMS AND
IN GENERAL THE XYLEM
AND PHLOEM, WHICH WE'RE GOING TO TALK ABOUT,
IS IN THESE LITTLE
BUNDLES THAT RUN THROUGH THE STEMS, BUT IN
MONOCOTS THE BUNDLES
ARE SCATTERED THROUGH THE STEM. THIS IS A
CROSS-SECTION. YOU
CAN SEE HOW THE BUNDLES RUN DOWN THE STEM
HERE. AND EUDICOTS
THOUGH, THE VASCULAR BUNDLES ARE ARRANGED
IN A RING. AND THIS
IS REALLY IMPORTANT WHEN WE GET TO TALKING
ABOUT HOW WOOD AND
BARK ARE FORMED IN PLANTS THAT, IN WOODY PLANTS
THAT UNDERGO
SECONDARY GROWTH. BUT MORE ON THAT IN A MINUTE.
THE LAST
FEATURES HERE THAT WE DIDN'T HAVE A CHANCE
TO GET THROUGH
ENTIRELY, MONOCOTS HAVE A FIBROUS ROOT SYSTEM
TYPICALLY, AND
THAT'S BECAUSE THEIR TAPROOT, WHICH IS THE
ROOT THAT FORMS FROM
THE EMBRYONIC ROOT, I MEAN THE SOLE ROOT IN
THE EMBRYO, IT
DOESN'T PERSIST. IT GROWS FOR AWHILE, AND
THEN IT'S REPLACED BY
ADVENTITIOUS ROOTS. AND THESE ARE JUST ROOTS
THAT ARE FORMED
FROM A, FROM THE BASE OF THE STEM. ANYTHING
THAT'S ADVENTITIOUS
IN PLANTS IS BASICALLY A STRUCTURE THAT'S
FORMED FROM SOMEPLACE
OTHER THAN ITS NORMAL ORIGIN. SO ROOTS DON'T
NORMALLY FORM FROM
THE SIDES OF STEMS, BUT THAT'S WHAT HAPPENS
IN MONOCOTS. AND YOU
END UP WITH A, A PRETTY DIFFUSE ROOT SYSTEM
LIKE YOU GET IN
GRASSES, OFTEN PRETTY SHALLOW. WHEREAS IN
EUDICOTS LIKE IN OTHER
SEED PLANTS, YOU GET A TAPROOT THAT IS THE
EMBRYONIC ROOT THAT
PERSISTS THROUGH THE LIFE OF THE PLANT, AND
IT'S THE DOMINANT
ROOT FROM WHICH LATERAL ROOTS ARE FORMED.
AND THESE CAN HAVE
VERY DEEP ROOT SYSTEMS. POLLEN DIFFERS FUNDAMENTALLY
BETWEEN
MONOCOTS AND EUDICOTS. IN THE MONOCOTS WE
HAVE THE ANCESTRAL
CONDITION OF JUST ONE OPENING IN THE POLLEN
GRAIN THAT ALLOWS THE
POLLEN TUBE TO EMERGE. AND THAT'S WHAT WE
ALSO SEE IN THE
GYMNOSPERMS. BUT IN THE EUDICOTS WE HAVE THREE
OPENINGS WHICH
IS A DERIVED CONDITION. THEY CAN EITHER BE
SLITS OR PORES.
BUT, AND SOMETIMES YOU'LL GET POLLEN THAT
HAS ADDITIONAL OPENINGS
TOO IN THE EUDICOTS, BUT AT LEAST THREE. AND
THAT HELPS TO
RECOGNIZE EUDICOTS IN THE FOSSIL RECORD BECAUSE
NO OTHER PLANT
PRODUCES POLLEN LIKE THAT EXCEPT THE EUDICOTS.
AND THEN IN
TERMS OF JUST THE FLOWER ORGANIZATION, IN
MONOCOTS THE FLOWER
PARTS ARE USUALLY IN MULTIPLES OF THREE. AND
THAT ACTUALLY IS
WHAT WE ALSO SEE IN SOME OF THE MAGNOLIIDS
AND SOME OF THESE
EARLY DIVERGING LINEAGES OF FLOWERING PLANTS
THAT ARE OUTSIDE OF
BOTH OF THESE GROUPS. SO THIS IS THE ANCESTRAL
CONDITION IN
FLOWERING PLANTS OR CLOSE TO IT. WHEREAS IN
THE EUDICOTS THE
FLOWER PARTS, LIKE THE PETALS AND THE SEPALS,
STAMENS, CARPELS,
THEY'RE IN MULTIPLES OF FOUR OR FIVE. SO YOU
TYPICALLY HAVE FOUR
OR FIVE PETALS, FOUR OR FIVE SEPALS. THAT'S
SOMETHING YOU DON'T
SEE TYPICALLY OUTSIDE THE EUDICOTS. SO THERE
ARE A LOT OF WAYS
YOU CAN TELL THESE GROUPS APART THAT ARE PRETTY
RELIABLE.
THOUGH THE QUESTION OF WHY ANGIOSPERM DIVERSITY
IS SO HIGH,
THEY'RE FAR OUTSTRIPPING THAT OF ALL THE OTHER
SEED PLANTS AND
REALLY THE LAND PLANTS TAKEN TOGETHER IS SORT
OF AN OPEN
QUESTION. WE JUST REVIEWED ALL THESE DIFFERENT
FEATURES THAT
DIFFERENTIATE ANGIOSPERMS FROM OTHER SEED
PLANTS, THEIR REDUCED
GAMETOPHYTES, THE DOUBLE FERTILIZATION, THE
FLOWER WITH ITS
OVARY, THE FRUIT, THERE'S A BUNCH OF FEATURES
THERE THAT
DISTINGUISH THEM. BUT ONE INTRIGUING POSSIBILITY
THAT MIGHT
EXPLAIN A LOT OF THE DIVERSITY IS THE FACT
THAT THEY'VE UNDERGONE
SO MUCH CO-EVOLUTIONARY CHANGE WITH OTHER
ORGANISMS IN REGARDS TO
POLLINATION AND DISPERSAL THAT WE TALKED ABOUT
AS WELL AS WITH
HERBIVORES THAT HAS LEAD TO REALLY RICH SECONDARY
CHEMISTRY.
THERE'S A LOT OF, THERE'S SOME EVIDENCE NOW
FROM LOOKING AT
GROUPS, THERE'S SO MANY GROUPS OF ANGIOSPERMS
THAT YOU CAN DO
INTERESTING COMPARISONS ACROSS TRAITS, AND
SOME OF THE FLORAL
SPECIALIZATION THAT I MENTIONED LAST TIME,
FOR EXAMPLE, BILATERAL
SYMMETRY OF FLOWERS, TRAITS LIKE THAT SEEM
TO BE ASSOCIATED WITH
DIVERSIFICATION, SO IT REALLY DOES APPEAR
THAT TO SOME EXTENT THE
COEVOLUTION OF FLOWERING PLANTS WITH ANIMALS
AND OTHER ORGANISMS
HAS IN PART LEAD TO THIS INCREASED SPECIALIZATION
AND INCREASED
DIVERSIFICATION. AND IN FACT, OF COURSE, THERE'S
SO MANY
FLOWERING PLANTS THAT WE DON'T REALLY KNOW
HOW MANY THERE ARE.
THEY'RE BEING DISCOVERED AND DESCRIBED FASTER
OR AT A SLOWER PACE
UNFORTUNATELY THAN THEY'RE GOING EXTINCT.
THEY'RE STILL BEING
DISCOVERED AT A VERY FAST PACE BUT, ESPECIALLY
DOWN IN THE
TROPICS, THE RATE OF DEFORESTATION AND LOSS
OF FLOWERING PLANT
DIVERSITY IS SO HIGH THAT THERE'S A REAL RACE
AGAINST TIME FOR
BOTANISTS TO TRY TO DESCRIBE AND, WILL DISCOVER
AND DESCRIBE AND
TRY TO PROTECT SOME OF THIS DIVERSITY AND
CHARACTERIZE IT IN
TERMS OF ITS ECOLOGICAL IMPORTANCE AND ITS
ECONOMIC, POTENTIAL
ECONOMIC IMPORTANCE BECAUSE MUCH OF OUR, MOST
OF OUR FOOD, OUR
MEDI-, A LOT OF OUR MEDICINES, OUR WOOD PRODUCTS,
AND IN SOME
CULTURES OUR, THEIR FUEL IS REALLY CRUCIALLY
DEPENDENT ON
ANGIOSPERM DIVERSITY. AND SO THIS IS SOMETHING
THAT WE REALLY
HAVE TO TAKE SERIOUSLY AND TRY TO INVEST MORE
IN.
AND ACTUALLY
SOME OF THE SAME CHALLENGES ACTUALLY EXIST
IN THE TEMPERATE PARTS
OF THE WORLD TOO, LIKE HERE IN CALIFORNIA
WHERE THE HERBARIA THAT
I CARRY DOWNSTAIRS, WE'RE DISCOVERING AND
DESCRIBING NEW PLANT
SPECIES ENDEMIC TO CALIFORNIA ALL THE TIME.
AND SOME OF THE
THESE ARE FOUND IN PROXIMITY TO HIGHWAYS,
THINGS THAT HAVE NEVER
BEEN COLLECTED BEFORE. THIS IS A BIODIVERSITY
HOT SPOT RIGHT
HERE THAT'S IN GRAVE JEOPARDY IN TERMS OF
THE RATE AT WHICH IT'S
BEING ALTERED. AND WITH CLIMATE CHANGE AND
ALL, WE'VE GOT OUR
WORK CUT OUT FOR US, EVEN IN THE NEARBY VICINITY
HERE. OKAY, SO
SEED MORPHOLOGY IS SOMETHING THAT I WANT TO
INTRODUCE NOW BECAUSE
WE'RE GOING TO GET INTO THE GROWTH AND DEVELOPMENT
OF PLANTS AND,
OF COURSE, AS FAR AS THE SPOROPHYTE GOES,
THIS IS WHERE IT
STARTS. AND THIS SEGUES RIGHT FROM WHAT WE'RE
TALKING ABOUT
WITH THE DEVELOPMENT OF THE SEED. AND SOME
OF THE DISTINCTIONS
BETWEEN EUDICOTS AND MONOCOTS ARE SEEN AT
THIS, IN REGARDS TO
SEED GERMINATION. SO GETTING BACK TO THE ANGIOSPERM
LIFE CYCLE,
THE END, THE END OF IT HERE WITH REGARD TO
THE FORMATION OF THE
SEED, REMEMBER THAT THE ENDOSPERM IS THE NUTRITIVE
TISSUE FORMED
FROM THE FUSION OF ONE OF THE SPERM WITH THE
POLAR NUCLEI OF THE
CENTRAL CELL OF THE FEMALE GAMETOPHYTE. AND
THE IMPORTANT THING
AS I MENTIONED IS THAT THE ANGIOSPERMS WAIT
TO INVEST IN THAT
NUTRITIVE TISSUE FOR THE EMBRYO UNTIL AFTER
FERTILIZATION IS
ASSURED RATHER THAN IN THE GYMNOSPERMS WHERE
THEY MAKE THE
INVESTMENT BEFORE FERTILIZATION WHICH CAN
POTENTIALLY RESULT IN
WASTAGE OF RESOURCES. AND ACTUALLY THE ENDOSPERM
BEGINS TO
DEVELOP REALLY BEFORE WE HAVE THE EMBRYO START
TO DEVELOP FROM
THE ZYGOTE. SO THE ENDOSPERM GETS A HEAD START
DEVELOPMENTALLY
EVEN THOUGH THE FERTILIZATION AND, THE DOUBLE
FERTILIZATION
EVENTS OCCUR MORE OR LESS SIMULTANEOUSLY.
AND WE EVENTUALLY GET
THIS EMBRYO FORMING THAT HAS THESE EMBRYONIC
LEAVES, THE
COTYLEDONS, AS WELL AS AN EMBRYONIC SHOOT
TIP AND AN EMBRYONIC
ROOT. SO THE, THE TWO MAJOR EMBRYONIC REGIONS
OF THE FLOWERING
PLANT, THE SHOOT APEX AND THE ROOT APEX, ARE
ALREADY PRESENT IN
THE, IN THE EMBRYO AT THAT STAGE. AND SO THE
PLANT HAS REALLY
EVERYTHING IT NEEDS FOR DEVELOPMENT AS WE'LL
SEE SHORTLY. AND
AS THE SEED REACHES MATURITY, IT UNDERGOES
MASSIVE DEHYDRATION
DOWN TO 5 TO 15 PERCENT WATER BY WEIGHT. AND
AS THAT HAPPENS,
IT ENTERS WHAT'S CALLED DORMANCY WHICH IS
A SITUATION WHERE THE
METABOLISM OF THE SEED ALMOST CEASES, SO IT'S
ALMOST INDETECTIBLE
THE AMOUNT OF METABOLISM GOING ON HERE. AND,
OF COURSE, THIS IS
A FEATURE THAT ALLOWS SEED PLANTS TO POTENTIALLY
PERSIST IN A
SEED BANK FOR DECADES, MAYBE HUNDREDS OF YEARS.
SOME OF OUR
FIRE FOLLOWERS HERE IN CALIFORNIA THAT ONLY
GERMINATE AFTER FIRES
HAVE GONE WELL OVER A HUNDRED YEARS BETWEEN
FIRES, BETWEEN
GERMINATION EVENTS, SO SEEDS HAVE A GREAT
WAY OF BEING ABLE TO
PERSIST, KEEP A ANGIOSPERM BASICALLY ALIVE
DURING PERIODS THAT
ARE NOT VERY CONDUCIVE TO, TO SURVIVAL. OKAY,
SO HERE'S A MAJOR
DISTINCTION BETWEEN THE SEEDS OF, OF SOME
EUDICOTS AT LEAST AND
SOME MONOCOTS. THESE ARE SORT OF EXTREMES
THAT DEMONSTRATE SOME
OF THE VARIATION WE SEE IN THE SEED. AND SOME
EUDICOTS, THE
EXAMPLE HERE BEING A BEAN, THE ENDOSPERM DOESN'T
PERSIST. THE
EMBRYO ABSORBS THE ENDOSPERM AND STORES THE
NUTRIENTS OF THE
ENDOSPERM INSIDE THE COTYLEDONS, THOSE EMBRYONIC
LEAVES. SO
WHEN YOU EAT A BEAN OR PEA, THE BULK OF THE
TISSUE THERE THAT
YOU'RE EATING ARE THE TWO COTYLEDONS. AND
IF YOU CAREFULLY PULL
THESE APART IN THE RIGHT ORIENTATION, YOU
CAN SEE THE TWO
COTYLEDONS HERE, THE TWO HALVES OF THE BEAN.
AND THEY'RE
ATTACHED TO A, A LITTLE MINIATURE PLANT ACCESS
HERE WHICH IS
ABOVE THE POINT OF ATTACHMENT OF THE COTYLEDONS
IS THE SHOOT
APEX, WHAT WE CALL THE EPICOTYL IN THE SEED
WHICH IS BASICALLY
JUST MEANS OVER THE COTYLEDONS, THE PART ABOVE
THE POINT OF
ATTACHMENT OF THE COTYLEDONS WHERE WE HAVE,
HERE YOU CAN SEE THE
FIRST TWO FOLIAGE LEAVES, NOT THE EMBRYONIC
LEAVES BUT THE TWO
FIRST FOLIAGE LEAVES WHICH IN A BEAN ARE ALREADY
FORMED IN THE
SEED. BUT IN SOME EUDICOTS THEY ONLY FORM
DURING GERMINATION.
AND THEN BELOW THE POINT OF ATTACHMENT OF
THE COTYLEDONS WE HAVE
WHAT'S CALLED A HYPOCOTYL WHICH IS JUST, MEANS
BELOW THE
COTYLEDONS, THE HEART OF THE, OF THE STEM,
THE EMBRYONIC STEM
THAT'S BELOW THAT POINT. AND THEN THE RADICLE
IS JUST THE
EMBRYONIC ROOT, THE EMBRYONIC TAPROOT WHICH
ATTACHES TO THE
HYPOCOTYL. AND YOU CAN'T SEE IT VERY WELL
THERE, BUT WE HAVE A
LITTLE MINIATURE PLANT ACCESS HERE WITH THESE
GARGANTUAN
COTYLEDONS ATTACHED TO IT. OKAY, SO IN THE
MONOCOTS LIKE THE
GRASSES, AND THIS INCLUDES ALL THEIR GRAINS
LIKE WHEAT AND RYE,
RICE, BUT THIS EXAMPLE IS CORN. THIS IS A
CORN KERNEL HERE, A
CORN FRUIT. THE GRASSES RETAIN MOST OF THE
ENDOSPERM INSIDE THE
SEED UNTIL GERMINATION. AND THEN THEY ABSORB
THE ENDOSPERM
THROUGH THE COTYLEDON WHICH IS THE SHIELD-LIKE
STRUCTURE RIGHT
HERE. SO THE COTYLEDON ARE JUST ONE OF THEM
IN MONOCOTS
REMEMBER. IT'S BASICALLY, IT BASICALLY IS
A SHIELD-SHAPED OBJECT
THAT ABSORBS THE ENDOSPERM MAKING IT AVAILABLE
TO THE REST OF
EMBRYO WHICH IS ON THE OTHER SIDE OF THE COTYLEDON
RIGHT HERE.
AND SO WITH THIS PARTITIONING OF THE ENDOSPERM
FROM THE EMBRYO,
IT'S EASY TO MILL GRAIN AND REMOVE THE ENDOSPERM
FROM THE REST OF
THE, THE GRASS FRUIT. AND THIS ISN'T JUST
THE SEED ACTUALLY.
THIS IS THE ENTIRE FRUIT OF THE GRASS BECAUSE
THE, THE FRUIT WALL
IS FUSED TO THE, THE SEED HERE. SO THIS YELLOW
PART, THIS THICK
PART HERE IS THE ACTUAL, ACTUALLY THE FRUIT
WALL, THE OVARY WALL
IN A GRAIN. AND THAT'S WHAT WE CALL COMMERCIALLY
THE BRAN.
YOU'VE HEARD OF THE BRAN, THE ROUGHAGE OR
FIBER CONTENT OF WHOLE
GRAIN. THAT'S MILLED AWAY FROM THE ENDOSPERM.
AND SO IS THE
EMBRYO WHICH IS REFERRED TO AS THE GERM, THE
GERM IN OUR
COMMERCIAL TERMS. SO REFINED GRAIN IS JUST
ENDOSPERMS,
SOMETHING LIKE WHITE RICE OR WHITE WHEAT FLOWER
IS JUST
ENDOSPERM. ENDOSPERM IS ALSO THE WHITE FLUFFY
SUBSTANCE OF
POPCORN. AND SO THE ENDOSPERM IS RELATIVELY
LACKING IN
NUTRITION COMPARED TO THE EMBRYO WHERE THERE'S
A LOT MORE
INVESTMENT OF RESOURCES. AND SO THAT'S IN
PART WHY IN ADDITION
TO THE ROUGHAGE PROVIDED BY THE BRAN OR THE
FRUIT WALL THAT WHOLE
GRAIN IS MORE HEALTHY THAN REFINED GRAIN.
IN ANY CASE THAT'S
THE GENERAL LAYOUT THERE IN TERMS OF A EUDICOT
AND A, AND A
MONOCOT SEED. SO SEED PLANTS HAVE A NUMBER
OF INNOVATIONS THAT
PROMOTE OPTIMAL TIMING FOR GERMINATION. AND
THIS IS REALLY
IMPORTANT BECAUSE THE ESTABLISHMENT OF A SEEDLING
AT THE SEED
STAGE WHEN IT'S UNDERGOING GERMINATION, THAT'S
THE PERIOD OF
HIGHEST MORTALITY. THAT'S THE MOST VULNERABLE
STAGE IN THE LIFE
OF A PLANT. SO IF YOU LOOK AT A MORTALITY
CURVE FOR PLANTS, THE
MORTALITY PEAK IS RIGHT DURING THE ESTABLISHMENT
OF THE SEEDLING
WHEN IT HAS TO GET A ROOT SYSTEM DOWN TO CON-,
IN CONTACT WITH
MOISTURE SO IT CAN DRAW WATER UP INTO THE
PLANT WHICH IS EXPOSED
TO THE AT-, MOST OF THE PLANT, THE UPPER,
THE SHOOT SYSTEM'S
EXPOSED TO THE ATMOSPHERE. WE ALSO HAVE TO
GET THE PLANT UP
INTO THE LIGHT SO, THE SHOOT UP INTO THE LIGHT
SO IT CAN ACTUALLY
START PRODUCING FOOD FROM LIGHT AND CARBON
DIOXIDE. SO IT'S
THAT PERIOD OF TIME THAT PLANTS ARE IN REALLY
MAJOR JEOPARDY TO
GET ESTABLISHED IN THIS LAND ENVIRONMENT.
AND SO THE TIMING,
THE CUES THAT STIMULATE GERMINATION VARY WIDELY
ACROSS PLANTS,
EVEN REALLY CLOSELY RELATED WILD PLANTS CAN
HAVE REALLY DIFFERENT
CUES FOR GERMINATION, AND THEY'RE OFTEN COMPLEX.
BUT THEY CAN
INVOLVE THINGS LIKE LIGHT AND, SOME SMALL
SEEDED PLANTS MIGHT
NEED LIGHT TO GERMINATE. THAT MAKES SENSE
BECAUSE THEY NEED TO
BE CLOSE TO THE SURFACE IN ORDER TO SUCCESSFULLY
GERMINATE.
THEY MIGHT NEED A COLD PERIOD THAT SIMULATES
WINTER SO THAT THEY
DON'T ACCIDENTALLY GERMINATE TOO SOON AND
ARE KILLED BY FROST, OR
BY, POTENTIALLY BY FROST OR IN SOME PARTS
OF THE WORLD
INSUFFICIENT LIGHT TO BE SUCCESSFUL. AND THEY
MIGHT NEED
CHEMICAL CUES LIKE ARE REQUIRED FROM PASSING
THROUGH THE GUT OF
AN ANIMAL OR FROM SMOKE OR CHARCOAL IN THE
CASE OF FIRE
FOLLOWERS. AND THERE MIGHT BE COMBINATIONS
OF THOSE CUES THAT
ARE NECESSARY IN ADDITION TO THE PRESENCE
OF ABUNDANT MOISTURE.
SO MOISTURE ALONE DOESN'T NECESSARILY RESULT
IN GERMINATION.
OUR CROP PLANTS HAVE BEEN SELECTED TO GERMINATE
READILY, AND SO
THEY'RE NOT A VERY GOOD GAUGE OF HOW DIVERSE
PLANTS ARE IN TERMS
OF THEIR, THEIR ADAPTATIONS TO DIFFERENT KINDS
OF CUES FOR
GERMINATION. SO IN THE PROCESS OF GERMINATION
WHAT BASICALLY
HAPPENS IS THAT THE SEED STARTS AFTER ITS,
AFTER ITS BEEN
STIMULATED TO GERMINATE WHICH CAN BE A HORMONAL
RESPONSE, WE HAVE
WATER STARTS TO BE ABSORBED BY THE SEED. IT
STARTS TO RESUME
METABOLIC ACTIVITY. AND AS IT WELLS, IT RUPTURES
THE SEED COAT
AND THEN WE GET THE EMERGENCE OF THE SEEDLING.
AND THIS HAPPENS
IN TWO VERY DIFFERENT WAYS IN THE EUDICOTS
AND THE MONOCOTS THAT
I JUST MENTIONED. SO IN THE EUDICOTS LIKE
THE BEANS WHAT WE SEE
IS FIRST OF ALL THE, IN BOTH THE EUDICOTS
AND THE MONOCOTS WE
HAVE THE EMERGENCE OF THE, THE ROOT. SO THE
ROOTS EMERGE FIRST.
AND THEY HAVE POSITIVE GEOTROPISM WHICH MEANS
THAT BASICALLY THEY
GROW WITH GRAVITY, AND THIS IS A HORMONALLY-INDUCED
RESPONSE THAT
RESULTS IN THE ROOT GROWING DOWN INTO THE
SOIL. THE TAPROOT
GROWS QUICKLY IN BOTH THE MONOCOTS AND THE
EUDICOTS. THEY START
PRODUCING ROOT HAIRS WHICH INCREASE THE SURFACE
AREA OF THE ROOT.
AND YOU'LL SEE THAT IN THE VIDEO IN A SECOND.
BUT THESE ROOT
HAIRS ARE JUST EPIDERMAL OUTGROWTHS THAT INCREASE
THE SURFACE
AREA FROM WHICH THEY CAN ABSORB WATER AND
NU-, AND MINERALS.
AND IN THE CASE OF THE MONOCOTS AS I MENTIONED,
THE TAPROOT
DOESN'T SURVIVE VERY LONG. WE START GETTING
THESE ADVENTITIOUS
ROOTS FORMING FROM THE BASE OF THE SHOOT THAT,
THAT CREATE THE
FIBROUS ROOT SYSTEM. SO AFTER THE ROOT SYSTEM
IS ACTUALLY
PRETTY WELL-ESTABLISHED, ONLY THEN DOES THE
SHOOT START TO EMERGE
FROM THE SEED OR START TO EMERGE FROM THE
GROUND I SHOULD SAY.
AND THE FIRST THING THAT WE SEE HAPPENING
IN THE EUDICOTS THAT
ARE SIMILAR TO THE BEAN HERE IS THAT THE HYPOCOTYL,
THAT REGION
BELOW THE ATTACHMENT OF THE COTYLEDONS, THE
LOWER PART OF
EMBRYONIC STEM, IT STARTS TO GROW UP WITH
NEGATIVE GEOTROPISM
GROWING AGAINST GRAVITY. AND AS IT EMERGES,
IT FORMS THIS
GERMINATION HOOK THAT YOU CAN SEE THAT. AND
SO BY DOING THAT,
BY HAVING A HYPOCOTYL RATHER THAN THE OTHER
PARTS OF THE SHOOT
RESPOND TO, TO BE THE LEADING EDGE OF THE
GROWTH, THIS HOLDS THE
COTYLEDONS AND THE PROTECTED SHOOT APEX THROUGH
THE SOIL. SHOOT
APEX IS SHIELDED BETWEEN THESE COTYLEDONS,
AND SO WE DON'T HAVE
THE ABRASION POTENTIALLY DAMAGING THE COTYLEDONS
WHICH ARE GOING
TO BE THE IMPORTANT FOR INITIAL PHOTOSYNTHESIS
FOOD PRODUCTION.
AND THE SHOOT APEX WHICH IS AS I'LL POINT
OUT IS THE CRITICAL
THING TO PROTECT BECAUSE THAT'S WHERE YOUR
EMBRYONIC TISSUE IS
THAT'S GOING TO RESULT IN THE FURTHER GROWTH
OF THE STEM. SO
YOU PULL THE COTYLEDONS AND THE SHOOT APEX
UP THIS WAY. AFTER
FULL EMERGENCE, THE WHOLE THING STRAIGHTENS
OUT. AND WE GET THE
GREENING UP OF THE COTYLEDONS, THE, THE EXPANSION
OF THE FIRST
FOLIAGE LEAVES AND ELONGATION OF THE STEM
THAT WE'LL TALK ABOUT
IN A MINUTE. OKAY, NOW CONTRAST THIS WITH
WHAT GOES ON IN THE
MONOCOTS WHERE YOU HAVE, WE ALREADY TALKED
ABOUT THE ROOT SYSTEM
GETTING ESTABLISHED. BUT HERE THERE'S A, A
SHEATH CALLED THE
COLEOPTILE THAT DOESN'T HAVE A HOMOLOGUE IN
THE EUDICOTS. IT'S
BASICALLY A SHEATH, A HOLLOW SHEATH THAT SURROUNDS
THE SHOOT APEX
OR THE, SHOOT APEX OF THE, OF THE, OF THE
EMBRYO. AND IT GROWS
STRAIGHT UP. THERE'S NO GERMINATION UP HERE.
IT GROWS STRAIGHT
UP, AND AS SOON AS IT EMERGES FROM THE SOIL,
THE SHOOT EMERGES
THROUGH THAT SHEATH. AND SO IT'S BEEN PROTECTED
FROM THE
ABRASION OF THE SOIL FROM EMERGENCE HERE AND
THEN IT UNDERGOES
EXPANSION OF THE LEAVES AND ELONGATION OF
THE SHOOT. SO IN THIS
CASE THE SEED AND ACTUALLY THE WHOLE FRUIT
REMAINS UNDERGROUND
WHEREAS HERE YOU CAN SEE THAT THE SEED EMERGES
FROM THE GROUND
ALTHOUGH THE SEED COAT IS SLOUGHED OFF AS
ITS PULLED THROUGH OR
IN THE COURSE OF THE BREAKING OPEN OF THE
COTYL-, THE SPREADING
OF THE COTYLEDONS, THE SEED COAT IS FURTHER
RUPTURED. WHEREAS
HERE THE SEED AND THE FRUIT REMAIN UNDERGROUND
AS DOES THE, AS
DOES THE COTYLEDON. BUT IT'S A REALLY DIFFERENT
SORT OF
DEVELOPMENT IN THE CASE OF EUDICOTS AND MONOCOTS.
AND SO NOW
WE'RE GOING TO LOOK AT THIS PROCESS IN VIDEO,
AND SO YOU'LL SEE
THESE STEPS. WE'RE GOING TO FIRST LOOK AT
THE, AT A BEAN
EMERGING. SO YOU CAN SEE HERE THE ROOT'S STARTING
TO FORM.
AND THESE ARE THE ROOT HAIRS ON THE TAPROOT.
SO WE HAVE RAPID
GROWTH. AND NOW THAT, THAT HAPPENED QUICKLY
BUT YOU CAN, THE
GERMINATION HOOK AND IT FORMED. THE THING
STRAIGHTENED OUT.
HERE ARE THE COTYLEDONS. YOU CAN SEE THE TWO
COTYLEDONS
EXPANDED. AND NOW THE SHOOT APEX HERE, THE
EPICOTYL WILL START
TO GROW.
OVER HERE WE CAN SEE IT BETTER WHERE WE HAVE
THE FIRST
FOLIAGE LEAVES NOW HAVE EMERGED AND WELL ON
ITS WAY. YOU CAN
SEE HERE THAT THE SEED COAT'S LEFT UNDERGROUND
OR IN SOME CASES
IT'S LEFT CLINGING TO THE, TO THE PLANT. WHEREAS
IN THE
MONOCOT, IN THE CORN, WE ALSO GET THE ROOT
SYSTEM ESTABLISHED
QUICKLY. AND HERE WE HAVE THE COLEOPTILE GOING
STRAIGHT UP.
THERE'S NO GERMINATION HOOK HERE. AND AS SOON
AS IT EMERGES, THE
SHOOT, THE SHOOT COMES OUT OF THE COLEOPTILE,
AND WE GET THE
DEVELOPMENT OF THE SEEDLING HERE. YOU CAN
SEE HERE THE
ADVENTITIOUS ROOTS STARTING TO FORM FROM THE
BASE OF THE STEM.
AND SO THE SEEDS, I DON'T KNOW IF YOU NOTICED
IT BUT THE, THE
CORN'S FRUITS REMAINED UNDERGROUND THERE.
THEY DIDN'T EMERGE.
OKAY, SO THAT'S THE GERMINATION PROCESS. AND
NOW WE'RE GOING TO
START TO LOOK AT, ARE THERE QUESTIONS ABOUT
THIS? YEAH?
STUDENT: [INAUDIBLE].
PROFESSOR: IT DOES HAVE A TAPROOT INITIALLY,
RIGHT. YEAH, IT
DOES. AND IT LIVES FOR AWHILE. IT WAS LIVING
THROUGH THAT
WHOLE PART OF THE VIDEO WE SAW THERE. AND
YOU COULD START TO
SEE THE DEVELOPMENT OF THOSE ADVENTITIOUS
ROOTS, BUT THE TAPROOT
WOULDN'T PERSIST INDEFINITELY, YEAH. GOOD
POINT. YEAH?
STUDENT: [INAUDIBLE]
PROFESSOR: OH, THE COTYLEDON, GOOD QUESTION.
THE COTYLEDONS
DON'T PERSIST FOR VERY LONG. AS SOON AS THE
FIRST FOLIAGE
LEAVES GET ESTABLISHED, THEY CAN HANG ON FOR
QUITE AWHILE, BUT
EVENTUALLY THEY'LL DROP OFF. YEAH, AFTER THE
RESERVES ARE
EXHAUSTED IN THEM. THEY ALSO FUNCTION IN PHOTOSYNTHESIS
YOU
SAW. THEY GREEN UP AS WELL. BUT THEY DON'T
PERSIST TOO LONG.
OKAY, SO WE'RE GOING TO START NOW LOOKING
AT THE, AT THE GROWTH
AND DEVELOPMENT OF THE PLANT BODY. AND BEFORE
WE CAN REALLY DO
THAT WE NEED TO TALK ABOUT CELL AND TISSUE
TYPES IN PLANTS. AND
THERE'S SOME REALLY DISTINCT CELL AND TISSUE
TYPES THAT WE SEE
REPEATED OVER AND OVER AGAIN IN, IN DIFFERENT
PLANT ORGANS.
THOUGH THE FIRST TYPE OF CELL THAT WE'RE GOING
TO TALK ABOUT ARE,
IS PARENCHYMA. AND PARENCHYMA IS A CELL TYPE
THAT'S GOOD TO
START OUT WITH BECAUSE THESE ARE THE MOST
METABOLICALLY ACTIVE
CELLS IN THE PLANT. THESE ARE THE CELLS THAT
UNDERGO
PHOTOSYNTHESIS, RESPONSIBLE FOR STORAGE OF
FOOD, FOR EXAMPLE.
AND THEY HAVE ALSO THE CAPABILITY OF CONTINUING
TO DIVIDE AND
DIFFERENTIATE INTO OTHER CELL TYPES IF THERE'S
WOUNDING OF THE
PLANT. BUT AT MATURITY THEY'RE TYPICALLY NOT
DIVIDING, AND THEY
HAVE VERY THIN WALLS. YOU CAN SEE HERE THE
THIN WALLS OF A
PARENCHYMA CELL THAT ALLOWS THEM SOME FLEXIBILITY.
SO THESE
CELLS CAN BE FULLY MATURE IN PARTS OF THE
PLANT THAT ARE STILL
GROWING. AND THEY'RE FLEXIBLE ENOUGH TO CONFORM
TO THAT.
THOUGH THAT'S A MAJOR CELL TYPE WITHIN THE
PLANT BODY IN GENERAL.
ANOTHER TYPE IS COLLENCHYMA. AND COLLENCHYMA
LIKE PARENCHYMA,
THESE ARE CELLS THAT ARE LIVING AT FUNCTIONAL
MATURITY WHICH MAY
SOUND A LITTLE BIZARRE BECAUSE ISN'T EVERYTHING
LIVING WHEN IT'S
MATURE, BUT ACTUALLY SOME OF THESE CELL TYPES
WE'RE GOING TO BE
TALKING ABOUT RIGHT AWAY ARE NOT LIVING AT
FUNCTIONAL MATURITY,
THAT IS WHEN THEY ACTUALLY ARE FUNCTIONALLY
ACTIVE FOR THE, OR
WHEN THEY ACTUALLY SERVE A FUNCTION FOR THE
PLANT. BUT
COLLENCHYMA CELLS HAVE VERY, HAVE UNEVENLY
THICKENED WALLS. YOU
CAN SEE ALL THIS DARK STAINING AREA. THESE
ARE CROSS SECTIONS BY
THE WAY. SO YOU CAN SEE THESE, THAT THE WALLS
ARE THICKENED
UNEVENLY HERE WHICH GIVES THEM SOME RIGIDITY
AND STRENGTH. SO
THIS TYPE OF CELL CAN INPART SOME STRUCTURAL
SUPPORT. BUT
THESE, THESE CELL WALLS ARE JUST PRIMARY WALLS.
WE'LL GET TO
SECONDARY WALLS IN A MINUTE. BUT PRIMARY WALLS
RETAIN SOME
FLEXIBILITY. SO EVEN THOUGH THESE HAVE SOME
STRUCTURAL, CAN
PROVIDE SOME STRUCTURAL SUPPORT, THEY ALSO
HAVE FLEXIBILITY AND
CAN OCCUR IN GROWING PARTS OF THE PLANT. SO
THEY CAN, CAN
PROVIDE SUPPORT IN GROWING AREAS. AND WE OFTEN
FIND THESE KINDS
OF CELLS JUST INSIDE THE EPIDERMIS, THE OUTERMOST
LAYER OF CELLS
ON A PLANT. AND ESPECIALLY IN THE PRIMARY
PLANT BODY WHICH
WE'LL GET TO THAT IN A MINUTE. SO AN EXAMPLE,
LET'S SEE, FOR
EXAMPLE, FIRST OF ALL FOR PARENCHYMA, I SHOULD
MENTION THAT THESE
ARE CELLS THAT ARE WIDELY FOUND THROUGHOUT
THE PLANT BODY.
THEY'RE MUCH OF THE SOFT TISSUE IN A PLANT.
SO IF YOU EAT A
FRUIT, FOR EXAMPLE, A LOT OF THAT TISSUE IS
PARENCHYMA. WHEREAS
COLLENCHYMA, WHAT YOU MIGHT BE FAMILIAR WITH
THERE IS IF YOU BITE
INTO A STALK OF CELERY, THE STRINGS THAT CAN
GET CAUGHT BETWEEN
YOUR TEETH IN THOSE, IN A STEM, IN A STALK
OF CELERY WHICH IS A
PETIOLE OF A, OF A CELERY LEAF, THAT'S COLLENCHYMA.
SO IF YOU'VE
PULLED THOSE OUT OF YOUR TEETH, YOU'LL NOTICE
THAT THEY'RE GREEN.
THEY'RE LIVING CELLS, AND THEY'RE, THEY DO
PROVIDE SOME
STRUCTURAL SUPPORT AS YOU CAN APPRECIATE.
THEY'RE PRETTY STRONG.
SO A THIRD TISSUE TYPE OR THIRD CELL TYPE
IS SCLERENCHYMA. AND
SCLERENCHYMA CELLS ARE DEAD AT FUNCTIONAL
MATURITY. SO WHEN
THEY'RE FULLY FORMED, THE PROTOPLAST DIES
AND THEY BECOME
HOLLOWED OUT. AND THEY LAY, BEFORE THEY DIE,
THEY LAY DOWN
SECONDARY WALL BETWEEN THE PRIMARY WALL AND
THE CELL MEMBRANE.
AND THESE SECONDARY WALLS ARE NOT ONLY ADDING
THICKNESS TO THE
CELL WALL BUT THEY ALSO ARE IMPREGNATED WITH
LIGNIN WHICH IS A
COMPOUND THAT IMPARTS RIGIDITY TO PLANT PARTS.
AND SO EXAMPLES
OF SCLERENCHYMA ARE THINGS LIKE, WELL, THERE
ARE A COUPLE OF
DIFFERENT TYPES OF SCLERENCHYMA. THERE ARE
SCLEREIDS WHICH ARE
NOT ELONGATED CELLS BUT PROVIDE STRUCTURAL
SUPPORT, FOR EXAMPLE,
THE SEED COAT, RIGID SEED COATS ARE MADE OF
THESE REALLY TOUGH
SCLEREIDS AS IS SAY THE OUTER FRUIT WALL OF
THE NUT, YOU KNOW
LIKE A WALNUT SHELL, SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
THOSE, THAT, THOSE
ARE SCLEREIDS THAT IMPART THAT HARDNESS. AND
IF YOU BITE INTO A
PEAR, I DON'T KNOW IF YOU KNOW, YOU'VE EXPERIENCED
THAT SORT OF
GRITTINESS OF A PEAR FRUIT. THESE ARE SCLEREIDS
INSIDE THE
FRUIT OF A PEAR WHICH IS OTHERWISE MOSTLY
PARENCHYMA TISSUE.
BUT THERE ARE SCLEREIDS IN THERE THAT GIVE
IT THAT GRITTY
TEXTURE. ANOTHER TYPE OF SCLERENCHYMA ARE
FIBERS. NOW FIBERS
ARE ELONGATED CELLS THAT FORM THREAD-LIKE,
THEY'RE OFTEN IN A
THREAD-LIKE ORGANIZATION. AND YOU MIGHT BE
FAMILIAR WITH FIBERS
FOR LIKE HEMP FIBER WHICH IS USED TRADITIONALLY
TO MAKE ROPE OR
FLAX FIBER, IT'S USED FOR WEAVING. FIBERS
ARE REALLY TOUGH AND
IMPART RIGIDITY TO TISSUE. BUT THESE SCLERENCHYMA
CELLS ARE
ONLY FORMED IN PARTS OF THE PLANT THAT HAVE
QUIT GROWING, BECAUSE
SCLERENCHYMA IS RIGID AND IT CAN'T ELONGATE.
IT'S INFLEXIBLE.
OKAY, SO ONLY IN THE PARTS OF THE PLANT THAT
ARE NO LONGER
GROWING IS SCLERENCHYMA FULLY DIFFERENTIATED.
ARE THERE
QUESTIONS ABOUT CELL TYPES? THERE ARE OTHER
COUPLE, THERE ARE A
COUPLE OF OTHER CELL TYPES IN THE VASCULAR
TISSUE, THE CONDUCTING
TISSUE. WE'RE GOING TO GET TO THOSE IN A MINUTE.
BUT THESE ARE
CELL TYPES THAT ARE FOUND, FOUND THROUGHOUT
ALL THE TISSUES OF
THE PLANT, NOT JUST THE VASCULAR TISSUE. OKAY,
SO THERE ARE
TISSUE SYSTEMS IN PLANTS AND JUST LIKE THOSE,
WELL, THERE ARE
MORE THAN THOSE THREE CELL TYPES, BUT THERE
ARE THREE TISSUES
TYPES. THERE ARE ONLY THREE TISSUE TYPES IN
PLANTS. AND
TISSUES ARE JUST A FUNCTIONAL UNIT THAT CONNECTS
ALL THE PLANT
ORGANS. AND THERE ARE THREE TYPES OF PLANT
ORGANS REGARDLESS OF
WHETHER WE'RE TALKING ABOUT REPRODUCTIVE PARTS
OF THE PLANT OR
VEGETATIVE PARTS OF THE PLANT. PLANTS ARE
MADE UP OF LEAVES,
STEMS, AND ROOTS. REMEMBER THE FLOWER IS BASICALLY
A, A SIMPLE
SHOOT THAT'S, THAT'S A STEM, THE AXIS OF IT
WITH MODIFIED LEAVES,
BOTH STERILE AND FERTILE, AND STEMS AND ROOTS.
AND THESE ALL
HAVE CHARACTERISTIC ATTRIBUTES WE'LL TALK
ABOUT IN A MOMENT.
AND ACROSS ALL OF THE, ACROSS THE LEAVES,
THE STEM, AND THE ROOT
WE HAVE THREE TYPES OF TISSUE SYSTEMS THAT
ARE KNOWN AS DERMAL,
GROUND, AND VASCULAR TISSUE. SO THE DERMAL
TISSUE IS THE TISSUE
THAT FORMS THE OUTER PROTECTIVE COVERING OF
THE PLANT, SO THE
OUTERMOST LAYER IN THE CASE OF THE PRIMARY
PLANT BODY, JUST THE
EPIDERMIS, A SINGLE CELL LAYER IN THICKNESS.
WHEN WE GET TO
SECONDARY GROWTH, IT CAN BE MORE THAN ONE
LAYER IN THICKNESS.
AND THEN THE VASCULAR TISSUE IN PURPLE HERE
IS THE CONDUCTING
TISSUE, CONDUCTING WATER AND FOOD, SUGARS
AND OTHER ORGANIC
NUTRIENTS. AND THE GROUND TISSUE IN YELLOW
HERE IS BASICALLY
EVERYTHING ELSE. MOSTLY PARENCHYMA THAT IS
THE MOST
METABOLICALLY ACTIVE TISSUE IN THE PLANT.
AND YOU CAN SEE HOW
THESE THREE DIFFERENT TYPES OF TISSUE WITH
THE EXCEPTION OF THE
EPIDERMIS, ACTUALLY THE VASCULAR TISSUE AND
THE, AND THE GROUND
TISSUE ARE ORGANIZED IN DIFFERENT WAYS IN
THE THREE DIFFERENT
ORGANS. THOUGH THERE'S A VERY DIFFERENT ORGANIZATION,
FOR
EXAMPLE, THE VASCULAR TISSUE AND THE STEM
COMPARED TO THE ROOT,
AND THE GROUND TISSUE AS WELL. AND THE SAME
APPLIES TO THE
LEAVES. BUT IT'S ALL INTERCONNECTED. IT'S
ALL A UNIFIED WHOLE.
THESE TISSUE SYSTEMS ARE ALL INTERCONNECTED
ACROSS THESE THREE
ORGANS, THREE TYPES OF ORGANS. BUT WE'LL TALK
ABOUT THE SHOOT
SYSTEM AND THE ROOT SYSTEM SEPARATELY IN TERMS
OF DEVELOPMENT
BECAUSE THEY ARE SO DIFFERENT ANATOMICALLY
AND DEVELOPMENTALLY.
THE SAME APPLIES TO THE LEAVES ACTUALLY. SO
THE DERMAL TISSUE
AS I MENTIONED, THIS IS JUST THE OUTER PROTECTIVE
COVERING OF THE
PLANT BODY WHICH IN THE PRIMARY PLANT BODY
WHICH IS ALL THERE
EVER IS IN A MONOCOT, IN MOST, ALMOST ALL
MONOCOTS AND IN ALL
NON-WOODY EUDICOTS, THE DERMAL SYSTEM IS JUST
THE EPIDERMIS, A
SINGLE CELL LAYER IN THICKNESS AROUND THE
OUTSIDE OF THE ENTIRE
PLANT. AND IT'S TYPICALLY COVERED WITH THIS
WAXY SUBSTANCE
CALLED THE CUTE- OR WAXY SUBSTANCE THAT CONSTITUTES
THE CUTICLE,
WHICH YOU CAN SEE IS TYPICALLY THICKER ON
THE OUTERMOST WALLS,
THE ONES THAT ARE MOST EXPOSED TO THE ATMOSPHERE
THAN ON THE
INNER WALLS. AND THIS CUTICLE IS CRITICAL,
OF COURSE, TO
PROVIDE A BARRIER SO THAT WE DON'T HAVE WATER
LOSS FROM THE PLANT
OUT INTO THE ATMOSPHERE. BUT THE PLANTS HAVE
TO BE ABLE TO TAKE
IN GASSES, ESPECIALLY, IN PARTICULAR CO2 IN
ORDER FOR
PHOTOSYNTHESIS TO OCCUR. SO THERE HAS TO BE,
HAS TO BE A WAY FOR
CO2 TO GET IN. DURING PHOTOSYNTHESIS OXYGEN
IS GENERATED SO
SOME OF THE RESPIRATORY NEEDS CAN BE MET BY
THAT OXYGEN. BUT
SOMETIMES OXYGEN NEEDS TO BE TAKEN IN THROUGH
THE EPIDERMIS AS
WELL. AND THAT'S DONE THROUGH WHAT ARE CALLED,
WHAT'S CALLED A
STOMA, WHICH THE PLURAL IS STOMATA, ADDING
A TA TO THAT, JUST
REFERRING TO MULTIPLE STOMA. AND HERE YOU
CAN SEE INDIVIDUAL
STOMA HERE. AND THESE ARE THE PORES RIGHT
HERE THAT ALLOW AIR
EXCHANGE WITH THE OUTSIDE OF THE PLANT. AND
THESE TWO, THERE'S
TWO CELLS HERE ON EITHER SIDE HERE WHICH ARE
CALLED GUARD CELLS
THAT REGULATE THE AIR FLOW. THEY REGULATE
THE SIZE OF THAT
PORE. THEY CAN COMPLETELY CLOSE THAT PORE
IF THE PLANT'S
EXPERIENCING DROUGHT STRESS FOR EXAMPLE, OR
THEY CAN OPEN IT
WIDELY, ALLOWING MAXIMUM ENTRY OF CARBON DIOXIDE.
BUT THE
PROBLEM WITH HAVING THIS OPEN, OF COURSE,
IS THAT IT IS A WAY
THAT WATER CAN LEAVE THE PLANT. AND SO IT'S
A TRADEOFF THAT THE
PLANT'S ALWAYS JUGGLING IS GETTING ENOUGH
CO2 INTO THE PLANT FOR
PHOTOSYNTHESIS TO OCCUR. AND IN SOME CASES
SUFFICIENT OXYGEN
FOR RESPIRATION BUT ALSO NOT LETTING OUT TOO
MUCH WATER AND
CAUSING THE PLANT TO WILT. THOUGH THAT'S,
THESE ARE STRUCTURES
THAT WE SEE ON THE EPIDERMIS OF THE PLANT,
AND ESPECIALLY ON THE
LEAVES, AND ESPECIALLY ON THE UNDERSIDE OF
THE LEAVES OF PLANTS
THAT HAVE BIFACIAL OR FLATTENED LEAVES WHERE
THEY'RE NOT IN
DIRECT EXPOSURE TO THE SUN AND THERE'S LESS
POTENTIAL FOR
EVAPORATIVE WATER LOSS. AND ALSO THE EPIDERMIS
CAN PRODUCE SOME
EXTENSIONS. SO EVEN THOUGH IT'S ONLY A CELL
LAYER IN THICKNESS
AROUND THE PLANT BODY, THERE CAN BE EPIDERMAL
CELLS THAT EXTEND
OUTSIDE THE, THIS LAYER AND EVEN MULTIPLE
EPIDERMAL CELLS THAT
CAN MAKE UP THINGS LIKE THESE HAIRS HERE YOU
SEE. AND WE CAN
HAVE HAIRS ON ROOTS. WE CAN HAVE HAIRS ON
STEMS. WE CAN HAVE
HAIRS AN LEAVES. AND THEY SERVE A VARIETY
OF FUNCTION. THOSE
ROOT HAIRS THAT I MENTIONED EARLIER THAT ARE
COMING OFF THE TAP,
WERE COMING OFF THE TAPROOT THAT YOU COULD
SEE IN THAT VIDEO,
THOSE ARE EPIDERMAL OUTGROWTHS. THEY'RE JUST
EXTENSIONS OF THE
EPIDERMAL CELLS OF THE ROOT. AND THEY ALLOW
FOR AN INCREASED
SURFACE AREA FOR ABSORPTION TO OCCUR. AND
SOME OF THE EPIDERMAL
HAIRS ON THE OUTSIDE OF THE SHOOT SYSTEM ON
THE STEMS AND THE
LEAVES, THOSE HAIRS CAN FUNCTION IN A VARIETY
OF WAYS. THEY CAN
DETER HERBIVORES BY PRODUCING TOXIC GLANDULAR
EXUDATES. YOU
OFTEN, MAYBE YOU'VE FELT STICKY PLANT PARTS
BEFORE THAT ARE
PRODUCING GLANDULAR SUBSTANCES THAT ARE DISTASTEFUL
TO HERBIVORES
OR MAYBE EVEN POISONOUS. THEY CAN ALSO FORM
A REFLECTIVE LAYER
IF THEY'RE DENSELY PACKED ON THE SURFACE.
YOU'VE SEEN HAIR,
LEAVES THAT ARE COVERED WITH WHITE HAIRS THAT
ALLOW THEM TO
REFLECT LIGHT. SO IF THEY GROW IN A HIGH-LIGHT
ENVIRONMENT,
REFLECTING LIGHT CAN BE BENEFICIAL TO KEEP
THE LEAF FROM
OVERHEATING. SO THERE ARE THINGS LIKE THAT
THE EPIDERMIS CAN
SERVE TO PROTECT THE PLANT BODY. ARE THERE
QUESTIONS ABOUT THE
DERMAL SYSTEM? WE'RE GOING TO TALK MORE ABOUT
IT SOON. OKAY, SO
NOW THE VASCULAR TISSUE INVOLVES SOME ADDITIONAL
CELL TYPES IN
ADDITION TO PARENCHYMA, COLLENCHYMA, AND SCLERENCHYMA
THAT I
MENTIONED BEFORE. YEAH, UNFORTUNATE NAMES,
BUT WE'RE SORT OF
STUCK WITH THOSE NAMES. VASCULAR TISSUE IS
OF TWO TYPES. AND
REMEMBER, THESE ARE THE CONDUCTING TISSUES
THAT TRANSPORT WATER
AND NUTRIENTS IN THE PLANT. SO THERE ARE JUST
TWO DISCREET
TYPES OF VASCULAR TISSUE. THERE'S THE XYLEM
WHICH CONDUCTS
WATER AND MINERALS THROUGH THE PLANT AND,
OF COURSE, FROM THE
ROOTS WHERE WATER'S ABSORBED TO THE OTHER
PARTS. AND THE XYLEM
HAS A COUPLE OF TYPES OF CELLS THAT WE HAVEN'T
SEEN YET, NAMELY
TRACHEIDS ON THE RIGHT HERE AND VESSEL ELEMENTS
HERE ON THE LEFT.
AND LIKE SCLERENCHYMA THESE ARE CELLS THAT
ARE DEAD AT FUNCTIONAL
MATURITY, SO THE PROTOPLAST DIES AND DISAPPEARS.
AND THESE ARE
BASICALLY HOLLOW TUBES THAT CONDUCT WATER.
AND THEY'RE ARRANGED
TOGETHER IN A CONDUCTING SYSTEM, BASICALLY
A PLUMBING SYSTEM
THROUGH THE PLANT. AND TRACHEIDS ARE THE TYPE
OF CONDUCTING
ELEMENT IN THE XYLEM THAT'S FOUND ACROSS ALL
VASCULAR PLANTS.
AND, IN FACT, THAT'S WHY THE VASCULAR PLANTS
ARE TECHNICALLY
KNOWN AS TRACHEOPHYTES, WHICH JUST MEANS TRACHEID-BEARING
PLANTS,
BECAUSE EVEN THOUGH SOME MOSSES HAVE CONDUCTING
TISSUES, IT'S NOT
HOMOLOGOUS TO TRACHEIDS. NOW THE TRACHEIDS
AND THE VESSEL
ELEMENTS LIKE THE SCLERENCHYMA ARE NOT ONLY
DEAD AT FUNCTIONAL
MATURITY, BUT THEY HAVE SECONDARY WALLS THAT
ARE LAID DOWN BEFORE
THE CELL DIES ON TOP OF THE PRIMARY WALLS.
SO THESE THICKEN THE
WALLS, MAKE THEM STRONGER. AND AGAIN, LIKE
IN SCLERENCHYMA, THE
WALLS ARE IMPREGNATED WITH LIGNIN, THE STRENGTHENING
SUBSTANCE
THAT IMPARTS A LOT OF STRENGTH TO THE, TO
THESE PARTICULAR TYPES
OF CELLS. AND THAT'S REALLY IMPORTANT FOR
THEM TO BE ABLE TO
WITHSTAND THE KINDS OF PRESSURES, NEGATIVE
PRESSURES THAT THEY'RE
UNDER DURING WATER CONDUCTION. THE WATER MOVES
BETWEEN THESE
TRACHEIDS NOT BY ACTUALLY BIG OPENINGS BETWEEN
THEM BUT BY PLACES
IN THE TRACHEID WHERE THE SECONDARY WALL WASN'T
LAID DOWN AND
WHERE THERE'S JUST PRIMARY WALL THAT'S VERY
THIN. AND THAT'S
WHAT WE CALL PITS. AND YOU CAN SEE PITS ALONG
THE SIDE OF THE
TRACHEID. THERE ARE ALSO PITS HERE ALONG THE
SIDE OF THE VESSEL
ELEMENT. AND SO WATER CAN MOVE THROUGH THESE
PRIMARY WALLS.
THERE ARE SMALL HOLES, VERY TINY HOLES IN
THE PRIMARY WALL. BUT
YOU MIGHT THINK, WELL, THAT DOESN'T SOUND
VERY EFFICIENT TO HAVE
THE WATER HAVE TO CROSS THESE MEMBRANES OR
TRY TO CROSS, CROSS
THROUGH THESE VERY SMALL OPENINGS. BUT ONE
OF THE FUNCTIONS OF
HAVING, ONE OF THE BENEFITS OF HAVING SOME
RESTRICTION TO
MOVEMENT HERE IS THAT IT PREVENTS AIR BUBBLES
FROM MOVING THROUGH
THE CONDUCTION SYSTEM. SO IF AN AIR BUBBLE
FORMS INSIDE OF A
TRACHEID, THAT'S GOING TO PREVENT CONDUCTION
FROM CONTINUING, AND
IT'S MUCH MORE DIFFICULT FOR AN AIR BUBBLE
TO MOVE THROUGH THESE
SMALL OPENINGS THAN IT WOULD BE IF THERE WERE
LARGE OPENINGS.
SO AN EMBOLISM IN VASCULAR TISSUE CAN HAVE
DIRE CONSEQUENCES FOR
CONDUCTION. AND TRACHEIDS HAVE MEANS OF PREVENTING
THESE
EMBOLISMS FROM SPREADING THROUGH THE CONDUCTING
TISSUE WITH
REGARD TO THESE PITS. NOW VESSEL ELEMENTS
HAVE MORE POTENTIAL
FOR EMBOLISMS TO SPREAD. BUT THEY ALSO HAVE
MORE EFFICIENT
MOVEMENT OF WATER BECAUSE THEY ACTUALLY HAVE
PERFORATION PLATES
IN THE ENDS. YOU CAN SEE ONE RIGHT HERE, AN
OBLIQUE VIEW. SO
THAT'S ACTUALLY, THERE ARE ACTUALLY OPENINGS,
THESE PERFORATION
PLATES HAVE OPENINGS THAT ARE NOT COVERED
BY PRIMARY WALL.
THERE'S NO WALL THERE AT ALL. AND SO THE ENDS
OF VESSEL
ELEMENTS HAVE PRETTY FREE MOVEMENT BETWEEN
THEM, AND TOGETHER
THEY MAKE UP WHAT'S CALLED THE VESSELS. SO
THESE THINGS ARE
HOOKED TOGETHER END-TO-END AND PROVIDE FOR
A VERY EFFICIENT WATER
MOVEMENT. BUT UNDER SEVERE DROUGHT STRESS,
THESE ARE MORE PRONE
TO FORMING AIR BUB-, FOR AIR BUBBLES TO REALLY
MOVE THROUGH THE
SYSTEM AND CAUSE, CAUSE A PROBLEM. SO WE CAN
GET BOTH VESSEL
ELEMENTS AND TRACHEARY, TRACHEIDS WITHIN ANGIOSPERM
WOOD OR
ANGIOSPERM XYLEM. YEAH?
STUDENT: IS THERE ANY [INAUDIBLE]?
PROFESSOR: WELL, THE TRACHEIDS BOTH SERVE
A STRUCTURAL FUNCTION
AS WELL AS A CONDUCTION FUNCTION. IN GENERAL
THEY'RE NARROWER.
THEY'RE MORE TIGHTLY PACKED IN THE TISSUE.
AND SO THEY IMPART
SOME MORE RIGIDITY TO THE, TO THE CONDUCTING
TISSUE THAN THE
VESSELS DO. THE VESSELS ARE USUALLY FOUND
IN ASSOCIATION WITH
FIBERS, A TYPE OF SCLERENCHYMA I MENTIONED.
AND SO WE HAVE IN
THE CASES OF PLANTS THAT HAVE VESSEL ELEMENTS,
THEY OFTEN HAVE A
MIXTURE OF FIBERS AND VESSELS. THE FIBER'S
SERVING A MORE OF A
STRUCTURAL FUNCTION AND THE VESSEL'S SERVING
MORE OF A CONDUCTION
FUNCTION WITHIN THE VASCULAR TISSUE. SO MORE
OF A SEPARATION OF
FUNCTION THAN WE SEE IN SOME PLANTS THAT JUST
HAVE TRACHEIDS.
AND SO VESSEL ELEMENTS ARE ONLY FOUND IN ANGIOSPERMS
AND IN THE
THE GNETOPHYTES, THOSE WEIRD THINGS LIKE THE
PLATYPUS OF THE
PLANT KINGDOM I MENTIONED, THE WELWITSCHIA.
AND IT USED TO BE
THE REASON THAT PEOPLE THOUGHT THE GNETOPHYTES
AND THE
ANGIOSPERMS, ONE OF THE REASONS THAT THEY
WERE THOUGHT TO BE
CLOSELY RELATED. BUT THEY'VE INDEPENDENTLY
EVOLVED VESSELS.
VESSELS ARE, ARE NOT FOUND VERY WIDELY OUTSIDE
OF THOSE TWO
GROUPS, THE FLOWERING PLANTS AND THE GNETOPHYTES.
ALTHOUGH
THEY'RE CONTINUING TO BE DISCOVERED IN SOME
OTHER GROUPS. BUT,
FOR EXAMPLE, CONIFERS LACK THEM ALL TOGETHER
AND JUST HAVE
TRACHEIDS. OKAY, THE OTHER TYPE OF CONDUCTING
TISSUE IS THE
PHLOEM. AND THE PHLOEM CONDUCTS THE FOOD THROUGH
THE PLANT, THE
SUGAR AND ORGANIC NUTRIENTS. AND WE'LL TALK
ABOUT EXACTLY HOW
THAT HAPPENS SOON AS WELL AS HOW THE WATER
MOVES THROUGH THE
PLANT. BUT IN TERMS OF THE CELL TYPES THAT
MAKE UP THE PHLOEM,
THERE ARE TWO MAJOR CELL TYPES THAT YOU NEED
TO REALIZE. ONE IS
THE SIEVE-TUBE ELEMENT WHICH IS THE TYPE OF
ELEMENT THAT ACTUALLY
CONDUCTS THE, THE SUGAR SOLUTION THROUGH THE
PLANT. AND THESE
ARE LIVING AT MATURITY. BUT THE BULK OF THIS
ELONGATE CELL IS
OPEN IN THE CENTER BECAUSE THE CYTOPLASM IS
JUST RESTRICTED TO A
LITTLE LAYER AROUND THE INSIDE, JUST INSIDE
THE WALL OF THE, OF
THE CELL. AND IT'S LOST THE NUCLEI. IT LOST
THE RIBOSOMES.
IT'S LOST THE VACUOLES. IT'S LOST ALL THE
ORGANELLES, INCLUDING
THE NUCLEI WHICH ALLOWS THE CYTOPLASM TO TAKE
UP A VERY SMALL
AMOUNT OF SPACE JUST AROUND THE PERIPHERY
OF THE INSIDE OF THIS
SIEVE-TUBE ELEMENT. AND SO IT ALLOWS THE CENTER
OF THIS ELEMENT
TO MOSTLY BE OPEN FOR CONDUCTION. AND THESE
SIEVE-TUBE ELEMENTS
ARE JOINED END-TO-END WITH ONE ANOTHER INTO
SIEVE TUBES. AND
BETWEEN THE SIEVE TUBES WE HAVE WHAT'S CALLED
A SIEVE PLATE THAT
HAS OPENINGS IN IT THAT ALLOW THE SUGAR WATER
TO MOVE THROUGH THE
PLANT. THIS IS A LONGITUDINAL SECTION HERE.
AND AS I
MENTIONED, THE FACT THAT THERE'S NO NUCLEUS,
THERE'S VERY LITTLE
IN THE WAY OF THE ABILITY OF A SIEVE TUBE
TO BE ABLE, SIEVE-TUBE
ELEMENT TO BE ABLE TO REGULATE ITS METABOLISM.
IT'S IN
ASSOCIATION, EACH SIEVE-TUBE ELEMENT HAS A
COMPANION CELL WHICH
IS A, A TYPE OF PARENCHYMA CELL THAT HAS A
NUCLEUS AND ALL THE
OTHER ORGANELLES OF THE PLANT CELL. AND IT
REGULATES, IT HELPS
TO REGULATE THE METABOLISM OF THE ADJOINING
SIEVE-TUBE ELEMENT
WHICH IS ALIVE BUT LACKING IN SOME REALLY
CRITICAL PARTS OF ITS
CELL. AND ACTUALLY, THE COMPANION CELL IN
THE SIEVE-TUBE
ELEMENT ARE FORMED FROM THE SAME INITIAL CELL.
THERE'S A CELL
DIVISION THAT RESULTS IN A COMPANION CELL
AND A SIEVE-TUBE
ELEMENT, SO THEY'RE DEVELOPMENTALLY CONJOINED.
THEY ACTUALLY
COME FROM A COMMON ANCESTRAL CELL THAT DIVIDES.
AND SO IF, THE
INTERESTING THING ABOUT THE SIEVE PLATE, WE'LL
TALK ABOUT IT
LATER, IS IF, THESE ARE REALLY PRECIOUS SUBSTANCES
THAT THE
PLANT'S MOVING THROUGH HERE, THE SUGARS. SO
IF THERE'S ANY
WOUNDING OF THIS, IF THE, THERE'S A BREACH
OF THE SIEVE-TUBE, IT
BEHOOVES THE PLANT TO SEAL THIS UP IMMEDIATELY.
AND IT DOES.
IN FACT, IT SEALS IT UP SO QUICKLY THAT IT'S
REALLY HARD TO STUDY
THE ANATOMY OF THESE CELLS BECAUSE THE SUBSTANCE
CALLED CALLOSE
IS FORMED INSTANTANEOUSLY THAT SEALS UP THE
SIEVE PLATE HOLES
HERE AND PREVENTS ANY FURTHER CONDUCTION.
THOUGH THESE, THESE
HAVE REALLY GOOD WOUND RESPONSE TO KEEP FROM
LOSING SUGARS. ARE
THERE QUESTIONS ABOUT XYLEM OR PHLOEM AT THIS
POINT? WE'RE GOING
TO GET INTO IT MORE LATER. OKAY, SO WE'RE
OUT OF TIME. AND
WE'LL JUST TALK ABOUT THE WAY THESE ARE ORGANIZED
AND GET TO THE
OTHER SYSTEMS SHORTLY.