We start with a search for hundreds of missing
people. They haven`t been seen since the typhoon
hit their home country last week. Typhoons
are the same kinds of storms as hurricanes,
and Typhoon Bopha was the strongest one that
hit the Philippines this year. You can see
some of the damage that it left behind in
this "I-Report" video. The storm`s heavy rains
led the flash floods and landslides, more
than 600 people were killed in this, and almost
1500 others were injured. More than 700 people
are missing including more than 300 Filipino
fishermen. Search efforts are underway, relief
groups are trying to get supplies to some
of the areas that were hit the worst, but
it`s difficult, because of damage to roads
and communication lines.
Next, we are looking at the civil war in Syria.
It`s been going on for almost two years now
with Syrian government forces fighting against
rebel groups. And official who`s represented
the United Nations in the Arab League says
the solution is possible, but he also described
the situation in Syria as bad and getting
worse. Some of the violence is happening in
the city of Aleppo. And this Youtube video
shows the fire in the city`s old market earlier
this year. The old section of Aleppo is a
world heritage site, it`s full of historical
and cultural significance. Arwa Damon explores
how it`s been effected by the civil war.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
ARWA DAMON, CNN CORRESPONDENT: Aleppo`s old
city has not seen such devastation since occupied
by the Mongol invaders eight centuries ago.
This mosque, for example, dates back to 1315.
This is Syria`s rich cultural heritage, and
now everywhere we look, it`s been scarred
by war. Once bustling winding streets, now
a maze of ever shifting front lines.
Overhead, the thundering of fighter jets,
a small khan, lodging for caravans down the
ages, lies in ruins. For more than three millennia,
Aleppo has been a crossroads for traders.
We hurry through the courtyard of a traditional
home.
Sheets are strung across streets to block
snipers line of sight. Those who dare venture
quickly across. A unit of fighters records
people`s names and license plates, only those
who have shops here are allowed through.
Abu Bashir says, they`re trying to clamp down
on robberies.
(woman talking Arabic)
DAMON: She shows us the list, the highlighted
names have cleared out all their possessions.
In one market, a shop recently hit by army
fire, still smolders. The heart of old Aleppo,
now the historic battleground for the very
uncertain future of Syria.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
REP. JERROLD NADLER, NEW YORK: Although the
emergency response agencies work hard to get
the city back up and running, there were gaps
in the recovery operations and there are many
challenges that remain, particularly for a
dense urban area like New York. Our transportation
system is too vulnerable, our infrastructure
is old and hard to replace. The power grid
runs more than just lights and computers,
it also powers heat and hot water and all
water in the high-rises all over the city.
And that operates the elevators that the elderly
and disabled rely upon to escape their homes
when they become unsafe.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: President Obama is asking Congress for
more than $60 billion to help the states that
have been effected by Superstorm Sandy. Now,
that money is not going to cover all of the
estimated damage from the storm, it would
be used for recovery and the prepare for future
natural disasters. Ryan Panetta and his family
are going through that recovery process right
now. Every day Ryan gets up and goes to school,
after classes he rides the bus to his house,
and all that sounds normal, but for Ryan and
his family, life is nothing like it was before
the storm.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
POPPY HARLOW, CNN CORRESPONDENT: The sun isn`t
up at breakfast time for the Panettas.
(on camera): How tired are you?
RYAN PANETTA, 8TH GRADER, SCHOLARS ACADEMY:
Very.
HARLOW (voice over): Tim, Ryan, Christian
and Carly are now living in a borrowed one-bedroom
apartment with their parents.
(on camera): How long is your commute to a
school now?
PANETTA: It feels almost like two hours.
HARLOW: And what did it use to be?
RYAN PANETTA: 15 minutes.
HARLOW: Wow.
(voice over): 6:30 a.m and they are out the
door. A long car ride ...
KAREN PANETTA, RYAN`S MOTHER: Have a good
day.
HARLOW: Then a bus to Ryan`s temporary school,
PS-13.
KAREN PANETTA: It`s unreal how much our life
has changed. You know, and we are trying to
make the best of it.
HARLOW: He is an 8th grade honor student,
one of 5400 New York students still in different
schools because of Sandy.
CARRIE JAMES, SCHOLAR`S ACADEMY HUMANITIES
TEACHER: He is the one that I think was probably
impacted the most, and yet he has the strongest
will to be here every day.
RYAN PANETTA: When something brings you down,
you`ve got to get up.
HARLOW (on camera): You are OK, buddy?
What makes you sad?
RYAN PANETTA: I honestly don`t know.
HARLOW: Everything?
RYAN PANETTA: It`s everything.
KAREN PANETTA: How did it go today, Ryan?
RYAN PANETTA: Good.
HARLOW (VOICE OVER): Every day after school
Ryan returns to Broad Channel to help his
dad try to put their home back together.
JOE PANETTA, RYAN`S FATHER: Everything that
I owned, everything I worked hard for everything
was there, and it`s gone, it`s nothing.
HARLOW: Joe was working overnights, and Karen
was home with their four children when Sandy
hit.
KAREN PANETTA: It was unbelievable, though,
how quickly it came in.
HARLOW: The water rushed into their one-story
house, Ryan swam to neighbor for help.
RYAN PANETTA: I jumped out.
HARLOW (on camera): You jumped out here in
the water?
RYAN PANETTA: Yes. I wasn`t even thinking
that like a log would hit me or anything.
HARLOW: Or the electrical power lines?
RYAN PANETTA: Yes.
HARLOW: You swam to this house?
RYAN PANETTA: Yeah, it`s right here. And they
took us in to the second floor.
HARLOW (voice over): The neighbor helped bring
the rest of the family over, and they watched
as the water engulfed the only home they`ve
known.
(on camera): What did you think when your
13-old son jumped in the water?
KAREN PANETTA: You know, I was panicking.
I was panicking.
HARLOW: Did Ryan helped save your family?
KAREN PANETTA: Absolutely.
HARLOW: No question?
HARLOW (voice over): Now, all the Panettas
are working to rebuild their home and erase
the bad memories.
RYAN PANETTA: After what I`ve just been through
like I don`t hope I have to see anything that
terrifying again.
HARLOW: Poppy Harlow, CNN, Broad Channel,
New York.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: See, if you can I.D.
me.
I`m a planet in our Solar System. I`m not
one of the gas giants, but I am the largest
of the terrestrial or rocky planets. I`m the
only planet whose name doesn`t come from Greek
or Roman mythology.
I`m Earth, the fifth largest planet in the
Solar System.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: You`ve seen a lot of pictures of the
Earth, most of the time they are taken during
the day because we have a lot of satellites
that can do that for us. There is a new sensor
on a satellite that was launched last year,
that`s especially designed to observe the
Earth at night. Scientists say these cloud
free images are from more detailed view of
our planet than ever before. What`s really
interesting are the lights, and how they sort
of define our world. For example, this is
Egypt, and that long line is the Nile River,
the satellite can distinguish the brightly
lit boats traveling along it. Some of the
lights around the Arabian Peninsula are gas
flares from oil exploration, and this border
between light and dark is marked by the Himalayan
Mountains, an example of how natural borders
can effect human settlement. You can see political
borders, too. The lights here in South Korea,
the darkness is North Korea.
There are some new officers on patrol in metro
stations around Washington, and they come
equipped with a unique skill set: it all starts
with their noses, these bomb-sniffing dogs
worked with the Marine Corps in Afghanistan.
They were recently donated to the Metro Transit
Police. Their new handlers are impressed by
their pedigree.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
SGT. ANDY KEAHON, METRO TRANSIT POLICE DEPARTMENT:
Every single one of the nine dogs that we
receive from the Marine Corps found bombs
in Afghanistan. We have one in particular
that found 37 improvised explosive devises
that were all buried down the road. We had
no idea that these dogs where as good they
are, and they are fantastic.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: And good looking, too. Now, we did a
dog story. So, before we go, in order to be
fair we are going to finish up with felines.
This little guy is down for a catnap. But
something seems to have spooked him, look
at those poor paws, flailing. Leave it to
mom to know just what to do: you brush down
the arms and come in for a quick kitty cuddle.
A classic move seems to do the trick, and
now you know the secret. If your pet is suffering
from nightmares, a simple hug will take care
of the whole kitten caboodle. Without any
fears of further catastrophe. CNN STUDENT
NEWS returns tomorrow. I hope to see you then,
bye-bye.