divide it by whatever you tried,
and then ask your mother.
- Ask me what?
- Hey, babe.
- Hmm.
- Something wrong?
- Not a thing.
- You sure?
- I'm fine.
Ask me what?
Is there a reason
you're listening to music
when you're supposed to be studying?
Kevin.
- He can't hear you.
Those are
noise-canceling headphones.
- Oh.
- Ask me what?
- Oh, do you know how to calculate
the surface area of a cube?
- Take the length of one side squared
and multiply it by six.
You didn't know that?
- Whoa, babe, we been
through this before.
Math is not my thing.
If it was, I could figure out
what's wrong with you.
- Kevin, why didn't you ask Lindsey?
She's done this stuff
a lot more recently than I have.
- I don't know.
- Lindsey.
- Yes?
- Did you not see you brother
sitting over here struggling?
- I saw him sitting there.
I didn't know he was struggling.
- Well, since you're so unsure
of what you're looking at,
your job for the next week is
to help Kevin with his homework.
- But mom...
- You want to make it two weeks?
I didn't think so.
Put that up.
sync and correct by dr.jackson
www.addic7ed.com
- Hey, Gigi.
- Hey, Nick.
- What's wrong with Suzanne?
- Shh.
Okay, your wife, she's upset.
- I can see that.
- Shh, man.
This morning, we had
a breakfast meeting
with a potential client, a woman,
throwing a post honeymoon party.
Suzanne was fine
until the woman asked her
where she went on her honeymoon.
So Suzanne tells her
about this amazing trip
she and you took to Hawaii.
- We didn't go to Hawaii because
we didn't go on a honeymoon.
- That's right.
- Y would Suzanne lie
about going on a honeymoon?
- Why wouldn't she like, Nick?
I mean, you can safely assume
not going on your honeymoon
is like not doing something
that would be really important
to a man that he didn't do
but was around a bunch
of other men who did do it,
and they were talking about it
all the time.
- Gigi, I promised Suzanne
I would take her on a honeymoon,
and I am taking her.
- Then what are you waiting for, Nick?
- I already got one wife.
I don't need you on my back.
- Well, you take her
on that trip or I will.
- Fine, Oprah, you take her.
- Don't mock me.
- I got this, Gigi.
- And what did she say?
And what did you say?
Oh-ho, no!
Oh-ho-ho, no!
Oh-ho!
Did Ralph call you?
Oh-ho, that boy
is on something.
I'm telling you.
No, no.
Him and rere went in.
Oh-ho, they went in.
No, no, you on something, boy.
No, boy, you on something!
No, a'ight, a'ight, check it.
Yeah, I got to do something real quick.
I'll hit you back.
A'ight.
I'm really sorry about that.
That was just...
- Yeah, I know, I know.
It's your boy.
He's on something.
So honeymoon.
Any place in mind?
- Someplace tropical.
- Uh, let's see.
Oh, yeah, here you go.
Let's see.
There we go.
Six nights all inclusive
at the Fiji grand tides.
- Yeah, how much?
- $8,442.
- Boy, you on something.
What can you do for 3,500
broken down into 12 easy payments?
- She like petting zoos?
- No.
- Civil war reenactments?
Look, I am looking for
a nice romantic beach getaway.
- Right, uh, oh, here, this is you.
All inclusive Maui swimming with
the dolphins honeymoon package,
$1,500.
- Man, what do I look like
swimming with the dolphins?
How am I supposed
to take pictures of that?
This is me.
This is me and a dolphin.
This is me and my wife and a dolphin.
This is me and my wife.
You know who took that picture?
The dolphin.
- No, you got it all wrong.
You don't have to swim
with the dolphins.
You can just sit on the beach.
I'll upgrade your room.
What do you say?
- Book it.
- Great.
Oh, uh, there is one catch.
You have to leave Tuesday.
Tuesday?
As in Tuesday?
- Yeah, Tuesday, this Tuesday.
Oh-ho.
- No. Brad is busy.
Who is this?
Rere?
- Oh-ho-ho, rere went in.
I call you back, Shawty.
- Nick.
Honey.
Babe, can you please help me
zip up my dress?
- Oh, no problem.
There you go.
- Thank you.
- Babe?
- Huh? Yes?
- You seem a little out of sorts.
Is everything okay?
- Yes, I'm fine.
Um, I was heaving a problem
with a client.
- You sure?
- Yeah, I'm good.
Thank you for asking.
- Ooh, I got to get this.
- Okay.
Kevin.
- Yes.
- Did Lindsey help you
with your homework?
- Uh, she...
- Yes.
She... mm-Hmm.
We did...
- We did geography and his vocabulary,
and we did the make-up questions
on a quiz he failed.
- What quiz did you fail?
- It was a hard quiz, mom.
And, plus, I didn't really fail fail.
I just missed a lot of the answers,
and we corrected them,
so I'm getting a "b."
- A "b" as in, boy, you better
not bring home another "f?"
- Yep, that's the one.
That's the one.
- Okay.
Yeah.
Love you guys.
- Bye, mommy.
- Hey.
- Hi.
Bye.
So you know that cute guy
at the coffee shop?
- The one who always gives you
the next size up?
- Right.
- Mm-Hmm.
- He asked me out.
- And what did you say?
- I said I'd think about it.
- Okay, instead of saying
you'd think about it,
why didn't you just tell him no?
- Because by my calculations,
at five visits a week,
say, over 48 weeks,
at 90¢ per up size times two,
that's about 450 bucks a year.
And I spend that little extra
money to help me look like this
so I can get free coffee.
- Why don't you just spend it
on coffee?
- And not look like this?
- Wow.
- Thank you.
- What are you talking about?
- Uh, never mind, honey.
What is it?
- Well, you might
be interested in knowing
that your boy,
Mr. Nick Kingston-persons,
has secured an interview with the one,
the only Ms. Laila Ali.
- What?
- Honey, honey, come on.
Okay, stop, stop.
Babe, babe.
That's fantastic,
but please don't do that
in front of her.
The lady might have
a flashback and knock you out.
Wow.
Laila Ali.
Nick.
- No.
- Suzanne.
- Nick.
- What?
- Can you please get her
to sign my boxing gloves?
Please.
- I'll see what I can do.
- Thank you.
- Honey, how did this come about?
Laila Ali, that's a big deal.
- Yeah, it's a big deal.
She has a speaking engagement
in Hawaii next week,
and they needed somebody this week.
- Wow.
Must be nice to work in Hawaii.
- Yeah, I wish I was going to Hawaii.
They got me going
to pebble beach next week.
- Oh, really?
What for?
- Local guy in the pro-am.
I'm working on a profile.
- All right.
Well, honey, we got to go.
I love you.
I'll see you later.
- Okay, baby.
- Bye.
- Uh, Gigi?
- What?
- When can I get those gloves?
- Oh, so I'll see you out there, okay?
- Okay.
- Um, tonight.
And can you also get her
holding my gloves
and take a picture.
- Gigi, enough about the gloves.
Listen.
What I am about to tell you,
you cannot say anything.
And by anything, I mean nothing.
You cannot discuss
what I'm about to tell you
with anyone but me.
- Nick, Suzanne is my best friend.
I... I can't have
no secrets with her husband.
- Gigi.
- What?
- I'm taking Suzanne on a honeymoon.
- When?
- That's the thing.
It has to be next week.
- But you just said you're going
to pebble beach next week.
- I'm not. I lied.
- Ooh.
- Listen, I need her
to think that I'm traveling
so she doesn't make plans
for me to be here
that I can't get out of.
- Nick, why are you telling me this?
You know I can't hold no secrets.
- I need you to clear her calendar.
- It's gonna be tough.
- What? She's got
a lot of appointments?
- No, I wrote everything in pen.
- Gigi.
- What?
Okay, okay, I'll see what I can do.
I got to go.
- Gigi.
- What?
- Not a word.
Or I will kill you.
You... wow, you're serious.
- You know, ma, I don't ask for much.
It's only five nights.
- And six days.
And you think you gonna sucker me
into staying here with those kids
by making me a sandwich?
- That is not just a sandwich.
That is hand-cut,
honey-roasted,
free range Turkey,
with cave-aged gouda cheese,
resting on seven grain
organic wheat bread.
No, man, that is not just a sandwich.
That is an experience.
Come on, ma.
Look at this place.
- Ooh, that is nice.
Is this the part where you hit me up
for the money to help with the deposit?
- No, ma, I just need
your help with the kids.
- Can I just give you the money?
I'll tell you what I'll do.
I will stay here with those kids
if you promise me
that while you're there,
you'll take Suzanne
on one of those boat rides
that I hear white men
take their wives on.
- What kind is that?
- The kind where the wives
don't come back.
Get it?
Ooh, I tickle me.
Almost there.
Uh. Whoa, replay!
Ha-ha!
- Kevin, come on.
I really want to hook up
with my friends.
I'm supposed to be helping you
with this essay,
not doing it for you.
- I'm only gonna be a few more minutes.
What's wrong with it anyway?
- What's wrong with it?
That's the stupidest essay
I've ever read.
Do you even know anything
about Barack Obama?
- If you hate it so much, you write it.
- Why would I do that?
- You're the one with friends waiting.
I got all night.
- Fine.
- Awesome.
So if you could get that
to me about 7:00,
8:00 at the latest.
- Oh, it'll be here.
- You should have it in a little while.
Okay, you're welcome.
B'bye.
Okay.
Maui emerald shores?
Six days, five nights,
Kingston-persons?
Hello?
Um, yes, I'm calling
to confirm a reservation.
Sure.
Nick Kingston-persons.
Thank you.
Yes, no, I just wanted to make sure
that it was a king non-smoking.
Upgraded to a sweet?
For two?
Oh, and it's part of the swim
with the dolphins package?
Right, next Tuesday through Saturday.
Thank you.
Yeah, you have a good day too.
Hello?
- Hey, can I please speak with Nick?
- Who's this?
- Uh, this is Skinner from the office.
I just wanted to let Nick now
that we're gonna take
Palmer off pebble beach
and do it next week with him instead.
So if he can check his schedule
and get back to me,
I'd greatly appreciate it.
- So Nick wasn't on
the pebble beach assignment?
- Well, he wasn't, but he is now.
- And it's next week?
- Right.
- And who are you calling for?
- Nick Kingston-persons.
- D you are?
- This is Skinner.
- From the office?
- Yes.
- Who's office?
- What?
- No, uh, I'm sorry.
Never mind.
B'bye. Thank you.
- Suzanne, that is ridiculous.
Nick is not having an affair.
- Gigi, I'm not stupid.
He said he was going
to pebble beach next week,
and instead I find
a reservation to Maui.
- Maui?
- Maui.
- Yes.
- Hawaii?
- That is amazing.
- Right?
And then I find out
that it's a king suite.
- King suite?
- King suite.
- Mm.
- I mean, isn't that crazy?
- Crazy.
- And then I find out
that he was never even going
on this alleged
pebble beach assignment.
- You know what?
I refuse to believe your husband
is cheating on you.
- Well, you don't have to believe it.
- Well, you know what?
Maybe someone stole his credit card
and put the room under his name.
Yeah, I mean, identity theft is real.
- So what?
So they broke into our house,
used our computer,
booked the reservation,
and had the confirmation email
sent to his address
so he would never find out about it?
- I didn't say they were good at it.
- Gigi.
- What?
- Why are you defending him?
Do you know something I don't?
- Do... no.
I mean, do I know... how can you
ask me do I know something?
Have I ever known anything?
- Well, if you knew something,
you would tell me, right?
I mean, you have to tell me.
- You are insulting me right now.
Because, girl, you know
if I knew something
that I knew you needed to know,
and you didn't know and I knew
you needed to know that,
girl, you know me.
When have I ever not
told you something.
- Never.
- Right.
So don't be questioning our friendship
over some obvious misunderstanding,
which I'm sure will be explained
to your satisfaction,
sooner rather than later.
- I'm not waiting for later.
- Where are you going?
- To find out if I need
to check Nick into a rehab.
- Go do what you got to do.
Just don't mention my name.
- Is there a particular fighter
you've had a problem with in the ring?
- You know what, I believe
that if you have a problem
with a fighter in the ring,
then you had a problem with your skills
before she even showed up.
So what I would do
is analyze my own weaknesses,
figure out how someone
was gonna try to beat me,
and then I wouldn't let it happen.
- Wait.
Not one problem with anybody?
Like, Jackie Frazier?
- Oh, you know what?
Don't even start bringing up
them damn fraziers, okay,
or I'm gonna have a problem with you.
Next thing you'll be asking me
if Rita foreman has a cookbook,
you know, when her daddy
got all them grills.
- Okay, okay, backing off, backing off.
- Back on up, now.
- You are the Beyonce of boxing.
You got your own clothing line,
cosmetics, fragrances,
line of skillets,
jeans, workout tapes.
So what's next for laila Ali, sleep?
- No, ma'am, you cannot come in here.
We're shooting.
- Oh, no, they ain't shooting.
I'm the one that's about to be
shooting, though, for real.
- Babe, what are you doing here?
- Don't "babe" me.
Sit down.
Is this her?
- Her who?
Baby, this is laila Ali.
- Oh, I know who she is.
Stand up.
Oh, no.
Come on, man.
Are you kidding me?
So what, you gonna take
your little boxing baby mama
to Hawaii and try and hide
the baby from me?
- Whoa, whoa, wait, you know what?
Listen here, little chick.
I don't know who you are
or what this is about,
but if you call me out
my name one more time,
I'm gonna smack you.
Okay, I don't care if you are little.
- And I don't care if you are big.
I may only hit you once,
but it's gonna be hard.
- Suzanne, have you lost your mind?
She is pregnant.
- Oh, whatever.
- You know what?
Let her try.
Me and this baby
will knock her little butt out.
- Laila, laila, please.
Please, let me handle this.
Don't hurt her.
- Are you seriously gonna stand there
and protect her over me?
Hell naw.
You know what? Sit down.
And don't you move.
Let me tell you something.
You need to explain yourself.
- Lady, if you don't take
your finger out my neck...
- Okay, explain yourself.
Why is my man going to Hawaii
with y'all, laila, Ali?
- What?
- Huh?
- You know what?
You're crazy.
I'm gonna go ahead and go,
because if I stay, I'm gonna have
to bop your wife
on the top of the head.
- Laila, laila, no, no.
Laila, no, please.
- Go ahead. Go ahead.
- Suzanne!
Whoa, whoa, this is crazy!
- You know what? Don't try
to play dumb, Nick, okay?
I saw your trip to Maui.
You said you were going
to pebble beach.
- I lied about that.
- Okay, so finally we get to the truth.
You know what, Nick?
I've had my heart broken before,
so now it's your turn.
So why don't you tell me?
Are you going to Hawaii
with laila or somebody else?
- Somebody else.
- Fine.
You know what?
Who is it? What's her name?
- Suzanne.
- Just tell me, okay?
- Suzanne?
Her name is Suzanne, Nick?
What?
- It's you.
Look, look, I'm taking you to Hawaii.
Damn, I was trying to be clever.
- What do you mean, you're taking me?
Now is not the time to be clever, Nick.
I'm about to shoot you.
- Whoa, whoa, baby, baby.
Whoa, hey, okay, look.
It was our honeymoon.
I'm taking you on a honeymoon.
It was supposed to be a surprise.
Give me the gun.
- Hawaii?
Are you serious?
- Yes.
How did you find out?
Did Gigi say something?
- No.
Honey, it was on your computer.
I saw it at the house.
Gigi knew about this?
- I needed her to clear
your schedule, baby.
- Honey, get up, get up.
Mm.
Oh, oh, I love you.
I'm so sorry.
Oh, my God.
Laila.
Ms. Ali.
I am so sorry.
I'm sorry.
Please forgive me.
Well, I guess it's okay.
Can't get mad at a woman
for coming after her man.
But you know you did almost
get knocked out.
You still have that gun?
- Mm-mm.
- It's right here.
Don't worry about it.
- Oh, okay.
If she makes one move, you hit
her as hard as you can, okay?
- All right, um, let's pick it up.
Where were we?
- Pick it up?
I never stopped rolling.
- What?
- No, you got to...
You got to erase that.
- What?
- Yes, I'm telling you,
her fist is, like, this big.
- I love her.
- Huge.
- Oh.
- Gigi.
One set of Laila Ali
autographed boxing gloves.
Thank you.
Where's my picture?
- Let me tell you something.
Suzanne almost got knocked out,
I almost got shot.
You better be glad you got those.
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
Got your gloves.
Now knock yourself out.
- Bye.
- B'bye.
- Whoo, looks like we have
a nice trip to look forward to.
- Oh, yes, honey.
And lord knows I could use it.
- Well, if you had paid attention
and proofread that thing
like I told you,
we wouldn't be in this.
- Yeah, but you shouldn't...
- Okay, what is going on here?
- Lindsey got me in trouble at school.
- How did Lindsey get you in trouble
and you don't even go
to the same school?
- Because mom asked her
to help me with my homework,
and she wrote my paper.
- You did what?
- I was only trying to help him,
but he kept playing video games
and I had other things to do.
- So that doesn't mean that you
do his assignment for him.
But how did that get you in trouble?
- When I was reading the paper
in front of the class.
She put in the wrong information.
- Well, what did it say?
- Barack Kevin Obama.
Born August 14, 1961.
He is the 65th president
and the first African-Hawaiian
to ever wear a do-rag
and listen to Jay-Z
in the White House.
He does not surf,
but he does play basketball,
enjoys grape now and laters,
long walks on the beach,
and beating his wife,
at x-box.
Barack Obama rose to prominence
in the ghetto
and then beat-boxed
and pop-locked his way
into the senate,
where he had three platinum albums
and four top 40 hits.
After touring with t-pain,
he left the senate and was featured
on several kanye west mix tapes.
Little known Obama fact:
He won the 2001 MTV Vanguard Award
for playing bass on the song
Give it away
by the Red Hot Chili Peppers.
Follow him on Twitter
at bareezy obeezy.
Thanks.
Any questions?
- Uh, Kevin, can I speak
to you for a moment, please.
- What?
sync and correct by dr.jackson
www.addic7ed.com