responsible for their creation,
courtesy of Hubbard
Electrometer Manufacturing.
I've always wanted one of these
just because they're
kind of goofy.
And they supposedly will tell
you certain information about
your spiritual being.
And if you've rid yourself of
past spiritual experiences
that were negative, and how
whole of a person you are.
The Hubbard Electrometer, more
commonly known as the E-Meter,
is a "religious artifact" used
to measure the state of
electrical characteristics
in the static field
surrounding the body.
E-Meters operate in a similar
fashion to lie detectors.
Relying on a type of electrical
circuit called a
Wheatstone Bridge, which
measures the subject's
galvanic skin response.
In short, the device produces a
small electrical current and
measures the subject's
electrical
resistance to that current.
Wilbert?
WILBERT: Yeah?
ROCCO CASTORO: Please
come over and
get an E-Meter reading.
WILBERT: [INAUDIBLE].
ROCCO CASTORO: Pick them
up again, take
them off the table.
OK, if it rises, the dial moves
to the left, that means
that you're non-confrontational,
your fear
or responsibility or
identification is coming through.
If it moves to the right, that
means you've got losses, lies,
present time problems, and a
disagreement with reality.
OK, so it moves to the right,
which it's doing, I think
Wilbert's got a disagreement
with reality.
Considering that Wilbert was
spiritually void, I decided
that a wider group of test
subjects was needed.
And headed out to Union Square,
where I told people
whether or not they were
good individuals.
This is a sign we made
before we came.
I just want to make sure people
know we're not "those"
guys, if that makes sense.
I'm winking.
You can't see it under
my sunglasses.
Now, don't tell anyone, but
we've commandeered some public
electricity from
the park here.
We don't know if we're
going to get fined or
arrested for that.
Hopefully we at least get a few
meter readings beforehand.
Ladies, would you be liking
a free E-Meter reading?
Would you like to have a
free E-Meter reading?
Ma'am, would you like a
Come get your E-Meter
readings.
E-Meter readings right here.
This is so fucking silly.
Get your E-Meter readings!
Hi.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Hi.
ROCCO CASTORO: Are you
interested in E-Meters?
You're just going to grip these
as so, very lightly.
Oh, wow.
You got some energy.
If you could transport to a time
period, any time period
throughout history, and off
the top of your head, what
would it be?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Harlem
Renaissance.
MALE SPEAKER: 1930.
ROCCO CASTORO: So dinosaurs,
you said?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Dinosaurs,
yeah.
ROCCO CASTORO: OK.
MALE SPEAKER: I'd
have said 1950.
ROCCO CASTORO: Why 1950?
MALE SPEAKER: Well, I
guess I like retro.
I've developed more of a sense
for vintage things since I've
seen all these hipsters.
ROCCO CASTORO: Is that right?
From antiquity, basically.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
And it just feels familiar.
ROCCO CASTORO: Do you feel
like you might have been
around during that time
in a past life?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Oh, yeah.
ROCCO CASTORO: Yeah?
Do you have any inclination of
what you might have done?
And you're falling right now.
So it looks like if you were, it
was a traumatic experience
of some sort.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yeah, there
was, but I don't
want to get into it.
ROCCO CASTORO: It
was bad though?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
ROCCO CASTORO: Do you think that
whatever happened to you
then that was a negative
experience has impeded you in
this life in some way?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Has it affected
decisions I've made
in this lifetime?
Yes.
The answer is yes.
FEMALE SPEAKER: I thought maybe
these rings were messing
it up because you
got me nervous.
ROCCO CASTORO: Well, you're not
supposed to have rings on.
But this whole thing's complete
bullshit anyway, so
it doesn't matter.
Like what's your
favorite color?
MALE SPEAKER Red.
ROCCO CASTORO: OK.
It's dropping, so that kind of
means you might be lying.
What's your name?
ALZEENA: Alzeena.
ROCCO CASTORO: Alzeena, OK.
And it looks like you're kind
of lying about that.
Are you sure that's your name?
ALZEENA: This might be some BS,
because that is my name.
ROCCO CASTORO: OK.
So that does show you're
a good person.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Glad
to hear that.
Not that I needed proof.
ROCCO CASTORO: No, you didn't.
But apparently certain
people believe that
this is proof of that.
So I'm not sure what
to say about that.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Good for them.
ROCCO CASTORO: Good
for them, right?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
MALE SPEAKER: So now,
am I a good person?
ROCCO CASTORO: You're at 2.56.
So would you consider yourself
a good person?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yes, I do.
ROCCO CASTORO: You do?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Falling.
ROCCO CASTORO: It is falling.
Would you consider yourself
a good person?
MALE SPEAKER: Yes.
ROCCO CASTORO: Let's say
somebody beats up your mom or
your sister.
You have a chance to send the
guy to jail, or you can kick
the shit out of him
for an hour and
then send him to jail.
Which would you rather do?
MALE SPEAKER: I'll
send him to jail.
ROCCO CASTORO: Oh, look!
He's fucking lying!
MALE SPEAKER: Nice.
ROCCO CASTORO: I think
we've got a good fix
on your moral character.
The majority of the subjects I
tested seemed to believe my
E-Meter readings wholeheartedly,
which makes me
think that true auditors
are full of shit.
So, oh wow, you're
really just--
FEMALE SPEAKER: What
does that mean?
Is that bad?
ROCCO CASTORO: It's
kind of bad.
FEMALE SPEAKER: So what
does that mean?
ROCCO CASTORO: I don't know.
FEMALE SPEAKER: What do you
mean you don't know?
ROCCO CASTORO: I don't know
what any of this means.
I'm just making it
up, kind of.
How old are you?
FEMALE SPEAKER: 30.
ROCCO CASTORO: 30, OK.
Oh, you're telling the truth.
Oh, maybe not.
Maybe something bad
happened to you.
FEMALE SPEAKER: I was probably
a heroin addict.
ROCCO CASTORO: It seems like
you're pretty at peace with
yourself, and there are
no evil engrams eating
away at your soul.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Really?
ROCCO CASTORO: Yeah.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Oh.
So I would have thought
the opposite.