an apartment in manhattan for six point
five million dollars now that's not
farfetched of course apartments in new
york are extremely expensive
the person who purchased the apartment
was at chinese woman how she is
identified we don't know exactly who she
is admits she was purchasing the six
point five million dollar apartment
for her to year-old daughter
of peace it does business and my wife's
trainees at a two year old need we have
a six point five million dollar bar in
new york
we do not before skepticism and we
really wealthy
your two-year-old needs to be able to
stretch out in a nice apartment in new
york city
belittling kiddo why wife now wide
mentioned you
now kevin brown explains in detail he
says i have
well her daughter was going to see and
go to columbia or n_y_u_ or maybe harbor
and so she needed to be in the center of
the city and that was why she was
picking this one particular apartment
so i said our college and honor and she
said well see still
and i was just shocked unloaded she does
with specificity
let's go to the columbia renoir u
enhance his yet her two-year-old
daughter department at
i got bad news for harbored would be a
telecommute
that seven boston that's going to be
about five hours
place it's kinda fast and she went with
that uh... i think it was definitely
more of a real estate investment that
anything else because she did purchase
that apartment two years ago
and a half frank's did increase
significantly
as i mentioned she takes six point five
million dollars for it
however it now costs
eight point nine million dollars
motorola so in essence you just made
more than enough money um... on her
investments you pay for her daughter's
education
uh... under review for graduated for a
pc
indeed going to do it
live weather is is the most of the
daughter honestly is that in china
uh... there's been sp some laws passed
recently
where the state
uh... you'd only own one property but
not the i don't think that would apply
here
i was kisses in the u_s_ is not in china
nose was a recent she wanted to years
ago
but i don't and bring them up because
i'm not sure if there was some other
tricky pretty do
position for tax reasons as sarah to say
that she bought it for a daughter
because otherwise it's just
wait to absurd now there have been some
accusations as i mentioned we don't have
this woman is that a lot of people are
speculating and death thinking that
maybe she is related to some corrupt
politician in china which is why the
powerful this kind of money abhe
disposal
and i like the smugness this you soon
rooms that are two-year-old limited to
an ivy league school relies on let's
talk about that for a second right so
let's think about hypothetical where as
she's not related to some crop
politician and she doesn't know people
who can pull strings right
and she's just a mother
assumes that her daughter is going to
get into one of the school speak about
the amount of pressure that puts on her
daughter
the who donated a pressured soooo
pressure anyway but what i wanna say
instance that it could
are backing so that's really interesting
i was a ship because
so uh... we have a friend uh...
polyester but that's what i see
his son is an absolute genius like
leaving in season for the words are
his accused
two forty
two forty is off the freakin chart and
he was reading newspapers at the age of
three
okay so u_n_ tour at one of the top
probably bad cop twenty private schools
in the country at one of them is here in
l_a_ nestle when he went to
uh... and he got a perfect s_a_t_ score
but he was a little bored by the classes
and slacked off his sheep here was only
three point nine
but they would release it like that it
was only three point nine
uh... he did not get into a any of the
ideas
sitting in the stanford
didn't get any u_c_l_a_
didn't get into
carnegie mellon
didn't get into paths
okay
so you are receiving your kid is going
to get into an ivy league school
detective so before you read this up
okay and then second of all that within
the constitution of the why what my
two-year-old
seven or one of those whose i do
do what i want to look at what is
necessary getting better than perfect
scores
to get their i'm not so sure about them
and i want them to have a childhood
select wanna put good expectations on
'em but at the same time initially to
compete with these people
all have pervert his state these scores
in
having sheepy is to the rupert steiner
europe with so much pressure on the kid
but he might break in it you gotta have
enjoyed haven't heard enjoyed
there lives a little bit too when their
kids