Man, she better be hot.
Listen, Mexican sideline reporters,
and American sideline reporters
are two different things.
- Yeah, you know
how you never see Hannah Storm
from the waist down?
- Yeah.
- She's the opposite.
No one knows
what her face looks like.
All: Oh!
- Gol!
- Man, look at that.
She's so hot, I would hit
Alyssa Milano in the head
with Fran Drescher
just to get to her.
- Yo, you know what?
Shorty make me want to brush up
on my habla español.
- She is so hot,
elderly couples from long island
spend the winter at her.
- [Laughs]
- I could not play football
with her on the sidelines.
I'd be dropping passes
or running the wrong plays,
showing up to the wrong game.
- You did that stuff anyway.
- Look, if anything
ever happened to me and...
Suzanne, hey.
How you doing, baby?
You're home early.
- Hi.
- All right.
- Hey, guys.
- Okay.
- And that's our cue.
- All right, it's been real.
- Good to see you.
- Next week?
- Hopefully.
Hey, babe, are you
gonna be here next Sunday?
- Uh, I don't know.
Why? You want to go out?
Oh, we could take the ferry
over to bainbridwe
and have some brunch.
- Oh, no, I was thinking about
having the guys over again.
I mean, but if you're
gonna be here,
we'll just go to a bar.
- How come I can't be here
if the guys are over?
- Well, I don't want
to disturb you.
- I never said
you disturbed me.
- That's 'cause you're not here
while we're watching the game.
I mean, if you were,
then you'd probably
be disturbed.
- Oh, I get it.
You don't want me here
when you're watching the game
with your little friends.
- Why does this
have to be about you?
I'm just trying
to watch the game.
- I like basketball.
How come I can't watch?
- You can.
Just not with us.
Baby.
Look, I love you.
But every now and then,
I just need some time
with the boys, you know?
Man time.
- Well, I'm gonna be here,
so you can just go
to your funky little bar
and have your man time.
- Sweetheart,
don't be like that.
Look, what's for dinner, baby?
- I don't know, baby.
Why don't you ask your boys?
- ♪ Are we there yet? ♪
♪ tell me, tell me, tell me ♪
- ♪ tell me,
are we there yet? ♪
- ♪ are we there yet? ♪
Sync &correct by dr.jackson
www.addic7ed.com
- please pass the milk.
- Are you sure
you want me to do it?
Maybe you want one of your boys
to pass the milk.
- I hope you're not like this
when my mother gets here.
- Oh, see, I was thinking
maybe you didn't want me around
when she's here.
I've already interfered
with your man time.
I don't want to interfere
with your mama time.
- Is grandma coming?
- Couple of weeks.
And please,
don't call her grandma.
You know she hates that.
- Why is she staying here?
- I asked the same thing.
- She's moving
into a new apartment,
and it's not ready yet.
- Kevin, she's gonna be sleeping
in your room,
so make sure it's clean.
- I made my bed.
- We mean,
if there's anything in there
you don't want her to see,
get it out of there now.
- Whose bathroom
is she gonna use?
- Ours.
- So he told you to your face
he didn't want you
to see the game with him?
- Yes.
Can you believe that?
- That's great.
Suzanne, that name loves you.
Shoot, I'm jealous.
- Uh, hello!
Are you paying attention?
He told me
he doesn't want me around.
- He's telling you how heels.
I mean, I wish
I had a man that honest.
No games.
No trying to figure out
if he really has money,
or is he just saying that
so you won't get mad?
- So you think Nick's right?
- What do you think?
Do you think he's right?
- No, which is why
I was thinking
that next Sunday,
you and I could go to no hitter,
get the table
right next to his,
and prove to him
that we fit in.
- A little stalker-y,
don't you think?
- You cannot stalk
your own husband.
- Mm.
You could be the first.
- Ooh.
Lord, I haven't slept
in a little boy's bed
since you peed in mine
when you were five.
Remember?
- So what happened
at your old building?
- Oh, they're tearing it down.
Apparently some guy cut corners
when they were putting it up,
so now the whole thing
is falling apart.
- Sounds like Lindsay Lohan.
- Uh...
- Hang on.
- Well, you know,
it works for me.
I got temporary housing fees,
and with that money,
I was able
to buy myself a new watch.
Bam!
- Ooh.
Don't tell Suzanne about that.
She might try to put you out.
- Hmm, I wish she'd try.
- Hey, Marilyn, can you...
- I know. You want me
to take you shopping.
- I've been saving up
to buy something.
- Saving up?
I'm impressed.
What is it?
- A pair of baby puff pants.
- What is a baby puff?
- It's P. Diddy's daughter.
She has her own clothing line.
- What's in the collection,
leather onesies
and platinum sippy cups?
- How much
do these things cost anyway?
- $150.
- $150?
I'm not letting you
spend that money
on some baby pants.
- Girl, I can make
that outfit for $20.
All I need is some fabric and my.
- Really?
You can make clothes?
- Where do you think
they come from?
- Stores.
- I told you not to put
these kids in public school.
- Hey, mom.
- Kevin, what are you doing?
- I'm building a tent,
because one day,
the world's gonna end,
and we're gonna be roaming
the streets like nomads.
Only the strong will survive,
and I'll be ready.
Can you open this?
- No.
- Hey, baby.
- Did you tell him
he could do that?
- Yeah.
He wanted to sleep
under a bush outside.
- Well, I would have
appreciated it
if you had talked to me
about it.
Or maybe this is another one
of those conversations
you can only have
with your boys.
- All right.
Game, set.
Uh.
Match.
But you are being unreasonable.
- I'm not being unreasonable.
- Okay, you're not.
- Don't patronize me.
- I'm not patronizing you.
I'm agreeing with you.
- But if you don't believe
in what you're agreeing to,
then you're patronizing me,
and I don't want you
to give up your principles
just to please me
or start lying to me
and doing things behind my back
because you think
I can't handle the truth.
Nick, I married you
for who you are.
- What are you talking about?
I mean, are we arguing?
Are we agreeing? What?
- You want me to take you
back through it?
- No, no, look.
Do you want to come watch
the game with us on Sunday?
- Are you asking me?
- I thought
that's what I just did.
- No, you asked me
if I wanted to come.
You didn't say
you wanted me to come.
- Okay.
Suzanne, I would like for you
to come watch the game
with me and the boys on Sunday.
Would you like to go with me?
- Why you got to say it
like I'm two?
Okay, okay.
I'm just playing.
Yes, thank you.
I would love to come.
[Chuckles]
- Man, she got all up
in your head.
-Day six.
- It's getting rough out here.
I miss my family and...
I'm almost out of honey o's.
[Mechanical whirring]
- Wow.
You're good at that.
Where'd you learn how to sew?
- School.
They used
to actually teach you stuff.
See, you used
to get out of school,
you had a diploma,
could get a job,
and lead a life.
Now you get out of school,
you're in debt, dumb,
and back at home.
- What's a diploma?
- Oh, lord.
Anyway, we didn't wear
designers back then.
And there was none
of this shopping all year long.
Oh, no, you got your new clothes
at the end of August,
and they had to last you
the whole year.
- But what if they went
out of style?
- Then you went
right with them.
[Both chuckle]
- Excuse me, ma'am.
Mind if you use your plug?
- What you supposed to be?
- The future.
- Go ahead.
See, that's the problem
with imagination.
- [Chuckles]
[All cheering]
- Oh.
- [Scoffs] Can I get
you guys something else?
- Si, si, a plate of nachos,
por favor.
- I'm not Spanish.
- I know, but you got me
speaking in tongues.
- Man, I would love
to get lost at sea with you.
- In that scenario,
we'd both end up dead.
- Listen, I want to apologize
for the behavior of my friends.
It's their make-a-wish day.
But if you'd like
to get together
and I could apologize
more, you know, vigorously...
- Whatever, Robin Thicke.
Walking away.
- Watching you walk.
- Hey, hey, hey.
All: Hey.
- Look who I got with me.
Hoo-hoo.
- Hi.
- Hey, guys.
- What's up, guys?
[Clears throat]
- There you go, 'zanne.
- Nick, you didn't mention
you were bringing Suzanne.
- Ah, you know, it's funny.
Nick didn't want me to come,
but I said,
"I like your friends.
I like basketball."
I thought this would be fun.
- Well, good for you.
- Great story.
Um, Nick,
I have got to show you
this autographed Jersey
they have out front.
- I saw it on the way in.
- No, you didn't.
This way, please.
What the hell
is wrong with you, man?
- You heard her.
I told her not to come.
- Well, then what is she
doing here?
- I asked her to come.
- Why would you do that?
- Dude, I'm married.
Now, where's
this autographed Jersey?
[All cheering]
- Oh, yes, baby.
- Whoo.
- That's what I'm talking about.
- Here you go, sweetie.
- Uh, gracias.
- Does your wife know
you speak Spanish?
- Uh, no comprende?
- [Chuckles] "Sweetie," huh?
[Laughs]
Somebody's looking
for a big tip.
Ooh!
- Oh!
- Did you guys see that?
All: No.
- Oh.
- Oh, damn.
- Rondo is playing
like a little girl.
Why doesn't he just take it
to the hole?
- Because every time he does,
they put him on his back.
- Thank you.
- I like the kid.
- Me too.
- Ten bucks says he scores
next time up the floor.
- Definitely.
- I'm in.
I want some of that action.
- Okay, y'all must like
losing your money.
Honey, can I have $10?
- [Chortles]
- Yes!
- Oh, man.
- You're gonna give me a chance
to win my money back, right?
- All right, Danny DeVito,
trying to man up.
- [Chuckles]
- Ten bucks says that's a ten.
- No way.
I'm taking that bet.
- [Chuckles] Booyah.
[Laughs]
[Humming rhythmically]
What? What?
20 bucks that's a charge.
- No, no way.
- All right,
that's my last $20.
- Ha!
- Oh, my God.
- Come to mama.
- That's it.
I'm done. No more.
- Me too.
- What about you, Martin?
You want to go again,
double or nothing?
- Uh, I think I'm gonna have
to go with nothing.
I am Toni Braxton broke.
- [Groans]
- Well, I guess we're done here.
I'll see you guys next week.
- Yeah, definitely.
- All right, guys.
- Yeah, see you later, Nick.
- [Chuckling] That was fun.
- Yeah.
- Hey, guys.
We're home.
- Hey, everybody.
Hey, Kevin.
- So how was the game?
- Oh, it was good.
- Ooh.
[Chuckles]
- Mom, dad,
look what me and Marilyn made.
- Oh, my God,
those are amazing.
You made those, Marilyn?
- That's right.
Stick with me.
You might learn something.
- I can't believe it.
They look just like
the real baby puffs.
But here's the best part.
Bam!
I got my own designer logo.
- Go take those off.
I need to finish
the inside seams.
- Okay.
- Nice work, Marilyn.
- You're lucky
I'm staying here,
or I'd be charging you a grip.
- Today was a good day.
Plus, I got some spa money.
- I am tickled pink
that you had a good time.
- Oh, come on.
Don't pout.
Admit it.
The guys had a blast,
and you know it.
- It may have looked
that way to you,
but what you just witnessed
was a master performance
of a show called
"men holding back
'cause a woman was there."
- [Chuckles] Okay.
You are just mad
because you wanted it to suck
and it didn't.
- You wouldn't say that
if it was you.
- Oh, no, see,
that's where you're wrong,
because women don't need
to change their behavior
just because
there's a man in the room.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I have some spa appointments
to book.
Oh.
And I want my $65.
- Buenos dias, ladies.
- Hi.
- Gracias.
- De nada.
For you?
- Thank you.
- You're very welcome.
Chbo.
- I love this spa.
- Mm.
- Ooh.
That boy would make me
get my weave wet.
[Laughter]
- And I know he broke,
but he almost makes me
want to slum it.
[Chuckles]
- Well, I'm glad I don't know
what his name is,
'cause I might accidentally
say it in my sleep.
[Laughter]
- For the purpose
of this conversation,
let's just call him...
Nick!
- Nick, hi.
- Hey.
Who's ready to get pampered?
- Avocado hot stone
shiatsu massage.
Whoo, that sounds messy.
What are you guys gonna do?
- Uh, I'm getting
the Nicky massage.
- I'm getting the first lady,
and my cousin here
is going for Oprah's big "o."
- It's organic.
- Mm, that sounds good.
- Oh, Suzanne, look,
cucumber water.
- I have water.
- No, no, not this water.
What's wrong with your man?
- What?
- You know Jevonne's boyfriend
just cheated on her.
I mean, we're trying
to cheer her up.
We can't do that
with your man here.
- Well, I didn't know
he was coming.
- How can you not know
he was coming?
- He's my husband.
How am I supposed to know
what he's doing?
Is that the cucumber water?
- Girl, sit down.
- So what do you say, spalding?
You want to surf the web?
No?
Yeah, you're right.
I guess I do need
to conserve the battery.
How about just one video?
Let's go for a classic.
Let's see.
I used to listen to this song
when I was a kid.
It's called the good life.
It's good, right?
Shh.
Try not to sing so loud.
- Kevin.
- Shh.
- I know you're in there.
- We don't want no trouble.
Ain't got nothing here for you.
And I'm telling you,
you don't want to come check.
- Whatever.
When Marilyn wakes up
from her nap,
tell her I went to the mall.
[Door clicks shut]
- [Exhales sharply]
It's about to get violent.
- Ooh.
Now, this would look good
on your toes.
- Mojo melon, huh?
Uh, okay.
Suzanne, you didn't tell me
Nick knows so much about toes.
- I didn't know.
- I didn't think most black men
cared about feet at all
till we saw boomerang.
That changed everything.
- Oh, my God.
Boomerang.
[Laughs] Eddie Murphy.
Oh, for years,
I wouldn't date anybody
that didn't have a mustache.
All that chocolate.
- Can you believe Halle Berry
played the plain girl
in that movie?
- I know, right?
And earth a kitt.
"I am not wearing
any panties, Marcus."
[Laughing]
You put this on,
me and your toes are gonna need
a moment to ourselves.
- [Laughs]
- Oh, here.
[Scoffs] Look at this.
Another reality show...
Real housewives of hip-hop.
- What?
Now, you know there only
but three wives in all of rap.
Everybody else
is just a baby mama.
That's what they should
name the show,
the real House of baby mamas.
- [Laughs]
- See, I couldn't have
all those cameras in my house.
- Oh, they might catch
some of that toe activity.
- How are you doing,
señoritas?
- Good.
- Ooh, I'm great.
- Fine.
- Fantastic. I'll be back
to check on you in a few.
- Those pants are tight.
- I know.
- Those pants make skinny jeans
look like sweats.
- I know.
- And that shirt was so tight,
I bet he could only breathe
through one lung at a time.
[Hyperventilating]
[Laughter]
Look, you do push-ups, dude.
We get it, all right?
The auditions for twilight
are over.
- Right.
- Shamar Moore called.
He wants to challenge you
to a eyebrow wax-off.
- Oh, that's funny.
- You can't get tighter
than that.
It's impossible.
- It's ridiculous.
- Nick?
We're ready for your pedicure.
- [Grunts]
- Uh, you're getting
a pedicure?
- Well, I was gonna get
some of these lumps
on my head worked on,
but getting my feet cleaned up
just seemed like the way to go.
[Laughs]
All right, ladies,
I will see you
on the other side.
- All right.
- Next time, bring you.
Uh, uh, uh.
- Oh, let's make a plan.
You better work.
[Laughs] Look at him.
He looks so funny.
[Laughs]
Bye, Nick.
- Hey.
- Hey, sweetie.
Look at you.
[Both chuckle]
- Marilyn, are you leaving?
- Yeah, they got my place.
And as sad as it makes me
to have to leave here,
got to go.
Fresh white carpet awaits.
Hey, turn around here
and let me take a good look
at your little fine self.
That is a nice jacket.
Where'd you get it?
- It's a baby puff.
- For $100?
- Since I saved the money
by making the pants,
I got the jacket instead.
- Lindsey, the only reason
I made you those pants
was because I was trying
to teach you
the value of a dollar.
And then you turn around
and pay $100 for that?
Girl, you missed
my point entirely.
- I'm sorry, Marilyn, but you
kind of missed my point too.
- And what would that be?
- I wanted some baby puff.
- You know, you ain't too old
to get choked.
I'm surprised more kids
don't go missing.
- Hey, babe.
Where's Kevin?
- Uh, he smelled.
I made him take down his tent
and get in the shower.
You look relaxed.
- My feet feel so good
from that pedicure,
I can't stand up.
- [Laughs]
- All that soaking,
massaging, moisturizing,
clipping, buffing, polishing...
I have never been treated
that nice in my life.
- Well, I'm glad
that you had a good time.
- I had a great time.
But honestly, I was doing it
to get back at you.
I thought I'd feel uncomfortable
around your girls,
but they were cool.
- No, they weren't,
and neither was I.
Nick, you proved your point.
I need to let you and your boys
hang and have fun.
I'm sorry.
- Hold on.
Can you say that again?
- Nick Kingston-persons,
I'm sorry.
- An apology and a pedicure.
Ooh, throw in a clock radio
and some socks,
and I don't need another gift
till I retire.
- [Chortles]
Well, listen, I'm glad
that you had a great time.
But I never want to see you
in that place again.
- Can I go
when you're not there?
- No.
- What am I gonna tell
that white girl, then?
[Applause]
Sync & correct by dr.jackson
www.addic7ed.com