lowest obesity rates
colorado comes in at number one on the
eighteen point seven percent of the
residence in colorado are peace coming
in number two is massachusetts and
montana connecticut california new tires
on a rhode island idaho new jersey
and washington mom sound anne as you
know i'm not surprised that colorado's
lotto
hippies biking karun
ride and windows
those guys it i don't know why but i
feel like colorado their all super
fidelity in the mountains
the green in that
and they don't work hard at work in the
lines are all on by x
drawing malcolm's
of a big believer yet colorado make
sense that present resembles a lot of
translate means
we favor top ten year rightly so um...
you know i i'd look at the margin of air
with this gallup study and i think that
they're underestimating the margin of
error and all discuss why in just a
little bit but al let's look at the ten
states with the highest obesity agreed
sentiment
coming in a number one is of west
virginia in fact in west virginia i has
been the most of the state
for the third year
uh... coming in over to his mississippi
than arkansas louisiana alabama kentucky
tennessee of high oklahoma and i wanna
unity secure anyway that was a pattern
here
okay nida self is a very well
represented
and they're almost allred states
bell-violin said that i wasn't but there
you know they're purple
is so it's
and i know i've been in west virginia
excitement
we were at the end of the most part of
that
they sell six on top of that that
patients dogs dogs
seventy and i was prepared for the pratt
state three years of war
that's incredible
um... while just to give you an idea of
you know what we're dealing with overall
about twenty six point two percent
of the united states is all these
however i do have an issue with the way
that they did the study now i have the
study was basically based on self
reporting
they called about three hundred fifty
thousand americans in all fifty states
uh... hands-off reporting already makes
me a little skeptical of the results
that they also uh... ask for their front
and their weight so they can calculate
b_m_i_
the issue of the sea bass at v_m_i_'s we
always do you agree to solve this
v_m_i_'s bs
they dislike super strong gusting
kentucky west virginia right
that fault lines
nowpublic really the other thing that is
is is all of those things are poor
and i wanted to leave therefore you are
the more likely you are to be obese is
very ironic when you think about it
but it makes sense this you're jumping
it was mostly courtroom who
seagram's fast food is really cheap
i go six happens in west virginia i
think they were ridiculous if you
remember boost
two dollars three dollars but couldn't
believe how
well was it may be why it's it's not
that good
you know i couldn't possibly permission
but before i i i believe those numbers i
think that
you know they might not be exactly right
but within the right context
i think some of those
statistics with a few more outdoor
activities in opening a groovy serotypes
aside
uh... they're more likely to be fair
in the states where there's a lot of
poverty they likely to be more of these
yep definitely in and uh... and of
course in
you always know that it's about
what you eat like healthy nutrition
means more attend the exercising too
exercise is good to keep your muscles
healthy your bones health the
abut
at the end of the day the most important
thing is what you put in your body and
what you eat
so you can you'd like
the six hot dogs and and do a little bit
of exercise the exercise means nothing
site and by the winters in connecticut
california massachusetts
so the richest states in the country
there on the most fit
cop so
as part of it