ERIC KOSTON: Things started to
get a little different over at
World with Rocco.
He was always able to throw
money around and, oh, if you
do this, I'll give you
$100, and he'd just
have a wad of cash.
After a time, it was fun, we
would always get cash off him.
Being young, we didn't
trust him.
Everyone started to mutually
feel that way, but never did
we get to the source of it and
talk it out and, hey, Rocco,
man, are you ripping us off?
None of us were old enough or
responsible enough to confront
something like that.
It's like, oh, no,
I'm convinced.
Fuck that dude.
Let's bounce, and that was it.
TIM GAVIN: We were riding
for Blind at the time.
I remember in '92, that's when
he started to hang out more
with Guy, and Rudy,
and me, and Henry.
And then I would bring the dude
up to LA periodically.
And I don't know when Eric
really got the cool
card with the crew.
I don't know when
that happened.
I don't--
I think it was we evolved
as friends during
those Plan B years.
In that two year span, we
all got really close.
GUY MARIANO: We started going
up to San Diego to hang out
with Eric and skate with Eric,
and I think Eric was coming
down here a little bit more.
I did a lot of World Park days
with Eric, and that was
interesting because if you've
ever seen Eric skate a skate
park, it's amazing.
And you can only imagine him
at a super young age just
really going for it.
I remember when we started Girl,
we were actually off of
Wilshire at Macy's, this
ledge off stairs.
And it was me, Tim, Henry
Sanchez, and Eric, and Rick
was telling us he's thinking
about starting this company
and he wanted all of
us to ride for it.
ERIC KOSTON: I remembering
me and Guy going, sure.
Let's do it.
Didn't really even
second guess it.
That would be awesome.
AARON MEZA: I heard about it
that weekend they came out at
the contest.
Mike York was like, everybody
just quit World.
They all started this company.
ERIC KOSTON: What's funny is
that that Back to the City
contest, in SF, I was already
up there just skating.
And [INAUDIBLE]
came up to the contest, and
then I wanted to tell him.
And he just looked at me and he
goes, are you leaving too?
And I was like, yeah.
And he was like, all right.
The team was sick.
It was all the dudes that we
hung out and skated with
anyway, so it was perfect.
TIM GAVIN: I was the last
dude to get on Girl.
Eric was definitely on before
me, because I was the last
dude on, literally.
I really befriended Eric.
We just became tighter.
He moved up to LA, and
we moved in together.
I think we were the only
dudes that had an
apartment in our crew.
MIKE CARROLL: His house was
definitely the crash pad.
It was just staying up until
like 5:00 in the morning
playing "Mortal Kombat" and
then getting up at 2:00 or
3:00 in the afternoon, going and
eating burritos, and then
maybe hit a spot that day and
skate, and then just do that
same old thing.
ERIC KOSTON: We were one of
the first ones to have a
place, so it's the play
house, basically.
It's the place that there's no
adults, and we started to
drink a bit and want
to get chicks.
I feel like Schner was the one
who brought the Arizona
drinking aspect into it.
TIM GAVIN: He never was
interested in drinking or
smoking pot, but whenever
he did, he was a
total fucking disaster.
I remember this one time he
fucking drank, and I think it
was the first time he smoked
weed, and he ate a box of
Cheez Its, and just
fucking threw up.
The entire house was
fucking orange.
MIKE CARROLL: I forget who it
was, but someone walked in on
Eric on all fours on his bed
after drinking Jaeger or
something like that, just
puking onto his bed.
It was that age for everyone.
Everyone's first drinking
experience, drinking the
shittiest Cisco and
all that shit.
MALE SPEAKER: People were
telling me about Mike York
pissing in one of your shoes.
That was a story that came up.
ERIC KOSTON: Dude, I still
have the shoe.
MALE SPEAKER: No.
ERIC KOSTON: Yeah.
York, what the fuck
are you doing?
And he just mumbled and he was
just like [MUMBLES], and his
back's to me, so he's
just like [MUMBLE].
TIM GAVIN: Apparently Mike
York does that a lot.
I guess he's known to take a
walk sleeping and piss in
random places.
Eric was so devastated
about this piss in
his Air-Pacs, man.
It was fucking hilarious.
I mean, fuck, those were
our college years.
Those were fraternities,
our dorm rooms.
I would do anything to get back
there and be living with
Eric again.
It was lame, but it was the best
times of our lives, dude.
GUY MARIANO: We would wake up in
the morning, he'd make egg
McMuffin sandwiches for
everybody and coffee.
He's the man.
It was Koston, dude.
Koston used to make me breakfast
every morning, and
for that matter, like
five other people.
AARON MEZA: I wouldn't even
be like, hey dude, is
it cool if I stay?
We'd all stay there.
Mike Carroll, York, everybody.
We'd stay there forever.
I mean, if you know Eric, he's
super generous, but I don't
think he necessarily wanted a
lot of people staying at his
house and making a mess
of the place.
He's not like fucking come
one, come all, fuck yeah,
party at my house.
He was just dealing with it
because he's so nice.
I mean, he would come pick me up
at the airport and we'd go
skate, and it was
just for years.
Seriously, since "Goldfish"
through the "Chocolate" tour I
stayed at his house.
MALE SPEAKER: Where did you
start actually taking a part
really serious?
Or have you always?
ERIC KOSTON: It was probably
"Goldfish" or really wanted to
get a good part.
Because that was Girl's
first video, too.
I wanted to make sure we
had a really sick video
when it came out.
Everybody did, just to
back the company.
TONY FERGUSON: It
was definitely
mellower, not as intense.
It was more of a friendly, fun
vibe, and I think that's what
Mike and Rick wanted
to portray.
It was everyone skating
together.
We would go skate the
same spot everyday.
We'd be at the courthouse.
That was just to take it
back to funner times.
MALE SPEAKER: Do you remember
the first time
you filmed with him?
AARON MEZA: I remember filming a
line with him at [INAUDIBLE]
that was super long with
tons of hard tricks.
I think he backside heelflips
over a wall in "Goldfish." I
just couldn't believe how
much good stuff was in
it how long it was.
I wouldn't necessarily say every
time we went out we got
something, but it's pretty
obvious he was definitely
fucking so naturally talented.
I think the most naturally
talented skater ever.
Back then when he was young and
carefree and only had to
skate, it was a joke how
he could do anything.
SAM SMYTH: And now I see
more people like that.
I feel like, at the time, he
might have been the only one
that I've ever seen work that
way or skate that way, where
he could do anything
that he dreamt of.
ATIBA JEFFERSON: Back then, it
didn't seem like skateboarding
was his main focus.
It seemed like being a young
kid was his main focus.
I mean, I really watched
skating turn
into his main priority.
"Mouse," you saw it.
That part to me is you're
seeing, oh, he's finally
taking skating seriously.
He's finally using
his potential.
His "Mouse" part, Eric's part.
His video parts have always
been better and better.
I don't know, dude.
He's just good.
GUY MARIANO: During "Mouse," me
and Eric were really close.
I was definitely living
with him at the time.
I liked being around Eric.
He pushed me on a skateboard.
I think things would have been
a lot different if I didn't
spend a lot of time with Eric.
I don't think I would be as
good of a skateboarder.
Not to say that I was
on Eric's level.
Eric's always been
way above me.
But I looked to Eric for what
was the next thing, and what
was possible.
TONY FERGUSON: Sometimes the
video doesn't give it justice.
[INAUDIBLE], we were skating
down with Eric one time,
because he did five tricks in
10 minutes on this rail.
It was insane.
He did nollie 50-50,
and he was like,
oh, I like this rail.
He did nollie frontside
noseslide, nollie frontside
nose grind, and then nollie
frontside nose blunt.
TIM GAVIN: Everyone
knows Eric's good.
I want to tell this, though.
In the "Mouse" video, when I
did that 50-50, I remember
Eric was trying it too, and I
did that before Eric did, and
it made it in the video.
I had to get that on record.
I mean, I consider Eric one
of my best friends.
I've known the guy for 20 years,
lived with him for 10,
I fucking barely know the guy.
ATIBA JEFFERSON: For a dude who
mumbles and is the worst
guy to talk to on the phone and
have a conversation with,
he really is good at acting
not like himself.
Even the Charlie Chaplin thing,
his personality and
charisma is so good, I'm
very surprised he
didn't go into acting.
SPIKE JONZE: The one with Eric
as Charlie Chaplin, we were
shooting something else
that day, I forget
what we were doing.
Something at the warehouse.
And then we wanted
to do that too.
And the thing that made that
one work is Eric had never
heard of Charlie Chaplin, or I
guess he'd heard of him, but
never seen any of his stuff.
So I bought him a box set of
Charlie Chaplin VHSs, and he
went home and watched it
over and over again.
And OK, here's what makes
Charlie Chaplin funny.
And he went and just sort of
studied his Charlie Chaplin.
I guess, knowing Eric, if he's
going to do something, he's
going to take it seriously.
AARON MEZA: I feel like he's
like a lot of the dudes that
have to do it, he
can pull it off.
They moved into the old
man thing, he was
pretty fine with it.
That's pretty hard to have to do
that stuff, but I feel like
he has done better than some
of the other guys.
Where someone like Tim was
awkward about it, or just way
nervous, I feel like he's always
been pretty good at
that stuff.
SPIKE JONZE: Yeah, we'd done a
set of boards with everyone
old a few years before that, so
it came out of that idea.
Whatever dumb idea that
anyone comes up
with, it's made a reality.
I don't know if they
ever pulled that
out for the box set.
The dailies of that stuff,
I could've just
watched that for an hour.
That stuff's best.
What school are we from?
MALE SPEAKER: We're from Santa
Monica Community College.
SPIKE JONZE: OK, Santa Monica,
what about Santa Barbara
Community College?
MALE SPEAKER: Santa Monica
City College.
SPIKE JONZE: You stop and you're
sipping your coffee,
and you look up and
down the street.
You see a set of stairs, and
then you get an idea.
You start pushing, and pushing
harder, and pushing harder,
and then racing towards the
stairs and then launch down
the stairs.
And then in slow motion,
close up view with
wind in your hair.
And then you land, come to a
stop, and proudly look back at
the stairs you've conquered
on your wheelchair.