This is the dish you want to cook for the
girlfriend, the boyfriend, get the mother
in law round. It's going to be super, super
good.
We've got some beautiful fresh salmon, that's
300 grams there. That's going to serve four
people.
Three heaped tablespoons of Malden sea salt
goes in there. Most of that is going to come
away but we need that salt to penetrate that
fish to cure it.
It gives you this sort of incredible waxy,
delicate texture that allows you to slice
it really thinly, easily and it looks and
tastes amazing.
So we want to add more flavour in there, brown
sugar one heaped tablespoon like that. Lemon
zest, orange, half of the zest. Then we're
going to use dill.
That, for later, but this part here, the stalks
really sweet. Slice it up and that's all going
to fall off so that's flavour for free, nothing
in the bin. And then the secret ingredient.
Some decent vodka. One shot.
This is not traditional, right but it adds
to the whole kind of flavour that we're after
here.
Massage up that lemon, vodka, sugar. What
I want to do is pack that salt onto this salmon
and put the other salmon on top.
Get a bit of cling film and we're simply going
to wrap it up super tight.
Put that in the fridge, I do it in the morning
by 12, 1 o'clock in the afternoon it's ready
and raring to go. If you leave it a little
bit longer it will get firmer and firmer and
firmer. Nine hours is fine, but five hours
is optimal.
This is what it looks like after 5 hours.
It's firmed up nicely. I'm actually just going
to brush this salt off, normally in a gravadlax
recipe you would to wash it off. You don't
need to do that.
We're going to use our dill. What I want to
do is kind of create a little herby bark on
the outside. Just finely chop it.
Right, and then the fish goes straight into
that. See how it just coats it beautifully?
Absolutely gorgeous. This goes into the fridge
until you need it.
What I'm going to do now is show you how to
make the beautiful horseradish sour cream
and beautiful crushed marinated beetroots.
So, so simple. Roughly, for four people. Two
heaped tablespoons of soured cream, about
two heaped teaspoons of horseradish, it's
got to have attitude or otherwise why bother?
Then half a lemon, do you remember the one
I grated? Squeeze it, catch the seeds. A nice
little pinch of salt. A little bit of quality
extra virgin olive oil in there. One tablespoon.
Mix it up.
All you really need to do is taste it for
seasoning and heat. Nice and hot makes your
nose go a little whoo hoo!
Next, beetroots, add a little bit of balsamic
vinegar, nice pinch of salt, a little oil.
I quite like crushing I like it being rustic.
That is going to be joyful. I'm going to have
a little clean up so you can fast forward!
Okay, so missus is coming round, mother in
law and the old man is coming round. If they
turn up and you're hot and sweaty and look
stressed. Not cool. Even if you're bad with
knife skills you'll manage half or just over
half a centimetre.
It's nice and thin. It's almost you can see
the light through it.
You've got the herb there, you know it's fresh
but it's lightly cured.
Towards the end just kind of flare it out
to take the salmon off because you don't want
that skin.
The second way of doing it.
Take the end off, you're simply going to take
your knife along the bottom of the salmon
and that takes all the skin off in one. All
of this you can do in advance. Okay so we've
got that on the plate. Horseradish sour cream.
Just going to do a little pile there.
I love the way the beets just kind of bleed
into the beautiful sour cream. You've got
the salon. It's really, really nice dish.
1980's cress. A nice bit there, fresh dill.
From a height just pick it off. Really nice.
A little olive oil.
Look at that absolutely gorgeous.
If someone gives that to me I am so chuffed!
Really, really good!
So good!
The salmon is lightly cured so it's got that
lovely sort of waxyness that you get from
things like smoked salmon and prosciutto and
stuff like that really nice to eat.
Beetroot's just sweet and gorgeous the heat
of the horseradish. So good!
So to go with this gorgeous dish for this
lovely night out, how about a nice cocktail?
An old Cuban. Click the box below and I'll'll
show you just how to do it. You're gonna love
it!