I can't wait to start cooking today. I'm going
to cook a classic Italian lamb stew. You going
to enjoy it.
You know what is look like? If you have ever
been home for twenty years and then out of
the blue you go back home and your mamma,
your friend, your pappa makes this dish. It
look like if you never left home.
First shoulder of lamb, put them in a bowl.
Salt, not too much, a bit of pepper in. Mix
it all together.
Extra virgin olive oil.
Anchovies, yes! That is give them a little
bit extra salt, make sure you melt those anchovies.
Now, lamb goes in. oh yes! Seal it.
It means, you make sure that the meat is all,
almost roasted, almost until all around. It
keeps the lovely flavour inside. Look at the
lovely colour.
You can see all the anchovies dissolved.
Now I'm starting with a carrot. I cleaned
this one I did not remove the skin. Cut it,
don't do it too small. Look at the colour!
Mmm. Oh. Straight in.
Give them a little stir now.
Now two onions should be enough to one kilo
of meat which will feed well four people.
I just chop them roughly. Yes.
Here in Malta this is the celery they have
so I use the leaves for later.
And then slowly you chop it. Look all in.
Such a simple dish to make. Give them a stir.
This is what we call a modore.
A modore is a, is a, a kind of a, a sense
of a flavour.
Keep stirring it, do not turn off the hear
because you wont to get a lot of water out.
Let the juice seal everything nicely.
Now I put a couple of clove of garlic.
Look what I do with the clove of garlic, I
press it remove it the skin, goes straight
in.
Next is the chilli. Do you know if the chilli
is very strong, you break it, you smell it.
Oh this is strong, I will use, for four people
half a chilli. Straight in. I keep stirring
it.
Nearly, nearly there.
Now thyme, let your feeling go walking in.
It's like to fall in love, you want to caress
your love. And this is what it does.
Look at that inside here! Yeah!
Wine. You put inside about a glass of wine.
Keep stirring it. And let almost all of this
wine evaporate. You need to balance with a
bit of vinegar. White wine vinegar.
Wow! Everything dance inside there. It is
a celebration. the smell which is overtaking
you!
I'm going to keep the smell the flavour all
inside, so I need a lid. I improvised one.
Aluminium foil, you can do exactly the same
cover. Turn it down and let's wait in for
20minute and I will show you what's happen.
Oh, my my!
Taste it wise. Yes! Yup, this is the way I
want it. Now potato, three potato. You cut
it, easy, put it inside. Yes.
Now, I need the extra little bit of salt.
It's for the potato only and it will be pepper
because pepper is a spice. Cherry tomatoes.
It's like a little plum tomato. They're so
sweet, so good. It's incredible.
Straight in. Give them a quite stir.
Now at this stage, you need to add to it about
250ml of stock. Mix everything together. You
turn the gas down. Cover it again and cook
it for about 35 minute to 40minutes.
Look how tender, I can squeeze everything
out. Mmmmm. So good! I can taste the flavour
of everythings. Now I have here some frozen
peas. If this was fresh I would have put in
about 20 minutes ago. Fantastic. Look at that
the colour already.
Give them a quick stir. While this one is
cooking. Maltese bread, yes!
Ah, yup this is ready. Ahh. Let's turn this
one off.
Celery leaves, chop them up very fine. Lovely.
A little bit of extra virgin olive oil.
And this is my classic Italian lamb stew,
which I've done with a shoulder but you can
do with a leg. My god, it's so good!
It is incredible because I'm eating the stew,
bring memories back. With the family, with
the friends. What a celebration. My god, it's
so good! So good! I'm sorry, I am sorry this
time.
WHY AM I COOKING SO GOOD?!
Don't forget, Jamie Oliver Food Tube channel
subscribe. It's free. I love you Malta. Wow!
Whyy?!?!