SUROOSH ALVI: We're at the Erez
crossing, which is where
you enter Gaza from.
So apparently, when you go into
Gaza, you have to walk
until you get to the
first town there.
And--
[GUNFIRE]
SUROOSH ALVI: And apparently,
that walk is
very dangerous, because--
[GUNFIRE]
SUROOSH ALVI: Because
you can get shot.
It's been brothers killing
brothers over there, Hamas and
Fatah, fighting over control
of the Gaza Strip.
Hamas declared victory.
Hamas is saying, you know,
enough with moderation.
It's time to create a proper
Islamic state.
We are driving through the Sinai
Peninsula on our way to
the Gaza Strip.
In 2007, we were filming in
Israel and we tried to access
the Gaza Strip through
the Erez crossing.
We couldn't get in.
It was sealed off.
Four years later, we are now
accessing the Gaza Strip
through Egypt, through
the Rafah crossing.
After the Egyptian Revolution,
the crossing was opened up.
The people wanted to support
the Palestinians inside the
Gaza Strip.
They've been under a blockade
by air and by sea.
It's been inaccessible, sealed
off to the outside world.
So it's finally open now, and
we're going to go in and see
what life is like for the
people of the Gaza Strip
underneath Hamas rule.
[HORN HONKING]
SUROOSH ALVI: Now even though
the Rafah crossing is open, it
doesn't make getting
in any easier.
MALE SPEAKER 1:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
SUROOSH ALVI: When we got to the
entrance, it was a jammed
mess of suitcases and people
screaming to get in.
MALE SPEAKER 2:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
SUROOSH ALVI: With our passports
and a little bit of
patience, we eventually pushed
through the chaos, slipped
through the gate and
into the clearing.
SUROOSH ALVI: After that, we had
to go to a holding center
to get checked and vetted again,
which ended up taking
about three hours.
The place was packed, but the
vibe inside was a bit calmer
and more organized and
it was outside.
People seemed genuinely excited
to be entering the
Gaza Strip.
MALE SPEAKER 3:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
SUROOSH ALVI: We eventually got
put on a bus, drove past
the border marker, and got
dropped off in Palestinian
territory on the other side.
The whole bus trip lasted about
three minutes, and we
drove the distance of about
two football fields.
But we couldn't argue
with protocol.
We were finally in
the Gaza Strip.
The drive from the border town
of Rafah in the south to Gaza
City in the north is just 25
miles, which gives you an idea
of just how tiny the place is.
According to the UN, more than
two-thirds of its 1.6 million
residents are refugees.
Even though Gaza is small,
it's a crucial part of
Palestine and completely
isolated from the West Bank.
In 2006, Gaza held elections for
the first time, and much
of the world was shocked when
Hamas, a group that the US and
Europe classify as a terrorist
organization, won.
The Bush administration, who
had championed elections in
the Arab world, were
obviously less than
thrilled with this outcome.
They began working to isolate
new Hamas-controlled
government.
In addition to helping impose a
blockade that cut off Hamas
from the outside world, they
equipped Hamas's rivals,
Fatah, with a raft of new
weapons and training in hopes
that they would unseat
Hamas from power.
It didn't work.
After a succession of
assassinations, kidnappings,
and street battles between Hamas
and Fatah, Hamas took
complete control of the Gaza
Strip and, for the first time
in its history, had to figure
out how to run a government.
MALE SPEAKER 4: [SPEAKING
FOREIGN LANGUAGE ON
LOUDSPEAKER]
In the days before we arrived,
militant groups inside Gaza
had been launching rockets into
Israel, and the Israelis
responded by launching
attacks on what they
called terror cells.
When we got to our hotel, we
could see Israeli drones
flying around everywhere.
Kind of screwed up our plan--
doing a story on Gaza without
ever mentioning Israel.
The constant buzzing of drones
overhead made us super
paranoid that anything
place we went
could be blown to bits.
Like the Hamas government
building where we met with the
group's spokesman,
Fawzi Barhoum.
SUROOSH ALVI: Can you explain
to me why there were rockets
being launched into Israel and
why Israel was bombing Gaza
over the last few days?
Why did the cease-fire
break down?
SUROOSH ALVI: Who
attacked first?
SUROOSH ALVI: Israel attacked?
SUROOSH ALVI: Islamic Jihad
is a group that--
it's more radical, I
think, than Hamas.
SUROOSH ALVI: The resistance
against Israel is part of the
fabric of everyday life in Gaza,
so when a militant group
like Al-Ansar decides to have
a pop-up press conference in
the middle of a busy street,
nobody bats an
eye, except for us.
Holy shit.
MALE SPEAKER 5:
[SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: And like
that, they were gone.
It was a hell of a first
day in the Gaza Strip.
[HORN HONKING]
SUROOSH ALVI: We're going
on patrol with the
Hamas police force.
Apparently, there's some
kind of fight going on.
We're going to see who's
kicking whose ass.
After the 2007 battle with rival
Palestinian faction,
Fatah, Hamas came out on top,
which meant most Fatah
supporters got the
hell out of Gaza.
So we were surprised when the
police rolled up to an entire
Fatah neighborhood.
We seem to be in
Fatah-controlled
territory right now.
Their flags are flying
everywhere.
And I'm not sure why we're here
or what the police are
investigating.
MALE SPEAKER 6:
[SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: What they seem to
be investigating with this
full-on show of force was a
minor building code violation.
MALE SPEAKER 6:
[SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: Hamas has a
reputation for imposing a
strict rule of law.
MALE SPEAKER 6:
[SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: Even more so if
you're a member of Fatah.
So basically, Hamas was just
harassing Fatah supporters.
SAMAH AHMED: All Fatah
members here in
Gaza cannot to anything.
The situation controlled
by Hamas.
She's the government and
she's the security.
She's everything.
It's not easy to have your
normal daily life with Hamas.
If the security of Hamas came to
any restaurant, any opening
places, and find boys and girls
sitting together, they
start to ask about the kind of
the relationship between you,
if it's legal or not.
Sometimes I feel that they
occupied my mind.
I didn't want to say that
Fatah is the best.
They have many faults.
They do many mistakes.
But at least they are
better than Hamas.
SUROOSH ALVI: Hamas viewed
the Fatah-run Palestinian
Authority in the West Bank as
an inherently corrupt entity
that failed to provide basic
services for Gazans and looked
the other way when it came
to alcohol and drugs.
Much of Hamas's popularity comes
from the fact that they
are seen as honest and
incorruptible.
And when they took power, they
put a concerted effort into
stomping out all forms
of vice in Gaza.
But the same tunnels that allow
Hamas to smuggle in
weapons from Egypt also allow
for a steady flow of drugs.
SAMAH AHMED: They're children
working in the tunnel.
They are 12, 13.
They are smoking and
taking drugs.
Through the tunnels, many kind
of drugs can enter to Gaza,
because there is no control
on the tunnels.
SUROOSH ALVI: So because there's
no control in the
tunnels, Hamas are constantly
doing drug raids around Gaza.
MALE SPEAKER ON RADIO:
[SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: And they round up
all kinds of drugs in all
shapes and sizes.
SUROOSH ALVI: Cocaine balls.
MALE SPEAKER 6:
[SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: It's cocaine in
perfectly formed triangles,
which is odd.
Lot of little bricks
of hash and pills.
SUROOSH ALVI: That's
100 grams?
MALE SPEAKER 6:
[SPEAKING ARABIC]
MALE SPEAKER 7:
SUROOSH ALVI: Now things like
hash and cocaine are pretty
standard for a drug raid.
But the biggest drug problem
in Gaza is Tramodol, or as
it's called there, Tramol.
Tramol is a prescription
painkiller that has become the
drug of choice for young people
looking to escape the
reality of life in Gaza.
MALE SPEAKER 6:
[SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: And where
is it all coming from?
Is ti coming from Egypt?
MALE SPEAKER 6:
[SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: Through
the tunnels?
MALE SPEAKER 6:
[SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: We decided to see
if we could find some kids
to talk to who might
be using Tramol.
Our fixer, Raed, said he knew
just the place to go.
RAED: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: We are now hunting
for kids on drugs, and
we figured a park is
a good place to go.
In my experience, parks are
great places for stoned kids
to hang out.
The psychological impact of
living under occupation in a
place that's sealed off
is really heavy.
They're poor, they don't have
jobs, they've lost their
family members to war.
They're turning to drugs.
They're numbing the pain.
They're trying to find a way
to escape, and the only way
they can do that is through
pharmaceuticals.
We spotted some kids hanging out
in the corner of the park
and walked over to them.
I let Raed do the talking.
MALE SPEAKERS: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: Really?
SUROOSH ALVI: They don't care.
MALE SPEAKERS: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: So according to
these kids, Tramol became more
popular after Hamas came to
power, and its reach is still
spreading, in spite of all the
crackdowns and in spite of the
harsh punishments suffered
by people who got caught.
People who we would be
meeting the next day.
[MUEZZIN GIVING CALL TO PRAYER
OVER LOUDSPEAKER]
SUROOSH ALVI: After seeing the
Hamas police squad show off
all the drugs they've
confiscated in raids across
the Gaza Strip, we wanted to see
what happens to the people
they catch.
Gaza City's central prison is
home to both drug smugglers
and drug users.
MALE SPEAKERS: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: We read that
drugs are a big problem.
For the crime of smuggling
drugs, or smoking hash, or
adultery, what are
the punishments?
SUROOSH ALVI: And how do
they execute people?
They hang them?
SUROOSH ALVI: Shooting.
Wow.
Heavy.
SUROOSH ALVI: It's all drugs?
And how many prisoners are
in this room here?
SUROOSH ALVI: 36?
In this one room?
SUROOSH ALVI: He's a good man?
SUROOSH ALVI: Why does
he like you so much?
SUROOSH ALVI: Right, right.
That's why he's being
nice now.
SUROOSH ALVI: How do you
know that they will
come back after Eid?
SUROOSH ALVI: Put the whole
family in jail.
SUROOSH ALVI: Anyone ever
escape from here?
SUROOSH ALVI: OK.
SUROOSH ALVI: How many women
are in the prison?
SUROOSH ALVI: That's all?
SUROOSH ALVI: In all of Gaza?
JAMILA AL-SHANTI: Yes.
SUROOSH ALVI: And what
are the crimes that
they're in prison for?
SUROOSH ALVI: Right.
[MUEZZIN GIVING CALL TO PRAYER
OVER LOUDSPEAKER]
SUROOSH ALVI: Rather than
letting us visit the women in
their cells, the women's warden
dragged the female
prisoners out and put them on
display for us in a room that
they apparently use to make
prisoner arts and crafts.
[MEOW]
SUROOSH ALVI: It's a
bit of a PR show.
They're giving them,
you know, like warm
clothes for the winter.
Basically, it's--
it's odd.
It's a bit weird.
She's the boss.
FEMALE SPEAKERS:
[SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: We weren't allowed
to interview the women
on camera, so we had Raed find
out what these women had done
to end up behind bars.
This woman here is in jail for
two years because she helped
her son escape and get out of
Gaza Strip illegally, to go to
Israel or the West Bank.
I'm not sure where he went.
And she was smiling and was
actually saying it with pride,
which was interesting.
The woman who had the little boy
out of wedlock, she is in
jail or six years
for that crime.
For having a kid
illegitimately.
SUROOSH ALVI: That's
interesting.
So basically what you're saying
is that Hamas is very
progressive when it comes
to women's rights.
SAMAH AHMED: Actually, it's a
complicated life for the women
and also for all the
Palestinians.
But especially for the women,
the girls, you cannot do
whatever you want.
It's not easy, actually.
SUROOSH ALVI: Just to be clear
about this, women's rights now
compared to five years ago,
how is it different?
SAMAH AHMED: The wife cannot
go to the police station if
she getting beated
from her husband.
Before, you can go to
the police station.
SUROOSH ALVI: Right.
SAMAH AHMED: And the police
station told the woman, just
go and solve your problem
with your husband.
I wish that Hamas didn't
win the election.
I have many good memories
with Hamas members.
We have been like brothers
and sisters.
But when they get the
power, they changed.
Gaza became another country.
It's not anymore a part
of Palestine.
SUROOSH ALVI: We're at
the Hamas police
station in Gaza City.
These are unexploded bombs, and
the police just told us
that they found a bomb in Khan
Yunis, a town nearby, and
they've asked us if we want to
go with them and watch them
blow the bomb up.
And we said yes.
The bomb squad grounds were
overflowing with tons of
unexploded ordnance, including
the infamous Qassam rocket,
which was developed by the
military arm of Hamas.
MALE SPEAKER 8:
[SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: We're looking
at a Qassam rocket.
It is made in a secret
underground
factory here in Gaza.
It's not very accurate.
It has a range of eight
kilometers.
Often not very effective.
Some Palestinians think it's
more trouble than it's worth.
But it has created a lot of
problems for Israel, and has
them living in fear in
the southern cities
of Ashdod and Ashkelon.
So these are all the
unexploded bombs.
Grenades in here.
Mortar shells, a lot of them.
Bit freaky in here.
MALE SPEAKERS: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: Just as we were
looking at all the weapons in
the truck, everyone started
freaking out and pointing up
at the sky.
It turned out that what we had
witnessed was Israel's test of
a new long-range missile capable
of hitting Iran.
We were happy it wasn't going
to come down on our heads in
Gaza, but it was a potent
reminder of the strength of
Israel's military.
It feels like everyone
was anticipating
something to happen.
Israel's been saying for the
last couple days these
cryptic, veiled threats.
They're going to go in and solve
this problem once and
for all in Gaza.
What does that mean?
Now that we were all completely
paranoid, we headed
off into the desert with our
truck full of bombs.
We're riding along here behind
a rolling bomb, essentially.
The truck is full of unexploded
ordnance.
We have grenades, landmines,
mortars, rockets.
They're loose, bouncing around
in the back of the truck.
We're driving through
crowded urban areas.
We just passed a school.
It doesn't seem like they're
taking a lot of precautions,
but it hasn't blown up yet.
Come on, man.
What are you doing?
Fuck!
No, that's good.
I'm good.
All right, you having fun now?
You enjoying yourselves?
We are on a former Israeli
settlement.
It's the only place in Gaza with
enough open area where
you can blow something
up without someone
getting killed or hurt.
I can't help but point out the
irony of blowing up Israeli
bombs that were left
here where Israeli
settlers used to live.
Makes us nervous.
You know, like, I don't know
that one of these things isn't
going to go off.
They're just dumping it off the
truck, dropping things.
Shouldn't they be exploding?
All right.
I--
I'm done.
MALE SPEAKERS: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: This is
the final stage.
We've left two cameras, one
right by the pit of bombs and
the other one up on the hill.
Hopefully they don't
get blown up.
We're trying to convince George,
our cameraman-- that's
you-- to stay here and
get a better shot.
But he doesn't seem to
be too into that.
Our producer Jason courageously
and/or stupidly
volunteered to go film
in the bunker.
MALE SPEAKERS: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: Feels
a little chaotic.
Apparently, they're having some
technical problems now.
MALE SPEAKERS: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: I'm more worried
about Jason inside of that
doghouse bunker that he's in.
MALE SPEAKER 9:
[SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: No?
MALE SPEAKERS: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: They're telling
us to get down.
MALE SPEAKERS: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
[EXPLOSION]
[SIREN]
SUROOSH ALVI: Behind
me is the crater.
It was done successfully,
although it took a while.
It didn't detonate the
first couple times.
And as we were sitting around
waiting, I thought about this
morning when the Israelis
launched a super high-tech
missile And then meanwhile,
20 kilometers over.
It's like a cartoon.
Not particularly calculated
and kind of chaotic.
Maybe that sums up life
in Gaza Strip.
We're doing some shopping
right now.
Got some--
some swag.
Al-Qassam.
MALE SPEAKER 10: Yeah, Hamas.
SUROOSH ALVI: Hamas
Military Brigade.
SUROOSH ALVI: Yeah, why?
The drone?
MALE SPEAKER 10: Yeah,
of course.
SUROOSH ALVI: Will it get me?
SUROOSH ALVI: I'm not worried.
I'm not wearing the right
shirt, though.
Like a button-down shirt with
my Islamic Jihad headband?
Doesn't really work.
I'm going to keep it on.
I'll go shopping with it.
I'm kidding.
All right, we'll take
those also.
Just as we were getting into the
groove of things in Gaza
and were starting to relax, we
found out that the border
crossing was closing
unexpectedly.
RAED: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: Raed got on the
phone to try and convince them
to keep the crossing open
long enough for us to
get back into Egypt.
We are trying to get to the
border now, to Rafah crossing.
If we don't make it there before
noon, then we might be
stuck in Gaza, in which
case, we'll have to
go through the tunnels.
Samah decided to hitch a ride
with us, hoping that she might
slip through in the chaos.
So if you get through today,
that's a pretty big deal.
Means that you're maybe not
being targeted anymore, or--?
RAED: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: In spite of Samah
having a visa to travel
to Germany, the Hamas border
guards weren't having it.
And we were rushed along without
her, leaving her
behind the walls of
the Gaza Strip.
RAED: [SPEAKING ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: After our first
try to get into Gaza in 2007,
it took us years to
finally get in.
In reality, if Israel hadn't
made it so hard to get in in
the first place, I don't think
we would have been so curious
about what was going on
behind those walls.
When we first arrived, we were
really impressed by this kind
of orderliness that you don't
see in many places that are as
poor as Gaza.
But then as we began to realize
that this was purely
the result of Hamas's
authoritarian approach to law
and order, it began
to creep us out.
MALE SPEAKER 11: [ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: The Hamas
government operates in an
environment of paranoia that
has them on guard not only
against the outside world but
against their brothers and
sisters in Fatah and against
ordinary Gazans, whose
poverty, they fear,
could tempt them
into spying for Israel.
What we have here is an
authoritarian government
operating within prison walls
and under economic siege.
It's like the set up for a Kurt
Russell movie, except
that it's real.
But as we crossed into the
chaos of post-revolution
Egypt, part of me just wanted
to turn around and go right
back to Gaza.
MALE SPEAKER 12:
[SPEAKING ARABIC]
JASON MOJICA: What do
you want money for?
MALE SPEAKER 12:
[SPEAKING ARABIC]
JASON MOJICA: Can we go?
Go, go.
[RAED AND MAN ARGUING
IN ARABIC]
SUROOSH ALVI: Can we
drive the car now?