BILLY BAD ASS: All right.
This is a grand finale tonight,
before we go to London.
I'm going to announce
one of the models.
She's going to be selected
to go to London.
And we're going to
make it happen.
CHARLET DUBOC: En route, he got
a call from Arlene, one of
the models from the casting.
She was already waiting at the
club, but none of the other
girls had showed up.
ARLENE: I'll see you
when you get here.
BILLY BAD ASS: All right.
Bye.
ARLENE: Bye-bye.
WILLIAM FAIRMAN: Who was that?
BILLY BAD ASS: That's
one of the models.
WILLIAM FAIRMAN: Arlene?
BILLY BAD ASS: Yeah.
BILLY BAD ASS: Yeah, Arlene.
WILLIAM FAIRMAN: What was she
saying about the other girls?
BILLY BAD ASS: I charge
a registration fee.
They didn't want to pay it.
WILLIAM FAIRMAN: They've
turned up, though?
BILLY BAD ASS: Hmm?
WILLIAM FAIRMAN: They've
turned up to
the place, or not?
The girls?
Are there other girls outside?
BILLY BAD ASS: No.
Arlene is the one that
is ambitious,
that wants to do this.
The other girls--
if $100 is going to hold them
back to go to London, they
don't need to go.
So what I'm going to do is I'm
going to announce that
Arlene's coming.
CHARLET DUBOC: Because she's
the only one that showed.
BILLY BAD ASS: She's
the only one that
showed that was qualified.
CHARLET DUBOC: I was worried.
Billy didn't seem to be
choosing a girl on her
modeling ability, but more
her willingness to
part with her money.
So what can we expect from
the announcement?
BILLY BAD ASS: People clapping
and happy for her.
WILLIAM FAIRMAN: Are
you excited?
BILLY BAD ASS: Yeah.
I'm excited.
I'm always trying to outdo what
I've done in the past.
I'm calm and collected.
I have to stay smooth, though.
CHARLET DUBOC: OK.
Let's do it.
As soon as we arrived at the
museum bar, it was clear no
one here was expecting
Billy Bad Ass and the
Urban Fashion Week.
After negotiating with the
bouncer, we were finally
allowed in.
The stage that Billy had
intended for the announcement
was occupied by a jazz band,
leading a Sunday dinner dance
for a subdued older crowd.
As I followed Billy wandering
aimlessly around the club, a
cold feeling swept over me that
maybe the London Urban
Fashion Week was all just
smoke and mirrors.
We eventually found ourselves
on a balcony,
where we met Arlene.
BILLY BAD ASS: I didn't even
realize those pants you had
on, those shiny,
glittery pants.
CHARLET DUBOC: Well, Billy,
I thought you
were a fashion guy.
So what are we doing up here?
BILLY BAD ASS: Well, we're just
going to announce that
this young lady right here is
going to be going to London.
ARLENE: Shut up!
[SCREECHES]
CHARLET DUBOC: Really?
ARLENE: Wait, wait a second.
Let me take it all in.
I'm taking it all in.
So I'm going to London?
BILLY BAD ASS: Yeah, you're
going to London.
ARLENE: [LAUGHS]
Oh my goodness!
CHARLET DUBOC: $100 for the
privilege of standing on this
cold balcony.
So much for the big
announcement.
Arlene seemed thrilled.
But I was skeptical.
ARLENE: Whew.
I'm just taking it
all in right now.
I was just shocked.
Charlet!
This is crazy!
CHARLET DUBOC: Why
are you shocked?
ARLENE: I've never been
overseas, ever.
And to have an opportunity to go
overseas, plus do something
that I've been trying to
pursue for a long time.
BILLY BAD ASS: What we're going
to do is you're going to
fly over there on Wednesday.
You're going to get
there on Thursday.
We're going to do a fashion
casting party where all the
designers are going to come.
And you're going to go
somewhere. we're going to have
a photoshoot.
We're going to hang
out on Friday.
We don't know where we're going
to hang out on Friday.
ARLENE: OK.
OK.
BILLY BAD ASS: But the camera's
going to be rolling
wherever we're going to be at.
CHARLET DUBOC: So what's
going to happen now,
between now and London?
What are the preparations?
BILLY BAD ASS: We're
going to talk about
that off the camera.
CHARLET DUBOC: Off camera?
Why off camera?
BILLY BAD ASS: I mean, you know,
we'll talk about it.
CHARLET DUBOC: OK.
BILLY BAD ASS: Yeah.
We waited outside the club for
Billy to have his off-camera
chat with Arlene.
Suddenly Arlene left.
And we got a silent ride back
with Billy, slightly unsure
about what had taken
place between them.
It was our last night
in Atlanta.
And by this point, I had no idea
what was going on, let
alone whether the London Urban
Fashion Week was going ahead.
The following morning,
Arlene called us.
She wanted to talk about last
night, and invited us over to
a photo studio across town on
our way to the airport.
ARLENE: He said, Arlene, I need
to speak with you inside,
away from the camera.
So I said, OK.
He said, so now you've won.
I have to let you know that
you're going to need to come
up with another $600.
He said, I'm sure you can come
up with it some kind of way.
I'm sure there's family
members that
could help you out.
There was no documents.
I did not sign up
for anything.
Everything was just happening
so suddenly.
Anyhow, nonetheless, I don't
think that I should pay.
CHARLET DUBOC: Yeah.
ARLENE: And that's what Tyra
Banks said on her show.
CHARLET DUBOC: So do you realize
now-- does it feel
like you were exploited?
ARLENE: Yeah.
I feel like it wasn't
authentic.
But a part of me wasn't
surprised.
Because here in Atlanta, there's
so many people who's
always trying to take advantage
of people here in
the model world, the music
industry, acting.
CHARLET DUBOC: Are you relieved
or disappointed?
ARLENE: A combination of both.
A combination of both.
I'd be lying if I said I wasn't
disappointed, because I
saw it as an opportunity to
further a potential career in
the model industry.
CHARLET DUBOC: It was clear
now that Billy had a very
unorthodox way of working.
And if teasing money out of
young girls with a desire to
break into the fashion industry
was it, we weren't
going to have anything further
to do with it.
OK.
So we're on our way
to the airport.
And I've still got one last
thing to do before I leave
Atlanta, which is call Billy and
break the news that we're
no longer going to be covering
his event in London.
So here we go.
[PHONE RINGING]
CHARLET DUBOC: Billy never
answered the phone.
I felt so disappointed in him
for taking these young
people's good nature for
granted, but also couldn't
help but pity him.
Could it be that as well as
being the villain in this
story, he is, in fact, his own
worst enemy, the victim of his
own environment and aspirational
culture, where
people will do anything
to get ahead?
It turns out Arlene isn't the
only girl who's been affected
by Billy's opportunistic
work practice.
There's a whole load of
disapproval online from other
disgruntled fashion people
who've had the misfortune of
stumbling across the ill-fated
Urban Fashion Week.
DISGRUNTLED VLOGGER 1:
How do I say this?
DISGRUNTLED VLOGGER 2: This con
artist, this thief, this
savage bastard named
Bill D. Foster--
"D" stands for "Dumbass,"
by the way.
DISGRUNTLED VLOGGER 3: And we're
forcing the models to
sell tickets, or better yet,
we're telling the models in
the fashion show that if you
sell enough tickets, you'll
get a flight to Paris.
Does that even sound right?
DISGRUNTLED VLOGGER 2:
God don't like ugly.
And karma's a bitch.
And when you fuck with people,
you get it back times 10.
DISGRUNTLED VLOGGER 3: I'm not
even going to say it's your
first time, because you
know what, sweetie?
It wasn't your first time.
So that means that
I have to go in.
I have to go in you with
no lube and raw.
DISGRUNTLED VLOGGER 2: It's such
a wonderful thing to know
that he's being banned from
a list of cities.
He cannot show.