HAYDEN GILLIM: We've had this
track for four or five years
and we've been riding
on it every day.
FRANKIE GILLIM: The good thing
is, now they're all old enough
that they can look over
the littler kids.
So I don't have to sit
up here and babysit.
They crashed a lot.
Now they crash and
it's all funny.
Back then they crashed
and it'd be
like oh, I hurt myself.
My granddad owned this
28 acres here.
That used to be his house down
there, his barn, raised
cattle, worked in tobacco.
KERRI GILLIM: They started
racing when they were about
six and eight and my family
all had raced.
So I raced when I was young,
my uncle's family races, my
dad raced, so we just always
have been around it.
I just want him to have fun.
I try not to think about
the whole if he's going
to make it or not.
Because life's too short.
I want him to experience it,
and I went him to enjoy his
friends and the whole
entire thing.
HAYDEN GILLIM: I crashed
at Indy--
it's pretty beat up.
And I got all the trophies from
last year that I got, and
the Rookie's Cup.
Canteen that my grandpa
gave me that he had
in the Vietnam War.
And then this is a plate
that was in my
collarbone last year.
Right after I broke my
collarbone, I won that weekend.
So it was a good and
bad weekend.
And that t-shirt was
made right after my
little brother died.
It's a picture of three of us
on the podium at the Flat
Track Nationals.
Picture of him holding
his Youth Dirt
Tracker of the Year trophy.
There's a picture of him and
then I'm right there, he's
beating me.
I had to stop wearing
it, couldn't put
it through the washer.
KERRI GILLIM: He was the clown,
the one that scared
everybody, the one that
kept us all laughing.
He was almost 11--
May 5, 2007, he died.
And it was just really
a freak accident.
I wasn't there, his dad
and Frankie Lee
and Hayden were there.
And he just got into some kind
of wobble that just took him
up into a wall and
hit the wall.
Just too much force for his
body to take, and he died
about 15-20 minutes
after he hit.
DANNY WALKER: Hayden was one of
the first guys there, and
he knew right away that it
was really, really bad.
It's still something they
struggle with constantly.
KERRI GILLIM: Two weekends
later, he actually went to a
race and I wasn't
crazy about it.
Then when I was watching all of
them, the only time at that
point through that whole year
it seemed like that's where
they were the happiest.
So I was like I can't
make them stop.
Five laps and you're
coming in.
MALE SPEAKER: [INAUDIBLE]
doing a five lap race.
KERRI GILLIM: Five lap
race and done.
The more kids you have and the
more people you have at your
house, the more likely they'll
stay at the house and then you
know what's going on.
HAYDEN GILLIM: Owensboro has
a lot of kids that race.
Everybody always comes over to
our house, just because we
have a track and our parents
don't really care about how
dirty the house gets.
Barbecue here's amazing.
This is Kentucky.
You don't find bad barbecue
in Kentucky.
KERRI GILLIM: Once Ethan died,
all of his friends at first,
the first few months, stopped
coming over because I don't
think they knew where
their place was.
And then as we would say you
could come over, come over.
And then they came over and
would realize it's not creepy,
it's OK to talk about him.
MALE SPEAKER: Oh, Hayden.
I'll see if you can spell a
three-letter word, like sweet.
But it's harder if they
weren't here.
Then it would be lonely
and Ethan
wouldn't have liked that.
FRANKIE LEE GILLIM: Me and
Hayden, we're real
competitive.
We road race, we don't really
race each other.
But flat track, we're in the
same classes and stuff.
I get more mad if he beats
me than anybody else.
Because it's my brother and we'd
be riding home together
and if I say something wrong,
he'll be like well, sh, be
quiet, I beat you today and it
makes us all mad and stuff.
Because we ride here together,
we can push
each other to go faster.
HAYDEN GILLIM: During the
summers, it's really hard to
get yourself motivated to work
out because of the heat.
The average is 90 degrees,
and then the
humidity here is horrible.
It just makes you have to push
that much harder with how the
landscape is here.
FRANKIE GILLIM: I don't think
any of this year he's actually
been mentally prepared.
It's kind of thrown a curve ball
to me to try to figure
out what to say to him.
Try to help improve or try to
help him realize that it's
just a learning process
and this is
something you have to overcome.
KERRI GILLIM: The first year I
think that they worried about
me and Frankie more on how we
were taking it, how we were
living, how we were
going to survive.
But the second year, I've always
heard it's worse on the
kids and it is.
I think this second year's
been really hard on them.
DANNY WALKER: I'll never,
ever, ever,
get over losing him.
It's weird, it's just such
a strong spirit--
you don't come across
those that often.
And the 10-year-old that's made
such a difference in my
life on how I talk to people
and treat people.
It's really a tough thing for
the Gillim family, and
everybody that was there.
It's a tough thing to go OK,
we're sending him back out.
HAYDEN GILLIM: I'm not
scared to die.
As long as I'm going to heaven,
I'll just embrace it
and I'll go up there and hang
out with my little brother and
all the friends that
have died racing.
I'll just go up there and hang
out with them, race some
motorcycles.