[MUSIC PLAYING]
RAVI KAPUR: My name
is Ravi Kapur.
I am the executive chef
here at Prospect.
We've been open a little
over a year.
Before that I was at Boulevard
as a chef de cuisine.
That was super influential on
how I think about food and how
my cooking is influenced
by the guest.
So we're not just--
we're not serving macaroni and
cheese and fried chicken.
But we are not isolating
ourselves, just cooking solely
what we believe in and
not thinking about
the guests as well.
If people aren't coming
in, we're kind
of missing the point.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
RAVI KAPUR: Thanks guys.
-See ya tomorrow.
-All right.
-Have fun.
RAVI KAPUR: We just
left Prospect.
Got my girl, Nana, and we're
heading up to To Hyang for
some Korean food.
We rarely get out at the same
time, but I evacuated her.
ROXANNA GUARDIA: [LAUGHING]
RAVI KAPUR: Now we're going
to get some food.
And the other two sous are going
to meet us when they're
done closing up the shop.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
RAVI KAPUR: So I started cooking
in Waco, Texas, at a
pizza parlor.
All my friends worked there.
I made pizzas.
But I never considered
myself a cook.
I was like, shit, I really
enjoy cooking.
And I moved out to San
Francisco, went to culinary
school out here in '98.
And that's kind of where
it all really, I
think, formally began.
-We're just going to head
back out this way.
RAVI KAPUR: I really like this
place because the woman that--
she's the owner, she's the
proprietor, the chef.
She pretty much makes all her
condiments and everything
that's a part of her cooking.
-This is where she keeps her
fermented bean paste.
RAVI KAPUR: She makes it all
in house, which is not very
common at all.
-We try to keep it as close
to authentic as possible.
RAVI KAPUR: Yeah, so
this is awesome.
I'm inspired by the way she
approaches cooking.
I don't think that if you're in
a really modest environment
that the core philosophy of how
you cook should change.
Maybe your ingredients
are different.
Your price point is different.
Your uniform might
be different.
But the way that you approach
the food, and approach the
ingredient, and how you deliver
it, I think should be
at the highest level possible.
From what I've had here, this is
probably my favorite dish,
the ox tails and the dates,
just savory sweet thing.
So this is a, what, 30-year-old
ginseng from the
mother land.
ROXANNA GUARDIA: [LAUGHTER]
-I'm hungry.
ROXANNA GUARDIA: We started
without you, sorry.
RAVI KAPUR: So this is the
tofu bean paste, yeah?
And then pork ribs.
But that's the winner.
And then this is
the pork belly.
CHRIS WADE: Oh my god.
RAVI KAPUR: Restaraunts aren't
just easy, and like super fun
to do, and we make
a ton of money.
It's a labor of love,
honestly.
If you don't love it, it really
makes no sense as to
why you would do it.
We're new and we're just, as
far as-- we're working out,
we're still working out kinks.
We're learning stuff about
ourselves every day.
But I feel like this is a place
that I don't need to be
poaching pig balls and pig
bladders and cutting it open
at the table.
So there's not--
while there are boundaries,
they are pretty vague.
I can go pretty far
here, depending on
how we package it.
CHRIS WADE: I went to the
beach on Thursday.
Over to Stinson beach.
And it was kind of an
overcast cloudy day.
I didn't feel the need to
put any sunscreen on.
I was out sun bathing,
and didn't really
think much of it.
My feet are so swollen they
barely fit in my work shoes.
RAVI KAPUR: He was like
walking around,
it was really sad.
[LAUGHTER]
RAVI KAPUR: No, you guys
should eat it.
I'm kind of getting full.
ROXANNA GUARDIA: We're gonna
go get a burger, man.
CHRIS WADE: We're gonna
get burgers?
RAVI KAPUR: This town is
like a ghost town.
ROXANNA GUARDIA: It just dies
as the hours progress.
Where do we go now?
RAVI KAPUR: The only
place that's open.
-The only place that
will have us.
RAVI KAPUR: Then we go to Nopa
where it's like super hip.
And not intentionally
hip, but just fun.
And they like doing
the right thing.
Their liquor program
is banging.
The wine list is killer.
Food is delicious.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
RAVI KAPUR: First of all, they
use really great, really great
ingredients.
Lawrence is at them.
I don't know, the last time he
told me, I think he goes to--
I want to say 14
markets a week.
But I might be exaggerating.
But definitely seven days
a week, they're
shopping at the markets.
And I think with Prospect, it's
totally share the same
philosophy and vision.
Without great ingredients
it doesn't matter
what you do to it.
It's not going to be--
where you take it if
it's mediocre.
It's so amazing to be a
chef in San Francisco,
especially right now.
I feel like the network of
farmers, and growers, and
purveyors that we have access
to is vast and increasing.
I've been super fortunate
to have close
relationships with farmers.
I can drive an hour and a half
north and I can go to the farm
where I get my goats from, or an
hour south and go see where
my peppers are coming from,
and onions. and all that.
It's kind of unique.
-Yeah, I think all of us
started off in lesser
restaurants, and enjoyed it.
And kind of progressed
to where we are now.
I didn't start in a restaurant
like Prospect.
RAVI KAPUR: Yeah she [BLEEP]
worked A.M. shift at a
cafeteria in Buffalo.
-In Buffalo.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
-Most burgers are
gray and [BLEEP]
That is nice and pink.
RAVI KAPUR: Nice rind
on there, though.
It's like fine, but
not too fine.
-They got it down.
I guess after five years--
-The best non-diner burger
in the city.
[LAUGHTER]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
RAVI KAPUR: This is really all
I do, and all I've done.
And all I ever really planned
to do is to cook and be in a
restaurant that I believe in.
Cook delicious food and take
care of your customer.
That's really, it's really what
we're here for at the end
of the day.
I can't really see myself
cooking anywhere else.
San Francisco is just great.
So we'll see.
[MUSIC PLAYING]