ALL SERE IS, IS A TERM WE USE FOR THE DIFFERENT
SUCCESSIONAL STAGE THAT'S OCCUR LEADING UP
TO
A CLIMAX. IT IS JUST A TERM TO DENOTE A PREDICTABLE
STEP IN THE ORDERLY SEQUENCE OF COMMUNITIES.
THAT IS
REALLY ALL IT IS. I PROBABLY COULD HAVE GOTTEN
BY
WITHOUT EVEN MENTIONING IT. IS THE TERM TAXON
LIKE SERE? OKAY. YOU HAVE TO SAY IT AGAIN.
THE
QUESTION IS, DOES THE TERM TAXON AND SERE
HAVE REAL
MEANINGS OR ARE THEY JUST FROM THE PERSPECTIVE
OF THE
OBSERVER? WELL, TAXON TENDS TO HAVE A MEANING.
WHEN
WE SAY TAXON, WE TEND TO MEAN A PARTICULAR,
A PARTICULAR TAXONOMIC UNIT. NOW, YOU ARE
RIGHT, IT
CAN VARY IN THAT SOME PEOPLE REFER TO A SPECIES
AS
A TAXON. A GENUS AS A TAXON OR A FAMILY DEPENDING
ON
WHAT LEVEL THEY ARE IDENTIFYING IT. SO YOU
ARE RIGHT
ON THAT. SERES, YES THEY ARE, THEY ARE IDENTIFIED
BY
SOMEONE DESCRIBING THEM. BUT, THEY USUALLY
ARE MORE
SET THAN THE TERM TAXON. IN OTHER WORDS WHEN
YOU
DESCRIBE A CERTAIN SERE YOU REALLY MEAN A
CERTAIN
STAGE IN THAT SUCCESSION. BUT, YOU ARE RIGHT
IT COMES
FROM THE OUTSIDE. IT IS MADE BY A DESCRIBER.
INTERESTING IDEA. NEVER HAD THAT. ANY OTHER
QUESTIONS BEFORE WE START?
OKAY. WE ARE GOING TO ADVANCE TO THE FINAL
AND
THE HIGHEST LEVEL OF ECOLOGICAL ORGANIZATION.
WE ARE
REALLY GOING ALL OF THE WAY TO THE TOP TODAY.
GOING TO THE ECOSYSTEM. TO THE ECOSYSTEM.
THIS IS
AGAIN, IN OUR PROGRESSION FROM POPULATIONS
TO
COMMUNITIES, TO ECOSYSTEMS. WE ARE GRADUALLY
GETTING
MORE COMPLEX. AND, AS YOU CAN SEE BOTH IN
YOUR STUDY
SHEETS AND IN WHAT ARE WRITTEN ON THE BOARD,
ECOSYSTEMS ARE THE INTERACTING SYSTEM THAT
INVOLVES
BOTH OF LIVING ORGANISMS, IN OTHER WORDS,
THE
POPULATIONS IN THE COMMUNITY AND THE NON LIVING
ENVIRONMENT. OKAY. SO THE INTERACTION IS
VERY
INTEREST IN THAT IT HAS A VERY, VERY SET DIRECTIONAL
COMPONENT. FOR EXAMPLE, ENERGY FLOWS THROUGH
THE
ECOSYSTEM. IT FLOWS FROM THE PRIMARY PRODUCERS
TO THE
CONSUMERS TO THE PREDATORS. SO THERE IS THE
FLOW OF
ENERGY. BUT, THERE IS THE CYCLING OF NUTRIENTS.
AND
THIS CYCLING OF NUTRIENTS AND THE FLOW OF
ENERGY IS
REGULATED. IT IS REGULATED AS A FUNCTION OF
THE
ECOSYSTEM. SO, WE ARE GOING TO TALK A LOT
ABOUT
CYCLING OF NUTRIENTS TODAY. AND, WHY THIS
IS
IMPORTANT, CYCLING OF NUTRIENTS, BECAUSE IF
YOU THINK
OF CARBON DIOXIDE OR NITROGEN OR OXYGEN OR
WATER, THIS
IS REALLY THE SOURCE OF ALL OF THE CARBON,
OXYGEN,
HYDROGEN, NITROGEN COMPOUNDS THAT WE USE IN
MAKES
PROTEINS AND MAKING AMINO ACIDS IN OUR OWN
BODIES. SO
HYDROGEN IS IMPORTANT FOR THE PRODUCTION OF
ATP. AS
YOU ALL KNOW IN THE GLYCOLYSIS REACTIONS.
SO, THESE
CARBON DIOXIDE, NITROGEN, OXYGEN, THEY REALLY
ARE ONLY
IN GASEOUS FORMS. WATER, AS YOU KNOW, GOES
FROM
A LIQUID TO A GASEOUS FORM. BUT, EVERYTHING
ELSE THAT
WE USE, EVERYTHING ELSE THAT WE NEED COMES
FROM THE
EARTH'S CRUST. SO, ALL OF THE MICRONUTRIENTS,
ALL OF
THE MACRO NUTRIENTS, SUCH AS THE ONES THAT
YOU PUT UP
THERE, THE MOST OBVIOUS, CALCIUM, SODIUM,
MAGNESIUM.
MANGANESE, PHOSPHORUS. THEY ALL COME FROM
THE EARTH'S
CRUST. SO IT IS ONLY THE CARBON DIOXIDE, NITROGEN,
OXYGEN THAT WE DEPEND ON FROM THE ATMOSPHERE.
AND WE
WILL GO INTO THOSE IN DETAIL. LIKEWISE, THESE
MICRONUTRIENTS LIKE SELENIUM AND MOLYBDENUM
THEY COME
FROM THE EARTH'S CRUST AS WELL. THAT IS WHERE
WE GET
THOSE FROM. SO, LET'S KIND OF LOOK AT ENERGY
TRANSFER. THE WHOLE PROCESS OF ENERGY TRANSFER.
WE
KNOW FROM WHAT WE TALKED ABOUT ON WEDNESDAY
IS THAT
ABOUT 1 PERCENT OF THE SUNLIGHT THAT FALLS
ON LEAVES
AND STEMS ENDS UP GETTING INCORPORATED INTO
PLANT
BODIES. THIS IS ABOUT 1 PERCENT. NOW, BUT,
THAT 1
PERCENT THAT IS IN THE INCORPORATED FROM
THE SUNLIGHT
INTO THE PLANT BODY, THERE IS A TRANSFER TO
THE
CONSUMER TO IS HERBIVORE THAT FEEDS ON THAT
PLANT.
AND THE TRANSFER IS ABOUT 10 PERCENT. IT IS
ABOUT
A 10 PERCENT TRANSFER. NOW, IF YOU LOOK AT
THE
TRANSFER OF ENERGY, WE CAN THINK OF IT AS
CALORIES OR
POUNDS, FROM OUR PRIMARY PRODUCER TO OUR SECONDARY,
NOT PRODUCERS, OUR SECONDARY PRODUCTION, WHICH
ARE THE
CONSUMERS AND THE PREDATORS, THAT IS ABOUT
10 PERCENT,
AS WELL. SO, REMEMBER, PRIMARY PRODUCTION
IS THE RATE
OF ACCUMULATION OF BIOMASS BY PLANTS. SECONDARY
PRODUCTION IS THE RATE OF ACCUMULATION OF
BIOMASS BY
CONSUMERS AND BY PREDATORS. SO, THIS 10 PERCENT
TRANSFER IS ACTUALLY EXTREMELY IMPORTANT.
FOR ONE
THING, IT IS REAL. IT REALLY DOES HAVE ABOUT
A 10
PERCENT EFFICIENCY OF TRANSFER. AND WHAT IS
INTERESTING ABOUT THIS IS, THIS WAS A VERY
THEORETICAL
IDEA THAT WAS DEVELOPED IN THE 30'S THAT THE
EFFICIENCY OF ONE TRANSFER FROM ONE TROPHIC
LEVEL TO
THE OTHER WAS ABOUT 10 PERCENT. AND IN THE
90'S THEY
DID THESE WORLDWIDE FISHERY STUDIES WHERE
THEY LOOKED
AT AREA THAT HAD PRIMARY PRODUCERS, IN OTHER
WORDS,
DIATOMS AND ALGAE. AREAS THAT ARE PRIMARY
CONSUMERS.
FISH THAT WERE FEEDING ON THEM. AREAS THAT
HAD
PREDATORS. AND THEY FOUND THAT IT WAS INCREDIBLY
CLOSE TO 10 PERCENT. MAYBE FROM AROUND 9 TO
11 IN THE
SYSTEM'S THAT THEY LOOKED AT. SO, THIS IS
REAL. AND
SO THE IMPLICATIONS OF THIS IS, IF YOU HAVE
100 OR SAY
A THOUSAND POUNDS OF GRASS OR VEGETATION,
YOU CAN
PRODUCE ABOUT 100 PONDS OF PRIMARY CONSUMER
AND YOU
CAN PRODUCE ABOUT 10 POUNDS OF PREDATOR. OKAY?
SO
THERE IS THAT 10 PERCENT TRANSFER FROM ONE
TROPHIC
LEVEL TO THE OTHER. SO ABOUT A THOUSAND POUNDS
OF
PRIMARY PRODUCTION PRODUCES 100 POUNDS OF
PRIMARY
CONSUMER AND ABOUT 10 POUNDS OF SECONDARY
CONSUMER.
OKAY? SO THAT IS REALLY VERY, VERY INTERESTING
THAT
THAT WORKS. NOW, WHEN WE TALK ABOUT BIOCHEMICAL
CYCLES, AND WE ARE REALLY TALKING ABOUT THINGS
THAT
INVOLVE OUR OWN BODIES. THESE ARE OUR OWN
BODIES AS
WELL. WE LOOK AT HOW THIS WORKS. SO, INITIALLY,
WE
HAVE AN ELEMENT, WHETHER IT BE CARBON, OXYGEN,
NITROGEN, MOLYBDENUM, PHOSPHORUS. IT IS INCORPORATED
FROM THE ATMOSPHERE IF IT IS ONE OF THE GASSES
OR IT
IS INCORPORATED FROM WEATHERED ROCK INTO PLANT
BODIES.
OKAY? FROM PLANT BODIES IT GOES TO ANIMAL
BODIES AND
THEN THROUGH FOOD WEBS. WE USED TO SAY A FOOD
CHAIN,
BUT ACTUALLY NOW WE THINK OF IT IN TERMS OF
FOOD WEBS.
WITH MUCH MORE COMPLEXITY AND MUCH DIFFERENT
LEVELS.
AND THEN OF COURSE, THESE ORGANISMS DIE AND
THEN
THROUGH DECOMPOSITION IT GOES BACK TO THE
NON-LIVING
WORLD. THE OLD DUST TO DUST IDEA. IT REALLY
WORKS
VERY, VERY WELL IN A WAY OF THINKING OF THIS,
THIS
IDEA. OKAY? SO, EVERYTHING WE HAVE HERE YOU
PROBABLY KNOW ALREADY. LET'S LOOK AT A FEW
OF THE
CYCLES. OKAY? FOR EXAMPLE, THE CARBON, ALL
CARBON
IN OUR BODIES. ALL CARBON IN LIVING THINGS
COMES
THROUGH ONE DIRECT PATH. AND THAT IS A PATH
THAT IS
INVOLVES CARBON DIOXIDE FROM THE ATMOSPHERE.
NOW, YOU
KNOW THAT CARBON DIOXIDE IS ABOUT .03 PERCENT
OF THE
GASSES IN THE ATMOSPHERE. OKAY? WE KNOW THAT
IT IS
RISING AND IT CHANGES. BUT, IT TOOK, YOU KNOW
ROUGHLY
LET'S THINK OF IT THAT WAY. NOW, THE AUTOTROPHIC
ORGANISMS AND WHAT ARE AUTOTROPHIC ORGANISMS?
PLANTS. THAT IS WHEN WE SAY AUTOTROPHIC WE
MEAN
PLANTS. AUTO, SELF. TROPHIC, FEEDING. WHEN
WE TALK
ABOUT ANIMALS THAT EAT PLANTS WE ARE TALKING
ABOUT
HETEROTROPHIC. HETERO MEANS OTHER. TROPHIC
MEANS
FEEDING, OTHER FEEDING. SO WHAT WE HAVE IN
THE CARBON
DIOXIDE CYCLE IS THESE AUTOTROPHIC ORGANISMS.
FIX
ABOUT 10 PERCENT OF THE ATMOSPHERIC CO2 PER
YEAR. YOU
PROBABLY HAD ALL OF THIS IN HIGH SCHOOL. SO
WE WILL
GO OVER REASONABLY BRIEF. AND THEN THE HETEROTROPHS
GET ALL THEIR CARBON FROM THEIR AUTOTROPHS
BY FEEDING
ON THE AUTOTROPHS. BUT THE ONLY IMPLEMENTATION
THAT
THEY CAN GET CARBON IS FROM FEEDING ON THE
AUTOTROPHS
OR FROM, IF IT IS A SECONDARY CONSUMER, FEEDING
ON THE
PRIMARY CONSUMERS. NOW, OF COURSE, WE KNOW
THAT
BODIES WHETHER THEY BE PLANTS OR ANIMALS,
DECOMPOSE
AND THEY GO BACK TO THE ATMOSPHERE. THE BODIES
DECOMPOSE AND THE CO2 GOES BACK TO THE ATMOSPHERE
AND
THEN IT GETS OR IT GETS REINCORPORATED INTO
THE BODY
OF HETEROTROPHS IF THE HETEROTROPHS ARE ACTUALLY
DOING
THE FEEDING. BUT EVENTUALLY ALL GOES BACK
INTO THE
ATMOSPHERE. THE AUTOTROPHS DIE FIRST IT GOES
RIGHT
BACK. IF THEY ARE EATEN BY THE HETEROTROPHS
IT GOES
BACK WHEN THE HETEROTROPHS DIE. IT ALL GOES
BACK.
THERE IS CYCLING. THERE IS CYCLING OF CARBON
DIOXIDE
THROUGH THE ATMOSPHERE. NOW, WE HAVE A COMPOUND
THAT
WE CALL CELLULOSE WHICH YOU KNOW FROM DR.
FELDMAN.
CELLULOSE IS A COMPOUND THAT BREAKS DOWN VERY,
VERY
SLOWLY. AND OFTEN TIMES GETTING INCORPORATED
BELOW
THE SOIL. SO WE TALK ABOUT FOSSIL FUELS. FOSSIL
FUELS BEING OIL, WHICH COMES FROM CELLULOSE
OR FROM OR
COAL WHICH COMES FROM CELLULOSE. THAT IS WHY
WE TALK
ABOUT THAT. SO, A LOT OF THE CARBON DIOXIDE
THAT
DOESN'T GO BACK TO THE ATMOSPHERE BECAUSE
OF THIS SLOW
BREAKDOWN OF PLANTS, OF SOME PLANTS ENDS UP
BEING
INCORPORATED AS FOSSIL, FOSSIL FUELS. AND
OF COURSE,
THE BURNING OF FOSSIL FUELS IS WHAT INCREASES
THE
AMOUNT OF CO2 IN THE ATMOSPHERE. NOW, A LOT
OF CARBON
IS ALSO STORED IN CORAL REEFS THAT TEND TO
BE IN THE
TROPICAL AREAS OF THE WORLD THAT IS FREE OF
FRESH
WATER, FREE OF SEDIMENTATION. AND THEY ARE
INCORPORATED AS CALCIUM CARBONATE, AS CALCIUM
CARBONATE. NOW, ONE OF THE THINGS THAT IS
REALLY
INTERESTING ABOUT CARBON DIOXIDE IN THE CYCLING,
IS
WHY AND A LOT OF IT TENDS TO REGULATE THE
AMOUNT OF
CARBON DIOXIDE, IS THAT THERE ARE TREMENDOUS
SOURCES
OF CARBON DIOXIDE THAT WE CAN'T DO ANYTHING
ABOUT.
OKAY. THAT JUST HAPPEN. AND LARGELY FROM
DECOMPOSITION OF PROCESSES OR FROM DIGESTION,
FROM
METABOLISM. AND ONE OF THE HUGE SOURCES, AND
IT HAS
BEEN ARGUED THAT IT IS ONE OF THE BIGGEST
SOURCES IN
THE WORLD, ARE TERMITES. TERMITES, NOW WE
TEND TO
THINK TERMITES AREN'T THAT BIG AN ISSUE HERE.
ALTHOUGH, AFTER THE FIRST RAINS COME OFTEN
TIMES YOU
SEE THE TERMITES EMERGING FROM THE GROUND
OR FROM
HOPEFULLY NOT FROM YOUR HOUSE AND FLYING AROUND.
BUT
TERMITES, BECAUSE OF BACTERIA, SYMBIOTIC BACTERIA
IN
THEIR GUT CAN BREAK DOWN CELLULOSE AND THROUGH
THEIR
DIGESTION OR PARTIAL DIGESTION, THEY RELEASE
CARBON
DIOXIDE TO THE ATMOSPHERE. ONE OF THE BIG
PROBLEMS,
AND MAYBE IN SOME WAYS THE BIGGEST PROBLEM
OF CUTTING
DOWN RAIN FORESTS, BECAUSE TERMITES REALLY
THRIVE IN
THE TROPICS, IS THAT YOU LEAVE A LOT OF SLASH,
YOU
LEAVE A LOT OF MATERIAL ON THE BOTTOM. IT
IS NOT, IT
IS NOT IN A BIG CHUNK, BUT IT IS SMALLER
CHUNKS SO YOU
HAVE A HIGHER SURFACE TO VOLUME RATIO TO IS
IDEAL FOOD
FOR TERMITES. TERMITES TO PRODUCE EVEN MORE
CARBON
DIOXIDE. SO, ONE OF THE REASONS THAT WE TALK
ABOUT
REGULATING INDUSTRIAL CARBON DIOXIDE IS BECAUSE
YOU
HAVE GOT HUGE SOURCES OF CARBON DIOXIDE LIKE
TERMITES
THAT YOU CAN'T REGULATE. THAT IS WHY THERE
IS THE
EMPHASIS. WE ARE NOT CERTAINLY, IT IS NOT
THE,
INDUSTRIAL CARBON DIOXIDE IS A PROCESSES ARE
NOT THE
ONLY SOURCE OF CARBON DIOXIDE, BUT IT IS THE
ONE THAT
IS MOST EASILY REGULATED. TERMITES ARE VIRTUALLY
IMPOSSIBLE BECAUSE THEY PROBABLY MAKE UP,
TERMITES AND
ANTS, PROBABLY MAKE UP THE LARGEST BIOMASS
OF ANY
ORGANISMS IN THE WORLD. IF YOU LUMP THEM TOGETHER
BECAUSE THEY ARE JUST HUGE NUMBERS. ALL RIGHT.
SO
THAT IS CARBON DIOXIDE. NOW, NITROGEN IS A
LITTLE
MORE COMPLEX A TOPIC. NITROGEN IS A LITTLE
MORE
COMPLEX. I WILL SPEND A LITTLE MORE TIME GOING
OVER
THIS. NITROGEN, AS YOU KNOW, MAKES UP ABOUT
PERCENT ATMOSPHERIC GASSES. THE PROBLEM IS,
IS UNLIKE
CARBON DIOXIDE, WHICH IS READILY USED IN THE
PHOTOSYNTHETIC PROCESS WHERE PLANTS TAKE UP
CARBON
DIOXIDE INCORPORATE CARBOHYDRATES INTO THEIR
BODY AND
RELEASE OXYGEN. NITROGEN GAS CAN'T BE TAKEN
UP BY
PLANTS. NITROGEN CAN'T BE TAKEN UP BY PLANTS.
THE
FORMS OF NITROGEN THAT CAN BE TAKEN UP BY
PLANTS ARE
AMMONIUM AND H4 AND THAT IS NOT REALLY EASILY
TAKEN UP
BY PLANTS. THEY CAN TAKE IT UP BUT THEY DON'T
TAKE IT
UP VERY WELL. AND THE OTHER IS NITRATE. NITRATE
NO
3. WHAT HAS TO HAPPEN IS, THE ATMOSPHERIC
NITROGEN
HAS TO BE INCORPORATED INTO A AMMONIUM OR
INTO NITRATE
BEFORE PLANTS CAN USE IT. THIS IS REALLY A
VERY, VERY
IMPORTANT PROCESS. NOW, THE WAY THIS TENDS
TO HAPPEN
IS THAT THERE ARE ON EITHER FREE-LIVING IN
THE SOIL OR
ON THE ROOTS OF PLANTS SYMBIOTICALLY, THERE
ARE
BACTERIA THAT ACTUALLY ENABLE THIS TRANSFER
OF FREE
NITROGEN N2 TO USE NITRITE, N02 AND THEN
TO NITRATE,
N03. THEY ARE ACTUALLY CRITICAL TO THE PROCESS
OF
PLANTS GETTING NITROGEN AS A NUTRIENT. THESE
BACTERIA
THAT PROCESS THE ATMOSPHERIC NITROGEN AND
CONVERT IT
IN TO FORMS THAT PLANTS CAN USE. THERE IS
SOME MINOR
SOURCES OF USEABLE NITRATE, IN THAT ABOUT
5 TO 10
PERCENT OF THE NITROGEN THAT CAN BE USED BY
PLANTS
COMES THROUGH FROM THE ATMOSPHERE EITHER AS
DISSOLVED
IN RAIN WATER OR ADHERING TO DUST PARTICLES.
SO THAT
IS A SOURCE OF NITROGEN. BUT, NOWHERE NEAR
AS
IMPORTANT AS NITROGEN FIXATION. IN FERTILIZERS
WE
HAVE ACTUALLY THE INDUSTRIAL CREATION OF NITRATES.
SOMETIMES AMMONIUM. BUT, THIS AGAIN IS A RELATIVELY
SMALL PART COMPARED TO THE BACTERIA AND ITS
ROLE IN,
IN NITRIFICATION. NOW, DENITRIFICATION,
NITRIFICATION. NOW, AS WE HAVE NITROGEN FIXATION
GOING ON FROM FREE LIVING AND ON THE BACTERIAL
PLANT,
ON THE PLANT ROOTS BY BACTERIA, WE ALSO HAVE
DECOMPOSITION. THE PLANTS DIE. AND ONE OF
THE THINGS
THAT IS VERY INTERESTING IS THAT WE GET A
TREMENDOUS
AMOUNT OF FROM DECOMPOSITION, THE REABSORPTION
OF
THESE NITROGENOUS COMPOUNDS THAT CAN BE USED
BY
PLANTS. WHETHER IT BE AMMONIUM OR NITRATE.
SO THERE
IS A LOT OF RECYCLING IN THIS SOIL. AND THIS
REALLY
WASN'T VERY WELL KNOWN UNTIL RECENTLY. AND
THEN, WE
HAVE A PROCESS, THIS IS A TERM THAT I JUST
USED OF
NITRIFICATION WHERE WE TAKE AMMONIUM, THE
PARTICLE
THAT IS NOT SUPER ABLE TO BE USED BY PLANTS
INTO
NITRITE, N02 AND INTO NITRATE, N03. YOU ARE
ACTUALLY
USING YOUR CHEM 1. AND, THEN, DENITRIFICATION
IS THE
REVERSE OF THIS, WHERE WE GO FROM NO3 TO NO2
TO
AMMONIUM BACK TO ATMOSPHERIC NITROGEN. OKAY?
SO, I
HAVE QUICKLY GONE OVER THESE CARBON DIOXIDE
AND SPEND
A LITTLE MORE TIME ON NITROGEN. AND OF ALL
OF THE
MINERAL ELEMENTS, I AM ONLY GOING TO GO OVER
ONE
BECAUSE IT IS PROBABLY OF MOST IMPORTANT.
AND THAT IS
PHOSPHORUS. BUT, THIS IS REALLY A PATTERN
VERY, VERY
SIMPLE. A VERY SIMILAR TO ALL OF THE OTHER
ELEMENTS
THAT WE GET FROM WEATHERED ROCKS, THE WAY
THIS WORKS.
WHAT HAPPENS TO PHOSPHORUS IS THAT IT IS,
IT IS ALL IN
A MINERAL FORM. THERE IS NO GASEOUS PHOSPHORUS
OR NO
GASEOUS PHOSPHATE. IT IS ALL MINERAL. SO,
IT TENDS,
BECAUSE OF THE WEATHERING, BECAUSE OF RAIN,
IT TENDS
TO GET LEECHED OUT OF THE SOIL AND THEN CARRIED
IN
WATER TO RIVERS. CARRIED IN WATER TO RIVERS.
FROM
THE RIVERS IT FLOWS INTO THE OCEANS. AND,
WHAT IT
DOES, IT TENDS TO SETTLE EITHER ON THE BOTTOM
OR
THROUGH MIXING PROCESSES GETTING INCORPORATED
INTO
PLANT BODIES AND THEN BEING EATEN BY FISH,
INVERTEBRATES WHO ARE THEN EATEN BY BIRDS.
BUT IT IS
STILL, IT IS IN THIS MINERAL FORM. NOW, THE
ONLY WAY
WE CAN GET IT BACK FROM THE OCEAN IS WE EITHER
MINE
IT. SO, FOR EXAMPLE, FOR THOSE OF YOU FROM
SAN
FRANCISCO, YOU GO OUT TO OCEAN BEACH AND YOU
CAN SEE
THESE ROCKS COMPLETELY WHITE FROM BIRD DROPPINGS.
VERY OFTEN PEOPLE GO TO ISLANDS WHERE THERE
IS A LOT
OF BIRDS AND THEY LITERALLY MINE THE PHOSPHATE
FROM
THAT BECAUSE IT IS IN A FORM THAT CAN BE USED
IN
AGRICULTURAL. OR THE ONLY OTHER WAY THAT IT
CAN COME
BACK TO THE LAND, IS THAT IT COMES BACK BY
LAND BEING
UPLIFTED. IN OTHER WORDS, SEA BOTTOM RISING
TO THE
SURFACE. NOW, CALIFORNIA IS, THE COAST OF
CALIFORNIA
IN THE CENTRAL VALLEY, IS UPLIFTED OCEAN BOTTOM.
IS
UPLIFTED OCEAN BOTTOM. SO WE HAVE VERY HIGH
CONCENTRATIONS OF PHOSPHORUS HERE BECAUSE
OF THE
UPLIFTING THAT OCCURRED IN GEOLOGIC TIME.
BUT UNLESS
YOU HAVE THAT UPLIFTING YOU DON'T HAVE ENOUGH
PHOSPHORUS UNLESS YOU CAN GET IT FROM MINING
SOURCES.
SO, IF YOU THINK BACK TO THE EXPERIMENT THAT
I SHOWED
YOU WHERE THE LAKE WAS SPLIT IN HALF, AND
THEY WERE
LOOKING AT THE EFFECT OF PHOSPHORUS ADDITION,
THEY
ADDED PHOSPHORUS TO ONE SIDE OF THE LAKE AND
NOT TO
THE OTHER AND DO YOU REMEMBER WHAT HAPPENED
TO THE
SIDE OF THE LAKE THEY ADDED PHOSPHORUS? IT
TURNED
BRIGHT GREEN BECAUSE OF ALGAL BLOOMS. SO,
THAT
EXPERIMENT WHERE THEY ADD PHOSPHORUS TO ONE
SIDE AND
NOT TO THE OTHER AND YOU GET A RESPONSE OF
ALGAE, IS
DEMONSTRATING THAT PHOSPHORUS IS A LIMITING
FACTOR.
OKAY? THERE IS NOT ENOUGH PHOSPHORUS IN THE
SYSTEM
SO AS SOON AS THEY ADD THE PHOSPHORUS IN,
THEY GET
A WONDERFUL RESPONSE INDICATING THAT PHOSPHORUS
IS THE
LIMITING FACTOR. OKAY. BEFORE I GO ON TO THE
NEXT
TOPIC, I WANT TO MAKE SURE EVERYBODY UNDERSTANDS
THIS.
OKAY? WE TALKED ABOUT ECOSYSTEMS, WE HAVE
TALKED
ABOUT THE FLOW OF ENERGY IN THE CYCLING OF
NUTRIENTS.
WE HAVE TALKED ABOUT ENERGY TRANSFER. WE HAVE
TALKED
ABOUT CARBON DIOXIDE, WATER CYCLES, NITROGEN
CYCLES,
PHOSPHORUS CYCLES. ANYBODY HAVE ANY QUESTIONS
OR
ANYTHING THAT THEY WANT ME TO GO OVER?
IS THAT EQUAL? NO. NO. NO. TWO DIFFERENT
PROCESSES. NITRIFICATION WE HAVE AMMONIUM
GOING TO
NITRITE GOING TO NITRATE. BECAUSE, NITRATE
IS THE
FORM THAT IS MOST USEABLE BY PLANTS. THE OTHER
DIRECTION WOULD BE DENITRIFICATION. SO, IF
YOU THINK,
DE, MEANS FROM. YOU ARE EITHER NITRIFYING
OR
DENITRIFYING. THEY ARE GOING IN TWO OPPOSITE
DIRECTIONS. DO YOU HAVE A QUESTION? OKAY.
ANYBODY
ELSE, YEAH? OH, OKAY. I WILL GO OVER THAT
IN
A SECOND. MYCORRHIZAE. YES? PLANTS USE AMMONIUM
AND NITRATE BUT THEY USE NITRATE MUCH MORE
EFFICIENTLY. SO, IN FACT, FOR MAXIMUM PLANT
GROWTH,
THE AMMONIUM HAS TO GO TO NITRATE, NITRITE
AND
NITRATE. IT TAKES IT UP MUCH, MUCH MORE EASILY.
I
HAVEN'T GONE OVER THAT YET. OKAY? I AM GOING
OVER
THE CYCLES FIRST. OKAY. ANYTHING ELSE?
EVERYBODY GET THIS? YEAH? THE QUESTION IS,
WHERE DOES THE NITRIFICATION OCCUR? IT OCCURS
PRIMARILY THROUGH THE SOIL. THROUGH BACTERIA
THAT ARE
IN THE SOIL. THROUGH BACTERIA THAT ARE ON
THE PLANTS.
IT IS PART OF THAT SIMPLE BIOTIC BACTERIAL
PROCESS.
IT IS PART, IT COULD BE CONSIDERED PART OF
THE
FIXATION PROCESS, YEAH. WHERE YOU ARE TAKING
ATMOSPHERIC NITROGEN AND YOU ARE FIXING IT
ALL OF THE
WAY TO NITRATE A FORM THAT CAN BE USED. OKAY.
VERY
GOOD. NITRIFICATION. ANYTHING ELSE? ALL RIGHT.
THERE IS TWO OTHER TERMS THAT I MENTIONED.
WHEN WE
THINK ABOUT THAT EXPERIMENT THAT WAS DONE,
THAT
EXPERIMENT THAT WAS DONE WHERE THEY SPLIT
THE LAKE IN
HALF AND THEY ADDED PHOSPHORUS TO THE OTHER
HALF AND
THEY HAD THIS TREMENDOUS ALGAL BLOOM. IF YOU
REMEMBER
PLANTS NOT ONLY PHOTOSYNTHESIZE, PRODUCE OXYGEN
AND
GROW, BUT THEY CONSUME OXYGEN. IN THE EXAMPLE
WHERE
WE SHOWED YOU OF THAT LAKE THAT WAS SPLIT
IN HALF,
DURING THE DAY THOSE PLANTS WOULD BE PRODUCING
OXYGEN.
BUT, AT NIGHT THEY WOULD BE USING IT UP. AND,
WHAT WE
HAVE IS A TERM THAT IS CALLED, EUTROPHICATION
AND IT
ACTUALLY CAN APPLY TO EITHER NITROGEN OR
PHOSPHORUS.
BUT, WHAT THIS TERM MEANS IS THAT THERE IS
SO MANY
NUTRIENTS THAT YOU END UP HAVING OFTEN TIMES
TREMENDOUS REDUCTIONS IN OXYGEN IN THE EVENING
WHEN
RESPIRATION IS GOING ON BUT NO PRODUCTION
OF
PHOTOSYNTHESIS IS GOING ON. AND WHEN WE TALK
ON
MONDAY, I WILL ACTUALLY GIVE YOU A LITTLE
MORE ABOUT
EUTROPHICATION. I WANTED TO MENTION IT NOW
BECAUSE IT
IS EXTREMELY IMPORTANT IN THE CREATION OF
PROBLEMS IN
LAKES. AND NEXT WEEK'S LAB IS ENTIRELY ON
WATER
POLLUTION. OKAY. NOW THERE ARE A COUPLE OF
THINGS
THAT I ALSO WANTED TO GO BACK TOO. WHEN WE
TALK ABOUT
THE WATER CYCLE, WE TALK ABOUT THE WATER CYCLE
WE HAVE
POLLUTION PROBLEMS. AND NEXT WEEK'S LAB IS
COMPLETELY
DEVOTED TO POLLUTION. SO I WILL TAKE THIS
OFF AND
WHEN WE TALK ABOUT WATER IT IS REALLY IMPORTANT
TO
REMEMBER THAT WATER AND THE WATER CYCLE IS
INVOLVED
WITH SOMETHING THAT ARE CALLED AQUAFERS. NOW
WHAT
AQUAFERS ARE, WHEN YOU GET WATER FROM GROUND
WATER
FROM BENEATH THE SURFACE, PEOPLE TEND TO THINK
THAT
THERE IS LIKE A GIANT RESERVOIR OF WATER.
LIKE A BIG,
JUST A, YOU KNOW, LIKE A BIG SWIMMING POOL.
AND IN
FACT, THE WATER IS NOT LIKE THAT. THE WATER
IS HELD
IN WHAT IS CALLED AQUAFERS. AND, WHAT AQUAFERS
ARE,
ARE PERMEABLE. BUT THEY ARE COMPLETELY SATURATED
WITH
WATER. UNDERGROUND LAYERS OF WATER, ROCK,
SAND AND
GRAVEL. SO THE WATER ISN'T LIKE IN A BIG SWIMMING
POOL, IT IS SIMPLY TIED UP WITH THE SOIL THAT
OCCURS
THERE. THE SOIL AND THE GRAVEL AND THE SAND
THAT IS
IN THE AQUAFERS. AQUAFERS ARE IMPORTANT BECAUSE
PERCENT OF THE DRINKING WATER IN THE US COMING
FROM
THESE SOURCES. IT DOESN'T COME FROM RIVERS.
IT
DOESN'T COME FROM LAKES. IT COMES FROM AQUAFERS.
AND, IT HAS BEEN ESTIMATED THAT ABOUT 2 TO
3 PERCENT
OF THE AQUAFERS ARE POLLUTED TO THE POINT
THAT THEY
CAN'T BE USED ANY MORE. SO THIS IS A REAL
POTENTIAL
PROBLEM WITH AQUAFERS, IS THAT THE GROUND
WATER IS
GETTING POLLUTED. THIS IS A PROBLEM FOR EXAMPLE
IN
SILICON VALLEY. WHERE, BECAUSE OF THE MICROCHIP
INDUSTRY THERE IS A LOT OF POLLUTION WITH
THE GROUND
WATER. BUT IN SILICON VALLEY WE DON'T USE
GROUND
WATER FOR DRINKING WATER. THAT, OF COURSE,
COMES FROM
OTHER SOURCES IN THE SIERRAS. NOW, I WANT
TO TALK
ABOUT POINT VERSUS NON-POINT POLLUTION. BECAUSE
AS I
SAY NEXT WEEK'S LAB IS ENTIRELY DEVOTED TO
POLLUTION.
IF YOU HAVE A FACTORY AND THE FACTORY HAS
A PIPE THAT
IS CARRYING CHEMICALS INTO A RIVER AND YOU
CAN
IDENTIFY THE EXACT POINT OR THE SOURCE OF
THAT
POLLUTANT WHERE IT IS FLOWING IN, SAY THE
WATER IS
FLOWING THIS WAY, SO THAT ABOVE THE WATER
IS CLEAN,
BELOW IT IS POLLUTED, YOU WOULD REFER TO THAT
AS A
POINT SOURCE OF POLLUTION. IN OTHER WORDS,
IT IS
IDENTIFIED EXACTLY WHERE THAT POLLUTION IS
CONSIDERING. ON THE OTHER HAND, IF YOU HAD
SAY THIS
SUDDENLY WAS TAKING CARE OF IT. IN THE UNITED
STATES
MOST OF THE POINT SOURCES OF POLLUTION HAVE
BEEN
ELIMINATED. SO THAT IS NOT REALLY A PROBLEM,
BUT, YOU
HAVE GOT SAY A PARKING LOT UP HERE AND THE
RUNOFF FROM
THAT PARKING LOT IS BRINGING OIL AND GREASE
INTO THE
STREAM. AND MAYBE YOU HAVE GOT AN AGRICULTURAL
FIELD
HERE AND THAT IS BRINGING SILT FROM EROSION
INTO THE
STREAM. WE WOULD CALL THAT NON-POINT SOURCE.
AND ALL
THE DIFFERENCE REALLY IS, IS WHETHER WE CAN
IDENTIFY
EXACTLY WHERE THAT POLLUTION IS COMING IN
OR IF IT IS
COMING IN FROM A VARIETY OF DISPERSED SOURCES.
OKAY.
JUST COMMON SENSE. THINK OF WHAT THE WORDS
MEAN. AS
I SAID IN NORTH AMERICA, IN MOST DEVELOPED
COUNTRIES
OF THE WORLD, POINT SOURCE POLLUTION IS NOT
A PROBLEM.
BUT, NON-POINT SOURCE POLLUTION IS A REALLY
BIG,
A REALLY BIG PROBLEM. OKAY? ANY QUESTIONS
ABOUT
POINT VERSUS NON-POINT? I WANT TO MAKE SURE
THAT YOU
GET THAT DISTINCTION. OKAY. PRETTY OBVIOUS.
THINK
OF THE MEANINGS OF THE WORDS. GETTING BACK
TO OUR
PHOSPHORUS CYCLE. BECAUSE THIS IS VERY, VERY
IMPORTANT IN AGRICULTURE IS THAT WE HAVE FUNGI
THAT
ARE CALLED MYCORRHIZAE. M-Y-C-O-R-R-H-I-Z-A-E.
JUST
LIKE WE HAVE SYMBIOTIC BACTERIA THAT HELP
BRING
NITROGEN INTO FORMS THAT ARE USEABLE BY PLANTS,
WE
HAVE MYCORRHIZAE THAT ARE SYMBIOTIC ASSOCIATIONS
OF
PLANTS AND FUNGI. AND THEY ARE CRITICAL IN
THE
ABSORPTION OF [INAUDIBLE]. NOW, AGRICULTURE
IN OUR
FOOD REALLY IS REALLY, REALLY DEPENDENT ON
THESE
PROCESSES. BOTH OF THE LEGUMES, THE PEAS AND
THE
BEANS AND THE CORN AND EVERYTHING WE EAT DEPENDS
ON
THESE BACTERIA CONVERTING NITROGEN INTO A
FORM. AND A
LOT OF TREE GROWTH DEPENDS ON PHOSPHORUS.
ENABLING
PHOSPHORUS TO BE IN A FORM THAT CAN BE ASSOCIATED
WITH
PLANTS. AND THEN WE CAN GO BACK TO WATER.
YOU KNOW,
ROUGHLY, IT TAKES ABOUT A THOUSAND KILOGRAMS
OF WATER
TO RAISE OR PRODUCE ONE KILOGRAM OF AGRICULTURAL
PLANTS. ABOUT A THOUSAND TO ONE RATIO. BUT
OF
COURSE, SIMPLY LOOK AT THINGS LIKE, YOU KNOW,
RICE
COMPARED TO POTATOES. RICE TAKES ABOUT YOU
KNOW, TEN
TIMES AS MUCH AS POTATOES DO. BECAUSE, OF
THE WAY
THAT IT IS GROWN. SO, THERE IS A LOT OF VARIATION.
BUT AS A RULE OF THUMB, WE SEE ABOUT A THOUSAND
TO ONE
KILOGRAMS OF WATER TO PRODUCE ONE POUND OF
PLANT. IN
CALIFORNIA, WHERE AS YOU KNOW, WE HAVE WATER
SHORTAGES
MANY YEARS. ABOUT 80 PERCENT OF THE WATER
GOES FOR
AGRICULTURAL USE. AGRICULTURAL USE. A LITTLE
FOR
INDUSTRIAL, BUT ONLY ABOUT 10 PERCENT TENDS
TO BE USED
DOMESTICALLY, MOST OF IT IS GOING IN TO AGRICULTURAL
PRODUCTION. YEAH? PLANT IN GENERAL. BECAUSE
REMEMBER, WHEN WE ARE GROWING AGRICULTURAL
PRODUCTS WE
ARE TENDING TO GROW AS MUCH EDIBLE PART AT
POSSIBLE.
YEAH. WE ARE TALKING ABOUT ONE POUND OF THE
PLANT.
THE MAXIMUM PART OF THAT WE TRY TO HAVE AS
EDIBLE.
OKAY, NOW, EVERYBODY PAY ATTENTION BECAUSE
THIS IS
REALLY IMPORTANT. OKAY? I WANT TO TALK ABOUT
AN
EXPERIMENT. NOW, HOW DO YOU KNOW IF YOU WANT
TO ADD
FERTILIZER TO YOUR LAWN OR YOU WANT TO REGULATE
THE
AMOUNT OF PHOSPHORUS OR NITROGEN THAT IS GOING
INTO
THE ENVIRONMENT, SUCH AS WE SAW WITH THAT
WHOLE LAKE
MANIPULATION. AND WE WANT TO ASK WHETHER N
OR P IS
THE LIMITING FACTOR. WHETHER N OR P IS THE
LIMITING
FACTOR, WE CAN DO AN EXPERIMENT. AND, WHAT
WE ARE
GOING TO DO IS SINCE WE HAVE USED NITROGEN
PHOSPHORUS
IN THE LAKE EXAMPLE, WE ARE GOING TO USE AN
AQUATIC
EXAMPLE AS WELL. SO, WE WANT TO SEE IF IN
AN AQUATIC
ENVIRONMENT, LET'S JUST SAY, IT IS A STREAM
THAT IS
FLOWING, WHICH ONE OF THESE TWO IS LIMITING?
WE CAN
DO A VERY, VERY SIMPLE EXPERIMENT. WE CAN
TAKE FLOWER
POTS, CLAY FLOWER POTS. AND WE CAN PUT 3 FLOWER
POTS,
LET ME MAKE THAT THE SIDES A LITTLE SO THEY
WILL LOOK
A LITTLE MORE LIKE FLOWER POTS, AND WE CAN
PUT THEM
UNDER WATER. NOW, WE FILL THE FLOWER POTS
UP WITH SAY
AGAR AND OTHER KINDS OF MATERIAL THAT IS
GOING TO HOLD
NUTRIENTS IN. AND, IN ONE FLOWER POT TO THE
AGAR, WE
ADD NITROGEN. TO THE OTHER FLOWER POT WE ADD
PHOSPHORUS. AND THEN WE LEAVE THEM UNDER WATER.
WHAT
IS GOING TO HAPPEN, AND LISTEN TO THIS VERY
CAREFULLY,
AND WE SEAL THE TOPS, LET'S ADD THAT, WE SEAL
THE
TOPS. NONE OF THE MATERIAL CAN LEECH OUT OF
FLOWER POT THROUGH THE TOP. THE ONLY WAY IT
CAN LEECH
OUT IS HERE THROUGH THE SIDES OF THE FLOWER
POT
ITSELF. NOW, USING THIS EXPERIMENT, USING
THIS
DESIGN, HOW COULD BE TELL WHETHER NITROGEN
OR
PHOSPHORUS WAS THE LIMITING FACTOR? LET ME
SAY IT
ONE MORE TIME. WE HAVE A FLOWER POT WITH NITROGEN
COMING OUT, ONLY NITROGEN. A FLOWER POT WITH
ONLY
PHOSPHORUS COMING OUT. HOW WOULD WE DECIDE
WHETHER N
OR P WAS THE LIMITING FACTOR? WHAT WOULD BE
OUR
INDICATION AT THE END OF SAY A MONTH OF LEAVING
THIS
IN THE WATER THAT ONE OF THESE WOULD BE A
LIMITING
FACTOR? TAKE 30 SECONDS TO TALK ABOUT THIS
BECAUSE
THIS IS THE TYPE QUESTION I AM GOING TO BE
ASKING YOU.
OKAY? 30 SECONDS. THINK OF THIS EXPERIMENT.
NITROGEN, NITROGEN IS LEECHING OUT OF ONE
POT.
PHOSPHORUS IS LEECHING OUT OF ANOTHER POT.
HOW WOULD
YOU TELL WHICH ONE IS LIMITING? REMEMBER,
YOU HAVE
GOT A STREAM OF ALGAE GROWING IN IT. THERE
IS ALWAYS
ALGAE IN STREAMS. DIATOMS. ALL UNDER WATER.
OKAY.
WHO HAS GOT AN IDEA? IT DOESN'T HAVE TO BE
THE RIGHT
IDEA, WHO JUST HAS AN IDEA THAT WE CAN START
TALKING
ABOUT IT? YOU TWO HAVE BEEN TALKING A LOT
YOU MUST
HAVE A SUGGESTION?
OKAY. WHAT HE JUST SAID IT,
WHICHEVER ONE HAS THE LOWER CONCENTRATION.
THAT WOULD
JUST REFLECT THE LEECHING RATE OF COMING OUT.
WOULDN'T REALLY TELL YOU WHICH ONE WAS THE
LIMITING
FACTOR. WHAT WOULD TELL YOU WHAT THE LIMITING
FACTOR
WAS? HOW ABOUT YOU? WHAT DO YOU THINK? YEAH?
BUT, YOU ARE ON THE RIGHT TRACK. WHICH ONE
IS, ARE
PLANTS USING? WHICH ONE. THAT IS GETTING
CLOSE.
SAY THIS REAL LOUD.
STUDENT: SO YOU LOOK AT THE ONE THAT DOESN'T
ANYTHING LEECHING OUT OF IT. BECAUSE THAT
IS LIKE
YOUR CONTROL. YOU SEE WHAT IS GROWING ON THAT
AND
YOU SEE THE ONE THAT'S ARE LEECHING MINERALS
OUT
AND YOU SEE WHICH ONE HAS MORE STUFF GROWING
ON IT.
PROFESSOR: WHAT KIND OF STUFF?
STUDENT: LIKE ALGAE.
PROFESSOR: GREAT. GREAT. THAT IS EXACTLY
RIGHT. NOW LET THE THINK ABOUT THIS EXPERIMENT.
YOU HAVE PHOSPHORUS LEECHING OUT AND YOU HAVE
NITROGEN LEECHING OUT. YOU LOOK AND SEE WHICH
ONE
GIVES YOU THE BIGGEST PLANT RESPONSE, IN OTHER
WORDS, AS I SAID ALGAE IS ALWAYS GROWING IN
THIS
SYSTEM. AND YOU LOOK AND SEE WHICH HAS THE
LARGEST
AMOUNT OF ALGAL GROWTH. LARGEST AMOUNT OF
ALGAL
GROWTH AND THAT WOULD BE THE ONE THAT WAS
THE
LIMITING FACTOR. OKAY. NOW, SHE GAVE YOU
A HINT
BUT WHAT IS THIS? WHAT WOULD WE CALL THIS
POT
THAT HAS AGAR IN IT BUT NEITHER NITROGEN OR
PHOSPHORUS? CONTROL. WHAT KIND OF CONTROL
WOULD
WE TALK ABOUT IT? NOT REALLY, A PROCEDURE
WISE
CONTROL. WE HAVE TALKED ABOUT THESE BEFORE.
A PROCEDURE WISE CONTROL. IN OTHER WORDS,
YOU
WOULD WANT TO FIND IF THE POT BY ITSELF PRODUCED
ALGAE. OKAY? SO IT IS A PROCEDURE WISE CONTROL
TO SEE IF YOUR EXPERIMENT MAKES SENSE OR YOU
HAVE
GOT SOMETHING THAT IS DOING THIS. NOW, LET'S
SAY,
YOU HAVE GOT POTS FROM MEXICO. POTS MADE IN
MEXICO
TEND TO HAVE VERY, VERY HIGH IRON CONTENT
IN THEM.
AND, YOU DON'T KNOW IT WHEN YOU DO THIS, BUT
IRON
WILL BIND TO PHOSPHORUS. SO, THAT IN FACT,
THE
PHOSPHORUS, WHEN IT STARTS TO LEECH OUT OF
THE POT
WILL BIND TO THE POT AND WON'T BE RELEASED.
WHAT
WOULD YOU CALL THAT? WHAT WOULD YOU CALL THAT?
AY YI YI. WHAT WOULD YOU CALL THAT? AN
UNCONTROLLED VARIABLE. OKAY. YOU ARE ASSUMING
THAT THIS EVERYTHING IS OCCURRING THE SAME
IN THIS
BUT IF THE IRON IS GOING TO LEECH TO THE
PHOSPHORUS, THEN THE PHOSPHORUS IS NOT GOING
TO BE
RELEASED. IT IS AN UNCONTROLLED VARIABLE.
FINALLY, WHAT KIND OF, OF ALL OF THE EXPERIMENTS
WE
DESCRIBED, WHAT TYPE OF EXPERIMENT WOULD YOU
CALL
THIS? IS IT AN EXCLUSION EXPERIMENT? IS IT
AN
EXPERIMENT? IS IT A CAGE EXPERIMENT?
SUPPLEMENTATION EXPERIMENT. WHAT WOULD YOU
CALL
IT? WHAT IS IT MOST LIKE? PROBABLY LIKE
A SUPPLEMENTATION EXPERIMENT. BECAUSE YOU
ARE
ADDING COMPOUNDS TO SEE IF YOU ARE RELEASING
COMPETITION OR YOU ARE GETTING A RESPONSE.
VERY
GOOD. OKAY. NOW, YOU HAD A QUESTION?
OKAY.
GOOD, I AM GLAD. WHAT SHE JUST SAID. THERE
IS
UNCONTROLLED VARIABLE. WHAT IF YOU PUT THE
NITROGEN IN AN AREA WHERE MORE WATER WAS
FLOWING BY
AND IT GOT IT TO LEECH OUT FASTER THAN THE
PHOSPHORUS. GREAT. GOOD WAY TO THINK OF IT.
YOU
ARE ALWAYS HAVE TO BE THINKING ABOUT UNCONTROLLED
VARIABLES. THAT IS A VERY GOOD EXAMPLE OF
ONE.
OR, WHEN THE NITROGEN MAYBE WAS IN THE SHADE.
AND
THE PHOSPHORUS WAS IN FULL SUN. OKAY?
OKAY. SAY
THAT AGAIN?
STUDENT: WHEN YOU ARE CONDUCTION THE EXPERIMENT
HOW DO YOU KNOW WHICH, HOW MUCH TO PUT IN?
PROFESSOR: HOW DO YOU THINK YOU WOULD KNOW
HOW
MUCH TO PUT IN? WHAT WOULD YOU DO TO DECIDE
MUCH YOU WANT TO PUT IN? YOU WOULD CONDUCT
WHAT?
WHAT WOULD YOU CONDUCT FIRST? A PILOT STUDY.
OKAY. THAT WAY YOU WOULD SEE IF YOU GOT ANY
RESPONSE AT ALL. YOU WOULD JUST CONDUCT A
PILOT
STUDY. OKAY. GOOD. VERY GOOD QUESTIONS. ALL
RIGHT. ANYTHING ELSE ABOUT THIS? OKAY. WE
ARE
GOING TO DO SOMETHING ELSE NOW THAT TIES
IN TO
EARLIER LECTURES. WE ARE GOING TO LOOK AT
HOW
SUCCESSION AND ECOSYSTEMS RELATE TO EACH OTHER.
NOW, LET'S LOOK AT THIS FIRST THING I HAVE
WRITTEN
ON THE BOARD. AS ECOSYSTEMS MATURE, AS ECOSYSTEMS
GET OLDER, THERE IS AN INCREASE IN TOTAL BIOMASS
BUT A DECREASE IN NET PRIMARY PRODUCTIVITY.
THERE
IS AN INCREASE IN BIOMASS BUT A DECREASE IN
NET
PRIMARY PRODUCTIVITY. THINK OF WHEN YOU WENT
TO
THE REDWOOD GROVE THIS WEEK. THOSE REDWOOD
TREES
HAVE HUGE AMOUNTS OF BIOMASS. BUT, VERY, VERY
LOW
RATES OF PRIMARY PRODUCTIVITY. THEY ARE NOT,
THE
RATE THE ACCUMULATION OF BIOMASS IS VERY SLOW
RELATIVE TO THE TOTAL AMOUNT OF BIOMASS THERE.
BECAUSE, THEY ARE NOT GROWING VERY FAST ANY
MORE.
MOST OF THE GROWTH IS ALREADY IN NON-LIVING,
IN
LIVING BIOPASS BUT IN NON-PHOTOSYNTHETIC BIOMASS,
THE REDWOOD TRUNK ITSELF. NOW, LET'S LOOK
AT THE
SECOND ONE. EARLY SUCCESSIONAL STAGES WHERE
YOU
HAVE A LOT OF R SELECTED SPECIES WHERE EMPHASIS
IS
ON GROWTH AND FAST REPRODUCTION AND GETTING
NUMBERS
OUT THERE. EARLY SUCCESSIONAL STAGES ARE MORE
PRODUCTIVE THAN LATER SUCCESSIONAL STAGES.
THESE
ARE RULES OF THUMB THAT WE SEE IN ECOSYSTEMS.
AND
THE THIRD ONE IS DISTURBANCE FUNCTIONS TO
KEEP
ECOSYSTEMS INTO EARLY SUCCESSIONAL STAGES
AND
HIGHER PRODUCTIVITY. SO, WE HAVE ALREADY TALKED
ABOUT CLIMAX COMMUNITIES ACTUALLY NOT BEING
VERY
REALISTIC UNLESS THEY ARE HIGHLY MANAGED SYSTEMS.
BECAUSE, WHAT YOU HAVE IS DISTURBANCES MAKING
THINGS GO BACK TO EARLY SUCCESSIONAL STAGES.
OKAY.
NOW, THIS IS REALLY IMPORTANT TO THINK ABOUT.
WHAT
DOES THIS HAVE TO DO WITH HELICOPSYCHE? WITH
THE
EXPERIMENTS THAT WE TALKED ABOUT HELICOPSYCHE,
BECAUSE THIS IS THE WRAP UP OF THE STORY,
IN THE
EXPERIMENTS WE TALKED ABOUT WITH HELICOPSYCHE
WE
DID EXCLUSION EXPERIMENTS, WE DID CAGE EXPERIMENTS
AND WE DEMONSTRATED THAT HELICOPSYCHE WAS
IN FACT
WHEN IT WAS EXCLUDED, CAUSED THESE HUGE GROWTHS
OF
ALGAE. BUT WHEN WE DID THE LIGHT BOX/DARK
BOX
EXPERIMENT WHAT WE SHOWED WAS THAT THE EXCLUSION
PRODUCED LESS OXYGEN AND HAD LOWER PRIMARY
PRODUCTIVITY THAN THE GRAZED TILES. THE EXCLUSION
HAD FAR LOWER PRODUCTIVITY THAN THE GRAZED
TILES.
HOW DO THESE 3 PRINCIPLES RELATE TO HELICOPSYCHE?
LET'S TAKE 30 SECONDS AND TALK TO EACH OTHER
ABOUT
THIS. THIS IS VERY IMPORTANT. TALK WITH EACH
OTHER.
OKAY. LET'S TALK ABOUT THIS. THIS IS AN
EXAMPLE WHERE WE ARE TALKING MATERIAL FROM
ONE
TOPIC AND RELATING IT COMPLETELY TO MATERIAL
WITH
ANOTHER TOPIC. WHAT DO YOU THINK? ANYBODY
HAVE
ANY SUGGESTIONS THEY WANT TO MAKE? EMILY?
OKAY.
GRAZING. WHAT SHE JUST SAID WAS, GRAZING BY
HELICOPSYCHE MOVES THOSE ALGAL COMMUNITIES
BACK TO
AN EARLY SUCCESSIONAL STAGE. IN FACT, IT
KEEPS
THEM AT AN EARLY SUCCESSIONAL STAGE BECAUSE
IT IS
CONSTANTLY GRAZING. CONSTANTLY GRAZING. OKAY?
WHAT IS ANOTHER THING?
BECAUSE IT IS AN EARLIER
SUCCESSIONAL STAGE IT IS KEEPING ALL THESE
R
SELECTED SPECIES, IT'S MORE PRODUCTIVE. OKAY?
THE R SELECTED SPECIES, EMPHASIS ON GROWTH.
WHAT
IS FUNNY? AM I MISSING SOMETHING. OH. KEEPING
THESE AT R SELECTED SPECIES WHICH ARE HIGHLY
PRODUCTIVE BECAUSE THEIR EMPHASIS IS ON GROWTH.
WHAT ELSE?
ALGAE HAVE HIGHER PRODUCTIVITY IN
THESE EARLY GROWTH STAGES. WHEN THEY GET TO
THAT
EXCLUSION TILE, WHICH REMEMBER LOOKED LIKE
THIS,
REMEMBER, HERE IS THE GRAZED TILES. YOU COULDN'T
EVEN SEE ANYTHING GROWING ON THEM. IN THE
EXCLUSION TILES, REMEMBER, IT WAS FORESTS.
IT WAS
VERY, VERY LOW PRODUCTIVITY. AND THE REASON
IS
THIS, IS THAT REMEMBER, EVERYTHING BELOW THAT
SURFACE IS NOT GETTING ANY SUNLIGHT. IN
A WAY,
THEY ARE LIKE REDWOOD TREES. IT IS MOSTLY
STALKS
AND DEAD CELLS AND NON-GROWING CELLS. SO,
IT IS
HIGH BIOMASS, BUT VERY, VERY LOW RATES OF
PRODUCTIVITY. OKAY? IN OTHER WORDS, IT WAS
MORE
OF A MATURE ECOSYSTEM THAN OCCURS HERE WHERE
EVERYTHING IS UNDER R SELECTION. REMEMBER,
THIS IS
WHERE THE EXCLUSION WORKED LIKE THAT. OKAY.
THIS
IS A VERY, VERY IMPORTANT POINT. AGAIN, THE
MOST
IMPORTANT POINT IS WE ARE INTEGRATING MATERIAL
ACROSS LECTURES. WHICH IS WHY WE TALKED IN
THE
BEGINNING THAT THIS IS CONCEPTUAL MATERIAL.
YOU
HAVE TO UNDERSTAND IT. YOU CAN'T, YOU CAN'T
JUST
MEMORIZE IT. ANYBODY HAVE ANY QUESTIONS ABOUT
THIS
OR ANYTHING YOU WANT ME TO GO OVER? I WANT
TO
MAKE SURE THAT YOU UNDERSTAND THIS. PLEASE,
IF YOU
HAVE GOT ANY QUESTIONS DON'T COME UP AFTER
CLASS.
ASK IT NOW. I WOULD RATHER MAKE SURE WE UNDERSTAND
THIS. BEHIND ME. THANKS. OKAY. OKAY. IN
THE
EXCLUDED TILES, THE ONES THAT ARE ELEVATED,
IT IS
NOT SO MUCH THAT THE MATERIAL IS DEAD, IT
IS JUST
NON-PRODUCTIVE. IT IS NOT PHOTOSYNTHESIZING.
OKAY. IT IS STILL ALIVE BUT IT IS NOT PRODUCING
OXYGEN. IT IS BASICALLY USING UP OXYGEN. RIGHT.
IT IS LIKE THE REDWOODS. THINK OF THE TRUNK
OF THE
REDWOODS NOT PRODUCING ANYTHING. IT IS THE
LEAVES
THAT ARE ON TOP THAT ARE PRODUCING. SO THAT
SECOND
POINT OF, HIGH BIOMASS. THE FIRST POINT AS
THE
ECOSYSTEMS MATURE THIS RELATES VERY, VERY
MUCH TO
WHAT YOU JUST SAID IS TO THE EXCLUSION, YOU
HAVE
GOT HIGH BIOMASS, BUT LOW NET PRODUCTIVITY.
OKAY.
THERE IS TWO OTHER COROLLARIES. NOSE THESE
ARE
LESS RELATED, WELL THEY ARE RELATED TO SUCCESSION,
BUT LESS RELATES TO HELICOPSYCHE. MATURE
ECOSYSTEMS HAVE MORE SPECIES THAN EARLY STAGE
ECOSYSTEMS. BUT, THE INCREASE IS NOT AMONG
AUTOTROPHIC ORGANISMS, IT IS AMONG HETEROTROPHIC
ORGANISMS. SO, PERDATION, PARASITISM, COMPETITION,
ALL OF THAT IS WHAT IS RESULTING IN THE INCREASE
SPECIES RICHNESS. IT IS AMONG HETEROTROPHS
NOT
AMONG AUTOTROPHS. NOW, ONE OTHER THING, PLANTS
AND
ANIMALS IN LATE SUCCESSIONAL STAGES TEND TO
BE MORE
SPECIALIZED. SO MAYBE THEY ARE PARASITES ON
A CERTAIN SPECIES. OR MAYBE THEY ARE FEEDING
ON
ONLY A CERTAIN COMPONENT OF THE ECOSYSTEM.
IN A
WAY ALMOST LIKE COMPETITIVE EXCLUSION, WHICH
REMEMBER TAKES PLACE OVER A LONG PERIODS OF
TIME.
SO THESE 5 RULES ABOUT ECOSYSTEMS ARE REALLY
QUITE,
QUITE IMPORTANT. AND, OFTEN TIMES NARROWER.
AND
AGAIN, THIS SHOULD ALL BE IN YOUR HANDOUTS.
OKAY.
ANYTHING YOU WANT ME TO GO OVER WITH THIS
BEFORE WE
GO TO ONE LAST TOPIC? YES? SO, IN THE FLOWER
POT EXPERIMENT. YEAH. THE ONE, OKAY, LET'S
LOOK
AT THIS. WHAT WE HAVE DONE IS WE HAVE RELEASES
NITROGEN AND WE HAVE RELEASED PHOSPHORUS.
WE ARE
MEASURING THE RESPONSE BY LOOKING AT THE ALGAE
THAT
IS GROWING ON THE OUTSIDE. THE ONE THAT HAS
THE
MOST ALGAE GROWING WOULD INDICATE THAT THE
SUPPLEMENTATION OF SAY PHOSPHORUS IS WHAT
WAS
NEEDED FOR THE ALGAE TO GROW. SO YOU KNOW
THAT IS
THE LIMITING FACTOR. OKAY. LET'S DO IT AGAIN.
WHAT YOU WOULD HAVE IS THE ALGAE THAT IS GROWING,
BECAUSE IT IS BEING RESTRAINED FROM GROWING
BECAUSE
THERE IS NOT ENOUGH OF THAT NUTRIENT THERE.
SO,
WHEN THE NUTRIENT LEECHES OUT AND YOU GET
ALGAL
RESPONSE YOU KNOW THAT IS THE LIMITING FACTOR.
OKAY? THERE IS NO PLANTS AT ALL. THERE IS
NO
PLANTS AT ALL. IT IS A FLOWER POT, AND ACTUALLY
THIS EXPERIMENT WAS DONE, IT WAS DONE BY A
GRADUATE
STUDENT IN COLORADO. SHE WENT ALL OVER THE
UNITED
STATES PUTTING THESE FLOWER POTS IN. AND,
UNFORTUNATELY, SOMETIMES SHE BOUGHT THEM FROM
MEXICO, WHERE THERE WAS A HIGH IRON CONTENT,
WHICH
SHE DIDN'T REALIZE SHE HAD THIS UNCONTROLLED
VARIABLE AND HAD TO GO BACK AND REPEAT A LOT
OF
THEM. BUT IT WAS AN ACTUAL EXPERIMENT THAT
WAS
DONE. ALL RIGHT. WE HAVE ABOUT 4 MINUTES.
I WANT
TO ASK YOU ABOUT THE PRIBILOF ISLAND SEALS.
WE
WANT TO WRAP THAT STORY UP TODAY. PRIBILOF
ISLANDS
SEALS. WHAT IS, WHAT HAPPENS TO THE POPULATION
IN
THAT PRIBILOF ISLAND STORY WHERE YOU HAVE
GOT 10
THOUSAND BACHELOR MALES BEING HARVESTED EVERY
YEAR.
THE POPULATION IS WELL OVER A MILLION. WHAT
IS
GOING TO HAPPEN TO THE POPULATION? IS IT GOING
TO
DECLINE DRASTICALLY? IS IT GOING TO STAY THE
SAME? IS IT GOING TO INCREASE? WHAT DO YOU
THINK? WHAT DO YOU THINK? YOU THINK IT WILL
DECLINE? WHAT DO YOU THINK? STAY THE SAME?
WHAT DO MOST OF YOU THINK IT WILL DO? DECLINE.
HOW MANY OF YOU THINK IT WILL DECLINE? REMEMBER,
THEY ARE PRODUCING SEALS CONTINUOUSLY. HOW
MANY DO
YOU THINK IT WILL INCREASE? YOU HAVE NO OPINIONS.
COME ON. OKAY. ONE MORE TIME, HOW MANY OF
YOU,
BECAUSE THIS IS THE TYPE OF STUFF YOU WILL
BE
GETTING IN A VERY, VERY SHORT PERIOD OF TIME,
HOW
MANY OF YOU THINK IF YOU TAKE 30 THOUSAND
OUT OF
THE POPULATION IN A HAREM SYSTEM THAT ARE
NOT
BREEDING, HOW MANY HAD YOU THINK THE POPULATION
IS
GOING TO INCREASE IN NUMBERS? VERSUS HOW MANY
OF
YOU DO YOU THINK IT WILL DECREASE IN NUMBERS?
WHAT ARE YOU SAYING, INCREASE OR DECREASE?
DECREASE. WHY? RIGHT. YOU GOT LIMITED NUMBER
OF
MALES MATING. IT IS A HAREM SYSTEM SO YOU
ARE
PULLING 30 THOUSAND OUT. BUT, IN FACT, ALL
OF
THESE MALES ARE MATING AND THE FEMALES ARE
PRODUCING OFFSPRING. OKAY? GUYS, LET ME TELL
YOU. THIS IS THE TYPE THING THAT I AM EXPECTING
YOU TO KNOW. IT IS NOT GOING TO BE BIO1 A
WHERE
YOU JUST HAVE TO MEMORIZE. OKAY? THE MALES,
THE
BACHELOR MALES ARE NOT MATING BUT THE MALES
THAT
ARE IN THE HAREMS ARE MATING SO OFFSPRING
ARE
CONSTANTLY BEING PRODUCED. OKAY. ANYTHING,
YEAH?
YOU JUST KILLING THE BACHELOR MALES. REMEMBER
THE
ASSIGNMENT WAS, LET'S END ON THIS NOTE, THE
ASSIGNMENT WAS FOR ALL OF YOU TO TALK TO PEOPLE
IN
YOUR DORMS THAT WERE PERHAPS SCIENCE MAJORS
BUT NOT
BIOLOGY BIOLOGISTS AND GO OVER THIS PROBLEM
WITH
THEM. REMEMBER I ASKED YOU SEVERAL THINGS;
WHAT IS
GOING TO HAPPEN TO THE POPULATION? WHAT WOULD
HAPPEN IF WE USED A DIFFERENT METHOD OF KILLING
THEM? WHAT WOULD HAPPEN IF WE HAD DIFFERENT
ORGANISMS WE WERE KILLING? WHY WE WERE KILLING
THEM? OKAY? JUST ONE LAST THING. I AM NOT
GIVING YOU ASSIGNMENTS. JUST FOR MY OWN BENEFIT,
IT IS REALLY TO TRY TO HELP YOU GUYS THINK
OF THIS.
SO HAVE A NICE WEEKEND AND I WILL SEE YOU
MONDAY.