Sharp objects and balloons.
I know you haven't given a lot
of thought to this, but it is
pretty fascinating.
What if you could find a sharp
object and a balloon, and make
them live in perfect harmony?
I'm pretty excited.
I think you will be, too.
Failed again.
I'm Steve Spangler, and I'm all
about making science fun.
For the last 20 years, I've
been teaching ways to turn
ordinary science experiments
into unforgettable learning
experiences.
I have an amazing team who will
do whatever it takes to
affect the way people
think about science.
And to do that, I live
by one motto.
Make it big, do it right,
give it class.
Remember that episode where we
took the pencils, and we put
the pencils through
the bag like this?
We called it the
leak proof bag.
The secret was the fact that
this plastic bag is a polymer.
A polymer's nothing more than
this long chain of molecules,
and we literally put the pencil
through this long chain
of molecules, and it sealed
itself back around, keeping
the water from leaking out.
The question today is could
you do the same thing with
another polymer, a
rubber balloon?
See, balloons are made out of
latex, and latex is nothing
more than a long chain
of molecules.
If we wanted to do the same
thing with the pencil through
the bag, you could,
but there's a
problem with the balloon.
It's under so much stress,
and so much pressure.
Watch.
See, most of the time we don't
think about blowing up a
bubble, and think about the
way that the molecules are
oriented here in the balloon.
We just think of blowing a
balloon up, tying it off, and
realizing that any sharp object,
like this cooking
skewer, and the balloon are
two things that don't mix.
See, when we get close here,
these strands of molecules are
stretched so thinly that just a
mere presence of that sharp
object, and it pops.
Let's do it again, but this time
we use a clear balloon.
This is a 9 inch, clear party
balloon that you would find,
like a helium balloon.
But by using a clear balloon,
you get to see some of the
properties of this latex balloon
that you couldn't see
what a colored balloon.
First and foremost, look at how
stretched and clear it is
in the very middle
of the balloon.
You'll notice two things.
You'll notice that there's a lot
of rubber around this area
here that's not stretched
tightly, and there's not a lot
of rubber that's stretched
tightly right here.
So this is the area that's most
like that bag when we did
the pencil through the bag.
The molecules are not
stretched as tight.
They've got a little bit
of give to them.
So if we were ever to try to
take a sharp object and stick
it through, this would be the
point of entry, and this could
be the point of entry.
If we could push it all the
way through, you literally
would do surgery on
a latex balloon.
Now it's time to get
a sharp object.
It's an ordinary cooking skewer,
the kind that you
would find at the
grocery store.
Except this one here, I'm not
going to take any chances.
I want that tip to be
super, super sharp.
So I'm using just a small
amount of really fine
sandpaper to get the
perfect tip.
All right, it's time
for surgery.
If I'm going to try to take this
and put it through the
balloon, I'm going to try to
go through this area here
where it's the greatest amount
of excess latex rubber.
When you push, you push, and
just keep on pushing, making
sure that your hand is at the
bottom, because every once in
awhile, OK, all the
time it will pop.
Watch this as it comes
out the other end.
And that's how you would do
surgery on a regular balloon.
Now, you see that a
little bit of air.
Well, you can't see the air.
I can feel it.
You can sometimes hear it.
A small amount of air
coming out here
as it's coming through.
Of course the air
is leaking out.
So unlike the leak proof bag,
where the water didn't come
out, the air will come out,
and we can slowly start to
pull this back out again here.
You can see the air goes down,
and finally we're at the very
end, and the balloon can pop.
So the secret here is stress.
And let's just use one of
these clear balloons.
Let's use a Sharpie pen to draw
something on the balloon
to see what it looks like
once it's inflated.
In this particular case, just
simple little dots.
We're going to give them
all the same size.
So the goal is to keep all the
dots the same size so we can
compare them once the
balloon is blown up.
So all the dots hopefully are
about the same size, but watch
what happens when you
blow this up.
Take a look at where the latex
is the most stressed.
See, the dots almost disappear
here in this part here.
Look at how big that dot is
compared to the size of the
dot down here, where it's
relatively unstretched.
Is it easy to be able to put
a needle through a regular
balloon where it's
not stressed?
Absolutely.
In fact, that's exactly what
you're doing when you do
surgery at this end, or
the end down here.
Sometimes the edge of the skewer
will catch, and so a
small amount of cooking oil,
or maybe a little bit of
Vaseline, works very well to
help this as the skewer tries
to make its way through the
balloon without popping.
Again, if you were to go
through the part of the
balloon here where it's the
greatest amount of stress,
it's sure to pop.
But this end right here, as
you push, and that small
amount of Vaseline will help.
It's perfect as it
goes through.
You just have to look on the
other end where it's coming
through, and that's the perfect
spot right here.
And it's the perfect
And you can see it's fairly
easy to make that skewer
travel right through
the balloon.
Simple.
So let's say you want to use
this as a metaphor, an object
lesson, attach some sort of
meaning to it other than just
teaching science.
Well, one of the things that
has been easy to do is to
think of this as handling
stress.
If I want to come up against
any stressful kind of
situation, I have to take a look
at the situation first,
and figure out where to enter,
where to get involved, and
most importantly,
where to exit.
And so if I took this volatile
situation that's here, it's
under a tremendous amount
of pressure.
And I guess the needle could be
the source of the problem.
If I try to go here, I'm trying
to do kind of a head on
collision with the problem.
This is where it's the greatest
amount of stress.
And then in negotiation,
it's horrible.
It's like asking mom and dad for
something during tax time.
Ask for nothing during
tax time.
March, bad time.
Christmas time, good
time, right?
So all you're trying to do is to
figure out where the least
amount of stress is.
And if we go in where the least
amount of stress is and
enter the problem, it's pretty
easy to be able to get knee
deep into that situation,
analyze it, try to fix it, and
have an exit point over
here like this.
So as a leadership principle, or
maybe a business idea, or a
way to be able to talk about
counseling or bullying,
whatever it might be, it's
kind of an interesting
illustration, I think, to be
to enter this very volatile
situation with something
that sharp, but you
get the point, right?
That was horrible.
But you're going
to be using it.
Well, back in the 1970s, my
mom and dad bought me this
magic trick called needle
through the balloon.
What you got was this needle,
a super, super long, sharp
needle that you always ended
up poking yourself with,
attached to some ribbon
down at the very end.
Now, there wasn't really
a science explanation.
They just said that the secret
was to enter the balloon
through the end and come out
through the very top, and it
would look as if the
magician had these
extraordinary powers.
But herein lies the problem,
because what was once a very
cool magic trick was no longer
a secret because of people
like Mr. Wizard and Bill Nye,
and Steve Spangler.
Take two.
All right.
Listen.
So, see, throw caution
to the wind.
All the kids know the secret
because of these people on TV.
So what if you could throw
caution to the wind, and
instead of going through this
end here that all the kids
knew about, what if you could go
through the side like this?
So you just poke it right
through the side, where
everybody knows that
it should pop.
And yet, in the hands
of a magician,
this is totally possible.
Try that fancy science
teachers.
But you see, my problem with
magic is I'm not very good at
keeping a secret, and I've got
to tell you how this works.
You just have to
get some tape.
So--
MALE SPEAKER: Mr. Spangler?
I'm gonna need your card.
STEVE SPANGLER: No,
not the card.
My membership card?
MALE SPEAKER: That's the one.
STEVE SPANGLER: Who made
you Captain Magic?
Not all tape works well.
You'll have to do a little
experimenting, but this
packing tape seems to
work perfect for me.
The secret here is to use this
to keep the sides of the
balloon from stretching,
expanding, and
exploding real quickly.
So you blow up the balloon, and
you don't have to use a
clear one for this, but
it's pretty effective.
Again, this is the
dangerous spot.
All the kids who think that they
know this trick know that
you have to go here
and you go here.
So you take a small piece
of tape like this.
You put it right at the
spot where they know
you can't go through.
You put it right there.
That's number one.
And one on the opposite side
would be perfect if you were
going to do the skewer
through the balloon.
Well, you can see that if I show
it to you, by holding it
here like this, it looks
like a regular balloon.
This is great.
All right, let me test my luck.
Watch.
Tape on the side, let's see if
you can do it with the skewer.
This is good.
It's leaking just
a little bit.
You have to go pretty fast.
That's the skewer through the
balloon, and hopefully nobody
knows how it works.
Hey, magic man.
Higginsworth.
Come here.
Look at this.
Big balloon.
I got a magic trick for you.
Watch this.
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah, I've
seen this one.
STEVE SPANGLER: No, you haven't
seen anything before.
Watch this.
This is the big balloon.
You've never anybody
do it like this.
Look, no tape on it.
And look, no extra rubber
right here.
This is just a huge, it's called
a cloudburst balloon.
Ladies and gentlemen, boys and
girls, pushing the skewer
through the giant balloon.
Here we go.
I never was very good
at that trick.
Could you get the vacuum?
MALE SPEAKER: Thanks for that.
STEVE SPANGLER: So with all of
this sharp objects going
through balloons, I know
what you're thinking.
Maybe it's the air.
What if we change the air?
What if it was helium?
Would that work?
Well, you could use the helium,
and it would probably
work the right way, but nobody
really cares, because you're
just using helium.
Nobody really cares
about that.
But what if we used a gas that
was six times heavier than the
air we breathe?
Sulfur hexafluoride.
Would the needle through the
balloon work the same way if
you use this gas?
Once again, nobody
really cares.
In fact, nobody cared about this
demo until we did it in
2007 on The Ellen Show.
Now it seems to be kind
of a staple with it.
You've gotta get oxygen
back into your
lungs, or you're sleepy.
Don't try this at home, kids.
Higginsworth!
Many people wonder what's magic
about a magic wand.
It has very many powers, like
passing through a solid object
without harming it.
Let me demonstrate with a
balloon and its holder.
We'll put the balloon
in its holder.
And now we're going to stick
the wand right through.
One thing.
Let's add something
to the mystery.
Let's put the handkerchief
over the want.
Now let's stick it through.
Went right through.
Let's pull the want out.
Pull the hank out.
I bet you're saying that it
isn't a real balloon.
Watch.
MALE SPEAKER: I know it's
a real balloon.
MALE SPEAKER: That was
MALE SPEAKER: Beautiful.
MALE SPEAKER: I liked it.
It was very good.