MICHAEL MOYNIHAN: The Orange
Lodge in Belfast, the oldest
Protestant fraternal
organization in the country,
organizes the July 12 parade.
Before the start of the march,
we stopped by their
headquarters.
It was teeming with people
from all around the
Anglosphere.
TOM HAIRE: The 12th of July is
the commemorating of the 121st
anniversary of the Battle
of the Boyne.
It is important to do because
at the end of the day, the
Battle of the Boyne gave
everyone through the world,
shall we say, civil and
religious liberty.
And sometimes that liberty, at
the moment, is being eroded by
different legislation, which
affects some of our parade.
MICHAEL MOYNIHAN: Explain to
those who would be completely
baffled by this how a bunch of
Canadians come to march in an
Orange parade in Belfast.
MALE SPEAKER: My family
roots here are
five generations gone.
Like, I'm a five-generation
Canadian, but
all Orange, in Canada.
Canada was a big place for
the Orange Order as well.
We don't say a whole lot when
we come here, because
unfortunately, it's
not our fight.
MICHAEL MOYNIHAN: You're not
throwing paving stones at
people
MALE SPEAKER: No, no.
MICHAEL MOYNIHAN: Molotov
cocktails.
MALE SPEAKER: As you know,
Canadians, we're probably the
most easygoing people around.
[MARCHING BAND PLAYING]
MICHAEL MOYNIHAN: The parades
have just begun.
We're walking down
Crumlin Road.
As you can see, I am
leading the parade.
I am leaving the Prods down
Crumlin road to a flash point
very close to here.
So far, there hasn't
been a hitch.
There's police presence,
very, very, very heavy.
And we'll see what happens.
[MARCHING BAND PLAYING]
MICHAEL MOYNIHAN: To everyone
willing to talk to us, the
parade was a celebration
of Protestant culture.
But increasingly, it became
apparent that it was also a
celebration of that particular
Ulster talent for massive
alcohol consumption.
We're about an hour into this
march in Ulster, in the city
center of Belfast.
Things, according to Twitter,
that we're following this on,
have passed off fairly
peacefully in
all the flash points.
But the atmosphere's
a bit strange.
It's a bit somber.
It's a bit grey.
It's a bit dim.
We were told last night that
Protestants don't like to talk
people from the media.
So we've asked a few people to
talk to us to tell us what's
going on here, and
no one wants to.
So tonight is when it kicks off,
and so we're just waiting
to go up to the sort of mixed
areas up by Ardoyne, where it
was bad last year.
And the police presence is
going to be pretty heavy.
And apparently that's when it's
going to get a bit hairy.
FEMALE SPEAKER: (SINGING) We
will hear the people cry, let
the POA go by, We are the
pride of Ardoyne.
MALE SPEAKER 1: Well, I disagree
with the march or the
parade being allowed to walk
through the district that it
does walk through, the road that
it walks on, because of
the symbolism that
it deals with.
In one case, they would carry a
banner to a UVF man who had
killed a Catholic.
That, obviously, is about more
than just symbolism.
That's about rubbing
your nose in it.
MALE SPEAKER 2: The Loyalist
position on that would be that
it's a traditional route,
it's historical.
Obviously, I believe that
there does need to be
dialogue, and I think symbols
and flags and songs that are
deliberately designed to be
provocative, that that
certainly should be
talked about.
MICHAEL MOYNIHAN: Things are
going slightly gnarlier.
Packs of kids that we tried to
talk to, who were drinking
bottles of straight vodka and
smoking weed on the street,
got a little friendly with the
camera and were a bit grabby.
MICHAEL MOYNIHAN: So we've
been-- we've been marching for
a couple hours now, and we've
passed city center, and I
think it's time for us to peel
off here and go find some
Republicans.
So we're gonna get the fuck out
of here, because things
are getting drunker and uglier.