fellow Americans: Fifty-one
years ago, John F. Kennedy
declared to this chamber that
"the Constitution makes us not
"rivals for power but
partners for progress."
(applause)
"It is my task," he said, "to
report the State of the Union --
"to improve it is
the task of us all."
Tonight, thanks to the grit and
determination of the American
people, there is much
progress to report.
After a decade of grinding
war, our brave men and women in
uniform are coming home.
(applause)
After years of
grueling recession,
our businesses have created
over six million new jobs.
We buy more American cars
than we have in five years,
and less foreign oil
than we have in 20.
(applause)
Our housing market is healing,
our stock market is rebounding,
and consumers, patients, and
homeowners enjoy stronger
protections than ever before.
(applause)
So, together, we have cleared
away the rubble of crisis,
and we can say with renewed
confidence that the State of our
Union is stronger.
(applause)
But we gather here knowing that
there are millions of Americans
whose hard work and dedication
have not yet been rewarded.
Our economy is adding jobs --
but too many people still can't
find full-time employment.
Corporate profits have
skyrocketed to all-time highs --
but for more than a decade,
wages and incomes have
barely budged.
It is our generation's
task, then,
to reignite the true engine of
America's economic growth --
a rising, thriving middle class.
(applause)
It is our unfinished task to
restore the basic bargain that
built this country -- the idea
that if you work hard and meet
your responsibilities,
you can get ahead,
no matter where you come from,
no matter what you look like,
or who you love.
It is our unfinished task to
make sure that this government
works on behalf of the
many, and not just the few;
that it encourages
free enterprise,
rewards individual initiative,
and opens the doors of
opportunity to every child
across this great nation.
(applause)
The American people don't
expect government to solve
every problem.
They don't expect those of us
in this chamber to agree on
every issue.
But they do expect us to put the
nation's interests before party.
(applause)
They do expect us to forge
reasonable compromise
where we can.
For they know that America
moves forward only when we do so
together, and that the
responsibility of improving this
union remains the
task of us all.
Our work must begin by making
some basic decisions about our
budget -- decisions that will
have a huge impact on the
strength of our recovery.
Over the last few years, both
parties have worked together to
reduce the deficit by
more than $2.5 trillion --
mostly through spending cuts,
but also by raising tax rates on
the wealthiest 1% of Americans.
As a result, we are more than
halfway towards the goal of
$4 trillion in deficit reduction
that economists say we need to
stabilize our finances.
Now we need to finish the job.
And the question is, how?
In 2011, Congress passed a law
saying that if both parties
couldn't agree on a plan
to reach our deficit goal,
about a trillion dollars'
worth of budget cuts would
automatically go into
effect this year.
These sudden, harsh, arbitrary
cuts would jeopardize our
military readiness.
They'd devastate priorities
like education, and energy,
and medical research.
They would certainly
slow our recovery,
and cost us hundreds
of thousands of jobs.
That's why Democrats,
Republicans, business leaders,
and economists have already
said that these cuts,
known here in Washington
as the sequester,
are a really bad idea.
Now, some in Congress have
proposed preventing only the
defense cuts by making even
bigger cuts to things like
education and job training,
Medicare and Social
Security benefits.
That idea is even worse.
(applause)
Yes, the biggest driver of our
long-term debt is the rising
cost of health care for
an aging population.
And those of us who care deeply
about programs like Medicare
must embrace the need
for modest reforms --
otherwise, our retirement
programs will crowd out the
investments we need
for our children,
and jeopardize the promise
of a secure retirement for
future generations.
But we can't ask senior citizens
and working families to shoulder
the entire burden of deficit
reduction while asking nothing
more from the wealthiest
and the most powerful.
(applause)
We won't grow the middle class
simply by shifting the cost of
health care or college onto
families that are already
struggling, or by forcing
communities to lay off more
teachers and more cops
and more firefighters.
Most Americans -- Democrats,
Republicans, and independents --
understand that we can't just
cut our way to prosperity.
They know that broad-based
economic growth requires a
balanced approach to
deficit reduction,
with spending cuts and revenue,
and with everybody doing
their fair share.
And that's the approach
I offer tonight.
On Medicare, I'm prepared to
enact reforms that will achieve
the same amount of health care
savings by the beginning of the
next decade as the reforms
proposed by the bipartisan
Simpson-Bowles commission.
(applause)
Already, the Affordable Care Act
is helping to slow the growth of
health care costs.
(applause)
And the reforms I'm
proposing go even further.
We'll reduce taxpayer subsidies
to prescription drug companies
and ask more from the
wealthiest seniors.
(applause)
We'll bring down costs by
changing the way our government
pays for Medicare, because our
medical bills shouldn't be based
on the number of tests ordered
or days spent in the hospital;
they should be based on the
quality of care that our
seniors receive.
(applause)
And I am open to additional
reforms from both parties,
so long as they don't
violate the guarantee of a
secure retirement.
Our government shouldn't make
promises we cannot keep --
but we must keep the
promises we've already made.
(applause)
To hit the rest of our
deficit reduction target,
we should do what leaders
in both parties have already
suggested, and save hundreds of
billions of dollars by getting
rid of tax loopholes and
deductions for the well-off and
the well-connected.
After all, why would we choose
to make deeper cuts to education
and Medicare just to protect
special interest tax breaks?
How is that fair?
Why is it that deficit reduction
is a big emergency justifying
making cuts in Social Security
benefits but not closing
some loopholes?
How does that promote growth?
(applause)
Now is our best
chance for bipartisan,
comprehensive tax reform that
encourages job creation and
helps bring down the deficit.
(applause)
We can get this done.
The American people deserve
a tax code that helps small
businesses spend less time
filling out complicated forms,
and more time
expanding and hiring --
a tax code that ensures
billionaires with high-powered
accountants can't work the
system and pay a lower rate than
their hardworking secretaries; a
tax code that lowers incentives
to move jobs overseas, and
lowers tax rates for businesses
and manufacturers that are
creating jobs right here in the
United States of America.
That's what tax
reform can deliver.
That's what we can do together.
(applause)
I realize that tax reform
and entitlement reform will
not be easy.
The politics will be
hard for both sides.
None of us will get
100% of what we want.
But the alternative will cost
us jobs, hurt our economy,
visit hardship on millions
of hardworking Americans.
So let's set party interests
aside and work to pass a budget
that replaces reckless cuts
with smart savings and wise
investments in our future.
And let's do it without the
brinksmanship that stresses
consumers and scares
off investors.
(applause)
The greatest nation on Earth
cannot keep conducting its
business by drifting from one
manufactured crisis to the next.
(applause)
We can't do it.
Let's agree right here, right
now to keep the people's
government open, and
pay our bills on time,
and always uphold the full faith
and credit of the United States
of America.
(applause)
The American people have
worked too hard, for too long,
rebuilding from one crisis to
see their elected officials
cause another.
(applause)
Now, most of us agree that a
plan to reduce the deficit must
be part of our agenda.
But let's be clear, deficit
reduction alone is not an
economic plan.
(applause)
A growing economy that creates
good, middle-class jobs --
that must be the North Star
that guides our efforts.
(applause)
Every day, we should ask
ourselves three questions as a
nation: How do we attract
more jobs to our shores?
How do we equip our people
with the skills they need to
get those jobs?
And how do we make sure
that hard work leads to a
decent living?
A year and a half ago, I put
forward an American Jobs Act
that independent economists
said would create more than
1 million new jobs.
And I thank the last Congress
for passing some of that agenda.
I urge this Congress
to pass the rest.
(applause)
But tonight, I'll lay out
additional proposals that are
fully paid for and fully
consistent with the budget
framework both parties
agreed to just 18 months ago.
Let me repeat -- nothing
I'm proposing tonight should
increase our deficit
by a single dime.
It is not a bigger
government we need,
but a smarter government that
sets priorities and invests in
broad-based growth.
(applause)
That's what we should
be looking for.
(applause)
Our first priority is making
America a magnet for new jobs
and manufacturing.
After shedding jobs
for more than 10 years,
our manufacturers have
added about 500,000 jobs over
the past three.
Caterpillar is bringing
jobs back from Japan.
Ford is bringing jobs
back from Mexico.
And this year, Apple will start
making Macs in America again.
(applause)
There are things we
can do, right now,
to accelerate this trend.
Last year, we created our
first manufacturing innovation
institute in Youngstown, Ohio.
A once-shuttered warehouse is
now a state-of-the art lab where
new workers are mastering the 3D
printing that has the potential
to revolutionize the way
we make almost everything.
There's no reason this
can't happen in other towns.
So tonight, I'm announcing the
launch of three more of these
manufacturing hubs, where
businesses will partner with the
Department of Defense and Energy
to turn regions left behind by
globalization into global
centers of high-tech jobs.
And I ask this Congress to help
create a network of 15 of these
hubs and guarantee that the next
revolution in manufacturing is
made right here in America.
We can get that done.
(applause)
Now, if we want to
make the best products,
we also have to invest
in the best ideas.
Every dollar we invested to map
the human genome returned $140
to our economy -- every dollar.
Today, our scientists are
mapping the human brain to
unlock the answers
to Alzheimer's.
They're developing drugs to
regenerate damaged organs;
devising new material to
make batteries 10 times
more powerful.
Now is not the time to gut these
job-creating investments in
science and innovation.
Now is the time to reach a level
of research and development not
seen since the height
of the Space Race.
We need to make
those investments.
(applause)
Today, no area holds more
promise than our investments in
American energy.
After years of talking about it,
we're finally poised to control
our own energy future.
We produce more oil at home
than we have in 15 years.
(applause)
We have doubled the distance our
cars will go on a gallon of gas,
and the amount of renewable
energy we generate from sources
like wind and solar -- with tens
of thousands of good American
jobs to show for it.
We produce more natural
gas than ever before --
and nearly everyone's energy
bill is lower because of it.
And over the last four years,
our emissions of the dangerous
carbon pollution that threatens
our planet have actually fallen.
But for the sake of our
children and our future,
we must do more to
combat climate change.
(applause)
Now, it's true that no
single event makes a trend.
But the fact is the 12 hottest
years on record have all come in
the last 15.
Heat waves, droughts,
wildfires, floods --
all are now more frequent
and more intense.
We can choose to believe
that Superstorm Sandy,
and the most severe
drought in decades,
and the worst wildfires some
states have ever seen were all
just a freak coincidence.
Or we can choose to believe in
the overwhelming judgment of
science -- and act
before it's too late.
(applause)
Now, the good news is we can
make meaningful progress on this
issue while driving
strong economic growth.
I urge this Congress to get
together, pursue a bipartisan,
market-based solution
to climate change,
like the one John McCain and Joe
Lieberman worked on together a
few years ago.
But if Congress won't act soon
to protect future generations,
I will.
(applause)
I will direct my Cabinet to come
up with executive actions we can
take, now and in the
future, to reduce pollution,
prepare our communities for the
consequences of climate change,
and speed the transition to more
sustainable sources of energy.
Four years ago, other countries
dominated the clean energy
market and the jobs
that came with it.
And we've begun to change that.
Last year, wind energy added
nearly half of all new power
capacity in America.
So let's generate even more.
Solar energy gets
cheaper by the year --
let's drive down
costs even further.
As long as countries like China
keep going all in on clean
energy, so must we.
Now, in the meantime, the
natural gas boom has led to
cleaner power and greater
energy independence.
We need to encourage that.
And that's why my administration
will keep cutting red tape and
speeding up new oil
and gas permits.
(applause)
That's got to be part of
an all-of-the-above plan.
But I also want to work with
this Congress to encourage the
research and technology that
helps natural gas burn even
cleaner and protects
our air and our water.
In fact, much of our new-found
energy is drawn from lands and
waters that we, the
public, own together.
So tonight, I propose we use
some of our oil and gas revenues
to fund an Energy Security Trust
that will drive new research and
technology to shift our cars
and trucks off oil for good.
If a nonpartisan coalition of
CEOs and retired generals and
admirals can get behind
this idea, then so can we.
Let's take their advice and free
our families and businesses from
the painful spikes in gas
prices we've put up with for
far too long.
I'm also issuing a
new goal for America:
Let's cut in half the energy
wasted by our homes and
businesses over
the next 20 years.
(applause)
We'll work with the
states to do it.
Those states with the best ideas
to create jobs and lower energy
bills by constructing more
efficient buildings will receive
federal support to
help make that happen.
America's energy sector is
just one part of an aging
infrastructure badly
in need of repair.
Ask any CEO where they'd
rather locate and hire --
a country with deteriorating
roads and bridges,
or one with high-speed rail and
Internet; high-tech schools,
self-healing power grids.
The CEO of Siemens America -- a
company that brought hundreds of
new jobs to North Carolina --
said that if we upgrade our
infrastructure, they'll
bring even more jobs.
And that's the attitude
of a lot of companies all
around the world.
And I know you want these
job-creating projects in
your district.
I've seen all those
ribbon-cuttings.
(laughter)
So tonight, I propose a
"Fix-It-First" program to put
people to work as soon as
possible on our most urgent
repairs, like the nearly 70,000
structurally deficient bridges
across the country.
(applause)
And to make sure taxpayers
don't shoulder the whole burden,
I'm also proposing a Partnership
to Rebuild America that attracts
private capital to upgrade
what our businesses need most:
modern ports to move our goods,
modern pipelines to withstand a
storm, modern schools
worthy of our children.
(applause)
Let's prove that there's no
better place to do business than
here in the United
States of America,
and let's start right away.
We can get this done.
And part of our rebuilding
effort must also involve our
housing sector.
The good news is our housing
market is finally healing from
the collapse of 2007.
Home prices are rising at the
fastest pace in six years.
Home purchases
are up nearly 50%,
and construction
is expanding again.
But even with mortgage
rates near a 50-year low,
too many families with solid
credit who want to buy a home
are being rejected.
Too many families who never
missed a payment and want to
refinance are being told no.
That's holding our
entire economy back.
We need to fix it.
Right now, there's a bill in
this Congress that would give
every responsible homeowner
in America the chance to save
$3,000 a year by refinancing
at today's rates.
Democrats and Republicans
have supported it before,
so what are we waiting for?
Take a vote, and
send me that bill.
(applause)
Why would we be against that?
Why would that be a partisan
issue, helping folks refinance?
Right now, overlapping
regulations keep responsible
young families from
buying their first home.
What's holding us back?
Let's streamline the process,
and help our economy grow.
These initiatives in
manufacturing, energy,
infrastructure, housing --
all these things will help
entrepreneurs and small
business owners expand and
create new jobs.
But none of it will matter
unless we also equip our
citizens with the skills and
training to fill those jobs.
(applause)
And that has to start at
the earliest possible age.
Study after study shows that the
sooner a child begins learning,
the better he or she
does down the road.
But today, fewer than 3 in 10
four year-olds are enrolled in a
high-quality preschool program.
Most middle-class parents can't
afford a few hundred bucks a
week for a private preschool.
And for poor kids who
need help the most,
this lack of access to preschool
education can shadow them for
the rest of their lives.
So tonight, I propose working
with states to make high-quality
preschool available to every
single child in America.
(applause)
That's something we
should be able to do.
(applause)
Every dollar we invest in
high-quality early childhood
education can save more than
seven dollars later on --
by boosting graduation rates,
reducing teen pregnancy,
even reducing violent crime.
In states that make it a
priority to educate our youngest
children, like
Georgia or Oklahoma,
studies show students grow up
more likely to read and do math
at grade level, graduate
high school, hold a job,
form more stable
families of their own.
We know this works.
So let's do what works and make
sure none of our children start
the race of life already behind.
Let's give our kids that chance.
(applause)
Let's also make sure that a high
school diploma puts our kids on
a path to a good job.
Right now, countries like
Germany focus on graduating
their high school students with
the equivalent of a technical
degree from one of our
community colleges.
So those German kids, they're
ready for a job when they
graduate high school.
They've been trained for
the jobs that are there.
Now at schools like
P-Tech in Brooklyn,
a collaboration between New
York Public Schools and City
University of New York and IBM,
students will graduate with a
high school diploma and an
associate's degree in computers
or engineering.
We need to give every American
student opportunities like this.
(applause)
And four years ago, we
started Race to the Top --
a competition that convinced
almost every state to develop
smarter curricula
and higher standards,
all for about 1% of what we
spend on education each year.
Tonight, I'm announcing a new
challenge to redesign America's
high schools so they better
equip graduates for the demands
of a high-tech economy.
And we'll reward schools that
develop new partnerships with
colleges and employers, and
create classes that focus on
science, technology,
engineering and math --
the skills today's employers
are looking for to fill the jobs
that are there right now and
will be there in the future.
Now, even with
better high schools,
most young people will
need some higher education.
It's a simple fact the
more education you've got,
the more likely you are to have
a good job and work your way
into the middle class.
But today, skyrocketing costs
price too many young people out
of a higher education, or saddle
them with unsustainable debt.
Through tax credits,
grants and better loans,
we've made college more
affordable for millions of
students and families
over the last few years.
But taxpayers can't keep on
subsidizing higher and higher
and higher costs for
higher education.
Colleges must do their
part to keep costs down,
and it's our job to
make sure that they do.
(applause)
So tonight, I ask Congress to
change the Higher Education Act
so that affordability and value
are included in determining
which colleges receive
certain types of federal aid.
(applause)
And tomorrow, my administration
will release a new
"College Scorecard" that parents
and students can use to compare
schools based on a
simple criteria --
where you can get the most
bang for your educational buck.
Now, to grow our middle class,
our citizens have to have access
to the education and training
that today's jobs require.
But we also have to make sure
that America remains a place
where everyone who's
willing to work --
everybody who's willing to
work hard has the chance to
get ahead.
Our economy is stronger when
we harness the talents and
ingenuity of striving,
hopeful immigrants.
(applause)
And right now, leaders
from the business, labor,
law enforcement,
faith communities --
they all agree that the time
has come to pass comprehensive
immigration reform.
(applause)
Now is the time to do it.
Now is the time to get it done.
(applause)
Real reform means
stronger border security,
and we can build on the progress
my administration has already
made -- putting more boots on
the Southern border than at any
time in our history and reducing
illegal crossings to their
lowest levels in 40 years.
Real reform means establishing
a responsible pathway to earned
citizenship -- a path that
includes passing a background
check, paying taxes and
a meaningful penalty,
learning English, and going to
the back of the line behind the
folks trying to
come here legally.
(applause)
And real reform means fixing the
legal immigration system to cut
waiting periods and attract the
highly-skilled entrepreneurs and
engineers that will help create
jobs and grow our economy.
(applause)
In other words, we know
what needs to be done.
And as we speak, bipartisan
groups in both chambers are
working diligently
to draft a bill,
and I applaud their efforts.
So let's get this done.
Send me a comprehensive
immigration reform bill in the
next few months, and I
will sign it right away.
And America will
be better for it.
(applause)
Let's get it done.
But we can't stop there.
We know our economy is stronger
when our wives, our mothers,
our daughters can live their
lives free from discrimination
in the workplace, and free from
the fear of domestic violence.
Today, the Senate passed the
Violence Against Women Act that
Joe Biden originally
wrote almost 20 years ago.
And I now urge the
House to do the same.
(applause)
Good job, Joe.
And I ask this Congress to
declare that women should earn a
living equal to their efforts,
and finally pass the Paycheck
Fairness Act this year.
(applause)
We know our economy is stronger
when we reward an honest day's
work with honest wages.
But today, a full-time worker
making the minimum wage earns
$14,500 a year.
Even with the tax
relief we put in place,
a family with two kids that
earns the minimum wage still
lives below the poverty line.
That's wrong.
That's why, since the last time
this Congress raised the minimum
wage, 19 states have chosen
to bump theirs even higher.
Tonight, let's declare that in
the wealthiest nation on Earth,
no one who works full-time
should have to live in poverty,
and raise the federal minimum
wage to $9.00 an hour.
(applause)
We should be able
to get that done.
(applause)
This single step would raise
the incomes of millions of
working families.
It could mean the difference
between groceries or the food
bank; rent or eviction; scraping
by or finally getting ahead.
For businesses
across the country,
it would mean customers with
more money in their pockets.
And a whole lot of folks out
there would probably need less
help from government.
In fact, working folks shouldn't
have to wait year after year for
the minimum wage to go up while
CEO pay has never been higher.
So here's an idea that Governor
Romney and I actually agreed on
last year -- let's tie the
minimum wage to the cost of
living, so that it finally
becomes a wage you can live on.
(applause)
Tonight, let's also recognize
that there are communities in
this country where no
matter how hard you work,
it is virtually
impossible to get ahead.
Factory towns decimated from
years of plants packing up.
Inescapable pockets of
poverty, urban and rural,
where young adults are still
fighting for their first job.
America is not a place where the
chance of birth or circumstance
should decide our destiny.
And that's why we need to build
new ladders of opportunity into
the middle class for all who
are willing to climb them.
Let's offer incentives to
companies that hire Americans
who've got what it takes
to fill that job opening,
but have been out of work so
long that no one will give them
a chance anymore.
Let's put people back to work
rebuilding vacant homes in
run-down neighborhoods.
And this year, my administration
will begin to partner with 20 of
the hardest-hit towns in America
to get these communities back
on their feet.
We'll work with local leaders
to target resources at public
safety, and education,
and housing.
We'll give new tax credits to
businesses that hire and invest.
And we'll work to strengthen
families by removing the
financial deterrents to
marriage for low-income couples,
and do more to
encourage fatherhood --
because what makes you a man
isn't the ability to conceive a
child; it's having the
courage to raise one.
And we want to encourage that.
We want to help that.
(applause)
Stronger families.
Stronger communities.
A stronger America.
It is this kind of
prosperity -- broad, shared,
built on a thriving
middle class --
that has always been the
source of our progress at home.
It's also the foundation
of our power and influence
throughout the world.
Tonight, we stand united
in saluting the troops and
civilians who sacrifice
every day to protect us.
Because of them, we can say with
confidence that America will
complete its mission in
Afghanistan and achieve our
objective of defeating
the core of al Qaeda.
(applause)
Already, we have brought home
33,000 of our brave servicemen
and women.
This spring, our forces will
move into a support role,
while Afghan security
forces take the lead.
Tonight, I can announce
that over the next year,
another 34,000 American troops
will come home from Afghanistan.
This drawdown will continue
and by the end of next year,
our war in Afghanistan
will be over.
(applause)
Beyond 2014, America's
commitment to a unified and
sovereign Afghanistan
will endure,
but the nature of our
commitment will change.
We're negotiating an agreement
with the Afghan government that
focuses on two missions --
training and equipping Afghan
forces so that the country
does not again slip into chaos,
and counterterrorism efforts
that allow us to pursue the
remnants of al Qaeda
and their affiliates.
Today, the organization that
attacked us on 9/11 is a shadow
of its former self.
(applause)
It's true, different al Qaeda
affiliates and extremist groups
have emerged -- from the
Arabian Peninsula to Africa.
The threat these groups
pose is evolving.
But to meet this threat, we
don't need to send tens of
thousands of our sons and
daughters abroad or occupy
other nations.
Instead, we'll need to help
countries like Yemen, and Libya,
and Somalia provide
for their own security,
and help allies who take
the fight to terrorists,
as we have in Mali.
And where necessary, through
a range of capabilities,
we will continue to take direct
action against those terrorists
who pose the gravest
threat to Americans.
(applause)
Now, as we do, we must enlist
our values in the fight.
That's why my administration
has worked tirelessly to forge a
durable legal and policy
framework to guide our
counterterrorism efforts.
Throughout, we have kept
Congress fully informed of
our efforts.
I recognize that
in our democracy,
no one should just take my word
for it that we're doing things
the right way.
So in the months ahead, I will
continue to engage Congress to
ensure not only
that our targeting,
detention and prosecution of
terrorists remains consistent
with our laws and system
of checks and balances,
but that our efforts are even
more transparent to the American
people and to the world.
(applause)
Of course, our challenges
don't end with al Qaeda.
America will continue to lead
the effort to prevent the spread
of the world's most
dangerous weapons.
The regime in North Korea must
know they will only achieve
security and prosperity
by meeting their
international obligations.
Provocations of the sort we saw
last night will only further
isolate them, as we
stand by our allies,
strengthen our own missile
defense and lead the world in
taking firm action in
response to these threats.
Likewise, the leaders of Iran
must recognize that now is the
time for a diplomatic solution,
because a coalition stands
united in demanding that
they meet their obligations,
and we will do what is necessary
to prevent them from getting a
nuclear weapon.
(applause)
At the same time, we'll
engage Russia to seek further
reductions in our
nuclear arsenals,
and continue leading the
global effort to secure nuclear
materials that could fall
into the wrong hands --
because our ability to
influence others depends on our
willingness to lead and
meet our obligations.
America must also face
the rapidly growing threat
from cyber-attacks.
(applause)
Now, we know hackers steal
people's identities and
infiltrate private emails.
We know foreign countries
and companies swipe our
corporate secrets.
Now our enemies are also seeking
the ability to sabotage our
power grid, our
financial institutions,
our air traffic control systems.
We cannot look back years
from now and wonder why we did
nothing in the face of real
threats to our security and
our economy.
And that's why, earlier today,
I signed a new executive order
that will strengthen our
cyber defenses by increasing
information sharing, and
developing standards to protect
our national security,
our jobs, and our privacy.
(applause)
But now Congress
must act as well,
by passing legislation to
give our government a greater
capacity to secure our
networks and deter attacks.
This is something we should
be able to get done on a
bipartisan basis.
(applause)
Now, even as we
protect our people,
we should remember that today's
world presents not just dangers,
not just threats, it
presents opportunities.
To boost American exports,
support American jobs and level
the playing field in the
growing markets of Asia,
we intend to complete
negotiations on a
Trans-Pacific Partnership.
And tonight, I'm announcing
that we will launch talks on a
comprehensive Transatlantic
Trade and Investment Partnership
with the European Union --
because trade that is fair and
free across the Atlantic
supports millions of good-paying
American jobs.
(applause)
We also know that progress in
the most impoverished parts of
our world enriches us all --
not only because it creates new
markets, more stable order in
certain regions of the world,
but also because it's
the right thing to do.
In many places, people live on
little more than a dollar a day.
So the United States will join
with our allies to eradicate
such extreme poverty in the next
two decades by connecting more
people to the global
economy; by empowering women;
by giving our young
and brightest minds new
opportunities to serve, and
helping communities to feed,
and power, and
educate themselves;
by saving the world's children
from preventable deaths;
and by realizing the promise
of an AIDS-free generation,
which is within our reach.
(applause)
You see, America must remain a
beacon to all who seek freedom
during this period
of historic change.
I saw the power of hope last
year in Rangoon, in Burma,
when Aung San Suu Kyi welcomed
an American President into the
home where she had been
imprisoned for years;
when thousands of Burmese
lined the streets,
waving American flags,
including a man who said,
"There is justice and
law in the United States.
"I want our country
to be like that."
In defense of freedom, we'll
remain the anchor of strong
alliances from the Americas to
Africa; from Europe to Asia.
In the Middle East, we will
stand with citizens as they
demand their universal rights,
and support stable transitions
to democracy.
(applause)
We know the process
will be messy,
and we cannot presume to
dictate the course of change in
countries like Egypt,
but we can -- and will --
insist on respect for
the fundamental rights of
all people.
We'll keep the pressure on a
Syrian regime that has murdered
its own people, and support
opposition leaders that respect
the rights of every Syrian.
And we will stand steadfast with
Israel in pursuit of security
and a lasting peace.
(applause)
These are the messages I'll
deliver when I travel to the
Middle East next month.
And all this work depends on the
courage and sacrifice of those
who serve in dangerous places
at great personal risk --
our diplomats, our
intelligence officers,
and the men and women of the
United States Armed Forces.
As long as I'm
Commander-in-Chief,
we will do whatever we must to
protect those who serve their
country abroad, and we will
maintain the best military the
world has ever known.
(applause)
We'll invest in
new capabilities,
even as we reduce waste
and wartime spending.
We will ensure equal treatment
for all servicemembers,
and equal benefits for their
families -- gay and straight.
(applause)
We will draw upon the courage
and skills of our sisters and
daughters and moms, because
women have proven under fire
that they are ready for combat.
We will keep faith
with our veterans,
investing in world-class care,
including mental health care,
for our wounded warriors --
(applause)
-- supporting our
military families;
giving our veterans the
benefits and education and job
opportunities that
they have earned.
And I want to thank
my wife, Michelle,
and Dr. Jill Biden for their
continued dedication to serving
our military families as
well as they have served us.
Thank you, honey.
Thank you, Jill.
(applause)
Defending our freedom, though,
is not just the job of our
military alone.
We must all do our part to make
sure our God-given rights are
protected here at home.
That includes one of the
most fundamental rights of a
democracy: the right to vote.
(applause)
When any American, no matter
where they live or what their
party, are denied that right
because they can't afford to
wait for five or six or seven
hours just to cast their ballot,
we are betraying our ideals.
(applause)
So tonight, I'm announcing
a nonpartisan commission to
improve the voting
experience in America.
And it definitely
needs improvement.
I'm asking two long-time
experts in the field --
who, by the way, recently served
as the top attorneys for my
campaign and for Governor
Romney's campaign -- to lead it.
We can fix this, and we will.
The American people demand
it, and so does our democracy.
(applause)
Of course, what I've said
tonight matters little if we
don't come together to protect
our most precious resource:
our children.
It has been two
months since Newtown.
I know this is not the first
time this country has debated
how to reduce gun violence.
But this time is different.
Overwhelming majorities
of Americans --
Americans who believe in
the Second Amendment --
have come together around
common-sense reform,
like background checks that will
make it harder for criminals to
get their hands on a gun.
(applause)
Senators of both parties are
working together on tough new
laws to prevent anyone
from buying guns for resale
to criminals.
Police chiefs are asking our
help to get weapons of war and
massive ammunition
magazines off our streets,
because these police chiefs,
they're tired of seeing their
guys and gals being outgunned.
Each of these proposals
deserves a vote in Congress.
(applause)
Now, if you want to vote
no, that's your choice.
But these proposals
deserve a vote.
Because in the two
months since Newtown,
more than a thousand
birthdays, graduations,
anniversaries have been stolen
from our lives by a bullet from
a gun -- more than a thousand.
One of those we lost was a young
girl named Hadiya Pendleton.
She was 15 years old.
She loved Fig Newtons
and lip gloss.
She was a majorette.
She was so good to her friends
they all thought they were
her best friend.
Just three weeks ago, she
was here, in Washington,
with her classmates,
performing for her country at
my inauguration.
And a week later, she was shot
and killed in a Chicago park
after school, just a
mile away from my house.
Hadiya's parents, Nate and Cleo,
are in this chamber tonight,
along with more than two dozen
Americans whose lives have been
torn apart by gun violence.
They deserve a vote.
(applause)
Gabby Giffords deserves a vote.
The families of
Newtown deserve a vote.
(applause)
The families of
Aurora deserve a vote.
(applause)
The families of Oak Creek
and Tucson and Blacksburg,
and the countless other
communities ripped open by gun
violence -- they
deserve a simple vote.
(applause)
They deserve a simple vote.
Our actions will not prevent
every senseless act of violence
in this country.
In fact, no laws,
no initiatives,
no administrative acts will
perfectly solve all the
challenges I've
outlined tonight.
But we were never sent
here to be perfect.
We were sent here to make
what difference we can,
to secure this nation,
expand opportunity,
uphold our ideals through
the hard, often frustrating,
but absolutely necessary
work of self-government.
We were sent here to look out
for our fellow Americans the
same way they look out for
one another, every single day,
usually without fanfare,
all across this country.
We should follow their example.
We should follow the example
of a New York City nurse named
Menchu Sanchez.
When Hurricane Sandy plunged
her hospital into darkness,
she wasn't thinking about
how her own home was faring.
Her mind was on the 20 precious
newborns in her care and the
rescue plan she devised
that kept them all safe.
We should follow the example
of a North Miami woman named
Desiline Victor.
When Desiline arrived
at her polling place,
she was told the wait to
vote might be six hours.
And as time ticked by, her
concern was not with her tired
body or aching feet, but whether
folks like her would get to
have their say.
And hour after hour, a throng of
people stayed in line to support
her -- because Desiline
is 102 years old.
(applause)
And they erupted in cheers when
she finally put on a sticker
that read, "I voted."
(applause)
We should follow the example
of a police officer named
Brian Murphy.
When a gunman opened fire on
a Sikh temple in Wisconsin and
Brian was the first to arrive,
he did not consider his
own safety.
He fought back until help
arrived and ordered his fellow
officers to protect the safety
of the Americans worshiping
inside, even as he lay
bleeding from 12 bullet wounds.
And when asked how he
did that, Brian said,
"That's just the
way we're made."
That's just the way we're made.
We may do different jobs
and wear different uniforms,
and hold different views
than the person beside us.
But as Americans, we all
share the same proud title --
we are citizens.
It's a word that doesn't just
describe our nationality or
legal status.
It describes the way we're made.
It describes what we believe.
It captures the enduring idea
that this country only works
when we accept certain
obligations to one another and
to future generations, that our
rights are wrapped up in the
rights of others; and that well
into our third century as a
nation, it remains
the task of us all,
as citizens of
these United States,
to be the authors of the
next great chapter of our
American story.
Thank you.
God bless you, and God bless
these United States of America.
(applause)