RB UMALI: Josh's personality
back then, you could tell he
came from a tough background.
He had a lot of tough family
issues that he dealt with.
And he had a funny way of just
telling stories about
his past and stuff.
And I didn't know whether
to believe him or not.
JOSH KALLIS: When I went to
live back with my dad in
Dallas, we didn't get
along at all.
I was doing my thing in the city
of Dallas, hanging out
with these dudes who were
not necessarily
gangsters, but kind of.
But they were skaters.
And I fell right
into that mix.
Around that time, I got locked
up in this mental institution
for six or seven months.
I got caught stealing.
And they took me to
jail for stealing.
And I was in there
for two days.
And this bounty hunter
dude in a full suit--
he was almost albino--
took me out of the jail.
He pulls out a 9 millimeter
and he says, hey, state of
Texas says I can do anything
in my power to
keep you from running.
So don't run.
It's like, all right.
So on the way down there he had
me filling out all these
crazy psych forms, like, do you
study license plates, and
just crazy questions.
So I got put in this institution
where there was
all these murderers who
got out on whatever.
They were like fucked
up in the brain.
So instead of going to prison,
they went here.
No shoestrings, no belts, big
magnet locks on the doors.
They take my blood every
couple days.
And I would go in to these
counseling sessions and they'd
be like, so what are
you doing here?
Johnny, Timmy, they all
killed somebody.
He raped four girls.
Blah, blah, blah.
And they'd come to me and I'd be
like, I don't fucking know.
You guys are all
fucking psycho.
One day I ran out
of toilet paper.
And you walk up to the lady.
She had to go back
into the closet.
So when she went back into the
closet, her little desk phone,
I picked it up, hit nine,
and dialed my mom.
My mom answered screaming
at me.
I told her I was in Salt Lake
City at some place.
And I ended up waking
up in a closet.
They hit me from behind
with some drugs.
So whatever.
You move forward.
And bounty hunter came, scooped
me up, says, all
right, you're on a plane
back to Dallas.
And he says that what it
was was my dad did it.
He thought I was this
fucked up kid.
And he hired this
dude to get me.
And then his insurance
company paid for it.
And shit, I'd've been
in there six years.
But I got out in six months.
And when I got out, the H Street
thing just wasn't even
an option for me.
The girl I would call to get the
boxes and all that stuff,
when I called her she was like,
yeah, Tony said no.
Josh is out.
So skating was almost
done for me.
I didn't give a shit, dude.
I didn't have a board.
I didn't have none of that.
And I didn't care.
I got back with my homies.
I told my dad, fuck him,
like, fuck you, I
know the whole story.
I don't want to have nothing
to do with you anymore.
And I went to Dallas.
And I just hung out
with my friends.
And we lived in North
Dallas, just hood.
I mean, it was cockroaches
and gangsters.
It was crazy.
And it wasn't until I heard
these rumors that Jamie Thomas
was coming in to Dallas--
shit, I hadn't even skated
in six or seven months.
JAMIE THOMAS: I was traveling
across the United States with
some buddies.
And at that time I rode
for Invisible.
And we went through Dallas,
Texas, and I don't know how I
even linked up with him.
But I think I heard he
lived in Dallas.
JOSH KALLIS: Jamie was like,
you got a board?
I said, nah.
And he hooked me up.
He gave me an Invisible board
and took me to the skate shop
and got some trucks.
And I got a set up.
JAMIE THOMAS: We went
skating that day,
and it was just like--
I was filming him, and he was
just seriously so good.
At that time it was obvious
he was way better
than a lot of people.
And he was definitely
good enough to be
sponsored by whoever.
But he was just hanging out with
these gang banger dudes
in Dallas, super thug dudes
that-- they were super cool
and stuff, but it was just
a whole other life.
There was nothing
about skating.
Even though all the dudes in his
clique used to skate and
were skaters, they were more
about being thug hustlers than
they were skaters.
It was obvious that he didn't
have a real stable
situation going on.
I think he was living with his
dad at the time, but I don't
even know if he was staying
with his dad.
He was probably maybe
just 18 then.
It was insane.
Right then I was like, wow, this
is one of the best kids
I've ever seen skate.
He's so good.
JOSH KALLIS: All I know is we
skated that weekend, and I
filmed, I don't know, like two
minutes of probably the best
skateboarding I've ever done
in my life to this day.
JAMIE THOMAS: I remember he
filmed a line that was like a
minute long.
It was the most flat ground
tricks I'd ever seen anybody
do in a row before.
And he did them all in a line.
At that point I was just
like, hey, man.
I wasn't running Invisible or
nothing, but I was just like,
hey, if you want to ride for
this company, I'm sure I can
figure out a way to
make it happen.
He probably didn't even know in
his mind if he was going to
continue skating or
not after I left.
But if he got free stuff showing
up in the mail, he was
either going to be able to skate
it, sell it, whatever.
It was going to be something.
So I left, got home, and then
lined up a package and started
sending him stuff.
JOSH KALLIS: Jamie called
me up, and he--
oh yeah, I forgot
about this part.
This was my very first tour.
He called me up.
He said, hey, man, we're doing
an Invisible tour.
Why don't you jump in the van?
So OK.
So I on the van, but
Jamie wasn't there.
Jamie had quit Invisible just
as I was going on this
Invisible tour.
So I went on the tour anyway.
JAMIE THOMAS: He went on the
tour with those dudes, and
they just went trucking
across the US.
And then basically I called him
when I got on Toy Machine.
He was back in Dallas.
Basically Ed was like, hey
man, you down to help me
rebuild the team?
And I was like, sure.
You got any guys you want?
And he was like,
no, not really.
But if you want to figure
something out or get some guys
on the team, I'd be psyched.
So I started with Kallis.
Basically he was one
of the dudes.
JOSH KALLIS: I went back to
doing my Dallas hood shit,
skating a little bit.
A couple months later he
got a hold of me, and
he's like, hey man.
Dudes are really fucking
hyped on your footage.
I don't know where he put it,
but he was like, dude, if you
can get out here, I'll let
you live at my house.
You just have to get out here.
I didn't know how I was
going to do it.
I made a little bit of money
just hustling kids and betting
on Mortal Kombat.
And we had this dude who would
work a full-time job, and me
and my homie would just take his
check and pay ourselves.
My dad told me $350 for gas
and he'd fly me out.
But he owned one of them
little Cessna planes.
So I went to California on a
Cessna airplane with nothing
but what I was wearing
and touched down.
Jamie picked me up.
Then it moves on to
the Riviera PB.
Jamie Thomas, Alien House.
Where do I hang out?
I hang out at the Alien House,
because they drink 40s and
play dominoes.
And it was tight.