Bring it on.
CHEERING
It's a good job.
You're a police officer!
You're so keen to move on,
I think you should.
Maybe your better class of mates
can put you up.
Some fucker's grassing them up.
What have you done?
He's spied for them,
he can spy for us.
Frank Gallagher, double agent?!
Fuck me. He must be desperate.
Anyone watching, thinking we know
fuck all about knowing fuck all
about owt, needs to
watch their back! Oooh!
So you've had your Labour,
reclassifying skunk,
sending prices sky-high. Literally
taking the grass from its own roots!
And now you've got
your ConDemNation,
Liberals noshing Tories
like altar boys picking dimps up!
Have we had a national
fucking stroke, or what?
Is revolution a word,
or was it never?
Anybody watching needs to know,
we cope better than average
with irony in Chatsworth.
Well for fuck's sake,
we live in Manchester
and they charge us for water?!
I wandered lonely as a clown,
necking mushrooms rarely found.
This green and pleasant land
in ancient times,
yak, yak, yak, yak, yak, yak,
yak, yak, yak!
It's not theirs any more!
This is our England now.
Party!
Sync and corrected by APOLLO
www.addic7ed.com
'Worst thing ever happened to me?
Losing me mam.
'She was my anchor.
'Even with her pissed and passed out
on the couch, I felt safe.
'Protected.'
DOG BARKS
Keep your fucking animal
under control!
'But my mother died,
and all the shit she kept at bay
'landed on my head
in one huge dollop.
'There were times I thought
I might do what she did,
'and take the easy way out.
'But something inside said "Things
will get better." And they did.
'I met Shane and had
some of the best years of my life.
'Then there was Marty. With him
came another big surprise.
'So when I hear of things going tits
up, I always think, "What next?"
'Cos, contrary to popular belief,
'I'm a "sunshine after the rain"
sort of girl.
'Your silver lining type.'
Slowly, through the nose
and when you exhale,
I want you to imagine
your breaths as arrows of light,
colours of the rainbow.
And shoot them out!
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha,
h-a-a-a-a-a-a!
And relax.
MUSIC PLAYS THROUGH HEADPHONES
Good morning.
KNOCK AT DOOR
Knock, knock!
Still allowed in my own house!
Haven't moved in a newer model yet,
have you?
Someone more socially acceptable?
Don't be soft.
Frank Gallagher's looking for digs,
is he more your type?
I'm OK to get some clothes,
aren't I? They are my clothes.
Dad...
Baby, I'm so sorry.
I'm so sorry.
You look like a Lennon man to me.
"Power To The People"... don't shoot!
Fuck's sake, Marty!
Just trying to make a living! Yoko!
It'll cheer them up at the
shelter. Nowhere to live,
but at least they've got some
decent knocked-off tunes!
Best of luck, mate.
Keep positive. It might be
the best thing that ever happened.
Where you heading to?
Runcorn.
You'll love this...
Snoopy Dog... ear worm!
Only dicks pay for music nowadays.
It's not Victorian times!
Bad day at the office?
Fucking recession.
No-one's got disposable income.
Disgraceful.
What you up to?
Not much. Why?
Going cruising with Madam.
Fuck it.
Late start this morning.
They can afford it.
They're winning.
They've won.
It's not over yet, Karen.
It's all about hearts and minds.
Thought it was about houses?
Well, yeah.
Thank you, ladies.
See you next session.
Partner couldn't make it again?
Really bad weather up in Aberdeen.
Force nine.
Couldn't get off the rig.
I'll make sure he's up to speed.
Fingers crossed he makes it for
the birth. Has he booked time off?
Not sure. Let me look.
Ah, here it is, filed under
"Mind Your Own Fucking Business".
You're clouding me chakra, man.
It's like The Sopranos, this!
Hanging outside the club, drinking,
talking, cruising the bitches.
What, with our changing bags,
and nappies, extra rice cakes,
in case she gets cranky?
Yeah, dead like The Sopranos(!)
Your future
flashing before your eyes?
Eh? Look, what happened,
it wasn't your fault.
It fucking was! Totally stole
Kelly off Shane like that.
Bullshit, man,
it goes against the code.
I'm talking about his wife and kids
frying in a fire in Spain, you twat!
Ah! And there is no code.
She's more Mafioso than you!
Fucking gangster, mate!
Pow, pow, pow, pow!
BABY CRIES
Coodgy coodgy!
I've got a flat screen there...
You'll be a good dad, you.
I won't!
Don't listen to that prick!
If it doesn't involve acne or MILFs,
he's got no experience.
I'm a fucking jinx, all right?
Everything I care about,
everyone I love, get damaged.
There's no such thing as jinxed.
Who's been in my life long-term?
Cum-Bucket!
Look, £10, take it or leave it.
Fucking thief!
Oi!
Guy's going off his nut
cos I won't give him £50
for a two year old portable.
Can't fucking move in there
with shit folk are selling.
I used to think it was "prawn" shop.
I always thought me granddad
was taking his wedding ring
down to the "prawn" shop!
You better have a good reason
for dragging me out of my pit.
Oh, yeah.
Sorry I'm late. Fucking yoga
stresses me out.
Bob upstairs?
Never showed.
Bob? He hasn't missed in... ever.
Had an accident, something to do
with a truck and a Pelican.
Poor bugger!
He's got no-one.
Mmm.
He was a gentleman, you know.
Always asked after me.
"How are we today, Kelly?"
And he'd actually wait
for an answer.
Then you'd toss him off.
I'm going to go see him.
Hospital's no place for you
in your condition!
You might catch something.
Maybe it's the hormones.
Fuck knows, I could bottle
and sell them at the minute,
but I'm going in.
You missed a bit.
Bastard!
Fucking blood,
I've just scratched myself now!
We're not robbing cars!
We'll never shift them!
It's not the cars we're after.
Watch and learn.
Stop fucking hitting me!
I'm 26-years-old!
Fucking explain yourself!
All those fuckers that are evicting
people from the estate, yeah,
the Gestapo, they've got to leave
their motors somewhere, don't they?
Can't bring them to the Chatsworth,
there's thieves knocking about.
It's not about the cars,
it's about the booty in the boot.
Have you seen the gear
that that lot carry?
Phones, laptops, tablets, scanners.
Got to keep it somewhere.
So you're taking pictures of it?
If I wanted to connect my printer
to my computer,
how do I do it if I don't want
wires everywhere?
You know I don't believe in
computers, don't you?
Bluetooth!
It detects another wireless device
and asks you if you
want to make a connection.
To which you reply?
You clever bastard!
ALARM PEALS
Mortgage or not...
Job or no job...
I will always be with you.
This makes you a very lucky man,
because I am a catch.
Say "Thank you, Avril".
I wanted more.
I didn't.
The whole world is fucked up
because people want more.
I want us, 'Tish.
Everything else is just...
stuff.
There are people round here
far worse off than us.
You can say that again.
What are you doing?
Evicted. We've been living
under here three days.
Listen to your missus, mate.
She talks sense.
Want one? Pig in a blanket? (SNORTS)
Unacceptable!
Oh, yeah? Didn't takeyoulong
to revert to type.
I am still the same lad.
I am Carl fucking Gallagher,
except now I've got a job.
It's not a job...
it's a Faustian deal.
You sold your soul to
Beelzebub, you fucking
muppet, and you
don't even know it!
Oh, yeah... what, cos of your father
or your grandfather,
or some fucking Irish bloke
we knew 200 years ago.
They're as much my blood
as they are yours.
Cos you come from here.
Have some dignity, change your name.
Fuck the past!
Katie, Stella, little Cilla...
that's why I'm doing it,
to make this place less of
a shit-hole for them to grow up in.
They've sucked out your soul.
Bollocks.
Well, prove it, then.
Yeah, go on.
Yeah, thought so.
(SLURRED) We were brought up...
to be suspicious of the police.
The oppressive arm of the state,
charging demonstrators on horseback,
and all that.
They got my motor back once, after
some little Welsh prick robbed it.
Me grandad was in Cork.
You know... Black and Tans.
We can't have a Gallagher
in the police.
It's a good pension.
I mean, he's a bright lad.
Not academic bright, mind...
he takes after his mother in that
respect but he can turn his hand to...
And he's a looker.
What? I always thought it looked
like he'd got his finger in a socket
or something, you know?
No. The teens, the
MILFS, the GILFS...
they'd all ride him,
given half the chance.
What the fuck is wrong with you?!
Was in here last night,
had one too many.
Someone fingered me in the snug.
Well, it wasn't me.
You can smell if you want.
I'll need reimbursing.
After all the business he's given you
over the years?
True. He was a lovely customer.
Isa lovely customer.
He's not dead yet.
He knowsyou'rehere.
Every time I saw him lately, I kept
complaining about my feet killing me.
Used to give me a foot massage.
Had a thing about feet, didn't he?
He had a briefcase
full of all kinds of books on feet.
He's a chiropodist.
Wouldn't put it past him.
Back to work, soon as.
Profit in that bump.
For old time's sake, eh, pal?
Do I look like a man
with 100 quid to spare?
It's quality gear, that...
shifted the other two already.
You could ask Jonesy.
Oh no, he won't be able to
take it, on account he's
got no house to live in.
How much?
That's all I've got.
How do you sleep at night?
(WHISTLES)
Right, I don't care who did it.
I even admire your cheek a little,
but... I want my computer back.
It's not a work computer,
it's my personal property,
material of sentimental value.
Pictures of my children,
Christmas, birthdays, holidays.
Things I can't replicate or replace.
And I stupidly have no back-up.
I'm sorry you've
lost your mementos.
Thanks to you, these people
have lost their homes.
They've still got photographs.
They just don't have anywhere
to put them.
This is a step too far. Personal
items are not part of the game.
The game?!
Yeah, the fucking game.
You people... think you're so clever.
What you do
is not a victimless crime.
You're a mad cow.
All your cheating and scamming
and benefit fraud...
- Good people, like me...
- And me.
Have our lives impacted upon
by your scavenging lives.
We bear the cost.
No, you fucking don't. What you mean is,
the rules are rigged in your favour.
Everything's rigged in your favour,
and the moment one of us bite back,
you kick and scratch and scream,
"I want mine! What about mine?!"
That's my man.
Look, come on, Miss...
Fuck off, you leech!
Leave me alone.
Upset by a couple of evictions, are you?
Yeah.
(IN AMERICAN ACCENT)
Getting all "Spartacus" on my ass?
Progress is coming, like it or not.
Five years from now, maybe seven,
this place won't even be here.
None of you will be here.
The rest of society are not funding
the underbelly any more.
We're not doing it. So it won't be
30 evictions, or 40, or even 100.
Ten years from now,
this place will be wasteland!
And that's not opinion...
that's policy.
(MAN) Go on, fuck off!
If I'd wanted misery,
I could have stayed at home.
What sort of shop
are you running here anyway?
This place is fucked.
It's always been fucked...
it's a vital part of its appeal.
People don't know what the future
holds... they're upset.
The future
is what you fucking make it!
Come on, where's the spirit of '68?
Oh, what the fuck?! Student riots?
Paris? Prague Spring?
Tune in, drop out,
shag a skank because she'll let you?
Civil... disobedience.
Huh? You don't have
to play by their
fucking rules... make
some up of your own.
Seize the fucking day.
It's like the French,
but they blockade the motorways.
And burn sheep. They do.
Thank you. You have to admire
the Gauls for their gall,
despite their cheese-eating
surrender-monkey tendencies.
What more can we do?
Why does it matter to you anyway?
Because all this misery
is ruining my fucking pint.
I'm hanging up my crotchless
when this little bundle drops.
Can't have your mam on the game,
can you?
I've got to be responsible. I mean...
If me and Marty go tits up like me
and Shane... cos these things happen...
it'll just be me and a kid.
I want this...
more than I've ever wanted anything,
Bob.
The fella, the kid, flat,
nice little job where
I don't have to wear a gum-shield.
I want the dream.
Reckon him upstairs
will let me have it?
Have what?
Sorry. Who are you?
His wife. Who are you?
Ta.
Not a typical hospital visitor,
if you don't mind me saying so.
I'm just aware
that some folk don't have anyone.
I mean,
I had no idea Bob were married.
You missed his wedding ring?
He never wore it.
Sorry, my dad never wore
a wedding ring.
I just don't even think to look.
That must've been a real shock.
I'm sorry.
The doctor said I should
prepare myself for the worst.
The damage to his brain's extensive,
and if he did make a recovery...
Look, you don't know what'll happen,
nor do the doctors,
they're just giving you
a worst-case scenario.
Have a look in "My Photos".
You know she'll
have some homemade porn
on there, don't you?
She's a businesswoman.
She is filth, I can tell, mate.
"This place will be wasteland!"
I almost come in me pants!
Hey, we could stick up a
couple of barricades,
block the roads, like
Derry in the old days.
Oh, that's all we need...
rubber bullets and petrol bombs.
Could enlist Marty Fisher,
he burns stuff.
Oh, that's opening
a can of worms.
He's imbalanced, he
wouldn't know when tostop.
That's what Kelly says!
Sorry.
Maybe we take the fight toher.
Why is the Chatsworth the
battleground? Take it to hergaff.
It's nice, hergaff. She tried
to seduce me there, you know.
(MIMI) Ha!
She's got a meeting
tomorrow at her hotel.
Council, Work and Pensions,
they're all coming.
Dress the girl up as a chambermaid,
bug the room.
I'd look brilliant
as a chambermaid.
Good idea, Jason Bourne! Should I
get my bag of listening devices?
I resisted, if anyone's interested.
I think
she craves the furry chalice.
Oh, fuck me,
I would pay to see that.
We won't need to bug the room.
How so?
You'll see.
Right, everyone, this is Jodie.
She's got a rather unique talent.
If you can just stand aside.
The old one is saying, "Dress you up
like a chambermaid at my place,
"we could charge a ton an hour.
" The young one says, "I will
have tuition fees to pay."
What the fuck?!
She can read minds?!
Lips, dickhead! She lip-reads. Jodie
is going to be our secret weapon.
Well done.
(LAUGHS)
DISTANT PLAYGROUND NOISES
# You stepped out of a cloud
# I want to take you away
# Away from the crowd... #
I don't understand.
This can't be happening.
# Alone and apart
# Out of a dream... #
Breaking and entering,
damage to property.
You said yourselves yesterday,
we make the rules.
Every time you break them,
you're giving us more ammunition.
You're damaging yourselves.
That's clever.
We'll just evict all over again,
only this time,
the penalties will be stiffer.
Custodial.
But no-one's back in the same house.
What?
No-one's returned
to the same properties.
All have got new occupants.
So, your info, work and pensions,
Inland Revenue, council tax.
Immigration.
Useless.
You don't know who's who,
or where.
You don't seriously think
this will stop it?
(LAUGHS) Yeah.
I seriously do.
(LAUGHS)
We're so screwed.
They'll be back. Only next time,
they'll hit twice as hard.
Dogs, PSCs, alarm systems
and custody for anyone
who doesn't comply.
I love my job.
MOBILE PHONE RINGS
Two, three, four
and out. Arrows of light!
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, haaah!
Camel toe!
Bless you!
What's wi' twitches?
You know I still get it with you,
when I've got the horn.
You've got the horn?
Yeah.
Fucking brilliant.
Now I've got the horn!
Great. OK, up we get, mums.
Thank you very much.
This is better than being
on a rig off Aberdeen, eh?
What?
Have you booked time off
for the birth?
Oi! "One-Born-Every-Minute."
Back off.
No, it's all right. How can I be
negative about this? We'll be good.
THEY GRUNT
You'll have to excuse us,
but you know what hormones are like.
I really need to go ride my boy.
Have you had any thoughts
on breast-feeding?
Unleash the beast.
Tit wank, nipple rash, areola!
Udders, puppies, milky mountains!
Tell me again!
I want our baby!
I love our baby.
Oh, baby!
The welfare state is over.
Housing, health, education.
It just got bloated
and unaffordable.
It's a direct consequence
of everyone living longer.
Blah, blah, blah. That's what you
sound like to me, do you know that?
We can beat them.
We're better than them.
It's not about them and us.
We're no fucking different.
What, you think they don't love
their kids as much as we love ours?
I have rejected 20 calls today, from
my estranged, alcoholic husband,
who presently is fucking a girl
barely scraping legality.
And yet, at some point,
at some point,
I will let him come back...
and rip the heart out of me again
and pay for the privilege.
How is that better?
My husband wets the bed.
Look, it's about the system,
and getting it to work for YOU.
That's all that counts.
It's time to grow some balls,
Feeney.
You don't sound like yourself.
Be very clear...
There are no lengths
I won't go to.
What, you think I'm going to let
10 lazy bastards
keep me from my salary?
Well, that's all right. You're
the middle of the sandwich...
I want one up there...
I might have fucking known.
I was tricked down here,
all right?
She said she'd give me a blow...
Only to lure him in.
I tried the trail of bread crumbs,
but he didn't pick up on it.
Right, that door stays locked
until you sort it out.
Any stock he drinks, you pay for it.
Shouldn't have to prove myself.
You're my dad.
Hundred million sperm, and me best
swimmer turns out to be a Judas.
What are the chances?
When are you due?
I'm five months gone.
Your first?
We only had the one. Unplanned.
This one took me
a little bit by surprise.
Scared?
I'm fuckin' terrified.
You'll be a great mum.
Look at the kindness
you've shown me.
Look at how you care for Bob,
someone you don't even know.
I think you're remarkable.
I love a man who's in touch
with his feminine side.
Got your moisturiser
on my forehead too.
The Christmas present,
or the good one?
Green bottle.
Can't read any more of this.
It's all spreadsheets
and proposals. Going snow-blind.
You did good.
I won't let it go to my head.
Have you seen this?
Her contract is on here.
It's totally gold-plated.
We've got to get this to Karen
and Jamie.
Here's the interesting stuff.
Her contract of employment.
Terms and conditions.
150 grand? What, that's her salary?
That's her bonus, if she manages
to permanently board up 120 houses.
That's horrible.
You can see why she'd be
pissed off at us.
Is it wrong, right?
That she gives me a full-on stiffy
every single time I see her?
D'you mind if I ask you a question?
How do you do it?
I mean, the whole wife thing?
All those years
and you're still in love.
We haven't been in love
in a long time.
We've been married 45 years.
People change.
But you change together.
The love we have now is...
It's nothing like the love
we used to have.
That's normal, isn't it?
I suppose.
Bob was never the most
physical of men.
He never...
He wasn't a sexual man.
Eh?
I know it must seem odd
to a woman of your age,
but, I need that attention.
The satisfaction.
So, I looked for it and I found it
with other men, other lovers.
Truth be told,
I'm very much in love with someone.
I was going to tell Bob,
but then this happened.
You were leaving him?
He's an old man. Inside
as well as out.
Maybe you weren't trying
hard enough.
Excuse me?
Never had any trouble
when he were with me.
Worked out well for you, hasn't it?
Bit of luck, he'll pop his clogs
and you won't have to tell him.
What do you mean, "with you"?
I'm a prostitute, love. A hooker,
lady of the night, Irma la Douce.
Bob was one of my regulars.
Probably saw me when you
were at your lover's.
You slut.
You're no better.
Get out!
No, Hannah, stop it!
Get off me!
Oh... (GASPS)
HEART MONITOR BEEPS
(RADIO) "Moving on, and a Moss Side
man has been arrested
"on suspicion of arson.
"The arrest follows a
three-month-long investigation
"of a suspected firebomb attack
on a house in south Manchester.
"Let's have a look at what's
happening on the roads.
"Traffic's starting to build up
in the usual places.
"We had reports of an
overturned lorry..."
BREAKING GLASS
Oh, oh! You fucking bastard!
# SEX PISTOLS:
Anarchy In The UK
# I am an anti-Christ
# I am an anarchist
# Don't know what I want,
but I know how to get it
# I want to destroy the passer by
# Cos I...
# Wanna be... #
What's happened?!
Now get in! Come on!
# And I wanna be...
# ..an anarchist
# I get pissed, destroy. #
Right, let's go.
She has destroyed people's lives,
she's caused total mayhem.
How's hurting her
going to benefit us?
I enjoy violence
as much as the next man.
We need to keep a cool head.
I want her to suffer.
Seen this film once where
a cowboy cuts off the squaw's tits.
Jesus, no! When did
you become so tough?
You've lost your bottle.
Your reverse psychology
has fooled me...
I'm off to take
a chainsaw to the woman(!)
Very funny.
What do you want?
I will not be intimidated.
I'm not trying to intimidate you.
You're going to get chopped up and
thrown in the Manchester Ship Canal.
I'm not so shocked.
You're not the first.
I knew a hundred lads like you
when I was growing up.
You don't have to be like this.
Don't be scared.
It's not that messy...
once all the blood
drains from your corpse.
The only question remaining for you,
is do you want to pass up
this, literally,
once-in-a-lifetime opportunity
and deliver me a blow-job,
before it's too late?
DNA, Shane!
Fuck off! I was just asking.
It's like the old days round here...
one in the bathroom,
two in the dungeon. Grub's up!
(FRANK) About fucking time.
Of course, the kidnapee upstairs
is worth a few bob.
150 grand bonus for kicking
people out their houses?
Horrific, that.
It's the poetry of the free market.
Shut up.
Insured up to the hilt, as well.
She so much as trips over a stiletto
and she's minted for life.
Can't lose for winning.
See what your lot are about?
My lot?
These are the ranks you've joined.
You are DIRECTLY responsible
for the death of this community.
It's not fucking funny, it's tragic.
You miserable arsehole.
This community'll never die.
Look how they're fighting back.
Kicked out their homes and
still refusing to lie
down, no matter what that
blonde bint does to them.
You are still spreading her gospel.
If you clobbered her over
the head for the insurance,
she'd be delighted.
What fucking side are you on?
I'm on my own side.
Shut up, shut up, shut up.
Shut up, yeah?
Shut up... thought forming.
Carl, Carl, Carl, Carl, Carl, Carl.
- Are you in there, son?
- What?
My boy.
That is the best idea I have ever...
What is?
Do her in for the insurance money.
Let her take her black,
black soul off somewhere else.
I never said that.
Yes, you fucking did
and I have never been prouder.
Under those layers
and layers of piggery,
a Gallagher heart still beats.
No. Under no circumstances.
You're covered by
a gold-plated insurance scheme
while on Agency business.
Absolutely not.
You'd get a six figure pay out.
That doesn't make it
any more palatable.
It's the "injured" bit
that leaves me cold.
You will NOT empty this place.
People won't just lie down.
We can arrange for you to be hurt.
In a controlled manner.
And in return, you erase
all databases, spreadsheets,
original copies...
mainframe and backup,
on every person on
the Chatsworth Estate.
You're not asking for much, are you?
Can you do it?
Yeah, it only takes a password.
I have remote access to all
the systems, I can delete them.
Permanently? Including backup?
Permanently and irrevocably...
if I have a mind to.
Which I don't.
Why are you so nasty?
I'm not nasty, I'm focused.
I think a woman needs to be.
Excuse me.
I have to visit
the little boy's room.
How old are you?
40? 45?
Fuck off. Scrape the cement away,
that one'll never see 50 again.
Your point being?
Is this how you want
to spend the next two years?
Are you really that committed
on getting one over on us?
But she's not committed,
though, are you?
It's not political.
It's not an agenda.
It's about being strong,
being in control.
I bet your husband's a right prick.
(LAUGHS)
You don't hide it well.
I believe in what I'm doing.
It's necessary.
But I'm so sick of
all this unpleasantness.
I am. I'm so tired.
I'm exhausted.
What safeguards would I have?
Trust us, violence is our thing.
Do you need me to get you a nurse?
You should be due some pain killers.
How's Bob?
Same.
I'm sorry. The baby, you...
I told you I was jinxed.
I don't need this.
Everything I touch turns to shit.
Everything.
I don't have the strength
for this to be about you, Marty.
Can't leave Bob on his own.
Will you forget about fucking Bob?
He has no-one...
and he could be stuck
inside that injury for years.
I'll take care of Bob... worry not.
You take care of her
or you've got me to answer to.
I'm sorry.
KNOCKING ON DOOR
Private meeting... fuck off!
Take one each and
don't let anyone else see it.
Everyone's volunteered,
but only one of us can do the deed.
"There can be only one."
Behave.
If anyone gets fingered,
they'll be looking at a long stretch.
Assault on someone
on government business.
What the fuck?
Am I holding the coats, or what?
She knows you. We don't want her
to be able to ID the attackers.
You're hardly inconspicuous.
GASPING
Firstly, Enoch, we're not
the only blacks in the village.
Secondly...
(GROANS)
Besides, Dad,
you couldn't beat eggs.
It's the principle.
Right, whoever's got it,
wear the mask...
"Wear the mask".
Right.
And exercise some restraint.
Beat her enough to get compensation,
not enough to piss her off.
Crack her on the nose.
What about, er, knee-caps?
They're always good, aren't they?
Definitely no knee-caps. Too far.
Yeah, she wouldn't walk for months.
I've heard nothing.
A targeted beating.
Just enough to fool a loss adjustor.
There you go, love.
Good boy.
You're DNR now, love.
You've already gone, haven't you?
Good night, sweetheart. God bless.
BEEPING
# You
# Stepped out of a dream
# You are too wonderful
# To be what you seem
# Could there be eyes like yours... #
(SCREAMS)
(KAREN) Forgot your flowers.
Ate your grapes.
Can you can move your hand?
Yeah, that's the correct account.
I just wanted to check how much we
have outstanding on our Council Tax?
Done.
You better not be winding us up,
cos there is still time
to plant you under a fly-over.
What, they've all crashed?
And when will they be
back up and running?
Everyone's system
went down at the same time.
Congratulations...
you're a wealthy woman.
Nice doing business with you.
(ALL) While I continue
to be a police officer,
I will, to the best of
my skill and knowledge,
discharge all the duties thereof,
faithfully according to law.
Can you eat that, after?
The Fondant Fancy?
APPLAUSE
# He's gonna step on you again
# He's gonna step on
# Hey, rainmaker, come away
from that man you know
# He's gonna take away
your promised land... #
Let's get you a drink, eh?
Fuck off.
Give the lady a beer before
I stick my toe up your arse,
and not in a nice way.
She's our guest. Treat her like one.
Mingle, Mrs Feeney.
# Gonna stamp out your fire
He can change your desire... #
No, can't make it out.
They're Polish... cheaper.
Cos that's what
you're looking for in a condom...
cheapness. Forget condoms, son.
Bareback is best, first and always.
Sorry for your loss.
Are you a fucking animal?
What?
Guy's just lost a baby.
Fuck off!
(MIMI) Can I have a cold one?
Why are you all being so nice to me?
You're losing your religion
as we speak.
We've all been there at one point.
You know, I never really thought
of you people as people before.
LAUGHTER
You're a curious one.
You've really achieved something.
I'm proud.
These people here, every one of them,
has a bar tab as long
as a bride's train.
Licence to sell alcohol... reinstated.
But you said everybody's drinks
were on the house.
You didn't believe that, did you?
Hearts and minds, Karen.
Hearts and minds.
Technique?
Rough.
Six out of ten.
Stamina?
I've flushed myself twice
just watching him.
Why am I sitting with you two?
Oh, I'm so confused.
(KELLY) 'So, when it seems
you can't take any more,
'looks like there's no way out,
no solution to your problems,
'just remember this...
there's always tomorrow.
'It's easy to give in, to give up.
'It's much harder to look
for the silver lining.
'But it's worth looking for.
'It's really worth looking for.'
Anything wrong with this picture?
Jesus, babe, we're different.
Different doesn't last.
I want an open relationship.
Is it him? Are you doing him?
Calm yourself, fella.
It's the shortest mass
in Manchester.
The funeral crashers. You're
like fucking vultures, you two.
It's a social responsibility.
Any more sherry,
I'll be shitting doilies.
Would you say a few words?
And then, of course,
there was Woodstock.
I want you to take your stepfather
out and get him laid.
You're shagging someone.
So, who do you want to ride?
I want to ride your mum.
Sync and corrected by APOLLO
www.addic7ed.com