NIMROD: She had made Sikh
people so proud.
I'm from the Sikh community,
which is represented in the
book, page 120.
She empowered us to
be who we are.
Yeah, because I'm, like, the
voice of my generation or at
least a voice of a generation.
I not like pushing.
I was honestly here
for a long time.
-No you haven't.
NIMROD: I'm not saying
you're before me.
-No you haven't.
No you haven't If you don't go
to the back of the queue, then
I'll just have to ask
you to leave.
NIMROD: That's fine.
I'm going, I'm going.
The thing is, I'm from the
Sikh community, which is
represented in the book and
just because I grab
attention--
-Wait the queue.
NIMROD: Yeah, definitely.
And I'm not saying I need to get
to her because I'm Sikh.
I'm just actually the only
representative of this community.
And she's done amazing things.
-I know what she's done,
whether you're--
NIMROD: Like, we're not allowed
to shave and she's
done the whole thing with
the mustachioed girl.
NIMROD: Sikh girls from my
community are proud again to
have mustaches.
-You're right.
Yeah.
NIMROD: Because they usually
weren't allowed to shave.
But now it's like a bit
modernizing the whole religion.
-That's good.
NIMROD: Yeah.
-Excellent.
NIMROD: Because the book is not
racist at all and, like,
denying racism is kind
of the new racism.
-Right.
NIMROD: And the book is
all for, like, racism.
I actually put the "Harry
Potter" book inside this book
hoping she would sign that
because I don't have any
"Harry Potter" book signed.
And yeah, I'm a Sikh Jew.
-Thank you very much.
NIMROD: Have you ever
dated a Sikh guy?
-No, I haven't.
NIMROD: Sikh girl?
-No.
NIMROD: I'm a Sikh Jew.
-You're Jewish?
-I'm Jewish.
NIMROD: Really?
-Yes.
NIMROD: I'm a Jewish part
of the Sikh community.
-All right.
NIMROD: Yeah.
-[INAUDIBLE]
NIMROD: No, no.
That's the actual book.
I just removed the thing.
-Is your book ready?
Oh, that's the wrong page.
-OK, thanks.
NIMROD: Thanks.
I love what you did for the
Sikh community, actually.
JK ROWLING: I kept
looking at you--
NIMROD: I wanted to ask, yeah.
JK ROWLING: --waiting for
someone to call on you.
NIMROD: It's OK for us to
shave the mustaches now.
JK ROWLING: Yes, I know.
NIMROD: It's perfectly
fine, yeah.
The Sikh bump--
thanks.
And by the way, I just want
to leave you the gift.
It's the Sikh god.
NIMROD: You just paint it
dot by dot, then you--
NIMROD: --go ahead
and paint it.
-Thank you.
Bye bye.
JK ROWLING: Thank you.
NIMROD: Finally, I can shave
because in the book, she
empowers Sikh women
to shave again.
It's a big development for us.
-No, she doesn't.
NIMROD: Yes, she does.
Page 120.
-No, no she doesn't.
-No, she doesn't.
-Don't get me started.
NIMROD: Start.
-No.
NIMROD: She did a big service
for the Sikh.
-She did a big service.
It's nothing to do
with shaving.
If that's your interpretation,
you need to go back to the
beginning.
-It's OK.
Leave it.
It's OK.
NIMROD: I think she--
I love her.
I am a big fan.
It's an amazing signature.
-Yeah.
NIMROD: You think I can sell
it to other people?
[INAUDIBLE]
-You can try, yeah, on eBay.
NIMROD: eBay?
-Or something, yeah.
NIMROD: Or Amazon resale?
-Yeah.
NIMROD: Yeah, 120 quid for
[INAUDIBLE], I guess.
-That's OK.
I mean, yeah, anything.
NIMROD: After I read it,
of course, yeah.
-Yeah.
[MUSIC PLAYING]