NOW, A COUSIN OF THESE SPIDERS
SPIN WEBS THAT ARE SO STRONG
THEY'RE USED AS FISH NETS
ON SOME ISLANDS IN
THE SOUTH PACIFIC.
IN F
EVEN
IGHT.
THIS WEEK WE ENTER
THE DELICATE WORLD
OF THE LOVELIEST DEATHTRAP--
THE WEB OF THE SPIDER.
Narrator:
IT IS AN ANCIENT CREATURE
AS OLD AS ANY
WALKING THE EARTH.
THROUGH THE AGES, IT HAS
BECOME AN EXPERT WEAVER...
A CONSUMMATE HUNTER
AND, WITH MORE THAN
30,000 DIFFERENT FACES
A MASTER OF ADAPTATION.
IT LIVES ALL AROUND US--
IN OUR BACKYARDS AND GARDENS
EVEN INSIDE OUR HOMES.
YET MOST PEOPLE ARE TERRIFIED
BY THIS SOLITARY SPINNER
AND ONLY A FEW KNOW THE INNER
WORKINGS OF THE SPIDER'S WORLD.
LONG BEFORE THE DINOSAURS
SPIDERS WERE ALREADY USING
SILK TO CATCH THEIR PREY.
FROM THOSE FIRST RANDOM SNARES,
THE CLASSIC ORB WEB EVOLVED.
THE SPIDER BEGINS
BY RELEASING A STRAND OF SILK
THAT IS
RRENTS
AN ORB CAN TAKE
AN HOUR OR MORE TO MAKE.
HERE, THE PROCESS IS COMPRESSED
INTO A MINUTE.
FIRST THE SPIDER LAYS DOWN A SET
OF LINES RADIATING FROM A HUB
LIKE THE SPOKES OF A WHEEL.
AFTER MAKING
A LOOSE SCAFFOLDING
SHE MOVES INWARDS
AND CRAFTS A TIGHTER SPIRAL.
THE SILK IS STICKIER NOW--
THE KIND THAT WILL GLUE
HER VICTIMS TO THE WEB.
ALL SPIDERS SPIN,
BUT WEBS CAN VARY GREATLY
EACH BEARING THE SIGNATURE
OF ITS MAKER.
ONE OF THE MOST UNMISTAKABLE
IS THE HOME OF THE AUSTRALIAN
LEAF CURLER.
SHE DESCENDS TO THE
FOREST FLOOR BY NIGHT
TO GATHER BUILDING SUPPLIES.
THE SPIDER ATTACHES A LEAF
TO THE SAME SILKEN CORD
THAT BROUGHT HER TO THE GROUND.
THEN, LIKE A HIGH-RISE
CONSTRUCTION WORKER
SHE HAULS IT SEVERAL FEET
INTO THE AIR.
THE LEAF WILL BECOME THE
CENTERPIECE OF HER NEW WEB
BUT FIRST SHE MUST MAKE
SOME ALTERATIONS.
THE LEAF IS COVERED WITH SILK
WHICH WHEN DRY, WILL CURL
THE LEAF INTO PROPER SHAPE.
THE JOB CAN TAKE HOURS
BUT SPIDERS SEEM TO HAVE
INFINITE PATIENCE.
WITH HER RETREAT FINISHED, THE
SPIDER CAN TURN HER ATTENTION
TO A MORE PRESSING MATTER--
HER NEXT FEEDING.
HER INSECT TRAP IS SET
OUTSIDE HER FRONT DOOR.
WEB SPIDERS HAVE
EXTREMELY POOR SIGHT
PERCEIVING MOST OF THEIR
WORLD BY TOUCH INSTEAD.
IT WAS BY THAT SENSE ALONE THAT
THE LEAF CURLER FOUND HER LEAF
AND CHANGED ITS SHAPE
AND IT IS BY TOUCH NOW
THAT SHE WEAVES THE INTRICATE
FABRIC OF HER LAIR.
AND THERE IT IS,
THE PERFECT WEB--
A WORK OF ART TO US,
A DEADLY SNARE FOR INSECTS
AND FOR THE SPIDER,
THE ONLY MEANS OF SURVIVAL.
SPIDERS ARE OPPORTUNISTIC.
AND IF THEY CAN FIND A SHORTCUT,
THEY'LL TAKE IT.
INSTEAD OF A LEAF AT THE HUB,
THIS LEAF CURLER HAS SUBSTITUTED
A PREFAB STRUCTURE--
AN EMPTY SNAIL SHELL.
MOST PEOPLE CAN RECOGNIZE
A SPIDER BY ITS EIGHT LEGS
BUT THERE ARE OTHER
COMMON CHARACTERISTICS AS WELL.
ALL USE SPINNERETS
FOR MAKING SILK.
THE ONES ON THIS RELATIVE OF THE
TARANTULA ARE UNUSUALLY LONG.
EVERY SPIDER'S BODY IS DIVIDED
INTO TWO SEGMENTS:
A HEAD WITH UP TO EIGHT EYES
AND AN ABDOMEN, WHERE ITS
VARIOUS SILK GLANDS LIE.
DIFFERENT SILKS ARE USED
FOR DIFFERENT NEEDS.
A FEMALE WEAVING AN EGG SAC WILL
LINE IT WITH HER SOFTEST SILK
BUT COVER IT WITH HER TOUGHEST,
FOR PROTECTION.
A SILK THREAD
CAN BE A SAFETY LINE
WHEN A SPIDER DANGLES
HIGH ABOVE THE GROUND
AND SILK IS USED
LIKE A TELEGRAPH--
THE
BETW
NK
AS NIGHT FALLS
ON AN AUSTRALIAN SUBURB
A LARGE FEMALE SPIDER
COMES OUT OF HIDING.
SHE HAS DEVELOPED A PARTICULARLY
INGENIOUS USE FOR SILK.
UNLIKE A WEB DWELLER,
THE OGRE-FACED SPIDER
DOESN'T WAIT FOR PREY
TO WANDER INTO HER HOME.
SHE IS A NET CASTER,
AND HER WEB IS A MOBILE TRAP.
AT NEARLY 200 STROKES A MINUTE
SHE COMBS OUT
A SPECIAL KIND OF SILK
WITH A ROW OF BRISTLES
ON HER LONG HIND LEGS.
SHE ATTACHES
THE FINISHED THREADS
AND STARTS COMBING
WITH THE OTHER LEG.
WHAT STA
IS N
F SILK
T.
BUT HOW CAN A SCRAP OF FABRIC
NO BIGGER THAN A POSTAGE STAMP
CATCH ENOUGH FOOD
FOR SUCH A LARGE SPIDER?
SHE LIES IN AMBUSH
ABOVE AN INSECT HIGHWAY.
UNLIKE THE LEAF CURLER,
HER NIGHT VISION IS EXCELLENT
AND SHE'LL DETECT
THE SLIGHTEST MOVEMENT BELOW.
THIS LARGE ANT IS
HOPELESSLY ENTANGLED
BUT THE SPIDER, WARY
OF ITS FEROCIOUS STING
RESTRAINS IT EVEN MORE.
THE OGRE-FACED SPIDER CAN
MAKE SEVERAL CATCHES A NIGHT
BUT FOR EACH ONE, SHE MUST
WEAVE A BRAND-NEW NET.
NOT EVERY SPIDER USES AN
AIRBORNE ATTACK TO CATCH PREY.
LIKE AN ENTRENCHED SOLDIER
THE TRAP-DOOR SPIDER
PREFERS TERRA FIRMA.
ITS SILK-LINED BURROW CAN
BE MORE THAN THREE FEET DEEP.
RELYING ON ITS FEET
TO DETECT THE VIBRATIONS
OF PASSING INSECTS
IT CAN DIFFERENTIATE BETWEEN
BUGS WITH AMAZING ACCURACY.
LIKE VIRTUALLY ALL SPIDERS,
THE TRAP-DOOR IS CARNIVOROUS.
IT CAN GO WITHOUT FOOD
FOR MONTHS IF NECESSARY
BUT FOR THIS ONE,
THE LONG SIEGE IS OVER.
TRAP-DOOR SPIDERS AND
THEIR CLOSE RELATIVES
ARE DISTINGUISHED BY LARGE,
DOWNWARD-STRIKING FANGS.
VENOM IS PRODUCED AS DROPLETS
AT THE TIP OF THE FANGS
AND INJECTED WHEN
THE SPIDER STRIKES.
MOST ARE DEADLY ONLY TO INSECTS
BUT THE BITE OF THE
SYDNEY FUNNEL WEB
CAN BE FATAL FOR PEOPLE AS WELL.
FUNNEL WEBS HIDE IN BURROWS
UNDER ROCKS AND LOGS.
THE VENOM OF THE MALE FUNNEL WEB
IS FIVE TIMES MORE TOXIC
THAN THAT OF HIS
FEMALE COUNTERPART.
DURING THE BREEDING SEASON
HE STRAYS AWAY FROM HIS HOME
IN SEARCH OF A MATE
BUT OCCASIONALLY MEETS
HIS HUMAN NEIGHBORS INSTEAD.
AN UNSUSPECTING GARDENER
UNLEASHES A LETHAL THREAT
WHEN HE DIGS UP ONE OF THESE
SPIDERS AND SETS HIM WANDERING.
THIS MAY LOOK LIKE
A DANGEROUS GAME
BUT THE CAT'S
NOT REALLY AT RISK.
AMONG THE BACKBONED ANIMALS
ONLY PRIMATES ARE BELIEVED TO BE
SUSCEPTIBLE TO FUNNEL WEB BITE
WHICH IS BAD LUCK FOR PEOPLE.
( phone rings )
IF YOU KNOW HOW TO HANDLE THEM
THERE IS ONE GOOD USE
FOR A FUNNEL WEB.
USING THE SPIDER'S
OWN TOXIC VENOM
SCIENTISTS HAVE FINALLY
DISCOVERED AN ANTIVENIN.
OUS
IS THE BLACK WIDOW.
THIS IS HER COUSIN,
THE REDBACK.
SHE BUILDS A PERMANENT TRAP
OUT OF STRONG, VERTICAL THREADS
BEADED AT THE BASE
WITH A CONTACT ADHESIVE.
IT'S AN INVISIBLE MAZE
WITH NO WAY OUT BUT DEATH.
THE ANT CLEANS ITS ANTENNAE,
A SIGN THAT IT SENSES DANGER
BUT ITS WARNING SYSTEM
IS TOO LATE.
ABOVE WAITS AN ASSASSIN.
WITH A SPECIAL COMB
REDBACK SPIDERS AND THEIR
RELATIVES TIE UP THEIR VICTIMS.
IN SLOW MOTION, THE SILK APPEARS
AS A RIBBON OF RAINBOW COLORS
BUT TO THE ANT,
IT IS SIMPLY A SHROUD.
THIS SPIDER ISN'T
STALKING AN INSECT.
IT'S UNSUSPECTING VICTIM
IS A FISH.
NEXT ON EXPLORER.
■■■■■■
E HEN
HUMMINGBIRDS ARE AMONG
THE VERY FEW ANIMALS
AMA.
THE P HAQUADPLEDOF TREE.
TO ENJOY OUR COMPANY.
■■■■■■■■■■■■■■■■■,
UNDERSTAND IT,
BU■■■■■■
■
YOU'RE WATCHING NATIONAL
GEOGRAPHIC EXPLORER ON TBS.
■
THIS IS YOUR LIFE,
AND NOT A BAD ONE AT THAT.
YOU FIND THE THINGS
THAT WORK FOR YOU,
AND YOU STICK WITH THEM.
LIKE YOUR TOYOTA
EXTRA CAB DELUXE.
OU NEED...
PLUS THE REPUTATION
FOR DEPENDABILITY
THAT'S A WELL-KNOWN FACT.
ALL THE SIGNS
OF A GREAT RELATIONSHIP.
THANKS TO SMARTRATE
FROM THE DISCOVER CARD,
INTEREST CHARGES NOW HAVE
A WHOLE NEW BOTTOM LINE.
CURRENTLY AS LOW AS
■■■■■■■■
AND NOW BACK TO NATIONAL
GEOGRAPHIC EXPLORER.
■■
Narrator:
IN THE COURSE OF EVOLUTION,
INSECTS DEVELOPED FLIGHT
AND SPIDERS FOLLOWED THEM
UPWARDS-- NOT WITH WINGS
BUT WITH ALL KINDS
OF AERIAL TRAPS AND SNARES.■
FOUND IN WARM CLIMATES
THE WORLD OVER
SPECIES OF NEPHILA ARE AMONG
THE BIGGEST SPIDERS IN THE WORLD
MEASURING UP TO
TEN INCHES ACROSS.
THEY OFTEN BUILD THEIR ENORMOUS
WEBS IN TROPICAL GARDENS
WHERE EXOTIC FLOWERS ATTRACT
HUGE MOTHS AND BUTTERFLIES.
THIS MASSIVE SPIDER'S WEB
IS SO STRONG
THAT IT HAS BEEN KNOWN
TO TRAP SMALL BIRDS
BUT ITS INTENDED PREY
ARE LARGE INSECTS.
SLOW
CAUGHT
BUT EVEN THE WORLD'S FASTEST
FLYING INSECT, THE DRAGONFLY
IS STOPPED COLD
BY THIS SUPER WEB.
THESE SILKEN THREADS
MAY LOOK DELICATE
BUT THEY HAVE
THE TENSILE STRENGTH OF STEEL.
USUALLY ANYTHING MOVING ABOUT
IN A WEB IS FAIR GAME
BUT THESE LITTLE SPIDERS FEED
FEARLESSLY ON NEPHILAS' CRUMBS.
THEIR RELATIONSHIP
IS KNOWN AS COMMENSALISM
WHICH LITERALLY MEANS
"FEEDING AT THE SAME TABLE."
THE COMMENSALS CLEAN THE WEB
OF TINY UNWANTED INSECTS.
IN RETURN, THEY GET PART
OF THEIR GIANT HOSTESS'S FEAST.
BUT FOR REAL COMMUNITY SPIRIT
NO SPIDER CAN MATCH
THE CRYTOPHORA.
SPIDERS ARE GENERALLY
AN ANTISOCIAL LOT
BUT THIS SOUTH SEAS NATIVE
SHARES ITS GARGANTUAN WEB
WITH HUNDREDS OF ITS KIND.
WITHIN THE WEB
EACH CRYTOPHORA DEFENDS
ITS OWN TERRITORY AND ORB
BUT THEIR HOMES
ARE ALL LINKED TOGETHER
TO FORM WHAT LOOKS LIKE
A FLOATING CITY.
MANY FOREST SPIDERS USE
NEITHER WEBS NOR NETS
TO CAPTURE THEIR PREY
BUT DEPEND RATHER ON SPEED.
THIS TREE TRUNK IS A PROMISING
SITE FOR THE SMALL TAMA SPIDER.
SHE WRESTLES AN ANT BETWEEN
HER TWO TAIL-LIKE SPINNERETS
AND THEN TIES IT UP WITH SILK.
SHE MOVES IN FOR THE KILL
BITING HER VICTIM
BEFORE EATING IT.
TAMA IS NOT ALWAYS SO FRENETIC.
WHEN SHE'S NOT HUNTING
SHE SITS SO STILL
SHE IS NEARLY IMPERCEPTIBLE.
JUMPING SPIDERS ARE THE AERIAL
ACROBATS OF THE SPIDER WORLD.
LAUNCHING THEMSELVES
AT HIGH SPEED
THEY LEAP ACROSS OPEN SPACES
BUT IF ONE MISSES ITS MARK,
A SAFETY LINE IS ALWAYS AT HAND.
OF THEIR EIGHT EYES,
TWO ARE DRAMATICALLY ENLARGED
GIVING THEM GOOD VISION
FOR DAYTIME HUNTING
AS WELL AS
A FRIENDLY APPEARANCE.
JUMPING SPIDERS ARE FOUND
ALL OVER THE WORLD.
MOST ARE LESS THAN HALF AN INCH
LONG AND ARE STRIKINGLY COLORED
BUT BECAUSE FEW MAKE WEBS,
THEY'RE OFTEN OVERLOOKED.
LEAVES OF PLANTS
ARE THEIR HUNTING GROUNDS.
A SUNBATHING FLY
CAN BE A REAL CHALLENGE.
THE FLY PROVES TOO QUICK
EVEN FOR A JUMPING SPIDER
BUT NO MATTER,
JUMPERS AREN'T PICKY EATERS.
THEY'LL EVEN PREY
ON OTHER SPIDERS.
SPIDERS HAVE EXPLOITED
EVERY CORNER OF THE GLOBE
EXCEPT THE DEEP OCEANS.
FRESH WATER SUITS THE DOLOMEDES
SPIDER JUST FINE, HOWEVER.
ITS DIET EVEN INCLUDES FISH.
THIS IS AN ANGLER
THAT USES NO BAIT
AND SURPRISINGLY,
NO SILKEN FISHING LINE.
THE HAIRS ON THE SPIDER'S LEGS
ACT AS FLOATS.
THEY PREVENT HIM FROM SINKING
THROUGH THE SURFACE FILM.
PATIENCE IS THE HALLMARK
OF ANY GOOD FISHERMAN.
WHILE FISH SWIM BELOW,
THE SPIDER WAITS FOR HIS MOMENT.
WHEN HE DIVES,
THE AIR BUBBLES ON HIS LEG HAIRS
WILL DRAW HIM BACK UP
TO THE SURFACE
SO HE DRIES HIS LEGS CAREFULLY
BETWEEN PLUNGES.
THE FISH SEE ONLY
A DISTORTED SHAPE ABOVE THEM
AND SHOW NO FEAR,
AND THAT'S THEIR UNDOING.
SPIDERS CAN'T EAT SOLID FOOD.
THEY MUST CRUSH THEIR PREY
AND PREDIGEST IT
THEN SUCK IT UP AS A LIQUID.
THIS ONE'S TURNING THE CATCH
OF THE DAY INTO FISH SOUP.
DON'T LOOK NOW-- THAT INNOCENT
BUMP ON A BRANCH
COULD BE A SPIDER IN DISGUISE.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
EXPLORER IS BEING
BROUGHT TO YOU BY IBM.
WHATEVER YOUR SIZE,
WHATEVER YOUR NEED
IBM IS WORKING TO BRING YOU
THE BEST SOLUTIONS.
■■■■
THANKS TO SMARTRATE
FROM THE DISCOVER CARD,
INTEREST CHARGES NOW HAVE
A WHOLE NEW BOTTOM LINE.
CURRENTLY AS LOW AS
THE FOLLOWING IS
A "GEOGRAPHIC MOMENT."■■■■■
■■■■■
THERE ARE PLACES YOU CAN GO
WHERE BIRDS AREN'T
THE ONLY ONES THAT FLY.
AND FISH AREN'T
THE ONLY ONES UNDER WATER.
WHERE YOU CAN TAKE A RIDE
IN THE WILD
OR JUST A WILD RIDE.
BUT IF YOU GO TO ANY
OF THE BUSCH GARDENS
OR SEA WORLD PARKS
BRING YOUR SENSE OF ADVENTURE
AND YOUR VISA CARD
BECAUSE EVERY ONE OF THESE PARKS
WILL TAKE YOUR BREATH AWAY
BUT NONE WILL TAKE
AMERICAN EXPRESS.
VISA.
TT: 1-800-833-3232
IT'S FOR EVERYBODY BACK HOME
IN YOUR COUNTRY
WHO WANTS TO KNOW
HOW YOU'RE DOING.
TT: 1-800-833-3232
IT'S FOR ALL THE COUSINS
WHO'VE ALWAYS KEPT IN TOUCH
NO MATTER WHAT.
IT'S SPECIAL COUNTRY SAVINGS
PART OF THE i PLAN FROM AT&T.
AND IT'S THE WAY
YOU CAN SAVE 15%
ON ALL THE INTERNATIONAL CALLS
YOU MAKE
TO THE ONE COUNTRY
OF YOUR CHOICE.
TT: 1-800-833-3232
SO IT'S PERFECT FOR CALLING
ALL THE NEW RELATIVES YOU GAINED
CALL NOW AND YOU CAN
START SAVING 15%.
AND NOT JUST
TO ONE OR TWO NUMBERS
BUT TO EVERYONE YOU WANT TO CALL
WHENEVER YOU WANT TO CALL THEM.
TT: 1-800-833-3232
IT'S EASY.
THERE'S NO SIGN-UP FEE
AND NO MONTHLY FEE.
SO CALL
FOR YOUR 15% SAVINGS TODAY.
BECAUSE IT'S FOR ALL THE PEOPLE
CLOSE TO YOU
WHO HAPPEN NOT TO LIVE SO CLOSE.
INTERNATIONAL SAVINGS
FOR THE WAY YOU CALL.
JUST ANOTHER PART OF THE i PLAN.
i IS FOR INDIVIDUAL.
TT: 1-800-833-3232
■■■■■■■
AND NOW BACK TO
NATIONAL GEOGRAPHIC EXPLORER.
Narrator:
WHEREVER THERE ARE FLOWERS,
INSECTS CAN BE FOUND
AND SPIDERS ARE BOUND TO FOLLOW.
THESE SPIDERS DON'T USE WEBS
TO TRAP THEIR PREY.
THEY RELY INSTEAD ON CAMOUFLAGE
AND THE FLOWER'S LURE.
SITTING ABSOLUTELY STILL
A FLOWER SPIDER MAY HAVE TO WAIT
DAYS FOR SUITABLE QUARRY.
EVEN THEN,
IT WON'T MAKE ITS MOVE
UNTIL ITS VICTIM IS AT
THE PRECISE STRIKING DISTANCE.
EVEN AN INSECT MUCH LARGER
THAN THE SPIDER
IS NOT SAFE FROM AMBUSH.
THE SPIDER'S DISGUISE IS SO GOOD
THAT IT EVEN FOOLS THIS
BUTTERFLY INTO LANDING ON IT.
CKGROUND
TO DECEIVE A KEEN-EYED PREDATOR
A SPIDER PRETENDS
IT IS SOMETHING INEDIBLE.
THE TRICK IS NOT TO MOVE.
ANY LUMP OR BUMP ON A TREE
MAY TURN OUT TO BE A SPIDER.
THIS ONE APPEARS TO BE A BIRD
DROPPING-- UNTIL IT WALKS AWAY.
WE OURSELVES ARE OFTEN UNAWARE
OF THE SPIDERS AROUND US.
THE FLAT SHAPE AND CAMOUFLAGE
PATTERN OF PANDERCETES
HELP CONCEAL IT.
HAIRS ON ITS LEGS BLUR THE
SHADOW THAT MIGHT GIVE IT AWAY.
IN THIS CASE, THE DISGUISE
IS NOT JUST FOR DEFENSE
AS A TINY BARK MANTIS
IS ABOUT TO DISCOVER.
PLAYING WALLFLOWER
MAY BE FINE FOR SOME
BUT OTHER SPIDERS HAVE TAKEN THE
ART OF DECEPTION A STEP FURTHER.
YOU CAN TELL THIS IS AN ANT BY
HER TWO ANTENNAE AND SIX LEGS.
BUT THIS ONE IS AN IMPOSTOR.
THE SPIDER WAVES
TWO OF ITS EIGHT LEGS ABOUT
IMITATING THE ANT'S ANTENNAE.
THERE ARE MANY DIFFERENT KINDS
OF THESE ANT-MIMICKING SPIDERS.
EACH ONE SPECIFICALLY COPIES
THE ANT IT PREYS ON.
THIS ONE IS A DOUBLE
FOR THE FIERCE WEAVER ANTS
OF TROPICAL AUSTRALIA.
LIVING LIKE A SPY
IN ENEMY TERRITORY
IT FEEDS ON THEM EXCLUSIVELY.
WHILE EATING AN ANT
THE SPIDER RETREATS SAFELY
TO ITS SILK THREAD.
BUT THE NUMBERS ARE STACKED
AGAINST THE SPIDER
AND SOMETIMES THE HUNTER
BECOMES THE HUNTED.
WARY OF THE ANTS
PATROLLING ABOVE
THE SPIDER DROPS DOWN
HIS ESCAPE ROPE.
IT RARELY HAPPENS
BUT THIS TIME THE TABLES
ARE TURNED ON THE SPIDER.
ANOTHER AUSTRALIAN SPIDER
ACTUALLY SEEMS TO SPEAK
THE LANGUAGE OF HER PREY.
SHE FEEDS ON MEAT ANTS, WHICH
LIVE IN LARGE MOUNDED NESTS
AT THE CENTER
OF WELL-WORN FORAGING TRACKS.
FROM HER UNIQUELY SHAPED WEB
THIS INDUSTRIOUS CREATURE
EARNED HER NAME:
THE LOBSTER POT SPIDER.
WHEN AN ANT COMES TO INVESTIGATE
HER LAIR, THE SPIDER EMERGES.
SHE APPEARS TO TAP OUT A MESSAGE
IN ANT FASHION
BUT FOR NOW,
HER GREETING GOES UNANSWERED.
AGAIN THE SPIDER TAPS OUT
HER TACTILE INVITATION
AND
ANT
THE UNSUSPECTING GUEST
IS SEIZED AND EATEN.
THE BOLAS SPIDER
IS EVEN MORE DEVIOUS
ATTRACTING HER VICTIMS
WITH AN IRRESISTIBLE BAIT.
THE CLASSIC ORB WEB
OF HER ANCESTORS
HAS EVOLVED INTO A SINGLE THREAD
IN HER SPECIES.
SHE DANGLES IT LIKE A FISHING
LINE BEADED WITH STICKY DROPS.
IT SEEMS LIKE A POOR WAY
TO CATCH A FLYING INSECT
AND THE BOLAS FEEDS ONLY ON
MALE MOTHS OF A PARTICULAR KIND.
INCREDIBLY, THE SPIDER
LURES HER PREY
WITH
BY FEMAL
MATING.
WHEN THE MALE MOTH HOMES IN
ON THIS SINGULAR PERFUME
THE MOTH ENDS UP IN THE ARMS
OF A VERY DIFFERENT FEMALE
THAN HE SET OUT TO MEET.
THOUGH FEMALES DOMINATE
THE LORE OF SPIDERS
MALES DO HAVE ONE
VERY IMPORTANT ROLE TO PLAY.
ON A SPECIAL WEB,
THIS LARGE-JAWED SPIDER
IS DEPOSITING A DROPLET
OF WHITE SPERM FLUID.
IT FLOWS FROM THE SPIDER'S
GENITAL OPENING
HALFWAY ALONG HIS BODY.
NOW HE PICKS THE DROPLET
OFF THE SPERM WEB
AND DRAWS THE FLUID INTO
THE MATING ORGANS ON HIS FEELERS
KNOWN AS PALPS.
HIS PREPARATIONS COMPLETE
THE MALE IS NOW READY
DOWN IN THE GRASS, A LINK SPIDER
TRIES TO CHARM A FEMALE.
LIKE ALL SPIDERS
THAT HUNT BY DAY
THEIR MATING HABITS
ARE VERY VISUAL.
THE FEMALE WATCHES INTENTLY.
SHE WON'T RESPOND
UNTIL HE'S ESTABLISHED HIMSELF
AS ONE OF HER OWN KIND.
WAVING HIS CONSPICUOUS BLACK
PALPS, HE SIGNALS HIS INTENT.
HE TAPS THE FEMALE
WITH HIS HAIRY FRONT LEGS
AND SHE SEEMS INTRIGUED.
BUT APPARENTLY
SHE WAS ONLY LEADING HIM ON.
THE MOST ELEGANT RITUALS
OF SPIDER COURTSHIP
ARE FOUND AMONG
THE JUMPING SPIDERS.
THE MATE OF THIS LITTLE FEMALE
FROM THE TROPICS
NED
BY HIS BLACK FACE
AND WHITE SIDE WHISKERS
MUST
NOT WITH HIS PALPS THIS TIME
BUT WITH HIS DISTINCTIVE
BLACK LEGS.
HE MUST FIRST CAPTURE
HER FULL ATTENTION.
PERHAPS BECAUSE
SHE'S MORE INTERESTED
IN CATCHING FLIES THAN A MATE
THIS IS HARD TO DO, BUT HE'S
PERSISTENT AND FOLLOWS HER.
HE MAKES PRECISE, RITUALIZED
MOVEMENTS WITH HIS FRONT LEGS...
BUT SHE STILL SEEMS ALOOF.
EVENTUALLY, THE FEMALE LETS HIM
ADVANCE AND STROKE HER HEAD.
THE MASSAGE PUTS HER
INTO A TRANCELIKE STATE
AND THE MALE IS AT LAST ABLE
TO TILT HER ABDOMEN
AND PROCEED WITH MATING.
WHILE THE EXACT RITUALS
OF COURTSHIP
ARE UNIQUE TO EACH SPECIES
ALL SPIDERS ARE HIGHLY SENSITIVE
TO TOUCH AND VIBRATIONS
SO COMMUNICATION BETWEEN MALES
AND FEMALES IS USUALLY TACTILE.
THIS MALE NET-CASTING SPIDER IS
ON THE LINE TO A POTENTIAL MATE.
HE PRESENTS HIS CREDENTIALS
IN THE SPECIAL LANGUAGE
OF HIS KIND...
AND WINS HER OVER.
THIS TANGLE OF 16 LEGS
LOOKS A BIT AWKWARD
BUT THE SPIDERS KNOW
EXACTLY WHAT THEY'RE DOING.
WITH HIS PALP SWELLING
LIKE A BALLOON
THE MALE FERTILIZES HIS MATE.
THE COILED DUCT, OR EMBOLUS
THAT DELIVERS THE SPERM
IS RETRACTED BACK INTO THE PALP.
SOON THE WHOLE PROCESS WILL BE
REPEATED WITH THE OTHER PALP.
BY STORING ENOUGH SPERM
FOR SEVERAL BATCHES OF EGGS
BUT MALES CAN MATE
SEVERAL TIMES.
THIS ONE'S CLEANING HIS PALPS
SO HE'LL BE READY
FOR HIS NEXT ALLIANCE.
WHEN SOME MALE
SPIDERS GO COURTING
THEY'RE ALSO COURTING DEATH.
IT'S "DANGEROUS LIAISONS" NEXT.
■
YOU'RE WATCHING NATIONAL
GEOGRAPHIC EXPLORER ON TBS.
■
THANKS TO SMARTRATE
FROM THE DISCOVER CARD,
INTEREST CHARGES NOW HAVE
A WHOLE NEW BOTTOM LINE.
CURRENTLY AS LOW AS
■■■■■■■■■
AND NOW BACK TO
NATIONAL GEOGRAPHIC EXPLORER.
Narrator:
MANY PEOPLE BELIEVE THAT FEMALE
SPIDERS ALWAYS EAT THEIR MATES.
WHEN THE SEXES ARE ABOUT THE
SAME SIZE, THIS SELDOM OCCURS
BUT THE FEMALE
SAINT ANDREWS CROSS SPIDER
IS A GIANT
COMPARED WITH HER MATE.
AND THE MALE THAT COURTS HER
COURTS DEATH.
WHEN A POTENTIAL SUITOR
APPROACHES A FEMALE
HE MUST QUICKLY IDENTIFY HIMSELF
AS A MALE RATHER THAN A MEAL.
HE SITS VERY STILL
ON THE OPPOSITE FACE OF HER WEB.
HE'S MADE A HOLE IN IT
SO HE CAN MAKE A DASH FOR SAFETY
IF SHE ATTACKS.
RISKING LIFE AND LIMB,
HE PERFORMS A MATING DANCE.
ONTO
THE OUTSKIRTS OF THE WEB.
HE PLUCKS A TACTILE SERENADE
ON A SILK THREAD
AND SHE
FEET.
HIS LOVE SONG HAS WORKED
AND THEY BEGIN TO MATE.
BUT THERE'S SOMETHING SINISTER
GOING ON BEHIND HIS BACK.
WHY IS SHE PULLING OUT
A SILK NOOSE?
SENSING TREACHERY,
HE LEAPS AWAY.
THE MALE SEEMS TO HAVE BEEN
KNOCKED OFF BALANCE
BY THIS DANGEROUS LIAISON.
IN FACT, HE'S ONLY GOT
SEVEN LEGS LEFT.
THE FEMALE'S EATING
THE EIGHTH ONE.
STILL, THE DRIVE TO REPRODUCE
IS OVERWHELMING.
THE MALE MAKES ANOTHER ATTEMPT.
IF HE'S LUCKY, HE'LL SUCCEED.
IF HE'S EVEN LUCKIER,
ONE THING IS CERTAIN: A MALE
SAINT ANDREWS CROSS SPIDER
IS UNLIKELY TO DIE OF OLD AGE.
THOUGH SOME FEMALES DISPLAY
OUTRIGHT HOSTILITY
TOWARD THEIR MATES
THEY ARE DEVOTED
TO THEIR OFFSPRING.
ALL SPIDERS ENCLOSE THEIR EGGS
IN AN EGG SAC LINED
WITH THE SOFTEST SILK.
BUT THE NURSERY
OF THE WOLF SPIDER
MUST ALSO HAVE A TOUGH EXTERIOR.
LIKE HER NAMESAKE, THIS SPIDER
IS ALWAYS ON THE MOVE.
SHE MUST DRAG IT ALONG
WHEREVER SHE GOES
LIKE A BABY CARRIAGE IN REVERSE.
VERY FEW SPIDERS RISK
PUTTING ALL THEIR EGGS
IN ONE BASKET, HOWEVER.
A BOLAS SPIDER MAY CREATE
MANY EGG SACS EACH YEAR.
POURING LIKE WATER FROM A TAP
THESE EGGS ARE JUST A FEW
OF THE SEVERAL THOUSAND
THAT THE MOTHER WILL LAY
IN A SINGLE SEASON.
EGG SACS ARE AS DISTINCT AS
THE DIFFERENT SPECIES OF SPIDER.
THE NET-CASTER ROTATES HERS
AS SHE WEAVES.
SHE SEES NOTHING
OF WHAT SHE'S DOING.
THROUGH TOUCH ALONE
SHE CRAFTS A PERFECTLY OVAL
CRADLE FOR HER BABIES.
PROGRESSIVE LAYERS ARE MADE
FROM DIFFERENT SILKS.
LIKE A JEWEL BOX,
A SPIDER'S EGG SAC IS OPENED
TO REVEAL EMERALD GREEN
SPIDERLINGS.
THE NEWBORNS STAY CLOSE
TO THEIR ABANDONED NURSERY
UNTIL THEY'VE MOLTED.
THERE'S SAFETY IN NUMBERS.
AFTER SEVERAL WEEKS
OF BEING PROTECTED
FROM THE ELEMENTS AND PREDATORS,
THESE YOUNGSTERS HAVE EMERGED
INTO A WORLD
FRAUGHT WITH HAZARD.
THE FEMALE HUNTSMAN SPIDER
HAS A STRONG MATERNAL INSTINCT.
SHE GUARDS HER YOUNG
AND PROVIDES THEM WITH FOOD
AS THEY GATHER AROUND HER MOUTH.
ANY DISTURBANCE SETS OFF
A CHAIN REACTION IN THE CLUSTER.
THEY DON'T EVEN HAVE TO BREAK
OUT OF THE SAC BY THEMSELVES.
THEIR MOTHER OPENS IT FOR THEM.
SHE KEEPS THE HATCHLINGS
CLOSE BY AT ALL TIMES.
CLINGING TO SPECIAL HAIRS
ON HER ABDOMEN
THEY RIDE PIGGYBACK EVERYWHERE.
AS SEASON FOLLOWS SEASON
ALL AROUND THE WORLD
NEW GENERATIONS OF SPIDERS
EXPLODE INTO LIFE AND DISPERSE.
MOST WILL LIVE ONLY BRIEFLY,
PREYED ON BY BIRDS, INSECTS
AND EVEN THEIR OWN KIND
BUT THOSE THAT DO SURVIVE
WILL NEED NO APPRENTICESHIP
IN SPIDERLY CRAFTS.
A BABY BOLAS SPIDER ALREADY
SHE'S SM
TIP.
AND THE SCENT SHE USES FOR BAIT
NOW LURES A MUCH SMALLER
KIND OF MOTH.
A YOUNG NET-CASTING SPIDER
MAKES A PERFECT MINIATURE NET.
A TINY ORB-WEAVING SPIDER
A BORN ENGINEER
WITH A GENETIC BLUEPRINT
IS MAKING ITS VERY FIRST WEB.
THINGS CAN GET CONFUSING
IN A CONFINED SPACE
WITH SO MANY SIBLINGS AROUND.
BUT SOON IT ALL GOES
LIKE CLOCKWORK.
THESE LITTLE SPIDERS
WILL EVENTUALLY SPREAD OUT
INTO THEIR SEPARATE TERRITORIES.
MANY WILL SPAN THE EARTH
ON SILKEN BRIDGES.
OTHERS WILL LAUNCH THEMSELVES
INTO THE AIR
TO BE CARRIED FAR AND WIDE
BUT ALL WILL BE
THE SCOURGE OF INSECTS--
MASTERS OF DECEPTION
AND WEAVERS OF WONDER.
THAT SPECTACULAR SPIDER FOOTAGE
IS THE WORK OF A UNIQUE TEAM
OF FILMMAKERS:
AUSTRALIANS JIM FRAZIER
AND DENSEY CLYNE.
WHEN WE COME BACK,
WE'RE GOING TO TAKE YOU
FOR A SPECIAL LOOK
AT THEIR WORLD.
NEXT, THE MAKING
OF A SPIDER FLICK.
SHOOTING THE NATURAL WORLD
MEANS GETTING YOUR HANDS DIRTY
AND MAYBE COVERED
WITH STINGING ANTS.
SE
OF
ES
HIS.
TOYOTA INVITES YOU TO TEST
YOUR KNOWLEDGE OF THE WORLD
WITH "NATIONAL
GEOGRAPHIC ATLAS."
STAY TUNED FOR THE ANSWER
THE 1993 TOYOTA TERCEL...■
NOT ONLY COMES WITH A
STANDARD DRIVER-SIDE AIR BAG,
THE TERCEL IS ALSO TOYOTA'S
LOWEST-PRICED 4-DOOR SEDAN.
WHY FOUR DOORS ?
BECAUSE YOU NEVER KNOW WHEN
YOU MIGHT NEED THE EXTRA ROOM.
WHAT ?
AND NOW, THE ANSWER.
■■
EVERY SPRING,
THE SIROCCO PICKS UP MOISTURE
AS IT CROSSES THE MEDITERRANEAN
ARRIVING ON EUROPEAN SHORES
AS A WARM, MOIST WIND.
THANKS TO SMARTRATE
FROM THE DISCOVER CARD,
■■
INTEREST CHARGES NOW HAVE
A WHOLE NEW BOTTOM LINE.
CURRENTLY AS LOW AS
AND NOW BACK TO EXPLORER
AND YOUR HOST, ROBERT URICH.■■■
AUSTRALIANS JIM FRAZIER
AND DENSEY CLYNE
ARE ONE OF THE PREMIER COUPLES
OF THE FILMMAKING WORLD.
THEY'RE MARRIED--
NOT TO EACH OTHER--
BUT TO A WORLD
MOST PEOPLE NEVER SEE:
THE WORLD OF MICRO-ACTION
WHERE THE STARS
ARE CATERPILLARS, SPIDERS
AND THE OCCASIONAL RIFLEBIRD.
AND NOW, JIM AND DENSEY
BEHIND THE WEB.
Narrator:
TO BE IN PICTURES,
A SPIDER'S GOT TO LOOK TERRIFIC.
AND TO BE DAZZLING ENOUGH
FOR THE MOVIES
EVEN NATURE NEEDS
PROFESSIONAL HELP.
MAKING SOME OF
THE SMALLEST CREATURES
LOOK THEIR BEST ON CAMERA
IS THE BUSINESS OF
THESE TWO AUSTRALIANS...
AND THEY'RE GOOD AT IT.
JIM FRAZIER AND DENSEY CLYNE
ARE AWARD-WINNING
WILDLIFE FILMMAKERS.
HE'S A CAMERAMAN.
SHE'S A NATURALIST AND WRITER
WHO BEGAN HER CAREER
AS A STILL PHOTOGRAPHER.
Clyne:
MOST OF MY PHOTOGRAPHY
IS DONE OUTDOORS
BECAUSE I LIKE TO BE
OUT IN THE BUSH
AND I LIKE TO FIND THE INSECTS
DOING THEIR THING
AND PHOTOGRAPH THEM NATURALLY.
BUT THERE ARE TIMES WHEN
I HAVE TO USE A STUDIO SETUP.
WITH VERY SMALL INSECTS,
YOU CAN CONTROL THEM MUCH BETTER
IF YOU'VE GOT THEM, FOR
INSTANCE, ON A STEM OR A LEAF--
CONFINED TO THAT AREA.
THEY'RE REALLY AT YOUR MERCY.
SO THERE YOU CAN
LET YOUR HEAD GO
AND YOU KNOW YOU'RE GOING
TO GET A SHOT.
Narrator:
JIM'S SPECIALTY
IS MOVING PICTURES.
Frazier:
I BECAME INTERESTED
IN PHOTOGRAPHY
APPROXIMATELY 20 YEARS AGO.
DENSEY WAS INTRODUCED TO ME
AND SHE WAS TAKING
THESE WONDERFUL PHOTOGRAPHS
AND I THOUGHT, "GEE, I'D LOVE
TO HAVE A GO AT THAT"
AND I'D NEVER EVEN HANDLED
A CAMERA BEFORE.
AND WHEN I FINALLY STARTED
WORKING WITH DENSEY
SHE TAUGHT ME THE RUDIMENTS
OF PHOTOGRAPHY
AND I GUESS MY WHOLE CAREER
GREW FROM THAT POINT ON.
Narrator:
FOR JIM TO ACTUALLY PRODUCE
THE SHOTS HE DREAMS UP
HE'S BECOME MORE
THAN A CINEMATOGRAPHER.
HE'S ALSO AN INVENTOR.
Frazier:
ONE OF THE PROBLEMS
WITH FILMING WILDLIFE IS
THAT MOST OF THE LENSES THAT
ARE AVAILABLE ON THE SHELVES
DON'T NECESSARILY DO
WHAT YOU WANT TO DO
SO I'VE ACTUALLY BEEN FORCED
TO BUILD LENSES
TO DO THE SORTS OF THINGS
THAT I'VE ENVISAGED.
ONE OF THE SUCCESSFUL
LENSES IS THIS ONE.
FOR INSTANCE, IF YOU WANT
A SHOT FROM GROUND LEVEL
LOOKING AT THE ACTUAL
SPECIMEN IN FRONT
IT PUTS A LOT OF IT IN FOCUS
AND YOU GET THEIR EYE-VIEW
OF THE WORLD.
NOW, THIS PARTICULAR ONE
I'VE USED A LOT ON BUTTERFLIES
FLIES
.
BUT BY MOVING THE LENS LIKE THIS
YOU'RE ACTUALLY
ACHIEVING CRANES.
THE LENS THAT HAS COME
TO MOST ATTENTION
IS THIS LITTLE SECRET
IN THE BLACK BOX.
Narrator:
IT'S HARD TO BELIEVE
BUT DAVID ATTENBOROUGH
ISN'T POSING WITH A MONSTER.
IT'S AN INCH-LONG CATERPILLAR.
THE ILLUSION IS A RESULT OF ONE
OF JIM'S OPTICAL INNOVATIONS.
Frazier:
I'VE COME UP WITH
A CONFIGURATION
THAT PUTS INTO FOCUS
EVERYTHING FROM AN ANT HERE
TO AN ELEPHANT OR MOUNTAINS
IN THE BACKGROUND--
IT DOESN'T MATTER.
I'M REALLY PROUD OF THIS
LITT
DOES.
Narrator:
FOR THE PHOTOGRAPHERS
AND THEIR ASSISTANT, JOHN YOUNG
FILMMAKING ISN'T ONLY FANCY
EQUIPMENT AND SPECIAL EFFECTS.
IT'S ALSO HANDS-ON WORK
IN THE FIELD.
.
Narrator:
ON THIS MISSION,
THEY WANT TO FILM A BUTTERFLY
AFTER IT EMERGES FROM ITS PUPA.
THE PROBLEM IS, THIS
PARTICULAR PUPA LIVES EMBEDDED
IN A NEST OF WEAVER ANTS...
AND WEAVER ANTS STING.
RIGHT.
GOT ONE,
JIM, LOOK!
Frazier:
OH, GREAT,
FANTASTIC!
Narrator:
BACK IN THE STUDIO,
JIM INVENTS A SYSTEM
THAT SOUNDS WHEN THE PUPA
IS ABOUT TO BREAK.
( alarm buzzing  )
AT THE ALARM,
ONLY ONE TASK REMAINS:
RETURNING THE PUPA
TO A NEST FULL OF ANTS.
THESE, TOO.
OH, BEAUTY.
( chirping  )
OKAY.
HIT THE LIGHT, PLEASE.
OH, LOOK AT IT!
OH, BEAUTIFUL!
Narrator:
THE FILMMAKERS GO TO
A GREAT DEAL OF TROUBLE
BUT IT'S THE ONLY WAY
TO GET PICTURES LIKE THESE.
THE PLACE WHERE JIM AND DENSEY
DO MOST OF THEIR FIELDWORK
IS THE AUSTRALIAN RAIN FOREST.
THIS TIME THEY'RE AFTER A BIRD.
TO GET A GOOD VIEW
CLOSE TO THE ACTION
THEY NEED A PLACE TO HIDE.
PLATFORMS IN THE TREETOPS
ARE JOHN YOUNG'S SPECIALTY.
Young:
IT'S AN EXTREMELY DANGEROUS
BUSINESS THAT I'M IN
BECAUSE OF THE CLIMBING ASPECTS.
ONE HAS TO BE SO CAREFUL
HE HAS TO KNOW THE TIMBER
YOU CLIMB, THE TREES.
Frazier:
THIS PARTICULAR TREE
WE'RE PUTTING A HIDE IN
AT THE MOMENT
IT'S CALLED A CODAHI--
ONE OF THOSE REALLY BRITTLE GUMS
AND JOHN KNOWS THEM
ONLY TOO WELL.
HE KNOWS WHAT SIZE BRANCH
WILL SUPPORT WHAT WEIGHT
AND THAT'S WHAT I RELY ON.
SOME OF THESE THINGS,
LIKE THIS ONE
WILL SNAP JUST LIKE A CARROT
AND THEY DON'T GIVE YOU
ANY
Narrator:
THE BIRD JIM AND DENSEY
WANT TO FILM HAS BEEN ELUSIVE
AND IT'S KEPT THEM REVISITING
THEIR HIDEOUT FOR MONTHS NOW--
OFTEN FOR DAYS AT A TIME.
Frazier:
IT'S ACTUALLY QUITE PLEASANT
SITTING UP IN A HIDE
IN THE RAIN FOREST FILMING.
YOU TEND TO NOTICE EVERYTHING
THAT MOVES AROUND YOU
AND SO WHILE YOU MAY BE
CONCENTRATING
ON ONE PARTICULAR SUBJECT
YOU CAN'T HELP BUT SEE
EVERYTHING ELSE
THAT'S HAPPENING.
THAT'S THE FASCINATING PART
AND THAT KEEPS YOU ALIVE,
THAT KEEPS YOU VIBRANT.
THES
TING
BUT THEY'RE NOT WHAT THE
FILMMAKERS ARE LOOKING FOR.
THEY WANT THE RIFLEBIRD.
( squawks )
JIM WANTS TO FILM
THIS BIRD MATING--
SOMETHING WHICH HAS NEVER
BEEN PHOTOGRAPHED BEFORE.
ALL THE RIFLEBIRD WANTS
IS A FEMALE.
JUST WHEN THE FEMALE SEEMS
AGREEABLE, SHE CHANGES HER MIND.
( screeches )
THE RIFLEBIRD ISN'T
THE ONLY ONE LET DOWN.
JIM AND DENSEY HAVE WAITED IN
THE BLIND SEVEN DAYS FOR THIS.
BUT THE VERY NEXT DAY,
EVERYONE GETS SATISFACTION.
THE RIFLEBIRD ESPECIALLY
HAS SOMETHING TO CROW ABOUT.
SHOWING US NATURE'S
SMALL CREATURES
AS WE RARELY SEE THEM
IS JIM AND DENSEY'S BUSINESS...
AND THEIR PLEASURE.
IT'S A LIFE THEY ALMOST
SEEM MADE FOR.
Clyne:
.
I LIKE TO FEEL FREE.
JIM AND I BOTH LIKE THAT BEST--
TO BE FREE, OUT THERE
IN THE BUSH, WITH OUR CAMERAS
JUST LOOKING,
SEEING WHAT WE CAN FIND.
Frazier:
I GUESS I WOULDN'T SWAP IT
FOR ANY OTHER LIFE IN THE WORLD.
IT'S GREAT.
YOU DON'T MAKE A LOT OF MONEY
OUT OF MAKING WILDLIFE FILMS.
IN FACT, YOU LIVE QUITE POORLY.
BUT THIS SORT OF LIFESTYLE
OF BEING OUT HERE
LEARNING ABOUT ANIMALS
AND WATCHING ANIMALS DO
EXTRAORDINARY THINGS--
THERE'S NO JOB
IN AN OFFICE IN A CITY