process
how important is it for him to do this
in a way it is different than which are
the cannon office which president pretty
important that one i don't think was
ronald
alike
governor kean uh...
matter of nor um... shinto attractive
candidate but based on your background
should women governor for court two
years
um... i don't think she pass that test
regretted abiam ready to take over
and um...
i think that was uh...
a mistake
you know this guy is
he is so much right
because u_n_ indeed within his own party
whether that like
attractive candidate
accordance that this
my god i guess he shows a hot woman
become on of course he wasn't qualified
you to pick someone like me
west of the interesting point group inc
dick cheney act anyway
to be vp
all right
dick cheney
do you remember that
back in mid two thousand election
george bush chose dick cheney
to help them select as vice presidential
nominee
and dick cheney came bags and i got the
program for you
now that's a testament to how painfully
stupid george w_ bush is
all right
what a lot of criticism actors that
especially ap
anything that cover highlight and yes it
is you did
he things about sort of a candidate is
the pre-k
but it could be derailed
well
massive star anti-war about iraq
and they should be a passive it
you know hey who should run the pic he
had to pick a name you know which in a
major
that janet
that would be the last time you wouldn't
know what
this guy a man with a character
what his last upon radio forgettable
wasn't twenties and thirties
when we had a conversation about his
mother fucker for anyway
i mean we who was taken as some of big
seriously
the hall meteorite
although they drag their reading part
always dick cheney's to dissolved
awkward detainees that's
well john edwards think i don't give a
shit when john edwards thanks
quote yes the guys pull in five percent
and exchange all budget on that
so why would you think as you know a guy
who is this
deeply on popular
walter stokely you would
if i wasn't brocco obama i would run my
campaign
the exact opposite way i'd say look
whatever the case in favor of
i'm automatically going to be a guest
dick cheney is a miserable failure
nearly seven seven
one other thing he said was all he had a
deadline capture that damian
and wait till the when president lot of
similar
that was upset
see or hear some of the information we
collect on the bush administration is
absolutely critical that really
well you had after the nine eleven
bodies you had more than seven years to
get you
always or ants
inaction
it'll get you can see all you could not
afford what did you catch up
concealed mujhse
the idea was blue sun iran iraq was very
but what happened with that even he
he'll forget your bs and there's nobody
believes weapons of mass destruction and
do you get about my lord no-one in
america believes that okay
we know what you're about right
for your main idea was ok we neutral oil
in iraq
that you know if we have also know what
happened
failure you lou
there are no words on the ground
we it you know why widow iraqi ironic
because they had a bit of a democracy
and a
dime government couldn't possibly keep
us there
ever made a private
so we can cure sorry asap
and now you know caracas top allies with
or wrong
indentations act
opposite of what you intend to do dick
cheney weicker's as always
miserable
alone to run against dick cheney
big reported to you
what kind of stupid ass politician what
ever agree with this it was a role loser
would like to which the country to spot
system
they're hiding um
he says he's gone fishing at the
convention
that convention
all of you can start there
acting kirsty looked the whole
structures built around the courtroom
rebate reporter we invade
who is there any punishment everybody
so all bomber goes along with
established in the national security
serious people and as a security said so
united keeps on and we now book
uh... e about
the inside were his little by ministers
to the million of those wishes by daniel
climbing
uh... it's really interesting uh... this
instance is something nobody in this
region is proud of
but it's act i think he should be
horrified at it in the beginning or
model comes under signature strikes
what you mean tell me what do we draw
strikes on people and we don't even know
who they are we just telling them
because their military age males
what is that what is military g-mail z
in the beginning all pos again susan i'm
not gonna sign off on that
by then and he's like yeah let's do it
in pakistan and you know what
argument for the listed in yemen to
by then easily everything cheney wanted
and more
bright brilliant brilliant politics
if he can't go this way president obama
you might also have an approval rating
at once