There's that one.
Fucking Dyrdek.
You got Arto's.
Grant's.
Mine's the bananas.
And I feel like that'll
be the hot seller.
Dill's.
MALE SPEAKER: Dang, there's
a lot of that Alien pros.
DYLAN RIEDER: Yeah.
I think Workshop 2, there's
not really a genre.
Everybody's so different.
You got Heath and then AVE
and then Dyrdek and a
broad expand of dudes.
MALE SPEAKER: Kalis.
DYLAN RIEDER: Kalis.
Well, now he's DGKalis.
Kalis left.
I'm sure he was feeling
a bit like an outcast.
Going on tour, I think it would
just be AVE, Jake, Dill,
Heath, and then Kalis.
BILL STROBECK: I could see where
it seemed like if Kalis
felt that way, which I feel like
he did, that he felt like
he didn't fit in.
Because Josh has been
on since forever.
Someone like Josh is
more of a team guy.
He likes to have the whole
team get together.
He's real about that.
I felt like he didn't feel like
he fit in when he was
there before all those guys.
They all took over, all those
new kids and AVE and Dylan--
and those guys.
It just seemed like it was
their team, kind of.
JASON DILL: Workshop got divided
into upriver and
downriver at one point.
And now that Kalis is gone,
there's less upriver.
Dyrdek, Mikey Taylor,
Berra is so upriver.
MALE SPEAKER: What
does that mean?
JASON DILL: They're upriver.
They're where TVs exist, the
internet, fishing's better.
Who's in the van on tour?
Who's dirty and in the
streets all the time?
The downriver kids.
So Dylan was instantly
downriver with us.
As far as Dylan goes, between
the time he got on the
Workshop and him just being with
us all the time and being
so much like AVE and I,
it seemed like he
wasn't ever not there.
ANTHONY VAN ENGELEN: He just
embodies a classic, good
style, gnarly, talented skater,
and into just who he
is and stuff.
It just fit into the Workshop.
Whatever.
He's his own person.
JASON DILL: Dylan's
like me and AVE--
hand tattoos, smoking
cigarettes.
There's so many times me and AVE
looked at him and we were
like, wow, look at him.
He's growing up so fast.
Oh, boy.
And then shit gets
new with him.
DYLAN RIEDER: These guys
are pretty tight.
Burgundy loafers.
They're slip-ons,
kind of cool.
MALE SPEAKER: These shoes
are pretty infamous.
DYLAN RIEDER: Yeah.
I think they got a lot of
talk when they came out.
I definitely got some
shit for them.
But I fucking dig them.
They're awesome.
When you skate them,
this red comes off.
It's super thin leather, so
it bleeds kind of crazy.
MARK OBLOW: Well, Dylan
was on Vans.
And at the time, he was
wearing the slip-ons.
That's all he wore,
slip-on, slip-on.
So when we started Gravis, that
was the thing was for him
and Arto, it's like this was
going to be their deal.
And they could do whatever
they wanted.
It was just really like,
what do you want?
And that's what he wanted.
Because he wanted something that
when he's skating, looks
like when he's walking
around at night.
So at the time, Dylan was super
influenced by fashion
and just stuff in that world.
And that's where it stemmed from
was not going, oh, how
can we rip off the
Nike Dunk again?
You look at a lot of shoes.
And it's sad to say, but they
rip off the classics.
He wanted to do something
different as well.
He was willing to take the
risk and said, fuck it.
I don't care.
Because he did get a
lot of heat for it.
And that's a part of Dylan, too,
where he is a tough kid,
where you can go, fuck you.
I don't care.
And yeah, that's my shoe.
Ha.
JASON DILL: Everybody secretly
wants those shoes.
Did you hear the story
about the enjoy team?
So the enjoy team was on
a tour with Joe Brook.
He just told me this.
And they kept talking
about Dylan's shoe.
And at first, it was like,
[DISCONTENTED MUTTERING]
who is this?
Maybe not so bad, but probably
something like that.
And they were like, man,
someone must have said,
actually, I saw them.
And they're fucking
so comfortable and
they're super sick.
And I just thought, see,
that's what it's about.
It's about, fuck you guys.
Fuck me what I think.
Look at this original little
fucker running around with his
cute little rolled-up pants and
his fucking shirts with
the buttons on and a little
necklace and shit.
He looks great.
That's what's funny.
You talk about the way
that Dylan dresses.
Look what we're doing now,
talking about Dylan.
So joke's on you.
You're not as good-looking
as him.
GREG HUNT: You should
be able to dress
however you want to dress.
Look at how Hosoi dressed
in the '80s.
He was full rock star.
It's all about doing
your own thing.
But what it really comes down
to is your skating.
| think he's a full skate rat.
Yeah, he might wear sometimes
nice clothes.
He might skate in
But dude, it's not keeping him
from trying something insane
and slamming for five hours
till he gets something.
So there's definitely
a little bit of
negativity towards Dylan.
But that's all people
who don't know him.
JASON DILL: I think that the
thing is, I think that the way
that Dylan dresses in "Mind
Field" sticks out so much.
Because when it starts, you
have Dylan, Vans shoe.
And someone would say a normal
type of that kid.
Then as the video part
progresses, all of a sudden,
Dylan's got some fucking jeans,
his little dance shoes
on, and a tank top.
And it's fucking great.
It's like, yeah, of course.
And now when you see
Dylan, the look
is perfectly together.
I back a look big time,
give a fuck.
I'm always coming
up with looks.
I love it.
But now I'm stuck in a look.
I can't get out of the
pulled-up socks.
BILL STROBECK: The way Dylan
dresses reminds me of
Dill at that time.
When I first met Dill, it was
like, here are my fancy,
fashionable shoes.
And here is these pants
that no one's wearing.
Dill had those cut-off pants
that were big and short.
They were like high waters.
But it had something
to do with fashion.
And I think that Dylan's
into that.
MALE SPEAKER: Do you
think that Dylan
takes that from Dill?
BILL STROBECK: I don't think
he takes it from Dill.
I think that he just expresses
himself in the same way that
Dill did when he felt like he
could be his own person.
He's young.
When I was that age, I had
Richard Avedon CK One photos
on my wall.
And this is his age to do
that kind of stuff.
He likes model chicks.
He'll grow out of that.
I'd say if you could look up
the words "cool breeze"
online, that's the perfect
explanation for Dylan.
He's a cool breeze, sunglasses,
and fucking
sitting in the corner and not
really talking to that many
people, especially
around that time.
He was just a fucking
young, mellow dude.
MARK OBLOW: And that's
how he's always been.
And that's part of the mystique
of Dylan, and even
covering up in the hoodies, and
all the shit is he doesn't
like that attention.
He doesn't like the whole pretty
boy and all this stuff.
And it's like, Dylan is
a good-looking kid.
And then because of that, he
gets points taken away, you
know what I mean?
Where if he was fucking
ugly, he would
be looked at different.
But he had to prove himself.
JASON DILL: You can give Dylan
all the shit you want.
But he looks great.
He's goddamn good-looking.
MARK OBLOW: That's obviously,
too, the big difference
fucking the chicks.
It's like, at his video
premiere, we had that party.
And it's like, you look at all
the people in the crowd and
all the guys.
And then there's just rows of
all these good-looking girls.
And they're all just staring,
watching the
whole entire parks.
And they're like, oh, he's
so good, his style.
He's so smooth.
You're just like, fucking
asshole, man.
What a dick.
BILL STROBECK: Dylan
can get ass, man.
He's confident.
He's real confident.
He'll fuck them and
chuck them, dude.
He gets some.
Him and Alex both have--
they're both good-looking,
like fucking Johnny Depp.
This one night, I went to this
place, this club out in LA,
and went and met Dylan.
And then I look over
and I'm like--
Alex is getting in.
He's like, hey, what's up?
What's up?
I was like, hey man.
What are you doing?
But they didn't really
say hi to each other.
I go, what's going
on with that?
And they have a nightlife
beef or something.
We'll see who gets the
girls tonight.
Usually, it's Dylan.
But it's real funny.
I think that girls probably
think little
Alex is better looking.
Dylan's more like a woman.
Not like a woman, but
he's very pretty.
And I guess little
Alex is more--
I don't know.
He's like his dad.
Except for his dad gets
more ass than him.
But little Alex, though, doesn't
really say that much
because he's kind of shy.
And I think that girls are
intimidated by him.
So they won't go up to him.
And meanwhile, he won't
go up to them.
Oddly enough, he ends up going
home probably alone.