A really fun thing to do
is watch them run.
This is the family farm
in Massachusetts.
Been here for about 20 years.
These goats, they're
three brothers.
They're Nigerian pygmy goats.
They are African.
They're used to really hot
climates, so they do really
well in the summertime.
Right now, at about six, seven
months, their guts, their
stomachs get a little rounder
on the sides.
But for the most part,
they stay that size.
So this is Morning, this is
Noon, and this is Night.
Night is sort of the ringleader
of the gang here.
They have back teeth, and most
of the time they just kind of
grab the food with their lips,
so you don't really ever get
bit unless you really stick
your finger in there.
And they're very, very gentle.
They're bred off dairy goats,
but these guys don't produce
milk or anything.
They're completely just
for show and for fun.
We have blueberry bushes,
raspberry
bushes, and this grapevine.
They really like these leaves.
They're very bitter.
They don't eat the grapes, it's
too sour for them, but
the leaves are bitter enough.
And they like the texture.
They also like, too, if you rake
up in the fall a lot of
dead leaves and put
them in bags.
They like crunchy.
They like the texture.
He's sneezing.
[GOAT SNEEZES]
Cy usually follows these guys
around and kind of herds them
a little bit.
But as he is right behind them,
they drop out their
little pachinko chips out of
their butts, he definitely
will eat them.
We have about 30 chickens.
We've got our dog.
We have a big fish pond where
we do koi and catfish.
We've got a big rooster,
and about 25 hens.
So we've got about--
looking at 18 eggs every
30 hours or so.
What's really cool about living
in a farming community
is that you can barter and
trade, and sort of connect
with your community by
giving your eggs
away and trading them.
[GOAT BRAYING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]