Museum and was briefly,
hilariously, and
catastrophically, the
creative director of
the Millennium Dome.
What's deplorable about the
Olympic merchandise, it
assumes a very low level of
intelligence amongst the public.
How is the person who consumes
this bit of tat going to be
changed or enhanced by
possession of it?
It's ugly, it's cynical,
and it's stupid.
Several design principles
have been violated here.
This is an ugly travesty.
Mindless, stupid, cynical,
patronizing, exploitative,
manipulative, ugly,
and useless.
We want to revive our industry
and revive the credibility of
our great nation by putting
something like this for sale?
I mean what purpose is
this meant to serve?
It's not a clever photograph,
and it shows this sort of
laborious conceit of the
London Eye as a target.
Given the ever-present threat
of terrorist activity, that
seems to me to be an unfortunate
lapse of taste.
But I think al-Qaeda
is probably too--
I think their aesthetics are
too advanced to take much
interest in this
sort of thing.
Appalling.
[OLD-TIMEY MUSIC PLAYING]