LUCY: Hi, I'm Lucy.
This is Misty Meadow
Farm in Kent.
Let me show you our ponies.
This is Olivia.
She's nine years old.
She's my best friend really.
She's really sweet.
But she's very quiet.
Olivia's favorite food
is probably things
like carrots, apples.
But she is actually on
a restricted diet.
She has a mask that she
wears when she goes
out during the day.
Because she'll just pig.
INTERVIEWER: Why do you
like Shetland ponies?
LUCY: Their size.
They're very cute, and they're
very friendly.
Ah, she's with the dog.
Shetlands tend to be a very
piggy breed of pony.
And we do things like jumping
with her to help her basically
keep the weight off.
Good girl.
This is Olivia's passport.
All ponies basically have to
have a passport which will
record any injections that
they've ever had.
And also it will show their
family tree, so that when you
buy them you know where they've
come from, what their
background is.
Olivia's father is called
Toy House Mousie
Prince John of Lancaster.
And her mother is called
Copperfield's Betty Boop.
She's friends with a lot
of ponies in her field.
She probably has a special mate
that she hangs out with.
They tend to, like, have
a best friend each.
This here is Julianne.
She's pretty much, I would say,
one of the naughtiest
ones that we've got here.
And she's actually
wearing a muzzle.
Because she's got a lot of
weight on her at the moment.
And the best way to keep it
off is to have this muzzle
thing on her.
But it's actually the first
day she's worn it.
And she hates it.
We've had a bit of an issue with
the fencing over there
which we've sort of
had to put up a
makeshift sort of barricade.
Well basically we turned up one
day and found that Olivia
and Julianne had got in there.
And they were scrumping away
on all the apples.
Some Shetland ponies
actually don't care
about electric fencing.
And they are happy to take the
shock, basically, just to get
to the grass that's on the
other side of the fence.
So the darker colored
pony that's closest
to us at the moment--
she's called Tia.
And her little foal
is called Morgan.
He's a boy.
He's only a week old.
And then the other one over
there-- she's called Holly.
That's her daughter, who
was also born last
week, called Hannah.
Yeah, they're so fluffy
at this age--
fluffy and tiny.
INTERVIEWER: Would you
say that you're quite
good friends now?
LUCY: Yeah, yeah, she is.
She's my little girl.
She's my little pony.
I love her.