DITULLIO: HELLO AND WELCOME TO
RIT SPORTSZONE. I'M JOHN
DITULLIO. HILL: AND I'M SHELBY
HILL. DITULLIO: NOW BRICK CITY
HOMECOMING AND FAMILY WEEKEND IS
ANNUALLY ONE OF THE BIGGEST
EVENTS AT RIT, BUT FOR HOCKEY
FANS, THIS YEAR'S EDITION MAY BE
TOUGH TO TOP. HILL: ONE OF THE
MAIN HIGHLIGHTS AGAIN THIS FALL
BROUGHT A SELLOUT CROWD OF OVER
10,000 DOWNTOWN TO THE BLUE
CROSS ARENA. DITULLIO: IT WAS A
SEA OF ORANGE AS WAYNE WILSON
AND THE RIT MEN'S HOCKEY
WELCOMED ST. LAWRENCE TO TOWN.
THIRD PERIOD, SAINTS UP ONE AND
ON THE POWER PLAY PATRICK
DOHERTY SCORES TOP SHELF, HIS
SECOND GOAL IN LESS THAN TWO
MINUTES AND PUT THE SAINTS IN
CONTROL 5 TO 3. ST. LAWRENCE
WENT THREE FOR FIVE ON THE MAN
ADVANTAGE. BUT RIT WOULDN'T
QUITE. BRYAN POTTS SCORES HIS
SECOND GOAL OF THE NIGHT IN THE
POWER PLAY TO BRING RIT TO
WITHIN ONE. UNDER THIRTEEN TO
PLAY IN REGULATION, CAMERON BURT
FIRES ONE IN, ADAM HARTLEY PUTS
IN THE REBOUND WITH JUST NINE
SECONDS REMAINING TO TIE THE
GAME AND FORCED OVERTIME. IN THE
EXTRA SESSION ST. LAWRENCE TURNS
IT OVER AND ADAM MITCHELL SNEAKS
ONE BY MATT WENINGER, JUST 14
SECONDS INTO OVERTIME AS RIT
PULLS OFF A STUNNING 6, 5
VICTORY FOR THE FIRST WIN OF THE
SEASON. HILL: RIT RALLIED FROM A
5, 3 DEFICIENT IN DRAMATIC
FASHION. SCORING WITH JUST NINE
SECONDS LEFT IN THE THIRD PERIOD
AND ONLY 14 SECONDS INTO
OVERTIME, THE TIGERS SEALED THE
DEAL AT A SOLD OUT BRICK CITY
GAME. BATTAGLIA: HERE'S THE
TIGERS IN FRONT, MITCHELL! OH!
AND MITCHELL'S WON IT IN
OVERTIME! HILL: WHAT WAS IT LIKE
WITH NINE SECONDS LEFT AND US
GETTING THE GOAL; HOW DID THAT
FEEL? MITCHELL: OH,
UNBELIEVABLE! THE ADRENALIN RUSH
WAS JUST GOING THROUGH ME,
ESPECIALLY SINCE MY BUDDY HARTS
GET IT, YOU KNOW, JUST OVER THE
MOON! ONE OF THE BEST GAMES I'VE
EVER BEEN A PART OF. HILL:
COMING FROM THE EMOTIONS IN THE
THIRD PERIOD AND BEING UP AND
DOWN, WHAT WAS IT LIKE SCORING
SO QUICKLY IN OVERTIME TO GET
THE VICTORY? MITCHELL: I WAS
STILL HIGH ON THE OTHER GOAL,
YOU KNOW? IT WAS UNBELIEVABLE
HOW QUICKLY WE GOT IT DONE AND
THERE WAS NO DOUBT IN OUR MINDS
WE WERE GOING TO WIN THE HOCKEY
GAME. WILSON: ONCE WE SCORED THE
GOAL AND THEN WE HAD THE LITTLE
BREAK GOING INTO OVERTIME THE
ONE THING WE TALKED ABOUT WAS
THE PLACE IS GOING NUTS, LET'S
USE THIS MOMENTUM AND TRY AND
JUMP ON THEM RIGHT AWAY AND WITH
ONLY FIVE MINUTES OF HOCKEY LEFT
WE WANT TO GET AFTER IT RIGHT
AWAY AND THEY MUST HAVE TAKEN
THOSE WORDS TO HEART BECAUSE THE
FIRST SHIFT WE GET THE WIN. WE
WERE HOPING FOR THAT BECAUSE WE
KNEW THEY WERE GOING TO BE A
LITTLE BIT DOWN GIVING UP A LATE
GOAL AND LIKE I SAID, WITH THE
CROWD, WE WANTED TO JUMP ON THEM
AND WE DID AND IT WAS GREAT.
MITCHELL: I'VE ONLY BEEN HERE
TWO YEARS, BUT TYING LAST YEAR
WAS JUST A TERRIBLE FEELING AND
BEING ABLE TO SCORE THAT GOAL IN
OVERTIME WAS JUST UNBELIEVABLE.
HILL: WHAT HAPPENED TO GET THAT
WINNING GOAL? MITCHELL: I THINK
WE LOST THE FACE OFF AND THE
PUCK WENT UP IN THE AIR AND BURT
ENDED UP WITH IT ON HIS STICK
AND JUST KIND OF MADE A CHIP
PASS TO MCGOWAN, WHO THEN
CHIPPED IT OVER TO ME AND I KIND
OF BOBBLED IT BUT I ENDED UP
SCORING THE GOAL AND THE CROWD
KIND OF WENT NUTS AND IT WAS
JUST AN AMAZING FEELING.
DITULLIO: THERE IT IS; CAREY
COULDN'T CLEAR THE PUCK, BURT
KEEPS IT IN, JUST THROWS IT ON
NET, WHICH HE SHOULD DO, AND
HARTLEY SPINNING AROUND, FINALLY
LOCATES IT. HILL: THAT THIRD
PERIOD GOAL THAT YOU SCORED,
WHAT HAPPENED THERE? HARTLEY:
COACH JUST SAID GO TO THE NET
AND HOPE FOR THE BEST AND I'VE
GOT TO GIVE BURT CREDIT, HE
WORKED HARD, GOT TO THE PUCK,
HELD IT IN AND THREW IT ON NET
AND IT WAS JUST THERE WAITING
FOR ME. HILL: WHAT WAS IT LIKE
GETTING TWO GOALS TONIGHT, FIVE
POINTS, HOW DO YOU THINK THAT
AFFECTED THE TEAM? POTTS: I HOPE
IT ENERGIZED THE TEAM, I WAS
JUST DOING WHAT I HAD TO DO AND
WHAT I COULD DO TO HELP THE TEAM
WIN AND I WAS CONTRIBUTING ON
THE SCORE SHEET TODAY AND IT
FELT GOOD TO FINALLY GET SOME
POINTS ON THE BOARD. WILSON:
CAMERON HAD A VERY GOOD; HE'S
OFF TO A GREAT START THIS YEAR.
HE WANTS TO MAKE THE MOST OF
THIS YEAR, HE WANTS IT TO BE HIS
BEST SEASON AND HE'S OFF TO A
GOOD START. WE'VE GOT A LOT OF
HOCKEY STILL IN FRONT OF US, BUT
IF CAM BURT'S PLAYING VERY WELL
FOR US, THEN IT'S GOING TO BE A
GOOD YEAR FOR US. HILL: WHAT'S
IT FEEL LIKE TO FINALLY WIN HERE
AT BLUE CROSS THE FIRST TIME
EVER? NEW SPEAKER: I WISH I
COULD DESCRIBE IT, BUT THERE
REALLY ARE NO WORDS. YOU SEE ALL
THE SUPPORT THE SCHOOL COMES OUT
WITH AND YOU KNOW, IT'S REALLY
AMAZING. I'M REALLY HAPPY I
PICKED RIT, I CAN TELL YOU THAT
MUCH, JUST BY THE TURNOUT
TONIGHT. NEW SPEAKER: JUST A
WAVE OF EMOTIONS. PERSONALLY, AN
UP AND DOWN GAME, AS A TEAM I
THINK THIS WAS A GOOD ONE TO WIN
FOR US AND HOPEFULLY COME
PLAYOFF TIME, KNOWING THAT WE
WON IN BLUE CROSS WE CAN HAVE A
LITTLE MORE CONFIDENCE WHEN WE
COME IN HERE. NEW SPEAKER: THE
CROWD REALLY HELPS US OUT, PUMPS
US UP, WHEN WE SCORED THAT GOAL
WITH NINE SECONDS LEFT TO TIE IT
UP, IT JUST GETS US ALL JACKED
UP WHEN THE CROWD GOES WILD. NEW
SPEAKER: IT'S JUST GREAT, JUST
GETTING THE SUPPORT FROM THE
FANS AND THE COMMUNITY AND THE
ALUMNI AND YOU KNOW, IT REALLY
FEEDS US AS A TEAM. WHEN WE'RE
DOWN FIVE THREE AND WE HEAR THEM
CHANTING IN THE BACKGROUND IT
REALLY MOTIVATES US TO GO OUT
THERE AND GIVE IT ALL AND TRY TO
COME BACK AND GET THE WIN. YOU
KNOW, IT'S HOMECOMING HERE AT
RIT, PUTTING THE SWEATER ON WAS
GREAT TO HAVE ONE UNDER OUR
BELT. IT'S GOING TO BE MY LAST
ONE SO I DIDN'T WANT TO LEAVE
WITH A LOSS AND SEEING ALL THE
ALUMNI AND EVERYBODY GOING CRAZY
AND SEE ALL THE OLDER HOCKEY
PLAYERS THAT PLAYED BEFORE JUST
LOSING IT BEHIND THE GLASS, IT
WAS A GREAT TIME AND I KNOW
THOSE GUYS WERE PROUD OF US AND
WE COULDN'T BE HERE WITHOUT THEM
AND THE WORK THEY PUT INTO IT.
WILSON: IT'S OBVIOUSLY A GREAT
FEELING. LAST YEAR WE TIED THE
GAME; THEY TIED US UP WITH I
THINK A SECOND LEFT AND WE ENDED
UP TYING THE GAME BUT IT DID
FEEL LIKE A LOSS AND WE
REMEMBERED THAT AND I THINK THE
THING THAT STANDS OUT ABOUT THIS
GAME WAS MENTALLY I THOUGHT WE
SHOWED SOME REAL STRONG
STRENGTH. WE GAVE UP A
SHORTHANDED GOAL AND REBOUNDED
FROM THAT AND SCORED OBVIOUSLY A
BIG GOAL TO TIE IT UP AND THEN
GETTING THE WIN GOAL. SO I
THOUGHT EXECUTION WISE WE HAVE
THINGS TO WORK ON, BUT I WAS
VERY HAPPY WHERE WE WERE; I
THOUGHT WE WERE VERY STRONG
MENTALLY TO GET THROUGH SOME
ADVERSITY AND HOPEFULLY THAT
WILL HELP US OUT IN SOME OTHER
SITUATIONS DOWN THE ROAD. HILL:
IT WAS A GAME THAT WILL NO DOUBT
GO DOWN AS ONE OF THE GREATEST
IN RIT HISTORY. IF YOU'D LIKE TO
RELIVE SOME OF THE UNFORGETTABLE
MOMENTS, YOU CAN RIGHT NOW IN
OUR HOCKEY CENTRAL SECTION OF
OUR WEBSITE AT RITSZ.COM.
DITULLIO: NOW STILL TO COME ON
SPORTSZONE, WITH SELLOUTS
BECOMING THE NORM FOR THE MEN'S
HOCKEY TEAM, HOW CLOSE ARE WE TO
SEEING A NEW ARENA ON CAMPUS?
WE'LL HAVE THE LATEST ON RIT'S
CAMPAIGN TO BUILD A NEW HOME FOR
HOCKEY NEXT. YOU'RE WATCHING RIT
SPORTSZONE IN HIGH DEFINITION.
DITULLIO: WELCOME BACK TO
SPORTSZONE. NOW EARLIER THIS
MONTH A MAJOR FACELIFT WAS
COMPLETED AT RITTER ARENA AND
WHILE THE PROJECT DIDN'T ADD ANY
ADDITIONAL SEATING, IT CERTAINLY
PROVIDED SOME MUCH NEEDED
AMENITIES FOR CURRENT AND FUTURE
TIGERS. SZ'S COURTNEY TENANT HAS
THE STORY. TENANT: RITTER ARENA
HAS FINALLY EXPANDED. NOT FOR
THE FANS, BUT FOR THE PLAYERS.
THE THREE AND A HALF MILLION
DOLLAR LOCKER ROOM FACILITIES
WILL NOW BE HOME TO BOTH THE
MEN'S AND WOMEN'S HOCKEY
PROGRAMS. WHAT DOES THE TEAM
THINK OF THE NEW FACILITIES?
WILSON: WELL WE JUST MOVED IN
YESTERDAY, SO THEY'RE PRETTY
EXCITED. WE HAD A GOOD PRACTICE.
I WAS WONDERING IF THEY WERE
GOING TO BE GETTING CARRIED AWAY
BUT I THINK THEY'RE VERY
APPRECIATIVE OF THE FACILITY
THAT WE HAVE. FROM MY
STANDPOINT, IT'S A LOT OF HARD
WORK ON EVERYONE THAT'S PLAYED
BEFORE THEM. NEW SPEAKER: IT'S
KIND OF A TESTAMENT TO THE LAST
COUPLE OF YEARS AND HOW WELL RIT
HOCKEY'S DONE AND I THINK THAT
YOU KNOW, IT'S A BIG STEP
FORWARD. I THINK THAT THE
ORGANIZATION AND THE SCHOOL IS
GOING IN THE RIGHT DIRECTION IN
REGARDS TO ATHLETICS AND I THINK
THAT IT SHOWS THEIR COMMITMENT
TO US AND OUR COMMITMENT TO
THEM. TENANT: SO WHAT DOES THIS
LOCKER ROOM MEAN FOR RECRUITING
PURPOSES? NEW SPEAKER: IT'S
GOING TO GO A LONG WAY. OUR
PROGRAM HAS GROWN SO MUCH, EVEN
IN THE THREE YEARS THAT I'VE
BEEN HERE. GOING INTO MY FOURTH
YEAR, WE WERE HOPING TO GET
SOMETHING LIKE THIS AND THIS
KIND OF EXCEEDS ALL OF OUR
EXPECTATIONS. COMING INTO A
LOCKER ROOM AS A RECRUIT AND
SEEING SOMETHING LIKE THIS, IT'S
A GREAT SELLING POINT. I MEAN I
WOULD BE HARD PRESSED TO FIND
ANOTHER COLLEGE TEAM WITH A
LOCKER ROOM AS NICE AS THIS.
WILSON: THE SPACE THAT'S BEEN
GIVEN TO US FROM OUR
ADMINISTRATION IS OUTSTANDING,
AND IT REALLY IS VERY, VERY
IMPRESSIVE AND I THINK THAT IT
WILL SHOW VERY WELL TO RECRUITS
AS WE BRING THEM IN FOR VISITS.
NEW SPEAKER: THEY TOLD ME WHEN I
WAS RECRUITED THAT IT WOULD BE
READY FOR MY FRESHMAN YEAR,
WHICH THEY DELIVERED SO IT'S
PRETTY EXCITING. TENANT: IS IT
EVERYTHING THAT THEY TOLD YOU IT
WOULD BE? NEW SPEAKER:
EVERYTHING AND MORE, DEFINITELY.
IT'S REALLY NICE. TENANT: WHAT
DOES THE LOCKER ROOM MEAN FOR
BONDING FOR YOU AND YOUR TEAM?
NEW SPEAKER: IT'S DEFINITELY
BIGGER. THE LAST ONE WAS SMALLER
SO WE WERE ABLE TO INTERACT WITH
EACH OTHER EASILY, BUT I THINK
OUR LOCKER ROOM EVERYONE HEARS
US SAYING, 'I CAN'T WAIT TO GO
BACK TO THE DRESSING ROOM! I
JUST WANT TO HANG OUT THERE!'
AND STUFF LIKE THAT, SO IT'S
GOING TO BE GOOD FOR US. WILSON:
WE'VE GOT TO BE A LITTLE BIT
CAREFUL THAT OUR TEAM ISN'T
SPLINTERED SO IF THERE'S FIVE
GUYS IN OUR ROOM, THREE IN THE
TRAINING ROOM, TWO IN THE VIDEO
ROOM AND SO ON, THAT'S ONE THING
I DID LIKE ABOUT OUR OLD ROOM
WAS SMALL AND COZY, WE'LL SAY,
AS IT WAS, IT WAS GREAT FOR I
THINK CHEMISTRY OF THE TEAM,
GETTING TO KNOW THE OTHER GUYS
ON YOUR TEAM VERY WELL BECAUSE
THERE WAS NOWHERE ELSE TO GO. I
THINK WE'LL LOSE A LITTLE BIT OF
THAT, BUT WE'VE TRIED TO MAKE
THIS OUR FOCAL POINT, OUR MAIN
LOCKER ROOM AND KEEP AS MANY
GUYS IN HERE VERSUS SCATTERED IN
ALL THE OTHER FACILITIES. NEW
SPEAKER: I THINK IT DEFINITELY
BOOSTS TEAM MORALE. I THINK EVEN
TODAY, WE MOVED IN LAST NIGHT,
AND TODAY WE HAD A GREAT
PRACTICE, EVERYBODY WAS, YOU
KNOW, THE NEW SOUND SYSTEM AND
PUTTING ON NEW MUSIC AND JUST
KIND OF THE CAMARADERIE THAT
HAPPENS WITH THE GUYS AROUND THE
DRESSING ROOM. I THINK IT'S
DEFINITELY SOMETHING THAT WE'RE
PROUD OF AND SOMETHING THAT
FEELS LIKE HOME. NEW SPEAKER:
JUST THE WAY OUR PROGRAM'S GROWN
OVER THE LAST FEW YEARS AND JUST
ALL THE GUYS WHO HAVE PUT SO
MUCH WORK IN, EVEN BEFORE US, TO
HELP BUILD SOMETHING LIKE THIS,
IT'S JUST GOING TO BRING OUR
TEAM CLOSER TOGETHER AND IT JUST
GIVES US ANOTHER THING TO MAKE
RIT HOCKEY EVEN MORE OF A PROUD
TRADITION. HILL: MEANWHILE, IT'S
BEEN ALMOST A YEAR SINCE RIT
ALUMNUS STEVE SCHULTZ DONATED
ONE MILLION DOLLARS TO THE
SCHOOL, OFFICIALLY KICKING OFF
RIT'S CAMPAIGN TO BUILD A NEW
ICE ARENA. SO HOW MUCH PROGRESS
HAS BEEN MADE AND WHEN MIGHT WE
SEE A NEW FACILITY ON CAMPUS? WE
SENT SPORTSZONE'S JOHN DITULLIO
TO FIND OUT. DESTLER: AND STEVE
AND VICKY HAVE PLEDGED ONE
MILLION DOLLARS, THE FIRST
MILLION TOWARDS OUR FIFTEEN
MILLION DOLLAR CAMPAIGN AND I
FOR ONE COULD NOT BE MORE
GRATEFUL (APPLAUSE). DITULLIO:
OK, DOCTOR, IT'S ALMOST BEEN
ABOUT A YEAR SINCE THE
ANNOUNCEMENT FOR A NEW ARENA.
NOW LET'S FAST FORWARD TO TODAY.
WHERE DO WE STAND IN TERMS OF
WHEN DO YOU THINK GROUND CAN BE
BROKEN AND LET'S UPDATE
EVERYBODY ON THE FUNDS AND HOW
CLOSE ARE WE. WATTERS: OUR
PRESIDENT HAS WORKED VERY HARD,
HE HAS SOME VERY, VERY
INTERESTED FOLKS WHO ARE DOING
SOME VERY SERIOUS DELIBERATION
ON A NAMING OPPORTUNITY. WE ARE
VERY HOPEFUL THAT WITHIN A NEAR
TERM WE MIGHT SEE A CULTIVATION
OF THOSE INDIVIDUALS TO THE
POINT WHERE THERE'S AN
ANNOUNCEMENT. HE'S VERY HOPEFUL
THAT SOME OF THESE INDIVIDUALS
REALLY UNDERSTAND THE COMPELLING
CASE THAT WE HAVE, THE TRUE NEED
THAT WE HAVE, SO I CAN'T SAY
ENOUGH ABOUT HOW HARD HE HAS
WORKED TO REALLY MAKE THIS DREAM
COME TRUE. DITULLIO: I KNOW
YOU'VE BEEN AROUND THE COUNTRY
LOOKING AT OTHER FACILITIES.
TALK ABOUT SOME OF THE
AMENITIES, MAYBE WHAT YOU TOOK
AWAY FROM SOME OF THOSE VISITS.
WATTERS: PITTSBURGH DID A
TERRIFIC JOB WITH THE CONSOL
ENERGY ARENA OF BRINGING IN THE
HISTORY OF PITTSBURGH INTO THAT
FACILITY. THEY DID A NUMBER OF
GREAT THINGS THERE. A NUMBER OF
THE CANADIAN CITIES, WHEN THEY
BUILT THEIR ARENAS, THEY BROUGHT
IN THE HISTORY AND LEGACY OF
THEIR PROGRAMS AND SO WE'VE
LEARNED FROM THOSE TRIPS. WE
WILL BRING IN, ELEMENTS FROM
RITTER AND FROM THE ROCHESTER
COMMUNITY INTO IT SO THAT OUR
DEVOTED FANS AND OUR LOYAL FANS
FROM HERE IN ROCHESTER CAN
REALLY FEEL AN AFFINITY WHEN
THEY WALK IN AND IT WILL MAKE
THEM FEEL AT HOME. ONE OF THE
THINGS THAT WE'RE STILL LOOKING
AT IS HOW MUCH OF AN ACTIVITY
CENTER IS IT AS OPPOSED TO HOW
MUCH OF A HOCKEY ARENA IS IT? IF
YOU MOVE TOWARDS A LITTLE BIT
MORE OF AN ACTIVITY CENTER, IT
HAS DEFINITE IMPLICATIONS FOR
THE GRID SYSTEMS OF THE
BUILDING, WHERE YOU SET UP
SUITES SO THAT THEY'RE NOT
BLOCKED OFF. IF YOU PUT IN
CURTAINS FOR PERFORMANCES AND
CONCERTS, SO WE'RE STILL
THINKING THROUGH HOW MUCH OF IT
WILL BE ACTIVITIES BASED VERSUS
PURE HOCKEY, AND IT WILL BE
DESIGNED TO DELIVER EXACTLY WHAT
WE'RE LOOKING FOR. DITULLIO:
WHEN PEOPLE SAY, YOU KNOW, YOU
JUST UPDATED RITTER; WHY BUILD?
WHAT DO YOU TELL THEM? WATTERS:
IT'S LIKELY THAT RITTER WILL
STILL BE VERY ACTIVE AND IT WILL
SERVE THAT FUNCTION THAT SHOULD
THE NEW FACILITY BE USED FOR AN
ACTIVITY, RITTER WILL BE OUR GO
TO PLACE. DITULLIO: WHEN YOU
LOOK AT CAPACITY, ARE WE LOOKING
FOUR, FOUR TO SIX IN TERMS OF
THE SIZE OF THE ARENA? WATTERS:
YES, RIGHT NOW WE HAVE BEEN
TALKING IN THAT FOUR TO FIVE
RANGE AND OUR PRESIDENT YOU
KNOW, IS STILL CONSIDERING
OPTIONS, BUT I THINK THAT AT
THIS POINT HE'S COMFORTABLE IN
HAVING US PURSUE A PROGRAM THAT
WOULD BE IN THAT FOUR TO FIVE
RANGE. DITULLIO: WHERE DO YOU
FORESEE THE NEW ARENA BEING
BUILT? WATTERS: IT LOOKS RIGHT
NOW THAT THE PORTION OF THE
CAMPUS THAT IS IMMEDIATELY SOUTH
OF GLOBAL VILLAGE, HAS RISEN TO
THE TOP OF THE LIST. THERE'S A
LOT OF GREAT THINGS ABOUT IT.
ONE, IT DISBURSES PEOPLE AWAY
FROM THE FIELD HOUSE AND THE
EXISTING ARENA, SO IF WE HAVE
DUAL EVENTS ON CAMPUS WE WOULD
HAVE TRAFFIC AND A LOT OF PEOPLE
MOVE TO A DIFFERENT ELEMENT OF
THE CAMPUS. DITULLIO: SHOVEL IN
THE GROUND IN 2012, DO YOU
THINK? IS THAT A POSSIBILITY?
WATERS: YOU KNOW, IT IS A
POSSIBILITY. WE'RE PROBABLY SIX
TO SEVEN MONTHS OF A DESIGN
PERIOD ONCE WE GET THE GREEN
LIGHT TO GO, SO IF WE WERE TO
SEE THOSE ANNOUNCEMENTS IN THE
NEXT TWO MONTHS, IT'S VERY
LIKELY WE COULD ACTUALLY BE IN
THE GROUND TOWARDS THE LAST PART
HILL: THE RIT WOMEN'S HOCKEY
TEAM NOT ONLY REACHED THE
DIVISION THREE NATIONAL
CHAMPIONSHIP GAME LAST MARCH,
BUT THEY EARNED THE OPPORTUNITY
TO HOST THE GAME ON HOME ICE.
DITULLIO: BUT THE PERFECT
SCENARIO TURNED OUT TO BE THE
PERFECT STORM AS NORWICH STUNG
THE TIGERS AND LEFT TOWN WITH
THE TITLE. EMILY CLARK SAT DOWN
WITH THIS YEAR'S TEAM AND
DISCOVERED THEY HAVE A MAJOR
CHIP ON THEIR SHOULDER. CLARK:
CAN YOU TELL ME A LITTLE BIT
ABOUT THE DISAPPOINTMENT OF LAST
SEASON AND HOW YOU'RE USING IT
AS MOTIVATION FOR THIS YEAR? NEW
SPEAKER: WELL DEFINITELY LAST
SEASON WAS A HUGE
DISAPPOINTMENT, NO ONE WANTED
OUR SEASON TO END LIKE THAT, BUT
WHAT CAN YOU DO? WE DID HAVE A
GOOD, LONG, STRONG YEAR AND SO
AS OF RIGHT NOW I THINK JUST
MOVING PAST THAT GAME, KIND OF
FORGETTING ABOUT IT AS WE DO
HAVE A NEW SEASON, A NEW TEAM,
BUT AT THE SAME TIME,
REMEMBERING HOW DISAPPOINTING
THAT GAME WAS AND HOW
HEARTBREAKING IT WAS. NEW
SPEAKER: IT'S JUST KIND OF
MOTIVATION TO COME OUT NOW WITH
A BANG, PLAY WITH A CHIP ON OUR
SHOULDER, AS WE KIND OF SAY. BUT
EVEN JUST USING THE EXPERIENCE
OF MAKING IT TO THE NATIONAL
CHAMPIONSHIP BECAUSE NOW LIKE
COACH SAYS, WE'VE SEEN IT ALL,
WE'VE BEEN ALL THE WAY SO NOW
IT'S JUST TAKING IT ONE STEP AT
A TIME DURING THE SEASON.
MCDONALD: WE SHOWED THE GIRLS
THE CHAMPIONSHIP VIDEO FROM LAST
YEAR. YOU SHOULDN'T FORGET THE
FEELING OF GOING SO FAR AND THEN
COMING UP THAT SHORT, BEING SO
CLOSE TO SOMETHING. DURING
WORKOUTS I'LL JUST MENTION THAT
WE DON'T WANT A SECOND PLACE
EFFORT ANYMORE; IT'S FIRST PLACE
OR NOTHING NOW. CLARK: COMING
INTO THE NEW SEASON, HOW DO YOU
FEEL YOUR NEW PLAYERS HAVE GROWN
AND DEVELOPED IN THE OFF SEASON?
MCDONALD: IT LOOKS LIKE THEY ALL
CAME BACK A LITTLE BIT MORE
MOTIVATED. NOT THAT THEY'RE NOT
MOTIVATED, BUT I THINK THE WAY
LAST YEAR ENDED IT KIND OF, IT'S
A LONG SUMMER TO BE THINKING
ABOUT THAT LAST GAME AND HOW IT
FINISHED. THEY LOOK IN SHAPE,
THEY LOOK QUICKER, THEY LOOK
STRONGER AND THEY SEEM MORE
MATURE RIGHT NOW. CLARK: HAVE
YOU SEEN ANYBODY STEPPING UP
INTO THE ROLES THAT WERE ONCE
HELD BY DAGG OR STACK AND HOW
HAVE YOU GUYS BEEN PRACTICING
WITHOUT THEM? MCDONALD: YOU
KNOW, I THINK THE THREE CAPTAINS
FOR SURE, THERE'S A REASON WHY
THREE JUNIORS ARE OUR CAPTAINS
NOW. THEY WERE STARTING TO STEP
INTO THOSE LEADERSHIP ROLES AT
THE END OF LAST YEAR AND IN
SPRING WORKOUTS THEY WERE THE
THREE THAT REALLY KIND OF TOOK
CHARGE OF EVERYTHING AND THOSE
THREE HAVE COMPLETELY EMERGED AS
THE TRUE LEADERS ON OUR TEAM
RIGHT NOW. NEW SPEAKER: I THINK
EVERYONE RETURNING IS KIND OF A
KEY PLAYER FOR US. WE DON'T
REALLY HAVE THE ONE STANDOUT
PLAYER NOW, THE ONE WHO SCORES
ALL THE GOALS OR GETS ALL THE
POINTS, SO IT'S KIND OF A
COMBINED EFFORT FROM EVERYONE ON
THE TEAM. I DON'T SEE OUR TEAM
HAVING ONE POWER FORWARD WHO'S
GOING TO PUT UP 30 GOALS LIKE
STACK COULD, BUT I DEFINITELY
THINK WE HAVE A LOT OF DIFFERENT
FORWARDS WHO CAN PUT THE PUCK IN
THE NET AND CAN PUT UP AN EQUAL
AMOUNT OF POINTS, IT'S GOING TO
TAKE JUST NOT ONE PERSON, IT'S
GOING TO BE DIFFERENT PEOPLE.
IT'S NICE TO SEE DIFFERENT
PEOPLE STEPPING UP AND STARTING
TO ADJUST INTO THEIR ROLES SO
WE'LL SEE HOW IT GOES. CLARK:
CAN YOU TELL ME A LITTLE BIT
ABOUT YOUR NEW FRESHMEN CLASS
AND WHAT YOU'RE HOPING EACH
PLAYER WILL CONTRIBUTE TO THE
TEAM? MCDONALD: IT'S AN EXCITING
BUNCH; THEY'RE ALL A LITTLE
DIFFERENT. THERE'S NO REAL ONE
PLAYER THAT'S THE SAME. TWO
FRESHMEN DEFENSEMEN HAVE COME
IN, THEY LOOK GREAT SO FAR, THEY
LOOK VERY POISED AND CALM AND
PLAYED AT A HIGH LEVEL LAST YEAR
AND THEN THE FOUR FORWARDS,
THERE'S SOME BIG KIDS, THERE'S
SOME SMALL ONES, TOUGH ONES AND
FAST ONES, SO I DON'T THINK, WE
GRADUATED A LOT OF SCORING, BUT
I THINK IF THOSE KIDS PLAY THE
WAY THEY CAN, I DON'T THINK
WE'LL MISS A BEAT. CLARK: WHAT
IS THE TEAM REALLY LOOKING HARD
TO REACH THIS SEASON? NEW
SPEAKER: AS OF RIGHT NOW, I
THINK JUST PREPARING FOR THIS
UPCOMING SEASON AND NOT DWELLING
ON LAST SEASON. I THINK WE
SHOULD TAKE THE SEASON ONE GAME
AT A TIME AND PLAY AS A TEAM,
PLAY TO OUR FULL POTENTIAL AND
JUST SEE WHERE THAT GETS US. WE
DO HAVE SEVEN NEW FRESHMEN, NEW
PEOPLE, NEW SKILLS, SO JUST KIND
OF WAIT IT OUT AND WORK HARD AND
LOOK FORWARD TO THE NEW SEASON.
AND AUTO. DITULLIO: RIT'S RUGBY
TEAM FIRST TOOK THE FIELD BACK
IN 1978. THE CLUB SPORT HAD A
LONG RUNNING TRADITION UNTIL AN
OFF CAMPUS INCIDENT LED TO THE
TEAM BEING BANNED FROM
COMPETITION FROM THE SCHOOL IN
2007. HILL: IT'S BEEN A LONG AND
DIFFICULT ROAD, BUT AS OLIVIA
ANGEROSA DISCOVERED, AFTER FIVE
YEARS THE RIT RUGBY PROGRAM IS
BACK WITH A BRAND NEW ATTITUDE
AND A CLEAN SLATE. ANGEROSA:
AFTER A HAZING INCIDENT THAT
BANNED THEM FROM THE GAME IN
2007, THE RIT RUGBY TEAM IS
GIVEN A CHANCE TO PLAY AGAIN.
HOWEVER, THESE TIGERS MAY HAVE
TO BOUNCE BACK FROM A BAD REP IN
ORDER TO GAIN THE SUPPORT THEY
ONCE HAD. HOW WERE YOU GUYS
FINALLY ABLE TO GET THE RUGBY
TEAM BACK AT RIT? NEW SPEAKER:
IN REALITY, IT'S ALL THANKS TO A
GUY NAMED JOEL WHITWORD. HE
ACTUALLY ALREADY GRADUATED, BUT
HE FOUNDED RIT RUGBY HERE. HE
WAS ABLE TO TALK TO THE PEOPLE
HE NEEDED TO, INCLUDING THE
COLLEGE ACTIVITY BOARD AND THE
CLUB SPORT AND GET US BACK ON,
ACTUALLY A YEAR BEFORE WE WERE
SUPPOSED TO. NEW SPEAKER: IT
ACTUALLY TOOK A LOT OF HARD
WORK, BUT AFTER HASSLING THE
SCHOOL FOR A WHILE AND GETTING
ENOUGH INTEREST BETWEEN ALL THE
DIFFERENT STUDENTS, WE WERE
FINALLY ABLE TO GET ALL THE
PAPERWORK THROUGH AND GET
APPROVED AND THEN WE GOT INTO
THE LEAGUE AFTER A YEAR AND THEN
NOW WE'RE FOUR AND 0. ANGEROSA:
AND HOW'S THE TEAM WORKING TO
GET GOOD STANDING BACK? NEW
SPEAKER: WELL, WE'VE CHANGED OUR
COLORS, WE'VE CHANGED OUR NAME,
THE ENTIRE TEAM IS DIFFERENT,
THE COACH IS DIFFERENT, THERE'S
ABSOLUTELY NOTHING BETWEEN US
AND THAT TEAM. WE'VE KEPT IN
TOUCH WITH THE OLD ALUMNI, BUT
AT THE SAME TIME WE'VE MADE SURE
TO DISTANCE OURSELVES FROM THAT
ACTUAL EVENT THAT HAPPENED THAT
GAVE US SUCH A BAD REPUTATION IN
THE FIRST PLACE. NEW SPEAKER: WE
MAKE SURE THAT THESE GUYS ARE
MAKING HIGH ACADEMIC STANDARDS
FOR THEMSELVES. ONE OF THE
THINGS TOO IS THE FACT THAT WHEN
WE GO AND PLAY OTHER TEAMS, WE
DON'T ALLOW DIRTY PLAY AND WE
MAKE A REAL STRONG POINT TO TALK
TO THE REF BEFOREHAND AND LET
HIM KNOW THAT IF ANY OF OUR
PLAYERS ARE PLAYING DIRTY,
THEY'RE GETTING KICKED OFF THE
CLUB. ANGEROSA: AND DO YOU FEEL
LIKE YOU GUYS ARE STILL UNDER
CLOSE WATCH? NEW SPEAKER: YEAH,
WE'RE DEFINITELY GETTING WATCHED
PRETTY SCRUTINOUSLY, BUT WE'RE
MANAGING AND WE'RE ALSO MAKING
SURE WE DON'T DO ANYTHING THAT
MAKES IT SO WE NEED TO BE
WATCHED, BECAUSE THE LAST THING
WE WANT IS TO NOT BE ABLE TO
PLAY RUGBY JUST BECAUSE OF SOME
STUPID INCIDENT HAPPENING.
ANGEROSA: HOW DID YOU HANDLE NOT
HAVING A RUGBY TEAM AT RIT? NEW
SPEAKER: FOR, I WOULD SAY, THREE
YEARS, I WAS GOING TO THE MEN'S
CLUB AND PLAYING WITH THE
AARDVARKS, WHICH IS ONE OF TWO
MEN'S CLUBS IN ROCHESTER, THE
AARDVARKS AND THE COLONIALS, SO
MOST OF THE GUYS JUST WENT BACK
AND FORTH BETWEEN THOSE TWO
TEAMS AND WE WERE STILL ABLE TO
PLAY, BUT IT'S NOT THE SAME NOT
BEING ABLE TO PLAY FOR AND
SUPPORT YOUR OWN SCHOOL. NEW
SPEAKER: I DIDN'T GET INTO RUGBY
UNTIL I SAW THE FLYER THAT THE
FIRST PRESIDENT, JOEL WHITWORD,
HAD POSTED UP AFTER RESTARTING
THE TEAM AT RIT, SO I HAD NEVER
ACTUALLY EXPERIENCED THE
ORIGINAL RIT RUGBY, BUT COMING
INTO IT, IT WAS KIND OF A COOL,
FRESH FEELING BECAUSE WE GOT A
CHANCE TO ACTUALLY START
SOMETHING NEW. IT WAS COOL TO BE
A PART OF THAT TRADITION TOO.
NEW SPEAKER: MY FRESHMAN YEAR I
MET JOEL AND I STARTED PLAYING
WITH THE AARDVARKS MEN'S CLUB
NEARBY, SO THAT'S HOW I STARTED
GETTING INTO RUGBY AND NOW IT'S
A LOT OF FUN. IT WAS GREAT TO
GET INTO THE SPORT BEFORE
STARTING TO PLAY WITH RIT.
ANGEROSA: AND HOW DID YOU CHANGE
THE RUGBY CULTURE AT RIT? NEW
SPEAKER: THE MAIN THING
OBVIOUSLY IS FOCUSING ON RUGBY
INSTEAD OF FOCUSING ON THE
SOCIAL ASPECT OF RUGBY, BECAUSE
FOCUSING ON THAT ASPECT
OBVIOUSLY GOT US IN TROUBLE. SO
WE DEFINITELY CHANGED THAT AND
AS YOU CAN SEE, WE'RE FOCUSING
ON RUGBY AND WE'RE WINNING. NEW
SPEAKER: I'D SAY A DRASTIC
CHANGE. NOBODY EVEN KNEW ABOUT
RUGBY; HALF THE PEOPLE JUST
THOUGHT RUGBY WAS SOME SPORT
GUYS JUST BEAT ON EACH OTHER,
AND NOW WHEN THEY COME OUT AND
SEE IT, HOPEFULLY WE'LL HAVE
MORE AND MORE PEOPLE COME OUT,
BUT JUST KNOWLEDGE OF THE GAME,
I GUESS, SO THAT PEOPLE KNOW
THAT WE HAVE RUGBY AND BEFORE
THEY DIDN'T. ANGEROSA: DO YOU
STILL FEEL LIKE THE TEAM IS
GETTING ADEQUATE SUPPORT FROM
THE RIT COMMUNITY? NEW SPEAKER:
WITH OUR FIRST TWO HOME GAMES,
WE'VE DEFINITELY SEEN A LOT OF
PEOPLE COMING OUT, ESPECIALLY
THE LAST HOME GAME WHERE IT WAS
KIND OF CRAPPY WEATHER. GET THEM
OUT ON THE SIDELINES. NEW
SPEAKER: IT'S NICE JUST HAVING
PEOPLE KNOW, EVEN IF THEY DON'T
KNOW HOW TO PLAY THE SPORT O
RUGBY, THEY STILL COME OUT TO
WATCH THE GAME AND THEY SEEM TO
ENJOY IT. NEW SPEAKER: EVER
SINCE WE STARTED BACK UP, WE'RE
SLOWLY GETTING MORE AND MORE
SUPPORT. WE STARTED OFF WITH NO
FUNDS FROM THE SCHOOL LAST YEAR,
AND WE'VE ALREADY INCREASED THAT
FROM ZERO TO $1,400 AND WE HAVE
AN ACADEMIC ADVISOR, WE WERE
ACTUALLY GIVEN FOR FREE ONE OF
THE AUDITORIUMS TO USE FOR FREE
EVERY SINGLE FRIDAY. THE
COMMUNITY HAS BEEN VERY
SUPPORTIVE AND VERY HELPFUL AND
WITHOUT THEM I'M NOT SURE WE
WOULD HAVE BEEN ABLE TO GET THIS
FAR AS QUICKLY AS WE DID.
DITULLIO: WELL THAT DOES IT FOR
THIS EDITION OF RIT SPORTSZONE.
HILL: DON'T FORGET YOU CAN STAY
UP TO DATE WITH SPORTSZONE BY
FOLLOWING US ON TWITTER AND
LIKING US ON FACEBOOK. DITULLIO:
SO UNTIL NEXT TIME, THANKS FOR
JOINING US IN THE ZONE.