[SOUND OF CLOCK TICKING]
JON KESSLER: I had a friend in
undergrad who grew up on North
7th Street.
He was Polish-American.
I was in the East Village
for six months in a
tiny, crappy apartment.
He just said, you should really
check out the first
stop on the L train.
And I'd never been
out here before.
And came out, drew a circle on
the map around the Bedford
Avenue stop.
And that day, I found about
six or seven places.
And I moved into this building
where I paid $150 a month for
the whole building, and
I got a 10-year lease.
MALE SPEAKER: What
year was that?
JON KESSLER: That was 1980.
I had that moment in my life
which I'd wanted, which was
the older generation had had
it in Tribeca and in Soho,
where you just go to a factory
building, and the landlord
just could not imagine that
you'd want to live in an
abandoned factory.
And this neighborhood was
so desolate at night.
And he was just happy
to have someone
looking over his factory.
It really seemed far
away back then.
I mean, I would tell people
I was going to Manhattan.
They'd say, you going
to the city?
This is only 27 years
ago, but it really
was a different mindset.
This is a photograph--
which I didn't take, it actually
was given to me-- of
a flower arrangement from Japan
of quite a well-known
arranger, Sofu Teshigahara.
And this will be motorized
and mechanized.
And so the motor here will be
moving these panels slowly, so
it actually deconstructs and
looks like that a lot.
But these are constantly
shifting.
And there is one moment
when it registers, and
it looks like that.
And I've used motors and lights
principally since I
started showing in 1983
at Artist's Space.
It was my first show.
The work always did have a
relationship to what was
mechanically creating
a representation.
Sometimes that representation
would be projected onto a
screen, sometimes a
representation would just be
the performance itself that
would sort of flatten out.
I learned how to do all the
stuff I was doing just from
the store owners on
Canal Street.
They were so generous, and I
didn't know really how to wire
up a light bulb.
And I'd go in there, and it was
pretty desolate back then,
Canal Street.
It wasn't the pirated CD, Louis
Vuitton, Gucci industry
that it is now.
It was just kind of a sleepy,
industrial, surplus
neighborhood.
And I'd go in there, and
buy the owners a beer.
And they'd sit down with me
and draw up diagrams.
That's how I really learned how
to make what I'm making.
That was my school.
This space had been
abandoned for 20
years, so it was a wreck.
It was really a wreck.
I lived without a toilet for
almost six months, and I had a
wood burning stove.
So I used to go out with my
truck, and collecting wood
pallets, bringing them home,
chopping them up with a
chainsaw, and sticking them
in the wood stove.
With Planet Thailand, they
started in Green Point, and
then they opened a small little
restaurant on Bedford Avenue.
And then they opened
this big place.
And when they did, they asked
me to design the fountain.
MALE SPEAKER: How'd
they know you?
JON KESSLER: They actually
knew me through my friend
Julius, who was the general
contractor on this job.
And they didn't know me.
They just basically said
they wanted a fountain.
And Julius said, you got to look
at my friend Jon's work.
So that's how it happened.
The idea was to make a
fountain with a boat.
I was determined to do
it without a motor.
So I guess starting with the
idea of maybe a rowboat, I
happened to have found
a large boat which
had two sets of oars.
And then the symmetry
of the fore-oars
sort of found itself.
And then I used the principle
of a Japanese--
this is quite common in a
Japanese garden, which would
be a bamboo cup which would
fill up with water.
And then the weight of the water
would tip the cup over.
And it would make a
knocking sound.
Just a sort of typical Japanese
idea of just the
small sound.
You're aware of it.
It keeps time.
And so when the cups fill up,
actually the oars move.
And then when the cups release
the water, the
oars move back down.
So it's a constant
moving piece.
The last element was the duck,
which is actually a taxidermy
duck that-- oh, my god, this is
such a crazy trip, going to
a taxidermist in the Bronx.
I found him in the
Yellow Pages.
And I go back there, and
it was mostly rats.
He had mostly taxidermy rats,
and then this one duck.
I called him on the phone,
he said he had a duck.
And I go there.
And then I put a life
preserver on him.
And he's wearing a little
sailor cap, and
he's walking the plank.
MALE SPEAKER: You ever get
mugged on this street?
JON KESSLER: Yeah.
I wasn't mugged, but I had a
knife to my throat, right at
my driveway.
And it turns out the guy puts
a knife to my throat.
And he was the guy from
Joe's Busy Corner.
The girls--
slice him up, Jimmie!
Slice him up!
And I'm like, I got
a knife here.
And I'm like, you're the guy
from Joe's Busy Corner!
They could have slit
my throat.
And no one would have found
me here for a few days.
It wasn't until after 9/11,
really, that the work changed
with the use of video.
And I had in mind a piece which
was in the PS1 show
called "One Hour Photo." Just
really, I couldn't get the
image of the cockpit, what the
terrorists saw on 9/11, I
couldn't get it out
of my head.
And I decided to actually
create it.
I used a surveillance camera
in order to make that scene
come to life using postcards
of the World Trade Center.
And that's when the work really
shifted and took a turn.
And all of a sudden I had this
duality between the mechanisms
and the monitors.
And that's when the work got a
new life, I would say, like a
new pair of legs.
The research that I did for the
show I feel like wasn't
really anything special, having
lived in America in the
last four years, that we are
all sort of experiencing
day-to-day all the lies and all
the deceit, and the shock
at things like, well, Bush
winning the first time around,
and then Bush winning again
the second time around.
It was an incredible
disappointment
and shock to me.
I think the show does
encapsulate a certain amount
of rage that I have, and
disappointment, but also a
certain alienation that I have,
the country in some ways
being stolen from me, and that
the Constitution was being
stolen from us.
And that in a funny way, had you
told me that I'd be making
this show four years ago, I
wouldn't have believed you.
And I feel in some ways I'm sort
of like Michael Douglas
in "Falling Down," or Henry
Fonda in "The Wrong Man," or
something, being
pushed, pushed,
pushed, until this happens.
And I'm just reacting to
what's coming upon me.
It was almost like a diary, just
like me processing all of
that information, all of that
day-to-day existence in
America, from 9/11 to the
buildup of the war, to the
Hurricane Katrina, to lots of
connections that were happening.
And coming to the studio, and
really sort of for the first
time maybe in a very long time
where I was just working very,
very intuitively, very
immediately, and very, very
quickly, actually.
And then not even processing
it so much.
Really just consciously sort
of knowing that as I was
working, I was getting my
confidence back, and my
intuition was being restored,
and I was just
going to let it flow.
And that's what I did.
Toys have been something that's
been very consistent in
my work since the beginning.
I think of the necessity
in this work to play.
It doesn't come off didactic.
And there's a level of play
that disarms the viewer.
And then you can, on
top of that, lay on
any content you want.
And I think there's a
certain power in the
simplicity of the mechanism.
But then the image that you see
on the screen is actually
quite sophisticated.
I wanted people to be suspicious
of the images that
they're getting.
I think you have to constantly
be questioning how those
images are coming at you, why
they're coming at you,
connecting the dots back to what
the media, in some ways,
is constructing for you.
And these pieces
are all there.
There's not a single thing in
that show that is not in the
room if you have the
energy and the will
to deconstruct it.
When I'm working on a
show, I don't know--
especially one of these big
shows, like the show I'm
planning, in scope is going to
be a very ambitious project
like the "Palace At 4 AM." And
I don't know what it's going
to be like before I start.
And I really do feel like I'm
finding my way in the dark,
and just gathering evidence,
and gathering forensic
information, bits and pieces,
like after the bombing, in
order to put it back together,
the scene of the crime.
The show is called "10:10--
The Time Was Now." And there's
going to be photographs I'm
working on.
There's going to be sculptural
installations.
There's going to be lots of
monitors all over the room.
So it's very, very crowded.
These are very large.
These are these paper pulp
pieces I'm working on.
These will be covering the
walls of suicide bombers.
Then you walk in, and it's
sort of all about time.
Here's the time.
It's 10:09.
This is like a minute before
the moment of detonation.
These will just be covering
the walls.
MALE SPEAKER: They're
all 10:10.
JON KESSLER: They're all,
you know, 10:08, 10:09.
And it's really how the
advertisers choose to portray
the watch face, because
it's kind of like
a happy face, right?
And it still shows the logo.
So I'm just taking advantage
of that fact, and sampling,
and using that, and stealing
the watch ads for my show.
The whole center of the show
is going to be sort of like
the atrocity exhibition of
using figurines, mostly
soldiers, to create
these events.
And here is one where
the soldier's just
covered in crude oil.
There's the one that you
saw where he's being
dragged along the floor.
And I've just started
to compose these.
And then there's this guy.
He's an aging hippie waking up
sort of on the beaches of
California, sun tanned, and
the long, gray hair, maybe
with a bottle of Ripple
in his hand.
And then he morphed into a kind
of much more complicated,
political character.
He figured very prominently in
the "Palace At 4 AM." And he
became a piece called
"Evolution," where he became a
right wing senator.
And he was on a blog site
kissing the troops in Baghdad,
and waking up in the
burning embers of
the World Trade Center.
But now he's really sort of
turned into just everything.
He's the mash-up.
I collide him with all
the characters
that I'm working with.
But his voice is gone.
He's trying to speak, trying
to communicate.
And all of those sounds, those
motor sounds, those server
motors are actually going to
be picked up with little
microphones that are on his
face, and they're going to be
coming through the
sound system.
So it'll be loud.
It'll be sort of a
loud, worrying,
whizzing, motor sound.
I'm not glorifying this.
But I really want there to be
this feeling when you walk
into this show that death is
imminent, or that it's somehow
suspended in that moment just
before death in order to make
you feel completely alive.
So the work, you can see,
has changed a lot.
Flowers and beauty.
Although I think the work is
quite beautiful still.
[SOUND OF CLOCK TICKING]