MALE SPEAKER: Just camping--
that was super fun.
The beach camping was awesome.
Because it was, like, a Mad Max
type of vibe, just with
all those big trees, a bunch
of those trunks and stuff.
BRIAN ANDERSON: Busted.
MALE SPEAKER: What?
Is this breakfast?
BRIAN ANDERSON: It's I guess a
little cliche or predictable.
But, yeah.
This is breakfast.
Just doing the cleaning.
MALE SPEAKER: There it is.
MALE SPEAKER: Nice.
MALE SPEAKER: Stoked.
MALE SPEAKER: It's back on.
MALE SPEAKER: Pure stokage.
MALE SPEAKER: Who's got
the potato on here?
BRIAN ANDERSON: It's mine.
I'm about to pull it.
I'm looking for a plate.
That is a hot potato.
MALE SPEAKER: It's already
like ketched-up.
BRIAN ANDERSON: It's
delicious.
MALE SPEAKER: It has ketchup
and seasoning.
You guys see the fight
last night?
BRIAN ANDERSON: Temo?
SAM SMYTH: John and Temo whooped
on those two dudes.
You seen those two dudes
the first time they
came around, right?
BRIAN ANDERSON: Yeah, yeah.
TONY MIORANA: When
you are asked to
leave, you have to leave.
And if you don't,
you got to go.
SAM SMYTH: See how he left
the first time, right?
Like all you guys are
fucking douche bags.
You're fucking faggots.
You're all fucking faggot,
fucking douche bag.
He left and fucking
came back, dude.
MALE SPEAKER: The fight
land on your tent?
SEAN MALTO: Kind of.
MALE SPEAKER: Were you in it?
SEAN MALTO: No.
I was off to the side,
just watching.
MALE SPEAKER: If it got out of
hand-- like if the guy had
gotten through Tony and--
ALEX OLSON: Yeah.
Well then if he'd gotten through
those guys, I'm just
basically a shield for someone
else to throw him at.
MALE SPEAKER: How
are you feeling?
MALE SPEAKER: He's
starting to move.
MALE SPEAKER: How
are you feeling?
Hung over?
MIKE CARROLL: [MUMBLES]
MALE SPEAKER: You
look hung over.
Whoa.
This is some steamy
ass tent in here.
MIKE CARROLL: I don't think
I'm hung over yet.
MALE SPEAKER: You're
still drunk?
MIKE CARROLL: I think I
might be still drunk.
MALE SPEAKER: You're lucky
with that one.
MIKE CARROLL: What?
MALE SPEAKER: He's still drunk
in the morning, not hung over.
MIKE CARROLL: Wait.
Don't get the sand in here.
MALE SPEAKER: Mike, why'd you
beat those guys up last night?
MIKE CARROLL: I didn't fucking
touch anyone, dude.
They got touched.
MALE SPEAKER: I heard
you jumped them.
MIKE CARROLL: Dude,
that dude--
he is so gay for fucking-- oh,
you guys fucking jumped me.
SPIKE JONZE: I was
sound asleep.
I heard you's coming over
like it's cool.
It's cool.
Well skate the skate park
tomorrow, play a game of
skate, do some grinds, do some
lines, give you some
autographs.
MIKE CARROLL: Autographs,
fuck you.
MALE SPEAKER: Yo, posh cubs.
MALE SPEAKER: Oh, is this our
only chance to skate this?
Can I sleep?
MALE SPEAKER: Most skaters--
they'll have to warm up.
He's completely opposite--
gets out of the car, does the
craziest or hardest shit, and
then is over it, like done.
JOHN ALDEN: That was
fucking psycho.
The first one he did, his tail
drug around on the chain link
and was like
duh-duh-duh-duh-duh.
It was so sick.
MALE SPEAKER: That's his shit.
Like he just likes to fucking
jump out and go nuts.
And then he's fucking
chilling for a bit.
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
It's almost like you
watch those parts.
And you don't realize that it
was all just first try.
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah,
all that shit is
straight out of the van.
Pretty much, dude.
He's fucking insane
with it like that.
MALE SPEAKER: Oh my--
[CHEERING]
MALE SPEAKER: I mean, that's
how good he is.
He just can go and do the
hardest line or, like, highest
air, or weirdest area of the
park and then, like, sit down
and drink a beer and be Tony.
ROBBIE RUSSO: Look
at that thing.
That thing is huge.
I wouldn't even roll
into that.
[CHEERING]
MALE SPEAKER: [INAUDIBLE]
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah, good.
You?
MALE SPEAKER: Good.
STU GRAHAM: It's crazy.
Because there's a
wee love seat.
MALE SPEAKER: Oh, is there?
STU GRAHAM: Aye.
It's a funny color.
And it blends in, man.
MALE SPEAKER: You're
going to sit on it.
No.
STU GRAHAM: I'm not trying
to make love to you.
MALE SPEAKER: Ah, well.
Great.
JOHN RATTRAY: What's that?
MALE SPEAKER: [INAUDIBLE]
JOHN RATTRAY: Doing fine.
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah?
JOHN RATTRAY: Yeah.
MALE SPEAKER: Big crew.
MALE SPEAKER: Three vans?
JOHN RATTRAY: Yeah.
Three big vans.
MALE SPEAKER: And a car.
[CHEERING]
MALE SPEAKER: Damn,
killing the park.
ROBBIE RUSSO: See, dude?
I keep it at four inches.
I don't mess with that shit.
MALE SPEAKER: Hey, did
you ever skate with
Peter Hewitt before?
MALE SPEAKER: No.
I never even seen him.
MALE SPEAKER: And you know
when you are a kid.
And you see these skaters.
And you trip out
how they look.
Because you see them
in magazines.
And then you actually
see them in person.
And they kind of look a little
different than you thought
they would look.
I was all--
I would, like, stare at them.
And like, I don't know.
Like, the dude skates the
most big stuff that no
one else can skate.
Like a mini ramp to him
is like a fucking
vert ramp for us.
MALE SPEAKER: You mean
the other way around.
MALE SPEAKER: Was
that what I--?
MALE SPEAKER: You mean a vert
ramp for him is a--
MALE SPEAKER: Oh, yeah, yeah.
So yeah.
MALE SPEAKER: Brian.
BRIAN ANDERSON: Hey, dude.
How are you doing, man?
MALE SPEAKER: All right.
What's up, Tim?
TIM: How you doing, man?
How are you?
MALE SPEAKER: Good.
MALE SPEAKER: And what's it been
like hanging out with all
these Girl guys with
that team?
MALE SPEAKER: Oh,
it's nice, man.
I've known most of them for,
like, 20 plus years.
And I've never actually
been on a skate
trip with any of them.
So that's nice.
These guys--
we've all been skating
for so long together.
It's the same world.
PRESTON MAIGETTER:
Yeah, Petey.
It's coming.
Next one, Pat, next one.
PETER TRUJILLO: I was
taking it short.
MALE SPEAKER: I thought you
were going to make it.
PETER TRUJILLO: And then I
took it long that time.
It worked.
Yes.
I sketched on the push in.
PRESTON MAIGETTER: They did.
PETER TRUJILLO: Yeah.
PRESTON MAIGETTER: Saw that
a little bit there.
PETER TRUJILLO: Yeah.
PRESTON MAIGETTER: All right.
We've got to get ready.
Because Petey's going to
get back in there, Pat.
PAT: What's he going to do?
PRESTON MAIGETTER: Yo,
you're going to see.
Because he doesn't tell you.
He just starts trying
something.
And it'll happen.
You've got to be ready
for him to skate.
PAT: What's that?
PRESTON MAIGETTER: I feel like
how you're kind of ill
prepared with the tape and the
battery last three minutes.
Usually you put a fresh
tape in when
Peter Trujillo is skating.
[CHEERING]
PRESTON MAIGETTER:
I told you, Pat.
You got to be ready.
Did you get that?
PAT: Yeah.
PRESTON MAIGETTER: So we don't
need to send you that clip?
MALE SPEAKER: [INAUDIBLE]
How did you first meet Julian?
MALE SPEAKER: We partied at one
and the Anti-Hero team.
MALE SPEAKER: Ah, the Hellride
Crew, I met when I was 21.
We went to Australia together.
Andy Roy invited
me to go along.
MALE SPEAKER: Did you feel like
when you met those guys
that that was something you
wanted to skate for, or that
was a crew you wanted
to roll with?
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
I definitely wanted to travel
with these guys as much as
possible and continue
the saga.
MALE SPEAKER: How'd that come
about, that they asked you to
ride for Anti-Hero?
MALE SPEAKER: We were
in Marseilles.
And I was staying with John
and Julian in their room.
And they were like, we want
to make this happen.
But it's just going
to take some time.
And then a year later from that
point, I was on the team.
MALE SPEAKER: How is the
experience of riding for
Anti-Hero different than
some of these other
companies you rode for?
MALE SPEAKER: Just we travel
good together is the main
thing, just being able to travel
with your friends and
have a good time.
MALE SPEAKER: Have you
been on camping trips
with these dudes before?
MALE SPEAKER: Oh, yeah.
Yeah.
That's how we've been doing
it for a while.
It's way better.
Because you get to know
people a lot better.
Because you don't get to the
hotel and you all just
disperse off to your rooms and
get locked away for the night.
You know, you're there at the
campsite, making food together
and just telling stories.
MALE SPEAKER: What kind of
back patch did you have?
MALE SPEAKER: I had a Saxon back
patch back in the day.
And I had an Iron Maiden Piece
of Mine painters cap with on
one flap had Def Leppard
triangular patch
on one of the flaps.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Triangular
mangular.
MALE SPEAKER: Triangular.
MALE SPEAKER: You should have
brought it on this trip.
MALE SPEAKER: I wish I had it.
But I think it got stole.
MALE SPEAKER: Look how Brogini
this outfit is.
FEMALE SPEAKER: He's about to
swallow that wang whole.
FRANK GERWER: Dude, I know.
It's a hooded fucking sleeve.
MALE SPEAKER: It's just
sleeves and--
MALE SPEAKER: Don't even
bite my shit, dude.
MALE SPEAKER: Brogini.
That's our clothing company.
FRANK GERWER: That might
be the first--
Yeah, whenever.
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah, anyway,
where's the music at?
Let's dance.
FEMALE SPEAKER: I'm
trying to do that.
Baby boy, you got hickeys
on your neck.
You are so corrupted.
You got one right there.
And turn around.
Turn around.
You got one right there.
ROBBIE RUSSO: Well.
MALE SPEAKER: Where is it?
How'd you get that?
ROBBIE RUSSO: Twice my age.
Twice my age.
FEMALE SPEAKER: The girl who
gave it to you is getting
fucked in the woods.
She's getting fucked
in the woods.
MALE SPEAKER: By what wood?
FEMALE SPEAKER: By a
little bit of wood.
MALE SPEAKER: She's getting
fucked in the
woods by some wood.
FEMALE SPEAKER: What
kind of wood?
MALE SPEAKER: Who's got wood?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Is
it hard wood?
MALE SPEAKER: It's hard wood.