I'm Steve Spangler, and I'm all
about making science fun.
For the last 20 years, I've
been teaching ways to turn
ordinary science experiments
into unforgettable learning
experiences.
I have an amazing team who will
do whatever it takes to
affect the way people
think about science.
And to do that I live
by one motto.
Make it big, do it right,
give it class.
Well, if you've never seen the
Mentos and Diet Coke reaction,
where have you been living
all this time?
It's OK.
I'll give you a 20-second
crash course.
Go.
Soda by its very nature is
packed with carbon dioxide and
it wants to come out when
you open up the cap.
In fact, anything you drop
inside will help that
carbonation come out.
Mentos have tiny little pits
or craters on the outside.
They're called nucleation
points.
It's the perfect place
for carbon
dioxide bubbles to gather.
Because they're so heavy, when
you turn it over and drop it
down inside, they fall to the
bottom, the carbon dioxide is
released, and you get
the perfect geyser.
Watch.
See?
It's perfect.
We have to thank Lee Marek, a
chemistry teacher-- not only a
chemistry teacher, a great
chemistry teacher-- from
Naperville, Illinois, who shared
at a conference that if
you happen to use Mentos, it was
a nice substitute for the
Life Savers.
So that's it.
That's how the Mentos started.
I can tell you that nobody
really cared for
a long, long time.
It wasn't until September
of 2005, the lovely Kim
Christensen, was in the backyard
at KUSA 9 News, when
she happened to get a little
soaked because she didn't move
out of the way.
Watch this.
Three, two, one, pull.
Tell me that that's
not awesome?
KIM CHRISTENSEN: I did get it.
That's awesome.
STEVE: So sorry.
KIM CHRISTENSEN: That's OK.
STEVE: Look at you, you are--
KIM CHRISTENSEN: It tastes
kind of good.
STEVE: Wasn't that fun?
KIM CHRISTENSEN: Yeah,
it was fun.
STEVE: That is the best
I have ever seen.
Although this little test
tube, called a baby soda
bottle, was a great dropping
device for it, this created a
problem and that was
not everybody
could drop them equally.
And when a producer from
Discovery Channel called, that
happened to work on a little
show called MythBusters, they
said we'd seen your thing with
Kim Christensen, and saw that
it went up 18 feet, how do
you make it go higher?
Well, there are a whole bunch
of different ways to look at
it, but that prompted me to
start thinking about a dropper
device that would allow
everybody to drop equally.
This was a device my
wife had purchased.
It was almost like PVC, but it
made this hamper for the dirty
clothes, and as I looked at that
pipe, I thought that's
probably about the size of the
opening of a two-liter bottle.
Well, lo and behold, it was.
It fit perfectly.
Now if there was just a way
to be able to attach it.
So this is where the two-liter
cap came in-- a regular
two-liter cap-- and this went
down inside like this.
And so now we had a way to be
able to secure this in place,
which was perfect, so this could
go on here like this.
And this was the first dropper
device for the
Mentos geyser reaction.
More pressure, that's
what I wanted.
I wanted it to go higher.
It should go 35 or 40
feet in the air.
It just needed to build up
more pressure, and that's
where this little device
saved the day.
It's basically the same idea.
It's just that there's no holes
on the side because
there's a new little dropping
mechanism, and you only have
to use three or four Mentos to
get almost 35 feet in height
as the geyser blasts off.
This screws onto the
top, and now your
geyser is ready to go.
But it's even better,
because watch this.
I can actually take the Mentos
after the reaction has taken
place and now collect them back
in the geyser tube, seal
it up, twist it off.
Even though they're wet,
the nucleation
points are still perfect.
This twists onto a new bottle,
and I get another reaction
using the same Mentos.
The next issue isn't a design
issue, it's really an
experimental issue, and that is
thousands upon thousands of
you have done this reaction, how
high does the geyser go?
That seems to be the
bragging point.
Well, little did I know that
I could solve that problem
simply by taking this
whole thing and
turning it 90 degrees.
In comes the skateboard.
Because all I have to do now
is to take the bottle and
attach it to the keyboard.
That's where we need
duct tape.
See, I have my kids.
I just put them on the
skateboard and make them hold
the Diet Coke.
Drop the Mentos in and the Diet
Coke and the kids and the
Mentos, but then my wife said,
that's not a good idea.
That's where this solution
was perfect.
All right, we've got a flat
surface, we've got a
skateboard, Mentos.
This is how it works.
Ready, you pull like this
and you drop it.
And it goes.
It goes really far.
Usually, right up into
some lady's driveway.
Higginsworth, can you
go get that, please.
Keep that light on me, please.
Thank you.
Well, while this is fun, it's
not the easiest way to do it,
and it's not the least expensive
way to do it, that's
why we had to come up
with a new solution.
It's this.
So we teamed up with our friends
at Science Museum,
Oklahoma, and turned 150
teachers loose, all with
geyser cars, to create an
unforgettable learning
experience.
Take a look at this.
[DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING]