he's like the Evel Knievel of
our time-- not "like," "is."
And me, Jeff, and Spike just
did a documentary on him.
Tremaine was actually
the director, me
and Spike, mere producers.
Anyway, the documentary is
called The Birth of Big Air.
And we made the movie because
Mat is awesome.
TONY HAWK: If you know anything
about BMX, you know
who Mat Hoffman is.
And maybe that's all you know.
[PUNK MUSIC]
SPIKE JONZE: There is this
point where it feels like
everything's been done.
And then somebody does something
else, and it opens
up a whole new realm
of possibilities.
And Mat's probably done
that a dozen times.
MAT HOFFMAN: Is that really
possible, or am I just
completely an idiot?
MALE SPEAKER 1: Mat's holding
on one-handed down this
rickety-ass plywood runway.
MALE SPEAKER 2: You could crash
and kill yourself just
on the run-up to the ramp.
SPIKE JONZE: He's like that
big, and there's that
much air under him.
The ramp's that big.
MAT HOFFMAN: And whether I
hold it, or skip to the
ground, that moment
was everything.
MALE SPEAKER 3: Three years
after Mat tore down his last
big ramp, X Games added MegaRamp
and made it the
centerpiece of the event.
MALE SPEAKER 4: You watch the X
Games today, and you've got
guys risking their lives
on these huge ramps.
And Mat was definitely the guy
who started ratcheting it up
to where it got to today.
TONY HAWK: He was the
first guy to do any
sort of big ramp stuff.
And now we've got the whole Big
Air event in the X Games.
And that's largely because of
Mat ever trying it, or ever
dreaming it.
JOHNNY KNOXVILLE: Today's a
little nerve-wracking because
a couple years ago, Mat almost
lost his right arm.
He was in a big wreck.
A semi hit him.
So he hasn't ridden anything
big for two years, and the
doctors told him he would
never ride again.
And today he's riding
a very gnarly bowl.
People say, oh, I love that
so much I'd give my
right arm for it.
Mat could do that today.
I don't know, I'm just
a little nervous.
MAT HOFFMAN: I have
no idea what I'm--
this is like a new beginning,
this is like a first
challenge, of like--
I've never ridden a
ramp like this.
I have whole new equipment.
My arm has got totally
new limits.
It's been a long kind
of ride that I've
been doing with this--
Thanks, PJ, man.
JOHNNY KNOXVILLE: Man, he's a
foul-mouthed little prick.
He cussed me the whole
way up here for
leaving him in the car.
I said, Yoda, I am a Baptist,
and my ears
aren't garbage cans.
So I'll put him over here.
MAT HOFFMAN: I really believed
that my arm wasn't going to
work, and that I had totally
new limits, but they were
limits that--
pain tolerance-- couldn't really
ignore, because it just
didn't work anymore.
The power of a semi truck
hitting you at 50 miles an
hour is just ridiculous.
And so I've just lost these
muscles that control this arm.
If you can kind of see my
collarbone, how that just
moves around, it's not even
attached to anything.
I've gone through here.
I've gone through
this one twice.
And I've gone through
this one.
And I've been looking at my
bike-- how am I going to
figure this out again, how
am I going to play?
I started looking at my
body like, more as--
JOHNNY KNOXVILLE: A bicycle
part, like Spike said.
MAT HOFFMAN: And doctors
are like carpenters.
After you get hurt enough, you
just start seeing your--
you're just a piece of--
your body's a part
of your bike.
It's all one piece
of equipment.
We're trying to keep going.
JOHNNY KNOXVILLE: I don't
think most people
look at it that way.
MAT HOFFMAN: And really, what
people don't understand is I'm
happy either way.
I'm happy waking up on the flat
bar, as happy as I am
airing out.
Because it's just like--
I'm just going for it.
JOHNNY KNOXVILLE: You had a
bunch of surgeries on you
before the wreck, right?
MAT HOFFMAN: Yeah, I've had
25 something surgeries.
JOHNNY KNOXVILLE: He's held
together by pins,
rods, and duct tape.
MAT HOFFMAN: I owe my life to
medical science, really.
JOHNNY KNOXVILLE: He's a very
nerve-wracking friend to have.
[PUNK MUSIC]
SIMON TABRON: That's
pure, encapsulated
passion right there.
In England, we call it
reckless abandon.
It's a beautiful thing.
Oh my god.
Sorry, he just did
something scary.
That's all he does.
Jesus.
JOHNNY KNOXVILLE: He can't
even shake someone's hand
without holding his right
forearm, so you don't pull his
right shoulder out of socket,
and he's out here doing that.
[PUNK MUSIC]
JOHNNY KNOXVILLE: Mat's got one
arm, no brakes, defying
all odds by riding again.
What am I doing?
Just lugging beer up the hill.
[MUSIC CONTINUES]
JOHNNY KNOXVILLE: He loves it.
He loves riding.
The doctor told him,
you cannot do that,
you won't ride again.
I'm Mat's personal
assistant today.
I'm his driver.
Actually, I'm not driving
I'm moral support.
MAT HOFFMAN: This is a story
that I never thought I was
going to tell.
So whenever I got this
opportunity to do this with
Spike and Jeff and PJ and those
people that kind of grew
up with this spirit and this
fire, like, being able to tell
the story through them, it's
really all of our story.
What it's all about is just
going for it, you know.
The way I like to play, and
the same with you--
not many people like
to live that way.
They just like to be like, OK
wait, are your sure this--
let me see some track record.
It's like, where are
you going in life?
You're just following what's
already been done.
When it comes down to it, to go
for it, that untalented--
JOHNNY KNOXVILLE: To
be that untal--
I take untalented to
a whole new level.
Thank you, Mat.
Jeez, I thought he was going to
give me some props on this.
MAT HOFFMAN: To be that
untalented, but then still go
for it, that's that spirit
that anybody should have.
I wish I had that because--
JOHNNY KNOXVILLE: Thank you?
MAT HOFFMAN: Totally.
He knows he can't do this,
because after watching him go
for this multiple times, I now
know he can't do this.
It's not acting.
But he's still going to go for
it because he can't help it.
He just goes for it.
He likes to go for it.
There's a great saying
in Bolt.
I think it was like, in order to
make the impossible become
possible, you must be awesome.
JOHNNY KNOXVILLE: Why didn't
I think of that?
I've just been being a douche.
I could be awesome, and things
would totally change.
MAT HOFFMAN: My favorite thing
is being as high as I can be,
and getting the best view.
And seeing all this spectacular
landscape.
I want to be up in there
and looking down on it.
[PUNK MUSIC]
[LIGHT APPLAUSE]
MAT HOFFMAN: I'm sorry.
JOHNNY KNOXVILLE: He said, one
more, I'm not going to try
nothing hard or anything.
I'm like, OK.
Knowing he was going to--
that was awesome.
SIMON TABRON: I'm sorry I made
your friend do craziness.
In the skateboard pool.
[LAUGHTER]
JOHNNY KNOXVILLE: You can't
high five that arm.
The other one you
can high five.