And abundance is the way to eliminate that.
- Well, right, right.
- Not only an abundance
in resources
but also knowledge: how
to use that abundance.
If you just produce an abundance
and distribute that to people
you'll [have] mass hedonism: a
total collapse of the society.
You must educate people
to live with that.
In other words, you
have to tell people
even during instruction, [for
example] learning to fly an airplane:
what you can't do, what your
landing speed has to be.
If you don't have a certain speed
you will not rise off the ground.
If you don't maintain the speed in landing,
your craft will fall to the ground.
These are laws, physical laws,
and we must become aware
of the physical laws that affect human
behavior, our values, our lifestyle.
- (Jacque) ...rates, going up like
that and the amount of people needed
to turn out a given
amount of products.
It's always less people and higher
products, do you follow me?
[J. Rifkin] said: "When
production hits this,
and the amount of people
required hits that,
when they cross, that's
the end of the system."
Has nothing to do with
good men, bad men
politics, corruption,
fascism, free enterprise.
All of these discussions
about communism, socialism,
free enterprise, fascism, become
irrelevant in a society of an abundance
where people have access to things.
All those things fade out:
labor unions, you just
don't need that anymore.
It just does not exist.
- (Host) [In a] truly free society we
would not have things like protectionism
and nationalism and things like that.
- (Jacque) OK.
If abundance existed
all over the world,
all the water you want, all the
food, growing all over the place,
no one would stake
out territories.
You stake out territories
because it promotes survival.
People living on a desert can only
have a tribe of a certain size
because that desert region can't
support more than 50 people.
You have wandering nomads that
wander with the animal migration,
so if there's scarcity and new
people come into that area,
they say "You're moving
in on my territory!"
You know a lot of vegetarians
actually believe
that vegetarianism produces more
amiable patterns of behavior.
Actually, that's not true.
Cows in the field have
all the grass they want
so they're not very aggressive.
Any place you walk there's grass to chew on.
They're not aggressive because
there's an abundance;
whereas herbivorous
animals, carnivores,
don't have as much abundance.
They have to run after
animals and hunt them down,
and sometimes you don't make it.
You're not always in great physical shape,
so they have to be
more aggressive.
They have to be more
aggressive to survive.
It's the scarcity of food
that generates that.
Hunger generates the hunt
for food, for animals.
If you didn't had pains of hunger,
it wouldn't be that [way].
Years ago, primitive societies
used soldiers to keep
people in line, or police.
Some inventor came up to the
old landowner and he said:
"I've got a cheaper
way of doing that,
that wouldn't require
as many soldiers."
The landowner said "What way is that?
" He said "Well,
I can project fire from my mouth;
I have several things I can do
and people would look at me in amazement
and then listen to what I say."
He says "I come from
The One-On-High
and that One-On-High can see you
through a mud wall ten feet
thick, no matter what you do.
If you take anything that doesn't
belong to you, he can see that.
After you kick the bucket
you're gonna burn eternally."
That was a method for
keeping people to behave
though the king can kill
anybody he didn't like:
"Behead that son-of-a-bitch" or "get rid of
that culture over there." They all did it;
but "Thou shall not kill"
was in that community,
and a wife being
obedient made it easier
for otherwise women would
protest their state of being.
They had to pledge obedience to
the old man, whatever he wanted,
so the old man got his way.
If a man worked for somebody
he was not to remove anything
that didn't belong to him.
Stealing was a crime,
so the man who conducted magic and did all
the magic, controlled a lot of people.
He was the priest in the
early days, the soothsayer.
Now the priest was bothered
continuously by people.
[They'd] come up and [say] "My
son doesn't listen to me."
"My daughter is disobedient"
and he said: "Well..."
He was so bothered by people
that he made a stone statue.
He said "Anytime you have any
problem drop a half a buck off here
and talk to the stone statue!
Tell him all the problems you've got."
Some of them did that, but they
didn't like the conclusion,
so they destroyed
the stone statue.
He made two: one with a
smile and one with horns.
He says "The bad one, you
yell at, spit on, all that
and the good one you thank
for your state-of-being."
These were forms, dead forms
made of clay or stone,
and people talked to them all day long.
They didn't bother the priests at all.
The priest was off somewhere
doing something else.
This is how all these
icons came into being
and all the laws and
all the contributions.
Jesus walked on water, men
walk in space, on the Moon,
so that aspect you can use;
but he was not a deity.
He was not another
manifestation of God,
nor were any of the
great teachers.
Great teachers were great compared
to what was available at the time.
The nearest thing to what you
would call 'honesty' is science,
the nearest thing, because the system
itself checks things out constantly.
You come up with an idea.
They put it to test,
and more so than
any other system.
Yes, technology makes mistakes,
buildings collapse, bridges fall;
but compared to
any other system,
it's by far the most
outstanding system,
and the only system that we know
of that transports people around.
Electrical power gives us refrigerators
to keep food in storage.
In other words, science
and technology
has given us and freed more
people from hard toil and labor
than any philosopher
and do-gooder.
Unfortunately, when people see Mother
Teresa going around helping people,
they can't grasp some
agronomist working alone,
increasing the agricultural
yield by five times,
who has fed people who
could never of been fed
that would have starved to death.
They can't grasp that!
They have to see.
If you show normal people movies
of thousands of children
with swollen bellies,
suffering, they would get
a lump on their throat.
If you want to raise
money: one child
crippled, with crutches,
moving toward the camera
and when he gets to the camera have
him look up and have a tear run down.
You can raise more money than
showing 8 million people.
They are pinheads!
They are conditioned to utter simplicity.
This is not condemning the human race.
I'm condemning the value system,
the indoctrinations that are given by
the institutions of higher learning.
They are not institutions
of higher learning.
They are detrimental in
developing human beings
who are what you would
call conscience and aware
of their surroundings
and other people.
Subscribe- thanks!