THOM DEVITA: All tattoos
are a collaboration.
ROBERT RYAN: Thom's back piece
is probably the most
incredible tattoo
I've ever seen.
And it was the dragon done
by Huck's Spaulding.
I believe, in late '60s,
that tattoo was done.
ED HARDY: And when I first saw
that picture, I was like,
Jesus Christ.
The tattoo world was
so tiny then.
It's just, you can't even convey
how unusual it was to
see any tattoos.
The only people with tattoos
were either in
jail or in the service.
And then seeing big work
just blew my mind.
He forced Huck to do
that that size.
He blew that up, the
Coleman dragon.
And Mike said that Huck really
grumbled about it.
That's too big.
ANGELO SCOTTO: Tattooing years
ago was a lot different.
Totally, totally, totally,
different.
Nobody got big back
pieces back then.
He was ahead of his time.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CLAYTON PATTERSON: At that
time, tattooing was very
underground.
There were very few
places where you
could learn about it.
And especially if you were a
kid here in New York, when
it's illegal and it's
underground,
there's no place to learn.
NICK BUBASH: We went up and
got tattooed from Huck.
And then Huck Spaulding helped
Thom get started.
That's all you ever did
was help somebody.
You didn't teach anybody
anything.
CLAYTON PATTERSON: DeVita takes
Malone and [INAUDIBLE]
upstate, where Huck
is tattooing.
And Malone takes pictures.
JOHN WYATT: He told me that
he was a photographer.
And he was so blown away by the
tattooing, this is what he
wanted to do instead of
being a photographer.
This is a photograph of Mike
Malone sitting in Thom's chair
on Fourth Street.
They became very, very
good friends.
CLAYTON PATTERSON: And it's who
opens the door for you,
and who turns on the light, is
one of the greatest parts of
your career.
If you look at Malone,
it always
starts with Sailor Jerry.
And that is absolute a big
crock of bullshit.
ED HARDY: DeVita was responsible
for Malone getting
into tattooing, for sure.
And I had started corresponding
with Malone when
I was still at Doc Webb's,
first couple of
years in San Diego.
And then Malone and I really
got along, had a lot of
similar things.
I was like, I'd like
to see New York.
I'd never been there.
Anyway, my first trip
to New York was in,
Christ, maybe '72--
spring of '72--
because I was tattooing a bunch
of wealthy people that
lived there that were getting
custom work, like big
businessmen type that were in
the closet sexually, and they
were in the closet
with the tattoos.
They were positions
of importance.
And the night I got in,
they had a party at
this person's apartment.
And then Malone had said, wait
until you meet deVita.
And then Malone was talking
about deVita's place.
And he said, you won't
believe it.
ANGELO SCOTTO: Thom's
place was--
I've got to say it was
a dangerous area.
The East Village was a bad place
in the '60s and '70s,
very dangerous.
He was on Fourth between
C and D.
CLAYTON PATTERSON: Yeah,
C and D, Coke and Dope.
That's what it stood for.
Where are you going?
It was very dangerous
down here, for one
thing, at that time.
It was totally ghetto.
It was all drugs.
That's the drug capital of
the world at that time.
THOM DEVITA: If you imagine
what it was in the bad
neighborhood, that's
where I lived.
ED HARDY: We'd go down
to see deVita.
We'd get in a cab, and I'd say,
we're going to Fourth
between C and D. And then
we got going Fourth.
And then finally, at about
Avenue A, he said, I'm not
going any further.
I won't take you any further.
It was like Berlin after
the fucking war.
It was like burned out
buildings and shit.
It was just totally crazy.
CLAYTON PATTERSON: If you look
at Lower East Side, Lower East
Side has changed the history
America probably 500 times
with the different people that
have come through here.
It's been massive.
Rothko had a studio down
here, Jackson Pollock,
Jimi Hendrix, Madonna.
It's just endless, the number
of creative people that have
come out of the Lower
East Side.
And the connection to that, the
root to all of that, was
cheap rent and inexpensive
lifestyle.
THOM DEVITA: Our Fourth Street
shop was on the top floor.
I lived downstairs,
on another floor.
ANGELO SCOTTO: But the only
thing is that Thom, he only
took five people a day.
And you had to be there at
7:00 in the morning.
And when you got there at 7:00
in the morning, there was
people waiting for
him on the stoop.
THOM DEVITA: I used to tell
them, you can wake me up at
any time as long as
it's light out.
Just call out my name
very softly.
And I'll hear you because
that's when I wake up.
I'll be ready in one hour.
NICK BUBASH: You had to walk
through his apartment, which
was kind of darkly lit.
So you didn't really get
to see anything.
But it was very mysterious
looking.
There was a lot of things there
that you would want to
stop and look at just
out of curiosity.
But he didn't give
you a chance.
You followed him in to what
was the kitchen of the
apartment, where the
tattoo shop was.
And when I walked into that
place, my mind was blown.
It was walking into
a work of art.
A lot of this stuff
was there then.
ANGELO SCOTTO: Thom had the
best sign I ever seen.
Like I said, he used to go out
at night and look for things.
It said, no bongo drums or
percussion instruments allowed
in the park after dark.
You felt like you were walking
in an art gallery.
I kind of envy that.
I wish I had a shop
similar to that.
NICK BUBASH: He would get
flash from people.
And those things were all
presented on the wall.
The sheet itself was embellished
with ink and
stamps, and he would paste
things on them, and put frames
around them.
He changed everything.
Fuck, he used to say,
our job as artists
is to change things.
Jeez, I think it wasn't until
years later you started seeing
things like that in the Lower
East Side galleries, things
like the collage
constructionism.
You would see things that looked
like what Thom had been
doing 10 years or
15 years ago.
ED HARDY: I never met anybody
that was in tattooing that was
like that at all.
He was working on grape crate
slats, because he said, well,
it's perfect.
They're, like, the
size of an arm.
And I just, I said, this
is your flash?
And he says, yeah.
This is what I do.
I said, what if they
want hot stuff?
Because he didn't have
any cartoons.
And in those days, all
of us were like,
oh shit, more cartoons.
It paid the rent, but you just
get so tired of them.
And then he said, yeah.
I said, well, I tell him,
I've got to get his dad.
And he had a big [? Hanja, ?]
big Japanese demon.
THOM DEVITA: I don't
like cartoons.
All that Mickey Mouse tattoos,
it started in California.
Tattooing is already
cartoonish.
Why make it so obvious?
I like tattoos that
look like tattoos.
ED HARDY: And it just
blew my mind.
It was like, you mean you don't
have to just give them
the main menu?
I was still tattooing sailors.
I was trying to get people to
get something different,
custom work.
I worked for almost nothing
just to get to
do something different.
It just changed my head
around completely.
I saw this stuff, but I didn't
have a plan yet to do a custom
shop, to do what I eventually
did with realistic.
Then I went to Japan.
I shut down the San
Diego shop.
And when I came back, I opened
a place where everything had
to be one of a kind.
And I fucked it up for a lot of
people, because I started
going, well, hey, we can
do whatever you want.
And a lot of tattooers
were not into that.
Then I started inching
the prices up.
When I came back from
Japan, it started
getting more realistic.
And then deVita, he had all
these signs, tattoos need not
be expensive.
And I'm going, Thom, you're
living here in a fucking
burned-out building in this
neighborhood where you don't
have any overhead.
I said, Jesus Christ,
I've got a family.
I'm paying rent.
You don't even know what it is
to be in the real world.
So we we're always going back
and forth about that.
THOM DEVITA: I used
to have a sign
saying, artists pay double.
NICK BUBASH: Yeah, that's true.
He did.
-Were you known for
your designs?
THOM DEVITA: No.
I was known for $30 tattoos.
I had a big room filled
with $30 tattoos.
But I had the smaller room that
had higher price tattoos.
-They were $50.
THOM DEVITA: They were $60.
-A $50 room and a $30 room.
THOM DEVITA: No, $60.
$30.
I can't figure out numbers
that easy.
So I made it $30, $60, $90.
Caught on pretty quick.
NICK BUBASH: People weren't
coming around to get collector
things from him.
He was almost completely doing
the neighborhood guys.
He was in a Puerto Rican
neighborhood.
Some 99% of his customers
were Puerto Rican.
ED HARDY: So I'd go down
there, and I'd
roll my sleeves up.
I had these same tattoos on.
So even though you're like a
Haole guy coming down in
there, and if anybody said
anything, we'd say we're going
to see the tattoo man.
Or sometimes people would
say, you going to
see the tattoo man?
I'd say, yeah, you know.
THOM DEVITA: I'd walk
down there,
and they'd say, tattoo--
tattoo man, "the marker"
in Spanish, the man
that does the marks.
Puerto Ricans just came by
like the Russian guys.
Just come by, and
got a tattoo.
People I'd tattoo didn't
have their bodies done.
-Just their arms.
THOM DEVITA: They want
an eagle over here.
They want a heart over here,
mom and dad over here.
That's the kind of
people I tattoo.
I had designs on the walls.
But nobody picked them out.
I was doing blue collar
workers and
guys who didn't work.
-Is that the monkey king?
THOM DEVITA: Yeah.
-You've done this one before?
THOM DEVITA: That's not
typical of the work
that I would do.
Blue collar guys don't come
up for a monkey king.
Plumbers don't want
monkey king.
Do you understand what I say?
-Yes, sir.
THOM DEVITA: And no customer
ever come in and
said, I want clouds.
I want water.
Couldn't sell them water.
I would sometimes tell them,
would your like some clouds
around the eagle?
Yeah, OK.
I wouldn't even charge them for
it, hoping maybe they'd
get out, and somebody
would come back and
say, I want the clouds.
Then I'd say, that'll
be $30 extra.
ED HARDY: Another thing that
I loved, as a formal
breakthrough, was he would
put that stuff on.
He'd have the panther, right?
The standard panther size.
He'd have the panther.
But then he'd do
the claw marks.
And he'd say, see, then it
fills up that space.
Or he'd do the big spiderwebs
behind it.
NICK BUBASH: He was always
trying to wipe out--
oh, you'll wipe out a whole
forearm with that.
He'd put stuff around it.
By the time he was done for
$30, your whole goddamn
forearm was covered.
ROBERT RYAN: I know his
reasoning for it was to make
people think they were getting
more for their money, even
though they were only paying
$30 for this tattoo.
But really, it's a
dynamic look that
really can't be faked.
You're just stunned.
Wow, look at that.
That's strong.
CLAYTON PATTERSON: If this was
like a traditional situation,
Thom would have probably never
gotten into tattoos.
The only reason that Thom would
be able to become a
tattoo artist, and be the
tattoo artist he is, is
because he was in a place like
the Lower East Side.
They thought, wow, it's
a great tattoo.
They're not part of the classic
tattoo lineage.
So they have a tattoo, which
they think is powerful and
great and unique.
But it's for this section of
the people, who are drug
dealers, and junkies,
and whatever.
Thom would be nowhere
without that.
ROBERT RYAN: To me, it's high
art, in some of the craziest
conditions.
He was bringing to that
neighborhood what
people could afford.
And it was illegal.
So there was risks at every
corner and turn.
And he's just doing this
really beautiful stuff.
He really was a tattooer for
the people at that time.
And I think that's so cool.
And I think people really liked
him for that, as well,
and respected him for that.
THOM DEVITA: There was one guy,
a Puerto Rican, his name
was Ralphie.
I done quite a few tattoos
on his arm.
And we had no electricity and
no air conditioning, because
the one who was in control of
the basement shut it all off.
So [? Jenny ?] went out and
bought me short pants.
And Ralphie is standing
on the corner.
And he couldn't believe that
my legs, they're solid.
And he looked, and
he's so stunned.
He says, Thom-- he pronounced
the H in Thom.
Thom--
I don't even know how to do it,
but he pronounced the H.
He said, Thom, we are
proud of you.
Thom, he says, we are