I kind of cut myself
a little bit.
Little Higgins, get over
here little Higgins.
Use that rotary dial on
the phone and call--
call Aunt Mabel.
She'll get us connected
with the sheriff.
And, uh, maybe you could
put the pressure
and stop the bleeding.
Alright, it's 2012.
It is awesome.
Fake blood--
that's what we're talking
about today.
The best fake blood ever.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
I'm Steve Spangler and I'm all
about making science fun.
For the last twenty years I've
been teaching ways to turn
ordinary science experiments
into unforgettable learning
experiences.
I have an amazing team who will
do whatever it takes to
affect the way people
think about science.
And to do that, I live by one
motto-- make it big, do it
right, give it class.
Well, you know the best thing
about this blood--
totally edible because
it's chocolate syrup.
Back in the '40s and '50s in
movies and television, they
just used chocolate syrup
to make fake blood.
It was easy to clean up and
because of the black and white
nobody even cared.
Well, today's day and age you've
got to be a little bit
more sophisticated about that.
So this episode is all about
the best ways to be able to
make the best fake blood.
Well, fake blood has come
a long way since
the 1940's and '50s.
In fact, I have a vested
interest in this whole kind of
fake blood business.
If you saw our episode in the
Spangler Effect where I
introduce you to my parents, you
know that my mom and dad
were responsible for making a
lot of fake blood back in the
late '50s and early '60s that
ultimately has been used for
the last four or five decades.
Dad even had this trick called
You Do Voodoo and here's one
of the original ones.
This is a trick were you put a
needle through your arm-- it
didn't really--
I don't really put your needle
through the arm, but-- but it
looks so good.
And part of the secret was this
blood that he invented.
The technology was a whole lot
more complicated than just a
syrup and something-- a little
red food coloring.
This particular blood here was
perfectly matched to human
blood, had a flow of regular
blood, and under all kinds of
lights it was acceptable.
See, under fluorescent light and
under incandescent light
things look a little
bit different.
The most important part about
this blood is there's a
special micro-encapsulation
to it, so that if
it got in your clothes--
that it wouldn't stain
your clothes.
You literally could
wash it right off.
Unlike the blood that was the
syrup, there's no way to eat
this because it's not something
that's supposed to
be in your mouth.
This blood-- extremely
expensive.
It doesn't clog small little
tubes that the Muppets would
use, for example, and some of
they're little puppets.
You can kind of see that this is
the extreme way to go with
fake blood.
Cool stuff.
But today how about just going
to the kitchen and we're just
going to use materials that
you'll find in your normal
pantry and be able to formulate
a fake blood that's
perfect for whatever application
you need.
Looks good though.
All right, so on to classic,
fake blood.
Now, a couple weeks ago you can
either be a mixologist--
a little bit of this, and a
little bit of that, or if
you'd like to follow the recipe
we put a link for you
in the description for this
particular video.
Start with water.
You don't need too much.
So here's the water and a small
amount of food coloring.
Believe it not, that is
the basic recipe.
The problem is you're going to
go through all of that food
coloring and there are
a couple problems.
First of all, it doesn't
look like blood.
It looks a little bit more like
syrup, because it's not
thick enough.
So it's too red, but it's
definitely not thick enough.
And the test is always on
that white handkerchief.
So if you take a look
at it like that--
See this?
Not thick enough.
So to that, you typically add a
small amount of Karo syrup.
So the goal is to make sure that
our blood is edible just
in case you kind of get it
on your face or whatever.
So the Karo syrup does
nothing but help
thicken it a little bit.
And that seemed to be
just about enough.
As you mix it around here--
this definitely gives it a
little bit more thickness, but
you can see how orange
it looks.
So for passing it as fake blood
it's not fantastic.
But believe it or not, if you
go to the Halloween store a
lot of the fake blood that
you're going to find looks
something like this.
The test for us--
the napkin test.
So we'll put this out
here like this.
Put it on here and
see how it looks.
Watch.
All right.
I think it's easy to say this
does not look like fake blood.
It looks like orange Kool-aid.
Not going to pass the test.
Here's where the science
comes in.
As we look at this, this is a
little too transparent, right?
I'd really like to have
something that is a little bit
more translucent.
Transparent's like water.
I can actually see images
through this.
I really don't want to be able
to see through it and I want
to darken it.
So a couple ways to be able to
do that-- we can go back to
our favorite Hershey's
syrup, right?
So this chocolate syrup down
inside will help darken it
just a little bit.
But you try it in some
small portions.
Watch.
That's about what we need.
And now you mix it up.
Again, it's starting to take
on a little bit more of a
translucent quality.
You see kind of that
chocolateness that you get.
It's definitely not there with
our fake blood just yet.
It has a little bit-- we'd need
a little bit more of the
red food coloring.
Here, let's take a look
at this and see
what this looks like.
Watch.
No, see it's just
not there yet.
A little too orange--
a little darker than this.
But maybe the chocolate syrup
isn't the answer.
So as we're experimenting,
you just want to see what
ingredients you can add and
what effect it has so that
when you make your batch
you know which way to
kind of push it.
So instead of using just the
chocolate syrup, try this--
this is cocoa powder.
So a small amount of the power
here inside will give it a
little darker quality.
Watch.
Again, I'm going to use about
a kind of a heavy teaspoon.
That goes in here.
Just mix it up and
see what we get.
A little hard to blend it
because you've got little
pieces in there and so you're
going to want to
get this mixed up.
But once it's there you can see
that it has a little bit
different quality to it.
So when it's on this
piece here--
it's losing some of the redness
that we had before.
So I think what we're going to
need to do is go back with a
little bit more food coloring.
I think we're on
our way though.
That's it for this batch,
let's start fresh.
Well, now that we know the
basics you can start looking
for some better products.
So instead of just food
coloring, you'll walk down the
aisles and you're just looking
for things-- this, for
example, is dessert topper--
cherry dessert topper made
by my friend, Dr Pepper.
A refreshing drink.
So a little bit of
this in here is--
is kind of blood-like
in and of itself.
Look.
Notice we've taken care of a
couple considerations here.
You have the thickness of that
Karo syrup, you have kind of
the coloring that's there--
so that's not bad at all.
It definitely is too thick, so
it's going to need a little
bit of water.
So we add a little bit
of water to it here.
Good.
And we know that it needs
a little bit of
food coloring as well--
just a little bit.
And mix it up and see
what we've got.
This is already looking good.
All right, look at this.
It doesn't have that candy-like
consistency that we
saw before.
And we found out that if we add
a small amount of cocoa,
that really kind of helps it not
become transparent but a
little bit more translucent.
So just--
this goes here.
Again, it's just mixing
and kind of guessing.
I found that the powder
seems to be a secret.
It really has a good
consistency.
And when it sits for just a
little while the blood seems
to be a lot better.
Right now it just looks
like dessert.
But a little mixing and it
should look pretty good.
I think we need to shift it on
the blue side a little bit.
So again, a drop of the
blue food coloring.
That's looking pretty good.
Mix it up.
Here's one of the problems--
with all food coloring that
we're using and the syrups and
everything else, unlike the
really expensive fake blood,
this stuffs going to stain.
So you have to realize that
Halloween will be fun, but on
November 1 you're going to look
a little weird because
it's going to stain
you a little bit.
But it's not bad.
Here, watch this.
Let's see how good this is.
Watch.
I can shift it definitely
a little bit
more to that red side.
And I think that's looking
pretty good.
It's just experimenting and
playing with a little bit.
And there is one more secret.
Because the thickening agent,
which is the Karo syrup,
doesn't add any color to it--
and so maybe we change the
thickening agent-- and that's
where cornstarch comes in.
Well, it's blender time.
So grab the blender.
And I found a different
kind of corn syrup.
Take a look at this.
This corn syrup is actually
brown, so it kind of helps us
with the color immediately.
So it's adding some of
the color and some
thickness as well.
So let's start with
cornstarch.
And how much, you ask?
Exactly that much.
I don't know.
Just experiment.
To that we're going to add some
of the food coloring.
So here's our food
coloring, here.
That's part of our concentrate
so we use quite a bit of that.
So that's looking good.
I think a small amount of that
cherry topping seems to work
fairly well especially since
it's brown and thick.
That's looking good.
There was a fair amount
of water in the
other mixture there.
They had the food coloring.
And now it's ready to blend.
Get your hand on the top
otherwise you're going to be
painting the ceiling.
Now as you see it
blending here--
looking pretty red but
that-- it's not bad.
In fact, that's looking
really good.
This is like liquid diabetes.
Don't drink it.
I'm going to save a small amount
out because this is
pretty good.
You know as I look at it,
it's a little too red,
but it's not bad.
It's not bad at all.
The thing that we're going to
add here is cornstarch.
Now cornstarch, of course, is
white and when it mixes in
there it's going to thicken
it just a little bit.
But that white is going to tone
this down and make it so
it's not as transparent.
So how much, you ask?
Who cares.
Just put some in, blend it
up, and see how it looks.
Lid on top, holding tight,
take a look at this.
Now it's not going to
thicken it too much.
Oh, look at the splattering
here.
So you can see the secret to all
of this is the cornstarch,
because look-- it doesn't look
nearly as transparent as it
did before.
This is perfect.
All right, take a
look at this.
Just a small amount here.
And now on to the handkerchief
Oh, this is really, really
looking good.
Man, that's fantastic.
So a small amount of cornstarch
really kind of
helps it on the sides here.
But I think we can darken
it just a tiny little
bit using the cocoa.
The key here is just
small amounts.
So you don't want
to use a ton.
But for this big batch
here, this much is
going to be just fine.
So I'm going put this in, grind
it, take a look at it,
see if it's good, then you
can adjust it from there.
And if anybody asks you what
you're doing in the kitchen
you just simply say, I'm
making fake blood.
Or if your neighbors come over
you should cover yourself with
it and say, oh, I
had an accident!
But then somebody's going
to call the police.
Just turn on the blender.
All right, look at this.
Looking even better.
See?
Looking better.
See this darkness
that's in there?
And that's exactly what that
powdered cocoa did for us.
So that was perfect.
This is looking even better.
This looks great.
So here-- just a small amount
here like this.
It's nice and dark.
Take a look at this.
You know what?
I like it.
I like it a lot.
We really don't have
a reference
point with real blood.
You can see where we started
here-- a little too orange.
And then moved to this area here
that looks like it's a
little bit more candy-like.
And finally, this is starting
to get into the real deal.
I think it's looking
pretty good.
Oh, it does not taste great,
but it's not the
object to eat it.
It's to gross people out.
I'm going to add just a small
amount of cornstarch.
The last little piece because
I want it sticking to the
walls, toning it down just
a little tiny bit.
Again, this much looks
pretty good.
Let's see if this makes the
perfect blood for us.
[BLENDING]
All right, this is
looking good.
It's nice and dark, sticking
to the walls here.
I think that could freak
somebody out.
If that's what they saw, this
would freak them out.
Uh, it looks good too.
It's perfect.
All right, let's see what
our little blood
recipe looks like.
Nice.
All right, well I don't have
real blood to compare it to,
but I can tell you that this
blood here looks a lot better
than what we started with
at the very beginning.
It took a little bit of tweaking
and playing with a
little bit, but I think
it's great.
And blood on a spoon doesn't
look fantastic, but blood in a
syringe would be perfect.
All right, here we go.
A little syringe.
This is perfect.
All right, so now let's put this
out on to the napkin and
see what this looks like.
All right, and now let's
spread it out and
see what this is.
Oh, this--
that's fantastic.
Look at this.
That looks fantastic.
I think we have the blood that
we need to doctor up
Higginsworth.
Higginsworth!
Oh, this looks so good.
The little bit of mixing
in the syringe.
Higgins, come here.
Here's little Higginsworth.
Look at you.
See, I told you this would
look perfect on you.
All right.
BRYAN HIGGINSWORTH: Yeah.
STEVE SPANGLER: And it's
very stylish, too.
All right, so here's what
we're going to do.
I'm going to cover you with this
and then we're going to
walk around the office
and freak people out.
BRYAN HIGGINSWORTH: Nobody's
going to care if
I'm covered in blood.
STEVE SPANGLER: Yes they are.
Are you kidding?
BRYAN HIGGINSWORTH: No, you
could put me in the middle of
the office on the ground covered
in blood, no one's
going to notice.
STEVE SPANGLER: That's a lie.
I am swear--
we need to get like a hammer
came out of your head or
something like that.
Or you slipped and fell or you
got a screwdriver and it's all
over-- these people are
going to freak.
They're calling--
I'll bet you they call 911.
BRYAN HIGGINSWORTH: I'll
take you up on that.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK.
Go lay down.
Hurry up.
I'm going to cover
you in blood.
He has no clue.
They're going to freak.
OK, Higgins we've got
to work fast.
Ready?
So just kind of just
jam these in here.
BRYAN HIGGINSWORTH: No one's
going to believe us.
STEVE SPANGLER: They're totally
Here, stay there.
BRYAN HIGGINSWORTH: All right.
STEVE SPANGLER: OK,
that's good.
OK, that looks good.
Here, lay down.
OK, now down here.
Make your legs look
like you're dead.
Yeah, that's perfect.
All right, so look.
See this band-aid?
So now here I've
got this blood.
So I'm just going to put
this blood under this
band-aid like this.
This is perfect.
All right, that's great.
Look at this.
See, I'm going to shoot
it on you like this.
Oh, that's awesome.
All right, so let's--
well here, here
hold on just a second.
Let's pretend like you -- all
right, so there's going to be
a little bit of stuff going
on here, like this.
Look at that.
How does that taste, Higs?
Is that gross?
You know, it looks better
on your hands.
Here hold-- put your
hand out like this.
Oh, perfect.
That's like a hangnail
right there.
Like you had a hangnail and
that was a problem.
OK, so watch.
Here's what we're going to do.
So we're going to get people
to walk by, and I swear
they're going to call 911.
All right?
This is going to
be so awesome.
BRYAN HIGGINSWORTH: I
don't think anyone's
going to even notice.
STEVE SPANGLER: Are
you kidding me?
They're going to freak out.
Get ready to see the paramedics
there little buddy.
Oh, you've got a nose bleed.
Two too.
OK, so here's your little
nose bleed.
OK, so pretend-- oh
yeah, see that?
You've got a bloody nose.
What do you think about that?
BRYAN HIGGINSWORTH:
It's pretty sweet.
STEVE SPANGLER: Is
that pretty good?
Oh, head trauma.
All right, there's some head
trauma right there.
That's perfect.
OK?
BRYAN HIGGINSWORTH:
Totally making
this my Facebook profile.
STEVE SPANGLER: I would
if I were you.
OK, so watch.
Let's pretend like--
[SNEEZES]
like that.
How's that?
That looks pretty good.
What do you think?
OK, so now I'm going to get all
this stuff, and now I'm
just going to hide off to
the side and let's see
what people say, OK?
People are going to freak out.
Pretend like your
dead Be dead.
BRYAN HIGGINSWORTH: All right.
[INAUDIBLE]
-What's up, Higginsworth?
-Excuse me.
-Hey, Bryan.
-Um, so anyway, I think we need
to do a reset on that.
-Yeah.
-Oh, hey Higgins.
We have your order up
front, all right?
We're got your uh-- a bunch of
flying film canisters and some
Alka-Seltzer.
So whenever you can come up and
get it that'd be great.
Take care, buddy.
-Hey, Higginsworth.
Looking good.
Huh.
-Bryan, I took three messages
for Laura and I'm getting
pretty sick of it, OK?
I'm not your messenger.
Excuses.
-Oh, hey, Bryan.
Our 3 o'clock meeting's
been moved to 4:00.
And you've got a little
something right there.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
-This place sucks.
All right, Higgins,
you're done.
Let's go.
Come on, let's go.
Knock it off.
It's not funny anymore.
[SCREAMING]
-Hey, Higgins.
So how's your birthday?
[INAUDIBLE]
[SINGING]
-Happy birthday to you, happy
birthday to you, happy
birthday dear Higgins, happy
birthday to you.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]