Waria are known as Indonesia's
third sex.
This centuries-old tradition is
largely accepted as part of
Indonesian culture.
However, it's one that doesn't
sit easily with Islam, which
has risen to become the
country's dominant religion
since it's arrival in
the 13th century.
Since Islamic law acknowledges
only two sexes, male and
female, and forbids men to dress
and adopt the mannerisms
of women, waria have been pushed
further and further
into the margins of society.
This makes it difficult to
practice their faith.
While it seems strange that the
waria are passionate about
a religion that shuns them, they
believe that even if the
majority of Islamic
authorities don't
accept them, God does.
I headed out to meet Maryani, a
50-year-old transsexual who
runs the Senin-Kamis School
from the back
of her beauty salon.
And is mother to her adopted
daughter Rizky, who she raises
on her own.
Maryani greeted my translator,
Mendez, and
myself at the door.
And asked us to come in quietly,
as we had arrived in
the middle of a Quran class.
MALE SPEAKER:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
MARYANI:
HANNAH BROOKS: As I talked with
her more, Maryani told me
about her life.
Despite living through some
tough times, she also had a
lot of fun when she
was younger.
She used to be the singer in
a dangdut band, which is
Indonesia's sexy style
of pop music.
And from her description,
it sounded like her
career was a big deal.
That all changed when she
converted to Islam in her 30s.
She left behind her hedonistic
lifestyle to focus on her
spirituality.
Because, as she puts
it, her conversion
came from the heart.
MALE SPEAKER:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
MARYANI:
MALE SPEAKER:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
HANNAH BROOKS: Following the
2006 earthquake that rocked
Yogyakarta, Maryani gathered
lots of her friends to
participate in some of
the mass prayers.
An older priest friend was so
impressed by her efforts and
ability to draw a large group
that he invited her to start a
place for the transvestites
to gather.
And thus, the school was born.
MARYANI:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
HANNAH BROOKS: I was enjoying
hanging out with Maryani and
wanted to spend some more time
talking to her one on one.
But unexpectedly, she asked me
if I'd like to attend the
funeral of a waria who recently
died from HIV
complications.
She told me that it would help
me understand some of the
difficulties they face.
I agreed, and we hopped
in the car.
Maryani's friend Yuni Shara,
who was a member of the
school, caught a ride with
us to the funeral.
She pulled out her phone and
started showing me photos of
her main squeeze.
YUNI SHARA: My husband.
HANNAH BROOKS: Your husband.
YUNI SHARA: [LAUGHING],
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
HANNAH BROOKS: He's married
to a woman.
HANNAH BROOKS: Oh, really?
MARYANI:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
HANNAH BROOKS: Do you
do your own makeup?
YUNI SHARA: Oh yeah.
HANNAH BROOKS: You do eyeliner
better than I do.
Much, much better.
Thank you.
The funeral was held
in the street of a
waria-friendly community.
Most of the local townspeople
were sitting around and
milling about, waiting for the
ceremony to get underway.
Wow.
There was also a huge amount
of warias sitting around,
smoking cigarettes
and chatting.
I'd seen photos of the
warias, and knew they
had distinctive faces.
But seeing them in the flesh
and dressed rather
provocatively was
overwhelming.
MARYANI:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
HANNAH BROOKS: Maryani made a
speech about the importance of
warias acting with dignity and
self-respect in order to be
seen as equal members
of society.
She encouraged them to
contribute to the funeral
costs of warias that
pass away.
However, most of the warias
didn't seem to be paying much
attention to what
she was saying.
They gave off the impression
that a funeral is just
business as usual.
And in fact, it wasn't
that far off.
Usually four warias die each
month, mostly from the things
that Maryani was trying to warn
against in her speech.
[SINGING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[MULTIPLE SPEAKERS SPEAKING
FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
YUNI SHARA:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
HANNAH BROOKS: Could you, while
we're here, take us to
see some of the street
performers?
YUNI SHARA:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
HANNAH BROOKS: We headed back
to our hotel to rest up for
the night, and prepared to set
out in the morning to meet up
with some of Maryani's street
singer friends.
MARYANI:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
HANNAH BROOKS: I went to meet
two friends of Maryani's,
Jamila and Wulan, who work as
street singers in central
Yogyakarta.
When I got there, I realized I
had met them the day before at
the school.
But then they had been
dressed as men.
[SINGING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
WULAN:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
HANNAH BROOKS: So you used to
work as a prostitute, and now
you work as a street
performer.
WULAN:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
JAMILA:
[SINGING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
HANNAH BROOKS: You got that
stuck in my head now.
[SINGING]
JAMILA:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
HANNAH BROOKS: Some people
got angry when the warias
approached and shooed them away,
while others happily
gave them money.
Virtually everyone stared.
One small boy burst into tears
and started screaming.
That was really intense.
We were just up there, and
the girls were singing.
And this little kid totally
fucking flipped out and
started screaming when
he saw them.
And the mother like, grabbed the
kid and was really angry.
Their reaction was really,
really-- like, the mother was
furious that the kid
was so upset.
And the kid looked like he had
seen the devil or something.
MENDEZ: Yeah, yeah.
HANNAH BROOKS: After spending
time with the warias, I began
to forget that their
appearance could
be alarming as first.
As I watched people's reactions
and the mockery they
endured, I felt a huge amount
of empathy for them.
WULAN:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
HANNAH BROOKS: While street
performing seems like a dream
job compared to prostitution,
the downside is that the hours
are long, and enduring
the noise and grit of
Yogyakarta is tough.
The negatives of working as a
prostitute are obvious, and a
lot more dangerous.
MARYANI:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
HANNAH BROOKS: That night I
planned to meet up with Novi
and Nur, who work
as prostitutes.
Nur, who's only 19, read about
Maryani and the school on the
Internet, and traveled all the
way from Lombok, which is a
small island near Bali,
to meet her.
NUR: [SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
HANNAH BROOKS: Do you
miss your family?
Or are you happy to
be away from them?
NUR: [SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
HANNAH BROOKS: What would you
like to do with your life?
NUR: [SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
HANNAH BROOKS: That's great.
I hope you can.
We gave the girls a ride to
their regular hooking spot,
which was in a sketchy area
next to a railway station.
I'd heard stories of waria
being hit by trains while
working in this location.
Is it safe working here?
NOVI:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
HANNAH BROOKS: So that's where
most of the customers hang
out, down there?
NOVI:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
HANNAH BROOKS: The girls stood
for a while by the train
tracks but didn't get
any customers.
They decided to head over to
a busier street they also
regularly work.
We hung out across the road,
away from potential customers,
so that the girls could
do their thing.
A few guys approached here and
there, but for the most part,
nothing really happened.
The girls drank booze with a
shopkeeper, practiced their
poses, and played with
their phones.
After a few hours, it didn't
look like they were going to
have much luck tonight.
It's about midnight now.
We've just been standing across
the other side of the
road to let the girls kind of do
their thing and try and get
some customers.
I don't know.
I just don't know
how they do it.
Like Nur was saying, she just
wants to go out tonight and
work so that she can have some
money to get through tomorrow.
They definitely have dreams and
things they want to do in
the future and stuff.
But they can only
think this far.
They can't really plan.
It's very much in the
day for them.
Anyway, it's time to go home.
I'm going to go across the road
now and say goodbye to
the girls, and wish them
good luck for tonight.
I hope they make some cash.
And I hope they stay safe.
As we were wrapping up, we
noticed one particular guy
pestering Nur and creeping
her out quite a bit.
He looked like the kind of guy
who couldn't afford the girls'
low prices.
As he kept hassling Nur, Novi
ran over to us and asked if
we'd take Nur home.
HANNAH BROOKS: Nur
wants to go home?
Yeah, sure.
Yep.
MARYANI:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
HANNAH BROOKS: The next morning
we woke up and headed
to a small village somewhere
outside Yogyakarta.
Jamila was getting a black
market breast job and agreed
to let us come, as long as we
didn't film where we were or
who was doing the procedure.
I knew that it was common for
warias who believe it makes
them look more feminine to
inject silicone into their
faces and breasts.
Jamila was really excited.
Because although she's had
injections in her cheeks and
chin, she would be getting
boobs for the first time.
MARYANI:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
HANNAH BROOKS: The room
was incredibly hot,
and definitely unsterile.
And the sight of Jamila's chest
growing into two oddly
shaped mounds was enough to make
both Mendez and I start
to feel ill.
JAMILA:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
MENDEZ: Was it painful?
Could you feel it?
JAMILA:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
HANNAH BROOKS: We needed a
little air after witnessing
the operation.
So we decided to head back to
Maryani's and check in with
the rest of the warias.
When we arrived, Maryani was
getting ready to head out on a
scooter with Rizky and
told me to hop on.
We were heading to the market to
buy makeup and accessories
for the big party
we were throwing
the warias that night.
Maryani seemed genuinely excited
to get the chance to
go out with me for a bit.
She said that tonight was all
about celebrating being a
waria, and about being
comfortable with yourself.
MARYANI:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
HANNAH BROOKS: The warias were
busy getting dolled up for the
party while Maryani instructed
her assistant to make me look
like the sexiest
waria possible.
So it appears that she
is now attaching
the other large growth--
some kind of tail, head tail.
It feels like I've got a giant
clump of weed on my head.
You like?
Yeah.
FEMALE SPEAKER:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
HANNAH BROOKS: While the girls
sat in the schoolroom taking
glamour shots on their cell
phones and gossiping about
cute boys, I noticed that
Maryani was sitting quietly in
the salon as she applied
her makeup.
MARYANI:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[SINGING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
HANNAH BROOKS: Going to have
to practice that more.
FEMALE SPEAKER:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
HANNAH BROOKS: What do
you think about God?
Like, to you, what is God?
I'm interested because I don't
know how I feel about it.
And I'm always interested to
hear other people's opinions.
MARYANI:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
HANNAH BROOKS: Holy
fucking shit.
The party was at a restaurant
with a stage, sound system,
and a resident keyboard player,
who wanted to know who
the new lady-boy was
when I walked in.
Obviously, Maryani had done
a good job on my makeup.
The waria were trying to be
on their best behavior.
But some of the younger girls
were sneaking swigs of booze
under the table.
It might have helped them with
their performance anxiety.
The warias took turns singing
and dancing, which involved a
lot of dangdut and a
lot of Celine Dion.
I was super impressed by
Maryani's numbers.
The warias sang and danced
well into the night.
I was dragged to the dance floor
over and over, and did
my best to shake it like
a Javanese bride.
Eventually, I was yanked onstage
to perform the love
song the warias had
been teaching me.
MARYANI:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
HANNAH BROOKS: Even though their
situation is far from
perfect, I was impressed by the
warias' determination to
better themselves, and
particularly by Maryani's
refusal to play by the rules.
It takes a courageous waria
to do what she has--
raise a child on her own, reach
the pinnacle of wariadom
by opening her own beauty salon,
and to start the school
so that others might
do the same.
As for the fact that the waria
are dedicated to the very
religion that refuses to accept
them, I agree with what
Maryani told me.
Since God is the one that judges
whether they go to
heaven or hell, it's their
relationship with Him that
matters, not the opinions
of people.
With lipstick in their pockets
and God on their side, it
seems the warias have
a fighting chance.