This is the five gallon version
with two five-gallon coolers.
We also have a ten gallon
version with ten-gallon coolers.
The five-gallon version
is big enough for most
five-gallon all-grain batches if you
brew mostly session beers,
anything up to about doppelbock strength,
you can use the system for years.. your
entire all-grain career and be totally happy.
If you brew ten-gallon batches or if you
start getting into really big beers like
barleywines in the five-gallon size
consider the ten-gallon system.
The deluxe all-grain system
includes two major components:
the mash/lauter tun and the hot
liquor tank.
This is a good moment to mention some
brewer's terminology.
"Liquor" in brewing doesn't refer to whiskey or
tequila,
it refers to water that has been treated
for brewing. So the hot liquor tank
is where we hold hot liquor
hot brewing water
for the sparge.
Mash/lauter tun is where we
mash and lauter
grain is mixed with hot water
to create wort
and then lautered (or
separated from the solids)
and to accomplish that the mash
lauter tun has a perforated, domed
stainless steel screen
called a false bottom.
that will keep the grain inside
while letting the wort drain into
your boil kettle.
Some of the advantages of this system
are: insulation.
Coolers will hold the temperature
very well. When you're all-grain brewing,
the temperature of the mash is pretty
critical. It affects the outcome of the
finished beer quite a bit.
Being able to hold a steady consistent mash temperature for hours on end is real plus.
All the coolers -- five and ten gallon -- also
include graduations inside
which makes measuring out
your brewing water very easy.
Finally, draining and transferring liquid from
both of the vessel is as hands-free as just
opening a valve and letting gravity do the hard work.
When you get your deluxe all-grain
system there's a little bit of assembly
required but if I can do it, anybody can do it
The coolers come with a factory spigot
installed.
Before we can actually brew with it,
we need to replace that
with the ball valves like I've already
done on this one.
Very easy you just need three things:
crescent wrench
pliers
and a roll of teflon tape which is available
from Northern Brewer or a hardware store,
which may be where you had to
go to get these things anyways.
Let's get into it.
There's a nut and a spigot on the inside fo the cooler
that needs to be removed,
to take the spigot out.
I've already looseen in this one up a bit
with the crescent wrench
so i can finish getting it
by hand.
Three pieces - there's the nut
gasket
and the spigot itself.
The valve assemblies
have two components:
the bulkhead which goes inside the
cooler...
and the valve proper
which goes on the outside of the cooler
like you can see
on this one here.
The bulkhead itself as a few parts
but the two we need to be concerned with
are the big hex nut...
and a big silicone O-ring.
These go on the outside of the cooler.
The rest of the bulkhead
goes on the inside.
The bulkhead goes inside their cooler
with coupling facing in,
and threaded nipple facing out.
Back on the outside
the big O-ring
gets snugged up against
the cooler wall
followed by the hex nut
with the flat side facing out.
Hand-tighten.
And use the crescent wrench on the outside...
the pliers on the inside to hold the
coupling...
tighten it down.
Next, we use a few inches of teflon tape
to wrap the threads
and help make a watertight seal
when we put the ball valve on.
[tightening components]
Finally, a little more teflon tape to wrap the
threads of the barbed fitting into the ball valve.
[tightening]
Now that we're ready for brewday, we need one
more piece  of sophisticated equipment
to make a gravity fed, tiered, brewing system.
[moves chair across floor]
Hot liquor tank will be the highest
point
mash/lauter tun in the middle
and your boil kettle of choice which is not
included with the all-grain system
will be on the floor
to receive the wort
from the mash/lauter tun.
To transfer the liquid from vessel to
vessel, the deluxe all-grain system
come with a couple sets of hoses.
There's a clear, high-temperature hose
to drain the mash/lauter tun
into the boil kettle.
Clear hose allows you to evaluate the
color and clarity of the wort
coming out of the mash/lauter tun.
The second hose is an opaque
high-temperature hose
to drain sparge water from the hot liquor
tank
into the mash/lauter tun.
This piece has a diverter tip,
a little siphon sprayer on the end
to diffuse
the hot water coming out
and deliver a gentle trickleinstead of
a full-bore stream
that could channel a hole
straight down into the grain bed
and have some adverse effects
on the finished beer.
To actually start moving liquid all you
have to do is open one valve...
open another valve...
and wort will be flowing into the boil
kettle.
Leaving both hands free for beer
or more important things like taking
notes.
This is the deluxe all grain system from
northern brewer.
Happy brewing and cheers!
www.northernbrewer.com