-Buddy!
Andrew, buddy!
SETH MILLER: The Washed Up Cup,
well, let's see, how to
explain it--
an event where the legends
can get together.
It's like a family reunion.
We can all come back and see
each other again and ride,
just for fun.
-Come, on [INAUDIBLE]!
SETH NEARY: It's fantastic,
you know.
It's fun.
There's a lot of people
competing.
It's really fun-- a lot
of people up at the
top drinking beers.
It's a good time.
It's a good time, for sure.
[CHEERS]
[HEAVY METAL MUSIC]
BRYAN TSCHORN: The first two
turns are pretty icy.
And then after you go over the
first lip, the next two gates
are super icy.
So if you can just make it
though those two turns and
then speed and then try to take
a little off and then
send it over the jump.
[HEAVY METAL MUSIC]
[CHEERS]
LIAM GRIFFIN: I was just
doing 12-ounce curls.
I didn't qualify
for the event.
I never actually competed
in the Open.
Maybe I qualify as a legend.
I don't know.
BOB KLEIN: The Open is kind of
like a reunion for all the old
school guys, but it's more like,
hey, let's go hang out
on the deck and drink
a beer together or
take a few runs together.
And it was just an awesome
idea to put on an event.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[CHEERS]
CHRIS DOYLE: You know, it was
amazing to see guys like Tim
Windell and Seth Miller come
in and just throw down and
really look like they have
not missed a beat.
SETH MILLER: When I think of
the US Open, definitely it
helped launch my career.
We were living here, just really
nobodies, until we made
it through the finals
at the US Open.
And all of the sudden, I'm on
a plane to Europe, and I'm
traveling the world and
doing the World Cup.
And all of the sudden,
it just happened.
And I think that's what the US
Open did for a lot of guys.
It put you on the map.
GUILLAUME MORISSET: 1997
was my first year
doing whatever contest.
I'd just started there.
And then I came back 1998
and 1999 and 2000.
And 2000 is the one year
that I won it.
Well, there is so much
adrenaline, so it's just so
fun to be here riding with tough
riders like Hakonsen and
[INAUDIBLE]
and everybody.
So it was the best
contest ever.
I'm so stoked.
The pipe was just perfect.
And 2000 was the first year they
brought this superpipe,
which was 18 feet.
Now, it would not be a
superpipe anymore.
But then, it was
something new.
LIAM GRIFFIN: It was 15-foot
pipe, or I guess hand-dug pipe
and then Lyle with
the excavator--
and then 12-foot, 15-foot,
18-foot, 22-foot.
And I mean, the pipes got
bigger, people went bigger.
The pipes got better,
people rode better.
But that's the thing.
You build this stuff wondering
if it's going to be possible,
and then you put the right
people on it and
just watch it happen.
ANDY COHGLAN: Now, it seems like
you just expect that, and
you expect them to go 15 or
20 feet up in the air.
But back then, it was
something that
no one could do.
And I guess it's the
same way now.
You look at it with awe because
it's something that
you can't do.
[CHEERS]
ZAK HALE: I mean, 15 years ago,
it was just a bunch of
homies going to a contest
and snowboarding.
It was just like, oh, sick.
I get to go shred
with my homies
and go ride a half-pipe.
BOB KLEIN: In '92, I saw a van
careening up the access road,
and I was like, hey,
that's Palmer.
And we caught up to him and
started racing back and forth.
And we clipped the back end of
his van, and it rolled right
in front of me.
And I freaked out.
It was Palmer and Noah Salasnek
and I thought they
were dead, totally dead.
And I ran back to the house
we were all staying in.
And 15, 20 minutes later,
everybody comes in the house,
and Palmer and Salasnek look
like they had glitter all over
their faces from all
the broken glass--
not a scratch on them.
Just laughing their asses off,
they thought it was the
funniest thing ever.
And it was like, holy shit.
CHRIS COPLEY: There were some
legendary parties--
couple crashed cars, probably
babies conceived.
DANNY DAVIS: Here, it's not even
like, I'm going to the
Open and I hope it's really
good this year.
You're going because
it's the Open.
It's a different contest.
Contests are contests, but the
Open, it's a good vibe.
JACK MITRANI: I mean
snowboarding and competing
began for us at the US Open, so
it's cool to grow with the
contest itself.
CHAS GULDEDMOND: This is the key
event of the year for me
and always brings back
good memories.
You're always like, dude, I want
to do good here, because
it's the Open.
It's prestigious.
ABE TETER: Having that energy
in the crowd to back you,
you'll drop into the half-pipe
10 times faster than you
normally would.
And it's pretty much
undescribable.
CHRIS COPLEY: There's people--
it's funny--
they used to say, I met my
wife at the US Open, and
they're a third-generation
snowboarder now.
So this dude snowboarded.
He met some broad there.
And then they had kids, and now
their kids are riding in
the US Open.
So there's this progression
now that's pretty amazing.
And the Open has spawned
a lot more than
just progressive riding--
spawned some new riders.
[PUNK MUSIC]
-Made a huge run [INAUDIBLE]
[CHEERS]
[PUNK MUSIC]
-Huge.
[CHEERS]
[PUNK MUSIC]