But some...
...are better at it than others.
I said, wait, this isn't New York.
Well, how do we move through Europe,
without attracting attention?
What?
Attention. We have detected
wild animals on the loose.
Get me Captain DuBois from animal control!
Poor animals.
Now you deal with me.
It's the fuzz! What are we gonna do?
We can't just blend.
You know this ain't Africa.
You gotta let us in!
Go-go-go!
Thanks. We're gonna get off at the next stop,
so we can get back to America.
We're going to America as well!
What? Can we go with you?
Whoa.
This train is for circus animals only.
But we are circus.
What is your act?
Uuh...
Really?
In order to get home, we will come up with
something that will blow everyone away.
I'm on a tightrope!
Melmin?
No.
They'll do whatever it takes...
...to get back home.
Fire in the hole!
Whooo!
Well, that was worth the price of admisson.
You can run, but you cannot save your hide.
What are you doing?
Zebra's can't drive!
Only penguins and people can drive.
Oh, yeah!
Hey. This is not first class.
Has anyone ever told you that
you look like a supermodel?
Whoa! What a woman!