from Dr. Aaron Judkins - this is Genesis
Week.
[Music]
And a welcome to this episode of Genesis
Week, the weekly program of creationary
commentary on news, views and events
pertaining to the origins controversy,
proudly brought to you by CORE Ottawa -
Citizens for Origins Research and
Education, and exclusive right here on
youtube.  Excellence in underground
broadcasting, we we bring you the
information the anti-creationists don't
want you to see or hear, and we show the
glory of God in the Creation.  Once again
in the top ten most discussed videos of
the week in Science and Technology on
youtube.
Typing in wazooloo.com or
genesisweek.com, will help you find us, or
click the ever-so-convenient subscribe
link up top, and you can also peruse other
episodes by following the links in the
upper corners of each episode. I'm your
host, Ian Juby
It's Darwin's birthday this Saturday, so -
Happy Birthday Darwin. I'm sorry, you
probably won't like the present I'm giving
you.
Back in the 1930's, an unusual report of
fossil human footprints surfaced.  These
fossil human footprints were in
Carboniferous rock, near Berea,
Kentucky, and were examined by Dr.
Burroughs who founded the geology
department at Berea college.  Creationists
had talked about these tracks for many
years, and I managed to obtain a copy of
the reference: A Scientific American paper
from January 1940.  I took one look at the
pictures, and said "Nope, those are
carvings, not fossil tracks."  It turns out I
wasn't the only one who did this.
Talkorigins and Glen Kuban both show
these photos on their websites,
badarchaeology refers to the SciAm
article, and Institute for Biblical and
Scientific Studies also refers to the SciAm
article in mocking disdain towards the
creationary claim of fossil human
footprints in Carboniferous rocks.
In fact, the Scientific American article is
the source of the quote that so many a
creationist has cited:
David Willis, of Indianapolis had contacted
myself, as he wanted to go investigate the
Berea tracks, as well as an alleged fossil
human footprint that had recently come to
light in Tennessee. I was in Ohio at the
time, so we ventured down together.  We
spent the day in the archives at Berea
college and found a copy of the SciAm
article in Professor Burrough's archives,
and thus got our first shock of the day.
The photographs presented in the SciAm
article were not the Berean fossil
footprints!  In fact, if you read Ingall's
article carefully, you can read between
the lines and note that he never did say
the tracks pictured were the Berean
tracks - though the Berean tracks were
the focus of discussion in the article.
Ingall's article can only be described as
scandalous, but the scandal didn't stop
there: A second article published by the
Christian Science Monitor showed two
photographs, neither of which were
photographs of the Berean fossil human
footprints.  The upper photograph was a
pencil rubbing of a pair of the Berean
footprints, which the monitor claimed was
oily stains left over from molding the
tracks, and the lower photograph was
fossil amphibian tracks from some
unknown location.  Burroughs himself
noted in his personal correspondence
that the Monitor even went to the trouble
of displaying only ten tracks in the
amphibian ichnofossil slab - which "just
happened" to match the number of prints
found at the Berean site!
It's being gracious to chalk all of this up
to bad journalism.  A more accurate
description would probably be fraudulent,
deliberately misleading reporting.
So just what was the evidence then? Why
is it that although both Scientific
American and the Christian Science
Monitor had access to photographs of the
actual fossil footprints at Berea, they
instead showed photographs of what
were obviously Indian carvings and
amphibian fossil footprints?  Why did both
SciAm and the Monitor both then
interview "experts" and get their opinions
on photographs of Indian carvings and
fossil footprints that were NOT the
Berean fossil footprints?
David and I both obtained wax castings of
the fossil footprints, as the originals were
all cut out of the rock.  Much to my
surprise, they were genuine fossil human
footprints.  There is clear displaced mud
surrounding the footprints, and multiple
researchers noted the increased density
in the sand grains surrounding the
footprints, verifying that they were
genuine footprints.  The footprints are
clearly human as there is no creature -
fossil or living, that makes a footprint like
a human, and there is no doubt the rock
is assigned the evolutionary age of 250
million years old.
So why does it matter?
Although Richard Dawkins was referring
to alleged fossil human bones in the
Carboniferous, his point remains the
same: Evidence of humans in the
Carboniferous would "...blow the theory
of evolution out of the water." These
footprints are only one of many pieces of
evidence of humans in the Carboniferous,
and shows that, exactly as the Biblical
account of Creation points out, man has
been around since the beginning of time.
These casts are now a part of my new
"Fossil human footprints" exhibit which
will be going on display this spring.  I will
be detailing the Berean fossil footprints in
the current issue of CORE Ottawa's
CrEvo news, which should be coming out
any day now, you can sign up for the
newsletter here:
Science Daily carried a report about the
successful sequencing of the DNA of a
relative of the Neanderthals.  Called
Denisovan, these peoples are supposed
to be a representative of an Asian group
of extinct humans related to the
Neanderthals.  Taking samples from a
finger bone found in a cave in Southern
Siberia in 2008, the Max Planck Institute
for Evolutionary Anthropology in Leipzig,
Germany, funded the DNA sequencing
research.  The sequence was made public
yesterday, and is available on the web
here:
This is not the first time DNA sampling
has been performed on a person so "old."
In fact, Neanderthal mitochondrial DNA
has already been compared to humans.
Sean Pitmann Hey contrasted the
differences between a few sample
humans and the Neanderthals, and
showed that the Neanderthals had less
difference with humans than humans did
with each other!  To put it in crude form,
Neanderthals were more human than
humans were.
So we look forward to the comparisons
that will arise from this newly sequenced
DNA!  The point to be made here is not the
comparisons that can be made, but rather
the fact that the Leipzig group was even
able to sequence DNA that is allegedly so
old!  The estimates are that this finger
bone was 30,000 to 50,000 years old!  This
is already clearly outside of the Biblical
timeline, so if the bone really is that old, it
causes huge problems for Biblical
Creationists.  Is the bone really that old?
Scientific study would refute such an
idea. We've all seen the CSI TV shows,
which has popularized forensic science.
Forensic research is such solid science
that it stands up in a court of law!  People
are jailed and executed on the basis of
forensic evidence - thats' how solid the
science is.  Of course, there is much
interest in the deterioration rates of DNA
in forensic research.  And such research
has shown over and over again that DNA
just simply cannot last for tens of
thousands of years!
Denisova cave is in a temperate climate -
about the same elevation and latitude as
Drumheller, Alberta, Canada.
Dr. Daniel Criswell discussed the
technical details of the rapid deterioration
of DNA in the Spring 2009 issue of
Creation Research Society Quarterly
article "Neandertal DNA and Modern
Humans." The worst thing for
deteriorating DNA is moisture, and
warmth - two things that caves are well
known for!
As Criswell pointed out:
In other words - forget about an entire
DNA strand being preserved! The most
you can hope for is small fragments of
DNA sticking together for maybe 10,000
years.
Dr. Theodore Siek, writing in the
May/June 2010 issue of Creation Matters,
also discussed why DNA breaks down so
quickly.  In the words of Dr. Seik:
Not only is the Denisovan DNA
recognizable - apparently the scientists
were able to sequence the entire thing!
The remarkable preservation of the DNA
provides excellent evidence that this
fossil finger is much, much younger than
the evolutionists are proposing.
[scary, dramatic music]
Wahoo! Mail for me?
[sound of a geiger counter detecting a lot
of radiation]
Hmmmm... I wonder what it tastes like?
[sounds of someone drinking]
[scary, dramatic music]
Dr. Aaron Judkins wrote in regarding last
week's show:
Ironman left a comment regarding the
alleged evolving virus in the last episode:
Really? So evolution explains how the fig
tree survived for millions of years before
the fig wasp evolved?  Even though the fig
wasp needs the fig tree to survive, and
the fig tree needs the fig wasp to survive?
I could cite probably dozens of examples
like that.  Scientists weren't around 17,000
years ago - and scientists TODAY have
not figured out this "co-evolution", so
obviously it isn't written in biology
textbooks.
Actually, when I have asked evolutionists
to define evolution, THAT is the definition
I have been given. So you're not
disagreeing with me, nor is this
misrepresentation.  I would encourage the
viewers to do their own survey - go
around and ask people what their
definition of evolution is.  Go on!
PaulChartley finished his statement with:
.
Thank you for admitting that evolution fits
every scenario - that immediately
disqualifies evolution as scientific,
because it is then not falsifiable.
Evolution simply conforms to whatever
evidence it is presented with.  Thank you
for making my point.
A significant point, thanks for writing in.
Well let's deal with that right now: First of
all it is astoundingly ignorant to claim
there are no creationists with science
degrees.  They have already disqualified
themselves with that one claim alone.
But I am also immediately suspect of
anyone who starts asking about
credentials - why? Because credentials
have absolutely nothing to do with
whether or not the person is right. That is
a subtle ad-hominem attack.
Credentialed people make stupid
mistakes, and uncredentialed people
make stunning discoveries.  Secondly,
you'll please notice that such people who
ask for credentials use the lack of
credentials to reject anything you say, but
then embrace the writings of Darwin -
who's only earned degree was in
theology.
Now if you have scientific credentials,
they reject your credentials.  Dr. Jerry
Bergman- 9 degrees, two of them PHd's -
you don't get more credentialed than that,
but the very people who were demanding
my credentials in the very next sentence
were rejecting Dr. Bergman's credentials.
There's no nice way to say it - this is
called hypocrisy and bigotry, and it was
glaring in the comments of last week's
show - I encourage the viewers - go read
the comments for yourself.
In like fashion, the anti-creationists loudly
demand peer review - but they seem to
forget that "Origin of the species" was
never peer reviewed.  The only peer review
they will accept is peer review which
defends evolution and refutes creation -
therefore by their twisted definition, there
are no Creationary peer reviewed papers.
Actually, in fact there's been plenty of
creationists who have published articles
in secular peer reviewed journals - but the
anti-creationists reject those works.
Obviously - the anti-creationists areare
playing head games. Ask yourself: Would
you listen to someone who contradicts
themselves like that?  Hypocrites and
bigots disqualify themselves from any
semblance of credibility. They are not
reasonable, nor are they worthy of being
listened to. I have addressed these issues
partly in my newsletters, item #3 here,
and partly in CrEvo Rant #213
Let me see what I can do - I'm way behind
in video production, as I've got several
videos in queue which need to be
produced first, but sure - that is a fun
subject, and again, forensic science has
much to say on the matter.
Okay - that's enough for this week, I'm
your host Ian Juby.  Thanks for watching
and pursuing the truth with me - just
remember - Pilate asked "What is Truth?"
Jesus said "I am Truth" - we'll see you
next Thursday.
[music]
Production Software was provided for
Genesis Week by the Big Valley Creation
Science Museum, located just 25 minutes
north of Drumheller, Alberta. In the heart
of the dinosaur badlands, the Big Valley
Creation Science Museum was built from
the ground up to give credit to our
Creator, portraying the scientific evidence
showing that creation is the faith that fits
the facts, and that evolution is the faith
that the facts have failed.
Visit BVCSM.com for more details.