Two weeks after the so called Super Storm
Sandy hit the North Eastern U.S., there are
some signs of recovery in the region. Power
has been restored for millions of people,
some bridges and tunnels have reopened. But
signs of devastation and struggle are there
too. Officials say the storm is responsible
for at least 113 death in the U.S., more than
160,000 people still don`t have power. That
means they are fighting the cold as the temperature
drops. Homeland Security Secretary Janet Napolitano
says the priority is to get food, shelter
and clothing to these victims of the storm.
Some of that is coming from relief groups
and volunteers like this team from New Orleans
that cooked and served thousands of meals.
Now, if you`d like to get involved, go to
the spotlight section. It`s cnnstudentnews.com,
and click on the "Impact Your World" link.
Find out how you can make a difference.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Is this legit? Saudi
Arabia is the world`s largest producer of
oil?
It`s true. The Middle Eastern nation is home
to around one fifth of the entire world`s
existing reserves of oil.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: But Saudi Arabia might lose that number
one ranking by the end of this decade. A new
report says the U.S. will be the world`s top
producer of oil by the year 2020. The U.S.
is going through a sort of oil boom right
now, and part of that is thanks to new technology.
For example, hydraulic fracturing, which is
sometimes called fracking. It`s a process
that involves pumping water and chemicals
into the ground to cause rock formations to
fracture and release oil and natural gas.
It`s controversial, though. Some researchers
are worried that the process could hurt the
environment. That same concern, producing
oil versus protecting the environment is happening
up in the Arctic, where some companies are
planning to drill. Miguel Marquez has more
on that.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
MIGUEL MARQUEZ, CNN CORRESPONDENT: This is
the spot where America`s oil needs meets environmental
frustration and concern.
The Noble Discoverer, one of two rigs Shell
is operating in the Arctic, the rigs aren`t
drilling for oil, only putting in 1500 foot
preparatory wells that they`ll revisit and
complete next year when the real work begins.
Success here doesn`t come easy. In a setback,
Shell scaled back its drilling plants this
summer after a major piece of cleanup gear
and oil containment dome was damaged during
testing. To win drilling right, Shell has
paid for and equipped its own armada of cleanup
vessels. Environmentalists and some Alaskan
native say, the failure is proof the Arctic
is not ready for oil exploration.
(on camera): You can`t have success in a controlled
environment, how can you be confident you
can control it in the place like the Arctic?
PETE SLALBY, VICE PRESIDENT, SHELL ALASKA:
Well, first of all, we are working on this,
this is why we were testing the containment
dome to begin with. We were looking at a really,
say, it is a serial number one piece of equipment.
So the work we are doing is really working
to work all the bugs out of the problems before
we bring it up to the Arctic.
MARQUEZ (voice over): But oil from the Arctic
won`t come cheap and it won`t come easily.
Shell has already spent $5 billion just to
get to this point, and they are not entirely
sure what they`ll find down there. They believe
that as much as 20 percent of America`s future
oil needs could be below the sea floor where
I`m standing.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: The U.S. Navy is hoping to send a message.
It punished seven of its elite Special Forces
members, its Navy SEALs for releasing classified
information. Now, normally, this kind of punishment
would be handled privately. But not this time
around. The U.S. Navy made this punishment
public, because commanders wanted to let all
SEALs know that this kind of behavior is unacceptable.
Brian Todd now tells us what this is all about.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
BRIAN TODD, CNN CORRESPONDENT: You are in
their eyes, as they sprint through dangerous
terrain, dodge explosions, gun down their
enemies.
The new video game "Medal of Honor: Warfighter"
from Electronic Arts brags that it gives you
the experience of fighting with SEAL Team
Six. It`s given seven real members of that
team the experience of losing half their pay
for two months and likely their careers. At
least one of those SEALs was on the raid that
killed Osama bin Laden last year. A Navy official
says the seven, all active duty, have been
reprimanded for giving up classified information
to the makers of the game when they worked
as paid consultants.
(on camera): Why do you think they gave up?
JOHN MCGUIRE, FORMER NAVY SEAL: I wasn`t part
of the game, but making the game, but I heard
that they might have shown their equipment
that they used, and for some people that might
not seem like a big deal, but you put a little
piece of information here, together with another
piece of information there and you can get
some information to put people in harms` way.
TODD: John McGuire is a former Navy SEAL who
served ten years. He says one big problem
with what these SEALs did was that it was
not authorized by their commanders, but the
problems go beyond that.
This episode adds more controversy over SEALs
capitalizing on their reputation. John McGuire`s
got an outdoor fitness business based on his
experience. He had to clear the name of that
business 14 years ago with the Navy. There
was a recent movie, "Act of Valor" featuring
real active duty Navy SEALs, that was cleared
by the Pentagon. But there was also a book
written by a former SEAL who was on the bin
Laden raid. The Pentagon complained about
that for revealing secret information.
HARRY HUMPHRIES, FORMER NAVY SEAL: It`s gotten
out of hand. There is entirely too much being
discussed about a community that lives on
the fact that it`s a group of folks that thrive
on a concept called silent pride.
TODD: The SEALs lives are secret, their identities
classified. Still, one former SEAL disputes
the notion that the video game gave much away.
He says raids of militants compounds have
not suggested they use video games for intel.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today`s "Shoutout" goes
out to Ms. Litkenhus`s students at John F.
Kennedy Middle School in Plainfield, Illinois.
The festival of Diwali is observed by which
of these religions? Here we go, is it Taoism,
Hinduism, Shintoism or Baha`I? You`ve got
three seconds, go!
Diwali is a festival of lights in Hinduism,
the world`s third largest religion. That`s
your answer and that`s your Shoutout.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Diwali is one of the most important
festivals in Hinduism, it`s happening right
now, starts today and lasts for five days.
The word Diwali means "row of lights," and
that`s what you`ll see a lot of during this
celebration. Everything from small lamps to
lights to giant fireworks displays. For Hindus,
the Diwali festival represents the victory
of light over darkness, good over evil. It
also marks the start of a New Year, and it`s
a time when many Hindus exchange gifts and
offer prayers for a successful year. ` All
right. Our next report today is from Sara
Hoye. It`s about a program for teenagers in
Philadelphia that`s called "Cradle to Grave."
It takes place at a hospital, and the people
who designed the program hope that by bringing
these teens there as visitors, they can teach
them about the dangers of gun violence and
prevent them from returning to the hospital
as patients.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
SCOTT CHARLES, CRADLE TO GRAVE Welcome. I
work with gunshot patients. How many of you
guys know somebody who`s been shot?
SARA HOYE, CNN CORRESPONDENT: Philadelphia
educator Scott Charles is on a mission to
save young lives. Charles and Amy Goldberg,
chief trauma surgeon at Temple University
Hospital, co-founded the Cradle to Grave program
to help reduce gun violence in the city of
brotherly love.
CHARLES: What we are going to do today is
kind of take you behind the scenes, pull back
the curtain and let you see what we do ...
HOYE: The Cradle to Grave program brings local
high school students inside Temple`s trauma
center to relive the final 15 minutes of life
of a teen killed by gun violence.
CHARLES: That young boy stood over Lamont
(ph) and fired ten more shots into him.
AMY GOLDBERG, CRADLE TO GRAVE: You know gun
violence can kill. But I think it`s really
our responsibility to prevent these kids from
coming in.
HOYE: Among America`s largest cities, Philadelphia`s
homicide rate is the worst. With African Americans
making up 85 percent of the victims.
CHARLES: You know, statistics suggest that
as a young black man, you have a greater chance
of being shot and killed in Philadelphia than
you would have if you were a soldier serving
in the conflicts in Afghanistan or Iraq. That`s
absurd to me.
HOYE: Since 2006, more than 7,000 students
have come to the Cradle to Grave program.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Like I don`t want that
to happen to me. Like I want to be able to
live, be someone my mom wants me to be.
GOLDBERG: We want to really teach them the
preciousness of life. That in an instant your
life can be changed forever.
HOYE: Change they want for the better.
Sara Hoye, CNN, Philadelphia.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: Thanksgiving is next week. And this
year, we`d like to know what you are thankful
for. You can comment on our blog and if you
are at least 13 years old, you can tell us
in person through an I-report. Now, on the
I-reports, no music, just you and the camera,
this is your chance to get on CNN STUDENT
NEWS. Visit us at cnnstudentnews.com.
Today`s before we go segment is either incredibly
cute or incredibly creepy. Actually, it might
be a little bit of both. This is a slow loris,
and this is how a slow loris eats a rice ball.
It takes the rice ball slowly. It considers
the rice ball slowly. It nibbles the rice
ball slowly. Well, at least it lives up to
its name. For the record, it`s holding a fork,
but eating with its hand. So, no table manners.
You might think loris is a made up name, but
that`s why we show you videos like this, so
you know what the truth is and what the lore
is.
That`s going to wrap things up for us today.
For CNN STUDENT NEWS, I`m Carl Azuz.