Buddhism is one of the most ancient
belief systems in the world.
Buddhism is both a religion
and a philosophy.
Only your own understanding
saves you from suffering.
It is practised by over
350 million people today.
There are many people who feel
attracted to a religion
which empowers the human individual.
I am going to travel to seven
wonders of the Buddhist world.
Seven wonders
that give an insight
to the long and rich history
of Buddhism.
At each location I'll meet Buddhists
who will help me to understand
the different concepts that form
the core of Buddhist belief.
I'm going to explore how it started,
where it travelled
and some of the most spectacular
monuments built by Buddhists
right across the globe.
And to try to get to the bottom of
the attraction of this philosophy
for mankind
for close on 2,500 years.
Buddhism's numbers grow
year on year
and I'll be uncovering why
as I experience seven
modern and ancient wonders
of the Buddhist world.
This is north-eastern India,
where Buddhism began
around 500 years before Christ.
Millions of pilgrims come to this
country, and to the sacred
city of Bodh Gaya,
to visit the place where a young
Indian Prince underwent
a life-changing
personal transformation
and came to be known as the Buddha.
I've studied the period in history
when the Buddha lived
for over 20 years
and I just love it
because this was such a radical age.
This was a time when men
like the Buddha,
and Socrates in Ancient Greece,
turned the world of belief
upside down.
Instead of focusing on tradition
and convention and ritual,
they dealt with ethics and the
possibilities of the human mind.
And I'm particularly fascinated to
follow in the trail of Buddhism,
because as the philosophy has
travelled through 25 centuries,
it's marked out a path
that leads directly
from ancient society
to the modern world.
This is Mahabodhi,
the "great awakening" temple
in Bodh Gaya in north-eastern India,
our first
wonder of the Buddhist world.
The reason Bodh Gaya is here at all
is because two and a half millennia
ago, one man
had an internal, personal revelation
while he sat underneath
a peepul tree.
It's a very quiet, simple beginning
to end up with all of this.
That man was called
Siddhartha Gautama,
and we're told he renounced
his privileges and family
to embark on a rigorous quest.
A journey to understand the inherent
challenges of the human condition,
sparked by the suffering, sorrow
and deprivation
that he saw all around him.
It was a long
and difficult journey.
Siddhartha renounced
the comforts of the material world.
He meditated for weeks on end.
He broke with the status quo
in a region that had been
dominated by the old gods
for the previous thousand years.
Finally he achieved Nirvana,
what we loosely translate
as Enlightenment,
and became known as the Buddha
or "the enlightened one".
The Buddha,
according to Buddhist scriptures,
made his way to this spot,
and determined not to move
until he found an answer
to the world's suffering.
So, it was here, on one warm
spring evening, 2,500 years ago,
that the Buddha came to sit.
We are told that all night
he was tormented by demons
but then, as the sun began to rise
in the East, he found enlightenment.
The Bodh Gaya temple is the Mecca
of Buddhism.
It is where the Buddha
attained enlightenment
according to their belief
and the Bodhi tree, or a great-
grandson of the Bodhi tree,
still grows there.
So, Buddhists go there to remember
the great breakthrough
that was the Buddha's discovery
of the true nature of the universe.
And inspired by
the Buddha's example,
you'll find visitors here
from every corner of the globe,
from the 90 or so countries where
Buddhism still flourishes today.
Bodh Gaya is one of those key sites
for all Buddhists worldwide.
It serves as a magnet,
as a centre point,
for Buddhists from around the world.
You could say it's the place
exactly where Buddhism started.
I'm not a Buddhist, but if you ask
anyone who's involved in Buddhism,
they'll tell you that
it's a very difficult philosophy
to teach or to explain,
and that the very best way to
understand it is to experience it.
And so, by experiencing Buddhism,
I'm going to try to get to the heart
of a philosophy
that can sometimes seem complicated,
out of reach.
I'll start with the three
key principles of Buddhism -
what are known as
its "Three Jewels".
The first is the life
and example of Buddha himself.
All Buddhists are encouraged to
model their approach to life on his.
The most important single point
in the Buddha's teaching,
and one that distinguishes it
very sharply from other religions,
is that the Buddha taught
that each of us
is entirely and solely responsible
for our own lives
and our own salvation.
No-one else can be responsible.
The Buddha didn't claim
any divine status,
nor did he profess
to be a personal saviour.
He called himself
a guide and teacher.
His message appealed to people of
all social classes in ancient India,
to merchants, to farmers,
and to the Untouchable caste.
The Buddha, in the course
of his spiritual awakening,
rejected a good number of aspects
of Hinduism.
He rejected some philosophical
components of Hindu beliefs,
he was very critical of the
position of the Brahmins or priests
in society at that time,
which was a very elitist position.
He was similarly critical
of the caste system.
He positioned himself, as a result,
outside of the caste system.
The Buddha spent his remaining years
travelling through deep forests,
across mango groves,
from village to village.
The curious would bring
food and clothing
for the philosopher
and his band of followers.
And, in turn, he encouraged them
to reconsider the purpose
and point of life,
to recalibrate their moral compass.
Although the Buddha didn't establish
a church or temple system as such,
over time, the significant
locations in his life
were gradually turned into shrines.
Originally Bodh Gaya was just
a pastoral sanctuary,
marked out with
a stone balustrade,
200 years or so after his death,
but by the 6th century AD,
a full-blown temple,
the Mahabodhi Temple,
marked the spot.
About 400 years after,
the first temple,
that was built here for the
worshiping of the Bodhi tree,
was replaced by this kind
of a temple, built to enshrine
the iconic image of Buddha, which
had gained currency by that time.
The temple,
particularly the Mahabodhi Temple,
is representative of how important
Buddhist temples were,
and how, you know, this idea of
building a temple to enshrine statues
started from here.
As Buddhism's travelled through
the centuries,
perhaps inevitably, it's taken on
more the aspects of a religion,
with temples and pilgrims
and a religious hierarchy.
You could be forgiven
for mistaking Buddhism
as one of the great,
god-driven faiths of the world,
but there is a key difference.
By putting such an emphasis
on a system of personal morality
and breaking with the conventions
and traditions
and rituals of the past,
in many ways, the Buddha was
one of those men
who gave us the modern world.
And although he never denied
that there were gods,
he simply said
you don't have to rely on the
gods to make everything OK.
According to Buddhist sources,
having seeded a radical
new world view,
the Buddha died at the age of 84.
His body was cremated
but his bones remained unburned.
They were distributed amongst the
various tribes, rulers and kingdoms,
who are now starting
to follow the Buddhist way,
and who honoured its founder
by building monuments, or stupas,
over his remains.
In Kathmandu, the capital city of
Nepal, stands The Bodanath Stupa,
our second wonder
of the Buddhist world.
It was first built in the 5th
or early 6th centuries AD,
then rebuilt and restored
a number of times,
finally as this giant,
enclosed tomb in the 14th century.
It is the largest
in the Indian subcontinent,
a sacred place for thousands
of Buddhists throughout the world.
Here at Bodanath,
I am going to find out more
about the three jewels of Buddhism.
Buddhism consists,
as far as Buddhists are concerned,
in three things
which they call the three jewels.
Those three things
are closely connected.
The first is the Buddha,
the founder of their religion.
The second is called the Sangha,
and that is the community
of monks and nuns.
The third is called the Dharma.
The Dharma refers to the preaching,
the teaching of the Buddha.
In other words, it's what the Buddha
discovered and it's also the truth.
As you walk around the Bodanath,
here, you always have this sense
that you are being watched
and that's because
the Buddha's all-seeing eyes
are always staring down at you.
That squiggle in the middle of his
face, incidentally, is not his nose,
it's actually the Sanskrit character
for the number one,
to represent a kind of
unity in the Buddhist faith.
Something you won't find represented
up there are the Buddha's ears,
and there is a particular
reason for that.
We are told that the Buddha said
he never wanted to hear
that he was being worshipped.
And of course, that is what is so
unique about Buddhism -
this is a religion without
a central authority figure.
Instead there's just this credo
that man is his own lord and master,
that mankind itself
can control humanity's destiny.
It's not atheistic, because
they do believe in the existence
of, sort of, Gods and angels and so
on, but they simply don't believe
that those beings
have the universe under control
and therefore they cannot
save us from suffering.
They themselves need
saving from suffering
from a future time
when they cease being gods
and they become beings that are
vulnerable to pain and suffering.
At the Bodonath Stupa,
one of the many people who come
to circumambulate and
to pay their respects to the Buddha
is Ani Choying, a Buddhist nun
famous throughout Nepal
for her sweet singing voice.
She is, in fact,
known as the singing nun.
This is a very highly spiritual
place, we consider.
It's a holy place, and we believe
that all the great relics of the
Buddha's are in the stupa
and it holds a very special
religious spot.
And every people
who come around here
are always reciting mantras
and really focusing
on meditation,
they do the circumambulation,
prostration,
to keep the physical healthy
and the mind, to be energy clean,
chanting mantras
as well as doing prayers
so trying to put yourself
in a very good, positive discipline.
This is a very,
very highly blessed place.
Ani is originally from Tibet.
Thousands of Tibetan Buddhists
now live in Nepal as refugees.
The brand of Buddhism is as much
Tibetan as it is Nepalese.
Flexibility and diversity has always
been one of Buddhism's strengths.
The Buddha himself
said there should be no one
official Buddhist language.
Instead, Buddhists are encouraged
to focus on the universal relevance
of the Buddha's wisdom.
There are some people here
who will tell you that
buried deep in that stupa
is a fragment of the Buddha's bone.
Now, I'm not certain that we're
going to be able to prove that
but what is sure
is that this is the biggest stupa
in the whole of Nepal
and one of the largest in the world,
and it is immensely impressive,
but do you know what's
significant about it, actually
is not how it looks
but what it means
because this was built to represent
something very special.
For the men who created this,
this was nothing less than
incarnation of the Buddha's mind.
The symbolism of the stupa
is very interesting because
it takes the elements of
earth, water, fire, wind and space,
different shapes
that represent those,
and they put them in an ideal
aesthetic form,
and so the idea is that
the Buddha's mind is the awareness
that the universe is the ideal
environment for the human being
to achieve freedom from suffering.
Around the Buddha
gathered men who shared with him
a common vision and goal.
Gradually, this group
came to be a formalized community,
a body that took its name
from the old aristocratic councils
of the day. The Sangha.
The Buddhist Sangha became
a monastic tradition,
comprising ordained monks and nuns
and it's one of the three
jewels of Buddhism.
My first experience of the Sangha
came at what felt
like an ungodly hour.
At Bodanath every morning,
just after dawn, monks of all ages
gather to perform the first of many
rituals of the day.
The Sangha is one of the oldest
continuously active
spiritual organizations
in the world.
LOW CHANTING
What's being recited here
is a Tara Puja,
it's a chant that aims to ensure
a kind of liberation from suffering.
And it's really interesting
because "Tara" is thought to be
a female manifestation
of Buddha's wisdom,
something which is
incredibly potent.
I mean, this isn't just
an abstract idea of wisdom
this is thought to be healing,
to actually be stronger
than medicine itself.
DRUM BOOMS AND BELLS RING
The Sangha includes
women and was set up
to allow those who wish to
practise Buddha's teachings
a disciplined environment
and maximum time
to focus on the philosopher's ideas,
free from the responsibilities
and distractions
of a domestic or
conventional lifestyle.
A few miles outside Kathmandu,
Ani, the singing nun,
runs her own nunnery.
It's a refuge for girls,
many as young as ten,
the age both sexes can embark
on the life of a Buddhist novice.
SINGING
I have here mostly
girls from families who are
facing some difficulties,
obviously poverty,
and the other thing is
the fathers are often very ignorant.
They get carried away with the
alcoholic behaviour, as well.
Very abusive behaviours, and they
do not think that it is good
to send their girls to school,
so I try to collect them here,
and give them a much
as I can give them.
Controversial for its time
was the inclusion of women
among the ranks of the Sangha.
The Buddha allowed women
to become nuns,
to lead a life devoted
to spiritual development.
Like Buddhist monks, nuns
are expected to remain celibate,
pure, since they are one
of the three jewels of Buddhism,
not just Buddha's foot-soldiers
but an incarnation
of the belief system itself.
So, I've learnt about two
of the three jewels of Buddhism.
The Sangha
and the life of the Buddha.
But what about the third jewel,
the Dharma, or teachings?
You can, perhaps, help me out a bit.
How do you describe Dharma?
What does Dharma mean to you?
According to my understanding,
what Dharma is
to do whatever you do,
very practically, skilfully,
for the benefit of all beings,
without causing any harm,
and for their wellbeing,
including oneself and all, is Dharma.
SHE SINGS:
Dharma means the purity of heart.
Dharma means peace,
and Dharma means wellbeing
of all human society.
Are there special ways
that you can achieve Dharma?
Are there rules and regulations
that show you what to do?
We are taught what causes suffering
and what can cause suffering,
and how to avoid causing suffering
in life, one's own life.
And when you implement
those teachings
I think that is what really
contributes towards
one's own wellbeing
and others' wellbeing,
and I think that
is considered Dharma.
In the Buddhist context,
the word Dharma refers, above all,
to the teachings of the Buddha
as he rediscovered them
in the process of his progress
towards enlightenment.
The reality of the Dharma
which holds you free from suffering,
is what they take, the root of the
word Dharma, which means to hold,
and the Buddha said Dharma
holds a being free from suffering.
Coming here to Nepal, it has been
relatively straightforward
to identify two of the jewels
of the triple jewels of Buddhism.
The Buddha himself,
both ideas about him and his image,
are absolutely everywhere,
as is the Sangha,
and here in Kathmandu,
there are monks and nuns
at every street corner,
but what has been harder to pin down
is the Dharma itself,
the belief system,
the philosophy, the religion,
whatever you want to call it,
of Buddhism.
Maybe it's unrealistic of me
to expect there to be
one single definition
for such a broad concept.
The Buddha himself said
the Dharma was like
the salt of the oceans of the world,
a universal taste.
So, the Buddha implied the Dharma
could be tasted anywhere, by anyone,
but the question for me,
as a historian,
is how that "taste" of the Buddhist
Dharma could become "universal",
practically,
how Buddhism established itself
as a global belief-system.
Buddha's teachings were charismatic
and radical for their time,
but, as with all big new ideas,
they needed a groundswell of popular
support or a patron, or both,
to gain a firm foothold
and to really fly.
While there was grassroots interest
in what he had to say,
it was about 200 years after the
Buddha's death that Buddhism
got a major boost.
In 250BC, the ruthless, all-powerful
emperor Ashoka,
who controlled most of ancient
India,
proved Buddhism's greatest ally.
Ashoka was haunted by the memory
of the blood that he'd acquired
on his hands as a result of the cut
and thrust of his rise to power
and he decided to turn to "the good"
and in order to realize
that ambition
he vigorously promoted
Buddhist ideals
right across the
Indian subcontinent.
According to Buddhist tradition,
in the centuries following Ashoka's
sponsorship of Buddha's ideas,
the philosophy evolved into
at least 18 different schools.
One of these, the Theravada,
still survives today
and is mainly associated
with south and southeast Asia.
Another came to be called
the Mahayana,
the "Great Vehicle" or "Way",
now most often found
in north and east Asia.
Ashoka, by embracing Buddhism,
put a particular emphasis
on the consequences of his actions,
on what he thought
and how he lived in the world.
On his Karma.
Karma is a word
well known in the west today.
It has its roots in
early Indian belief systems,
but the value of Karma became
a fundamentally important
Buddhist concept,
and one that I am going to explore
at...
..our next wonder
of the Buddhist world.
Sri Lankan Buddhists believe
that the tooth relic
was brought to their country
around 300 BC.
Safeguarding the relic
became the responsibility of kings
and over the years,
the custodianship of the relic
came to symbolize the right to rule.
The Buddha is said to have given two
legacies to future generations -
the body of his teachings,
the Dharma,
and also relics of his physical
body itself,
which are now scattered
in shrines right across the globe,
and one of the most precious is kept
in here, in the Temple of the Tooth.
That relic makes the presence of
the Buddha more graphic to people,
so it gives them a power.
Actually, many Buddhist temples
around the world have relics,
a piece of bone or something,
just as in Europe,
you have relics of saints,
so it's a way of making the person's
presence feel more immediate.
That gives the temple more power,
as a magnet to draw the worshipper.
The shrine stands right at the
centre of a paved courtyard.
The ceiling is decorated with
moonstones and floral designs.
There are ivory reliefs
on the doorways.
The inner chamber contains the
tooth relic and other sacred objects
and all around there is
a brightly painted corridor.
DRUMMING AND WIND INSTRUMENT
Monks conduct daily worship
in the inner chamber of the temple.
Rituals are performed at dawn,
at noon and in the evening.
The tooth is in this upper chamber
in a casket of gold
and is only revealed
to a chosen few.
The sacred relic
is symbolically bathed
with an herbal preparation made from
scented water and fragrant flowers.
This holy water is believed
to contain healing properties
and is distributed
among those present.
Once a week, mothers gather
at the temple with their babies.
All these little babies
are waiting to be taken in to
be blessed by the priests
so that they have
Buddha's power with them
for the rest of their lives.
They're given a white piece of
string to wrap around their wrist
which shows that the Buddha is
with them from now until they die.
It's thought incredibly important
that they get the blessing
at this early stage
because everything
that they do from now on,
all their intentional actions,
what they think, what they say
and what they do, their karma,
will affect how they are then
reborn in the next life.
Karma is one of the main concepts
of Buddhism.
It is the belief that
any of our intentional actions,
both thought and deed,
will be mirrored by something
similar happening to us in future.
So, if you harm someone,
someone will harm you.
This principle of cause
and effect can bring consequences
that are either good or bad
depending on what it is you've done.
Because Buddhists believe we have
many lives, this good and bad karma
can generate consequences
both throughout this life
and long into the next.
Karma is what you do. The word
literally means deed or action.
But the Buddha said
that all Karma that matters
is what is morally good
or morally bad,
and you decide what to do.
Now, we must remember
that for Buddhists,
your life goes on beyond what
we normally think of as this life.
In fact, you are reborn
an infinite number of times
until you manage
to bring that to an end.
Buddhists use a metaphor
to help explain what karma is.
They say that
if you sow thistle seed,
then you can't expect
apple trees to grow,
and that is very clear. It's a basic
principle of cause and effect
and as a historian, I know that
that principle has real validity.
We are all affected by our past
and our past and our present
together informs our future
so when the Buddha said
that we should be mindful of our
intentional actions, of our karma
and that our highest authority
is our conscience,
than he was making real sense
and he was also clarifying something
about what it is to be human.
Of course, the issue is that
karma can be both good and bad.
And in Sri Lanka, the fallout
of action and reaction,
of cause and effect, has been
brutally tested in recent years.
For nearly three decades,
the country has been locked
in a violent civil war,
in which close on 100,000 people
have been killed.
Sri Lanka is only now emerging
from this debilitating conflict
between the Hindu Tamil minority
and a Buddhist Singhalese majority.
The Temple of the Tooth
was badly hit
and partially destroyed
during the war.
It has now been fully restored.
Buddhists believe this cycle of
death and destruction can be broken.
They assert that by following
a certain path, it is possible
to break out of a continuous
round of life and death and rebirth,
which in Buddhism has a name.
Samsara.
And Samsara is the concept
I am going to investigate now
as I move to the next wonder
of the Buddhist world.
Once Buddhist ideas
had flourished in Sri Lanka,
Sri Lankan monarchs sent emissaries
to adjoining kingdoms
in southeast Asia to carry
the Buddhist message.
By the 11th century,
Theravadin Buddhism was
well established in Thailand
and here in Bangkok, close on
90% of Thais are now Buddhist.
The reason that Buddhism
has thrived so vigorously
and tenaciously here is because
right from its very outset,
it's had the support
of the Thai kings.
A king here can aspire
to be a Buddha himself
and there is one king who was
actually a monk for 25 years
before he came to the throne.
Every time the royal family
builds a new palace for itself,
it will also constructs next door
a monastery and a temple complex
as a kind of outward sign of its
righteousness
and commitment to the Buddhist cause
and here in Bangkok, the temple
complex is certainly fit for a king.
This is Wat Pho, our next wonder
of the Buddhist world.
It's the largest and oldest
temple complex in Bangkok.
It's home to more than
1,000 Buddha images.
The complex includes a temple,
a working monastery
and a large courtyard
with a forest of stupas,
thick with exquisite
hand-made lotus motifs.
And hidden within its own
palatial hall...
the golden reclining Buddha.
The gold Buddha is 141ft long
and 49ft high.
Started in 1788,
it took over five years to build.
This one of the most
stunning, gobsmacking
works of monumental art
I have ever seen.
I have to say I love its audacity,
I love the fact that it says,
"Look at me, look at what
mankind can do
"when he manipulates raw materials
to create a thing of beauty,"
because here there are thousands
of fragments of mother-of-pearl used
and a 153 plates of gold,
but what it doesn't seem
to me to say
is that this is an incarnation
of the Middle Path,
that essential Buddhist notion that
extremes and excesses
should be avoided at all costs
because there is no doubt that
this is a thing of opulence.
It's enormous, it's gorgeous
and it's very sensuous.
In history of Thailand
there are a lot of large-scale
reclining Buddhas built all
over central part of Thailand,
because to build a reclining Buddha,
it's not a very easy process
because most of the reclining Buddha
is not made from casting
it's made from bricks,
plaster, or cement.
It's considered
very respectful image,
so it must be decorated with
very valuable materials
and, of course, the most
valuable materials
for decorating the image
of Lord Buddha should be gold.
Gold in Buddhism symbolizes
the sun, or fire.
The most valuable of metals,
it is accorded a sacred status
through its association with Surya,
the sun god of the Hindu pantheon.
For Buddhists in Thailand,
and other South Asian countries,
gold is an element that
signifies homage.
A gift of gold is the ultimate
demonstration of one's piety.
The meritorious act
of putting gold leaf
on the surface of a Buddha's skin
is to commemorate the living Buddha,
who had a golden-like aura,
a radiance, they believe.
But gold and its association
with wealth and might
is also the way Thai monarchs have
used a showy form of piety
to forge a strong relationship
between Buddha's ideas
and the power of the state.
It was King Rama III
who had the statue of the reclining
Buddha opulently restored
at the height of his reign
in the mid-19th century.
It's called the Lion Pose,
so, as he lay there in the lion
pose as he was preparing to die.
It's described that he lay
down on his right side
and he rested his head
on his right hand.
There is a reason that this Buddha
has got such a serene smile -
it's because he has achieved
enlightenment, Nirvana.
It means that he has escaped what
Buddhists call Samsara,
an endless cycle of life,
of birth and death,
of passion and desire and delusion,
that can only lead
to pain and suffering.
Samsara effectively constitutes
a cycle of birth and re-birth,
and as long as we are in Samsara
we are born innumerable times
and moving from one existence
to the next.
We can be re-born as a human being,
as a divinity,
or you can be re-born
as an animal, etc.
'Tell me what you think Samsara is?'
For me it's not just
a physical picture
of, you know, the circle of being
born and ageing and dying,
for me it has something to do with
the state of mind as well.
That you have to deal with your bad
emotions if you have problems,
if you're suffering, you have...
feel frustrated,
you don't know how to deal with it,
but this is just a small sample
of bad things that happen to you,
just keep go on and on and on,
can find a real peace or happiness.
The wheel of life is a common
visual depiction in Buddhism.
At the time Buddha started to teach,
many understood life
as a relentless cycle,
where all were born, grew old, died
and were re-born in another life.
It was an eternal morass,
from which there was no release,
but Buddha felt that
an escape was possible.
He taught that
through one's actions,
karma, and through a way of life
that was characterized by wisdom,
morality and compassion,
via meditation and the triumph
of the mind over craving,
desire and excess,
it was possible to achieve
enlightenment, Nirvana.
He believed that this enlightenment
would empower ordinary people
to break free from Samsara.
THEY CHANT
This idea gives Buddhist funerals
a distinctive character.
Those present mourn their loss,
but also hope that, thanks to their
beloved's good karma,
the dead are at least one step
closer to enlightenment,
that they have the chance of
a re-birth as a better being
who one day can escape Samsara.
What goes around comes around,
and that's what I believe,
this body is just like a house that
we rent for a while.
After we die we have to find a new
place to live,
it's impermanent,
it's just temporary.
So, good Buddhists believe that we
should do our best in this life
to guarantee a better place
after we die.
Buddhists say that there
is only one certain way
to break free from Samsara,
to eliminate the desires,
and the passions,
and the distractions
of everyday life.
Now, of course, that is very easy
to say and it's very hard to do,
so over the centuries Buddhists have
employed specific rigorous methods
to break free from all of this,
from the troubles and the
temptations of the real world,
and to set themselves on the path
to enlightenment, to Nirvana,
and that is the truly radical thing
about the Buddha's example,
his belief that each
and every one of us
has the capacity
to achieve liberation,
to achieve our own enlightenment.
It took the Buddha years to arrive
at this radical belief.
Ideas he developed through his own
personal experience -
in particular, an intense
form of meditation.
And it is Buddhist meditation
that I'm now going to experience
in our next wonder
of the Buddhist world.
Buddhism continued to spread
throughout the Mediaeval period.
Come the 13th century
and Buddhism was flourishing
in the Khmer Kingdom...
modern-day Cambodia.
The temple complexes here at Angkor
are our fifth wonder.
Angkor Wat began life
as the sacred palace complex
of a Khmer Emperor who,
in fact, favoured Hinduism
over Buddhist ideas.
These aren't just buildings,
but have a grand ambition.
The whole complex is said to be
a symbolic representation
of Hindu cosmology.
The original temple honoured
the Hindu god Vishnu
and incarnates the centre of the
physical and spiritual universe,
a mythical mountain.
A series of five rectangular walls
represent other mountains
and the moats here evoke
the cosmic ocean.
This place reeks of a combination
of earthly and divine power,
and of the close-knit relationship
between gods and kings.
And, of course, it was a belief
in that relationship
that inspired the creation of this
complex in the first place,
but for some people it was
just TOO exclusive,
too strictly hierarchical...
and Buddhism offered a solution.
It was the Khmer Emperor Jayavarman
VII who converted to Buddhism
and his regime marked a clear
dividing line
with the old Hindu past.
Before 1200, art in the temples
mostly portrayed scenes from
the Hindu pantheon.
After his conversion, Buddhist
scenes began to appear
as standard motifs.
During his reign, there was a focus
on building libraries,
monastic dwellings, public works,
and more "earthly" projects,
accessible to the common people.
So history in Cambodia
takes a humanist turn
and as Buddhism rises in popularity,
you find images of the Buddha and
his followers emerging everywhere
in the architecture...
in gates, in walls and in temples.
So now Angkor is showing
the world a more human face.
The Angkor complex is a prime
example of the classical style
of Khmer architecture.
By the 12th century,
Khmer architects had become skilled
and confident in masonry,
facing the monuments with intricate
sandstone blocks.
Angkor Wat is famous for the harmony
of its world-class design.
Architecturally, towers shaped
like lotus buds are characteristic.
Half-galleries broaden
the passageways,
other galleries connect enclosures
and terraces appear along the main
pathways of the temple.
The walls are decorated
with bas-reliefs
showing Hindu mythological figures
and detailed narrative scenes.
This one depicts the churning
of the oceans.
Other elements of the design have
been destroyed by looting
and the passage of time.
They included gilded stucco,
gold on some figures,
and elaborate carved ceiling
panels and doors.
This was the largest sacred
building in the world.
Although there is an eerie,
crumbling beauty to this place now,
you have to imagine
it in its heyday.
All this stonework would have
been brightly painted
and in this corridor there would
have been many hundreds of
statues of the Buddha,
wrought out of precious gold.
The light from the statues would
have been reflected back
from the walls,
which would have been studded with
emeralds and sapphires and rubies,
and outside there would have
been crowds of monks,
their eyes closed in meditation,
their faces lit by the glow of
torches made out of jungle resin.
Since Buddhism is primarily
an educational system,
meditation is a key component
of that educational system.
Meditation is the way you become
viscerally and directly aware
of all these deep connections and
connectivenesses to the universe,
and you have to become
directly aware of it
to become free of being controlled
by unconscious processes.
And that freedom is liberation,
that freedom is Nirvana.
I'd been invited by a group
of trainee Buddhist monks
to experience meditation for myself.
Members of the Sangha can spend
hours each day meditating.
The way they sit, the position
of their hands,
is copied from the practice
of the Buddha himself.
They are still and concentrate
on their breathing...
not doing anything to alter
the way they breathe,
not worrying about whether
they're doing it right or wrong,
clearing their minds of thoughts,
of feelings, of fear and anger...
of the distractions
of the outside world.
Just following the breathing
and becoming one with each breath.
I can't say I've managed to
completely block out the
sound of the world going on
and it feels hard to stay
this still for so long,
but if someone were to ask me if
I had any anger in my head
or my heart right now,
I would have to say there is none.
The Pali Canon advises that
there are particularly good
places to meditate -
a mountain, a hillside,
a rock cave, a cemetery,
an open field, an open forest,
the root of a tree,
deep in the jungle.
And this place certainly fits
some of those criteria,
but I have to say,
I'm probably going to carry on
meditating in my own sweet
way for a while.
I am not quite ready yet
to do the deep breathing
and the lotus position.
But still I have huge respect
for the practice of meditation,
not least because it is
a firm vote of confidence
in the power of the human mind.
It suggests that in order to
transcend the difficulties
of this world,
we don't just need to appeal
to a higher, divine authority...
but to look to our own
consciousness.
Well, certainly the people of
Cambodia have had more
cause than most
to find internal resources to deal
with the troubles that the world
has thrown at them.
Cambodia has suffered some of the
worst violence and genocide
of the last century.
Between 1968 and 1976, over 3
million Cambodians were killed
in the war that engulfed Vietnam and
other countries of southeast Asia.
This was then followed
by the terror and genocide
unleashed by the Khmer Rouge,
a communist movement that ruled
Cambodia for four years.
The Khmer Rouge dealt particularly
viciously with Buddhism.
Thousands of monks were slaughtered
and monasteries were destroyed
and if people tried to hold
on to their beliefs,
they were often tortured and killed.
But gradually, as the nightmare
is beginning to fade,
Buddhism is finding its feet here
again and when you come to Angkor,
you'll find little active shrines
like this tucked away into corners.
In Cambodia, Buddhism is slowly
reasserting itself.
This country, which had experienced
such horrors, is now peaceful
and Angkor, which had
been brutalized
by the Khmer Rouge regime,
is now a world tourist
site once again.
It's been very moving
coming here to Cambodia
because this place has been the home
to the most dramatic twists and
turns in the fortunes of Buddhism.
For centuries, Buddhism was
the philosophy of choice,
for both the kings and the people,
and then thanks to the horrors
of the Khmer Rouge,
there was a chance that it was
going to be eradicated
virtually overnight.
But gradually, gently,
it is now making a comeback
and there's even a possibility
that this place,
which was once the biggest and most
active Buddhist complex
in the world,
could be that again,
some time in the future.
While in Cambodia Buddhism
is emerging out of the darkness
of the Khmer Rouge regime,
Buddhism in mainland China,
and here in Hong Kong,
is also reasserting itself,
an ancient tradition
reappearing in modern society.
Buddhism is on the rise once again,
partly perhaps because its positive
attitude feels well-suited
to an emerging superpower.
Particularly popular
is the Zen form of Buddhism.
Little surprise given that Zen,
although now typically
associated with Japan,
started off life in China.
And I'm going to explore Zen
in one of the places in the world
where it is most vigorous...
Hong Kong.
Our sixth wonder
is the giant Buddha that overlooks
this great Asian city.
This mammoth bronze statue
was completed in 1993.
It symbolises the relationship
between man and nature,
people and religion.
The building
of the giant Buddha in Hong Kong
was a reassertion
of an old Buddhist tradition
of constructing
massive Buddhist images.
And the monks who initiated
the project in Hong Kong
had visited Japan, and they'd visited
various sites in mainland China
and seen medieval massive images
of Buddhas,
and this was something they
were trying to re-create in Lantan.
It's the only statue of Buddha
to face north towards Beijing,
and is named Tian Tan after
the Temple of Heaven in that city.
When Buddhism first starts out,
it seems that people actively
choose not to represent
the Buddha figuratively.
But then as the philosophy passes
through regions like Afghanistan,
which had a really
strong Greek influence
thanks to the invasion
of Alexander the Great,
it becomes the done thing to
represent the Buddha in human form.
Now, once the belief system
enters China,
a new tradition gains popularity.
Not just to represent
the Buddha in human form,
but to do so on a monumental scale.
And that's an art form that's now
being revived here in Hong Kong.
Everything about this statue
means something.
The Buddha is sitting
in a lotus position,
which shows that he was like
the beauty of a lotus flower
emerging from the muddy waters
of a pond.
His face is that beautiful
round shape, which is supposed
to be a reflection
of the perfection of the moon.
And his head is domed,
which tells us just how wise he is.
His hands are interesting
because the right hand
is raised in a gesture of blessing.
This is the Buddha's vow
that he will release the entire
world from its suffering.
And on his chest he's got
that so-called Swastika symbol.
Of course the Swastika
was unfortunately appropriated
by the Nazis,
even though they got it
the wrong way round.
But what it actually means
is the power of the universe,
so this tells us that the Buddha's
compassion and wisdom
is available to all.
The Buddha statue sits
on a lotus throne
on top of an altar.
It's surrounded
by six smaller bronze statues.
They're shown offering gifts
like fruit and incense,
gifts that symbolise different
aspects of Buddhist philosophy,
all virtues which are necessary
to achieve enlightenment.
The giant Buddha is part of the
Po Lin monastery and temple complex
set up nearly 100 years ago
by three Zen masters.
Zen has developed as a part
of Mahayana Buddhism,
the school of Buddhism
practised in China
and other northern Asian countries.
Zen Buddhists believe that
all people have the qualities
that the Buddha had,
and emphasise that these can be
developed and were not unique
to the Buddha only.
The aim of Zen is to discover
this quality within each person,
through meditation and practice
of the Buddha's teachings.
The ultimate goal is to become
a completely enlightened Buddha.
Meditation has always
been central to Buddhism,
but here in China a new
brand of meditation was born,
and it took its name from
a Sanskrit word Dhyana which
is actually very hard to translate,
but it means a kind of
alert, productive state of mind.
In China it was called Chan
and when it travels to Japan
it becomes Zen.
It's a school of Buddhism which
lays enormous emphasis on certain
kinds of meditative practice.
What you try to do
is purely to empty your mind.
It has an ideology that rational
thought is not going to get
you to enlightenment or Nirvana.
It's practised here
in a small secluded monastery,
minutes away from the giant Buddha.
Formal silent meditation
is central to Zen
and is practised by both the laity
and the ordained together.
Some people find the concept
of Zen quite difficult to grasp.
How would you define it?
So Zen means we never
separate our life and our practice.
Zen is like 24 hours
when you are standing,
sitting, walking, lying down,
so never separate.
You know, our everyday life
and our practice cannot separate,
it's not two things.
Zen also means inside,
inside, you know, our mind,
and outside objects, inside and
outside both become one, that's Zen.
So if you're not making
that separation between
Zen practice and everyday life,
does that mean that when you do
everything, when you sweep the floor
or prepare food or clean something,
that is an act of Zen itself?
Zen means what are you doing now,
you know.
So somebody might get enlightenment
while they are eating meal,
washing bowl, all these were designed
to help people be in the moment
and maybe at that moment
your mind becomes clear
and your life becomes clear.
THUNDER RUMBLES
This is called water bowl meditation
and the purpose is to carry the
water without spilling a drop.
The idea is that you can do this
through the application of Zen,
because if you think
you're carrying a bowl of water,
you're bound to shake and lose some
but if you clear your mind
completely, you will complete
the task successfully.
In the West a lot of people
have heard of Zen. It's something
that is quite popular.
Do you think that's partly because
people's lives are so demanding
and Zen offers a way out from that?
Not only the West are very busy,
now Asia is more busy! It's true!
It's very money-oriented,
everybody worry about the living,
so it's very important
our mind know how to relax
and to be living at this moment
and to keep clear.
If you can live in this present,
even if some problem appear, it's OK.
You have this clear mind
and you are not agitated.
I think these are very important
practice for everybody.
Zen practitioners today
don't like to use specific words
to limit what Zen is,
but if you want to find
a definition for the practice,
probably as close as you'll get
is that this is something
that really believes
in the power of intuition
and in a productive simplicity.
I can see that cherishing
intuition, living for the moment,
living day by day,
with a clear mind, is a very
productive way to spend your time.
Perhaps it explains why
of all brands of Buddhism, Zen
has become particularly attractive
to those who live
in our demanding 21st century.
Zen, and its ancestor Chan,
is a very practical
form of Buddhist wisdom.
It encourages a process
of rediscovery by living simply.
The Zen tradition emphasises
that enlightenment is possible
here and now.
Is it then very different
from other forms of Buddhism?
Zen means pointing directly to our
mind, it means right now wake up,
and be clear,
what are you doing now.
Actually, our mind is not
complicated.
It is our thinking with our life
that is very complicated.
So Zen is a tool to help us
to bring back our mind
to our everyday life and be simple.
Zen, like all Buddhist practice,
turns philosophy into a tool
to help in day-to-day life.
Meditation is also used
to bring about a tangible outcome,
either in the understanding
of the world or in our ability
to deal with it,
and with the suffering we
see all around and feel within us.
One thing that struck me
was that whatever the regional
variations of Buddhism,
issues of suffering are right
at the core of the philosophy.
Now that is really interesting
because in general
over the last 2,500 years
the cultures of the East have been
very unabashed about suffering,
they don't mind putting
it centre stage.
Whereas in the West, these are
issues that we can sometimes
try to brush under the carpet.
In the modern age, for instance,
we've been accused of trying
to cheat death itself.
But just look at that statue,
there's the Buddha promising to deal
with all the suffering in the world.
So it does make you wonder
what future Buddhism
has as a global belief system.
What's going to happen
when ideas of the East,
which put suffering to the fore,
start to take root in the West?
Buddhist ideas and philosophy
have become increasingly popular
in the fast-paced and highly
competitive world of California.
New Age concepts mixed
with the counterculture
of the hippies in the 1970s
have made words like Karma
and Nirvana commonplace.
Buddhism offered a spiritual life
and an emphasis on morality
without being too authoritarian.
Buddhism initially spread
into the West and especially
the West Coast of the United States
in the 19th century, thanks
to Japanese and Chinese labourers
brought in to work on the railways.
In Los Angeles, the first
Buddhist temples were set up
at the turn of the century.
Today, the city is home
to one of the largest
Buddhist temples in the West.
Hsi Lai Temple at Hacienda Heights,
our seventh wonder
of the Buddhist world.
Here I am going to try
to understand what has to be
the most important Buddhist concept,
the ultimate goal
for Buddhists, Nirvana.
The planning and construction
of the temple in the 1980s
was met with suspicion and
resistance from local communities.
The building of the temple
at its current location survived
six public hearings
and 165 explanatory sessions.
Finally, in 1985, the temple
was granted a building permit.
It was completed in 1988.
I tell you what there
is definitely a wealth of here,
and that is Buddhas.
I have never seen so many.
There must be 10,000 or something.
Yeah, there are over 10,000
Buddhas here, big and small.
And if you look at all the Buddhas,
you may find some names there.
It's a Chinese practice
that people make an offering
and then to have the name
of the family. It's their Buddha.
And it's also a form of supporting
the temple,
they come in and say
"I have a Buddha in there".
It's like the connection
between the Buddha outside
and the Buddha inside.
One of the many American Buddhists
who come to the temple is Mario Cee.
He became a Buddhist six years ago.
There are some who'd say
that the attraction of Buddhism
for many Americans
is that it's pleasingly mystical,
it comes from the East
but at the same time it ties
in with an "anything goes"
materialist lifestyle.
How do you speak to that?
I don't mean any disrespect by this,
but I have some friends
who use Buddhism
and Eastern religion,
Eastern philosophy,
and they mix it up with New Age,
and that's OK, if it works for them,
but my concern is that
it is that sort of anything goes,
you know, it's a free market
in spirituality. Whatever I'm saying
and thinking today is fine.
Because we have these core teachings
in Buddhism, it keeps us in check,
so we don't go into anything,
"If it feels good, it's OK."
We're really trying to avoid that.
Buddhism gave me a discipline
without a necessity of a God
to reward me or punish me.
There has been a tenfold
increase in the number of Buddhists
in Europe and America
over the last 40 years.
Most observers put the figure
at between two to three million
practising Buddhists in America,
with the number of Buddhist
"sympathisers" estimated
at over 10 million.
The His Lai temple is one example of
the modern expansionism of Buddhism.
BUDDHIST CHANTING
Many Buddhists come to the
His Lai temple for worship...
..others come
to practise meditation.
In the West, there's recently
been great interest in yoga,
simply as a way to keep fit
and as a form of meditation.
Yoga has its roots in Indian
traditions that predate
both Hinduism and Buddhism
and it's sometimes used by Hindus
to assert mind over matter.
For Buddhists, yoga's key purpose is
to achieve personal enlightenment.
It is a very
ancient philosophy, Buddhism,
but in some ways do you think
it is very suited to American life,
because it does have
this kind of can-do attitude.
It's very suited to America.
One reason is that we've been
materialistic, we're known for it,
and I've found in my experience, it
doesn't get you where you want to be.
I can't believe that I'm alone
in that, I can't believe that.
It offers reasons why that is.
I'm sure other people, like me,
who can't understand why all
this stuff didn't make them happy
would be looking for something else.
I'm not surprised that it is popular.
It's not against any other religion
and it's not against science.
It's very in line with everything.
The temple then offers American
Buddhists lots of reasons to visit.
But if you're a devotee of Buddhism,
then one of your main motivations
for coming here
is to seek enlightenment...
..Nirvana.
I'd love to be able to tell you
that I've got a textbook definition
for what Nirvana is,
but considering the Buddha himself
said it was beyond words,
beyond logic,
I suspect it is going to be
quite a tricky concept to pin down.
Nirvana certainly
is a state of mind,
and it's a state of mind
in which you have
abolished strong emotions
of very much wanting things
or very much hating things
or being confused.
It's a state of mind
which you attain, and, at that
moment, and thereafter,
you will enjoy
a kind of blissful calm.
And that path, is the end of that
path, Nirvana, is that your goal?
Yes, Nirvana, enlightenment,
full understanding, awakening.
Those are all terms that are very
similar and, to me,
it's understanding the truth,
understanding what this is,
what it really is.
How confident are you that Nirvana
is a goal you are going to attain?
I am cautiously optimistic -
how about that?
There are people that say
that it's very possible,
and these are people
that are very smart people
and I'm following their advice
and I think it can be done.
I think it can be done.
Like so much in Buddhism,
Nirvana clearly has
to be experienced, not explained.
But for Buddhists, the journey
to get there, the path you take,
seems to be as important
as the arriving.
Buddhists will tell you that Nirvana
has no fixed point in time or space.
That's actually a little ironic
because one of the few accepted
fixtures of the Buddhist story
is where the Buddha himself
found enlightenment.
We're told that that took place
in Northern India
under the spreading branches
of a peepul tree.
Which is where my quest had started,
at Bodhgaya, at this spot
where it's said Buddhist philosophy
really began 2,500 years ago.
In this journey I have explored
key facets of Buddhist belief
and got a little closer
to understanding something vital
about the core of Buddhist
philosophy, the Dharma.
The Dharma is simply
the way the world is.
We can all best live our lives
if we follow a path
that allows us to deal
with the world as passionately,
as compassionately,
as positively
and as wisely as possible.
Now, whatever the permutations
and interpretations of Buddhism,
that seems to me to be pretty simple
and pretty enlightened.
I've learnt about Karma, how mindful
actions impact on our lives,
about Samsara, the cycle
of life, birth and death,
about meditation, about Zen,
and the final goal
for all Buddhists, Nirvana.
I have seen some of the most
beautiful architecture
inspired by Buddhist ideas
and how, after 25 centuries,
Buddhism still attracts
millions across the globe.
A philosophy that is rooted
in its ancient past and yet
gives character to the modern world.
How Buddhism places
the responsibility to realise
the truth on all of us.
As Buddhism travelled,
it transformed the cultures
it came into contact with,
just as it too was transformed.
You wonder if Buddha could ever
possibly have imagined the impact
that his ideas
would have on human history,
particularly given the one thing
he was certain about,
was that impermanence and change
were the only things
that were definite in this world.
Just listen to this - it's one
of his most poetic epithets.
"So shall you think
of all this fleeting world.
"A star at dawn,
a bubble in a stream,
"a flash of lightning
in a summer cloud,
"a flickering lamp,
a phantom, and a dream."
Well, the Buddha's dreams of 2,500
years ago are still with us
and they've been made incarnate
in one of the most tenacious
belief systems of all time
and in some of the most iconic and
beautiful monuments in the world.
Subtitles by Red Bee Media Ltd
E-mail subtitling@bbc.co.uk