trade war with Russia over the
right to produce vodka.
It was the first time that
Poland officially tried to
claim the drink as its own, but
it would not be the last.
This is the story of
the Vodka Wars.
So where are you taking us?
I want to go to a
big, big club--
huge club.
TAXI DRIVER: Yeah, porno.
IVAR BERGLIN: Yeah?
TAXI DRIVER: Yeah.
IVAR BERGLIN: No, not porno.
Just a big, big club.
[LAUGHING]
TAXI DRIVER: What.
Cinema?
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
IVAR BERGLIN: I'm taking the
tour of Moscow on vodka.
[HOUSE MUSIC PLAYING]
IVAR BERGLIN: Keep going.
TAXI DRIVER: [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
IVAR BERGLIN: Look at that.
Look at that.
And look at that.
Now, have some vodka.
No.
TAXI DRIVER: Yeah.
[CLUB MUSIC PLAYING]
IVAR BERGLIN: These guys are
going to send me around the
world, it turns out, to find
the origins of vodka.
I need you to show me--
TAXI DRIVER: Show me.
IVAR BERGLIN: --the first
piece of Russian vodka.
Where do I need to go?
You gotta keep it going.
TAXI DRIVER: [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
[ACCORDION MUSIC PLAYING]
MALE SPEAKER: [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
IVAR BERGLIN: I'm Ivar, and I
work for VICE in Scandinavia.
I do a lot of different
things--
lots of the shit jobs no one
else wants to do, really.
But in New York, they think I
don't do anything at all.
It's a bit of a bummer, except
that it works out pretty good
for me, because every once in
awhile, they call me up and
tell me to pack my things
on a moment's notice.
I'm getting to do another
doc for VBS.
Eddy, my boss at VBS in New
York, called me and said he
had an idea to make a film
called The Vodka Wars.
It sounded nuts.
Vodka war?
For me, it's good time juice--
something you put into a
cocktail, not something
you fight over.
Well, in Russia and
Poland, it is.
These two nations have been
fighting over who invented the
drink for years.
For them, it's a matter
of national pride.
And apparently, it's a reason
to literally go to war.
I was hooked.
I had no idea that Poland
made vodka.
Like most people in the rest of
the world, I thought vodka
came from Russia.
Where is vodka from?
MALE SPEAKER: Russia?
IVAR BERGLIN: Russia?
MALE SPEAKER: Russia.
IVAR BERGLIN: Russia.
MALE SPEAKER: Maybe Russia.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Russia.
FEMALE SPEAKER: I
think Russia.
think Sweden.
MALE SPEAKER: Poland.
FEMALE SPEAKER: From Russia?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Poland.
IVAR BERGLIN: Poland, Russia.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Yeah.
IVAR BERGLIN: OK.
So I needed to do some
more investigating.
First off, Mother Russia.
[CAPTAIN OVER INTERCOM,
INDISCERNABLE]
IVAR BERGLIN: I'm following the
American elections, but
more important, there's
a new club opening.
We're going there tonight.
11 suspects have been charged
over a smuggling operation of
vodka from Russia to
Estonia via a two
kilometer underwater pipeline.
They're even building
pipelines to
get their vodka across.
This was my first trip to
Moscow, so like any good
tourist, I went straight
to Red Square.
My first Russian interviews
were awesome.
FEMALE SPEAKER:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
IVAR BERGLIN: Vodka?
FEMALE SPEAKER:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
IVAR BERGLIN: That's great.
That's what I always say.
Lenin.
MALE SPEAKER: Mr. Lenin
MALE SPEAKER: Mr. Stalin.
IVAR BERGLIN: Mr. Stalin.
Nice to meet you.
MALE SPEAKER: Welcome
to Moscow.
IVAR BERGLIN: Thank you.
Do you know where I could find
some good vodka around here?
MALE SPEAKER: Vodka?
IVAR BERGLIN: Yeah.
MALE SPEAKER: Be careful
with Russian vodka.
If you drink it, only with
the food, understand?
And Russian women-- is
a danger, understand?
IVAR BERGLIN: Russian
women are dangerous.
MALE SPEAKER: Dangerous, yeah.
IVAR BERGLIN: Yeah,
if you drink too
much vodka, they are.
After palling around with Lenin
and Stalin, we headed to
the Russian vodka museum, where
they were celebrating
500 years of Russian vodka.
As soon as I got into the
museum, they stuck me in a
screening room and showed
me the history of Russia
according to vodka.
NARRATOR: [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
IVAR BERGLIN: Oh, thank you.
ALEXANDER NIKITIN:
You're welcome.
What is your name?
IVAR BERGLIN: Ivar.
ALEXANDER NIKITIN: Ivar.
IVAR BERGLIN: And you are?
ALEXANDER NIKITIN: Where
did you come from?
Alexander.
IVAR BERGLIN: I'm from Sweden.
ALEXANDER NIKITIN: Very
good, Sweden.
IVAR BERGLIN: Yeah.
ALEXANDER NIKITIN: Very good.
With please.
IVAR BERGLIN: So can you
tell me a little
bit about this museum?
ALEXANDER NIKITIN:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
IVAR BERGLIN: So who owns
this collection?
ALEXANDER NIKITIN:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
IVAR BERGLIN: All these things
are 500 years old?
ALEXANDER NIKITIN: [RUSSIAN].
IVAR BERGLIN: [RUSSIAN]?
No.
[LAUGHING]
IVAR BERGLIN: But how old
is Russian vodka?
ALEXANDER NIKITIN:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
IVAR BERGLIN: How do
you know that?
ALEXANDER NIKITIN:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
IVAR BERGLIN: Do you have a
document or something to show
me where I can see that
it's written down?
ALEXANDER NIKITIN:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
IVAR BERGLIN: So "Russian
Vodka, an Illustrated
History."
ALEXANDER NIKITIN:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
IVAR BERGLIN: Russian culture
and vodka, I'm guessing.
ALEXANDER NIKITIN:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
IVAR BERGLIN: In what bar can
I see this today, tonight?
ALEXANDER NIKITIN:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
IVAR BERGLIN: So the museum
was a little light on any
evidence regarding the Russian
origins of vodka.
But this isn't just
about vodka.
It's about Russian
nationalism.
And vodka, like oil and gas, is
just another commodity that
can be traded for power.
To really understand the Vodka
Wars, we had to understand who
the hell we're dealing with.
What is modern Russia
really like?
To learn more we had to meet
the KGB all the way back in
Washington, DC.
Oleg Kalugin is a former KGB
general that now lives in
Washington, DC.
Oleg knows old Russia and new
Russia, and he explained the
complexities of both to us.
OLEG KALUGIN: Well, let
me put it this way.
In the Soviet days, we
had three pillars--
Communist Party, bureaucracy,
KGB,
military industrial complex.
After the collapse of the
USSR, it's Russian
government, KGB, 70%.
Second--
private business, most of them
connections with the KGB, and
criminals who also
have connections.
It's all under one roof.
And that's what makes Russia an
entirely different country.
This is the fusion of
government, private
enterprise, and criminal
elements.
That's what Russia is today.
IVAR BERGLIN: Sometimes, after
a night of good, clean vodka
fun, it's good to get naked and
beaten with branches, even
if it's by a dude.
[SHOUTING]
IVAR BERGLIN: Gives you time to
really think about stuff.
If cleared my mind and reminded
me that even though
Oleg's Russia is kind of
ominous, it actually was
Poland the that the
first shot in the
world's first Vodka War.
In the fall of 1977, a trade
war took place between USSR
and Poland.
Known as the Vodka War, it
saw Poland claim in the
International Trade Court that
vodka first came from Poland.
As such, only they had the right
to call their product
vodka, and all others, including
the USSR, had to be
labeled bread wine.
At first, the Soviets dismissed
Poland's claims as a joke.
But when they realized their
small neighbor was serious,
they ask well-known historian
and Soviet patriot William
Pokhlebkin to investigate.
This dude claimed that vodka was
first instilled in Moscow
in 1440, decades before it
apparently appeared in Poland.
Based on his research,
the court ruled
in the USSR's favor.
Poland lost the first
Vodka War.
Recently, many academics have
disputed Pokhlebkin's work and
this date, 1440.
Pokhlebkin died in 2000, but we
managed to find his friend
and publisher in Moscow.
We wanted to know more about
the man that wrote the book
that squashed Poland's
vodka ambitions.
BORIS PASTERNAK:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
IVAR BERGLIN: Pokhlebkin?
BORIS PASTERNAK: Pokhlebkin.
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
IVAR BERGLIN: Was the book
"The History of Vodka"
well-received here in Russia?
BORIS PASTERNAK:
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
IVAR BERGLIN: Pokhlebkin's
book can't be trusted.
In fact, one academic was
particularly blunt.
"If you read this book, keep a
strong bottle of vodka by your
side to stun the more thoughtful
parts of your
brain." So we went looking for
some evidence of our own.
We went to Oxford, England to
find out something that we
thought would be
crystal clear--
the origins of the
word "vodka."
NINA KRUGLIKOVA: The origin of
the book "vodka" is not as
crystal clear as it may
seem at first sight.
Most Russian speakers would
consider it to be a word of
purely Russian origin.
And even the first etymological
dictionaries of
the Russian language did
not include this word.
Some Slavonic scholars think
that its origin can be traced
to the Polish language, to
the Polish word "wodka."
IVAR BERGLIN: Most dictionaries
have the word
"vodka" spelled with a V. And
the Poles have it spelled with
a W. How come the West
excepted the V
as its common spelling?
NINA KRUGLIKOVA: I'm not sure
about this question.
But it might get back
to that particular
case in 1972, I think.
No, 1982--
the year [INAUDIBLE] was given a
priority to produce vodka as
the Russian original alcoholic
drink and has exclusive rights
on its advertising under this
label in the international
market, as the book says.
IVAR BERGLIN: Is that right?
NINA KRUGLIKOVA: It depends
on what you mean by right.
IVAR BERGLIN: Do you think that
vodka might be Polish?
NINA KRUGLIKOVA: I think
that there is great
likelihood of this.
IVAR BERGLIN: So I went all the
way to Oxford just to end
up right back with Pokhlebkin's
book, "The
History of Vodka." Bummer.
If Pokhlebkin's book isn't to
be trusted, why didn't the
Poles fight back with some
evidence of their own?