had here. He's got a square nail, some burnt
wood. So we decided, let's map this off. Let's
figure out exactly what's going on here. Kind
of starting to peter out right here. Me too,
it's almost like it shut off. I got perfect
hits all on this side, nothing on that side.
Right here I start losing it. It's almost
like I got a straight line here and a straight
line here. I wonder if it's like the corner.
We think it's the corner of the house so we
decide to just rope it off. This is our chance
to do something gigantic. This isn't just
any old foundation out in the woods. On a
site this important we're going to stop and
call the Kentucky State archeologist and turn
the site over to them. We're here to do a
preliminary assessment of the site. There's
already been preliminary metal detecting to
locate concentrations of artifacts so now
we are beginning with very small excavation
holes that we will use to understand the deposits
here. Here look at this. This is window glass
and this is one of the artifacts that I'd
been hoping we'd find. This is as good as
finding a piece of gold, you know we didn't
have to find this to prove it's a house but
it's a great find. We have found some pretty
interesting evidence that we have the Randall
McCoy house site here.
Diggers: Hatfield's and McCoy's airs Tuesday,
January 29 on the National Geographic Channel."