ADRI MURGUIA: The following
morning, Faustino began making
the last preparations before a
trip to the Green Lake, which
is a day's horse ride away.
We would spend the
night there.
And so we needed to take enough
supplies to get us
through our stay.
The Green Lake was the
first piece of land
he owned out here.
And it was also central to
his cattle business.
He hadn't returned for
over four years, but
we didn't know why.
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
ADRI MURGUIA: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
ADRI MURGUIA: It's a tent.
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
ADRI MURGUIA: Every inch of land
that we crossed over to
get to the Green Lake
belongs to Faustino.
It was a six hour journey.
We were only halfway there.
And the crew felt exhausted
by the attacks of the
blood-sucking horseflies.
But Faustino and Marcos were
unfazed, even by the
blistering sun that barely
sets during the summer.
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
ADRI MURGUIA: When we finally
arrived, after six hours of
riding our horses, and
encountered Faustino's
settlement that he had left
behind, we started
setting up our camp.
And Marcos began cooking
the lamb we had
killed the day before.
MARCOS LANCASTER:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
MARCOS LANCASTER:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
MARCOS LANCASTER:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
MARCOS LANCASTER:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
MARCOS LANCASTER:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
ADRI MURGUIA: Faustino would
spend every summer here and
oversee his cattle.
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
ADRI MURGUIA: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
MARCOS LANCASTER:
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
MARCOS LANCASTER:
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
MARCOS LANCASTER:
ADRI MURGUIA: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
MALE SPEAKER: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
MARCOS LANCASTER:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
ADRI MURGUIA: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
Yeah, yeah.
ADRI MURGUIA: We were finally
starting to wind down and
couldn't wait to have our
only meal of the day.
[SPANISH]
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
ADRI MURGUIA: Prime
Patagonia sheep.
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
[AFFIRMATIVE GRUNT]
ADRI MURGUIA: Fresh.
I think Marcos is going to
take over the land when
Faustino finishes
his time here.
He's inheriting this
whole thing.
He lives in O'Higgins
and he has a family.
But he's planning on
bringing them here.
I don't know, I don't think he's
trying to take advantage
of him or anything.
Seems like a nice guy.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
MARCOS LANCASTER:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
ADRI MURGUIA: After spending
the night, we gathered that
Faustino hadn't returned to
the Green Lake since 2007,
when his nephew started stealing
his cattle and
selling the meat in
nearby towns.
Due to his age and the vast
amount of land on this
property, it was impossible
for him to keep it under
constant surveillance.
Feeling powerless over what was
happening to him, he let
his cattle run free and brought
in Marcos Lancaster to
take care of it, but more
importantly, to protect him.
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
ADRI MURGUIA: It's impossible
to understand who Faustino
really is, when like his nephew
or brother, we have a
very limited view of the life
of a man that has spent most
of his time on Earth alone.
He shared some stories with us,
but who knows what he's
chosen to keep to himself.
And it's difficult to say
whether or not we would have
liked to meet him 30 years
ago, when he was very
different, given the few things
we know about him now.
Here's an 81-year-old man that
is kind and welcoming.
And it might seem natural
to see him living alone.
But he makes it look so simple,
when the few days
we've been here have proven that
we couldn't have survived
without him.
As we made our way back to
Faustino's home, we have to
get ready to return
to New York.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
ADRI MURGUIA: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
After spending four days with
him, it's impossible to
imagine spending a lifetime in
Chilean Patagonia, imitating
the way of life of the original
gauchos, something
Faustino Barrientos is
trying to preserve.
[MUSIC PLAYING]