HANNAH BROOKS: Hello, I'm
Hannah, I'm an addict.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
HANNAH BROOKS: I went to a rehab
like this about a year
and a half ago.
I know how hard it is.
It's a really, really
hard thing to do.
And I think you're all
very, very brave.
To be here.
[CLAPPING]
[CHANTING]
HANNAH BROOKS: Thankfully
I didn't come to
Indonesia for treatment.
And I'm not here to interview
this group
of recovering addicts.
I'm here to buy a
pair of shoes.
[CLAPPING]
[CHANTING]
HANNAH BROOKS: I'm at a drug
treatment center called YAKITA
in Bogor, an area about 60
kilometers outside Jakarta.
Indonesia experienced the
beginnings of an unprecedented
drug epidemic in the 1980s.
Sparked in part by rapid
economic growth and the
increasing availability of new
drugs, Indonesia found itself
facing a crisis it had no
idea how to handle.
A couple, David and Joyce,
founded the center in 1999 in
response to the growing
problem.
DAVID GORDON: The drug of choice
that really kicked it
off was ecstasy in the '80s, in
the early '80s, because it
became the love drug.
And it was in the
discotheques.
It was in the night life.
And from there it immediately
dropped to heroin.
And then in the late '90s
is when shabu shabu
methamphetamine began
to surface.
HANNAH BROOKS: In the past
decade, shabu shabu has
overtaken heroin as Indonesia's
drug of choice,
with meth labs popping up all
over the country, making it
cheap and easy to access.
DAVID GORDON: There was no
recovery in the country.
Hospitalization was
unheard of.
Rehabilitation was unheard of.
It was too big.
Where do you start when
nothing's been started?
HANNAH BROOKS: While YAKITA is
a center for men, they also
run a program for female
addicts and partners of
addicts, focused on providing
support, skills, and income.
These women design and produce
sandals called junkies.
I love the name.
And I really want a pair.
So we go to the workshop where
the junkies are produced.
DAVID GORDON: We were just
thinking about what we could
do, in a sense of what they
call vocational training.
What we call just trying
to get some
jobs for young people.
HANNAH BROOKS: Dian showed
me around the workshop.
DIAN:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
HANNAH BROOKS: As none of the
women had made shoes before,
their initial designs were
simple slip on sandals,
thongs, ballet flats,
and some bracelets.
While Joyce oversees the
project, the women design and
assemble the shoes themselves,
and have the final say about
what becomes a junkie shoe
and what doesn't.
So how do you guys
know each other?
Is it through meetings, or the
center, or just through here?
OK, are you guys friends?
Best friends?
BFF?
You too?
Do you do lots of shopping?
That's your new addiction,
is it?
I find it really, really funny
that they're called junkies.
What do you guys think
about that?
So you can kind of see
the humor in it now?
JOYCE DJAELANI: We chose that
name together because we felt
in the past addiction,
junkies, is a
negative part of you.
But how do you change that
into something that's
empowering?
So changing the connotation
of the word junkies into
something that's positive.
[SPEAK FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
HANNAH BROOKS: So you're
an addict?
Can I ask what your drug
of choice was?
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
HANNAH BROOKS: Dian explains
that she grew
up in a broken home.
She left when she was 14 and
began selling heroin for her
brother, becoming addicted
in the process.
Did you ever get busted
when you were
helping them deal drugs?
DIAN:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
HANNAH BROOKS: That's
pretty ballsy.
[LAUGHTER]
HANNAH BROOKS: Wow.
In Indonesia, shabu is kind of
taking over as the big drug.
ANITA:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE].
HANNAH BROOKS: Home delivery.
That's convenient.
ANITA:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
HANNAH BROOKS: A lot of women at
the center have lost their
spouses to drugs, including
Novi, who was addicted to
heroin for the past 16 years.
And do you just buy
it up the street?
From your husband.
Your husband was a heroin
addict too?
Sorry to hear that.
JOYCE DJAELANI: We began to
think also in terms of how to
keep the women coming and not
to be dependent on their
spouses, who were
still addicts.
How can they generate
a little income?
A sort of type of livelihood for
them to continue coming to
the center.
So they are able to have some
money to actually pay for the
bus to come over, have some
money for their daughters to
go to school, so that
was how it started.
HANNAH BROOKS: So
did you struggle
with relapsing initially?
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
HANNAH BROOKS: Yeah.
JOYCE DJAELANI: It's not like
being in a factory, where
you're timed by whatever
it is you create.
But actually just by making
the sandals together and
sharing your life stories,
it becomes so fluid.
And everybody gets to
know one another.
It's empowering for everyone.
HANNAH BROOKS: And so are
you practicing Muslims?
And with your drug use in the
past, how have the two things
kind of sat together?
Has that been really
difficult?
ANITA:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
DIAN:
HANNAH BROOKS: Oh, wow.
Did you have a hard time
finding veins?
DIAN:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
HANNAH BROOKS: So you were
injecting in your feet.
DIAN:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
HANNAH BROOKS: And, I mean
did you overdose?
DIAN:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
HANNAH BROOKS: Have a lot of
people in your life died?
DIAN:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
HANNAH BROOKS: A hundred.
DIAN:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
DAVID GORDON: A lot of the young
people that are with us,
that have HIV, and they have
AIDS, and they have
tuberculosis, they don't have
any way to pay for medicine.
And we thought this would be a
really good way to generate
jobs where a bunch of the young
people could actually be
there and make these sandals,
and then we would be
able to sell them.
HANNAH BROOKS: Would
you guys like to
model some of the shoes?
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
HANNAH BROOKS: What about
the black ones?
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
HANNAH BROOKS: I
have big feet.
Shoe sizes run small
in Indonesia.
But the women eventually found
a pair that fit me, made from
a local batik.
Yeah, they're nice.
Dian glued the label onto my
very own pair of junkies.
JOYCE DJAELANI: If they were
not addicts, they would not
end up in these programs, and
learn so much about life and
living and getting a family that
really cares about them.
And that's what's important
for them.
[MUSIC - JINGLE PUNKS]