SUROOSH ALVI: Since it was the
Muslim holy month of Muharram,
which is especially significant
for the Shia, we
decided to head to Sadr City.
It's Friday.
We're going to check
out the big prayer.
Apparently, it's a
sight to be seen.
Everybody prays on the streets
for a huge distance from the
mosque all the way out.
Now, just a few years back, the
idea of Westerners paying
a little visit to Sadr City
would have been unthinkable as
it was the heart of the
insurgency against the
American occupation--
the home of firebrand cleric
Muqtada Al-Sadr
and his Mahdi Army.
Even now, it took a lot of work
and a Mahdi Army escort
to get us in.
It's supposedly forbidden
to fight during
the month of Muharram.
But with heightened Sunni-Shia
tensions, the Iraqi army
thought it was a good idea to
have the bomb squad present
just in case.
-[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
SUROOSH ALVI: More than 13,000
people turned out to pray and
to listen to a cleric who
influences the attitudes of an
even greater number of
Iraq's Shia majority.
METHAL AL-HASNAWI:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
SUROOSH ALVI: How do you feel
about the westernization of
Iraqi youth since the American
occupation and
since they've left?
METHAL AL-HASNAWI:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
SUROOSH ALVI: The cleric made
it clear that getting the US
out of Iraq wasn't enough.
He wants to eliminate American
influence of any kind.
We headed back to the
neighborhood of Karrada to
meet up with Waleed and get
a tour of his old haunts.
Hey, welcome to Iraq, buddy.
Welcome home.
Waleed wanted to check out
Acrassicauda's old practice
space, that is, if
we could find it.
There's a strange feeling
walking around, considering
the last time I was here I
wasn't even allowed to get out
of our armored car.
WALEED: It's been a very, very
long time since I've last
walked this street.
This is filled with memories
of starving nights with the
band hitting the shit out of the
instruments, rocking out,
and trying to figure out--
how the fuck are we
going to go back home?
SUROOSH ALVI: This is basically
10 years ago.
WALEED: Yeah.
This is it.
SUROOSH ALVI: It's
been rebuilt.
WALEED: Yep, completely
changed now.
SUROOSH ALVI: It's like
art galleries.
If we hadn't been sure this was
the spot, we would have
walked right by it.
The practice space got
completely bombed
out during the war.
And today it's unrecognizable,
which I guess is a good thing.
WALEED: The area changed
so much that it
looks completely different.
SUROOSH ALVI: Waleed wanted to
see if his childhood home was
still standing.
But on our way there, we were
re-introduced to one of the
most notorious features
of Baghdad--
checkpoints.
Car bombs are such an issue in
Baghdad that hundreds of the
checkpoints that were originally
established by the
American military are still
in place today.
WALEED: Look at this
fucking shit, man.
Have you noticed, every street
has a checkpoint, every area
has a checkpoint of
entrance and exit.
It's so sad.
Literally, you have to plan
your day to the T.
SUROOSH ALVI: Because it
slows everything down.
Not only does it make getting
around a nightmare, but doing
anything other than staring
straight ahead and hoping you
get through can throw your
entire day into a tailspin.
Put it down.
What are they saying?
You can't film?
WALEED: They're like, don't
film near a police patrol.
SUROOSH ALVI: After inspecting
our press credentials and
undergoing a thorough search, we
were allowed to slowly make
our way to Waleed's old house.
WALEED: Everything
is blockaded.
You can't really access the
house or the neighborhood.
So we had to turn around, go
all the way back, and then
come through here.
SUROOSH ALVI: Did it get bombed,
this neighborhood?
WALEED: Yeah, and it looks
pretty fucking different.
That's pretty fucking insane.
This used to be my
old library.
It's like a fucking
junkyard, man.
SUROOSH ALVI: Right before
Waleed left the country, he
received a series of
death threats.
His work as a fixer for foreign
journalists and as a
member of a heavy metal band
made him a target.
WALEED: I'll show
you right here.
So at 6:00 in the morning,
I would leave.
And there was a note right here,
an envelope, right here.
And when I opened it, it was a
very, very frank letter of--
we shall cleanse the soil of our
country from the stench of
people like you.
So I went kind of crazy, and I
went into the street, and I
started screaming and yelling,
like if you're a man just come
up right now.
I came back after two weeks, and
I left at a different time
this time in the morning.
And there was another
one of those.
SUROOSH ALVI: Waiting for
you when you walked in.
WALEED: Waiting for me.
So what I realized is that the
person who had dropped it had
to have been watching over from
somewhere around here,
where he can see me leaving the
apartment and going down.
And that's when I knew that
the danger was very, very
imminent on my family
because of me.
So yeah, three days after
that, I was in Jordan.
SUROOSH ALVI: But the death
threats against anyone who's
not on the straight and narrow
continue to this day.
And as we would learn, these
threats are not empty.
-[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]