HARVEY FOSTER: I liked pulling
into that bowl and just being
like, what there's a
skatable bowl here?
Where are we?
Is there electricity here?
-No, I've done it twice.
-I just smoked weed.
-I've dranken six beers.
-It's only day one
of the trip.
If it was like day 9 and we
were closer to San Diego.
Will you get that Medevac
thing out?
[LAUGHTER]
-Right?
HARVEY FOSTER: I like all
the contrasts, man.
Mexico's really laid back.
And beer's cheap, and the
smokes are cheap.
And there's no pretty girls
anywhere, so I'm not getting
trouble with my woman.
That's good.
-You just want an excuse to hack
shit up with a big knife.
Toss it in.
HARVEY FOSTER: Mexico's
fucking sweet.
[LAUGHTER]
HIME HERBERT: Found an old
church, that was kind of cool,
climbed around in it,
and then came back
later, and blew it up.
[EXPLOSION]
KYNAN TAIT: I don't know where
we got them from, but someone
had a big bag of apple bombs
and little firecrackers,
little bombs or whatever, and
we just threw them in the
little empty cement
box out back.
HIME HERBERT: Dude,
I felt that shit.
[LAUGHTER]
[INAUDIBLE]
-This is Harvey with
both hands--
ten fingers.
HARVEY FOSTER: Don't say that.
HIME HERBERT: Son of a bitch.
[EXPLOSION]
HARVEY FOSTER: Whoa, that
was the best one.
HIME HERBERT: No mas.
-The dirt bike guy,
I have no idea.
That dude was a wingnut,
guaranteed.
Everything was pioneered by
offroad racers and surfers
down here, as far as good
spots to go to.
Everybody's running from
something, whether it's
running from a 40 hour a week
job, or responsibilities, or
just tired of the rat race.
And I think they come down here
and just get turned on by
the freedom.
And they want to come down and
not pay a bunch of taxes, and
live somewhere where they
can sort of do what they
want and check out.
RICHARD STEVENS: I've
been living in
here, now, for 30 years.
Back in 1980 I came down here
with a lot of friends, come
down here surfing all the time,
and ended up with an
opportunity to buy a piece
of property down here.
And I had a lot of friends in
construction, so we nabbed a
bunch of wood and stuff from
the job sides and came down
here, saved our money
up, and I started
building a little spot.
And that's how, really,
Quatro Casas as a
service community started.
Because I was the first person
to come out here and make it a
place to live, you know.
If you ever come to Mexico,
don't worry, there's
no danger out here.
We're far away from all the
city and all the trouble.
This place is famous for its
wave because its real long.
And we get that off South swell,
so when the Antartic
starts to go into its winter--
drop it!
These guys are burning
themselves.
-Straight up.
You straight [INAUDIBLE].
-They are fucked up.
-Howdy.
[LAUGHTER]
-Nice.
RICHARD STEVENS: Hey, fire it
that way because, otherwise,
if it hits those solar panels,
it's going to be problems.
[LAUGHTER]
-That's a proper cannon.
ARTO SAARI: Burning wood,
chopping fucking shit with an
axe, is, fucking
pretty awesome.
a fire, to me, is like
watching TV.
I love fire.
I like burning things down.
And I think it's just in my
blood, mostly, I think.
HARVEY FOSTER: Yeah, because
he's, like, from Finland.
And I was in Sweden before, and
I know they're all, like,
outdoorsy people.
And then I heard he had the
nickname of Norseman of the
woods or something.
KYNAN TAIT: Well, he was kind
of like another guy that I'd
seen in skate videos since
I really young.
You know, all these pretty epic
skate videos for years,
since I was a little kid.
Well, he's a lot bigger in
person, so he seems just like
a woodsman to me because I
haven't really even seen him
skate that much since we've
been on the trip.
ARTO SAARI: What [INAUDIBLE]?
KYNAN TAIT: Like, as much as I
love skating, I don't want to
hear about it 24/7.
So I think I get along better
with like minded people who
like skating but don't want
to talk about it, really.
So it's been easy getting
along with him.
-That's what she said
nine months later.
HARVEY FOSTER: You should
throw it on.
You did it.
-That was team effort.
HARVEY FOSTER: Oh, OK, I just
had the torch passed to me.
ARTO SAARI: When we got to
Quatro Casas, just that,
whatever, San Diego to
Quatro Casas, what
was that, 150 miles?
For those two days that we spent
there, I couldn't even
think about skating.
My ass piece was so
just, mm, tense.
[INAUDIBLE]
I was just like, can't
get my legs moving.
I haven't ridden a bike
for a year before I
came on this trip.
RICHARD STEVENS: I know a whole
group of skaters that
come from San Diego.
They all come down on their
hogs, skateboards tied on the
back, hell yeah.
RICHARD STEVENS: Everybody has
a lot of dogs out here.
You've got to have them
for protection.
They don't live long.
-No?
RICHARD STEVENS: Not out
here in the wild,
no, shit kill them--
other dogs, coyotes, raccons,
bobcats, they just get-- yeah,
they just disappear.
I don't see them again.
They all have disease names,
even the cats.
There's Measles, and her three
kids, which is Valium,
Vicodin, and Viagra, the
three orange ones.
And then there's Ebola and
gods, what's the one that
looks like her, I forget
her name--
pneumonia, that's it.
Pneumonia, and then
there's Raunches.
Raunches means hives.
I've run out of names.
I've got to think
of new names.
And I don't like to give the
same name to an animal, so--
-Sexual diseases.
RICHARD STEVENS: Giving
me new names.
You guys have a good
night, and I'll
see you in the morning.
All right?
All right, guys.
-I think people get psyched
any time they
see a pack of bikers.
In the middle of nowhere, on
like the long stretches of
highways or whatever.
People there are just like--
-Fuck yeah.
People are like, they're
going somewhere,
they're doing things.
-You can see people looking
at us on the road.
-Yeah, I think when there's
multiple of you.
MATT FRICK: I secretly--
-You're curious.
You're motorcycle curious.
RICHARD STEVENS: I'm very
motorcycle curious.
-You just need to
let yourself go.
RICHARD STEVENS: I look at
motorcycles at the same time I
masturbate.
This is a whole thing.
-I'm not sure what that means.
Let's go ahead and make sure
you mark that section.
-In private, in private.
-There is a camera here.
MATT FRICK: In private.
I look at these motocrycles
in private.
And I'm like, god damn
it, I know what.
I know what I want.
I know exactly what I want.
And I've just got to pull
the trigger, and
I've got to do it.
And I just--
[LAUGHTER]
-This is bromance.
-This is the bromantic
weekend getaways.