Powered by a 6.2 liter LS9 aluminum block
V8, the ZR1 produces 638 horsepower at 6500
RPM and 604
pound feet of torque at 3800 RPM. It can go
from zero to sixty in 3.4 seconds and has
a top speed of
205 miles per hour.
Ive been trying to find a time to come out
to this school for months so when we finally
put it in the
books I was supremely happy. But just when
I thought I couldnt be any more jazzed, I
found out that
my instructor was going to be Darren Law.
Hes the only driver to have competed in every
one of the Grand Am Rolex Sports Car Series
races
since the series started in 2000. And hes
the 2001 Rolex Series GT champion. In 2003,
he moved into
Daytona prototypes and posted a fourth place
finish. Since 2006, hes been racing for Brumos
Racing
and in 2007, along with his teammate David
Donahue, finished twelve consecutive races
in the top ten.
Suffice it to say, Darren has spent a lot
of time at the podium and has no shortage
of bragging rights.
The first objective for our day was to do
the heel-toe rev-matching. It sounds pretty
simple.
Conceptually, its not that complex, but it
definitely takes practice to master it.
So these revs, when you go to give it the
rev, when you put on the brake, youre gonna
give it a rev
and youre gonna get out of there. You dont
want to stay. You dont want to leave your
foot twisted
and stay on the RPM. Dont be afraid to get
it up to at least 4000.
Okay.
There you go.
I have particularly small feet so I had to
really come up with a maneuver and crank my
leg so that I
could be on the gas and the brake at the same
time.
Clutch in. Rev it. There you go. Perfect.
Alright, that was good.
One of my favorite things that we did all
day was when we got in the skid car and messed
around with
understeer and oversteer.
So understeer. Why does it happen? Youve basically
lost grip on the front of the car. You could
possibly just be going too fast. You basically
dont have traction on the front end. Youve
either
overloaded the front end with too much brake,
or theres not enough braking or weight on
the front of
the car.
So Darren, obviously, is operating these controls
and he can lift my wheels off the ground and
completely cause me to lose control.
Alright, so first things first. Well do the
understeer, the front-wheel skid.
But it gives you this awesome education on
how to recover, how to course correct and
save your life
and other peoples lives.
Youve got to ease in here. Ease up. Let it
get turned. There you go. Then youve got to
come off the
throttle. Add a little brake. Wait til the
car starts to turn a bit more. Now back on
the gas and straight
for the line.
After messing around with the nuances of understeer,
it was on to oversteer. So oversteer is, of
course, the opposite. This is when you lose
control of your back end. Now, most peoples
first impulse
is to brake but, in fact, what you need to
do is to utilize the throttle to regain your
grip.
This is awesome!
Isnt this a great learning tool?
Yeah!
Gas, gas, gas, gas, gas, gas, gas, gas, gas.
Good. That was good. That was smooth.
And then it was on to the next maneuver. Autocross!
When you come in and you turn in the corner,
if it starts to understeer, you need to get
out of the
throttle. If its still sliding, you have to
ease it with a little bit of brake until the
front end starts to come
down. Just like we did with the skid car.
And again, oversteer, if you come in and the
back end gets
sideways, turn into it, add a little throttle.
Not too much, this thing has so much power.
It will just light
them up.
Start it now.
So youll hit the brake. Youll have some understeer.
You see how it got a little sideways?
Yeah.
For the sake of friendly competition, we decided
to do some loosely timed trials, so Darren
went first.
Okay, stop!
53.4
And then it was my turn.
I dont know, theres something about autocross,
man. It speaks to me. I love it! But I think
that the
ZR1 has ruined me because I am not sure if
I will ever be satisfied competing in an autocross
in
anything less.
Heres Jessis best time so far.
There was some understeer.
I
was actually able to improve more than one
second from my first trail to my fifth, which
is a really big
deal. Hundredths of a second matter greatly
in autocross.
For the second part of the day, we moved on
to the oval and this was where I got to put
together all of
the pieces Id learned throughout the day.
Some apexes are long, some are short, some
are early in the corner, some are late in
the corner. So its
the closest point to the inside of the corner
to which your car comes in contact.
Hard on the gas.
Brake point.
Ease off of the brake, turn into your apex,
look to the throttle.
Come back out.
Brake. Okay, so far so good?
Yeah.
What if we dont drive out here and we dive
down in here before our apex cone? Look at
this.
Woah!
With each exercise, I begin with Darren in
the drivers seat, me in the passengers seat,
and hed give me
pointed instruction as we would go around
the course. Then, he would get out and it
would be just
me and the ZR1. And I savored every single
minute of alone-time we got.
I just became much more familiar with spotting
the apex, you know, in a decreasing radius
turn, in an
increasing radius turn, in a constant radius
turn. You know, the more practice you have,
you begin to
sort of get a sense for where the apex is
located.
So its the end of day one, but lucky for me,
we are coming back tomorrow. We are going
to spend the
whole day on the track and I cant wait to
see how much more Im able to learn and gain
and grow.
Alright, it is day two. Last night at Wild
Horse Pass Hotel and Casino, I resisted all
urges to gamble and
instead got a good nights rest. And I am ready
to go.
Although I couldnt wait to get back in the
ZR1, when we arrived, I ran into Bob Bondurant
and I could
not let him leave without treating me to some
hot laps.
Are we ready to go?
Ready to go!
[Laughter]
Woohoo!
He is just balls out, man. You would never
know hes about to be eighty years old. And
hes such a
good driver still. Hes remarkable. I learned
a lot as his passenger.
You recover it so quickly. When you get oversteer
or understeer, in a second you correct it.
And he is such a kid in a candy store in that
ZR1.
Wanna go for a couple more laps?
Sure!
He kept going and going and going. Darren
had to come out on the track and throw the
checkered flag
and say stop already!
That was amazing! Absolutely amazing!
Was that fun?
Yeah, I wanna be you, man. I just wanna be
you.
Today functioned as the culmination of everything
we learned. We put everything together and
spent
the entire day on the track.
Remember where your apex is. Okay, that looks
good. That looks good.
When the day began, you know theres always
this time when you have to reacclimate yourself
and
reorient yourself with the car and its particulars.
Remember, just like we were talking about
even with the skid cars. Look at your apex,
look where you
want to go. You need to drive to that point.
Okay, look for your cones. Stay left, stay
left. Now turn
into your apex right there. Good. Much better.
See now how we are pointed down the road already?
Again, early in is gonna be early out.
A whole lot of the progress I was able to
demonstrate throughout these two days was
a testament to
how fantastic a teacher Darren is.
Okay, this is way too tight through here and
youre way too early. Look at how youre going
off in the
dirt. You see that?
Yes.
Nice downshift! Wow! That sounds good.
He just gives you the most pointed feedback.
He constantly is correcting, tells you what
you did well,
tells you where you were lacking, and then
puts you back out there right away again to
implement that
feedback.
In addition to trying to execute all of these
skills simultaneously, today we also had a
lot of other
drivers on the track, which introduces a completely
new element and a whole lot of pressure on
the
driver.
Im really happy to say though that I was absolutely
able to hang! I was able to keep up with the
fastest
car in the other group and, man, that was
such a satisfying feeling.
So throughout the ZR1 course, youre being
evaluated constantly and youre given a grade
at the end,
upon completion of the course. Its on a scale
of 1 to 5 and 5 is perfect, you made absolutely
no
mistakes, so nobody gets a 5. But I am proud
to say I got a 4 and I was told that is something
to be
proud of.
So my whole objective here was to tame the
ZR1 and what I came away from this knowing
is that the
ZR1 is not meant to be tamed. It should be
wild, free, and unbroken, and you just need
to respect it.