Over the last few months, I've been
approached several times about the
subject of death,
including a tag by the wonderful Largo64, and the glorious Rozeboosje,
enquires about psychological studies,
assertions that I'm 'pro-mortality',
questions about my responses to some
thought-terminating cliches,
and about my personal outlook.
I've always been fascinated by how we
cope with death --
or more interestingly how we fail to
cope with it,
with all the destructive consequences
those failures bring.
It's also had some personal residence
for me recently.
It feels the right time to share that I
started experiencing throat problems a few
months ago that wouldn't go away.
When I reported the symptoms,
the doctors immediately suspected an
aggressive type of cancer that one of my
brothers died of, and I was rushed
through a series of tests.
I recently received the results of those
tests.
My condition is benign.
Given this temporary stay of execution, I
thought I'd address all of these
solicitations in two videos,
dedicated to death.
But before I begin,
I'd like to invite you to take a moment
to consider your personal reaction to
these videos about death --
your reactions as you watch them
and also before you started watching,
when you saw they were available.
What with the thoughts and feelings that
came up for you?
Were they positive?
Negative? Mixed?
Blank?
I'd invite you to hold these responses
in mind
and, if it feels ok,
perhaps share some of them.
We have a lot to deal with in this experience
we call life don't we?
At the most basic level, we're faced with the
physical challenges of survival:
finding and competing for food,
water, shelter,
and -- if we so inclined --
sexual partners,
while distancing ourselves from diseases,
parasites,
predators,
natural disasters.
On the social level, we find ourselves
within a species containing huge
variation.
We must determine the significance of
these differences -- if indeed there is any --
and find our own place within this
variety.
On the psychological level
we wrestle with all kinds of unknowns,
unpredictabilities,
ambiguities, dissonances.
We live with swathes of unanswered
questions:
questions about the universe we find
around us,
and the one we find inside us:
our own mind, with so many of its
processes blocked out of our awareness.
Perhaps the most profound paradox we
experience comes when we bring the
universe and the mind together -- as the
meaningless meets the meaning-hungry.
Within that paradox, the task we seem to
find most intimidating of all is
the business of confronting death.
We can infer that level of intimidation
by the extreme lengths we employ to deny
death.
Extreme protected lengths,
employing a range of physical and
psychological barriers to block
the fear out,
and extreme aggressive lengths,
dehumanising, attacking and killing those
who face us with our fears.
We witness and experience all kinds of
disproportionate emotional responses in
life.
An example familiar to us all is phobias.
For the phobic individual, there's a
sizeable mismatch between the perceived
and actual levels of threat associated
with the phobic object or situation.
As a child, I was arachnophobic. I ascribed a
quasi-human intelligence to
the spider's stealthy behaviour,
and imagined that its goal was to get
into my mouth.
I never questioned why it might want to do
that.
But that's the self-preserving nature of
fair -- it facilitates irrational
fantasies and pseudo-explanations that
maintain the fear,
while simultaneously diminishing our
capacity for the kinds of rational
processing that might break its hold.
One of the saving graces of phobias is that they're generally owned by the
individual.
As that arachnophobic child, I didn't go round thinking everyone else was
wrong not to have a spider phobia.
I knew the problem was mine.
But there are other kinds of
disproportionate emotional responses
where ownership of one's own fears aren't so easily accepted.
As a child coming up to 14,
about to announce my departure from the
religion into which I'd been
indoctrinated,
I actually expected a positive reaction.
Having spent months in private thought,
trying to justify my belief in that
religion,
it dawned on me:
every magical being so far had been
hoaxes played by the adults.
I kicked myself for spending so much time working through the arguments and I looked forward
to having a laugh with the adults when
they found out I'd seen through this
religion hoax too.
My announcement of non-belief was
greeted with rage,
contempt and punishment.
When the fatwa was declared on
Salman Rushdie in 1989,
I initially dismissed it as a prank.
Appealing to worldwide followers to
implement a death sentence
just for writing a novel?
I'd never heard anything so pathetic and
ridiculous — but Khomeini's decree was
genuine.
Such homicidal theocracies actually
existed.
Ten years ago, a muslim friend of mine
shared that her nephew had come out to her
as a homosexual.
She told me that if their family found
out, he'd be taken to India and
buried alive.
Furthermore, if her family found out that she
knew and hadn't told them,
the same would happen to her.
Five years ago, when I first heard of the
anti-atheist hate widely promulgated
across the US, I thought it had to be
some big national joke.
Some trendy,
ironic, faux-prejudice.
When I realised it was serious,
I joined the discourse.
My focus back then was purely on the
prejudicial aspects, rather than debating
the existence of gods.
But in response to simply revealing my atheism
I received death wishes,
death threats,
suggestions that I was already dead
spiritually -- and of course salivating
references to my perpetual living death
in hell.
Talk about overkill. But I recognised some of
my own stuff here too.
At age 12, when I was an active
christian, a religious education teacher
asked me why I believe what I believed. The
question seemed innocuous enough at
first.
But as I reflected on it, I realised nothing valid was coming to mind.
An appropriate response would've been to simply admit that.
My actual response?
I wanted that teacher wiped from the
face of the planet.
What drives these extreme reactions? What's
the big deal?
Were the believers here any less free to
believe whatever they wanted?
Divine beliefs are generally claimed to
bring inner peace -- but what kind of inner
peace is it that demands that other
people get their inner peace the same way ....
or else!
Clearly in each of these cases,
with such hyper-aggressive defences
being mobilised,
the aggressor was protecting something
tremendously fragile.
Emerging out of the cocoon of religion,
the big deal for me was death --
realising that there was no reason
whatsoever to believe I'd be reborn,
reincarnated,
resurrected or reconstituted in any way
after my physical demise --
let alone reunited with loved ones in
some sugary hereafter.
It quickly occurred to me that this was of
course the prime psychological function
of the part of our culture we label
'religion':
to deny death.
To reject the unthinkable thought that
when our brains stop,
we stop.
We have a host of other cultural
props and mechanisms explicitly designed to
help us deal with the passing of friends
and family:
ceremonies where we can share our
feelings;
professional services to help us process
our bereavement;
dedicated locations we can visit to
keep our memories alive.
But for many of us, these things just aren't enough.
The pain of fully letting go
feels unendurable.
Added to which,
if we admit the finality of our loved
ones,
we're implicitly faced with our own
finality.
In this state of denial, we seek out illusions
that offer a promise of perpetuity.
On the physical front, there's not much
scope for illusions of perpetuity --
corpses wreak of finality.
In the initial stages, while they still
maintain some semblance of the living state,
we might just about be able to
sustain some fantasies consistent with
natural processes --
for example that the person's merely
sleeping.
But when the decay really kicks in,
the evidence of finality is just too
uncomfortable.
To deny death,
we turn to the non-physical -- to the
realm of symbolic thought.
Our capacity for this kind of thinking has
led us to entertain a multitude of
figurative forms of immortality.
Some folks see themselves preserved in
their children.
Some folks pursue their own individual
fame or power as a buffer against extinction.
Some devote themselves to
influential figures, or invest themselves
in a group they feel to be emblematic of
their own values.
Impersonal cultural institutions like
the law offer a sense of order and
protection,
diminishing our awareness of disorder
and vulnerability.
Architecture, built to spend many
lifetimes, provides a huge reinforcement
of symbolic permanence. But our ultimate psychological alchemy came when we
managed to convince ourselves our
symbolic self could exist outside
our literal self.
We called it a 'soul'.
Once humans had committed this violation,
there was really no end to the
possibilities on offer.
The soul could be reborn in another body --
perhaps another species.
It could be reinserted in the same body.
It could even simply continue with
nobody at all.
On the face of it, the concept of the
independent soul
would seem to provide enough denial to
keep everyone happy.
So why isn't everyone happy?
The problem with illusions is that they're devilishly difficult things to maintain.
Not only do they constantly run up
against reality -- they're also vulnerable to
competing illusions.
Group A denies death with a fantasy in
which the soul departs to a paradise or
realm of torture
after one physical life.
Group B denies death with a fantasy in
which the soul just keeps getting
reincarnated on Earth.
When these fantasies meet
there's gonna be a clash.
The existence of the competing illusion
serves as a constant contradiction to
the other --
undermining its death-denying capability.
It soon becomes clear that, in order to keep a death-denying illusion going, everyone has
to believe the same thing.
Over the years, I've noticed a range of
strategies to reduce the threat of
conflicting ideas.
They might simply be dismissed as
ridiculous, implausible,
maybe primitive.
But however much we try to dismiss
conflicting ideas psychologically,
it's much better if they're just not there at all.
History's festooned with aggressive
proselytisation programmes,
where one death-denying illusion is displaced by another.
Sometimes the poison's sweetened by the
addition of medical aid,
or enhanced educational prospects,
supporting the aggressors' delusion that
they're 'helping the savages' -- rather than
eliminating the competition.
History also abounds with the more
violent step up from that,
when members of the competing death-denying illusion are exterminated.
Where dismissal, proselytisation or
murder seen non-viable,
we have the truce.
Here parties focus on common aspects
between the illusions,
while trying to downplay the threatening
differences.
Some folks have tried this with christianity
and islam
saying it's the same god.
Problem is, it isn't the same god
The god that gave its only son
in explicit reference to a purported
original sin
is not the god that had no such son.
This is not a minor detail that can be
discarded.
It informs the whole rationale for the
belief.
And beneath all the magnanimous gestures
towards inclusion,
multiculturalism and pluralism,
these differences are not forgotten.
The inherent supremacism of the individual's ideology merely moves from
overt
to covert.
And when things get rocky,
that supremacism is quick to surface.
Out come the flags, the icons,
and the feverish assertions
of monoculture.
Truces have an elastic limit. Finding
common ground gets harder as differences
between groups increase. When confronted
with groups who have no divine beliefs
at all, it is of course possible to offer a truce based on human values.
But that tacitly acknowledges the redundancy of divine beliefs.
Hence
strategy number five: emotional blackmail.
Here, folks attempt to coerce those who
don't share their illusions into silence
by evoking guilt or fear.
Sometimes the blackmail his preemptive.
The blackmailer lets it be known publicly
that they couldn't bear it if anyone
confronted their illusions.
Other times, the blackmail's reactive.
The blackmailer tries to stifle any further
challenge with the same manipulative
methods --
casting folks who expose their illusions
as cruel,
destructive and heartless --
hoping they'll be persuaded to mask their
dissent.
Whatever the strategy, the goal is the same.
Unable to withstand scrutiny or challenge,
the poorly constructed illusion can only survive by blocking
them out.
Having reflected on this death denial
over several years, it was intriguing to
come across experimental support last
year, when my friend Tim introduced me to
the work of Sheldon Solomon, Tom Pyszczynski
and Jeff Greenberg --
the proponents of 'terror management
theory'.
Sheldon Solomon explains:
'If culture serves a death-denying function
then if you remind people that they're going to die,
that should momentarily .... increase the
need for the death-denying aspects of
their particular beliefs about reality --
and that should be reflected by their
reactions to other individuals, who
either bolster or support those beliefs,
or who undermine those beliefs by either
being hostile to them,
or merely different from them.
The terror management team have
conducted scores of studies to
investigate this
'mortality salience hypothesis'.
In a study into attitudes, two groups
of christian subjects were asked to
fill out a questionnaire, ostensibly about
how people form impressions of others.
The questions in one group were specifically phrased to remind the reader
of his or her own death.
Both groups were then asked for their
impressions of two fictitious students
who shared personality traits.
One student was a christian.
The other was jewish.
Subjects who'd been reminded of their own
death gave an especially positive
assessment of the christian and an
especially negative one of the jew.
The subjects who weren't reminded of their death showed no preference.
Another study investigated the effects
of mortality salience on behaviour,
looking at subjects' willingness to use
cultural symbols and icons in
inappropriate ways.
In the first of two tasks, subjects were
given a variety of objects
and asked sift sand from a jar with
water and ink.
The American flag was the only object that would do the job.
In the second task,
subjects had to hang a crucifix on the
wall -- but in order to do that
they had to use the crucifix to bang the
nail in.
Subjects who'd been reminded of death in
a prior questionnaire
took twice as long as those who hadn't.
The researchers also looked into the
effects of mortality salience on
subjects' choice a political candidate,
using campaign statements expressing
three different leadership styles.
The task-orientated leader's statement
emphasised high but achievable goals
implemented through efficient resourcing
and delegation. The relationship-orientated
leader's statement focused on
respect, compassion, trust,
communication
and appreciation.
The charismatic leader's statement alluded to
the nation's greatness
and stressed the importance of vision and
group identity. Initially, only 4%
voted for the charismatic leader,
with the remainder fairly evenly split
between the other two.
But when subjects were reminded of death,
votes for the charismatic leader
soared to 33%.
Interestingly,
votes for the relationship-orientated statement fell sharply.
The researchers noted how these results
echoed George Bush's rise in popularity
around the 9/11 attacks, with his
appeals to the nation's greatness and
righteous war against the axis of evil.
In a subsequent experiment, the
researchers found that reminders of both
mortality and 9/11 significantly increased support for Bush --
not just among conservatives
but also liberals.
As the researchers pointed out, we
should be extremely concerned
at how easy it is to manipulate an electorate's political preferences through
appeals to a combination of nationalism
and fear.
While it's natural to fear legitimate threats, we'd do well to keep some
rational perspective and demand facts, rather
than allow ourselves to be seduced by
heroic, fear-based rhetoric.
In this video, I looked at the illusions we construct to deny death
and how they lead to divisive and
disproportionate emotional responses
to folks who don't share those illusions.
In the second video, I'll be exploring several
other grave subjects, including the label
of 'pro-mortality atheist', the demands of immortality, the claim that there are
'no atheists in foxholes', and the
possibility of peace of mind without
recourse to illusion.