MIKE RUBENDALL: Keep
these bugs away.
Show them how it pumps.
It's funny, because when I got
into tattooing, it was at a
strange stage in my life.
Because I was 17,
and growing up I
guess made good decisions.
I did well in school and was
heavily into sports, and I
chose a different path,
which was tattooing.
And everybody looked at me like,
you've done so well up
until this point.
And now you're going to hang
out with all these fuck-ups
and devil worshipping, drug
dealing, motorcycle riding
type of guys-- so what are
you doing with your life?
So at the time, nobody thought
it was a really good idea.
Now I'm 33 years old, and they
look at me like maybe it
wasn't such a bad idea.
FRANK ROMANO: There's a group
of people leading the pack.
FRANK ROMANO: Oh, absolutely.
I mean, recently, talking to
one of the guys at the shop
about this, he said,
do you think Mike's
in the top 10 guys?
And I said, yeah.
Name nine guys that are
better than him.
And I'm not looking to hurt
anybody's feelings, but I
think it's closer
to the top five.
And we agreed, yeah, maybe
it's not even the top 10.
Maybe it's the top five.
MIKE RUBENDALL: You
want a pillow?
MALE SPEAKER: Nah.
MIKE RUBENDALL: You got to wait
'til noon 'til the shop
help gets in here though.
MALE SPEAKER: Nah,
that's fine.
MIKE RUBENDALL: I've always
described my tattooing as
Asian influenced.
I think I have a contemporary
approach on traditional
Japanese tattoo style.
Overall look, I want my tattoos
to be timeless.
I want it to be beautiful
as the day I
did it 20 years later.
I don't want somebody to look
at my tattoos and know what
year or whatever I did it in.
MATT BRECKERICH: It's exciting
to look at-- detailed and
simple at the same time.
Exciting, action packed.
That's what I said
the other day.
JUSTIN WEATHERHOLTZ: He has
that extra little bit of
edginess to it that always
kind of grabbed me.
Even the way he does his
compositions and stuff, an
overall look I guess.
CHRIS O'DONNELL: He still does
all kinds of subject matter.
It was pretty much centered
around doing a good quality
job for the person that
comes in the door.
He's not like, I'm going to try
this crazy thing, and if
it doesn't work, it doesn't.
He's like, no, this person wants
this, and this is what
they're going to get.
I'm going to add a lot to that,
but it's going to be in
the nuances, in the progression
of my drawing ability.
And people respond to that.
The whole process is
his personality.
It's very structured
and very right.
He'll show up when he's
supposed to show up.
He'll work really hard.
He'll do the research, he'll
have the drawing, he'll have
it all thought out, takes
it very seriously, and
he'll do a great job.
MIKE RUBENDALL: I'll even chase
my clients, like, can
you come in for a
consultation?
Can we talk about what
you're getting?
I want to be prepared.
I don't want you to show up and
me draw it on the spot.
I don't work well like that.
It's possible I could do a
tattoo like that, but I don't
feel like they're
getting my best.
When the time comes to do the
tattoo, then I try to knock it
out of park.
Even little stuff, they'll come
in, and I said, any of
the guys in the shop are more
than capable of doing this.
You don't need to wait for me,
they'll do an outstanding job.
And they're like, no, we've been
watching you a long time,
and we just want a
piece from you.
I was born and raised in
Massapequa, New York.
It's a small town
on Long Island.
I think I had an average
upbringing.
I came from a middle-class
family.
I think I stayed in Massapequa
because I felt very
comfortable there.
I had this mentality that if you
build it, they will come.
So I felt like why not be in a
place that I grew up in, that
I feel most comfortable in, and
I know the most people?
I felt like I could open up in
my mother's basement and
people would still come and get
tattooed by me-- luckily,
I was fortunate for that.
JOE PAPPALARDO JR.: I think
there was a lot of hesitation
about putting a tattoo shop in
that area because it's so
residential.
I think he had to meet with a
lot of people and show them
his credentials.
And show them he wasn't going
to have people pulling up on
their bikes at all hours
of the night
and doing drugs outside--
that he has a respectable
clientele.
I mean, he's tattooed
celebrities.
His rates are weaning
away people of
that element, I think.
MATT BRECKERICH: Kings Avenue
in Massapequa, it's known as
kind of the classy
tattoo shop.
You know, the shop that we're
hardworking, we have our shit
together, and I would like to
think we're known as the best
of the best around here.
GREZ: Working in Long Island,
it was a shock of how things
were done compared to Boston.
In Long Island, they want
to get tattooed, and
they want it done.
They come in and OK, I'll make
15 appointments to get my
sleeve, I'll do it
every two weeks.
It's a dream.
MALE SPEAKER: The clientele here
is actually pretty open
to bigger work.
You've got big, huge pieces on a
lot of people running around
here, it's pretty crazy.
MIKE RUBENDALL: I remembered I
tattooed a few guys that were
starting big projects
like a sleeve, and
they lost their jobs.
So I would start the
conversation by so, what do
you do for a living?
And the guy would be like,
I just lost my job.
And I'm like, you sure you
want to get into this?
It's a big commitment, a
lot of time and money.
And they're like no,
I need to do this.
They fucking want this,
no matter what.
MATT BRECKERICH: My theory on
that is that a lot of these
people around here, family guys,
they don't go out to the
bar, they got kids.
So it's almost like that's their
way of doing something
cool that makes them feel
alive, I guess.
GREZ: One guy came in once,
and he wanted Mike to do a
sleeve on him.
And he's like, oh, I don't
know, I want some fucking
demon or something.
So he brings in a Lord of the
Rings picture of-- you know
that guy that whips Gandalf,
the guy made of fire and he
pulls him down into the
pit or whatever?
He brings that in and Mike does
a Fudo sleeve on the guy.
The guy, he sees the fire
and he's like fuck yeah.
He was just kind of like joking
around a little bit,
and I looked down at him and I
go, you don't even know what
that is on your arm, do you?
And he goes, psh, yeah I do.
I go, OK, what is that?
He goes, it's fondue.
And Mike and I lost it.
They see your tattoos for what
they in a quality sense.
But a lot of times it's your
job to incorporate more
interesting aspects into the
tattoo that tell a story for
other people that
are viewing it.
JOE PAPPALARDO JR.: People he
knows and that he does a lot
of work on, he pushes it.
Because I think--
I'll use myself as an example.
For my back, I told
him I wanted
a hani with a spiderweb.
I mean, my hani doesn't look
like a typical hani I think he
just went for it.
In my mind, he'd the artist,
he's doing what he's doing.
I think he has the most fun when
people kind of approach
it that way.
I'm sure a lot of these tattoo
artists do, they don't want to
be told what to do,
they're artists.
They want to push it,
they want to go.
I don't know if he has
a favorite piece.
I know whenever I see him, I'm
always kind of blown away.
Like, the other day he was
doing a Phoenix that
I thought was cool.
Like it was just deep
purples and stuff.
I always like-- he does great
stuff with heads.
Someone he was doing a leg
sleeve on, it was like seven
severed heads.
It was just gory and raw,
and I think he was just
having fun with it.
I grew up with Mike, I know
Mike, I know he's an awesome
tattoo artist.
To see it in a different
setting, really kind of go,
holy cow, this guy's a name.
And I'm great friends
with him.
He's like almost a celebrity
in this little circle.
GREZ: One thing I've observed
about Mike is that he always
continues to have
relationships with these people.
Because he's got
the mayor feel.
He knows everyone's name,
shaking everyone's hands.
I was working one day at the
shop, the door opens and I
hear, Mikey!
And I look up, I'm like, that's
Steve Guttenberg.
I remember him from Police
Academy, and he's walking
around looking for Mike.
MIKE RUBENDALL: Him and his dad
came into the shop to get
matching tattoos, and his
mother found out--
oh, look at this.
There they are!
Holy shit.
Speak of the devil.
JOE PAPPALARDO, SR.: Hey!
MIKE RUBENDALL: Look at this.
JOE PAPPALARDO, SR.: Are
you filming for your
documentary right now?
MIKE RUBENDALL: Yeah,
right now, baby.
JOE PAPPALARDO, SR.: All right,
you want to go to the
pizza shop?
MIKE RUBENDALL: Sure.
STEVE GUTTENBERG: Mikey boy.
MIKE RUBENDALL: How
you doing, buddy?
JOE PAPPALARDO, SR.: Steve,
you got five minutes?
MIKE RUBENDALL: You
got a minute?
JOE PAPPALARDO, SR.: They're
doing a tattoo documentary.
STEVE GUTTENBERG:
Tattoo on you?
MIKE RUBENDALL: Say a couple
of kind words?
JOE PAPPALARDO, SR.: Yeah,
you're the guy, Massapequa.
STEVE GUTTENBERG: I got to lie.
Oh, no.
MIKE RUBENDALL: You
got to lie?
STEVE GUTTENBERG: Mikey,
you look great man.
You look terriffic.
MIKE RUBENDALL: You, too, man.
How's everything?
STEVE GUTTENBERG: It's good.
I'll see you at the shop.
MIKE RUBENDALL: OK, cool.
JOE PAPPALARDO, SR.: This
is the first place
that Michael worked.
Came in a young man, what,
15 years old, Mike?
MIKE RUBENDALL: Yeah.
JOE PAPPALARDO, SR.: 15
years old, [INAUDIBLE]
Mike Rubendall.
MALE SPEAKER: Hey, Mike.
MIKE RUBENDALL: What's
up, Frank?
How are you man?
Good to see you.
JOE PAPPALARDO, SR.: Larry's our
manager here, he told me
not to hire Michael Rubendall.
I don't know why.
Why is that, Larry?
LARRY: I don't know.
GREZ: It's like he hasn't
burned any bridges.
All the people he grew up with,
they all still live in
Long Island.
He remembers everyone, he
takes care of everybody.
MIKE RUBENDALL: Yo, Ed!
ED: Mike!
MIKE RUBENDALL: My man.
ED: Welcome to New York.
MIKE RUBENDALL: You're back?
GREZ: You know, some of the
characters that he hangs out
with are so entertaining.
MIKE RUBENDALL: This
guy's a legend.
Say something to the camera.
ED: Next time I get a tattoo,
it's going to be a pizza pie
right on my arm, Mikey
Rubendall style.
GREZ: It's incredible how much
he brings from the world to
Massapequa.
It's special, because we
have the train there
and all these people--
the taxi cab drivers.
Every time our clients would
come in, it's like oh my God,
this taxi cab driver is chewing
my ear off about how
he brought three people from
Europe last week and two
people from California.
None of them can believe
that so many people
travel just for a tattoo.
MALE SPEAKER: You said that
you've taken some people to
the tattoo parlor before?
JUAN SUAREZ: I take a
lot of people there.
When they come in, I
usually ask them
where do you come from?
Oh, from the city, one guy
Pennsylvania, another guy from
some different places.
Yeah, we do, we do--
we drop them off, pick them up,
I know the place by heart.
MIKE RUBENDALL: It's flattering
because people come
all over the world.
And people live down the block
from the shop, and they're
just happy to get tattooed.
Some of them don't even know how
successful the shop is, or
that the job is world renowned,
or that people come
in from all over the world.
They're just like, oh, he's
local, he does a good job,
he's a nice guy.
That's all we need,
the simple life.