We have
a big problem here, girls.
Your behavior is
completely unacceptable.
Mr. Connor...
Did we do something wrong?
The three of you have
been disrupting my class
and you're making it difficult
for the students
who actually want
to learn something.
Not only am l going
to call your parents,
but you all have detention.
Not only am l gonna
call your parents...
But you all have detention.
You've got detention
You girls think this is funny?
No, Jim!
l don't find anything
funny about this.
l wasn't finished!
Put these on!
l don't think these
are appropriate to wear here.
You fucking imbecile,
did l stutter?!
l said put 'em on.
This is outrageous!
l'm just trying to give
you girls a good education!
Ooooh...
We'll give you
a good education...
ADULT education!
Just let me go!
Somebody really needs detention.
That was fun, right?
Yeah, that was crazy.
l love it when it's
the three of us together.
lt's like Charlie's Angels,
look out!
More like Hells Angels.
And Natalie...
that dildo was way too big
to use on him like that.
But l think he liked it
the way he was moaning.
You think he liked it?
Who cares.
l liked it.
Are you girls hungry?
So hungry l could eat
the balls off a snake right now.
You know, l have the strangest
craving for foie gras.
Eew! That's nasty!
The way they force-feed
those poor little geese -
it's animal cruelty, you know.
Honey, you the last one to
be talking about animal cruelty
after what you just
did to that poor man.
Ashtray.
Taboo, good afternoon.
Hold please.
Janet, line 2.
Taboo, good afternoon.
Marie, line 4.
- Hey V.
- Hey.
Do l have any new bookings?
You have Tony at 3 o'clock...
You have a 4:30
with a new guy
into latex fetish
and heavy bondage,
and Karen and her
husband want to push to 7.
- Can you e-mail me that to me?
- Sure.
Jim should be ready.
Let me write him up
so you can get out of here.
All right, we got
an all-girl gang bang,
CBT, nipple, humiliation -
verbal and physical -
foot fetish, spitting,
forced fem,
rape fantasy, heavy cursing...
Ah! Face slapping...
l've gotta last minute booking -
basic trampling and a golden.
Any takers?
Nah, l'm good.
l'll do it.
All right.
Don't do nothing l wouldn't do.
Later, beauties.
He's gonna be here
in 20 minutes.
Awesome.
[ Skipped item nr. 75 ]
Hi, Natalie.
lt's Grandma.
l have great news...
l think l found someone for you.
Call me back.
[phone rings]
Hi, Mommy.
Sure, l'd love to.
OK...
l'll see you later.
Natalie, l think you should
go back to being blond
or at least put some blond
highlights in your hair.
lt looked so beautiful that way.
Thanks, Ma, but the bleach
dried out my hair.
l like it better natural.
Ma, she looks
beautiful the way she is.
l know she does.
What's going on with your hair?
l just got it cut this morning.
lt's a little too short,
isn't it?
l mean, just don't go
any shorter.
l've been getting my hair cut
like this for a year.
Nat, you think it's too short?
No, it looks real cute.
l like that dykie look.
What?
l mean, if l saw you
on the street
l'd definitely think
you were gay.
Natalie, not everybody
sees things the way you do.
Maybe it's not about the hair.
Then what is it?
You know what it is?
lt's the hair with the clothes,
it's the way you carry yourself.
Everything about you screams,
''l don't need a man.''
Some people might
confuse that with being gay.
Well, just because l don't
walk around town
with long, red, flowing hair
and my tits and ass hanging out,
doesn't make me gay.
l'm sorry.
My bad.
Do you forgive me?
C'mon, Becca, forgive me,
pretty please!
l like your hair the way it is.
- Come on.
- OK!
Rebecca, how's work going?
lt's going
pretty well, actually.
l have an evaluation next week.
and l think l'll be
getting a promotion.
- Congratulations.
- That's very exciting.
How about you, honey?
How's work going?
lt's good.
l've been working on
some other things though.
That's great.
Finally use your
Psychology degree...
The one l sent you
to school for?
Cute, Ma.
Seriously, though...
l'm going into
the film business, Ma.
Film?
Well, that's something new.
Now, l know you don't
wanna hear this,
but l think it would be nice
if one of you young ladies
would just start to think
about settling down
and having a little one.
[both laughing]
C'mon!
l want someone
to call me Grandma
before l get too old
to be bothered by it.
Oh, that's easy...
Grandma!
- Nana!
- That's not funny.
- Granny!
- OK!
OK, fine.
Can we change the subject?
What time is it?
l don't know what time it is.
Are you going uptown
any time soon?
No, l'm staying here
with Nana.
Granny's my date.
Why didn't you invite me?
We thought you were
going out with your friends.
You can stay with us, honey.
What are you doing tonight?
Yeah, hang out with us.
Goin' out with my friends.
Hey, Joe!
How you doin'?
Hi, Nat. l am good!
You comin' out with us tonight?
No.
l gotta work at that
new club on 46th Street.
- Swank!
- Yeah!
l know the owners from this
place that l danced at in Vegas.
That's cool.
Where's Mel?
She is in the bedroom
doing a session.
ln the bedroom?
She turned the extra room
into a dungeon
so she could get some
work done on the side.
- Hey, baby.
- Hey.
Hey, watch that thing!
So you're doing sessions now?
Oh, yeah.
But l screen them
down to their diets.
Where are we going tonight?
Juicy's.
We always go to lesbian clubs.
Why can't we go
to a straight club?
Because we're lesbians.
Oh, yeah.
All right...
l'll go with the girls tonight.
But l need to be around
some men some time soon.
You're around men all the time.
No, some real men.
Ah, come on.
You know you love the ladies.
No...
You love the ladies.
[door buzzes]
Oh, shit.
That must be Sonia.
What the fuck
is going on in here?
Which one of these lucky bitches
you 'bout to put it on?
Stop it! l'm in a session.
Uh huh.
- Hey, mamacita.
- Hi, doll.
You look fierce, as usual.
Thank you.
You are so damn cute!
Okay, all right!
So, who's not ready?
That would be...
You!
l gotta finish my session,
don't l?
C'mon!
l thought you fucked
your bitch already?
Tinkle-tinkle.
Aw, c'mon!
Bitch!
Get your sissy-ass out here!
What is this now?
Oooh, you have
a sexy little slut.
You think?
l'm gonna soak
this little slut's panties.
Hey, you wanna try?
Yeah, l need the practice.
Practice?
Yeah, l'm gonna
start doing sessions.
To the bathroom.
[giggling]
Do you realize it's been a month
since l broke up with Bianca?
And l'm going crazy!
Not to mention
l'm horny as fuck!
You'll meet someone else.
There are plenty
of fish in the sea.
Hold up.
l don't want no parts
of no fishy chicks!
l don't do sushi boo, OK?
l have to meet a girl
that's a straight-up masochist.
That's what l really need.
ln our line of work,
we are destined
to always be single.
Speak for yourself!
l mean, it's not like
we're porn stars!
Now they have issues!
[door buzzes]
Please!
No need to stand up,
no need to bow down,
watch out girls...
'cuz l'm the
hottest man in town!
Hi, Noah!
What's up, hotnesses!
Damn, girl!
- Hi, honey.
- l missed you, sweets.
- Noah!
- What?
This is Natalie.
l know Natalie.
A fairly frequent
client of mine.
l live right around
the corner from you, girl.
Really? l didn't know that.
How long have you lived there?
How long?
Shit...
Let me put it to you this way.
l remember when the
neighborhood was nothin'
but abandoned buildings and
crackheads and dope fiends...
before these yuppie bastards
and trust-fund babies
came in here and fucked up
my once quaint little 'hood.
l know you're not tryin'
to call me a Yuppie!
No, l ain't tryin to say
you're no yuppie.
l'm just sayin' they took all
the hustle off the street,
which is cool,
but they also put out
all the working class people
on their asses.
Yeah, it's fucked up.
Now me, l just had to evolve
my game a little bit.
lnstead of hangin' out
on the corner
and y'all comin to me,
l come to you.
Our friendly
neighborhood delivery man.
Tips are appreciated.
But for real...
this is just a little side
hustle to keep the lights on.
You feel me?
ln here...
tryin' to do that artist thing.
Oh, OK.
What kind of artist?
l used to do a little taggin'
back in the day.
l parlayed that into a little
bit of paintin',
little bit of rhymin'.
But the thing that's
really settin' me off...
is this writin' thing...
Like what?
A book? Poetry?
Screenplays....
And from pen to pad, girl,
l am writin' down some shit
that is alive!
Hey, aren't you working on
something like that?
l heard about you,
little Miss Tarantino.
Yeah, l'm workin' on
a few things.
Then you guys should
totally collaborate
on something really fabulous.
Collaboration, huh?
You like brown babies?
That's what's up!
ln the meantime, how about
we collaborate on this L?
Here you go.
lt's tight, ain't it?
l know it is.
Here, Mel.
This is some good shit.
Thanks!
So...should l call
a slave to chauffeur us?
Most definitely.
Big Pimpin' for sure!
Hey Pimpstress,
you got five minutes.
Look at little mama there.
Shut up.
You hear the reggae remix
of Purple Haze?
Nah, is it good?
You know he was murdered, right?
Who?
Jimi Hendrix, yo!
He was down with the 27 club.
Oh, God...
He was one of the
revolutionary artists
that was murdered
by the government
at the age of 27.
Oh, l see...
You're one of them, right?
- One of who?
- Conspiracy theorists.
That's exactly what
they want you to think!
That's a whole fuckin'
conspiracy right there!
For real!
Check out the list
of names of motherfuckers
who all had mysterious deaths.
Now l'm not talkin' about
the way they died,
but at the time,
all at the height
of their careers,
when they had
the most influence
over a motherfuckin'
revolutionary generation!
l'll be right back.
All right, mama.
John Lennon -
shot in Central Park.
Bob Marley,
cancer in his big toe.
At 27, Janis Joplin...
[phone ringing]
Uh, yeah.
This is Jim.
Hey, Jim.
Workin' late again?
Ashley?
You sound surprised.
Yes, Miss...
l...l just didn't know
you had this number.
Oh, this won't take very long.
l just wanted to tell you it was
so funny what we did to you.
Um...OK.
You wanna see
something even funnier?
Check your e-mail.
Bye, Jim.
[screaming in pain]
Marvin Gaye -
shot by his daddy.
At 27, Jimi Hendrix choked on
his own vomit in an ambulance.
ln an ambulance, yo!
How the fuck you choke on
your own goddamn vomit
in a motherfuckin' ambulance?!
lt's in an ambulance!
Ain't somebody there that's
supposed to save him?!
lt's motherfuckin' Jimi Hendrix
for Christ's sake.
Curtis Mayfield -
hit by a stage lamp.
Tupac Shakur -
shot on the Vegas strip.
And don't even get me started
on the non-27-year-olds...
Black Panthers, MLK,
Malcom X,
Bruce Lee, Lenny Bruce,
Kurt Cobain,
Timothy Leary with
the drug experiments!
Damn, you got issues.
We ready to get outta here?
Noah, you do know we're goin'
to a lesbian club?
Hell, yeah!
Some of my best motherfuckin'
clients is up in there.
The herb has no problem
with da
girl-on-girl action, mon!
Don't matter if you're
black, white, red or brown.
As long as you got cash,
you can all be down.
Woo! That shit is tight!
l can connect with
my feminine side,
which allows me an ethereal
connection with lesbians, so...
[phone ringing]
Hi, Natalie.
lt's your Grandma.
Sara's friend's son,
he's a nice Jewish boy.
We want you to meet him.
You're not so young anymore.
You should live to 1 20.
Damn, ma...
You still got
an answering machine?
You got a beeper too?
lt's for my grandmother.
She just figured out
how to leave a message.
You are a lesbian, right?
Couldn't you tell?
Oh, shit...
l'm sorry.
ls this some kind of sign?
l just met you and you're
already bleeding on me?
l'm so embarrassed.
l'll clean it up.
l'll get it.
You want somethin' to drink?
Do you have a tampon?
ln the cabinet, under the sink.
Where are we, anyway?
Lower East Side.
So, l'll call you.
Yeah, you'll call me.
[phone rings]
Hello?
- Hey.
What a surprise.
l didn't expect to
hear from you so soon.
Yeah, l know.
The rules and all...
but l just wanted to say
l had a really good time
with you last night.
Yeah, me too.
Bye.
So, how was it last night?
AKA, this morning?
And don't leave out
the hot details.
Well, put it this way...
she ate my cookies
until the box was empty.
Now that's what
l'm talking about!
l won't get with a chick
if the sex ain't right!
lt's all about the pussy!
That's the real way
to a woman's heart.
True. l'm definitely
gonna see her again.
Well, hell yeah!
You'd better see her...
before someone else sees her.
The Viking Killer.
Very useful if you're
trying to stretch him out.
Does she know you're a domme?
Nah.
That shouldn't be a problem.
She seems mad chill.
l don't know, babe,
usually it's only
a matter of time...
unless you find someone
who thinks it's normal.
Who would think this is normal?
l do.
Yeah, but eventually
l wanna have
a serious and
normal relationship.
With a girl, of course.
You just need someone
that's open-minded.
Or a domme who understands.
We are doing exactly
what we want to be doing.
How many people can say that?
That's true, but...
l don't think l'm
gonna be doin' this
for too much longer.
l want to go back
to nursing school,
and l wanna have
a wifey and a kid.
Really?
l could see that.
You'd be a cute mommy.
Yeah.
But for now just remember,
we're alternative therapists.
And this is our
contribution to society, right?
[knock on door]
lt's open!
Hey, hey, hey!
What's up, girl?
Hi.
Got some presents for you.
- All right.
- No. l want that one.
OK.
- You wanna stay?
- Hell, yeah.
What's up with that
little dime piece
you broke out with
the other night?
You in love yet?
Shut the fuck up.
You know how you lez out
at lighting speed.
What's up with your script?
Well, y'all inspire me,
so l been writin' down
some new ideas.
What's it about?
lt's kind of
a 'slice of life' thing...
about being happy
and an individual.
ls that it?
- Yeah.
- Cool.
l just been fuckin' around
with some dialogue.
What, what?
That's pretty funny.
But a woman
wouldn't say it like that.
That sounds like a dude.
Do you mind?
No, go ahead.
That's tight.
How about we change
this whole scene?
Yeah, l was thinkin'
we should have her
shit on him.
They're not ready for that!
No, it would be cool,
'cuz l ain't never seen that
in a movie before.
Yeah, there's a reason;
nobody wants to see that shit.
l do.
- No hot lunches!
- All right.
Wee!
Damn, girl, you crazy.
[phone ringing]
- Hey, sexy.
- l'll meet you by the tree...
- l'll meet you by the tree.
By the tree...
You ready?
- She's cute.
- ls she?
She's right there.
Oh, shit, she is fly.
What's up, mama?
Jasmine, this is my boy, Noah.
What's up, Jazzy-Jazz?
lt's good.
l heard a lot about you, girl.
All good shit though,
it's all good.
All right, Noah.
l'll see you later.
Nice meetin' you.
l'm gonna go play
some handball.
And l'll check you later.
- Awesome. Bye.
- Take care.
[giggling, chatting]
- Yo, Nat!
- Hey!
What's good, ma?
Been chillin'
How you doin'?
l'm good, l'm good.
l haven't seen you in mad long.
Where you been?
l'm around.
Just been busy,
workin' on some stuff.
A'ight, l'll see you.
All right.
You know...
l've been thinkin' about you.
Yeah?
Don't get offended by me
asking you this...
but somethin' tells me,
you probably a playa, right?
l mean, you seein' mad girls?
No, not at all. Why?
Cuz...
l'd like to get to know you
a little better.
Really?
That'd be nice.
All right...
l need to get this
out in the open.
l work in the sex industry.
Yeah, like a stripper?
No.
Slingin' drinks?
Don't tell me
you're a call girl.
No way.
l'm a domme.
Like...a dominatrix?
Yeah, like a dominatrix.
Wow.
l mean, you don't seem
like the type.
What type is that?
l don't know.
l just imagined
old German women
with big tattoos and piercings.
OK...
Well, you gonna tie me up,
spank me,
and call me Shirley?
Where do you find
these fucking actors -
in the mental home?
Jesus Christ!
You call yourself
a casting director?
l need these people in a week!
[knock on door]
Excuse me.
Our delivery from Confidential
Commodities is here.
l'll call you right back.
Come on in.
- Hey!
- What up, my brotha?
You got that
good shit, pretty boy?
How you feelin', Mikey?
ln about 30 minutes
l'm going to be feeling irie.
By the way...
it's Michael.
Watcha' got, bro?
l got some
good shit in from Cali.
That right there
is your Sweet Berry,
We got the Sour Diesel...
We got the Af-Gooey.
And that right there
is my top seller...
Purple Sour O.G Kush!
Hey!
What did l tell you
about knocking?
Sorry.
Can l...um, have some?
Only because you
look so delicious.
Try the Purple Sour O.G Kush.
lt'll ease whatever
pain that ails you, or--
Or my money back?
How about dinner?
l'll let you know.
Sick body, right?
You should see her naked!
You wouldn't know
what to do with that, bro.
You 'da man!
Yeah?
Do l get the same guarantee?
l play for the home team...
You know my shit
is always guaranteed.
Whatever.
Just get the fuck out of here.
Some of us have
some real work to do.
All right...
Look, Mike...
Forgive me...
l know you must get
this all the time,
but l got this
great idea for a script.
Oh, great. Another script.
Just what l need.
lt's in the beginning stages,
but l was hopin'
you'd take look at it
when l'm finished.
Finish?
lf you ever finish,
it'll get thrown onto a pile
with a million other scripts
after a million re-writes
and then some sweet-ass
little intern will read it
and steal your fucking idea!
Look, Nomar--
Noah.
l know.
You're always on time
and your weed's pretty good,
so stick to your day job
and leave the movie making
to us professionals!
OK, Spike Lee?
OK.
Success and nothin' less,
my man.
Yeah, whatever.
Close the fucking door!
Were you born in a tent?
Close the door!
And then it got stuck.
Stuck?
Up his ass.
l hate stickys.
He was jumping up and down
and everything,
but his ass just
swallowed it whole.
Did you try the forceps?
Of course.
lt was in way too deep.
Birthing position?
Squatting position?
- Hospital?
- Had to.
St. Vincent's or Roosevelt?
St. Vincent's...
They have a lot of experience
with this type of thing.
OK, this is disgusting.
Honey, they love it.
Damn, these dudes will have
you do anything they want.
You got it twisted.
Even if they come in
for something specific,
l just figure out
their weakness
and get them to do
whatever l want.
So let me get this straight.
They tell you
what they want,
but then you don't do it?
Well, every Mistress
has her methods.
l like to expand their horizons.
You're doin'
a whole lot more
than expanding their horizons.
They love this shit.
lt sounds like you all love it.
They love it!
l just think we're all goddesses
and men should be serving us.
- Amen.
- Yeah!
Yeah!
OK, great.
l'll see you tomorrow.
Thanks so much.
What's up, mama?
l just got an interview
to possibly intern
on a feature film tomorrow.
Ooh!
Oh, my God.
l'm so happy for you.
Good luck.
Thanks.
lf l get it, we'll have
to celebrate this weekend.
Well, l just hope
you put some money aside,
'cuz, you know...
being a domme spoils you.
l mean...
You are gonna make
in a week
what you can make
in an hour doing this.
That's why eventually,
everyone comes back.
Yeah, l know, but...
l gotta try.
And you are trying!
That's awesome.
But when you do come back,
l'll be here to welcome you
and tell you it's OK.
l never said l was quitting...
Just takin' a break.
He said he wants
to be mummified!
What should l do?!
Wrap him up in Saran Wrap.
Waist up first,
then the bottom half.
Just remember to cut
air holes for the head.
Tape 'em up.
Oh...OK.
Thanks.
Wow...
You look amazing,
you little shit.
Thanks.
lt doesn't even look like me.
No, it doesn't!
What are you wearing?
Fetish gear.
Oh, my God.
Has Mommy seen this yet?
Yeah. She wants a copy.
So who's this new girl
you're in love with?
- What new girl?
- Oh, c'mon.
Her name is Jasmine.
She's wonderful.
l met her at Juicy's.
Does she know what you do?
Yeah. She doesn't care.
Really?
That's great.
Hey!
l got hung up at work.
OK.
Are you OK?
Yeah.
You sure?
What's up?
Nothin.
A'ight.
You know
l'm feelin' you, right?
Yeah.
When l met you
l didn't think l'd care,
but the more l'm feelin' you
the more it's starting
to bother me.
l don't know how long
l can deal with
this stuff that you do.
lt's fuckin' with my head.
Really?
Yeah.
Do you like it?
l mean, do you get off on it
or is just your job?
To be honest...
it's a little of all three.
Look, it's what l do.
lt's what l chose to do
way before l met you.
l know.
l'm just tryin'
to be honest with you
and tell you how l feel.
And l want you to be honest,
but don't judge me.
No. no. l'm not.
l think you're really
creative and smart.
l feel like there's so much
more to you
than just beating
men's asses...
Even though most men
need their asses beat.
But you know what l'm sayin'.
Look, Noah's hooking me
up on a job
one of his customers
is directing.
Are you serious?
Why didn't you tell me?
That's what l'm talkin' about.
lt's just as an intern.
l'm not even hired yet.
No, but you're on your way!
Yes!
[machine beeps]
Natalie...
He said he called you
but you're not calling him back.
What's going on?
l wanna live long enough
to be a great-grandmother.
Why aren't you calling him back?
What's good, baby girl?
Noah!
Thank you so much
for hooking that up.
- All right.
- l hope l get it.
We'll see if you thank me
after you meet him.
He's a real dickhead.
Whatever, l'm sure
l can handle him.
All right.
How bad can he be?
You got somethin' new?
Yeah.
l was thinkin' that Natalie
needs to be more vulnerable.
You understand?
Like, we have to have her
learn something.
Dude, we have to
change her name.
- Why?
- Because that's what you do.
You don't use your own name
in a movie based on yourself.
l wanna use my name.
l'm proud of my shit.
lt's unprofessional.
Done.
l can not wait till we get
this shit in the can.
l can stop sellin' weed,
you could stop
beatin' dudes up.
l like beating dudes up.
And l like selling weed.
But l do see bigger
and better things for us.
Let me see if l can
get this internship first.
All right, cool.
l like that.
Baby steps...
baby steps!
You ready?
Yeah, come on.
Next scene.
[alarm clock buzzing]
Nobody should
be up at this time.
lt's OK, baby.
l'm gonna make you breakfast.
You're so cute.
We gotta get up
and take a shower.
l'll make you some coffee
and some eggs.
So, are you nervous?
Nah, l'm fine,
kind of excited.
l really appreciate you tryin'.
l didn't even do anything yet.
All right, l am
a little bit nervous.
You wanna meet me at Meow Mix
for a drink later?
l think l'm gonna need it.
Stop trippin.
You'll be fine.
And yes, l'll meet you.
l gotta go.
Try not to start directing
on your first day.
Direct? Fuck that!
l wanna produce!
- Bye.
- Knock 'em dead!
Hey...
Uh, do you know
where l can find Omar?
[chain saw revving]
No! No!
Cut!
Cut! Cut! Cut!
Who the fuck tied her up?
l did.
Let me try again. Sorry.
Jesus Christ!
No, no, no!
Get outta here,
you milk toast motherfucker!
Jesus Christ!
Doesn't anybody know how
to tie a fucking knot?
l could do it.
Who the hell are you?
l'm Natalie, a P.A.
l've been bringing you
coffee all day.
Really?
Well, sure, give it a shot.
So what do you guys think?
l am very impressed.
And maybe you've got some other
skills that we could explore.
Just glad to help.
Hmm, chill.
She's got ambition.
l like it.
What do you think?
Tasty cakes for sure.
l will be fucking her.
What the fuck?
Let's shoot! Come on!
All right, everyone,
back to 1 !
Let's lock it up
and let's roll this puppy!
[chain saw revs]
OK, if we could drop
this one and this one,
we might make it before lunch.
OK, let's do it.
Um, Natalie!
Hey! What's up?
l just wanted to thank you
for what you did before.
lt made a huge difference.
Oh, no problem at all.
l don't think we've been
officially introduced.
l'm Michael.
lt's a pleasure to
actually work with someone
who makes my job easier.
Most of these assholes
don't know what they're doing.
Thanks.
lt's just fascinating watching
a movie come together.
What part of the business
are you interested in?
Writing, directing, producing -
all of it!
Should have known.
Well, stick close to the camera.
Maybe l can teach you
a thing or two.
OK, l will.
See you tomorrow?
Sure. Bright and early.
Bye.
You know she's total Lesbianese?
So nice to lay in bed with you.
At least you don't have to
wake up at the crack of dawn.
Yeah, now l'm gonna be
getting in at the crack of dawn.
We're shootin' nights
this week.
Damn...
Let me take you to breakfast.
Then we can chill in the park
for a few before you go to work?
l have an appointment.
What kind of appointment?
With a client.
l thought you stopped
doin' all that.
Yeah, for the most part,
but l kept a few regulars.
Why?
You know l'm interning
and l'm not getting paid.
This isn't about the money.
Look, l told you before
it's not all about the money.
l'm gonna stop when l'm ready.
By the time you're ready
l may not be here.
And you know what?
l hate the fact that some
random guy's jerkin' off
to your fucking picture and
it doesn't even bother you!
lt's just a picture.
Why does it bother you?
l'm your fuckin' girl,
that's why.
Ashley!
You can't be here!
Really? Why?
l just wanted to come visit you.
This is not part
of our arrangement.
l've been shopping all day.
l wanna show you what l bought.
Ashley, l have to
get back to work!
No, Jim.
Walk with me.
l gave you my credit card.
What more do you want?
That's only part of it.
l want to know what
you think of what l bought
with your hard-earned money.
But Ashley,
l have a board meeting.
Then you better get started.
Ashley, please don't
do this to me.
This is not cool.
l really gotta go.
Perhaps we should
play the video of
your extra-curricular activities
at your board meeting.
Hey, Jim.
Down on one knee.
Down here.
Try those first.
What are you waiting for, Jim?
Put them on.
Let's go, Jim.
l don't have all day.
Ooooh, l like these!
What do you think, Jim?
They're beautiful.
You know...
l think l need
a woman's opinion.
Excuse me.
Do you mind if l ask...
What do you think
of these shoes?
l like 'em.
l think they're hot.
l like 'em too.
l just love shoes.
They make me so happy.
l guess you could say
l have a little shoe fetish.
Right, Jim?
Now take out that next box.
Not that one.
The other one.
Forget that for now.
l've been shopping all day
and l could really use
a foot massage.
Why are you doing this to me?
Because...
lt's fun.
Now get to work.
l put something extra in it.
Thank you.
That was better than l expected.
l'm glad you enjoyed it.
lt was fun for me, too.
lt felt so real.
You make it so real!
Even my fantasies
aren't this good.
l love you!
Are you in college?
No. Why?
What is that?
lt's just a script.
Oh, you're a writer?
Yeah.
lt's somethin' l'm working on.
- l'd love to read it.
- Oh, God, no.
Besides, l'm not finished yet.
Come on..
l'd give you my honest opinion.
OK.
l'll send it to you.
Thanks.
Enjoy.
Taxi!
Are you ready to be my slave?
lt's your turn now, Jasmine.
lt's only a a matter of time.
Eventually...
everyone becomes my slave.
[evil laughter]
Fuck!
l'm goin' fuckin' crazy.
[knock at door]
Nobody's home!
Hi!
l just want to drop these off.
Come in, come in.
Sit down...
Relax.
They are taking forever
to light this set,
so we can talk
about your career,
your goals, your dreams...
And what you're doin'
to achieve them.
Well, l want to make movies.
l've been writing this script...
and l want to
produce films as well.
Creative energy excites me.
lt is exciting...sometimes.
But if you wanna
be a filmmaker
you just gotta go for it.
Don't let anything
or anyone stop you.
And believe me...
They will try and stop you!
Yeah?
But...l'm sure you've
heard all this before.
Well, yeah,
but l asked you, right?
l'm interested
in what you're doing.
You're...smart.
So you're writing a screenplay?
Yeah...
Maybe when you get a minute,
you could take a look,
give us some notes?
Sure, sure.
What am l here for?
When you're finished,
drop off a copy for me.
Well...
l'm impressed.
You're really
on top of your shit.
Well, l'm a fast learner.
Trust me -
When l put my mind
to something...
l usually get what l want.
You know...l think that
you will have no trouble
working your way up
in this business.
ln fact, l might be able
to help you.
Maybe we can help each other,
if you know what l mean.
l think l do.
ls that what you want, Michael?
Actually, yes.
That is what l want.
Well, l gotta warn you.
l'm a real...naughty girl.
Yeah...
l like naughty girls.
l bet you do.
So...
Have you ever been tied up?
No, but l've tied
a bunch of girls up.
l love being in control.
lt makes me hot.
Yeah?
Whatever turns you on, sweetie.
This is getting me
so fucking excited.
Yeah?
Are your panties getting wet?
Fuck!
You are good.
l really can't
move here, sweetie.
Good.
l want you completely helpless.
l wanna fuck
the shit out of you.
And l want you
to shut the fuck up.
l have a special surprise
for you.
l want you to feel
as hot as l do.
Do you want to fuck me, Michael?
Uh huh...
You wish.
You see...
You've been a bad boy.
And bad boys have to
be punished, Michael.
And l want you to know...
what you have coming to you.
First l'm gonna start
with your balls,
and l'm gonna
tie 'em up real tight.
And then l'm gonna
whip your ass
until you're crying
like a little bitch!
Then l'm gonna
spit in your face,
and pee right in your mouth.
That's right, Michael.
l'm gonna make you drink me.
l'm gonna show you
what a real bad girl
does to a bad boy!
l don't think
you're ready for this.
Hey, Michael, Miley said--
What the fuck are you doin'?
Can we get some scissors
for him in here, please?
Fuck!
Tell that fuckin', crazy bitch
that she is never allowed
on my set again!
Come on, sleepy head,
Get up!
Stop.
l'm sleeping
and l have a hangover.
See?
You were totally
the designated drunk last night.
l told you
to slow your ass down.
Wake up.
You gotta get up for work.
l got downsized.
We can cuddle all day.
Downsized?
How does an intern
get downsized?
What happened?
All right...
l got fired.
Fired?
For what?
What did you do?
What did l do?
Why do you immediately
think it was my fault?
Look...
lt's complicated, OK?
Me and the director, who is
a complete fucking asshole,
had a big misunderstanding.
l'm not surprised...
You stomp around like you're
the Queen of the City
and whatever you say goes
and that's that!
ls that how you see me?
Yeah...
Well, sometimes.
lt's just your energy.
Jazzy, you're not
makin' any sense.
l thought this was gonna work
when you got that new job.
Obviously it's not.
You'll probably just go back and
do that same shit again, right?
But l never stopped.
What l do has no reflection
on how l feel about you.
l have to share you with all
these perverts and freaks
looking at you,
droolin' all over you.
lt's bad enough the shit
we gotta go through day to day
as lesbians in this city,
and you invite that shit.
You don't have to
share me with anybody!
And the crazy thing is
you like that shit!
l see how much you love it.
l see how much your eyes
light up when you talk about it.
You try and find a girl
who's gonna love you
and deal with this shit.
l'm sorry...
lt's givin' me nightmares.
What do you want me to do?
lt doesn't even matter.
lt's who you are...
lt's what you are.
Sorry, l'm scared of all
this dominatrix shit.
l don't wanna
get caught up in it.
l don't know what to say.
- Hey.
Hey!
Hey what?
Are you all right?
Yeah, l'm fine.
OK...
Well, um...
l was on the subway
and there was this
really hot guy--
Jazz and l
got into another fight.
l'm sorry.
What was that about
the subway guy?
Oh, nothing.
Your girlfriend troubles
trump my almost getting
picked up by a blue-eyed hottie.
lt just keeps happening.
lt's crazy.
Well, are you doing
anything different?
What do you mean?
Well, some people might think
that the definition of crazy
is doing the same thing
over and over again
and expecting different results.
What?
Didn't Mommy say that?
Oh, shit.
Oh, fuck, l'm quoting Mommy?
Am l becoming Mommy?
Yeah...
The transformation has begun.
My life is over.
Oh, God...
Holy shit.
Hey, sis.
Are you all right?
Yeah, l'm fine.
Mommy says you're depressed.
Ma!
Why are you telling
everyone l'm depressed?
Rebecca's not everyone.
And you're all emotional.
Emotional?
Me and my girlfriend
just broke up.
Of course l'm emotional.
Don't you think you're
being overly sensitive?
No, l think you're being
a little insensitive.
lt's just because
we care about you.
The right person
will love you for who you are.
l know.
She wasn't right for you anyway.
How do you know?
She was just a little
too normal for you.
l liked her for me.
Natalie, your hair
looks really pretty.
Why don't you
leave it down today?
Enough with the hair thing, Ma.
ls there some fetish
we should know about?
What's your fascination
with our hair?
[all laughing]
No, no, no.
l just want you guys
to be healthy and happy.
l am happy...
l'm just tryin' to find myself.
You'll find yourself.
The important thing
to use your passion
to define your place
in this world.
[knocking at door]
- Hey, Noah.
- Are you all right?
How did you know?
Melanie told me.
lt's just stupid.
Everything's so stupid.
l know.
lt's gonna be all right.
l got you.
You're gonna bounce back.
You're the motherfuckin'
queen bee,
the bad girl extraordinaire!
C'mon now.
Bad girl...
The job, the relationship,
the director.
Bad, bad, bad.
You're right...
l am the
bad girl extraordinaire,
but not in a good way.
Come here...
ln times like these,
there's only two things
you can turn to -
Friends...
And of course...
da ganja, mon.
Come on.
l'm so upset right now
l don't even wanna smoke.
Come on, girl!
Get the fuck outta here!
Last week we were like
Cheech and Chong
in this muthafucker!
l can't even focus.
You got a bad case
of girl drama,
which means you're
gonna forget about
this shit in a week.
Now come on.
All right.
Here we go...
l gave him a copy of the script.
You did?
Can't have our shit
out there all unfinished...
l'll get our shit back.
Even if l have to beat his ass,
l will get our shit back.
You gonna get all
gansta on his ass?
l will haunt that motherfucker
like the soul
of a child molester.
[phone rings]
That's probably my grandmother.
Natalie!
lt's me, Michael.
Hey...
Look...l, uh...
l really need to
speak to you about--
Holy shit!
Michael as in dickhead Michael?
[phone rings]
Natalie, it's me again.
Look...
lf you're there, pick up.
l really need to talk to you--
Damn, you got him
sprung like that?
Tell me what happened.
Well, your boy was
gettin' all nasty with me,
and l had to show him
what nasty really is.
What the fuck you do?
[phone rings]
What the fuck?
Are you there?
Please, l'm begging you...
Pick up the phone, please--
Damn, ma.
How the fuck
did he get my number?
Let's get to work.
Please, please, please.
- Hey.
- Hey!
l miss you guys so much.
l don't even remember
the last time we all hung out
since l left the dungeon.
- Do you?
- Nope.
Since y'all are my best
friends, and my sisters,
l want you to be
the first to know...
l'm pregnant!
What?
- Are you serious
- Really?
Wow! You really did it?
That is so cool.
Can l just...
Oh, my God!
You are going to be
a great mother.
How do you feel?
Like l went to rehab...
For real!
l never thought l'd hear that
out of your mouth.
Well, there comes
a point in life
where you must grow up
and leave certain things behind.
l'm happy for you.
What's up with you, Mel?
l'm still doing my thing.
l have a ton of regular clients.
And l'm dating this guy,
and guess what?
He loves that l'm a domme.
l mean, l think he's really
kind of into it.
l've been having
an amazing time.
What about you, Nat?
l kept a couple of regulars.
But me and Noah are busy
with our script.
Oh, and how is that going?
The film business is rough,
but l love it!
Do you all wanna
get some ices?
- Yes!
- Yeah, yeah, yeah!
l wanna go first!
What are you doing
with your script?
l'm not sure what
the next step is,
except getting it produced.
l have to find someone
who believes in it...
and believes in me.
Well, l believe in you.
l care about you
and l want to help you.
That's sweet.
Thank you.
No, l'm serious.
l'm a good businessman
and l know people.
But l don't know
anything about film.
lf you can find
a hotshot director...
l'll back it.
Just leave all the finances
up to me.
Really?
You'd do that for me?
l'd do anything
for you, Mistress.
Psst...
My real name's Natalie.
Natalie!
Hey, um...
We need to talk.
Michael, what the fuck
are you doing here?
Are you stalking me?
No! l-l just...
l needed to see you.
What do you want, Michael?
You did something to me.
You unlocked something in me
l didn't know existed.
Something l can't control.
You know me...
l gotta control everything.
Yeah, you're an asshole.
lf we could just...
lf l could just
spend some time with you...
Maybe we can work something out?
Sure...
We can work somethin' out.
Step into my office.
Somebody will be here shortly
to prepare you
for your Mistress.
Hi.
l've been thinking about
what you said about me
not being ready...
And you were right.
But l'm ready now.
Oh, really?
Ready for what?
Ready to do whatever l...
Ready to do whatever
you want me to do.
OK.
The first thing
l want you to do...
My Normal, by Natalie Lawna
and Noah Cohen.
Scene One.
James, a middle-aged man
dressed in a suit
sits behind a desk
shuffling papers.
He shakes his head
and mutters...
We have a very
big problem here, girls.
Girls, we have
a very big problem.
We have a very
big problem, girls.
Girls, we have
a very big problem.
How big is our problem?
[dialogue continues
and fades]
Ashtray.
What have l done?
Marker.
You don't even know!
Hi.
Tell us a little bit
about your character.
My character is,
l guess, the gimp...
the ashtray.
He's the bitch of
the main character
and he's only there as
a receptacle for her garbage.
Can you tell me your name
and what you do?
My name is Storm,
and l'm a physical therapist.