uh... we don't know about that 'cause
this is happening right now but we do
know what they look like
because they have got video and it got
pictures of two suspects
lissa here from f_b_i_ today where
listing the public's help to identify
the two suspects
after very detailed analysis of photo
video and other evidence
we are releasing photos of these two
suspects
they are identified a suspect one and
suspects who
they appear to be associated
suspect one is wearing a dark at
suspects who was wearing a white house
suspects who sat down a backpack at the
site of the second explosion
just in front of the forum restaurant
terial
immediately everybody's learned of those
pictures going
are the middle eastern
or are they white
i'd look at adam all day long and
suspect there were two of the white hat
use that kind of a scruffy look there
in the beginning one of the shots of the
way he had a mustache
plays at a middle eastern mustache or is
that a west virginia mustache
i don't know
for now
that suspect number one with a black at
at least is smart enough to put the had
on forwarded supposed cover-up a space
and what is harder to see him
uh... summer saying he looks darker i
can understand why they're saying that i
don't know if it's a stigma cap
or fears darker this idiot has done with
the baseball cap on backwards
thereby giving the whole point because
we did see his face a lot better
it's not covering his face
so
those aren't you guys and everybody in
the country now look at those pictures
over and over
obviously if you're in the boston area
wondering if you know them to spot them
to figure out who they are
uh... on that note let me just say
whatever you do not do the joy the
justice
based on these pictures you are not
going to have any certainty whatsoever
you should call that the i wanna eight
hundred call f_b_i_
if you think you've got a lead on 'em
absolutely don't take action on your own
this is no way you could be absolutely
sure base on those pictures they can do
further investigations and figure out if
really at those guys are really it or
not right
now yesterday on the show i told you
i was on her all those radio show as
south because then
that's what he said he was
and so we're looking for these guys and
they cops bettered
uh... they better hope the cops get in
before we do
you don't know who got the right guy
don't they go on your own hands now
at going back to the race issue come up
i think hop suspect number two at the
white house looks white
that's what everybody's saying that
the other guy looks darker
uh...
can you tell
jr hasten his thoughts
that's exactly what it looks like he
looks like the person suspect as glasses
you've gone on here
that several of them in person
c and that is that this year is is that
the act he created he looks like he did
poorly be white
and could it be a lighter shade of
middle-eastern
i want to go
these are things you can win uh... law
enforcement gets too
is that
our look at this hour they must have
something then we
also you find my like this
yet but you know the is
uh... my guess they don't have a better
than this otherwise it was sherry cuz
they work
if you're sharing the pictures that
means we don't
have them
and we need your help
now to are certainly not look like much
but if you knew of the guys
then you might see him women did that
looks like bob
and that's what helps the thorniest but
then you got a report it to them so now
the reason why race is relevant here of
course
look it's gonna be a much different
reaction in the country keep it real if
it's white words middle east davis rotor
orton article that was
very controversial early in the week
talking about you know he's rooting for
them to be white
now as we got the pictures
i realize why he was right
weakest as i was out of the bridges
honestly i was rooting for them to be
white
because look at their white people
aren't going to go on random violent
attacks basis there are typing white
people
suffocated alike all dude is a white guy
let's attack a
that's not gonna happen in this country
because a majority the treasury's white
uh... any people get it you'd r_b_c_
can't make that assumption distrust
because the boss unabomber was white
you should attack brenda white people on
force after nine eleven a lot of people
may decide chin sister taggers are
muslim there we should attack random
muslim people now is that assumption
baeza of course i just loved i was
assuming never a white guys a bomber if
these guys turn out to be white
or let's eternity right wingers can you
make the assumption
leisure tag every right warehouse if it
is that
r_t_c_ can do that
these are extremists no matter what
their politics says
and a lot of other ideology or
nationality or races
but unfortunately becomes a muslims in
this country people do make assumptions
of undoubtedly the wrong as substance
after nine eleven and it's so continues
to this day a lot of sikhs were attacked
it was a bitter but also they get its
act position in the sikh temple
people are still that dumb this late in
the process
i couldn't help us say hey you know what
man
i hope they are not middle eastern
'cause we know what happens when their
middle eastern and it has been pretty
whereas the people are not going to make
a research hopes about why people in
this country so that's part of the
reasoning behind it not being honest
about it now do i know who they are of
course i don't i i don't know if they're
white and middle eastern
whether nationality or what their
ideology is
but i sure hope the parties get 'em
uh... because
i'm also worried that it's been a couple
of days now if they planned this well
and they planted well ahead of time
they obviously
should i have an escape route
and we didn't get them in a couple of
days and if they were foreigners
it even if they're not borders they
could be long gone
god knows where they are
it we have a name we might be able to
track them down better
out but i was there incredibly series
entirely possible
they wouldn't be
anywhere near the boston area now
another hand we've seen time and time
again
wears a guy you're looking for
right next to you
eleven with christopher dorfner and have
been all the way back with a with
interpret an end
that he killed reciting in miami no i
don't like i was using it as well as a
target self
now internet is a couple months down the
street in miami
we don't know yet
but with a whole country's hoping we
find him
no matter what their ideology or their
racists