is finally becoming a reality.
This is from a
couple of days ago.
And it is still one of
the biggest videos today.
It's got Christopher
Lloyd, AKA Doc Brown,
unveiling the world's
first working hoverboard.
TONY HAWK: I can't
believe how well it works.
I didn't think it'd
be that smooth.
You know, it always
looked, in the movies,
like it was just awkward.
It was going sideways.
And once I got on
it, it felt natural.
MOBY: It's intuitive.
Like, the moment you start
riding it, you know what to do.
JACOB SOBOROFF:
It's magnificent.
It's wonderful.
It's a hoax.
[IMITATES BUZZER]
Yesterday our darkest
fears were confirmed.
TONY HAWK: I want to apologize
for the hoverboard prank.
I wish as much as you do
that hoverboards were real.
And I'm sure that
one day they will be.
But until then, we
still need roads.
JACOB SOBOROFF: Be
honest, were you fooled?
We put together a
great playlist for you
after the show of some
of the best fake ads
and hoaxes on the web.
LIZZIE: We've all been
watching the events
in Ukraine unfold for
the last few months.
And the situation is
overwhelmingly complex.
Thankfully, John Green
was put on this earth
to explain every major crisis.
The VlogBrothers just posted
this comprehensive history
of the Ukrainian conflict
dating all the way back
to the 19th century.
JOHN GREEN: In 2004,
there was an election.
And there were widespread
reports of vote rigging,
but the Russian-friendly
Viktor Yanukovych was elected.
The opposition leader,
Viktor Yushchenko
led massive street
protests in Kiev
that came to be known as
the Orange Revolution.
The arc of history
is long, Hank.
Let's hope that it
bends toward peace.
LIZZIE: Seriously,
watch the whole thing.
It's only seven minutes.
And share it if you can.
It's so important
to understand why
this is all happening right now.
JACOB SOBOROFF:
Julian Smith has been
called the Monty
Python of YouTube.
And even though he only posts
about once a month, his videos,
I'm telling you, are
always worth the wait.
[MUSIC - JULIAN SMITH, "CAR
PHONE!"]
Julian has more than 100
high-quality, high-concept
videos on his channel.
Get into it.
MILES: Whatever.
As if.
How could anyone
forget "Clueless"?
The video for Australian rapper
Iggy Azalea's new single,
"Fancy", has her teaming up
with UK artist Charli XCX
to pay homage to
the hit '90s film.
[MUSIC - IGGY AZALEA FT.
CHARLI XCX, "FANCY"]
Iggy even included
250 of her fans
in the production as extras.
The attention to detail in
this video is ridiculous.
That's probably why it already
has over 2 million views
in just a couple days.
Side note, I met Iggy once.
But don't worry,
I played it cool.
JACOB SOBOROFF:
Who's Jamie O'Brien?
Only one of the
biggest freesurfing
badasses I have ever seen.
And we have an exclusive look
at his new reality web series.
It launches tomorrow
morning at 10:00 AM.
And besides some
awesome surfing,
you can watch as Jamie, once
again, tortures his buddy
Poopies.
I'm not sure that's
his given name.
POOPIES: I'm scared.
JAMIE O'BRIEN: That
looks like a life jacket
you get on the snorkeling boat.
JACOB SOBOROFF: Prepare yourself
by watching past seasons
on Red Bull's channel right now.
I promise you, it is
much safer than paddling
into some of these waves.
TAY ZONDAY: I'm Tay Zonday.
And I'm here to take you
back to April 22, 2007, when
I uploaded the video
"Chocolate Rain".
[MUSIC - TAY ZONDAY, "CHOCOLATE
RAIN"]
The video sat around
for about three months.
Then someone posted it on Digg.
It got picked up on 4chan.
And boom, I ended up
on "Jimmy Kimmel."
I did a big ad with Dr. Pepper.
It was a national news story.
[MUSIC - TAY ZONDAY, "CHERRY
CHOCOLATE RAIN"]
I make tons of videos.
I'm still doing original music.
You can check it
out on my channel.
The best thing to come
out of "Chocolate Rain"
for me are the stories
and hearing that perhaps I
was a small part of making
people's days a little bit
brighter.
And that's very touching.
JACOB SOBOROFF: No
YouTube experience
is complete without
a little Tay Zonday.
You guys have a favorite
throwback video?
Let us know using the
hashtag #YouTubenation.
Now play us out,
The Chainsmokers.
[MUSIC - THE CHAINSMOKERS,
"#SELFIE"]