CLEO LE TAN: We're going
to the flea market.
I cannot really remember the
last time and I cannot really
remember why, but I have
already been here.
I don't like the aesthetic
of reggae.
I only like the sound of it.
That's not the way it looks.
This is the Thug Life t-shirt.
If anybody wants to give
me a Christmas gift,
this is what I want--
Thug Life t-shirt.
"If you want to fuck me, you
would need a whole army to
fuck me in the bum."
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
MALE SPEAKER 1:
CLEO LE TAN: Oh, it's not about
sex, this t-shirt, it's
about fucking people over.
During our little walk around
the market, we heard that a
rapper called Morsay had
a clothing store there.
Morsay is controversial even in
the rap world and infamous
for raps about raping,
torturing, and killing anybody
that makes fun of him.
So I was a bit nervous.
MORSAY: [SPEAKING FRENCH]
CLEO LE TAN: [SPEAKING FRENCH]
CLEO LE TAN: We just met this
young gentleman in real life,
and he looks much less scary,
much less mean, and more nice.
So should I buy this?
Maybe I'll buy this.
Maybe not.
I'll think about it.
The Pyramides Estate in Evry was
one of the worst affected
by the riots, and it's still
known for violence between
rival gangs.
We went there to meet the rapper
Al-K-Pote who had a big
hit last year with a song called
"Bande de Putains Sales
Putes," which roughly translates
as, "bunch of
fucking dirty whores," which
isn't very nice.
We're walking through Evry,
and it's perfectly nice.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
Al-K-Pote's there, apparently.
Do you think he's lying?
He's lying.
On our first visit to meet
Al-K-Pote, not only did he not
show up, but a gang of teenagers
threw a lightbulb at
our cameraman's head, which was
also not very nice at all.
I didn't get a good vibe from
this neighborhood in any way.
No one was nice.
Bullies, bullies, that's
what they were.
Undeterred, we returned to the
Pyramids a few days later for
a second attempt to meet him.
AL-K-POTE: [SPEAKING FRENCH]
CLEO LE TAN: He took us to his
studio, which was through a
dark alleyway under a bridge.
This made us all feel
extremely awk.
SIKO: [SPEAKING FRENCH]
MALE SPEAKER 1:
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
SIKO: [SPEAKING FRENCH]
MALE SPEAKER 2:
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
AL-K-POTE: [SPEAKING FRENCH]
CLEO LE TAN: Despite the odd
beginnings of our encounter,
Al-K-Pote seemed a good person
who was genuinely concerned
for the well being
of the younger
members of his community.
To make things even more fun,
I got a call from my friend
Vincent, who's one of Paris's
most renowned raconteurs.
He told me that he had tickets
to watch one of my favorite
singers, the French diva Arielle
Dombasle, at the
Chatelet Theater.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
This is a special music
hall kind of show.
She's a very famous French
singer, and I think she's in
her 60s, but she dresses
like a Barbie doll.
She's very funny
and very cool.
Even more fun was that she was
going to be performing with a
guy called Mokobe, who was in
one of France's most famous
rap groups, 113.
That's him!
MOKOBE: Do you speak French?
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
CLEO LE TAN: [SPEAKING FRENCH]
I wonder when he'll come back.
Then we followed him to the
stage, even though we weren't
allowed to.
MALE SPEAKER 3:
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
CLEO LE TAN: [SPEAKING FRENCH]
MALE SPEAKER 3:
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
CLEO LE TAN: And then we got
caught, and they were furious
because she's really famous.
She's got loads of bodyguards
and so the
theater is really strict.
But it was fun.
It was a fun moment.
So now we're just going
to wait for Mokobe.
Here they come.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
I was under the impression that
Mokobe was trying to get
rid of us, but I really wanted
to talk to him properly, so we
followed him anyway.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
MOKOBE: [SPEAKING FRENCH]
CLEO LE TAN: [SPEAKING FRENCH]
VINCENT DARRE: [SPEAKING FRENCH]
MOKOBE: [SPEAKING FRENCH]
CLEO LE TAN: [SPEAKING FRENCH]
VINCENT DARRE: [SPEAKING FRENCH]
ARIELLE DAMBOSLE:
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
CLEO LE TAN: [SPEAKING FRENCH]
MOKOBE: [SPEAKING FRENCH]
CLEO LE TAN: I had a wonderful
time at the opera, even if
Mokobe was a bit awk.
But when I told Byron about
it, he seemed distinctly
unimpressed and told us, if you
really want to know about
what's happening in the French
rap scene, then come with me
now, because we're going back
to Clichy to meet the future
players in underground
French rap.
So we did.
OK, I'm going in there to
find some young people.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
BYRON: [SPEAKING FRENCH]
CLEO LE TAN: I think the
responsible guy came in and
was like, you can't do this.
You had to ask me.
We're about to find out.
Oh, there's something
going on.
There's something honestly
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
CLEO LE TAN: Well, I wasn't
expecting this at all.
We tried to smooth things
out, but no one was
giving me any attention.
And then the youth center man
tried to smash our camera.
MALE SPEAKER 4:
[YELLING IN FRENCH]
CLEO LE TAN: After a while,
everybody calmed down and made
up, and we finally got to meet
the kids that Byron had been
raving about.
[RAPPING IN FRENCH]