in from Carl as we start a new week of CNN
STUDENT NEWS.
First up, we are heading to Kenya, it has
the largest economy in East Africa. It`s a
relatively stable country in the region that
isn`t always stable. And it`s a major U.S.
Ally in the war against terrorism. So, what
happens in Kenya, can have a big impact on
other countries. Here is what happened there
this weekend.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: I therefore declare Uhuru
Kenyatta the newly elected president ...
(CHEERS AND APPLAUSE)
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: ... of the Republic of
Kenya.
RAILA ODINGA: Now, it is clear that the constitutionally
sanctioned process of electing a new set of
leaders to take us to the next level has been
thwarted by another tainted election.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
ANDRES: Uhuru Kenyatta, the son of Kenya`s
first president, is said to become its youngest
president. He`s also facing charges from the
International Criminal Court. The charges
against Kenyatta involve his alleged role
in violence after Kenya`s last presidential
election in 2007, when he was not a candidate.
Kenyatta denies those charges. Raila Odinga
was Kenyatta`s main challenger in this election.
He is the one who said it was tainted. Kenya`s
constitution says the candidate has to earn
just more than 50 percent in order to win.
Kenyatta got 50.07 percent. Odinga said he`ll
challenge the election results in court.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Is this legit? Vatican
City is the smallest country in the world.
It`s true. Vatican City, which is also called
The Holy See is smaller than the National
Mall in Washington D.C.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
ANDRES: Vatican City is also the headquarters
of the Roman Catholic Church. The pope is
the head of that church, but right now, there
is no pope. Pope Benedict XVI resigned last
month. Tomorrow, cardinals, leaders in the
Catholic Church will start the process of
electing a new pope during a conclave. Jonathan
Mann explains what that is and how it works.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
JONATHAN MANN, CNN CORRESPONDENT: It`s the
oldest enduring electoral system in the world.
And many of its traditions have been unchanged
for centuries. The conclave, which literally
means locked with a key dates back to a time
when cardinals were locked in until they chose
a new pope. Now, it`s the world that`s locked
out, figuratively speaking, as much of the
conclave will take place behind closed doors.
The gathering begins with a morning mass in
St. Peter`s Basilica. In the afternoon the
115 voting cardinals, those under 80 years
old, enter the Sistine Chapel where each will
take an oath of secrecy. The penalty, automatic
excommunication. After the oath, preparations
are made for the election taken by secret
ballot. Lots are drawn to select three cardinals
who will help collect ballots, three more
cardinals to count the votes, and three others
to review the results. Printed on the ballots,
the words "Eligo in Summum Pontifecem," meaning
I elect as Supreme Pontiff. Each elector writes
the name of one candidate on the lower half
of the ballot and folds it in half. Cardinals
are not allowed to vote for themselves. Then
in order of seniority, the cardinals take
their ballots to the altar. Each places a
folded ballot onto a small desk and then the
ballot is dropped into a chalice.
Once all the votes are cast, the ballots are
tallied, and the results are read aloud. More
than a two thirds majority is needed to declare
a winner, in this case, 77 votes. If there
is no winner, there is another vote. If there
is still no winner, two more votes are scheduled
for the afternoon. Voting continues up to
four ballots each day until there is a winner.
The ballots are burned after each session
in an incinerator inside the chapel. If there`s
no winner, they are burned with the chemical
that gives off black smoke telling the crowd
waiting in St. Peter`s Square that a new pope
has not yet been selected. When there is a
winner, white smoke, a sign from the cardinals
that they have chosen a new pope to lead the
church. Jonathan Mann, CNN, Atlanta.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today`s "Shoutout" goes
out to Mr. Bredehoeff`s history class at the
Tina-Avalon school in Tina, Missouri. The
USS Monitor was a naval ship involved in what
war? Here we go, was it the War of 1812, Civil
War, Spanish-American War or World War I?
You`ve got three seconds, go!
The Monitor was an iron-clad union ship used
during the U.S. Civil War. That`s your answer
and that`s your Shoutout
(END VIDEO CLIP)
ANDRES: The Monitor helped change the face
of naval warfare, with the ship from wooden
ships to iron ones. It sank around 150 years
ago, but that wasn`t the end of the ship`s
story. In 1973, the wreckage of the Monitor
was found. 2002, remains of two crew members
were discovered. And just this past Friday,
those remains were laid to rest. Barbara Starr
fills in the details.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
BARBARA STARR, CNN CORRESPONDENT: Shoes worn
by sailor 150 years ago, perhaps in the final
moments of his life on board the USS Monitor,
a renowned Civil War battleship.
(on camera): This is extraordinary. We are
looking mismatched, put a pair of shoes that
one of the sailors wore.
DAVID KROP, MARINER`S MUSEUM: He had a different
shoe on his left foot than he did on his right.
And it`s hard to explain why that is. One
of the possible options is that as these guys
were leaving the ship the night of the sinking,
it was chaotic, it was dark.
STARR (voice over): The shoes, just one clue
in the detective story that started 240 feet
below the surface of the sea. Who were the
two men whose skeletons were found in the
ship`s turret in 2002? The Navy is burying
them with full honors at Arlington National
Cemetery, not knowing the answer yet.
STARR: This is the 120 ton turret of the USS
Monitor. It`s seating in this water preservation
tank right now. This is the precise spot were
they found the remains of the two Navy sailors.
More clues, buttons from a uniform, a gold
ring, a comb, some coins. The Monitor itself
made history as the first iron-clad ship,
caught in the storm of December 30th 1862
off Cape Hatteras, North Carolina, it flipped
over and sank. 16 sailors were lost.
Captain Bobbie Scholley led Navy dives to
the wreckage.
CAPT. BOBBIE SCHOLLEY (RET.), NAVY DIVE TEAM
COMMANDER: We needed to take all the appropriate
steps necessary to recover those sailors with
all the honors and dignities.
STARR: A military lab analyzed the bones.
DNA samples were taken, facial reconstructions
were made. African-American sailors and officers
were eliminated. The remains were Caucasian.
The buttons - not from officer`s coats. The
list is now down to five or six men, two possibilities
- Robert Williams (ph) and William Ryan (ph).
Back at the water`s edge at Virginia, where
the Monitor battled the Confederacy, the official
who oversees the ship`s legacy says it`s more
than just history.
DAVID ALBERG, NOAA: Whether it was 150 years
ago, or two weeks ago in Afghanistan, the
nation`s commitment to bring her fallen home,
laying them to rest and returning them to
the families stays as strong today as it ever
was. Barbara Starr, CNN, Newport News, Virginia.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
ANDRES: Teachers, don`t forget to tell us
what you think about today`s show- the feedback
link is on our homepage. That`s also where
some students reply to our latest blog. We
asked what you thought about women competing
in male-dominated sports. Bobby is all for
it. "Women should have a chance to try and
show their talents." Claire thinks, "Girls
competing in sports is OK, if the girls are
physically able to play them." But Scott says,
"In sports like wrestling, with physical contact,
girls should have their own division."
Scott might think differently when he hears
Danielle Coughlin`s story. She is a high school
senior who loves to wrestle. When reporter
asked her about her competitive spirit, Danielle
had a very humble response.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Would you rather be described
as like tough or intimidating or something
like that?
DANIELLE COUGHLIN, HIGH SCHOOL WRESTLING CHAMPION:
Just a hard worker, that`s all.
ANDRES: Her hard work paid off, because Danielle
is a high school wrestling champ, and she
didn`t get the title by competing against
other girls, she beat her all male opponents
on the Massachusetts division Tuesday tournament,
Danielle is the first girl in the state`s
history to win a wrestling title. Here is
how she described the moment.
COUGHLIN: Definitely say it was probably the
moment in my life. And I`ll get my hand raised
after that match and thinking that eight years
worth of hard work got me there.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
ANDRES: If you want to talk to Danielle about
her huge accomplishment, do you have a question
you want to ask her? If so, you can tell us
on our Facebook or a blog or send us an iReport.
Ever wished someone else could do your chores
for you? Apparently, it just takes some training.
Jessie here can be an alarm clock, she can
fetch her owner a towel for the shower. She
even does house work. Maybe not the most thorough
dusting, but still impressive. Youtube videos
like this one have made Jessie a big hit.
She is eight years old, and I feel pretty
sure she didn`t know how to do any of this
stuff as a puppy. So I guess you can teach
an old dog new tricks. But don`t expect her
to do them right when you ask. After all,
Jessie is a terrier.
That`s where we pause for today. I`m Tommy
Andres. Have a great day.