CARL AZUZ, CNN ANCHOR: President Barack Obama,
Republican presidential nominee Mitt Romney
in 90 minute debate at Hofstra University
in Hempstead, New York, but the set up for
this one was different than their first debate
two weeks ago. This time it was a town hall
format. That means instead of the candidates
just answering questions from a moderator,
they were asked questions directly by members
of the audience. And for last night`s debate,
those questions came from people who hadn`t
yet made up their minds about whom they would
be voting for in November. This second presidential
debate covered domestic and foreign policy
issues, here is a look at some of the questions
and some of the candidates` answers.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: As a 20-year old college
student, all I hear from professors, neighbors
and others is that when I graduate, I would
have little chance to get employment. What
can you say to reassure me, but more importantly,
my parents that I`ll be able to sufficiently
support myself after I graduate?
MITT ROMNEY, REPUBLICAN PRESIDENTIAL CANDIDATE:
The key thing is to make sure you can get
a job when you get out of school. And what`s
happened over the last four years, it`s been
very, very hard for America`s young people.
I want you to be able to get a job. I know
what it takes to get this economy going. With
half of college kids graduating this year
without a college - without a job and without
a college level job, that`s just unacceptable.
And likewise, you get more and more debt on
your back. So, more debt and less jobs. I`m
going to change that. I know what it takes
to create good jobs again.
BARACK OBAMA, PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES
OF AMERICA: The most important thing we can
do is to make sure that we are creating jobs
in this country, but not just jobs, good paying
jobs, ones that can support a family. And
what I want to do is build on the 5 million
jobs that we`ve created over the last 30 months
in the private sector alone, and there are
a bunch of things that we can do to make sure
your future is bright. Number one, I want
to build manufacturing jobs in this country
again.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: In what new ways do you
intend to rectify the inequalities in the
workplace? Specifically regarding females,
making only 72 percent of what their male
counterparts earn?
OBAMA: Women are increasingly the breadwinners
in the family. This is not just a women`s
issue, this is a family issue, this is a middle
class issue. And that`s why we`ve got to fight
for it. It also means, that we`ve got to make
sure that young people like yourself are able
to afford the college education.
ROMNEY: We are going to have employers in
the new economy, in the economy I`m going
to bring to play that are going to be so anxious
to get good workers, they are going to be
anxious to hire women. In the last four years,
women have lost 580,000 jobs. That`s the net
of what`s happened in the last four years.
We are still down 580,000 jobs.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: See if you can I.D. me.
I`m a position in the U.S. presidential cabinet.
I`m fourth in line to the presidency. My primary
job is to give the president advice on foreign
policy and then carry out the president`s
policy.
I`m the Secretary of State, a position currently
held by Hillary Clinton.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Secretary Clinton says another part
of her job is to be in charge of security
at American diplomatic facilities, that means
U.S. embassy and consulate buildings in other
countries. One of those facilities, the U.S.
consulate in Benghazi, Libya, was the target
of a terrorist attack last month. Four Americans
were killed and there have been a lot of accusations
and questions about whether there was enough
security at the consulate, and about which
government officials should be held accountable.
HILLARY CLINTON, U.S. SECRETARY OF STATE:
I take responsibility. I`m in charge of the
State Department. 60,000 plus people, all
over the world, 275 posts. The president and
the vice president certainly wouldn`t be knowledgeable
about specific decisions that are made by
security professionals.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: A group of center Republicans responded
to Secretary Clinton statement. They called
it, a laudable gesture, but said the security
of Americans serving the nation around the
world is ultimately the job of the president.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today`s "Shoutout" goes
out to the social studies teachers and classes
at Bemidji Middle School in Bemidji, Minnesota.
Who was the first person to break the sound
barrier? Here we go. Was it Chuck Yeager,
Sally Ride, Neil Armstrong or Usain Bolt?
You`ve got three seconds, go.
Chuck Yeager broke the barrier when he flew
faster than the speed of sound in a rocket
plane named after his wife. That`s your answer
and that`s your "Shoutout."
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Yeager made that supersonic flight back
in 1947. He was an Air Force test pilot who
flew more than 200 types of military aircraft.
Yeager said his historic flight help give
the U.S. a huge advantage in aviation advancement.
Now, the speed of sound is the rate at which
sound waves move through different materials.
In the air it can depend a little on temperature.
But it`s usually around 750 miles per hour.
On Sunday, Felix Baumgartner was traveling
faster than that without a plane on his record
breaking skydive. But he wasn`t the only one
breaking the sound barrier. That same day
exactly 65 years to the minute after he first
broke it, Chuck Yeager did it again, the 89-year
old retired general went up in an F-15 jet
to fly faster than the speed of sound again.
All right, here is a quick quiz for you. What
is the best-selling toy of all time? Your
hint: it is not a doll, it`s not a videogame,
it`s not an action figure or a toy car. It`s
a puzzle, and it`s based on geometry. It`s
named after the guy who invented it and if
you give up, because I probably would have
by now, we are going to let Nick Glass fill
in the answer.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
NICK GLASS, CNN CORRESPONDENT: This is a stainless
steel sculpture of the world`s best-selling
toy here in a park in Hungary. We know better
from the handheld version, and hundreds of
millions of these can be found around the
world.
It`s named after the professor who first dreamt
up the puzzle in 1974. Although, against his
wishes, Erno Rubik didn`t really want to be
famous.
The Rubik`s Cube, the toy of 1980s, is now
enjoying the revival with 7 million sold last year.
A professor in interior design, Rubik first
used the cube as a teaching aid.
ERNO RUBIK, INVENTOR: I believe the most characteristic
part of the cube is contradiction between
simplicity and complexity. First of all, I
love geometry, because geometry is the knowledge
of how the whole universe is structured.
GLASS: The three-by-three cube consists of
27 cube faces. Color- coded, these can be
arranged in 43 quintillion different ways.
But there is only one solution.
The last few years has seen a rise in speed
cubing competitions, demon cubers racing against
each other and the clock. It`s been proved
that every cube can be solved in surprisingly
just 20 moves or less.
If only it was that easy.
Erno Rubik himself cannot compete with the
young guns. It took him a month to crack it
way back in 1974. And now ...
(on camera): Are you a good Rubik cube player?
RUBIK: It`s for me it was about one minute,
my time when I was practicing, and actual
world record is five point something seconds.
GLASS: Most toys come and go. But not Rubik`s
cube. It`s now almost 40 years old, and it`s
here to stay.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: Felix Baumgartner`s record skydive,
this video makes it look like child`s play.
But what do you expect when you recreate the
moment with Legos? They got it pretty close,
too, although I don`t think this capsule is
going up quite as high as Felix`s did. That
first step is still a doozy, and chances are,
this guy didn`t break the speed of sound on
his way down, but there were some cheers,
probably, when his chute open and he made
a successful landing. Of course, he refused
to give interviews afterward, he was kind
of a blockhead about it. But how do you come
up with the idea to recreate something like
that? You really have to use your homagination.
We were toying around with other ideas for
the pun, but it`s just time for us to Lego
your attention. We`ll see you tomorrow when
CNN STUDENT NEWS returns.