They're called Botham Burgers.
This is from the '80's.
This is what Duran Duran would have eaten.
You wanna make the perfect burger, Chuck steak
is the cut to go because there's a natural
mix of fat and incredibly tasty meat.
I've got some rosemary here. Beef and rosemary
are best friends, just a couple of little sprigs.
Jimbo, can you just pass me that Lincolnshire
Poacher. Look at that. Cooked or uncooked,
it's off the chart.
So, I'm just gonna take about 2, 3 ounces.
A little trick, you know, when you're doing
a burger, putting the cheese in there just
seasons it and makes it really delicious as well.
So just scrunch that in Jim. Now the whole
point of a Botham burger is it's a Botham Burger.
My old man's pub was called The Cricketers
and it was next to a cricket pitch and it
was after Ian Botham.
So basically, by doing this recipe we are
admitting that my old man has basically taken
advantage of a celebrity's name.
This is like our dream. I dunno, the last
time we did this we must have been...
We were about 15
Yeah. And camping out and it'd be like a tin
of beans and a backpack and a really crappy
tent.
I know.
Just imagine if our wives could see us right now.
I've told my wife I'm working really hard today.
Normally you put this in a really hot oven
and roast the burger. To create an oven I'm
just gonna put a metal tin over like this
and pour the charcoal on top so we've got
an oven basically, a little mini oven.
And then to go with it, the really important
part to making this work is a salsa.
In sort of New Mexico, L.A, East L.A with
the Mexican communities they just blacken
up peppers, tomatoes, I've got spring onions
in there.
I've got a Scotch Bonnet in there. Make sure
you put a hole in the Scotch Bonnet because
it will explode and then we get covered in
chilli and it's hideous.
And what I'm gonna do is literally just spend
a few minutes just pinching the skins off
and underneath you're left with just hot,
sweet, juicy, lovely tomato.
If there's a few bits of like charred pepper
it doesn't matter at all because that's all
part of the flavour.
I want you to taste that now.
That Scotch Bonnet's hot huh?!
That's hot.
Yeah, right. Now calm down.
If you'd done more of this at school we'd
have had loads more girlfriends.
Yeah I know. But we never could get girlfriends.
I've got some mint here, so our fresh element.
You've tasted that original one, which is
completely unseasoned, now I'm chopping the
mint into it. You could use coriander, you
could use basil, you could go parsley.
A little olive oil in here and I've got lemon
and lime. You want that herb and you want
that citrus to balance the heat of the chilli.
Yeah.
With a bit of meat.
That's gonna be,
Oh that's beautiful.
Amazing.
And that heat now,
Is just,
ooooh, level.
Get rid of that.
Oh yes!
Look at my burgers.
You've just done Botham Burgers.
And I feel that I've been transported back,
to being,
14 again?
Yeah.
Right, dish it up.
Chuck steak, rosemary, Lincolnshire Poacher
cheese just melted in the middle of it, seasoning
every little grain of beautiful meat in there.
And then the grilled salsa. Look at that.
Bad ass!
Jimmy, God bless you.
I've never seen the Botham Burger looking
so posh.
Look at that. Look, that's the cross section,
come on Eileen!
Mmm, this is brilliant. Sitting by the fire,
few beers, Botham Burger.
Great day today Jim.
Yeah, good.