-There's nothing more amazing
than having vibrating metal
steel between your legs.
I mean, those fucking
horny ass drivers--
they thought they were going
to have Stephanie's hard
nipples against their backs.
Instead, they had me and Harry's
dick and balls on
their denim material.
And there's nothing better
than having your dick and
balls leave an imprint on denim
material while you're
doing the fucking gay
ass Titanic pose.
It's amazing.
So anyways, we're
in Zhengzhou.
It's a big town for
transportation.
All the trains come
through here.
We're going to go down the
street and get some food.
OK, let's go.
Ask them where the other
people that look
like him hang out.
Damn, fool.
Ancient Chinese style.
I got to make my man look good
for the Chinese girls.
That's a good one.
Yeah, we're not looking
for fine.
We need it to be awesome.
That one looks better.
You like it?
That's good?
Would you fuck him?
-Sexy.
-This one?
You like this haircut?
Let's do it.
This might be the winner.
-Is this it?
-This might be it.
This might be the way
to go, right?
Harry's already cute,
and the dog is cute.
Cute on cute.
-Aw, you are so cute.
-It's getting better.
It's getting better.
Let's try this guy.
Oh, is that [INAUDIBLE].
Yeah, dude--
-Is that my style?
-This is the Chinese style.
I think the girls appreciate
this one.
And if it doesn't work out, you
can eat him for dinner.
It sucks to feel like an alien
no matter where you go.
Harry's been to almost
every Asian country.
He lives in America.
[? You never ?] feel at home.
Everywhere he goes, outcast.
He goes to Africa; they've
never seen
Asian people before.
He goes to fucking China.
Everyone here looks like him.
Or am I not seeing something?
But I think he looks
like everyone else.
They look at this
guy like he's a
fucking alien or something.
[INAUDIBLE] want to cry
right now, dude.
-It's you.
-Dude, I'm so fucking
bummed out for you.
China's like a 1950s America
with freeways being built,
small towns--
these little empty towns
being built everywhere.
And Harry's like the Filipino
Michael J. Fox coming back
from the future.
And the people out here--
they don't understand him yet.
They don't appreciate it.
But their kids will.
We started our trip
here in Beijing.
This is all of China.
Me and Harry, we don't speak
the fucking language.
We don't know where we are.
We don't know where
we're going.
I guess we're look at this right
now, and we went into
inner Mongolia.
And now we're in--
how you say that?
Zhengzhou, in the
Henan territory.
And we're trying to cross
the entire country.
So we're trying to either get
to Hong Kong, Macau, any of
these countries down here.
What do you think?
What do you think
we should do?
-I think we should go to the
coastline to Shanghai and then
go south right here.
Beaches, bitches, dark
skin, good food.
What do you think?
-That sounds good.
I like that.
-I want to go this way.
-Why the fuck you want
to go that way?
-I like the squiggly
line right here.
-What about bitches
and beaches?
-Harry, if we go that way,
Stephanie knows people.
All her friends are
super horny.
I heard their music's good.
They got the hairy crab there.
They got the soup dumplings.
-Hairy crab.
-And you want to go this
way 'cause the line--
-I want to go this way.
-'Cause the line's squiggly.
-'Cause I like the
squiggly line.
-What squiggly line?
What?
-You want to go this way 'cause
the line's squiggly.
-Yeah, I want to go this way.
I want go that way.
Yeah, 'cause, yeah.
-You're splitting up the team.
-It's Shanghai or bust.
-I mean, I'm sorry.
I mean, if Harry wants
to go that way, it's
got to be bros versus--
you know, bros come--
-You just said [INAUDIBLE].
-Bros come before hoes.
I'm sorry.
But listen, you're--
-Always get your fucking way.
-I fucking heard you.
You were talking to your
boyfriend last
night on the telephone.
You're going back 'cause you
want to see your boyfriend.
-I have boyfriends in
every fucking city.
Give me a fucking break.
I'm a big girl now.
-No, no, no.
Let's not end this angry.
If you come with us, there
will be action, adventure
around every corner.
It might not be the
most exciting way.
But if you go back--
I can see it in your eyes.
You're going to go
back to work.
You want to see your
boyfriend.
I understand that.
But you will regret it for
the rest of your life.
-I said go coastal.
I'm going coastal.
-Listen.
Listen, listen, listen.
Come here.
If that's the way you want
to go, we'll just
let you go that way.
And we've had an amazing
adventure so far.
We've seen and done things.
When you're back to your regular
life in Shanghai,
you'll regret not being on the
road with me and Harry.
Guaranteed, you'll regret it
for the rest of your life.
But it's your life.
It's your prerogative You
can do what you want.
So god bless this trip so far.
And please look out for us
for the rest of this
trip, on this journey.
I'm sure our paths will
cross again one day.
I love the both of you.
But in the end, I
choose Harry.
I'm sorry.
You're going to be all right?
All right.
Group hug.
-Bye, Stephanie.
-Love you guys.
-Love you too.
-I want to fist you both.
-[LAUGHTER]
-All right, I'll
see you later.
Dude, your sister's starting
to look kind of cute, man.
-Yeah.
-Dude, you fucked her, huh?
You fucked her, dude.
Let's get out of here.
[LAUGHS]
-The road is like a woman.
It's very temperamental.
It's very moody.
One day it can be like a cold
hard bitch, make you sleep on
the couch, don't let you hang
out with your friends.
And sometimes, she can be the
most kindest, loving--
make you a homemade apple pie
and leave it on the windowsill
for you, and draw you a
bath, scrub your dick
and balls for you.
Give you a blow job as you
come out of the shower.
-Love you guys.
-Love you too.
-I want to fist you both.
-We lost a family
member today.
And it's back to the old team--
me and Harry, which is
sort of exciting.
But then at the same time, we've
been extremely spoiled
on this trip.
We had a woman with us,
Harry's sister.
And we never waited longer than
five minutes, maybe no
longer than three minutes
for a ride.
If you're a woman, you will
never, ever in your life have
a problem getting picked up.
However, 99.9 percent of the
people that pick you up will
either be thinking of doing
horrible things to you or try
to do horrible things to you.
So it's good to have
a guy with you.
I guess that's the sucky part
of having tits, 'cause guys
are such perverts and creeps.
But we love you, Stephanie.
Let's get out of here.
Hello.
Ni hao.
-[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
-Someone lives here?
-Ah.
We just stayed on the
roof tonight.
So sorry for--
I didn't see you last night.
We just sleep a little bit.
-Yes.
-Yeah.
-[INAUDIBLE]
-And wow, this is crazy.
-Harry doesn't know what
anyone's saying to him.
I know what you're
thinking, dude.
She's way too young
for you, dude.
-But she could always
fuck my head.
[CHUCKLES]
-Bye bye.
This is what I'm
talking about.
Like even in all the zombie
towns where it's abandoned,
there's like always like
one person somewhere.
It's like, I don't know how many
times we've been caught
taking a shit or masturbating
on this trip.
Still in Zhengzhou.
We're going to try to head south
and hit Wuhan today.
And I guess the reason why
we're going to do that is
because it's a squiggly
line, and Wuhan
falls on that squiggle.
We're going to put
some work in.
Come on, Harry.
Do it like you want it.
Oh!
Get your bag.
All right.
That's Harry.
That's me.
That's us floating down
the Yangtze River.
Deja vu.
It's not just the place where
you can see naked ladies.
It's also the feeling I'm
having right now.
I'm getting older.
My memory's not so good.
I don't remember what
I did yesterday.
I don't remember what I did
the day before yesterday.
But what I do remember is a few
years ago, me and my man
Harry, we floated down the
Mississippi River.
And I will never, ever forget
that for the rest of my life.
If I had died on that river, I
would have lived a good life.
But I'm alive and
I'm still going.
And now we challenge China and
this great Chinese adventure.
Pumping up our boat?
-That's right.
-I'm with my man Harry.
What else do I got to say?
[INAUDIBLE] the Yangtze River.
It's the third largest river
in the entire world.
It starts in Tibet.
It invades every orifice of
China-- the mouth, the pussy,
the asshole.
And then it empties out into
the East China Sea.
Every single person we talked to
said, once again, we're the
biggest fucking idiots.
It's super dangerous.
There's huge barges and shit
going down near the city.
There's sinkholes.
All right, everyone say
hello our cameraman.
Me and Harry's fat asses are
filling out the weight on this
tiny vessel to maximum
capacity.
So we're going to film our own
shit, and hopefully we'll see
you alive and well
in the next city.
Thumbs up, China.
Bye.
We got dropped off in
[INAUDIBLE] outskirts of Wuhan
from Zhengzhou.
The air quality in China's
fucking horrible.
So I don't know if you can even
see this, but it looks
like there's the city.
As you can see how everyone
said this
was a dangerous river.
I mean, I guess it is dangerous
'cause there's all
this giant metal claws and big
boats and shit around our
tough exterior boat.
But there's absolutely
no fucking current.
Me and Harry are cruising along
at zero miles per hour.
Hopefully, we can hitch a ride
on one of these little boats
and go a little bit faster,
but we'll see.
Let's just try to get to
this island right here.
[LAUGHS]
This guy's like you
fucking morons.
[LAUGHS]
There's his wife, echoing
his sentiment.
You fucking moron idiots.
[LAUGHS]
How's it feel, Harry, being
back on the river?
-It feels good.
Feels a little different,
though.
-It's a pretty ugly river.
-Yeah, nasty.
-There's fucking
loud ass ducks.
Uhh!
-Err!
Err!
-We just docked our Challenger
2 on this little island.
We're going to just chill here
for a second and then try to
get closer in.
Hey, Harry, you ever
have geese before?
Just creep up on them.
Let's try to fucking
eat one for dinner.
-Yeah, I'm hungry.
-Get 'em, Harry!
Go!
Get one!
Get the big one!
[BARKING]
Oh, shit.
Hey, Harry, watch out, dude.
Dude, what happened, man?
-They got away this time.
-Oh dude, watch out, man.
Here, come on.
Let's go.
Come on.
Come on, dude.
[LAUGHS]
-Oh man.
[ELECTRONIC GUNFIRE
AND EXPLOSIONS]
I totally fucked with
those bitches.
They're getting so pissed.
[INAUDIBLE] fuck with my
bitches [INAUDIBLE].
[BARKING]
[ELECTRONIC GUNFIRE
AND EXPLOSIONS]
-That's your geese, dude.
-Huh?
-That's your geese.
Oh shit.
-Oh dude.
You're in trouble, bro.
Mm.
Let's go talk to them.
-[SPEAKING MANDARIN]
-We were hungry.
Sorry, we didn't know they
were your geese.
We were just trying to
get the little geese.
-[SPEAKING MANDARIN]
-I know.
My man--
when he's hungry, he
can't stop himself.
How should we explain
this to them?
OK, this is your boat
right here?
Your boat.
That's your boat.
This is our boat.
Little boat.
We will give you our boat
if you give us a
ride on your boat.
-[SPEAKING MANDARIN]
-This boat we'll give to
you if you give us a
ride on your boat.
OK?
Yeah!
Here, let's just put this
boat on their boat.
-OK.
-The best ride we've
ever gotten.
Thank you.
Say bye to our friend
in the hot pink.
Say goodbye to our friend,
the little doggy.
Our speed just picked up
about 1,000 percent.
We just upset the shit out of
these people by attacking
their geese, but then we told
them that we would give them
our futuristic boat.
And so they have agreed to
take us into the city.
Once again, life does not
get better than this.
I'm with my man Harry.
I would have much rather been
with his wife with the hot
pink blouse, but she wanted
nothing to do with us, and now
we're with this salty
old fuck.
We're speeding down the river.
Life is good.
Catch you later.
-Oh, we're slowing down.
-Looks like his boat's having
some technical difficulties.
-What's he looking for?
-I don't know.
Stay out of his way, though.
Oh, gas.
-He ran out of some gas.
Shit, man.
If his boat breaks down, he'll
be riding the Challenger into
shore with us.
I don't think there's room
on there for three of us.
Can you swim?
-All right.
-I don't understand anything
this guy's said to us so far.
He still gave us the
ride even though he
fucking hates our guts.
Looks like we're in a pretty
industrious area, and there's
all these apartment buildings
and shit being built over
there, so I'm guessing
we're in Wuhan.
I can't be sure.
-Xie xie.
Xie xie.
-Bye bye.
-Bye.
-Hey, look at that, dude.
We got a smile at the
end of the ride from
our salty old friend.
He wasn't such an asshole
after all.
Well, actually, you
were the asshole.
-Yeah.
-We just gave him our futuristic
boat craft, and now
we're in fucking Wuhan.
Look.
We finally found some
graffiti in China.
I can't read what it says, but
I think it's graffiti.
Yeah, Harry.
-Trying out my new guitar here
that I just bought, 'cause I'm
in (RAP SINGING) ching chong,
China, ripping a vagina.
-Harry, that's your
bro, brother
from a different mother.
[LAUGHS]
All right.
Dude.
-[GIGGLES]
That was--
wow.
-Me and Harry jamming
by the river.
Thumbs up, China.
Love you.
[GUITAR]
Thumbs up, everybody.
I got a little bit
of bad news.
We just got to the city Wuhan.
It's a big city.
It's like one of the
big cities after
Shanghai and Beijing.
We're trying to track
down our cameraman.
We're trying to track down--
Harry just fucking--
Jesus Christ, man.
I went to the bathroom for one
second, and Harry disappeared.
I don't know where he is.
He doesn't have a phone.
There's no way to get
a hold of him.
I just--
fuck, man.
I fucking hate that guy, man.
He just pisses me--
All right, hold up.
I'm going to find him.
Don't worry, everybody.
We'll get him back.
We'll check every eatery and the
shitter around here, and
hopefully we'll be
able to find him.
I don't know where he is.
I don't know where
he could be.
Shit.
Harry!
Where the fuck are you, man?
Every time I get to a good place
with this guy, he does
something to fuck it up.
You know what I mean.
If me and Harry were a gay
couple-- if we were--
I would have divorced
or broken up.
We would be the make up,
break up couple.
I mean, we just had an amazing
day on the river.
Our cameraman called.
We were going to meet
up with him.
And the guy just--
you can't keep track--
the guy's like a--
but then you can't get mad at
him either, 'cause he lacks
common sense.
He's like a dog.
You can't get mad at a dog.
He's like a little cute puppy
that's really disgusting and
gross sometimes.
It started raining right
as we lost Harry.
We found out he--
this fucking--
we got a strange call
from a strange phone
number from this girl.
He's at the roof of a
love hotel in Wuhan.
So we're heading there now.
[SIGHS]
Wish us luck.
Come on, come on.
[INAUDIBLE].
[DOOR SLAMS]
Harry is a fucking animal.
So we are about a week
into the trip.
We're halfway through
our destination.
Harry ditches me today.
We have the cameraman.
Everyone on the crew's looking
for Harry all day today.
He met this nice girl Sheeka.
This is Sheeka, everyone.
They had an awesome
time today.
And I guess halfway through
their wonderful day together,
a dude shows up.
Turns out it's her pimp.
And he's not happy that
she went missing too.
But Harry has a way
with women.
The situation was Harry was
smaller than the dude.
The guy was a fucking asshole,
a total monster.
Fucking all his other girls
have like cigarette
burns out on them.
I told him, look.
I will give you $1,000 of US
money if you beat the shit out
of my friend.
And if my friend beats the shit
out of you, then you have
to let her go and
come with us.
He said fucking no problem.
We found a spot, and Harry
fucking pummeled
the shit out of him.
We don't want to go to jail.
I don't want to go to jail.
I've already been there.
I don't want to see what a
Chinese prison looks like, so
we're going to go against
Thumbs Up policy
for one night tonight.
I hope you forgive us.
And we are going to stay in the
cameraman's room and try
to put all the pieces together
and figure out what happened,
where to go from here.
This is sort of worse than
bringing a stray dog home.
I don't know what your plans
are, Harry, for taking care of
her or what.
But she seems to speak a little
bit of English, so that
is awesome.
And I guess we'll just--
you all right, dude?
-Yeah.
-For real?
-All right, thumbs
up for tonight.
We'll catch up with
you guys tomorrow.