CROWD: Nine, eight, seven, six, five, four,
three, two ...
(CHEERS)
(END VIDEO CLIP)
CARL AZUZ, CNN ANCHOR: Well, of course, we
wish you a very happy new year and a very
warm welcome as we kick off 2013 on CNN STUDENT
NEWS. My name is Carl Azuz. We are glad you`re
joining us. We hope your year is off to a
good start.
One question we had going in to the break
was, will Congress and President Obama find
a way to avoid the fiscal cliff? When we put
this show together last night, we still had
that question. What came to be knows is the
fiscal cliff was really a series of automatic
tax increases and government spending cuts
that were scheduled to take effect at the
start of the year.
The reason - U.S. Government has too much
debt. Now, the president and Congress could
have avoided that fiscal cliff by coming up
with the compromise, a different plan to reduce
the debt. But as of yesterday, still no agreement.
There are two main ways to reduce debt: cut
down on spending and or raise taxes. One big
sticking point was whom to raise taxes on
and by how much? The president wanted families
making more than $250,000 a year to pay more
in taxes. He said they could afford it. Critics
said the economy is too weak to raise taxes
on anyone.
The Senate came up with a bipartisan compromise
to raise taxes, but only on families making
more than $450,00 a year. The plan would be
a temporary fix, it would last for two months,
and it would delay any cuts in government
spending. The thing is, the compromise also
has to pass the U.S. House of Representatives,
and it wasn`t clear yesterday if it would
do that. Cnn.com has your latest updates.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: See if you can I.D. me.
I was born in Chicago in 1947. In 1992, my
husband was elected president and in the year
2000, I was elected to the U.S. Senate. I`m
the only former first lady to have served
there and in the presidential cabinet.
I`m Hillary Clinton, the current U.S. Secretary
of State.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Secretary Clinton spent New Year`s day
in the hospital after getting a blood clot
in her head. Doctors say she`s on blood thinners
to dissolve the clot and they expect she`ll
be OK. This is the latest of a few health
issues she had. Clinton caught a stomach virus
in December, which made her dehydrated. She
fainted because of that, which gave her a
concussion. This blood clot was a result of
that concussion. Clinton had to stay home
for most of December. She didn`t testify as
scheduled about September`s deadly terrorist
attack on the U.S. Building in Benghazi, Libya.
Dr. Sanjay Gupta explores what`s next in her
recovery.
DR. SANJAY GUPTA, CNN CORRESPONDENT: It is
a blood vessel that actually drains blood
away from the brain. It`s called the cerebral
vein, and I want to show you here, we know
that in Secretary Clinton`s case it is actually
on the right side of her head, somewhere in
this area, it`s called the right transverse
sinus.
Let me show you on this model here, I`ll show
you the left side just for sake of demonstration
here. I removed the hemisphere of the brain
here. You can actually see where the - where
the veins are. You see that blue area right
in there. That is the area that is actually
draining blood away from the brain. And one
of these veins in this area, that`s where
that clot actually has occurred. Most likely,
due to a combination of the head trauma that
she had a few weeks ago in addition to the
fact that she has had a problem with blood
clots in the past, dating back to 1998. We
heard from her doctors. They say that she`s
on blood winners, they say she`s awake, she`s
talking. And most importantly, there is no
evidence of stroke or neurological damage.
My guess is that they are going to monitor
her at least for another couple of days in
the hospital and probably get another scan
at some point to make sure that clot is in
fact dissolved as the result of those blood-
thinning medications. As we get more details,
we certainly bring them to you. Back to you
for now.
AZUZ: Thank you, Dr. Gupta.
For a while now, Secretary Clinton has been
planning to step down from her position, once
a new nominee is confirmed by the Senate.
The president`s choice for the job is this
man, Senator John Kerry. You might have heard
that name before. He ran for president and
lost to incumbent president, George W. Bush
in 2004. On December 21st, President Obama
nominated Kerry for U.S. Secretary of State.
He`s done extensive traveling and met with
international officials on behalf of the Obama
administration, but as many of you have already
learned, Kerry`s nomination doesn`t necessarily
mean he`ll get the job. The Senate will have
the final say as part of the advice and consent
it gives the president.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Time for the year`s first
"Shoutout." Which of the following is associated
with Abraham Lincoln: if you think you know
the answer, then shout it out!
Is it the Treaty of Paris, Emancipation Proclamation,
Articles of Confederation or Treaty of Versailles?
You`ve got three seconds, go!
President Abraham Lincoln`s Emancipation Proclamation
took effect on January 1, 1863. That`s your
answer and that`s your shoutout.
And that made January 1, 2013 the 150th anniversary
of when the Emancipation Proclamation took
effect. In honor of that. U.S. Postal Service
unveiled this new stamp yesterday.
President Lincoln`s proclamation was made
during the U.S. Civil War. It said that anyone
who was a slave in a rebellious state was
set free. It didn`t apply to all U.S. States,
and it didn`t officially end slavery in the
U.S. The 13th Amendment did that. But the
Emancipation Proclamation helped pave the
way to the end of slavery.
Of course, there are a number of new laws
in effect as of yesterday. Last fall, we told
you a couple of states were legalizing recreational
marijuana. In some others, voters approved
same sex marriage. Here are a few laws you
might not have known about. In Illinois and
California, employers can no longer require
workers to share their social media passwords.
Some privacy concerns about that. Also, if
you live in Illinois, forget about shark fins
soup, it`s now illegal to have shark fins
at all. And you could get fined to thousand
bucks if you pop a wheely on a motorcycle.
If you own a swamp buggy in Florida, you no
longer have to register it as a motor vehicle,
that will save some folks a step. Concord,
Massachusetts has officially banned plastic
bottles. They could be confiscated and as
far as animals go, cat lovers in Wellington,
Kansas, might call a new law, catty (ph).
It says you can`t have more than four felines
living in your house. And if you`ve got a
wild hog in Kentucky, you`d better not release
it into the wild. Officials don`t want their
state to become a hog haven.
Well, if you live in or near major city, you
might have heard some fire works the other
night, as people welcome 2013 with a bang.
Times Square topped off today`s show, but
before we sign off we are going to give you
a glimpse of the pyrotechnics prowess proudly
portrayed by cities around the world. Sit
back and enjoy our international tour of how
12 a.m on January 1 looked, as the world`s
spun around to a new year.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: One!
CROWD: One! Happy new year!
CROWD: Two! One!
(CHEERING)
CROWD: Four! Three! Two!
(END VIDEO CLIP)
END