Hey, what's up?
My name is A-Trak and I'm going
to tell you the story of
one of the wildest
nights I've had.
Going back to the early years
of my DJing, because I had a
bit of a crew, we all
got booked in
Houston Halloween weekend.
I went there with my
friend, DJ Craze.
We walked off the plane and
this girl picked us up--
she was hot.
She takes us to the hotel,
and as I mentioned,
it's Halloween weekend.
So she's like, can I change in
one of you guys' bathrooms?
We're like, oh yeah, sure.
So she goes into the bathroom
and comes out in full-leather
cat woman suit--
I'm like, whoa.
I'm getting a call
from my agent.
He's like, your promoter's
missing.
We start hanging out in the
lobby because we're just
waiting for a call to
know where to go.
And in the lobby there was some
sort of formal party,
people were wearing suits and
stuff and there was a piano.
And lo and behold, [INAUDIBLE]
in Humpty-Hump attire
walks up and starts
playing on the piano.
And these girls are getting
completely drunk right next to
them, so very strange
juxtaposition.
So my agent's like, all
right, I think I know
what the venue is.
I don't care if you guys play or
not, but I need you to pick
up the money.
So we break up into two cars.
Me and Craze are in the
car with the one
chick in the catsuit.
So you see someone with fur
boots and someone in neon
attire and a visor hat and
you're like, they know.
So we're rolling down the window
being like yo, guys,
where's the party?
And they're like, what?
They don't get that
we're the DJs.
Like they're trying to not
tell us or something.
We went to one spot, there's
nothing there.
We go to another spot and we
walk into the place, there's a
rave going on, there's
a party going on.
I did my DJ set and as soon as
I walked offstage, chaos
ensures and the word
gets around the
Fire Marshall's here.
People are running in every
direction and the party's
getting shut down.
And we're looking for the
promoter, and everyone we ask
is sort of like ha, everyone's
looking for him.
His buddy comes and finds me,
and he's like, yeah, Scott,
had to uh-- go take
care of something.
I see the promoter dude actually
jump out the window.
Not as a suicide, just to run
away-- we're like ah, ah.
My friend, DJ Craze, comes
in and finds me.
Like glorious smile, super
excited, he's like "I got it."
He managed to hide the little
tin container of
cash from the cops.
And the homegirl in the catsuit
was like you guys want
to go to another party?
And I'm just like, you guys
got to get me to my hotel.
Now the hotel at least had
a hot tub in the room.
And I'm going to kick back.
Fuck everything, I'm getting
in the hot tub.
And someone's knocking on
my door, and I'm sort
of like who is it?
I just throw on a robe
and open the door and
be like what's up?
And the homegirl in the catsuit
was like dressed in
borderline S&M gear.
I was like, oh man.
I think she had a whip
or something.
And that was one of the weirdest
nights I've ever had
on the road.
[MUSIC PLAYING]