[HEAVY METAL]
JOHN MARTIN: We're here in
Istanbul, Turkey, visiting
Acrassicauda, Baghdad's first
heavy metal band.
They escaped Iraq,
went to Syria.
Now they live here in Turkey.
These guys play fast and loud.
They've obviously listened to a
lot of Slayer, Megadeth, and
Iron Maiden.
This is Practice Space.
[MUSIC-ACRASSICAUDA]
JOHN MARTIN: So this
isn't actually your
practice space, right?
MARWAN: Yeah, different
studios.
Whatever's like available,
you know?
We just go down there,
down like
crossing the street, here.
We've got like three or four
studios that we go-- and
different every time.
Changing instruments and
stuff like that.
But you know it's better,
better than
the situation before.
FIRAS: The only practice space
we had of our own was back in
Baghdad, in Iraq.
And after the war situation got
bad, this place got bombed
and explode.
Like you look at it, and it's
still shaped as a building,
but you go inside,
there's nothing.
It's just hollow.
So then we start on the run.
We left to Syria.
And Syria, also, we didn't have
practice space, because
we couldn't like afford
to rent a studio.
Plus--
MARWAN: They don't have
studios there.
FIRAS: Yeah, they don't
have a studio that
fits our kind of music.
Anyway so we moved and once we
got here to Istanbul, Turkey,
then we find different studios
with different equipment.
And pretty much they're
all good.
JOHN MARTIN: So three different
countries, more than
three practice spaces in
a little over a year?
FIRAS: Yeah, like a
couple of years.
Two years, almost.
[MUSIC-ACRASSICAUDA]
[SONG FADES OUT]
MARWAN: It's weird cause
like Iraq-- and we're
talking about Iraq--
and Syria and now Turkey--
which is a beautiful place.
It's like heaven for
us down here.
And we've never got to see any
band actually playing.
None of the bands that we listen
to, or like we even
heard of, playing.
FIRAS: I would love to be in
somebody else's concert.
Other than my concert, because
we haven't been in any shows--
live shows.
MARWAN: Different feeling.
A beautiful feeling.
FIRAS: In the live shows, other
than our show, you know.
Our show we just play.
You don't feel like, OK--
MARWAN: You just feel the
people are watching you.
FIRAS: Yeah, watching you.
MARWAN: In case you
go and listen-
FIRAS:I want to be--
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
FIRAS: One day I want to be
between the audience and
listen, and feel like
audience, you
know what I'm saying?
JOHN MARTIN: So what was
the deal with Syria?
Like, you guys practiced,
what was going on?
MARWAN: Yeah, we practiced
a lot in Syria.
[LAUGHS]
MARWAN: So basically, we all
gather, and we set up the
drum, and we would like put
tons of clothes on it, and
stuff like that.
MARWAN: And the guitars like
one-- two small amplifiers.
And he don't need
like microphone,
[MIMICS SINGING SILENTLY]
you know?
And that's the way that
we jam, you know?
And we got like that neighbor.
FIRAS: That's the funny part.
MARWAN: He was like above,
and he's so cool, man.
Like whenever he got a chance to
hear me playing, or to hear
these guys playing, he
will come and knock
on the fucking door.
And he would be like, what
the fuck, what the
fuck you are playing?
Stop playing.
And they started calling us
satanic, the whole building.
I mean I was coming from a
place to the building.
I just walked into the building,
and I saw a bunch of
kids, like teenagers gathering
all together.
And when I came, like I food
with me and stuff.
They looked at me.
And they gave me
the weird look.
And they were like:
[WHISPERING]
It's the devils--the devil,
the devil worshippers.
And I was like--
[GRUNTS]
[LAUGHTER]
MARWAN: But that
neighbor, man.
So we decided to go and, as soon
we all leave here, just
like put a big pile of shit
in front of his door.
[MUSIC-ACRASSICAUDA]