MALE SPEAKER: Good afternoon.
I hope everyone is having a
wonderful Big Tent Conference.
We do this because we care
a lot about information.
We care exactly for the same
reasons you do, because of the
impact that it can have.
I think about what these
devices represent.
When I look at this, I say
to myself, Oh my God.
This device is really a
small supercomputer.
And this is a slightly larger
supercomputer, all connected
over this fast network to
these powerful servers.
But then I realize that this is
just really the beginning
of something much,
much bigger.
And the numbers tell
the story.
There are now 1.3 million
activations of
Android devices per day.
And that number has doubled
in the last six months.
A little bit of math will tell
you that we're on our way to
more than a billion or so of
these kinds of devices pretty
soon, there are more than
a half a billion now.
And of course everyone's waiting
for the announcement
of the major competitor
on Friday.
And everyone's very excited
about that, which is
wonderful--
another great competitor, a
smaller percentage than we
have at this point.
The fact of the matter is that
both these platforms are
completely changing everything
we do, the way we live, the
way we operate in
so many ways.
It would never have occurred to
me in all my years of doing
this sort of thing that you'd
have start-ups that would all
be about what people want, what
information they want,
how to meet other people, where
they should go, what
they should do, how they should
entertain themselves.
But not only are those start-ups
being formed,
especially here in New York,
but they're going to be
successful because of the
sheer logic of numbers.
But even more interesting is to
imagine what's going to be
possible with these devices
over the next few years.
Imagine these not just as pieces
of hardware but as
ecosystems.
Ecosystems that are highly
personal that you've opted
into, so you've let us know
these things, where we can
help give you advice.
They serve as your assistant.
They suggest things.
This is all in the works.
So now imagine a few
steps farther.
What does the future
look like?
This is not the end.
This is the beginning.
And this is where it gets
particularly interesting.
All of us have been trapped in
this model, the traditional PC
model of everything
right there.
The most interesting thing about
computers is that they
almost disappear because they
become so commonplace.
I'll give you a scenario.
When you wake up in the morning,
the room is alive.
And the room knows roughly how
to wake you at the optimal
point in your REM cycle.
It knows what you need in the
morning and it alerts you
through complex and powerful
screens the things that you
care about, so that you know
whether you have a crisis
today or whether you can relax
and stay in bed for a while.
Pretty straightforward.
What's interesting about
this new world
is that these devices--
again all opt-in, all in ways
that you've set up--
help you every day
along the way.
Not only do they measure your
heart rate and how you're
doing, but they also make your
life so much more efficient.
How much time do you spend,
wasting, making travel
reservations, trying to figure
out where the bus is, how do I
get from here to there,
and so forth.
They anticipate what you need,
where you're going, because of
the things that you have told
it, the things that
it thinks you want.
And all of a sudden you begin
to realize it's not just an
assistant, it's really a
very smart assistant.
Now as these devices get
stronger and as they become
more capable, they can
do other things.
Now there's no better example
of this than in medicine.
The app that I want, I
call, Where's My Mom.
Many people have elderly
parents.
I want computers to help monitor
how my mom's doing.
How was her day?
Is she good?
Is she bad?
In case there's some alert or
something that she needs.
The good news is she's in good
health but you never know.
Why can't we do that?
Well, in fact people
are building those
devices right now.
But now let's go one
step further.
Eventually over the next decade,
you'll be able to
actually have things that you
ingest, it will transmit
through WiFi, it will say what's
going on inside of you.
You can decide if you want
to do this or not.
But trust me, your health
will be better.
You guys don't look like you're
very happy about this.
But people are developing
this stuff now.
What about transdermal
measurement?
These are devices--
you hold your phone and again
without pricking your skin, it
can measure your blood pressure,
your various other
vital signs, and so forth.
We're going to build the systems
so the doctor calls
you and says, you better get
yourself to the hospital right
now, rather than you
calling the doctor.
And that's the ultimate
inversion of this model, that
these devices, that the
micro-miniaturization, the
technology that we've taken
that's been so heavy and hard
to use for most of us becomes
embedded inside of us.
There's a new generation of
technology, social robots,
that can actually recognize
gestures and can actually
interact, all of which will be
put to the service of us.
So when you think about this
from an art perspective and a
culture perspective, it says
that these devices, which
we're so incredibly excited
about, will be seen as so
extraordinarily primitive.
And that the ability to build
systems that interact, that
help us, that monitor
us-- again because
we want them to--
will make a huge,
huge difference
in everybody's lives.
And the most exciting thing
about this is that in the
spread of this, it happens not
just for us, the wealthy,
developed world.
But the same story at a
slower scale works in
the developing world.
So we sit there and we go, well,
we're really excited.
We can use Google here.
We can watch YouTube
and so forth.
In a country with no schools,
no textbooks, and the only
thing they have are these
devices, these devices are
life-changing.
And over the next three to
five years, the next five
billion will get low-end
smartphones
of one kind or another.
It will finally enable them to
join our conversation, to get
the benefits of the information,
the culture, the
art, and all the things that you
all have worked so hard.
It's extraordinary to imagine
all of the world now being
able to participate at the state
of the art, at the level
of technology that we're
talking about today.
This is I think why we're so
excited about our partnerships
with you all and why we're
putting so much money in this
kind of stuff.
I thought what I should do is
pause and perhaps ask people's
comments or questions
as we begin
the rest of the afternoon.
Who would like to start with
questions or comments on this
or on anything else?
In the back, go ahead,
yes sir.
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
what in the future the
individual's responsibility
for themselves will
be or could be?
And how does that change in
our relationship to larger
corporations who would have
to run these systems?
MALE SPEAKER: Very
good question.
The technology can be programmed
to be more of a
nanny state or more of a
libertarian model, for
purposes of discussion,
if you want to imagine
the two most extremes.
I believe societies will
ultimately choose somewhere
along that arc.
And I think societies will
choose different points based
on culture, legal precedent,
sort of the way they run.
Autocracies, for example, will
be much less interested in
your personal freedom than a
democracy, for obvious reasons.
And there's lots of
evidence of that.
That's the first observation.
It will vary.
All of these systems, in my
view, will ultimately be
designed around, the individual
has to opt in.
It's simply too scary to imagine
these things being
imposed on people, I argue and
I feel very strongly that in
the hawks versus doves argument,
the hawks tend to
win and there tends to be
a stripping of privacy.
There tends to be a loss of
individual responsibility, if
you will, the ability to
make your own choice.
But I do think that societies
will make those decisions but
in different levels.
And the technology
will serve that.
The second part of your question
was, what are the
responsibilities of
global companies?
We spend a lot of time at Google
thinking about this.
And the conclusion we've come
to, is we have a set of
principles that we believe
in to make the
world a better place.
And we will push them as hard
as we can up to the point
where we're violating the laws
of the other country.
So we will take a position--
when there's an ambiguity--
for free expression, openness,
freedom of
choice, we trust you.
When it comes to literally
violating the law of the other
country, then we're forced to
back away, sometimes in our
view for the wrong reasons.
Most global companies
will come to that.
Our attitude is seen in many
countries is American hegemony.
It's important to understand
that my message, which plays
well in the US, does not
necessarily play
well in other countries.
More questions?
Yes, yes, ma'am.
AUDIENCE: What I brought
up before about market
saturation, I'd like to hear
your thoughts on making the
availability of any kind of a
creative work, whether it's a
newspaper, a work of art, but
making it available so broadly
that it therefore saturates a
market, which tends to push
pricing down.
Which tends to then support
industries as a whole but not
the smaller company, not
the smaller individual.
And is that where we're going?
Where it becomes almost like the
old motion picture studio
model for all creative works?
And that that's the only way
to make money is if the
companies own all of this,
because of this market
saturation.
MALE SPEAKER: I agree with the
first half of your question
and not the conclusion.
So the rough analysis of what's
going on is that we
went from an era of scarcity
to an era of abundance.
That the distribution models
of the past were largely
limited by physical constraints,
the difficulty of
copying et cetera, et cetera.
So you had high cost of
distribution, high cost of
manufacturing.
In the digital world, you have
essentially no cost of
distribution and no cost
of manufacturing.
So you've gone from the
era of scarcity
to the era of abundance.
In an era of abundance, there
are many, many strategies to
make money.
Unfortunately, the people who
made the money in the era of
scarcity often don't make the
transition to the next.
They struggle for all
sorts of reasons.
In the newspapers--
which is an easy one
to understand--
there are number of newspapers
that were formed that are new
that are doing very well, that
adopted an advertising model
as opposed to a subscription
model.
The Politico and Huffington
Post, as to Huffington Post
run out of here.
And so those are some examples
of new ventures, new business
models where they ditched
the old model.
And it's fine to keep the old
model but the point is, it's a
hybrid model.
So it does not then follow that
all the content is owned
by big companies.
I think what it means is that
at each point in the value
chain of distribution, you
have to come up with a
strategy to build an audience
that will get you enough
market that you can
monetize it.
The old model of hey, I'm going
to restrict access to my
content works if you have
something which you can get
the subscription revenue for.
It doesn't generally work in a
world where everything's so
easily copyable.
That's where we are.
A lot of people are struggling
with this.
We do have a lot of very
good examples now.
If you look at YouTube,
classic example.
The major studios took years to
get to the point where they
were comfortable putting their
content on YouTube.
And now we've pretty much got
partners with every single one
of them and pretty much
every one of those
deals making money.
So we together with them figured
out a way to monetize
that content in a new way.
Just took a while.
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
MALE SPEAKER: The question is,
does it go to the companies
rather than the individual
creators?
The logic would be the inverse
because the networks should
disintermediate the middle man
and the aggregate revenue
should increase to the content
provider at the end state.
So you may be seeing a
transition effect or you may
be seeing some aspect of the
market doesn't make sense.
But typically the internet
disintermediates the middle people.
And it forces the middle men
to become much more highly
verticalized and specialized,
because sheer distribution is
no longer an asset.
Yes, sir, go ahead.
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
is the YouTube film which
is [INAUDIBLE]
MALE SPEAKER: This is not
the first time we've had
controversial videos
on YouTube.
Our team has reviewed this video
very, very carefully.
It's well within the guidelines
that we established
in 2008 for what would be
permissible on YouTube.
And you can read them
on the site, so
there's no secrets here.
So it'll stay up.
We have blocked it in a couple
of countries where the law
does not allow it to be shown.
And we have blocked it in two
other countries where we
thought it was a matter
of public safety.
We don't want to be associated
with this violence, of course.
My personal view is that you
have internal strife.
The vast majority of people who
seem to be engaged in this
bad behavior have not
seen the video.
They heard it through oral
reports and so forth.
So to argue against keeping
the video up is to argue
against core freedom of
expression argument.
And I think all of us believe
in religious tolerance.
And that includes religious
criticism.
And you'll see that
our policies.
So we've made the decision
to keep it up.
We obviously do not endorse
any of those actions or
violence that have
consequences.
And frankly, I think, this is
going to happen again in other
forms, consequence of
the connected world.
The alternative is to shut
off the internet, which
[? you're ?] not going to do.
AUDIENCE: I have a question
about what the
gentleman was saying.
You said at some point doctor
will call you, you don't need
to call the doctor.
Let's assume in a country where
it's illegal to be gay.
You have AIDS.
Do you want your doctor
to call you?
MALE SPEAKER: This is why I said
earlier it's incredibly
important that these systems
be user choice.
So if you were aware that you're
potentially eligible
for some health disease which
is illegal in your crazy and
stupid country.
Right?
If you find yourself stuck in
the world's worst country
which would do that, obviously
it's a terrible situation.
You would appropriately decide
not to expose yourself to this
possible risk.
There is an issue here that
these systems tend naturally
to be connected and naturally
have tracking capabilities
just because of the
way they're built.
So that's why opt-in, people can
turn them on and off, and
user buy-in are very
important.
One more, yes?
The one there.
Yes.
Over here or here.
Go ahead.
It doesn't matter.
Yes. sir.
AUDIENCE: We've had experience
in the age of the internet of
material not being available
anymore and
storage systems change.
And there are constant upgrades
move faster and
faster and faster, especially
with mobile.
So that eventually people have
to recognize a day may come
when oh, my photographs, my
music, my texts, my novel,
they disappeared.
Where are they?
I think if Ray Bradbury were
writing 451 in this day and
age, it wouldn't be about
burning books.
It would be about pushing a
button on a computer somewhere
and they would all just
digitally disappear.
As our technology progresses,
how do we know that we're
going to be able to retain that
from the past as a new
storage system comes
into being?
MALE SPEAKER: There
are whole teams
looking at this question.
This is known as the digital
archival question.
I'm not as worried about this
because the systems that
Google and others are building
tend to preserve everything in
a format that is presentable.
Eventually, I think your
argument is correct.
But, for example, the ubiquity
of jpegs and photographs,
there will always, 100 years
from now, be a converter from
that jpeg format to
whatever exists.
There's simply too much.
There's too many.
I don't worry about this
issue for things
which are highly common.
I do think that if you have a
very specialized format, there
really is danger
of losing that.
And so if you're using the
very standardized data
representation formats, you'll
probably be fine.
And for the specialized stuff,
there are people trying to
figure out archivally keep
this, things like the
Smithsonian and things
like that.
But your your safety in terms of
preservation is to use the
most common formats.
YouTube's not going to go away,
as an example, Uses
common formats.
Yes.
There was a question over here.
Yes, sir.
AUDIENCE: I just wanted to ask
you about search and curation.
You talked about five billion
more people entering this
conversation.
It seems like two things
sort of happen.
One, we all go into an echo
chamber and we find the things
we find over and over again
versus being given things.
As the conversation increases,
how are we going to find the
things that are really
important to us?
MALE SPEAKER: There's been a lot
of people who worried that
the nature of the selection bias
and the systems that are
being built will ultimately
produce narrow echo chambers
where we only hear ourselves and
our friends and so forth.
This has been measured and so
far it's completely not true.
So far, we've managed to escape
the outcome of lack of
criticality.
And I personally believe that
as more voices come in, it's
good from a standpoint
of more choices.
We would argue that this
is a ranking problem.
How do you-- with all these new
voices-- how do you rank
those voices compared
to others?
We're in the business
of ranking.
It's not perfect but we
do the best we can.
We have time for
a couple more.
Yes, yes.
AUDIENCE: Good afternoon.
I want to follow up on your
disintermediation point and
ask if you might envision the
technologies that Google
facilitates development of
as an ultimate disruptor,
possibly eventually
disintermediating the need for
the real estate that cinemas
offer for alternate content?
And that possibly opening up
the abilities for a greater
amount of this artistic
alternative content to find
its way there?
MALE SPEAKER: I--
AUDIENCE: Three points
to it, just quickly.
If the [? end cinema ?] is
big, democratized in it's
offering and community, can
not those three things and
more be offered online?
AUDIENCE: I have a very strong
opinion on movie theaters.
I think that they're incredibly
important because
they're the only places
that people turn off
their mobile devices.
[AUDIENCE LAUGHTER]
MALE SPEAKER: No, no
think about it.
Is there any other place
in the world?
You keep it on when you're
asleep but not when you're in
the movie theater.
This is landmark status.
[AUDIENCE LAUGHTER]
MALE SPEAKER: I think going
to the movies is a social
experience, the sense of
going to the opening.
that's not going to go away.
And so I think the movie folks
all believe that you're seeing
a compression of windows.
But I think the model will
preserve at least the notion
of opening night.
People want to feel special.
It goes back to the question
earlier about scarcity.
Very clever marketeers
understand that if they make
slightly fewer of a product
and there is demand, it
creates excessive lines.
That's what happens in the
clubs around here.
The most popular club is defined
as the one with the
longest line, not the
greatest capacity.
We have one final question.
Right over here.
Yes.
AUDIENCE: How do you go about
educating entire populaces
about the ins and outs of opting
in, when they should do
it, how they should do it, when
they shouldn't do it.
MALE SPEAKER: First that you
start with an awful lot of
information that's online.
And you try to make it readable
in people's language
and they can understand it.
Most people are confused by
what's happening because
they're not computer
scientists.
They don't really understand
how this stuff can be used.
So we've tried very
hard to do that.
I think the reality is that
education in general is going
to change a big deal around
the world because you no
longer need to memorize
all the stuff.
Now you need to have a
significant education in being
an online citizen.
As a young person, what does
it mean to be a tweeter?
What does it mean
to be texting?
So, for example, all these
high school students are
probably going to be rather
surprised to discover all
those pictures are still
around when they're 45.
And nobody told them that or
if their parents told them
that, they discounted it.
But if their teachers tell them,
maybe they will listen.
I think there's a whole
series of steps that
society will go through.
What I will tell you is that
the shift from the analog
world to the digital world that
we're going through--
we're not going back.
We need to get organized
around how we're
going to run society--
respectfully, with appropriate
levels of privacy, respecting
the rights of public safety,
and sort that out.
Countries will make those
decisions differently.
And this will be a constant
discussion in the media.
And that's how the education
really occurs.
So with that, Peter,
thank you.
Thank you very much.
Thank you all.
And we'll continue.