you for joining us. I`m Carl Azuz. Today`s
show begins in Connecticut.
The community of Newtown, Connecticut is in
mourning after a massacre at an elementary
school. Our complete coverage of the story
is in Monday`s show at cnnstudentnews.com.
As police expand their investigation into
what led to the tragedy, people in Newtown
are banding together and they are getting
support from across the country. They are
holding memorials and vigils for the victims.
Mourners are saying prayers for the victims,
their families and their community. The U.S.
Postal Service has set up a place where people
can mail their condolences and messages of
support to Newtown. If you are interested
in that, the address is "Message of Condolence",
it`s P.O. Box 3700, Newtown, Connecticut,
06470.
When President Obama spoke at a high school
there on Sunday night, he questioned whether
Americans were doing enough to bring this
kind of violence to an end.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
BARACK OBAMA, PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES
OF AMERICA: Can we truly say as a nation that
we are meeting our obligations? Can we honestly
say that we are doing enough to keep our children,
all of them safe from harm? Can we claim as
a nation that we are altogether there, letting
them know that they are loved and teaching
them to love in return? Can we say that we
are truly doing enough to give all the children
of this country the chance they deserve to
live out their lives in happiness and with
purpose? I`ve been reflecting on this the
last few days. And if we are honest with ourselves,
the answer is no. We are not doing enough.
And we all have to change.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: All right, but how? There are a lot
of people out there in the media, from leaders
and journalists to musicians and actors sharing
their theories on what led to this and how
to prevent it. We`d like to hear from you,
what are your ideas on how the nation can
change to keep kids safer? Please, share your
thoughts and only your first names on our
blog at cnnstudentnews.com
Some of the people who live in Newtown are
sharing their thoughts on this, they are trying
to turn some of the attention that`s focused
on them to the issues that they believe should
be addressed to prevent this from happening
somewhere else. CNN`s Kyung Lah reports on
what some citizens of Newtown are saying.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
KYUNG LAH, CNN CORRESPONDENT: You can hear
their frustration.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: At the point you buy body
armor, shouldn`t the FBI be at your door?
LAH: These are questions asked before after
Columbine and Virginia Tech and again, this
year, in places like Aurora, Colorado and
Clackamas, Oregon. This time, it`s this Newtown
residents who knew the children and teachers
killed at Sandy Hook.
CRAIG MITTLEMAN, NEWTOWN RESIDENT: We have
the benefit and the misfortunate of being
on the national stage right now. This is a
real opportunity for us to make a statement.
LAH: They have no political power in this
room, just grief. Grief channeled into a will
to bring change.
LEE SHULL, NEWTOWN RESIDENT: I think we need
to talk about what`s reasonable. I don`t think
it`s reasonable for assault weapons in any
way in our society except for the military
or police.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Mental illness, shove
it underneath the rug. We can`t do that anymore.
MARY SIRECI, NEWTOWN RESIDENT: We do something
now and leave here with some proactive things,
some action.
LAH: What you are looking at is the birth
of a grassroots effort from a town in pain.
They have built a Facebook page calling themselves
Newtown United. They admit they don`t know
what they are doing, just that they have to
do something.
BILL TOOMEY, NEWTOWN RESIDENT: If this is
a trigger point, or a tipping point for us
and our elected officials to actually start
talking to each other in a way that`s respectful
and results in real change that would be huge.
LAH: The goal of Newtown United to prevent
another town from suffering what this one
is enduring will not go unheated. Kyung Lah,
CNN, Newtown, Connecticut.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: See if you can I.D. me.
I used to be part of the Ottoman Empire, you`ll
find me between the Black Sea and the Mediterranean
Sea, my largest city is Istanbul, but my capital
is Ankara.
I`m Turkey, and I bridge countries in Europe
and the Middle East.
(END VIDE CLIP)
AZUZ: That bridge between East and West makes
Turkey an important country in international
issues. You see in this map how one of its
border countries is Syria, well, some of the
weapons fired in Syria` civil war have hit
locations in Turkey. Turkey is a member of
NATO, the North Atlantic Treaty Organization.
That makes it an ally of 27 other countries
including the U.S. And Germany. So, those
two nations are sending Patriot missiles to
Turkey to help protect it from the violence
in Syria. This is a file photo of a Patriot
missile launcher, one thing these missiles
can do is intercept and destroy other missiles,
and that`s the idea here. If weapons used
in Syria` civil war come close to Turkey,
the Patriots could intercept them and help
keep Turkish citizens safe.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: It`s time for the "Shoutout."
What is the biggest source of U.S. Government
revenue? If you think you know it then shout
it out. Is it taxes, interest on loans, land
leasing or borrowing? You`ve got three seconds,
go!
Taxes on citizens and businesses account for
most of the government`s revenue. That`s your
answer and that`s your "Shoutout."
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: That`s why the debate over taxes, who
gets taxed and by how much is so important
to the U.S. Government`s debate over the upcoming
fiscal cliff. It`s a series of tax increases
in government`s spending cuts that will automatically
happen in January. A lot of experts agree
it would be a bad thing for the U.S. Economy,
and it can only be avoided if Congress and
the president can agree on another way to
address the nation`s massive debt. One way
to do that is by reducing government spending,
but that`s is easier said than done. Tom Foreman
has an excellent illustration of "why".
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
TOM FOREMAN, CNN CORRESPONDENT: What you are
looking at in this room, is everything the
federal government spends money on, and that
score board back there shows you the problem.
Last year we spent $3.6 trillion on all this
stuff, but we only took in $2.3 trillion in
taxes or revenue. Now, Democrats tend to like
to talk more in these talks about the revenue
side of the equation. They say if we can find
the way to gin up more taxes, lean on the
rich harder, that`s how we can deal with this
deficit. But Republicans while agreeing we
may need more revenue want to talk a lot more
about all this stuff, and whether or not they
can cut some things down.
One of the first things you may notice is
that not all spending is equal. You could
have dramatic cuts in things like Homeland
Security, the Energy Department and the Interior
Department. If you cut those programs out
entirely, yeah, you`d save $80 billion, but
that`s only a small fraction of the deficit.
That`s why the talk is largely about this
back row, where the big ticket items reside,
such as Social Security, health and human
services, home to Medicare and Medicaid and
defense. Each one of these accounts for more
than $700 billion in spending, so yeah, if
you could find a way to somehow chop about
25 percent out of each program here, you`d
get real savings, about half trillion dollars.
But doing that would be unbelievably tough,
the simple truth is some of them are protected
from cuts. Social Security is something that
Democrats and Republicans alike have been
very afraid to go after. The social programs
are very much protected by Democrats and the
Republicans are equally protective of Defense.
That`s why these talks are so tough. The simple
truth is, every program in this room has constituents
who will fight tooth and nail to hold on to
the funding.
What there is this, if no deal is struck and
the fiscal cliff comes, than $600 billion
in automatic tax increases and spending cuts
will kick in, that could effect a lot of programs
in this room and that will absolutely leave
an awful lot of voters, Democratic and Republican
unhappy.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: Before we go today, it`s a Christmas
mystery:
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: We found it at 5 a.m,
in the morning, and it glows, it lights up.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: Yeah, it does. And it mysteriously showed
up in someone`s front yard in a Missouri community.
This 30-foot Santa came with instructions.
Enjoy it or at least leave it up there for
24 hours, then schlep the statuesque Santa
in a slay or maybe more realistically a pickup
truck over to the house of someone else with
children. Kids love it. Well, why shouldn`t
they? It`s santastic! And not keeping the
mystery alive would be positively deflating.
We hope you enjoy the rest of your day and
you`ll join us again tomorrow on CNN STUDENT
NEWS.