EILENE: Hello.
My name is Eilene.
Come and see the
red squirrels.
Upstairs, into the bedroom.
[LAUGHTER]
[MEOW]
EILENE: [CHUCKLES]
Right.
Get out, you.
Red squirrels are, I think,
they're reported to be the
most intelligent of all the
small rodent family.
They are without question one of
the cutest mammals we have
in this country.
There's no doubt about it--
if not the cutest.
These squirrels were in
a dray in a garden.
We have terrible gales here.
And the dray blew
out of the tree.
There were actually
five of them.
And when they went out to have
a look, one was dead.
And the other four
were starting to
crawl along the path.
So they took them to the local
vet in [INAUDIBLE].
That actually them rang me and
said, can you take them
because they were going
on holiday.
Oh, look who joined in now.
There you go.
Now, how cute is that?
How cute.
There are three girls
and one boy.
So the boy is easy
to distinguish.
He's the runt of the litter.
He's the smallest.
All he wants to do is sleep.
Whereas these three
girls are hyper.
Before-- oop, there he goes.
Don't you dare jump
in my coffee.
FEMALE SPEAKER: So you're
like mother--
Mother Squirrel?
EILENE: [CHUCKLES]
At the moment, I'm Mommy.
And I suppose, my
husband's Daddy.
For me, looking after any
baby really is a joy.
I think I must be a
natural nurturer.
And when my children left home
and had grandchildren and then
proceeded to live miles away, I
just had nothing to nurture.
The cutest thing about a red
squirrel is I just have a
thing about the little tufts
that get on the ears.
That really just
melts my heart.
There's a question mark over
humanizing with wild animals.
A lot of people will say that
maybe we've got them too tame.
But my feeling is that if they
were with their mother, their
mother would be nurturing
them.
And I just feel that when
they're very young and
vulnerable, nurturing won't
do them any harm.
Well, that is the most
unprofessional squirrel
feeding I have ever done.
It's a very bittersweet moment
the day they go.
If they're fit and
they're healthy,
then you have to release.
And they are all fit
and healthy.
And I can't, at the moment
anyway, see any reason not to
release them.
I'm going to be so sad.
[CHUCKLES]
You have such a wonderful
tail.
And now, it's time
to go to bed--
tired, tired little squirrel.
Oh, look.
Time to go to bed.
Yes, you can be Zebedee.
There you go into your bed.
There'll be a little bit of
hodgy podgy, a bit of rough
and tumble, and then eventually,
silence.
[MUSIC PLAYING]