AUREL SCHMIDT: My name's
Aurel Schmidt.
I'm from Kamloops, BC, British
Columbia, Canada.
INTERVIEWER: How long have you
lived in New York now?
AUREL SCHMIDT: Three
years in April.
INTERVIEWER: How do you think
that this city has
affected your work?
AUREL SCHMIDT: So the work
changed with the city,
definitely.
Like, all of the garbage rat,
decay stuff started coming in
when I moved here.
Everyone's fighting for space.
There's like--
there's no room for emptiness.
There's always noise or
background noise, you know?
So I think the pieces started
getting filled with the
clutter of a city in a way.
I moved here.
I was extremely lonely
and paranoid.
And doing, like, a lot of drugs
for some reason as well
as those things, so it was
like this really intense,
like, paranoid, lonely state,
which I think then I put a lot
of it into the work.
Because it was a way to deal
with those paranoias and
feelings and the things you see
out of the corner of your
eye, you know?
When you're paranoid, you're
like, oh my god,
is that a dead body?
Oh, it's a pile of garbage.
Like, don't worry, calm down.
Everything's OK.
The world's not out
to kill you.
INTERVIEWER: I mean, it's
very beautiful.
But it's definitely shocking
when you get up close and see
all the different bodies
and decay.
AUREL SCHMIDT: The rats, the
maggots, the cigarette butts,
the flies are all the same
symbol, basically.
And it's like old Dutch
[INAUDIBLE] painting would use
the same thing or a
Vanitas painting.
But it's also just a metaphor
for the real world.
It's just that everything
beautiful dies.
There is decay.
There's renewal.
But there are symbols of death
and decay, which is also in a
way a symbol of inner--
like for me, I have a lot of
anxiety and bad thoughts.
And I think that it's also
a symbol of that.
Like the underlying says
things are good.
But no, things are bad.
There's this badness
to everything, or
like a sense of--
yeah, like a doom and a badness
to all things sometimes.
And those are just symbols that
symbolize that without
having to draw Iraqis getting
their heads blown off.
I mean, that's like a way to
kind of just for me to think
about those ideas, and they
become just symbols for me.
They're the tools to
make a drawing now.
I think only 12 drawings
in it.
But they're full page.
The drawings came first, and
Tim Barber at Tiny Vices
wanted to do a book.
And I think the burnout
project's kind of over now.
They're like, I think that I'm
done with the burnouts.
INTERVIEWER: OK.
AUREL SCHMIDT: I think.
INTERVIEWER: Because you're
self-taught, do you ever come
up with problems that you
encounter, where you think of
an idea and you just have to
figure out how to make it, or
you're not sure how you
want to make it?
Or how do you get over
those barriers?
AUREL SCHMIDT: I feel like it's
a huge barrier, and I
feel like I'm dealing
with it every day.
If I looked at what I would
want to be as an artist, I
don't want to be a drawer.
I don't want to be a drawer.
I want to be an artist.
I want to be someone who has
ideas and figures out, yeah,
how to make the idea
of the show.
Yeah, I want to make a bunch
of things right now.
I have no idea how to do it,
how to even experiment.
I have no idea what
medium to use.
And how I'm learning is just
going to other people's art
shows, going up to Chelsea and
be like, wow, this culture is
made of bronze and wax, or
blah, blah, blah, blah.
OK, That's materials, like I can
use those materials maybe.
I think most good work I've
ever made comes from not
knowing what I'm doing, figuring
it out, and then the
kind of surprises that
come from that
becoming the real work.
I think the new things I'm going
to start making, like
with sculptures, say, is
going to be crazy.
It's probably going to be crying
and freaking out, and
being really happy, and throwing
tons of stuff away,
and figuring it out,
but that's fine.
INTERVIEWER: What do you
think about people
collecting the work?
Your work was bought by some
really big collectors, by
Sachi and other people
when you first
started showing, right?
Do you feel like that has
influenced your work at all?
AUREL SCHMIDT: I think
that it's probably--
I think actually it's a
really amazing thing.
Those big collectors, they put
it into a collection where it
will go into other
exhibitions.
It's for galleries.
Those kind of collectors, they
don't put it above their
couch, which I think
is really important
for me to think freely.
It frees me to make work
as gross as I want, as
self-revealing as I want.
I'm not like, oh, people
like buying colors.
I should add more colors.
Or how am I going
to pay the rent?
I know people love those animal
drawings, you know?
It's like I can now do
whatever I want.
And if they do or don't like
it, doesn't matter.
INTERVIEWER: I would think that
it would kind of make you
feel more secure about making
the decision to be an artist.
AUREL SCHMIDT: I feel like it
was less of a decision and
more of just something
that happened.
And the fact that right away
those collectors did buy the
work, it was like, wow, this
stuff I make anyway is just
sold to someone good.
And wow.
So it's almost like that, those
things define the fact
that I'm an artist as a
career, whatever, now.
INTERVIEWER: Yeah.
AUREL SCHMIDT: Before I would
have just been making art, but
not necessarily like this is my
career choice or something.