what it offers. It must then look into the environmental aspects of The Venus Project. How we intend to support and
restore the damaged environment. Then: what different types of vehicles would be used for transportation.
How we solve the transportation problem. If they find shortcomings in it, say, "Present your recommendations."
But don't say "I don't like that system." - Present your recommendations, or alternatives.
If you want people to be safe in swimming, safe from sharks, you really don't have to make a swimming
pool any deeper than 5ft. You can swim in 5ft of water. Its hard to drown if you can't make it, you can reach bottom.
And children's pools will be shallow. And you can swim in it. You can't drown in it.
It isn't that I like shallow pools. If children have difficulty, you can't always see it.
I think our friends child drowned because mother couldn't watch over her in the ocean.
And she blamed the old man, the old man blamed the mother for not watching, and then they both
blamed the lifeguard. You know. It's inadequate systems: what you're dealing with.
Do you understand?
I don't find lifeguards submitting new ways of watching older people on the beach.
They're always a lifeguard. They never seem to innovate; make a life preserver connected to a cable that
goes out to the drowning person. That's what they need. Not the lifeguard grabbing him.
They need the thing getting there faster. Lifeguard can only get there at a certain speed.
So I would design a life raft that moves out very fast; stops by proximity mechanisms, and then moves
slowly to the person so he can grab it. And if they can't grab it, you send human assistants on a vehicle
out that way. Anyway, I've never heard of lifeguard associations making recommendations except
binoculars for the lifeguard to look around. But limited, very limited. Lifeguards are not trained as innovators.
But if you bring innovators to the system and say "How can you innovate that system to make it more efficient?"
If a man is mechanical, he might make a life reserver connected to a cable.
If he's electronic (into electronics), he would pick up distress in the water. You know, whatever it is.
But I don't find Academia to be critical of a political system. I don't find many opinions coming forth
on how to modify our system; so that we have less problems. I don't find that.
Now in books on politics, I don't think George Washington would be surprised at the decision-making today.
Cause its not that different. Benjamin Franklin, or anybody else. Our political system is based on opinions,
projections, inadequacies, incompetence. That's why I say "They would feel at home in this society."
But they would not feel at home in a Venus Project. No politician would know how decisions are made.
They wouldn't understand why our schools are the way they are. They wouldn't; even if they came and visited
the schools. They wouldn't understand. They wouldn't understand the nature of environmental reclamation.
Why it's done. And they wouldn't understand where you get the money to do environmental reclamations.
If the earth is declared common heritage, that's the only way you can have access to anything.
I can't understand if you base all your decisions on "How much will it cost?" Well, you wouldn't do anything.
Cause everything costs a lot of money. Except war. It makes a lot of money.
It isn't that I want to direct the whole thing. I haven't gotten assistance from others on how to put
up buildings faster. That were that new. So I had to innovate all this shit, cause I didn't get anything from others.
I'm not interested in doing all that. I'd rather have people capable of knowing when they see a ship;
"What is it you want?" - "You want the whole cargo unloaded at a given place." You don't want to take off
one container at a time. That's okay, if different containers go different places. And you got one ship.
But in the future, you must design automobile manufacturing at a certain region, so you deliver metals to that region.
Not all over Detroit or wherever you have auto factories. You have automotive production in a given region.
You know what I mean? With production lines. So you deliver more stuff; the same kind of stuff to all
the auto producers. Cows and farming would be in a region with farming canning factories nearby.
Not 50 miles away. Do you understand what I'm saying? I don't know any other system. I've never heard
of a food producer that said "I'm going to open a cannery on my grounds so I can can the string beans."
And besides, they wouldn't rot if they did that right away. I've never heard of an undertaker making recommendations
for the use of usable organs before the burial. You know what I mean? A kidney, whatever it is, you can get.
And you don't ask people whether or not they want to give their kidney after they're dead.
They say "Oh, I wanna be buried whole." The Jews do not permit dissection.
But the Jews won't ever know what the inside of the body is like if you don't permit dissection.
You know what I mean? But people will die due to their belief systems. But, if you wanna go with that
belief system. You can go, but I can assure you, you won't live as long as other systems.
And if our system can't make the appropriate decisions, we'll be surpassed by China, or North Korea,
or some other country that can make those decisions.
I don't say they will. But we will be surpassed if we can't make the appropriate decision.
So nature is a final eliminator, not Fresco. I don't eliminate people. If they're insufficiency is
"Every man for himself." Than that society will run as long as evolution will permit it to run.
You know, until the system is automated, and they fall on their face. That doesn't mean social change
won't be made. It means people might die fighting each other. And killing each other. And riots because
of different values; unless there is something put out there that people can understand.
I think I could sell the package if not all the people, a great many people. Enough to influence them.
Because they don't come there as an American to get them to accept our value system as the only one.
And you don't attack their customs. You wait till evolution passes the need for customs of that kind.
There are a group of Israeli's that are interested in The Venus Project. But if I went to Israel I'd
be boo'd off a platform. The majority does not believe. Does not lean towards science. You know what I mean?
So, I would try if I were invited, don't misunderstand me. If there were a big enough group in Israel,
I would go there and talk to that group and tell them how to reach the other group.
If I talk to the other group, I need three days, not a one-hour lecture.
I never came up with ideas because academicians approved it. I came up with them to try to find a
working solution. Academia doesn't know how to stop wars. Academia doesn't know hot to ask "What is the
bomber for?" They don't seem to do that. That's why I don't respect them. If they understand my direction,
that's more important than being a member of Academia.
And people would say to me, are there any great people that accepted The Venus Project?
There's something the matter with them; they have a low self-sufficiency. If the great man says "It's
a good idea. They'll follow it." I don't want that kind of shit. Do you understand?
If you say "Are there any famous people that accept The Venus Project?" Not that I know of.
Because you would then go on if Einstein said it was okay. What about you?
Roxanne: "Bill Gates..."
If you understand what I'm talking about, you say its okay, even thought the world doesn't agree with you.
The guys in the old days that believed the earth was round must have had a very rough time with Academia.
I think it was Academia that burnt them. It's Academia today that can cut you off. That can say "That man's
completely unqualified, never went to MIT, has no record of achievement in this world." - All true!
But that doesn't mean anything. What means something is if people understand that if you don't take care
of the environment, you lose it. That isn't difficult. But it may be "I guess the experts know what they're doing.
Let's leave it to politicians. At least they know what they're doing." I don't believe they even know what
they're doing. I don't believe they have the slightest idea what they're doing. I believe they're academicians
that believe one opinion is as good as another.
www.thevenusproject.com
cont'd.
Subscribe - Like - Friend - Fav ・ Thanks!