Higginsworth, quiet.
HIGGINSWORTH: What did you
get for number four?
STEVE: Your name.
Write your name.
Gosh.
So all you're going to
do is get some really
cool stuff at home.
I'll put the whole thing--
HIGGINSWORTH: Psst.
STEVE: I didn't want
to have to do this.
It's going to be a good year.
I'm Steve Spangler and I'm all
about making science fun.
For the last 20 years, I've
been teaching ways to turn
ordinary science experiments
into unforgettable learning
experiences.
I have an amazing team who will
do whatever it takes to
affect the way people
think about science.
And to do that, I live by one
motto: make it big, do it
right, give it class.
Well, every year also starts
with great school supplies,
and if you have a great mom like
I do, she stocks you up.
So let me see, tape, pencil,
glue, pen, scissors.
That's good.
Straw?
Why did she give me a straw?
Higginsworth, Mom
gave me a straw.
HIGGINSWORTH: It's for
the pitcher of water.
STEVE: Pitcher of water?
Oh, yeah.
Put that on your desk.
What are you writing?
HIGGINSWORTH: Nothing.
Hey, come on, Steve.
STEVE: Do you like me.
Yes, no, maybe?
No, she doesn't like you.
And my mom always packed
me a great lunch.
Higgins, why do we have
to eat at our desks?
HIGGINSWORTH: Because you
read my note out loud.
TEACHER: Spangler, Higginsworth,
it's quiet time.
STEVE: Sorry, Miss Jenkins.
Let's see what she got me.
Moms are so awesome.
Notes.
HIGGINSWORTH: Steve?
What's the note say?
STEVE: It's from my mom.
It says, have a great
first day of school.
PS, stay away from Higginsworth,
he's trouble.
And, San Pellegrino, so
sparkling and refreshing.
HIGGINSWORTH: Hey.
STEVE: Hold that.
I'll share it with you.
HIGGINSWORTH: Come on.
STEVE: What else?
Peanut butter.
When you want only
the best, Skippy.
Take this, Higgins.
Who doesn't like cheese?
Junior Mints, very refreshing.
Stewed tomatoes,
Mexican style.
Gnocchi, when all your friends
want to enjoy pasta, the pasta
alternative.
And a Slim Jim, spicy
but great.
Tempeh for those people who
don't like to eat other
carnivores.
And who doesn't love Cholula?
Cholula, the spicy alternative
to salsa.
And for dessert, Fiji.
Fa gee yogurt.
Don't eat all the fruit.
What the heck?
Why another straw?
HIGGINSWORTH: Psst, its
for the Cheese Whiz.
STEVE: Cheese Whiz.
Oh, I hate those.
Yum.
Higginsworth, look at this.
I spelled something
inappropriate on the cal--
TEACHER: Spangler!
STEVE: Sorry, Miss Jenkins.
Well, since Miss Jenkins said I
had to stay after school, it
means that I can show you some
cool science experiments using
only the stuff that Mom sent.
We're going to need that
sandwich bag first.
So grab a sandwich bag.
And to the sandwich bag you're
going to add some water.
Start by filling the plastic
bag with water,
probably 3/4 full.
Seal it up.
And now we're going to
do the impossible
with these sharp pencils.
Now, normally if you were to
take a sharpened pencil and
puncture a hole into a bag,
it would leak with
no problem at all.
But if you know something about
the science of this
plastic bag--
See, plastic bags are nothing
more than polymers.
And a polymer is a long
chain of molecules.
I want you to think of these
long strands of molecules
almost like fibers that make
up the plastic bag.
In this particular case, if
you take your sharpened
pencil, and you just have to
believe it's going to work,
and you push through, you
literally, can separate these
long chains of molecules.
The bag seals around the pencil
and hopefully, it
doesn't leak.
Bingo.
That look great?
So now the object is just to see
how many pencils you can
get through.
It's kind of like doing
sandwich bag surgery.
You will get a couple leaks here
and there, but, for the
most part, you can do this right
over a friend's head and
they should be fine.
Or for extra credit, do it right
over the teacher's head
and they will love it.
The only problem with this, the
waterproof bag, is pulling
out the pencils.
Higginsworth?
He'll do anything.
I've been doing this--
TEACHER: Spangler!
STEVE: Sorry, Miss Jenkins.
You can do something very cool
if you have a ruler.
You just need a regular ruler
and a sheet of newspaper.
And some air.
The object of this challenge
is to karate chop
this ruler in half.
I know, that's bad.
But you can only use one hand.
Now, if you just put the ruler
here like this and you karate
chop it like this.
It doesn't work.
And that's where the sheet
of newspaper comes in.
Believe it or not, we need this
flimsy little sheet of
newspaper to hold the
ruler in place.
It'll do it.
The only change we're going to
make to the newspaper is to
increase its surface area.
See it's 506 square inches.
If every square inch has air
pressure pushing on it and if
we were at sea level, that would
be about 14.7 pounds per
square inch.
That means that on this sheet
of newspaper, if it was laid
out completely flat, this sheet
of newspaper would have
nearly 7,438 pounds of pressure
pushing on it.
I think it's enough to hold
the ruler in place.
Ready?
Three, two, it's not exactly
about just the air pressure.
Yes, there's air pushing down
on it, but if you'll notice,
there's a little bit of air
sneaking underneath.
So in theory, it's air.
In reality, it's a combination
of the air pushing down on it
and the drag, or what's going
to happen when it tries to
flip back up again, and the
sheet of newspaper with the
air pushing down kind of
holding it in place.
Look at that.
Right in half.
That wasn't me, it
was the air.
You know, Mom said never
to play with your food.
So did Miss Jenkins.
But in this particular case,
it's a great idea because you
could use this spoon
as a catapult.
Now, there have been lots of
activities out there where you
just simply take a spoon
and tape it down.
We want more variables because
we want to turn this into a
real science experiment.
So this notebook will be perfect
because we're going to
attach the spoon to the notebook
and allow this to be
able to change the angle.
And we can figure out how far
it's going to go and have a
nice little hypothesis.
And believe it or not, the
secret is the staple remover.
Step one, attach the spoon to
the staple remover just using
some of that tape.
Perfect.
Now we've got to attach that
contraption to the notebook.
This is perfect.
Now we just need ammunition
and a target.
Higginsworth.
HIGGINSWORTH: Knock it off.
STEVE: Quiet.
HIGGINSWORTH: Miss Jenkins.
STEVE: God, that hurt.