in common -- both our
teams lost yesterday.
(laughter)
I mean, I would like to come
here and talk a little smack
about the Bears, but we
didn't quite get it done.
But it is wonderful to be back.
It is good to see everybody in
the great state of Michigan.
(applause)
A few people I want to
acknowledge -- first of all,
the Mayor of Detroit here --
Dave Bing is in the house.
(applause)
We've got the Redford Supervisor
-- Tracey Schultz Kobylarz.
(applause)
We've got some outstanding
members of Congress who are
here -- please give them
a big round of applause.
(applause)
I want to thank
Martin for hosting us.
I want to thank Jeff and Gibby
for giving me a great tour of
the factory.
(applause)
I've got to say I love
coming to factories.
Audience Member:
I love you!
The President:
I love you.
(applause)
So in addition to seeing the
best workers in the world --
(applause)
-- you've also got all
this cool equipment.
(laughter)
I wanted to try out some of the
equipment, but Secret Service
wouldn't let me.
(laughter)
They said, you're going to
drop something on your head,
hurt yourself.
(laughter)
They were worried I'd
mess something up.
And Jeff and Gibby may not admit
it, but I think they were pretty
happy the Secret Service
wouldn't let me touch
the equipment.
(laughter)
Now, it's been a little over a
month since the election came
to an end.
(applause)
So it's now safe for you to
turn your televisions back on.
(laughter)
All those scary political
ads are off the air.
You can answer your phone again
-- nobody is calling you in the
middle of dinner asking
for your support.
But, look, I have to admit
there's one part of the campaign
that I miss, and that is it is
a great excuse for me to get out
of Washington and come to towns
like this and talk to the people
who work so hard every day
and are looking out for their
families and are in their
communities, and just having a
conversation about what kind of
country do we want to be; what
kind of country do we want
to leave behind for our kids.
Because ultimately,
that's what this is about.
And I believe -- and I've been
saying this not just for the
last six months or the last
year, but ever since I got into
public office -- I believe
America only succeeds and
thrives when we've got a strong
and growing middle class.
(applause)
That's what I believe.
I believe we're at our best when
everybody who works hard has a
chance to get ahead; that they
can get a job that pays the
bills; that they've got health
care that they can count on;
that they can retire with
dignity and respect, maybe take
a vacation once in a while --
nothing fancy, just being able
to pack up the kids and go
someplace and enjoy time with
people that you love; make sure
that your kids can go to a good
school; make sure they
can aspire to whatever
they want to be.
That idea is what built America.
That's the idea
that built Michigan.
That's the idea that's at the
heart of the economic plan I've
been talking about all year
long on the campaign trail.
I want to give more Americans
the chance to earn the skills
that businesses are looking for
right now, and give our kids the
kind of education they need to
succeed in the 21st century.
I want to make sure America
leads the world in research
and technology and clean energy.
I want to put people back to
work rebuilding our roads and
our bridges and our schools.
(applause)
That's how we grow an economy.
I want us to bring down our
deficits, but I want to do it
in a balanced, responsible way.
And I want to reward -- I want a
tax code that rewards businesses
and manufacturers like Detroit
Diesel right here, creating jobs
right here in Redford, right
here in Michigan, right here
in the United States of America.
(applause)
That's where we need to go.
That's the country
we need to build.
And when it comes to bringing
manufacturing back to America --
that's why I'm here today.
Since 1938, Detroit Diesel has
been turning out some of the
best engines in the world.
(applause)
Over all those years,
generations of Redford workers
have walked through these doors.
Not just to punch a clock.
Not just to pick up a paycheck.
Not just to build an engine.
But to build a middle-class life
for their families; to earn a
shot at the American Dream.
For seven and a half decades,
through good times and bad,
through revolutions in
technology that sent a lot of
good jobs -- manufacturing jobs
-- overseas, men and women like
you, your parents, maybe even
your grandparents, have done
your part to build up America's
manufacturing strength.
That's something you
can all be proud of.
And now you're writing a new
proud chapter to that history.
Eight years ago, you started
building axles here alongside
the engines.
That meant more work.
That meant more jobs.
(applause)
So you started seeing products
-- more products stamped with
those three proud
words: Made in America.
Today, Daimler is announcing
a new $120 million investment
into this plant, creating 115
good, new union jobs building
transmissions and turbochargers
right here in Redford --
(applause)
-- 115 good new jobs
right here in this plant,
making things happen.
That is great for the plant.
It's great for this community.
But it's also good for
American manufacturing.
Soon, you guys will be building
all the key parts that go into
powering a heavy-duty truck,
all at the same facility.
Nobody else in
America is doing that.
Nobody else in North
And by putting everything
together in one place,
under one roof, Daimler
engineers can design each
part so it works
better with the others.
That means greater fuel
efficiency for your trucks.
It means greater savings
for your customers.
That's a big deal.
And it's just the latest
example of Daimler's leadership
on this issue.
Last year, I was proud to have
your support when we announced
the first-ever national
fuel-efficiency standards for
commercial trucks, which is
going to help save consumers
money and reduce our
dependence on foreign oil.
That's good news.
(applause)
But here's the other reason
why what you guys are doing,
what Daimler is doing,
is so important.
For a long time, companies,
they weren't always making
those kinds of investments
here in the United States.
They weren't always investing
in American workers.
They certainly weren't
willing to make them in
the U.S. auto industry.
Remember, it was just a few
years ago that our auto industry
was on the verge of collapse.
GM, Chrysler were all
on the brink of failure.
And if they failed, the
suppliers and distributors
that get their business
from those companies,
they would have died off, too.
Even Ford could have gone
down -- production halted.
Factories shuttered.
Once proud companies chopped
up and sold off for scraps.
And all of you -- the men and
women who built these companies
with your own hands -- would
have been hung out to dry.
And everybody in this community
that depends on you --
restaurant owners,
storekeepers, bartenders --
(laughter and applause)
-- their livelihoods would
have been at stake, too.
So I wasn't about
to let that happen.
I placed my bet on
American workers.
We bet on American ingenuity.
I'd make that same bet
any day of the week.
(applause)
Three and a half years later,
that bet is paying off.
This industry has added over a
quarter of a million new jobs.
Assembly lines
are humming again.
The American auto
industry is back.
And companies like Daimler
know you're still a smart bet.
They could have made their
investment somewhere else,
but they didn't.
And if you ask them whether it
was a tough call, they'll tell
you it wasn't even close.
So the word is going out all
around the world: If you want to
find the best workers in the
world, if you want to find the
best factories in the world, if
you want to build the best cars
or trucks or any other product
in the world, you should invest
in the United States of America.
This is the place to be.
(applause)
See, you're starting to see the
competitive balance is tipping a
little bit.
Over the past few years, it's
become more expensive to do
business in
countries like China.
Our workers have become
even more productive.
Our energy costs are starting
to go down here in the United
States.
And we still have
the largest market.
So when you factor in
everything, it makes sense
to invest here, in America.
And that's one of the reasons
why American manufacturing is
growing at the fastest
pace since the 1990s.
And thanks in part to that boost
in manufacturing, four years
after the worst economic crisis
of our lifetimes, our economy is
growing again.
Our businesses have created more
than 5.5 million new jobs over
the past 33 months.
So we're making progress.
(applause)
We're moving in the
right direction.
We're going forward.
So what we need to do is simple.
We need to keep going.
We need to keep going forward.
We should do everything we
can to keep creating good
middle-class jobs that help
folks rebuild security for
their families.
(applause)
And we should do everything we
can to encourage companies like
Daimler to keep investing
in American workers.
And by the way, what we
shouldn't do -- I just got
to say this -- what we shouldn't
be doing is trying to take away
your rights to bargain
for better wages and
working conditions.
(applause)
We shouldn't be doing that.
These so-called "right to work"
laws, they don't have to do with
economics; they have
everything to do with politics.
(applause)
What they're really talking
about is giving you the right
to work for less money.
(applause)
You only have to look to
Michigan -- where workers were
instrumental in reviving the
auto industry -- to see how
unions have helped build not
just a stronger middle class
but a stronger America.
(applause)
So folks from our state's
capital, all the way to the
nation's capital, they should
be focused on the same thing.
They should be working to
make sure companies like this
manufacturer is able to
make more great products.
That's what they
should be focused on.
(applause)
We don't want a
race to the bottom.
We want a race to the top.
(applause)
America is not going to compete
based on low-skill, low-wage,
no workers' rights.
That's not our
competitive advantage.
There's always going to be
some other country that can
treat its workers even worse.
Right?
Audience:
Right!
The President:
What's going to make us
succeed is we got the best
workers -- well trained,
reliable, productive,
low turnover, healthy.
That's what makes us strong.
And it also is what allows our
workers then to buy the products
that we make because they got
enough money in their pockets.
(applause)
So we've got to get past
this whole situation where
we manufacture crises
because of politics.
That actually leads to less
certainty, more conflict,
and we can't all focus on
coming together to grow.
Audience Member:
That's right!
The President:
And the same thing --
we're seeing the same
thing in Washington.
I'm sure you've all heard the
talk recently about some big
deadlines we're facing in a few
weeks when it comes to decisions
on jobs and
investment and taxes.
And that debate is going to
have a big impact on all of you.
Some of you may know this:
If Congress doesn't act soon,
meaning in the next few weeks,
starting on January 1st,
everybody is going to see
their income taxes go up.
Audience:
No!
The President:
It's true.
You all don't like that.
Audience:
No!
The President:
Typical, middle-class family of
four will see an income tax hike
of around $2,200.
How many of you can afford to
pay another $2,200 in taxes?
Not you?
Audience:
No!
The President:
I didn't think so.
You can't afford
to lose that money.
That's a hit you
can't afford to take.
And, by the way, that's not a
good hit for businesses, either
-- because if Congress lets
middle-class taxes go up,
economists will tell you that
means people will spend nearly
$200 billion less than
they otherwise would spend.
Consumer spending
is going to go down.
That means you've
got less customers.
Businesses get fewer profits.
They hire fewer workers.
You go in a downward spiral.
Wrong idea.
Here is the good news: We
can solve this problem.
All Congress needs to do is pass
a law that would prevent a tax
hike on the first $250,000 of
everybody's income -- everybody.
(applause)
That means 98 percent of
Americans -- and probably 100
percent of you -- (laughter)
-- 97 percent of small
businesses wouldn't see
their income taxes
go up a single dime.
Even the wealthiest Americans
would still get a tax cut on the
first $250,000 of their income.
But when they start making
a million, or $10 million,
or $20 million you can afford
to pay a little bit more.
(applause)
You're not too strapped.
So Congress can
do that right now.
Everybody says
they agree with it.
Let's get it done.
(applause)
So that's the bare minimum.
That's the bare minimum we
should be doing in order to
the grow the economy.
But we can do more.
We can do more than just
extend middle-class tax cuts.
I've said I will work with
Republicans on a plan for
economic growth, job creation,
and reducing our deficits.
And that has some
compromise between
Democrats and Republicans.
I understand people have
a lot of different views.
I'm willing to
compromise a little bit.
But if we're serious about
reducing our deficit,
we've also got to be serious
about investing in the things
that help us grow and make
the middle class strong,
like education, and
research and development,
and making sure kids can go
to college, and rebuilding our
roads and our infrastructure.
(applause)
We've got to do that.
So when you put it all together,
what you need is a package that
keeps taxes where they are for
middle-class families; we make
some tough spending cuts on
things that we don't need;
and then we ask the wealthiest
Americans to pay a slightly
higher tax rate.
And that's a principle I won't
compromise on, because I'm not
going to have a situation
where the wealthiest among us,
including folks like me, get
to keep all our tax breaks,
and then we're asking students
to pay higher student loans.
Or suddenly, a school doesn't
have schoolbooks because the
school district
couldn't afford it.
Or some family that has a
disabled kid isn't getting
the help that they
need through Medicaid.
We're not going to do that.
We're not going to
make that tradeoff.
That's not going
to help us to grow.
Our economic success has never
come from the top down; it comes
from the middle out.
It comes from the bottom up.
(applause)
It comes from folks like you
working hard, and if you're
working hard and you're
successful, then you become
customers and
everybody does well.
Our success as a country in this
new century will be defined by
how well we educate our kids,
how well we train our workers,
how well we invent, how well
we innovate, how well we build
things like cars and engines
-- all the things that helped
create the greatest middle
class the world has ever known.
That's how you bring new
jobs back to Detroit.
That's how you bring good
jobs back to America.
That's what I'm focused on.
That's what I will stay
relentlessly focused on
going forward.
(applause)
Because when we focus on these
things -- when we stay true to
ourselves and our history,
there's nothing we can't do.
(applause)
And if you don't believe me, you
need to come down to this plant
and see all these
outstanding workers.
In fact, as I was coming over
here, I was hearing about a guy
named Willie.
(applause)
Where's Willie?
There's Willie right here.
There's Willie.
(applause)
Now, in case you haven't heard
of him, they actually call him
"Pretty Willie."
(laughter)
Now, I got to say you got to be
pretty tough to have a nickname
like "Pretty Willie."
(laughter)
He's tough.
On Wednesday, Willie will
celebrate 60 years working at
Detroit Diesel -- 60 years.
(applause)
Willie started back
on December 12, 1952.
I was not born yet.
(laughter)
Wasn't even close to being born.
He made $1.40 an hour.
The only time he spent away
from this plant was when he
was serving our country
in the Korean War.
(applause)
So three generations of Willie's
family have passed through
Detroit Diesel.
One of his daughters works
here with him right now --
is that right?
There she is.
(applause)
In all his years, Willie has
been late to work only once.
It was back in 1977.
(laughter)
It's been so long he can't
remember why he was late --
(laughter and applause)
-- but we're willing
to give him a pass.
So Willie believes in hard work.
You don't keep a job for 60
years if you don't work hard.
Sooner or later, someone is
going to fire you if you don't
work hard.
He takes pride in being part of
something bigger than himself.
He's committed to family; he's
committed to community; he's
committed to country.
That's how Willie
lives his life.
That's how all of
you live your lives.
And that makes me hopeful about
the future, because you're out
there fighting every day for a
better future for your family
and your country.
And when you do that, that means
you're creating value all across
this economy.
You're inspiring people.
You're being a good
example for your kids.
That's what makes America great.
That's what we have
to stay focused on.
And as long as I've got the
privilege of serving as your
President, I'm going to
keep fighting for you.
I'm going to keep
fighting for your kids.
I'm going to keep fighting for
an America where anybody, no
matter who you are, no matter
what you look like, no matter
where you come from,
you can make it if you
try here in America.
(applause)
Thank you very much, everybody.
God bless you.
(applause)