and
further never know what a wonderful
privilege of years to come into your
presence
we thank you for your holy word
which is a shoe or compass
in a world of confusion and rebuild
and as we study today how about
sulaiman
a character in reaping a destiny
we ask that your holy spirit will be
here to teach us
we thank you for hearing our prayer
for we ask it in jesus name, amen
during the course of this seminar we
have been studying
primarily the meaning obj and assist
chapter three and versus fifteen
and i would like to refresh our memory
about that verse which is foundational
to all of scripture
any adverse god is speaking to the
serpent
and adam and eve are spending their
endlessly
and dot says to the serpent
i won't put admit the
between you know and the woman
and between your steven and her seat
he shelled bruise your head
and you shell bruise
his feet
one thing is very very clear investors
and that is that there were only tour
groups
that exists in this world
from the beginning
till the end of time
although it does scenes
the scene of the righteous embassy of
the week
now in our study today we're going to
notice
itgroup which is classified as the
wicked
there are three different kinds
of people
or ask unblocked side
there is only one
tight of person
so in the category outs safe and see
are free types of people
whereas on the side of goradze
there is only
one time
number of other study today the famous
parable of jesus
of the seller
who sold the sea
and as we began i would like to say that
this parable is found in all three
of the synoptic gospels when i mean by
the synoptic gospels is matthew
mark
and lou
this terrible has filed an all three of
these gospels
which means that we're not going to
remain only in one gospel as we study
this parable
were going to go out to matthew mark and
luke
in order to do we need details
from every single one arby's
gospels
and as i am speaking now i would like to
ask
the deacons to please distribute the
list of cuts and almost hit my mind
we have less attacks and we would like
the deacons at this point to please
quickly
distribute
these lists of tents
we want them again
look at matthew chapter thirteen
adverse thirty-seven
matthew chapter thirteen
adverse
thirty-seven
we want to determine first of all
who sa lawyer of the cv is
it says they're and matthew thirteen and
burst thirty-seven
the following
he answered and said to them
whose sole role is
dot blot cd
is the psalm
abang
son the parable of the solar
the person whose sole was
but let's see
is not less
vinci's was
now we also want to determine what the
seeded represents
going to make to the gospel of luke
chapter eighteen
actually not chapter eighth not eighteen
look chapter eight and verse eleven
luke chapter eight
and verse you havent
it says here now the parable is this
that's either
gears
bullard
of god
so nice that we have one solar
jason's
we have on the one seat
which is the word of god
no i want your daughters that that seed
that word of god
is very very powerful
got what nato i say that chapter fifty
five
and versus ten any levin
isaiah fifty five
and versus ten
and eleven
here we find the profits speaking the
following wertz
isaiah chapter fifty five
and vs
and eleven
for us the rain calms down
and this al from heaven
and do not return there
but a lot of the earth
and make it bring forth embarked
that it may give seat to this solar
and director of the heater
saw show mind worded
being that goes forth from my mouth
it shall not to return it to me about it
but inshallah com police
what high please
and it shall prosper engulfing for which
i sent it
here god promises that what he saw
secede
his cv well bear fruit
his seat is powerful his word is
powerful
so what do we have so far
we have a sartre
who is jesus
we have a seed which is the word of god
and that seed is powerful to produce the
results for which got sent it
but had this terrible we also have for
the effort saw deals
for different grounds so-to-speak
now the question is what do these four
soils
represent
daughter making the gospel of mark
chapter four
and verse fifteen
marked chapter four
and verse
fifteen
here we have an explanation of what is
meant to be
by the soils
it says here
the following
and this is speaking about the seed
that fail by the wayside
but it'll give us the principal for all
alba solos excessive risk fifteen
and these are the ones by the wayside
where the word is sold
i hear
saic outcomes immediately
and takes on going
but what are the that was solloway
there was solid in their hearts
so that's it
in his sock in the ground or at the soil
but that's all i a lot represents what
the seidel represents
the heart
and so this parable of the sort you out
for it
different kinds of hearts
reactance hearts an undesirable
all only one of them is desirable
in fact three
have these hearts etc dot being in the
camp of satan
and only one of these aesop being on the
side
of god
edsall summarizing what we've studied we
have this parable what's sort who is
jesus
we have watched seed which is the word
of god
the work of god is powerful to account
police dot dot progress for which it is
sent
and finally
this sidles
represent
for different kinds of of hearts upon
which the seed of the truth of god's
word
falls
now let's examine all four of these
sorts
and see what they have to teach us today
let school first of all up to that
seemed that failed by the wayside or on
the path
dark made on both chapter eight
and we'll read verse twelve look chapter
eight
adverse twelve the scene
by the wayside
it says here
bolstered by the wayside
i don't want to hear
by the way everyone in this parable
here's
blowouts who cesar planted by the
wayside
the hearts
here
though i wasn't starting classes
the people here
but some on flyers
bars on the ground the people in it
in other words there's no way of saying
i didn't know all this
in other words everyone is responsible
because every one of these soils
here's
the word of god
now knock us once again it says in verse
twelve lost by the wayside
are the ones who here
vet devil comes
and tanks are weighing dole word
out of their hearts
lest they should be leaving
and do you want
n_b_c_
falls on the wayside are on the path
does not even begin to germany
democracy vase of the heart
the devil comes and takes away to see
these are individuals who hear the word
of god
anne makes deadly they've reject the
word or they postpone they refuse to
accept
what god
is teaching them
we have that legal examples of this type
of person
you remember for example when the
apostle paul appeared before feely ts
the story is found in exchequer
twenty-four converse twenty five
the apostle paul preach this tremendous
powerful sermon
and after you preached a sermon he was
hoping that felix
what except the message
but i want to notice
what happened
with three weeks
it says here
in
villa book of acts chapter twenty four
inverse
twenty-five the following
not asking you resend about right
justice
self contribu
and a judgment to cum laude ismael
ceremonies bridge in the word of god
about these things
felix was afraid
and answered
blow away for now
what i have a convenient time
i will call for you
do you know the opportunity never k
because
that was his moment of opportunity
what a sad
it's convenient i will call you
not convenient time in turkey
we have also the apostle paul spanning
the fourteen agreed upon
not as acts chapter twenty six
and versus twenty seven and twenty eight
exchequer twenty six and versus twenty
seven and twenty eight
once again the apostle paul is priest a
powerful sarma about receiving jesus
christ
and preparing for the judgment
and much of a notice what happens when
he finishes his sermon
it says they're in acs chapter twenty
six and verse
twenty seven
and twenty eight
doug reply
don't believe the profits
i'm not
i'll bet you do believe
that hug repulsive to paul
you almost
persuade me
to become
actress
tragic war
some properties powerful service
be far phoenix
before work but
felix s
i will call you at a convenient season
he puts it off
acrobats says
you know what you're saying is very
persuasive and powerful you almost
persuade me
to become a christian but not quite
deceived fail underpaid
the seed failed by the wayside
it did not given begin to germinate
in the heart
these types of here is our also
illustrated bites
those
who stalled steven the first christian
barter
but what made to the book up acts
chapter seven
acts separate seven
but either way this whole chapter almost
yes a sermon presented
by steven
to the jury said he'd read
to the jewish council
now watch notice what happens after
the sermon is preached
chapter seven and starting with versus
fifty four
it says well they heard these things
they were cut to the heart
and a net
stab him with their he
they were really angry weren't there
but heat being fought the holy spirit
day is going to happen
and saw the glory of god and jesus
standing at the right hand of god
and said look
i seem to have a solvent and the set-up
man standing of the right hand of god
vandyck krakow without loud voice
bear
errors
and ran at him with a card
and a cat scan out of the city and
stoned him
and the witnesses lay down their clothes
at the feet of a young man named song
gnashing their teeth
their hearts a raging within them
rejecting this wonderful simon that
stephen had preached
beginning way back in the old testament
and showing how prophecy was fulfilled
and eventually the messiah came
the openly rejected
the message that god presented
through stephen
by the way in the end time there are
going to be people like this also
in fact all of those who received the
message of the anti christ will be
eventually be people of this time
not a second thessalonians chapter two
second fazal audience chapter two and i
would like to read afew verses that we
find they're beginning with burst eight
it says they're embattled lol this one
will be revealed
that's the anti christ by the way
hold a lark will consume with the breath
of his mouth
and destroyed with the brightness for
this coming
the coming up a lot less one is
according to the working of satan
without power assigns and line wonders
and that's all i might just be section
among those who perished
and now morris why they perish
because
they did not greasy what
the laugh public truth
that they might be saved by the way what
is truth
jesus said in john seventeen percent
gain
sanctified and through your truth yaar
wondered is truth
so what has rejected if they did not
receive the love of the truth
they rejected truth which is found where
in the holy bible
norris what we find enforced eleven
and for this reason dot will send them
elsewhere
notion
that they should be in the black
the line
that they are
they condemned who did not
relieve what
the truth
but had pleasure
in on righteousness
and as a serious rang
to have the word of god preached
and presented to you
and the first type of soil represents
those
who hear our caller
but email
hardly wear cubs they shot out the word
the work does not even began germinate
and as a result take sacred takes the
troops from the heart
and those who have this kind of soil
i lost
but we have a second kind of song
it's the soil
unse stoney
go with me to the gospel of luke
chapter eight adversities
the gospel of luke chapter eight
and versus six
the description obvious conduct so
little
it says there
the following
fail under a rock
anis has its frank
it with their outweighing because it
lacked what
meister
now i watch visualize that what's
happening here
there is a rock but there's also some
good site
because the scene germinate skynet
begins to grow isn't that right
you know is that this cd this saw is
different than the first so because the
first solo even before the siege
emanates
the devil concentrated from the heart
but here at least
the cd cancer its process of growth
there
yes some subtle there
but we noticed then looked after eight
that that's on a lot lack slot
it lacks
mores jer
and by the way it's stony it's rocky
this not year or so little
there's also stalled with the soil
by the way as we witness in matthew
thirteen it gives us an additional
detail
noise matthew thirteen vs five and six
matthew chapter thirteen
and vs five
and six
it says here
south fail un stony places
werent they did not have much whacked
much are
and the email
italy sprang up
because they have no depth of cars
but notice but when the sun was opt
they were sparked ste
an because they have no route
they work
they withered away nonetheless the
combination that we have here
we have saw al
which is not always so little but you
have rocked
in the song
you outside a little
that does not have moisture
and you have the same dead
it's down upon the soil
and scratches
the sea
starches the newborn client
now you imagine some of you living here
in the valley i may i imagine have
gardens
what would happen if you plant a seed
and it adds just a little bit soil
enhancements stall owner underneath that
and so you plant the seed superficially
there's no forrester hardly in the earth
and the sound of that fresno side are
intending residual i you know about that
is big
came out of time to see
how much of an opportunity does that
seem to have to germinate and grow and
eventually produce fruit
very
now what does the seed planted
i'm stony ground
represent
well it represents those individuals
who when the dust bowl it's preach to
them
thrilled with excitement and with the
motion
has planted in the heart
and a they say this is wonderful i've
never heard anything like it in my light
and they got all of those
but then trials and tribulations come
you see one of the problems that people
have is that they think that when they
accept the gospel it's been a key or all
of their problems they're not going to
have temptations are difficulties are
tribulations anymore the fact is false
their greatest tribulations com after
baptism
the greatest tests of the devil come
after we've decided to get our hearts to
jesus christ i see many of you nodding
you say yes
that's absolutely true
because the devil has lost a child
and he's got to make it as difficult as
possible to try and gain that child back
but there are people that when the dust
was preached when we have a series of
meetings like this
their all pumped up
and they're really excited
and then they have problems with their
families that have problems with their
relatives they have problems at work
they have all sorts of difficulties
perhaps i can tell you having problems
with some of the habits that they had
and they get discouraged
and as a result the fall
by the wayside
by the way this c this so little
represents those
who want disarmed jesus and themselves
you see the stone represents a stoner
that some other kind of good song which
means that they want to serve the lord
but they also want to keep some of self
these are the ones that jesus spoke
about what he said
noel man
ken starr effort to masters
you cannot serve the lord with a divided
heart in other words
it easy there everything are nothing
now i want you to notice acouple of
passages in scripture
did speak about
what happens when we receive the gospel
of jesus but what made a mark chapter
ten and versus twenty eight to thirty
one
mark chapter ten
and versus twenty eight
two thirty one
jesus has just talked about how
difficult it is far rich man to enter
the kingdom of heaven
and i want you to notice
what jesus continues saint of the
disciples because they say we've left it
all what's in it for us see they were
kind of mercenaries
and so jesus says unmarked and beginning
adverse
twenty-eight
the following
mark ten twenty eight
that appear began to say to him
we have left all and followed you
sought jesus answered and said
assuredly i say to you
there is no one who was left house
or brothers or sisters or father
or mother or wife
or children
all our lands
for might say abduct schools
who shall not receive haha dreadful now
and this time houses and brothers and
sisters and mothers and children and
lands
now most
the next expression
slot
persecutions
enemy you stuck come
eternal life
did you know is that you receive many
blessings because you have a new family
into a church family
and so you have everything you need
within the church family
but the etc but we find jesus saying
that this will be with what
persecution
norris matthew chapter ten
and beginning with versus thirty-four
the same idea coming through
matthew chapter denver study for by the
way it's become very popular today
to see on television television
preachers
would tell you that when you receive
jesus
you're going to prosper you're going to
get directs
and things are going to go well
that cost totally against the grain
of scripture
and particularly this parable not so
that we find in matthew chapter ten
and beginning with verse
thirty-four
jesus says this
think that i came to bring peace unrest
i did not come to bring this by the
sword that's sound strange coming from
blitz is jesus is indeed the prince of
peace
modest verse thirty five
far i have come to settle man against
this pop his father
anna dot against her mother
anna daughter in law against her
mother-in-law
events cummings will be balls up his own
household
breast thirty-seven
he wore last father or mother more than
me is not worthy of me
and he will not sign a card bader
marconi is not worth the of me
yusuf ops the second soil represents
those individuals
cool here at work
they get excited
they think everything is gonna be a good
everything is gonna be prosperity
they have a divided art they haven't
totally given up on self they have very
little lost your of the holy spirit in
their lives
they have a stocky heart and aside
out collections
sop and a m in the fall
by the wayside
and ultimately
are lost
you know several years ago while i was
teaching in our our university in
colombia
there was this young lady that came to
our theological school she came to study
is a bible instructor her name plus a
female mendes
she was involved in an accident and she
died a few years ago
but she came to our school
and uh... you know i tried to get close
to the students and find out about their
background and so
one day i was sitting under the trees
there another dimension
uh... you know she came and sat down we
started talking as she told me her story
she's ed pastor aryan i'd lived in this
town in colonial remember the name of
the town burned in this town in colombia
and uh... there are received and ellen
the mail that they were going to have
uh... this series of meetings
and saw uh... i decided that i would go
to that series of meetings even though i
did
but i didn't know anything about the
church where the rabin held i didn't
know anything about the speaker
but god
opening night i went to the meetings
there was an evangelistic series you can
guess
and so she went for the whole
evangelistic series
and at the end of the series he decided
that she would be the attached
insult she went home
and she told her parents i've been going
to these meetings
and uh... i believe that the truth is
being proclaimed their they ask you what
churches that is that the catholic
church he said no on if the seventh
adventist church and uh... immediately
the parents frantz calden frowns and
says you've been going to the seventh
evidence church she said yes
and i've been hearing these wonderful
messages and i believe that's the truth
and i've made my decision to be back on
ste
her father looked at her and he said
a subpoena
if u get baptized
you don't have a father and mother
we're all this are you
and also been a lot better father
insisted father i love you the bible
says that we're supposed to honor our
father my mother
but i told my allegiance first of my
heavenly father
and therefore i'm going to go through
with this
i'm going to be baptized on
such-and-such a day
and her father xavier baptized on that
date
united daughter you can't live here
anymore
she went to the church
she got baptized
her parents knew about because they were
checking it out
when ha subpoena came home
all of our few belongings were on the
front door step of the house
entered at matter at the door and he
said also fiat
don't chew ever come back here again
and she said i'm sorry father
i love you very much
but i must obey god rather than men and
that includes my own parents
and she came to the school she did have
anyplace to go
and that's why she came and decide to
study at the school
she became a bible worker she married a
seventh-day adventist pastor
and by the way her parents never
accepted the message
as far as i know
she was disloyal
for the rest of her life
she did not receive the work like this
stalini ground here is
army went revelation came and the fact
directly against her
she says
mileage and spears with god
by a personal and a superficial religion
with very little holy spirit a very
little moisture because the monitor
represents the holy spirit
what
they followed by the wayside
and said
oh laughs values
i can have my foot
outlier kids make i can't have my fellow
workers against me hike at my friend's
against me
and in full
by the wayside
by the way did you know that judas it's
scary it fits in this category
i'm not going to read a passage brandon
matthew eight verses eighteen to twenty
two
there's a certain scribe it comes to
jesus and he says to him i'll follow you
wherever you go
that was yours
jesus tried to discourage him because
you know it's hard
says
barracks at mass
foxes have holes
but the son of man doesn't have anyplace
delays it
what jesus was saying to him as a look
if you're if i don't mean
for those also that this is
no i'm not going down the wrong road
because i don't have any prosperity and
all that money and i don't have anything
to offer your in terms of material
prosperity
if you follow me for that reason forgave
do you know if you look at the context
of that passage
you're going to find that judas offered
to follow jesus
when jesus was popular
multitudes were following jesus
a people were excited because jesus was
healing diseases and he was fading
thousands of people
it's a lot
out this is the guide that we want to be
with but then we just are preaching the
word
accorded the judge after six
only the disciples were left
and jesus says are you going to leave
too
empiricism lowered if we leave work and
we go
you have miracles
so what readers at
you have what
you have works
see peter he said many things without
thinking
but this was one good thing that he said
yes i do you have not goes and signs and
wonders he says you path
but why arts of life
everybody else left because i would no
longer in our cause
but peter
headed straight
and so we have two kinds of soil
those by the wayside who don't respond
at all when the worries preached they
showed no religious interest
saket
the laws on the stony ground they have a
superficial
acceptance of the truth
part rock
there also and partnered soiled part
jesus
trying to sacto masters accepting jesus
at that time of emotion and feeling
tribulations com
they fall by the wayside
but there's a third type afzal
and that is the seed that fail
among the
form
used to have a good sign
but there were a farce
not a salute chapter eight inverse
fourteen
luke chapter eight inverse fourteen
describes this current of soil
it says there
invoke chapter eight inverse fourteen
the following
now the winds that fail amato
forums
i've always cool
have heard sleeping here also
well they have heard it
gault
and are what
anike shopped
by what
with perris
by the way if you go up to the gospel
uh... of mark
chapter four inverse nineteen it adds an
ex-president says
by the kerry's obvious world
it adds that by the cares of this world
you know because of this world arc
wanting to accumulate houses
and cards
and money in stocks and bonds
in wanting to work two jobs
things that are not bad and themselves
but with jobs all or part time and
effort
that's part of the forms
that care is of this life
not us once again uh... looked chapter
eight and verse fourteen
it says
now the ones that felt among the
florence and also wet may have heard got
out an art shot with a care
this of this world if you compare mark
what else
actually mark says with that d_c_
fullness of riches
so that's why you have to compare all
three gospels because it's one expresses
that a little differently
riches
is that the e_c_
formats of riches
and then something else
and a lot
and apply
fisher's out alive
and bring no proof
to maturity
the florence by the way what the forums
represent in scripture
you remember in genesis chapter three
adverse eighteen
what came in consequence of sin
god said car scares the ground for your
state
in talking would you show event although
days of your life
and at what does he say
both clarence and fred souls
it shall bring forth
for you
foreign census vessels
represent
saying
it comes in
the pleasures of this world
dot
of this life
that decided for mass aldrich is scott
and and they chaal
the plant
which has begun to grow
now we have been brutal examples of this
we have a rich young rumor that came to
geez
do you know the bible says that jesus
loved this young man
he seems easiest blessing the children
missus i'd love that they look at how
the children
i've drawn
so he comes to jesus
and he says what do i need to do to have
eternal life juices will keep the
commitments
he says which
so then jesus quotes
the last table of a lot
and the address es i've done all these
thanks since i was a young boy
what part of it
and jesus looks at him
and he says
you would be perfect
gold sales all that you have
and give it to the poor
and you will have treasure with me in
heaven come follow me
and the bible says
that this young man left
southville
because he had a lot
because he had
possessions
did he allowed the d_c_ fullness of
riches to choke
the seat in his heart
you know folks as as seventy evidence
precios many times you say although i'm
not a slave to money i have no problems
of money i can handle it
and yet what are we doing
work too hard waiting finance dept were
not that we don't really need
isn't that right
doing it for houses
to live in
doing actually we
for automobiles
don't actually need
tens of thousands at first
files on some balance and the bank
while the work of god is languishing
do you know that i miss coming when
people are gonna cry out
why didn't i use my money why didn't i
invest my money in the kingdom of god
defer that the gospel
why did i acutally for myself
when we won't be able to buy and sell
people are going to say that
but it's going to be too late
the d_c_ fullness of riches
has been the ruin
of their soul
by the way the apostle paul had
something very interesting to say first
timothy chapter six verses nine and ten
first timothy chapter six versus nine
and ten the apostle paul had something
very interesting to say about money
analogical reed had to read it carefully
with me
because i'm
some people misread it they get the
impression that riches abit ridges are
not bad
notice what the apostle paul says in
first timothy chapter six converse nine
but also desire to be rates lotus is not
even say the rates because a lot of the
rich
but also a desire to be rich
did temptations and a lot
a smear
an internet foliage and ha
default lasts
which drowned and in destruction and
producers
because the more money in our the more
twice you want and the more entertaining
that you want and the more popular
now modest verse ten
far molly
is the root of all kinds of evil
uh... thank you thank you
for the lack of money
is on rooftops on times of evil was the
king james says is the root of all evil
novelist this for weeks on the head
straight
and from the fight in their greedy miss
and pierce themselves through with many
sorrows
do you know
i have
scene
many rich people that are absolutely
miserable
because they're always afraid they're
going to lose their riches
and they're always thinking about making
mark and investing more
do you know that jesus gave a parable
which describes this type of person
no absolute chapter twelve
looks chapter twelve and verse fifteen
luke chapter twelve and verse fifteen
foster said not time for us to invest
art treasures in the heavenly bed
did not get how you can send your money
panel now
you don't send video back nasa
and have now so send it in a rocket
but they haven't
what you do is you and bask in its cost
and the salvation of souls
and when the solid penned up their your
investment is there
now not so that we find in look once
again chapter twelve
and beginning at first fifteen twelve
verse fifteen this is another parables
jesus
and he said to them
take heed
and beware of covered just nuts
for once life does not consist
india but that's not the frenzy plus
taxes
life does not consistently abundance of
what
things which we possess
nice running illustrate
danny spark a parable to them same
background of a certain richmond yielded
plentiful e
and he fought within himself
saying
whatcha like you
so yes i have no room to store my crafts
sali said
i will do this
local down my barnes and build greater
and their all will start all my
crops and mag goods
and i will say to my soul so
you have many goods led up for many
years date carries
etc and be mary
how you get in the connection with the
parable of the song
brass twenty
but god said to him
full
this not your soul will be required of
you
then holds will postings
be which you have provided saw is he
coolest op treasure for himself
and he is not
rich
tort
we find jonassaint love not the world
no other things better in the world
and i know we paid lip service to this
folks
do you believe that we're living in the
last moments of human history
this in as we look at what's happening
in the world
i can't help but my revel in the last
couple of weeks what we've been seeing
how the united states is fulfilling the
prophecy of revelation thirty in the
initial stages at least
and how all of the questions are coming
together with a common attend dot
it stopped we are as practically clear
the question is what are we doing with
the resources that god has given us
are we
investing please and the cause of
dinosaur well pastor bar you just want
to be paid
well let me tell you the private comes
here to this church
but you know which in none of it comes
into my pocket
it all goes to a central location
and then they pay all of the pastors
anat equitable basis
i don't receive any of the offerings
that come into the church the offerings
golfer the writing of this church for
the preaching of the gospel for
evangelistic meetings for health
seminars
for all of these things which have the
intent on reaching people with the got
school
and i pray to god that we will late
everything we have time to talk to have
sacrificed because soon it might be too
late
we need to wake up from a slumber
we better not call not too long
we've got it
who aren't too long
it's time to get up
and make a sacrifice regard as i
mentioned in one of the previous
lectures
the little window
she comes in chief closer to mike sin
jesus says she gave more than all of us
will be a great a great sums
and explain why
he says because
came out of their abundance and others i
get what they have leftover what they
really didn't
eight but she gave all
that she had
her only system
it's
and so we have jesus said
by the way in looked after twenty one
thirty four
he says make sure that your heart is not
weighed down by carousing drunkenness
and the cares obvious life death that
day come upon you
unexpectedly
an easy kill chapter seven burst
nineteen we're told that in the day when
the wrath of god is poured out upon this
world
people attacked their called and their
silver and they will find
hence on the streets
and there are saying what does this
world
we return only lost what good is that i
have all of these things silver and gold
will be absolutely worthless
and so we have three different kinds of
people so far that we stay
number one they hear the word
be rejected
doesn't even begin to germany
number two
those individual so here's alert
and in a moment of emotion they accept
that they say this is wonderful
and that relations com
the sun comes out and beats on the
planet
impacts
then you have balls
they are on foreign soil
for whom the d_c_ elissa preachers
riches the terracotta this life
strangle the seed that has been planted
the plant that is beginning to grow
but i thank god that there's one other
kind of slow
and that is the good summer
norris what we find in the gospel of
luke chapter eight and versus fifteen
luke chapter eight
and verse
fifteen
we find out there
the following words luke eight inverse
fifteen
but the ones that fail and a good ground
eyeball sku
having her
their word
without noble and good heart
do what
chia pet
and bear fruit with what
patients
noticed that the good side represents
loss will hear the word of god
where what
patients
and eventually if there's a lot fruit
does affect starbucks on l
bear fruit
does a second type of soil bear fruit
that's a fact dot gov soil bear fruit
nor the plant begins to route but more
fruit
what is quite interested in
goddess interested and planting the seed
of his word in our hearts
and that we might we see
that c
wef al-assad
with plenty of the moisture of the holy
spirit
and a taxi driver named
emperador supplier
which eventually will bear whacked will
bear fruit for god's under and god's
glory
revelation chapter one in verse three
we find john speaking about this book
which deals with ken tiny bits
he says blessed is he
and
and also here the parts of this prophecy
and what and people most things
which
are repent ended
for the time is near
notice
reiki
hearing that means to pay attention and
what
and
noticed john chapter fourteen and verse
twenty three john chapter fourteen and
verse twenty three
by the way jesus are biting in our
hearts
has a condition he will not candid abide
in any heart
notice what we find in john chapter
fourteen
and vs
twenty three
guarantees us
says this
if everyone loves me
he will work
hywell cape
my
wire
and my father will love him
and we will come to him
and make our home with him
isn't that the other four
if anyone here is my work and watch
and
sly word
behind the file
other will come
and we will make our holm are uphold
with them
james tells us that it's not duck
here is of the word
which will be justified but whom but
donors of the word
by the way do you know that indian time
they're going to be many christians
who hear the word
but don't do it
noticed
the gospel of matthew chapter seven
matthew chapter seven and verse twenty
one
one this is a very solemn passage
i'm gonna read several vs
jesus is not everyone who says to me
lord lord
jackets that
not everyone who says to me lord lord
show after the kingdom of heaven
but he who does that will have my father
in heaven was if not only hearing but a
lot
doing if not only saying
doing
verse twenty two
many will say to me in that day
lord art
have we not prophesied in your name
passed out demons and your name
and done many wonders in your name
by the way were these christians
why would they be doing it in the name
of jesus if they were christians
out this week the questions
so what is jesus was right
and then i will declare to them
i never ignore you
d part from maine you know who practice
lawlessness and then jesus gives an
example
the parable
of the man who built this house up on
the rock and the man who built this
house upon the saint
we even sing about this in summer school
do you still saying this is our school
the wiseman builtin spouse upon the rock
i remember i used to love to sing that
song
still do
style of a child at heart
but anyway jesus gives a parable abotu
builders
who is the one who builds on the rock
and it was the one who builds on the
sand
listen up
verse twenty four
therefore whoever here
first these words sayings of mine
and does them
hello
anybody out there today
therefore whoever hears these things of
mine and spam
i would like him him to our wiseman who
built his house out a lot
on the rock
and the rain descended the floods came
words blue and
on that house
and it did not fall
four it was founded on the rock what
does that mean to be found on the rock
it means that you'll be here are the
words of jesus and what and through them
now morris what about the man who build
on the same
verse twenty six
but everyone who hears these sayings of
mine and does not
do them
will be like a policeman who built his
house on the senate
and the rain descended the flags came in
the winds blew
and
on that house
and it fail
and great
by the way these verses are speaking
about the tribulations that is coming up
on the world
flooring tiles are hoping the far went
on strike
why are we ask you at the storm dot com
installer
and all the calls who here
or words of jesus
and two of them
will be safe
in that great day
i'd like to take the last
few moments that we have
to talk about the process of god
planting the seed in the so little of
our hearts
how this god
do it
well listen to what i'm gonna sing
the cd
is a word of god
we've already studied
the word of god is preached
and what that means is that god is
taking the seed and he's putting it
where
he's planting the seed in the heart
by the way faith comes by hearing and
hearing by what
by the word of god
what happens with people who are not
into the word of god
cornerstone can block plant
his seat in our hearts
if we're not studying the word
absolutely not
because god speaks to our hearts to the
word
but now we're starting to work
but mark dot plants his will antecedent
in our hearts
antennae morrison's
the ground where black
with but do out his holy spirit
and i'm mark time that i suspect or
the longer
the plant grows
ever continue in this process
eve actually what's gonna happen is that
plant is going to go out to into a tree
and victory eventually is going to bear
whacked
is going to be here
and by the way what is the fruit
though it may delay since chapter five
galatians chapter five
and i would like to begin reading
adverse nineteen
uh... well actually let's let's begin
reading adverse twenty-one ending about
though works of the flesh
and the murders drunkenness rebel armies
and the like
which i tell you beforehand
just as i also told your diet
basketballs
who practice such things will not
inherit the kingdom of god
reticence about the fruit of the spirit
verse twenty two but the fruit of the
spirit is
love joy
piece
long suffering
kindness
goodness
faithfulness gentleman's self controlled
do you know what the fruit of the spirit
is
if the character of jesus
is is a description of the character
jesus
let's read again
it says
lob joint peace long-serving kindness
goodness faithfulness gentleness self
control
that's different
how does the front cover
do you have to plant before you artistic
uh... fruit
proceeded
so what does god do
he takes the scene of the truth he
planted in her heart the more that were
in the words studying the word
assimilating the work
god speaks to us
he placed the word in our hearts
through the influence of the holy spirit
that plaque begins to watch
to grow and eventually it produces in
our lives
the fruit of the spirit
in other ways it produces in our lives
that character of jesus
do you know we take the mold of the
character of that which we dedicate our
time too
you know this right
if we gotta get most of our time
music and well endeavors and television
and videos and all these things
what type of character regatta
we're going to reflect that character
but the market we allow the word of god
to enter through our allies
by bible study by listening to sermons
by watching three ibn
by watching sports all things
guard plants and seed in our hearts
the sea grows into a plaque then grows
into a tree and in our lives changed
because we had as a result the fruit of
the spirit appearing in our lives
which is christ likeness
the hope of glory incidentally
so we have four solar house
three of them will eventually be lost
one of them only will be saved in the
kingdom
what is the soil of your heart
are you
away side here
r_u_ any story ground here
are you
forney ground here
or are you a good salil
our decision
will determine
r_u_ ternal destiny
and folks let me finish with a positive
note
do you know that we're not stuck with
the heart that we have
god can't change the heart just look at
some of parsons
have style he was like
are starting steven along with uh... not
actively but he was encouraging the
people to start a statement
and yet the lord changed his heart
from stony salil
two-way sought from wife side so
a soft
the good news is that give god can
change the soil for hearts
and i pray to god that we will be like
the good side
where the seed truth
despite
unto eternal