press conference.
-You're not allowed to
leave the hotel.
JOHN MCAFEE: No, dude, if I had
not left that hotel, do
you know what would have
happened tonight?
They would come and get me,
with no one watching, at 2
o'clock in the morning
for something.
Trust me.
-Hey, let me tell
you something.
JOHN MCAFEE: Guatemalan jails
have beds, dude, and food.
It's pretty awesome.
I'm not too concerned.
And you should not be.
Federales.
We don't mess with Federales.
-What's the problem?
JOHN MCAFEE: The problem is
they're trying to detain me.
-For what reason?
JOHN MCAFEE: I think this--
excuse me, sir.
No, no.
This gentleman here
was the one who
detained me, right here.
You should get a picture of
him, and these three guys,
right here.
These three guys, right here.
-For what reason?
JOHN MCAFEE: I'm not sure.
But I was just standing here,
And they were just-- this one
here, this guy came
up to me, here.
May I smoke, sir?
-Yes, you can smoke.
You can definitely smoke.
JOHN MCAFEE: OK.
Make sure you get a
picture of him.
Come here.
-Can we not bring you
into the hotel?
JOHN MCAFEE: What's that?
-So is the arm longer
than you thought?
JOHN MCAFEE: It's
long, isn't it?
It's a long arm, now,
is this not proof?
Is this not proof?
Excuse me, sir.
I'm sorry.
And they could take me back
to police tonight?
-No, never.
JOHN MCAFEE: Are you sure?
Can you promise me, sir?
-I am sure.
JOHN MCAFEE: Because I'm not
worried about anything else.
-Of course.
They won't take you to police.
No, never.
Never.
I will go with you?
We are going to speak with
the vice minister.
JOHN MCAFEE: Sure.
-OK?
Yeah?
JOHN MCAFEE: You will
come with me.
Is that true?
-He is coming.
Yes, I am going with you.
Just wait a minute.
-John.
-We are waiting for
[INAUDIBLE]
your passport.
And afterwards, we will go.
I told them already.
-You blow from here.
-So I guess I should tell
Jeff not to come?
JOHN MCAFEE: No, tell
Jeff to come.
I think this will be short.
-Where are they taking
you, John?
-Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Wait.
-John, where are you're going?
JOHN MCAFEE: To jail.
-When will you be out?