infatuated with fire as well.
And this is the kind of episode
where most shows would
say, don't try anything
at home.
And that's kind of
the problem.
This is what we want you
to be able to try.
So, a couple things said.
You're going to be using
flammable materials.
There's a couple things
that you need.
First of all, safety glasses.
And secondly, you need
a fire extinguisher.
You don't have those two, you
can't do this at home.
And third, if you're a kid,
you got to have adult
supervision.
If you're an adult who is
careless, you need to have a
better adult to give you better
adult supervision.
Make sense?
I think you're going like this.
Watch.
So here are the things
we need.
So we need some isopropyl
alcohol--
this is just rubbing
alcohol, 70%--
something to mix it in, water--
just in case we get
into trouble--
some tongs, and of course,
the lighter.
So here's what happens,
let's start
with the rubbing alcohol.
And now, we need something
that will catch on fire.
Ah, this is perfect.
Lunch money.
I don't know even a lunch that
you could buy using a dollar,
but a long time ago, this, I
guess, was your lunch money.
All right, so this goes down--
and you always borrow this.
This is where we say, don't try
this at home, try it at a
friend's home, right?
Well you always use a friend's
bill as well.
So you say, can I please borrow
some money, and they,
of course, will only
give you a dollar.
It's a hundred times better if
you could get a hundred dollar
bill, but good luck.
So this dips down inside.
This is our flammable
material, here.
OK.
You ready?
Watch this.
This is off to the
side like this.
And now let's light it
and see what happens.
Oh, that's a nice flame,
looks good.
And--
perfect.
It's out.
Well, there was a little
bit of trickery.
Although we used all the
materials that you see on the
table, if you had done it
exactly the way I just showed
you, there would have
been a problem.
And I'll show you what
that looks like.
We actually used a real dollar
bill, but this solution here
isn't actually just 70%
rubbing alcohol.
Let me show you what would
happen if you would have used
real rubbing alcohol in
its full strength.
Now we pull it out of the
way so that nothing
else catches on fire.
Watch what happens with
pure rubbing alcohol.
It burns and it burns.
And then, it continues to burn,
and it burns, and you'll
notice that it continues
to burn.
And well, this is a problem,
because now you've destroyed
money, and you might think
that there's going to be
another problem on
top of that.
Come to find out, the way the
law reads, you can destroy
money and not go to jail.
You just can't destroy money
and try to pass it.
That's counterfeit, right.
And I think you can see there's
just no possible way
that I think you can
probably pass that.
You know as a kid, you would
take a penny and you'd go to
the circus or that place, and
you'd put it in that machine
and crank it, and it would
flatten the penny and put a
logo on there or you just got
a name or your birthday, or
whatever it is.
That is kind of the same thing
that we're doing here.
It's destroying the penny, but
by law, that's OK to do
because you'd never take
that penny and then
try to pass it again.
Same thing here.
We're not trying to pass it.
The whole goal is that you're
not lighting the
bill on fire at all.
I just wanted you to see what
would happen if you really had
done it the way I told you.
Here's the secret.
First of all, 70% rubbing
alcohol-- isopropyl alcohol--
means that there's seven parts
of the isopropyl alcohol to
three parts water, right.
So there's already water
in this mixture.
And at the very beginning, I
said, this is everything that
you'll need.
The secret was sitting in front
of you the entire time
and it was actually
right here.
It's the water that's
in this pitcher.
What we want is we want to add
more water to the isopropyl
alcohol so that what
happens is that we
burn off that fuel--
but by the time the fuel burns
off, the evaporating water
that has coated the
dollar bill as
well begins to evaporate.
And as it begins to evaporate,
it cools the bill down.
So here's the mixture that
you're going to need.
This all varies, so you're going
to have to experiment a
little bit.
And I think you can do the
dollar to experiment.
Here's 70% rubbing alcohol,
and we're going to add--
I'm going to put about
300 milliliters.
I'm going to add about 200
milliliters, which again, is
going to be about 3/4 of a cup
if you're doing it that way,
of water, and there's
your mixture.
It looks just like rubbing
alcohol, and that entire
mixture got put back
into the bottle.
So I hadn't dumped that last
little part out and put it
back into bottle so that you
didn't know that I had done
anything to it.
There is a little secret.
If you use this mixture right
here, it's going to burn
awfully blue, so you
need some salt.
And if you put some salt inside,
the sodium from the
salt will help kind of
color it yellow.
The salt dissolves with
no problem at all.
Good.
And now just kind
of stir it up.
All right.
Now our special watered-down
mixture goes
back into the container.
That's perfect.
And now we're ready to go.
This is the set up.
This looks awfully science-y,
so you could
substitute a bowl.
That'll be perfect.
You need a friend's
dollar bill.
Friend?
Got a dollar bill, that's
perfect, and now
you're ready to go.
All right.
So now we put the mixture out.
Again, we're telling them
that, look, it's
just rubbing alcohol.
But you know that it's
a mixture of
rubbing alcohol and water.
And now, here's the
cool thing.
When you take this, the secret
is you've got to completely
soak the dollar bill.
If you don't soak the dollar
bill, then it's easy for it to
catch on fire.
So just make sure it's
completely soaked.
Move this container off to the
side, and now we're simply
going to light this on fire.
What's going to burn, instead
of the dollar
bill, is the fuel.
Look at that nice yellow
kind of look there.
And--
it's perfectly fine.
Now if you're trying this and
you see that it starts to
burn, just shake it for a second
and it will come out,
and you may have to tweak
the formula just
a little tiny bit.
But your dollar bill is back.
You can't tell this, but right
now, it's cool to the touch.
So anybody who touches it will
be amazed that it feels cold.
It was just on fire,
but it's cold.
And of course, that adds to the
secret and kind of gives
away that part of it, that it's
the evaporating water
that kind of keeps this safe.
All right, so this is the true
test of your solution, if it
really is going to work.
This makes you a little
bit nervous.
All right, so there's the
hundred dollar bill.
This goes down inside
like this.
I'm going to make sure that
every little piece of this is
completely soaked.
If you paid your dues in the
local science club, you've
done well--
I'll move this out
of the way--
hopefully everything
will be just fine.
Watch.
There it burns.
It's looking good, it's
looking good, and--
bam.
It's there.
Look at this.
There is my good hundred
dollar bill.
I know what you're thinking.
Let's say you're watching us
from another country, and
you're thinking well, does
it work with my money.
We have this huge following in
the UK, so you just use your
UK, your pounds.
Do you have any pounds?
This is a pound, got it.
Let's see if it works.
This goes down into the
water like this.
I've never tried this before,
so this will be interesting.
OK, ready?
This is really thin
and flimsy.
Your money is going to be
much better than this.
Let's just see if this is OK.
Watch.
That's looking pretty good.
And--
that's truly amazing.
Look at that.
With just notebook paper, it's
still perfectly fine.
That's pretty cool.
All right, so you want to try
this and you want to use
paper, right?
And you might say, I'm
not using my money--
although that is the
best way to do it.
You can do it the original way
that I learned how to do it
using a man's handkerchief.
I know you don't use these
today, but just head to the
local department store, you can
find a piece of cloth or a
man's handkerchief.
We just need to have ceilings
that are higher than what you
see here, otherwise it's going
to be a much more exciting
science experiment than
I'd ever want.
Let's go to bigger and
higher ceilings.
Taller ceilings, safety glasses,
we're going to use
the man's handkerchief, and we
need a fire extinguisher, so
make sure that you
have a fire--
Bo, you got a fire
extinguisher?
OK, here's your job.
Stand close by.
You hang on to this.
If anything bad happens and
I start to catch on
fire, take me off.
Pull the pin and
go for it, OK.
Don't get overactive, I'm not
catching on fire, just stay
there, all right.
See this, so excited to maybe
get to pull the fire
extinguisher.
OK, here we go.
Are we ready.
So here is the cloth.
Now this one here, you really
got to work on kind of getting
it nice and wet.
OK, nice and wet.
And now you're going to take
this out, and we're going to
wring it out.
The other thing I can tell you
is that you want to make sure
that your hands now
are not wet.
So now, dry your hands off.
OK, perfect.
Now my hands are
completely dry.
All right, move this
out of the way.
It's time for fire.
Hopefully, the water will
keep it nice and safe.
Here we go.
Oh, this is looking good.
So here it is.
Now this is a pretty good flame,
you definitely don't
want to do this in your house.
This is outside.
Here's the flame.
Look at that, isn't
that awesome.
Look.
To the touch, it's fine.
It's not singed.
Ta-da.
Take your bow.
The secret is water.
It keeps the material from
catching on fire.
And whether you're doing it with
a dollar bill or you're
doing it with a handkerchief,
the secret is trapping water
close to the surface, because
the evaporation of that water
produces this cooling effect.
Water is this great
conductor of heat.
And we're not just messing
around with this.
This is actually being used as
a fire-fighting technique.
They're finding ways to be able
to take water, make it
sticky, so to speak, and to put
it on a structure like a
building and try to keep
it from burning.
And believe it or not,
you might have played
with it as a toy.
The toy is called Gravi-Goo.
It's actually a powder that
you can see inside.
It's really a very, very high
molecular weight polymer,
polymer just being a long
chain of molecules.
Look, we haven't used much there
at all, you can see that
little bit sitting
in the bottom.
Let me add the water.
And now you just keep on pouring
it back and forth.
The super-absorbent polymer will
literally pull itself out
of the beaker like a
self-siphoning gel.
So here's the batch that
I made previously.
This is probably four or
five of these batches.
And now, I'm going to get my
hands inside so we can kind of
play with it, and you can
see what it looks like.
It's extremely sticky,
and it's almost
completely made of water.
Here's the test, nothing
terribly scientific, but
here's our board.
And let's take some of this
polymer in the water and put
it on the board like this.
Perfect.
Now we just test it
with the fire.
Watch the side of the board
without the polymer.
Watch.
It doesn't take long at all
for that to start on fire.
Watch this over here.
See, it's the heat-absorbing
properties of the water that
are keeping the board safe.
Now eventually, it'll catch on
fire because it will burn all
the way through.
But it definitely is better
than no water at all to be
able to help mitigate
any of the damage.
Am I saying that this toy right
here is going to save a
burning structure?
No, but I think the science
of it is very, very solid.
If you can get water close to
the structure and allow the
heat from the fire to be able
to cause the water to
evaporate, it only makes sense
that you're going to buy time
for firefighters as they try
to save the property.
Who would have thought that the
science of toys could help
possibly save a burning
structure.
Well, if you enjoyed this week's
episode, go ahead and
click the Subscribe button here,
and you'll be the first
to know when a brand new episode
appears each week.
This button right here will
show you some more cool
science experiments that we
do outside of this show.
This button right here will
take you to last week's
episode, just in case
you missed it.
And, if you want to see the
stuff that you shouldn't see--
that's the bloopers and the
outtakes-- well, just click
this one right over here.
And if you want to hear me
stop talking, through the
magic of television, just click
this button right here.
Go ahead, click it.
And I'll stop.
[MUSIC PLAYING]