yet you take the lives
of American soldiers
and put them up
to defend the US.
Are they defending the US
or are they defending
the social institutions
the war factories,
the war industries?
Do you see what I mean?
Merely marching in front of the
Stock Market or Stock Exchange
is only part of this system.
The public pays taxes.
They support the police
the Army, the war
weapons, everything.
The very rich pay
very little taxes
yet they control the police
and the National
Guard and the Army.
It's the public that pays
the police's salary.
I am told they arrested... - 700
- By now, you say 700.
Well, that's interesting
but remember the public
pays their salary.
They don't know who they
hell they're serving.
When they serve Wall
Street that means
the money people really control
the country, not the public.
80% of the people say
they are not satisfied with
the government's decisions.
If you walk in front of the
Stock Exchange, and you say
that these people are corrupt,
the whole system is corrupt!
You have to point
out these things.
They want to cut
Medicare for the poor.
"What do you suggest as an alternative?
Let them die?" Bring that up!
"What do you suggest?"
The guy that says "We don't want
to give people free medical care."
"What do you want them to do?
Die? Yes or No?"
They can't answer that
so pin them down when they say
"We love this country.
Our boys are out there fighting
giving up their lives
for the country."
"Don't you think we ought to
take the profit out of war also
just like the guys don't make
money fighting over there?"
They get minimum wage fighting.
When you figure out
the cost of war
all the aircraft carriers, all the
airplanes, all the cities destroyed
and all the nations wiped out
it's cheaper to take that money
and build new cities all over
the world, helping people
to understand the benefits
of technology and knowledge.
The whole country is
involved in exploitation.
If you are a dentist, you make money
on me if I need a root canal.
If you dent your automobile,
somebody makes money
straightening out the fenders.
Everything is profitable
and we want that changed.
We want the world to
concern itself with people
and taking care of the environment.
It's the greatest gift we have:
the trees, top soil, oceans
where ships, luxury liners, empty
their bilge into the ocean.
That means the oil and all the
stuff; they pump it into the ocean.
The oceans are the
toilets of the world.
All big hotels pump their fecal
matter out into the oceans.
So what do you expect from that?
Do you expect the dolphins to
live on [with] healthy lives?
They can't.
If you use genetic manipulation
without a long-term study
of the effects of it, you
are going to hurt people.
It's the system, not Wall Street.
The system produces all that.
Therefore, we offer an alternative
system and this is what it is:
to declare the Earth the common
heritage of all the world's people.
For those of you
that are religious
God didn't make the Earth for
the Greeks or the Polocks
of the Jews or the French.
He made it for all the
people of the world.
Use religion, use it that way.
You can find that in the Bible
"Love your enemy" it says.
It says "Thou shall not
kill" in all Bibles
and yet people don't
seem to follow that
so apparently they don't
understand what they are reading.
They believe in honesty
and good and fair-play.
Where did we get this land?
We stole it from the Indians.
Women who disagreed were burned as
witches in Salem, Massachusetts.
The Ku Klux Klan in America
had 3 million members.
If you don't bring that
up, that's a problem.
The problem is that freedom
and individual opinions
can become dangerous.
I asked many people years
ago whether they thought
man will ever get to the Moon.
They said "not in a thousand years."
I said "Do you know anything
about rockets?" No.
"Do you know anything
about space travel?" No.
Well how do you formulate that?
How come we give everybody a
right to their own opinion?
Why don't you give them
access to information?
Essentially, you have
to educate people
teach them about the system, how
it works, where it's offensive.
If a man commits a crime
say he steals a watch worth $200
it's his third offense, he
goes to jail for 7 years.
It's cheaper to give him a watch
than feed him for 7 years
and take care of his
medical problems
and hotel, his food.
Putting a man in jail is
cruel beyond description.
It's confining a human,
taking away his life
putting him there for 10 years,
some 20 years, some life in prison.
The judge has no idea
what he's doing.
He doesn't know the condition
that shaped that value system.
If he knew where
that man came from
if he knew the conditioning
of that man, he'd say
"It's not his fault.
He was brought up to hate
and kill and murder."
It seems that all people
that kill and murder
are really enacting the way
movies (all our cowboy pictures)
[They] never sit down to discuss anything.
They shoot people.
[They] have their two guns.
The Indians were fighting for
their land; we stole it from them
but we shoot Indians, and we show
the guys in the covered wagons ...
What the hell, are you taking
their land away from [them]?
Why don't you ask them whether we can
settle down here? They said "No."
We didn't ask them. We took it
and we drove the Indians
into the desert region.
They're still looking
for justice.
The Indians aren't going to get
justice because they have no power.
If they get an Indian
in the Congress
if he doesn't conform to the
views of the Congressmen
they'll move him out.
Do you understand?
Now, as long as sports
exist: racing cars
football, baseball,
they act as detractors.
They detract people
from the real issues.
They don't even know what
the real issues are.
The real issues are to take
care of this God-given Earth
if you're talking to them,
to take care of nature.
God put the trees here
to give us oxygen.
We give out carbon dioxide;
the trees use that.
Use religion, whatever,
wherever they're at.
Talk to them.
Say it's not going to change anything
if you march in front of Wall Street,
but if you talk to other people
and get a sufficient
amount of people organized
to demand the Venus Project.
When 80% of the people don't
trust their government anymore
(what the Republicans
say about the Democrats
or the Democrats say
about the Republicans)
they just don't feel comfortable,
and they don't know what else to do
so they would like to (like
the Arabs) change the culture
but what do you change it to?
They don't know.
If they succeed in
changing the culture
it'll revert back
to the old values
unless you teach them about
the new value system.
Then they say "Well, they've tried
that for years and it never worked."
Who tried it? When did they try it?
Pin them down.
"Well, I don't know..."
Say "I'm not interested in your
opinion, I want facts!" OK?
And they'll try to detract you.
They'll say "It will kill incentive.
" "Have you ever tried it?"
"No, Russia has." "Well, Russia
didn't have the resources we have
and they didn't steal the
land; it was their land."
Russia had men pulling boats
along the Volga River.
Did you know that?
They had no power system.
Life was so miserable for
the majority of people
they took to an ideal that
if the people owned the
means of production
they wouldn't hurt each other
so they tried this social
experiment and they failed
because they didn't know how
precisely to carry it out
to attain what they wanted.
If the socialists got into power
they'd be concerned
about the working man.
If automation came up they'd say "No,
we have to have people working,"
and other nations
will pass us by
surpass us, because
they put in automation.
When you get new machines that
work everything in the factory
(let's say you've got 3,000
people working in it)
[but] now you got 1500, and
machines are assembling cars.
You have to point out that
if new machines come in
you'll get the workers
together and say:
"Instead of working 8 hours,
you now work 4 hours a day
and instead of getting
a week off every year
you get 2 months off with your
family," and they'd get paid.
That's what the machines
do, but if machines
cause you to lose your job,
you're going to hate machines.
Machines, when
used intelligently
if they turn out 50 times
more than a man can turn out
industry will use machines.
They don't give a shit about people.
They don't care whether they lay
off 400 people, 500 or 3000
if they make more
money doing it.
The Japanese are presently
working on human faces.
They're not quite good enough.
When you get human faces on
television to sell toothpaste
it works for about
15 cents an hour.
Eventually, instead of having
people selling goods on TV
you'll have a face: sweet
old lady, excellent face
but today, their heads
turn like this.
They don't turn naturally.
When the Japanese finally get there
everybody can be displaced,
including doctors, lawyers.
If you don't understand that,
the more sophisticated
say "Well, a scientist can't
be displaced, he can think."
No, a scientist is given
every word in school
that gravity is a force
that shows itself
by electrical, magnetic
and chemical effect.
Every word that they
use is pumped in.
If you made a computer,
an architectural computer
you can say to it
"I want a home"
and it'll say "What kind of home?
" It has to say that
and you'll say "I'm not sure"
because you're not of
student of architecture.
Different homes will
appear and rotate
and you say finally
"No not, that one!"
Then you'd say to the computer
"I'd like to see the floor plan"
and it understands language.
If you don't understand that, there
are machines that can type the speech
that understand language,
so just like the architect
you say ''I'd like to see the floor
plan," and the roof lifts off
or a blueprint is
presented to you.
You begin to design
integrated systems.
Do you know what that means?
That they take in the whole factor
and instead of selling an
air-conditioner to every home
we pipe air-conditioned
air all around
and you absorb what you want.
You turn it on and off.
That's much cheaper than
selling an air-conditioner
or a lawn mower to 5000 houses.
The lawn mower people
would love to do that
to sell a lawn mower
to each house.
Instead of that you have
4 or 5 giant lawn mowers
that take care of the whole area.
Do you understand that?
They say "Do we have
enough resources?"
We don't, using it the
way it's used today:
a lawn mower, an air-conditioner
hanging out of every window.
That's not a way to do things.
You have a thousand farms
growing the same thing.
You have farms, large
farms, industrial farms
without genetic engineering, unless
it's been tested for many years
to make sure there's
no negative effects.
The system I'm talking about
doesn't profit anyone to lie.
Everybody has access to books,
school, free of charge
and there's no taxation.
If you don't like that system
"What are you, an atheist?"
You approach religious
people that way
"This is what God wants.
It's called the brotherhood of man."
This doesn't differ from
any religious teaching.
It really doesn't, so if
you're with normal people
if they say "Will you come
to the Presbytarian church
and give a presentation?
" do it in that guise.
If you go to a bunch of
humanists that are atheists
you don't need to use religion.
You can just point out
the shortcomings.
I think I told you about
the girl that came with me
with a whip and
handcuffs and she says
"I'd like to be whipped and
handcuffed to the bed."
She was a Catholic and
couldn't think of having sex
without force, and
it's not her fault.
She always dreamt of guys holding
her down and making love to her
and that was legitimate to her.
Whenever she thought of 'gee',
having sex, that was sinful.
Is she bad? No.
Is she wrong? No.
She was brought up under
different circumstances.
It takes a long while
to learn that.
It's much easier to
get mad at people.
When you get mad at them,
you feel relieved.
In the future when you understand
that's where they're coming from
you don't get mad.