I can run a
marathon in this thing.
But can the guy wearing
the suit take the abuse
dished out by a real
marine drill instructor?
Bodette: You ain't
got time to be tired.
Travis Taylor:
I'm Travis Taylor.
I'm a rocket scientist
in the space and
defense industry here
in my hometown of
Huntsville, Alabama
where my daddy helped
build the rockets
that sent us
to the moon.
Daddy: Have y'all
been drinking
rocket fuel again?
Travis Taylor:
Sometimes big science
moves too slow for me.
So come the
weekend I round up
my best friend Rog.
Rog: Hey!
Travis Taylor: My
nephew Michael and
my buddy Pete to
tackle important
problems with a little
down-home ingenuity.
Rog: Damn it, boy.
Travis Taylor: Right on.
Hey, is there any more
beers in the cooler?
Today we are doing
a little shooting,
but it's not
just for fun.
My big brother,
Michael's Daddy
he's in the Air Force
and he tells all the time
about this big
armored jacket that
he has to
wear when he goes
into combat situations.
There has got to
be better way.
So we're doing some
baseline testing of
military issued body
armor to see if we can
come up with a
lighter version that
works just as
good or better.
Michael: My daddy wears
one of these all the time
so it be good to put
something else out there
as an option that
could be better.
Travis Taylor:
Holy crap.
Pete: I was really
surprised at how
well the vest stood
up to gunfire.
A typical military
vest is sewn out of
multiple layers of Kevlar,
which is a synthetic woven
fabric that is 5 times
stronger than steel.
Travis Taylor: Pull
that plate out.
Kevlar alone can stop
certain ammunition.
The vest also
holds armor plates.
And this piece
right here.
Pete: That's what,
boron carbonate?
Travis Taylor: That's
boron carbonate or
silicate carbonate
look at that.
They are small arms
protection inserts that
are made of hard
ceramic materials and
they offer additional
protection.
It weighs whatever just
to cover their torso and
then they have to
carry their packs.
That's a lot of weight
to be walking around in.
I got something in
the back of the truck
I want to show you all.
I want to play
around with this and
let y'all see what
it feels like to
have to wear one
of these things.
I think for us to
truly understand what
these guys have to wear
and do and put up with.
The only thing to do
is to run a mile in the
shoes of the
people who wear it.
Daddy, I am gonna take
'em all around this way
and up this hill
you get in the truck
and you follow
us on out.
Out that way and we are
gonna do at least a mile.
Rog: I don't
want to do this,
I'm no runner but
it's for the troops
so I'll give it a try.
Travis Taylor: Come on.
Daddy: Hey keep it going,
doing good, doing good.
Left, left,
left, right, left.
Travis Taylor: You ok Rog?
Back in high school
I couldn't out run
Rog to save my life.
Rog was one of the fastest
at the 800-meter run and
I would run about
10 or 20 seconds
behind him at least.
Stay with it, Rog.
Rog: I'm through running!
Travis Taylor: And now
seeing how after only
.4 miles he just falls over
and off the side of the
road and he is so winded
he can't get along.
I think he sees what his
lifestyle has done to him.
Daddy: Get in here before
you have a heart attack.
Michael: These suits are
heavy and they're hot and
they're awkward to wear
and they're bulky because
these plates are stiff so
every time you move you
feel 'em on your
back and you can feel
where they restrict you.
Travis Taylor: What
we got to do is
figure out
something better.
They're good I mean
it's the best state of
art armor in the world,
but it'd be great if
we could do something
even better.
There are dozens of
new materials and
ultra tough
polymers out there
that the government
hasn't tested yet.
We could research these
materials for them.
And we are gonna do
it lighter, faster,
cheaper and we are gonna
do it all in one weekend.
I like to the cut
the weight in half
and keep the
same protection.
Daddy: Now, I don't
know of anyone
creating a
full armor suit.
That's a tall order.
Travis Taylor: We
want to make a full
body armor suit that
covers a soldier's
torso, arms,
legs and head.
It's got to be bullet
proof and blast proof
and still be light
and flexible enough to
maneuver through
a battlefield.
Once we figure out the
materials which you all
need to go be gathering
up some materials and
go do some testing but
you know got to make
a vest out of that.
So uh I think I'm gonna
have to go recruit some
help on that cause don't
none of us how to sew.
Daddy: I know as
much about sewing
as a hog does
arithmetic.
Travis won't do it,
Michael and Pete
not gonna do it, Rog
sure ain't gonna do it.
Travis Taylor:
Guess what, momma!
Well look you all gather
up all the materials you
can think of that
might be useful and
I'll see if mom can break
her sewing machine out
and help us figure
out to make a vest
out of this thing.
Y'all, y'all
go get with it.
Michael: You
Mama: Show me what
you got in mind.
Travis Taylor: Well, we
are gonna make a vest.
We're starting with
a vest the same size
as the military vest.
Our first challenge is
to make half the weight
and just as
bullet proof.
Now if we can
pull that off,
then we'll scale it
up to a full suit.
Rog: Get out of
the way, Yerp.
Quit calling them gals!
Pete: We were looking
around for materials in
the neighborhood and we
picked up a water tank
from the neighbors
farm it's made of
high-density
polyethylene.
We also found a sheet
of ultra high molecular
weight polyethylene
which is used for
anything from fishing
line to hip replacements.
These should make great
body armor plates.
And then we picked
up some Kevlar material
from the local
surplus store for
Mrs. Taylor to
sew the vest with.
Travis Taylor:
Hold up a minute,
hold up a minute,
hold up a minute.
Hold up a minute;
let me show you
all something.
Michael: Show
us something.
Rog: What do you got?
Travis Taylor: Mom and
I have been in there
working on a template
for what we got to have.
This is what the vets
is gonna look like;
these are the hard pieces
that we got to make.
Go head and draw
it up on a piece of
plywood or something.
Michael: Something
to trace.
Travis Taylor: 'Cause I
got to get these back to
momma and get her
some fabric did you
all find me some
Kevlar fabric yet?
Pete: Yes.
Michael: Yes there is some
out right over there.
Travis Taylor:
Hey lookie here.
Pete: The boys came up
with several things.
The first thing is
we got this UHMWPE
Ultra High Molecular
Weight Polyethylene.
Travis Taylor:
Oh, yeah, yeah.
Pete: So it's a lot
more dense it's got
a look more
aero density.
Travis Taylor: Yeah it's
the same polymer but
that stuff there has
like thousands of atoms
on the molecule chain and
this one has like
millions right?
Ultra high molecular
weight polyethylene
is a polymer made up
of very long chains
of polyethylene molecules.
The more molecules
on the chain,
the greater the
impact resistance.
This stuff has a
molecular weight 15 times
greater than
regular polyethylene
that makes it
incredibly tough.
Yeah this stuff should
stop a .22 cold just by itself.
While Momma sews the
Kevlar vest together
we cut our armor
plate pieces.
Michael and Rog and
I were hanging out in
the back of
the truck and
I looked at my bed
liner on the truck.
Look at this right here.
And that reminded me
that Line-X is one
of the strongest
materials that you can
put on a bed liner
of a truck and
you dump rocks
and all sorts of
stuff in there and
never bothers it.
What if we sprayed
that armor with Line-X?
Michael: Uh
they're tough.
Rog: Their tougher
on hobo stuff.
Michael: It would
sure make it rugged.
Travis Taylor: It
would make it rugged.
Michael: You wouldn't
never tear it,
or scratch it or it
would never come apart.
Travis Taylor: A lot
of folks take their
trucks to the Line-X
shop to have their
bed sprayed for
added protection.
Line-X is made of a
strong polyurethane plastic
and it's so tough,
the Pentagon building
is even got parts
sprayed with this
stuff to protect it
from bomb blasts.
I think a coat or
two would really help
with our
armor protection.
You know Momma is
about done with that
vest in there, I
am gonna go get it
and get it sprayed.
Rog: Shot gun.
Michael: Road trip.
Travis Taylor: No,
no, no you two get
back in there and
you all, you all stay
and work on that armor.
Michael: Let's go.
Travis Taylor: And the
helmet and all that.
I am gonna
take Pete over.
It's about time
that me and
Pete got to go
on a road trip.
We grabbed the vest
that Momma sewed all
the armor
plates into and
we took it over
to get it sprayed.
Safety glasses Pete.
Pete: I'm suprised he
has any buckets left.
Travis Taylor: Check
that out, look at that.
Pete: It get's pulled right
to those vents over there?
Travis Taylor:
Oh yeah, oh yeah,
that's beautiful man.
I think we're done.
As soon as it cools
off enough we can pick it up,
we'll pick it up and
we'll throw it in the truck.
We'll shoot
it, blow it up.
Now it's time
for our big test.
Will this lighter vest
hold up to combat
conditions as well as
the standard issue vest?
We had the guys meet
us at the gun range
along with a
buddy of ours.
And Daddy you got
your 9-millimeter
and what else?
Daddy: I got it.
Travis Taylor: Look
here, look here.
A buddy of ours, Soupy,
came up he's a vet;
he actually wore these
things over in Iraq.
I wanted you to take a
look at what we did and
maybe give us some
pointers on it and
tell us whatever,
this is our prototype
we are about
to blow it up,
shoot at it do whatever
we come up with.
But I wanted you to see
what you think about it.
Soupy: Man, I'll
tell you that,
that's a whole
lot lighter than
what we actually wore.
Travis Taylor: Yeah?
Soupy: Yes, sir.
The main thing is
the flexibility.
Travis Taylor: We're
gonna work on that a
little bit more too
but this is the basis
of what the
material would be.
So we wanted to use this
as the one we shoot.
Soupy: All right.
Travis Taylor:
Well Michael,
let's go throw this
thing on that dummy.
You all get
the guns ready.
Daddy: I'm ready.
Travis Taylor:
We in good shape,
move his arms down so
Pete can shoot them off.
Rog: He's got pretty
eyes don't he?
Travis Taylor: I'm scared
to look into them.
First Pete gave them
the same treatment
with his AK-47 that we
gave the standard vest.
Then it was Daddy's turn
with his 9 millimeter.
Daddy?
Daddy: Yes son?
Travis Taylor: I hate
to ask but do you
think you can hit
that thing from here
with your 9 millimeter?
Daddy: We'll
try it and see.
Travis Taylor: See
what you can do.
Daddy: All right, ready?
Going hot.
That's it.
Travis Taylor:
Well let's go look.
Rog: Yeah.
Travis Taylor: Well
it looks like you
shot right through
his hand right there.
Daddy: Yeah.
Travis Taylor: Look it
went in right there.
The question is
did it come on
out the other side?
I can get
right here and
I can see if he
got this one.
Try to feel the
bullet caught in;
right there I got
the bullet in my hand
it's caught
in the Kevlar.
The plates stopped
the bullets but there
is a serious
design flaw.
The bullets went
through the seams
between the
armor plates.
We got to
figure that out.
I say we raise
it up a notch.
Now we know that
the methods and
materials we used
on this first vest
can stop bullets,
which is great,
but can it
stop an IED?
I rigged us up an
IED this could be
loud so be prepared,
are we ready?
3, 2, 1.
[explosion]
Travis Taylor: We've been
creating lightweight
flexible body armor for
soldiers to use in combat.
We already proved
that our armored
vest stops bullets.
Now we are
gonna see if it can
stand up to explosives.
This could be loud
so be prepared.
Pete: All right.
Travis Taylor: Let's
see how we do against
an IED, are we ready?
3, 2, 1.
[explosion]
Pete: Whoo!
Michael: What happened?
Travis Taylor: Just
look at this thing.
Michael: Let's
go check him out.
Daddy: Man, there is
his poor old leg.
I'll tell you, doin' a
test like this makes you
think about what our
soldiers have to deal with.
Travis Taylor: Look
at this it didn't
bother him up here.
Michael: No.
Travis Taylor: Didn't
bother him at all up here.
Soupy: But that proves
that you know we still
need something on
the lower torso.
Travis Taylor: Yeah
that's right man.
Soupy: I mean you can
see what an IED does.
Travis Taylor:
Yeah it blows,
that's why we have
so many guys with
their legs blown
off right now.
Soupy: Exactly.
Travis Taylor: We got
to make some armor that
will do just
that for the legs.
This test was a success;
we made a bullet proof,
bombproof vest that's
less than half the weight
of the standard vest.
The challenge here is
to find a way to protect
the limbs while
maintaining flexibility
and mobility
in a full suit.
We need to get back
to the garage and
make this thing
so it will protect
not just the torso,
but also the legs.
Poor old mannequin.
So I went and recruited
my mom some help.
I got some my
students from some my
classes over at the
local university to
come over and
help her out.
Look at this
right here,
there's a
bullet in there.
Mama: Oh wow.
Travis Taylor: It
caught it just fine
and it worked well.
The interesting thing
that we learned though
mom is look here,
these bullets came
out in a straight line
and that there is
where the seam is.
Mama: That's where
the seams are.
Travis Taylor: So we are
gonna have to figure out
a way to overlap
that armor in there
so that they wont
come out on the seams.
Maybe where they
overlap more like
fish scale or lizard
scales or something.
Hey, hey, look here!
Rog: Whatcha got?
Travis Taylor: Well I have
been talking with mom and
been thinking about how
we wore this we are gonna
have to do these pieces
smaller and Line-X the
individual pieces and then
put them on the inside of
the armor in order
for it to be where
I can move around in it.
That's gonna be the key
in stopping fragments
and bullets and
making it more mobile.
Let's work on that.
The suit is one thing,
but what about
head protection?
The American military
has been making helmets
for a hundred years,
but we want to make one
with full-face protection.
We used the design of
a motorcycle helmet to
protect more
of the face.
We added some foam pieces
to make up the basic
structure and then
covered it all in Kevlar.
And then we held it all
together with fiberglass.
Michael: I am gonna
wash my hands so they
don't like smell
like these nasty gloves.
Smell my fingers, Rog.
Rog: Nope, nope.
Travis Taylor: We
got plenty more to do
lets get on the next one.
Pete: Heard that.
Travis Taylor: Things
are moving along.
Momma and her student
helpers Chris and
Katie spent all
day cutting and
sewing on that
yellow Kevlar fabric.
Mama: And that will
make, easy to make
strips of pockets and
then we do another layer
and come back over here.
Travis Taylor: Then
they sewed them into
pocket packs that fit
perfectly in the vest.
I decided that we needed
to add armor plates
to the outside
of the legs and
arms just like a
catcher's shin guard.
That's gonna have
to be tightened up.
So these, I need
to put a strap on it
for me Michael.
Just maybe uh cut 'em,
drill out a slot.
Michael: Use a
Velcro strap yeah.
Travis Taylor: Yeah ok.
This time around we
only sprayed the
armor plates
with the Line-X
to make the whole
suit more flexible.
Mama: The last
step is cover all
that itchy Kevlar
with cotton fabric.
I hope Travis likes orange
cause that's all I got.
Travis Taylor: We've
got to finish these
exterior armor plates,
which means dinner
in the garage again.
Tomorrow we do a full
mobility test on the suit.
Everybody worked
really hard.
Mom and students worked
their butts off;
we worked really
hard cutting all the
plates up getting
everything all together.
Here's the suit.
Rog: Tear it up, Mule.
Travis Taylor:
All this is Kevlar.
The inner shirt and
the vest with the
armor plates in it,
it's ready to go;
total weight, 39 lbs.
Rog: That thing looks
like bulky as hell.
He ain't gonna be
able to even move in
that thing much
less run across
a battlefield
getting shot at.
Travis Taylor: This
thing might look kind
of goofy in
prototype stage,
but the concept is
what's important.
It's got to save lives.
So I decided the
best place to test a
military armor suit was
the local playground.
Man, I believe its
getting warm up in here.
Michael: Yeah,
it's getting hot.
Travis Taylor: A
kid's playground is a
great place for
a mobility test.
It's got a
challenging terrain,
sand and lots of
obstacles to get through.
Michael: Really,
a playground?
Uncle Travis
doesn't know it yet,
but after this I'm
gonna set him with
something a little
more challenging.
Daddy: This playground
test is simple.
Can Travis move
enough in this thing
to get through every
obstacle without stopping?
On 3, you ready?
Travis Taylor: Mm-hmm.
Daddy: 3, 2, 1.
Travis Taylor: Wait a
minute you just said 3.
Rog: You should have went.
Michel: Go.
Rog: Watch them kids.
Daddy: It was just like
the pied piper every kid
on that playground
got right behind him and
tried to emulate
what he was doing,
it was funny.
Rog: Stay with it, Mule.
Travis Taylor: Turns
out it's not so easy
to do monkey bars
in an armor suit.
Pete: Come on, technique.
Travis: [sighs].
Rog: How bad
is it, Mule?
Travis Taylor: That
was a lot harder than
I thought but this
proves the suit works
and it's flexible
enough to tackle
anything on
this playground.
And uh Michael must have
thought that was silly.
Michael: How are
we gonna test anything
to military specs
on a playground?
You know if he was
running through this
and being chased by
a bunch of 7 year old
kids that's not
gonna get it;
that shows you right there
that is not gonna get it.
So I call in my
buddy Bodette who
is a retired Marine.
He is gonna put
Uncle Travis through
a real training course.
Travis Taylor: He
walks like a Marine.
Michael: Yeah he does.
Bodette: Hey uh,
explain something to
me real quick you
really think that
playing on
a little kiddie
playground is gonna
simulate you in anyway
shape or form in any type
of combat situation?
Travis Taylor: Uh.
Bodette: Absolutely not,
it ain't gonna happen!
The playground was stupid.
Well I got news for you
if you cannot shoot,
move and communicate
wearing that it's
absolutely
useless to me.
I got a real
test for you.
Michael: Its funny
to me to get ready to
see what old Bodette is
gonna put him through.
Travis Taylor: We're
making a lightweight armor suit
and a retired Marine
Corps Drill Instructor
is gonna put me
through the ringer.
Bodette: What we are gonna
do here today gentlemen,
is I am gonna put
Travis through a
civilian version of
a combat fitness test.
It's simulating him
being able to overcome
obstacles in a
combat situation
while wearing his gear.
Daddy: I am thinking
now this is gonna be
tough on Travis you know.
Bodette: I need you
Michael to go over there
and put that flight
jacket on and lay down.
Michael: All right.
Bodette: You're gonna
be a wounded warrior.
Michael: All right.
Bodette: You go
do that right now we
are getting
ready to start.
Any type of protective
gear that you wear
you cannot really
give up mobility.
If you can't shoot, move
and communicate with the
body armor then it's
absolutely useless.
Are you ready?
Travis Taylor: Ready
as I'll ever be.
Bodette: Go!
Pete: Come on, Travis.
Bodette: All right,
Travis, drop right now.
Drop right now and
right now give me
5 push ups hurry up!
1, 2!
Travis Taylor: When
Bodette said go,
I thought I was just
simply running over to
a log to cross it but
somewhere in the middle
he stopped me and had me
do a bunch of push ups.
Bodette: 5.
Get up, hurry up,
hurry, get up.
Rog: Get up, mule!
Bodette: Hurry up,
come on we ain't got
all day now hurry up.
Rog: This sucks.
I am glad I ain't
doing that crap.
Bodette: Go, go, go!
Rog: Go mule!
Michel: Look at him go.
Travis Taylor: By then
I was getting winded
and then we come
to these wires that
I had to balance across.
Bodette: You ain't
have all day;
people are shooting
at you right now.
People are depending on
you, you got to move,
you got to move,
you ain't got time.
Keep going, keep going!
Your buddies need
you right now.
They're depending
on you right now!
You need to
hurry up, go!
That's it.
Rog: Arch your back.
Bodette: Grab that rope.
I ain't grabbing
it for ya!
Rog: He ain't never
gonna make it.
Bodette: Grab it.
That's right, that's
right good job.
Rog: Stay with it mule.
Bodette: Come
on hurry up,
you got people
shooting at you.
You ain't got time to
be tired right now.
Go ahead and grab
that log right there,
press it above
your head 5 times.
Travis Taylor: Then I
had to pick up a log,
I wasn't expecting that.
Bodette: 1, keep
going, 2, 3.
Pete: Yeah!
Bodette: 4, 5, good job,
put 'em down now
go over there.
Get over there and
run over there.
Now let's go Travis,
you are gonna jump
over all these tables.
Travis Taylor: Ahh!
Bodette: Jump over 'em.
Travis Taylor: I had to go
and jump over these tables
and I was getting really
winded at that point.
Bodette: There's gonna
be a lot of obstacles
in combat you are gonna
have a lot of gear on you,
people are
depending on you.
You can do this.
That's right.
Keep going, keep going.
Rog: Go, mule.
Bodette: Keep going.
Go over here, here just
go right over here,
crawl underneath this
thing low crawl.
You got to be low,
you got to be fast.
You got a low crawl
Daddy: And I figured
well he'll get that
suit all tangled up in
it we'll be out there
cutting him out of it.
Bodette: Right about now
you got machine gunfire
breaking over your
body right now you
got to be low.
You got to hurry
up and get there.
Rog: Go mule.
Bodette: Fire, go get it.
Pete: Stay low, brother.
Bodette: We
ain't got time;
you ain't got
time to be tired.
Rog: Stay with it, mule.
Bodette: Let's go,
hurry up, let's go,
hurry up get on up out
of there right now!
Hurry up, get
up and hurry up!
Get on those
tires right now!
Daddy: But he made it
through that thing.
Bodette: This
ain't nothin'.
This ain't nothin'
your buddies need you.
Pete: Come on buddy.
Bodette: Your buddies
need you right now.
Yup, just like that,
just like that.
Travis Taylor: And then
run through a bunch of
tires that was the
hardest part the tires
cause I was
already dead.
Rog: Oh, man.
Bodette: Just like
that, just like that,
just like that.
Let's go!
That's all right.
Let's go, let's go!
Right now people are
shooting at you.
You got buddy he is
laying down right over
he's got a 762
round right in
his chest let's go.
Hurry up, go
pick him up!
This ain't nothin,
this ain't nothin'.
Rog: Stay with it.
Travis Taylor: Then
at the end of all that
he's got Michael
laying over there as
a wounded warrior
and I had to
drag him probably
20 or 30 feet.
Bodette: Let's go!
Rog: Get him, mule.
Pull him, mule!
Bodette: Little
bit farther,
little bit farther,
little bit
farther, hurry up!
Rog: Bring him on home.
Bodette: There you
go, there you go!
All right, you're done.
Good job.
Rog: Come on, bubba.
Bodette: Good job.
Pete: All right,
man, all right.
Rog: Good job, bubba.
You need some air.
Put them arms up,
get them arms up.
Travis Taylor: And
at that point I was
just ready to throw up.
Michael: Uncle Travis
did pretty good that
was a tough
obstacle course and
Bodette didn't take
it easy on him.
Travis Taylor:
Take my helmet off.
Pete: Take
your helmet off?
Bodette: Let me
tell you something.
That was a great job.
One of the things that,
that either makes you or
breaks you in combat isn't
always your gear its your
intestinal fortitude
and that's exactly
what you had
right there.
That's exactly
what you showed me.
Travis Taylor: One of
the things I learned
a lot was uh was
something about myself.
That I believe I could
push through some things
that I didn't think
I could before and,
and had it not been
for Bill Bodette
I probably wouldn't
have done that.
Travis Taylor:
You know what?
I believe with a little
bit of training I could
run a marathon
in this thing.
So I did run a
marathon in this suit.
26.2 miles in a
40-pound suit;
it took me over 6 hours.
Like I said, I'm
a science geek from
North Alabama
and I did this.
Thank you very much, man.
Marine: Congratulations.
Travis Taylor: Think
what a young strappin'
marine could do.