-In the last while, it's
actually calmed
down quite a bit.
I haven't heard of that many
kidnappings lately.
You know, usually it
was like, boom.
Every other day,
oh my goodness.
There was another kidnapping,
you know?
The Joneses got kidnapped,
Romney got
kidnapped, or you know--
just someone you affiliated
with.
-Now, it's hard to picture a
place that's so fucked up that
not that many kidnappings
is a sign that
things are going well.
But in northern Mexico,
everything is relative.
The sobering reality of it is,
in Mexico in 2011 there were
49 kidnappings a day.
-Things have actually kind of
calmed down enough to where
they actually have parties
and rodeos and whatnot.
-So they're having this rodeo
because a dude lost his leg?
-Yeah, one of the cowboys lost
his leg and they're doing a
benefit for him.
-Right.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
-One of the things that we were
worried about before we
came here was people knowing
that we were here.
People knowing that
we were shooting.
And now we're in front
of the whole town.
-There you go.
-In a town where they used
to have three or four
kidnappings a week.
And we're just parading in
front of everyone with a
camera going, turn the music
off, [INAUDIBLE].
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
-They've just announced
to the whole town
that we're here shooting.
In the most dangerous
town in Chihuahua.
I'm just going to get drunk.
-Woo!
Put that on.
SHANE (NARRATING): Now, hanging
out with the LeBarons
and playacting as a cowpoke
relaxed us a little bit.
As did the booze.
-I'd like to say cheers to the
LeBaron family because you
guys fucking rock.
-To the LeBaron family.
-LeBaron Family.
-Good times, good friends.
-Salud.
-Cheers, cheers,
cheers, cheers.
[HOWLING LIKE WOLVES]
[SINGING IN SPANISH]
SHANE (NARRATING): We had a nice
lunch, got a bit drunk,
and sang some songs together.
It was fun.
[SINGING IN SPANISH]
SHANE (NARRATING): After
drinking for a bit with Brent,
he suggested we go on a
ride-along on the nightly
patrol of the LeBaron colony.
Now, I was picturing a pickup
truck with a CB and a couple
of good old boys in the back.
But we got instead was some
heavy, heavy business.
SHANE (OFFSCREEN): What are
we doing right now?
-So we're just going to take on
a routine route that they
normally take.
And then they'll probably do
a security checkpoint for a
little while and maybe
check some
suspicious vehicles or something.
These guys use our town as
a base because they trust
everyone here.
-One of things that's pretty
crazy is you're driving
through with pickup trucks with
four armed guards in the
back and two guys in the front,
all with machine guns,
for a town of 1,200 people.
So shit is serious.
SHANE (NARRATING):
So the federales
kept stopping people.
And they didn't seem to mind
us riding along with them
until they roadblocked the
actual highway, which,
remember, is one of the main
drug routes into America.
-The cops are going to
stop some cars and
look for some drugs.
Then as the sun was going down,
they warned us that we
should leave because it was
very dangerous to even
be seen with them.
Because as it turned out, riding
around with them on the
back roads is one thing.
But stopping actual
drug runners on
the highway was another.
SHANE (OFFSCREEN): Want a beer?
-Yeah.
SHANE (NARRATING): Back at the
hotel, we realized that our
fun, boozy afternoon had some
unforeseen consequences.
About an hour ago, a black
pickup sort of drove by really
slowly and then kind
of sped off.
SHANE (NARRATING): Black trucks
like the ones Julian
had pointed out earlier had
actually stopped, taken
pictures, and checked us out.
And all a sudden, our LeBaron
run around town drunk time
didn't seem so smart anymore.
-All right.
So we have to leave now because
we shot today at the
rodeo and then we did a drive-by
with the cops, so
everybody in town knows
that we're here.
And then we've just have a black
truck with black windows
stop, pull up, check us out,
and then drive off.
And a black truck, I just found
out, came by and took
pictures of us before
I got here.
So we have to go to another
hotel that we've arranged,
which is crazy.
SHANE (NARRATING):
So we took off.
And when we called Brent to tell
him we had left, I half
expected him to say hey,
you're overreacting.
It's nothing.
But in actual fact,
when he heard the
story, he said, oh yeah.
You should get the fuck
out of Dodge.
-Who do you think should be
the next president of the
United States?
-Mitt Romney has a great,
great policy.
His family lives right across
the mountain here.
SHANE (NARRATING): Now, when
Brent says "his family," he
means presidential candidate
Mitt Romney's family.
-Mitt is a relative.
He's a second cousin.
I wish Mitt would make contact
with us, and I really think
that we could help him.