his newborn son home.
So to kill time, we decided to
explore one of our favorite
Atlanta urban legends.
We went to meet the guy
responsible for the face
tattoo which catapulted Gucci
Mane to viral fame.
So Shane, what happened
that day?
SHANE WILLOUGHBY: He had quite
a few tattoos on his face.
And he felt that some of the
ones around his eyes made him
look like he had a black eye.
And he wanted a tattoo that
took away from those.
I was like, I couldn't
really suggest
anything for your face.
He was like, well,
what about this?
And he unzipped his hoodie, and
he had the largest piece
of jewelry I've ever seen.
This large ice cream cone
medallion that was just
covered in diamonds.
And I was like, OK.
I think I could put something
together.
Here's the stencil right here.
CHARLET DUBOC: [GASP]
Oh my god.
SHANE WILLOUGHBY: One day I'll
get around to framing it.
CHARLET DUBOC: Let me imagine.
No way!
SHANE WILLOUGHBY: He said, I
want it to be rock and roll.
And so that's where the
lightning bolts came from.
CHARLET DUBOC: And
with the Brrr.
SHANE WILLOUGHBY: That
was kind of funny.
I see a lot of people stating
how I misspelled that.
And it's kind of funny.
CHARLET DUBOC: It's
not a word.
SHANE WILLOUGHBY: Yeah.
It's a sound.
CHARLET DUBOC: What happened
at work the next day?
SHANE WILLOUGHBY: The phone
ringing off the hook.
Hip hop radio stations
calling.
After misquotes got out, I
no longer really wanted
to talk about it.
CHARLET DUBOC: What about the
actual tattooing process?
Was he a hard man or was
he a bit of a pussy?
SHANE WILLOUGHBY: It's almost
like he was asleep.
CHARLET DUBOC: Really.
SHANE WILLOUGHBY: Yeah, he
didn't move, didn't make a
sound, unless we were talking.
CHARLET DUBOC: Have you found
that there have been more
rappers getting tattoos?
Is it a lot more popular?
SHANE WILLOUGHBY: Oh, yes.
It's gone from rappers having
the little forearm tattoos to
being fully covered.
Tattooing in Atlanta, no matter
where you tattoo-- if
you tattoo in Atlanta, you're
an urban tattooer.
CHARLET DUBOC: What's been your
weirdest tattoo request
in your career?
SHANE WILLOUGHBY: A penis on a
lady in her 50s, lower back.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHARLET DUBOC: And with that
charming image in mind, we
said goodbye to Shane and
went to meet Billy.
We've come out to the
suburbs of Atlanta.
This is where Billy lives.
He's invited us to his house,
which is really nice
considering the circumstances.
He's got a 48-hour-old
baby in there.
He's invited us to come and
see where he works from.
And then I think the plan is
that we're going to the local
car dealership to maybe
buy a Range Rover.
BILLY BAD ASS: Hello.
Hey.
What's happening?
CHARLET DUBOC: I don't want
to wake the baby.
BILLY BAD ASS: Come on in.
Come on.
My war room-- this
is my war room.
My treadmill.
CHARLET DUBOC: Your war room?
BILLY BAD ASS: Yeah.
I put my information
of my events--
what city I'm going to.
Information I need,
like locations.
They gave me an award.
I'm a pioneer in urban fashion,
and they felt like
they needed to give me something
for my outstanding
achievement.
CHARLET DUBOC: You're
a fashion pioneer?
BILLY BAD ASS: Yes.
CHARLET DUBOC: Despite the
disorganized appearance of the
war room, Billy was keen to
share some of his theories on
achieving success.
What was the book you were
telling me about yesterday?
"Who Moved the Cheese?"
BILLY BAD ASS: "Who Moved
the Cheese?" This
was about two rats.
They call them Hem and Haw
and Skip and Scurry.
They had a maze--
it was a maze.
Hem and Haw went in first
and went around.
And they didn't see any cheese,
so they came back out.
Well, Skip and Scurry went
in and kept going.
And they looked, and they
didn't see nothing.
They kept going all the way.
And then they found cheese.
So Hem and Haw was like,
they in there.
They must have found
some cheese.
So they went and found
the cheese where
Skip and Scurry was.
And after a while, the
cheese ran out.
There was no more cheese.
So what Skip and Scurry did--
they went further in and
looked for more cheese.
And it took them
a little while.
They kept going.
They found more cheese.
But the moral of the story was
that the cheese might run out.
So what do you do?
Are you going to sit around and
wait for more cheese in
the same area, or are you going
to find another solution
to solving a problem?
HAW: What will happen if the
cheese isn't here tomorrow?
I've made plans based
on this cheese!
CHARLET DUBOC: It was clear that
Billy had every intention
of chasing the cheese.
Maybe that was part of the
reason behind taking his Urban
Fashion Week on the road--
to find some exotic
foreign cheese.
Some Stilton, perhaps.
However, in my experience,
putting on a fashion week
takes some work.
And I'd yet to see examples of
the clothes, designers, and
crew that are usually a
requirement for such an event.
Billy assured me that this
was all in hand.
But first there were more
pressing issues
to take care of.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHARLET DUBOC: So where
are we going?
BILLY BAD ASS: We're going
to a dealership.
I've been looking at some
cars I want to get.
CHARLET DUBOC: And what
car do you want?
BILLY BAD ASS: I want
a Range Rover.
CHARLET DUBOC: Cool.
BILLY BAD ASS: Isn't that
an English car?
CHARLET DUBOC: Yeah.
People who drive Range Rovers
really are like wealthy white
women with kids.
BILLY BAD ASS: [LAUGHS]
CHARLET DUBOC: It's
funny, right?
BILLY BAD ASS: That's
hilarious.
Yeah, the guy that we need to
meet is not there right now.
So we're going to come back.
I don't know if you remember
Holyfield, the boxer?
Well, he's being sued.
The car that I'm getting ready
to buy was his car.
He's a celebrity.
I'd like to have the car.
It just reminds me of how
he was at his prime.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHARLET DUBOC: Listening to
Billy talk of his aspirations
to buy the repossessed car of
a broke boxer didn't seem to
fit with the cheese-chasing
philosophy.
So little time and London
creeping ever closer.
However, Billy was unfazed, and
wanted to take us to one
of Atlanta's high end urban
fashion boutiques, as he said
it would give us an idea of what
we could expect to see on
the catwalk at London
Urban Fashion Week.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
BILLY BAD ASS: How you doing?
-What's up?
BILLY BAD ASS: All right.
I've just told them
about your store.
You do a lot of celebrities in
the market, so I just want to
make sure I give
you some love.
-No problem.
Definitely.
Welcome to Moda404.
BILLY BAD ASS: What are the
price points on those up
there?
-$695 for these.
BILLY BAD ASS: Those are like
boss glasses right there.
When you wear those, you
know you a boss.
What are the price
point on these?
-This pair is actually
$595, I believe.
BILLY BAD ASS: What's the price
point on something like
that?
-This one here is $425.
BILLY BAD ASS: I just met this
gentleman named Quincy.
He's got a lot of core urban
luxury, and I do
Urban Fashion Week.
This was a great fit.
-Urban luxury, to me,
is basically--
the hip hop community, once
they make it to a certain
level, then they feel
like they have to
dress a certain way.
But you do have those guys that
just don't break code.
They still going to
wear T-shirts.
They going to jump out of
Maserati wearing T-shirts.
They're going to wear Levi's.
But they still going to have
$400,000 worth of jewelry on.
It's urban luxury--
what we consider luxury
in the hood.
BILLY BAD ASS: Well, listen.
How many shirts you
going to give me?
-When people use the term
"urban," to be quite honest
with you, I take
offense to it.
It's such a stereotype as far as
fashion, because fashion to
me is worldwide.
CHARLET DUBOC: Is there
anything that's become
fashionable in the Atlanta
hip hop community that
you think, oh god.
You don't really like.
-When guys wear their suits with
the tag on the sleeve.
And then the butt implants
on the ladies' side.
Atlanta is really notorious
for their strip club.
And also--
yeah.
It's definitely a show
when you go out.
CHARLET DUBOC: Atlanta strip
clubs are heavily referenced
in countless hip hop songs, to
the extent that stripping has
become a covetable
career choice for
young women of Atlanta.
Something to aspire to rather
than a last resort, which is
so often the case elsewhere
in the world.
-[RAPPING - FUTURE, "MAGIC"]
CHARLET DUBOC: We headed to the
Vatican of strip clubs--
Magic City--
to talk to some of the
girls about pussy
popping on the handstand.
Oh, and fashion.
PASSION: My name is Passion.
I just graduated from Alabama
State University.
This magnitude of this
place helped me fund
my way through school.
This one individual can make
thousands of dollars just by
taking off her clothes
and nothing else.
She doesn't have to be smart.
All she has to do is bend over
and shake her ass for money.
That's freaking crazy.
CHARLET DUBOC: Stripping
is cool in Atlanta.
How did that happen?
PASSION: Big Meech, from
Detroit, well, he came in the
clubs and he started this
make it rain era.
Rain falling from the ceiling.
And it just looked like it's
just trickling down.
CHARLET DUBOC: You mean money?
PASSION: Money, yes!
Money just coming down.
And he made stripping cool.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHARLET DUBOC: Hip hop
and strip clubs
feed off each other.
-It's the inspiration
both ways.
We inspirate them, I believe, as
far as what they rap about.
Strippers poles, money,
and all that.
And then we feed off of--
because they come in here and
play their song.
They throw the money.
They actually do what their
song is talking about.
So we enjoy each other.
So it's back and forth.
Motivation.
-We still get rappers that
talk about Magic City, of
course, in all of their songs.
CHARLET DUBOC: Is the whole
style and expression of
stripping filtering down
into Atlanta fashion?
PASSION: This club is the most
flashiest club you're ever
going to see.
The first time I saw these
feathers and these glitter,
glitzy bras and things
were inside here.
And now I see women outside
of here wearing it, too.
So, yeah.
They are trying to imitate us.
Maybe because they're
trying to keep their
men a little longer.