DAVID: Day six, America.
We are dangerously close
to the Canadian border.
I don't know, fucking almost
a week into the trip.
Tensions are running high.
I got a lot of unresolved
issues with Harry.
I'm pretty fucking tired,
arguing, whatever.
I don't know.
We're in Eugene, Oregon.
And we walked into
a restaurant.
And I'm not pointing fingers
or anything.
But it was, like,
a crab house.
And we really wanted crab.
This fucking asshole's a
vegetarian now because he saw
Meet Your Meat.
So he doesn't eat, you
know, whatever.
And the whole restaurant
had maybe three
people eating at it.
And they said, sorry,
no seats available.
So I'm not saying
they're racist.
But what the fuck?
I mean, how do you say that to
someone when there's a whole
empty restaurant?
We got a really bad
vibe, so we left.
People don't realize this.
But you know, sometimes
when you go north,
shit gets pretty crazy.
People always equate shit
with the south,
like Texas and shit.
But you know, the north
is pretty bad, too.
Anyways, thumbs up, America.
Fucking Harry, I can't even talk
to this guy right now.
I'll see you soon.
I'll catch up.
You be good, America.
I love you.
I want to be gang-raped
by a big, mean drunk.
Fuck my throat hard deep like
a cunt with a fat, nigger
horse cock.
Wow.
We had no luck on this train.
There was no open boxcars.
But beggars can't be choosers.
We hopped on the
Santa Fe line.
Notorious says one
of the biggest
ball-busting train lines.
They like to arrest hobos,
and throw them off, and
throw them in jail.
Here we go.
Slow build.
Sometimes you got
to work it up.
I got to fact-check my shit.
But all these lines, all these
railroads, they weren't
getting done on time.
Like, they weren't making
the kind of progress
that they'd like to.
So someone was like,
hey, why don't we
hire a bunch of chinks?
They made that, what
do you call it?
That Great Wall of China.
They could probably work hard.
And using Chinese methods, I
guess they did all kinds of
dangerous shit, like upside
down off mountains and
blasting with dynamite
and shit.
But they made all these
train lines.
And now we're riding them,
riding the rails.
We're riding this this fucking
giant metal dragon.
Climb to the top.
See it slither this
way and that.
[DRUMMING SOUNDS]
[DRUM MUSIC PLAYING]
DAVID: So we just jumped
off this train.
I don't know if we're
in fucking
Washington, Oregon, Canada.
All I know is there's a bunch
of these little fuckers
getting down, fucking, on
cowbells and drums trying to
make me look bad.
But whatever, it's rad.
The beat is strong
in their hearts.
The force is strong.
[DRUMS PLAYING]
DAVID: Thumbs up, America.
Day seven.
We're really close to
our next country.
We're in Seattle.
I thought it would smell
like Teen Spirit.
But it smells more like
fucking Starbucks.
I guess because we're standing
next to the Starbucks
headquarters right there.
The Canadian border is
just ahead of us.
And we got fireworks, drugs,
ninja stars, swords, guns, all
kinds of orange plastic
dildos.
I don't know how we're
going to get through.
We'll find out.
$0.75, $0.85, $0.95--
fucking $0.99 in US change,
priceless souvenirs.
Oh my God, dude.
That one got fucking grinded
into the track.
Oh, shit.
[LAUGHTER]
DAVID: Fucking awesome.
HARRY: Hot as hell.
DAVID: Let's try to
fucking buy a taco
with that, soft shell.
What's up, America?
We're by the train tracks with
our friend, Luis Flores.
Luis wants to tell us a story
about his Salvadorian fellow
and his encounter
with the trains.
What happened?
LUIS: This guy, he told me if
I want to go to Canada with
him, I would have to
jump on the train.
But I tell him no.
And then he got a couple
more guys.
And they got drunk.
And then they came to
wait for the train.
It slow down.
And they did try to
jump in the train.
And then this guy fell.
And then his leg got between the
railroad and chop it off.
DAVID: It cut his leg off?
LUIS: Yeah, right
from the knee.
DAVID: Don't fucking drink
and hop trains.
LUIS: If you cross the line,
you just got to immigration
and tell them, hey, I
got nothing to eat.
And they help you
with apartment.
And then they--
DAVID: Let's go.
LUIS: Wait.
DAVID: Luis!
LUIS: Let me fixing
[INAUDIBLE].
DAVID: The train's
right here, man.
Let's go.
LUIS: No, that train is
too dangerous, man.
DAVID: No, man.
Let's drink and let's go.
LUIS: Oh, no.
DAVID: Come on, man.
Our train's calling.
Let's go.
[TRAIN WHISTLE]
LUIS: I need to fix my car.
DAVID: [SPANISH].
Let's go.
LUIS: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
DAVID: [SPANISH].
Let's go.
[LAUGHS].
Hey, kids.
Just because you see me and
Harry riding the hotshots
doesn't mean you should
ride them, too.
Each one of those crates has
about $100,000 to half a
million dollars worth of
merchandise in there.
And grainers and boxcars
is one story.
They go about 40
miles an hour.
The hotshots go up to 70
to 80 miles an hour.
And those are the ones that the
train cops and the cops
will really, really fuck with
you and actually throw you in
jail if you get caught
riding those.
They have all the merchandise.
So just because you see us
do it doesn't mean you
should do it.l it.
We're fucking professionals,
you're not.
Thumbs up, America.
[MUSIC--"STAR SPANGLED BANNER]
DAVID: Right now I'm standing
in front of the fucking
Canadian flag and the beautiful
American flag.
We are right on the border.
And because of some
indiscretions when I was a
fucking kid, this is exactly
what the guy told me last time
I was going into Canada.
I said, dude.
And he embarrassed me
in front of all the
people I worked with.
I said, hey, man.
He said, Mr. Choe, we're waiting
for you at customs.
And I said, oh, customs?
What's going on there?
He said, nothing happen to
you, like, 15 years ago?
And was like, 15 years ago
I was a fucking kid.
And I go, yeah, I got caught
doing some shit.
And then some graffiti,
some shoplifting,
just normal kid shit.
And I told them, look, when I
turn into an adult, you know,
that stuff gets erased.
Maybe in America, but
not in Canada.
So Canada has a long memory.
They didn't forget
about my shit.
So here I am trying to have fun,
trying to do a fun and
excellent adventure with
my buddy, Harry.
And you know, here we are
in the same situation.
America gets attacked by
terrorists a few years ago.
And all a sudden, Canada becomes
so fucking secure.
Like, who gives a shit?
You think anyone cares
about you enough to
fucking attack you?
No one gives the
fuck about you.
What the fuck have you
contributed to society?
The only thing you're passionate
about is hockey.
That's it.
And no one gives a fuck
about hockey.
See the flag right here?
There, you get one of these.
See this one right here?
You get one of those.
Stupid motherfuckers!
All you have are cheese curds.
No one gives a fuck about
cheese curds!
No one gives a fuck
about hockey!
Fuck!
So anyways, if you can't tell,
I'm extremely upset right now.
HARRY: Because Canada is
in the way of Alaska.
DAVID: Me and Harry just tried
to walk across the border in
the forested area.
And flood lights flashed on,
border patrol showed up.
What the fuck?
I mean, it was easier getting
out of Mexico.
And Mexico was almost
impossible.
And they confiscated
our tapes.
You'll never get to see the
high-speed Canadian chase.
And here we are in fucking
US mini mart with
our dick in our hands.
So I know this is supposed to be
"Thumbs Up, Alaska." And I
promised you guys we'd have an
amazing Alaskan adventure, I'd
find crazy shit in Alaska.
But this looks like it's
the end of our trip.
I mean, what else is there?
[SINGING]
Oh, fuck Canada.
Fuck Canada.
You're just jealous and
insecure, 'cause you wish you
were America.
But you're just red maple leaf,
patch-wearing, faggots.
Fuck Canada.
Don't take it personal,
Canada.
America's bigger assholes
than you guys are.
Day eight.
We've come full--
[GAGGING]
[SPITS].
We've come full circle.
It's Monday.
What a rough night.
I think at this time, I'd like
to issue a formal apology to
the wonderful people
of Canada.
Yesterday I was turned away
from the Canadian border
because of something
I did as a youth.
And I got angry.
And I'm a grown man.
I should take full
responsibility for my actions.
Canada has a long memory,
longer than
the American people.
I'm welcome here.
No judgment, no bitterness,
no sarcasm.
I was turned away which really
set me off, really upset me.
And I probably said some things
last night that I
shouldn't have said.
All you have are cheese curds!
No one gives a fuck about
cheese curds!
No one gives a fuck
about hockey!
I'm sorry.
I probably came off
really ignorant
and hateful and angry.
And that's not me.
I'm not really that
kind of person.
I'm moody sometimes.
But I take pills for
that kind of stuff.
And it puts a major roadblock
in our trip.
I mean, Alaska's a
long way away.
We're down to either hiding in
the trunk of someone's car,
which I've had a tough time
convincing people to do.
The tanner and darker he gets,
the more Osama-ish
he starts to look.
So people become distrustful.
So it's down to sneaking on a
boat, ferry, or hopping a
train and risking maybe our
legs getting cut off like
Luis's friend yesterday.
So we're down to trains
and boats.
You get sea sick?
How are your sea legs?
HARRY: They're fine.
DAVID: All right.
[AIRPLANE SOUNDS]
DAVID: Is that a plane?
HARRY: Yeah.
DAVID: Looks like we've
got some competition.
You guys hitching?
How long you guys been
out here for?
DAVID: You guys hitching
up to Canada?
DAVID: Oh, really?
Hi.
HARRY: Hi, how you doing?
DAVID: How's it going?
Hi, how's it going?
BERNADETTE: [INAUDIBLE].
DAVID: What's going on?
DAVID: Rummi?
DAVID: Lummi?
Oh,
DAVID: You guys Indian?
BERNADETTE: Yes.
DAVID: Which tribe?
BERNADETTE: He's Alaskan.
And I'm Canadian.
DAVID: Wait, you're
from Alaska?
BERNADETTE: [LAUGHS].
DAVID: Well, that's where
we're trying to
get to right now.
Because of my juvenile
record, I'm not
allowed back into Canada.
I don't know how easy
it is to sneak in.
We'll help you out.
What about Alaska?
You don't want to go
back to Alaska?
DAVID: In Alaska?
DAVID: All right.
Well, what do you think, I mean,
is there anything ideal
up in Alaska?
I've never been there before?
BERNADETTE: [LAUGHS].
DAVID: Like what?
What's amazing?
DAVID: Like a Husky?
DAVID: Right.
Doing what?
How much longer you guys
going to be out here?
DAVID: North?
If you guys don't get a ride,
what's going to happen?
Where have you guys
been sleeping?
BERNADETTE: Right there.
DAVID: Right there?
All right, you guys seem
like you guys need a
ride more than us.
So we'll let you take the
prime hitching spot.
But nice meeting you.
JERRY: Nice meeting you.
DAVID: Good luck, guys.
Well, that was our competition
for hitchhiking.
But they look like they're a
little down on their luck.
I don't want to fuck
with that.
If we get a ride up here,
we'll have them pick up.
There's, like, a little
airport I saw up here.
We're lost.
We can't find the boat yards.
There's all these helicopters
and planes everywhere.
Taildraggers Restaurant &
Lounge, some guy said this is
where a bunch of pilots,
maverick Goose men, guys like
that hang out here.
You want to get something
to drink.
HARRY: Yeah.
Sounds good.
DAVID: All right.
We're here with Grant.
Grant is a cook over here
at Taildraggers.
And who eats here mostly?
GRANT: Mostly pilots.
DAVID: Pilots and stuff?
And what kind of breed
are pilots?
Like, what kind of people
are they, usually?
GRANT: Most of them are
actually older guys.
DAVID: They're older guys?
GRANT: Yeah, blackjack pilots,
they're formation pilots.
DAVID: Are they mean?
GRANT: Some of them are mean
if you're younger.
You're younger?
GRANT: They don't like
teenagers and stuff?
DAVID: Well, you're young,
you're a teenager.
And by all your bumper
stickers, I'm
guessing you're gay?
GRANT: No.
My girlfriend's bisexual.
And her mom's gay.
DAVID: OK.
So how is that going?
GRANT: She's pregnant.
DAVID: But then she
still likes girls?
GRANT: Yeah.
DAVID: And you're
OK with that?
GRANT: Yeah.
DAVID: You're a disgusting
human being.
GRANT: [LAUGHS].
Probably.
DAVID: Wait, so did you know
that when you started your
relationship with her?
So you've had, like, tons
of threesomes and stuff?
GRANT: No.
DAVID: She never brings
home girls?
GRANT: No.
DAVID: Do you guys look
at porn together?
GRANT: No.
She looks at it with
her dog, though.
DAVID: How old are you?
GRANT: 20.
DAVID: And how old is she?
GRANT: 19.
DAVID: Is she hot?
GRANT: I'm dating her.
DAVID: All right.
Anything else you want to tell
us about working as a cook at
a pilot's restaurant?
GRANT: There's lots of gay
people that come in here.
I don't know if they're
pilots, though.
DAVID: Do you think that's
a gay pilot right there?
GRANT: I don't know.
I've never seen him before.
DAVID: And what do you
know about Alaska?
GRANT: Not much.
DAVID: Anything.
GRANT: That the capital's
Juneau.
[LAUGHTER]
DAVID: All right.
Thanks for talking to us.
GRANT: Yeah.
DAVID: So what we're finding out
Taildraggers is from what
everyone tells us, it's a
restaurant for pilots.
But it's also, like,
Taildraggers.
I guess it's an analogy for
gay sex, or something.
So it's like a gay pilot's
restaurant or something.
I don't know.
He's pretty flaming.
He started petting
Harry's hat.
We got the most flaming pilot to
give us a ride into Alaska.
Fucking skip all of Canada.
Fuck you, Canada--
thumbs down.
Thumbs up, America.
We love you, Alaska.
We'll see you soon.
ANDREW: You guys ready?
DAVID: Yeah.
You thought you were going
to stop me, huh, Canada?
to get in my way.
But we're going to skip
you altogether.