RAY BARBEE: I mean, to me,
honestly, I always looked at
punk as more of a way of
thinking, if you will.
It's kind of more that part of
you that's just like, man, I
want to do this.
This is the norm?
I want to do that!
If there's a heavy metal show
and then they book a jazz band
in there, that's punk.
PATRICK O'DELL: Hi,
welcome back.
This episode is about Ray
Barbee, who was actually the
first pro board I ever had.
I think, to me, he
looked different.
He just looks cool
when he skates.
And even back then, those old
videos, I remember when Ban
This came out, seeing his
skating, and he would do a
bunch of no complies and
then a kick flip.
And I'd think, like, wow!
I can't believe he can do all
those tricks in a row.
It doesn't take him 10 tries to
do each trick or whatever.
And I sat down with Ray, and I
asked him a little bit about
filming for those old
Powell videos.
He's a really awesome skater.
And this is it.
The Ray Barbee episode.
MALE SPEAKER 1: How long
have you been skating?
RAY BARBEE: Six years.
MALE SPEAKER 1: When
did you start?
RAY BARBEE: Six years ago.
When I first got into
skateboarding, again, it was
in between sixth and
seventh grade.
And I had a friend named Danny
that I always hung out with.
We rode bikes together
all summer.
And for his birthday he
got a skateboard.
And it was just like, whoa!
It made such an impression
on me.
And he was riding that, and I
was riding my bike, and I was
like, man, I want to
get a skateboard.
He was like, well, my
dad used to skate.
Let me see if he has his old
skateboard out in the garage.
So, sure enough, we went in
the garage and found it.
It was a Sims wood kick.
It was like a '70s board.
There was a group of guys that
were like, what did you guys
do over the summer?
And we were like, dude,
we skateboarded.
They were like, you
skateboard?
We skateboard, too.
Come hang out with us.
One of the guys, he had
a quarter pipe.
We started off there just
learning tricks, like be in a
line in the garage, hit it, come
back, get in line, and
then do that.
Because of the ramps then, it
was a lot of the vert pros
that I would hear about.
We knew that there was Caballero
in San Jose.
And these were all the guys that
we were like, whoa, we
want to be like--
we want to rip like they do,
kind of thing, you know?
And it was crazy, because back
then, it was so different.
Nowadays kids are like,
give me a board, give
me a sticker, whatever.
We were just like, whoa.
We didn't want to bug him.
We were like, whoa!
We didn't want to say
nothing to him.
We were just like, let
him do this thing.
PATRICK O'DELL: Was Public
Domain the first
video you were in?
RAY BARBEE: That was the
first video, yeah.
Well, you know what?
I was in Sick Boys, but Public
Domain was definitely the
first featured thing
of me, for sure.
Yeah, it was called the Rubber
Boys, that segment.
And it was Steve Saiz,
Chet Thomas, and Eric
Sanderson and myself.
Because of, for us, street
was being so new,
the list was blank.
So for us, it was really
exciting because it was like,
whoa, we can just
make up tricks.
So we had a lot of fun just
kind of stumbling across
things and making up tricks.
And I think a lot of the stuff
that we stumbled on were
things that people
had never seen.
Because street skating, I almost
liken it to underground
hip-hop or Indy music, where
it's like it's own culture.
It's doing things, but
it takes something
to bring it to light.
But once that one thing gets
brought to light, people think
that that's the first time.
But it was happening for
so long in the--
whatever you want to say.
In its little culture and
in its little scene.
It'd been going on for years,
but it was just a matter of it
getting surfaced out.
And that's when people always
link it to that, but it was
going on for a while.
PATRICK O'DELL: And what was the
process for filming then?
It was just sort of like one
day just skating around?
RAY BARBEE: Three days total
was that whole--
all that footage
was three days.
And it's funny because
Stacy wanted it to
look like one day.
So I remember, we'd skate--
get going at 7:00 in the
morning, be done
at 8:00 at or whatever.
And he'd want us to put on the
same clothes the next day.
And we did that for three
days straight.
Yeah, the same Levi's, and the
same shirt, and the same
shoes, maybe switch
out the socks.
PATRICK O'DELL: So then the
next video is Ban This?
RAY BARBEE: Ban This was right
after Public Domain, yeah.
PATRICK O'DELL: And I
remember in that one
you had lots of lines.
It would be like seven
tricks in a row.
RAY BARBEE: Yeah.
That was the first one
with my own part.
PATRICK O'DELL: When you decided
what spots you were
going to go to, did
you decide?
Or did Stacy decide?
RAY BARBEE: That's what
was cool for me.
A lot of those spots were
like the first time
I ever skated them.
Because we'd just get with Stacy
and Stacy would just
drive around and be like,
you want to skate that?
And I'd be like, cool.
PATRICK O'DELL: It looked like
some of the video was looking
for scenery and not
so much like--
RAY BARBEE: It was before the
days of where you'd find spots
and film one thing.
Back then, it was more like
let's just capture the feel of
what it's like to just go
skating, go skating out in--
so I could tell definitely
around Ban This time, Stacy
was getting more of an idea of
what he wanted to do visually.
So he would take me to spots,
and I would be like, OK, you
just want we to skate on
the ground right here?
And he's like, yeah.
I'm like, OK.
PATRICK O'DELL: Did you feel
like then a part was about,
like you said, expressing
skating?
Or did you ever feel--
RAY BARBEE: It's hard to say
because it's always easy to
see what it grew into, and then
look back, and then try
to think did you feel like
you wished it would
have been like this?
But it was way before
any of that.
So it was what it was.
It was just being created.
So there was no--
the only goal was let's
just be on our boards.
And, OK, you're documenting
it.
But to me, the whole video
thing was so new.
I didn't know what was going
to come of any of this.
For street skating, back then,
there weren't too many parts.
Again, it was such new
terrain, new area.
I mean, I dig where it is now.
There's a place for all of it.
Because of the growth of it,
the reality is the way
skateboarding got pushed, it
just got to a place to where
you can't do that
in three days.
There's just no way to
physically pull that off.
It takes a long time because
of where it's got pushed.
So that's great.
Because everything's got
to get pushed, man.
You can't stay still.
Everything's got to keep moving
and growing and growing.