That's 1987.
Backside smith stall.
Could be '88, it's
probably '88.
But anyway, it's a backside
smith stall in the big block
at Embarcadero.
PATRICK O'DELL: With
sweatpants?
JAMES KELCH: Yeah, sweatpants
and a generic indie shirt my
mom got at the flea market, And
that one is 1986 with the
SMA shirt, olleying a bum that's
sleeping on the way.
PATRICK O'DELL: Hi, what's up?
Welcome back to the Epicly
Later'd show.
This episode is about
James Kelch.
When I first moved to San
Francisco and I wanted to be a
skate photographer, he was
probably the first pro that I
got to shoot pictures with.
James Kelch in the early '90s
was known as the Mayor of EMB.
People always have stories about
people being jerks down
at EMB, but James being
really cool.
But he did definitely
run some scams.
We asked James some questions,
and then I'll run it by Maza
or Mike Carroll and they'll
say that what he's
saying's not true.
But then there were some things
he told me that I
didn't think were true, and
then they were true.
I don't know, I think he's just
a really good storyteller
and he likes to embellish
a little bit maybe.
People talk about James like
he's a super amazing skater.
So in the course of making this
episode, Maza sent us
lost Kelch tapes that I think
are really awesome and really
show why he was pro.
And here it is, James
Kelch episode.
How long did you live
in Ohio for?
JAMES KELCH: Before I went
to San Francisco?
Hardly at all.
I was born here and we were in
a military family, we moved
around a lot.
So hardly at all, ever.
Just come to visit and
stuff like that.
I moved to San Francisco from
Shreveport, Louisiana.
PATRICK O'DELL: You went to high
school in San Francisco?
JAMES KELCH: Yeah, I went to
middle school and high school.
Trail Hill Middle School,
Galileo High School.
PATRICK O'DELL: Galileo,
the one in--
JAMES KELCH: OJ went
to school.
It's on Van Ness down
by the wharf.
It's a pretty gnarly,
rugged school, man.
Sure changed the way
I look at stuff.
PATRICK O'DELL: Then how'd
you start skating?
JAMES KELCH: I lived
on [INAUDIBLE]
Island and I was just cruising
around on my bike one day and
I seen this kid skating down in
one of the little squares.
I don't know what they're
called, cul-de-sacs or
something like that?
Just some kid back
there skating.
He did a little bonus off a
bumper of a car, all these
people were around
all fired up.
And I was like wow,
that's dope.
PATRICK O'DELL: Do when'd
you first go to EMB?
JAMES KELCH: I went to EMB the
first time around in the
middle of '85 or so.
I took the bus into the city,
got off just to skate around,
first time skating
in the city.
And I asked some random kid with
a skateboard, where do
people skate?
And he's like, well, there's
this plaza down the street.
I see skaters there every
once in a while.
I just skated down there
and never left.
PATRICK O'DELL: So it wasn't
a spot that people skated
regularly then?
JAMES KELCH: Not at all.
I'd go there all the time,
there'd be no one
ever, all day long.
Me and someone I might
have come with.
And then randomly though,
you'd see maybe Tommy or
someone would skate through,
do a few tricks and leave.
But mostly you would see Ken
McGuire doing hand plants.
I used to get heckled
for sitting down
there all the time.
I used to tell them I wasn't
a real skater.
Until I'd blow their spots and
show them that if you learn to
skate one place, you can skate
anywhere, you dummies.
SAM SMYTH: Back then if I'm
11-years-old, this is '87.
If you skated in '87 and you
bumped into a kid in San
Francisco, told him you skated,
he'd ask you how high
could you ollie.
If you could ollie the highest,
then you was the best
skater out there.
And Kelch, for sure, could
ollie the highest in
Embarcadero.
AARON MEZA: At the time I'd been
going to Embarcadero for
a long time just randomly.
Because I lived just
outside SF.
And he's somebody I seen there
throughout the years.
One day I was just filming my
friend and he was like hey, do
you want to film some stuff?
And we filmed a couple
lines of lines
and a couple of tricks.
So I would just go film with him
and that dude Jake Vogel.
He was trying to get on
one-on-one with Jake.
We'd come this one line, like he
seriously skated the whole
place, it was super sick.
He had been sponsored, but I
think Dogtown might have went
out of business.
Maybe a week later, it was
funny, he was like there's
this company, all these dudes
are going to quit H-Street,
Mike Churnowski's leaving.
It's going to be called--
I don't know if he
knew the name.
I guess he knew the name.
It was going to be
called Plan B.
He named off all the dudes, he
was like it's going to be
Carroll, Hensley, Sheffy,
Rick Howard, Danny Way.
He's like they maybe
want me to be the
AN like Jason Carney.
I remember that was
another AN.
He might have said Eric Coston,
too, but he definitely
said Jason Carney.
Was going to be the
AN with him.
So that's what we were filming
for, his Plan B sponsor video.
But then I think later I got to
know Mike and he was more
like yeah, I think it was just
me being like yeah, you should
try to get on.
And at that time, I was like
James was so good, it made
sense to me.
I was like that's sick, dude,
that'd be so rad.
PATRICK O'DELL: Did the footage
you filmed with James,
the early footage,
end up anywhere?
AARON MEZA: No, none of it.
-You know, he was a little bit
older, he could fight, he can
hook up with chicks.
So he was like a cool dude to
all those dudes, so they all
looked up to him.
As many people like maybe he
was mean to, which I don't
think was that many, he probably
would be the one dude
who would say hi to a random
guy out of town, you know?
SAM SMYTH: People came to him
because they knew he was going
to be the bodyguard, the big
brother, just the whole
Embarcadero regulator.
I can remember something
going down.
My buddy was trying to
sell some weed, got
punched in the face.
And I ran to get James like
I was getting the fucking
cavalry, you know?
PATRICK O'DELL: Tell me
about stealing boards.
I've heard rumors of that.
JAMES KELCH: If you came through
and it was one of them
hectic winters and no
one had a new board.
And you had all brand new shit,
and you just got out of
your mom's Lexus or whatnot.
Yeah, you're probably going
to get your board stolen.
It's the same as if you wear a
big ass huge gold chain and go
hang out in Oakland
real quick.
I mean nothing's different.
Everyone thinks oh, just because
they were skaters.
We were still just city kids.
But it wasn't an everyday crazy
out of hand, you go
there, you get your
board stolen.
It gets exaggerated
way out of hand.
SAM SMYTH: I mean, he's always
been that personality, man.
Cool as the Fonz, young
Burt Reynolds face.
He always had that charisma,
ever since he was young.
I guess when you got
it, you got it.
-This is James' car.
Here goes the front panel.
Let me see what I can do
with this wheel here.
Hey, let's see if
we can start it!
Look out, everybody,
it might blow up!
-What's the scene
with this car?
Why's it all fucked up, dude?
-Because fucking dumb ass Billy
took it and ruined it,
and him and Jeff and Dune.
JAMES KELCH: Come on,
P. Out of the way,
Gotto, we got company.
[INAUDIBLE]
blah, blah, blah, I swear I seen
it just lying right here.
Yeah, film the whole shit.
This is the real life,
no Ferraris, no
motorcycles, no nothing.
PATRICK O'DELL: So when this
video came out, what year was
this video made?
JAMES KELCH: The video
came out in '93.
PATRICK O'DELL: When the real
video was made you were
already pro?
JAMES KELCH: Yeah.
PATRICK O'DELL: How did
you first get on Real?
JAMES KELCH: I had knew Jim
Thebo and he was giving me
wheels every once in awhile.
And then one day I seen him
and Givanti and a bunch of
heads skating brown
model benches.
I just started skating the
benches like a maniac, man,
just trying to show off.
And then Thebo called me that
night and was like look, I
can't do pressure flips.
And it was a joke, of course.
And I was like, yeah,
me neither, really.
And he was like well,
we need a new pro.
You want to skate for us?
And I was like, yes,
of course.
PATRICK O'DELL: So he just
saw you skate one time?
JAMES KELCH: Oh, no.
He had seen me skate a million
times, but I hadn't seen him
in a while.
I was AN for other companies
before I got on Real.
Like Dogtown, H-Street, 101
for a little bit, rode for
Plan B for a little while.
I watched this video
the other day.
It's pretty gnarly that
we even put a
video out like that.
Yeah, that's that girl, Molly.
Every time I [INAUDIBLE], she
always something to say.
That bitch, blah, blah, blah.
PATRICK O'DELL: They're
doing the wave?
JAMES KELCH: Yeah, they
were doing the wave.
I'm a gymnast.
Ollie [INAUDIBLE] flip, the
only time I ever did it
outside of a skate park,
I had no wheels.
I was just rolling on bearings
right there.
I was actually really proud
of that [INAUDIBLE].
It always used to
feel real good.
I was actually pleased I
even worked a part out.
I wasn't even barely skating
when we filmed all this shit.
When they came to me and were
like oh, the video's done, I
was like but hold on,
I didn't even film.
PATRICK O'DELL: You
weren't skating a
lot because of drugs?
JAMES KELCH: Actually, no.
It was mostly injuries
at first.
And then the drugs came with me
just sitting around doing
nothing because of my ankles.
Because I had childhood
arthritis growing up,
rheumatoid arthritis.
And so I got all these
crushed-up, clicking bones and
all this bullshit, and I just
would go around it.
And then it started getting
worse and worse until
eventually I was just,
I'm not even going to
try to skate anymore.
But then I was still pro, and
doing drugs, trying to skate
here and there.
Dude, I would be just standing
there all drugged out and Jim
would just be like
do something.
I'd be like just tell
me what to do, man.
They he would just bring
up a random trick he
saw me do one time.
I'd be like all right.
PATRICK O'DELL: Who
filmed it, Maza?
JAMES KELCH: Most of the real
video was filmed by, I would
go with Thebo.
Because he knew if it
wasn't him, that I
wouldn't even come out.
Like, all those other dudes
would show up to get me and I
wouldn't even go outside.
I'd be like, well, fuck off.
But then Jim would come and
I'd have to get up.
I'd be like all right,
Jim, let's go.
He'd put me the shower
and said come on.
It's very, very weird
when I watch it.
A lot of those tricks, toes are
dragging, no one's rolling.
You might as well just
stop and pick your
board up and walk away.
Except for Solomon's part.
All I know is I was chilling on
Oak Street one day at the
party palace.
And there's a knock at the door
like 7:00 in the morning.
I open it, it's like Gonzo.
He's like dude, I just saw
your part, I love it.
It's one of my favorites.
You want to go skate?
I was like oh, I didn't go to
sleep all night and I kind of
just shut the door
in his face.
PATRICK O'DELL: On Gonz?
JAMES KELCH: Yeah, I just
went back in the house.
I was too embarrassed to
hang out with him.
I was up all night
doing drugs.
I didn't want to hangout with
Gonzo, he's like my idol.
As you could tell, the house is
a tad bit cluttered so it
took me a while to find it.
My girl put this
shit together.
I don't know if that plastic's
going to be
reflecting on you or not.
This one, this is how
skateboarding actually works.
Whether they, not now maybe, but
I know these guys always
cared about me and everything,
but listen to this story.
It's a light brown coat,
and you see all the
dark spots on it?
That's all blood, and spray
matter, and people bleeding
and shit like that.
Well, I got into a big bar fight
with these bikers and I
just beat their faces in.
They beat me up, too,
as you can tell.
So the next day I go down to
the Deluxe to get maybe
cleaned up, some money, see if
my eye's all right, it's all
swollen, and get some
clothes or whatnot.
But instead as soon as I walked
in, no one cared about
any of that.
They were like dude, just
go take pictures.
I couldn't walk, nothing, I
couldn't get no new clothes.
They were like, you got to
get photos of this shit.
They just drug me out to these
abandoned projects behind Real
and took this photo.
PATRICK O'DELL: How much longer
did you write for Real
after this?
JAMES KELCH: After the
video came out?
So if the video came out '93,
'94 I moved to [INAUDIBLE] and
lived with Kelly Bird
and Diedrich.
And then we were going to go on
tour, so I came to Ohio to
hang out for a little bit.
Went on the tour, left early,
they wrecked the van.
So I'm figuring right before '95
started they called me and
asked me if I was skating
and all that shit.
And I didn't like the tone
of whoever's voice
I was talking to.
So I told them no, I don't
skate no more, I quit.
PATRICK O'DELL: You were
talking to Tommy?
JAMES KELCH: It was
Tommy, yeah.
He wasn't being a dick or
nothing, but I could tell he
wasn't happy with me.
PATRICK O'DELL: Here's a photo
I took, it was really bad.
Sorry.
JAMES KELCH: It is the
photo you took.
I remember that day.
Those are some tight pants
on my butt, man.
Gross.
You should have told me.
PATRICK O'DELL: No,
I'm not retiring?
JAMES KELCH: Yeah, this is an ad
I got like a month after I
told Real I was retiring.
PATRICK O'DELL: Who is God?
JAMES KELCH: Yeah, I got in
"Big Brother" one time.
It was the "Who is God" thing.
They asked me a question, what
do I think about God, and took
a picture of me doing
a smith grind.
PATRICK O'DELL: What's
you say?
JAMES KELCH: I said, here,
want me to read it?
I don't even remember.
"I believe in religion because
I believe there's a greater
force than ours.
I think when people die their
souls leave to some spiritual
place, whether that's
good or bad.
I'm not religious, because the
way people go about their
religions is weird.
I don't tend to judge
others' religions,
because I don't care.
The world's really
a better place
when people are religious.
It keeps a lot of people nice.
It changes psychos into somewhat
normal peoples.
I think most of the Earth is
evil, because this is Satan's
land to do with as he pleases.
Most good things must
be somewhere else.
The only way religion has
affected my life is when it's
helped change some of my friends
into better people."
And that's that.
I'm going to give a Solomon
secret out real quick.
You know for like a year and a
half, almost two years, he
used to skate the other way?
And then he pushed mongo.
PATRICK O'DELL: What
do you mean?
JAMES KELCH: He skated
goofy-footed
and he pushed mongo.
And people told him like
yo, you're whack.
Unless I'm just making
it all up.
You never know, my
brain's confused.
But I remember all
the stories.
Yeah, dude skated goofy-footed
and pushed mongo, and they
told him yo, you're a bum.