Ok that sounds great. Thanks a lot, bye bye.
He says he can't get enough, he says everytime
you hear it you hear something new and, you
know. He put it together differently - he
was great. He wants to come on a tour. Besides
the tours on schedualed Saturdays, Jacque
is continuously creating and revising new
designs, in all areas of the social sequences.
For every design and drawing that he keeps,
he probably throws out about 10. He then selects
from the sketches, ones he wants to be rendered
into 3D annimations. Andrew and Julita are
located in London, and they head up the venus
project design team. Just give you an idea
of size. It looks very good Andrew. It's getting
there. We've been working with Julita and
Andrew for about 2 years now. They take Jacques
sketches and turn it into a beautiful vision,
of what the future can be. So if you'd like
to learn more about our design team, visit
thevenusprojectdesign.com. On the same site
we have a tremendous professional database
that you might want to check out and join
as well. We're also filming the hundreds of
scale models that Jacque made with an HD camera,
because they were originally shot on high
8 over 10 years ago. There's always a lot
working against you when you shoot outside,
there are the bugs, the wind, the rain, the
sun, making sure the shadows are in the right
places, and the sun is always moving. So it's
always an interesting venture. After we do
get the models shot, then it's into the editing
room, where we go over the shots, and see
what we're going to pick. We're doing this
for presentations, because we are always having
meetings with people for the possibility of
doing the first city or a more extensive research
centre. In addition, I'm presently narrating
Jacque's book, the best that money can't buy
beyond politics, poverty, & war into an audio
book. Unfortunetly, I don't know the release
date on that yet.
We appreciate everyone's interest and support.
And keep watching for new content and lectures
which we'll try to post regularly. Thanks.