Bryan: For the New
Madrid earthquake.
Wilma Bryant: For a
series of F5 tornadoes.
Narrator: And
protect themselves.
Man: Watch it, man.
Push him away.
Blevins: Stop
right there!
Narrator: From what they
perceive as the fast
approaching end of the
world as we know it.
Daughter: Dad!
Braxton: Leave
her alone!
Narrator: Next, we
go inside the lives
of three committed
preppers who have
devised
extensive plans.
Patrick: Let's get
the house secure,
get the doors locked,
get the windows locked.
Brian: Come on.
We're bugging out.
Let's go, babe.
Narrator: Gone to
great lengths and
made huge personal
sacrifices to
ensure their
very survival.
Bryan: We carry
usually 3-4,000
rounds of every
single caliber of
ammo at all times.
Narrator: The experts
will assess their preps,
to see if they
have what it takes.
Jay: There's a very
thin fabric that
holds together a
civilized society.
Narrator:
To survive.
Jay: Go!
Go!
Narrator: This is
Doomsday Preppers.
Jay Blevins is a
young father of three.
Jay: Oh man.
You're too big.
Daughter:
No, I'm not.
Narrator: Living in
the small town of
Berryville, Virginia,
60 miles outside
Washington D.C.
He and his wife,
Holly, love the
tranquility of
their neighborhood.
Here, they can raise
their children in
a spacious home,
alongside a close-knit
community of friends.
But behind the front doors
of Jay's quiet cul-de-sac
there's growing fear
about the future.
Jay: We're preparing for
the breakdown of social
order caused by an
economic collapse.
Are they shooting
up there?
Go!
I believe our life is
different because we prep.
I believe it's a
better quality of life.
I think it was a
combination of things,
like September 11th,
like the tsunami of 2004.
A combination of
experiences I've had as
law enforcement officer
lead me to believe we are
susceptible to
certain situations
that are out of
our control.
I want my family
to be ready for
those type of
situations.
Narrator: Jay believes the
world will soon enter a
global depression, causing
unemployment worse than
the Great Depression
that could collapse
civilized society
altogether.
Jay: When people
can't get jobs and
then can't feed
their families,
I think those are
the types of things
that will really
set them off.
You see people
rioting and
you see people basically
destroying things
because they're not
getting their way.
There's a very thin
fabric that holds
together a
civilized society.
Narrator: With more
than 5.5 million
people in the
greater D.C. area,
Jay fears that urban
unrest could spill into
suburbs and overwhelm
local police officers.
Jay: Once the mob
mentality sets in it all
adds up to a situation
that could be very,
very dangerous to
try to survive in.
Narrator: Jay fears
violence and looting could
potentially spill
into his neighborhood.
So he's fortified his
4,000 square foot
home with things
he'll need to stay
off the streets, like six
months of food and water.
Jay: We believe strongly
in sheltering in place.
You know, we have the
home field advantage here.
We know where
our supplies are.
We have a lot
of supplies.
Holly: I prefer that
all of our preps
be kept in closets,
garages and storage sheds.
We like to maintain
some normalcy,
even though we do
this on the side.
Narrator: As a former
police officer,
Jay's main focus
is on security.
Jay: We keep a total
of about 7,000
rounds of ammunition
in the bedroom.
Holly: Ok, so I guess
we have a samurai sword
in this closet.
Jay: I love my
kids so much.
I love my
wife so much.
I don't ever want to see
them hurt or to go without
and so if a crowd were
ever to come to my house
for whatever reason, I
would defend my family.
Narrator: Mob violence
is considered highly
dangerous because it
is so unpredictable.
To survive, officers are
trained to cycle through
multiple defense options,
starting with deterrents
and ending with
lethal measures.
Police call this continuum
the Circle of Force.
Jay: Seven things that I
believe are essential for
the circle of force
are: rifle, a handgun,
edged weapons, impact
weapons, pepper spray,
martial arts and
verbal commands.
Jay: Stop!
Get on the
ground!
You can use different
things immediately.
You can go to
whatever option you
need based on
the situation.
You encounter a person and
they're attacking you with
a knife, you don't have
to say something first.
You can go straight to
lethal force because
it's being brought
against you.
Narrator: Jay wants
to avoid having
to use lethal
force, if possible.
Jay: Who needs
gloves out there?
Holly: I
need gloves.
Narrator: So today he's
working with Holly to
install a non-violent
first line of defense.
One he hopes his entire
prepping network
can implement to
persuade looters to
move on to
other houses.
Jay: The way our
plan is set up,
we have many
families.
In fact we probably 20
families representing
75-100 people involved
in our network.
In a shelter in
place scenario,
the network puts boards
over the windows and
doors in order to secure
the first level and
then the network would
work together to
secure the perimeter
of the property.
So we're basically trying
to get all the entrances,
all the entry points on
the first floor because
those are the points
that are vulnerable
to attack if someone
is trying to get in.
Friend: Okay.
Narrator: Plywood is often
used to fortify homes in
hurricane zones,
because it is flexible
and able to absorb
the impact of
100 mile per
hour winds.
Jay: I need the
two-by-four,
who's got that?
Narrator: But anchoring
plywood boards to the
front of the window,
by bolting them to a
horizontal
two-by-four,
gives the wood
increased strength.
Jay believes it's
perfect for preppers.
Jay: Push
on it guys.
Narrator: Because a
three-quarter-inch thick
piece can withstand
repeated blunt force
attacks without
cracking or breaking.
Jay has custom
pieces ready to go,
so that he and Holly can
install them in all their
downstairs windows in
half an hour or less.
Jay: If you hear beating
on this window right here,
you'll know okay I
got to go upstairs,
look down and see
what's going on and
try to take care
of that threat.
Holly: Okay.
Okay, I can do it.
Jay: They wouldn't
last forever.
If you had an
unlimited amount of
time you could probably
chop or hack through them,
maybe pry them off.
Narrator: So now, Jay,
Holly and their friends
are putting their
fortifications up against
a number of weapons
looters might possess.
Friend: That's
pretty good.
You're going to be
there all day trying
to get in
with a knife.
Jay: Wow.
There you go.
Friend: Three strikes
and you're out.
Jay: Man.
Holly: Good,
Katie!
Jay: Wow.
That was a,
I'm impressed.
Friend: Come
on, harder.
Katie: Come on, your
kids are hungry.
Friend: Harder!
Friend 2: You can't
hit it hard enough
to make it go through.
Holly: By the time you
hear them doing it,
you're going
to shoot them.
Jay: Holly will
be upstairs with
the .22,
hopefully.
Holly: Picking
you off.
Jay: Yeah,
all right.
Good.
The way that we've
designed this is that
we put the boards over
just the first level,
so that on the
second level we can
watch from there.
We can utilize the
different weapons
we have to defend
the homes.
Narrator: But rather than
rain down lethal bullets,
Jay's moving up the Circle
of Force to a non-lethal
measure, one used by
97% of American police
departments for
crowd control.
Jay: We do manufacture
our own pepper spray here.
If you have a group of
armed people outside of
your house I wanted
to have an option to
encourage them to
get of the property.
Having had pepper spray
used on me in the Police
Academy, I know it
works very well.
I do recall one person
actually crying for their
mommy when they were
sprayed with pepper spray.
Narrator: The base
ingredient of law
enforcement grade pepper
spray is capsaicin,
the active component
of chili peppers.
Today he's going to test
his recipe on two other
members of his prepper
network, Trevor and Eric.
By mixing store-bought
peppers with an acidic
binding agent
like lemon juice,
Jay believes he can make
a homemade brew potent
enough to cause temporary
pain and blindness.
Jay: And then the
Habanera sauce of course
is to burn
your face off.
The whole bottle.
Friend: That's
really gonna hurt.
Jay: That's perfect.
Friend: That's not gonna
feel very good on my face.
Friend 2: So how are
you gonna deliver this?
I mean, are you gonna
splash it on me,
are we gonna dip
our face in there?
I mean what
do you?
Jay: Well actually
lemme go get it and
I'll tell you.
Narrator: For delivery,
Jay's repurposed a
suburban mainstay
that is inexpensive,
has a range of 30 feet
and is inconspicuous
in a neighborhood
filled with children.
Jay: Okay guys, so this
is our sophisticated
delivery system here.
Friend: Water guns of,
uh, death and fire.
Narrator: Jay's recipe
should be strong enough to
cause excruciating
pain, burning and
involuntary swelling of
the eyes and throat.
But Jay is basing
today's test on the
police rule of thumb that
aggressors can cover
21 feet in one and
a half seconds.
If the pepper spray
doesn't drop Trevor and
Eric to the ground
before they can get
close enough to assault
him, it's useless.
Jay: Stop
right there!
What do
you want?
Friends: We're
taking what we need!
Jay: Stop
right there!
Friend: We're
going in!
We're taking
what we need!
We're taking it!
Ahh, ahh!
Jay: Stop!
Stay down!
Friends: Owwww!
Uhhh, owww!
Jay: Pepper spray
feels like having
liquid magma
on your face.
Friend: Oh,
it works!
Jay: Put your
head down,
otherwise it's going to
just go all over you.
Ready?
Friend: What
is this?
Jay: It's
the milk.
Friend: It
definitely stopped
what I wanted
to do.
Narrator: Jay's
pepper spray worked,
but not fast enough.
Trevor and Eric were able
to reach his position
before the spray
took effect.
So he's ready to move
up the Circle of Force
to more extreme
options.
To prepare for
the possible mob
attacks he fears,
Jay is building a
prepper response
force of his own.
Now, they'll set their
sights on each other,
for the ultimate test
of home security.
Narrator: Former police
officer Jay Blevins has
turned his home into
a suburban stronghold.
Jay: This can be a
suburban fortress,
a place where my
family can be safe.
Narrator: Behind these
walls he expects to make
his stand against an
invasion of rioting
marauders following
an economic collapse.
But he doesn't plan
on doing it alone.
In Jay's densely
populated cul-de-sac,
neighbors could
easily turn into
the mob he fears.
But Jay hopes to
preempt this threat,
by recruiting
his neighbors
into a prepping
network.
Together, he believes
they can defend their
neighborhood through
whatever means necessary,
including
lethal force.
Jay: We have a group
here at the house
that meets
once a month.
It's my network
of preppers.
Prepping is a
growing movement.
Specifically this
year, I would say,
the group has
doubled in size.
Narrator: Today, Jay
has gathered his
prepping group to run
the ultimate test of
all his preps: a mob
assault on the front door.
Armed with pellet guns,
Jay will lead one team
acting as a mob
of home invaders.
Patrick, a certified
firearms expert,
will work with Holly and
a second team inside the
house to neutralize
the marauders.
Patrick: Let's get
the house secure!
Get the doors
locked!
Get the windows
You're using this
wall as cover,
so when they come through
they're not gonna be able
to see you, so you can
pop out and engage.
Narrator: Not knowing from
what direction the attack
will come, the goal is to
see if they can use their
preps to take control
of the situation.
They hope the boarded-up
windows will direct
intruders toward the only
available entry point:
the front door.
The plan is to turn
it into a kill-box,
a bottleneck where
intruders can be
shot down from
multiple angles.
Patrick: Remember, they
all still have to get
through the
funnel of death.
They've gotta get
through that choke point.
Jay: All right
guys, game faces on.
Man: Is this
John's house?
Girl: Get off
the property!
Jay: Oh hey.
We're just
looking for John.
What are
you doing?
I got pepper
sprayed!
Are they shooting
up there?
Go!
Patrick: Library,
report.
Holly: VCA down
in the library.
Patrick: Close the
front door and lock it!
All operators into
the family room!
Scenario's over.
Safeties on,
guns holstered.
Muzzles down.
Narrator: In all,
50 shots were
fired in today's
assault.
All three of the
mob assailants were
"killed" within 3 feet
of the front door.
Jay: Ah dude,
I got lit up.
I came in straight
and to the right.
Bullets seemed like
they were coming from
the front and the side.
And I got hit about I
don't know, 14 times.
There was like four
or five fatal shots.
Holly: As soon as I
heard the front door
get kicked open, I was
already ready for them.
And I got Jamie and then
I got Dan and about ten
seconds later Ryan
came to the door
and I, to the
chest immediately.
So I got all 3, yay!
My only thought is to
make sure that none
of these men get
past me to my kids.
Jay: So the moral of the
story is be the good guys,
not the bad guys.
In a prepper situation,
it's good to have a
variety of different
things at your disposal to
deal with the person
that is attacking you.
A lot of times people
think that preppers are
sort of a subculture
or a fringe of society.
But if an economic
collapse takes place,
I do believe that
our prepper network
will survive.
Narrator: Jay,
the experts,
practical preppers,
commend you for adapting
the policemen's Circle of
Force to defend your home.
Additionally, by working
with a prepper network,
you diversify the skills
at your disposal and
further protect
your family.
However, while your
security is adequate,
your food and water
storage are insufficient.
Jay: I think we do need
to get a little bit
more in our
food storage.
Uh, but we also
have in our network,
some folks that can do
hunting and trapping.
Narrator: To determine how
long you could initially
survive a catastrophe,
practical preppers has
scored your preps in five
categories of 20 points
each, for a total
possible score of 100.
Food: 10 out
of 20 points.
Water: 11 out
Shelter: You need a
plan to heat your home,
8 out of 20 points.
Security: 16 out
of 20 points.
In addition, your network
of preppers is excellent
and will increase your
family's odds of survival.
13 x-factor points.
Overall, you get 58
out of 100 points.
You have eight months
initial survival time.
Jay: I think we're doing
a little bit better in a
couple of those areas,
but there is definitely
room for improvement.
We'll definitely take
a lot of those into
consideration 'cause
we do wanna survive
a lot longer.
Since National
Geographic was here,
we've planted fruit trees,
a large garden and other
edible plants and have
begun canning and will
continue to do so for
long term storage.
Narrator: In spite of
the recent recession and
European debt crisis,
most economists believe a
near-term depression is
unlikely and the odds of a
global collapse that
would result in a severe
breakdown of
society are remote.
In his effort to survive a
potential third world war,
Brian Murdock thought the
one prep he needed most of
all was a wife.
But when he tells
his new bride-to-be
that he's a prepper,
he might find himself a
bachelor all over again.
Tatiana: Leave
me alone.
I need to get
out of here.
Narrator: Brian Murdock
is a real estate broker,
who lives in Somerville,
Massachusetts,
a blue collar college
town a few miles
north of Boston.
As a single guy
in his twenties,
Brian was always out
enjoying the city.
But these days
he's settling down,
and focusing on more
serious matters.
Brian: I believe
there will be a
third world war
in my lifetime.
It's inevitable
that there will be
nuclear weapons
in World War III.
I know that with every
fiber of my being.
Narrator: Brian believes
that an attack by the
United States on
Iran will result
in a counterattack
on Israel.
He sees the world
then breaking into two
factions, each
armed with weapons
of mass destruction.
He fears a series of
nuclear detonations
could kill a third of
all people on earth.
Brian: There were 50
million casualties
in World War II.
World War III is
going to be 40 times
World War II.
And it's going to be
2.3 billion people.
One third of the
Earth will perish.
All it takes is
someone to put their
finger on a button.
Narrator: Brian lives
in a 1,200 square foot
apartment, three miles from
Boston's busiest square.
A beginning prepping setup
for this kind of space
would usually cost
around $1,500.
But last year Brian sold
most of his belongings and
spent the proceeds,
around $75,000
to secure a new home,
somewhere to bug out to.
Brian: In a year of being
a prepper I've purchased a
motor home RV and
50 acres of land.
There's water sources
on the 50 acres
of land that I own.
There's two ponds.
There's a
dedicated well.
Narrator: As
is recommended
for urban preppers,
Brian's bug-out location
in upstate New York
is more than two hours
from a city center
but can be reached in
less than five hours.
But before Brian
permanently moves out of
Somerville there's
still one of part of his
prepping plan
that's missing.
Today, that final
piece is due to arrive.
Brian: It's a
work in progress,
but I'm very close
to having everything
in place for my
prepper goal.
Tatiana: I'm
so excited.
Brian:
Hello, baby.
How was your
flight?
Tatiana: It
was good.
Brian: Nice
weather.
Kind of like
Colombia, right?
I can't believe
you're finally here.
Tatiana has made
her first trip to
America to marry me.
Brian: How do you
like my house?
Tatiana: It's
beautiful.
Super beautiful.
Brian: Did you have
any problem getting
through immigration or
anything like that?
Tatiana: No.
Everything was
so perfect.
Brian: I think
Tatiana will be the
perfect prepper wife.
Narrator: A year ago,
Brian met Tatiana on a
dating website and
then made two trips to
Colombia to get
to know her.
He asked her to leave her
life in Colombia behind
and come to Somerville
to be his fiancée
and prepping partner.
Today is the first day
of her new American life.
Tatiana: A nice house.
Brian: Si baby,
thank you.
This is a
bedroom here.
Tatiana: Is
this your room?
Brian: I believe the
blessing of marriage
and the covenant of
marriage is very
essential to prepping.
Narrator: When Brian
met Tatiana he believed
he'd not only found
the ideal partner,
but a powerful prep.
Brian: I had heard a
lot of good things
about her culture
and the way of life.
It's very simple, there's
a lot of gratitude.
A lot of the
aspects of prepping
already resides
within her.
Tatiana: Baby.
Brian: What's
going on?
Tatiana: Can you help me
to turn this on please?
Brian: Of course.
Narrator: In the past
year he's learned that the
chances of surviving any
catastrophic event greatly
increase when you have
a partner who is also
invested in
your survival.
But Brian hasn't told
Tatiana that he plans for
them to one day leave
all of this behind and
bug-out to his rural
tract of land.
Now, Tatiana's learning
that coming to Somerville
was only the first part
of her American journey.
Brian: So.
I've talked to
you about uh,
things I'm
concerned about,
you know if there was
ever a nuclear attack.
You know, Boston
we're three miles
from downtown
right here.
I love you to death and
as we start our lives
together, you know I
really want to position
ourselves, you know in a
place where if something
like this were to happen
we'd be able to get out.
My house, it's been
a great place to
live but I bought 50
acres, it's about
seven hours from here.
I feel that's
the direction
that we ought to go.
Run for our
lives, you know.
She's had to blindly jump
off a cliff, you know,
to take the risk to
come here to America.
Tatiana: I can't believe
I came here to die.
You didn't tell
me that before.
Brian is telling me
a little about it.
Like, because things
that are happening here
in your country, you
know you're afraid that,
war is coming.
When Brian told
me he was a prepper,
I thought that
he was crazy.
In Colombia we
don't do it.
It's like a new
concept for us.
We don't know about saving
food for the bad times,
you know because
there are bad times
all the time over
there I guess.
But when I marry Brian
I will become a prepper
because I will support him
in whatever he's up to.
He's very wise.
I will be the perfect
prepper one day.
I hope.
Narrator: Fearing a
nuclear attack on the
heart of Boston, Brian
believes that he and
Tatiana must be
able to bug-out and
head for his land at
a moment's notice.
So before Tatiana has even
unpacked her suitcase,
he wants her to
prepare a bug-out bag
free of any
extraneous luxuries.
Brian: We'll
ease into it.
We'll go through
your stuff,
you know and kinda get
an idea of what's good
and what's not, you know.
Did you bring
a lot of stuff?
Got all mangled
up, huh?
Tatiana: My
creams, lotions.
Brian: Oh boy.
Baby, what are
these honestly?
These are beautiful shoes
for going out on the town
but ah, if, if we really
had to bug-out and
get out of town and we
had to move quick,
do you think this
is, I say that
with all due
respect.
I'm trying to, you
know, get you to think.
Tatiana: See now
you're scaring me.
I came to America 'cause
this is a safe place
and now we have
to run away.
Brian: I know,
it's funny.
Tatiana: I don't know it's
very emotional because,
you know I'm
like nobody here.
I can't go outside,
I don't have a job.
I don't have
friends here.
It's sad because I'm
leaving everything,
you know and I'm
starting like a baby.
I tell Brian, you have
to teach me everything,
like I don't know
many things here.
And I'm leaving my
family and my mom,
my daughter, my dad
and that is hard.
You know?
Will I be allowed
to have a razor?
Brian: Will you be
allowed to have a razor?
Of course.
Why wouldn't you be?
Some aspects of her
adjustment to America
that are going to
be tough for her.
Even though Tatiana is
unaware of it right now.
Time will reveal to her
that she is a prepper.
Narrator: Before she's
even had a chance to
absorb the shock, Brian
wants to see how much
natural prepper instinct
Tatiana possesses
and how much he'll
have to teach her.
Brian: I think it's very
important to teach her
necessary skills
to protect us.
Narrator: So, just
hours after she arrived,
he's decided to put
Tatiana through her first
full-fledged
bug-out drill.
But is Tatiana really
ready to accept
the life of a doomsday
prepper wife?
Brian: What are you just
going to wait inside?
Tatiana: Yes, thank you.
Narrator: Brian Murdock
believes the world is on
the brink of
nuclear war.
He's purchased 50 acres
of land 375 miles away in
upstate New York and an
RV and plans to bug-out
there as soon
as possible.
But Brian believes it's
essential his fiancée,
Tatiana, has all
the prepper basics
down pat first.
So even though she's only
just arrived in the U.S.,
it's already time for her
to leave Somerville behind
and experience her
first bug-out drill.
Brian: Let's
bug-out.
We're getting
out of here.
Come on.
We're bugging out.
Let's go, babe.
Tatiana: My sandal.
Brian: I got it.
I got.
Tatiana: My sandal.
Brian: Don't
worry about it.
You're not going to need
that where we're going.
Narrator: Brian's RV will
operate both as a home
and a defense outpost
for the couple.
He expects Tatiana will
learn to use firearms and
guard the 30
days of food and
water he keeps
in the RV.
Brian: So babe now that
we're here at the land,
I'll be teaching
you how to keep
the perimeter safe.
And you're going to
have the opportunity
to fire your
first handgun.
Get you comfortable
with a firearm,
we'll work our way into uh
working on the perimeter.
This is better than the
living room isn't it?
You feeling
comfortable here?
Tatiana: I have to
see how it goes.
And I will tell
you how I feel.
Brian: I understand.
Tatiana: Let's see if the
bugs leave me alone here.
Brian: The bugs
like light skin,
so I think
you'll be okay.
Tatiana: Yeah right now
the bugs are bothering me.
I need to get out
of here right now.
Meet you inside.
Brian: You're just
going to leave me
out here like that?
Don't you think we're
going to need to get
used to this if we're
gonna live up here?
Tatiana: Let's
see what happens.
Brian: Well,
I understand.
But this is, this is
the North Country.
This is God's
country up here.
You know?
There's a lot
of bugs.
I've got
bug spray.
Tatiana: Okay, I
will put on some.
Brian: What are
you going to do?
Just wait inside?
Tatiana:
Yes, thank you.
Brian: Ah, alright.
I'll get the
fire going.
uh venison on.
Tatiana: Okay.
Brian: All right?
See you later.
Brian: Go to work on
the beans and rice.
All right baby.
I love you.
Tatiana: I guess
preppers are a little,
little bit crazy.
Don't get upset.
Brian: Tatiana's got a
little learning to do,
but soon we'll
be married and
I know we'll
be happy here.
Narrator: After a tough
initial adjustment,
Tatiana is ready for her
first shooting lesson.
One important advantage
of prepper partnering is
always having backup.
Just as World War II
soldiers were assigned to
defend trenches and
foxholes in pairs,
Brian believes it is
essential he and Tatiana
are both able to
defend the RV.
So today, he's teaching
her to shoot a handgun for
the first time.
Brian: So as you know,
this is an important part
of our prepping and
central to the blessings
of being an American
and the 2nd amendment.
I have a banana
up there for you.
It was the closest I
could come to a plantain.
I know you like
plantains.
Want to give
it a shot?
Tatiana: I will try.
Brian: Alright.
Tatiana: I don't want
to offend anybody,
but it's a little bit
arrogant to think that
you're gonna
save yourself,
you know because I think if
God wants you to you know,
that you're not
alive anymore.
He will do it, no
matter how many water,
how much water you
have in your van or
in your camper
or whatever.
I hope you know that
everything I'm doing
it's because I love you.
And I want to share
everything with you.
Your life and all your
experiences prepping and
all that, because
I love you.
Brian: I appreciate that
baby and I love you too.
Tatiana: Sometimes,
I want to kill you.
Brian: I love
you, too.
Tatiana has already been
prepared to be a prepper,
she may not know it but
I think she'll realize,
like, "Yeah Brian, you
know, this makes sense.
This is who I am too."
It's a life-changing event
when you meet the right
person to share
your life with.
Narrator: Brian,
the experts,
practical preppers,
commend you for moving
forward with your prepping
plan and securing a
bug-out location.
However, the remainder
of your preps could be
fatally inadequate.
Your food and water preps
are nowhere near basic
levels necessary for
long-term survival.
Brian: A hundred
percent on the money.
I mean, your
thoughts, Tatiana?
Tatiana: Si.
Narrator: Your
shelter situation
is slightly better.
Having a mobile
bug-out RV provides
shelter with
flexibility.
Tatiana: Yeah,
that's true.
Narrator: To determine how
long you could initially
survive a catastrophe,
practical preppers has
scored your preps in five
categories of 20 points
each, for a total
possible score of 100.
Food: You should have
a hidden cache at your
bug-out location,
4 out of 20 points.
Water: 9 out
of 20 points.
Shelter: Having no
infrastructure at your
bug-out location will
limit your ability to
survive long-term,
11 out of 20 points.
Security: 8 out
of 20 points.
Your biggest advantage
is your mobile home,
which can provide
you with basic
shelter anywhere you go.
11 x-factor points.
Overall, you earn 43 out
of 100 survival points.
You have eight weeks
initial survival time.
Brian: Yeah, I'm glad
you folks have been uh,
crystal clear
honest about this.
It just reminds
us of, you know,
the intensity with which
we need to raise our game.
Tatiana and I have
tied the knot and ah,
we are moving in three
days to that location.
We are getting out.
Things have heated
up in the world.
At that time, once we
are at our destination,
we intend to
aggressively add to our
food and water storage.
Narrator: Since
the 1980's,
the world's
nuclear stockpile
has decreased 80%.
However, with more
countries now in
possession of
nuclear weapons,
the possibility of a
limited nuclear exchange
remains a concern.
While earthquakes are a
common fear in some parts
of the United States,
they're not generally a
concern in much
of the Midwest.
But Bryan and Lacey May
believe that if more
Midwesterners were
aware of the major,
active fault line
running through the
center of the country,
they'd be worried.
Bryan: Everybody knows
where the San Andreas
Fault line is but not
a lot of people know
where the Madrid
Fault line is.
We're preparing for the
New Madrid earthquake
that would change the
world as we know it.
Me and my
wife, we prep.
We're a prepping
family and
she's right
there beside me.
Lacey: I think the male
prepper is a stereotype.
I'm sure there's more
women preppers out there.
Once I became
a mother,
I definitely started to
think about the future and
just having extra things
that would be needed.
My nightmare is not
having what I need
to provide to my child.
Narrator: The highest
risk of earthquakes in
the U.S. outside the
west coast is along the
New Madrid Fault.
The fault runs 150 miles
from Illinois to Missouri.
There are more than
200 measured seismic
events along the
fault each year.
In 1811 and 1812, a series
of nearly 8.0 magnitude
earthquakes rocked the
New Madrid each one
roughly as powerful as
the 1906 earthquake
that destroyed
San Francisco.
In 1812, the
New Madrid area
was relatively
unpopulated.
Today, more than 10
million Americans live
within the fault zone.
Bryan: We're talking
about just major cities
being affected by this.
There will be no
food inside the
grocery stores
after three days.
So if no one
has preps,
they would
basically starve.
Lacey: People who don't
plan wouldn't know
what to do and so they
would be wreaking havoc
on what is left
of society.
Bryan: If the Madrid was
to happen today you would
have essentially an
ocean running through
the middle of the
United States that
was probably 100
to 200 miles wide.
Let me show you this.
This right here
is showing the,
what would happen after
a Madrid earthquake.
Louisiana's going to
be underneath water.
So it's gonna
stretch from there,
some of Mississippi's
gonna be underwater.
Arkansas, it's
gonna be cut in,
pretty much in half.
Missouri's got a smaller
path of water going
through it but it goes all
the way up to Illinois.
And up to us.
Lacey: And where do
we sit on this map?
Bryan: We're gonna
be, we're up here.
They're predicting
about 7 million people
will be affected
by this.
Seven million
people panicked,
is not a good thing.
Narrator: Bryan and Lacey
want to start prepping for
the catastrophic quake
and flood they fear
as much as they can.
They have income from the
car stereo shop they own,
but they currently
have no savings.
So in order to make more
money to afford the preps
they think they'll
need, Bryan and Lacey
have gone to extremes.
Narrator: Small business
owners living in Indiana,
Bryan and Lacey may are
preparing for a massive
earthquake they fear
will strike in the heart
of the U.S., tearing
the country in two.
Bryan: If the Madrid
Fault line was to hit,
we'd have to rethink how
we got our goods across
the United States, because
now we would have a
gigantic mass of
water dividing the
United States.
There's gonna be no way
to truck supplies in
from the Western half
and most of our imports
come from California.
Narrator: Their fears have
spurred them to try to
fill their home with
enough supplies to
one day ride out the
end of civilization.
But Bryan and Lacey
have no cash savings.
Lacey: So how are we
gonna get the things
we don't have?
That we don't
have stocked up?
Bryan: We're gonna need
to barter for items.
I believe bartering
should be done a lot more.
Bartering pretty much
built the world the way we
know it as right now and
then we got sidetracked
with paper money
with no backing.
Narrator: Because he
believes the dollar is
failing, Bryan converts
the bulk of his money into
either silver or gold,
to use for bartering.
Bryan: I mostly
barter with silver.
Sometimes gold.
And I have it in all
denominations from one
gram all the way up
to ten-ounce bars.
Lacey: How much money
do we have in silver?
Bryan: In silver
we're right around
5 or $6,000
give or take.
I won't know exactly
until I weigh it all up
and figure out the
current price.
Narrator: Today most coins
are made of nickel and
copper, but before 1965
a quarter was 90% silver.
Brian: So,
alright, here's $5.
Narrator: An actual silver
quarter is worth $5 today.
Bryan: Whenever I
go to the bank and
get my change or through
a drive through,
I always check all my
coins to make sure,
see if any of
it's silver.
Narrator: Bryan has
been using his silver
stockpile to barter
for some big preps.
Bryan: I've got
about $700 worth of
solar panels here.
And the trade was about
23 and a half ounces of
silver in trade
for these panels.
If the Madrid Fault
Line was to hit we's
going back in the Stone
Age for most of us.
You'd have to make
power somehow.
We have these
solar panels.
We also have a
wind turbine.
Narrator: Solar and wind
power are only effective
on sunny and windy days,
unless you have some way
of storing the
energy they create.
So Bryan has run wires to
his basement where he has
ganged together 40
batteries to store the
excess electricity from
his solar panels and
wind turbine.
Bryan: We currently
have 40 batteries
wired in parallel.
Each battery's
100 amp hours.
We would be able to live
for maybe two weeks to a
month without any
interruptions if we
had no sun
or wind.
Narrator: In his
basement safe room,
Bryan also stockpiles
other items for bartering.
Items like medication
and alcohol,
which he believes will
be rare and therefore
valuable after a
catastrophic earthquake.
Bryan: I believe when
the shelves go empty,
there will be a premium
on alcohol as you will
not be able to
find it anywhere.
I have taken the medicine
from the pet store before
to treat my urinary tract
infections or kidney
infections and they've
worked out excellent.
Narrator: If a New
Madrid earthquake
one day cuts supply
lines across America,
Bryan thinks people will
return to bartering
for the vital
supplies they need.
But right now, Bryan and
Lacey need to develop
other sources of income
in order to be able to
continue prepping
for doomsday.
So in addition to
their auto shop,
they breed and sell
bearded dragons.
Lacey: Bearded dragons,
depending on what color
phase they are,
can sell anywhere
from $25 up to $250.
Narrator: And they
run an adult website.
Lacey: When Bryan first
came to me with the idea
for an adult website, I
thought it was a good idea
because at the time I had
a friend that was selling
bachelorette accessories
and things like that
and she was making
tons of money.
Everybody's always going
to buy adult toys no
matter what type
of, you know,
what the economy's at.
Narrator: With
this added income,
Bryan and Lacey have
turned their basement into
a prepper pantry, stocked
with enough food to feed a
family of four
for four years.
Bryan: FEMA says you
should have a three-day
supply of food.
We got over 1,400
days of food.
On all our preps combined
I would say we probably
have spent $60,000
to $75,000.
Any amount of
money is important,
no matter what
the amount is,
but for feeling
safe and secure,
you cannot put
a price on that.
Narrator: Bryan and
Lacey are confident their
extensive home preps will
allow them to survive the
initial aftermath
of a catastrophic
New Madrid earthquake.
But they also believe
these same preps will make
them prime targets for
the millions of people
expected to be displaced.
So Bryan has something
much bigger in mind,
something he believes
could mean the difference
between life and death.
Convincing its owner to
part with it, however,
might be a tougher
sell than usual.
Dave: With delivery
it's $2,900.
Bryan: That
sounds good.
Are you willing to
take any barter?
Narrator: Bryan and Lacey
may are preparing for a
major earthquake along the
New Madrid fault line in
the central U.S., which
they believe will cause
major flooding
in the heartland,
displacing several
million people.
They've spent
more than $60,000
making their suburban
home self-sufficient,
but they're worried their
security cameras and
arsenal won't be enough
to protect them from the
millions of refugees
they fear will come
knocking after the
earthquake strikes.
So Bryan and Lacey's
current number one
priority is to
establish a secure,
secret bug-out
location.
Lacey: We've thought
about getting a shipping
container to actually
bury in our backyard.
Bryan: A shipping
container would be great
because it would be hidden
underneath the ground.
So therefore we could
basically bug-out
and not be seen.
Bryan: So you want to dig
about a nine-foot hole and
connect it through either
a basement or a sub-floor
and have one or more ways
to get in or out of it.
Narrator: Using shipping
containers as shelters and
emergency housing is
a growing industry.
In the event of
an earthquake,
a shipping container
is 100 times stronger
than a conventionally
designed home.
Dave: It's all
been repainted.
It's basically
rust free.
It's got some
added vents.
Bryan: Wow.
Dave: Hardwood
floors.
Bryan: Boy.
That's great.
Dave: With the
delivery it's $2,900.
Bryan: Do you want
to do any bartering?
Dave: I'm open to
whatever you got in mind.
What are you thinkin'?
Bryan: Well, I've
got my older bug-out
vehicle and then I
also have some gold.
Dave: Bug-out vehicle?
What does that mean?
Bryan: Well, a bug-out
vehicle is a vehicle that
you would get out of
Dodge with per se.
You know, something
that's 4x4, you know,
something not low
to the ground.
Dave: Can we take
a look at it?
Bryan: Yes we can.
It's an older
Explorer, but you know,
I figure worth a
couple grand in barter.
Dave: Okay, I might want
to hear it run and take it
for a ride, but
I'm interested.
And then you're going
to add some gold?
Bryan: Yes, we are.
These are 24-carat
gold, one-gram bars.
Each one of them
at current value
is about $50 apiece.
So we need, you know,
enough to cover 900 or so.
There's the last one.
Dave: Perfect.
It's like a credit
card but it's.
Bryan: Good anywhere,
anywhere will take it.
Dave: Anywhere,
any time.
Bryan: Exactly.
If people don't
prep on their own,
when the time comes, the
government does not have
the resources out there
to help everybody.
That was proven
in Katrina.
They basically put
everybody in a stadium
and left 'em.
That kind of proves
when something that big
and overwhelming happens,
that you're pretty
much on your own.
Narrator: Bryan,
the experts at
practical preppers have
assessed your preps.
You have enough ammo to
defend your family in a
crisis, but your
communications plan
is inadequate.
We recommend investing
in a HAM radio.
Bryan: That is
something we've already
been looking into
buying already.
We're also trying to
figure out ways to do
other means of
communication other
than HAM as well.
Narrator: We commend
your energy storage
capabilities and power
generation and your food
storage is exceptional,
you could feed your family
for more than a year.
But you need a
re-supply plan.
Bryan: And that is
something that we thought
about and we are
going to be doing.
Narrator: Practical
preppers has scored your
preps in five categories
of 20 points each.
Food: 15 out
of 20 points.
Water: You need additional
filtration options,
16 out of 20 points.
Shelter: Your location in
an urban area is not ideal
for sustainability,
15 out of 20 points.
Security: 10 out
of 20 points.
Your biggest advantage is
your solar and wind power.
For this you receive
15 x-factor points.
Overall, you receive a
score of 71 out of 100.
You have an initial 13
months survival time.
Bryan: I can live with
that assessment, um,
there's always room
for improvement.
Since National
Geographic was here,
we've started breeding
more and more dragons.
We've produced hundreds
of babies since the show.
We also have done
enhancements to
our rain
catchment system.
Also, we've started a few
websites for preparations
to sell different kinds
of preparation products.
Thank you.
Narrator: Earthquakes
on the New Madrid Fault
occur once every 500
years on average.
Scientists believe there's
a greater than 1 in 50
chance that the New
Madrid Fault will unleash
a major earthquake in
the next 50 years.