ANJEM: We are here maybe saying
to you, look, there's a
better way of life.
You don't need to live
like animals
following your own desires.
The big industries you see
nowadays in the West are
things like gambling,
pornography, alcohol, drugs,
homosexuality.
REPORTER: If you took over
Britain, you'd ban alcohol?
ANJEM: Of course.
Alcohol would be banned.
Drugs would be banned.
Pornography would be banned.
Gambling would be banned.
But the money saved--
REPORTER: The Queen?
ANJEM: There'd be no monarchy.
[CHANTING IN ARABIC]
ANJEM: Yeah, we're basically, we
were inundated with threats
of violence, with threats
to kill and murder.
We had hundreds of them in the
two weeks when we were
advertising the--
on the text, via email,
on blogs.
Basically, the reality that I
envisage was that Piccadilly
Circus, which is a place of
rallying, would have been
occupied, and the people were
planning to attack us in
Trafalgar Square.
Now, I have with me women,
children, elderly.
Therefore I had no option
but to relocate.
DAVE: I don't think any person
with those views, no matter
what color, race, or religion he
has, has the right to speak
on the street.
If I came out with half of what
he said about beheading
people, et cetera, et cetera,
I would be arrested for
incitement.
ABU: First of all, I believe
that the British people, they
are very ignorant about the fact
what is happening abroad,
even about Sheikh Osama.
If they came to actually verify
with us, rather than
show an ugly face and be angry
with us, they'd find that
Islam is truly something
they'd like.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
MAN 1: These are extreme
Muslims.
MAN 2: No, he's a Muslim.
ANJEM: No, he's a pure Muslim.
He adheres to the Islamic
text completely.
What does he do that is
wrong in your eyes?
ABU: I've spoken to many
of my colleagues,
for instance at work.
One instance was about
the Shariah.
Where they were saying that,
how barbaric chopping the
hands of the thief was.
And two weeks later, his laptop
was actually stolen.
And he [INAUDIBLE], he said, I
feel like killing the man,
chopping his head off.
I said, for God's sake, all we
said is chop the hands off.
Don't go chopping the
man's head off.
ANJEM: Shall I take you to the
training camp, where we're
doing Al Qaeda training?
And where we're making
nuclear weapons?
Maybe I'm doing that
in my garden.
INTERVIEWER: It's underneath
the football pitch.
ANJEM: It could be, it
may well be, yeah.
There might be a bunker
underneath the [INAUDIBLE]
Mosque.
Maybe we need to dig it
up and have a look.
You don't want to believe
everything that you see and
read in the media.
One of the problems of the
media is that they'll
fabricate something.
And then they'll start believing
it, you see?
That's quite dangerous,
really.
You invent Frankenstein and
Dracula, and then you start to
become afraid of it, forgetting
the fact that you
invented him in the
first place.
[MEN ARGUING]
ABU: My name is Abu Sumayyah
from Stoke-on-Trent.
I became Muslim about five years
ago now, March 5, 2005.
Basically, whatever Allah
has given for us, we
are going to take.
If Allah tells us that we lash
the person who doesn't pray
his prayer, we lash the person
who doesn't pray his prayer.
If he tells us we stone the
adulterer, we stone the
adulterer, only because
our Lord told us to.
That's all.
Whatever our Lord told
us, we follow.
ANJEM: [ARABIC GREETING].
We're going to eat downstairs.
I've brought some
crew with me.
You don't mind, do you?
MAN 3: Have you seen
this before?
MAN 4: That's the American major
in the army who turned
on his colleagues.
ANJEM: Well I don't think
he went crazy.
I think he woke up to his
reality as a Muslim.
And he realized that
[INAUDIBLE], in fact, his
so-called fallen comrades were
going and occupying Muslim
land, killing innocent men,
women, and children.
And it's something that he
could not handle, when he
realized that he has
a responsibility.
And he probably did what I think
many other people may do
within the US army and the
British army, even, if they
continue with their
foreign policy.
It is a very severe lesson for
the British and the Americans
in Afghanistan, that the Afghan
police are killing them.
And even their own comrades
are killing them.
So they need to pull out.
They cannot possibly win.
I don't feel sorry at all
for the non-Muslims.
Because Allah said in
the Koran, he said,
[SPEAKING ARABIC].
He said, don't feel sorry
for the non Muslims.
Allah destined for them
not to embrace Islam.
He destined for them to
die as non-Muslims.
go to the hellfire.
So why should I feel sorry for
people who ended up like that?
MAN 5: Is that chocolate?
What, chocolate's
your favorite?
MAN 4: When we're eating, at
the end of it, we lick the
fingers, as the prophets
did then.
And Muslim scientists have found
that these three fingers
release a chemical.
And when it gets to our
[INAUDIBLE] system, it helps
us digest the food.
ANJEM: Do you feel
enlightened?
You're not going to look at
a Muslim the same now?
INTERVIEWER: In the press
you come across as
quite scary, guys.
ANJEM: I am a quite scary guy,
for people who don't believe,
who believe that they
can occupy our land.
And they can just discriminate
against
Muslims, we're very scary.
But for those people who believe
that we can live
together under divine
law, we're not very
scary at all, really.
If you broke wind, that would be
a natural bodily functions.
If we did, they'd have Hans Blix
down here, seeing if it's
a weapon of mass destruction
of some kind.
[LAUGHTER]