It's inefficient to put a
kitchen in every bedroom
on the ocean liner.
Do you understand that?
They have areas set
aside for that.
They have a nurse, several
nurses, on the ocean liner
but what does a nurse do?
A nurse can bandage.
She can close in surgery.
There's no reason why
the future will not have automated
systems for doing that.
They can invite a doctor
from any area of the globe
on board that boat.
They can invite him
as a virtual image or
as a symbol manipulator
and that doctor can study the
condition without being there.
You have a totally different system.
That's why I use the term
'total enclosure systems'.
Each building generates
its own electricity.
It provides for all human needs
and even grows or prepares
food in the building.
Today you have places
where you have fast food.
You have 15 cooks and
waitresses and all that.
In the future, you'll be
able to extrude the food
very rapidly with no people at all.
You don't need people.
You don't need waitresses,
cooks, and all.
What you need is
the food handled
the way the food is handled
by people, only much faster.
Remember, it takes a
doctor time to diagnose.
He's got to study the symbols and
tell what the problem might be.
Scanning by machine
is very fast.
I can't tell you exactly what
hospitals will look like
or what the cities
will look like.
Although we know that beds
would be very similar
only they'd be more flexible.
Not only that, the bed will
have monitors built-in.
If there's any kind of emergency,
the bed can stimulate you
out of that emergency and call for
help without you even knowing it.
If you have palpitations or
unusual physical conditions
while you're asleep, a
staff would arrive.
When I say 'total
enclosure' I mean
methods for dealing with all
problems that humans might have.
Does that mean there won't
be a kitchen in every home?
There will be, during
the transition.
Until we realize, instead
of having 5,000 homes
with 5,000 sinks and 5,000 ovens
and refrigerators, you have
gigantic refrigerators
and a food preparation system.
Do you understand that?
It will not be like it is today.
When people look at these
cities that I drew up here
they picture
conventional approaches:
a bedroom, a kitchen, a
dining room, a dining area
because you have
people over for lunch
the same value systems
we have today.
I would say that this is
where the future is going
and the future design would
depend on how far into the future
and how far technology has gone.
When they can read symbols
and make diagnosis
when a machine can do drafting
instead of thousands of draftsmen...
A machine can do drafting
much faster than man.
It can scan those lines in
if you put in the specifications
of what you want.
If you want a hospital to
house a thousand people
with the most
economical structures
which have built-in heating
and cooling systems
all that can be stored
in information systems.
The building can probably
be forthcoming in minutes
than rather hours that it
takes draftsmen to do it
and the amount of draftsmen and the
amount of space allotted for things
will not be the same.
If you took an industrial area
with movable walls
and if some manufacturing
process needed
the production of
100 aerocars a day
that space could be assembled.
The movable walls could move to
accommodate the production methods.
If the production methods are
faster two years from now
the walls come together,
the factory is smaller
and the production
rate is higher.
Whatever you have today: ovens,
kitchens; all those things
will be smaller in the future,
produce things much faster
and not occupy the same space.
When you say "How much space
do you need for hospitals?"
It depends: If people eat
nutritious food, do exercise
you don't have many hospitals.
I can't tell you exactly what
the hospital space will be
or how technical they will be.
I can only say this:
The future will occupy much
less space for the same turnout
and that's the message.
If you try to design a city
with a hundred drafting
tables in it, or 30 machines
that is with today's thinking.
And the building will get...
The zone that creates that
will be smaller and
have less people.
Instead of having generalists
where the doctor is a
generalist and he knows
everything from neurology
to other physical problems
it's much easier to have
computers with that information.
Not only do they scan you and
record it in symbolic logic
what the condition
is, it is then read.
Instead of doctors, it's read
by a machine, very rapidly
and then the appropriate action
can be taken by a machine
if it's surgery or
whatever else is required.
To sit down and design
a surgical system
based on today's values
and today's methodology
would be inappropriate
for the future.
A city of that size will
do ten times the work
that a city today of
the same size does.
That's why I can't give
you an exact description
of what hospitals will be like,
only an overview, in general.
A ship is a total
enclosure system.
A passenger liner that has
a thousand passengers
has hospital equipment, cooking,
dining areas, sleeping areas
air conditioned, children's room,
and nurses take care of children.
It has everything that a
thousand passengers may need.
Do you understand that?
A ship is almost a total enclosure system.
It doesn't generate
its own energy.
It uses machines, diesel engines
to generate electricity to
operate the generators.
In the future, the
surface of the ship
will supply the energy needed.
The wave power
and the surrounding area
will supply that ship
with the energy it needs
rather than require input.
Most of the buildings that
I draw that you see there
can be put in the cities of the
future on the outer perimeter.
You need not... You can use the same
basic drawings that I have today
but trying to fill in the
buildings, as to what's in them
I'd rather not divulge
that specific information.
I can go into specifics
but they would only
serve temporarily.
The method of delivery of
people or moving people
depends on the
technology of the future
and it depends on how easy
it is to move people.
If you have total enclosure
systems, it means each system
is self-operating.
It doesn't depend on central power
but they're all connected
to the central computer
and they're connected to all
events in other cities.
If the city system
mechanisms fail
other mechanisms take over
and notify the
appropriate people
or the appropriate machines
to carry out a given task.
They took all kinds of
cardiograms of me today
and then it goes to
the cardiologist.
The blood test is divided
into different systems
where people with microscopes
analyze the blood.
Whatever they see,
they draw conclusions.
If it's symbolic rather than
visual, they draw conclusions.
Machines can draw the same
conclusions and many more.
(Roxanne) They've had experiments
where they've given the same blood
to many different labs and they
drew up different conclusions.
- I know, because their equipment
varies in sensitivity, sometimes
and the time period, the
temperature and other variables
which are not controlled.
Also the profit motive
affects how late their
equipment is, how modern.
People are more concerned
with how many customers
or how many clients they've had.
The future concern is:
optimizing human performance
which is very different,
or equipment performance
making it date optimal
and all information's
available and no patents
so you can use the latest information
in designing your machinery.
You can correspond with people that
know more about it than you do
or you can correspond with machines
that know more about it than you do.
I can't say.
It depends on when it's built.
"Total Enclosure Systems" from Series 4
(DVD or CD); Lecture Series 2010-2011