that's no longer the case. First of all we've
had this car the BMW M1359 and now AMG have
got in on the act with this, the A45 - with
a 2.0-litre turbocharged engine and four-wheel
drive, it's going to be a stern rival for
the BMW. But which is going to be the most
fun and which is going to be fastest? We'll
let's have an Auto Express track battle to
find out. Okay so we're going to start with
the BMW, reason being is that this car is
the benchmark really, so if the AMG is going
to become the best of the pair it's going
to have to beat this car. We've driven this
car before -in fact we've done a track battle
in it before - and it's really rather special.
Six cylinder engine, rear-wheel drive. The
engine is a real gem, revs to 7000rpm but
peak torque is at just 1300rpm so it's just
got instant power and it's just so silky smooth.
You can have a manual in this car, but we've
got the automatic gearbox. Eight speed, so
it's quite a short ratio, you don't find yourself
using second gear box. It's rear-wheel drive
so that's one area where the Mercedes has
got the advantage. It has less power than
Mercedes but identical torque, it's a little
bit lighter as well. It's going to be really
interesting to see which comes out on top,
it's going to be really close I think. This
is just a joy to drive though, so rear-wheel
drive we can play around with this through
this long corner can start to get it slighting,
massive long oversteer slides - can't do that
in four-wheel drive Mercedes. Obviously that
isn't quick, we're gonna come around now and
start a clean fine lap, to see how fast the
BMW is and see if it's a benchmark the Mercedes
can beat. On the road the BMW's really nice
to drive, great steering really engaging to
drive and good fun on track as well. Time
to concentrate on a lap time. A little bit
of roll in the BMW, not completely tied down
the body. The car is working quite hard, can
feel there's a six-cylinder in there it's
a little bit heavy. When you're being smooth
traction is pretty good, hard on brakes here,
down through the gears. Only need to use third
don't need to use second. Nearly nudging 100mph,
hard on breaks here down to third gear. Hard
on brakes, carry momentum here, try not to
get any oversteer. Little bit of understeer
on the exit, up to fourth. Really worth the
drive, and across the line. Okay so how does
the Mercedes stack up? Well for starters it's
£5000 more than the BMW, so that's something
to think about. It's got 40bhp more but same
torque. 2.0-litre turbocharged engine four-wheel
drive. It's got a dual-clutch gearbox so straight
away you notice that... it's quite a fast,
aggressive gearbox. Which is a good thing.
The engine hasn't got the character of the
six-cylinder BMW. You also notice the body
control is really good in the Mercedes. Sits
a bit tighter on the road than the BMW, but
the flip side to that is that the ride is
really stiff. So it's a mixed bag so far.
The big question is: is it going to be faster
on the stopwatch? It's got four-wheel drive,
but it's not permanent. The system senses
when it looses grip and sends power to the
rear. Let's try a lap and see how we get on.
Crisp gear change down to third gear, in long
corners the Mercedes has quite good body control,
little bit of understeer, but helps when changing
direction. As we come up to the corner, hard
on brakes. braking similar in both cars. Little
bit of understeer towards far end of the corner.
Up to fourth gear, hard on the power, similar
top speed here to BMW just nudging 100mph,
down to third. One irritation with Mercedes
you have to wait later before going to downward
gear. Body control is good, nice and tiny
through last through corners. Little bit of
grumble through the brakes, nothing too bad.
Hard on power through exit, and across the
line. I spent the day driving a fantastic
day of performance hatch backs, but which
comes out on top? Well if you want to be fastest
against the stopwatch, with four-wheel drive
and amazing body control, you're gonna need
the Mercedes. But if you want to spend a little
less money - and I think, have more fun - then
you need to choose the BMW.