Steve Van Roekel, U.S.
Chief Information Officer.
[laughter]
And it is our
great pleasure to welcome
you here today both those
here in person and those
watching on live stream.
Today we've all come
together to celebrate the
Launch of the Presidential
Innovation Fellows
Program, a new initiative
that is bringing 18
incredibly talented
private sector innovators
from across America to
D.C. to work with our best
innovators for six months
on five high-impact projects.
These projects promise to
support entrepreneurs,
small businesses, job
growth and the economy
while also significantly
improving the ability of
the federal government to
serve the American people.
Today you will learn more
about these five important
projects and meet the 18
extraordinary Americans,
our Inaugural Presidential
Innovation Fellows who've
agreed to drop everything,
come to D.C. in the middle
of summer, work incredibly
hard to do great things
for the American people.
And you can follow the
conversation on twitter,
contribute to the
conversation at #innovategov.
Steven Van Roekel:
So three months ago today
Todd and I
launched the U.S.
Digital Government
Strategy which is a
groundbreaking plan to
unleash the power of
innovation and technology
within government.
The goals of the digital
strategy were sort
of three-fold.
One was one to just have
great impact, to focus on
impact, and driving
impact across government.
Two was saving
taxpayer money.
We think we can do things
better, faster and cheaper
by unleashing innovation.
And three was delivering
government in a very
citizen-centric way.
Now given all of this
we've made incredible
progress the last
three months.
Today we are proud to
announce a few things.
One is the release of
"Bring Your Own Device
Toolkit for government" so
teaching agencies how to
use the resources to bear
to allow employees to
bring devices to work and
utilize new technology
within the boundaries
of government.
The second, and the census
team is here from the
Commerce Department, and
today we are very proud to
announce the launch of
their new multi-platform
mobile app that actually
triangulates census data
with economic data in
really interesting ways.
So I encourage all of you
to go and check that out.
But one thing Todd and
I really realized going
through this process was,
you know, just releasing
toolkits, just unleashing
technology wasn't enough.
We needed to bring to bear
the power of people within
government and that is
what today is really all about.
So based on programs like
our Entrepreneurs and
Residents Program we ran
at the FDA and other
places, and I believe the
team is here from there as
well, and programs like
Code for America,
a civic program --
Todd Park:
Whahoo!
Steve Van Roekel:
-- based on the West Coast,
you know, we, Todd and I,
on May 23rd, announced the
Presidential Innovation
Fellows Program which as
Todd mentioned was a
program that called on
entrepreneurs from around
America to come to
Washington, to pick up
their lives, to move, in
many cases, across the
continent to come work in
government for a fixed
period of time on these
focused innovation
projects.
Within three weeks of
announcing the innovation
program, we had over
700 people apply for
18 positions within
government and thousands
more had signed up to be
followers and follow along
and work with us as
we moved forward.
You'll meet the 18 today.
We're very
excited about it.
And then hear more about
the projects that all of
the innovators are
going to innovate on.
Todd Park:
And we were
just so, so incredibly
delighted at the
outpouring from folks who
wanted to come and serve,
who wanted to help the
projects, it was
just an explosion of
civic-mindedness, of a
desire to serve country,
you know, a dedication
to the nation's future.
And it was an incredibly
difficult task as you take
the 700 applicants, who
were amazing, and somehow
boil them down to just 18
folks that would actually
come to D.C.
to be fellows.
Many reviewers actually
told us in all their
careers in government
they had never seen an
applicant pool quite
like the 700 before.
In the end the agency
did actually select 18
extraordinary Americans
to serve as inaugural
fellows, fellows who
embody the spirit of
American innovation,
American entrepreneurship,
and could can be the best
ideas from the private
sector from across the
nation to bear on the
critical task of building
an ever more effective and
efficient government.
To say a few words about
the critical importance of
this work, it's my great
pleasure to welcome to the
stage Jeff Zients, the
Acting Director of the
Office of Management and
Budget and Champion of
Innovation on
Awesomeness in general!
Please welcome Jeff!
[applause]
Jeff Zients:
That's a -- can you hear me?
Good morning, everybody.
That's a tough act to
follow, Todd and Steve.
And I see Steve Case
here in the front row.
Steve's daughter Katie
and my daughter
go to school together.
And my daughter -- they're
both 17 so you can imagine
what we're dealing with.
[laughter]
-- but she
frequently, she frequently
reminds me "you're no
Steve Case," as I struggle
with my technology.
But speaking of
technology, having spent
all of my time before
three years ago in the
private sector, so 20 odd
years, I know firsthand
how important technology
has been to driving the
success of the private
sector and our overall
global competitiveness.
The President has been
onto this since the
beginning when he
appointed for the first
time ever a Chief
Technology Officer and a
Chief Information Officer.
So right from the
beginning the President
has recognized the
importance of technology
for our economy, our
global competitiveness,
and for our government
operations.
If you think about
productivity and the
productivity increases,
the year over year
increases in the private
sector, 1 1/2 to 2%
increase for the last
couple of decades in
productivity, that
compounds in a pretty big
way and companies that
weren't on that curve are
no longer with us.
It's hard to measure
productivity in
the federal government.
But the best metric is
some work done by McKinsey
which says that the
federal sector has grown
in productivity but slower
than the private sector.
So there is a gap, a
productivity gap between
how the federal sector has
increased its productivity
across the last couple
of decades and what the
private sector has done.
We all know that it is
wrong to assume technology
is the answer and lead
with technology but
technology at the same
time has been at the
center of those
productivity gains.
And we need to close
that productivity gap.
So central to closing
that productivity gap is
improving innovation
and technology in
the federal government.
And I think we have made
some good progress since
the very beginning of
the Administration.
We have great people in
the federal government.
The idea of pairing the
great people in the
federal government with
the best of the private
sector to accelerate those
efforts has me and all of
us incredibly excited
by the potential.
I think that this is, all
of us here, are present at
the creation of
something great.
We're starting with
-- is it 18 or 19?
Steven Van Roekel:
Eighteen.
Jeff Zients
-- eighteen, I think we will
compound in a big way and
look back and say remember
when we were only 18?
Because this idea of
bringing the best of the
private sector to the
federal government and
pairing our great
resources here in the
federal government with
the private sector is
something that we need to
be doing more and more of.
So thank you all
for being pioneers.
I am incredibly excited
by the early work.
And look forward to a
great future of technology
and innovation in the
federal government.
Thank you.
[applause]
John Berry:
Well, congratulations
to our fellows.
I'm John Berry, the
Director of the Office of
Personnel Management,
the people side of the equation.
And as everybody knows,
innovation starts with
an idea somewhere.
A lightbulb that happened
over somebody's head,
came out of a discussion, was
provoked by an observation
or inspired by a thought.
And innovation is only
worthwhile, I would argue,
if it benefits somebody
because it makes
people's lives better.
Because it makes
their lives easier.
Or maybe it makes
their lives longer.
And we can't forget that
from end to end, there is
always a human
element in innovation.
Now, we've tried to focus
on human-centered design
in our approaches at OPM.
We've launched our innovation lab around that concept.
And we are participating fully in collaborative
initiatives like this one.
And so that's why I wanted
to focus on the human
collaboration side of
innovation and the
reasoning behind the
Presidential Innovative
Fellows, Bill Joy,
a Co-founder of
Sun Microsystems, pointed out
what is now known as Joy's Law.
No matter who you are,
most of the smartest
people work for
somebody else.
Now, while we have great
teams in the government
already, and that was
proven once again last
week with the landing, the
successful landing of the
Mars Rover, which was a
phenomenal success, there
are also a lot of really
smart, talented folks in
the private sector, in
academia, and in
the nonprofit world.
And what if we were to
team some of these best
innovators outside of
government with some of
our brightest innovators
inside of government,
just imagine what we
might accomplish!
And that's where this
program came in.
We laid out five
challenges.
And we said, okay, who
wants to tackle these?
And as you've heard, the
response was amazing.
For the 18 fellowship
spots, we received over
700 applications
representing tremendously
diverse backgrounds
and incredible talent.
Applicants willing to drop
everything, move here to
D.C., and serve
their country.
And from that pool of
talent, we have assembled
the truly impressive teams that you're going to see here today.
You're going to see
what I mean in a moment.
People from nuclear
engineering, start-up
businesses, and best
selling books, these
fellows are brimming
with talent,
accomplishment and courage.
But before we introduce
our new teams, let me just
reach back for a quick
moment 200 years to a
British admiral, Horatio
Nelson, now famous for his
very brilliant
Naval victories.
He won battle after
battle, often outgunned
and outnumbered, and he
did it because unlike many
admirals before or since,
he didn't depend on direct
command over every ship.
And he didn't stick to
textbook tactics that
everyone had used
for years and years.
Instead, Nelson discussed
strategy with his captains
well in advance and set
for them broad goals that
he expected them to
achieve in whatever battle
they would find
themselves.
His approach meant that
when his fleet engaged
another, his captains knew
immediately how to work
together, react quickly,
and to work towards those
overall goals that Nelson
had set without waiting
for specific orders.
It meant more brains and
more creativity were
unleashed on Nelson's side
than on his adversaries'.
Now, we're asking
you the same thing.
We have set out these five
broad goals and we're
counting on your smarts
and your creativity in
figuring out ways how to
reach these goals better
and more efficiently.
New ways for our
government to operate
using ideas that right now most of us can't even imagine.
We're counting on you to
think boldly, fail early,
learn quickly, and above
all, dare to do great things!
Do good things!
And now it's time to hear
about each of our great
projects today and meet
the teams that are going
to be powering them.
To kick things off, would
you please welcome
Peter Levin, the Chief
Technology Officer of the
Department of Veterans
Affairs
and Farzad Mostashari, the National Coordinator for Health
Information and Technology
at the Department of
Health and Human Services.
Take it away, guys!
[applause]
Peter Levin:
Well, hello and good morning, everybody.
Audience Members:
Good morning.
Peter Levin:
We are so happy to
be here and to
kick off this discussion
of the Presidential
Innovation Fellows with a
conversation about Blue Button.
Some of you might have
already heard about Blue
Button but in the next
couple of minutes, ten or so,
we're going to explain
to you why we've done this
and what's coming next.
It's so exciting I can
hardly talk ...
but I'm going to try.
If you have a parent, if
you are a parent, you
might have a partner that
you care about or a pulse
you want to keep going for
a long time, then you know
what a pain it is to get
your medical records.
So imagine this situation
just as a "for instance."
You have an elderly
parent, an elderly mom,
and she is living in
Washington, D.C. a couple
months ago, she is
relatively healthy but she
has got to take a few meds
every day, she has got to
remember to do this every
day, and all of a sudden a
ferocious storm comes
along and knocks out the
power to her house.
Now, it ends up that
that's not really the crisis.
The crisis occurs a couple
minutes later when she
falls down and she has to
go to the emergency room.
And she can't
remember her meds.
She is not going to
remember the name.
remember the dosage.
She is not going to
remember the frequency,
how often she
has to take it.
And you know something?
You're not going to
remember it either.
Let me give you another
"for instance."
What if you're a doc,
imagine you're a doctor
and a patient comes in to
see you and the guy seems
okay, he seems smart,
he seems lucid.
He's got a problem, that's
why he's there, and you're
going through the medical
history and he remembers
everything, he has got
most of it written down,
but not all of it, but
okay, it's time for the
physical exam, the guy
takes off his shirt and
there's a big scar
right down the middle.
The guy says, Wow!
What's that?
He says, oh, my God, I
forgot to tell you, I had
open heart surgery a
couple of years ago . . .
you know, something like that would be good to know! Right?
So now we have these
problems, so now we have
these problems
of complexity.
So if you're a doctor, you
have got to keep all of
this stuff in your head,
you're dealing with
hundreds or thousands
of patients.
If you're a patient, you
may have dozens of doctors
and they all need
the same information.
And you know something?
The combination of that
complexity, thousands of
diagnoses, thousands of
conditions, thousands of
medications, dozens of
doctors, combine that with
paper and people, this
is a losing combination, folks.
This is not where
you want to be.
But I have good news.
The days of having to
remember everything or
remember where you put
everything, are numbered.
The days of having to
schlep around a suitcase --
I've seen pictures of
this-- schlep around a suitcase
full of the
medicines you have taken,
your surgical history, the
immunizations you and your
kids have had, the films
of your radiological
studies, all that stuff
is about to move from
physical atoms to
electrons as we're going
to put it in the cloud.
Those days are numbered.
In 2010, two years ago
this month, President
Obama announced that the
Department of Veterans
Affairs, where I work, is
going to make the personal
health record of veterans
available online with
something called
Blue Button.
Blue Button was and is
still today an
incredibly simple idea.
It basically just puts
electronic information in
the hands of veterans
safely, reliably,
conveniently, stuff that
we all would want for ourselves.
So in the words of
President Obama, with the
push of a button, your
records are downloaded,
and you can share them
with your doctor or with
other people you trust.
All we did really was put
the name where the name
is supposed to go.
Medications and a
list of medications.
Penicillin, even if it
wasn't spelled right, goes
in the medications part.
And sore throat?
Well, that's a problem.
That's maybe why you are
in the doctor's office
today, we just
listed that as well.
The trick -- this is not
a hard technical problem, right?
The trick really is to
break through the red
tape, the can'ts and the
don'ts and I don't wannas
and what about this and
all about that, right?
Was to make people
aware that it wasn't a
technology problem and
that the clinical, the
operational, the patient
impact was immeasurable.
And we did.
So you might say, well,
jeez, I mean, all you've
done is give some silly
ASCII files, the kind of
files that any person can
read on a screen or on a
mobile device, all you've
done is give that to
people and put it, oh, my
God, you put it in the
hands of patients? Really?
And yet that's
exactly what we did.
We took that file and we
said it's available to you.
And we've done it
now 1 million times!
[applause]
So just a few
days after President
Obama's announcement, not
only did the VA make their
Blue Button available, so
did CMS, so did DOD, and
shortly thereafter, a lot
of our private sector
partners are now making
their Blue Buttons
available, too.
Now today fast forward two
years later, thanks to
Director Berry's
leadership, all of the
carriers of federal health
insurance, all the people
that insure all the folks
that work for the federal
government, they're going
to make a Blue Button available.
Thank you, very much!
Large software companies
of your acquittance have
readers, large insurers
that you probably know or
even belong to are going
to say -- are going to
open up the floodgates
on that data.
Last month 80,000 people
just at the VA alone
downloaded their
personal health records.
That number is going
up and to the right.
And as I said, in less
than two years a million
people have already
used the Blue Button
successfully and happily.
Now, if you're Todd Park,
you say, a million people?
That's amazing!
We should have some
Presidential innovation
fellows to help
to make it bigger.
And if you are Dr. Farzad
Mostashari, you say,
eh, it's good.
It's a nice start.
Farzad Mostashari:
It's a good start, Peter.
It's a good start.
Peter Levin:
Farzad?
Farzad Mostashari:
Thank you.
Peter Levin:
What are
we going to do next?
Farzad Mostashari:
So now what?
The VA brilliantly moved
simply to be able to make
this information available
to veterans and as we
heard, a million veterans
have downloaded their information.
And where the VA led,
others have now followed.
So how do we take this
to the next level?
We have an MVP, right?
And for you startup
folks out there,
this minimally viable product.
But it's not
really a product.
We're not trying to get 10
million of some thing sold
or a hundred million.
It's an idea.
It's an attitude that
says it's okay to get
your own record.
It's an attitude among
providers of openness.
Openness means letting
other people help.
When you are talking about
open government, when
we're talking about open
data, when we're talking
about opening, that means
letting others help.
And in this case, who
are we letting help?
The patient.
We're letting the patient and the people who love them help.
So it's an attitude,
and it's an action.
Let's turn Blue Button
from a noun to a verb.
So I can say, you know, I
was talking to my mom last
night, I'm kind of worried
about her, yeah, she's
going to Blue Button those
scans, and we're going to
send them to my uncle.
That's what we want to do.
We want to make
it an action.
To do that, we're going to
need help to take this to
the next level up on three
fronts, that's why
we got three fellows.
[laughter]
Each of you guys have
got to solve one
of these problems, right?
The first is people, we've got to change those attitudes.
You've got to know that
you can get it and
increasingly today,
right now, you can't.
If I go all over America
and I say to one of you
ask your doctor.
In fact, ask your doctor!
Do that.
Say what's in my record?
Believe me. Trust me.
Trust Leon Rodriguez, the
head of the Office of
Civil Rights, it's
not against HIPAA.
It's not against HIPAA to
ask for your own records.
It actually is your right.
But we need to
stimulate that demand.
We need to have more
people asking, saying can
I get a copy of
my own records?
If you're on Medicare
now you can get a
copy of your records.
If you're a veteran now you can get a copy of your records.
Increasingly we're going
to work with those who
hold the data to change those attitudes and make it available.
Stimulate the demand, the
attitudes on the one hand
and the access on
the other hand.
And this is the most fun
part, well, it's the
fellow I'm going to be
working with, the most fun
is going to be not just
having it be data that,
yes, you can print and you
can read and you can have,
and you can share, but
things you can do with it now.
To have that data, that
information and the
incentives turn into
combustible magic
in the startup crucible.
To have people help you
use your data to do things
you want to do.
I want to manage
my health.
I want to connect
to other people.
I want to manage my
health care finances.
I want to get a
second opinion.
I want to find a
clinical trial.
I want to be able
to do things.
And for that we need to
not just liberate the data
but we need to make it so
that those entrepreneurs
can come in an openness
to that innovation.
And that's what
we're going to do.
So that's our goal.
Is to take the million,
and call it a good start,
and say how do we take it
to 10 million by next year
and a hundred million
two years from now.
So meet the Blue
Button Team.
I talked to Ryan
Panchadsaram on the phone
as we were interviewing
these phenomenal -- hang
on, I'm going to praise
you for a sec --
[laughter]
-- as we
were interviewing these
amazing, and it was like
amazing candidate after
amazing candidate, we were
like, oh, we've got to get
that one, oh, how
could we do better?
And then I talked to Ryan,
and, yeah, he graduated
from UC Berkeley with
engineering and he has
this real design
sensibility and he worked
on, he was in charge of
Microsoft Outlook for Mac
and getting that, all of
you all love that, right?
-- the design sense that
he won the 2012 Google's
International Design
Information Design
Visualization competition.
And he's this amazing guy.
But what got me goose
bumps was when he said
when I was 18, I talked to
my parents -- and we go
back and we started with
veterans, we go back to
veterans -- and he said,
my mom is a marine, my dad
was in the Air Force and
served in the Navy, and I
always thought that I
would join the military,
that I would be in the
armed forces and the service.
And my parents said to me,
son, we did this so you
could serve your
country a different way.
And he said, when I
saw the Presidential
Innovation Fellow
opportunity, I knew this
was my way to serve.
Ryan, come on up. Whooo!
Congratulations.
[applause]
Peter Levin:
So the guy who I deal with
a lot at OSTP besides the
CTO of the United States
Todd Park, is this guy
standing over in the
corner, John Farmer, calls me
up some Friday afternoon.
John is very direct.
You just do what he says.
It's easier, right?
[laughter]
He says, listen, dude,
I got bad news for you.
You've got until Monday to
cut the pile of resumés.
And, you know, there
were 700 all together.
I don't know how many were
Blue Button, there was 300?
I mean, there
was a lot, right?
And he says, you know,
how hard can it be?
Okay, 300 resumés.
Oh, my God!
The same experience
that Farzad has, right?
And then I run into a resumé which just bowled me over.
The guy's name
is Matt McCall.
I know this name.
I know who that guy is!
I remember reading
about this.
That wasn't the only one.
And you're going through
it, and what we didn't
about too much was that a
lot of what we're trying
to accomplish here is not
build proprietary silos of
secret code, of secret
sauce that only we have,
only the government has.
We're trying to make this
as open as possible.
Literally put it into
the public domain.
Literally make
it open source.
Matt McCall did that
already on the platform
that actually is the
driver of Blue Button.
So Matt, would you
please come up.
I'm so glad I found you.
Farzad Mostashari:
Henry, come up, too.
Matt McCall:
Thanks, very much.
[applause]
Peter Levin:
Okay, so that was
the easy one. Right?
the harder one was a guy,
you know, finally Farmer
is, I know he's going to
call me Monday morning, I
know this is going
to be an unpleasant
conversation, they mostly
are even when I have good news.
[laughter]
So I mean I've
got like the top three, right?
And it's really hard, I've
got this checklist, excel
spreadsheet, I'm an
engineer, right?
So you know you
model all this stuff.
And then I'm thinking, you
know, what I really want,
you know, a most abstract
thing, what I really want
is a guy who like knows
the provider/payor world,
that, you know, has been
to places that I've heard
of, it's like if I'm going
to hire somebody who I
don't actually know very
well and never heard of
before, and then I
get this phone call.
It's like, hey,
you know something?
You've got somebody in
your pile of 300 resumés
that you probably want
to talk to and the guy's
resumé was right in front
of me as I'm getting this
phone call, it's
like, oh, my God!
So Henry Wei -- please
come up and join us --
[applause]
-- his last
title at a major American
health care provider was
Director of Clinical Innovations.
But, oh, wait there's
more, undergraduate in the
ivy league, medical
degree from Cornell.
And this guy knows, this
guy has forgotten more
than all of us together
know about health informatics.
So can you imagine the
dream team, the people who
build the platform, the
people who are going to
stimulate customer demand,
and people are going to go
around to all the
providers and say, it's
okay, you can do this.
And in fact we can
do this together.
Thank you so much for
being here today.
We're so excited
about this.
[cheering and applause]
Farzad Mostashari:
Next up we have Sean Greene
from the Small Business
Association to kick
off the next group.
Sean Greene:
Everyone, thanks for coming.
I'm Sean Greene.
I run the Investment and
Innovation Programs at the
Small Business
Administration, SBA, and
I'm here to talk about
Project RFP-EZ which is a
project to make it easier
for startups to sell to
the federal government and
to make procurement of
federal I.T. better,
cheaper and faster.
So to put it in context,
I think everybody in the
room and those watching
at home know that
particularly in the world
of the web and mobile
development, costs have come down dramatically, 5X or more.
And personally as someone
who formerly was a web
entrepreneur and investor,
what I've seen is a
massive disconnect between
how technology is being
used in the private sector
and how it is being
used in government.
And I see that manifested
itself in the frustration
of entrepreneurs who have
tried to sell to the
federal government and
literally see a quote
there from an entrepreneur
who said no matter how
fast or better, and
cheaper my product, it's
just impossible to sell to
the federal government.
I see frustration in
venture capitalists who
advise their portfolio
companies don't bother
trying to sell to
the government.
It's too much time.
It's not worth the energy.
It's not worth
the bandwidth.
And if investors are
saying this, and telling
their portfolio companies
not to bother selling to
the largest customer in
the world, then we have
something
fundamentally wrong.
At the same time we see
opportunity and I will
pick on Todd as others
have to give an example of
when Todd was CTO at
health and human services,
a team within HHS came to
him saying, Todd, we've
got a problem.
We've got an
important need here.
The initial estimate on
the technology to serve
this project
is $5 million.
We just don't have that
much in our budget.
And so Todd worked with
the team, pointed them to
look at cloud-based
solutions.
And as a result of that,
the team was able to go
ahead, find some
innovative companies that
could deliver the solution
for just over $400,000,
10 X cheaper.
And so the opportunity and
the challenge in front of
us is how do we
replicate that.
How do we make that
happen more often.
And why should we care?
Because there is a
tremendous opportunity for
a win/win here.
For the federal government
the win is an opportunity
to save taxpayer dollars or get far more bang for the buck.
And with federal I.T.
procurement we're talking
about $80 billion.
A massive, massive
opportunity.
But it's also an
opportunity for the
innovative startups who,
by the way, are the ones
who create all of the net
new jobs in the economy.
And so as we -- as I've
traveled around the
country talking to
hundreds, more than a
thousand entrepreneurs,
and we asked them what
barriers they're facing to
growing their companies
and creating jobs, we
heard about things like
access to capital,
changing immigration
policy, And we're excited
about the success and
progress we've made.
But what I've also heard
is, hey, make it easier to
sell to the federal
government. Right?
People have told
me make it easier.
I know my product is
better, cheaper, but help
me get my foot
in the door.
And so the opportunity we
have in front of us is to
help take the success
story that I pointed to
Todd and let's replicate
that and scale that at a
much bigger level and
let's help a lot more
innovative companies get
their foot in the door.
So to understand how to
do that, let's start with
understanding the problem.
The fundamental
problem is complexity.
So here is how the federal
procurement process works
for the uninitiated.
It's all clearly mapped
out right there --
[laughter]
-- with, you
know, an example from the
Department of Defense.
So, you know, your startup
who is already working,
you know, ridiculous
hours, where do you begin?
Startups don't have
dedicated teams to help
navigate the federal
procurement process.
And at its core we have a
problem when the process
for $150,000 software
procurement works the same
way that it does for $150
million procurement.
More broadly as we think
about the problem what we
see is a fundamental gap
between the innovative
startups and
federal buyers.
So how do they find
each other, right?
Most federal buyers don't
hang out on TechCrunch to
find out what's the latest
and what's happening
with innovative startups.
The startups don't hang
out on Fed Biz Ops
or Federal Register.
Even if they know where
to find each other, what
we're seeing is they speak
different languages.
Startups don't speak
government acronymeese, right?
People looking to do
web development for the
government may have to
know how to search on
terms like "content information distribution platform."
So how do we get over
the language barrier?
And then how do we
challenge the issue of
just different
timeframes. Right?
The traditional RFP
process that works in the
federal government is three lifetimes for a startup.
How do we address
those challenges?
So our solution is
something we're calling
RFP-EZ. Right?
So RFP is request for
proposal, that's the
traditional way government
initiates a contracting procedure.
We're borrowing from a
successful example, the
1040EZ and the metaphor,
right, that we all know
that took something fairly
complicated and said, hey,
for a subset of the people
who don't need all that
complexity, how do we make
something easier to work.
And we said let's bring that concept to procurement.
Specifically we'll
start with federal I.T.
And at its core what
we're trying to do is
build a marketplace.
A marketplace of buyers
and sellers,
to bring together fragmented buyers and sellers to
make transactions happen.
And to the economists in
the room you know this is
all about lowering
transaction costs.
But to the entrepreneurs
in the room it's about
making it faster
and simpler.
So we're going to do that
by focusing on a couple
of different things.
First we're going to
focus on discovery.
How do we help the buyers
and sellers find each other.
With an opportunity to
leverage things like
online directories, simple
video demos of products
and services to help each other know what's available.
And as appropriate,
in-person demo days that
we know have worked very
effectively in the
private sector, right?
Because in the discovery
process you've got a
chicken and egg
problem, right?
If there aren't enough
government buyers, you
can't get the innovative
startups to come.
If you don't have
innovative startups with
good products, the
buyers won't come.
So simplifying a process
by which you can
communicate helps that
discovery process.
At the end of the day,
though, what we really
want to do is to drive
more transactions.
And so changing and
creating templates and
simplified processes for
easier transactions are
critically
important as well.
So we have a screen shot
here of one specific
module that the team has
been focused on that we're
calling statement
of work composer.
The whole idea here is a
simple templated solution
that creates statements
of work for
a specific procurement.
Why this matters is to the
program officer who wants
to do the buy, by
leveraging a template,
half of the work
is already done.
And they can get
it done faster.
To contracting officers,
they then know that the
language in this has been
reviewed by a group of
their peers to make sure
it is valid, legitimate,
et cetera.
And then to the small
business, it's written in
plain English in terms
friendly to them,
understandable to them
to make it happen.
So I point to a statement
of work composer not as an
idea of something that
we want to do, but I'm
incredibly pleased to say
the team is already ready
to ship this product.
So in the spirit of rapid
innovation, they said,
let's not -- no pressure
to the other teams --
[laughter]
-- you know, we
haven't shipped anything
yet, but the team has
already written the
code for this.
For the developer's paying
attention, they'll be
posting the code to GitHub
later this afternoon.
And very much in the
spirit of let's get
something up and running,
let's get people to kick
the tires, give feedback
and we'll rapidly innovate
and improve
things from there.
So with that as a segue,
let me turn to the team.
So we have a
phenomenal team.
So you heard the dream
team metaphor, there are
going to be all kinds of
great metaphors coming.
At its core what we're
really seeing is each one
of these individuals are
successful entrepreneurs
and successful
technologists.
So let me
introduce them now.
Let me start and lead
off with Clay Johnson.
Clay, come on down!
[applause]
So Clay is a
successful entrepreneur.
A founder of Blue
State Digital.
He also is the Director
of Sunlight Labs at the
Sunlight Foundation where
he led a community over
2,000 developers building
apps and functionalities
it helps to make the
government more
open and transparent.
He's a best
selling author.
Recently released the
"Information Diet."
And was, in 2009 won
Google and O'Reilly Medias
Award for Open Source
Organizer of the Year.
But most importantly, he
is the proud father of an
adorable seven-week-old
Felix, who is in the
house today. Felix?
[cheering and appplause]
Hey, quiet, quiet, clap
quietly, Felix
might be asleep.
And so when we were
thinking about what
profile do we want in our
innovation fellows, we
said, well, where can we
find someone who is not
going to be sleeping for
the next six months?
[laughter]
Hum. So, welcome, Clay.
Next I want to
call up Jed Wood.
Jed, come on up.
[applause]
So Jed is coming in from Chicago, Illinois.
Jed has more than ten
years of experience kind
of merging the worlds of
design and user
experience and programming.
Both critically important
to this effort.
He actually, at the
first-ever White House
Code-A-Thon, was Top
Mention in that effort.
Also a successful
entrepreneur, has led the
effort or started, created
a startup called LimeChili
that has already spun off
three different apps that
have been acquired.
And with a name like
LimeChili, we're going to
turn to him as
the brand guru.
And Jed lives in Chicago,
as I mentioned, with his
wife and two daughters.
To the metaphor that we
had before I only have one
daughter who, Steve,
is 13 going on 17.
So good luck with two!
And then finally I would
like to call up Adam Becker.
[applause]
So Adam comes
in from Oakland where he is
an avid cyclist and
lives with his two cats,
slightly less challenging
than the two daughters,
but we know it's work.
So, again, another great
example of somebody who is
a talented entrepreneur
and developer.
He was the founder and CTO
of a company GovHub that
focused on helping
stakeholders at the local
level improve
communications on key
issues of
important to them.
Has also had a ton of web
or despite his youth or I
should say probably
because of his youth --
[laughter]
-- but a ton of
web development projects
under his belt already,
and his first website he
ever built was for his
junior high punk rock band.
So everybody is going to
say that their team are
rock stars, but we have a
legitimate punk rock star
on our team.
So, welcome the team.
[applause]
And I would
also like to give a
shout-out to Ashon Wardak
who is somewhere in the
room who is on my team
at SBA, Ashon is also an
entrepreneur and
technologist who is the
point person working
with the team on RPZ-EZ.
So quickly, here is our
game plan, here's what
we're trying
to accomplish.
So in the short-term we
want to walk before we can
run so we want to focus
this effort on I.T.
specifically and in
particular on one targeted
sector web development.
What we want to do in the
next six months is build
an app and a working
alpha, let's run with a
handful of actual
procurements through this
process.
Let's have some case
studies that demonstrate
how we can save money, get better solutions for taxpayers.
And then let's create
the blueprint to scale.
Beyond that, what we're
trying to accomplish is
attract new businesses
into government contracting.
Save significant money.
And then finally, close
that gap that I talked
about, and Jeff Zients
talked about it at the
beginning as well, of how
the private sector uses
technology and
the government.
So finally an ask to
everyone out there here's
how you can help.
First of all, follow us
on Twitter, you see our
Twitter handle there or
you'll see it on the next page.
If you're a developer,
this is all on an open platform.
Check out what we're doing
and contribute on GitHub.
Folks in the federal
government, if you are a
contracting officer
we need your input.
Kick the tires.
Give us the feedback on
what matters to you.
Federal buyers, come in and be a beta buyer on the platform.
And to small businesses,
particularly in web
development, contact us.
We'd love to have you
participate and join.
So that's project RFP-EZ.
Thanks for coming.
We look forward to your
input going forward.
[applause]
And again on
any of these e-mail us if
you're interested at the
following e-mail -- sorry,
projectRFP-EZ@SBA.gov.
Thank you.
[applause]
And so now I
want to turn the mic over
to Macon Phillips
to talk about MyGov.
Macon is the Director of
Digital Strategy here at
the White House.
[applause]
Macon Phillips:
All right.
Welcome everyone, welcome
to the White House.
You're getting a sense of
why sometimes we call this
room the South
Beach Auditorium!
[laughter]
But I'm the halfway mark
so hang in there.
I'm here to talk to you
about project MyGov.
And project MyGov is an
effort to reimagine how
citizens interact with
government through an
experience designed around
their needs but
not our bureaucracy.
And to kind of give you a
sense of what I mean,
I'm going to talk to
you about Alice.
Just as sort of persona
we're going to use to
illustrate this, Alice is
married, she's got two kids.
She served in Iraq
for four years.
She's a veteran.
She started her
own small business.
She is in catering.
And she owns her own
home in my hometown of
Huntsville, Alabama.
There is a lot of
government information
relevant to her.
Of course, she goes to
the Veterans Affairs for
information about
her benefits.
She'll probably interact
with the Department of
Education for information
about student loans.
Of course, there is the
Consumer Product Safety
Commission that is going
to help her keep tabs on
product recalls and cribs
and all sorts of issues.
There is the Small
Business Administration
for information about
loans and other support
for her business.
And then say you have
got something like the
Consumer Financial
Protection Bureau that is
going to have resources
about her mortgage or a
way for her to
file a complaint.
She has to go to each
of these places to
get that information.
And sometimes, she may
not even know that these exist.
And that is a problem.
That is also just the
tip of the iceberg.
The government has all
sorts of things
relevant to her.
They are scattered and
they are buried deep
within this bureaucracy.
And that is the key
question of MyGov.
How can we identify those
things and bring them to her?
Now, we first tried to
tackle this problem with
FIRSTGOV, which whose
mission was to provide the
public with easy one stop
access for all federal
information and services.
And I think twelve years
later we can all agree
that FIRSTGOV was
certainly not the last dot gov.
But that is not to say
that websites are bad.
We have actually had some
really great examples of
websites in the
last few years.
Take the recent student
aid.gov that education
just put out.
It is a great example of
user centric design that
helps people find the
right student aid
resources based
on their needs.
Of course you have
got Health Care.Gov.
Which for the first time
you can find all of your
public and private health
care coverage options in
the same place.
And it too is
built around users.
Or Consumer Finance.Gov.
Here is a site for the
Consumer Financial
Protection Bureau that
offers a range of
resources to make, to
empower consumers and also
a way for them to
file complaints.
Each offers powerful
tools to the user.
And each is organized
around a regular person,
not a subject
matter expert.
With that said, there is
still more we can do.
These are three distinct
sites produced
by different agencies.
And although Alice might
end up at Student Aid.Gov
with her kid, researching
college affordability
options, she might not
know about some of the
benefits relevant to her
at Health Care.Gov or that
she can actually get help
with her mortgage at
Consumer Finance.Gov.
There is not an efficient
super structure across the
federal web space to help
her discover these things.
And of course as I said
earlier this is the
tip of the iceberg.
The web has brought
incredible efficiency to the
relationship between
government and citizens.
You can pay taxes
in your pajamas.
You can go research energy
efficient light bulbs or
laundry machines
at Energy Star.Gov.
You can even track
a robot on Mars.
All right.
So there is a NASA fan.
[laughter]
All right.
There is a lot to discover
and shifting that burden
from the citizen back to
the government is what we
are trying to do here.
But back to Alice.
I want to stress that we
are not here to create yet
another website that
Alice has to remember.
MyGov is a service that
goes out into the federal
bureaucracy, identifies
the information and
services relevant to
her based on her needs.
Brings that together into
a personalized experience
and that we can present
perhaps through it's own
stand alone dashboard or
perhaps in the contexts of
sites that she is
already visiting.
And this is a pretty
big challenge.
But the good news is, it
is building on momentum
that is already out there.
Of course, we have got
USA.gov, which does, has
done incredible work
laying down the groundwork
for how we organize
information around topics
rather than bureaucracy.
And I am sure many of
you have heard about our
colleagues across the pond
at the government, United
Kingdoms Government
Digital Service that have
made some remarkable
achievements with Gov.UK.
Now, both of these makes
search a central part of
their strategy and that is
going to serve as a key
component of ours
moving forward.
But our bigger picture is truly a no wrong door approach.
Where every federal touch
point participates in this
agency agnostic people
centered service.
And we are not just
solving for today.
This approach also allows
us to add a new dimension
as people's information
and needs change over time.
Imagine if Alice creates a
custom profile focused on
her interest, one that
enables notifications and
alert, if contents she saw
yesterday changes tomorrow
like a new product recall
or veterans benefit.
So what is this
going to look like?
In one month we are
planning to have a basic
prototype of the
MyGov platform.
In three months, define
this basic persona
standards for personalizing services and information.
And in six months have
at least two important
citizen and government
interactions using the
platform and a
personalized notification
center for government
services and information.
Now, this is the fun part.
Let's talk about who
is going to do it.
Kara. Come on up.
[applause]
Kara DeFrias'
enthusiasm for creating
great experiences is
contagious whether she is
working on the Oscars,
with the Gold Medal
winning US Women's Soccer team
[applause]
Or taxes.
[laughter]
At Turbo Tax,
we got her to come here
all the way from San Diego
to work with us on making
user experiences awesome
which if you ever paid
your taxes, you can
understand how it could
not be awesome.
But she knows, she knows
how to get it done.
This three time cancer
survivor has got a knack
for speaking to user in
their language, tapping
into their emotions, and
relentlessly pushes for
what is best for them.
Phil. All right.
[applause]
Phil Ashlock
is steeped in the open
government community from
years building open source
civic infrastructure at
Open Plans and sharing it
through Civic Commons.
As a primary instigator
behind the Community
Driven Open 311
Initiative, a service up
and running in a lot of
cities including this one,
Washington, D.C., he has
created, he has helped a
complete a common platform
for citizen services that
is revolutionizing the
way people interact with
government
around the world.
He has got a gift for
bringing people together
to solve complex
challenges. Ben.
All right.
Ben Balter everyone.
[applause]
All right, man.
This guy is lightning
in a bottle.
He is the kind of guy
that has been hacking
government from the inside
out already at places like
the CFPB, the Consumer
Financial Protection
Bureau, and FCC.
All the while pursuing
degrees in law and business.
Obviously, an
under achiever.
[laughter]
Danny,
come on up.
All right.
[applause]
So Danny Chapman
brings his award
winning design shops and
recent work at Rhode
Island's RI.Gov among
many other sites.
And he has got that rare
intersection of experience
with both design, but
also empathy for user
experience with
government services.
And finally we
have got Greg.
[applause]
All right.
So Greg has made a career
of creating products that
make information
more accessible.
Most recently he was on
the core team developing
USA Search Platform and
his idea of relaxing with
a movie is building a
custom application to
search I Tunes, Amazon, Netflix, and Hulu for the best options.
[laughter]
It is out there.
It is Cinidex.come
with an I.
Right. All right.
Cinidex with an I.
So any way we are looking
for ideas from everyone.
For example, are you
an expert in privacy?
We want, we want
to talk to you.
Providing a level of
personalization requires
knowing something
about that person.
And this must be handled
with a strong emphasis on
user permission, control,
and transparency.
Have you had experience
developing platforms like this?
We want to connect.
The bottom line is that
even though this project
is called MyGov, the
challenge is all of ours.
Yours, mine, and Alice's.
And we cannot wait
to get to work.
So thank you everyone.
[applause]
All right. All right.
And now I am going to
introduce Maura O'Neill,
who is the Chief
Innovation Officer at
USAID, Maura?
Maura O'Neill:
Thanks so much.
Thanks so much, Macon.
Hi, I am happy to be here.
And so excited to share
this platform with these
amazing Presidential
Innovation Fellows and the
awesome people that I get
a chance to work with in
this administration.
As Macon said, my name is
Maura O'Neill and I joined
administrator Raj
Shah three years ago.
At AID, the US Agency for
International Development.
USAID's development work
is a key component of our
foreign policy along side
with the defense work that
our military does and the
diplomacy work that our
state does, our State
Department does.
We know that our economic
prosperity at home and our
own national security is
at risk when one third of
the people in the world
live in extreme poverty
and a million more
live under oppressive
governments for which they
don't have a hope to build
a better life for their,
or their children.
Development as President
Obama and Secretary
Clinton note is essential
to advancing American
interests and solving
global security problems
as diplomacy in defense.
Our job at USAID is to
reduce that risk by being
relentlessly focused
on finding ways
to deliver results.
Faster and more efficient
than traditional development.
And humanitarian
assistance has done.
So come back with me to
that first week of work
that Raj and I were at.
It was Wednesday, it
was late afternoon.
And across, flashed across
our screens the
Haiti Earthquake. 7.0.
Turns out it ends up being
the most, the largest
urban disaster in
modern history.
It effected a third
of the population.
And it claimed all, nearly
a quarter of a million
peoples lives.
Since it was dusk, it
would be morning before we
could assess the damage.
Could we land planes?
Could we dock ships?
How were we going to
get help down there?
We worked all night.
It was the first of many.
We worked in lock step
with other US government
agencies and our
military to help Haiti.
The earthquake left a
government in rubble, an
economy in shambles and
people living in make
shift camps coping
with enormous loss.
It also caused
a cash crisis.
The earthquake destroyed
nearly a third of all of
the branch, bank
branches, and the ATM's.
But for over 90 percent of
the Haitians, who didn't
have access to either
one of those before the
earthquake, their life
savings went down
with their house.
Their cash was buried
hopelessly under thousands
and thousands of
pounds of rubble.
So here they were with no ability to actually buy anything.
So imagine for a minute,
what it meant if your
savings were wiped
out in a second.
Walk with me and walk with
the people in Haiti for a
second as we put
ourselves in their shoes.
Their house has been
destroyed, a loved one has
probably been killed,
everything around you
seems to have crumbled.
And because your entire
life's worth is your
assets and your cash,
has been swept away
with the destruction.
You have no ability
to buy food.
to buy water.
And you have no ability
to buy any supplies to
rebuild your house.
This cash crisis was one
of the least understood
but hugely damaging
effects of the earthquake.
I often think about this
story and think how lucky
you and I are to live in
a place that has a safe
place to store our money.
At AID, we know that
financial inclusion and
financial infrastructure
is critical for families
and economies to grow.
In our, in Haiti, where
mobile phones were the
only thing left standing
at the end of this
earthquake, we thought
what if we could turn
every phone into a wallet?
A cash register?
A bank branch?
President Obama had
challenged us to create a
world in which AID and aid
is no longer necessary.
This was the kind of game
changing innovation that
was going to be necessary.
Priya Jaisinghani and I,
she is the Director of our
Mobile Solutions Team at
USAID, lead an effort with
the Bill and Melinda
Gates Foundation.
The USAID Haiti office and
local companies to build a
mobile monies platform
in Haiti months
after the earthquake.
I was in Haiti just last
month and excited to tell
you about the progress.
The Haitians celebrated
the five millionth mobile
money transaction in
less than two years.
So we have a long way
to go in rebuilding the
country and people
rebuilding their lives,
but we have a financial
infrastructure that is
beginning to work.
To better explain why this
is important and what it
means, let me introduce
you to -- so this is what
a lot of the ATM's and
bank branches look like
the day after
the earthquake.
So let me introduce
you to Martine.
Before the earth -- after
the earthquake she had to
move 75 miles north of
Port Au Prince to live
with her family.
Taking only what
she could carry.
She made a living by
selling food, soaps,
sponges, and other
miscellaneous items.
She made a few dollars
here and there.
But she didn't have
anywhere to put it.
She carried around
a bag of cash,
she stuffed it in her clothes.
But she lived in
a state of fear.
Worrying every day that
a thief or a stranger or
maybe somebody that had a
little less than her would
steal that sum of
money from her.
This began to change when
Martine participated in
one of USAID programs
with Mercy Corp.
She learned how to use
mobile money and she sent
it back and forth with her
family in Port Au Prince.
As a result of the
training she received, she
decided to start using
mobile money in her business.
To more efficiently
collect fees, to deposit
her money in the bank,
and for her products.
Just like we use credit
cards in our businesses today.
Martine told us that
mobile money is like
a safe for me.
Like a safe,
it makes Martine feel
secure and empowered.
Like a safe, it keeps
money close so Martine
doesn't have to
travel to a bank.
And like a safe, it
enables Martine to grow
her business and
support her future.
Martine's story is not
that unique in Haiti.
And electronic payments
won't solve all
of her problems.
But it is helping
her in profound ways.
If you only remember three
things from this talk
today, I want you to
remember that electronic
payments reduce
transaction costs, they
reduce corruption and
violence, and they enable
businesses to grow.
And these are the
conditions necessary if
donors to create a world
where donors are not needed.
Now think about the
US for a moment.
The industrial revolution
wouldn't have happened
without thriving
commercial banks like Bank
of America, Wells Fargo,
and thousands of community
banks around the US.
EBay might not have been
the eBay powerhouse that
we know today if it
weren't for Pay Pal.
Our economy depends on
the ability to send and
receive monies seamlessly.
Your livelihood and mine
depend on the ability to
save, invest money, and
use credit and debt cards
in your wallet.
But we also know that
this kind of thing
just doesn't happen.
Think back to the history
of the credit card.
It actually took 50 years
for the credit cards to
really become
ubiquitous in the US.
People didn't trust credit
cards, at least they
didn't know whether they
should trust credit cards.
Not enough
merchants took it.
But we don't have 50 years
to wait to get people out
of extreme poverty and
create new markets for
American products.
So let's see what is
happening around the world.
The technology exists,
the innovation payments
platform exist.
And here is a picture of
the place in the world
that this is
happening so well.
And that is Kenya.
And we are honored to have
the ambassador to the US
from Kenya joining
us here to today.
Kenya's M-Pesa mobile
money product, 80 percent
of Kenyan adults use it
as a way to store
and transfer money.
And they have done this
in just five years.
Not 50 years.
80 percent of the
adults are using it.
But this is one of the
few platforms to
reach mass scale.
There is about 130
deployments of mobile
money and electronic
platforms world wide that
are stalled.
They are stalled for
various reasons.
But in large part they are
stalled, because there
aren't any anchor tenants
to this mobile money platform.
They are -- it is
a network effect.
There needs to be huge
volumes of transactions to
support the kinds of
agents on every corner
just like there was to
have an ATM machine
on every corner.
So we need to and can jump
start these efforts to
find these anchor tenants
for that mobile money mall.
Until today, cash was
the only alternative.
And for those of us who
live in the US, it seems
pretty easy, we go to
the ATM, we get cash.
We don't put our lives at
risk as we are storing our
money in our pockets or
have, or have to use our
credit cards to actually
buy things that are remote.
But at this unique moment
in history when technology
allows us to envision a
world where everybody can
soon keep their money
electronically, safely,
soundly and together build
a better and stronger
economy, that is
what we are about.
So I am so excited to
launch the 20 Percent
Initiative today.
Which aims to reduce 20
percent of the cost with
cash based programs across
the US government and put
these tools in the hands
of the poorest people
in the world.
At USAID we are proud that
we have taken bold steps
to motivate a change in
the way our partners and
we do business.
We continue to use our
budget as a force for
good, creating incentives
that encourage partners to
implement new
payment methods.
The Catholic Relief
Services in Haiti when
they instituted paying
their salaries through
mobile money, reduced
their administrative costs
by 60 percent.
So we think that
20 percent is a,
is a huge goal.
But you know, we have an
awesome set of other teams
here and we have got to
beat them on some metrics.
And Shawn released his
data today, so we can't
actually do that.
So we think that 20
percent is, is a great goal.
But we also as
aspire to do higher.
We are prouder still that
the White House wants to
expand this initiative
across the US government.
Like the Department
Of Defense.
Which has said it needs to
get cash off of the battle
field to keep our
soldiers safe.
In Afghanistan where
police officers began to
get paid through mobile
money instead of a series
of cash payments, they
discovered that they had a
30 percent raise.
They thought they got that
actually from the
mobile money company.
But in fact that was
actually the amount of
sticky fingers that were
happening from the time
the cash was deployed to
the time they got it
in their hands.
A really important thing
about this is, when they
were getting 30 percent
less, they were getting
paid less than the Taliban
was willing to offer them
to come to the other side.
When they got that 30
percent raise, the money
that they should have had
in the first place, they
were getting paid more
than the Taliban was
willing to offer them.
So if we don't think this
has huge implications not
just for disaster but for
national security as well
as Americans to sell
products over seas, the
effect of this kind of
payments platform, and the
efficiencies and
opportunities are enormous.
So moving from cash to
electronic helps us, helps
our security, it creates
new products, and makes
the world more safe.
So we say to ourselves,
well, this is so simple.
We thought this too.
We said okay, well, we'll
just -- how many programs
could we possibly have
doing cash at USAID globally?
We are in almost a
hundred countries.
Well, we had a 140
projects that used cash
because it is hard to
actually transport
anything else
around the world.
So we got into this and
we found this is actually
pretty darn complicated.
It sort of looks like
navigating this slide.
It didn't take us long to
realize that there were
deep challenges to
internal processes,
contract language, audit
requirements, internal
champions, and oh, yes, we
wanted to make sure that
terrorists and money
launderers around the
world couldn't actually use this new financial structure.
So we have been working
very closely with our US
Treasury colleagues.
And other things I
won't bore you with.
But it is a challenge that
cuts across the banking
industry, the payments
industry, technology,
consumer protection,
and a whole lot of other
sets of bureaucracies.
So the White House and us
went on a hunt to find an
entrepreneur with the
experience and skill to
join Priya, to join
[inaudible] and others to
tackle this
multi-faceted challenge.
So I like to introduce
Karl Mehta, our
Presidential
innovation fellow.
[applause]
We are really
excited to have him.
Karl is a Silicon Valley
based entrepreneur from
Fremont, California.
He is an engineer,inventor.
He started three
companies.
His last one, PlaySpan, he
worked -- that he sold to
Visa, he worked with
companies like Warner
Brothers, Nickelodeon,
Disney and Facebook.
So you may have actually
used if you brought,
bought some virtual goods
on those sites, or you
bought some real goods you
may have actually used the
payment platform of Karl.
So we are so excited
to have you, Karl.
And we think his expertise
is just going to be
essential to us
accelerating the
development of these
platforms world wide and
the efficiencies that
we can gain in our
development program.
So a minute ago I
mentioned that USAID is
proud of our work.
We are.
But actually if we are
going to move from a cash
based world to
electronic world,
we have to build a movement.
We have to build a
movement across the US
Government hand in hand
with the public sector and
the private sector
to get out of cash.
And that is where
you come involved.
If you work for a company
that does business over
seas, if you worship at a
place that does charitable
work over seas, if you
know an NGO that works
globally, ask them to
start using electronic payments.
Join us.
Build this mobile money
and this electronics
payments platform
and let us realize at
ProjectTwenty, the kinds
of opportunities that I
have described today.
So join me in thanking
Karl and come help us
revolutionize the world.
[applause]
So I would now
like to introduce my good
friend and most amazing
chief technology officer, for
the country, Todd Park.
[applause]
Todd Park:
Thank you.
Hello. I just got the news flash that the hash tag innovate.gov
is trending across the United States of America.
So join the conversation,
join the fun on Twitter.
So it is my great pleasure
to talk with you about the
5th and final Presidential
Innovation Fellows
Project, the Open Data
Initiatives Program.
And I would like to start
by talking about the weather.
Or more specifically
weather data.
So decades ago, the
government made a key
decision which was to
actually make all of the
weather data it was
collecting downloadable
electronically by
anybody for free.
What then happened is that
free fuel powered enormous
rising tide of innovation
in the project.
Entrepreneurs, who picked
up that data and turned it
into the Weather Channel,
Weather.Com, iPhone
weather apps, weather
insurance and much more.
Growing the economy,
creating jobs, and adding
a lot of value to
all of our lives.
Government ran a similar
play in the 80's when
President Reagan began
the process of liberating
access, civilly and
commercial access to the
global positioning system. GPS.
Which, of course, now
has spun everything from
navigation systems to
precision crop farming to
four square on your iPhone
and everything in between.
In fact, actually last
year alone it is estimated
that civilian and
commercial access to GPS
created $90 billion of
value for the American economy.
Growing jobs, growing the
economy, and improving all
of our lives in
immeasurable ways.
And so we love this play.
We love this play of
basically without
legislation, without
regulation, without
actually really spending
a ton of money, right,
taking data that is
sitting in the vault of
the government that
taxpayers have already
paid for, and Jiu Jitsuing
it into the public domain
as machine readable
fuel so the American
entrepreneur can take
and turn into magic.
Turn into all kinds of new
products, services that
help improve American
lives, create jobs, and
grow the economy.
So that is what the Open
Data Initiatives Program
is all about.
It is expanding and
accelerating the work to
liberate data as fuel for
American entrepreneurship
and innovation.
We are focused on
these seven sectors.
Health is actually an area
where through the Health
Data Initiative we have
been liberating health
related data, information
resources for a few years
now with hundreds of
companies, large and
small, taking that data
and turning it into all
kinds of products.
It will help you pick the
right hospital or doctor
for your family.
Connect to a clinical
trial that can save your life.
Help doctors deliver
better care.
Help you manage your
asthma, using the latest
medical knowledge
and much more.
We just kicked off in May,
a Safety Date Initiative.
We kicked off actually
a couple of months ago
Energy Data Initiative.
An Education
Data Initiative.
I see folks on that team
here in the room for the
Department of Education.
We will shortly be
launching an Impact Data
Initiative focused on non
profit sector related data.
Global Development Data
Initiative focused on food
security and
other key topics.
And a Finance Data
Initiative as well.
And the whole idea is not
just to liberate data. Okay.
Because data by
itself is useless. Right.
I can't feed
my babies data.
I can't pour data on a
wound and heal it, right?
I can't actually pour data
on a road and fix it.
Data is only useful
if it is applied.
So you do actually have to
make new data available,
that is actually
very helpful.
You also need to take
existing public data, that
may be available, but
in books, PDF's, static
websites that are useless
to a developer, and
actually make it available
in forms that are useful
to a developer. Right?
Bulk down loadable files,
you know, liquid machine,
readable data, accessible
through API's, basically
forms that are
usable by developers.
You do that too.
But if you just do that,
you have accomplished
actually some of what
you need, but not all.
And the last thing you
need to do is you need to
actually engage the people
that you hope will use the
data, will apply the data
to create tangible benefit
for the American people.
Engage with the
entrepreneurs, innovators,
spread the word about the
data that is available.
Get their feedback on what
can be improved about,
what feedback actually
would be useful to make a
new data resources
available so on and so forth.
Celebrate what they are
doing, spread the word
about what they are doing,
and catalyze a chain
reaction of innovation
that continually expands
the array of services,
products, features
benefits, produced for the
American people, produced
by entrepreneurs using
our data, in a way that
actually improves lives
and creates jobs.
And so what does success
actually look like at the
end of the day?
Success looks like Dr.
Pete Hudson, emergency
room doc and entrepreneur.
And Pete Hudson, in fact,
happens to be here.
What do you know?
He is on the stage,
Dr. Pete Hudson.
[applause]
Dr. Pete Hudson:
Well, thank you,
Todd, and thank you very
much for having me here at
this very exciting
event here today.
Lots of energy
in this room.
And Todd asked me to come
here to talk to you about
the perspective as an
entrepreneur from the
private sector who has
worked with open data from
the government before.
And it has been a really
important part of our
company and so I want to
tell you our creation story.
So iTriage was created in
2009 by two crusty old ER
docs who are unlikely
entrepreneurs.
The good looking one up
here is Wayne Guerra on
the left and the other guy
has a little bit more
gray hair now.
And we started the company
after practicing emergency
medicine for about 20
years and taking care of
about 50,000 patients.
What we noticed during
that period of time was
that people struggled
with the core information
surrounding their
health care.
That they didn't have the
right information at the
right time to make the
right decision and an
informed decision about
what to do about
their health care.
And that led to
huge problems.
Increased costs, bad
outcomes, and huge
inefficiencies
in the system.
And one day we just
decided we had had enough,
we had to do
something about it.
But we weren't really
sure how to do it.
Enter the Smart Phone.
Todd Park:
Should be.
Dr. Pete Hudson:
So enter the Smart Phone a
device that you can take with you anywhere you need to be.
It can access
data remotely.
It has a beautiful
interface.
It is easy for people to
use and you can distribute
technology wirelessly.
We called it our iTriage,
because we wanted people
to be able to make
decisions based on
information and based on
the taxonomy of health care.
So we started to assemble
data and we put together
clinical information, we
connected that to provider
directories, and built a
technology that allowed
people to start to work
through the pathways of,
of clinical information
starting with the symptom,
going to conditions, then
all of the way to the
right providers, and then
connecting directly
with that provider.
It was a very fun exercise
in building a product and
so we launched it
in the marketplace.
We didn't know
what would happen.
And you know, one of the
reasons I am here today is
because I think it became
wildly successful.
Millions of people
have downloaded it.
In fact, we are up to 7
million people right now.
Every month about it is
used about 3 million times
to make health care
decisions and to get the
information to make
informed, take informed action.
It has been adopted by
close to 20 percent of the
acute hospital
marketplace, and we have
added on functionality to
like appointment setting
and ER check in, urgent
care check in, and things
like that to connect
directly into the HIT
systems in the hospitals
and provide that data
right back to
the consumer.
It is -- it has been well
reviewed by people all
around the country.
In fact, we have had
60,000 people write in
reviews and it is a four
and a half out of five
stars on both markets.
We were so passionate
about this and drove this,
this technology as
quickly as we could.
In fact, from start up to
the first significant
M Health Acquisition in the
marketplace by Aetna, it
was about two
and a half years.
And now we are part of
this amazing group at
Aetna that is looking
at post reform business
models for health care.
And how we fit into that.
So let's go back to the
creation story and
back to 2010.
One of our employees
Jonathan White, who is
starting to work with
different sectors of
government came into me
and said, have you heard
about this Open Data
Initiative thing?
I said, no, I haven't
heard about it.
But it sounds interesting.
So we got connected with
Todd and others here in
the government, and we, we
found out that there was
great data, provider
data that we needed.
Federally qualified health
centers provider, Medicare
provider data sets, mental
health and substance abuse
data sets and they were
actually put together and
opened up by great people
in the government.
And made available to us.
We participated in two
different events and presented.
And I am happy to announce
that there has been
125,000 people that have
found federally qualified
health centers since
we started that.
About 25,000 people have
found mental health and
substance abuse centers
through our technology
with this data.
So we are actually really
connecting people.
But I think the two things
that I am proudest about
with this company are,
one, that we went from two
employees who were unpaid,
and I can vouch for that
because I was one of them.
To now 80 employees.
15 contractors.
30 open requisitions.
So for those of you who
are motivated, like to
build stuff, and are
really talented come join
the most amazing group of
employees at our offices.
I know they are watching
right now and they
are absolutely fantastic.
So that is one of the
things that I am proudest of.
The second thing that I am
proudest of is the number
of stories we have gotten
of people who have been
empowered by this
technology and made better
decisions from a man who
had jaw pain, didn't know
what it could be, used our
technology and connected
to, oh, it could
be a heart attack.
I am going to call 911.
It saved his life.
To a story I just got the
other day, a visually
impaired woman with
cerebral palsy, who has
multiple medical problems,
and is bed bound, who uses
our technology to become
more informed about her
health conditions
and medications.
And now can actually have
communication with her
doctor about the
different issues.
Those are the
things that matter.
So that is our story.
It is a story of American
innovation that is trying
to tackle a really
big problem.
So download iTriage.
And it took us 20 years
to take care of 50,000
patients and three to
take care of 7 million.
That is how technology
should scale and
make things better.
So thank you very much.
Todd Park:
Thank you so much, Pete.
[applause]
Rock on.
And so what is the play?
What is the Open Data
Initiatives Play exactly?
It is clone Pete Hudson.
That is the play.
Clone the story.
And very specifically
clone the actual use
of the data.
The application of data by
American entrepreneurship
innovators to create real
benefit in people's lives.
Right.
Help people find the right
doctor that could
save their life.
Help your daughter find
the college that will
provide the best
value for her.
Help a new father or
mother know what products
have been recalled, what
cribs have been recalled
so that you can actually
keep your baby safe.
Get transparency on the
non profit marketplace so
you actually put your
charitable contributions,
your hard earned dollars
into the non profits that
will produce the best
value socially for your money.
Real tools, real services,
built by American
entrepreneurs using free
government data that can
help make American lives
easier, make them better,
and create jobs and grow
the economy all at
the same time.
And we are so incredibly
excited by the fellows
that have come to town to
help our amazing team do that.
And so I would like to
introduce them starting
with Ian Kalin from San
Francisco, California.
Ian has a story out
of a Hollywood movie.
He started his
professional career as a
counter terrorism officer
for the United States
Navy, post 911.
He later served as a
nuclear engineer for the
fairly large boat the
Aircraft Carrier USS
Ronald Reagan.
After leaving the navy,
he joined, a fast growing
energy start up.
Had a brilliant
career there.
That delivered market
intelligence solutions to
the electricity
and gas sectors.
He is incredibly
passionate about energy
and empowering
people through data.
And he has chosen to give
up a full ride to Harvard
University's Kennedy
School to serve his
country once again as a
Presidential innovation fellow.
[applause]
Next
up Marina Martin.
Hailing from
Seattle, Washington.
[applause]
Another
unbelievable human being.
She has been a business
efficiency consultant and
a web developer, combining
two very high octane
skills in one incredible
person for the past
decade, helping businesses
save time and money
through optimization
and code.
She has written extensively about business efficiency.
She has worked on
open gov products
across Washington state.
She actually did the first
start up weekend focused on gov.
In her spare time, I don't
know how she finds the
time, she works with medically fragile foster children.
And she will be a critical
force propelling our
Education Data
Initiative forward.
So thank you so much
to serve, Marina.
[applause]
Next
up Nick Bramble.
[applause]
Hailing from
New Haven, Connecticut,
Nick is a lawyer who is
passionate about improving
how governments release
data and promote
engagement by citizens
and start-ups.
He directed the law and
media program at Yale law
School's information
society project.
And has done a research in
the realms of data policy,
privacy and
intellectual property.
Interesting trivia fact,
he also has been an extra
on several episodes
of Dawson's Creek.
[laughter]
And helped
build grammar learning
software and work prior to
attending the
Harvard Law School.
He will be a critical
force propelling our
Finance Data
Initiative forward.
Welcome and
thank you, Nick.
[applause]
Next up
is Raphael Majma.
Hailing from the borough,
Brooklyn, New York.
[applause]
Raphael is a
second generation Mexican
Iranian American who
transitioned from a career
path in commercial law to
pursue the opportunity to
use his legal expertise as
a passionate advocate for
the cause of open data.
He most recently worked
on the initiative on open
government data in the non
profit sector for Beth
Novak at New York Law
School creating strategies
for getting data unstuck.
He is an eager, selfless,
young innovator who is
dedicated to public
service, dedicated to
actually making data
more accessible.
We couldn't be more
excited that he is here.
He will be instrumental
in helping to drive our
Impact Data Initiative
which is focused on non
profit sector related
data liberation.
Thank you and
congratulations to Raphael.
[applause]
Next up Dmitry Kachaev.
Welcome Dmitry.
[applause]
Back in the
summer of 2006, ages ago,
way before it was cool,
Dmitry worked to design
and develop and launch the
first government open data
catalog for the
District of Columbia.
He was also part of the
two person team that came
up with, and launched and
help to run the very first
open innovation
competition around
government data, building
apps using government data.
He has also collaborated
with a number of big
American cities to design,
implement, and launch the
Open 311, API.
He hails from
Arlington, Virginia.
He will be a key force
powering our Global
Development Data
Initiative.
Welcome and
congratulations, Dmitry.
[applause]
And last but
definitely not least,
Nathaniel Manning.
[applause]
From San
Francisco, California.
Nathaniel is the director
of business development
and strategy at a
legendary organization the
tax base Ushahidi which is
a non profit tech company.
It specializes in
developing free and open
source software for
information collection,
visualization interactive
map, and actually played a
critical role in the response to the Haiti earthquake.
He is also a robotics
entrepreneur on top of that.
He co-founded and is the
chief operating officer of
Nine Cents Robotic.
He sits on the World
Economics Forum Personal
Data Tiger Team, on
Googles Data Colloquium
Team, on the Technical
Advisory Board for the
Rules which is an
organization dedicated to
fighting poverty, and is alumnus of Singularity University.
He will join Dmitry in
powering forward the
Global Data Initiative.
Thank you for your
service, sir.
[applause].
So please join me in
congratulating the amazing
Open Data Fellows.
And we are excited not
just about the fellows
coming to town, we are
excited about anyone and
everyone in America
plugging in who actually
wants to help.
So we are very interested
in talking with
entrepreneurs and
innovators who want to
learn more about our data,
give us feedback about,
just new data to be
liberated, and we are
interested in folks
unleashing their inner
pique and building great
things that can help
American people create
jobs, using open data.
Data owners across the
government as per the
digital government
strategy, right, we are on
a real, real movement
here, a bunch of work to
make the defaults data
open, of data in the
government open and
machine readable.
So we are really, really
interested in seeing if
you have data that you
want to liberate, make
machine readable, and turn
into goodness for America.
So if you are a data owner
that wants to join the
movement, opening your
data, please let us know.
And anyone who wants
to host, meet up with
entrepreneurs innovators,
technologists, wants to
code the thons(sp), we
would love to actually
work with you.
A lot of this is about
actually on the ground
engagement, actually being
out there, meeting up with
developers, meeting up
with the entrepreneurs,
and getting feedback on
our data, helping to see
what they actually do,
celebrate what they do and
catalyze more of it.
So if you are interested
in being part of that, do
let us know.
And you can contact us
actually at this Twitter.
Hash tag, you can also
you can go to White
House.gov/innovate fellows
and sign up to follow any
of the projects.
And stay tuned for more
opportunities to be helpful.
This team needs you and will
be looking for your help.
So thank you and
congratulations again.
[applause]
Okay.
Steve Van Roekel:
All right.
To close on the day I want
to ask you that join me
one more time.
I know we have been
clapping a lot, to thank
all of these great
Americans that have been
coming to work with us.
You know, Todd and I, the
leadership here at the
White House, the
leadership in the agencies
that we have talked to and
the President are thrilled
that you are here.
And this is an incredible
opportunity to do
incredible things for the
American people and, and
thankfully, we have as you
learned have incredible
people here to
help us do that.
Todd Park:
Again, it is an opportunity for
everyone across the
country to get engaged.
We have actually had about
4,500 people already
signed up to follow the
projects and contribute to
them in some capacity.
So here again are
the hash tags.
You can actually sign up
for email updates for all
of them at White House.gov
at/innovation fellows.
Stay tuned for
opportunities to plug in
specific ways and we are
grateful in advance for
all of your help.
Actually, it is one
additional opportunity to
engage, we'll be having
Twitter office hours to
talk about the fellows
program and the five
projects today at 5 PM.
And you can actually
tee up your ideas and
questions at the Twitter
hash tag, WH chat.
And now to close our
event, we would like to
welcome the fellows all
back to the stage with the
Director John Barry for
the ceremonial swearing in.
Fellows come on up.
[applause].
John Barry:
Okay. This is your
last chance to back out.
I am going to administer
to you your oath of office.
It is a solemn oath and it
is one that dates back to
the beginning
of our country.
And everyone who has
served our country has
taken this oath.
Our men and women in
uniform take the
exact same oath.
And so this oath has a
certain solemnity to it.
And I am going to -- you
will repeat after me.
I will begin by saying I,
and I will pause and allow
you to say your names.
If you would
say your names.
And then you have the
option to either
swear or to affirm.
And you can adjust
according to your conscience.
And then the rest you
just repeat after me.
Okay. Everybody ready?
If you would raise your
right hands, please. I.
The Group:
I.
John Barry:
Do solemnly swear.
The Group:
John Barry:
That I will support and defend.
The Group:
John Barry:
The constitution of
the United States.
The Group:
The constitution of
the United States.
John Barry:
Against all enemies.
The Group:
John Barry:
Foreign and domestic.
The Group:
John Barry:
And that I will
bear true faith.
The Group:
And that I
will bear truth faith.
John Barry:
And allegiance to the same.
The Group:
John Barry:
That I take
this obligation freely.
The Group:
That I take
this obligation freely.
John Barry:
Without any mental reservation.
The Group:
John Barry:
Or purpose of evasion.
The Group:
John Barry:
And that I
will well and faithfully.
The Group:
And that I will
well and faithfully.
John Barry:
Discharge the duties.
The Group:
John Barry:
Of the Office.
The Group:
John Barry:
On which
I am about to enter.
The Group:
On which
I am about to enter.
John Barry:
So help me God.
The Group:
John Barry.
Welcome aboard.
[applause]