JACOB SOBOROFF: The
biggest video of the day
has been almost a
year in the making.
Last March, champion race
car driver Jeff Gordon
took a used car salesman on the
world's scariest test drive.
MALE SPEAKER: You can't
go through that gate.
JACOB SOBOROFF: This thing
has over 40 million views.
However, some-- Travis
Okulski-- questioned
the stunt's authenticity.
TRAVIS OKULSKI: I
started to suspect about
on the second viewing.
JACOB SOBOROFF: So
almost a year later,
Jeff went back undercover
as an ex-con taxi driver
to prove to Travis
that he ain't no phony.
JEFF GORDON: Oh.
What?
TRAVIS OKULSKI: Sir.
JEFF GORDON: I
can't go back, man.
I can't go [BLEEP] back.
TRAVIS OKULSKI: No!
JEFF GORDON: I can't
[BLEEP] go back, man.
I'm sorry.
TRAVIS OKULSKI: No!
No!
JEFF GORDON: This
is our only chance.
We'll lose this guy.
TRAVIS OKULSKI:
This never works.
JACOB SOBOROFF: This
thing is incredible,
and it is getting
shared like crazy.
LIZZIE: Beyonce's super sexy
new video for "Partition"
just dropped this
week, and it's already
gotten over 13 million views.
But that's not
the only Queen Bee
video that's blowing
up right now.
Two beautiful angels
from San Francisco
realized correctly that
the only thing missing
from Beyonce's
"Drunk in Love" video
was a box of joe
and some bear claws.
[MUSIC - "DUNKIN LOVE," ADRIAN
ANCHONDO]
LIZZIE: Hang in there,
Reggie and Adrian,
because the Dunkin [? Deezy ?]
train arrives in California
next year.
JACOB SOBOROFF: If
you ever make excuses
for why you can't
do something, and I
know that I do all
the time, watch this
and you will be out of excuses.
Back in 2009, Jed McGiffin
was hit by a sanitation truck
crossing the street
and he lost his leg.
His ability to find
strength and resilience
in the face of an
incredible trauma
prompted him to
change career paths.
JED MCGIFFIN: It was a
transition, a transformation.
What I've learned is that the
ability to rebound and heal
is the norm.
When we're knocked
down, we get back up.
It's in all of us.
JACOB SOBOROFF: I found
this video so inspiring,
and I think that
you guys will, too.
MARY DOODLES: Hi.
My name's Mary Doodles.
I'm super excited
because today I
made not one, but two
very special videos
with "Convos With
My 2-Year-Old."
The first is an illustration
of the very short story of Tony
that Coco tells her dad.
MATTHEW CLARKE: One more story.
COCO FRANCES HARRISON-CLARKE:
I want to read it.
MATTHEW CLARKE: OK.
Go ahead.
COCO FRANCES HARRISON-CLARKE:
Once upon a time,
there was a boy named Tony.
He had no hair, no
sunglasses, and no seat belts.
MARY DOODLES: And
the other video
is the third in my
"SUPERPOWERED" series, where
you get to find out what
Coco's superpower is.
In addition to the
videos we made,
we're auctioning off this
fully interactive piece of art.
What am I doing?
There's a link to the eBay
auction in the description
below.
All of the proceeds are going
to the Angelman Syndrome
Foundation.
JACOB SOBOROFF: For
these next videos,
I'd like to throw it over to
our friends at the White House.
Always wanted to say that.
BILL NYE: Hey, YouTube Nation,
Bill Nye the Science Guy here.
And here is the White
House, at the first
annual White House
Film Festival.
Let's roll that digital medium.
JACOB SOBOROFF: The nearly
3,000 entries feature everything
from a group of students
3D printing a satellite
to a seventh grader
with lymphoma
who uses a robot
to attend school.
CHILD: Without the robot,
I would be in school
without any interaction.
I wouldn't see my friends.
I wouldn't be doing much at all.
JACOB SOBOROFF: Go over to the
White House's channel right now
and you can catch up
on the live stream.
I wish they had this
when I was in school.
MALE SPEAKER: Stump Earnest.
JACOB SOBOROFF: OK, Earnest.
Today's challenger is TMKSEditz.
"Earnest, find me a
video of someone dancing
while skiing down a mountain."
EARNEST: Oh, TMK, I feel sorry
for the mountain you ski on,
for this apres ski on skis
is about to blow your mind.
Equipped with
nothing but grooving
'80s tunes and the
desire to shake it,
this ski dance
competition might just
be my new favorite
winter activity.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
EARNEST: TMK, your
challenge was cute,
but it's time for you to
head back to the bunny slope.
Boom.
JACOB SOBOROFF:
Drop your challenge
for the champ in the comments
with the hashtag #stumpearnest.
Check back tomorrow for
our Saturday Oscar special.
We're going to have a bunch of
great stuff lined up for you.
Now play us out, Haim.
[MUSIC - "IF I COULD CHANGE YOUR
MIND," HAIM]