orange five million-year-old landed
still the moment
has come in shifting clamor
volcanoes erupt
glaciers role when received
the rest rosters foreign companies
resonating with his
pediatr
a little geological mysteries behind you
one of the greatest right p_l_o_ still
national parks in wyoming
sc
this is one of the world's most
geologically active please
five thousand replete everything
geysers and hot springs than in the rest
of the world comply
twice yellowstone
selected
how did it for
and why he in the heart of the rock
scientists studying yellowstone are
uncovering the violent past
by warts
crushed by simply chance
blasted by the biggest organic eruptions
ever known on the plane
even today
yellowstone's is one of the most
dangerous places on earth
yellowstone national park is one of the
most amazing places on earth
had
saying some of america's most stunning
scenery
wildlife that attracts three million
tourists a year
to understand we're yellowstone came
from
why it is so acted today
we need to take a journey back into the
distant past at the north american cars
deep into the earth's painting
sixty thousand feet up on the road
of mountain plateau
primarily with in wyoming but stretching
into parts of ohio
montana
park covers three thousand
four hundred sixty eight square mile
sixty three miles north of south
fifty four-mile
and it's a long time
most unusual
geological structures
warts and usual doubt partner
are the wildlife unusual
is the wide open space unusual
no you've got it all over the western
u_s_
what's unusual
it's a very unusual geology and created
a partner
yellowstone was fair
hundred as the world's first national
park because of
victory our dream
it's this strange geology that attracts
teams of scientists to the park
their task
to piece together the story of the
incredible processes that build this
unique extraordinary landscape
hiking indeed
into yellowstone's past
geologic history
yellowstone
goes back to the formation of the north
american continent
summarizing it was still
are two point eight
three point two billion your old rock
some of the police in north america
only by traveling back into the past and
we figure out why didn't this particular
location
there are two thousand four hundred
miles of river more than three hundred
waterfall
and the world's greatest concentration
ten thousand hot water springs
development models
yes vents
and guys
what did these features revealed about
this landscape
how it was for
the investigation begins at yellowstone
star traction
old faithful
it's a key clues to what's going on
underneath the surface
located in the southwest of yellowstone
park
geyser puts on an explosive display
every ninety minutes or so
blasting out thousands of gallons
scalding hot
yellowstone is like no other places on
earth there is so mickey coming out here
it's really singular phenomenon
flat fair and i did
will pay for his word back to life there
was an actually napping was recharging
the temperature of the water was
increasing missus was fresh arising
develop it was a rather complex plumbing
systems filled with patrons and conduit
think constrictions
rainwater saturating the ground around
the geysers slowly feels is underground
reservoir
hot rocks below ground heat the water
under pressure for around ninety minutes
suddenly some water spurts through a
tiny five-inch white crack in the wrong
this causes a drop in the pressure
within the water chamber
in an instant
thousands of gallons of water returned
to steve blasted up into the air
under pressure builds up enough steam
bubbles rise to the surface persistent
depressurizing senate collapsed
faithful shows that rocks below the
surface of very hot
scientists find clues to a violent past
thirty four miles southeast of the hot
springs
on the shores of the circular lake
called indian park
telecast
my job is to basically be a rock detect
them
and so i decided to determine what their
origin is and what they history isn't
that particular rock
okay now in this particular case
let's look at this
this track
when it started it was just a loose
saint you can just bring your fingers to
it
the solid boulder is formed from the
millions of individual grains of sand
microscopic analysis reveals the grades
have been cemented together by chemicals
and pressure deep under the ground
how did the rock get to the surface
morgan has chemically david the rocks
discovered in three thousand years ago
the boulder was blasted out of the
ground by the hot water explosion of a
gigantic geysers
u_n_c_
for a little longer
rock fragments
team in terry l
rejected i think i mean
as high as
he took five thousand feet
and their at some point material would
start with
running this explosion column
now you wouldn't wanna be standing next
to one of those
indian park
as the crater that the guys are left
behind
but fifties dwarfed by the crater morgan
has found it may repay
in yellowstone
stated this geyser explosions of
thirteen thousand years ago
so here we are one yellowstone lake
and it says you can see in beautiful day
and flights in plastic
on the floor of yellowstone lake it's
anything but quiet
morgan's research proves that geysers
were exploding around the lake and even
under the water between thirty thousand
and three thousand years ago
fantasizing jess that whatever was power
in numbers
but is it still active today
aclu comes from underwater events at the
bottom of the guys are greater
they talk about vast quantities of hot
water and gases
we
to find out what's creating the gases
gigolo eastern in his assistant collect
samples from the hot springs in the
center of the park
the final they use is designed to
collect up gas bubbles before they reach
the surface so that they're not
contaminated by four to three years
soooooooo
it is a very complex with the gases and
but we have a lot of tools that we can
use to try to unravels rather
complicated information
so will look at all of the gas is the
kind and caring for about the different
kinds of rocks beneath the ocean
and try to understand how things might
be changing from from week to week here
two years
defeat
analysis of the gases reveals that they
are a mix of carbon dioxide sulfur
dioxide
and hydrogen sulfide
it is the same mix that is found coming
out of altadena
but the final clue to what is actually
going on underground is found on the
edge of the same hot springs
sent the request crystals that we've
collected on the site of the pool
all their discusses what remains gets
pasta proposal but one-sided
consultant beautiful little quartz
crystals some of them have a little bit
of iron staining in other things
uh... that most most of the american and
said she was in the olympics here
quartz crystals like being used in a
moment of formed as a hot molten rock
lava flow
slowly cool after being erupted onto the
surface from deep underground so the
crystals a clear evidence that under the
springs is a volcano
yellowstone's hot water features all
going to one conclusion
yellowstone must be power
geysers only erupted the rocks are hot
enough to turn water into steam
gases from underwater have the same
composition as those from volcanoes
ports in the hot springs must have come
from paul ten o'clock
there is an immense amount of energy
coming out of the gramm
the six prayer
the guises the mud pots the hot springs
in the standards where's all that heat
coming from is coming from the molten
rock associated with the yellowstone
volcano
that leaves a big question
unanswered
this gentle rolling landscape
clears the ball
yellowstone's unique volcanic geology
is potentially deadly dangerous
it makes a crucial to monitor what's
happening under the ground
they yellowstone what do you know is a
very very active volcanic system and so
it really
requires observation
everything that we do here has a
research component but it also has a
volcano monitoring component
and that is is
is activity picks up here we're gonna
want to know something about the
plummets dancing
to try and project when yellowstone's
hidden volcano with the roads in the
future
scientists study it's geological past
predatory passed because to look at the
landscape
in reno
the geologic story and there's so many
clues and so much evidence here
yet that it's a fascinating place to
work
scientists began investigating
yellowstone
even before it became the world's first
national park
in eighteen seventy two
but observations of this astonishing
land began long before that
dating aged arrowheads shows that native
americans first lived here eleven
thousand years ago
their legends of yellowstone's angry
spirits who made the ground tremble were
passed on to her early explorers such as
louis and clark
later reports from trappers explorers
and mountain men like john coulter jim
bridger sold of geysers defiance in
defeat into the air and springs so hot
that meet was red lead kolkata
but these with ought to be told tales to
the eighteen sixties when geologist
investigated and found that the lava
flows and high there's which side
so volcanic activity
s
sts
tests
but something really wasn't liked
nobody could actually find the
yellowstone volcano
considerate know as soon as one of the
world
most active volcanoes
people come out here visitors other son
interest-sensitive what do you mean
oh... i don't see it
smoking volcano i don't see it
crater
all the things that one normally thinks
of for an active volcano
so without obvious signs of a volcano
scientists wanted for other things
they would find them
in the sweeping forests of launch cold
calling
these are the only plans to thrive on
the poor soil that comes from a
particular type of lava called right
away
yellowstone's constant plagues of
mosquitoes also revealed the presence of
that same right life lol
then i lighter
are you not very firmly involved
makes those long ponds and water that
member info away
knows her wonderful breeding grounds
with students
are a lot of status if you can see and
flying around my head
so the pine trees in the insects both
indicates that there's a lot of right
like in yellowstone
because while i'd love a creates
incredibly violent volcanic eruptions
that's much more like a bread dough it's
about a thousand two million times
thicker are more viscous we put a bunch
of gases
we can have a very explosive eruptions
but if the rial i'd love it that
explosive
how big a bang did it for today
to find that out scientist looks not
inside yellowstone park
within a faraway river valley meadow
creek wyoming
cutting down through the land over
millions of years the river has exposed
and unusual thin layer of plaque rocking
in the cliff face
nearby road cutting leads investigators
examined the mysterious dark rod
if you look at this airport indicate
what close
you can see that the here's a promise
fragment
these these
restaurants here fragments
and to pat if we were to make it this
section of this rock i look at it under
the microscope
you in fact seat compressed
uh... glass shards
the black later the geologists call them
sitting
is actually a type of glass
it's crucial evidence that the rocks and
soil here came out of a volcano
because of sitting in his support
boiling hot passion gas rapidly cool
under great pressure
and that's just what happened
when hot mechanical out
rollout across the land
deals in the importance of the very
bottom layer
from below and crushed by the way to pop
the agreeing on the top
national air the crash the city in the
head of free still
visible today
its base is characterized by this very
that dancin sitting in a citizen blow
came to rest and was compacted
and then above this dance glass layer is
their grades upwards into a tam sort of
region and continues up for about an
additional thirty feet and then up on
top of that
is expose today marshall has formed and
we can see growing up there three sets
of education trees and grasses and
things of that sort
study in the middle composition of the
proved that it came from an ancient
volcanic blast in yellowstone park
and there's only one way did so much
that she could have been blasted so very
far away
from its own
eruption must have been larger far
larger than anything ever seen by man
so big
scientists now label it as a super
eruption
we're looking at the statistics deposit
from a super optioned and yet where over
fifty miles source of the will be
eruption
geologists of recreated what must happen
here on the day the p_l_o_ so that's
good
can destined avalanches of ash raced out
of the park in all directions
services traveling at very high velocity
uh... easily over
hundred miles per hour crossed one
sentence
and february everything in its path is
extremely hot movie right
and perhaps is not a specific united
degrees fahrenheit
sewage wastes a pizza oven and it's just
very hot
someone would it have been like to be
standing on this five hundreds of
thousands of years ago
the date when the yellowstone ash cloud
roared over the horizon
that the impact of this would would be
in absolutely
unimaginable you would be i think you
would be dissecting culated
there and and and unrecognizable and it
would be very difficult to find any of
you
all of the evidence about the size of
the super eruption help solve the
mystery of the missing volcano
scientists realized that the super
iraq's and was so enormous
but it must have blown the volcano to
pieces
swarms of mosquitoes
show that explosive rial i'd love a
underlies parts of the park
subsidy in the last sixty miles away
reveals that nashville spread from miles
around yellowstone
thick layers of debris
confirm how gigantic an explosion this
must have been
problem now is the explosive legacy
physical volcano left behind
deadly dangerous to listen
deep onto the ground
for nearly a century after yellowstone
national park was established nobody
realized one
astonishing fat
at the park
is located inside one of the biggest
volcano creators on her
it wasn't until the late nineteen
sixties that american geophysicist
robert christians realized that rock
formations he had been studying for
several years all around the edges of
the park
in fact formed a giant circular free
he compared his findings on the ground
with a series of nasa pictures taken
between nineteen sixty six
in nineteen seventy
confirming
that the rain was the reason of a giant
crater
forty-five miles across
parts of the crater reimburse still
clearly visible today
but the other
edge is almost out of sight
finding the crater coincided with
another scientific discovery in a
totally different part of the country
in california scientists identified a
strange then later in any buried
underneath the modern days only
dash matched material from the
yellowstone crater
dating the soil layers proved that the
ash arrive six hundred forty thousand
years ago
scientists at last had a date
yellowstone super
gash was later found all over the
western u_s_ confirming the huge size of
the eruption
at least eighty times the size of the
eighteen eighty three explosions that
destroyed the island crack itself
and twenty five hundred times bigger
nineteen eighty arrests of mount saint
helens
the almost unimaginable sides of the
yellowstone last means but scientists
now with all that
a super lonely
but that creates another mystery
this peaceful landscape
weird is the steaming hot crater that
the volcano must have left behind
aim when you're looking at a press
toward instant also
rolling hills and entry
so obviously there's not a big hole left
in the ground uh... from the reaction of
the above the elston volcano so
something else has happened
one of the first processes was
instilling with all sorts of volcanic
lava flows
entity that's just down from the
landscape for dust recency one of their
all this blah blah flows that
happened after the sixteen forty
thousand your option
over hundreds of thousands of years this
flow has weathered insists oreo been
covered with stream
minnows we're in the born or a different
type of love and it wasn't
still bare of vegetation because this
love of was still a rough up until about
one hundred thousand years ago and
later love of was far less explosive and
more running cooled slowly
this move the harsh mohammed landscape
into yellowstone softer countryside
that made
when it first more tranquil
but there's evidence here that the land
was soon varied once again
this time by freezing snow and ice
the perot
the ice that polish the rocks has a
story to tell
it offers crucial evidence about
volcanic forces still shaking the park
to this day
its tail unfolds through the tiniest of
clues
scratches on the rocks reveal which way
the ice was moving
they show that lisa is always sleep the
same way
outwards and downwards from the vice
captain of the heart of the farm
the only conclusion is that something
pushed up yellowstone park
so much higher than the surrounding
hills the glaciers formed on the top
but what force could possibly powerful
enough to have raised yellowstone speaks
off into the air
the first clues to help answer that
question comes from yellowstone's
numerous persuades
whenever on the forms
the creaks and groans like astronomer
this violent but the creaks and groans
and since the earthquakes
the quakes are recorded by sized
monitors all over the phone
the earthquake monitoring is a critical
part of the trip because it's basically
it's the stethoscope that we have to
really see incense
the the heartbeat of the system
smith is investigating possibly
geological mystery
yellowstone has up to five thousand
earthquake cv
even though it's in the stable heart
the north american continent
scientists needed to know what was
happening underground to shake the park
so my
to find out
they plotted the precise locations and
deaths of earthquakes under the ground
so why are there so many quakes
the answer had to wait until the
mid-nineteen eighties whenever more
powerful computers first let's scientist
c
engineer
seismic waves burning out from
earthquakes travel rapidly through cold
wrong
but slow down
the rocks are hot
the burying wave speeds can be
translated by confusing
two color three d images revealing
exactly where on-ramp rising to the
ground
seismic waves propagate through the
years
just like x_-rays go through a body
so we use the same physics
to reconstruct
the structure of the general of the of
the earth beneath this seismic waves of
outlined the parks underground
structures
revealing a graphic history what's
happened upon the yellowstone
they've revealed this gigantic reservoir
of molten
rock which created yellowstone's crater
landlocked erupted out
the ground above collapsed into the
space left behind
and seismic waves still slow down under
yellowstone today
showing that the magma chambers still
lurks under the park
it's more than thirty miles long twenty
five miles wide ten miles in death
criticizing alters here two years since
bill for campaigns with sending liquid
rock managing
credible fifteen hundred degrees parents
this is the hidden feeding park
yellowstone park
moves give form to the ground above
explaining the fault lines in the
earthquakes the
and its heat ultimately powers all of
yellowstone's hot water food
print guys
subterranean yellowstone is getting a
bit secrets
seismographs reports thousands of
earthquakes in the park
the evidence earthquake waves reveals a
massive mac machine
under yellowstone sir
yellowstone investigation is far from
finished
because they're scared
another even more monstrous size
structure
under the park
by the beginning of the twenty first
century scientists investigating how
yellowstone was made had images of what
lay under the party
there was a problem
technology only allowed a view of a few
miles below the surface
then as more and more data was heading
to more and more powerful computers
there was a breakthrough
in april two thousand six geologist
publishing diagrams amman structures
quarantined under the form
more detailed pictures
resolves restoring
investigators all over the last time
sleeping monster
realized below millissa
snaking down hundreds of miles into the
earth
far deeper into the relatively shallow
magma chamber
is a colossal
volcanic playing
really sorry
howdy bingo
but they can picture it down to four
hundred miles or more
twice the distance between washington
and new york
smith makes an educated guess about what
the underground plume is like
our best estimates doesn't start doing
the physics and i
and to these things if such a conduit of
melted rock what the chimney
that should be called a hot spot
pumped up enough heat to build the rocks
of the crust and feel the overlying
magma chamber
which then erupted
blast out yellowstone's last crater
the malval
understanding of the crater fall
was an important moment for the
investigation
because there was evidence similar
russians that happened before many times
before
throughout the nineteen sixties various
teams of geologist studied the snake
river plane
to the southwest of yellowstone park
and found traces of ancient volcanic
craters
the crater rims had long been eroded
their outlines were confirmed by aerial
pictures over the following decade
there and in a straight line along the
plane
heading for the hearts yellowstone park
on average each crater was a couple of
million years boulder than its neighbors
investigators realize that these are the
remnants of earlier super volcano
explosions
unbroken chain stretching far back
to geological history
it seemed clear time after time
the hot spot that last bit of a civil
rights and
hot spot appeared to have traveled
things of mine
os yet another meeting
how could a hot spots
anchored to the core of the planet
okay
an important clue had been found in
nineteen eighty-five by american
volcanologists williams gosh he realized
that plotting the location of thirty
thousand earthquakes around yellowstone
produced an amazing patterns
the quake's traced out a giant the ship
on the surface of the year
the vichy wrapped around the hot spots
location
it seemed at first to confirm that the
hot spot was still moving
dribbling of the land around it with all
the lines and tens of thousands of
earthquakes
but the real answer is made with the
theory of plate tectonics
it showed that is the american continent
not the hot spots that's moving
and the chain of craters on the snake
river plane is there because for
millions of years
the moving american continent
has continually bush new land over the
stationary hot spots
what is the north american plate with
the forces source of that
that pops troop
loaded
and creates the hot spot track
assisted you're playing the also just
the active proponent of a
repeated hot spot explosions on the land
of make yellowstone
other hot spots have been identified
around the world
like the one that has created the island
chain olwein
only played for a hot spot has erupted
accounts
earlier explosions knew the original
mountain
histories
dandelions smoothed over with later
flows of more running amok
that was released from deep into the
earth's crust
multiple strands of evidence combine to
reveal yellowstone slumbering monster
gigantic hot spot
lying under the fall
quake maps show the hot spots location
seismic waves revealed the depth of the
flu
earlier craters proof regular super
eruptions
for millions of years
all of which leads to the most
question of law
we'll yellowstone iraq's again
measuring the amount of geographical
spread a bashful from yellowstone
superdrive produced some terrifying
thing
six hundred forty thousand years ago
eruption poured out around two hundred
forty cubic miles of material
enough to bury the home of new york
state tens of the d inaction
if it happens again
thousands will die
vast areas of the united states will be
buried involved can a degree
but when we get low stone erupt again
loops and when that next eruption will
happen
comes from investigating the eruptions
of the past
the hot spot punches out a super
eruption on average every six hundred
thousand here
six hundred
and forty thousand years ago
but geologists expect that there will be
warning signs before yellowstone
explodes again
volcanic eruptions are usually preceded
by an increasing number of her
quakes are assigned underground volcanic
chambers are filling
molten rock an expanding
stretch than before
land ball
yellowstone park usually experiences an
average of twelve tiny earthquake
tremors everyday
most urgent week to be felt like
tourists and register only on the most
sensitive sized monitors
but in early two thousand on
more than four times as many quake
started striking everyday
over one ten day period there were more
than five hundred points
some of the month of magnitude three
point nine
powerful enough to frighten the visitors
and with the scientists on alert
there's a second indicator of increasing
paul canning activity
molten rock
does inflating underground chamber
ground above
will rise
seems to be happening right now
unusual evidence to prove it comes from
an unlikely source
the waters of yellowstone lake
around one hundred years ago small steen
ships carried tourists on sightseeing
trips across the lake
but one of the ship's caught fire and
saying forever below the surface of the
lake
but now yellowstone's astonishing
geological forces have resurrected the
ship's remains from their watery grave
here we have absolved run down to a
wider level
and so this al says something about the
defamation and yellowstone
and basically what's happened is that
the uh... floor of the lake has risen
ringing the bell out of water
the reappearance of the rack shows that
land under and around the lake is rising
because of the expansion of the magma
chamber
even more alone
the rate at which it's rising seems to
be increasing
in geological observance
a huge area of yellowstone park is
positively soaring up into the air
faster than it's ever done before
the biggest uplift of all has been
recorded just a few miles from the shore
of the lake
there's a g_p_s_ system here
a much more sophisticated version of the
one in your car in
in measures not only the surface
position
but also its exact altitude
into with infractions of image
there's a small radio intimates here
from sits on top of this still ride
his entered into this route three or
four feet
so if the ground was opened and in turn
was opened
the g_p_s_ and on land on which it's a
good removing upwards
horrible for the
magma chamber
and beginning in late two thousand six
all area ground
started to rise
uh... the order of two to three inches
per year
and as our
sc soul system right here this is an
about that much
and it still moving today
and so we're really seriously pinko
stresses the deformation
the uplift the worst thing at this
station
goes the other thing that yellowstone
superbowl kato is threatening to around
once again
the question what lies in yellowstone
geologic future is fascinating
and uh...
all of my colleagues glow know the
answer to that question
scientists keep a careful watch of the
volcano is active
c_i_d_
sciences to understand the process
and so we have a responsibility
to see how the system is performing and
how it's working
confirmed that they were the store for
us to live of will continue after these
are folks after all it's what made the
system and there was no reason to think
that people who is in stock
yellowstone investigation has shown
at the park sleeping super volcano is
still alive and dangers
underground plumbing
reveals volcanic each
obsidian blast tells of a massive
eruptions
seismographs records thousands of
earthquake
one of the earthquake way revealed
terrifying underground chambers
reappearance some info
at the land is rising
ultimate yellowstone geological
questions remain to be answered
with the super bowl pinoy rock
once again
we know there is enough made me laugh we
know there is enough he we know that
there will be
fieldtrip works in seeking your stuff
we don't know
fissile
e another tennis
straw for corruption
for the investigation
is left with a deadly serious warning
on the time scale the geologists works
coming super eruption in yellowstone may
well be right around the corner
corner could be ten thousand
five hundred thousand years ago
devastating chapter
ever-changing store
how earth was made