I got this secret from one of my friends Patrick
who works in a West Indian takeaway in Uxbridge
road. And mate, it's amazing. Trust me.
First things first, I've got my chicken. These
are the cheaper cuts of meat, were got the
thigh and we've got the leg. Loads of flavour,
keep the bone on, that's what it's all about
you want to suck all that lovely flavour off.
I'm getting hungry talking about it. Right,
let's season these up.
Salt and pepper. It's a must, we're not putting
no chilli so any heat is going to come from
this pepper. We've got garlic powder. Make
sure you get every single piece of chicken.
Okay, with these spices. Some dried herbs.
It could be rosemary, it could be sage. I
like to use a mixture of all of them.
Let's getting exciting in there. Now look
at this, now this allspice. Now you can find
it in most supermarkets, okay. It's pretty
much an essential in West Indian cooking,
there's nothing else like it.
Now I'm just going to mix it up together,
like dry. I keep the skin on because I think
it crisps up nice in the oil. Alright? More
flavour.
That's what it's all about.
Now I would leave that fro an hour, two hours,
overnight would be ideal. But I'm hungry,
the crew's hungry, so let's crack on with
it.
I'm just going to shallow fry it first. I
just want to get a nice bit of colour. So
not too much oil. To be honest with you it's
only really crisping up the skin and it can
be finished in the oven.
Right, so. Let's pop this on, there you go
you want it as high as you can go. A little
tip for you. To see if the oil is ready and
hot to fry in, you want to just drop a bit
of salt in. If it goes crazy then you're ready.
Yup, he's ready. There you go.
Be careful use a pair of tongs, alright there's
going to be a bit of spitting. Because obviously
there's a lot of moisture in the chicken.
Do about three at a time because what happens
the temperature drops.
We're doing both sides. Skin side first. Lovely.
Let's have a look at this one.
You want it to go nice and dark brown. That's
enough because it's going to go back into
the oven. Right?
I've got my roasting tray over here and ready
to go in the left hand, tongs in the right
hand. Very important you don't mix em up because
look what happens!
Can't do it! Doesn't make sense.
Right, here we go. A nice bit of chicken.
Let's throw in a drumstick. Throw it in there,
have a little swim.
It's looking good, it's looking fresh. that's
ready now. Phase one is done. We've seasoned
it. Phase two's done. We've fried it.
Now for phase 3 in the oven, half an hour
180!
Oh yes, look at that! It's started to brown
up a nice bit there. See that? Nice and crunchy.
Fantastic. Bit of foil on that, watch your
hands on this bit here. Just pop that on.
We want to penetrate all that chicken in there
with the steam and the flavours, so it goes
tender and juicy. I'm going to turn this temperature
down because we don't want it to boil up.
We want it to just simmer away in there. Okay?
So 130, an hour.
Boom! See you in a bit.
Okay guys, phwoar! Beautiful colour, really,
really moist. That's literally just falling
off of the bone. Wow! That's why, what's why
you cook it low, that's why you cook it slow.
You can't rush art.Absolutely not!
Chipotle chilli paste. Really, really nice.
Just a splash of it in there. I like a bit
of spice, if you don't, don't worry about
it, just eat it like this. But I'm just going
to introduce it to all that lovely juice there.
Don't tell me you're not going to make that.
You know you're going to make it.
Here we go, let's plate up.
I've got this lovely little baby gem lettuce
here. You can dress that with a little bit
of oil just to be sociable. Let's get some
of this chicken in here, look.
Boom!
Wonderful ketchup we made, Banana and Guava
check it out. A little bit of that on top.
Just to finish it off, some spring onion,
lovely. West Indian fried chicken. Aaron styley!
Yeah!
Ahh mate, melt in the mouth, falls off the
bone. Easy to make. Guys, you've got to get
involved in this one. If you don't you are
a fool!
If you want to come to my neighbourhood, you
don't have to get a bus, just subscribe. Have
a go at that chicken, it is fantastic. Patrick,
you would be proud of me!
Now if you do like chicken, I have got another
recipe. My Lebanese street roast chicken.
If you want to see that, click down there
now. The way TV works nowadays. It's fantastic.