world, and the culture and
politics behind them.
This time we're in Kingston,
Jamaica, for
Caribbean Fashion Week.
[MUSIC  PLAYING]
CHARLENE: In June 2012,
Caribbean Fashion Week
descended on Kingston,
Jamaica.
Although Jamaica might not be
known for catwalk couture,
reggae and dancehall style have
become a worldwide export.
CHARLENE: Whilst dancehall
parties are probably the best
parties in the world, they're
also the place where you'll
find some unusual
beauty trends,
including skin bleaching.
CHARLENE: And girls ingesting
agricultural chicken feed to
get a bigger ass.
CHARLENE: Welcome to Caribbean
Fashion Week.
[KIDS SINGING]
CHARLENE: Caribbean Fashion Week
has been running for the
last 12 years, mainly without a
hitch, with the exception of
2010 when the whole event had
to be to postponed due to a
small war being fought between
the army and local hero/drug
lord, Dudus Coke.
This year's fashion week was
going ahead without a drugs
war in sight at the National
Sports Center in New Kingston.
The problem with sports centers,
is that no matter how
much hotel furniture and DHL
fashions stalls you set up,
it's always going to look
like a sports center.
Once the show is actually
started, the gorgeous models
definitely had their own way
of working the runway to an
eclectic soundtrack of Skrillex
and Bob Marley.
However, it wasn't until the
fashion stopped and the
after-show entertainment
began that the
catwalk really blew up.
[MUSIC - CONSCIOUS]
CHARLENE: As local dancehall
artist and heartthrob
Conscious took to the catwalk,
the previously prim girls on
the front row summarily
transformed into insatiable
dancehall queens.
In Kingston, dancehall nightlife
is omnipotent.
You can rave every night of
the week if you want at
imaginatively named parties such
as Mojito Monday, Nipples
Tuesday, Weddy Weddy Wednesday,
and so on.
To find out more, we were going
to meet a man who, to
describe as an authority on
the subject of dancehall,
would be an understatement.
We just spontaneously were told
we had an interview with
Elephant Man.
And I was like, yeah, cool.
Let's do it.
And then when we walked in and
I met him and I shook his
hand, I became completely
overwhelmed and I dissolved.
MAN: Love this!
CHARLENE: Yes, pretty man.
CHARLENE: I wore them
just for you.
CHARLENE: And what about trends
like skin bleaching?
CHARLENE: What for you is the
essence of Jamaican beauty?
CHARLENE: How are you
going to stay fresh?
CHARLENE: Back at the party, it
was easy to see why some of
these girls might cause
the men some problems.
Their outfits made their
bodies pop in
all the right places.
However, it was hard to ignore
an unnatural paleness on some
of their faces.
Skin bleaching is a
controversial topic
all over the world.
But Jamaica is the only country
where it has become a
subject immortalized in song
with popular dancehall stars
such as Vybz Kartel
endorsing it.
CHARLENE: However, this is not
the only DIY beauty treatment
causing a stir, as we'd
find out the next day.
[MUSIC  PLAYING]
CHARLENE: So we're coming to
look at this private farm in
someone's backyard.
A poultry farmer.
Now, this is obviously not
entirely fashion-related, but
you'll see.
Hi.
We were here to find out about
an underground trend that
started in Jamaica in the
'90s of girls consuming
agricultural chicken
feed in the hope of
obtaining curvier bodies.
Colloquially known as fowl
pills, they might contain
anything from growth hormones
to appetite stimulants.
And one of the key ingredients
is arsenic.
Yummy.
CHARLENE: How many
do you have?
CHARLENE: You're going to end
up as KFC, my friend.
CHARLENE: So girls put this
in their porridge?
CHARLENE: And it helps them get
bigger, just like a chicken?
CHARLENE: As this is an
underground phenomenon,
there's no actual proof that
this plumps girls' breasts and
buttocks the way it
does chickens.
CHARLENE: What's
nice about fat?
CHARLENE: Why is it better
to be bigger in Jamaica?
CHARLENE: Another thing, since
I've been here, one of the
fashion is bleaching skin.
CHARLENE: Do you bleach?
BOY: Yeah.
CHARLENE: Yeah?
When did you start?
CHARLENE: It's bad
for your skin?
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHARLENE: As usual, fashion week
was bucking the trend on
the street.
But if eating chicken pill
porridge for breakfast was one
of them, then it's probably
best left on the street.
I wanted to ask the models what
they thought of these
trends, if indeed they'd
heard of them.
CHARLENE: General opinion seemed
to suggest that this
was a matter of economics and
education, as these practices
are popular in low-income
areas.
My questioning was eventually
overwhelmed by the
excruciatingly loud Europop,
so we left fashion week and
headed back to a dancehall
party.
[MUSIC - LISA HYPER,
"BLEACHING FIT ME"]
CHARLENE: I'd heard dancehall
superstar Lisa Hype was going
to be at the party.
She was a protege of Vybz
Kartel's and fellow bleaching
advocate, so I was keen
to talk to her.
[MUSIC - LISA HYPER,
"BLEACHING FIT ME"]
CHARLENE: The dancehall may
initially seem intimidating,
like walking into an exclusive
club where everyone dances
better and is hotter than you.
But on closer inspection, you
realize this is an arena that
welcomes all sorts, just as
long as you get involved.
[MUSIC - LISA HYPER,
"BLEACHING FIT ME"]
CHARLENE: We make plans to
meet Lisa the next day.
In most countries, a celebrity
turning up at a nightclub
causes a scene.
Not here.
I was surprised Lisa's presence
didn't cause some
sort of hysteria, but not
half as surprised by
what happened next.
King of the dancehall, Beenie
Man, strolled in to break the
news of the death of
his father to the
unsuspecting crowd.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CHARLENE: So we've come this
lovely house on the outskirts
of Kingston for a photo shoot
for Lisa Hyper's album.
Lisa Hyper is one of the biggest
female dancehall stars
at the moment.
She started out as one of Vybz
Kartel's proteges, and since
he's been in prison she's trying
to reinvent itself.
Obviously, she's one of the most
influential female stars
of the moment, but one of the
main reasons I want to talk to
her is because she's one of the
few stars that advocated
skin bleaching.
LISA HYPER:
[UNINTELLIGIBLE PHRASE]
CHARLENE: Obviously,
here, fashion is so
tied up with music.
LISA HYPER: Yes
CHARLENE: How do you feel now
about being a role model to
young girls in Jamaica?
How do you feel about
that responsibility?
CHARLENE: People overseas are
obsessed with the fact that
everyone is bleaching
their skin.
Do you still bleach?
CHARLENE: Yeah?
LISA HYPER: Yeah, I still do.
CHARLENE: And can you explain
for us why it's so popular
here, because I think there's
a lot of ignorance and a lot
of people don't--
CHARLENE: I mean, for some young
girls I think because
the processes is not monitored,
you can't go and
safely buy the cream and there's
no real instructions
because there's no education
around it, do you think it
would be better if there was--
somewhere it was more
regulated so that--
LISA HYPER: Yes.
CHARLENE: --people weren't
hurting themselves.
CHARLENE: Lisa seemed
uncomfortable
with the term, bleaching.
Many people here prefer to
sugar coat the trend by
referring to it as rubbings or
toning the skin, making it
sound more like a health
treatment at a beauty spa.
CHILD: Come watch me.
[CHILDREN SINGING]
CHARLENE: After meeting Lisa,
someone who grew up in the
ghetto and is so influential
there, I wanted to talk to
some young girls from there for
whom the bleaching trend
is a part of everyday life.
So that one is when you're
at your whitest?
CHARLENE: So that's like
the lightest you got?
CHARLENE: At what age?
CHARLENE: Did people tell you
that you shouldn't do it?
It's dangerous for
your health?
CHARLENE: And who are the
people that say that?
CHARLENE: That's how
I clean my bath.
CHARLENE: Do you think, also,
the popularity of having
lighter skin comes
from the media?
CHARLENE: So what is
this chicken pill?
CHARLENE: And it works the same
you think for humans?
GROUP OF WOMEN: Yeah.
CHARLENE: Peritol.
The pills they showed me had
Peritol stamped on them.
These have nothing to
do with chickens.
Peritol is actually an appetite
stimulant for
depressed cats.
Chicken pills seems to be
an umbrella term for any
under-the-counter pharmaceutical
that may help
you gain weight.
Some girls aren't too worried
about what they are putting in
their bodies if there's a chance
it'll bring them closer
to their ideal look.
CHARLENE: So what happens?
Where do you get the pills?
CHARLENE: The girls then took
us into downtown Kingston so
we could see just how easy
it was to get hold
of bleaching products.
So where are we going now?
CHARLENE: We are in Kevin's
Haberdashery and this is where
the girls buy their
bleaching cream.
How do you know what
you're buying?
There are so many
different types.
CHARLENE: What do you
mean by risk?
CHARLENE: Because it's kind
of a bit illegal.
You can't just go and ask the
doctor what to do, you have to
try yourself.
CHARLENE: I'm looking at Vybz's
own brand cake soap.
WOMAN: [UNINTELLIGIBLE]
cake soap.
CHARLENE: Is it--
does it work?
CHARLENE: Really?
CHARLENE: So we just kind of
followed the girls into the
place where they buy the
bleaching cream, and I was
quite surprised to see it all
on display because from what
I've heard, I thought it
was kind of more of an
under-the-counter thing because
it's not legal.
So we were OK for a while and
then once the people who
worked there realized that we
were filming, they asked us to
stop because they thought we
were going to expose them.
So we've had to step outside.
CHARLENE: We managed to find a
vendor of lightening products
who agreed to talk
to me about it.
Generally, like any other
accessory fashion store that I
might find in the world.
Except that you sell bleaching
cream just like
it's another accessory.
What is it about being lighter
at the moment that is more
attractive?
VENDOR: Hmm.
CHARLENE: Despite the risk of
atrophy, stretch marks,
chemical burns, and acne, not
to mention the long-term
systemic health effects such
as Cushing's syndrome and
diabetes, many girls and boys
continue to bleach in the name
of fashion.
The girls we'd met were
unwilling to actually apply it
in front of us, so we headed to
one of Kingston's premier
strip clubs, Caesar's, to
meet a girl who would.
So the girls that we spoke to
before, they were really open
about skin bleaching and they
let us talk about it for ages.
When it came down to actually
showing us how the process is
done, they were a bit
uncomfortable doing it.
So, we've been put in touch with
a girl who works here.
This is a strip club in Kingston
called Caesar's.
I've got to tell you, she's
not a stripper,
she's only a hostess.
But she's going to show us and
hopefully give us some further
insight into why girls bleach.
What do the men here want?
Who are these girls here?
CHARLENE: So is this kind
of what the demand is,
lighter-skinned girls?
CHARLENE: So using skin
bleachers is logical, really.
It makes sense--
CHARLENE: Interesting.
Do you ever think about it,
and just wish that it was
different and the trend
was to be black?
CHARLENE: She took us into one
of the back rooms usually
reserved for more amorous
encounters where she could
demonstrate her bleaching
technique.
So show me what you do.
HOSTESS: All right.
CHARLENE: What do you think
would happen if I used it?
CHARLENE: Shall I try?
CHARLENE: It's definitely
a little bit warm.
HOSTESS: Yeah.
CHARLENE: So you would go out
with this under your clothes?
All day?
CHARLENE: If you have a
boyfriend already, doesn't it
interfere with your sex life?
CHARLENE: What's
more important?
Sex or bleaching?
CHARLENE: And even in summer,
like how it is now--
CHARLENE: Some of the beauty
trends we've seen here may
appear extreme, but when put
up against permatanning and
plastic surgery, it's just
another example of the theory
that making our self darker,
lighter, fatter, or thinner,
is going to radically
alter your fortune.
Fashion week had definitely been
a celebration of the more
positive side of Jamaican
fashion, but I think couture
will have a tough job taking
over from dancehall as the
flagship of Jamaican style.
And a good thing, too.
[MUSIC PLAYING]