This guy.
I'm Steve Spangler and I'm all
about making science fun.
For the last 20 years, I've
been teaching ways to turn
ordinary science experiments
into unforgettable learning
experiences.
I have an amazing team who will
do whatever it takes to
affect the way people
think about science.
And to do that I live by one
motto, make it big, do it
right, give it class.
As a kid you probably had a
whole bunch of these Christmas
lights, you know the strand
that breaks, and somebody
throws them away and you
figured this out.
You figured that you could take
a pair of scissors-- no,
not while it's plugged in--
you could take a pair of
scissors, cut it, strip the
ends off and get something
that looks like this.
This now, was perfect to be able
to learn how to use and
make circuits.
So you'd find yourself a big
battery, because you needed to
have a good supply
of energy there.
Because you never wanted
to hook up just one.
You'd want to hook
up multiples.
So you'd hang onto this one.
And this one would hook up
and use alligator clips.
And, low and behold, if you
completed the circuit, it
looked like this.
You see, as a kid, I
was easily amused.
You could do parallel circuit
and series circuits and
switches and whatever else you
wanted to but, in short order,
LEDs gave way to all of
this material here.
And this, was the new battery
and bulbs unit.
LEDs, light emitting diodes.
They come in all these different
sizes and shapes and
colors, and they run off such
a small amount of energy.
This is a watch battery, so
instead of that huge one we
had before, now you just have
this small little battery.
In this state here, this will
last 30, maybe 40 days
constantly on, and this is the
basis of today's project.
It's amazing what you
can find online.
I want to show you how
to make a throwie.
A throwie is a device that was
invented back in 2005, by
Graffiti Research Lab.
The idea was this-- what if
you could make light in a
device that you could throw and
have it stick to a metal
object and literally, graffiti
the side of a bridge or a
building, something like that,
using light as a graffiti
source instead of
a can of paint.
And that's exactly what
a throwie is.
Still don't understand what
we're talking about?
Take a look at this video from
Graffiti Research Lab.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Here's what you're going
to need, some LEDs.
Now, LEDS come in all
shapes and sizes.
These are 10 millimeter LEDs.
They're super bright and
they're probably--
I don't know--
$0.20, $0.30 cents apiece if
you're buying a bag of 100 of
them, in bulk, online.
To power them you're going to
need to have these watch
batteries here.
These are CR 2032s,
very, very common.
It's a three volt battery.
Again, in quantity, maybe
$0.30, $0.40.
You're going to need to have
some electrical tape.
And finally, neodymium
magnets, so
super strong magnets.
And that's what's going
to hold it in place.
So let's start by making a red
LED throwie and you're going
to start with the LED.
Now, these are 10 millimeter
super brights.
And you're going to open up the
little ends like this, so
that you can take the watch
battery and kind of put it
right in between.
No extra wires needed, just hold
it in place and it works.
If for some reason it doesn't
work, it just means that you
have the LED probably
reversed.
So if you put in place and it
doesn't work, it doesn't mean
the battery is bad or
the LED is bad.
Try just reversing it since this
is polarity sensitive,
meaning plus goes to plus
and minus goes to minus.
And it's ready to go.
It's just a simple
little diode.
It starts with a piece
of electrical tape.
If you pull off a piece of the
tape, you can now make the
throwie like this.
And you want to just tape the
leads in place around the
battery so it's making constant
contact and this, is
a simple circuit.
Now, I guess it could
be tossed around.
You could do something
with it.
But it's not sticky and that's
where the magnet comes in.
Well, to turn the LED and the
watch battery into a throwie,
you're going to need to have a
super strong neodymium magnet.
Now, these little guys have
become expensive over the last
year and a half or two years,
so that's the most expensive
part of the project, but you
really do need these small
little neodymium magnets.
Here's how it works.
We use the watch battery to
complete the circuit here with
the LED and then, we put the
magnet right on the lead so it
literally, holds it in place.
Now, this whole thing gets
wrapped with the electrical
tape and you have yourself
a throwie.
We have everything in place
now we just need to have
something metal.
That's where the trash can
lid comes into place.
And that's what you
call a throwie.
Now, you just need more.
What a perfect way to be able
to combine science and art.
What if you had a throwie that
you could turn on and off
using this little plastic tab?
It's easy to make.
Higginsworth actually
came up with this.
This is a little plastic
tab here that you
just pull in and out.
And it's made out of this
little plastic here.
So we just took a piece of
recycled packaging material,
cut it up in there.
It was perfect.
And this electrical tape that
you see here, has another
piece of electrical tape here
that won't stick to this, so
that it's easy to be able
to slide it in and out.
Wrap the electrical tape around,
put it on the magnet
side, and watch this as you
pull, it lights up.
When you're done playing
with it you are
back as you were before.
So let's say you're making a
throwie, you've got your LEDs.
You've got the battery.
You've got your electrical
tape.
The only thing you're missing
is, of course, those super
expensive neodymium magnets.
Is there another way to get
it to stick to something?
Well, how about Velcro?
So we just went out and bought
some of the sticky back Velcro
and cut the Velcro so that
you put, for example,
the hook side here.
And now, it's easy to be able to
throw it onto the loop side
and it sticks perfectly.
Which got me to thinking, what
if you could make an entire
suit, a jumpsuit,
out of Velcro?
And you had, oh, I say, 150 or
so friends that would throw
throwies on that jumpsuit.
Take a look at this.
Well, you know how to make a
throwie using the Velcro.
The only thing you need now is
something to throw the Velcro
to and that's where Higginsworth
comes in.
Higginsworth, you have the
Velcro and it's the other side
and it sticks.
It's perfect.
But that's not very fun.
It would be fun if there are
hundreds of them like this.
Now, that's cool.
Now, I have three Velcro people
and hundreds of friends.
Watch this.
Go!
Let's here it for
Velcro, people!
HIGGINSWORTH: What kind of ice
cream do we get to try?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Caramel cone,
cookies and cream, mango
sorbet and Belgian chocolate.