Blah, blah, blah,
blah, blah, blah.
I pray thee,
good Mercutio, let's retire.
Blah, blah, blah,
blah, blah.
The day is hot.
Blah, blah, blah.
The Capulets abroad!
Ha ha ha!
If we meet we shall not
'scape a brawl.
For now
these hot days,
is the mad
blood stirring.
Mercutio,
let's retire.
Blah, blah, blah,
blah, blah, blah!
Thou art like one
of these fellows
that when he enters
the confines of a tavern
claps me his sword
on the table,
and says, "God send me
no need of thee:"
blah, blah,
blah, blah;
and by the operation
of the second cup,
draws him on
the drawer,
when indeed
there is no need.
Am I like
such a fellow?
Nay and there were
two such
we should have
none shortly,
for the one would kill
the other.
Why thou hast
quarreled with a man
for coughing
in the street,
because he hath wakened thy dog
that hath lain asleep
in the sun.
Blah, blah, blah!
And thou wilt tutor me
from quarreling! Hah!
Mercutio...
By my head,
here come the Capulets.
By my heel,
I care not.
Gentlemen, good den.
Good den.
A word
with one of you.
And but one word
with one of us.
Couple it
with something,
make it a word
and a blow.
You shall find me
apt enough to that, sir,
and you will
give me occasion.
Can you not take some occasion
without the giving?
Mercutio, thou
consortest with Romeo.
Consort? Ha ha ha!
What dost thou
make us minstrels?
Ha ha ha!
An you make
minstrels of us,
you look to hear
nothing but discords.
Here's my fiddlestick.
Here's that shall
make you dance.
Zounds! Consort!
We talk here in
the public haunt of men.
Either withdraw unto
some private place,
or reason coldly
of your grievances,
or else depart;
here all eyes gaze on us.
Men's eyes
were made to look,
and let them gaze.
Mercutio!
I will not budge for
no man's pleasure, I.
Well, peace be
with you, sir,
here comes my man.
Mercutio!
Tybalt.
Romeo, the love
I bear thee
can afford no better
term than this--
thou art a villain.
Tybalt, the reason that
I have to love thee
doth much excuse
the appertaining rage
to such a greeting--
villain am I none.
Therefore farewell,
I see thou knowest
not me.
Ha ha ha!
Boy...
This shall not excuse the injuries
thou hast done me,
therefore turn
and draw.
I do protest
I never injured thee,
but love thee better
than thou canst devise.
Till thou shalt know
the reason of my love.
And so, good Capulet,
which name I tender
as dearly as mine own,
be satisfied.
Ha ha ha!
No, no.
No, Mercutio.
O calm, dishonorable,
vile submission!
No, Mercutio, no!
Leave me...
Tybalt, you ratcatcher!
What wouldest thou
have with me?
Good King of Cats,
nothing but one of
your nine lives,
that I mean to
make bold withal...
And as you shall
use me hereafter...
Dry-beat the rest
of the eight.
Please, good Mercutio.
Will you pluck your sword
out of his pilcher
by the ears?
Make haste,
lest mine be about your ears
ere it be out.
I am for you, sir.
Ha ha ha!
Gentle Mercutio,
put thy rapier up.
Come, come.
Benvolio, beat down
their weapons!
Gentlemen, for shame!
Forbear this outrage!
The Prince expressly hath
forbid this bandying
in Verona streets.
Tybalt!
Mercutio!
Leave us!
Leave us away,
you coward!
Go hang thyself.
Uh!
Ha ha ha!
Ha ha ha! Hey!
Hey!
Aah!
Cut his hair, Tybalt!
Ha ha ha!
Hey!
Keep your distance, Tybalt.
Hyah! Hyah! Hyah!
Keep away, coward!
Make haste, Tybalt,
we cannot wait all day.
Ah, mother's baby
has dropped his sword.
Hey!
Tybalt, no!
Abstain from
this crusade!
Tybalt, go!
Mercutio, come down!
Begone, begone...
Fly, Tybalt.
Fly away.
I am hurt.
Uh!
What! Art thou hurt?
A scratch, a scratch,
marry 'tis enough.
Courage, man, the hurt
cannot be much.
No, 'tis not so deep
as a well,
nor so wide as
a church door,
but 'tis enough;
you ask for me
tomorrow,
and you shall find me
a grave man.
Where is my page?
Go, villain,
and fetch me a surgeon.
Fetch me a surgeon!
Ha ha ha!
Did he hurt you?
Why the devil
came you between us?
I was hurt
under your arm.
I thought all
for the best, I...
Help me into some house,
Benvolio,
or I shall faint.
Whoa!
Yay!
A plague o'
both your houses!
They have made
worms' meat of me.
I have it,
and soundly too...
Your houses!
He jests!
Mercutio!
Romeo, Romeo...
brave Mercutio's dead.
This day's black fate,
on more days doth depend.
This but begins the woe
others must end.
He gone in triumph!
And Mercutio slain!
Away to heaven,
respective lenity,
and fire-eyed fury
be my conduct now!
Tybalt!
Romeo!
This way!
Tybalt!
Romeo!
Now, Tybalt...
Take the villain
back again,
that late thou gav'st me;
for Mercutio's soul
is but a little way
above our heads,
staying for thine
to keep him company:
either thou, or l, or both,
must go with him!
Aah!
Let him go!
Sword, Romeo.
O thou wretched boy,
that didst
consort him here,
shalt with him hence.
This shall
determine that.
Hit the feet, Romeo!
Protect the eyes, Romeo!
Give me your sword.
Watch his feet!
Hyah!
Give me the sword!
The sword!
Romeo! Romeo!
Give it to me!
Your sword, Romeo!
The sword, Romeo!
Aah!
Tybalt!
Romeo, away, be gone.
The citizens are up.
Stand not amazed,
the Prince will
doom thee death,
if thou art taken.
Hence, go away!
Romeo!
Oh, I am fortune's fool!
Oh, Romeo!
Away, away!
A curse on the Montagues!
Oh, Tybalt!
Tybalt! Tybalt!
The best friend I had,
oh, courteous Tybalt,
honest gentleman,
that ever I should live
to see thee dead!
Oh, God!
Did Romeo's hand
shed Tybalt's blood?
It did, it did,
alas the day, it did!
Oh, nurse,
oh, serpent heart,
hid with a flow'ring face!
Was ever book containing
such vile matter
so fairly bound?
There's no faith,
no trust,
no honesty in men;
all perjured,
all forsworn,
all naught,
all dissemblers.
Shame come to Romeo.
Blistered be thy tongue
for such a wish.
He was not born
to shame.
Upon his brow shame
is ashamed to sit.
Will you speak well of him
that killed your cousin?
Shall I speak ill of him
that is my husband?
Poor my lord,
what tongue shall
smooth thy name
when I
thy three-hours wife
have mangled it?
But wherefore villain,
didst thou kill my cousin?
Capulet! To the prince!
Speak, Benvolio, speak!
Go on, speak.
Prince!
As thou art true,
for blood of ours
shed blood of Montague.
Benvolio, who began
this bloody fray?
Tybalt, here slain.
No!
Romeo did
speak him fair,
bid him bethink how nice
the quarrel was,
and urged withal
your high displeasure.
It's true, Prince.
The picture
makes him false.
He speaks not true.
I beg for justice,
which thou,
Prince must give.
Romeo slew Tybalt,
Romeo must not live.
Romeo slew him.
He slew Mercutio.
Who now the price
of his dear blood doth owe?
Not Romeo, Prince...
He was Mercutio's friend.
His fault concludes
but what the law should end.
The life of Tybalt!
And for that offense,
immediately we do
exile him hence.
Let Romeo
hence in haste,
else, when he's found...
That hour is his last.
Ah, banishment...
Be merciful, say death!
Do not say banishment.
Arise.
One knocks;
good Romeo, hide thyself.
Who's there?
Who knocks so hard?
Whence come you?
What's your will?
Let me come in,
and you shall know
my errand.
I come from
Lady Juliet.
Welcome then.
Holy friar,
o tell me, holy friar,
where's my lady's lord,
where's Romeo?
There, on the ground.
With his own tears
made drunk.
There is no world
without Verona walls.
Even so lies she,
blubbering and weeping,
weeping and blubbering.
Stand up!
Stand and you
be a man.
For Juliet's sake,
for her sake,
rise and stand.
Why should you fall
into so deep an 'ole?
Nurse.
Ah, sir, death's
the end of all.
Speakst thou of Juliet?
How is it with her?
Does she not think
me an old murderer?
Where is she?
How doth she?
What says
my concealed lady
to our canceled love?
She says nothing, sir,
but weeps and weeps,
and Tybalt calls,
and then on Romeo cries.
As if that name
did murder her.
O tell me, friar,
tell me,
in what vile part
of this anatomy
doth my name lodge?
Tell me that I may sack
the hateful mansion!
Hold thy
desperate hand.
By heavens!
Leave it!
Thou hast amazed me.
Thou a man?
Thy form
cries out thou art.
Thy tears
are womanish,
thy wild acts denote the
unreasonable fury of a beast.
Hast thou slain Tybalt?
Wilt thou slay thyself,
and slay thy lady,
that in thy life lives,
by doing damned hate
upon thyself?
Rouse thee, man...
Thy Juliet is alive.
There art thou happy.
Tybalt would kill thee,
but thou slewest Tybalt;
there art thou happy.
The law that threatened death
becomes thy friend,
and turns it to exile;
there art thou happy.
A pack of blessings
light upon thy back...
Ascend her chamber,
hence and comfort her.
But look thou stay
not till the watch be set,
for then thou canst not
pass to Mantua,
where thou shalt live
till we find a time
to blaze your marriage,
reconcile your friends,
beg pardon of the Prince,
and call thee home,
with twenty hundred
thousand times more joy
than thou wentest forth
in lamentation.
Go before, nurse...
Commend me to thy lady,
and bid her hasten
all the house to bed,
which heavy sorrow
makes them apt unto
Romeo's coming.
Wilt thou be gone?
It is not yet
near day.
It was the nightingale,
and not the lark,
that pierced the fearful hollow
of thine ear.
Nightly she sings
on yond pomegranate tree.
Oh, believe me, love,
it was the nightingale.
It was the lark...
The herald of the morn,
no nightingale.
Night's candles
are burnt out...
And jocund day stands tiptoe
on the misty mountaintops.
I must be gone and live,
or stay and die.
Yond light is not
daylight...
I know it, I.
Therefore stay yet,
thou needst not
to be gone.
Oh, let me be taken,
let me be put to death.
I am content so thou
wilt have it so.
I'll say yon gray
is not the morning's eye,
nor that is not
the lark
whose notes do beat
the vaulty heavens
so high above
our heads.
I have more care
to stay than will to go.
Come death, and welcome,
Juliet wills it so.
It is...
It is, hie hence,
be gone away.
Romeo, it is.
It is the lark that
sings so out of tune,
straining harsh discords,
and unpleasing sharps.
Some say the lark
makes sweet division;
oh, this doth not so,
for she divideth us.
So now be gone,
more light and light
it grows.
More light and light,
more dark and dark
our woes.
Madam!
Your lady mother
comes to your chamber.
Nurse.
Your lady mother is
coming to your chamber.
The day is broke,
look about.
Oh, art thou gone so,
my husband, friend?
I must hear from thee
every day in the hour,
for in a minute
there are many days,
o by this count
I shall be much in years,
ere I again behold my Romeo.
I will omit
no opportunity
that may convey
my greetings, love, to thee.
Oh, think'st thou
we shall ever meet again?
I doubt it not,
and all these woes
shall serve
for sweet discourses
in our time to come.
Farewell, farewell,
one kiss
and I'll descend.
Adieu.
Adieu!
Oh, God!
We will have vengeance
for it,
fear thou not...
No!
Then weep no more.
I'll send to one
in Mantua,
where that same
banished runagate doth live
shall give him such
an unaccustomed dram,
that he shall soon
keep Tybalt company.
No!
But now I'll tell thee
joyful tidings, girl.
Well, then thou hast
a careful father,
one who to put thee
from thy heaviness
hath sorted out
a sudden day of joy.
And joy comes well
in such a needy time.
Marry, my child,
early next Thursday morn,
the gallant, young
and noble prince,
the county Paris,
at St. Peter's church,
shall happily make thee
there a joyful bride.
Now by St. Peter's church,
and Peter too,
he shall not make me there
a joyful bride!
No! No!
So, it is concluded.
Son, Paris.
How now, wife, have you
delivered to her our decree?
Ay, sir,
but she will none,
she gives you thanks.
I would the fool were
married to her grave.
Soft...
take me with you.
Take me with you, wife.
How? Will she none?
Doth she not
give us thanks?
Is she not proud?
Doth she not count her blessed,
unworthy as she is,
that we have wrought so worthy
a gentleman to be her bridegroom?
Wretched fool!
Let me see her!
Ungrateful baggage!
Say what thou wilt,
thou shalt not house with me!
Fie! What, are you mad?
Hang thee,
young baggage!
Disobedient wretch!
I tell thee what,
get thee to church on Thursday,
or never after
look me in the face.
Oh, father, good father,
I beseech you.
Speak not, reply not,
do not answer me.
My fingers itch.
You are to blame, my lord,
to rate her so.
And why,
my lady wisdom?
Hold your tongue!
Good prudence, smatter
with your gossips, go!
I speak no treason.
May not one speak?
Speak!
You mumbling fool!
Utter your gravity
o'er a gossip's bowl,
for here we need it not.
You are too hot.
God's bread,
it makes me mad.
Thursday's near.
Lay hand on heart, advise.
An you be mine,
I give you to my friend;
an you be not,
hang, beg, starve,
die in the streets.
No!
For by my soul,
I'll ne'er acknowledge thee,
for what is mine
shall never do thee good.
Father!
Trust to't, bethink you,
I'll not be forsworn.
Oh, no! No!
Oh sweet, my mother,
cast me not away.
Delay this marriage
for a month, a week, oh!
Talk not to me,
for I'll not speak a word.
Do as thou wilt,
for I have done with thee.
Oh, God!
Oh, nurse?
How shall this
be prevented?
What sayest thou?
Hast thou not
a word of joy?
Some comfort, nurse.
Faith, here it is.
Romeo is banished...
And all the world
to nothing,
that he dares ne'er come back
to challenge you;
or if he do, it needs must
be by stealth.
Then since the case so stands
as now it doth,
I think it best
you marry with the county.
True.
O he's a lovely
gentleman.
Romeo's
a dishclout to him.
An eagle, madam,
hath not so green,
so quick, so fair an eye
as Paris hath.
Beshrew my heart,
I think you happy
in this second match.
It excels your first.
For if it did not,
your first is dead,
or 'twere as good he were
as living here,
and you no use of him.
Speakest thou
from thy heart?
And from my soul, too...
Or else
beshrew them both.
Amen.
What?
Well, thou hast comforted me
marvelous much.
Go in, and tell my lady
I am gone,
having displeased my father,
to Laurence's cell,
to make confession
and to be absolved.
Marry, I shall,
and this is wisely done.
Go!
You say you do not know
the lady's mind.
Uneven is the course,
I like it not.
Immoderately she weeps
for Tybalt's death,
and therefore have I
little talked of love,
for Venus smiles not
in a house of tears.
Oh!
Happily met,
my lady and my wife.
That may be, sir,
when I may be a wife.
Come you to make
confession to this father?
Are you at leisure,
holy father, now,
or shall I come to you
at evening mass?
My leisure serves me,
pensive daughter, now.
My lord, we must entreat
the time alone.
God shield I should
disturb devotion.
Juliet, on Thursday early
will I rouse thee.
Till then, adieu...
and keep this holy kiss.
Oh, shut the door,
and when thou hast done so,
come weep with me,
past hope,
past care, past help.
Oh, Juliet, I already
know thy grief.
Tell me not, Friar,
that thou heard'st of this,
unless thou tell me
how I can prevent it.
If in thy wisdom
thou cans't give no help...
Hold, daughter.
I do spy a kind of hope,
as that is desperate
which we would prevent.
If rather than to marry
county Paris,
thou hast
the strength of will to--
O bid me leap,
rather than marry Paris,
from off the battlements
of any tower,
or bid me go
into a new-made grave
and hide me with a dead man
in his shroud.
Hold then.
Go home.
Be merry.
Give consent
to marry Paris.
Oh, no.
Wednesday is tomorrow.
Tomorrow night
look that thou lie alone,
let not the nurse
lie with thee in thy chamber.
Take thou this phial,
being then in bed...
And this distilling liquor
drink thou off...
When presently through
all thy veins shall run
a cold and drowsy humor;,
for no pulse shall keep
his native progress,
but surcease;
no warmth, no breath
shall testify thou livest...
And in this borrowed likeness
of shrunk death
thou shalt continue
two and forty hours...
And then awake
as from a pleasant sleep.
In the meantime,
against thou shalt awake
shall Romeo by my letters
know our drift,
and hither shall he come,
and he and I
will watch thy waking,
and that very night shall Romeo
bear thee hence to Mantua.
Give me, give me!
Tell me not of fear.
Hold, then.
Get thee gone.
Be strong and prosperous
in this resolve.
How now, my headstrong.
Where have you
been gadding?
Where I have learnt me
to repent the sin
of disobedient opposition.
Pardon me,
henceforward l,
I am ever ruled by you.
Why, I am glad on't!
This is well.
Stand up.
This is
as it should be.
Love give me strength.
Give this letter
into the hand of Romeo,
in Mantua.
Aah!
My lord! My lord!
She's dead,
Juliet is dead!
My Lady Juliet, my lord.
She's dead, she's dead!
Juliet!
My baby,
where is she?
O lamentable day.
Death lies on her
like an untimely frost
upon the sweetest flower
of all the field.
Master.
Balthasar!
How fares my Juliet?
For nothing can be ill,
if she be well.
How fares my lady?
She's dead, my lord.
She's dead.
Her body sleeps
in capel's monument.
I saw her laid low
in her kindred's vault.
Then, I defy you, stars!
Live...
and be prosperous.
Farewell, good fellow.
Juliet.
O my love...
My wife.
Death that hath sucked
the honey of thy breath,
hath had no power yet
upon thy beauty.
Thou art not conquered...
Beauty's ensign yet
is crimson in thy lips
and in thy cheeks.
Death's pale flag
is not advanced there.
Tybalt.
Liest thou there
in thy bloody sheet?
What more favor
can I do to thee,
than with that hand
that cut thy youth in twain
to sunder his
that was thine enemy?
Forgive me, cousin.
Ah, dear Juliet.
Why art thou yet so fair?
Shall I believe that
unsubstantial death is amorous,
and that the lean
abhorred monster
keeps thee here in dark
to be his paramour?
For fear of that,
I still will stay with thee.
Never from this palace
of dim night depart again.
Here, here will I remain,
with worms that are
thy chambermaids.
Eyes, look your last.
Arms, take your last embrace.
And lips,
o you the doors of breath,
seal with a righteous kiss
a dateless bargain
to engrossing death.
Here's to my love.
Thus with a kiss...
I die.
Who's there?
A friend, and one
that knows thee well.
Balthasar. How long
hast thou been here?
Full half an hour.
Go with me to the vault.
I dare not, sir.
My master knows not
that I am gone hence.
Stay then,
I'll go alone.
Fear comes upon me.
O much I fear
some ill unlucky thing.
Romeo!
Oh, what an unkind hour
is guilty of this
lamentable chance?
Ohh!
O comfortable Friar,
where is my lord?
I do remember well
where I should be,
and there I am.
Where is my Romeo?
I hear some noise.
Oh, where is my Romeo?
Oh, lady, come from this nest
of death, contagion,
and unnatural sleep.
A greater power
than we can contradict
hath thwarted
our intents.
Come along.
The watch is coming.
Where is my Romeo?
Come. Go, good Juliet.
No.
I dare no longer stay.
No!
Juliet!
I dare no longer stay.
I dare
no longer stay!
What's here?
Poison, I see,
hath been his timeless end.
O churl!
Drunk all,
and left no friendly drop
to help me after!
I will kiss thy lips;
haply some poison
yet doth hang on them
to make me die
with a restorative.
Thy lips are warm!
Oh, no, no!
Lead, boy, which way?
Search about
the churchyard.
Go, some of you...
Yea, noise?
No!
Then I'll be brief,
o happy dagger!
This is thy sheath;
there rest and let me die.
Where be these enemies?
Capulet!
Montague!
See what a scourge
is laid upon your hate...
that heaven finds means
to kill your joys with love;
and l, for winking
at your discords too,
have lost
a brace of kinsmen.
All are punished.
All are punished!
A glooming peace
this morning with it brings.
The sun for sorrow
will not show his head,
for never was a story
of more woe
than this of Juliet
and her Romeo.