We're at Healesville Sanctuary
and up in the hospital,
specifically.
Healesville Sanctuary has what
is called the Australian
Wildlife Health Center.
And it's designed not only to
service our collection of
animals, but also wildlife.
So people bring in these orphans
or an injured animal.
Now, that's perfectly
normal [CHUCKLES]
behavior.
So people will bring
in their sick,
injured, or orphaned wildlife.
And the vets and other hospital
staff will look after
their medical needs.
At which point, they would
either go into one of the
wards behind you.
Or they would go
off to a carer.
This is Belle.
And she is around
10 months old--
it can be hard to judge.
She's over 6 kilograms.
Belle's mother was
hit by a car.
And the people who saw her on
the side of the road went over
and checked to see if the
wombat had a pouch.
And Belle here was inside.
She likes to be rocked.
And I don't know if it makes any
difference, but I like to
sing to her sometimes.
[HUMMING]
Come on.
This is my little
wombat shuffle.
It gets their attention
usually.
Good girl.
Nice work, Belle.
At this stage, she usually likes
to have a little cuddle
and a bit of a snooze.
But because Phoenix is here,
she'll probably want to get
down and play.
Yes, you like that, don't you?
Yeah.
You too, Phoenix.
What I love about wombats is
they've got good, funny
characters--
extremely cheeky.
Phoenix is very confident.
I think of her as a
bit of a tomboy.
She often acts inappropriately,
biting things
she's not meant to do.
And Belle is a real lady.
So she's quite shy as well--
of people, generally.
Phoenix doesn't only like
people, she seems positively
fascinated by people.
So I'm often chasing
her around,
trying to get her back.
And Belle's much happier
to stick close to me.
Aren't you, darling?
And then again, they've got
a lot of similarities.
They like to dig and nip
and headbutt me.
They're my beautiful monsters,
aren't you?
Oh, not at the same
time, girls.
Goodness, you're
hurrying today.
[CHUCKLES]
[MUSIC PLAYING]