but I realised that what you need to replace
is the carbs. So I came up with an all natural,
high carb smootie.
Check it out, it's Datorade.
I've only been a vegan for a year, I like
tom keep things as simple as possible. So
I chose the fruit with the highest carbs.
Bananas and dates.
Start things off, bananas. I want four of
these. That's when you want to be blending
them up when they're spotty, nice and ripe.
Peel them, from the bottom. Bananas are 93%
carbs, 3% fat, 4% protein so you're getting
some protein in there as well. It really doesn't
matter if they're bruised, they're getting
blended up anyway.
Natural sugars you've for in the banana which
is helping to replace the glycogen you need
to replace in your body after a workout.
Another thing I like to do is scrape from
the peel. You wouldn't want to eat that if
you're eating from the banana, but blending
it into a smoothie it really doesn't matter.
I came up with these smoothie recipes. Just
have fun with whole foods and see what you
like.
I've got four bananas in there, now you want
to double up with the dates. I go 8 dates,
two for every banana.
Medjool are my favourite, look how gooey that
is. It's like fudge caramel. You want to make
sure there's no stone inside.
These ones have already been de stoned. Put
it in. These have really dense calories. That's
2,3,4,5,6,7,8.
I really enjoy cinnamon. I add it to almost
everything I have, so one spoon of that. Also
some ginger, gives it that nice little after
kick then about one litre of water.
Keeps you hydrated, which you really need
to do as you are going throughout \the day.
It;s important.
If you're going all out and don't mind a bit
of fat in there, you can use almond milk to
make it a bit creamier. You can put other
things. If you want to put a squeeze of lemon,
it's all up to you.
It's whatever you like, whatever you enjoy.
Whatever you know is good for your body you
can mix it in there as well. You might not
even taste it so that's fine.
Let's whizz it up.
Alright, here it is. One big, fat datorade
smoothie. I don't like to blend it too fine.
Because it's nice to have a bit of dates to
chew on as your drinking it, i think it's
important.
Banana and dates makes a nice caramel liquid
here. Creamy like fudge drink.
That is so sweet, so good post workout.
So that's it, real simple, real delicious
being vegan can be so sweet when you have
datorade.
Subscribe to foodtube. Also check out me on
my channel youtube.com/livewire to see me
do more free running tricks . Alright, enjoy,
you'll love it.