SIMON OSTROVSKY: After spending
the night in Tel
Aviv, it was time to head back
to the West Bank for a
Palestinian protest, which was
only about 30 miles away, but
things are never as easy
as they sound.
In addition to all the usual
barriers between Israel and
the Palestinian territories, the
heavens had conspired to
shut down traffic across Tel
Aviv for the annual marathon.
This was a celebration
of fitness that I
hadn't prepared for.
It's Friday morning
in Tel Aviv.
We're going to the West Bank
where it's Land Day, and all
of Palestine celebrates
their land.
But it's also an occasion when
they clash with Israeli
troops, so we're going to see
what that vibe is like.
We're having to carry all of
our stuff across the entire
city, and frankly, it's
really pissing me off.
This is the Qalandia
checkpoint.
There's tons of soldiers and
police here today because
they're expecting a
confrontation with the
Palestinian demonstrators.
We're going across the
checkpoint while we can
because once the trouble
starts, they're
going to shut it down.
Oh, man.
Not another one.
You've got to be kidding me.
OK.
Now I'm pretty sure
we're here.
Three hours after we set out
from Tel Aviv, we were finally
in the seat of the Palestinian
Authority--
Ramallah.
We met Tawfiq Haddad, a
Palestinian-American who'd
agreed to take us on
a sporting event
of a different kind.
Palestinians were marking Land
Day, an annual event that
draws attention to the fact
that the territory they
control keeps shrinking and
shrinking in inverse
proportion to the amount of land
controlled by Israel and
its settlers.
JAMAL JUMA: Land [INAUDIBLE]
for the Palestinians
[INAUDIBLE].
When the Palestinian land has
been taken, Palestinians
became refugees around the world
because the Zionists
have been expelled them from
their land in '48.
We are still, until now,
suffering from--
in the diaspora--
from this refugee problem.
They want to keep their
occupation and
colonization forever.
This is not going to happen.
SIMON OSTROVSKY: But their
politicians say they want to
have a two-state solution.
JAMAL JUMA: This is
lip services.
If you really, as a politician,
want two-state
solution, prove it
on the ground.
Stop your settlements.
Take out your settlers from the
West Bank and Jerusalem,
and stop demolishing the
houses and the ethnic
cleansing and confiscating
the land.
Stop the wall that
you are building.
Then we can believe that you
want two-state solution.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
SIMON OSTROVSKY: The protests
were taking place at the
Qalandia checkpoint that I'd
crossed through earlier.
And Israel's security forces
were determined not to let any
of the Palestinians near it.
Meanwhile, a local cell phone
company decided that the
madness erupting all around
was the perfect place to
advertise its services.
So the funny thing is while
this protest is going on,
somebody's handing
out these hats.
And what these actually are are
from the local cell phone
company because apparently,
Palestinians never miss an
opportunity to do some
direct marketing.
MALE SPEAKER: What are they
fucking-- people are going to
die today and they just
want them to be
wearing the Jawwal hat?
Land Day demonstrations like
this one were taking place all
around the West Bank and along
the borders of Israel and
Syria-Lebanon and in Gaza, where
one of the protesters,
just 20 years old, was shot
dead as he approached an
Israeli crossing.
But I'd heard that Palestinian
demonstrators weren't the only
ones in the habit of throwing
stones, so I headed to an
ordinary Palestinian town a bit
further away from all the
commotion to hear their
side of the story.
MALE SPEAKER:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]