MIKE CHANTRY: Woo.
This is 80--
no, this is 90.
Yeah, 90.
It's a team board.
All the team boards
were black.
The earlier Sims boards--
all the teams were black, except
for a very few protos
that were white.
And then, there's a couple
of red ones that
are floating around.
Those are back in
the archives.
And I've got another
white one.
I was one of the original
pipe guys.
Every contest, I was
always in the pipe.
So I'd draft the pros and
go, you want to ride?
Show up here.
After practices is done,
be here with shovels.
When the cat guy's done, then
we'll start shaping.
And then, the hips and all the
rails, and stuff didn't come
around until like '90, '91--
just something different.
I went, oh cool-- a little
twist on the original.
Because we didn't do that
the first year or
the first three years.
[SOUND OF DIGGING]
MIKE CHANTRY: The pipe builder's
job is never done.
TOM BURT: Mike Chantry, he was
kind of like our father figure
to hold Tahoe's skate
team together.
He had Mile High Ramp.
And he kind of took care of
Terry, and was always at the
contests, and became a judge.
He's kind of like a local guy
who put it all together for
people around here for
quite a few years--
for our generation, basically.
MIKE CHANTRY: Hey, Don?
Don?
It's a lovely day.
Come on.
- [INAUDIBLE].
DONNIE: A lovely day in
the neighborhood.
Here we are at Donner's
Ski Ramp.
MIKE CHANTRY: Snowboarders
and skiers can get along.
There's no way they're going
to get their hands dirty.
Donnie and all them?
Doing this stuff?
That's why they have
the machines.
DON BOSTICK: Donnie doesn't
know what a shovel is.
Where's Frank Wells
when you need him?
MIKE CHANTRY: Yup.
Frank would do--
He would kick ass on this.
DON BOSTICK: Yeah, Frank has
definitely shoveled pipes.
This log would be about
another 6 to 8
feet over my head.
MIKE CHANTRY: Or a dragon.
DON BOSTICK: This is like--
for a new pipe that's not even
the top of a normal superpipe.
Request of Jeff Brushie--
he wanted it a little
bit deeper this year.
So we're trying to make trying
to make Jeff happy, I think.
MIKE CHANTRY: Oh, Brushie
is going to show?
DON BOSTICK: Yeah, he's in Reno
for a poker tournament.
So he'll be here tomorrow.
MIKE CHANTRY: He's not going
to injure his elbow at the
tournament, is he?
DON BOSTICK: Nah,
Brush is good.
Tom Zekus, who's supposed
to be here as the head
judge on that tour.
And then, Brushie's been doing
X Games and Dew Tour for the
last few years.
Rippey is supposed to
be here too digging.
Another guy--
the cool thing is taking pros
like Rippey, Brushie and like
Yeom Morset--
who's got a US Open
win behind him--
taking guys like that and
bringing them into judging.
It brings more validity
to the judging staff
at those big events.
TOM BURT: Don Bostick, who was
a shop owner, but now he ran
Go Skate Or Go Home.
But then, he started
some of the first
amateur snowboard series.
And then, he's been involved
with skating.
He puts on X Games for
snowboarding and all the big
skate contests also.
You name it.
And he's pretty much involved
in all those.
MIKE CHANTRY: That's why we
invented the pipe dragon, and
the Zog and everything else.
So we wouldn't have to come
back and do this crap.
If anybody wants anything else,
they know where the
shovels are.
In the morning, if they
want to shovel
another run, go for it.
That's the way it was
in the beginning.
If you didn't like it,
there's a shovel.
Go dig it.
If you still don't like it--
T.S.
We'd come up, ride with the
Cat guy, dig it out--
Tom Sims or myself.
And we got the first
three pipes.
And then, everybody would
show up to practice.
We'd all give out shovels.
And there'd be 30 to 50 guys
with shovels running around
the pipe digging their own
trannies and hits.
And one year, we wound up with
like 100 hits, freeways all
over the pipe.
So even if you missed where you
wanted to go, you still
had an option.
So there was options A through
Z. Oh, I'm going
to sleep good tonight.
DON BOSTICK: I see the lines.
The lines going to
be over there.
But at least it's a cleaned
up [INAUDIBLE].
MIKE CHANTRY: Do you
want an option?
DON BOSTICK: Yeah.
MIKE CHANTRY: Let's go.
And pop a little in here.
NORM SAYLER: When Don and
Danielle Bostick came to
Donner Ski Ranch and came to
work for me, I was the major
owner along with my wife
and my family.
And I had a lot of
stockholders.
And we were all home-bred
This was just a family place.
The stockholders would come and
help paint, fix, cook if I
needed a bartender, needed
a dishwasher.
That's the way this place was
in the original days.
When I took over in 1958, I got
on the phone and called
all my friends and said, I'm
running Donner's Ski Ranch--
help.
And they all showed up.
And that's how we got
the place going.
But when Don and Danielle showed
up, that was the start
of doing things.
And then, snowboarding
came along.
And they stepped right
into that.
Because they were
skateboarders.
We went from 25,000
skier visits to
54,000 in three years.
That's how much it increased.
And all of that, basically,
was snowboarding.
We didn't know this was
going to happen.
Didn't have a clue.
Every snowboarder would show
up with their snowboard and
their shovel.
And they'd start working
on the pipe.
And what you're looking at is
truly about what it was.
So everybody would put in
their individual hit.
This was the place they're
going to do
their trick and stuff.
And that's what it was.
And you can see today there was
a lot of hand shovelling
on this pipe.
And that's what made it.
But I'm a little disappointed
now.
Because it's kind of lost that
really homegrown attitude that
it had early on, when
the kids just came
hardcore to have fun.
They were all street wise.
They plain came and said--
I don't know if I
can say this.
You can take it out--
they just plain said,
fuck you.
We're going to have fun.
Leave us alone.
And I says, give me $10.
And I'll leave you alone
all day long.
And this is kind of a place
that really helped get it
started with them.
But without their help, it might
have been a lot harder,
might have been a few
years in coming.
But I don't think it would
happened as quick.
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYING]
MIKE CHANTRY: We're going
to make a warm-up.
-I can't wait.
-Who was the first
[INAUDIBLE]?
MIKE CHANTRY: I was.
TOM BURT: The hardest part about
the day-- trying to get
the Fastx buckles on.
I feel like the game?
I don't know.
Hopefully, the Fastx holds
out through the day.
It is what?
25 plus year-old plastic?
You got no high backs.
Yeah?
Well, these are L.L.Bean
throws.
They're actually the original
ones I used to ride in.
All this has a metal edge
and they inlaid.
DAVE SEOANE: See?
It's all coming back--
first run of the year.
It doesn't click in.
It clicked.
Here, come over here.
See this?
See that tree with that
cliff right there?
That's the first cliff
I ever went off,
probably 20 years ago.
That was the first cliff
I ever went off.
It's probably about 15 feet.
And I thought it was
like 115 feet--
the first one ever.
Did I land it?
No.
[INAUDIBLE]?
DAVE SEOANE: Yeah?
-You going out there
on the top?
DAVE SEOANE: I'm scared.
Way up there?
-Way up there?
DAVE SEOANE: Altitude.
-Too scary?
DAVE SEOANE: I gotta train.
First rode of the year.
So we've got perfect weather,
two to three mile an hour
nor-easterlys.
I think we're looking good.
OK, it's just like riding
a bike, except for--
oh god.
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYING]
DAVE SEOANE: Look how far
this pipe goes down.
It goes down for about
a mile and a half.
I can't even get up one.
OK, we're going to
try another one.
JEFF BRUSHIE: For real,
dude, that is so
hard what he's doing.
I couldn't go down a
pipe on a Backhill.
The only thing I'm thinking
about on a Backhill is a
powdery field.
-Hence the name "Backhill."
JEFF BRUSHIE: I don't think
that pipes were
around either then.
So it's not really
meant to be.
So that's pretty gnarly.
[CHEERING]
JASON BORGSTEDE: Well, we're
here at the Geritol Open and
running with some old timers,
and talking about some of the
people that influenced
me growing up.
And I would say, probably, at
least of the people here, I
would say probably Chris Roach
was the biggest for me.
When I first got into it,
Fall Line Films was
the big film company.
And we'd watch those--
I mean, we're talking about
films that were not half hour
little quick snippets of
snowboard porn like they put
on now, like oh shot,
shot shot.
Let's go.
Chris Roach was definitely one
of those guys who had a sick
style that you didn't
really see a lot
of yet to that point.
It was kind of like our
transition out of the
neon era and stuff.
You had a guy who wore black
stuff, who had tricks that
weren't just three back
flips in a row.
It wasn't just grab the
tip of your board.
It was stuff that looked
real smooth and
made you want to snowboard.
And as far as I knew, I mean,
that's the only reason I
wanted a Santa Cruz snowboard.
It was because Chris Roach
was riding one, you know?
JEFF BRUSHIE: Chris what?
Chris Roach was always
awesome.
-Should we?
We should probably wait
for a second.
DAVE SEOANE: Yeah, get a
little Roachie shot.
JEFF BRUSHIE: Get
a Roachie shot.
DAVE SEOANE: Yeah, zoom in.
Zoom in.
[CHEERING]
JEFF BRUSHIE: He's still
got the style.
DAVE SEOANE: That's rusty
Roach, right there.
JEFF BRUSHIE: Yeah, but you
could still see it.
DAVE SEOANE: Oo, that's kind
of classic Roachie.
CROWD: Oh.
DAVE SEOANE: So innovative--
he's so innovative.
JEFF BRUSHIE: Everyone always
respected Roach.
He's right up there at the
top of the list for
all time best styles.
Jamie Lynn is up there.
Roach is up there.
Classic, method grasser
style--
that was the Roach, you know?
Just a sick style overall.
JASON BORGSTEDE: Jeff
Brushie too.
Brushie was our pipe
guy, you know?
Funny story about
Jeff Brushie--
when I was a kid growing up in
Alaska, it was well known that
Jeff Brushie loved McDonald's
anyway.
But he came up to Alaska, when
the Trout Board came out, to
do an autograph signing.
And we ran to the autograph
signing, saw him.
And then, he's like oh, I'll
be riding tomorrow at
Hatcher's Pass--
you know, a hiking spot
early in the year?
So we get up there, I guess,
maybe like 20 minutes after
what he said he would
be there.
But you know, we're figuring
everybody will hike all day.
And right when we get there,
Brush is coming down the hill.
And we're like, yes,
Jeff Brushie.
And we're like, what's up man?
And he's like, oh, I'm
going to McDonald's.
And we're like, all right.
I guess we missed it.
-I remember it being either
really cold or bad conditions.
JASON BORGSTEDE: Yeah,
it was pretty bony.
It's like the beginning
of the year.
It's October and stuff.
So there's rocks and stuff.
And we were little kids.
So we had ultimate rock star
expectations of him.
So we thought, OK, he's a pro.
He's going to want to
ride all day long.
And he's going to do every
trick perfect.
And he's going to
do it 10 times.
And then, he's going to give
us all free stuff.
That's what we thought
at that time.
And then he's like, so you
guys can come hang out at
McDonald's if you want.
And we were like, aw man.
So, of course, we went to
McDonald's when we were done.
JEFF BRUSHIE: You know what?
I still have a deep
love for it.
And sometimes, I get the
cravings for it.
But I try to stay
away from it.
I don't eat beef no more.
I just eat chicken.
And it's kind of mystery
chicken at McDonald's.
JASON BORGSTEDE: It's the
hot dog of chicken.
JEFF BRUSHIE: Every now and
then, on a road trip, I'll
stop in for a six-piece.
JASON BORGSTEDE: Long
live The Trout.
[PUNK ROCK MUSIC]
[CHEERING]
-Sick, Mike!
MIKE BASICH: I like to
support and be a part
of the Legend thing.
Just because it's a part of our
history that most everyone
today has no idea.
Every kid doesn't know that
you used to not be able to
have vert in a half pipe.
Even though it's on a small
scale of contest, it helps
people remember what
it was like.
And riding an old board, you
ride like it was back then.
Technology is a huge impact
on how the style is of our
snowboarding now.
It's good.
I like seeing everybody
again and hearing
what they're up to.
You kind of get to see who
really stuck with it, as far
as a passion, who still rides.
Like Chris Roach, he rides at
Sugar Bowl all the time.
It's neat.
It's the only event I
know of to really
gather everyone together.
[CHATTERING]
DAVE SEOANE: Can you just
photoshop this?
Kinda nervous.
Are you guys nervous?
-Nah, I'm OK.
DAVE SEOANE: Yeah?
- [INAUDIBLE].
- [INAUDIBLE]
ANNOUNCER: There's a trooper.
This guy [INAUDIBLE]
facial hair.
[CHEERING]
ANNOUNCER: Coming out with a
[INAUDIBLE], Dave Seoane.
[CHEERING]
ANNOUNCER: Binding this,
does he want to
call his binding strap?
[CHEERING]
-See do we have Jim Rippey?
-We got him right here.
[CHATTERING]
-OK, you're next, Jim.
-Yeah, Rippey.
JEFF BRUSHIE: Watch out.
You're gonna feel
it for a week.
JIM RIPPEY: I already feel it.
Do you?
-OK, go.
JIM RIPPEY: We good?
-You're good.
Jim.
-And then, Rocker?
-And then, Rocker.
[CHEERING]
SHAWN FARMER: Dude, my
stance was like this.
I was just like--
actually, my board was sweet.
But that stance was like--
I'm all, you've got
to be kidding me.
It was like, I swear it was
like 15 or 16 inches.
I was just like, wow.
-On each tail?
SHAWN FARMER: Yeah,
it was silly.
-Like you had to steer
like that?
To do a turn, like the tail
just did not want--
SHAWN FARMER: Yeah, you
could get a turn.
But you gotta wait for
it to come around.
-You good show in there?
SHAWN FARMER: Yeah, I
remember that line.
That snow was so great, man.
Like you could have done
that all day in there.
I mean, you could of done a
couple of drops and stuff--
that was sweet-- in there.
That was great snow, man.
-I don't know how they
[INAUDIBLE].
-Woh.
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYING]
-Nice.
TOM BURT: It's all good.
-That looked really good.
TOM BURT: Not bad
for an '84 year.
-Not bad at all.
TOM BURT: No highbacks.
I got to go hit the roller.
Let's do that hillside
[INAUDIBLE].
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYING]
TOM BURT: All right, I got to
take a quick lunch break.
I need to get some food.
I haven't eaten anything
all day.
[CHATTERING]
DON BOSTICK: In the room--
Italians do not lie
on American soil.
It's got to be great wearing--
this goes to Tina.
-Open it up.
Drink it.
DON BOSTICK: Well, stay
right there, Mike.
Because we have a
double B here.
Mike Basset is winning the men's
event today, and $300,--
[CHEERING]
DON BOSTICK: --and a bottle
of wine from [INAUDIBLE].
-Open it up.
And drink it.
-Bust it out.
-Open it up.
DON BOSTICK: $300
tonight in cash.
[CHEERING]
DON BOSTICK: So Mike, what do
you think it was that put you
over the top?
That J-Tear or what?
MIKE GOSSET: I can definitely
feel a J-Tear the most out of
anything right now.
[LAUGHTER]
MIKE GOSSET: So I'm going to
go hire a chiropractor
-Two for one.
DON BOSTICK: All right, the
basset is on top today.
Give it up.
[CHEERING]
DON BOSTICK: I'll
give you a hint.
He's from Grass Valley.
[CHEERING]
DON BOSTICK: Chris
Roach, everybody.
[CHEERING]
CHRIS ROACH: How much money?
DON BOSTICK: $150.
TOM COLLINS: You got money.
Second.
DON BOSTICK: Second place.
Chris Roach, what do you got to
say to your fans out there?
CHRIS ROACH: Thank you
for being here.
[INAUDIBLE].
Thanks for coming.
We had a great time.
[CHATTERING]
DON BOSTICK: Give it
up for Chris Roach.
A class act, right there.
Always a pleasure to
see him out there.
OK, third place--
Jason Borgstede.
[APPLAUSE]
JASON BORGSTEDE: I would
like to say a
few thank yous though.
Because there are people who
came out today, like
[INAUDIBLE] and Chris Roach,
who were kind of my heroes
when I was coming up.
And it was pretty awesome
to see these guys
snowboarding, you know?
And I'd also like to thank
Tom Collins for the best
impersonation of a
hot dog today.
[LAUGHTER]
[CHEERING]
DON BOSTICK: Ladies and
gentlemen, Jason Borgstede.
We're going to get into our
awards presentation.
It's for the Legends of
Tahoe Snowboarding.
I was pretty excited that Damian
Sanders said that he
would be here.
Damian was the guy that married
Playmate of the Year.
He went out there.
And he was the rock star.
One of the first rock stars of
snowboarding, Damian Sanders,
we are honoring him this year.
Unfortunately, he was injured
on the motorcycle just a
couple of weeks ago.
Damian Sanders could not
be here with us.
We've got a nice
crotch rocket.
And we'll be sending
this to him.
Legendary-- in fact, if he was
here he would've won the
[INAUDIBLE] clearly with
that shot right there.
What do you think?
OK, I'm going to open
up the mic.
I'm sure Joe has got something
to say about this guy.
Come on up, Joel.
I'm putting you on the spot to
talk about Keith Kimmel.
JOEL GOMEZ: I have a lot of
memories here in snowboarding.
Mike Chantry is a big memory.
Because we used to stay
at Chantry's house.
But this is about
Keith Kimmel.
Bob Klein, Keith Kimmel, Terry
Kidwell, Allan Arnbruster.
These are all guys that I rode
with back in '81, '82, '83,
'84, early '80s.
And Keith looked a little
bit like Dave Seoane,
except Keith is taller.
And Keith is a really
good skateboarder.
I don't know if Davie can
skateboard at all.
Anyway, for Keith Kimmel.
-Cover the first snowboarding
magazine.
[CHEERING]
[CHATTERING]
SHAWN FARMER: I'll sound check.
[CHEERING]
SHAWN FARMER: Check.
Check.
We're trying to use soundcheck
dude, but.
- [INAUDIBLE].
SHAWN FARMER: [INAUDIBLE].
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYING]