What are you watching?
Mojo Joe.
Hmm.
Hey, baby.
What are you reading?
Uh, I'm not reading.
I'm writing an invitation
to a divorce party.
I'm trying to figure out
how not to make it sound
like, you know.
Like a woman is happy
she broke up with her husband?
Exactly.
How did you know it was a woman
throwing a party?
No man celebrates
losing half his money.
Can I talk to you
for a second?
Uh, sure.
What's wrong
with this picture?
What picture?
This.
What kind of family
has this turned into?
We haven't even
been together a year,
and already, no one's
paying attention to one another.
The only way you can get
more ignored than this
is by being a piercing
in Dennis Rodman's face.
So what do you suggest
we do about this?
We should have a get-together.
How is a party gonna make us
pay attention to each other?
It's not a party.
It's a get-together.
It's about people hanging out,
talking,
eating,
playing cards together.
And who is cooking
all this food,
setting up the card tables,
and cleaning up
after all these people
get together?
Why are you making it
so complicated?
Because it is.
No, it's not.
Fine.
Then you handle it
on your own.
Cool.
Hey, kids,
we're having a get-together.
Huh?
♪ Are we there yet? ♪
The Get Together
S01x10 Original Air Date on June 30, 2010
♪ tell me, tell me, tell me ♪
♪ tell me,
are we there yet? ♪
-- sync, corrected by elderman --
-- for www.addic7ed.Com --
Terrence,
you're going on a date?
And that's what you're wearing?
What's wrong with this?
You said dress casual.
Now, paramilitary gear
is very comfortable.
It don't ride up my butt,
I don't have to worry
about chafing,
and it don't hold in moisture.
It lets me breathe.
And where's your gun?
I don't have one.
Really?
Really.
Who are you,
Gilbert Arenas?
Come on, Suzanne.
I need this,
just in case
something jump off.
Let somebody else handle it,
Terrence.
You're not the only one
with this job.
Yes, I am.
Well, you're not wearing that.
She picks
your clothes out too?
She don't pick out my clothes.
Yes, I do.
Terrence has a date.
Oh, yeah?
Who is she?
We met at the bank.
No, no, no, no.
Met?
He saved her in a shoot-out.
No, it's not just that.
She made me laugh.
All right?
I was behind the desk
during the shoot-out.
Blah! Blah! Blah!
And she was like,
"wait a minute.
"I need some quarters
to put in the meter
before I get a ticket."
It was so cute.
I told her, I said,
"don't worry.
"If I see the meter maid,
that's the last time
you gonna see the meter maid."
[Chuckles]
She thought I was funny.
Sweet.
Well, she's seen you
at work,
so let her see
your other side.
I don't have an other side.
Why don't you bring her
to the get-together?
It's easier than a date.
Plus, we can check her out
for you.
Oh, y'all having a party?
It's not a party.
It's a get-together.
What's the difference?
Doesn't anybody in this house
know what a get-together is?
[Spits]
Ugh!
This is nasty.
I see you didn't marry her
for her cooking.
Question.
[Clears throat]
Who had the biggest
divorce settlement of all time?
Juanita Jordan.
[Mimics buzzer]
Didn't she get, like,
$400 million?
Nope, it was closer
to $168 million.
Technically, she had the biggest
celebrity divorce.
But the biggest
divorce divorce--
are you ready?
Okay.
Rupert Murdoch's ex,
Anna Murdoch,
reportedly received 1.7...
[giggles]
[Both laugh]
Billion dollars.
$1.7 billion?
Yes.
Juanita couldn't even
afford to pay Anna's lawyer.
No.
[Both laugh]
Okay, so where did you
get the idea
for the divorce game,
anyway?
That's a long story
that begins with a lawyer
and ends
with a bottle of tequila.
All your stories end
[Giggles]
I know.
You know what?
Nick told me
you were having a get-together.
Why didn't you tell me?
I need to know what to wear.
Ask him.
I'm staying out of it.
I don't want it
to get too complicated.
What's complicated about it?
That's what he said.
Where are all these people
supposed to sit?
When do they come?
When do they leave?
Oh, gosh, you keep on,
you gonna end up hosting
one of these divorce parties.
You need to loosen up.
I need to loosen up?
Yes.
Well, if it doesn't matter,
then why do you need to know
what to wear?
Even if it's a get-together,
I need to have it together
in case I meet the rich
white man of my dreams.
[Giggles]
And you know they like
a certain kind of dress.
So how are the plans coming?
Great,
'cause I don't have to plan.
I'll just make a few phone calls
and tell people what's up.
Oh, you guys can tell your
friends to drop by if you want.
Cool.
I'm posting an invitation
on facebook right now.
Can Troy come?
As long as he comes.
I don't want him
using us as an alibi.
I'll probably be having
everybody bring something.
But can you make
your famous potato salad?
Okay, how much
do you want me to make?
However much you want.
Whoever gets some,
gets some.
That's how you do it
at a get-together.
It sounds like
that's how you do it
in a prison yard.
Come on now, man,
it can't be that bad.
Think of it like a drill,
like running maneuvers.
You got to do it in the lab
before you take it
into the field.
I don't know.
It's pretty bad.
Ooh!
Terrence, I'm telling you.
If you were
running for something,
I might have to vote for you.
Yeah, you look
like a younger,
better-dressed, slightly cooler
Colin Powell,
only scary.
You would say that.
No, man, I'm serious.
I'm not a woman,
but if I was--
don't.
Wherever you're going
with that,
don't, okay?
I look too good right now
to play, all right?
I'm not overdressed, am I?
Well, where are you going,
dinner, the club?
He's bringing her
to the get-together.
Excuse me,
did you take one to the head?
Yeah.
Why would you bring
a complete stranger
to a place where
you already know everybody?
So those people can tell him
if she's the right woman
for him.
Oh, you mean so they can
nitpick and criticize her
until she runs out of the place
in tears?
Look, man, Suzanne did not
mean to make that girl cry.
You were gonna find out
she was a dominatrix
sooner or later.
Yeah, and your wife
deprived me of that wonderful--
yo! Yo.
This is about me.
Okay?
Now, take a good look.
I'm good, right?
You good.
Y'all don't see it, do you?
Nope.
Look now.
Look carefully.
What am I supposed to see?
Pow!
Whoa!
Where'd you get that?
Don't worry about it.
But if anybody
make my date cry,
there's more
where this came from.
What's that?
All right.
[Mutters]
Look, I'm having
a little get-together
at the house this weekend.
Bring whatever you want.
It's over when it's over.
I'll see you there.
Hey.
You okay?
Yeah, I guess.
I can't think of anybody
to invite to the get-together.
What happened to Troy?
He can't come.
What about your friends
from camp?
Still at camp.
[Sighs]
Well, you can invite
anybody you can think of.
If they're cool with you,
they're cool with me.
For real?
For real.
Thanks, Nick.
Slap!
[Beeping]
Hello?
Hey, dad.
It's Kevin.
[Doorbell ringing]
Can I help you?
How you doing?
Staten Island Mike.
I'm here for the get-together.
Right.
Come on in.
Am I the only one here?
Yes, you're the only one here.
I got some
banging potato salad.
Thank you.
Who shows up for a party
at 9:00 A.M.?
Party?
I thought this was
a get-together.
You're right.
It's not a party.
It's a get-together.
Follow me.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa.
It ain't
that type of get-together.
Let's go.
Honey.
Guess who's here.
Nick.
Hmm?
[Moans]
Who is that?
This is
Staten Island Mike.
He's here
for your get-together.
What's up, brother?
He brought
some bangin' potato salad.
And that's the goods, man.
What is wrong with you, man?
See, honey?
This is
what I'm talking about.
Baby, where is
the real food?
Uh, I got a little problem.
See, I told people
to bring something,
but they all
brought the same thing...
Both: Potato salad.
[Doorbell rings]
Ding dong.
Hey.
Hey, y'all.
Oh, thank you. Thank you.
All right?
Here she is.
Remember Lisa from the bank?
Hi, it's nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you too.
Oh, Lisa,
you look a little different
than I thought you would.
Well, let me tell you.
Almost getting killed
will change a person.
Hey, you know what?
Getting killed
will change you too.
Well, the old Lisa is gone,
and the new Lisa needs a drink.
Please tell me
you have a punch bowl.
Yeah, it's in the kitchen.
Is it spiked?
It's not.
That's okay.
I got it.
[Laughing]
Ah, she's funny.
Well, if by "funny"
you mean crazy,
well, she's hilarious.
She's gonna
spike my punchbowl, isn't she?
I think so.
Lisa!
You look good, man.
Don't touch me.
Hey, Nick.
Do you have
any Margarita mix?
Margarita mix.
All right.
Where are you going?
Um, to grab some things
from the store.
Nick, this is
your get-together.
You cannot leave.
Are you two gonna fight?
Go on.
Look, I'll be right back.
You don't have to do
a thing.
Really?
Because some guy
I've never met
was upstairs
with some girl I've never met
giving her
a tour of the house.
A tour, huh?
Ooh!
Don't forget
my Margarita mix.
Bring two:
One for me
and another one for me.
Oh!
This the shizzle my nizzle.
I am not your nizzle.
Ooh, ooh, ooh.
[Laughs]
[Girls scream]
[Excited chatter]
This is just crazy.
Lindsey.
Does your father know how many
people you invited to the party?
It's not a party, mom.
It's a get-together.
Hey.
Lisa.
Look, girl,
you're starting to embarrass me.
Now, will you please
sit your butt down
and get it together?
I like the way
you take charge.
And that's why
you're the President of
the United States of America.
Go, Bama.
You all right, man?
Yeah, I'm all right.
So y'all wanted her here.
What you think?
Well, I think you're a lot
less embarrassed with her here
than you would be out in public.
No, I'm pretty embarrassed
here too.
Lisa!
Girl, put your clothes
back on.
Pow!
Wait for it.
[giggles]
Is that your
rich white man's dress?
You like?
Mm-hmm.
And where would you be going
in that?
What difference
does it make to you?
A guy can't ask?
Well, you can ask,
but it's none of your business.
Man, look at you.
Wherever you're going dressed
like that is where I want to be.
[Giggles]
If you were gonna be
where I was gonna be,
I could guarantee
I wouldn't be there.
[Laughs]
That is good.
If that's
her get-together outfit,
I want to see her
when she goes out.
Can I ask you something?
Shoot.
Who are you?
'Cause Nick said you told him
I invited you.
I was at your store;
I heard you talking about it,
so I just came by.
It's a get-together, right?
What's her name, anyway?
That would be Gigi.
Is that you?
Not anymore.
Do you mind?
Would it matter?
Not really.
Thanks.
Lisa.
Uh, uh.
Okay.
When I say "get to,"
you say "gether."
Get to...
All: Gether.
Nick, I told you
he shouldn't have brought her.
Now we got to find a way
to get her out of here
without causing a scene.
Why don't you set
a Margarita outside?
Lisa, you got to stop this,
all right?
Not only are you
embarrassing me,
but you're embarrassing
yourself.
Now, I know you got a small case
of post-traumatic stress,
but acting like a fool
is not the way to deal with it.
Actually, acting like a fool
is how most people deal with it.
Do you want to get shot?
Oh, that will never happen,
not if he's around.
He's my hero.
Yeah, but if I'd have known
you was gonna act like this,
I'd have left you
under the desk at the bank.
I'm sorry.
I don't usually act
this way.
I just don't want
to be boring anymore.
You're not boring.
You're a fine,
beautiful woman.
All you got to do
is be that way.
You don't have to act
like this.
Oh.
Thank you.
That is the nicest thing
anyone has ever said to me.
Excuse me.
Everybody, can I
have your attention, please?
When I say, "get it,"
you say "started."
Get it...
All: Started.
[Laughter]
All right.
That's it.
Get off of my chair.
Stop eating my food.
Quit doing freaky stuff
in my bathroom.
Everybody get your stuff
and get out of here,
because this party is over.
All: It's not a party.
It's a get-together.
Well, now
it's a get out together.
Right now.
Everybody.
Buh-bye.
Take care.
See y'all at the next one.
[Girls squealing excitedly]
[Clears throat]
You too.
Really?
[Laughing]
Terrence.
What?
When I say, "get it,"
you say--
slam!
Thank you.
Suzanne,
what is wrong with you?
Baby, I know you want us
to spend time as a family
and pay attention to each other,
but all these people
in my house,
it's too much.
Everybody we need
is right here.
Yeah, but where's Kevin?
Yeah, I haven't seen him.
I thought
he was out in the garage.
he was in the kitchen.
[Doorbell rings]
Maybe you threw him out.
Oh, goodness.
Suzanne.
Frank.
Brought you
some potato salad.
So you ain't gonna
invite me in?
Whoa. Whoa.
Wait a minute.
What you doing here, man?
After breaking
my little sister's heart
and running out on the kids,
you got the nerve
to show your face?
Terrence, don't.
Can I?
Nick, stop it.
You know what?
You a low-down--
Gigi, come on.
Yeah, that's right,
Robin Thicke.
Check your girl.
Hold it. Hold it.
Let it go.
What are you doing here,
Frank?
Kev said y'all
was having a get-together.
Dad!
How you doing, son?
He invited me over.
And you, Pumpkin,
what's going on?
Hi, dad.
Will you please
not call me Pumpkin?
It's a baby name.
You still
will always be my baby.
Her and half of Seattle.
I brought a couple of gifts.
For you, I have badminton.
What's badminton?
It's kind of like tennis
for people who really
want to play volleyball.
And for you, Chris Brown.
Chris Brown?
He could transform you.
Really?
Do you not watch the news
at all?
Why don't the three of you
go and catch up?
Good idea.
That's a good idea.
Yeah,
I can show you my room, dad.
Hey, Frank, how you doing?
You know, you look like
you've been watching
a whole lot
of exercise videos.
Shut up.
How long you gonna
let him stay up there?
As long as Kevin likes.
I'm doing this for him.
Frank better hope to God
he's never taken hostage,
'cause he ain't gonna make it.
What does that even mean?
Don't worry about it,
Robin Thicke.
Who's Robin Thicke?
Fun, fun, fun.
Mm, mm, mm.
That was fun, wasn't it?
Thanks for coming, dad.
Hey, thanks
for having me, Kev.
Thanks, daddy.
Come here, Pumpkin.
See you later, dad.
All right, y'all go on.
Bye, dad.
All right, my kids.
Y'all have a good time?
As a matter of fact, we did.
In fact, I'm thinking
about a couple of things.
Thinking about what?
Me spending a little more time
with the kids.
Well, next time
we have a get-together,
I'll be sure to let you know.
Well,
what I'm trying to say is,
I think
that we ought to work out
a joint situation,
like shared custody.
Let's be clear about this.
You made a decision.
All this
wasn't good enough for you.
And don't think you're about
to start coming around here
and playing remember the time.
I remember
all the time with you.
See, now, those are your kids,
and I respect that.
But this is my family.
And don't think
you're about to just
start dropping in on them
like that,
trying to flip the script
'cause you're feeling guilty.
Come on, Nick,
speak up for yourself, man.
What he said.
You know,
speaking of family,
I understand
you've been using my name,
Nick Kingston-Persons.
I can have you arrested
for identity theft.
Well, since I took your wife
and I took your kids,
I figured I might as well
take your name.
Yeah, well,
seeing how we taking things,
why don't you take it all?
You know, take my bathrobe,
my flip-flops,
my jock strap.
I would.
But all that's too small.
Ooh.
Game, set, match.
[Giggles]
Frank, I think it's time
for you to leave.
Okay, fine.
I'll leave.
But I'll be back.
And I'll be waiting on you.
[Scoffs]
Yeah, me too.
Yeah, me three.
Dude's got a lot of nerve.
You handled your business.
I got to give it to you, man.
All: Who are you?
Staten Island Mike.
We need to do this
again sometimes.
Smooch!
[Sighs]
Is he serious?
I don't know.
-- sync, corrected by elderman --
-- for www.addic7ed.Com --