Madame Speaker, Mr. Vice President, Members
of Congress, and the First Lady of the United
States:
I’ve come here tonight not only to address
the distinguished men and women in this great
chamber, but to speak frankly and directly
to the men and women who sent us here.
I know that for many Americans watching right
now, the state of our economy is a concern
that rises above all others. And rightly so.
If you haven’t been personally affected by
this recession, you probably know someone
who has – a friend; a neighbor; a member
of your family. You don’t need to hear another
list of statistics to know that our economy
is in crisis, because you live it every day.
It’s the worry you wake up with and the source
of sleepless nights. It’s the job you thought
you’d retire from but now have lost; the
business you built your dreams upon that’s
now hanging by a thread; the college acceptance
letter your child had to put back in the envelope.
The impact of this recession is real, and
it is everywhere.
But while our economy may be weakened and
our confidence shaken; though we are living
through difficult and uncertain times, tonight
I want every American to know this:
We will rebuild, we will recover, and the
United States of America will emerge stronger
than before.
The weight of this crisis will not determine
the destiny of this nation. The answers to
our problems don’t lie beyond our reach.
They exist in our laboratories and universities;
in our fields and our factories; in the imaginations
of our entrepreneurs and the pride of the
hardest-working people on Earth. Those qualities
that have made America the greatest force
of progress and prosperity in human history
we still possess in ample measure. What is
required now is for this country to pull together,
confront boldly the challenges we face, and
take responsibility for our future once more.
Now, if we’re honest with ourselves, we’ll
admit that for too long, we have not always
met these responsibilities – as a government
or as a people. I say this not to lay blame
or look backwards, but because it is only
by understanding how we arrived at this moment
that we’ll be able to lift ourselves out
of this predicament.
The fact is, our economy did not fall into
decline overnight. Nor did all of our problems
begin when the housing market collapsed or
the stock market sank. We have known for decades
that our survival depends on finding new sources
of energy. Yet we import more oil today than
ever before. The cost of health care eats
up more and more of our savings each year,
yet we keep delaying reform. Our children
will compete for jobs in a global economy
that too many of our schools do not prepare
them for. And though all these challenges
went unsolved, we still managed to spend more
money and pile up more debt, both as individuals
and through our government, than ever before.
In other words, we have lived through an era
where too often, short-term gains were prized
over long-term prosperity; where we failed
to look beyond the next payment, the next
quarter, or the next election. A surplus became
an excuse to transfer wealth to the wealthy
instead of an opportunity to invest in our
future. Regulations were gutted for the sake
of a quick profit at the expense of a healthy
market. People bought homes they knew they
couldn’t afford from banks and lenders who
pushed those bad loans anyway. And all the
while, critical debates and difficult decisions
were put off for some other time on some other
day.
Well that day of reckoning has arrived, and
the time to take charge of our future is here.
Now is the time to act boldly and wisely –
to not only revive this economy, but to build
a new foundation for lasting prosperity. Now
is the time to jumpstart job creation, re-start
lending, and invest in areas like energy,
health care, and education that will grow
our economy, even as we make hard choices
to bring our deficit down. That is what my
economic agenda is designed to do, and that’s
what I’d like to talk to you about tonight.
It’s an agenda that begins with jobs.
As soon
as I took office, I asked this Congress to
send me a recovery plan by President’s Day
that would put people back to work and put
money in their pockets. Not because I believe
in bigger government – I don’t. Not because
I’m not mindful of the massive debt we’ve
inherited – I am. I called for action because
the failure to do so would have cost more
jobs and caused more hardships. In fact, a
failure to act would have worsened our long-term
deficit by assuring weak economic growth for
years. That’s why I pushed for quick action.
And tonight, I am grateful that this Congress
delivered, and pleased to say that the American
Recovery and Reinvestment Act is now law.
Over the next two years, this plan will save
or create 3.5 million jobs. More than 90%
of these jobs will be in the private sector
– jobs rebuilding our roads and bridges;
constructing wind turbines and solar panels;
laying broadband and expanding mass transit.
Because of this plan, there are teachers who
can now keep their jobs and educate our kids.
Health care professionals can continue caring
for our sick. There are 57 police officers
who are still on the streets of Minneapolis
tonight because this plan prevented the layoffs
their department was about to make.
Because of this plan, 95% of the working households
in America will receive a tax cut – a tax
cut that you will see in your paychecks beginning
on April 1st.
Because of this plan, families who are struggling
to pay tuition costs will receive a $2,500
tax credit for all four years of college.
And Americans who have lost their jobs in
this recession will be able to receive extended
unemployment benefits and continued health
care coverage to help them weather this storm.
I know there are some in this chamber and
watching at home who are skeptical of whether
this plan will work. I understand that skepticism.
Here in Washington, we’ve all seen how quickly
good intentions can turn into broken promises
and wasteful spending. And with a plan of
this scale comes enormous responsibility to
get it right.
That is why I have asked Vice President Biden
to lead a tough, unprecedented oversight effort
– because nobody messes with Joe. I have
told each member of my Cabinet as well as
mayors and governors across the country that
they will be held accountable by me and the
American people for every dollar they spend.
I have appointed a proven and aggressive Inspector
General to ferret out any and all cases of
waste and fraud. And we have created a new
website called recovery.gov so that every
American can find out how and where their
money is being spent.
So the recovery plan we passed is the first
step in getting our economy back on track.
But it is just the first step. Because even
if we manage this plan flawlessly, there will
be no real recovery unless we clean up the
credit crisis that has severely weakened our
financial system.
I want to speak plainly and candidly about
this issue tonight, because every American
should know that it directly affects you and
your family’s well-being. You should also
know that the money you’ve deposited in banks
across the country is safe; your insurance
is secure; and you can rely on the continued
operation of our financial system. That is
not the source of concern.
The concern is that if we do not re-start
lending in this country, our recovery will
be choked off before it even begins.
You see, the flow of credit is the lifeblood
of our economy. The ability to get a loan
is how you finance the purchase of everything
from a home to a car to a college education;
how stores stock their shelves, farms buy
equipment, and businesses make payroll.
But credit has stopped flowing the way it
should. Too many bad loans from the housing
crisis have made their way onto the books
of too many banks. With so much debt and so
little confidence, these banks are now fearful
of lending out any more money to households,
to businesses, or to each other. When there
is no lending, families can’t afford to buy
homes or cars. So businesses are forced to
make layoffs. Our economy suffers even more,
and credit dries up even further.
That is why this administration is moving
swiftly and aggressively to break this destructive
cycle, restore confidence, and re-start lending.
We will do so in several ways. First, we are
creating a new lending fund that represents
the largest effort ever to help provide auto
loans, college loans, and small business loans
to the consumers and entrepreneurs who keep
this economy running.
Second, we have launched a housing plan that
will help responsible families facing the
threat of foreclosure lower their monthly
payments and re-finance their mortgages. It’s
a plan that won’t help speculators or that
neighbor down the street who bought a house
he could never hope to afford, but it will
help millions of Americans who are struggling
with declining home values – Americans who
will now be able to take advantage of the
lower interest rates that this plan has already
helped bring about. In fact, the average family
who re-finances today can save nearly $2000
per year on their mortgage.
Third, we will act with the full force of
the federal government to ensure that the
major banks that Americans depend on have
enough confidence and enough money to lend
even in more difficult times. And when we
learn that a major bank has serious problems,
we will hold accountable those responsible,
force the necessary adjustments, provide the
support to clean up their balance sheets,
and assure the continuity of a strong, viable
institution that can serve our people and
our economy.
I understand that on any given day, Wall Street
may be more comforted by an approach that
gives banks bailouts with no strings attached,
and that holds nobody accountable for their
reckless decisions. But such an approach won’t
solve the problem. And our goal is to quicken
the day when we re-start lending to the American
people and American business and end this
crisis once and for all.
I intend to hold these banks fully accountable
for the assistance they receive, and this
time, they will have to clearly demonstrate
how taxpayer dollars result in more lending
for the American taxpayer. This time, CEOs
won’t be able to use taxpayer money to pad
their paychecks or buy fancy drapes or disappear
on a private jet. Those days are over.
Still, this plan will require significant
resources from the federal government – and
yes, probably more than we’ve already set
aside. But while the cost of action will be
great, I can assure you that the cost of inaction
will be far greater, for it could result in
an economy that sputters along for not months
or years, but perhaps a decade. That would
be worse for our deficit, worse for business,
worse for you, and worse for the next generation.
And I refuse to let that happen.
I understand that when the last administration
asked this Congress to provide assistance
for struggling banks, Democrats and Republicans
alike were infuriated by the mismanagement
and results that followed. So were the American
taxpayers. So was I.
So I know how unpopular it is to be seen as
helping banks right now, especially when everyone
is suffering in part from their bad decisions.
I promise you – I get it.
But I also know that in a time of crisis,
we cannot afford to govern out of anger, or
yield to the politics of the moment. My job
– our job – is to solve the problem. Our
job is to govern with a sense of responsibility.
I will not spend a single penny for the purpose
of rewarding a single Wall Street executive,
but I will do whatever it takes to help the
small business that can’t pay its workers
or the family that has saved and still can’t
get a mortgage.
That’s what this is about. It’s not about
helping banks – it’s about helping people.
Because when credit is available again, that
young family can finally buy a new home. And
then some company will hire workers to build
it. And then those workers will have money
to spend, and if they can get a loan too,
maybe they’ll finally buy that car, or open
their own business. Investors will return
to the market, and American families will
see their retirement secured once more. Slowly,
but surely, confidence will return, and our
economy will recover.
So I ask this Congress to join me in doing
whatever proves necessary. Because we cannot
consign our nation to an open-ended recession.
And to ensure that a crisis of this magnitude
never happens again, I ask Congress to move
quickly on legislation that will finally reform
our outdated regulatory system. It is time
to put in place tough, new common-sense rules
of the road so that our financial market rewards
drive and innovation, and punishes short-cuts
and abuse.
The recovery plan and the financial stability
plan are the immediate steps we’re taking
to revive our economy in the short-term. But
the only way to fully restore America’s economic
strength is to make the long-term investments
that will lead to new jobs, new industries,
and a renewed ability to compete with the
rest of the world. The only way this century
will be another American century is if we
confront at last the price of our dependence
on oil and the high cost of health care; the
schools that aren’t preparing our children
and the mountain of debt they stand to inherit.
That is our responsibility.
In the next few days, I will submit a budget
to Congress. So often, we have come to view
these documents as simply numbers on a page
or laundry lists of programs. I see this document
differently. I see it as a vision for America
– as a blueprint for our future.
My budget does not attempt to solve every
problem or address every issue. It reflects
the stark reality of what we’ve inherited
– a trillion dollar deficit, a financial
crisis, and a costly recession.
Given these realities, everyone in this chamber
– Democrats and Republicans – will have
to sacrifice some worthy priorities for which
there are no dollars. And that includes me.
But that does not mean we can afford to ignore
our long-term challenges. I reject the view
that says our problems will simply take care
of themselves; that says government has no
role in laying the foundation for our common
prosperity.
For history tells a different story. History
reminds us that at every moment of economic
upheaval and transformation, this nation has
responded with bold action and big ideas.
In the midst of civil war, we laid railroad
tracks from one coast to another that spurred
commerce and industry. From the turmoil of
the Industrial Revolution came a system of
public high schools that prepared our citizens
for a new age. In the wake of war and depression,
the GI Bill sent a generation to college and
created the largest middle-class in history.
And a twilight struggle for freedom led to
a nation of highways, an American on the moon,
and an explosion of technology that still
shapes our world.
In each case, government didn’t supplant
private enterprise; it catalyzed private enterprise.
It created the conditions for thousands of
entrepreneurs and new businesses to adapt
and to thrive.
We are a nation that has seen promise amid
peril, and claimed opportunity from ordeal.
Now we must be that nation again. That is
why, even as it cuts back on the programs
we don’t need, the budget I submit will invest
in the three areas that are absolutely critical
to our economic future: energy, health care,
and education.
It begins with energy.
We know the country that harnesses the power
of clean, renewable energy will lead the 21st
century. And yet, it is China that has launched
the largest effort in history to make their
economy energy efficient. We invented solar
technology, but we’ve fallen behind countries
like Germany and Japan in producing it. New
plug-in hybrids roll off our assembly lines,
but they will run on batteries made in Korea.
Well I do not accept a future where the jobs
and industries of tomorrow take root beyond
our borders – and I know you don’t either.
It is time for America to lead again.
Thanks to our recovery plan, we will double
this nation’s supply of renewable energy
in the next three years. We have also made
the largest investment in basic research funding
in American history – an investment that
will spur not only new discoveries in energy,
but breakthroughs in medicine, science, and
technology.
We will soon lay down thousands of miles of
power lines that can carry new energy to cities
and towns across this country. And we will
put Americans to work making our homes and
buildings more efficient so that we can save
billions of dollars on our energy bills.
But to truly transform our economy, protect
our security, and save our planet from the
ravages of climate change, we need to ultimately
make clean, renewable energy the profitable
kind of energy. So I ask this Congress to
send me legislation that places a market-based
cap on carbon pollution and drives the production
of more renewable energy in America. And to
support that innovation, we will invest fifteen
billion dollars a year to develop technologies
like wind power and solar power; advanced
biofuels, clean coal, and more fuel-efficient
cars and trucks built right here in America.
As for our auto industry, everyone recognizes
that years of bad decision-making and a global
recession have pushed our automakers to the
brink. We should not, and will not, protect
them from their own bad practices. But we
are committed to the goal of a re-tooled,
re-imagined auto industry that can compete
and win. Millions of jobs depend on it. Scores
of communities depend on it. And I believe
the nation that invented the automobile cannot
walk away from it.
None of this will come without cost, nor will
it be easy. But this is America. We don’t
do what’s easy. We do what is necessary to
move this country forward.
For that same reason, we must also address
the crushing cost of health care.
This is a cost that now causes a bankruptcy
in America every thirty seconds. By the end
of the year, it could cause 1.5 million Americans
to lose their homes. In the last eight years,
premiums have grown four times faster than
wages. And in each of these years, one million
more Americans have lost their health insurance.
It is one of the major reasons why small businesses
close their doors and corporations ship jobs
overseas. And it’s one of the largest and
fastest-growing parts of our budget.
Given these facts, we can no longer afford
to put health care reform on hold.
Already, we have done more to advance the
cause of health care reform in the last thirty
days than we have in the last decade. When
it was days old, this Congress passed a law
to provide and protect health insurance for
eleven million American children whose parents
work full-time. Our recovery plan will invest
in electronic health records and new technology
that will reduce errors, bring down costs,
ensure privacy, and save lives. It will launch
a new effort to conquer a disease that has
touched the life of nearly every American
by seeking a cure for cancer in our time.
And it makes the largest investment ever in
preventive care, because that is one of the
best ways to keep our people healthy and our
costs under control.
This budget builds on these reforms. It includes
an historic commitment to comprehensive health
care reform – a down-payment on the principle
that we must have quality, affordable health
care for every American. It’s a commitment
that’s paid for in part by efficiencies in
our system that are long overdue. And it’s
a step we must take if we hope to bring down
our deficit in the years to come.
Now, there will be many different opinions
and ideas about how to achieve reform, and
that is why I’m bringing together businesses
and workers, doctors and health care providers,
Democrats and Republicans to begin work on
this issue next week.
I suffer no illusions that this will be an
easy process. It will be hard. But I also
know that nearly a century after Teddy Roosevelt
first called for reform, the cost of our health
care has weighed down our economy and the
conscience of our nation long enough. So let
there be no doubt: health care reform cannot
wait, it must not wait, and it will not wait
another year.
The third challenge we must address is the
urgent need to expand the promise of education
in America.
In a global economy where the most valuable
skill you can sell is your knowledge, a good
education is no longer just a pathway to opportunity
– it is a pre-requisite.
Right now, three-quarters of the fastest-growing
occupations require more than a high school
diploma. And yet, just over half of our citizens
have that level of education. We have one
of the highest high school dropout rates of
any industrialized nation. And half of the
students who begin college never finish.
This is a prescription for economic decline,
because we know the countries that out-teach
us today will out-compete us tomorrow. That
is why it will be the goal of this administration
to ensure that every child has access to a
complete and competitive education – from
the day they are born to the day they begin
a career.
Already, we have made an historic investment
in education through the economic recovery
plan. We have dramatically expanded early
childhood education and will continue to improve
its quality, because we know that the most
formative learning comes in those first years
of life. We have made college affordable for
nearly seven million more students. And we
have provided the resources necessary to prevent
painful cuts and teacher layoffs that would
set back our children’s progress.
But we know that our schools don’t just need
more resources. They need more reform. That
is why this budget creates new incentives
for teacher performance; pathways for advancement,
and rewards for success. We’ll invest in
innovative programs that are already helping
schools meet high standards and close achievement
gaps. And we will expand our commitment to
charter schools.
It is our responsibility as lawmakers and
educators to make this system work. But it
is the responsibility of every citizen to
participate in it. And so tonight, I ask every
American to commit to at least one year or
more of higher education or career training.
This can be community college or a four-year
school; vocational training or an apprenticeship.
But whatever the training may be, every American
will need to get more than a high school diploma.
And dropping out of high school is no longer
an option. It’s not just quitting on yourself,
it’s quitting on your country – and this
country needs and values the talents of every
American. That is why we will provide the
support necessary for you to complete college
and meet a new goal: by 2020, America will
once again have the highest proportion of
college graduates in the world.
I know that the price of tuition is higher
than ever, which is why if you are willing
to volunteer in your neighborhood or give
back to your community or serve your country,
we will make sure that you can afford a higher
education. And to encourage a renewed spirit
of national service for this and future generations,
I ask this Congress to send me the bipartisan
legislation that bears the name of Senator
Orrin Hatch as well as an American who has
never stopped asking what he can do for his
country – Senator Edward Kennedy.
These education policies will open the doors
of opportunity for our children. But it is
up to us to ensure they walk through them.
In the end, there is no program or policy
that can substitute for a mother or father
who will attend those parent/teacher conferences,
or help with homework after dinner, or turn
off the TV, put away the video games, and
read to their child. I speak to you not just
as a President, but as a father when I say
that responsibility for our children's education
must begin at home.
There is, of course, another responsibility
we have to our children. And that is the responsibility
to ensure that we do not pass on to them a
debt they cannot pay. With the deficit we
inherited, the
cost of the crisis we face, and the long-term
challenges we must meet, it has never been
more important to ensure that as our economy
recovers, we do what it takes to bring this
deficit down.
I’m proud that we passed the recovery plan
free of earmarks, and I want to pass a budget
next year that ensures that each dollar we
spend reflects only our most important national
priorities.
Yesterday, I held a fiscal summit where I
pledged to cut the deficit in half by the
end of my first term in office. My administration
has also begun to go line by line through
the federal budget in order to eliminate wasteful
and ineffective programs. As you can imagine,
this is a process that will take some time.
But we’re starting with the biggest lines.
We have already identified two trillion dollars
in savings over the next decade.
In this budget, we will end education programs
that don’t work and end direct payments to
large agribusinesses that don’t need them.
We’ll eliminate the no-bid contracts that
have wasted billions in Iraq, and reform our
defense budget so that we’re not paying for
Cold War-era weapons systems we don’t use.
We will root out the waste, fraud, and abuse
in our Medicare program that doesn’t make
our seniors any healthier, and we will restore
a sense of fairness and balance to our tax
code by finally ending the tax breaks for
corporations that ship our jobs overseas.
In order to save our children from a future
of debt, we will also end the tax breaks for
the wealthiest 2% of Americans. But let me
perfectly clear, because I know you’ll hear
the same old claims that rolling back these
tax breaks means a massive tax increase on
the American people: if your family earns
less than $250,000 a year, you will not see
your taxes increased a single dime. I repeat:
not one single dime. In fact, the recovery
plan provides a tax cut – that’s right,
a tax cut – for 95% of working families.
And these checks are on the way.
To preserve our long-term fiscal health, we
must also address the growing costs in Medicare
and Social Security. Comprehensive health
care reform is the best way to strengthen
Medicare for years to come. And we must also
begin a conversation on how to do the same
for Social Security, while creating tax-free
universal savings accounts for all Americans.
Finally, because we’re also suffering from
a deficit of trust, I am committed to restoring
a sense of honesty and accountability to our
budget. That is why this budget looks ahead
ten years and accounts for spending that was
left out under the old rules – and for the
first time, that includes the full cost of
fighting in Iraq and Afghanistan. For seven
years, we have been a nation at war. No longer
will we hide its price.
We are now carefully reviewing our policies
in both wars, and I will soon announce a way
forward in Iraq that leaves Iraq to its people
and responsibly ends this war.
And with our friends and allies, we will forge
a new and comprehensive strategy for Afghanistan
and Pakistan to defeat al Qaeda and combat
extremism. Because I will not allow terrorists
to plot against the American people from safe
havens half a world away.
As we meet here tonight, our men and women
in uniform stand watch abroad and more are
readying to deploy. To each and every one
of them, and to the families who bear the
quiet burden of their absence, Americans are
united in sending one message: we honor your
service, we are inspired by your sacrifice,
and you have our unyielding support. To relieve
the strain on our forces, my budget increases
the number of our soldiers and Marines. And
to keep our sacred trust with those who serve,
we will raise their pay, and give our veterans
the expanded health care and benefits that
they have earned.
To overcome extremism, we must also be vigilant
in upholding the values our troops defend
– because there is no force in the world
more powerful than the example of America.
That is why I have ordered the closing of
the detention center at Guantanamo Bay, and
will seek swift and certain justice for captured
terrorists – because living our values doesn’t
make us weaker, it makes us safer and it makes
us stronger. And that is why I can stand here
tonight and say without exception or equivocation
that the United States of America does not
torture.
In words and deeds, we are showing the world
that a new era of engagement has begun. For
we know that America cannot meet the threats
of this century alone, but the world cannot
meet them without America. We cannot shun
the negotiating table, nor ignore the foes
or forces that could do us harm. We are instead
called to move forward with the sense of confidence
and candor that serious times demand.
To seek progress toward a secure and lasting
peace between Israel and her neighbors, we
have appointed an envoy to sustain our effort.
To meet the challenges of the 21st century
– from terrorism to nuclear proliferation;
from pandemic disease to cyber threats to
crushing poverty – we will strengthen old
alliances, forge new ones, and use all elements
of our national power.
And to respond to an economic crisis that
is global in scope, we are working with the
nations of the G-20 to restore confidence
in our financial system, avoid the possibility
of escalating protectionism, and spur demand
for American goods in markets across the globe.
For the world depends on us to have a strong
economy, just as our economy depends on the
strength of the world’s.
As we stand at this crossroads of history,
the eyes of all people in all nations are
once again upon us – watching to see what
we do with this moment; waiting for us to
lead.
Those of us gathered here tonight have been
called to govern in extraordinary times. It
is a tremendous burden, but also a great privilege
– one that has been entrusted to few generations
of Americans. For in our hands lies the ability
to shape our world for good or for ill.
I know that it is easy to lose sight of this
truth – to become cynical and doubtful; consumed
with the petty and the trivial.
But in my life, I have also learned that hope
is found in unlikely places; that inspiration
often comes not from those with the most power
or celebrity, but from the dreams and aspirations
of Americans who are anything but ordinary.
I think about Leonard Abess, the bank president
from Miami who reportedly cashed out of his
company, took a $60 million bonus, and gave
it out to all 399 people who worked for him,
plus another 72 who used to work for him.
He didn’t tell anyone, but when the local
newspaper found out, he simply said, ''I knew
some of these people since I was 7 years old.
I didn't feel right getting the money myself."
I think about Greensburg, Kansas, a town that
was completely destroyed by a tornado, but
is being rebuilt by its residents as a global
example of how clean energy can power an entire
community – how it can bring jobs and businesses
to a place where piles of bricks and rubble
once lay. "The tragedy was terrible," said
one of the men who helped them rebuild. "But
the folks here know that it also provided
an incredible opportunity."
And I think about Ty’Sheoma Bethea, the young
girl from that school I visited in Dillon,
South Carolina – a place where the ceilings
leak, the paint peels off the walls, and they
have to stop teaching six times a day because
the train barrels by their classroom. She
has been told that her school is hopeless,
but the other day after class she went to
the public library and typed up a letter to
the people sitting in this room. She even
asked her principal for the money to buy a
stamp. The letter asks us for help, and says,
"We are just students trying to become lawyers,
doctors, congressmen like yourself and one
day president, so we can make a change to
not just the state of South Carolina but also
the world. We are not quitters."
We are not quitters.
These words and these stories tell us something
about the spirit of the people who sent us
here. They tell us that even in the most trying
times, amid the most difficult circumstances,
there is a generosity, a resilience, a decency,
and a determination that perseveres; a willingness
to take responsibility for our future and
for posterity.
Their resolve must be our inspiration. Their
concerns must be our cause. And we must show
them and all our people that we are equal
to the task before us.
I know that we haven’t agreed on every issue
thus far, and there are surely times in the
future when we will part ways. But I also
know that every American who is sitting here
tonight loves this country and wants it to
succeed. That
must be the starting point for every debate
we have in the coming months, and where we
return after those debates are done. That
is the foundation on which the American people
expect us to build common ground.
And if we do – if we come together and lift
this nation from the depths of this crisis;
if we put our people back to work and restart
the engine of our prosperity; if we confront
without fear the challenges of our time and
summon that enduring spirit of an America
that does not quit, then someday years from
now our children can tell their children that
this was the time when we performed, in the
words that are carved into this very chamber,
"something worthy to be remembered." Thank
you, God Bless you, and may God Bless the
United States of America.