WOLF BLITZER, CNN ANCHOR: CNN projects that
Barack Obama will be re- elected president
of the United States. He will remain in the
White House for another four years.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
CARL AZUZ, CNN ANCHOR: Month of campaigning,
primaries, caucuses, rallies, debates, all
leading up to that moment -- the announcement
of a victory and a second term in office for
President Obama. It takes at least 270 votes
in the electoral college to win the presidency.
In Tuesday`s elections, CNN projected that
President Obama won more than 300. In the
race for the White House, Republican and Democratic
candidates clashed over their differences,
but as that race came to a close, the president
talked about the things that Americans have
in common. And he talked about what lies ahead
for the nation.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
BARACK OBAMA, PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES
OF AMERICA: It doesn`t matter whether you
are black, or white, or Hispanic, or Asian
or Native American, or young or old, or rich,
or poor, able, disabled, gay or straight.
You can make it here in America if you`re
willing to try.
(APPLAUSE)
OBAMA: I believe we can seize this future
together, because we are not as divided as
our politics suggest. We are not as cynical
as the pundits believe. We are greater than
the sum of our individual ambitions, and we
remain more than a collection of red states
and blue states. We are and forever will be
the United States of America, and together
with your help and God`s grace, we will continue
our journey forward and remind the world just
why is that we live in the greatest nation
on Earth. Thank you, America.
God bless you. God bless these United States.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: For former Governor Romney Tuesday`s
election marked the end of a journey that
started nearly a year and a half ago. He won
the Republican Party`s presidential nomination,
but he wasn`t able to rally enough support
to win the White House. Last night he congratulated
his opponent, he thanked his supporters and
he talked about his hopes for the country`s
future.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
MITT ROMNEY, REPUBLICAN PRESIDENTIAL CANDIDATE:
This election is over, but our principles
endure, I believe that the principles upon
which this nation was founded are the only
sure guide to a resurgent economy and to renewed
greatness. Like so many of you, Paul and I
have left everything on the field. We have
given our all to this campaign.
(APPLAUSE)
ROMNEY: I so wish, I so wish that I had been
able to fulfill your hopes to lead the country
in a different direction, but the nation chose
another leader and so Ann and I join with
you to earnestly pray for him and for this
great nation. Thank you and God bless America.
You guys are the best. Thank you so much.
RONALD REAGAN, PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES
OF AMERICA, NOVEMBER 4, 1980: I`m not frightened
by what lies ahead and I don`t believe the
American people are frightened by what lies
ahead.
(APPLAUSE)
GEORGE H.W. BUSH, NOVEMBER 4, 1988: I want
to work for the hopes and interests, not only
of my supporters, but of the governors and
of those who didn`t vote at all. To those
who supported me I will try to be worthy of
your trust and to those who did not, I will
try to earn it.
BILL CLINTON, NOVEMBER 4, 1992. On this day,
with high hopes and brave hearts and massive
numbers the American people have voted to
make a new beginning.
GEORGE W. BUSH, DECEMBER 13, 2000: The presidency
is more than an honor, it is more than an
office, it is a charge to keep and I will
give it my all.
BARACK OBAMA, NOVEMBER 4, 2008: Because of
what we did on this day, in this election,
at this defining moment, change has come to
America.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: Some big moments for those men who were
all on their way to be presidents of the United
States. But how much do you know about the
position itself? Here is a little quiz we
have for you. You may know that you have to
be at least 35 years old, and you have to
have been born in the U.S., but you also have
to have lived in the U.S. for at least how
many years?
The answer is 14. Next up, who was the longest
serving U.S. president? Franklin D. Roosevelt
was elected to four terms, and that record
appears safe, because there`s a current limit
of two terms. That song you hear played for
president at official events, what`s the name
of that? It`s titled "Hail to the Chief."
What about the oldest elected U.S. president?
Ronald Reagan was 69 when he became president.
And the youngest elected? John F. Kennedy
was elected at the age of 43. And finally,
what is the U.S. president`s salary? $400,000
a year.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: It`s time for "The Shoutout."
Which of these U.S. political positions serves
a two year term? If you think you know it,
shout it out! Is it president, senator, representative
or vice president? You`ve got three seconds,
go!
U.S. representatives serve two year terms,
the shortest of these options. That`s your
answer and that`s your "Shoutout."
AZUZ: That means the entire U.S. House of
Representatives, all 435 voting seats were
up for election yesterday, before yesterday`s
vote, Republicans had control with 240 seats,
Democrats had 190 seats, and five seats were
vacant. Last night, CNN projected that Republicans
would keep control of the House. When we produced
this show, Republicans had won an estimated
221 seats, Democrats had won 163 seats, and
51 seats were still undecided. As a balance
of power was closer in the U.S. Senate and
it was going to stay that way. Senators serve
six-year terms, so only a third of the Senate,
about 33 seats, were up for a vote on Tuesday.
Going into that vote, there were 51 Democrats
and 47 Republicans in the chamber, plus two
independents who usually vote with the Democrats.
When we produced this show, CNN predicted
that Democrats would retain control with 51
seats, and Republicans would have 44 seats.
Independents would have 2. Three seats were
still undecided.
Now, to get the latest numbers in the House
of Senate races, go to cnnstudentnews.com.
We`ll talk about the White House and both
houses of Congress. Voters also cast their
ballots on all sorts of state and local races
yesterday. We are going to focus on that top
spot in state government, the governor. 11
were voted on yesterday. Let`s start with
these six states. Vermont, Delaware, West
Virginia, Missouri, North Dakota and Utah.
In these states, the incumbent, the current
governor was running for reelection, and in
all of them, the incumbent won. The five other
states that had gubernatorial elections yesterday
were definitely going to get a new governor.
The races in Washington and Montana hadn`t
been polled when we recorded this program,
but in New Hampshire and Indiana, the new
governor will be from the same party as the
current governor. North Carolina is the only
state where we know there will be a different
party in the governor`s mansion. So what it`s
like to actually get out and vote in the presidential
election? Especially for the first time? And
I-Reporter in Georgia cast her first ballot
yesterday. She talked to us about why she
thought it was both cool and important for
her to vote.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
SHELBY NORMAN, FIRST TIME VOTER, AGE 18: Hi,
I`m Shelby Norman, and I`m in Saville (ph),
Georgia waiting to go inside to start my first
voting experience. I`ve been preparing for
a little while, now I`ve been reading news
editorials and learning a little bit about
each candidate and everything that I will
be voting for.
So, I`m inside now, I`m getting ready to vote.
They`ve got my photo I.D. ready to go. And
right now I`m feeling pretty anxious and pretty
excited. Being a first time voter is a really
crazy experience, and it`s something that
I really looked forward to for a while now.
And so, I`m just really excited to go in there
and stand in line with my parents and we`re
just going to stand and wait. I`m not really
sure how long it will take, but the line seems
pretty short, and we can actually wait inside,
which is really nice, because it`s really
cold outside. So it`s time to go.
So I just came out of my polling place and
I have finished voting for the first time,
and I got my commemorate "I`m a Georgia Voter"
sticker.
The whole process took around 45 minutes.
It`s very important for you to do your research.
Because you are not just voting for who you
think is going to be president, but also your
state representatives. It`s very important
that you go out and exercise your right to
vote, because not everyone gets that choice.
And it`s really important because your voice
does get heard whether you think it does or
not.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: All right, before we go, here is a look
at what it was like to be here at CNN on election
night.
So, the time is just after 7:15 p.m. The staff
of CNN STUDENT NEWS is just coming right now
on election night. There is so much anticipation
in the air, it`s so much going on here, at
CNN Center. We thought we`d give you a behind
the scenes look of election night 2012. Come
on.
So, we are downstairs right now in the CNN
Center food court, and what you see behind
me, is a panel assembled by CNN en Espanol.
We are looking at folks who are Democrats,
Republicans, independents. What they are going
to be viewing is watching the coverage live
as it develops and giving their comments and
their thoughts on this election night. All
the while, taking a look at it, up on the
big screen here, at CNN Center.
We are now at CNN`s Image and Sound headquarters
where a lot of the shows, a lot of the materials
we show you are edited. In fact, you could
see CNN STUDENT NEWS being put together as
I speak.
Well, there is more to be seen on CNN STUDENT
NEWS this week, but for now we have reached
the end of the race, so we will be back on
the air Thursday, and we will be looking for
your support.