And I'm here in Los
Angeles with Vice.
And I'm about to meet Larry
Flynt, pornographer, rebel
godless heathen, political
activist, and so much more.
Let's go.
Mr. Flynt, thanks so much for
inviting us into your office.
It's incredibly generous
of you.
LARRY FLYNT: All right.
Thank you.
REIHAN SALAM: I wanted to ask
you, was there a moment when
you were a kid when you decided
that you were destined
for extraordinary things?
LARRY FLYNT: I was about 10
years old, and I was standing
on a swinging bridge across the
river in Eastern Kentucky.
You don't understand,
our biggest
industry was jury duty.
You couldn't get
a job anywhere.
And I just felt there was
more to the world
than where I was living.
I felt I wanted to be wealthy
because I was so poor then.
I felt that success was
measured by money.
Now I realize that success
is not measured
by what you've got.
But it's measured by the
obstacles you had to overcome
in order to achieve it.
REIHAN SALAM: Was there a
particular person when you
were 10 who inspired you, or
someone who came from the
outside world, someone who gave
you a bigger sense of the
world outside of Eastern
Kentucky?
LARRY FLYNT: My role models were
really world leaders and
politicians and people like
that, rather than actors.
I was influenced a great deal
by President Kennedy.
REIHAN SALAM: Kennedy is a guy
who grew up in great privilege
and someone who, I suppose you
could say, used that privilege
to go into public service and
devote himself to a larger
cause than himself.
But I wonder why it was Kennedy
who sparked that
enthusiasm in you, given that he
came from a very different
kind of background.
LARRY FLYNT: I don't have a good
answer for that, other
than when he would speak, I
used to get goose pimples.
JOHN F. KENNEDY: Before this
decade is out of landing a man
on the moon and returning
him safely to the earth.
LARRY FLYNT: I always thought
he was so profound.
REIHAN SALAM: I would love to
know, the Obama presidency
began with tremendous
enthusiasm.
And I wonder, as someone who
is a great devotee of
President Kennedy, do you think
that President Obama has
proved to be up to snuff?
LARRY FLYNT: I think President
Obama has overperformed.
I know this has become a cliche,
but it's so true.
He got handed on his platter
when he became president more
than any president in history
ever had to deal with.
I'm just amazed he's--
Sure, he hasn't done
everything perfect.
He made a few mistakes
along the way.
But he did a marvelous job.
REIHAN SALAM: When you say he's
overperformed, is there a
particular quality that
he has that you think
accounts for that?
LARRY FLYNT: I see him and Jack
Kennedy have the same
intellect, in terms
of being smart.
That's been his best asset.
But now you don't understand
that when he was trying to do
business with the Republicans
on the deficit and the debt
ceiling and all that kind of
stuff, he was just one man
fighting everybody to
try and get a deal.
REIHAN SALAM: Did you
ever think that
you'd go into politics?
Did you ever think you'd
run for office?
LARRY FLYNT: No.
But I've always been fascinated
with politics.
And I actually think that I know
more than most people do
about the political status
of our nation.
REIHAN SALAM: You recently
announced a
challenge, a bounty.
Can you tell us a little
bit about that?
LARRY FLYNT: Well, in every
presidential cycle for the
last 30 years, we've run a full
page ad in the Washington
Post where we offer a $1 million
reward for anyone that
can provide information
on their politicians.
REIHAN SALAM: Have you
paid out the $1
million in the past?
LARRY FLYNT: Oh yes.
We've had a number
of different--
Sometimes they've had to split
it up because there've been
more sources than one.
There is nothing that will
change someone's moral outlook
more than cash in large sums.
REIHAN SALAM: Indeed.
LARRY FLYNT: And I don't think
that because you pay for
information that it's
any less credible.
REIHAN SALAM: You're not just
a political activist.
You're also are someone who
built a mammoth, innovative
publishing empire.
And I wonder what was
the innovation?
What was your key insight?
LARRY FLYNT: I was successful
not because of what I did, but
in spite of what I did.
I did not know the publishing
business.
I just knew that I
read magazines
like Playboy and Penthouse.
I had a chain of clubs
in the Midwest.
And somebody said, why
don't you do a club
like Playboy did?
So I looked at the magazines,
and I just realized, hey, if
they want to know which
car to buy,
they'll buy another magazine.
If they want to know how to
make some perfect martini,
they can find out from
a local bartender.
They really wanted to know about
girls, and they want to
see pretty women.
And that's more or less
a philosophy that
I applied to Hustler.
It's that if you look at
Playboy, it's obvious that
Hefner likes blonds with big
boobs, Amazon-type girls.
You look at Hustler, you
don't know what I like.
Small, medium, large.
We have brunettes, redheads,
blondes, whatever.
It's the girl next door look.
You might see a girl in Hustler
who reminds you of a
girl you've seen at the
laundromat or something.
REIHAN SALAM: What was the
initial inspiration to go into
opening these clubs and sort of
basically going into this
business of--
LARRY FLYNT: Well, when I
got out of the Navy, I
didn't have a trade.
I didn't have a lot of
formal education.
So the easiest business for me
to get into would be to go in
the bar and club business.
And that's what I did.
And that's how I get started.
REIHAN SALAM: Where did the
original money come from?
Was it just your savings
from the Navy?
LARRY FLYNT: I worked in
factories, GM factories.
And I saved a little money.
The first license--
All I had was only a beer bar.
You couldn't even
serve liquor.
REIHAN SALAM: And this
was in Dayton?
LARRY FLYNT: Yeah.
And then I continued to expand
into other cities in Ohio.
REIHAN SALAM: So in recent
years, obviously the rise of
the internet and internet
pornography has been a huge
challenge to a lot of those
established publishing empires.
And I wonder, have you ever
felt under siege by it?
Have you ever felt like this
world you had built was really
being shaken up?
LARRY FLYNT: I first took notice
in the '70s, when VHS
and Betamax came along.
I felt that that definitely was
going to take adult movies
into the home.
And then in the '80s, as the
internet started becoming the
focus, I felt the industry's
changing, and I
better change with it.
So I put up my first website
in the early '90s.
REIHAN SALAM: Do you ever miss
that world of '70s, back
before VHS and Betamax,
and adult movies
came into the home?
Do you ever miss that world
where people had to go to
movie theaters and go to
the red light district?
LARRY FLYNT: Yeah, I
miss it because it
was a lot more simple.
People think the world is simple
today because you have
all the gadgetry and the
internet and everything.
But life was much more
simple then.
And there's a certain
yearning.
REIHAN SALAM: Was there a
camaraderie there in those
clubs in Dayton and everywhere
else that you were building
up, where people were going to
peep shows and going to adult
movie theaters?
Was there a spirit that you
miss in those places?
Or is that an [INAUDIBLE]?
LARRY FLYNT: I definitely do.
Those are my fondest memories,
the early years with Hustler
and building Hustler up.
But then as I was saying, but
I continued to diversify.
I went into the gaming
business.
We have probably one of the
most successful casinos in
California, about half an hour
south of LA, which is very
profitable.
REIHAN SALAM: There are a lot of
people who fret a lot about
how accessible pornography is
and how the easy availability
of pornography has really
changed relations
between men and women.
Do you worry about that all?
Do you think that it's changed
things for the worse, or do
you think it's changed things
for the better?
LARRY FLYNT: I think it changes
it for the better.
One thing that pornography does
that people don't realize
is it desensitizes people.
Because one of the biggest
problems in relationships now
is premature ejaculation
on behalf of the man.
Well if I'm viewing pornography
and being exposed
to pornography, it takes that
immediate impulse away.
And you're not as apt
to be so quick.
REIHAN SALAM: Although I wonder,
when you were growing
up in eastern Kentucky, say when
you were in your early
teens, was there an excitement
around forming those early
attachments, those early
relationships with girls that
isn't necessarily there
for today's teenagers?
LARRY FLYNT: Possibly they
may be a little bit more
promiscuous today then it was
then, as the religious right
would try to get
you to believe.
They attribute this
to my pornography.
REIHAN SALAM: But it's also true
that there are a lot of
folks, a lot of feminists,
who've given you a pretty hard
time, and who've been
very hostile.
And I wonder, do you think that
they just have it wrong?
LARRY FLYNT: When they would
criticize me about
pornography, they'd say I was
exploiting women, what I was
doing was demeaning to women.
That's like saying that Sports
Illustrated exploits sports.
That's what I was selling.
I've never, ever had a woman
pose for the magazine and say
that she was coerced into doing
it or that she felt she
was being exploited.
That's just the feminists
coming up
with their own brand.
REIHAN SALAM: There was a moment
in the late '70s when
the evangelical movement
was really on the rise.
And there were a lot of people,
who had never been a
part of it, really got
drawn into it.
And my understanding is that in
the late '70s, there was a
moment when you yourself
embraced religion.
Do you remember that?
And what was it that
led you there?
LARRY FLYNT: I got over that.
REIHAN SALAM: What was
it though back then?
Because you were already a
pretty successful entrepreneur
at the time.
LARRY FLYNT: I did have a very
profound religious experience.
And most people, when they
have this born-again type
experience, the average person
has nobody to talk to.
They don't want to go to the
doctor because they don't want
to be perceived as being
mentally ill.
So the only thing they can do
is talk to a member of their
family or neighbor
or something.
And they're directed to
start going to church.
So that way, you're already
caught up in
the religious sect.
But I sought out a psychiatrist
immediately after
it happened to me.
REIHAN SALAM: It's funny that
it led you to the doctor,
because most people when they
feel that warmth, they would
welcome it rather than
go to the doctor.
LARRY FLYNT: My psychiatrist
simply told me--
He said, we know nothing
about the brain.
He said, even brain surgeons
don't know anything about it.
He says, this is largely thought
to be because of a
iodine deficiency
in your diet.
REIHAN SALAM: Do you think that
more devoutly religious
Americans would be less devoutly
religious if they
just ate more salt?
LARRY FLYNT: He showed me a
whole map of the world.
It shows where stronger iodine
deposits were in the salts.
And there was always a higher
degree of manic depressive
people that lived in those
particular areas.
So he says there's definitely
a correlation between the
iodine in the salt and the manic
depressive and the use
of lithium as treatment.
REIHAN SALAM: How did that
change things, that experience
of having faced death?
LARRY FLYNT: Somebody asked me
once, they said, what's it
like to be in a wheelchair
all these years?
I said, I don't know.
I never thought about it
until you asked me.
I don't dwell on things I
can't do anything about.
So that in a nutshell
tells you about the
type of person I am.
I don't waste time dealing
with things
that I can't solve.