We just got back from North
Korea, and all I
can say is holy fuck.
[PUNK MUSIC]
Before I went North Korea, I
didn't know that much about
it, except for that was the
last real deal cult of
personality socialist utopian
state left on earth.
I mean, I knew Kim Jong Il was
the permed dude with the big
glasses who drank more
Hennessy than
anybody else on earth.
But when we did more research,
we found out that, oh, Kim
Jong Il is a huge film buff.
He has over 20,000 titles.
He built seven personal, private
theaters, and he loves
slasher films, Godzilla movies,
and Elizabeth Taylor.
In fact, he loves film so much
that he built a huge studio
right in the middle of the
nation's capital, Pyongyang.
So Kim Jong Il, freakiest
guy in the world.
North Korea, freakiest
country in the world.
Kidnapping people to make the
freakiest films in the world.
This all equals freakiest
film story ever.
[MILITARY MARCH]
Kim Jong Il came to power
in 1993 after the
death of his father.
His father, Kim Il Song was
the first ruler, slash
Generalissimo of North Korea.
Kim Jong Il made a film about
his dad, which helped sort of
smooth and solidify his move
into power to become the next
God, slash father, slash
ultimate ruler, slash Playboy
of North Korea.
Kim Jong Il is known to his
people as the great general.
But he's also great
at everything.
He's a perfect architect, a
perfect clothing designer.
He's the best that
animal husbandry.
He's also the best
at making cheese.
He's perfect at all arts,
especially film.
In fact, he wrote
a book about it.
So Kim Jong Il builds this huge
film studio in the middle
of Pyongyang, but
he doesn't have
anyone to make the movies.
So he goes out and
kidnaps them.
[SPEAKING KOREAN]
So as most people are trying to
get out of North Korea, we
were trying to get in, which
is no easy task.
And it took us about a year
and a half of continual
nagging and calling before we
got a tentative OK to come to
Northern China in Shenyang and
apply in person at the North
Korean consulate for a visa
to get into North Korea.
They pick you up.
They put you in a car.
They take your passport.
They take your money.
And they drop you off in
a North Korean bar.
You're in this North Korean bar,
and they're singing these
propaganda songs right away.
And if wasn't for my buddy Mark
from the LA Times-- thank
you Mark-- who twigged me to the
fact that everybody in the
bar is secret police, and if
you don't show the proper
enthusiasm for the propaganda
songs, you're not
going to get in.
So I drank blueberry wine, got
pissed, got up, started
singing the songs as
best as I could.
And because of that I got my
visa the next day, and I got
into North Korea.
So you arrive in Pyongyang.
And your guards come and
get you right away.
And they put you in a car, and
they take you into the city.
The first thing you notice on
the drive in is that there's
no traffic.
There's no cars.
People walk everywhere.
Then you drive up to your
hotel, which is
this 45-story hotel.
But there's only one
line of lights
through the whole hotel.
And you realize, oh, there's
only one floor being used.
You go into the lobby, and
it's totally empty.
All there is is a sort of tragic
sea turtle floating by
himself in this tank.
We've come to a 1950s communist
time capsule.
Industrial wasteland.
Flooding, dirt, dirt.
I can't go anywhere.
The hotel's on an island, and
you can't leave without your
guard, your guide, and
secret police.
The only way I knew he was
secret police is that he was
never on camera.
But when they do take you,
they take you where
they want you to go.
It's a government-approved
itinerary.
And the first place they
take you is to the DMZ.
The DMZ, or the demilitarized
zone--
which is actually kind of a
funny name because it's the
most militarized zone
in the world--
is the last vestige
of the Cold War.
This is the last place on earth
where East meets West.
This is the historical spot
where the Korean People's Army
made the Americans kneel down
like dogs, and they should
remember that.
Alright.
I'll tell them.
So this kind of tour goes
on for about three days.
They take you to
this monument.
that monument.
You don't know where it is.
You don't know what it is.
But you have to do it.
You have to go to the House of
the People, the Library of the
People, the Soccer Player of the
People, the Juche Ideals
of the People.
The People of this, the
People of that.
Stultifyingly boring monument
after boring monument.
And the whole time we're saying,
hey, can we go to the
film studios?
Please can we go see
the film studios?
And they're just
like, nothing.
They won't show anything.
They won't say anything.
But they did take us to one
place that really blew our
minds, and that was Arirang,
the mass gymnastics.
You sit here in the biggest
stadium in the world with
150,000 kids out there, just
getting ready to do a show.
We're sitting on a dais
generally reserved for the
great General Kim Jong Il,
and we're sitting here--
[CHEERING CROWD]
--all these people are waiting
to perform for us.
It's the most insane feeling
you've ever had in your life.
[NORTH KOREAN PROPAGANDIST
MUSIC]
The Arirang games are like a
live version of a Hollywood
action film.
There's 120,000 kids that have
trained for two years to do
all these card changing
and back flips.
But nobody's there.
The whole show is put on for
a handful of people.
Because they're so paranoid that
they won't let anybody in
to actually watch it.
And on one side, you're
kind of blown away.
But on the other side
you're saying, why?
You have no gas.
You have no electricity.
Your people are starving.
Yet all your money is going to
the best and brightest you
have in the country to put on
a spectacle for 10 people.
I realized, this is what North
Korea is all about.
It's about putting on a show.
At this point, we're five days
in, we've asked them 50 times
to see the film studios.
We're running out of time.
And I start bad tripping.
We're not going to go see
the film studios.
And if we don't, this whole
trip has been a bust.