is a lot like lemon meringue pie but way better!
Pie's so last everything.
We're gonna make that with lots of lovely
lemons and sponge and we're gonna cover it
in marshmallowy meringue icing and blowtorch
it, so there's some danger involved.
Right, so I've got 375g of caster sugar and
I'm just gonna pop that in my mixer and add
375g of butter. Which is really super soft.
I'm gonna start that on a low speed then speed
it up to a medium-high speed until it's really
super white and fluffy. It's gonna take maybe
like five minutes or so.
It's gone really super pale and really super fluffy
and I could just eat that right now
to be honest because that's delish!
You're gonna need 6 eggs. I'm using large,
free range, organic eggs. With the mixer on
a low speed, one at a time crack them into
your mixer and give them a little mix before
you add the next one.
I'm just gonna stop it and give it a quick
scrape just to make sure I've got all the
bits and bobs out of the bottom.
So give it one last whiz up.
Whiz, whiz, whiz, whiz, whiz.
Alright, I'm gonna put the lemon zest in now.
Pop that out.
And I've given these a wash. I used unwaxed
lemons. The zest of the lemon sort of gives
it a tang without the pang.
I think I've got all my zest of my lemons
now so I'm gonna whack my paddle back in.
I've got 375g of self raising flour, which
I've sifted and on a really low speed mix
it just really gently.
Here we go.
Give its bum a little pat so that all the
flours off the sides.
I've got two tablespoons of milk and two and
a half tablespoons of lemon juice. On a really
low speed, pour it in at the same time.
Get in there with your spatula and just make
sure you scrape down the sides and all down
the bottom so that any nuggets get mixed in
as well.
And I think we're ready to go.
I've got three 8 inch sandwich tins which
I've greased with butter and then dusted with
flour. And then as evenly as possible, dish
this lovely batter out into them.
I'm just gonna use a palette knife just to
smooth that all out so that you bake a nice,
even cake.
Right, so we've got the three layers for our
cake ready to go in the oven and I've preheated
my oven to 170°C and I'm gonna pop them in
there for 25-30 minutes then we'll just check
them after 25.
While that's cooking I'm gonna make some Marshmallowy
Meringue Icing. I've got a Bain-marie, which
is a saucepan with a bowl over the top. The
saucepan has about an inch of water in. You
don't want to have too much because you don't
want it to hit the bottom of the bowl when
you put it on.
So in my bowl I have a 175g of caster sugar
and then I'm gonna add a 1/4 tsp of Cream
of Tartar and a 1/4 tsp of salt. We've got
5 tbsp of Golden Syrup or if you're in the
States you can use Corn Syrup. So that just
goes in there as well. We have a tsp of Vanilla
extract, then 2 tbsp of water. Right, that's
that. And then we need 2 egg whites. So I'm
just gonna separate them into my bowl.
You need to start mixing immediately.
And I'm using an electric whisk because this is
gonna take quite some time. Your heat should
be sort of medium to high and the speed of
the mixer, make it quite fast as well.
And this is gonna be almost white in the end.
You don't wanna watch me doing this for 10
minutes so let's skip ahead.
It's pretty sticky stuff! Mmm it's really
good actually, I'm just gonna.. mmm it is
like a marshmallow, mixed with a meringue.
It's exactly that.
So that's all ready to go. We'll just pop that
to one side until we're ready to use it.
So we've done our topping and now we need
to get our fillings.
I have made a delicious lemon buttercream and it's
exactly the same method as my vanilla buttercream
video recipe. So just replace the milk and
vanilla for lemon juice and if you want to
see that video then click this blob.
The other filling is lemon curd. If you want
to learn how to make that then click this
blob. Now! hahaha.
If you don't have the time or the inclination
to make your own lemon curd then don't despair,
you can get these in most supermarkets. It's
really tangy and lemony. Perfect for all this
sweet stuff we're chucking on the cake.
So, speaking of cake, we've got three layers
out of the oven. They've cooled down.
And you can tell they're ready because they
are just kinda springing back. And I'm gonna
just pop them out of the tins now. And if
you wanna slide a palette knife underneath
them just to loosen them up a bit. I'm putting
them on grease-proof paper just so I can move
them around really easily.
Right, so I'm gonna take the tops off my cake
just to make sure they are really super flat
and all the crispy bits have come off and
I'm using a cake leveller for that. You can
use a serrated knife if you want but this
is a little bit more accurate.
You can eat this in secret or you can just
throw it away. Or you can eat it in secret!
I'm just gonna do that for all of the cakes.
Now we've levelled our cakes off there's one
more thing I'm going to do. Now you don't
have to do this if you don't want to but I'm
not a massive fan of the edge of the cake,
the cake that's been in touch with the tin.
Because it's where the cakes got the hottest
and it's usually the driest part of the cake.
So I like to get rid of that.
I've got a 7 inch cake board and I'm gonna
basically cut around each cake and then you
can just get rid of that or you can sneak
a little bit. Just to make sure it's nice,
and it is nice.
Right so our three layers are ready.
I have a turntable. I did for many years decorate
cakes without one so don't be alarmed if you
don't have one. You can do it but it's just
a little bit easier with one. I've also got
an 8 inch board here for my 7 inch cake and
I'm just gonna whack a little bit of buttercream
on the bottom so that my cake sticks to it.
On with our first layer. Just pick it up with
both hands and whack it as in the middle as
you possibly can and just squish it down a
little bit just so it's nice and stuck.
And first of all we're gonna use this lovely,
delicious, creamy, lemon, zingy buttercream.
Make sure it goes all the way to the edges.
As level as possible. Then it's lovely, zingy
lemon curd time. You don't wanna mix it in
with the buttercream. You want it to kind
of maintain the layer. And with this one you don't
wanna go too close to the edge because you
don't want this to be oozing out. Oooh but
that looks nice doesn't it. It's like a giant
fried egg, but much tastier.
Right, so on with the next layer. And then
do the same thing again for this layer.
Ooooh Yeeeeah!
Now it's time for the final layer and because
I want this to be nice and straight I'm gonna
turn this layer upside down because the side
that it's been baked in the tin on is really
straight, as you can see.
Right, give it a little spin, make sure it's
all straight and lovely. Clean it up at the
sides.
Right, so my cakes naked and delicious but
it's gonna be even more delicious in a minute
because we're gonna put the final pièce de
résistance on top, which is the Marshmallowy
Meringue icing.
Gently, but assertively smooth it on. What
you want is to cover your entire cake.
I'm really slathering it on here which is absolutely
fine because it's delicious.
So, just generous and gentle, but assertive.
Next it's the danger zone. Get yourself a
blow torch and because we're dealing with
fire I'm gonna use a baking tray to pop my
cake on just so I don't melt my turntable.
Ready... woooo.
So what this is going to do is caramelise
the sugar in your frosting so it's gonna get
a really nice caramelly flavour and it's also
gonna make it look really blimming awesome.
So, very gently, from a little bit of a distance,
not pointing the flame at the cameraman,
lick it with the blowtorch.
You can smell the burnt sugar coming off this
cake. It's like caramel, it's so good.
Right, so that's the top. Now we need to do the sides,
so...
This is where having a turntable comes in
really handy.
Alright, i think we're just about done. So,
turn off your blow torch.
We're done with the fire but we are not done
with this cake. We need to eat this cake pronto.
It's so good! Look at that!
Wooooo!
Ooooh caramelly.
So there it is! My super-duper Lemon Meringue
cake with Marshmallowy Meringue icing.
If you like this video and you want to see
more videos by me then don't forget to check
out the Cupcake Jemma channel by clicking
this link where there's loads more videos
to see. And I've really enjoyed making this
for you so I'm probably gonna really enjoy
eating for you on your behalf so...
Look at that!
Oooooooh!
Look at those lovely layers of the buttercream
and lemon curd. I'm so excited about eating
this.
Mmmm tangy and sweet and marshmallowy and
light and delicious. It's like sunshine.
It's a slice of sunshine.
C'mon guys, give us a hand!
Mmmmmm