DERRICK BECKLES: We went down
to West Virginia to take a
look at coal mining, because
instead of going underground
like they used to for decades
and generations, they have a
whole new way of doing it
that blew our minds.
We're on our way up
to Larry Gibson's.
He lives on this mountain.
And you'll see his property just
has an incredible view of
what's going on around here.
By the way, us being up here
isn't exactly what they're
thrilled about.
These companies don't
want people to know
this is going on.
The locals are kind of screwed,
because this is how
they make their living.
So if they shoot their mouths
off too much, they're shooting
themselves in the foot.
[EXPLOSION]
DERRICK BECKLES: Holy shit.
This is the new way that
we mine for coal.
I could easily tell you we're
in Afghanistan in the
mountains, and we're looking for
Osama bin Laden, and you'd
believe me.
This is the second most
biodiverse area in the world.
And unfortunately, we need
what's under these mountains,
and we'll do anything
to get it.
DWIGHT SIEMIACZKO: Coal
companies like to do
mountaintop removal because they
can get more coal quicker
and cheaper with less people.
The bad part of that is its
environmental impact that it
has on the streams and
the environment.
Because you just literally
destroyed the mountaintops and
the valleys below them, where
a deep mines does not.
B.I. SAMMONS: When the
old timers mined
coal, it was hard work.
But now they need to mine coal
faster than men can mine it.
So they're taking the tops off
of mountains to get it faster.
When George Bush first took
office, he said, mine the
coal, get the oil,
get the gas.
The country needs it.
So he just opened the doors.
You know, this is
Pandora's Box.
DERRICK BECKLES: Coal is also
being sold to North Americans
as this beacon for
self-sufficiency in terms of a
fossil fuel that we
can depend on.
But this is how we get it.
And then you heat your
homes with it.
DWIGHT SIEMIACZKO: But those are
things that happens under
the public's eye, under
their noses.
They just don't realize
what is at stake here.
And the coal companies get by.
CHRIS HAMILTON: I guess every
single mountain out there is
important to somebody
to be retained in
its original contour.
But mining is what we do
here in West Virginia.
And it's something we
do extremely well.
DERRICK BECKLES: Yeah, and
there's no reason--
absolutely, I don't think
there's any reason there
shouldn't be pride taken
in that at all.
But to be frank, I was just
horrified at this form of
mining, where they just kind
of take away mountaintops.
And I'm wondering what that
impact is, or what you
consider the impact to be.
CHRIS HAMILTON: There's no
pretty way to mine coal.
Nature has a remarkable way of
healing itself over time.
DERRICK BECKLES: So those are
the mountains of West
Virginia, which so many
people talk about.
And then when you see it from
the air, it is another level
of understanding the devastation
around here.
CHRIS HAMILTON: To the extent
that a mountain is removed, a
little bit of a misnomer
there.
We're removing mountaintops.
We're not removing the
entire mountain.
DERRICK BECKLES:
So how far down
would you go, for example?
CHRIS HAMILTON: Well, sometimes
it's the ground level.
But it's usually just
the upper--
DERRICK BECKLES: Sometimes it
is the mountain, though.
CHRIS HAMILTON: Sometimes
it is.
DERRICK BECKLES: After talking
to the Coal Association
representatives, I have to say
that if you're interested in
the world looking like Mars
or Pluto, this is a
great place to start.
Hi, I'm visiting you from
Zebulon Five, a new planet
that Earth is conquering.
We're currently blasting away
to make room for Earth
inhabitants.
Luckily, we can breathe here,
and it looks just enough like
West Virginia to make
you feel at home.
CHRIS HAMILTON: They've
been surface
mining for 40, 50 years.
So while we're here mining, if
we can reconfigure and reclaim
this land to accommodate that
post-mine land use, it's going
to be a win-win for everybody.
DERRICK BECKLES: They're
planing these
things off as a win-win.
And I'm sure you've
heard this.
You're getting land for things
like an airfield or a golf
course, or a shopping
center can be built
on this planed land.
WAYNE LANHAM: Show us the
shopping centers on them.
Show us the airports.
OK, show me the first one.
DWIGHT SIEMIACZKO:
It's not there.
I don't care what Chris Hamilton
or anybody else is
telling you.
It's not true.
It is not true.
As far as growing back in 100
years, there's no way.
There's no way.
DERRICK BECKLES: Let's
say 200 or 300.
DWIGHT SIEMIACZKO:
200 or 300 years.
I mean, there's no way.
There's no way.
If you don't have topsoil there,
it's not going to grow.
WAYNE LANHAM: If you just go--
rabbits, right-- that deep,
you're out of the black dirt.
You're down in the yellow.
Just that deep.
DWIGHT SIEMIACZKO: From a
distance, it looks like a
green pasture.
WAYNE LANHAM: It's beautiful.
Well, they call it
hydroseeding.
Got this big hose like us in
here now, and we can spray it
on those walls, and it's
so lush and green.
DWIGHT SIEMIACZKO: And it
would grow on the walls.
WAYNE LANHAM: No, really.
You can spray it on us,
and make it grow.
DWIGHT SIEMIACZKO: Yeah.
It's grass on steroids.
That's what we call it.
WAYNE LANHAM: But it's
rock right under it.
DWIGHT SIEMIACZKO: It's
a camouflage.
WAYNE LANHAM: It's
DWIGHT SIEMIACZKO:
It's camouflage.
DERRICK BECKLES: This is it.
This is hydroseed.
And they spray the mountains
with this, and then everything
grows back.
Everything's fine.
It's magical pixie dust.
It feels like mulched toilet
paper, dyed green.
I mean, there's little
seeds in it, I think.
I can't even tell.
It'll look just like it used
to, trees and everything.
And you can see that
this is topsoil.
Really good topsoil.
And then once they put this
really good topsoil down, you
can come anywhere around here
and check it out yourself.
It's done with respect and
attention to detail.
And then they spray it with
green toilet paper.
And everything's
back to normal.
So nobody's losing.
Nobody.
It's not exactly surprising to
find out that the miners and
the mining companies
don't get along.
But to truly understand why and
how they don't get along,
you have to go to the
miners themselves.
WAYNE LANHAM: I'm Wayne Lanham,
retired coal miner,
disabled coal miner.
Lived here all my life.
57 years old.
I'm a radical, a redneck.
Rednecks started this state,
you know that?
Because when they had the coal
mining wars, you wore a red
bandanna around your neck.
That way I could recognize
you guys.
Those guys over behind those
bushes are union men.
They're on my side.
They're coal miners.
DWIGHT SIEMIACZKO: The coal
industry in this state has a
horrible record on
human relations.
In this particular watershed
here, in 1913 and 1914 there
was a coal strike here.
They was trying to unionize.
HERSHAL WILEY: The county
had police there.
The state had state
police there.
WAYNE LANHAM: And when they come
by Holly Grove-- because
the people who had been kicked
out was living in tents.
It was tent city.
When they come by, they opened
up on them with a machine gun.
Companies did that.
That's why there's such
a hard feelings
towards coal companies.
They just came up and
shot the people.
DWIGHT SIEMIACZKO: When
you are hired,
you sign a quit slip.
You sign a slip that
says you quit.
It's not dated.
So when it gets down to the
point that you do something
that I don't like as a coal
operator, I'll tell you.
I'll say, Wayne, today's
your last day.
Well, why?
Is something wrong?
Yeah, you quit.
Oh no, I didn't quit.
Oh yeah, here's your
quit slip.
You signed this.
And you do not have
a leg to stand on.
Most people outside of the
state, and some who are in
this state, don't realize
the history.
And it's the same pattern
being played over again.
DERRICK BECKLES: At the end of
every shift, I noticed that
you could actually hear the
mountain powering down and
then powering back up again.
And that's just because coal
mining around here is a
24-hour operation.
At the end of the day shift, the
miners go to their local
watering holes, so we
follow them there.
MALE SPEAKER: I love to coal
mine, because it's a
adrenaline rush.
You know?
FEMALE SPEAKER: Right.
MALE SPEAKER: I brought
her back from Florida.
And I said, you know what?
I'm working to come home
and take care of you.
Her job is to take
care of my house,
take care of my daughter.
I do everything else.
And I love her for that.
You know?
FEMALE SPEAKER: I didn't
want to come into this.
It just happened.
I mean, yeah the money is good,
and the money is great.
But the money is not worth
nothing but him.
MALE SPEAKER: Being totally
honest with you, do you think
I like going underground,
knowing that I can die?
Knowing that there's a big
chance that I can die?
I do sometimes.
MALE SPEAKER: All coal miners
deserve $35 an hour or more,
because they work
their ass off.
And without them, the
country would fail.
DERRICK BECKLES: So right now
to me, coal mining is a
necessary evil.
And it's not the miners
that are the ones--
MALE SPEAKER: We're not evil.
The miners themselves
aren't the bad ones.
You've met me.
You've met him.
We're not bad guys.
MALE SPEAKER: But the corporate
American CEOs and
people like that, they're
going to want to
make the big dollars.
And we're just tools.
DERRICK BECKLES: If the mines
aren't so good, if you've
known this for generations, why
don't you just leave and
go somewhere else and get
a job somewhere else?
MALE SPEAKER: I mean, it's like
you graduate from high
school, and we say, we'll give
you a job making $17 an hour
working in the mines.
You'll have medical, dental,
and vision, and blah, blah.
Or you can go try to do the
college, even if you are
smart, or go work
at McDonald's.
What do you want to do?
You go with the mines.
DERRICK BECKLES: Do you think
they're just going to keep
leveling this whole area?
MALE SPEAKER: You're damn
right they will.
MALE SPEAKER: If we
let them, they'll
level this whole place.
You might feel bad about it
because you're worried about
the environment.
But you're still going to cut
the top off this mountain,
because hey, I got to eat.
I've got shit I got to do.
B.I. SAMMONS: You see that
mansion on top of that
mountain yonder?
Can you see that through
your camera?
DERRICK BECKLES: That--
B.I. SAMMONS: That.
DERRICK BECKLES: That
weird-looking thing
on top of the hill?
That's a mansion up there?
B.I. SAMMONS: That's
Don Blankenship's--
one of his mansions
right there.
Because he is knowingly--
I won't say intentionally.
But he is knowingly endangering
the lives of every
man, woman, and child in
this area for miles
and miles and miles.
I don't know how he
sleeps at night.
DERRICK BECKLES: The symbolism
of that, him up there and you
down here, is remarkable.
Just the symbolism of that, and
that he has a bird's-eye
view, potentially watching
everybody down
here get washed away.
B.I. SAMMONS: There's more coal
left in these mountains
than has been mined.
He intended to buy all this
property out, and he's tried,
and he still intends to do it.
Force it done, if necessary,
to move all the
people out of here.
And then start taking these
mountains down, step by step.
I've spent 59 years here, and
I'm not going noplace unless
he washes me off.
I'll die here.
DERRICK BECKLES: Not bad, huh?
[DOG BARKING]
[BIRD CHIRPING]
DONNETTA BLANKENSHIP: I start
getting to talking about Don,
and I start getting
pretty upset, so I
won't say too much.
We have a right and--
especially kids have a right
as much as he does.
Why does people like that
think that they can--
I don't know.
It's like they don't care
if they go ahead and
kill us, and let--
like my kids here, they're
14 and 15.
What's going to happen
to them?
CHRIS HAMILTON: We have
local residents who
have legitimate concerns.
And we have processes and
programs in place to try to
deal with those concerns.
And then we have also another
portion of our population who
simply do not like mining and
would just as soon see it all
be abolished or all go away.
DERRICK BECKLES: Who are they?
It doesn't sound like this--
CHRIS HAMILTON: In a--
DERRICK BECKLES: Who would
those people be, though?
CHRIS HAMILTON: Well,
I saw both in the
committee room today.
DERRICK BECKLES: OK, so we're
at the West Virginia
legislature.
And this is Subcommittee B. And
this hearing's going to
deal with this slurry
injection into the--
MALE SPEAKER: Excuse me.
Sorry.
DERRICK BECKLES:
--mine shafts.
After coal is mined, there's
a lot of leftover rock and
unusable materials, as well
as chemicals from
the coal mining process.
The stuff's called coal slurry,
and it gets pumped
back into the mountain.
It's legal.
The mining companies claim
it's regulated.
And the citizens whose well
water and drinking water is
contaminated claim it's
making them sick.
MALE SPEAKER: Basically what we
do is, when we permit the
sites themselves, we have
a half-mile radius on
groundwater surveys
for the permit.
FEMALE SPEAKER: I think
I'm confused.
Now, you can't inject within 1/4
of a mile of a well or a
municipality, correct?
Well then, I don't know if you
were present at the last
meeting last time.
MALE SPEAKER: No ma'am,
I wasn't.
FEMALE SPEAKER: But we had
several people who brought
samples of their water, which
had huge contaminants in it.
MALE SPEAKER: I think a lot of
people don't understand that
you have to maintain a well
just like you do your car.
A lot of people just turn on
the spigot, and they think
it's going to work for them,
when they have things like
iron hydroxide precipitate and
other minerals built up in
their wells over the years.
And every time I go out on a
well complaint, I tell people,
you need to have a friend at
the local volunteer fire
department come out and
flush your well
after a couple of years.
DWIGHT SIEMIACZKO: Again,
they're going to blame it on
somebody else.
They're not going to
take the blame.
I mean, just like the
far-fetched notion that you're
not cleaning your wells out.
I've never heard of that.
I have never, ever
heard of that.
WAYNE LANHAM: That
guy's an idiot.
You quote me on that.
Tell him to come on over here
too if he wants a piece of it.
Those guys, they make fun
of your common sense.
DWIGHT SIEMIACZKO: Yeah.
WAYNE LANHAM: Common sense.
DWIGHT SIEMIACZKO: And where
is the toxins coming from?
I mean, if you have used your
well for generations and never
had a problem with your well
water, and all of a sudden you
get toxic metals coming
into your well,
where did it come from?
Why wasn't it there
100 years ago?
But it's kind of odd that
someone nearby you is
injecting into the ground the
same thing that's coming into
your well, and your well has
been operational for
generations after generations.
Then to say you're not cleaning
your well out?
B.I. SAMMONS: But
you was there.
You heard those two gentlemen
from the DEP make the
statement that they could prove
that nothing that had
been done in the mining industry
had harmed our
drinking water.
It was just a damned
outright lie.
They're killing people.
And somebody has to do
something to stop it.
DERRICK BECKLES: Protection
agencies are supposed to be
helping you.
Local government.
State government.
Federal government.
How this just goes on for this
long, it boggles my mind.
B.I. SAMMONS: Politics.
I'm waiting.
It's been a year and a half
now, almost two years.
I'm still waiting on a man
that works for the DEP.
He's in charge of the gas well
mining operation in the state
of West Virginia.
I'm still waiting for a
call back from him.
DERRICK BECKLES: You've
got to be kidding.
B.I. SAMMONS: No,
I'm not kidding.
And I've got the number of calls
that I called, and who I
called, and who I talked to.
You truly have no idea what
goes on around here.
The things I want to say to you,
it'll come to my mind,
then I'll forget it.
But the doctor from New York
that called me and told me
said, I'm surprised you can
talk, that's how much lead
that you've got in your brain.
DERRICK BECKLES: Could you
explain to me how this is
affecting your family, then?
Like physically?
B.I. SAMMONS: Brittany,
come in here.
Tell me.
You went to the doctor today.
What did the doctor say?
BRITTANY SAMMONS: Nothing.
B.I. SAMMONS: What did he say
about the knot on your cheek?
BRITTANY SAMMONS: That it
could be infection.
It could be a fluid sac,
or it could be a cyst.
He didn't know.
B.I. SAMMONS: So what
do you got to do?
BRITTANY SAMMONS: Nothing.
He gave me antibiotics
and sent me home.
B.I. SAMMONS: He don't want
you to go see nobody else?
What kind of antibiotics
did he give you?
BRITTANY SAMMONS: I've
never heard of them.
B.I. SAMMONS: And I've
got a little boy.
He's nine years old.
From the time he was a child,
he's been on antibiotics more
than half of his life because
of this damn water.
And we didn't know what
was causing it.
Right there is what I have
to take on a daily
basis to stay alive.
Now, that's almost
hard to believe.
DERRICK BECKLES: Can I
see those, please?
B.I. SAMMONS: Yeah.
And I'm not going to be here
long, because you cannot live
with that many chemicals
in your body.
DERRICK BECKLES: How does
that make you feel,
saying that out loud?
B.I. SAMMONS: Mister, I'm just
telling you the truth.
DERRICK BECKLES: I know.
B.I. SAMMONS: I'm telling you
what the doctor told me.
Don't plan on being here
long, having to take
that kind of medicine.
I've got stacks of
these tablets.
This is the amount of medicine
that I take.
And I have to take them.
I don't take them because
I want to take them.
I want to be alive for
that little boy.
DERRICK BECKLES: This is what
they claim isn't happening.
B.I. SAMMONS: Yeah, the
DEP and the EPA.
DERRICK BECKLES: The DEP.
The EPA.
The mining companies.
The everybody who's not
living in these areas.
Everybody's who's
not a miner are
claiming this isn't happening.
B.I. SAMMONS: This
doesn't happen.
That's right.
DERRICK BECKLES: And that this
is your imagination.
What do you think every night
before you go to bed?
B.I. SAMMONS: You pray
before you go to bed.
And you just ask God to take
care of your family.
That's all you can do.
Because man has done done
the damage to the Earth.
And I don't see how man can
correct what's been done.
God can handle this.
He will.
When the right time comes, he
will do what has to be done.