If youre truly an automotive enthusiast, then
you have probably heard of this place.
Leslie, thank you for having us today.
What a pleasure.
Likewise.
Tell us a little bit about the Petersen Museum.
How did it begin?
The Petersen Museum was the brainchild of
Margie and Robert E. Petersen. Mr. Petersen
founded
Hot Rod Magazine and Motor Trend magazine,
and a couple of dozen other enthusiast magazines.
And he wanted there to be a special place
in Los Angeles where we could celebrate our
car culture,
and as it happens, a car culture that he helped
to create.
And how many cars do you have in your collection?
We have over 400 cars in the collection.
What Im really excited to see is the vault.
Will you take me there?
Id love to. Lets go.
So were finally here in the vault. Im really
excited to be here. Tell me a little bit about
this collection.
Well, the collection was acquired by Margie
and Robert E. Petersen during their lifetime
and by people
who have donated cars to the Petersen Automotive
Museum Foundation. And since we only have
room for about 150 upstairs, we keep a good
couple of hundred down here in reserve for
future
exhibits and to take to car shows throughout
the country. Its living, breathing workspace
so its very
unusual for the vault to look exactly the
same two days in a row.
Alright, I want to see some of your favorite
cars.
Id love to show them to you.
One of my favorites in the collection has
to be this 1939 Bugatti Type 57C. Straight
8, twin cam,
supercharged. But thats not where it ends.
This car was actually a gift from the French
government
to the Shah of Iran in 1939 when he got married.
But its so beautiful, its so exquisite. Its
really a piece of rolling sculpture. I mean,
you cant help but
notice the concealed wheels, the spats over
the front and the rear, these really clever
air vents on the
side that open to let the flow of air come
into the passenger compartment. You have hidden
door
handles that open in a very unique way. And
once youre inside, you have a hand crank under
the
dashboard that you can raise or lower the
windshield. Its really a very practical car.
Its a lovely car. Its built during the height
of the art deco era and has to be one of the
most exciting
combinations of chassis and coachwork and
history of any car thats been built.
This is our 1913 Mercer, a century-old car.
And in its day, this car was as sexy and as
exotic and as rare
as any Lamborghini and Ferrari is today. This,
in fact, was a supercar of its era, an era
where there
were still dirt roads and a lot of horses
on the road to kind of try to maneuver around.
You were really
something if you could have one of these cars
and handle it properly. But this car required
about a six
to eight step starting procedure, depending
on whether or not it was recently running.
You have to
set little controls and you have to go under
the hood and you have to prime the engine.
But this was
the kind of authentic motoring experience
that you wouldve had one-hundred years ago.
Alright, well I cant wait any longer. I really
want to see the Ferrari that Enzo gave to
Henry Ford.
We can go right now. I know where it is.
Here it is! Ive been waiting for this.
Jessi, you picked a really good car to like.
This is a 1952 Ferrari 212 225 Spyder. This
car has a really
special history because its the only one of
its kind ever made and it was given by Enzo
Ferrari to Henry
Ford II. There was a time when ford and Ferrari
were thinking about getting together. It never
happened, but there was some thought there.
And we come back here and you notice this
is strictly a fair-weather car. Theres absolutely
no
provision for weather protection. And because
theres no side windows, you dont need outside
door
handles because you can just reach inside
and open the door. This car has never been
restored. It
only has about 12,000 miles on it. And its
the original paint. The engine has never been
outside or
apart. Its just a really extraordinary car,
a true survivor.
The car that really stayed with me throughout
the day was that massive Rolls Royce. Ive
never seen, I
mean it doesnt even look like a Rolls Royce,
Ive never seen anything like it. From the
circular doors to
the fan-shaped opening windows, its really
just an incredible and monstrous creature.
Theres the Toyota 2000GT, Japans first supercar.
It looks like a Datsun, but it was actually
built three
years prior to Datsun being introduced. It
was built by Yamaha for Toyota and everything
on it is
entirely original. The paint, the interior,
theyve never been redone or restored.
Steve McQueens Jaguar XKSS is the sexiest
Jaguar Ive ever seen. And he mustve agreed
because he
liked it so much he bought it twice.
Its absolutely obvious from looking around
the vault that Mr. Petersen loved his hot
rods. He
founded Hot Rod Magazine in 1948 and it seems
his love grew throughout his life. Theres
so many
different combinations and ways that you can
build them. Some of them have crazy grilles,
ridiculous
detailing, upholstery on the running boards.
No two are alike.
The collection they have in the vault, its
almost overwhelming, its almost automotive
overload. Just a
ton of iconic cars surrounded by equally iconic
cars. You could spend days there.
I really love how all the vehicles down here
are, you know Im not kept away from them by
ropes and
there arent any, theres no historical context
surrounding them.
Youre right and thats not always a bad thing
to have cars that are really stripped from
their context.
And thats the idea behind the vault. People
can come down here and see a sea of cars and
they can
get pretty close to them. They can see how
the cars differ, how much theyre alike. They
can
compare a 39 Bugatti to a 39 Mercury if they
want to. They can see how the differences
of French
coach-building compare with American coach-building
and get a whole new perspective on
automobiles.
Now I know that you guys opened the vault
to the public for the very first time over
the 2012 holiday
season and that it was so popular that youve
extended the hours. How long does the public
have to
get down here and see the vault?
Well, we have indeed done that. Im not sure.
The public can come down here indefinitely
but Im
not even sure how long indefinitely is gonna
be. As long as theres an interest then well
want to
make it available to people.
So, you heard him. Nobody knows how long the
vault doors will stay open and times a wasting!