First up, we want to talk a bit about how
this day is going to go. For starters, it`s
already going. In a unique election day tradition,
two New Hampshire towns started voting at
midnight. For the rest of the country, polls
started opening up as early as 5:00 Eastern
time this morning. By noon Eastern, voters
will be casting ballots in all 50 states.
Polls start closing at 6:00 p.m Eastern. And
then the closings kind of move their way across
the country. Now, voters are deciding on the
presidency, of course, but also U.S. Senate
and House races, some governors races, state
and local elections, and proposed state laws.
We`re going to have more on that coming up.
The presidency is expected to be a close race.
In fact, a new CNN poll showed president Obama
and former Governor Romney in a dead heat.
Governor Romney is scheduled to visit Ohio
and Pennsylvania today. President Obama is
planning to spend the day in Chicago. Now,
as the votes are counted and the election
results start coming in, both candidates are
going to be keeping a close eye on the electoral
college count. That is the big prize today.
Tom Foreman explains why and how this works.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
TOM FOREMAN, CNN CORRESPONDENT: The electoral
college in its essence is basically a compromise,
a compromise between having Congress select
all of our presidents, which Congress once
did, and letting us by popular vote select
our presidents.
The electoral college is what actually elects
a president. We all think we do, we don`t
really. What we do is we vote for these people.
These people are the ones who actually have
the vote that actuate everything, that make
it happen. Each state selects its electors
from a bunch of the good citizenry of that
state, and they are proportional by the size
of the congressional delegation from the states.
For example, all of your Congress members
and your senators combined produce the number
of electoral votes you get in your state.
So California gets a whole lot, Texas gets
a lot, Montana, North Dakota, not so much.
The behavior of the electors is one of the
great acts of trust in this country, because
only in a few places are they actually bound
to what the people and the population say.
They can change their minds, and there have
been rare occasions in which electors have
gone to the actual process of electing the
president and said, I disagree with my state,
and they have cast another vote.
One of the big reasons you always hear for
the electoral college is that it evens out
power a little bit. If you just had a popular
vote, then the most populous state would really
consolidate all the power, and if you lived
in a state like North Dakota, you would have
very, very little influence or ability to
create any influence, unless you banded together
with a bunch of other states. And beyond that,
all the campaigning would only happen in giant
population centers.
The biggest con you hear is that it can override
the popular vote. People can triangulate the
electoral votes, and actually win the presidency
when most of the people in the country do
not want that person in the Oval Office.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: So 435 congressional seats, plus 100
seats in the U.S. Senate and three electors
for the District of Columbia. That all adds
up to 538 electoral college votes. It takes
a majority of these votes, at least 270, to
win the presidency. John King looks at the
math for both of the candidates to see how
those votes could add up to history.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
JOHN KING, CNN ANCHOR: Look at this. If the
president can take Iowa, can take Wisconsin
and can take Ohio, it`s game over. If nothing
else changed on the map, that would get the
president to 271, and it would be game over.
That`s why the president is ending his campaign
right here in the heartland, places where
he can talk about the auto bailout. He thinks
that`s a big plus for him. So that`s one way.
That is the president`s quickest way. I won`t
say it`s the easiest, but it`s his easiest,
not an easy way to 270. So what does that
mean? It means for starters, Governor Romney
has to take the state of Ohio.
Let`s take these back and make them tossups
and show you. That was the president`s fastest
way. How does Governor Romney get there? He
has to win the state of Florida. Not negotiable.
Governor Romney needs Florida, he needs those
29 electoral votes. He has to take North Carolina.
We already have it leaning that way, and he
has to take Virginia as well. That`s 13 more.
That would get Governor Romney there. Then,
the governor`s most reasonable scenario is
to take Ohio. No Republican has ever won without
it. If Governor Romney can get those electoral
votes, plus Virginia, North Carolina and Ohio,
what does that do? That would get him to 266.
Over here in the east, he would need just
one more, any one of the remaining states.
If Governor Romney can do Florida, Virginia,
North Carolina and Ohio, any one of the remaining
states would put him over the top. That`s
what makes this one so, so, so important.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: So who do you want to win? We`ve seen
so many polls in this race for so many weeks
now, we`re taking our own informal poll at
cnnstudentnews.com. Tell us whether you`re
hoping for the incumbent president, the former
governor or someone else to lead the country.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Today`s shoutout goes out
to Mrs. McKay`s and Mrs. Miller`s language
arts classes at Glenview Middle School in
East Moline, Illinois. In a blank, voters
decide on a proposed government law or policy.
Is it a rebuttal, a filibuster, referendum,
or oligarchy? You got 3 seconds, go.
A
referendum is a vote on a proposed law or
policy. That`s your answer and that is your
shoutout.
AZUZ: There is at least one referendum on
the ballot in 38 states today. All in all,
voters will decide on almost 180 proposed
laws or policies, and that includes some pretty
controversial issues. For example, President
Obama`s health care reform law. Four states
are voting on whether people and businesses
can avoid the part of the law that requires
that they purchase health care for themselves
or their employees. Voters in other states
will be looking at proposals that involve
same-sex marriage, abortion, the death penalty
and legalizing medical marijuana. And two
states, Washington and Georgia, have referendums
on creation of charter schools.
Watching the results come in on election night
is kind of like watching history as it happens.
I mean, these are the names that wind up in
your textbooks. So as we wrap up our coverage
of election day, we are going to take a look
back at these historic announcements.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Right now, Jimmy Carter
is preparing to get into the presidential
limousine. He will be making his concession
speech.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: President Carter told by
his pollster Pat Caddell that it is all over
reportedly is preparing to concede defeat
to Ronald Reagan in the 1980 presidential
election.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Stand by 2.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Cable News Network`s election
watch, presents election night, 1984.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE:: So we have Mr. Mondale
with 41 percent of the vote, and Mr. Reagan
with 58 percent.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: CNN election night `88.
From CNN Center.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: George Bush easily crushed
Michael Dukakis`s campaign, in the popular
vote, as you can see, 54 to 46 percent.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: CNN election night.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: The president-elect Bill
Clinton, Vice President- elect Al Gore still
relishing the smell of success.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: William Jefferson Clinton
has a job for four more years.
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE:: He becomes the first
Democrat since Franklin Roosevelt to win reelection
to the White House.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: At 18 minutes past two
o`clock Eastern time, CNN declares that George
Walker Bush has won Florida`s 25 electoral
votes, and this should put him over the top.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: Stand by, stand by. CNN
right now is moving our earlier declaration
of Florida back to the too close to call column.
WOLF BLITZER, CNN ANCHOR: With 270 electoral
college votes needed to be elected president,
right now, we`ve projected President Bush
will carry 246 electoral votes, John Kerry
188.
And CNN can now project that Barack Obama,
47 years old, will become the president-elect
of the United States.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: All right, that was a look back at the
past eight presidential elections. Tomorrow,
we`re going to add a ninth to that list, and
we hope you`ll elect to join us for that.
I`m Carl Azuz. Have a great day, everyone.