of course states that you're not allowed
to have a sexual relationship with your
peers at work and this our policy
actually extends to outside of the
workplace and she claims that as a
result no one wants to hang out with her
her mail appears the male lawyers do not
want to hang out with their so according
to our lawsuit they created a segregated
culture that process a call to the
denies female attorneys the same
opportunities for business
and for raises as their male colleagues
and hurts their ability to work so dave
what do you think about this the first
uh... you know we were uh... would you
can send me the story cases from so i'm
back on and i have to read the headline
of what the headline exactly lawsuit
alleges texas employer barred men and
women
from being alone together
it sounds like onion like it does sound
like the idea method and women should
not to be alone together because if you
put them now
and a woman
in an office and you close that door
it's not all my god the chances that
they won't be banging each other in ten
seconds
persona
i mean this is hold completely
insane it's really on
so chris ryan who's the author of sex it
don had a really great out conversation
with me about this for the point which
is on you tube dot com slash fax counts
where you guys to check that out
and he was making the argument that when
it comes to workplace relationships and
workplace romance is it's one of those
things where you have to
tolerated and accepted in order to
control it so do workplace romances
happen uh... dot all the time isn't
necessarily a good thing in some cases
it's not
but i think that this is you make it
tougher big difference
and people are gonna wanna get together
and they're gonna wanna become sexual do
you know what i have sex on the buses
that stuff is going to have buried never
been a group of more sexually repressed
people live here in this office and when
you do that it's brutal ground for crazy
things it's fertile ground for them to
have sex behind the water cooler
and to go through the inflating the
sexual partner right
that this atmosphere that you can create
in this environment in that what can you
imagine working in a place where if you
felt you had to quote will keep the door
open at all times if you were with the
man
it just couldn't believe renault
increases in insurance can't be good
for the productivity during the day
right absolutely i think it's a terrible
idea obviously other another thing that
you know i kinda wanna discuss is
how we can actually hinder someone's
upward mobility because
let's say you're data a male in a female
dominant uh... workplace right out what
happens if all those women get together
outside the workplace ni socialize and
they have you know close relationships
they're probably more willing to look
out for one another because they have a
personal relationship with one another
head and i think that's what this female
attorneys experiencing at this firm by
the way the law firm is uh... schieffer
in stone
uh... on-site sheep in stone an anxious
she's saying that after work she wants
to go grab a drink with the guys and the
guy who do not want to hang out with her
because they're so worried about this
policy and you know this is missus
reject because this is what women have
been saying about the golf course for
many years that menard all got together
and usually the women don't do that
although there actually are when u print
winning oscars
uh...
that then they're gonna be cutting deals
on the gulf was when women are so the
it's just crazy numerous separating
the sex is this is twenty thirteen
america and might i add if i happen to
get
the gate and go to this and so then what
happens if
give to game and they're allowed to
close the door but the uh... the man in
the woman with the we have no so that is
actually pro-gay still