A landing party is investigating.
[scanners hum]
[McCOY] Jim, I don't know why we're taking this risk.
I mean one false move and a chain reaction could
blow away half this continent.
Uridium may be unstable, Bones, but it's essential
to starship construction.
A source in this sector is going to be extremely
important to the Federation for many years to come.
Besides...
I trust my people.
[scanners hum]
He's suffered a terrible loss, Jim.
Freeman meant everything to him.
Duty leaves little time for personal pain.
Or personal relationships?
Like Uncle, like Nephew.
You both ignore what you can't control:
Grief, family.
Don't you see?
No amount of throwing yourselves into
work is going to make either disappear.
We WERE having a conversation.
You were psychoanalysing, Bones.
I wasn't listening.
[SPOCK] Preliminary scans indicate a rich deposit
close to the surface.
There will be minimal danger in extracting it.
An extraordinary find.
Let's mark this vein and wrap things up, Spock.
[communicator chirp]
Kirk to Enterprise, come in.
[static]
The signal is being jammed... locally.
[explosion]
[DICKERSON] Arrrghh!
[explosions]
[McCOY] What the devil's going on?
[KIRK] The big question is...
What's going on up there?
[Main Theme]
Space,
The Final Frontier...
These are the voyages of the Starship Enterprise.
its five year mission...
To explore strange new worlds...
To seek out new life and new civilisations.
To boldly go...
Where no man has gone before.
[KIRK] Captain's log: supplemental.
During a general mining survey
on an uninhabited planet....
We've been attacked.
Security Chief Dickerson:
Dead.
In orbit a similar ambush.
Reason or reasons:
Unknown.
[RAND]
Deflector screens raised.
[rumble]
[XON] Minimal damage. Weapons and shields are class 13.
They're not acknowledging hails, Mr DeSalle
Phasers set to one half.
Locked.
Fire.
[phaser fire]
Hostile’s weapons are offline.
Uhura, try to raise the landing party.
[UHURA]
Aye, sir.
Re-establish orbit, Mr Kyle.
Xon, Scan for human lifesigns.
Have the transporter room standby.
Still no contact with the planet, sir.
[phaser fire]
[groans]
[CHEKOV]
Keptin!
[phaser stuns]
[PETER]
Damn!
[KIRK]
Bones!
[engines humming]
[PETER]
I'm all right.
[SPOCK]
The hostiles have retreated.
But communications are still being jammed by
a device on the surface.
[KIRK]
Find it.
Who are you?
Why did you attack us?
All your kind...
... will pay
[loud hum]
[humming stops]
[communicator chirps]
Kirk here.
Communications restored.
Kirk to Enterprise.
[DeSALLE]
Enterprise, DeSalle here.
Captain, we've been attacked but are undamaged.
An alien ship of unknown design.
We disabled their weapons...
...but they've taken on a landing pod
and are fleeing the system.
Mr DeSalle, the landing party needs an emergency beam-out.
Have medical and security standing by in the transporter room.
Plot a pursuit course on that alien vessel.
Still no response to our hails, sir.
Ve are falling back, Keptin.
Scotty...
They're a wee bit faster, sir. We're stoking the boilers.
How's the captive, Bones?
He's sedated. He's got a concussion
but otherwise he's fine.
Now you're nephew on the other hand is beating...
[KIRK, annoyed]
The business of this ship--
He was distracted on the planet.
He could've been killed.
[McCOY]
Whose distraction are you worried about?
HIS... or YOURS?
[McCOY]
Now you have an opportunity here
to be a real father figure.
Maybe you are more comfortable
as his Captain. But what that boy needs--
[KIRK]
What I need is my ship's Chief Medical Officer
to attend to ship's business.
We're at Red Alert.
Now get the prisoner ready for questioning.
Of course, CAPTAIN.
[KIRK]
Spock, hostile's position?
They have exceeded our maximum speed
and are slipping out of sensor range.
Scotty, We can't lose them.
We're givin' it all we've got, sir.
[CHEKOV]
Keptin, I'm reading several wessels incoming.
[SPOCK]
Confirmed.
Nine vessesls. Similar to the alien
hostiles, on an intercept course.
DeSalle, tactical report.
They've got speed on their side, sir, but our weapons
and shields completely outclass them.
They haven't got a prayer.
[KIRK] Mr Sulu, maintain course, reduce speed.
[SULU] Aye, sir.
Open a channel, Lieutenant.
Let's give them one more chance.
[UHURA]
Aye, sir.
Channel open.
This is Captain James T. Kirk of the
Federation Starship Enterprise.
We have aboard a member of your team
from the unprovoked attack on our vessel.
Standby to prepare--
[rumbles]
Unremarkable lasers and weak gravitic torpedoes.
Minimal damage to our shields.
[KIRK]
Uhura?
[rumbles]
[CHEKOV]
This makes no sense. Ve'd have to lower
our screens for them to do any damage.
[SPOCK]
On the contrary, Mr Chekov. They're concentrating
their fire on one area near our starboard nacelle strut.
They appear familiar with our configuration. They
will eventually break through our shields at that point.
[KIRK]
Mr Scott, reinforce the starboard shields.
Chekov: Half phasers. Warn them off.
[CHEKOV]
Aye, sir.
One alien vessel has taken heavy damage and is
losing life support. Another has lost warp power.
[KIRK] That's a warning, Mr Chekov?
[CHEKOV] I'm sorry, sir. They're more fragile than expected.
[torpedoes crash]
[SPOCK]
Shields on starboard nacelle strut down 3 per cent.
[CHEKOV]
It's like being attacked by...
... kittens.
[SPOCK]
Indeed.  But given enough time
their claws WILL do damage.
[KIRK]
I'm not just going to order their destruction.
Why won't they communicate with us?
[SPOCK]
They must believe doing so would
be less fruitful then their attack.
Security to Sickbay.
I want the prisoner brought to the bridge.
[phaser fire]
[deflector hits]
[doors open]
[KIRK]
Who are you? Why did you attack us?
My name is Alkar Kyril...
Adjutant Commander of the Ninth Peshan Fleet.
You will get no more from me.
[KIRK]
We're not here to harm you or your people.
If they'd simply respond to our hails...
KYRIL:
OUR hails have always been answered by insult
and invasion. Why would we answer yours?
Impressive.
Are you mercenaries?
Or Alersa's new personal toy?
[KIRK]
Alersa? Listen I don't know
anybody named Alersa.
We're not your enemy.
[KYRIL]
You may as well kill me now.
Your Meskan mind tricks won't work.
[KIRK]
Meskan? We're NOT Meskan. We represent
the United Federation of Planets.
We're here on a peaceful mission.
[explosion]
[KYRIL]
Meskan murderer!
200 people!
On each interceptor!
[CHEKOV]
Ve didn't fire.
[SULU]
Captain!
[KYRIL]
There!
Perjure yourself again as the evidence
against you destroys my fleet!
[MCCOY]
Jim?
Is that one of our ships?
[SCOTTY]
Sir, the Eagle was lost 8 years ago with all hands.
[KIRK]
On the other side of the quadrant.
[SPOCK]
There's been significant alteration.
Armour plating, disruptor canons.
But it is the Eagle, Captain. And she's
attacking Peshan ships with alacrity.
[KIRK]
Mr Scott extend our shields to cover them.
[SCOTTY]
We can't protect them all, sir. And the ones
we can -- it'll take some doing to maintain.
[KIRK]
Do it.
Lieutenant Uhura, try to raise the Eagle.
[UHURA]
They're jamming all channels, sir.
[CHEKOV]
Keptin, they are picking off the Peshan
ships von by von.
[KIRK]
Mr Sulu, put us between them.
Change course: two thirteen mark six.
[SPOCK]
Another Peshan vessel has been destroyed.
[rumble]
[SPOCK]
Yet they continue to attack us from
within our own shields.
[KIRK]
Release him.
Tell your people we're trying to
protect them.
[KYRIL]
They won't listen.
They'll assume subterfuge.
[SPOCK]
One Peshan vessel on collision
course -- attempting to ram.
[KIRK]
Tractor beam.
[SPOCK]
Damage to secondary hull.
[CHEKOV]
Shields are buckling, sir.
[UHURA]
Damage control teams. Decks 18 to 21.
[SULU]
The Peshans are breaking away from our shields.
[CHEKOV]
Eagle is altering course to pursue.
[SPOCK]
They cannot withstand an assault
outside our protection.
[KIRK]
Lock phasers on the Eagle, Mr Chekov.
[SPOCK]
Eagle now targeting us. Both phasers
and disruptor banks.
[KIRK]
Evasive.
[phasers fire]
[KIRK]
Return fire, Mr Chekov.
I want that ship disabled.
[phaser fire]
[CHEKOV]
Little effect against their armour plating, Keptin.
[KIRK]
Spock. The prefix codes.
[SPOCK]
The prefix code may be intact,
but normal ship to ship communication
links are jammed.
[KIRK]
Change our codes.
The Eagle. How long?
[KYRIL]
Eight years now.
You really don't know?
This isn't a trick?
A trick? Commander Kyril this is a nightmare.
Who commands that ship?
[KIRK]
Now!
[KYRIL]
Alersa.
A vile, dangerous creature.
She and her crew worm their way onto free vessels,
twisting innocent minds into doing their bidding.
[SPOCK]
Telepaths?
[KYRIL]
No, they don't read minds. They're psychomorphs.
Twisting the perceptions of others and forcing
their wills on those who are receptive.
The Meskan used to revile
those with such power but...
Now they've risen for control and
cast Alersa as their saviour.
What do they need to be saved from?
We're not proud of it, but far in Peshan history,
my people subjugated the Meskan.
Alersa is now bent on revenge.
Captain, they've devastated our fleet
from 700 strong to fewer than 70.
No matter our past crimes, this is not justice.
[KIRK]
Evasive means to evade, Mr Chekov.
[SULU]
They've reconfigured their thruster ports
and impulse drive, sir. They outrun us at sub-light.
Let's show them what these engines can do.
Aye, sir.
[strong phaser fire]
[explosions]
[CHEKOV] Aarrgghh!
[KIRK]
Bones!
[SENTELL]
Dorsel shields weakening.
[UHURA]
They've blown the long-range subspace transceiver.
[KIRK]
Sentell, Torpedoes. Deck 24.
There's no armour there.
[torpedo fires]
[SPOCK]
We've damaged their cargo bay.
Section 3A. They're breaking off.
They're the bully on the block, Spock.
They're not used to having a bloody nose.
[KYRIL]
But there's no strategic value there.
[KIRK]
Oh yes there is. It's a coolant system for their
weapon's subsystems.
There's bypasses but they may
not know about them.
[UHURA]
Captain, the Eagle is hailing.
It's a non-standard frequency. All other
channels are still blocked, sir.
[KIRK]
Stall them.  Analyse that signal.
If we can get into those computers
while their weapons are down...
[UHURA]
Aye, sir.
[KIRK]
Commander Kyril, we're going to set this right.
[CHEKOV]
I need to get back up there.
[McCOY]
Nurse...
[CHEKOV]
Vill that help?
[McCOY]
Yeah... me.
It'll paralyse your fingers.
[CHEKOV]
Vhere did you intern? A gulag?
[MCCOY]
I haven't killed you... yet.
[CHEKOV]
And how are you doing, Mr Kirk?
Other than my destroyed career?
I wasn't thinking down there.
I rushed out. Got myself shot.
Stupid mistake.
I endangered the whole landing party.
The ship.
I'm sure my uncle is drawing
up the transfer orders himself.
[CHEKOV]
Yes. He probably is.
Ve are in the middle of a battle
with two unknown attack forces.
The security guard who dashed instead
of crawled on the planet's surface
is foremost on the captain's mind.
My actions could have
gotten people killed.
Perhaps it vas a clever diversion.
[PETER]
It wasn't. It was a mistake.
Ensign, if you continue to crucify yourself like
this you're going to drive yourself insane.
Listen to him. He's speaking
from experience.
Mistakes are supposed to be a learning experience.
If I don't examine them I won't learn.
[CHEKOV]
And that's something most people
never understand.
It's examine. Not dissect.
Thank you, Lieutenant.
Sir, am I fit for duty?
[McCOY]
Yeah. But your shift has ended.
Take advantage of the downtime.
Doctor's orders.
We're at Red Alert.
I'm needed at my station.
Ensign, someone else will cover your
station. Give yourself a break.
Go. You can save the
galaxy tomorrow.
[doors open and close]
Remind you of anyone you know?
[CHEKOV]
Yes. But he doesn't need to punish
himself for everything.
Of course not. He's not Russian.
Am I fit for duty now, Doctor?
Nope. But that's never stopped you before.
Go on. You're released. Get out of here.
[RAND]
We're in, sir.
They've replaced many of
the computer systems.
[UHURA]
These changes are acting like a firewall.
There's no remote access from here, sir.
[KIRK]
Then get me their logs from
as far back as you can.
[SULU]
Done slacking?
[CHEKOV]
I am not the one who vas malingering
on extended leave.
There's more to life than
Starfleet, my friend.
[CHEKOV scoffs]
Lies.
[UHURA]
Captain, we're locked out.
We've retrieved some of the logs.
Nothing recent.
[RAND]
They're going to take some time to decrypt.
[KIRK]
Then let's buy some.
Uhura, patch me through.
Alersa?
Don't be fooled, Captain,
she's quite deadly.
Especially in person.
I'll take that under advisement.
[ALERSA]
It seems we've gotten off on
the wrong foot, Captain Pike.
It's Captain Kirk. Your library
computers are out of date.
Captain Kirk. You'll forgive me, of course.
Of course, now just return that ship.
Oh, dear.
You're going to be difficult.
How disappointing.
Do you really expect me to give
up such a comfortable ship.
It's so...
cosy.
Well, perhaps we can come to
an understanding, Captain.
I could send a shuttlecraft
for you, if you like.
And we could discuss an armistice
of sorts, here... on my flagship.
I could even give you a tour of
the improvements we've made.
That's an interesting proposal but why don't I just
slit my throat right now and save you all the trouble.
You would do that for...
little old me?
[KYRIL]
I've warned him about you, Alersa.
He's not going to put himself in your clutches.
Alkar. I hope you're well and...
...and how are the rest of your family?
Oh...
Oh, dear.
I miscounted.
NONE are left.
I don't suppose you'd like to beam over to
this vessel and we'll have a little chat.
[ALERSA]
Beaming?
Yes, the transporters.
That is one technology that we
have been unable to decipher.
Kirk, if you'd be willing to
let my technicians...
[KIRK]
That's not going to happen, Captain.
[CONDRIS]
The codes are either
corrupt, or different.
Oh, he's a clever boy. I'm sure he changed them
as soon as he realised we were a threat.
He's not like that blue buffoon.
Kirk is formidable.
Do you fancy him?
Careful, Andoch. A tongue as sharp
as yours could slit its own throat.
Remember, darling, one can
never have too many pets.
Condris, how long?
[CONDRIS]
Any moment, m'lady.
Excellent.
[KIRK]
She's no fool. She knew those
codes would be changed.
She's stalling. Why?
[KYRIL]
She may be waiting for assistance.
Our intelligence reports reveal she's
developed a new battleship
We thought your vessel, one of them.
It's why we attacked you.
[SPOCK]
Scanning...
They're effectively hampering
our long range sensors.
The disadvantage of their close
familiarity with our systems.
[UHURA]
Eagle is hailing again, Captain.
I'm sorry we couldn't come to an
understanding, Captain Kirk.
Perhaps we'll renegotiate...
When my boot is on your throat.
[KIRK] Captain's log: supplemental.
The U.S.S. Eagle, missing for eight
years, has been found in the
hands of alien aggressors.
Reverse engineering our technology, they've
apparently created their own starships:
An enemy Starfleet.
Spock. Analysis.
An interesting amalgam of Federation
and alien technologies, Captain.
They have less of the inveterate armour
and weapons arrays of the Eagle.
Of course. She keeps the most
powerful vessel under her control.
Chekov, concentrate fire on
the newer ship.
Mr Sulu, alternate warp and sub-light
attack vectors. Keep them guessing.
[SULU]
Aye, sir.
Protect the Starstalker.
I have not come this far against
the Peshan to have it all taken
away by one Federation ship!
Fight them, Andoch.
Fight them as if your
life depends on it!
[DeSALLE]
Coolant leak.
Deck 7, Section 2.
[KIRK]
Damage Control. Deck 7, Section 2
Clear and Contain.
[UHURA]
Engineering on the com, sir.
[KIRK]
Scotty.
[SCOTTY]
We've got three main power
couplings down, Captain.
We've rerouted, but it's jury rigged.
It'll take an hour to repair.
Understood. Kirk out.
[SPOCK]
The Meskan hybrid starship
is disabled and drifting.
Sensors detect seven incoming contacts:
Peshan design.
[KIRK]
Kyril, you've got to make them
understand we're not their enemy.
They won't believe me, Captain.
They'll assume I'm under
psychomorphic control.
[SPOCK]
The Eagle is changing course
turning on the Peshan.
My god.
Our technology is going to
slaughter the Peshan fleet.
[SPOCk]
Full scan of the Eagle's current
configuration now complete.
Reviewing it will take time, but it may
provide us with an exploitable weakness.
And with Mr Scott needing an hour.... We've
got to find a way to knock out her screens.
[SPOCK]
Those circuit nodes are heavily
protected from weapons fire.
What about a stimulus overload?
Possible. Such a flash would impair
our sensors as well, however.
Leaving us open to attack from both
Peshan and Meskan forces.
[KIRK]
It's a chance we're going to
have to take, Mr Spock.
I don't want to see another ship
destroyed by a Starfleet vessel.
[ALERSA]
What's happened?
[ANDOCH]
Sensors are down across the grid.
The Enterprise caused it. We cannot
accurately move or fire. We're blind.
Then fire on Kirk's
last known position.
Voral. Get those
sensors fixed.
NOW!
Mr Sulu, continue on the pre-plotted course
Get us some distance.
[SULU]
Aye, sir.
[SPOCK]
We're likely to recover sensors
simultaneously with the Eagle
but the Peshan may
rebound more quickly.
[SPOCK]
Confirmed.
They already have.
[KIRK]
Transfer all power to the deflector screens.
Stand down from battlestations.
Mr DeSalle?
[DeSALLE]
They'll hold against the
Peshan lasers, sir.
[UHURA]
If we can get out of jamming range for
30 seconds, sir. I can send a burst
transmission to Starfleet Command.
[KYRIL]
Captain, we can't wait for your fleet to arrive.
Those new ships of her's will destroy my people.
[KIRK]
Lt Uhura. Get me the information
from the Eagle's logs.
I want to know how to hurt her.
Mr Spock, you have the con.
[KIRK]
Engineering.
[McCOY]
Deck eight.
One of your officers needs his captain.
I'd call that 'ship's business.'
[PETER]
Enter.
Captain...
At ease, Ensign.
I'd be on duty, sir, but the doctor
has ordered otherwise.
Well Doctor's orders can be a bit
annoying at times.
Dr McCoy is under the impression
you need a little guidance.
That maybe you're being a bit too hard on
yourself about this incident on the planet.
I'm trying to learn from
my mistakes, sir.
That was your order.
Peter, that was advice
not an order.
You might try listening to me a little bit.
It might be easier for you if you just relax.
Could you just please, sit down?
Lt Chekov thinks I'm over-analysing.
You are.
And i know this because it's what
another Ensign Kirk used to do.
Listen, your distraction on the planet...
Perfectly normal.
Your wounds...
... very raw.
But there's no way he would want
you to risk your life for his memory.
PETER:
No, sir. He wouldn't.
[KIRK]
Then don't.
More than anybody else on this ship
I know that you came here to be with him.
And for no other reason.
Now that he's gone...
...you feel alone
Really alone.
Peter, you're not alone.
Nobody on this ship is alone.
And you have a duty to honour his memory.
Honour it by living.
Please don't let his loss be the
weight that pulls you down.
Is that what you would do?
If you lost someone you loved so much?
[KIRK]
It's what I've done.
I'd like to return to duty, sir.
But the doctor...
Yes, the doctor.
What exactly did McCoy
have to say to you?
To take advantage of the downtime.
Peter.... That's exactly what
you should do.
[VORAL]
Alersa...
[ALERSA]
Don't waste my time, Voral.
If sensors aren't restored I expect
for you to be working on them.
[VORAL]
Alersa, my apologies. My report: I-I've restored
some circuits, but not all. With time--
[ALERSA]
Time?
How much time, Voral?
The time it takes to bandage a wound?
[VORAL]
I don't know m'lady. We've never
done battle with such a ship as theirs.
They know more about certain systems.
[ALERSA]
But... they don't know me, yet.
And you do.
Will you fail me? You know
the consequences.
[VORAL]
Yes, m'lady.
[ALERSA]
Yes, you'll fail me?!
[VORAL]
N-no. I'll restore the sensors.
[ALERSA]
Immediately?
[VORAL]
You have my word...
...and my heart.
[ALERSA]
Of course, I do.
[laughter]
[PETER]
Do you think the Captain has someone
in mind to replace Dickerson?
[SENTELL]
I think you should concentrate more on
getting your sea legs under you...
Before vying for department chief.
You have a knack for this stuff.
Scotty, would be eager to
shanghai you for extra work
We've decrypted the Eagle log data.
[EAGLE CAPTAIN]
Captain's Log, Stardate 813.2
An imperfection in our dilithium crystals
has caused an engine imbalance.
It's created a wormhole and
sent us across the quadrant.
Long range communications are down.
We have received an answer
to our distress call...
from a nearby race known as the Meska.
They've sent a ship
[explosion]
-- they sent a ship to help.
Captain's Log: Supplemental.
The Meskan! The Doctor warned me!
... Must attempt self-destruct!
Last resort! Take as many of them
with us as we can!
[EAGLE SCIENCE OFFICER]
No!
[Alersa cackles]
[McCOY]
Maybe the Doctor wasn't affected.
[KIRK]
The Captain obviously was.
Alersa affected his mind.
She made him do things. Give orders
he otherwise wouldn't have.
That crew was bound to follow.
[KYRIL]
My wife suffered the same fate.
She was a captain in our fleet.
Three years ago...
Alersa captured her...
Twisted her mind.
Used her against us all.
At Alersa's order, Shati killed my
commander and destroyed his vessel.
To avoid further carnage...
I had to give the order to--
My wife's death was at my OWN hands.
Alersa did more than deprive
Shati of her identity, Captain.
She stole from me my life.
When I thought you Meskan...
I thought my fate the same as Shati's...
I owe you an apology.
KIRK:
No. We owe you.
For allowing our technology to be stolen
and used against you in the first place.
Options, Mr Scott?
[SCOTTY]
Damn few. That blasted armour
is a rodinium derivative alloy,
protecting her most sensitive areas.
[SPOCK]
Scans of the armour's characteristics
indicate a large fleet
moving toward the Peshan homeworld.
[KYRIL]
Captain, you must stop them.
[KIRK]
We can't engage an entire fleet.
We'd be killing thousands.
We've got to take the Eagle back.
Kill the snake at it's head.
While its body devours my people?
[SPOCK]
There may be a way to stop
both Alersa and her fleet.
A review of the Eagle's logs indicate this area
of space is uncommonly susceptible
to subspace disruption.
Local subspace disequilibrium.
Were the Eagle's engine output modified,
it would disrupt subspace in this area for some time,
rendering faster than light travel impossible.
They're not going to voluntarily
modify their engines.
[CHEKOV]
It would take a saboteur.
[McCOY]
Wait a minute...
"This area" includes where, exactly?
[SPOCK]
We cannot know the location of
every Meskan hybrid starship.
To be effective the disruption must
encompass BOTH star systems.
[McCOY]
My god, Jim...
That would isolate them totally.
What if their colony worlds
can't survive without support?
Millions could die. On both sides.
[KIRK]
Mr Spock...
How long would this disruption last?
Unknown.
[KYRIL]
Many of our colonies would
find life difficult for a time...
But this would keep my homeworld safe.
[McCOY]
And what of the Meskan?
Who speaks for them?
They can't all support this war.
Those who don't die along with those who do?
[KYRIL]
Such is the unfortunate
price of warfare, Doctor.
WE are not the aggressors.
[McCOY]
Yeah, well ask the dead if they give
a damn who the aggressors are.
[KYRIL]
Fewer would die this way.
[MCCOY]
You don't know that. You CAN'T know that.
Jim, we can't do this.
[KIRK]
I agree with the Doctor.
We'd be making a decision that would not
only affect this generation
...but countless generations to come.
We can't doom two cultures like this.
[KYRIL]
Captain, you argue for a posterity that
won't exist should we die today!
Commander...
This isn't the answer.
[bosun whistle]
Kirk here.
[XON]
Sensors have been restored, Captain.
But the Eagle is already gone.
[KIRK]
Find them.
All hands, battlestations.
[alert klaxon]
[KIRK] Captain's Log: Stardate 7232.8
Commander Kyril has contacted his government.
They have approved the subspace
destabilisation plan.
That makes my decision no easier.
What's left of the Peshan forces have
pulled back to defend their home-world
from an attacking Meskan fleet
that I must stop.
If necessary, with the drastic
measure Spock has suggested.
[KIRK]
She's alone again. Target the Eagle.
[CHEKOV]
Aye, sir.
[SPOCK]
Two vessels, incoming.
Hybrid Meskan starships.
Time to intercept:
Three point two minutes
[KYRIL]
Our sixth fleet...
Seventy-five hundred souls...
They're gone.
Now nothing stands between
her and my planet.
We've got to get through that armour.
Keptin, it may be possible to strengthen
our phasers enough to burn through
Ve could reroute our power
directly through the varp engines.
[SCOTTY]
Our relays really aren't designed
to withstand that.
[KIRK]
Bypass them.
Aye. But the firing circuits will
only hold for a minute or two.
A minute or two will get her
attention, Mr Scott.
Aye, sir.
Mr Spock, this plan...
How certain are you
this thing's going to work?
The problem is not
execution but timing.
In order for the Enterprise to
escape the subsequent dead zone
The engine imbalance which created
the wormhole and brought the Eagle to
this system must be duplicated.
And only moments before setting off
the susbspace disruption.
Kyril? Are you sure about this?
Are your people sure?
I'm not.
But it's a price they
are willing to pay.
There will at least be peace if neither
side can visit war on the enemy.
If we are to be trapped together forever...
Maybe it's a just accounting for
our respective crimes.
[KIRK]
I can send you home in a shuttle.
You'll reach your colony in--
[KYRIL]
Captain, I was an astrophysicist.
If my people are to be lost to
space-normal travel...
someone needs to be outside the
phenomena, looking for a solution.
And I have no family to return to.
[KIRK]
What adjustments do i need to make
to the Eagle's engines?
Captain, I am the logical choice to beam
over to the Eagle and affect the modifications.
Alersa's abilities may
be a threat to you,
while my Vulcan mental disciplines--
[KIRK]
Are needed here.
That woman murdered a starship
captain and killed his crew.
I'm going, Spock.
[SPOCK]
It will take two saboteurs.
Someone must route power
to the proper circuits
while the other modifies the plasma flow.
[KIRK]
Peter?
[PETER]
Yes, sir?
I understand that you've been polishing
your engineering skills.
Good. Because you're coming with me.
[ANDOCH]
They're cruising at Warp 8,
heading deep into our system.
[ALERSA]
Increase speed to match.
[ANDOCH]
The drain to the engines will limit disruptor
batteries and our structural integrity.
ANDOCH!
Intercept the Enterprise.
Everything I have worked to achieve
will not be destroyed.
You know why? Do you?
Because you will not let that happen.
[PETER]
Mr Scott?
Request permission to assist
with the warp phasers.
"Warp phasers"? Is that what
we're calling 'em now?
They will be powered
by the warp engines, sir.
Aye.
You lads finish these bypasses.
I gotta get back to
ruining my engines.
[KYLE]
Imbalancing the engines puts the
lives of everyone onboard at risk.
Nobody knows that
better than Scotty.
[PETER]
What if it doesn't work and
there is no wormhole?
[KYLE]
We're sending out a warp buoy
ahead of the destabilisation wave.
Starfleet will be briefed
in three weeks.
[PETER]
And we'll be trapped here?
[KYLE]
Not to worry, Ensign...
There's a Class 'M' planet only
thirteen years away at impulse.
Mr Chekov, It's the Eagle we want.
Even the odds.
Aye, sir
[SPOCK]
Eagle is returning fire.
All weapon banks.
[UHURA]
Casualty reports.
Multiple injuries, Captain.
Bridge to Kyle.
Captain, I should really
run a diagnostic--
We need those phasers now!
[KYLE]
These circuits weren't meant
for this. They're going to blow.
Kyle, throw the switch!
[CHEKOV]
Keptin! Phasers online!
Fire.
[ANDOCH]
Shields and weapons offline.
[ALERSA]
Hide them from, Kirk --
and jam their sensors!
And get those weapons back!
[CHEKOV]
Chot!
Phasers -- torpedoes -- The
whole weapons sub-system.
Gone.
[KIRK}
Kyle, get those weapons back online.
[KYLE]
Aye, sir.
KIRK:
Uhura, get me the Eagle.
Onscreen.
Alersa. I think its time we
meet face to face.
We're prepared to beam you
aboard the Enterprise.
[ALERSA]
Captain Kirk...
I had no idea what a developed sense
of humour you Starfleet men have.
Well we've flexed our muscles...
We've tested each other.
We've looked and found our
strengths and weaknesses.
Let's talk.
I'm sure we can come to some
sort of understanding.
So now it's my turn to slit this
pretty throat for you?
[KIRK]
No.
I'll come to you.
This way you will get a first hand look
at the operation of our transporters.
Captain Kirk...
You become more interesting
with each passing moment.
Come to me.
[SENTELL]
Transporter controls have been rewired so
we can beam both signals in at the same time...
The second signal won't be detected.
We've rigged it for maximum speed transport,
to limit time shields are down.
[KIRK]
You have the co-ordinates to beam
Ensign Kirk to the Jefferies tube.
[SENTELL]
Aye, sir.
MCCOY:
Keep a lock on those subcutaneous
transponders at all times.
And you...
Try not dig this one out with a spoon.
[KIRK]
Energise.
[SENTELL]
Energising.
[McCOY]
Two Kirks...
God must be punishing me.
[ANDOCH]
If we were smart we'd kill him now.
[communicator chirp]
[ALERSA]
What's the delay?
[ANDOCH]
He's aboard m'lady, we'll take
him to the briefing room--
[ALERSA]
My quarters, Andoch.
[ANDOCH]
I thought that--
[ALERSA]
What have I told you about thinking?
Don't think. JUST DO as I say.
[SENTELL]
No change, Mr Spock.
We can't maintain a lock
on the Captain's transponder.
We've done everything we
can to boost the signal.
[SPOCK]
The armour is interfering
with the transmission
[McCOY]
What about, Peter?
[SENTELL]
I have a lock on Ensign Kirk.
He's in a less protected section.
Mr Spock, if we can reach the Captain via
communicator to establish his general position
...and keep the shields
down 75% longer.
That would leave the Enterprise open to heavy
attack should the Eagle restore her weapons.
Spock, we are not
leaving Jim behind.
If we cannot locate him, Doctor
we may not have a choice.
[ALERSA]
Captain Kirk...
Well, in person at last.
Are you truly here to talk?
Or are you secretly
planning to kill me?
[KIRK]
Well telling you would take away
half the challenge, wouldn't it?
Ohhhh... We are two of a kind.
Why don't we just start with a
tour of your modifications.
I have something else in mind.
[ANDOCH]
Alersa...
Do not question me, Andoch.
Or your next visit to these quarters
will be far less pleasant than usual.
[KIRK]
No guards. I'm flattered.
[ALERSA]
You don't strike me as the type of man
who would hurt a defenceless lady.
And you don't strike
me as a lady...
...who's defenceless.
You are right about one thing...
I'm anything but defenceless.
[ALERSA]
You see we are the same... don't you?
Yes, we are...
But not exactly.
I'm glad you noticed, Captain.
Call me, Jim.
Call me, Alersa.
Jim, you were going to
tell me why you're here.
Well...
I'd like too.
[ALERSA]
Yes...
I... I can't.
You can..
Jim....
You trusted me the
moment we met.
[KIRK]
I trusted you.
[ALERSA]
Yes.
[communicator chirp]
[PETER]
Modifications complete, Mr Spock.
Acknowledged. Activate at Mr Sentell's
signal for transporter coordination
[McCOY]
Peter, the Captain's
transponder isn't working.
Mr Spock, Standby. I can set
this to trigger remotely.
I'm going to find
the Captain.
[ALERSA]
Jim...
Jim, I think it's time for you
to tell me why you're here.
[KIRK]
Your armour modifications would take
us years to learn about from scans.
I came to get the information
for Starfleet.
[ALERSA]
Jim...
That would have been
very, very, very naughty.
You should beg forgiveness
shouldn't you?
[KIRK]
I should.
[ALERSA]
Yes...
[KIRK]
The transporter. You want it.
I could show you how to fix it.
Show me.
Show me how to
have more power.
... and all will be forgiven.
[KIRK]
Take me to your Engineer.
Yes.
I'll show him.
[ALERSA]
It's alright.
[stuns]
[ALERSA]
Impossible...
You couldn't have.
Oh, I wouldn't have.
Not with you.
[stuns]
[PETER]
Somehow I knew I'd find you here.
What happened?
]KIRK]
Exhaustion.
What are you doing here?
There's no signal from
your transponder.
I've set the disruption to
trigger from remote.
[KIRK]
Inside.
[SENTELL]
Mr Spock, we've lost
both signals now.
[XON]
They've restored weapons and
are charging all ports.
[SCOTTY]
The imbalance will begin at warp one
but if they fire their disruptors.
Take evasive action.
The Eagle's engines are
whining like a toy...
We've got less than 50 seconds.
[bosun whistle]
[KIRK]
Enterprise, two to beam out.
Deck 5. Section 7.
[SPOCK]
Transporter room.
Prepare to energise.
Lower the shields.
Mr Sentell...
You have 42.9 seconds.
[UHURA]
We've got them, Mr Spock.
[CHEKOV]
Shields up.
Launch the warp buoy, Mr Chekov.
Mr Sulu, warp one.
[beeping]
[ALERSA]
Noooooooooo!
[SPOCK]
Federation Space, Captain.
[SULU]
Exactly, three parsecs
from Starbase seven.
[SPOCK]
I thought we might need the
benefit of their repair facilities.
[KYRIL]
Did you kill her?
[KIRK]
She's stranded, Commander.
Powerless.
I'd call that justice.
[KYRIL]
A shallow justice, Captain.
[KIRK] Captain's Log: Stardate 7233.1
Repairs are almost complete.
Starfleet is gathering a taskforce which
will be heading for Peshan Space.
Probes detect the dead zone blanketing
the entirety of the Peshan and Meskan systems.
For how long we can't be sure.
[door buzzer]
[KIRK]
Come.
[CHEKOV]
You vanted to see me, sir.
Yes, I did.
Mr Chekov, your idea to channel the
phasers through the main warp engines.
Do you realise it destroyed the
entire weapons sub-systems.
[CHEKOV]
Yes, sir, I...
I'm aware of that.
I'm sorry, sir.
[KIRK]
You saved the ship.
You saved my life
on the planet.
Keptin, I vas only doing vhat
any good officer vould do.
Mr Chekov, you consistently see dangers to this
ship and this crew long before the rest of us do.
You're at the navigation station, you...
Strategise and Analyse.
See things the rest of
us never dream of.
You have a fatalistic
heart, Mr Chekov.
Sir, I'm sorry i have
disappointed you.
I'm going to make you
Chief of Security.
In addition to your
duties as navigator.
Thank you, sir.
You realise of course this will put
Mr Kirk under your direct command.
I understand you've already
taken him under your wing.
N-not that I'm
aware of, sir.
[KIRK]
Well...
He's going to need a mentor and I can't
think of anyone more suited to the task.
You know how he is...
He's a bit too rash.
Stubborn.
Competitive.
And he's way too hard on himself.
Consensus on this ship is that he
reminds you of somebody else.
[CHEKOV]
Yes...
You.
Keptin.
[KYRIL]
Captain. Gentlemen.
I'm glad we got the chance to say goodbye
before I transport to the Lexington.
My people are safe and I have
all of you to thank for it.
Especially you...
for risking yourself to
Alersa's powerful will.
[McCOY]
Well she'd never
met a Kirk before.
[PETER]
We have will to spare, sir.
[KIRK]
And we managed to
use it together.
[McCOY]
Commander Kyril...
Good luck on finding a
solution to the dead zone.
[SPOCK]
I shall be interested in monitoring
the progress of the taskforce.
[KIRK]
There may be no solution coming.
[KYRIL]
No but it was necessary to
stop the slaughter.
Perhaps now, both sides will be more focused
on the problems the dead zone presents
Rather than on a war that
can no longer be fought.
[KIRK]
Well...
I hope that you see your home
again and that your people prosper.
No matter what their conditions.
[SPOCK]
Lexington signals. They're ready, sir.
[KIRK]
Safe travels, Commander.
And you, Captain.
Energise.
Now there goes one brave man.
The Peshan are a brave people to have embraced a
solution with such complex challenges.
The challenge begins now, Spock.
Where facing life in a world that everyday
presents a new set of challenges.
It's going to take a lot of courage to
work together for the common good.
Courage, gentlemen:
The order of the day.
[music swells]
This is James Cawley.
Stay tuned for exciting scenes
from our next 'Star Trek'
Next Time on Star Trek: Phase II
Reading something ahead, Commander.
Looks to be a nebula.
Should we wake the Captain, sir?
I don't understand it...
I have not broken my vow.
What's wrong Isel?
I'm pregnant, Doctor.
KIRK:
That child may pose a threat to this
ship in ways we cannot anticipate
No matter how much Isel,
loves that child.
It was placed inside her
by an unknown alien.
For an unknown reason.
ISEL:
Mother...
[Baby laughter]
PETER:
Something is being beamed
aboard from the alien cylinder.
The alien energy beam is focused on
impulse engine: plasma cooling unit 2
KIRK:
Lock phasers on target.
SULU:
Locked on target, sir.
KIRK:
Fire
SCOTTY:
Medical team to Engineering
Lt Ross has taken a massive
dose of Theta Radiation
KIRK:
Do you have any idea whether or not
she's connected to that cylinder out there
CHILD:
I didn't mean to hurt you.
KIRK:
Spock. What happened?
SPOCK:
It was intoxicating
CHILD:
Mr Scott is dying.
I have to help him.
SPOCK:
It is an extreme bio-toxin and we
were exposed to a lethal dose
Unless Dr McCoy can
counteract it within 6.2 hours
It will kill us all.
[English Subtitles - Peter Goundrill and Peter Walker]