Can you do this?
And all these practices.
We've got that giveaway.
So we're going to do the big
wind bags with everybody.
We've got our team that
practiced the huge solar bags.
And they're running
through that.
We practiced in the parking
lot with the
exploding trash cans.
We've got that piece.
I think I've got a good
shot with the potato.
It's all coming together.
So now this is the unknown.
This is what happens when
you put a live audience.
And somebody says go.
And 45 minutes later.
Oh, and by the way, Guinness
World Records showing up.
So an adjudicator from Guinness
World Records said
yes, and so we flew him in,
and so they're here.
And so if we do it, this will be
the world's largest physics
demonstra--
the world's largest
physics lesson.
Let's see how it goes.
Thank you so much
for being here.
I greatly appreciate it.
Thank you so much
for being here.
And being part of
our first annual
Weather and Science Day.
You are going to have a blast.
We've got so many things
scheduled for you.
We know that sitting and
watching a science program is
not as much fun as doing it,
so we may teach you some
things that you can
try later on.
We actually have something that
you're going to do with
us later on as well.
And so I'm going to need your
help in doing that.
We're going to try to attempt
the world's largest physics
demonstration or lesson right
here, at Coors Field.
And we're going to need
everybody that we have here in
the stands.
Well, let's get started because
when we're talking
about weather and science, we've
got to talk a little bit
about what goes on with solids,
liquids and gases in
those things.
And so I thought that it might
be a smart idea to do the very
first experiment you and
I ever did together.
Fair enough?
KATHY SABINE: Oh, let's do it.
STEVE SPANGLER: And we just
happen to have a couple little
ingredients I'm sure you've
never seen before.
These are kinds of things
that you can find
at home, all right?
KATHY SABINE: I don't
get to drink this?
STEVE SPANGLER: Which
is wonderful.
Good job.
Everybody in the stands, you
should have a roll of Mentos
and a test tube, do you?
KATHY SABINE: Everybody got
them, hold them up.
All right.
STEVE SPANGLER: That roll
of Mentos and test
tube is for you later.
But you must start with
me this way, ready?
Say I promise not to
do this at home.
CROWD: I promise not
to do this at home.
STEVE SPANGLER: I will do
it at a friend's home.
KATHY SABINE: Oh!
STEVE SPANGLER: Perfect,
all right?
Here's what we're going to do.
Kathy, If you take
a bottle of soda,
KATHY SABINE: OK.
STEVE SPANGLER: And you shake
up that bottle of soda.
KATHY SABINE: Let
me shake it now.
STEVE SPANGLER: Carbon dioxide,
that gas, will come
out of the soda.
So what we're going to
do is we're going to
help it come out.
This time, we're going to use
these Mentos, all right?
Mentos are amazing because
there's these tiny little pits
that they have.
And so all the carbon dioxide
kind of comes running to it.
The trick here, kids, is what
you have to do, is you're
going to put your fingers
at home--
I mean at a friend's home--
over here, like this.
Don't do it inside either.
That's the other little
problem, all right?
When you drop them all in
it once, the carbon
dioxide will come out.
All right, so are you
ready, Kathy?
KATHY SABINE: I don't know.
STEVE SPANGLER: You and I are
going to hold it together, we
turn it upside down.
Three, two, one drops it.
See, that's why that-- nice.
Nice, that was good,
wasn't it?
KATHY SABINE: Wow, that's
minty fresh.
That's good.
STEVE SPANGLER: Nice.
KATHY SABINE: That's good.
STEVE SPANGLER: But here's
the problem, all right?
The problem is if you just take
Mentos and drop them into
Diet Coke, that's not a science
experiment, that's
just doing something fun.
KATHY SABINE: That's making
a mess, Steve.
STEVE SPANGLER: It
is making a mess.
We need to turn this into a
real science experiment.
In order to do that,
we need to be able
to control a variable.
So I think we're going to be
able to do it if we have a
really good geyser team.
So ladies and gentlemen, from
the dugout, please welcome the
Steve Spangler Science
Geyser Team.
Come on out, guys.
All right guys, this is our
geyser team right here.
These are geyserologists.
They have been practicing
and practicing.
Earlier today our geyserologists
went into the
stands and found 10
lucky people.
If you're one of those 10 lucky
people, you look at the
geyserologists.
They're going to look at you.
Right now, give us a little
music, and go get your kids.
Would you do that for me?
Go get your kids.
Go.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
KATHY SABINE: We've got
to root them on.
We're going to get
them sticky wet.
STEVE SPANGLER: Ladies and
gentlemen, nice round of
applause for our 10 helpers,
would you?
Nice?
All right.
All right, geyser team, it's
really important that we
practice safety, so would you
please put on the safety
glasses, all right?
Put on those safety glasses.
Kids, you adjust those safety
glasses, team go get to the
goodies, all right?
Go get the goodies.
Let me tell you the experiment
that we've set up.
You can only change
one variable.
So this time, Kathy, we're
going to use Diet Coke.
KATHY SABINE: All right.
STEVE SPANGLER: We're not going
to change anything.
KATHY SABINE: I love that.
STEVE SPANGLER: Same temperature
of Diet Coke.
The only thing that we're going
to do is we're going to
change the number of Mentos.
I want you to know the
number that gives
us the highest geyser.
So from left to right, we're
going to do one Mentos, two
Mentos, three Mentos, all
the way up to 10 Mentos.
KATHY SABINE: Great.
STEVE SPANGLER: So if we were to
do a finale, I don't know.
But if we were to do a finale,
you would know the number of
Mentos you should drop in
for the highest geyser.
Fair enough?
All right, kids, your
geyserologist is going to is
going to put on your poncho
for you, all right?
10 ponchos, 10 kids.
KATHY SABINE: Perfect.
STEVE SPANGLER: It's funny how
math kind of works that way.
KATHY SABINE: Yes, it does.
STEVE SPANGLER: It's a little
tube that we have on the top.
It's the geyser tube that's
just holding it in place.
So when we pull, we'll
pull the first one.
We'll get a chance to be able
to see what that looks like.
Then the second one.
Then the third one.
All right?
Kids, put your hands over
the top of the bottles.
All right?
They're pulling the pin
here in just a second.
Let's do the very first one.
Are you ready, Zara?
Three, two, one.
Pull it.
All right, so one Mentos is
OK, but a little boring on
Science Day.
Two Mentos, go.
KATHY SABINE: Aw, Steve,
that could be the one.
STEVE SPANGLER: That's good.
KATHY SABINE: Two
is looking good.
STEVE SPANGLER: Three
Mentos, go!
KATHY SABINE: No, it's
got to be two.
Whoa!
STEVE SPANGLER: Nice.
I see a pattern here.
KATHY SABINE: Three is better.
STEVE SPANGLER: Four Mentos.
KATHY SABINE: Let's
go with four.
STEVE SPANGLER: Try four.
Nice.
Five Mentos.
Good job.
KATHY SABINE: Whoa!
STEVE SPANGLER: Now
six Mentos.
Give me a six.
KATHY SABINE: Woo!
STEVE SPANGLER: Are you kind
of seeing what I'm seeing?
We're kind of hitting
a plateau here.
Seven Mentos.
Nice!
We just hit a magic number.
Eight Mentos--
nice!
KATHY SABINE: Woo!
STEVE SPANGLER: Nine Mentos.
Nice!
Give me a 10, would ya?
KATHY SABINE: Go Jack!
STEVE SPANGLER: Nice!
KATHY SABINE: Whoa!
STEVE SPANGLER: If you were
going to do it, and you were
actually going to use
a bottle, how many
Mentos would you use?
AUDIENCE: 10!
STEVE SPANGLER: All right
guys, go get 'em,
let's do 10, all right?
Now the hard part here is our
geyser team has to get
everything ready.
So they have to unroll it, and
then we have to have a team
together so we can pull
all at the same time.
KATHY SABINE: So everybody
has 10, Steve?
STEVE SPANGLER: Is
everybody ready?
Let's count 'em down from five.
Ready?
ALL: Five, four, three,
two, one.
STEVE SPANGLER: Give
them a pull now.
Nice job!
KATHY SABINE: Wooo!
STEVE SPANGLER: Well, I guess
those seats aren't so good
after all, are they?
KATHY SABINE: Yes!
STEVE SPANGLER: Ladies and
gentlemen, let's hear it for
our geyser team.
KATHY SABINE: Yes!
And how about those
volunteers?
STEVE SPANGLER: So Kathy, I told
you you'd have to do a
couple little demos.
So I'm going to ask
you to blow up a
balloon in front of everybody.
KATHY SABINE: OK.
Are you saying I'm full
of hot air, Steve?
STEVE SPANGLER: No, I'm just
saying you're going
to blow up a balloon.
It's just fine.
KATHY SABINE: All right.
STEVE SPANGLER: But if I have
you blow up a balloon, I don't
really know where to
get you to stop.
You know what I mean?
How many breaths does it take
to blow up the balloon?
It could be this many,
could be this many.
KATHY SABINE: OK.
STEVE SPANGLER: So here's what
I have for you, right here.
Watch this.
KATHY SABINE: Great.
STEVE SPANGLER: This is a little
different balloon.
It's eight feet long, it's 10
inches around, and it holds 45
liters of air.
Blow into the bag.
Ready?
KATHY SABINE: Ok.
STEVE SPANGLER: Go.
Now this is the problem, people,
because this takes
about 32 minutes.
So, don't worry,
it'll be fine.
Kathy, look at this.
Watch this.
If we slide it down like this,
it comes out this big old hole
down over here.
So that, tiny little problem.
I got so excited, I forgot
about that part.
KATHY SABINE: Me, too.
STEVE SPANGLER: Just give
me three breaths.
Would you do that?
Three breaths.
KATHY SABINE: All right.
STEVE SPANGLER: Nice,
there's one.
There's--
I didn't tell you it'd be a hot
day and you'd be breathing
into a stupid bag.
There's three.
KATHY SABINE: Is that enough?
STEVE SPANGLER: Look at this.
Now--
Look at little miss
athlete over here.
Three breaths of air, people.
It's not bad.
KATHY SABINE: And no lipstick
left at all.
STEVE SPANGLER: I think you
could do the whole bag in
probably 10 breaths of air.
But I want to show you
another way to do it.
KATHY SABINE: Yeah, could you?
STEVE SPANGLER: Another
way to do it.
Maybe a different way to do
it would be to do this.
If we could actually use the
air around us to help blow
into the bag, it would
be extremely helpful.
KATHY SABINE: You're going
to let my air out.
I worked hard for that.
STEVE SPANGLER: That's OK.
It's all right.
I'll show you the secret.
It's all about the shower
curtain in the morning that
attacks you every
single morning.
When you turn on that shower
and the water comes rushing
down, that silly shower
curtain starts
to move in on you.
When it does, it's Bernoulli's
principle.
It says fast-moving
air will create
this area of low pressure.
So if you just hold
from far away.
KATHY SABINE: Yeah, I'll
do the holding.
STEVE SPANGLER: Watch what's
going to happen.
If you and I hold like this--
and in just a second, when you
try, you're going to open
up the bag like this.
And then a long stream of air
into the bag, but stand back.
Watch what happens.
See how fast?
KATHY SABINE: You made
that look so easy.
STEVE SPANGLER: Single breath
of air, but you
have to stand back.
Turn to the person
next to you and
say, Bernoulli's principle.
Tell 'em, right now.
KATHY SABINE: We're not
going to ask them to
spell it, are we?
STEVE SPANGLER: In just a
second, we're going to stand
up, and you are going to
have two minutes to
inflate 7,000 wind bags.
KATHY SABINE: Are you
up to the challenge?
STEVE SPANGLER: And our good
friends over here from Sky
Nine are going to circle right
in and take a look at us.
Stand up everybody.
KATHY SABINE: Stand
up everybody!
STEVE SPANGLER: Roll
the bags out.
Ready?
Go for it.
Roll those bags out.
Tie off one end, all
right, people.
Give us a little bump music.
Would you do that for us?
A little high energy--
something that would be fun
to inflate some bags by.
Fair enough?
[MUSIC--
REPUBLICA, "READY TO GO"]
STEVE SPANGLER: All right,
tie off one end--
KATHY SABINE: Boy, they've
got it up there.
Steve, look at those
kids in the back.
They've got it.
STEVE SPANGLER: Nice job.
KATHY SABINE: Nice
job back there.
STEVE SPANGLER: Find somebody
a couple rows back from you
who will hold on to the bag
maybe, so that you can try to
inflate it with a single
breath of air.
Oh, you're looking good.
I'll know you're done
when you hold it up.
Nice job.
KATHY SABINE: Woo!
STEVE SPANGLER: Ladies
and gentlemen, look
at this around you.
You're halfway there.
All right?
We have a minute and
10 seconds to go.
A minute and 10 seconds.
Help the people around you.
Daniel Bernoulli would
be very proud of you.
He's just not here right now.
Gosh, that looks good.
Isn't that fun?
KATHY SABINE: It's so fun!
STEVE SPANGLER: I told you
that would be fun.
A little Bernoulli's principle
never hurt anybody.
Here we go.
We're at 30 seconds.
Help the people around you.
KATHY SABINE: You've got it.
STEVE SPANGLER: Over 7,000 bags
in less than two minutes.
We're at our countdown.
15, 14, 13, 12,
KATHY SABINE: 11, 10, 9,
8, 7, 6, 5, 4, 3, 2, 1.
STEVE SPANGLER: Let's
hear it, people.
You got it.
Look at this.
KATHY SABINE: Woo!
STEVE SPANGLER: Nice job.
That's over 7,000 bags
in under two minutes.
That's absolutely amazing.
KATHY SABINE: That is
amazing, Steve.
STEVE SPANGLER: Isn't
that fun?
Congratulations for paying
attention and allowing us to
be able to do that.
Take the air down.
Teachers, help us out.
Let me direct your attention
to the field right now, and
watch what's going to
happen on the field.
Our 9News Spangler Science
Team is out on
the field right now.
But they have wind bags that are
50 feet long and hold 350
cubic feet of air.
And the only thing that's
powering them is the sun.
So the hot sun is heating
the air in the bag.
And now, watch what we've got.
We literally have floating
solar sausages out here.
So that you can kind of
see on Coors Field--
I don't think that these
have ever been
on Coors Field before.
KATHY SABINE: I'm
pretty sure not.
STEVE SPANGLER: Isn't
that nice?
Nice job.
Throw them up in
the air, guys.
Let's see if anything happens.
Now, Kathy, we have to be very
careful because, if you're a
teacher in the audience, and you
try this experiment, you
can't let go of the bag.
Because if you let go of the
bag, the FAA will think that
it's a fighter jet--
KATHY SABINE: And they'll
call Steve, and
he gets in big trouble.
STEVE SPANGLER: And then we're
in trouble, all right?
Then once again, we have
to go through legal.
We don't want to
do that again.
KATHY SABINE: And your people
don't want to go
through that again.
STEVE SPANGLER: Look at this!
They're actually using the
bag as a kite, ladies and
gentlemen, holding onto
it with a string.
So you can see it floating
there, using only the
power of the sun.
So that hot air rises, and
you're able to see what it
looks like there with
those solar bags.
We're going to let them play
out there for a second, but
would you do me a favor?
Would you give them a nice big
round of applause right now?
Nice job, guys.
Mr. Announcer, would you let
us know who's coming out of
the dugout?
Ladies and gentlemen--
KATHY SABINE: Hey,
you guys, look!
It's Jeff Francis.
[INAUDIBLE], yeah!
STEVE SPANGLER: Ladies and
gentlemen, Jeff Francis.
Hi, buddy.
How are you?
KATHY SABINE: Nice
to see you again.
STEVE SPANGLER: So,
Jeff, here's what
we've come up with.
Instead of a baseball, I've
got a potato and a straw.
So that's all I've got, is
a potato and a straw.
So, come here, watch this.
So I'm taking my straw
and carving out a
little piece of potato.
Kathy, remember doing this
in the news room?
KATHY SABINE: Oh, yes I do.
STEVE SPANGLER: So now, we're
going to push this little
piece of potato down here.
And using a little--
nice.
Got that?
So, Jeff, take a look at this.
A piece of potato here, and a
piece of potato here, and air
right here.
So if we were to compress the
air, we might be able to shoot
this little potato out
into the stands.
So I'll show you what
it looks like.
Ready?
So I've got it here,
like this.
And we just compress, and
now watch what happens.
KATHY SABINE: Whoa!
STEVE SPANGLER: Not bad.
But that's not Colorado
Rockies style, is it?
JEFF FRANCIS: No, it's not.
STEVE SPANGLER: It's kind
of boring, isn't it?
I'm glad you agreed
so quickly.
KATHY SABINE: Although, Steve,
that was pretty good.
STEVE SPANGLER: But
it was good.
Jeff would you bring on--
and Carly and Renee, go ahead
bring some of these on.
Jeff, these are giant
potato launchers.
I don't know of any other way to
be able to do this besides
at Coor's Field.
So, come on, Carly,
help us out.
All right, so this is our
giant potato launcher.
So here's the deal, you push
the button, the piece of
potato comes out here.
KATHY SABINE: Should
I give it to him?
STEVE SPANGLER: If I were you,
I'd fire it out there and see
if he can catch it.
JEFF FRANCIS: OK.
STEVE SPANGLER: Fair enough?
JEFF FRANCIS: Yeah.
STEVE SPANGLER: So I'm going to
let you hang on here, and
when you're ready to go, I just
hit the button, and see
if it fires.
Ready?
[DRUMROLL]
KATHY SABINE: Whoa, nice!
STEVE SPANGLER: Come on.
Catch it.
Yeah!
We have one more.
It's a little bigger, Jeff.
JEFF FRANCIS: I can't even
throw a ball that far.
STEVE SPANGLER: This one's
just a little bit bigger.
Just because I thought
that 10 Mentos would
be better than one.
Ready?
Go for it.
KATHY SABINE: Maybe I'll just
move out of the way.
Whoa!
[DRUMROLL]
STEVE SPANGLER: Home
run, people!
Ladies and gentlemen, let's
hear it for Jeff Francis!
KATHY SABINE: Yeah!
STEVE SPANGLER: Thanks, buddy.
Thank you very much.
No problem.
On injured reserve, anytime
you want to practice your
pitching, let us know, and
we'll help you out.
KATHY SABINE: Thanks, Jeff.
STEVE SPANGLER: Once again,
people, nice round of applause
for our Colorado Rockies.
Part of our Guinness World
Record is the largest physics
lesson over a 30-minute
period of time.
And so that means we've got
to at least incorporate a
test of some kind.
So if our nice people who are
controlling our video board
will show us what the test looks
like, it'll be right
behind you.
Take a look at this.
KATHY SABINE: Which element
makes up most of the air that
we breathe?
STEVE SPANGLER: Are you
ready for this?
So the answer is, C. Most
of the air that
you breathe is nitrogen.
So, we have this little
demonstration we want to do
right here, Kathy.
KATHY SABINE: Little
demonstration, Steve?
He never does anything little.
STEVE SPANGLER: We've never
done this before, so--
I mean with you, anyway.
I practiced one time
with a friend.
And, honestly, the ambulance
showed up really
fast, so it's fine.
Do you have the goodies
for us?
We've got a lot of stuff that we
have to bring out here, so
take a look at this.
KATHY SABINE: Oh, Steve,
I don't have to
get in that, do I?
STEVE SPANGLER: No,
no, no, no, no.
Thank you, Harmony,
I appreciate it.
Good job.
We've got some hot water
that's over here.
KATHY SABINE: Cold water
would be nice.
STEVE SPANGLER: Which is
probably pretty good.
Kathy, see your boots from
the 9News weather center?
KATHY SABINE: Uh-oh.
When Steve has me put on
my wellies, something
bad's going to happen.
STEVE SPANGLER: I would take
off those sandals--
although they're very nice-- and
I'd stick on those boots.
We have a very scientific
instrument for you.
It's called a bag.
KATHY SABINE: It looks
like a body bag.
STEVE SPANGLER: It's a poncho.
Put on your poncho.
I'll help you.
Good.
Got it?
KATHY SABINE: I don't know.
Do I got it?
STEVE SPANGLER: You're fine.
Inside the trash can, we now are
going to put some of that
liquid nitrogen.
So I have Brian on this side
and Jeff on this side, and
what I'm going to have
them do is to pour
in the liquid nitrogen.
If you take the air that we
breathe, and you compress it,
and you get it very cold,
you get liquid nitrogen.
Now, Kathy, the safety glasses
are great, but this is going
to be awesome.
So put on your--
got it?
How are you looking?
So here's the deal.
We're going to take hot water
that's at about to 200 degrees
right now, so it's really,
really hot, and then we're
going to dump it into
the liquid nitrogen.
And, I don't know, you
might see a little
bubbling take place.
KATHY SABINE: Wouldn't you
be afraid if you were me?
STEVE SPANGLER: Or you
might get a cloud.
And if it's cool, hopefully
we get to hear from you.
Fair enough?
OK, Kathy, here we go.
Let's--
KATHY SABINE: What
do I do, Steve?
STEVE SPANGLER: Prepare
for whatever.
KATHY SABINE: Prepare
for whatever?
STEVE SPANGLER: Countdown
from five.
Ready?
BOTH: Five, four,
three, two, one.
STEVE SPANGLER: Isn't
that wild?
KATHY SABINE: Wow!
That was refreshing!
STEVE SPANGLER: That
kind of fun?
I love that!
KATHY SABINE: Woo!
Can we do that again, Steve?
STEVE SPANGLER: We made
a cloud, people.
This is a cloud, right?
So there's our liquid
nitrogen.
We went from a liquid to
a gas in just a second.
Let me take this off.
KATHY SABINE: That was very cool
and refreshing, Steve.
STEVE SPANGLER: It was cool.
What we had, people,
was an explosion.
But what were we missing
with the explosion?
We were missing the
kaboom, right?
So would you look right
in front of you.
There are four trash cans and
four trashcanologists--
I don't know what else
to call them.
KATHY SABINE: Sounds
good to me, Steve.
STEVE SPANGLER: These guys here
are going to help us with
the next spot.
Please understand that what's
going to happen is only
happening here at Coors Field.
We are not doing
this at school.
We are not doing this at home.
This is just our special
demonstration that we are
fortunate to be able
to share with you.
KATHY SABINE: Steve, there's
stuff in my boots.
STEVE SPANGLER: They
have a bottle
sitting down by the side.
They have a funnel-- show them
the funnel, if you don't mind.
They have safety glasses, and
they have safety gloves.
All right.
Ready, team?
Pour--
give them a little applause and
a little cheering for the
pouring because it's a little
hard getting it in there.
Julie, you are going to speed
that up a little bit?
Good job.
So we figured that a little,
tiny kaboom at the very end
would be a wonderful way to
finish up our program.
Team, would you show me when
you are at that point.
You can hold up the bottle
and show me.
Please notice their
safety glasses on.
Kathy, you and I have our
So now we're going to get a
rapid expansion of that gas.
Ready?
Three, two, one, cap it.
Go!
Cap it, cap it, cap it.
Drop it.
[KABOOM]
STEVE SPANGLER: Nice job.
Cover your ears!
Cover your ears.
I'm sorry.
I forgot to tell you,
cover your ears.
Nice.
Let's hear it.
[MUSIC - P.O.D., "BOOM"]
STEVE SPANGLER: Nice job, guys,
all the way around.
That was fun.
KATHY SABINE: Way to go!
STEVE SPANGLER: Ladies and
gentlemen, from Guinness World
Record, would you
please welcome
the stage Danny Gerten.
Come on up, Danny.
KATHY SABINE: Let's hear it.
DANNY GERTEN: Thanks, guys.
Everybody having a
great time today?
AUDIENCE: Yeah!
DANNY GERTEN: I know
I sure did.
It was really fantastic to see
all of you take part in this
amazing event.
Guinness World Records is the
ultimate authority on
record-breaking achievement.
And it inspires people to strive
for their personal best
while making the ordinary
extraordinary.
And that is something, without
question, that each of the
5,401 of you did today in
helping to set the new
Guinness World Records
achievement for the largest
physics lesson.
Congratulations.
[MUSIC--
TINA TURNER, "SIMPLY
THE BEST"]
STEVE SPANGLER: Kathy,
hang on to that.
That's really good.
Thank you very much.
DANNY GERTEN: Thank
you, Steve.
STEVE SPANGLER: Ladies and
gentlemen, thank you so much
for helping us out.
We can't thank you enough
for being a part of it.
Thank you very much to Guinness
World Record.
Huge thanks to my great friends
at 9News, to Kathy
Sabine for helping make
this possible.
And please a nice round of
applause for the Colorado
Rockies who is helping
us enjoy--
The coolest part about yesterday
was seeing the video
once it all was ingested.
And you see the helicopter
flying over.
And the event's, like,
bigger than life.
I'm a science teacher, and
all of a sudden, there's
7,000-plus people there all
blowing up wind bags.
And to see our team come out
and do the geysers, and the
people cheering.
And all of the concerns about
the sound, people could hear.
And seeing the thing on the
Jumbotron was great.
And then it kind of made sense,
because at the very
end, the judge from Guinness
World Records stands up, and
it's like, oh I forgot
about that.
We were going for a Guinness
World Record.
And then you go, tada!
We got it.
How cool is that?
For a teacher to say,
well here's the
Guinness World Record.
Maybe the best part is that my
kids were in the front row.
And they got to come up
and take off school.
And when your three boys
give you a thumbs up,
life's pretty good.