[WIND]
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
ADRI MURGUIA: After settling in
on Faustino's land, we went
back to meet with him.
Our first impressions so far
were positive, despite what we
had heard from his relatives.
We wanted to understand how he
had managed to survive out
here on his own for
over four decades.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
ADRI MURGUIA: Augusto Pinochet
ruled Chile with an iron fist
from 1973 to 1990.
During this time, hundreds of
thousands of people were
forced to leave the country
in the wake
of an economic crisis.
Faustino was part of
this migration.
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
ADRI MURGUIA: When Faustino
returned to Chile, he used the
skills he picked up in Argentina
to build his first
home on the other end of this
property, by an area known as
the Green Lake.
This same skills would continue
to help them survive
even in the smallest of ways.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
ADRI MURGUIA: Since his return
from Argentina, Faustino has
not travelled beyond
Villa O'Higgins.
But he manages to stay in touch
with the rest of the
world through radio broadcasts
and by reading newspapers that
he gets once or twice a year.
He's watched TV maybe
once in his life.
But he knows more about politics
than the average
person in the area.
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
ADRI MURGUIA: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
ADRI MURGUIA: He's kept up with
everything, from 9/11 to
space exploration research.
But he has a first-row seat to
the unfolding tragedy of
global warming, despite not
knowing exactly what it means.
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
ADRI MURGUIA: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
ADRI MURGUIA: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
ADRI MURGUIA: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
ADRI MURGUIA: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
ADRI MURGUIA: He's going
to put us in the books.
FAUSTINO BARRIENTOS:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
ADRI MURGUIA: [SPEAKING SPANISH]