you could go into Afghanistan
and do day after day of
stories of quoting Marines,
quoting American soldiers
trashing President Obama.
Nobody does that.
They did it for Bush in Iraq.
When a soldier criticized
President Bush, it was news.
So this criticising Obama
because of the media's love
for Obama is not news.
BEN ANDERSON: McChrystal was
supposed to have gotten fired
because of your piece
in Rolling Stone.
Do you think he was fired
because of that piece?
MICHAEL HASTINGS: No.
I think there had been tensions
between the Pentagon
and the White House.
Was the Rolling Stone story the
excuse to fire this guy?
Look, if he'd been winning the
war, and the president would
have been happy with him, they
could have easily said, oh,
it's Rolling Stone.
People make mistakes.
General McChrystal and his staff
didn't think they were
going to get fired even when
the story came out.
They thought the story was
going to be worse,
according to them.
I had overheard this other
comment, which
was very, very bad.
BEN ANDERSON: From McChrystal
himself?
MICHAEL HASTINGS: From
one of his guys.
I can't even go into
what it was,
because it's so explosive.
So to see these senior military
officials criticize
the president not only in front
of me, but in front of
staffs of dozens,
I think was--
they questioned the judgment.
BEN ANDERSON: Yeah.
Everything came out
in the book.
You named people you
hadn't named in the
Rolling Stone article.
MICHAEL HASTINGS: Sure.
BEN ANDERSON: Well, did
you get a reaction
from the guys featured?
MICHAEL HASTINGS: The book
critically did quite well.
It was well received.
Really positive response in
terms of consumers and
whatnot, actually.
The most overt volley from the
sort of Pentagon was this
review in the Wall Street
Journal, which they had a
military contractor who worked
for Petraeus and General
Caldwell and was an unofficial
advisor to General McChrystal
trashed the book in the
Wall Street Journal
in the first day.
And he didn't disclose that
he actually worked
for all these generals.
So that's how they operate.
They had made attempts over
the previous year.
There had been two, actually
three Pentagon investigations
into my work.
They had made pretty serious
attempts to try to undermine
the reporting in
Rolling Stone.
I bet they felt on some level
they were making progress
there, but I think that with
the success of the book and
the fact that no one has
disputed anything in the book.
No one has ever-- has yet to
dispute any facts in the
original story.
BEN ANDERSON: Whenever you meet
anyone from the very top
guy to the very bottom guy,
nothing is off the record.
MICHAEL HASTINGS: Yeah.
BEN ANDERSON: That's
one of the first
things they tell you.
MICHAEL HASTINGS: Yeah.
You actually have to sign a
piece of paper when you go on
embed that says everything
is on the record.
And it was interesting.
Complicit in this were my
colleagues in the Washington
Pentagon Press Corps, who would
just sort of take this
bullshit that the Pentagon was
feeding them and run stories,
not calling for comments from
me, not even reading the
reports that they were quoting
from and characterizing.
So this is me complaining about
my Pentagon colleagues.
BEN ANDERSON: I think I was in
Afghanistan and someone said
you'd applied for an embed
and been denied
MICHAEL HASTINGS: Right.
BEN ANDERSON: --an embed.
That's true?
MICHAEL HASTINGS: I had already
been approved for an
embed, and I don't think
the military knew.
ISAF didn't even
know about it.
And then I was doing a talk,
and someone asked me, well,
how is your relationship
with the military?
I said, actually, I talk to
soldiers all the time, and in
fact, I'm going on an
embed next month.
They sent in, someone did a
blog post within 24 hours.
Apparently my name is in Google
Alerts somewhere.
I got a letter that said,
because of your story about
General McChrystal and the
political fallout, you're no
longer allowed to come over
unless you get like four
written sworn statements.
And it was a headquarters
thing.
BEN ANDERSON: I was reading
before the fuss it caused, you
still thought this
would make a--
MICHAEL HASTINGS: Oh,
yeah, yeah, yeah.
And I interviewed them for
hours and hours when
I was on this trip.
I knew after day two of them
that I want to write a book
about them.
BEN ANDERSON: And
they knew that?
MICHAEL HASTINGS: Yeah,
I'd make jokes
about it all the time.
And one of the interesting
things was they were sort of
holding out access.
They were playing this game with
a variety of reporters,
some big names, about who was
going to get the best access
for the book projects.
BEN ANDERSON: Because someone
was going to do the official
biography of McChrystal, which
was going to be a big seller.
MICHAEL HASTINGS: So this was
sort of the carrot they were
putting out there for me.
BEN ANDERSON: You know, they
seemed excited by the idea of
having a Rolling Stone
journalist as opposed to Wall
Street Journal, or Washington
Post, or New York Times.
McChrystal said, my kids want
me to be on the cover of
Rolling Stone.
So you feel like you've change
the course of the war in
Afghanistan or changed policy?
MICHAEL HASTINGS: Well, a lot
of this story is actually
about how counter-insurgency
doesn't work.
We can take credit for sort of
cementing that narrative or at
least making it very obvious
that this is a real problem.
Great.
BEN ANDERSON: Michael,
thank you very much.
MICHAEL HASTINGS: Later, man.