One of the first tours we've
ever done when we were a
completely unknown band just
traveling in Pete's Rav 4
across the continent, we had a
gig in Santa Rosa, which is
like in the wine valley.
And we heard that we were
going to open for
Chippendales, male strippers.
We pull up to this place, and
it's a saloon, and it's got
the flapping saloon doors.
And I just remember there being
wall-to-wall carpeting
on the stage.
PETE: "Beer" neon signs
and arcade machines.
DAVE: Yeah, it was like straight
out of Twin Peaks.
I remember they served
us spaghetti, and
there was no one there.
There was like a completely
empty room and the promoter
and his friend in one
corner and one lone
cougar by the bar.
And she had mom jeans and a
frayed leather jacket with
fringes and stuff.
And then there was
the obligatory
heavy metal sound guy.
So Pete and I were playing for
these four people in a huge
room, two drunken cougars
in front of us.
And it was really, really
awkward, and we felt super
uncomfortable.
And then Pete and I didn't
know what to
say between the songs.
And I went for it, and I
go anyways guys like--
PETE: We're sorry.
DAVE: We're sorry we're
not the Chippendales.
And then the sound guy yells
back "the Chippendales are
dead," followed by feedback.
There's so much tension
in the air.
PETE: They had a car accident.
DAVE: I think a van full of
Chippendales died or at least
got really badly injured.
It was pretty dark, and
we felt awful, and we
were like OK, um.
PETE: We just finished playing,
and we drove off into
the night, petrified.
DAVE: Well, that's one
of our crazy stories.