This week on Waterways,
Inasive Exotics in
South Florida.
Dumeril's boa,
Argentine boa,
Cockatoos! These animals are
just a few of the pets
handed over to the Florida
Fish and Wildlife
Conservation Commission
at Pet Amnesty Day.
The list is long; and the
potential danger to the south
Florida ecosystem from some
of these invaders is grave.
One particular invasive exotic
animal has captured many
media headlines: the
Burmese python.
A native to Asia,
the Burmese python
is one of the six
largest snakes in
the world, but it's just one
of an estimated three to
four hundred different
invasive plant and animal
species in south Florida and
that's just south
of Lake Okeechobee. Some
of these organisms
are known to be invasive; while
others have proven to be
invasive elsewhere, but have not
yet reached critical numbers
here.But how did these
snakes get here from Asia?
One theory postulates that
pythons were introduced in
1992 when Hurricane Andrew
tore through Homestead,
Florida, a town near the
southeastern boundary of
Everglades National Park.
The storm flattened a flimsy
storage facility for
imported snakes and other
reptiles resulting in a
release of snakes into the
surrounding ecosystem.
But a more likely theory
is that Burmese pythons in the
Everglades are a cumulative
effect of multiple pet
owners releasing their
snakes into the wild. It
became obvious really early
on that the reason we were
having problems with
constrictors out here in
Everglades National Park and
elsewhere in south Florida
was because people were,
perhaps, making poor,
uninformed decisions about
purchasing these snakes
while they were small and
then in a year when that
snake got out to seven or
eight feet or two years when
it hits double digits they
had no alternatives. To be
honest with you that
question of how these
animals arrived here in the
first place is somewhat
moot. We know that they were
here for one purpose
and one purpose only:
to be eventually sold into
the pet trade at one time or
another. These are animals
that are brought in here
specifically for ownership,
for pet ownership. In south
Florida, Burmese pythons
are considered an invasive
exotic species. Exotic
species are non-native
plants and animals
introduced intentionally or
accidentally to an area
through human activity. It
is crucial to draw a
distinction between an
exotic species and an
invasive exotic species. An
organism can be exotic and
not be invasive. An exotic
organism is not necessarily
harmful to an ecosystem; an
invasive exotic can be
disastrous. Fortunately for
us, the vast majority of
species that are introduced
into an area, exotic
species, don't turn out to
be invasive. Invasive
species are those that go
out of control; that move
beyond cultivation and get
into areas where we don't
intend them to be and begin
reproducing on the
landscape. It's that small
percentage of those
non-native invasive species
that we target in our
management efforts here in
Everglades National
Park. Invasive exotic
species are able to dominate
an ecosystem because they
often have no or few
predators. In their new
environment, there are no
mechanisms to keep the
population in check.
Invasive exotics have not
evolved to live in the
delicate balance of their
new surroundings. Thus, some
invasive species can
decimate the flora and fauna
of an entire ecosystem. The
first line of attack to keep
out invaders? Prevention.
Biologists at Everglades
National Park knew that
eradicating ALL the pythons
within the park boundary
would not solve the problem;
they still needed to
eliminate the source. So in
2006, the Don't Let It Loose
campaign was developed.
Through publications, school
posters, PSAs, billboards
and presentations,
Everglades National Park
made a concerted effort to
reach out to the community
and remind them of the
danger posed by invasive
plants and animals. As part
of the Don't Let It Loose
campaign, resource managers
decided to give people a way
to get rid of their exotic
pets in ways that did not
hurt the environment.
Starting in 2008, the Park
partnered with The Florida
Fish and Wildlife
Conservation Commission and
actually presented the first
non-native pet amnesty day
here in south Florida at
Miami Metro Zoo. And it was
a phenomenally successful
event where we offered folks
the opportunity to come out
with their animals and no
questions asked surrender
their non-domestic pets with
us. A wide range of animals
appear at Amnesty Day
events; turtles, birds and
of course snakes. Resource
managers in Everglades
National Park also knew that
they could not control
python populations or other
invasive exotics if they
could not reach beyond their
borders. So in 2006, the
Everglades Cooperative
Invasive Species Management
Area, or Everglades CISMA,
was created. This
interagency working group
operates across
administrative boundaries to
better manage invasive
species in south
Florida. We've been dealing
with some of these organisms
for literally a century or
more that they've been here
in south Florida and have
been actively managing them
for decades. And they're
species that you're familiar
with; things like melaleuca,
Brazilian pepper, Australian
pine. And the reason we
focus so much attention on
these plant species is that
they are capable of
consuming entire
acreages. While invasive
exotic animals, like the
python, get most of the
media attention, invasive
exotic plants could pose an
even greater threat. Large
areas of the Everglades that
were once dominated by
melaleuca, a native of
Australia, are now at
maintenance levels. Despite
these successes, there are
many areas of south Florida
severely impacted by
invasive exotic plants.
Brazilian pepper,imported in
the 1800s, now covers more
than 700,000 acres in
Florida and Old World
Climbing Fern which can
smother entire forests. It's
unlikely these species will
ever fully be
eradicated. We have five
success stories where our
management actions have
deliberately resulted in the
eradication of a species
from the south Florida
landscape. And now I will
tell you, again this depends
on your definition of
eradication, it's the
black-tailed jack rabbit;
the red-bellied piranha; the
giant Gambian pouch rat; the
giant African snail; really
I don't think we should
importing anything with the
word ëgiant' in its name;
but that's just me. And,
most recently a bird called
the sacred ibis. Upon
closer look at those five
successful eradication
efforts, there is one common
thread: resource managers
learned about those
invasions early on;
and they took action
immediately.
This is Tony Pernas. Tony works
for Everglades National Park
and one of his jobs is to track
an invasive exotic lizard
called the Tegu.
Well we basically, what
we want to find out
about the tegus is
their movements in the
Florida City area and
whether they're moving into
natural areas and what
habitats they're using. We
just want to find out as
much information as we can
about the tegus so we can
hopefully effectively manage
their population. Tony and
his team have caught tegus
within the boundaries of
Everglades National Park.
Today, they are collecting
images from their field
cameras in areas surrounding
the Park. So as part of an
effort to assess the
population of Argentine
black and white tegus, we
have a system or a network
of camera monitoring traps
and this is one of them that
we check periodically to see
if any tegus are present in
the area. These cameras are
triggered by motion and
infrared sensors. Using
chicken eggs as bait, the
researchers have had a lot
of success capturing images
of tegus. Really quickly,
we're just downloading the
data card and see if we had
any activity on this one
particular camera. This is a
good thing about these
cameras, because you don't
actually have to be there.
You can set up a network of
these cameras with bait so
you get a record of anything
that's visiting this site,
twenty-four hours a day. So
why are all of these exotic
species showing up in south
Florida in the first
place? We are a biological
hot spot for these
invasions. We're up there
with southern California and
Hawaii for being just a hub
of having these things
introduced; largely because
of the large amount of
commerce in the area as well
as the favorable climate
that hosts these organisms.
So we've had a lot of things
introduced, but we've been
lucky so far that we haven't
really had that one
cataclysmic species. That
was until very
recently. MUSIC Beautiful,
bold, maroon and white
striped patterns across the
body; ornate spires jutting
in all directions, regal and
striking with long pectoral
fins and prominent dorsal
spines: the lionfish. So
beautiful that people buy
them for their home
aquariums; However, these
beautiful fish now threaten
the coral reefs of
the Florida Keys.
Lionfish are an
Indo-Pacific reef fish
and the Florida Keys are far
away from their native range.
Today, however, they are
established from North
Carolina throughout the
Caribbean, and are now
invading the Gulf of
Mexico. And if you look at
the time in which they have
achieved that geographic
range, it is astounding. We
first saw lionfish off the
coast of North Carolina in
2000. That marked the
beginning of the
establishment of
lionfish. And the Bahamas
are probably the most
heavily invaded area in the
Caribbean right now. And the
density of lionfish in the
Bahamas now are among the
highest we know of anywhere
in the world. We're talking
in excess of four hundred
lionfish per hectare. That's
a lot of lionfish. They are
becoming one of the biggest
predatory fish on the reef.
A big question everyone has
is how did this invasion
start? And of course there
are a number of different
potential pathways; ballast
water from ships; natural
migration is highly unlikely
seeing that it is a long way
to the Indo-Pacific and
there have been no
populations established
along the way. But aquarium
releases are another
pathway. And that's the most
likely pathway that these
fish were introduced
from. Releases usually
happen because it gets too
big for the aquarium; it
costs too much to keep
feeding it; the person
holding the fish feels sorry
for the fish because it's a
pet and they want to release
it- sort of the ëNemo'
syndrome. Or they're moving
and they don't want to kill
the fish or give it back to
the pet store. Once
introduced to the Atlantic,
lionfish spread rapidly.
They have a superior ability
to colonize, and their life
history creates a perfect
storm of propagation,
starting with the
larvae. The long larval
duration period of lionfish
allows them to basically be
distributed anywhere in
their invaded range. So
lionfish spawned in the
Caribbean for example can
end up off of North Carolina
waters because of that
larval duration. And so that
is one of the many
characteristics of lionfish
that has facilitated or
allowed this invasion
to take hold.
Another reason lionfish have
been able to colonize so
effectively, is due to the lack
of competition for reef space
and food. For years,
top-level predators that
inhabit the Florida Keys
reefs have been
over-fished - this reduction
of native species has left a
vacant niche. And in the
case of invasive species, we
see classically that
invaders can come in and
occupy vacant niches in new
environments and can cause
real problems to those
environments. Such is the
case with lionfish and the
real concern is that if
lionfish come in and take
over that niche then how
will that impact our stock
rebuilding efforts for the
snapper grouper complex? And
how will that impact the
structure of the
reef communutities?
Lionfish competing for a food
source with economically
important species is bad;
lionfish eating economically
important species is worse.
Biologists have found Nassau
Grouper, yellowtail snapper,
and vermillion snapper in
the stomachs of lionfish in
the Atlantic. We're
concerned that as lionfish
continue to prey upon these
species and prey down the
numbers, beircause lionfish
are one of the most dominant
reef fishes now in some
coral reef environments like
in the Bahamas, that they
will then go to some of the
juveniles of economically
important species. And
that's a real concern
because increase predation
pressure on those
economically important
species could in fact hamper
stock rebuilding
efforts. Lionfish also
consume ecologically
important species, such as
parrotfish and wrasses; fish
that graze the reef and eat
algae, which competes with
coral. Lad Akins from Reef
Environmental Education
Foundation sees signs in the
Bahamas that alarm
him. They're becoming one
of the most abundant
predatory fish on the reef.
And the impacts that those
fish are having are being
seen as simply
unsustainable. They're
consuming native reef fish
at a rate far faster than
the native fish can
recover. The first
confirmed lionfish sighting
in the Florida Keys National
Marine Sanctuary was in
January 2009, and resource
managers in the Keys were
ready for it. NOAA had been
working on a lionfish
invasion response program
for nearly a decade. The
program's key
element engaging the public.
Months before the first
confirmed sighting,
sanctuary staff and their
partners at Reef
Environmental Education
Foundation and Mote Marine
Lab educated the public on
how to identify the fish and
who to call to report a
sighting. When the first
lionfish sighting report
came in January 2009, a
response team from Reef
Environmental Education
Foundation, also known as
REEF, was mobilized and
caught the culprit the very
next morning. Sanctuary
managers even issued the
fish a mock citation for
trespassing. As reef
managers anticipated,
lionfish populations spread
quickly throughout the
Florida Keys reef tract. Six
months after the first
sanctuary sighting, the
first lionfish was caught
just south of Miami, in
Biscayne National Park, the
largest marine park in the
National Park System. So
far, park staff have caught
nearly 900. Invasive
exotics are a problem in
Biscayne National Park. The
lionfish represents the
first case of a marine
invasive that we've been
concerned about. Before our
main issues had been with
plants, so this is a whole
new realm for us. As the
invasion progressed, so too
did the response. In 2009,
sanctuary managers and REEF
began training dive-shop
personnel, marine-life
collectors and researchers
on how to safely collect
lionfish. Since 2009, more
than 500 divers have been
trained to safely handle and
collect lionfish in
the Florida Keys.
Lionfish are very quick over
short distances, which make
them a challenge to catch. Many
people say, well what is the
best way to collect a
lionfish? And certainly
spearing a lionfish is an
option where spearing is
allowed. But because the
fish are so quick and have
such fast reflexes, it's
easy to miss with a spear;
even on a very close
approach. The lionfish just
moves at the very last
second and you miss. And
once the spear goes flying
by, the lionfish gets the
idea- when I see a person,
they are trying to get me
and I'm going to leave. And
it makes subsequent
collection efforts for that
fish very
difficult. Lionfish hunters
have had much more success
using nets. Using two nets,
the diver can gingerly
maneuver the nets
around the lionfish.
That doesn't mean don't use a
spear, in fact on some of the
bigger fish that may be a better
option. But especially for
small fish and a higher success
rate, the nets seem to work
very, very well. Those who
hunt lionfish need to
exercise caution. It is
highly recommended that
anyone who handles lionfish
receive training on how to
do it safely. Although the
spines on a lionfish are not
lethal, reactions to the
stings can vary and usually
include pain and swelling.
If you're stung, the best
treatment is to immerse the
wound in hot, but not
scalding water. A lionfish
is venomous. Just the spines
contain the venom. You don't
eat the spines and therefore
you are not, you are not
going to be exposed to any
of the venom. We eat the
flesh, we eat the filets and
they are not poisonous in
any way. If you haven't
been trained or you don't
feel comfortable capturing a
lionfish, the next best
thing is to mark down the
location where you saw
it. The good news about
that information is that if
we get a report, it's very
likely that fish is going to
be in the same spot when we
go out to respond. So we can
have high confidence in
being able to respond in our
early detection and rapid
response efforts.
We have been looking
at what's going
to keep them in check here.
What keeps them in check in
their native range; what
keeps them in check in their
invaded range. And what
we're finding is that few
things eat lionfish. In
feeding trials conducted fin
a lab, Morris tested whether
or not native groupers would
feed upon lionfish. In
almost every situation, the
native groupers fed upon
alternative prey when given
a choice, avoiding lionfish
even during extreme
starvation. Not to say that
nothing eats lionfish, but
we're finding that few
things eat lionfish. That
again is one of the
characteristics in their
life history that has
probably allowed them to
become so
invasive. However, there is
one predator at the top of
the food chain that could
help manage lionfish
populations, us. Lionfish is
actually a very good eating
fish; and REEF and NOAA's
Eat Lionfish campaign are
working to create demand for
lionfish. Restaurants in the
Florida Keys have already
begun serving lionfish, and
REEF has published The
Lionfish Cookbook: The
Caribbean's New
Delicacy. Encouraging
restaurants to serve them on
the menu is important. And
trying lionfish; it is a
great eating fish. It's kind
of a cross between on
hogfish and a grouper; very
delicate, light flavored
meat. So encouraging that
and eating lionfish when it
is available. It's going to
help create that market
demand. Lionfish are here
to stay, but resource
managers are working hard to
keep their numbers in check
using some novel control
strategies. In 2010, REEF
and the Florida Keys
National Marine Sanctuary
hosted three lionfish
derbies in which 660
lionfish were removed from
sanctuary waters by dive
teams competing for more
than $10,000 in cash and
prizes. More than 1200
lionfish were removed in two
derbies in 2011 and more
round-ups are being planned.
Researchers collected
samples from lionfish caught
at the derbies to learn more
about lionfish genetics,
growth and impacts to native
marine life, and tournament
attendees sampled lionfish
dishes. These events, along
with diver involvement and
lionfish consumption are
important strategies in
keeping lionfish under
control. If the lionfish
populations are going to be
kept in check, the National
Parks and the Marine
Sanctuary need your help. To
report a lionfish sighting
or capture, take note of the
location and submit a report
to www.reef.org. I don't
want to minimize that fact
that people are going to be
the controlling factor of
this. And if anyone wants to
get involved and take part,
they are really going to be
doing a lot to help protect
the oceans. Minimizing and
managing lionfish
populations is also
dependent upon eliminating
the historic source of
lionfish introductions into
the wild: people. The best
thing to do if you have an
unwanted fish is first
contact the store at which
you purchased the fish and
see if they're willing to
take it back; and many are.
If that's not feasible, you
may have other aquarium
owners that may be
interested in your fish. And
finally if you just can't do
anything else, the most
humane way to deal with the
fish is probably just freeze
it. Put it in a container,
put ice in there, the
temperature will cool off
very quickly and the fish
will just kind of shut down
and end up passing away. You
certainly don't want to
release it into the
wild. The Keys is an
especially sensitive
environment. One, because of
the status of coral reef
environments in general; the
stressors that are happening
in coral reef environments,
like coral bleaching and
others, can in fact compound
the stress felt by a
lionfish invasion. And how
these stressors all work
together and impact the fish
community and the coral
community is really unknown.
And we're sort of getting
out on virgin territory in
terms of assessing or
forecasting or predicting
the impact of an
invader like this.
Each year, at least two or three
new ìinvadersî appear in south
Florida that don't belong
here. Will these exotic
species become invasive?
What will their impact be on
the south Florida
ecosystem? When we do have
a new introduction, we count
on those five to six million
people out here to be our
twelve million eyes and
ears; our first line of
defense in letting us know
when new introductions
happen. Recently, the
Everglades Cooperative
Invasive Species Management
Area, launched a new
campaign called I've Got
One. Anybody in south
Florida who sees a plant or
animal that they don't think
is quite right it looks
different, sounds different,
they think it's an invasive
species, they can report it,
either by calling
1-888-I-GOT-ONE or online at
www.Ivegot1.org. Making
that report sets into motion
a team of responders, just
like a call to 911. A group
of individuals goes out,
verifies that report and if
management actions mandate
it, we can act quickly,
interagency, to go and quell
that population before it
expands out of control. And
that's the key  acting
quickly before a population
gets out of control. But the
local, state and federal
land management agencies
can't do it without your
help. Here's what you can
do: first and foremeost  be
a responsible pet owner. If
you have an exotic pet you
can no longer take care of,
go to myfwc.com/nonnatives
for dates and locations of
upcoming non-native pet
amnesty days. Second, learn
to identify what's native
and what's not. If you spot
a plant or animal that
shouldn't be here, like the
elusive Burmese python,
report it at www.IvegotOne.org.
To report a lionfish sighting or
capture, go to www.reef.org.
In the end, the natives
will thank you.