SIMON OSTROVSKY: We headed out
in the morning to see if we
could find some Jewish outposts
in the West Bank,
ones that were small,
unestablished, and
unauthorized.
We decided to drive to Havat
Gilad, which is known for
having clashed with both its
Palestinian neighbors as well
as the Israeli Police
force and the Army.
Israel has a love/hate
relationship with the settlers.
Nearly 40% of Israelis think the
settlers shouldn't be in
the West Bank, but their views
have never translated into
government policy.
And many blame this on the
influence of extremist
religious parties who believe
that the Palestinian
territories were promised
to them by God.
Israel's prime minister says he
wants a two-state solution,
but he's never actually said
he wants to evacuate the
settlements.
And although he recently broke
free of a coalition with the
religious parties, he's still
a strong supporter of the
settlement enterprise.
BENJAMIN NETANYAHU:
[SPEAKING HEBREW]
TRANSLATOR: There is no
government that supports or
will support settlements more
than the government I lead.
SIMON OSTROVSKY: This means
Palestinians can expect more
settler expansion and more
attention with the Israelis
and their army.
And on our way to the
settlement, we noticed a bit
of a commotion involving a bunch
of Palestinians and some
Israeli soldiers.
We saw off to the side of
the road this group of
Palestinians, but they're being
watched over by Israeli
security forces.
So we're wondering what's
going on here.
MALE SPEAKER:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
SIMON OSTROVSKY: It turns out
Israel had mobilized its army
to allow an Israeli
archaeological
team to dig up a field.
The Palestinian villagers
weren't happy because they saw
it as the first step in the
expansion of a nearby
settlement.
This is totally crazy because
this is an archaeological dig
being carried out
by the Israeli
authorities in the West Bank.
And this is how many soldiers
you need in order to protect
this archaeological
excavation.
But what's even more nuts is
that Palestinians are doing
the manual labor.
So the Israelis have hired
Palestinians to do an illegal
excavation in the Palestinian
territories.
MALE SPEAKER:
SIMON OSTROVSKY: What
is this place?
What is the significance
of this site?
But they're on the wrong side
of the green line for doing
archaeological digs.
No?
I mean I'm just asking
if that's correct.
MALE SPEAKER:
SIMON OSTROVSKY: I don't know.
I don't know.
MALE SPEAKER: No
picture today.
SIMON OSTROVSKY: So the soldiers
really didn't want me
to talk to the Palestinians who
are apparently upset about
this archaeological dig
taking place here.
And the reason they're upset is
because a lot of times when
the Israelis do an
archaeological dig, they then
build a sort of memorial around
any Jewish artifacts
that they find.
And it becomes a place of
pilgrimage for the settlers
who come here.
And then, bit by bit, the
Palestinians feel that they're
losing even more land.
It turns out the guy who was
leading the excavation, and
who casually shrugged us off,
was Michael Ben-Ari, an
ultra-right member of Israel's
parliament who lived in the
settlement across the road.
And Ben-Ari had a history of
questionable behavior.
Besides openly advocating for
the departure of Palestinians
from the West Bank, the US
refused to grant him a
visitor's visa because he'd
been included on the State
Department's Terrorist
Watch List.
Oh, and he's also been known to
post heartwarming photos on
his Facebook page, like this
one, which shows him and a
buddy relaxing on a couch
confiscated from an Arab
family that had just been
evicted from their home.
Unfortunately, the soldiers
were pressuring us
to leave the site.
So we got back on the road and
continued our trek to Havat
Gilad, which is known
for attracting
its own set of problems.
Besides it being a hot spot for
violence, Israel is known
to come in and routinely
bulldoze
these illegal outposts.
But the settlers are always more
than happy to rebuild.
So we were curious to see what
shape the place was in.
When we arrived, we came upon
two teenagers who were
building a house from
the ground up.
MALE SPEAKER:
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[MUSIC PLAYING]