Carolina, any Southern state,
Daytona Beach might as well be
the south of France
for these people.
SEAN BISHOP: The way I've always
described Daytona Beach
to people is it reminds me of
somebody who fell in love with
a hooker and is trying to
turn her into a lady.
She's always going
to be a whore.
On a good spring break night,
we'll have well over 100 girls
dancing here.
NADIA: By the time midnight
hits, this place is crazy.
SEAN BISHOP: At first, when we
started letting the spring
breakers in, the girls looked at
them like they were a bunch
of young kids without any money
until they find out they
were spending money.
And now they embrace it.
And the unique thing about it
is if you look at the age
group, our average dancer
is a girl in her
young 20s, late teens.
NADIA: I've had girls say
they've walked out of here
with $2,000.
I mean, crazy, off-the-hook
amounts.
What happens in Daytona
stays in Daytona.
DAVE: Daytona is just the Vegas
of Florida, because it's
so trashy as it is that people
come down here for spring
break, leave all their
morals at home.
SEAN BISHOP: You go to bed one
night, and you wake up and
there's an extra 200,000
people in town.
So the place just explodes.
MATT: It's just a bunch of
people who came to one place
with good weather to just get
hammered and have sex.
RANDY PHILLIPS: Dirtona
Beach, man.
That's the name that sticks.
That is Dirtona.
MATT: If you spend five minutes
in a hotel room during
spring break, you have to wonder
all the atrocities that
are going on.
All the hotel room
doors are open.
There's a beer bong in every
room, people having sex as
loudly as possible, belongings
everywhere.
Like people just left
their shit, and
they're down on the beach.
There could be a whale that just
washed up on the beach
and is decaying and
smells like shit.
If there's people around it,
they'll flock to it and
they'll get hammered by it.
RANDY PHILLIPS: These two girls
were totally going at it
right on one of my mop sinks.
And I literally walked in.
I was like, are you
women serious?
Do you realize what I
put in that sink?
And they're totally going
to town on each other.
MATT: The sweetest girls
back home are the
craziest girls down here.
You could definitely have at
least two girls every night.
SEAN BISHOP: The whole "Girls
Gone Wild" thing started here
in Daytona Beach, Florida.
I mean, if you look at it, it
is the perfect environment.
MATT: These girls don't
care what's going on.
You can pass them to your
buddies even though they know
what has happened.
DAVE: It's a really great town
to be a drug dealer, because
everyone's on drugs.
Everyone's a customer.
As a spring breaker in Daytona
Beach, you're looking to get
those things that you don't
think you can get at home.
Recently, it has been more
meth, ecstasy, coke.
Pills are really big now.
And the pills are cheap down
here, so they know
they can get them.
Mostly you can sell them
whatever you want.
Ripping them off is real easy.
Quality doesn't have
to be there.
Sometimes you can just take
the money and run.
Sometimes you can give them a
bad bag, a lot of cut, bad
weed, tell them it's
good weed.
Hook them real easy, because
they don't have a lot of
options when they're
on vacation.
SCOTT EDWARDS: Fifteen or 20
years ago, spring break would
bring about $100 million
into this economy.
We have MTV.
We had the Miss Hawaiian Tropic
International pageant.
STEVE PENDLEND: We had 250,000
to 300,000 kids for an
eight-week period of time.
-We would do, I would say, on
an average, anywhere from 30
to 45 tattoos a day.
It was really good for
everything, all the way down
to gas stations and
restaurants.
I don't see where all
the problem--
what they tried to say was
such a big problem.
-So everybody thinks, oh, it's
spring break, it's party time.
In reality, there's another
element that
comes into this city.
They're out there
selling drugs.
They're looking to do rapes.
They're looking to
do burglaries.
hurt somebody.
DAVE: There's nothing really
to do but do drugs, so it's
right up someone's alley
if they want to get
fucked up all the time.
MATT: If this was mid-October,
the owners would
just kill us all.
But it's during spring break,
so they just let the
ridiculousness happen.
SCOTT EDWARDS: We are marketing
to America's best
and brightest young people.
I don't see what
the problem is.
RANDY PHILLIPS: They want to
make it this pristine, clean,
clear, no vacationers, no
whatever, family town.
STEVE PENDLEND: They didn't
replace it with any business.
SCOTT EDWARDS: The newspaper did
an expose about two months
ago in talking about all the
closed businesses on A1A.
And I think they
counted up 205.
RANDY PHILLIPS: I hate to use
the word blight, but it has
become a blight.
Look at the cityscape
around you.
It literally looks like
a bomb went off.
This town could be
something again.
I want it to change
for the better.
I want to go back, not
necessarily to what it was,
but I definitely want it to
aspire to be something better.
But Daytona's got that unique
quality about it.
SCOTT EDWARDS: The college
students really took a bad rap
in a lot of ways.
We are still a spring
break destination.
DAVE: More spring breakers are
starting to come back.
Every year there's
more and more.
SEAN BISHOP: Embrace the kids.
Come down.
Let them have fun.
I mean, that's what this
town's known for.
MATT: If spring break was to
ever class it up, I think it
would lose the element
of freedom.
[MUSIC PLAYING]