Television News has the story. TOM CLARKE:
He's behind the two highest-grossing movies
of all time, but this was James Cameron's
most ambitious production yet. MAN: Above
all, have fun. JAMES CAMERON, filmmaker: Have
fun, exactly. TOM CLARKE: He set off in the
middle of the night, but it makes no difference
when you're heading to the darkest place on
Earth. Once in the water, the sub turns vertical
to drop like a torpedo to the bottom. Sinking
like a stone, it still took James Cameron
two-and-a-half-hours to reach the bottom.
His descent took him straight past the depth
of the English Channel at just 180 meters.
He wasn't even halfway when he passed the
depth of the Titanic at 3,700 meters. That's
more than two miles. And his journey into
the abyss even took him beyond the height
of a submerged Everest, before he finally
reached the bottom of the trench, 11 kilometers,
nearly seven miles deep. He was three hours
at the bottom and an hour coming back. So
what exactly did the film director see? Well,
you will have to wait for the 3-D movie being
released some time in the near future. But
the ocean's deepest spot might not be a blockbuster.
MAN: You did it, man! JAMES CAMERON: We all
did it. This is a vast, you know, frontier
down there that's going to take us a while
to understand that -- the impression to me
was that it was a very lunar, very desolate
place, very isolated. My feeling was one of
complete isolation from all of humanity. TOM
CLARKE: It may be featureless, but these videos
from British researchers using robotic subs
have recently revealed remarkable animals,
like these snailfish on a giant shrimp-like
arthropod from four miles down. Who knows
what Cameron's team might find. JON COPLEY,
marine biologist, University of Southampton:
There's always a very good chance of new species.
We have already heard that Jim Cameron has
seen some sea cucumbers down there, very small
ones. So it will be fascinating. He is going
to go back and collect some samples, we hope.
We should get to see what is down there. When
we're deeper than two miles -- and that's
more than half our planet is covered by water
that is two miles deep -- there's a 50-50
chance that we find new species. TOM CLARKE:
James Cameron admits diving the Mariana Trench
is a boyhood dream fulfilled. What lurks beneath
captured the public's imagination ever since
that record dive in 1960. And now it's attracting
some other big fish too. Richard Branson and
Google's Eric Schmidt are now building deep-diving
subs as well. The abyss, so far James Cameron's
private domain, is about to become the new
frontier, provided you're rich enough. GWEN
IFILL: In addition to the 3-D movie, Cameron
plans to direct a National Geographic special
using the footage he gathered in yesterday's
deep dive. hj<{ hj<{ hj<{ gdj<{ :pj<{ urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:smarttags
PlaceType urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:smarttags
PlaceName urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:smarttags
place GWEN IFILL: Finally tonight: a voyage
deep into the sea Normal Microsoft Office
Word GWEN IFILL: Finally tonight: a voyage
deep into the sea Title Microsoft Office Word
Document MSWordDoc Word.Document.8