a million flights,and could easily feed
the entire british population through its
gates every year.For Heathrow to get this big
,it took a series of major technological
innovations.We have lined up seven
landmark airports,historic giants of aviation.
At the heart of each one lies a technology
that allowed airports to feed ever more people
through their gates,safely,quickly and comfortably
One by one travelling up the scale we will reveal the
incredible stories behind these airports
and the inventions that transformed them into
sprawling city-like structures.Seven ingenious
leaps forward that enabled airports to evolve
from big to bigger into the worlds biggest
Heathrow Airport,Britain's gateway to the world
and a huge powerhouse for the country's economy
,and now it will get even bigger,T5 an immense new terminal
that cost over 8 billion dollars to build is about to open.
Lead Architect Mike Davis can't wait "It's going to
be fantastic,it's 19 years of work all going to come into
frutition when the first plane comes through.  "
T5 has three huge terminal buildings,assembled
from 80,000 tons of steel.The main terminal is a true
skyscraper of a terminal,reaching 40 metres
into the sky."This is a building of immense complexity
we had to satisfy the needs of 43 different groups of people
,to make sure that this building got a tick in the box
from everybody,and you are talking about major systems
like passenger check-in and you got the retail and various
passenger services.We got three big railway stations
under this building,all of that has to be co-ordinated
together.T5 will process 30 million passengers a year.
It takes Heathrow's capacity to nearly a 100 million
travellers.To understand how Heathrow became this busy,
we need to go back in time,and look at how airports begin.
The first big breakthrough comes with a small
airport just outside London.Before it can get any bigger,
Croydon airport must make the sky above it safer.
In 1920 Croydon is the main airport in London aviation
is young and navigation primitive."Flying was really
the pilot made use of landmarks such as coastlines,
rivers,large towns,roadways.But the Mark I eyeball
can't always be trusted.On the 7th of April 1922 a French
pilot heading out of Paris airport drops below the clouds
to get his bearings.Scanning the ground for landmarks
he doesn't realise that a cargo plane from Croydon
is approaching on exactly the same heading.The first
collision in the history of civil aviation kills seven
people.It was an accident waiting to happen."Pilots would
be looking out to see the road they were following,.
they were looking over to the side,the road was here
,the other jet was looking maybe the same side,the road
and they were really over the top of the road.
To stop such disasters from ever happening again,Croydon
invents a clever new technology.Every aircraft heading
towards the airport sends out a radio burst.
A radio receiver at Croydon then measures the angle of this
signal which reveals where the plane is coming from.
" I'm getting a call which is telling me that Croydon
has a bearing of 140,So I'm taking out the mouse
and placing it on a bearing of 140 " .But a plane's bearing isn't
enough to pinpoint it's precise position,so Croydon
installs two more radio stations and their recievers
lock on as well." Huramenel now calling they have a
bearing of 195,and just here Lim-Lim have a bearing of 230
I can see now that the strings cross at Haistings, the pilot
is over Haistings." Once Croydon knows the plane's
coordinates they can safely guide it to the airport.
This is the birth of Air Traffic Control.In 1921 Croydon
Airport had about 60 flights per week,today Heathrow
pushes in to upto a 100 flights per hour.Air Traffic Control
guides planes out of the sky and hands them over to
the Ground Traffic Controllers,they need to be able to see
every single tail fin on the tarmac with their own
eyes.This is where the construction of Terminal 5 creates a
problem.The T5 buildings are so tall  that controllers
can't see the planes at the far end.They need a new
taller control tower right in the middle of the airport,
one of the busiest crossroads at Heathrow,turning  it into a
construction site would cause chaos for the aircraft.
The only option is to build the new control tower
on the edge of the airport and move it into position
in one piece.But the tower weighs nearly a 1000 tons
moving it onto the airport takes months of careful planning
there is no margin for error." It was a great challenge
to do it because we had to do it without stopping airline
operations,not a single aircraft should be rescheduled.
We decided one great friday evening to wheel it across
the airport and we took the fence down and rolled it out
on to the apron . " Just after Heathrow shuts down,the tower
begins it 2km journey across the airport,balanced on
three transporters designed to carry the space shuttle.
The crew must deliver their precious cargo before the airport
reopens in 5 hours." It was literally going 2 miles an hour
so one point on that friday night,it became the fastest
building in the UK.Once safely in place over its foundations
engineers jack the tower 87 metres up into the sky.
Now air traffic controllers at Heathrow have a tower
that lets them do their job without T5 getting in the way.
Air Traffic Control  technology allows more planes
to reach airports safely.But as airports become cluttered
with aircraft,it gets more difficult for passengers to board
and disembark safely.For London Gatwick to take on
20,000 passengers,they need to bring planes
and passengers closer together,yet keep them apart.
In the 1920s Air travel is only for the super rich.
But conditions at the airfields are from first-class.
" They had to walk across a windy apron to reach the plane
,so it was a fairly sort of primitive kind of activity.
And it wasn't consistent with the pampered rich."
Boarding planes isn't just inconvenient,it can be downright
dangerous.Propellers and human bodies don't mix.
But in 1933 a young man has an idea.Morris Jackerman
wants to offfer passengers at Gatwick Airport something
revolutionary,a terminal,but he struggles to find the right
shape for the building." You could imagine that he was umm...
he was playing with all the variables and he  was thinking
about the way the aircraft would position themselves
taxiing in,and although that positioning of aircraft
was good from the passengers point of view
it wasn't good for the movement of the aircraft
because if that aircraft is in position,that aircraft
can't move.If that aircraft is in position that
aircraft can't move.And there's wasted space there
he just couldn't make the square work an as far
the said,you are going around in circles aren't
you?.And it was then that he had that eureka
moment that the circle is the solution and here is the
end-product,still standing today,the beehive at Gatwick."
Jackerman's design is revolutionary,its shape is ideal
for both passenger and plane.Each aircraft can quickly
and independently taxi to its gates to unload,refuel
and load up again.And inside the Beehive
passengers wait in comfort,until telescopic canopy's
take them right to the aircraft door.The beehive is the first