Sitting in a big white room alone
Tilt my head back, feel the tears fall down
Close my eyes to see in the dark
I feel young, broken, so scared
I don't wanna be here anymore
I wanna be somewhere else normal and free, like I used to be
But I have to stay in this big white room
With little old me
I'm going crazy, I'm losing my mind
I'm going crazy, in this big white room of mine
Sitting in a big white room alone
Close the door don't want the pain to come in
I clench my fist and try to stay strong
I cry, feel sick my hearts beating b-b-b-b-beating beating out of control
Can I run, run faster than you
I wanna feel my body again, feel the wind in my hair - yeah
But I have to stay in this big white room
Cuz' no one else cares no
I'm going crazy, I'm losing my mind
I'm going crazy, in this big white room of mine
Everybody's looking at me, everybody's staring at me
What do I do now - smile, yeah, yeah
I'm going crazy, I'm losing my mind
I'm going crazy, in this big white room of mine