Whilst here, the Lebanese
version of "Dolce Vita" is in
full swing.
And exactly how dolce
can vita be?
Well, just you watch.
[MOVIE MUSIC OVERLAID
ON STREET SOUNDS]
SHANE: We're going from where
our neighborhood is, in Hamra,
and we're going to Burj
El-Barajneh camp to see our
buddies who we left
some cameras with.
AHMAD: We can see everything
in the camp.
SHANE: Everything that's here.
AHMAD: Actually, it's dangerous
for us to be here.
SHANE: Why?
The power.
AHMAD: The power and
electricity.
SHANE: Really?
AHMAD: In the winter,
every day we
have electric explosion.
SHANE: Really?
When we returned to Beirut, we
found that Ahmad had not only
been using the camera, but had
actually shot a short film.
It's about a one-armed
pool player who
grows up in the camps.
Last time we saw you was last
year, just after the war.
And we give you a camera.
So tell us what happened.
[SPEAKING LEBANESE]
SHANE: How did he
lose his hand?
Three years old.
And he lost it in the war?
[SPEAKING LEBANESE]
SHANE: Are there are a lot of
Palestinian filmmakers that
came out of the camps?
Ahmad also found another
use for the camera.
Because it's nearly impossible
for him to get a job, he used
the camera to shoot weddings
and engagement parties,
birthday parties,
and get paid.
But it also turned out to be
training, because his next
project is a love story
set in the camps.
So just to reiterate, you're
living in one of the most
hopeless, depressing, fucked
up places on earth, and the
film you're dying to make
is a love story.
[UPBEAT ROCK MUSIC]