right now.
Catastrophic, historic, unthinkable -- those
are some of the words being used to describe
the impact of the storm named Sandy that hit
the U.S. on Monday. Now, when that happened,
when it made landfall, it wasn`t a hurricane,
it was technically a post tropical storm,
because its energy was coming from a different
source. Whatever you want to call it, Sandy
was very, very dangerous. Flooding brought
on by Sandy`s wind and rain and the storm
surge, the waves that were created along the
coast. Some towns in New Jersey were under
four or five feet of water. Floodwaters rushed
into New York City subway tunnels as well.
Sandy is being blamed for at least 30 deaths
across the U.S. And this -- that`s a power
transformer that blew in New York. Nearly
8 million people lost power because of Sandy,
and some officials said it could be out for
days.
That kind of gives you an idea about how strong
Sandy`s winds were. And so does this -- the
smoke you are seeing there, the front of the
building just collapsed, apparently from the
wind. You might wonder how wind can be that
strong. It could have something to do with
where this thing hit. Tom Foreman breaks down
the science.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
TOM FOREMAN, CNN CORRESPONDENT: As the winds
of Hurricane Sandy have spread out over hundreds
of miles, the estimate of how much damage
they can do has also grown to $7 billion.
How is that possible from wind alone? Well,
we`ve sliced up Hurricane Erin (ph) here into
layers to show you what -- look at the bottom
down there. You see all that red -- that`s
where the wind is the most intense. As you
move up in the storm, it becomes less intense
once you get several miles in the air, but
all of the tallest buildings on the East Coast
fit right down in that red zone, and in a
strange way, they actually make the storm
more ferocious for the people who are living
there.
Let me show you why. If you have an air flow
passing over an empty field or perhaps low
buildings, it can do so largely unimpeded.
But once you introduce something like New
York City to the equation here, you change
everything, because now the air has to speed
up to get around all those buildings and maintain
its air flow to go over those buildings, and
that magnifies three things that are very
dangerous about hurricane winds. First of
all, it makes them more explosive. In aerospace
terms, whenever an airflow hit`s a square
or rectangular object, it creates what`s called
turbulent flow. In simple layman`s terms,
that means the air becomes all roiled up and
it starts pounding against itself and against
other objects, and it simply becomes more
violent.
Secondly, in hurricanes, you are always talking
about sustained winds, winds that will continue
not for a few minutes, but for hour after
hour, grinding away, looking for weak spots
around doors or windows or the cornices of
roofs. And thirdly, you are talking about
directional wind. That means it`s always going
to be attacking from the same direction. So
if it finds that weak spot, it`s going to
exploit it, because it just keeps yanking
away at it without letting up. All of that
comes together in this terrible witch`s brew
for the cities of the East Coast in the winds
of Sandy.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: With storms like Sandy, you expect strong
winds and heavy rain, but the different effects
of this storm are almost unbelievable. Water.
We mentioned flooding in New York subway.
This is what it looked like. And those water
levels won`t go down on their own. That water
is going to have to be pumped out.
Fire. This one broke out in a neighborhood
in New York. Sandy`s winds helped it spread.
At least 80 homes were destroyed by the flames.
Snow. Sandy spawned a blizzard in West Virginia.
Parts of Maryland and North Carolina were
hit with heavy snow as well. This is what
part of the Jersey shore looked like yesterday.
Rows of houses damaged or destroyed by the
storm. And along flooded roads, rescue crews
are out in boats and trucks. Some people had
to wait on their roof for rescuers to arrive.
Relief organizations are working to get help
to the victims of this storm. You can help
them too. Go to the Spotlight section at cnnstudentnews.com
and look for the "impact your world" link
to find out how.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
MITT ROMNEY, REPUBLICAN PRESIDENTIAL CANDIDATE:
I want you to be able to get a job. I know
what it takes to get this economy going.
BARACK OBAMA, PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES
OF AMERICA: The most important thing we can
do is to make sure that we are creating job
in this country, but not just jobs, good paying
jobs.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: You`ve heard Governor Romney and President
Obama talk a lot about the economy in this
presidential campaign. There is a good reason
for that. For many voters, it is the most
important issue in the election. It`s also
what we are looking at today as we continue
our series on the candidates positions.
Part of Governor Romney`s plan is to cut taxes
for all Americans. He would also lower the
tax rate for businesses. The governor`s campaign
site says that cutting taxes will help the
economy grow. For example, companies will
have more money to hire workers. Romney`s
also talked about making the federal government
smaller in order to reduce government spending.
President Obama also wants to lower the tax
rate for businesses. For most individual Americans,
he said that he wants to keep the tax rate
where it is. But he wants to raise taxes on
wealthy Americans in order to help generate
more revenue for the federal government. The
president also wants to create incentives,
rewards for companies that bring jobs back
to America.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Today`s "Shoutout" goes
out to Mr. Butler`s social studies classes
at Atlantis Academy in Coral Springs, Florida.
Ichiro Suzuki, Hideki Matsui and Yu Darvish
are known for playing what sport? Here we
go, it is basketball, badminton, billiards
or baseball? You`ve got three seconds, go!
They are all Major League Baseball players
who were born in Japan. That`s your answer,
and that`s your "Shoutout."
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: All right, so in the majors they are
probably used to playing in front of sell-out
crowds or near cell out crowds, but back in
their home country, some Japanese teams are
struggling with half empty stadiums. So how
do you get people to come out and fill the
seats and to root, root, root for the home
team? Well, the Yokohama Bay Stars have some
unique ideas. Alex Zolbert steps up to the
plate with details.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
ALEX ZOLBERT, CNN ANCHOR: It is arguably Japan`s
most popular sport, a national pastime. And
this is the league`s least successful team
this year. In fact, the Bay Stars, who hail
from Yokohama just south of Tokyo, have sat
in the league`s basement for the past four
years. Which helps explain all the empty seats
at one of their final home games this season.
But the team has been testing some clever
ideas to try to change that. But in the tough
Japanese economy, how about discounts for
fans who are trying to pay off their mortgage?
Or offering refunds if you weren`t satisfied
with the team`s performance? A few fans lined
up after a game even though the Bay Starts
won. Some of the gimmicks are the idea of
team president, June Ikeida (ph), a 36-year
old with a background in advertising and marketing.
He tells me, it`s all in effort to entice
folks who aren`t die hard baseball fans. How
about a side show of pro-wrestling?
This stadium holds about 30,000 people. The
average attendance this year was just over
half of that. And while the boss recognizes
the gimmicks might help, what will help the
most is to win more games.
Alex Zolbert, CNN, Yokohama, Japan.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: Well, next stop today, we have a story
about Chy Johnson. She is a sophomore at Quinn
Creek High in Arizona. She was born with a
brain disorder, and she said she was bullied
because of that. One day, Chy`s mother emailed
a family friend to ask for help. That friend
was Carson Jones. He`s the starting quarterback
in the school`s undefeated football team.
Carson heard what was happening and decided
to tackle the bullying head on. Now from the
first bell to the last one, Carson and some
of his team mates hang out with Chy. They
keep an eye on her, they make sure she is
not getting bullied. One of the players says,
it feels good to know that they can help make
someone else`s high school experience a positive
one. Great stuff.
Finally today, we are checking out some of
your I Report pumpkin projects. Bats on Halloween?
Sure. Bat-man? Well, he can symbolize a dark
knight. How about this ghoul climbing out
of the grave? Scary enough to make anyone
bury his head under a blanket? Old-time truck,
piles of pumpkins, perfect symbol of the season,
but hey, let`s bail on that, so we can check
out these class`s pet project. Seriously,
it`s their pet. That`s the tooth. And Becca
(ph) High gets special prays because they
love carving pumpkins. And we love that they
do.
That was awesome. Big thanks to everybody
who`s sent in I Reports. Goodness gracious,
ghost (ph), we`re out of time for today, so
we`ll look forward to seeing you tomorrow
on CNN STUDENT NEWS.