-[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
LELE SAVERI: At the beginning
of 2008, world news outlets
were flooded with images
of garbage piles in
the streets of Naples.
The newly reelected premier,
Silvio Berlusconi, made
countless TV appearances,
personally picking up trash
and promising to resolve
the situation.
Naples and the entire Campania
region had been officially
declared an environmental crisis
over 14 years ago.
The garbage piles were just a
current distraction from the
real emergency--
almost 8 million tons of rubbish
stockpiled throughout
the region, illegal toxic waste
dumps, a serious human
health crisis.
And behind it all, the largest
criminal organization in
Italy, the Neapolitan Camorra.
We're in Naples now, and we're
about to meet Michele Buonomo,
who's the president of
Legambiente Campania.
Legambiente's the
most important
environmental-protection
group.
-[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
LELE SAVERI: They're doing this
protest because they want
to fill up this empty space in
a mountain with just rubbish,
without doing anything to them,
not burning or nothing.
-[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
LELE SAVERI: Senor Montano.
LUIGI MONTANO: Ciao.
LELE SAVERI: Hi.
[ITALIAN].
-[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
LELE SAVERI: We're standing
right on top of the highest
legal garbage dump
in Campania.
[EXHALES HEAVILY]
It stinks really bad.
-[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
LELE SAVERI: That
is ridiculous.
This is a joke.
We're not allowed in.
We need to have an
interview there.
We'll be late for
the interview.
But we're not allowed to go
through the main square of
Naples, because Cavalieri
Berlusconi made the head of
the state-- and to go across
from that building to that
building to have our
press conference.
So they decide to
stop everything.
The guys just told us that the
only way of going to the other
side to have this interview
would be to go all the way
around the city.
It would take us about 40
minutes to walk around for a
one minute walk, just to have
a press conference and tell
everyone who's going to
deal with the rubbish.
Quite bizarre.
-[SPEAKING ITALIAN]