today is how Congress and the president sort
of backed away from the edge.
It came down to a vote in the U.S. House of
Representatives on Tuesday night, the Senate
had already passed a temporary fix to the
fiscal cliff, but the House had to approve
that plan and for the president to sign it
and to make it law. When the votes were counted,
representatives have voted 257 to 161 to approve
the plan. It`s not perfect. Many lawmakers
don`t like it. For one thing, it does not
reduce government spending, something that
will need to get done in order to reduce the
debt. It does raise taxes on families that
make more than $450,000 a year. It`s the first
federal income tax hike since 1993. And it
does put off some other tax raises and automatic
government spending cuts that would have happened
if no agreement had been made, but if the
government had done this for a grade, it wouldn`t
be an A, it wouldn`t really be an F. It`d
be an "Incomplete." Christine Romans explains
why.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
CHRISTINE ROMANS, CNN CORRESPONDENT: Part
of the fiscal cliff was averted, but there
are two big issues not addressed in the bill:
the spending cuts or the sequester, that issue
was delayed two months. Two, there`s nothing
about the debt ceiling in this bill either.
Treasury Secretary Tim Geithner says the government
has officially reached its limit, its $16.394
debt limit. Some analysts are warning that
the gridlock in Washington is what could cause
as even worse, more problems. Steven Englander,
CitiFX said, quote "The process was so chaotic
and the outcome so unsatisfactory, that we`re
likely to see a further U.S. downgrade at
some point. All this drama in Washington could
well put the breaks on Wall Street. Christine
Romans, CNN New York.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Is this legit? Article
1 of the U.S. Constitution focuses on the
powers of the presidency.
Not true. Article 1 is all about the powers
of Congress.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: There is new Congress in town, the 113th
Congress of the United States, it`s getting
started today. All 435 voting members of the
U.S. House of Representatives were elected
last November. Representatives serve two year
terms, and they are chosen in even numbered
years. The more people a state has living
in it, the more representatives it has in
Congress. And in the 113th Congress the House
is controlled by Republicans who hold 234
seats, Democrats have 201 seats. Things are
different in the Senate. There are 100 Senators
there, two for each state, and they serve
six year terms, so only about a third of their
seats were up for election in November. Democrats
have controlled the Senate with 53 seats,
Republicans have 45 seats, and two seats are
Independent, though the Independents usually
vote with the Democrats. Some of the top priorities
of the new Congress: a longer term solution
of the fiscal cliff as we talked about, getting
federal money to victims of Hurricane Sandy.
And generally, figuring out what the government
spends money on.
With Democrats in control of the Senate and
the presidency and Republicans in control
of the House, you can see it`s going to take
compromise to get legislation passed.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: Time for "The Shoutout.":
which of these documents is the oldest? If
you think you know it, then shout it out!
Is it the Dead Sea scrolls? Gutenberg Bible,
Declaration of Independence or Beowulf? You`ve
got three seconds, go!
The Dead Sea scrolls date back to the 3rd
Century, B.C. Which makes them the oldest
of those documents. That`s your answer and
that`s your "Shoutout."
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: The Dead Sea scrolls were discovered
in caves between Israel and Jordan. Many of
the manuscripts appear on parchment, those
are animal skins used for writing in ancient
times. A new project is bridging thousands
of years of technology, bringing the scrolls
to your classroom, or to your living room.
Sara Sidner shows you how this biblical and
ancient texts can be as close as a click.
(BEGIN VIDEOTAPE)
SARA SIDNER, CNN CORRESPONDENT: The painstaking
process to preserve a tiny piece of history,
more than 2,000 years old. In this delicate
pieces of ancient parchment you can see the
text of the Ten Commandments, Genesis, Psalms,
many of the writings that make up the Bible,
as well as other non- biblical books. These
are some of the thousands of fragments of
the Dead Sea scrolls found by a Bedouin shepherd
in caves 65 years ago near the Dead Sea and
what is now the West Bank.
PHINA SHOR, ISRAEL ANTIQUITIES AUTHORITY:
These are all manuscripts written 2,000 years
ago at the time when both Judaism and Christianity
were formalizing as we know them today.
SIDNER: There are only five conservators on
the planet allowed to handle these fragments,
which when pieced together reveal some of
the holiest and well-known texts of the world.
Now they are available for anyone to sea and
study online. A joint project between Google
and Israel`s Antiquity Authority. The five
year process included photographing thousands
of fragments, 28 times each front and back
using different colors of the spectrum and
NASA technology to reveal previously undetectable
writings.
SHAI HALEVI, DEAD SEA SCROLLS PHOTOGRAPHER:
Then I`m getting older exposures on the screen,
and I`m combining them all into one multispectral
image.
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: We`re going to integrate
at this point the infrared image of this part,
exactly this part, and no secret writings
are going to be revealed by the infrared image.
SIDNER: In the 1950s, the scrolls were photographed
and last year, five of the 900 manuscripts
were put on the Internet. But for this project,
nearly all 900 manuscripts are online and
1000 of the fragments have been enhanced by
the new technology. Controversy has followed
these scrolls from the day they were discovered.
Arguments bound over who actually wrote them
and who owns them. Now that they are available
to the entire world for crowd sourcing, who
knows what new controversies or perhaps answers
can be uncovered in these ancient writing.
Sara Sidner, CNN, Jerusalem.
(END VIDEOTAPE)
AZUZ: Fascinating stuff.
Have you ever heard of Havard Rugland? Probably
not. You might have seen his work on Youtube.
He is a sort of trick shot champion, but with
a foot in football instead of a basket in
basketball. He says nothing about what you
are seeing here is faked, though some of the
shots did take more than one try. The video
went viral on Youtube and the coolest part
besides his fantastic foot was an email he
got about it. It was from the NFL.
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)
HAVARD RUGLAND, NORWEGIAN KICKER: I`ve got
(inaudible) and things started to calm down
a little bit, and maybe a weak or so, I got
an email from New York Jets. The email asked
me - and told me that they liked what they
were seeing and I should contact them if I
would be interested in the tryout with the
New York Jets. I, of course, thought, these
were some of my friends joking around.
(END VIDEO CLIP)
AZUZ: But it wasn`t. So Rugland tried out
with the Jets just before Christmas. He says
it went well and that he`s got another tryout
coming up. If he eventually makes the team,
we`ll all get a kick out of it.
Right on our blog over the Christmas break,
we asked what you think is the best kind of
gift to give. Katie says, the best present
to give is love. Whether it`s your dad coming
home from Iraq and you get to see him or simply
giving your mom a hug.
From Kaitlin, "I think the best gift to give
or get is quality time with your family."
Cole says "A good gift doesn`t have to be
expensive or come off a list. A legitimate
good gift is something you put time and effort
into to make someone happy."
Jahnavi thinks a holiday carol would brighten
people`s days. Her best friend "always sings
"Rudolph, the red-nosed reindeer," and it
makes everybody forget about their stress
and join in with the caroling.
From Brynn, "I think that the best to give
is happiness and joy and you could give some
cookies to Santa and give carrots to the reindeer.
The reindeer like carrots."
And finally, Jace says, "Our country is so
focuses on the "What will I get or what will
I receive" and it doesn`t get the full meaning
of the holidays. That full meaning is to be
with the family and people you care about,
not those pointless gifts.
AZUZ: Well, before we go today, a common new
year`s resolution is to trim down a little
bit. This wouldn`t help. It`s one Australian
shop`s way to ring in the New Year with some
new weight. The Brobdingnagian burger bangs
the scales at 220 pounds, it weighs more than
I do, and it`s not just chuck that`s up on
it, it`s fried eggs, bacon, it`s chickens,
yeah, more than one. The usual stuff, too,
like lettuce, tomatoes and of course, some
really big buns. Vegetarians might have beef
with the whole idea, and there will be plenty
of meat to their argument. Eating too much
would leave even the carnivores grounded,
though no one would have to ask where is the
beef?
It`s not too rare that we cook up these many
puns on the show, though they are pretty well
done, I have to say. We`ll be glad to stack
up more news for you tomorrow, if you let
us. For CNN STUDENT NEWS, I`m Carl Azuz.