ANTWUAN DIXON: Sorry, officer.
MALE SPEAKER: [SINGING]
ANTWUAN DIXON: Hey,
what's up, nigger?
MALE SPEAKER: [SINGING]
ANTWUAN DIXON: Fuck this now.
We goin' too far.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
ANTWUAN DIXON: No,
I don't get it.
SHANE HEYL: Numerous times,
numerous times.
I mean, we were on that
one trip, and
Twuan had gone to jail.
We get him that night
or the next day.
We have 24 hours.
He's back in.
You know, so that's twice
in three days.
Wrong place, wrong time.
OFFICER: What're we
talking about?
ANTWUAN DIXON: All right.
MALE SPEAKER: What'd
the cops say?
ANTWUAN DIXON: This is
my nigger right here.
Huh?
Oh, they said, fucking pull
your shit out and
you're the man, bye.
I mean, pretty much
what I know.
MALE SPEAKER: Second
cop incident today.
ANTWUAN DIXON: Fuck, dude.
Right?
What's up nigger?
MALE SPEAKER: How
you livin', dog?
ANTWUAN DIXON: I'm good, baby.
You don't even know, man.
Hey, hey.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
What's up, man?
Hey, can I get a wristband?
Whatever, fuck it.
Hey, hey!
FEMALE SPEAKER: Why you
looking so good?
ANTWUAN DIXON: Why
am I looking so--
she says, why am I
looking so good?
[LAUGHTER]
MALE SPEAKER: Hit that!
ANTWUAN DIXON: Wooo!
What's up, motherfuckers?
MALE SPEAKER: Want a beer,
dude, or what?
ANTWUAN DIXON: Yeah.
Fuck, yeah.
TIM CAVIN: Look at your bus.
ANTWUAN DIXON: Fuck, nigger.
I'm rolling deep, nigger.
Niggers rolling deep.
We rolling deep.
All right, nigger.
That DMX nigger, where's
my dogs at?
Where's my dogs?
[BARKS]
MALE SPEAKER: We're doing a day
in the life of this guy.
TIM CAVIN: Fuck you.
[INAUDIBLE].
MALE SPEAKER: He almost
went to jail twice.
TIM CAVIN: Of course.
MALE SPEAKER: Fighting somebody
and drinking.
TIM CAVIN: Really?
MALE SPEAKER: Once at
the hotel and then
once when we got here.
TIM CAVIN: Really?
ANTWUAN DIXON: Oh,
motherfucker.
Nice on, asshole.
On my new Nikes.
Fuck, man.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
ANTWUAN DIXON: I wish
you would, nigger.
I'd beat your little ass.
[LAUGHTER]
SHANE HEYL: Are you asking, is
he doing it more because of
that reason?
There's consequences for sure
with what he's doing.
And he knows that.
He's well aware of it.
And he's battling something
that some people
have in this life.
ANTWUAN DIXON: What's
up, nigger?
BOY: Yo!
ANTWUAN DIXON: You good?
BOY: Yeah.
ANTWUAN DIXON: What's up, boy?
BOY: What's up?
ANTWUAN DIXON: What the
fuck you doin'?
BOY: Skating the concert.
ANTWUAN DIXON: Really?
BOY: Yeah.
ANTWUAN DIXON: Getting crazy?
ANTWUAN DIXON: Yeah?
BOY: Where's your
skateboard at?
SHANE HEYL: I've had
it, you know?
I have a disease.
I have an alcohol-- you know,
alcoholism kills.
I'm not going to say that
that's what he has.
That's for him to find out.
But I love it when he's not in
that bullshit, not in that
trouble, and he's just skating
and being what
he needs to be doing.
And he knows it.
ANDREW REYNOLDS: Like a lot of
skaters and like myself,
people struggle with
drinking and drugs.
And it gets in the way of
where you're going.
So that's what I see.
I could be wrong.
MALE SPEAKER: Yeah, yeah!
MALE SPEAKER: Oh, like a pro.
ANTWUAN DIXON: I won't do
nothing I don't wanna do, you
know what I'm saying?
Nobody tell me nothing,
man, except my mama.
I don't wanna do nothing.
MALE SPEAKER: Does Andrew or
Jim or Eric try to tell you
what to do?
ANTWUAN DIXON: Fuck no, dude.
Hell no, dude.
None of those dudes,
they don't run me.
You know what I'm saying?
But they don't run me,
but they're with me.
You feel me?
They just give me the best
advice, from-- nigger, they've
been there, done that.
You know what I mean?
And they just see when I was
doing whatever, you know, he
was faded and whatever.
They know, you know, we know.
But they just gave me advice
before, because I'm young.
I'm only 21, dude.
All this, all this crazy
stuff, and I'm
only 21 years old.
You know what I mean?
See, all that shit you probably
see out at parties
and all that bullshit
on the internet.
You probably I'm like
30 or some bullshit.
With all these tattoos,
probably
think I'm old as fuck.
But I'm not old as fuck.
I'm young as shit, you
know what I mean?
Jim is the one that really
doesn't want nothing to
fucking, like--
me to go down the wrong road.
Let me put it that way.
ANDREW REYNOLDS: Being an
alcoholic and an addict
myself, you just can't
do anything.
You just can't make
someone stop.
They have to just stop
on their own.
MALE SPEAKER: [LAUGHS]
How you feeling?
Feeling good?
Need a hand?
MALE SPEAKER: Hey, Antwuan,
come here.
ANDREW REYNOLDS: Everybody
wants him to do good.
And he wants to do good.
It's not like people tell him
we want you to do good and
he's like, fuck you.
MALE SPEAKER: I've
been chilling.
I was right here
chilling, dog.
ANTWUAN DIXON: Bullshit.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
MALE SPEAKER: I don't
want to go to jail.
Let's go.
FEMALE SPEAKER: Do you want
to go to jail, Antwuan?
MALE SPEAKER: Just go.
MALE SPEAKER: Let's go.
ANTWUAN DIXON: You know
what I'm saying?
[INAUDIBLE].
MALE SPEAKER: Just go home.
ANTWUAN DIXON: All
right, all right.
God damn.
SHANE HEYL: Like, how many times
can you get away with
some gangster-ass shit?
I don't know.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
MALE SPEAKER: Hey, hey.
Hey, man, we're telling
you to chill, homey.
MALE SPEAKER: Hey, read him
the riot act right now.
Give him the riot warning.
Get him out of here.
MALE SPEAKER: We've leaving.
MALE SPEAKER: Come on.
MALE SPEAKER: It's his
car right here.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
ANTWUAN DIXON: This
shit is fuck!
MALE SPEAKER: I know, fuck
everything, man.
ANTWUAN DIXON: [INAUDIBLE]
nigger.
Woo!
SHANE HEYL: I hope that they
continue to be able to live
their lives in a positive way
and get through with what they
need to do.
[LAUGHTER]
ANTWUAN DIXON: Y'all niggers
be good, niggers.
All right [INAUDIBLE] nigger.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
[CAR HORN]
MALE SPEAKER: [LAUGHS]
Hey, they called the riot
in on you, Twuan.
They called the riot
in on your shit.
ANTWUAN DIXON: [INAUDIBLE].
MALE SPEAKER: [INAUDIBLE]
riot.
ANTWUAN DIXON: Believe it!
MALE SPEAKER: It
was good, dog.
Hey, thanks, man Thank you.
Later!
Yo, later.
Check you later, player.