But now I live in Brooklyn.
I have a real job at
a real magazine.
I have a bank account and
a bunch of shirts.
So I figure I can go back,
revisit some of my failures,
and, with a little bit of luck,
turn them into successes.
This is "All Around Losing"
with Harry Cheadle.
You know how every youth soccer
team has that one weird
kid who just kind of stands off
by himself and lets the
ball go right past him?
My whole team was those guys.
There were a couple
guys named Carl.
Prithvi, Prithvi Shankar.
We could have won a math
championship with all the
brains we had on my team, but,
running around, not so much.
And I was part of the problem.
In six years playing, I scored
exactly one goal, got hit in
the nuts with a soccer ball more
times than I can count.
Sometimes it would hit
me in the face.
I feel kind of responsible for
a lot of the bad seasons we
had, including the last
one, where we didn't
win a single game.
Now I've got a little bit more
self-confidence, better
foot-eye coordination, so maybe
there's a chance I will
actually be an all right
soccer player.
But in order to not embarrass
myself, I'm going to need some
coaching from an Austrian
named Gerhard.
HARRY CHEADLE: Hey, Gerhard.
GERHARD STOCHL: Hey.
How are you?
HARRY CHEADLE: I'm good.
So the deal is, I'm trying
to get back into soccer.
I haven't played in
like seven years.
All I want to do is
impress people.
GERHARD STOCHL: That exactly.
HARRY CHEADLE: I don't
really care about--
GERHARD STOCHL: Because
otherwise it
will take 10 years.
How long we got?
A week?
HARRY CHEADLE: Like a day.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
GERHARD STOCHL: I think
you did good.
HARRY CHEADLE: Yeah?
GERHARD STOCHL: You
got the juggling.
HARRY CHEADLE: I kind
of like juggling.
GERHARD STOCHL: Goalkeeping.
Good penalties.
Maybe a few push ups and--
tonight, before the game.
HARRY CHEADLE: OK.
GERHARD STOCHL: And
you're ready.
HARRY CHEADLE: I'm feeling
pretty nervous about this.
I sat on my glasses this
morning when I woke up.
My arm hurts for no reason.
It's pretty cold.
Practice with Gerhard went OK,
but actually playing a game is
a lot different than just
kicking a ball around.
So, these guys are probably
going to be a lot better than
me, and I'll try not to
embarrass myself,
but I always do.
The first person
I met was Minh.
Hey, Minh.
Sort of an unofficial coach or
referee, or at least the guy
who brings the jerseys.
The other guys are
really friendly.
I'm--
MALE SPEAKER: Are those your
special soccer shoes?
HARRY CHEADLE: They seem
supportive of my
weird little mission.
Wherever I can do the
least damage.
MALE SPEAKER: Defense.
HARRY CHEADLE: Defense?
Yeah.
And then, all of a sudden,
I was playing soccer.
I've got no idea what
I'm doing here.
I just was trying to follow my
man around a little bit and
couldn't do that.
Oh, that was probably
my fault.
Sometimes I saw where I was
supposed to be way too late.
Oh shit!
Sometimes I'd get the ball,
purely by chance--
it would just deflect off
of someone's foot-- and
I had to kick it.
And that was just totally
impossible.
Oh shit!
Not very well.
A little winded.
[INAUDIBLE]?
Yeah.
Yeah, sure.
It's tough to run around.
I haven't run around like
that in a long time.
No one was making fun of me
for being really bad.
Although I could tell they
didn't want to pass it to me.
I don't really know how this
works, but I'm too intimidated
to ask questions.
Actually, the hard part was
running for half an hour, or
45 minutes, or two days,
or whatever it was.
Because I'm in really, really
bad shape, I realized.
I've got to sit down,
actually.
I was feeling pretty bad.
I just met all these people.
And my rule is don't throw
up in front of people
you've just met, ever.
And then a black guy started
talking, but I was also trying
really hard not to throw
up at that point.
MALE SPEAKER: How long
you haven't played?
HARRY CHEADLE: Years.
MALE SPEAKER: Really?
HARRY CHEADLE: And then your
body's like, nope.
This is coming up.
And I was like, oh, shit.
I was trying not to puke
on anyone's bag.
I succeeded in that, at least.
I know how to puke probably
better than I
know how to play soccer.
MALE SPEAKER: That's
a good thing.
HARRY CHEADLE: What?
MALE SPEAKER: Once all
that's out, you're
going to play better.
HARRY CHEADLE: Oh, shit.
And then I puked again.
HARRY CHEADLE: Jesus.
That's how my life
usually goes.
I gave the guys some orange
slices, and I hope that kind
of patched things up.
I was like, here, not only did I
puke, but I brought you some
vitamin C.
Nothing like a good orange
slice, right?
And I kept playing, at least.
I'm glad I didn't bitch out.
I did try to bitch out.
MINH NGO: You only
played what?
30 minutes?
HARRY CHEADLE: I'm really
out of shape.
MINH NGO: You have one
more game in you.
HARRY CHEADLE: All right.
One more.
Even though I was bad, and I had
just thrown up, Minh was
like, come on, get in
there and play.
And that was nice.
During the last play of that
game, no one was paying
attention to me--
probably for good reason.
I got the ball, and I'm looking
at the goal, and I
kicked the ball pretty hard--
Sorry.
It went right to the goalie,
but it was a shot on goal.
MALE SPEAKER: [INAUDIBLE],
just nail it in.
HARRY CHEADLE: I probably would
have thrown up again if
I had made that goal.
I think this situation was about
a 70% failure, mostly
because of the puking.
Honestly, you don't feel good
when you puke in front of
other people.
I've lost this one.
Just like I lost the ones
when I was a kid.
Same feeling.
Keep looking.
Keep looking for redemption.
And I guess that's what
I'm going to do.
It wasn't that bad out
there, though.
Maybe I could--
if I practiced--
get a little better at
soccer, I think.
But I'm not sure I will because,
honestly, I remember
all those times, my favorite
part of the soccer game was
when it's over.
And you're in the car, and you
get to go home and take your
shin guards off.
So that's what I enjoyed most
about it, was stopping it.
Is that good?
MALE SPEAKER: No.
Keep going.
[MUSIC PLAYING]