Mexican Pointy Boots.
The story, it's about this
fashion trend that started in
Matehuala, which is a town in
central Mexico, about four
hours north of Mexico City,
where these kids started
wearing these ridiculously long
pointy boots to dance to
music called Tribal.
The music and the boots became
incredibly popular.
We also took those guys to
perform at the Vice Mexico
anniversary party last year,
and it was pretty amazing.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
ANNOUNCER: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
MALE SPEAKER 1:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
MALE SPEAKER 2:
KIKO: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
BOY: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
MALE SPEAKER 3:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
[MUSIC - ERICK RINCON]
ERICK RINCON: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
MALE SPEAKER 4:
[MUSIC - ERICK RINCON]
ERICK RINCON: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
MALE SPEAKER 5:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
MALE SPEAKER 6:
[MUSIC - ERICK RINCON]
ANNOUNCER: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
[CROWD CHEERS]
[MUSIC - ERICK RINCON]
MALE SPEAKER 7:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
ANNOUNCER: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
[MUSIC - ERICK RINCON]
KIKO: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
MALE SPEAKER 3:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
[MUSIC - ERICK RINCON]
MALE SPEAKER 8:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
[MUSIC - ERICK RINCON]