THE FIRST TURBINE WAS BUILT IN THE 1960S.
>> >>PEGGY: ALSO AHEAD, HUNDREDS OF PEOPLE
ARE SICK AND SIX PEOPLE HAVE DIED IN SAN DIEGO
FROM THE FLU THIS YEAR.
HOW LONG OUR FLU SEASON WILL LAST AND SHOULD
YOU STILL GET VACCINATED.
THEN IN THE FIRST STATE OF THE CITY ADDRESS,
MAYOR BOB FILNER COMPARES SAN DIEGO TO A SICK
PATIENT.
>> >>: TONIGHT THE STATE OF OUR CITY CAN BE
COMPARED I THINK TO A PATIENT WHO HAS FACED
A LIFE THREATENING DISEASE, WHO HAS SURVIVED
PAINFUL TREATMENTS AND A LENGTHY RECOVERY.
>> >>PEGGY: I'LL TALK WITH MAYOR BOB FILNER
TONIGHT ABOUT THE CITY'S PROGNOSIS AND HOW
HE PLANS TO SPEED UP ITS RECOVERY.
CAPTIONS PROVIDED BY ECAPTIONS.
>> >>DWANE: GOOD EVENING THANKS FOR JOINING
US.
PRESIDENT OBAMA IS CALLING FOR A SERIES OF
SWEEPING LAWS AND RESTRICTIONS TO OVERHAUL
THE NATION'S GUN LAWS.
SOME OF THE STEPS COULD IMPACT WEAPONS TRAFFICKING
ACROSS THE BORDER INTO MEXICO.
THE PRESIDENT SAYS HE WILL ASK CONGRESS TO
CREATE A FEDERAL ARMS TRAFFICKING LAW, REINSTATE
THE ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN, UNIVERSAL BACK GROUND
CHECKS AND LIMIT GUN MAGAZINES TO 10 ROUNDS.
900 PEOPLE HAVE DIED IN THE U.S. BECAUSE OF
GUN VIOLENCE SINCE THE SANDY HOOK MASSACRE
IN DECEMBER.
>> >>: IF THERE'S EVEN ONE LIFE THAT CAN BE
SAVED THEN WE'VE GOT AN OBLIGATION TO TRY.
I WILL SIGN A DIRECTIVE GIVING LAW ENFORCEMENT,
SCHOOLS, MENTAL HEALTH PROFESSIONALS AND THE
PUBLIC HEALTH COMMUNITY SOME OF THE TOOLS
THEY NEED TO HELP REDUCE GUN VIOLENCE.
>> >>DWANE: THE NATIONAL RIFLE ASSOCIATION
RELEASE AD STATEMENT FOLLOWING THE PRESIDENT'S
ANNOUNCEMENT IN RESPONSE TO THE GUN CONTROL
PROPOSALS.
IT SAYS IN PART ATTACKING FIRE ARMS AND IGNORING
CHILDREN IS NOT A SOLUTION TO THE CRISIS WE
FACE AS A NATION.
ONLY HONEST LAW ABIDING GUN OWNERS WILL BE
AFFECTED AND OUR CHILDREN REMAIN VULNERABLE
TO THE INEVITABILITY OF TRAGEDY.
THE OPERATOR OF THE SAN ONOFRE NUCLEAR POWER
PLANT WANTS MOST OF ITS TESTIMONY IN THE STATE
INVESTIGATION KEPT SECRET INTO WHAT WENT WRONG.
KPBS REPORTER AMITA SHARMA HAS BEEN FOLLOWING
THE STORY.
AMITA, SAN DIEGO GAS & ELECTRIC IS A MINORITY
OWNER.
ON WHAT GROUNDS ARE THEY ASKING THIS INFORMATION
BE KEPT FROM THE PUBLIC?
>> >>: THE PUC HAS STARTED AN INVESTIGATION
AS TO WHY THE GENERATOR MALFUNCTIONED.
THAT INQUIRY IS LIKELY TO ASK FOR DATA AND
ANALYSIS THAT SDG&E AND EDISON RELIED TO ON
TO PURCHASE THE GENERATORS.
THEY'RE SAYING SOME OF THAT INFORMATION THEY'RE
GOING TO BE ASKING US TO TURN OVER MAY CONTAIN
CONFIDENTIAL AND PROPRIETARY INFORMATION.
FOR EXAMPLE, EDISON SAYS IF IT HAD TO MAKE
PUBLIC AN ANALYSIS OF THE STEAM GENERATOR
DESIGN, THAT WOULD VIOLATE A CONFIDENTIALITY
AGREEMENT THE COMPANY HAS WITH MITSUBISHI
WHICH MADE THE STEAM GENERATORS.
>> >>DWANE: WHAT DOES THAT HAVE TO DO WITH
THE PUBLIC.
>> >>: IF THE CALIFORNIA PUBLIC UTILITIES
COMMISSION DECIDES TO GRANT SDG&E AND EDISON
THE PROTECTIVE ORDER, ANYONE WHO HAS NOT SIGN
AD NON DISCLOSURE AGREEMENT MAY NOT BE ABLE
TO VIEW THE INFORMATION.
ONE OF THE ALLIANCE FOR NUCLEAR RESPONSIBILITY
IS CHALLENGING THE LEGALITY OF KEEPING THE
COMPANY'S TESTIMONY SECRET.
>> >>DWANE: THE NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION
HEARD A PETITION FROM GROUPS WHO CLAIM SOUTHERN
CALIFORNIA EDISON FAILED TO GET PROPER APPROVAL
BEFORE REPLACING SAN ONOFRE'S STEAM GENERATORS.
IT WAS THE FIRST TIME THE NRC SKIRTED REGULATIONS
WHEN IT REDESIGNED THE PLANT'S STEAM GENERATORS.
THE GROUP FRIENDS OF THE EARTH SAY A LOT OF
EVIDENCE IS BEING WITHHELD.
THE NRC SAYS IT HAS NO AUTHORITY TO MAKE THE
DOCUMENTS PUBLIC BUT WILL CONSIDER THE PETITION.
SIX WEEKS INTO HIS TERM AS SAN DIEGO MAYOR,
BOB FILNER DELIVERED HIS FIRST STATE OF THE
CITY ADDRESS LAST NIGHT.
PEGGY PICO TALKS WITH THE MAYOR ABOUT HIS
PLANS FOR SAN DIEGO.
>> >>PEGGY: SAN DIEGO MAYOR BOB FILNER WELCOME
BACK TO EVENING EDITION.
GOOD TO HAVE YOU HERE.
LAST NIGHT YOU LAID OUT SOME VERY AMBITIOUS
PLANS WHICH INCLUDED ENVIRONMENTAL FRIENDLY
FORESTRIES, SOLAR FOR GOVERNMENT BUILDINGS
DOWNTOWN, I THINK A LIGHT RAIL TO THE AIRPORT.
JUST A MYRIAD OF THINGS.
ONE IN PARTICULAR, THE NEW DEPARTMENT FOR
NEIGHBORHOODS FOR IMPROVING NEIGHBORHOODS.
FIRST OF ALL, A LOT OF PLANS.
HOW DO YOU PLAN TO PAY FOR THOSE PLANS?
>> >>: IT'S REALLY IMPORTANT FOR THE LEADER
O THE CITY AND MAYOR TO LAYOUT A VISION.
WHEN PEOPLE KNOW WHERE WE WANT TO GO, THERE'S
EXCITEMENT ABOUT IT, A SENSE OF PROGRESS.
I THINK THAT'S THE HARDEST POINT THAT PEOPLE
FEEL GOOD ABOUT THE DIRECTION WE'RE GOING.
AND THEN HOW WE DO IT BECOMES NOT TRIVIAL,
BUT COMPARED TO LAYING OUT THE VISION.
>> >>PEGGY: ARE TAXES INVOLVED IN THAT?
>> >>: I HAVE NO PLANS TO ASK FOR ANY TAXES.
WE'RE A THREE BILLION DOLLAR OPERATION.
IT'S A QUESTION OF ONE CHANGING PRIORITIES.
I WANT TO MOVE MONEY, FOR EXAMPLE, WHERE 200ﾊMILLION
DOLLARS HAS GONE DOWNTOWN, I WANT TO MOVE
THAT INTO THE NEIGHBORHOOD INFRASTRUCTURE.
WE CAN DO THAT.
A LOT OF MONEY GOES FOR ADVERTISING OF P PRIVATE
HOTELS ACROSS THE COUNTRY.
LET'S MOVE THAT INTO PUBLIC SAFETY, FOR EXAMPLE.
>> >>PEGGY: BUT JUST I WANT TO TOUCH A LITTLE
MORE ON THAT.
REDEVELOPMENT MONEY IS GONE.
SO WHERE WOULD THAT YOU HAVE PLANS OF WHERE
THAT MONEY COULD COME FROM.
>> >>: THAT REDEVELOPMENT MONEY WAS BASED
ON THE FACT THAT PROPERTY TAXES WENT UP DOWNTOWN
AND THAT MONEY STAYED DOWNTOWN.
NOW WE'RE GOING TO GET BACK A LOT OF THAT
TAX MONEY INTO THE GENERAL FUND.
WE'RE GOING TO SHIFT IT FROM WHERE IT WAS
TO THE WHOLE CITY.
WHEN I TALK ABOUT SORT OF GRANDE OAS THINGS
WE'RE GOING TO SOLAR POWER ALL OUR PUBLIC
BUILDINGS WITHIN FIVE YEARS, I HAVE TALKED
WITH MANY SOLAR COMPANIES WHO WILL UP FRONT
THE CAPITAL COST FOR SUCH A PROGRAM AND THEY
GET PAID OFF THE SAVINGS OF OUR ENERGY BILL.
SO IT'S NOT GOING TO COST US ANY MONEY TO
PUT IT IN. WE PAY FOR IT FROM THE SAVINGS.
WE CAN DO THIS.
IT DOESN'Tﾊ AND THERE'S GOING TO BE PUBLIC
PRIVATE PARTNERSHIPS.
THERE'S WAYS TO DEAL WITH THIS.
THE MONEY IS OBVIOUSLY IMPORTANT, BUT NOT
AS IMPORTANT OF THE VISION.
>> >>PEGGY: AND MOVING FORWARD WITH CONCEPTUAL
VISION, YOU WILL OPEN I THINK IN JUST A FEW
WEEKS AN OFFICE IN TIJUANA.
FIRST TIME.
WHAT IS YOUR FOCUS THERE, WHY DO YOU WANT
TO DO THAT?
>> >>: THAT'S GOING TO HAPPEN ON FEBRUARYﾊ1.
THE CITY OF TIJUANA HAS A MUNICIPAL OFFICE
IN SAN DIEGO, BUT WE'VE NEVER HAD AN OFFICE
IN TIJUANA. I JUST THINK MUTUAL RESPECT AND
MUTUAL INTEREST.
WE'RE THE BIGGEST METROPOLITAN AREA BINATIONAL
METROPOLITAN AREA IN THE WORLD.
WE HAVE A LOT TO TALK ABOUT EVERY DAY, WHETHER
IT'S TRADE, RELATIONSHIPS, WHAT HAPPENS AT
THE BORDER.
I WANT TO HAVE A VERYﾊ STAFF, PEOPLE THERE
WHO CAN DEAL WITH THESE ISSUES AS THEY COME
UP.
BY THE WAY, WE HAVE, YOU SAID HOW MUCH IS
THIS GOING TO COST, PEOPLE ARE GOING TO TO
SAY.
THE CITY OF TIJUANA IS GIVING US A SPACEﾊ
THE ECONOMIC DEVELOPMENT CORPORATION AS IT
WERE OF TIJUANA IS GIVING US SPACE IN THEIR
BUILDING, RIGHT IN THE CENTER OF TIJUANA,
VERY ACCESSIBLE, AND FREE.
SO WE'RE GOING TO BE ABLE TO DEAL WITH TIJUANA
IN A MUCH MORE RAPID WAY, IN A MUCH MORE WIDE
SPREAD WAY, AND BUILD UP NOT ONLY OUR BUSINESS,
BUT OUR EXCHANGES OF STUDENTS, AND ART, AND
COMMERCE.
>> >>PEGGY: LET ME TOUCH BRIEFLY ON THE COMPARISON
O THE CITY'S FINANCIAL HEALTH TO A VERY ILL
PATIENT THAT'S RECOVERING.
YOU PROJECTED UP TO A 40ﾊMILLION DOLLAR
DEFICIT.
WHAT IS THAT DEFICIT BASED ON?
>> >>: WHEN THE MAYOR PREVIOUS MAYOR WHO DID
AN INCREDIBLE JOB PUTTING US ON A SOUND FINANCIAL
FOOTING, HE LEFT THINKING THERE WAS GOING
TO BE A SURPLUS, BUT THERE ARE LAND MINES,
I CALL THEM DOWN THE WAY THAT MIGHT EXPLODE
ANY MIN MINUTE AND CAN PROJECT US INTO A 40ﾊMILLION
DOLLAR MORE DEFICIT.
FOR EXAMPLE, PROP B WHICH IS THE NEW PENSION
SYSTEM IS GOING TO COST US JUST 37ﾊMILLION
DOLLARS TO SET UP A NEW SYSTEM.
THAT WAS NOT FULLY PUT INTO THE BUDGET.
THIS REDEVELOPMENT THAT YOU MENTIONEDﾊ THE
STATE IS RULING THAT CERTAIN FUNDS WE'RE GOING
TO HAVE TO PAY THAT WERE PAID OUT OF THE REDEVELOPMENT.
WE PAY $15ﾊMILLION OR SO FOR PETCO, STADIUM.
THAT'S GOING TO BECOME NOW PART OF THE CITY
BUDGET.
>> >>PEGGY: THAT WE HAVE TO PLAN FOR.
WE HAVE ABOUT 30 SECONDS LEFT.
YOU HAVE A PLAN TO WORK WITH THE UNION AND
CITY WORKERS OVER FIVE YEARS TO HELP SORT
OF OFF SET THIS DEFICIT.
CAN YOU BRIEFLY EXPLAIN WHAT THAT IS?
>> >>: I WANT TO HAVE A FIVE YEAR CONTRACT
THAT WOULD SAVE A LOT OF MONEY, YOU DON'T
NEGOTIATE EVERY YEAR.
IT GIVES US A CHANCE TO REWARD EMPLOYEES THAT
HAVE NOT HAD ANY PAY RAISE IN THE PAST FIVE
OR SIX, SEVEN YEARS.
IT SAVES MONEY OFF OUR PENSION DEBT JUST BECAUSE
YOU HAVE THE CERTAINTY OF A CONTRACT NOT JUST
A PROJECTION.
I WANT TO FOLLOW ON MY PROPOSITION B AND MY
PROMISE NOT TO RAISE PENSIONABLE PAY OVER
THE NEXT FIFTEEN YEARS.
LET'S SEE IF WE CAN HELP EMPLOYEES IN HEALTH
CARE COSTS, AND SHOW WE RESPECT OUR PUBLIC
EMPLOYEES BUT WE HAVE TO RESPECT OUR TAX PAYERS
SENSE OF WHAT'S APPROPRIATE FOR WHAT TO ACHIEVE.
>> >>PEGGY: SAN DIEGO MAYOR BILL YR, NR BOB
FILNER, THANKS FOR JOINING US.
>> >>DWANE: JAPAN AIRLINES SERVICE MAY BE
IN TROUBLE. THE AIRLINE GROUNDED ITS NEW FLEET
OF BOEING 787S AFTER AN ELECTRICAL FIRE.
SIMILAR INCIDENT HAPPENED LAST WEEK IN BOSTON.
BOEINGS NEW DREAM LINER HAS HAD PROBLEMS WITH
FUEL LEAKS.
FLIGHTS BETWEEN LINDBERGH AND TOKYO ARE CANCELED.
A STUDY FROM THE CALIFORNIA DEPARTMENT OF
MOTOR VEHICLES FIND SAID UNLICENSED DRIVERS
ARE NEARLY THREE TIMES MORE LIKELY TO CAUSE
A FATAL CRASH THAN DRIVERS WITH VALID LICENSES.
IT LOOKED AT FATAL CRASHES IN CALIFORNIA OVER
23 YEAR PERIOD AND FOUND UNLICENSED DRIVERS
MORE LIKELY TO BE AT FAULT IN FATAL CRASHES.
A CALIFORNIA LAW NOW NOW ALLOWS LICENSES FOR
UNDOCUMENTED YOUTH AS PART OF A FEDERAL DEPORTATION
POLICY.
SAN DIEGO ATTORNEYS HAVE FILE AD CIVIL LAWSUIT
AGAINST THE BOY SCOUTS OF AMERICA.
IT CLAIM AS 14 YEAR OLD BOY WAS SEXUALLY ABUSED
BY A CAMP COUNSELOR WHO WAS NOT PROPERLY SUPERVISED.
THE SUIT CLAIMS IT HAPPENED ALMOST 15 YEARS
AT A SUMMER CAMP IN THE NORTH COUNTY. THE
ALLEGED VICTIM IS NOW 29.
THE MAN ACCUSE SAID OF MOLESTING HIM WAS ARRESTED
IN 2001.
THE PLAINTIFF'S LAWYER SAYS HE HOPES THE CASE
WILL FORCE THE SCOUTS TO DISCLOSE A PRIVATELY
HELD LIST OF OTHER CHILD ABUSERS.
>> >>: A MOLESTATION ISN'T JUST A PHYSICAL
ACT, IT'S EMOTIONAL MURDER.
SO IN OUR COUNTRY, WE NOW KNOW THAT THERE
WERE HUNDREDS AND HUNDREDS OF BOY SCOUT LEADERS
FROM 1965 TO 1991 THAT DID THIS, IF NOT THOUSANDS.
BUT THEY HAVEN'T RELEASED THE DOCUMENTS AFTER
1991.
THERE VERY W WELL MAY BE PREDATORS STILL IN
SAN DIEGO WORKING WITH CHILDREN WE DON'T KNOW
ABOUT.
>> >>DWANE: KPBS CONTACTED THE BOY SCOUTS
BUT THEY DIDN'T RETURN OUR CALLS REGARDING
THIS LAWSUIT.
TODAY A CALIFORNIA JUDGE HAS ORDERED TO RELEASE
TWO DECADES OF FILES DETAILING SEXUAL ABUSE
ALLEGATIONS.
SAN DIEGO IS WORKING ON A FIVE YEAR PLAN TO
IMPROVE THE DEPARTMENT RESPONSE PLANS THROUGHOUT
THE CITY.
THE PLAN COMES FROM A REPORT THE CITY COMMISSIONED
IN 2010.
AMONG THE 10 ACTIONS SUPPOSED TO BE COMPLETED,
FOUR HAVE BEEN COMPLETED, A NEW DISPATCHING
PROCESS FOR MEDICAL EMERGENCIES HAS BEEN ADOPTED.
THE REPORT SAYS SAN DIEGO COULD USE UP TO
19 ADDITIONAL FIRE STATIONS TO PROVIDE A FIVE
MINUTE RESPONSE TIME TO MOST OF THE CITY.
AN ICONIC SAN DIEGO FIXTURE IS ABOUT TO BECOME
A MEMORY.
THE SOUTH BAY POWER PLANT IN CHULA VISTA HAS
TURNED FOSSIL FUEL INTO ELECTRICITY SINCE
THE FIRST TURBINE WAS BUILT IN THE 1960S.
KPBS BUSINESS AND ENVIRONMENT REPORTER ERIK
ANDERSON SAYS THE TOWERING METAL STRUCTURE
IS COMING DOWN SOON.
>> >>: A HULKING METAL FRAME HOLDS TOGETHER
A MACHINE BUILT TO MAKE POWER.
FOUR HUGE TURBINES THAT TURN STEAM INTO ELECTRICITY.
THE COMPANY IS OVER SEEING THE DEMOLITION.
KATIE SULLIVAN POINTS AT BOILER TUBES THAT
ARE PART OF A TANGLED METAL MESS ON THE GROUND.
>> >>: THERE ARE HUNDREDS OF TUBES LIKE THIS
THAT RUN THROUGH THE BOILERS THAT CARRY HOT
WATER AND STEAM, THAT'S ALL PART OF THE POWER
GENERATION PROCESS.
THESE TUBES WILL COME OUT ONCE THE STRUCTURE
IS SALVAGED.
>> >>: CREWS HAVE RIPPED OUT THE BOTTOM FLOORS
OF THE PLANT.
SULLIVAN SAYS THE STRUCTURE HAS BEEN GRADUALLY
GUTTED.
CONCRETE AND METAL PILES ARE SIFTED, AND SEPARATED.
AND THEN CARTED AWAY.
>> >>: THIS IS A LARGE JOB.
WE'VE REMOVED 7,000 TONS OF STEAL SO FAR FROM
THE SITE.
WE COULD HAVE UPWARDS OF 24,000 TONS OF STEAL
THAT ARE RECYCLED AND SALVAGED.
VERY LITTLE WASTE ACTUALLY FROM A DEMOLITION
OF THIS SIZE.
>> >>: WORKERS ON THE GROUND AND IN EXCAVATING
AND SKIV GEARS DO THE HEAVY LIFTING.
MAJOR SUPPORT BEAMS ARE BEING READIED FOR
A EXPLOSIVE CHARGES THAT COULD GO ON FOR UP
TO TWO MINUTES.
>> >>: IT WILL SOUND A LITTLE BIT LIKE ROLLING
THUNDER AND THESE FIRST THREE FACILITIES WILL
FALL TO THE NORTH.
THIS LAST WILL FALL TO THE EAST, ALL OF THEM
FALLING AWAY FROM THE WATER.
>> >>: THAT WILL HAPPEN IN A MATTER OF WEEKS,
BUT DEMOLITION DAY CAN'T COME SOON ENOUGH
FOR LAURA HUNTER, THE ENVIRONMENTAL HEALTH
COALITION ACTIVIST STRUGGLED FOR YEARS TO
SHUT DOWN WHAT SHE CONSIDERS AN ECOLOGICAL
DISASTER.
>> >>: IT COMES FROM A DAY WHEN WE DIDN'T
KNOW ANY BETTER AND WE THOUGHT WE HAD TO PUT
POWER PLANTS ON THE COAST USING THE OCEAN
TO COOL THEM.
WE'RE NOT AT THAT DAY ANYMORE.
REALLY IT WAS JUST A MATTER OF TIME.
>> >>: THE FACILITY SPEWED AIR POLLUTION INTO
NEARBY NEIGHBORHOODS AND CREATED ECOLOGICAL
HAVOC BY USING THE SHALLOW BAY WATER TO COOL
THE GIANT TURBINES.
THE WATER WAS PUMPED BACK INTO THE BAY.
>> >>: BASICALLY THE ENTIRE SOUTH BAY IS A
FISH NURSERY, SO JUVENILE FISH F WE WANT TO
HAVE BIG FISH, WE HAVE TO HAVE BABY FISH,
THEY GROW UP HERE.
THE SHALLOW WATERS ARE REALLY VERY IMPORTANT.
THAT'S WHY THIS PLANT WAS LOCATED IN THE MOST
DAMAGING LOCATION IT COULD POSSIBLY HAVE BEEN,
RIGHT IN THE MIDDLE OF A FISH NURSERY AREA,
SHALLOW WATER, DENSELY POPULATED.
>> >>: IN THE SHADOW OF THE FACILITY, DELICATE
MARSH LAND NURTURES ALL MANNER OF FISH, BIRDS,
AND BUGS.
>> >>: THE PLANTS ARE VERY PRODUCTIVE, YOU
LOOK AROUND, SEE THE BIRDS USING IT, AND WE
HAVEN'T DONE A VERY GOOD JOB FEATURING AREAS
LIKE THIS BECAUSE WHEN YOU LOOK HERE YOU DON'T
SEE THE BEAUTIFUL SALT MARSH, YOU SEE THE
EYE SORE.
>> >>: TANYA TH POWER PLANT'S 115 ACRE FOOT
PRINT WILL CHANGE DRAMATICALLY.
>> >>: WE'RE LOOKING FORWARD TO THE REMOVAL
OF THE POWER PLANT.
IT'S PART OF THIS GRAND VISION FOR THE 500
PLUS ACRES OF THE CHULA VISTA BAY FRONT TO
MAKE IT A MORE WELCOMING ACCESSIBLE PLACE.
>> >>: IN ITS PLACE, HOPING TO DEVELOP PARK
LAND, AREAS THAT ARE MUCH MORE USER FRIENDLY
THAN THEY HAVE BEEN.
>> >>: WHEN WE REMOVE IT THAT'S GOING TO IMMEDIATELY
AFFECT THIS WHOLE LAND AREA; GOING TO MAKE
IT MORE DESIRABLE, HELP US BRING IN THE DEVELOPERS
AND TO BUILD THE WORLD CLASS BAY FRONT WE
DESERVE.
>> >>: THAT POTENTIAL DEVELOPMENT COULD REPLACE
THE REVENUE THAT THE PORT EARNED FROM THE
SOUTH BAY POWER PLANT WHEN IT WAS CHURNING
OUT ELECTRICITY.
SHE SAYS BAY FRONT DEVELOPMENT HERE HAS BEEN
HELD BACK BECAUSE NOT MANY DEVELOPERS WANT
TO BUILD A WORLD CLASS HOTEL WITH A VIEW OF
A GAS FIRED POWER PLANT.
ERIK ANDERSON, KPBS NEWS.
>> >>DWANE: THE SOUTH BAY PLANT STOPPED PRODUCING
ELECTRICITY AT THE END OF 2010 AFTER A STATE
OF THE ART POWER PLANT WENT ONLINE IN OTAY
MESA.
FIRST COM POSTING CENTER PART OF AN EFFORT
TO REDUCE WASTE THAT AFFECTS BOTH SIDES OF
THE BORDER.
IT'S OPENING THE CENTER WITH HEALTH HELP FROM
A 93,000 DOLLAR GRANT FROM THE U.S. ENVIRONMENTAL
PROTECTION AGENCY COM POSTING TAKES ORGANIC
MATERIAL LIKE PLANT AND ANIMAL WASTE AND TURNS
IT INTO FERTILIZER.
THE CENTER EXPECTS TO PRODUCE 150 TONS OF
COM POST IN ITS FIRST YEAR.
THE NATION MAY BE NEARING THE PEEK OF A DEIVE
ESTATING FLU SEASON.
SAN DIEGO'S FLU SEASON WON'T PEAK FOR AT LEAST
ANOTHER MONTH.
>> >>PEGGY: SAN DIEGO HEALTH OFFICIALS SAY
THE FLU HAS KILLED SIX PEOPLE IN THE COUNTY
THIS FLU SEIZE EXPN SAY THE NUMBER OF PEOPLE
WITH INFLUENZA IN THE COUNTY HAS DOUBLED SINCE
LAST WEEK TO TOTAL 670 REPORTED CASES.
DIRECTOR OF EMERGENCY MEDICINE DR.ﾊCHRISTIAN
TOMASZEWSKI JOINS ME.
SAN DIEGO HAS WHAT IS CONSIDERED A LATE FLU
SEASON.
WHEN IS OUR FLU SEASON TYPICALLY AND HAS IT
PEEKED YET?
>> >>: USUALLY THE PEEK IS IN FEBRUARY, BUT
IT MAY COME IN JANUARY THIS YEAR, A LITTLE
EARLIER.
THE THING THAT HELPED IT IS THE COLD, DRY
WEATHER.
THAT'S WHAT THE FLU NEEDS TO SPREAD.
>> >>PEGGY: HOW DOES IT SPREAD THAT WAY? I
THINK THERE'S A MISCONCEPTION THAT COLD WEATHER
CAUSES THE FLU.
>> >>: NO, DRAFTS DON'T DO IT.
IT'S IT COLD DRY AIR ALLOWS IT TO GET AIR
LIFE AND SURVIVE LONGER.
>> >>PEGGY: AND PEOPLE ARE IN DOORS MORE SO
THEY'RE IN CONTACT WITH PEOPLE WHOﾊ
>> >>: PERFECT COMBINATION FOR A VIRUS THAT
WANT TO SPREAD.
>> >>PEGGY: WE'VE HEARD ACROSS THE COUNTRY
THERE'S BEEN MANY DEATHS.
THIS SEEMS TO BE A PARTICULARLY BAD FLU SEASON
BACK EAST.
IS THE FLU STRAIN THIS YEAR PARTICULARLY WORSE
THAN OTHER YEARS?
>> >>: IT'S NOT THE WORST, BUT IT IS A BAD
ONE, AND ESPECIALLY IF YOU HAVE HIGH RISK
FACTORS TO GET COMPLICATIONS FROM THE FLU.
>> >>PEGGY: SUCH AS, WHO WOULD BE MOST AT
RISK?
>> >>: UM, THE ELDERLY, PEOPLE OVER 65, INFANTS,
AND PREGNANT WOMEN, AND ANYONE WITH A COEXISTING
ILLNESS, LUNG DISEASE, HEART DISEASE, KIDNEY
DISEASE, THAT KIND OF THING.
>> >>PEGGY: THESE PEOPLE, CAN THEY GET VACCINATED
AND WHO SHOULD BE VACCINATED?
>> >>: THEY CAN ABSOLUTELY GET VACCINATED,
I THINK EVERYONE SHOULD GET VACCINATED.
NOT ONLY DO WE NEED TO TAKE CARE OF OURSELVES
WE NEED TO KEEP THIS VIRUS FROM SPREADING.
>> >>PEGGY: LET'S TALK ABOUT THAT SPREAD.
THERE'S A COUPLE THINGS EVERYONE KNOWS ABOUT
PROPER HAND WASHING, MAYBE STAYING HOME.
WHAT CAN YOU RECOMMEND IF YOU THINK YOU'RE
COMING DOWN WITH THE FLU WHAT SHOULD YOU DO?
>> >>: STAY HOME, DO US A FAVOR, DON'T SPREAD
IT, AND IF YOU NEED TO GO OUT OR SEE OTHER
PEOPLE, TRY TO KEEP YOUR COUGH TO YOURSELF,
COUGH INTO YOUR ARM OR SLEEVE.
AND MAKE SURE YOU TRY NOT TO TOUCH YOUR FACE,
AND GOOD HAND CLEANSING.
>> >>PEGGY: IT'S AMAZING HOW MUCH HAND WASHING
CAN STATISTICALLY IMPROVE THE LESSEN THE SPREAD
OF THE DISEASE.
I WOULD LIKE YOU TO DISPELL SOME MISCONCEPTIONS
ABOUT GETTING THE FLU SHOT.
CAN YOU GET THE FLU FROM A FLU SHOT?
>> >>: IF YOU'RE GOING TO GIVE A HUNDRED MILLION
FLU SHOTS LIKE THE NUMBER OF PEOPLE WHO HAVE
GOTTEN THE FLU SHOT, SOMEBODY IS GOING TO
GET SICK AT THE SAME TIME THIGH GOT THE FLU
SHOT.
AND BECAUSE OF THE MAGICAL THINKING THEY'RE
GOING TO THINK THE FLU SHOT CAUSED IT.
THE YOU MIGHT HAVE A MILD ALLERGIC TYPE RESPONSE
BUT YOU'RE NOT GOING TO GET THE FLU FROM THE
FLU SHOT AND YOU'RE NOT GOING TO GET SICK
FROM IT.
>> >>PEGGY: THE REASON IS BECAUSE IT'S NOT
A LIVE VIRUS, CORRECT?
>> >>: ABSOLUTELY.
IT'S BEEN KILLED.
>> >>PEGGY: THERE'S NO WAY YOU CAN GET IT
FROM THAT.
IS IT TOO LATE FOR PEOPLE IN SAN DIEGO TO
GET VACCINATED, HAVE WE PASSED THE MARK WHERE
IT WOULD DO US ANY GOOD?
>> >>: THE GOOD NEWS IS WE'RE JUST ON THE
SHOULDER.
THE FUN IS ABOUT TO START IN TERMS OF THE
FLU HAVING A PARTY HERE.
SO GET THE FLU SHOT.
IT'S NOT TOO LATE.
>> >>PEGGY: OKAY, HOW DO YOU KNOW WHEN YOU
SHOULD GO SEE YOUR DOCTOR, AND/OR DARE I SAY
GO TO THE ER WHEN YOU HAVE A FLU?
>> >>: POST MOST OF THE FLU CAN BE HANDLED
ATD HOME WITH FLU UDS AND MAYBE SOMETHING
TO HELP WITH THE FEVER AND THE MUSCLE ACHES.
BUT IF YOU HAVE A COEXISTING ILLNESS, YOUR
PREGNANT, YOU'RE OLDER, OR YOU HAVE ILLNESSES
OF THE HEART OR LUNGS, THEN YOU PROBABLY SHOULD
CALL YOUR DOCTOR IF YOU THINK YOU'RE COMING
DOWN FOR THE FLU.
>> >>PEGGY: SO DOCTOR FIRST.
>> >>: RIGHT, AND CALL YOURﾊ OR GO TO A
LOCAL CLINIC IF YOU CAN'T GET HOLD OF YOUR
DOCTOR.
YOU REALLY DON'T WANT TO GO TO THE EMERGENCY
ROOM UNLESS YOU'RE HAVING THE WARNING SIGNS
OF THE FLU.
>> >>PEGGY: WHICH WOULD BEﾊ
>> >>: CHEST PAIN, TROUBLE BREATHING, ABDOMINAL
PAIN, YOU CAN'T KEEP UP WITH YOUR FLEUD FLUIDS
YOU'RE VOMITING SO MUCH.
IN THOSE CASES I COULD SEE YOU COMING TO THE
EMERGENCY DEPARTMENT.
>> >>PEGGY: BECAUSE IT'S MOVED TO A SEIVE
SEVEREﾊ I WANT TO TOUCH ON THIS AFEW RETAILERS
ARE HERE IN SAN DIEGO SAYING THEY'VE RUN OUT.
IS THERE A SHORTAGE?
>> >>: I DON'T CONTROL THE SUPPLY CHAIN FOR
THE FLU VACCINE, BUT I'VE HEARD OF SPOTTY
SHORTAGES IN AREAS.
THE GOOD NEWS IS MORE SUPPLIES ARE COMING
IN. SO IF YOU GET A CHANCE, I GET CAN'T GUARANTEE
IT'S GOING TO STICK AROUND.
IF YOU SEE A VACCINE, GO GET IT.
>> >>PEGGY: RIGHT THEN.
ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR TALKING ABOUT THIS,
AND CHRISTIAN TOMASZEWSKI WILL BE BACK AT
THE HOSPITAL.
>> >>: I'M JEFFREY BROWN ON THE NEXT NEWS
HOUR, PRESIDENT OBAMA ROLLS OUT HIS GUN CONTROL
INITIATIVES, THAT'S RETIRED GENERAL STANLEY
MCCRYSTAL ON THE AFGHAN WAR.
THAT'S WEDNESDAY ON THE PBS NEWS HOUR.
>> >>DWANE: SAN DIEGO WEATHER MOSTLY SUNNY
AND WARM OVER THE NEXT FEW DAYS, NEAR 70 AT
THE BEACHES WITH NIGHT TIME LOWS IN THE 40S
AND 50S.
INLAND VALLEYS WILL WARM INTO THE 70S THROUGH
IS SATURDAY, DIPPING INTO THE 40S AT NIGHT.
CHILE IN THE MOUNTAINS, MID 50S AND BREEZY
TOMORROW.
PLENTY OF SUN SHINE IN THE DESERT WITH TEMPERATURES
IN THE LOW 70S THROUGH SATURDAY.
AFTER SIX WEEKS IN OFFICE, SAN DIEGO MAYOR
BOB FILNER DELIVERED HIS PROGNOSIS FOR THE
CITY OF SAN DIEGO.
HE COMPARED THE CITY'S FINANCIAL HEALTH TO
THAT OF A PATIENT RECOVERING FROM A LIFE THREATENING
ILLNESS PROJECTING A 40ﾊMILLION DOLLAR DEFICIT,
FILNER SAYS HE CAN HELP THE CITY GET THROUGH
THE ROCKY TIMES.
HE SAYS HIS RELATIONSHIP WITH LABOR UNIONS
WILL ALLOW HIM TO IMPLEMENT FINANCIAL REFORMS
THAT WILL SAVE THE CITY MONEY.
A CALIFORNIA JUDGE HAS ORDERED THE BOY SCOUTS
OF AMERICA TO RELEASE TWO DECADES OF INTERNAL
FILES DETAILING SEXUAL ABUSE ALLEGATIONS.
A CIVIL LAWSUIT WAS FILED IN SAN DIEGO TODAY
AGAINST THE BOY SCOUTS ON BEHALF OF A 29 YEAR
OLD WHO CLAIMS HE WAS MOLESTED AS A TEENAGER
BY A CAMP COUNSELOR.
JAPAN AIRLINES SERVICE BETWEEN SAN DIEGO AND
TOKYO MAY BE IN TROUBLE.
THEY GROUNDED THEIR BOEING 787S AFTER ELECTRICAL
FIRE'S SMOKE WENT INTO THE CABIN OF SIMILAR
PLAN PLANES.
BOSTON PS DREAM LINER HAS HAD PROBLEMS WITH
FUEL LEAKS.
AND YOU CAN FIND TONIGHT'S STORIES ON OUR
WEB SEAT KPBS.ORG/EVENINGEDITION.
THANKS FOR JOINING US.
YOU HAVE A GREAT NIGHT.