Hey, it's a thing.
If you hadn't heard, Tabletop
Day is happening this
Saturday, March 30.
What is that day?
You can check out
Tabletopday.com for all the info.
But basically, we are making a
holiday for everybody to go
out and play board
games together.
Guys, there are over 2,200
events in 50 countries.
We even have Antarctica
on board.
This [BLEEP]
is real.
Also, we are going to be
streaming live on Geek and
Sundry all day Saturday,
starting at 9 AM Pacific.
My friend Wil Wheaton
is coming over.
We're going to be playing
games all
day with our friends.
We're going to be having
so much fun.
So you can tune in between,
you know,
setting up all your games.
Also, do not forget to take
pictures and make videos of
everything you guys are doing,
and share it with the hash tag
#Tabletopday.
We want everybody to be aware of
this day, so that it lives
in eternity.
But also we want to find it,
so we can put your stuff in
our wrap-up video at the end.
Thanks, everybody, for making
this event so huge.
And remember, March 30,
that is happening.
Bye.