and civil
the republican promises for policies
that create economic growth
we believe lower taxes less regulation
balanced budgets
assault on social security a solvent
medicare
will all stimulate growth using taxes to
punish the rich
in reality punishes everyone because
we're all interconnected
high taxes and excessive regulation and
massive debt are not working
no republican questions
or speed civil rights
i've never wavered in my support for
civil rights for the civil rights act
dispute
if there is one has always been about
how much of the remedy should come under
federal
or st
or private party
okay hope to get on a lot out of the
bond and
no i mean when it was a frightening for
scholars is that in his first statement
about social security minutes it's
strange because i think it would be to
make this point in the earlier today
that you know he's ideologically opposed
to programs like social security and
medicare suffering in the car
yet it is not that is not interested in
hurting so so it is just it's an
outright lies in military use there was
a solvent so secure on a silent night
here so what he means is we have to cut
benefits
completely until the program doesn't
work anymore it to kill the program
getting that's what he's saying and the
democrats although the budget hostage
yes indeed yes soldier account so that
was kinda he's amused and also said that
uh...
you know high taxes and high debt which
is not working right now
we have the lowest tax rate effectively
then we have since the fifties and i saw
her return yesterday of a proper tax a
personal tax rates are the lowest
penicillin and that's where yes or not
trying that right now what we're
traveling trying is a low taxes
and uh... and a lot of wars
that sort right now it doesn't work
so far so good that we're having a
problem here
and they keep pretending that wall
street is still regulated the problem
with our economy is wall street is
actively
is operating in them
in interest of wall street only so
that's that without regularly was never
mohammed regulations so
it is this whole rewriting of history
that though the right wing seems to do
and then of course in the mainstream
media goes to cover them they have to
pretend that both sides of this is wrong
and just as stupid as david both sides
both sides
that no one really gets me about this is
his attempt at revisionist history
hands-on rights yeah the civil rights
that that the idea
that you know i've been ebay willfully
delicacy willfully ignores the fact that
the law
fundamentally related merrick and
political parties
to the point that they no longer bear
any resemblance to their nineteen
fifties catholic parties fees just
remains wrecked these kids into thinking
that oh well you know martin luther king
he was a republican yell yell back when
the republicans actually listed four you
know nice thanks my head rights and stop
headset it wants the civil rights
legislation was passed
the southern democrats became a republic
and they flew out of the railroad and
monkey and they're now the party and
that's i don't see how he thinks it is
doing without this is that new thing
that the right keeps pushing and i know
of cuz im on face book
and i see this all the time
when they say all you know the democrats
are the racists it was the republicans
that freed the slaves and most of those
rebel and republicans voted for the
civil rights act okay so they again what
you just pointed out big no ring that
the civil rights act which was passed in
nineteen sixty four out when johnson's
sign that he said i'm lou signing away
the south and losing the south of the
democratic party for a generation
because all the racists terry that when
bigots that were in the democratic party
left them for that uh... and went to the
republican party
and that's how we got realigned so yes
back before the civil rights act
the democratic party was just as racist
and just as horrible but since then
the republicans have instituted their
southern strategy
which is too deep too appealed to the
prejudices and fear of minorities in the
southern white right so that in fact to
has worked very well thanks to it's a
lot of the last three republican
chairman has as apologized
for this including michael steele
and uh... ten million had and they had
apologized
for the southern strategy so
ignore recent history they concentrate
on history before nineteen sixty four
and uh... i didn't get to see the whole
speech but due to rain and put them into
the civil rights act in the sixty four
but the rainfall go into these this
african-american let's talk about the
uh... the the voting rights act of
nineteen sixty five that republicans are
now in court
trying to go out did he bring this up
knows even didn't say anything and in
saving bank curtain current legislation
that republican legislators are trying
to put an antenna and more difficult
for people to can't imagine why he would
want to highlight that his speech that
he also said in the senate republicans
are for economic growth they just can't
let that go without answering the fact
is if you go back
on this story as you know as long as ram
paul is in the mood for a month to go
back and look at history
go back and look at the economy go back
and look at the stock market's pullback
it look like any economic measure you
want over the last eighty years
and see
how the stock market it under democrats
how the economy did under republics the
fair one to the other
it's not
even close
democratic policies whether you like
them or not
are more successful economically other
part i wanted to mention he said i never
waivered in my support of civil rights
uh... because he couldn't we don't have
msnbc at our house is saying i get that
there is getting
but he went on in return the palestinian
and and this is a interview that he did
at the louisville courier journal back
in may of two thousand
five don't like the idea of telling
product business a or racism
i think it's a bad business decision
ever exclude anybody from the restaurant
but at the same time i do believe in
private ownership
but i think this should be absolutely no
discrimination in convincing the public
funding and that's what most of what
civil rights act was about to my mind
most of them
uh... you know he he didn't mention the
there that he went on the civil uh...
ridge amana jo was asked what he had
voted for
the civil rights act and that could not
answer that question right
yes other than that
he has and where r these are all right
so there is no landfall